Look, I didn't mean it
to be this way.
This— Every— The reasons why
I'm leaving are on this tape.
It points out the 6 points
of why I think
our relationship is doomed
and why I'm leaving it.
You can watch it later.
I was gonna mail it
but now-- I'll just
give it to you now.
Are you taking your VCR,
or did you leave that upstairs?
I bought the VCR!
I'm taking my VCR!
I bought—
It's the only thing I'm taking.
What is that on top of the car?
Is that a futon on top of the car?
That's our futon.
That's my futon.
I'm takin' the—
Can I please take the futon?
Please?
-Get in the car!
-Violence is not the answer!
Don't be drivin' back here
in a couple days, okay?
I'm not going through this
over and over and over.
I'm not…
That's on the tape.
I think that's point
number 4 on the tape
because I have my vision,
you have your vision
and I'm leaving, because
the Tantoonis need me.
-The who?
-The Tantoonis.
What is…?
It's an Indian tribe.
It was in the newspaper.
It was on CNN!
You don't even watch TV.
You don't read the paper.
You don't know what's going on in the world!
That's one of my reasons.
That's point 1!
-You can't just walk out, Sean.
-Listen, listen.
I'm gonna go,
and I'm not coming back.
-Take Fidel.
-Please take Fidel.
I'm not taking Fidel, Sean.
I'm not taking your fucking cat!
I don't have the time and
energy to take care of the cat.
I have to go and get
something accomplished.
That cat would be in the way—
Ow! I am a man of peace!
You are a woman of violence.
I'm not a man like that.
And you're turning me into that man.
That's like point number 8. I don't know.
-Hi. Good night.
-Good night, Erin. Have a good night.
Dr. Kravitz, you have a visitor
in the main lobby.
Dr. Kravitz, a visitor
Do you guys know Bob, that
security guard from the lobby?
-He's really something, huh?
-Yeah.
He asked me to go to this little soiree
with him on Saturday to the aquarium,
'cause that's where
he used to work,
and then yesterday he drops,
like he mentions that
Rick hit on him last summer.
Oh, he didn't say that!
I only flirted.
It was his uniform.
I couldn't resist!
I know, but the thing is
that he said some really
mean and nasty things about you.
They made me feel
really bad.
All right,
so he's a homophobic prick.
So what else is new?
Story of my life.
I already said yes,
that I would go.
-You left me the witches' costume?
-Honey, it's you!
Thank you very much.
I really appreciate it.
You're confused, honey.
What would you do
if you were me, Erin?
Well, you want to get out of it?
Yeah.
Tell Bob
that you're meeting
a friend and her "date"
at the party.
And then, when her date
doesn't show up,
she gets really upset,
she wants to leave,
you need to take her home
and then you're out.
That's it. It's really simple.
Men are really easy to trick.
Or treat, you witch.
That's perfect! I need a friend, though
and I have no friends so
Erin, will you please go with me
and be my friend?
No. I hate parties.
You always have a reason.
Please come with me.
Oh, Erin, you have just got to go!
I mean, what man could resist
the wicked witch of the west wing?
Listen, my mother
is in town this weekend.
I don't have any time.
I have to be with her.
Yeah, okay, well.
Wait a minute. My mother
is in town this weekend.
Yeah, I'll go.
Oh, thank you!
Trick or treat!
Mama! Mama!
Oh, oh, honey!
Mama!
-I want my daddy!
-Mama!
Daddy!
I found it.
-You haven't got much Wordsworth, have you?
-No.
I'll let you have that one half price.
Oh, shoot!
-Got it?
-Yep.
There you go.
No, no. Don't close it.
You should never close a book
until you've read something from it.
What?
Just a sentence or a word.
It can be very, very revealing.
Just read something, anything.
Read from the top, then.
"When from our better selves
we have too long Been parted
by the hurrying world,
and droop,
Sick of its business,
of its pleasures tired,
How gracious,
how benign is Solitude"
Hi, it's Mom. I fly in
at 9:30 tomorrow morning
so I'll see you at the gate.
Hope we can have a little fun tomorrow
night. Kick up our heels or something?
Airport Station next.
Change here for the airport
terminal shuttle. Next stop, Airport.
Change here for the Logan
Airport terminal shuttle.
The airport shuttle service is located
up the escalator, to the left.
Inbound train approaching.
This is Airport Station.
Stay clear of the doors.
Aquarium Station next.
Next stop, Aquarium.
Welcome to the Boston Aquarium,
home of Myrtle the turtle
and Puff the balloonfish.
What's expanding faster than Puff,
the balloonfish?
We are. The North Addition,
coming in 1999.
Watch us grow!
Hey, you guys? Who is this?
That is… Fred Astaire?
No, no, no. This is Burgess Meredith.
Remember? I was telling you this yesterday.
You have to recognize that marking there.
-By his neck.
-I knew it.
Oh, he escaped from the tray
again last night.
Oh, don't worry about it. That's okay.
I mean, they always escape.
-Hey, Ben.
-How you doin'?
Yuri needs you for a second down in pumps.
He has another pipe leak.
I can't, Ben.
I'm diving in two minutes.
It's a two-minute job.
For you, anyway.
Did you have a chance to go over the
Assistant Aquarist application I put in?
Okay, nothing's been decided.
But you're still on the running.
All right. Thanks, Ben.
The dolphin
show begins in…
Ahh, good!
I'm a volunteer diver,
not volunteer plumber, Yuri.
This is the last time I'm comin'
down and doin' you a favor, all right?
I'm not getting paid for this. I don't want
to be down here helping you. No moreski.
I do. I do you favor.
Yuri, first of all, what's this?
You have half a gasket in here.
Where's the other half
of the gasket?
Bye!
So, that isn't a problem.
Just fax it to the hotel.
I'll sign it, and then
I'll fax it back. All right.
Now, darling, you weren't there.
-And this gentleman…
-I was here, Mom. Your plane was early.
Well, whatever.
I didn't see you,
and I thought
you weren't gonna make it
so this very lovely man offered me a ride
and so I took it and I'm sorry
-but I did leave you a message on the machine.
-Okay, forget about it.
It gave me some time to walk around.
I went to the aquarium.
Wait a minute. Hold on.
Let me make it up to you.
My latest acquisition.
What do you think?
Blinding teeth.
-Well, he's available.
-What?
-They're not all gay, you know.
-Piper!
Darling!
-Oh, hi!
-Oh, my God!
-It's so good to see you!
-I have never, ever seen you in red.
What has happened?
Oh, this isn't red.
This is Hollywood black.
You look great.
And this—look at this—
this is my latest find.
He is going to be the
biggest thing ever.
-Isn't he big now?
-Oh, yes, you know, he is.
-It pays the tuition.
-Tuition?
-I'm in med school.
-Really?
My daughter went to medical
school. Yes, Harvard.
-Harvard.
-Yes. She didn't want to continue.
I didn't finish.
She didn't finish because it
was her choice not to finish.
She had the highest grade point
average of any female at Harvard.
-No, I didn't.
-Yes, she did.
-No. No, I didn't.
-Yes, you did.
-Piper.
-I did not!
-So, what are you doing now?
-I'm a phlebotomist.
You study insects?
She is not a phlebotomist.
She is a registered nurse,
a profession her late father
esteemed very highly.
And she's a very good one.
-I'll see you later.
-It's inevitable to see you later.
Bye-bye, Rory.
Good luck to you.
He'll need it.
So, how's the old place?
It's quiet.
Renovations?
We never finished.
Have you really been by
yourself ever since that…
that Marxist left?
-He was an activist, Mother.
-Well, it's the same thing.
I must say I was delighted when I heard
you gave him his walking papers.
Sean left me, Mom.
No. And you let him?
Did I have a choice?
Dear, sweetness,
light of my life,
with men, you always have a choice.
Well, you didn't.
I am sorry, Mom.
I don't know why I said that.
-It's okay.
-There's no comparison.
You're right.
Loss is loss.
It's the same thing, either way.
You know what I think
your father would have wanted?
I think he would want you
to move on,
find yourself a new man
and be happy again.
I am happy.
Well, there's no crime
in showing it, is there?
Look, Mom. I know that you
don't think that a woman
-can be alone and be content.
-What are you talking about?
This is me you're talking to.
Of course, I do.
Oh, come on.
You are never alone.
You're always surrounded
by all these people.
Listen, what are we going
to do tonight?
I had an idea. Thought maybe
Dodge and I would come over
to the old apartment
and have some cocktails—
Dodge?
-Dodge!
-Who is Dodge?
The gentleman I met
at the airport. I told you this!
-You never listen to me!
-His name is Dodge?
His name is Dodge and we thought
we'd take you out tonight.
I have a date.
Anyway Dodge and I thought
that we would have some drinks—
-What?
-I have a date.
You have a date! Goddamn you.
What have I been carrying
on about? Who with?
Who is it with? Come on.
A girl from work.
This is Wonderland Station
in the Wonderland commuter parking lot.
A quarter-pound of pecorino, please.
The price of cheese.
Reporter Arnie Reisman has
been following that story.
It's only the latest in a series
of anonymous acts of vandalism that began
last month during the Boston Aquarium's
prolonged legal battle
with Lesser Construction.
Yesterday, Lesser Construction
lost its bid to build
a state-of-the-art mausoleum
on this waterfront lot,
now officially, future home of
the aquarium's North Addition.
I want to congratulate
Miss Shebola and the aquarium
for getting the approval
for their Addition.
Now, the good people of Boston will
have a place to cavort with fish
instead of a place to
properly, hygienically,
not to mention economically,
bury their loved ones.
Now, this will not send
our company, in any sense,
into any kind
of financial distress.
We're now in the business
of building privately run,
for-profit,
commercial prisons.
There's no need to tell
you how successful they are.
What about the allegations that
you're behind the aquarium vandalism?
That is very… I've heard.
That's ridiculous.
I love fish. They're good creatures.
I've nothing against them.
Are you worried that you're going to wind
up in the same prison you're building?
-Is that funny?
-That's enough!
-You're actin'like an idiot!
-Stupid!
I am not acting like an idiot!
No, you're not actin'like an idiot.
-You just don't fuckin' listen!
-Who do you think you are, leavin' here?
-You're acting like--
-Take it easy!
Hey, hey, hey,
cut, cut, cut!
Will you guys please shut up?
What is the matter with you?
We had an argument, all right?
I'm sorry.
Try to keep it down.
Will you please
try and keep it down?
He is trying to study, all right?
Have a little respect.
Who cares what other
fuckin' people say?
You moron!
-I'm not an idiot, you are!
-Man!
…their continued support
for the protesters
said they now prefer to
negotiate with developers.
-This is Renita Harrow, BSN News.
-I don't give a damn!
And it is with pride that I pronounce
that when construction finishes
on the North Addition in 1999
Boston will again have
the nation's premiere public aquarium.
Let us christen
this voyage tonight,
leave the port, move forward,
put the bad water behind us.
On behalf of myself and Puff,
our little fish mascot…
-Frankie, get me a drink.
-You got it, Arty.
…enjoy the festivities.
Thank you.
So, what kind of an idiot
would blow off a woman like you?
He's a bastard.
Let me tell you
something about this guy.
He's a little acey-deucey.
You know what I mean.
No straight guy in his right mind
would blow off a woman like you.
Yeah, well, I guess
it wasn't meant to be.
I don't know.
I think I'm gonna go home.
No, wait.
What do you say
I go with you?
You're alone, I'm security.
I mean, she and I,
we're not even involved.
As far as I'm concerned, Bob,
there is no security.
Only security guards.
Hey! Hello. Hey, Erin.
-Could I just have a minute?
-Certainly. Certainly.
See you, Bob.
Okay, all right.
Are we done? Can we go now?
Are you done?
Can you go?
Wait a minute. I thought that the
whole point was that I would be here--
Right. But now
the point seems to be
that you are really
preoccupied with my date.
Oh, I'm preoccupied with Bob.
Hey! We havin' a good time?
Cricket, what do you say
we dance, right now?
-I'd love to.
-Great!
-Alan! Alan!
-Yeah?
Bob? Bob? Remember?
Bob, how are you?
This is Cricket.
Cricket, Alan. Alan, Cricket.
-How are you?
-Hi.
Cricket's a nurse
where I work now.
Over at the hospital.
Hey, we could have used you here last week
what with the shenanigans and everything.
A guy like Bob,
back in the saddle again, huh, Bob?
If I were still here,
that shit would never happen.
-Good seeing you.
-Alan.
-You here alone?
-Yes, I am.
I got a chick
you're not gonna believe.
A hot chick, free thinker, rubbin' against
the furniture right now, all by her lonesome.
She's trawlin'for action,
beggin'for somethin'
and I think you are the kind
of guy that can give it to her.
Well, you know, Bob. I'm really
quite flattered that you'd think of me
but to tell you the truth,
I'm real busy at the moment.
-So, I'll see you later.
-Wait a minute.
-What are you, some kind of fag?
-Alan!
Yo, Alan! How are ya?
-Oh, shit.
-I'll meet you at the bar!
-Great to see you again, Bob.
-Good to see ya.
Where ya been, buddy?
Hey, I'm gettin' the feeling
you're trying to avoid me.
No, no, no.
I'm not avoiding you, Frank.
I'm just very busy, you know.
I've got classes. I'm volunteering here…
-I got a little favor I gotta ask ya.
-Oh, Christ, Frank.
If this is about your toilet,
I can't come by every time.
No. It's flushin' like a champ
since you've been in there.
Listen, maybe you can take me
on a little tour.
-You want a little tour, Frank?
-Yeah.
You can show me that little Poof
fish that's on the news all the time.
Puff, Frank. It's a puffer
fish, all right? Come on.
When threatened,
a balloonfish can rapidly
inflate its body
with water or air.
Frank, do you see where it says,
"Do not tap on the glass"?
All right?
These are very sensitive fish.
-They got feelings?
-Yeah, they do, Frank.
You know what? You're really
not supposed to smoke here,
so why don't we go back
where we came from
and I'll just see you in a couple days
and I'll give you some money, all right?
You were doing just fine
when you were plumbing, Al.
When you were workin' with your
father, when you were a team.
Look, Frank, you did me a really
big favor by lending me the money
so I could go to school,
but I'm a full-time student now
and it's just gonna take me
a little more time.
I can't give you
any more time.
Christ, Frank.
What do you expect me to do?
I don't have any money.
Small favor. Do it, and I'll knock off
the interest on the loan.
…the North Addition, coming in 1999.
Certain people just want
a message sent, that's all.
So what is this
"favor"?
Just eliminate the fish,
that's it.
-Puff?
-Yeah, Puff!
What, are you kidding me, Frank?
There's no way!
Oh, for Christ's sake!
It's a goddamn, pansy-ass fish!
Look at it!
Ladies.
You know, Frank, I can't believe
that you're asking me to do this!
I'm not gonna do it!
But don't worry—you know what?—
'cause I will definitely
get you your money, one way or the other.
Next Monday I will see you,
I will have your money
plus your three points, all right?
Hey, Alan.
Who's gonna loan you the money,
your father?
He's at the dog track,
blowin' the two grand
I fronted him last week.
…biologists call it
a defense mechanism
because it defends the fish against
attacks by hungry predators, like sharks.
Smile! Hey, looks like you
just made the society page!
What's your name, gorgeous?
Hi, this is Erin.
Please, leave a message after the beep.
Hi, doll. I've got some
interesting news for you.
Okay, now. If you look
in this week's Herald…
Hi, sweetie, it's me. I'm in London.
-I just picked up a copy of the Herald.
-Yeah, I know. I saw it.
What do you mean you saw it?
Who spoiled it for you?
What are you talking about?
Wait a minute.
Why do you have the Herald?
Aren't you in London?
If you'll just look at page 67,
I'll be able to tell you.
Wait. These are
the personal ads.
Just look, in the middle
of the second column,
right between "Vivacious Vixen"
and "Wasting Away".
"Waiting For You"
"Do you believe in destiny? I do"
"Be part of mine"
"Me: 29, five foot six"
"Brains, beauty, body, all in one"
"Frisky, cultured and carefree
professional with zest for life"
"Number one in fun!
You: Sophisticated, smart
and sumptuous success story
who will make me smile"
"Us: soul mates seeking
spontaneous combustion?"
"Pervs or drunks need not apply"?
Darling, you sound so excited!
I'm very happy!
You put in a personal ad for me?
I admit I did have
a little help from my publicist.
-Oh, my God.
-Darling, look.
If you're not going to help yourself,
I feel, as your mother,
that I have the right
to help you if I can.
As my mother?
As my pimp is more like it.
Look, sweetie,
it's only an option.
You can access your messages
by dialing a four-digit code.
I gave you your birthday, 1966.
You know, Ma,
I would never do this. Never!
And who is this person?
"Frisky, carefree, with a zest for…"
Oh, this is you.
Isn't it, Mom?
-This is you.
-No, sweetie, it is not me. It is you.
It is the you I remember,
the sweet, darling, happy you
that you used
to be before…
I'm sorry.
I've got to get ready
to go to work.
I know.
Listen. I just wanted to remind you,
actually, about Thanksgiving in Manhattan.
I won't forget about Thanksgiving, Mom.
I'll be there.
Feel free to bring a new friend
if you like.
Yes. Here we are, ladies and gentlemen.
The angler fish.
This is the female, by the way.
My apologies, ladies.
Nature can be cruel.
Can anyone tell me,
out of interest,
why the male is so humbly displayed?
Come on, people. Wake up! Someone!
Someone other than Alan.
Anybody but Alan.
Okay, Alan.
-The Ceratadeam…
-Ceratoidea.
Ceratoidea has evolved
so that the male is always
right there with the female,
ready to inject it with the sperm.
It's what you would call
a "symbiotic relationship".
Thank you, Alan. Another
amazingly accurate answer.
Moving on, next snapshot,
if you would.
Ah! The Coelacanth.
The Coelacanth is known to be
one of the most elusive
of the deep-sea creatures.
Julie, come here.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
I stand corrected.
This is probably the most elusive
of the sea creatures.
And by "sea", I mean C
or maybe D or most probably F.
-Sit down.
-Sorry.
I'd like to see you
in the office a little later.
You're the only one
who takes notes in that class, Alan.
Everybody takes notes.
They have notebooks,
and you have a…
You know, you're a tutor and you should
be making sure I do things like that.
Wait a minute.
Julie, I'm not your tutor.
-Yes, you are.
-No, I'm not.
I hired you.
No, you didn't hire me.
I'm just a friend.
You make it sound like
I'm some old man or something.
Well, you gotta help me, then.
I'll give you my notes, all right?
Make copies of them
and definitely copy--
Let's go to the study hall now
and then you can…
-No, no, tell you what.
-…catch me up a little.
You take the notebook.
Give it back to me tomorrow.
I gotta go see Ray
about my paper.
You're such a pill!
What're you talking about?
I'm not a pill.
I like a good time
as much as the next guy.
I'm just not the next guy.
I'll see you later.
Good morning, Boston! 20 minutes past the hour…
Rick, you are definitely water.
Olly, I know you're fire, all right?
So, how did you two meet?
-Well, all right.
-No, no, no, no. I'll tell the story.
-Let me--
-No, 'cause you always lie.
-I don't lie. I embellish.
-Make it juicy. Just tell me!
Well, it was about four years ago.
I was out on the duck tour, you know?
Oh, yeah.
You know, the amphibious thing
that goes in the water?
-Can I tell the story?
-Yes, sure. I'm embellishing.
-I get seasick really easily.
-We were still on Newbury Street.
We weren't even out of the
harbor yet. He's seasick.
I was on the side.
Basically, I was getting sick.
Oh, but as a nurse
I'm used to that kind of thing
-and I took right over, didn't I?
-He did.
And I was very professional.
And, I consider myself, now
the luckiest nurse in all of Boston.
Except, of course, for you, Erin.
Erin, this is a great shot.
Correction, my dear.
That is not luck. That is fate.
-Fate is bullshit.
-I don't believe in fate.
What?
What, like there's some unseen hand
leading you down the garden path?
-Exactly.
-I wish. I'm sorry, I don't believe it.
-It isn't necessarily unseen--
-Unseen hands can be fun!
I totally believe in fate.
I mean, like, for instance,
if Erin hadn't been
at the aquarium party the other night
I never would have realized
how much I wanted Bob.
-Ta-da!
-Who's Bob?
-This guy that I'm dating.
-Case in point.
-You know, I heard he quit.
-No, Bob was fired, actually.
He was demonstrating
how to load his gun
in the commissary
to a small child.
Yeah. That was a total setup.
I don't know, Erin. You have
to believe in something, right?
-It makes life more fun.
-That's right! And Erin is the fun girl.
-Fun, fun, fun.
-Yes. All of Boston society knows it now.
You look great.
All right, all right.
Here's one, here's one. Ready?
"I am a divergent thinker with a
sharp wit, but a reflective soul."
"I value quiet reads, sublime sunsets, humor, tenderness and balance."
That's not a personal ad!
That's a fuckin' daily affirmation!
I'll find you a personal ad.
Alan, are you in?
What are you talkin' about? In what?
Oh, it's a bet. We're all gonna
reply to the same personal ad.
We go out with the chick.
First guy who scores gets 200 bucks from the two losers.
-Right on.
-Or three.
So I guess Traci's what, history?
No, I ain't got time for a townie.
I mean, no offense, bro.
None taken, bro.
-What do you say? You in or…
-Okay, so what do you have to do to win?
Well, we agreed on it.
It's gotta be a French kiss.
That's tongues,
intermingling consensually, right?
-Unforced. That means you, all right?
-Yeah, unforced.
Just out of curiosity,
hold on a second.
How will the two losers know
that the winner actually won?
-We watch it.
-Right.
-We'll be there.
-Incognito.
Yeah. We'll be in disguise.
-It's gonna be great. Are you gonna be in or what?
-Well, no. Are you kiddin'?
That's, like, the stupidest
thing I've heard in my life.
Of course I'm not in. Maybe it's
just when you get to be my age.
I realize that I can only be who I am.
I can't present myself in any different way.
I don't wanna meet somebody who
presents herself in a different way
because then you have two people that
are basically lying, gettin' together
talkin' a bunch of crap, you know?
I know this firsthand, because
what I've been tryin'to do
is to change my destiny and not just
spend the rest of my life being a plumber.
Not that there's anything wrong with
plumbing, but it gives me a freedom.
I can pursue the thing I really love.
How do you find what you love?
-Well, I think…
-I'm kidding.
Oh, man!
Things are getting like…
Jesus, what are we?
A bunch of chicks or something?
-Bob's probably my soul mate.
-I believe that. I totally believe that.
-How could you say that?
-I dearly hope that Bob is not your soul mate.
Look, look. It's not about Bob.
It's about whether or not there's
meaning and direction in our lives.
-I suggested that--
-Well, there isn't!
What do you mean,
"There isn't"?
I'm not saying there's not meaning,
but there's no direction, you know?
Case in point, my parents.
They met on an airplane.
They were flying back from Paris.
The only reason my mother was on the flight--
she was supposed to be on an earlier flight
but on the way to the airport
her taxi struck and killed a little dog
who was chasing a little furry squirrel
and she was delayed.
That's a totally random act,
you know?
-That's why she met my father.
-No, Erin, that is fate.
-Oh, come on.
-Tell that to the dog.
-Yes, tell that to the dog.
-No, no, I'm serious!
You don't want to be a plumber, Alan.
The point is I don't wanna be a plumber
but I got nothin' against my father,
I got nothin' against my grandfather.
He's doin' what he wants to do.
I'm tryin' to do what I want to do.
And What are you doing?
You're gonna be a marine biologist?
I'll tell you something.
I don't know from marine biology.
But I don't see any money in it.
I mean, plumbing, money.
And you're still
workin' with water.
I got nothing against being a plumber.
Someone asks me what I do,
and that's what I'm doing, I'm a plumber.
I mean, it's not about
being a plumber.
What does Dad think about you
not wanting to be a plumber?
You know what? I'm gonna go up to the bar
and buy a round of drinks
to celebrate my brother
moving to the South End.
You don't have a problem with a
drink from an eastie, do you, Kev?
Sure.
Man. What's the matter
with your brother?
He's got his head in
the books, every night.
I Mean, he's studying
and studying and studying.
We never studied that hard
and it never hurt us.
"Consistency is the hobgoblin
of little minds."
Yeah! Yeah.
-Consistency.
-Of course.
"Is the hobgoblin of little minds."
-Harry! What's happening?
-Hey, how are you, pal?
Funny you should stop by.
You know who was in
this morning lookin' for you?
-Who?
-Frankie.
What?
You know, Frankie the collector.
Frankie! We all know Frankie.
What can I get you, my friend?
-Three Sam Adams and a ginger ale.
-You got it.
So, what's an attractive girl like you
doing in a bar so early?
Lookin' for fun, maybe?
What's that on your nose?
You know, the purple blemish
on the end of your nose?
Looks like a basal cell nevus
or maybe a melanoma?
You know, you may want
to get that checked.
For a man your age a malignant melanoma
could be fatal if not promptly removed.
"Me: 29, five six.
-Brains, beauty, body. All in one.
-That's nice.
Frisky, cultured and carefree
professional with zest for life.
-Number One in fun."
-"Number One", that's good.
"Pervs or drunks
need not apply."
-That's you two.
-That's funny!
Look, we fake it
just like she is.
Gentlemen, believe me,
the fact of the matter is
this woman's not what she seems.
If she's a beauty, I'm a perv, okay?
-Oh, shit! C'mon, man!
-I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
-What's goin'on? You all right?
-I'm fine.
Just spilled some water.
I got it. I got it.
Okay, sugar. You have a good one.
-Will you wake me up when you get in?
-Yep.
-Bye, Oliver.
-See you!
-That's so sweet!
-Olly is so wonderful.
I love how you two met.
I mean, he is so Sag.
Olly would hate me
for telling you this
but I can't resist.
We actually met
through a gay dating service.
What?
Manhunters on the
"Meat Market" bulletin board.
You call in a description,
like "Tenderloin" "Butt"…
No, I'm kidding.
But it was through a gay dating service.
But what about the mystery?
Oh, honey, it does not matter
how you meet Mr. or Ms. Right.
I will tell you what
the real mystery is.
The real mystery is:
What keeps two people
together after they meet?
Okay.
You have no new messages.
End of messages.
Hi, Erin. Just want to be clear.
This is very important.
I know I've left before.
I know I've come back with my tail
between my legs and cowered and such.
I'm not gonna do that again.
I'm leaving. This is it. I'm fed up.
I don't want to fight with you anymore, and
the reasons are what I'm listing right now.
That's 4 or 5. I can't remember.
First off,is, uh,you've never
come with me once to my rallies.
The reason why you don't want
to come to my rallies is that
you do not like the
masses, crowds, whatever.
What do you have against the
masses, is what I want to know?
I am in the mass. I am
a member of the crowd.
No new messages. End of messages.
…workers, Erin, is the
only way we as a people
in this country, we as a people
in this society, will move…
End of messages.
You have no new messages.
You have no new
messages. End of messages.
Say this was a rally,
our relationship, and I showed up to it.
No matter how many signs, how many slogans,
how many things I'm chained to.
I cannot, somehow,
change our relationship.
I can't change you.
I really have to say I wonder
if any man really ever could.
Hi. Welcome to the Herald personals.
To access your messages, please,
punch in your personal code
followed by the pound sign.
To hear your new messages, press 1.
To hear saved messages, press 2.
To delete a message, press 3.
You have 64 new messages.
To hear your new messages, press 1.
Hi there. This is, Bob calling.
Hi, I'm Daryl.
My name is Elliott, and I
am an insurance adjuster.
Hi!
Hey, how you doin', toots? It's me, Joey.
Anyway, let me tell you
a little bit about myself.
I'm active. I'm energetic. I'm outgoing.
Forty-si--
Actually, 43 years old.
I have slightly thinning hair.
None on my back.
I have no back hair.
I'd say five nine,
five nine and a half.
Give or take a--
Let's just say around six feet.
Let me tell you about what I do.
I'm…
…a very successful 30-year-old attorney.
I decided to go back to school, actually,
and get a graduate degree in divinity.
I'm a Vietnam-era vet.
I'm a temp. But that's not,
like, a permanent thing.
I own my own business.
I'm calling you
from the office right now.
-My interests are…
-I like women a lot.
I was brought up Catholic, but we
can go into that when I meet you.
I like to do pull-ups
and occasionally I will do a squat thrust.
I think that probably we would
have a lot in common, because…
Come on!
I get along well with people.
I actually just finalized my divorce
about four days ago.
I have to admit
I've got some betrayal issues.
I'm looking for a woman
who is tall, yet clean.
Someone that likes their mother
and hopefully likes my mother.
Reading your ad made me feel like
we were soul mates, I thought.
If you could hold on, I have
a fax coming in now. I…
Beep
-My number's 5 5 5
-9536. And… over and out.
That was great.
-You know what?
-What?
You might as well
give me the check right now.
You don't have a chance in hell.
Hey! Alan!
Nice computer.
Here's your 135 bucks, Frank.
Just like usual.
You wanna count it?
Hey, what the hell
happened to your nose?
Let's take a little drive.
Shit.
Don't matter about the money now.
Don't matter about the money? Frank!
Look at this grease on my face, man.
You have any idea what I went
through to get this money?
I put my ass on the line
and vouched for you.
I thought I could count on you, Alan.
I promised certain people results.
They're expecting results now.
-If they don't get 'em…
-What did you bring me here for, Frank?
Your father's tool kit.
He comes in here yesterday
practically begging for another two grand.
And he gives me this for collateral.
I told him I can't loan him any
more, but he wouldn't take it back.
What am I gonna do
with a tool kit, Alan?
Thought that maybe you'd want it,
not that you need it anymore.
Go give 'em back to him.
He's down in section three.
Where he always is.
There goes Swifty!
Erin?
-Hi. I'm Nathan.
-Hi.
So, I take it this is your first time.
Yeah. You're the first suitor.
Suitor. I like that.
It's old fashioned.
I'm kind of an
old-fashioned guy myself.
You surprise me, frankly.
Why?
You just don't seem
like the sort of woman
who would resort
to placing an ad.
Sorry.
I'm sure you get that
all the time.
You're a very attractive woman.
-So, you study God?
-God?
-Aren't you a divinity student?
-Yeah.
Well, God's an immense subject.
We don't have to talk about it.
I think it makes
some people uncomfortable.
No! Let's talk about God.
I'm the V.P. of Operations at
the Krylex Corporation in Waltham.
Krylex manufactures small rubber
parts for a variety of commercial
and industrial products-- products
ranging from the small rubber helmets
on wall-mounted spring door studs
to the waterproof gaskets on
street newspaper vending machines.
You're starting to glaze
over. I see it. Don't worry.
Happens all the time. I'm not
offended. I'll tell you why.
It's because most people are blind
to the impact small rubber parts
have on their daily lives.
Erin, how often do people
look under their phones?
Precisely. When you get home,
I'd urge you to do just that.
You'll appreciate what
I'm about to tell you.
The four small rubber nubs
that your phone rests on?
Admittedly, not very exciting.
But, consider what the consequences
would be without those rubber nubs.
You know, you don't say a lot
but it's pretty obvious
what you're telling me.
-Really?
-Your body language says it all.
You're palming me.
I'm sorry?
You're palming me. Your
palms are exposed to me.
When a woman does that,
she's subconsciously flirting.
Yeah? What does this mean?
Oh. Tiger, hmm?
Let's just sum up here, okay? God is
definitely a woman, because only a woman
would have the kind of compassion
necessary to create someone
as beautiful as you.
Okay. There is one giant
hole in your argument.
Daryl, no female deity would have had
the absence of mind to create you.
The male gender, a gender that spends all
of its time looking forward to getting off.
God is a man. Why?
Because men need women.
Women don't need men.
And yet, you're here.
It's a hole in your argument.
I collect art. South American, mostly.
Really? South American?
Have you been?
Yeah, my dad took me to Brazil
when I was very young.
But I love
Brazilian music.
Well, I was down there
for a conference ten days ago.
My tan's faded, but…
-That's it. You're playing with your hair.
-I'm bored.
Do you always deal
with people like this?
I… Well.
It's just that I've been taking this course in
communication and trying out things I learned.
Can I just drop it, I mean, really?
-I'm just so lonely.
-I'm sorry.
I can't meet people. It's like
I've got a sign on my forehead.
Yeah, that's the thing.
About God-- He's so hard
to pin down, at any moment.
-He?
-She.
You know, he, she, it.
As Cicero said
"Consistency is the
hobgoblin of little minds."
Ralph Waldo Emerson, you mean.
How come you never smile?
Would that make you more comfortable?
-You don't really like me, do you?
-No! I don't like poseurs.
I mean, you're probably
a very nice person
but I have no way of
knowing that, you know?
You're all uncomfortable,you're
telling all these strange jokes
and why are you trying
so hard to impress me?
You would be much more appealing
if you would just be yourself.
Here, let's see. " Frisky and carefree."
-So who's the poseur?
-My mother put in that ad.
Oh, really? Well, what's her number?
Who is the real Erin Castleton?
Please stand up.
Well, uh, what would you like to know?
First I'd like to know what
attracted you to nursing.
Other people's pain.
That's funny. I like that.
No, actually I was in medical
school at Harvard, but I dropped out.
Why?
I lost…
-I lost my motivation. It's a long story, anyway.
-Got all night. All morning.
Here you go, pal.
-Let me get this round.
-Refill?
-Yeah.
-Least I can do.
Uh, what the heck is that?
This is funny. I…
I was married once,
a long, long, long time ago.
But, I carry that as a sort
of, you know, good luck charm.
Well, I guess it's not working.
I can't put this here.
I got this dry-cleaned.
Don't worry, Kev.
There's plenty of room.
Just put it in the--
Aw, smells like fish, man. I'm
gonna get fish smell in my fabrics.
-Hello?
-Yeah, hi. My name is Erin.
You called about my ad in the Herald.
No, I think you must want my
brother Kevin. Hold on a second.
Hey, Kev! Telephone! It's for you!
Coming!
Sorry.
I got it! Hello?
This is he. Oh, it's nice
to finally meet you, Erin, so to speak.
Yeah, you'll have to excuse me.
I'm a little out of breath.
I'm moving out of the place I'm living in.
Yeah, I'm moving to a much nicer place.
You're the most beguiling
woman I've ever met.
You don't take men's
compliments very well, do you?
-I take what I need.
-Which is?
-Another round.
-You got it.
Barkeep, another round
for the lady, please.
Thanks.
I liked what you said
earlier about
-what was that?
-sticking to your principles
and following your dreams.
But, um, do you really
believe that if you do that
that things will just come to you
like it's destined?
Yeah, I really do.
You know, my brother says that a lot.
You know, he says you create
your own luck, but…
-You know, take me, for instance.
-No, no.
No, let's take your brother.
Okay. My brother.
-What's his name?
-Alan.
It's funny. When I think
of Alan, I think of
what W.C. Fields said which was
"Consistency is the
hobgoblin of little minds."
No, Emerson.
It was Ralph Waldo Emerson.
Well, whatever, I mean, whoever said it is
not so much important as I remembered it.
But I think of him that way because
he's always, always in his books.
-Books?
-Yeah, you know.
-Really?
-and I respect his determination.
I'm lucky, you know, because
I have more than determination.
I have determination plus talent
plus, like a natural intelligence
and then sort of a street savvy
that I think I've picked up myself.
And sometimes that's hard
to deal with, you know.
'Cause you know you've
got both barrels loaded.
And sometimes you only
wanna use one, but you can't.
You know, it's funny to
me when I think about it
because I remember back when
I was studying for the bar--
And I don't think I had to study
as hard as a lot of people--
Every night Alan was out
partying, and I'm at home
directed, and now it's sort of weird.
Because, you know,
I'm out there. I'm grabbing.
I'm taking, you know.
I see. I want. I take.
And he just sits at home
every night and studies, so…
Puff? Oh, my God.
Freeze!
But I'm not lonely.
I like to be by myself.
I mean, people
don't understand that.
You know, they think that you're a bitch
or that you must certainly be depressed.
I mean, say a woman is
sitting alone in a bar reading.
You know, a man who comes in,
he automatically makes an assumption
that she is either sitting there
waiting to be propositioned
and, you know, if she doesn't want it,
then there must be something wrong with her
because, you know,
what woman in her right mind
would be content just
sitting by herself, you know.
But I'm not lonely when
I'm sitting in a bar by myself
and I'm not even lonely
when I'm at home alone.
I get… you get lonely
in a crowded room
or a subway
that's packed with people.
You know, all these people
and every one a stranger.
My father had one
of those quiet Irish souls.
He was a poet.
Well, actually, he was a cardiologist,
but he wrote beautiful poetry.
He would take us to Ireland in the summers
and he and I would take these long walks
and then we would just sit
together staring out at the sea.
He said that if you can learn to contemplate
just one beautiful thing every day
that it would give you
something very special.
Ciúnas gan uaigneas
It's a Gaelic expression.
It means
"Quietness without loneliness."
Oh, my God.
I have been talking and talking.
It seems for hours.
I'm sorry, Barry.
It's… I think you're
the first man that I've met
that hasn't had a pathological
need to talk about himself.
But anyway, let's talk about you.
-What do you do?
-I'm a therapist.
Does that make you
feel uncomfortable?
Today, youngsters throughout Boston
struggled to express their feelings
for the fish we all called Puff.
Reporter Arnie Reisman was with
the children of the Wimble School
and got some of their reactions.
It wasn't just another day for
the kids here at the Wimble School.
For some, it was a difficult day.
When I heard that he
got eaten by a piranha
that, I felt like
he'd never come back again
'cause I never saw a fish in my life.
-How does that make you feel?
-Sad.
What a shame. Thanks, Arnie.
In national news, the Tantooni
standoff in Tantooni, Arizona--
You know, a nurse.
It's like the expression
"Consistency is the
hobgoblin of little minds."
What did you just say?
Oh, I was just quoting Marx, Karl Marx.
I tend to contradict myself
a lot, you know,
Especially around a…
you know, a…
You know, I'm feeling bloated.
I'm gonna go, take a pee-ski, okay?
And you want anything?
I mean, I'm sure you don't
want anything from the bathroom.
I'll just go.
That's gonna end up in my bank account.
You forget I was watching you.
I don't think you did so well.
What are you talkin'about? I did great.
Really couldn't see too well.
How do you think he did?
Are you kidding?
-He struck out.
-No surprise there.
-Think she can see us?
-Nah.
She wouldn't recognize us anyways.
Hi, honey. I'm home.
-Eric?
-Yeah?
-I like you.
-I like you too.
-You're my little hobgoblin.
-Number four.
And I'd rub your head and make a wish,
but there's too many people watching.
What do you mean?
-She's touching him.
-No. That can't be happening.
But I'd like to be alone
with you some place.
-Sure.
-No, not now, Eric.
Right, I mean, we should wait.
-Tomorrow night.
-That's a good time.
A little getaway I know of.
Don't tell anyone, okay?
It's just gonna be our little secret.
You promise me?
Right, right, absolutely.
Why would I say anything?
Meet me tomorrow night, 9:30.
It is a big deal, because Puff was
more than your average balloonfish.
-She represented to the children
-She? Did you say "she"?
-Puff was a female, yes.
-I can't believe I gave her those notes.
-You know what I mean?
-What?
-Talking about that girl Erin.
-Erin who?
Erin, the nurse.
-Oh, yeah, yeah.
-Yeah, she was sharp.
She was nice. I mean, I think
she was intimidated by me.
That's probably why
she didn't call back.
Along those lines, why don't we go out to
Zanzibar tonight and pick up a couple of ladies?
You know what, I'm out tonight.
I can't do it. I'm just not feeling up to it.
-You guys go.
-I'm just gonna nuke some fish sticks tonight.
Look on the bright side.
At least you didn't lose your money to me.
Let's go out. You gotta get back up
to the plate, man. Take your whiffs.
The prison will be privately
run and inmates charged for their stay.
Hello? Who?
The penal system took a detour into the twilight zone
-No, I'm not surprised at all.
-once again, thanks to the crafty ways
-Tonight?
-of Arty Milhous Lesser.
-It began this afternoon when the Suffolk County zoning
-Sure, tonight's great.
-reluctantly awarded Lesser
-9:30's perfect.
Our little secret, huh?
Don't worry. I won't tell a soul.
-Can I get you anything else?
-Just the check.
-What are you doin'?
-Hey! Hey!
Outside!
Get goin'! Get goin'!
What are ya both of ya
doin' here, ya freaks?
Oh, don't wipe it off, Alan.
What? You didn't like it?
I mean, it's not that I didn't like
it. It just came a little unexpectedly.
Come on. You've been flirting with me
since I hired you as my tutor in September.
-You didn't hire me as your tutor, all right?
-Yes, I did.
I accepted the respon-- I'm tryin' to
help you out in the class. That's all.
-I'm doin' you a favor.
-Don't deny it, Alan.
-Did you bring my notes, by the way?
-Oh.
I forgot them, but they're home.
I'll give them to you tomorrow.
Oh, good, well, you know, that was kind
of like the point of gettin' together.
I mean, the thing is…
It's just I'm tryin' to finish a paper tonight.
I mean, I kind of need the notes,
because that's what I took them for.
Well, this is our date. I didn't know
I was supposed to bring a bunch of papers.
It's not exactly. I mean, we were gonna get
together, and you were gonna give me the notes.
I mean, that was sort of
the point of it, I thought.
So you asked me to this
fancy restaurant on a date
so I could bring you back your notes.
That's really nice.
You look really beautiful.
Thank you. I got dressed
up especially for our date.
You know, I wonder if it would be possible
not to keep using that word, okay?
You are funny.
Have you ever seen a whale
swimming around in the ocean?
No.
Maybe you'd like to go with me on this
whale watch. It's incredible out there.
I mean, first of all, it's, like,
a half hour out on the boat
which is beautiful, and you're
looking over the expanse of the ocean.
And It's a very…
--"romantic" would be the wrong word--
just a serene pleasant time and I think
it'll perk up your interest in class.
-You wanna go?
-Yeah.
-All right. Well, let's see.
-So it's like another date.
No, I would say more of
a low-pressure, low-key
kind of just a couple
of friends hanging out.
I'd really be interested
in that. Seriously.
-I read Moby Dick.
-Okay.
Paging Dr. Betcher.
Paging Dr. Betcher, please.
-Hi.
Paging Dr. Stateman.
Dr. Stateman, please.
Bob's gay.
-He is?
-Yeah.
He came out on our last date.
That whole macho thing-- That
was, like, this huge cover-up.
I'm sorry.
Uh, you were right. I made,
like, this huge mistake.
It's just that Bob was there,
and I thought that that was my only choice.
You know, with men there's
always-- There's a choice.
It's just a really weak selection.
The only person that can
make you happy is yourself.
I know that sounds really hokey,
but I'm finding that to be true.
Yeah. Don't you just hate men?
Oh, God, I wish I did. That
would make my life so much easier.
-Who's got the malaria patient in room 18?
-He's mine.
Oh, to have been a mosquito
upon that man's cheek!
Mr. de Silva, you're dressed?
-Yes, I…
-I need to give you
a gamma globulin shot.
Would you take off your pants, please?
-I had all my shots yesterday.
-Not this one.
-Should I take off my pants?
-Yes, sir.
-ust my pants, right?
-Just your pants.
Okay.
What?
You like bossa nova?
-This gonna hurt?
-It's gonna be painful sitting down for a little while.
My flight is on Friday.
Where did you contract the malaria?
It was in Bolivia. I was on expedition.
I'm a musicologist.
I collect ethnic folk songs.
I'm going to Sao Paulo for holiday.
You like my country's music, right?
-I can tell there is a little bit of Brazil in you.
-Oh, yeah?
See, you are sad and happy.
You don't smile, but you are content.
You are sad and happy at the same time.
In Brazil we have a term
for that. It is saudade.
It's like melancholy,
nostalgia. It's very bossa nova.
§ Tristeza não tem fim. §
§ Felicidade sim. §
It means…
Sadness has no end. Happiness does.
-I like that song.
-Yes, it's a very good song.
Listen, there's a club in Somerville that
plays Brazilian music if you are interested.
-I work the night shift.
-Well, what time do you get out?
I'm sorry. That was very forward of me.
-I do not ever, ever
-Show me your hands.
I'm not married.
Well, you might have taken it off and put
it in your wallet. You know, men do that.
I'm not that kind of man.
My wallet just has pieces
of paper and lots of plastic.
I'm becoming a plastic person
I have so much plastic in…
I get out at 7:30 in the morning.
Well, my name is Andre de Silva.
And it was a pleasure having
you care for me…
-Erin.
-Erin. Yes.
You should have said it was a pain
in the ass. An American would have.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
I know, but I am
Brazilian, and we--
Erin.
-See you, Al.
-All right, Stu.
-Take care, Stu.
-All right. See you later.
-Hey, Alan.
-Hey, Ben.
-They want to see you up in Administration.
-Yeah.
Sit down.
We're all a little distracted
because of this latest incident.
Attendance has skyrocketed
because of all this publicity.
But all the kids want to see
now is the piranha exhibit.
Poor Puff, eh?
You volunteer a lot of hours here, Alan.
It's well worth it, Miss Shebola.
We think so too. We'd like
to start paying you for them.
It's great, because
I could really use the money.
Yuri Spinov needs a part-time assistant
in Physical Plant. He recommended you.
We know it's a change from
what you've been doing.
But it will put you on staff.
Well, I'll have to just
think about it a little bit.
Of course. Let us know by Monday?
Okay.
-Oh, God.
-This is to South American men with good sweaters.
But you should go back.
You really should.
The people are so wonderful.
That spirit-- You don't
find it anywhere else.
And the land.
The beaches are wonderful.
-Some day I will go back.
-You should go back. I'm going back.
-Yeah, why?
-This city…
It's all schools and hospitals
and bars and graveyards.
The young people here, all they
do is-- They study, and they drink.
It's terrible. I think one's
school year should be spent
you know, by the ocean walking with
someone that they love very much,
eating fried fish by the…
Anyway, you should go back.
You should go there.
I think you should be somewhere warm.
I think it would be good for your heart.
I don't know. I guess-- I feel that
if I left right now I would be running away.
Running away? I don't understand.
If you're running away, somebody's chasing you.
So what is it that's chasing you?
Personal business. I understand.
So let's make a toast. To perhaps the
most beautiful woman that ever lived.
Yes, the most beautiful woman
that ever lived which is you.
-Let's not confuse matters.
-And to me, the greatest man that ever lived.
Okay.
-Cheers.
Oh, geez.
I'm going to buy you the most expensive
$5 bottle of wine you ever saw.
Look what I got us: a bottle
of wine and a corkscrew.
No, no, don't, don't.
I need to get some air.
I need to get out of here.
Grab your binoculars and cameras,
folks, and get up on the deck
because in another few minutes, we'll be
entering the humpback whale feeding grounds.
What we have here is hands
down the best whale watching--
You all right?
My stomach is just,
like, wobbly, gobbly.
You know what's good. Just
look out there on the horizon.
Where?
The horizon would be
where the land and the sea meet.
Right. Just look directly out there
and take a couple of deep--
-Okay.
-Can you breathe deeply?
Feelin' a little better now?
Huh. Whoa.
Look at that! Spectacular!
Oh, shit!
Alan, I'm really sorry.
I'm being such a drag.
I'm keeping you from watching the
fish. Why don't you just go up there?
-I'll be all right here.
-No, no, no, no.
-No, go.
-No, I wouldn't dream of it.
-No, I feel really bad.
-It's just like a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
It's not a big deal.
No, I'm just kidding.
I'll come back out when you're feelin' better.
Without you, but I'll come back out.
You know what. I'm really not feeling very
well. I think I should just walk myself home.
No, I think you should stay.
It's fine.
I don't think I'm going to be
very good company right now.
This is the perfect company.
Look-- Look at the water.
That's very beautiful, like, like you.
See, it's-- You can be alone, but to be
alone with someone else who is alone--
Alone together--
That-- That is perfect.
-Do you know what I mean?
-I know what you mean.
Relaxation is everything.
It's the answer.
See, what relaxes you? Tell me.
You like to fly, right?
-I am terrified of flying.
-Oh, perfect.
Now you are in a two-seater
and it is being flown by my father who
weighs 462 pounds, because he lost 10.
And he can't see
out of his right eye or his left.
It changes.
And the plane goes like this.
And there's clouds inside
the plane, outside the plane.
And then all of a sudden, you're
getting sick. You're about to scream.
And then the plane just drops,
and you look out the window.
Then it clears, and there's beautiful
sunlight in the plane, and you look out
and you see Corcovado.
-Oh!
-Ah, and the beaches
and then the plane just glides in.
The door opens, and you're there.
You relax, and it's perfect.
-It's beautiful.
-Yes, very beautiful.
So why don't you come with me
to Sao Paulo?
-You're joking.
-No, I'm not joking.
God! Look at your
tattoo.
That is, like, so cool.
That's like Popeye.
It's really hard.
You know, Julie,
Seriously, you know,
I know what you're thinking.
And I mean…
Really, I…
-What am I thinking?
-I just invited you out here
because I wanted you
to experience this with me.
-Oh.
-All right? I'm sorry. I don't wanna hurt your feelings.
-So you don't have any desire to kiss me?
-Oh, no, no.
-You don't?
-No, of course, I have a desire to kiss you.
-But I just think
it would be best…  -I like you a lot.
Oh, I like you a lot too.
-You do?
-Yeah.
Geez--
-I will take care of everything. Visa.
-I can't believe you're asking me this.
-We're strangers.
-We are not strangers.
I have known you at least
two lifetimes that I know of.
-Oh, don't give me that bullshit, please.
-How is that bullshit?
-I know how you feel.
-I don't know what I feel.
I have to spend Thanksgiving
with my mother in Manhattan.
No, no, that's wrong.
Forget your mother.
-I love my mother.
-Yes, I love your mother.
I don't know her. When I know
her, I will love her, but--
Do this for you, darling. Please, come.
-No, no, no, no.
-Oh, yes.
Yes, come for a little bit.
-I don't think this is really
gonna work out like this.  -Why?
I mean…
I just want this to mean something.
It means a lot to me.
I'm gonna walk myself home from here.
Listen, I leave in three days.
Three days.
I fly planes.
I was adopted.
My father is not my father.
I'm not going to get fat.
-Hey.
-Hi.
-You cut your hair.
-Yeah.
Uh, well, we finished the job.
We stopped them from building
the dam, we saved the land,
the reservation,
the river, everything.
What are you doin' in Boston?
Well…
We saved the burial grounds.
And the Tantoonis were very grateful.
They were so grateful that they
decided to build a casino on it.
You know? It's just all about money.
You know, my heart isn't in it anymore.
It was just really lonely down there.
I really missed you, and I'm wrong.
You're the one
who doesn't need to change.
I'm the one who needs to change.
I don't want you to change.
I mean, don't ever change.
You know what I mean.
-Come on.
-The paper.
This better be good.
Did you spell-check it?
-I slaved for hours.
-All right.
I'm trying to make what we've
got together mean something.
I know. It means everything.
In northern Brazil, people
who believe in Candomble
they offer this to the
goddess of the sea, Iemanja.
Now, there is also supposed to be
fried fish. I thought better of it.
What is this offering for?
Good luck.
-What is this?
-I leave tomorrow morning.
Erin, will you come with me?
You are crazy.
Yes, crazy for you.
There goes Swifty!
A lot of worry about nothing.
Busted blood vessel or somethin'.
Guess I gotta lighten
up on the booze, huh?
That's great, Frank. You know,
I'm really glad you're gonna live.
But actually I just
came by to give you this.
This is way more than
just one installment.
I got a part-time job,
and I'm gettin' you
off my back once and for all, all right?
Hey, Frank, what the hell are you doin'?
Certain associates of mine really appreciated
what you did, how it all worked out.
The attendance at the aquarium
has doubled. It didn't work out.
The point is, you worked out, Alan.
And this
is your reward.
Hey, Arty!
This is my boy, Alan.
-Alan, say hello to Mr. Lesser.
-It's good to finally meet ya.
Frankie's told me a lot about
ya. He said you were a student.
You look like you've been out of short
pants for a while now. What are you, 40, 41?
-No, I'm 35.
-35, huh?
You're at a pivotal
junction in your life, Alan.
It's good to have you aboard.
Greyhounds now
entering the--
Frankie, we got a wacko down on
the new waterfront place there.
Come on! He's makin'
waves. Do somethin'.
Or maybe use this new
guy here? Send him down.
I'll get on it right away, Mr. Lesser.
Number Five, Satin Flame, 70 pounds.
Number Six, Burden's Drought, 73.
Number Seven, It Is Gently, 72.
Number Eight,Jar Man, 75.
-Hello?
-Erin, hi.
-It's me. Are you packing?
-Hi.
-Oh, my sweet.
-Yeah, I'm packing.
You know, I want to come
over and help you pack.
-We should pack together.
-Um, no, no, no, don't.
I'm sorry, darling. I
get so eager to see you.
I'll see you at the airport tomorrow.
I'll be there in the morning.
What does that mean?
Ah, what this
means, darling--
It means, "I want your love for me.
The two of us like this until the end.
I do not want sadness anymore.
I will make you happy
and destiny is what tells me this."
Erin, I will make you smile.
I swear I will, Erin.
So, uh, tomorrow at the airport, right?
-Yeah, I'll see you tomorrow.
-Good, and, please, a small bag.
All you need is toothpaste
and a little two-piece.
Puff?
What time your train is
gonna arrive tomorrow?
Oh, it's gonna be so fabulous.
Everybody's gonna be there.
Everybody is dying to see you.
Dodge is gonna be there.
Brazil, wow. Does that
sound beautiful, huh?
I hear that's beautiful this
time of the year. Brazil.
That's way past Medford, Brazil.
-What time's your flight?
-9:35.
-You're not gonna make it.
-I'm sorry?
You're not gonna make
it. The tunnel is jammed.
Oh, I have to make it.
The tunnel is clogged.
All right, um-- All right, take me
to Bowdoin Station, the Blue Line.
Airport Station next.
Change here for the airport
terminal shuttle. Next stop, Airport.
This is Airport Station.
Excuse me.
I'm trying to get out of here.
Why don't you just knock me down?
Come on!
This is Airport Station.
Change here for the
airport terminal shuttle.
This is Airport Station.
Change here for the Logan
Airport terminal shuttle.
Wonderland Station will be next.
Next stop, Wonderland.
Headset?
-In-flight movie?
-Yes. Thank you.
-Headset?
-Yes, please.
-In-flight movie
-None for me, thanks, and none for the lady.
-Headset?
-Yes.
-So. You are traveling alone?
And you?
Yes.
It seems always alone.
You travel for business?
No. For pleasure.
Ah! Pleasure.
Well, you must like my
country's music then.
Yes, I do.
That's beautiful, but what does it mean?
Ah, what this means. May I?
It means this, darling.
§ So close your eyes §
§ For that's your lovely way to be §
§ Aware of things your heart alone §
§ Was meant to see §
-Over there?
-Right over here.
§ The fundamental loneliness goes §
§ Whenever two can
dream a dream together §
-Feelin' a little better?
-Yeah, a little. Thanks. I…
-This way?
-I'm sorry about that. I…
-No. That's totally all right.
-I think I just needed some air or something.
-The train was so crowded.
-I know, yeah. I mean, that Airport Station is horrible.
-People are, like, shoving.
-Yeah.
They're in such a rush
to get outta there.
-Sit down.
-Thanks.
Yeah, my father used to bring
us to this beach all the time.
I still come here every
day to read or relax.
Do you? Every day, that's so nice.
Well, I think it's important to have
some daily ritual in your life
that gives it a sense
of consistency, you know?
Consistency?
Yeah.
But, uh, um, wouldn't
you say that, uh
"Consistency is the, uh,
hobgoblin of little minds"?
Well, actually, it's:
"A foolish consistency
is the hobgoblin of little minds."
-That's Ralph Waldo Emerson.
-Waldo Emerson, right.
But I don't think coming to a place
like this every day is foolish.
No. No, not at all.
Because I think it's important
sometimes just to sit in a quiet place
and stare out at
the sea and just--
Contemplate something beautiful.
It's funny, though.
I never realized such a beautiful
beach was so close to Boston.
Well, it's not always this nice.
Well, I guess I better get home.
-You wanna take a walk?
-I'd love it.
-Great.
-Okay.
Ah, it's right down here.