NICOSTRATOS
THE PELICAN
I want to tell a story
that changed my life.
It happened on the island gradskiyat Zora ..
Ogkrit ... French corsair
in the 17th century
Winter here is like paradise.
Today Zora is a
small village ..
All ... where life revolves
proshtada around in the cafeteria "Aristotle."
You all know ...
News spread for a moment ..
Legend ... and forward
from generation to generation.
And of course, all remember
history of unending love ...
... Between my parents,
Demosthenes and Antonia.
And the day of their wedding
when my father gave my mother ...
Family ... a gold cross.
When my mother died,
Golden Cross was mine.
And I say Janis ...
And your story will start
of today.
Pedaling! ..
One after another, up and down!
There is a divine sight
but to move the legs is useful!
What did you say?
- Chto ehaty need, stand at pedalyah!
Pedaling with your feet!
- Pedaling with your feet!
Stop grumbling! ..
The biggest climb yet!
If you have enough forces
just wait.
come on!
Zap, zap! ..
Zap, zap ...
Lord, give me strength ...
Faster, peasants! ..
push the pedal!
With strong! ..
Zap, zap ...
Now I feel the passion,
going to Golgoto.
Hello, Father Foma!
- Zravey to you, Janis!
Drive slower, Father Kosmas,
I will bring them to death!
This year proved only weaklings.
So then you also
"Great land" are you going?
By order of my father ...
And you know of away?
Today Orthodox Synod
the archipelago is found
desperately need to get there!
Ra-I two, zap, zap! ..
Brethren, press!
Cast:
Emir Kusturica
Thibault December Gellek
Hello, Janis!
- Hey, George!
François-K'Sava Demezon
Jade Rose Parker
Genadios Patsis
Author of script:
Olivier Orleans and Eric buasen
"BLUE STAR"
Based on the novel by Eric buasen
"Nikostratos"
Composer:
Panagiotis Kalantzopoulos
Operator:
Michelle Amatyo
Artist:
Kiki Pita
Produced by:
Philippe Gauthier
Do not worry.
- Okay.
Where are you?
- In master.
In the master? ..
Come with me.
Directed by:
Olivier Eagle
I'll look ...
Itschakay here.
Chap ...
Oh! ..
Too much stinks.
Where was gone! ..
But that naglets.
Want to drink ...
It is clear as day.
Where is water?
Let's get out ... Did brandy?
- Yes, that is behind the door
Smuggler you? ..
I thought it would be any greater.
What is smuggling??
It's fat brandy.
For you 60 euros.
From where did you bird? ..
That I have not seen.
From Cuba ...
Here hold and get out of here.
Give me this bird.
I'm not stupid!
I wear it for a client ...
The bird is not home.
- How?
Sixty euros.
My father would beat me
if not give him money.
And what is this cross on your neck?
Okay? ..
Will it be enough?
Well .. Is it gold?
- Of course it is golden ...
My mom is ..
She died three years ago.
And get ready to swap it for this
plucked bird?
I like plucked birds.
Are not you afraid that your father
will disconnect when out?
You will not understand.
I'll tell him not to move
Thai and not felt.
So what better than a cell is? ..
But we must also Chairman hide.
My father was not home animals suffer.
I often think
if I'm doing the right thing then
Was it not folly to exchange
Mama's Cross ...
... For some kind of stinking bird?
Damn! ..
My father is back!
But somehow I was sure
that my mother will forgive me ..
I traded ... family relic
to preserve this beautiful bird ...
But my father? ...
that's another story.
Hi, Kitsa!
Do not run ...
You must help her father.
Sit quietly ...
Kitsa, get ...
Go walk.
Enjoy ...
Today was not going fishing.
Looking so there?
- Kitsa, go away! ..
Who can know ...
You may insolation.
A tank?
- Oh, I forgot ... Excuse.
What are you my apologies!
Do not forget that the network will be towels.
Kitsa! .. go away! ..
Run ... get out of here ...
This miracle is called with goat horns.
Stupid is
but her milk is delicious ...
In time it will get used to.
Lay your head,
're prigladnyalo much.
Here's your bread with milk.
What are you so ...
This M. .. beak of a swan ...
feet of a duck ...
neck with a frog ...
chicken, chicken!
Eat!
Delicious!
Hai De, smell it well ...
This is a bird and you - a goat ...
Jealous.
I will wear it for the gold ...
if you do not understand - I'm not lazhech ...
Come, rest in peace ...
Do not be afraid, my father will not come here.
Oh! ..
Have a strong beak.
Hey! ..
Okay!
You want to eat it?
Tomorrow, after my father went into the sea
will feed you ...
Now a quiet ...
If they find my father -
and they will beat us.
Better not to irritate.
Lie.
You are sea dweller, I knew ...
I will baptize with the name of the ship.
Nikostratos ...
Great, huh!
Nikostratos.
Needless to say,
that the bird is quite unusual ...
Such an inflexible.
An interesting and touching.
Wonder what kind is it?
Some cross between an ostrich and a dog ...
Or swan suffering from laryngitis ...
To explain this puzzle
Only one man can ...
Father Kosmas.
Monk where he did not look like a monk
who knows everything about birds.
Good morning, Holy Father!
- Hey, Janis.
I need a Father Kosmas.
- Once you? .. Or then?
As soon as ...
I will show him something.
Well ...
Let's go.
Octopus spews
black ink cloud ..
Ink ... which is
here in this bag ...
We will not allow losses
the valuable liquid ..
... And would do so here
and tampered with our rice ...
See how simple it is ...
What an amazing color!
Well, enough now harder.
Rice with octopus brothers is very
food dish, rich in protein.
And if you add
and a few glasses of wine ...
That is food for the gods.
Janis, very early today.
Come, friends, places ...
So, what do you show me?
A bird.
Oh, and what is this bird?
- I do not know ...
This brought it to you ...
Hey now ...
Take a look.
A! ..
This is Pelekanus Onokrotalus!
What?
Pelekanus Onokrotalus, it is
Latin name of Pink Pelican.
Who gives it?
A bad man ...
Tormented him.
Well, you gave it your ...
Not seem so bad.
Nisho not give away my ...
I had to give him something in return.
So what?
- His cross.
This was where your mother?
- Not very well know.
Received his noble ...
Replacing its okrashenie for being ...
The birds grow quickly.
And in case you want to know
Pelicans reached five feet.
In the wingspan?
No, no - in height ...
This is a huge bird!
Now let h ...
It turned a giant bird!?
Come on children, their water pipe
remove and notebooks ...
Kitsa! ..
But that goat!
Wow, now eight!
Sleep my friend ...
I go out, but will be back.
Fruits are very tasty!
- I do not want ...
It is delicious, it is delicious!
Good morning, Mrs. Karusos.
- Good, Janis!
And you think this cucumber? ..
This is a small gherkin!
Your vegetables are shriveled in fear
Christina!
You know what, Father Kosmas,
if you like - go to Kiki.
Hello, Aristotle!
- Hey, Janis!
And when you nothing! ..
And you do not have squid?
Well my mock ...
Thank you for refreshing me.
As always polite.
No wonder fish
they shun.
The cheese alone I do it?
- Not just me ...
Goat also helps.
For cheese milk gives me,
and for vegetables - fertilizer.
Janis, hello!
This is cheese! ..
Fresh goat cheese!
Hello Demosfen! ..
What are you wearing?
Working overalls.
- Download it ...
With overalls is not traded.
Demosfen, what ...
You scare people!
Kokvo?
- Goal you will trade!
Before you give advice
why not put it gracefully ..
Better ... to have seen
in the mirror!
Do not boil your nose ...
Educate his son as you want ...
Got it? ..
And you understand? .. A?
Swine his Demosfen, pig!
When my mother died,
My father changed ...
Sometimes silent for days.
Luckily I already have a friend.
I decided to put my Nikos
in the annexe, ..
Entrance ... and slashed in their room
for better movement.
Grow quite rapidly.
And every day it became
stronger and more beautiful.
Island life
obeyed the seasons ...
Fall gathered mushrooms
winter chestnuts.
Come on, girls ...
Gladly accept all
generous gifts of nature.
This is for you, Father Alexius.
- Thank you.
Nikos also enjoyed life.
But hiding it became
harder and harder.
Quiet right, quiet! ..
What a glutton've become.
Give me a hug ...
We work a little, then play.
I need a new pump ...
I will write you a letter?
Of course.
First the address: "George Karbunis ...
Motor Boat "Piraeus" ...
What is it?
- Nothing.
"Athens, the port area" ...
I bike "YANMAR"
48 horsepower. "
Mo-tor ...
Ian ... Jan-Mar ...
UAA-chezvay!
48 horsepower.
What's up?
- Meaning?
Break the fuel pump is ... ...
Get out! .. Quick! .. Shoo! ..
Get out! .. Get out!
You hear me?
- I hear you!
Please let me know,
if you have one in stock ...
And the sign: "Demosfen Kuzmanovic."
- Kuz-ma-no-vich.
With the advent of Nikos
our usual home line ...
... Turned upside down ...
The first victim
Nice was the goat ...
Equip ..., Porva suffer
new occupant.
To live under one roof
was not so simple.
The two neighbors fought tirelessly ...
Beak horn ... Beak horn for ...
Overcoming that you're
greater creativity.
Each fiercely defended
its territory ...
At the end of kraishtatav, realizing
they have no choice, be reconciled.
"FAVORITE ANTONIA"
But, of course, the main battle
was between me and my father.
Well then ...
Now we have to learn to fly ...
Believe me, it's not complicated ...
That look will show you ...
Open the wings - and fly ...
Go ahead, hop!
Get wings and bounce!
E! ..
Come on!
Now bounce, Nikos, bounce!
You lazy, lazy!
Hop! .. Hop! ..
Bravo!
Watch not to swallow ...
Hop! .. Hop! ..
Give the pass!
So run, run!
Now returns ...
Shoo! .. Get out and hide!
So what kind of bird is this?
- This is the Pelican ... A friend of mine.
And where do you have?
- Long story.
Here is what constantly busy? ..
In a game bird fitbol?
I do my job ...
And take care of it ...
What's wrong with that?
- Where did you hide?
In podnavesa ...
There sleeps.
Who gives it? ..
Just do not you dare lie to me.
I bought it from the master of
"Son of Star."
What? ..
More specifically Traded it for one thing.
Exchanged?
For Mama cross.
Change your cross its
mother for Pelican?
And this? .. Where is it? ..
What is this? .. A? ..
How ...?
Daddy, Daddy!
"Daddy, Daddy" ...
Dad!
"Dad" ...
Dad, let him!
Fly! ..
In Live!
Dad ...
"Dad" ... Pelican! ..
Go on ...!
Go medicine!
Just to see Pelican
and it is done!
More ...
Cross me.
- Broke is f
Nikos!
You're back! ..
How nice!
Nikos ...
My Nikos.
No noise ...
Do not Wake the evil enemy.
Do not be afraid ...
I will not divide us ...
I'll take you to Myrtle ...
See how beautiful.
Wait for me!
Wait for me.
Soon will fly, Nikos.
However his father did not speak.
Hear me ...
Nothing will help so happens ...
But actually that's great.
Why?
Grab the corners ... Go ...
Bravo.
Now that the truth is revealed
things came to my place.
What I think is not so
holy Father.
My father is angry at me,
I lied to him and to cross ...
I will not forgive me.
- Have patience, Janis ...
Naturally you
You can easily say it.
Everything will be fine ...
This is his message.
Are you sure that you understand?
- Hey you!
Nikos!
Nikos learn to fly ...
I envied him that sees
islands of high ...
Nikos has become a big
beautiful bird.
We realize that there
could not go unnoticed.
Vish pilotage, Nikos! ..
Landing least it should not.
Promise not to fly away, Nikos ...
I do not wanna lose.
It was a pelican, Dad?
I first saw it!
- No, I was first.
No, I do!
- No, I ...
Cafe 'ARIOTOTEL "
Do not cry, you're not home.
Hello Demosfen ...
Go there?
Go.
By Thursday I will bring you
a crate with mackerel and two squid?
Consider them as delivered.
Lemonade as you stir your children?
Pelican have seen huge ...
The whole village talking.
Hovered in the sky over Pharos!
Only Ado About Nothing,
I keep repeating!
Apollo is the Pelican ...
I can understand why kids ...
Eighty.
Stop, to whom I speak!
Four, five, six ...
How is Janis? ..
Long has not been seen ...
Drava you?
- Yeah, where ezchezna?
Six, seven, eight ...
- As always silent ...
Torgoviyata today are you mine?
Still ...
People do not buy just about anything.
And I do not know why.
And tomorrow ...
For tomorrow, what are you plans?
- Tomorrow?
Yeah right, tomorrow.
- I'm going to clean the monastery icons ...
Father Kosmas rely on me.
To turn on your music?
Tourists in droves
arrive on the island ..
To ... a glimpse of his
Pelican stupid.
Clean penalty
you, Aristotle?
Save us!
True flood, friends!
Soon it will be necessary
get together in pairs.
I started the match?
- No, Holy Father ...
Team just released the pitch ...
What do you pour?
Brandy!
What business would do
only touch this bird.
Vazilis,
Should I talk about this now?
Today is Mata, what your pelican! ..
Get out there on the street and talk!
Starts! ..
Zapalchete all!
At the end!
Where is Uncle?
Angelica! ..
Niece!
Hello!
- Good evening!
Good evening!
- Hello!
Beauty, eh? ..
The daughter of my brother ...
Arrives to work during vacation.
Look how the "Spree" those Germans.
Remember my words ...
Away you go ...
Can you look aside?
- I did not understand?
Do not treat.
For me what you think?
- For an Orthodox priest.
There, you see!
The sun does not sit long ...
There is no coverage ...
How much cheese?
- 2 euro 40 cents.
Here he is!
How quickly fly ...
And turbot is huge!
No, no, Nikos, you should!
This is not for you ... Fly! ..
Go home!
I have to work!
- You could have asked for cheese?
This albatross is it?
- No, Pelican.
Oh! ..
Did you see that!
Look back up!
Just fantastic!
- Oh, landed on the roof!
Pelican Is yours? ..
Why are you silent until now?
I'm not his master ...
Friends are.
Go! .. Fly!
- How wonderful ...
Buy fresh fish!
Why not listen? ..
Let's go.
Stand back, do his time!
Come on ...
It is now flying ...
Fly ...
Fly to the cave ...
Unbelievable!
Bravo! .. Bravo! ..
Bravo!
That's it! ..
What a beauty!
Your son can make a roll collar.
This pelican was a gift from heaven.
Get out, get out of here.
Get on!
Hello, Yannis.
Yannis! ..
Today I will buy you a drink ...
Tell me more.
- No, thanks ...
I go,
that the consignment is unattended.
Work TRULY MEET work.
It does not happen often
Aristotle, one to draw.
Do not give up! ..
I'm Angelica, his niece.
And you are?
- Yannis.
Angelica! ..
I have one hundred hands.
Just a minute, uncle.
Do not call me uncle at work,
this is not professional.
Okay.
I gotta go.
Today I saw
of "private transport".
We will ride with you if you ask me.
Go ...
Fly!
The heads are gone ...
Tomorrow I will go to the village of his stand two.
How do you say?
- Nikostratos.
A large is it?
- Very high.
How tall are you?
- 1.56.
And I love steaks?
And where steaks at sea? ..
Pelican is a marine animal.
Hello!
Pilgrims annoy you?
This is it, the burden of fame ...
Help me to get off.
Chichomi about you
day and night.
Yesterday, for example,
so work-
as never was making.
When the accounts relates only wept.
Pelicans your home you?
My father was against it.
How so?
- I have been on the island.
Who?
- For what I'm talking about.
And rightly so.
Customers continually ask for this.
Terribly afraid of bees.
Angelica!
What do you interfere now
come on time?
And do everything
I pay and without too much?
Too much!?
Is my salary ovilichil!?
Janis, wait! ..
I'll buy from you cheese.
Hang on, my uncle wants
to talk to you about the pelican.
Now we see Janis.
Juice at the expense of the establishment
young friend, accommodated.
You can cry, and the pelican,
not vazrazavam ...
Angelica,
Bring juice to a local celebrity.
Do not forget to put and straw.
- D yeah!
After a minute, boss.
Your pelican
has hit number one.
All seemed to go crazy.
- Angelica said.
Brought you a big profit.
For this gain will be silent.
Do not worry, Aristototel,
I understand everything.
In this case, come in five
with his Nikostratos.
By noon it is too hot ..
Afternoon is dead time.
Many customers want
to be photographed with the pelican.
You can sleep on the terrace.
Magical time at sunset.
We earned decent money.
Nothing is going to take for themselves.
An orange juice through a straw.
Oops!
It is now without a straw.
And what funny imav this?
- Relax it's only a joke.
I did not understand her joke
You think you ... A?
This is the guy with the bird.
Are you the guy with the penguin?
- Please?
With Penguin, actually a pelican.
I want to shoot him.
He says he wants the bird to shoot.
And in return for what?
- In cash?
White money for a simple picture.
I agree!
I do not need anything.
Thank you anyway.
Not receive inheritance
or all of your home?
You are with his uncle.
Departments are not the most important.
My friend asks, "how?"
Pay 10 euros for photography.
What did you say?
He said the pelican you beaut.
Tell her that I know.
He says that "it is little."
Business man.
- Right.
I give 15
my last word.
Her younger sister is very ill
and can not come here ..
Pelican ... and her favorite bird.
Many will be glad if
gift to get a photograph.
Have you no mercy?
- Ok, it happens.
But only once.
- Agreed, but 20.
Bida not look like Bill Gates?
We agreed.
See Nikostratos!
More than you earn
of cheese, right?
Hello Kitsa!
Tomorrow off to Tyre.
For vintage.
For long?
- There will understand.
We need money, and you alone.
Time flies and do not feel it.
Kitsa!
This is rubbish.
My father is going to go to far.
Of gasoline you do not need.
You have to help.
And "Dawn" was
"Pelikanski island."
Tourists arriving in waves.
infinitely glad that Aristotle
owner
the only cafe on the island.
What air.
What a sight.
And as the only benchmark
was making big profits.
What do you want?
- Two photos of pelicans.
Group?
- Not alone.
Idividualnite photos are more expensive.
Keep this in mind.
What would you order?
- Ook, please.
On that Nikos had no incumbent.
That's why our business does not go bad.
But everyone kept a secret.
What do you want?
Now I come!
Jump her legs become too small.
Good!
Guess I'll hire another waiter.
Do not lose your mind!
Steam on my arm falls?
Angelica - a family member.
All enter into a pocket
but you that you clearly.
If you want to help do not worry!
A young rabbit.
Does not understand the subtleties of the craft.
Here's your share.
For what do you think?
- For a brilliant manager ...
What not to give up white money?
Not receive inheritance
or all of your home?
Boss!
I want tomorrow, Yannis
to lead him in stores.
Where?
In high season? ..
Do you want me bankrupt?
Wonderful to deal without me.
Glamorous and have a great experience.
Any conversation can lead.
And I do not have to pay dase.
Until recently, Aristotle!
Look!
This Court
I sold Nikostratos.
A police captain arrested him.
- Police? .. Why?
Poured fuel on the coast.
This suits many.
And how much you paid for it, this bird?
Mama gave him a golden cross.
She gave it?
- Her is gone three years.
Your mother has died?
And you and replaced the cross?
Let's go.
Forgive me
always speak first, then think.
Everything is fine.
You're my only friend.
No offense.
And your father how he reacted
uznavuznavayki,
that he replaced the cross on the bird?
Poor, but
not a gift from my father.
Hold on Athens! ..
People!
Hello everyone!
Watch in mine!
Go ...
Are you afraid?
Add a little!
Omotri traffic jam!
Look!
Do you see?
We go now!
I'll meet Cousin.
What people ..
I see today with his company.
This is Janis!
To dance?
- Yes ...
To go?
- No! .. You do not like to grind.
And I love it!
Yannis!
Look.
But that snore!
Cross me!
From where?
Go and look - something shiny in the dust.
I look closely - your cross!
Just kidding, silly, I bought it
while the master slept.
What, one night
in its port you gone?
With me was a cousin.
For me it will do.
He's my bodyguard.
This will not forget it.
I guess a lot of money you gave.
What?!
Marketplaces as a gypsy for him.
Now you owe me.
I want to Myrtle.
Do not give up easily, eh?
Aha!
Where is our Nikostratos?
Hiding somewhere.
I'm starving.
Is there anything zayadene?
Okorsh will.
Just nalovya.
I eat fish for breakfast?
Hey, you!
High f
Jump! Do not be afraid!
Do not hurt?
I'll try here.
Not jealous, Nikos!
Fool you, Janis! ..
You scared me.
I'll bake
and will lick your fingers.
Who dives more deeply ...
... Gets bigger!
I won!
- No, I do!
Hey!
What are you doing?
Nikos!
- That is what is the real winner.
P earlier fish together
and spent much time.
After the death of my mother
everything changed.
Curse?
- Permanently.
And the beat?
- No, do not beat me.
But I stuck permanently
and not for something.
Pick? ..
And that's all you can say?
Do you believe that enough?
Now ke teach an oath
it will help you ...
Repetition! .. From the fools do not fear! ..
Do not be afraid!
From the fools do not fear!
Fools! ..
From the fools do not fear! ..
Do not be afraid!
What do you frowned?
- What?
I asked them: What do you frowned?
- I frowned.
Today is the finest
day of my life.
Glad to meet you.
With you is not easy
but it is fun.
You will not get anything
Nothing will give you.
Get out, Nikos! ..
Do not be afraid.
What do you do?
- Struck me.
What is happening here?
- It's okay.
The location of wildlife is
zoo. Do not cry my dear little boy!
For him, this is a game.
Flying to the cave!
Dad is furious.
Yes, but not touched him,
only ice cream and bitten.
Big deal, a great drama.
And if it veshe bitten in the eye?
Maybe we would still be funny?
A pelican has Dio animal.
I turned it into a circus performer
and here is the result.
Olives paw
and other such nonsense.
All food brought him
and never think about fish.
Not exaggerated ...
Just like it is among the company.
This is better than alone in the cave.
- It is,
Listen, listen!
I will buy him sunglasses
and let them hang out on the beach.
So no one know it nyamada
- Funny you?
You're with her uncle - only
their respective interests you think.
And you - when your father!
Manoli! ..
Manoli, where he fled?
Now we hide.
You are looking for!
You can not hide.
Manoli, you are looking for!
- I do not want!
Manoli!
Come on.
Who is this?
When your father returns?
Does anyone know.
When the grape harvest.
Carefully, Father Kosmas! ..
Let me help you.
That's it.
Leave no longer needed.
How do you feel without him?
- Neither good nor bad.
But I was sad.
Do not be surprised:
of how two Sundays left.
Sadly, even when I was here.
Cafe
"NIKOSTRATOS"
It looks bad?
Praise goes to your son.
As for his bird.
Come get in.
In your absence
here has changed a lot.
I see.
This pelican is a blessing for the island.
We never had such tourists.
Ferry which leads to Mycenae
comes to us on the island.
Business protsavtyava
- Circle of your interests has not changed.
And your character too.
- Hordes of idiots you are a heart?
These tapatsisa our customers! ..
And deserve due respect ...
If you do not like -
go home.
I'm home! Thomas is my village.
You did your wedding!
Hear my advice:
marry again.
And your visitors will not command me!
Iztreshtyalka.
What happened?
Who is this?
The father of Janis.
Slightly scrimmage.
He stood by my side uncomfortable.
Dad.
Dad!
Have you been back?
Just.
I go and no one at home.
Where have you been?
And where are those new clothes
Room?
And the shoes?
Who is this?
Mine.
- And what is bought?
With my earned money.
And from where?
Tourists pay.
When taking pictures with Nikos.
With my pelican!
- And you think this is working?
Better than your fishing!
I even have my mum's Cross.
Yanni!
Nikos, let me sleep.
Nikos, do not be afraid.
This is safe.
Nikos, relax.
Nikos!
Angelica!
Did you at any time predicting the sea?
- Ha-ha, belly ached from laughter.
Not now ..
Next. Let's get out.
Then you will play.
I have no mood.
No, no, no!
This is no time to play.
Marsh, Nikos ... talk to you!
Get out of here.
Go on the street!
Nikos!
Here is my bill so.
Dance with the pelican,
a pelican ...
For fun!
Dance with the pelican,
a pelican ...
Approaching the village with the pelican.
Pelican called Nikostratos!
Mrs. Flora, our otdovno tions us
worn by their bread.
I had to buy from others.
- My old man is already pretty lazy.
A Nikostratos! ..
Come here.
Well, go, I have a job.
- See you tomorrow.
Not tsupi, please.
Come here!
Brzo faster!
Dancing ...
No!
Not my fault!
Aristotle!
Nikostratos ...
Why are you wearing dark glasses and their
you see nothing!
I have nothing in common.
Why do you see in the hall of abtobusa?
- Who has driven them to talk!
Come on, Christina,
bad enough for me.
Both are guilty.
Spread out in the country.
Let mine.
Shut all.
Shut up!
Help!
What happened?
- The bus hit him!
Squeeze his beak.
- Come on.
Free table.
Scissors, Scissors!
More vivid, more vivid!
Poor.
Save him, save him.
I will die.
Help my dad.
Now it is better to leave him in peace.
Because of me ...
do not let him die!
Dad ...
As I felt nothing.
Dad!
Mom ...
Mom!
The whole village suffered in this tragedy
and worried about my condition.
Angelica visited me every day
brings new and the others.
But the island was obvzet of sorrow.
A Myrtle, Where I was so happy
now deserted.
Aristotle!
Demosfen coming!
Here's the devil!
Something I really sour.
- And another way you look?
We're all worried about Janis.
Yes ...
Is there such a rush ...
Thanks ...
Plemyannitsata you here?
Angelica!
I am here.
What can not you see?
Will you stay with Janis today?
- Uncle? .. Can I?
What a question!
Forgive for impact.
- I have asked him to cm.
He stood by my side ... not convenient
I was not prepared ...
All along, relax.
Angelica sat with me,
To my father was at sea ...
But I would have been like ...
Even I wanted nothing to eat,
except lukuma Mrs. Flora.
Family recipe?
I prepared a potion with your father ...
It is a mixture of herbs ...
Do not worry ...
Now is better.
Angelica drink!
I feel guilt for what happened.
Why now you do.
You did not hit him,
but its sought first aid.
But surely I am convinced they can do
its star.
If I had listened,
nothing wrong with it dase did not happen.
Life was so bright ...
If it was not taken by the ship
might not learn to fly.
Fate, that's it.
You not everything you know.
Before this happened I cried,
and he flew at me ...
The appearance, then the lack
Nikostratos of our lives ...
Many changes ... islanders ...
Aristotle at all at heart ...
Nikos many lacked.
And not because of profit
just loved it!
Our Aristotle
had a sensitive soul.
Vazilis did could not forgive
that abducted attention chauffeur, ..
Become cost culprit ...
the death of Nikos ...
Often lost in thought
circling the square.
I also changed ...
I got up, how to tell an adult ...
Yes, I think ...
Older.
Life of the village still
usual move ...
Madame Karusos
and her pious man ...
Were prepared ...
to complete their family.
My father, yet he spent his time
at sea or in the cafeteria of Aristotle ...
Every sailor knows how to quell
grief at the death of a friend at sea.
Soon travel agencies
leaflets dropped the island from ...
We no longer docked ferries ...
Life returned to his bed.
Everything is back in his old.
Quick, quick! ..
All places!
This is not so bad.
Cafe 'NIKOSTRATOS "
Violation of the prohibition of his father?
We need to stay home
until a restore.
I do hear it,
But now I am better.
So it seems what you want?
- Coffee frappe.
Odno coffee frappe
will now arrive!
Yannis!
What a surprise only!
Weak, there's no appetite you?
Do not worry;
eating until full.
We have not seen with your father.
- How so?
He every night with you your drink.
If I do not where you ...
you somewhere else to drink ...
That where? ..
The island has only one cafe.
Not so stupid father.
Is your girlfriend.
A friend?
Off does not know him.
But if one does not ohazhva,
then go where?
You'll have to figure it out.
And your coffee?
- Otstapvam you do!
Do not tell me that it happened at sea.
- The sea?
He took with him Nikostratos.
Do you suffer?
He died almost immediately.
Why it took the boat?
- To not watch.
And where the body away?
- Threw it into the sea ...
But do not trovozhi ...
it will catch fish.
And I pluuu-vaaaa!
I knew that I will never forget
time spent with Nikostratos.
My father told again
what happened.
But I could not lie ..
And its history ...
seemed inconclusive.
And interrogation is not subsidized.
Sometimes, to understand the truth
should posrachkat little things.
If my father would not go in cafe
then what do you do?
Persistently sought answers.
And, it's you!
- And what happened?
I will clarify what my father does ...
Just in time coming ...
We stand on guard.
"If you do not have anything in mind!"
- I beg you!
Okay ...
Away you go?
We search the boat ...
If you see my father - played ...
Know how, right?
- As for the question.
Damn it!
Yannis!
Good day!
- Good to f ..
Where is Janis?
- In the monastery ...
I come to you.
To ask:
hard you fish?
Interested in fishing?
- Can you go into the kitchen?
My eyes capital.
Now seriously -
It eletniyat my project.
For professions ...
All anglers must have a strong?
I guess it is difficult to
draw heavy nets from the water?
I have a winch.
No one can winch
remove from the water network.
Yeah, I know, I know.
It's that shturavina
the bow of the boat!
And it succeed
To keep your balance?
You need skill.
I can not imagine how
you are given to manage a boat ..
Where ... is full to the brim with fish?
Here for example, if I
wearing a heavy backpack ...
Always ... I feel
something that weighs me.
In the way,
Janis helps you?
Lately
just run the monastery day and night.
As a mania.
So heavy nets filled with fish
you pull with the help of a winch.
then is not difficult
as a bicycle with three wheels.
All the problems come from there
people want to get everything for free.
This has become a phobia.
Take your work.
If you calculate the value
fuel, nets, repair - ...
Then the fish ...
will cost a fortune.
Just imagine
so this is just nonsense.
Do you know how much
a coffee frappe?
Now I'll tell ...
After all I do ...
Here at ...
You're also a mechanic? ..
How romantic ...
Talk between the read, ..
Itself ... that remotirate bike?
And anywhere that you have not learned ...
For us this is long gone.
I think you just have ...
gold hands.
And you are here
- We're not.
How went the rehearsal?
- Cool.
I'm leaving.
- Thank you for interesting conversation.
Yep.
Did you find something?
- Treated it is ..
I found drugs and that's what ...
I lied that is
And what does that mean?
If it is treated,
Nikostratos may be alive.
Just do not worry,
there is insufficient evidence.
Your father was Lucullus ...
but obviously it has not healed.
But what disappears?
Here is the answer.
In nothing sure.
- Listen ...
I am confident that swim to it.
Yannis!
Course at Myrtle ... In the cave.
- Yannis! ..
I'm coming with you.
Yannis!
Wait, I can not so fast!
Dad!
Nikos ...
Nikos!
Why do not you tell me?
Why me
to believe in his death?
In order not to drive them to suffer.
I was not confident that it will heal.
It was probably not happen.
But it proved tough guy.
- But what do you heal?
I got everything you need for treatment
by Dr. Lizandros ...
I wanted to surprise you.
But everything failed.
- No surprise it worked.
The surprise is received.
I do not know what to say, Dad.
Do not say anything!
Until recently, Christina!
- Until recently, Germes!
Enough only murmur.
Mrun-Mrun-Mrun-Mrun.
Spare me!
Damn!
How many more?
Good grief!
That alone should be a ...
- Forget it!
Think finally
and something else!
Day of St. Demetrios ...
The annual spectacular
holiday on the island.
All will be dressed in festive clothes,
there will be songs and dances
Brass band ... and monastery
will recreate the relaxed atmosphere.
This year my father decided
to make the inhabitants surprise.
Nikos had stage fright
me too.
Stop, relax.
Nobody knew
what awaits them tonight.
Even Father Kosmas.
This year with my bratyareshihme
you fulfill contemporary music.
I hope you will spend with us
an unforgettable evening.
I congratulate you all.
Thank you.
A Nikostratos!
A! .. Watch it!
Nikostratos!
Look!
That's Nikostratos! ..
Nikostratos ...
Congratulations!
I'm an adult
but this day still remember it.
Father Kosmas loved to quote
famous philosophers.
John Hallows Klimak said ...
... "There are troubles that divide,
and other people gather. "
The story of Nikos me
sections of my father - on the contrary.
She rallied us.
Again, we felt
relationship between us.
In tonight prazdnika of
Dimitri holy father
helped me ... how to say -
to stretch its wings.
Yes, namely:
What is this?
Dance of the earthworm it?
wait.
SubtitleSync (http://www.subtitlesync.com.ar)