You still can't sleep?
I'll read you a book.
I know! I'll tell you a wonderful story.
Once upon a time, there was a cute girl
named Little Red Riding Hood.
One day, her mother sent her on an errand.
Her grandmother was sick,
so she asked her to visit her.
"Yes, I'll go!"
Little Red Riding Hood took a basket
and happily left for her grandmother's house.
She met a big bad wolf
at the entrance of the forest.
"Hello, Little Red Riding Hood."
"Where are you going in such a hurry?"
"I'm going to visit my grandmother!"
The wolf thought to himself...
"She looks fat and delicious."
"Yes, I'll deceive her and eat her,
along with her grandmother!"
The wolf sneaked into the grandmother's house,
crawling in through the window.
"Lucky for me, no one is at home!"
But when he took out the grandmother's kimono,
he saw that she was sleeping soundly.
So he got into bed and waited
for Little Red Riding Hood to arrive.
Just then, Little Red Riding Hood
came through the door.
"Hello, grandmother!"
Little Red Riding Hood
put her basket on the table.
"Oh, Little Red Riding Hood,
what did you bring me?"
"A big, white napkin."
"What else did you bring me?"
"A sparkling knife."
"And did you bring me any food?"
"Yes."
"I brought you a wolf!"
Then, she grabbed the knife
and cut the wolf many times.
Then she cut the wolf's flesh into pieces,
each one dripping with dark red blood.
Good night...
Yumi.
BIRTHDAY COCKTAIL
Happy birthday, dear Yumi!
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday!
Why are you eating alone?
Because I have the biggest appetite!
You should be ashamed!
Eat more, Miyoko.
Hey, I was eating that!
Come on, give it back!
No.
Unlike you, I have a boyfriend.
It's just because you play
the damsel in distress!
You always get your way, don't you?
Hey, that's enough.
Stop it, you two.
Just try not to add on
any more fat, okay?
You don't understand...
I just...
I just need to eat!
I don't care.
You were born to eat fried chicken,
and you're living up to your destiny!
Didn't you know?
Oh, she's mad...
Come and get me!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Stop it, already!
I'm scared!
It's good.
It's good!
It's really good!
Did you always have such white skin?
Lick it up, lick it up!
Why do you always make fun of me?
Swallow it!
Come on! What's wrong?
I can't...
She couldn't take it!
I said, that's enough!
Eating and sleeping, just like a pig.
Yes, that's right!
Come on, get up already!
I think she's sleeping...
Come on, get up!
Come on!
What's the matter?
Towako...
It's not my fault...
I didn't do anything!
I...
I was just having some fun!
It's not my fault!
That's right!
We didn't do anything.
Yes... That's right.
It was just an accident!
He's right...
We're all friends here.
We wouldn't hurt her.
Is that so?
Why do you trust other people
and call them your friends?
Miyoko.
Remember what you said?
"You were born to eat fried chicken."
"Try not to add on more fat."
You said that to your friend.
- I was just kidding!
- Just kidding?
Really? I can see your true colors.
Miyoko, what are you trying to say?
You never know what
other people are thinking.
- Did you do it?
- How can you blame me?
You were laughing, weren't you?
People are different from how
they look on the outside.
You look serious, but I don't know
what you're really thinking.
He's not like that.
You like to deceive girls, don't you?
Today's target is Yumi.
You just came to this
party to seduce Yumi.
What?
Now we see your true colors...
Mamoru, is that true?
- Don't listen to her, Yumi!
- But don't worry...
Yumi isn't interested in you anyway.
I'm so stupid...
I killed myself...
What do you mean
she's not interested?
Yumi has someone else
who she would do anything for.
Who is that?
Where do you think
Yumi's father is tonight?
He said he had to work...
and wouldn't be home until late.
I see...
So that's why you invited us.
Sorry that you couldn't celebrate
your birthday alone with Papa.
It's your 20th birthday...
It should have been a night to remember!
That's ridiculous!
So Yumi loves her father?
So what? That's normal!
Why shouldn't a child love their parents?
Is that all it is...?
Come on, Yumi...
Tell her!
You're just father and daughter.
Hey, what's wrong with you?!
What a joke...
They might as well be married.
He's more like a
lover than a parent.
Yumi... You take good care of
your father, don't you?
- Just like a wife would...
- Shut up!
Hey, are you really...
thinking about having sex
with your father?
Even when you know how I feel?
Tell me it isn't true!
Tell me you're not
that dirty and defiled!
Don't touch me!
I see.
You were having sex
with your father all along.
I see how it is...
I understand perfectly!
It's not true...
Really... I've can't believe it...
So that's what you really are!
No!
It's pathetic.
I didn't realize what
a sick person you were!
Stop it!
See?
Just when you start to trust someone,
you realize that you can't.
You betrayed him.
First, you betrayed him
and then you killed him.
I don't like people
because I can't trust them.
People always act one way,
hiding their true feelings on the inside.
You always felt sorry for me
and thought I was lonely.
That's why you invited me to your party.
But you really shouldn't have bothered.
Here, this will put you to sleep.
You can rest now.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Don't worry, I'll die with you,
since you're too weak to do it alone.
I don't want to live in
such a dirty world anyway.
Yumi, I'm home.
Papa...
You're home!
Papa!
Yumi, what's wrong?
You'll stay with me, won't you?
You won't betray me, right?!
That's right.
Papa won't betray you, Yumi.
Promise?
Papa, don't leave me...
Papa...
Oh, this is Kei Asakawa.
Actually, I was thinking of remarrying.
I see...
Papa, will you celebrate
my 20th birthday with me?
I'll probably have to
leave this house for a while.
Okay, let's get started!
Kei, I'm sorry.
We didn't have enough wine glasses.
Here you go.
Here's to Papa and Kei.
Here's to your 20th birthday.
Cheers.
Here's to Papa and my future.
Cheers...
OUT OF THE WINDOW
Takashi...
Ta... ka... shi....
It's so cute!
Be careful not to burn your fingers.
The battle between you and
the strange monster is about to begin.
Do you have what it takes to survive?
This is the start of the survival game.
You have 3 minutes to stop the game,
if you do not wish to proceed.
I repeat.
You have 3 minutes to stop the game,
if you do not wish to proceed.
1 minute remaining until start...
In 1 minute, the game will start automatically.
This is the start of the survival game.
A monster will appear.
I repeat.
Your mission is to defeat the monster.
The monster will power up once every hour.
Please defeat the monster
as soon as possible.
It is no longer possible to stop the game.
I repeat.
SURVIVAL GAME
Warning! Warning!
The power of the monster
has increased by 20%.
I repeat.
The power of the monster
has increased by 20%.
Hello?!
The number you have dialed is
not in service at the moment.
Warning! Warning!
The player's power has been reduced by 20%.
Your mission is to defeat the monster.
The monster will power up once every hour.
Please defeat this monster
as soon as possible.
It is no longer possible to stop the game.
I repeat.
Exterior is multi-colored.
Eyes, ears and nose are sensitive,
finely tuned to detect humans.
IQ is 200.
Foul smell...
There is no information on file.
I repeat.
I know... I'll lock it out.
I'll just lock it out...
Fire...
I'll use fire!
I found it!
Please...
Survival Game 2 is about to start.
As the winner of Survival Game 1,
you will now face an
even more powerful monster.
It is no longer possible to stop the game.
I repeat.
No!
Here.
I'm sorry, but...
Give me my...
letter back.
Someone better than
Tetsuya is waiting for me.
If I keep spending time with Tetsuya,
I won't be able to see him, right?
Oh, well.
I'm sorry, but...
Sorry?
Does that mean...
I still have a chance with him?
Yes, I'm sure of it.
That's it!
All right, I'll do my best!
CINDERELLA
What are you talking about...
Why not?
It's easier if everyone does it...
I knew it wouldn't work.
It's Yumi...
What's with that face?
Why don't you just give up?
Kaori suits him because
she's got style and sense.
Haven't you realized that?
I bought it!
Oh...
It's Kaori...
Oh, I forgot!
It's Tetsuya's birthday today!
Kaori?
He's too good for her.
Just accept it...
There's no way Yumi
could get him to like her.
Kaori is a rich young lady.
Even if they break up,
he still wouldn't stoop to her level.
I know, right?
Yumi...
What?!
I want to talk to you, but...
- Is that okay?
- What?
Me?
Yes.
No way!
Well, see you later.
Okay... Bye bye...
What just happened...?
He didn't...
I can't believe it.
I've always been watching you.
Just you.
What?
We broke up.
Oh, so she went home!
No, it's over.
Maybe it's not too late for us?
Yes!
Well, wanna go somewhere?
Come on, get in!
Okay...
I'm sorry, I'll get in now.
Excuse me...
I had a lot of fun today.
Thank you so much.
See you!
Yumi.
What?
I'll call you at 9, okay?
Also...
Well...
Good night!
Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Who is the most beautiful...
of all?
Yes...
Hello?
Oh... Tetsuya?
What's wrong?
You don't sound well.
By the way, I was wondering if we could
have dinner at my house tomorrow.
What's wrong?
I'll drive you home.
No, it's not that.
My mom wants to see you.
What? Really?!
I'd love to!
Excuse me.
Well, come on in.
Where's your mom?
She'll be home soon.
She probably went shopping.
Oh, I see...
What time is it?
Don't worry about Kaori.
My mother might bring
her up, but it's okay...
She's really late.
I wonder where she went.
Dinner should have been almost ready...
It's okay...
All right, I'll make dinner for us!
Mother's not here yet, but...
Cheers.
Cheers!
Te... Tetsuya!
What time is it?
It's 9:30, but...
That clock is always wrong, so...
Maybe around 9?
I see...
I... don't feel very good.
I'm sorry!
Th... This face!
If Tetsuya sees me like this...
Yumi...
What's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
Don't open it, please!
Don't come in here!
Tetsuya, please!
Please!
Please open the door...
Please come and join me...
I'm scared...
Tetsuya...
Why do people worry so much
about their appearance?
AI Subtitle Revision and Timing:
WiseJake237
-- JINGI MINAMI SUBS --