NIGHT OF DEATH!
Martine?
DEAR SERGE
"Darling...
Our argument was ridiculous.
Please forget it.
I don't want to be a burden,
so I've decided to leave.
I'm going to take the job
you so kindly found for me.
Thanks again. "
- I'm here for the job.
- There is no job.
But-
- This is Deadlock House, right?
- Yes.
I want to see the director.
I was sent this letter.
Read it, if you don't believe me.
What is this, a prison?
Convenient for visitors!
Do they need a pass?
Was it from the war?
Which one?
Birth defect.
It's quiet here.
A FILM BY
- Wait here.
- Outside?
Here.
I don't think I'll last long here...
Mr. Léon!
I'm sick of chasing you!
I don't want a damn shot!
- You must have your shot.
- I don't want it!
Follow me.
Sorry.
We expected you tomorrow,
not today.
I admire initiative...
but detest excessive zeal!
One day early
doesn't change much.
That's your opinion, not mine.
- So?
You're problematic.
Hello?
No, don't worry.
Certainly. That's right.
I'll call you back.
I have nowhere else to go.
- How did she get here?
- By bus.
- Who saw her?
- Everyone.
Prepare a place for her in the attic.
- But-
- I know!
You see, dear...
I wasn't expecting you until tomorrow,
nothing is ready.
But here you are!
Tonight you'll sleep on a cot in the attic...
and tomorrow-
Don't worry, I can sleep anywhere.
Even on the floor.
What's going on? Tell me!
I haven't quit.
Unless I'm being fired...
That's it- I'm being fired,
without warning!
You're wrong, dear,
you're not being fired.
- Then what's she doing here?
- The same job as you.
I do fine on my own.
Ever since you've arrived
you've complained!
- I was just griping.
- I believed you, so I hired Miss Clement.
Wonderful!
With all our free time,
we'll twiddle our thumbs.
In the meantime, why don't you show
Miss Clement around?
You don't seem to like her much.
That's for sure! And the others,
they're annoying as hell. You'll see.
They drive me nuts, I swear.
- Been here long?
- Two months.
- Don't you ever knock?
- No time.
Young people do whatever they please!
- Did you wet the bed again?
- Absolutely.
At your age?
It can happen at any age.
I piss in reaction.
You know...
perhaps you shouldn't drink
before going to bed.
How sweet!
Unlike you!
What are you knitting?
A sweater, a scarf?
When my work is finished...
the old people's revolt will begin!
I'm knitting revolution!
- Nicole!
- What?
- What day is it?
- You already asked. The 28th.
Get it through your skull.
The 28th.
28, 28...
We spend a lot of time here.
The meals aren't complicated,
they're all vegetarians.
They don't want to get fat,
don't want to get old. Typical old people.
- We eat what they eat?
- Yes.
With my appetite,
it won't be easy!
Better get used to it.
At the orphanage, I shined the pots.
- I'm an orphan, too.
- Really?
You certainly don't
take care of your pots.
- We never use them.
- It's a shame.
Ready?
- I'll take care of them.
- What?
- The pots.
- If it makes you happy!
- I'll kill you!
- Save me! He's picking on me!
I'll kill him!
- I'll kill him like the Golden Needle Killer!
- But he only kills women!
You're a woman, I know it.
That's enough, Mr. Léon.
Bitch!
Comrades, revolution is at hand.
From all corners of the world,
old people and children...
the forgotten, the useless...
will form an army
of the Future and the Past...
to fight the final battle!
That's the whole lot.
They're a bit weird, as you'll see...
but they're not bad.
Typical old people.
I lack 432 calories.
- Martine?
- Ma'am?
I hope you'll manage my meals
better than your co-worker.
Should I make something else?
No point.
I'll make up for it tonight.
You may go.
Although the first few days,
I really thought I'd quit.
But I ended up staying.
Jobs are so hard to find, you know?
You'll see, at first they're annoying...
then it gets easier.
- The hardest is not being able to go out.
- We never go out?
Never. For the first two months.
Ms. Hélène says it's necessary
for the old people to adapt to you.
- You'll have your first day off soon?
- That's right!
I haven't seen my man for two months.
It's going to be wild!
- Have you got a guy?
- Yes.
What's he like?
He's smart, charming, and...
And?
He's a great lover.
- Can I meet him?
- I'm really jealous.
Don't worry, so am I.
- I'm crazy about my guy.
- What's he like?
I'll show you a picture,
you'll see for yourself.
Sweetie, you'll fall for him!
Unbelievable.
- Hey, look.
- What?
That's Léon.
He walks as well as you and I.
The wheelchair is just to bug people.
Old people, I swear!
- Where's that photo?
- Hold on.
What is it?
- Telephone.
- For me?
- Yes, you.
- Really?
- What do you want?
- The new girl seems nice.
Unlike me.
Why are you so mean to me?
I'm not mean to you.
I just find you extremely unpleasant.
What do you want?
Nicole...
would you marry a man like me?
- I didn't say me.
- I understood you.
- Too bad.
- Why?
Yes.
I don't know if I can.
Hold on.
Ma'am, my fiancé wants to know-
He wants to-
Could I have the night off?
- Excuse me, but-
- I heard you. I was thinking.
In case your co-worker didn't tell you,
outings are forbidden the first two months.
- I know. She told me.
- She's improving.
Since you don't start until tomorrow,
I'll make an exception. You may go out.
Thank you, ma'am.
Hello? It's okay.
At 8:00.
Of course I'll be alone.
Who would I bring?
Okay, take care.
- Martine?
- Ma'am?
You've just had your only phone call.
Yes, ma'am.
That's the good thing
about working here.
I'll stay a few more months
and then I'll leave.
- So it does have good points!
- Sure.
I'd like to buy a café with Maurice.
You still haven't shown me his photo!
We have plenty of time, now.
What's that?
- The boiler room. Want to see it?
- Sure.
- There's nothing to see.
- Stupid jerk!
- That guy bugs me.
- It must be hard to be like him.
Oh! Saint Martine!
- Then, he took my hand!
- I don't believe it!
It's the whole truth!
What a charmer!
Hey, buddy.
Hello.
You're so lucky.
As soon as they've finished their party,
I'm off to bed.
Say...
- give a kiss to...
- Serge.
... Serge for me.
You'll introduce me?
Yes.
- Hang in there.
- Bye.
Mr. Léon, what is this?
Don't move.
Hands up?
Keep laughing, stupid bitch!
- Listen, you-
- Don't move!
- Mr. Léon-
Jerk!
You slapped me,
so I stained your dress!
Look at that!
- I'm telling the director!
- Perhaps you shouldn't have slapped him.
This goody-goody act of yours
is really getting on my nerves!
- Well, good-bye.
- Bye.
Mr. Flavien, please open the gate.
Return it to me tomorrow.
Thanks.
We fall asleep
It's a mistake
We're old and grey
When we awake
Like a blood-thirsty tiger
Your claws are sharp
I hate you
We are afraid to see youth fly
And we are afraid to die
Your face is dark and dry
Your claws are sharp
I hate you
- Who wants it?
- I do!
You believe
that you hold sway
You give life
You take it away
But now it's time
for you to pray
Though your claws are sharp
And I hate you
TimeI
I'll get youI
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
I had a nightmare.
Calm down, honey.
Your heart is pounding.
It was awful.
What time is it?
- 1:00 a. m.
- I'd better get back.
Not so soon.
It's my first day tomorrow, I need rest.
Just a little longer.
You don't know how strict the director is!
I don't care.
Now I've got you, I'm keeping you.
Nicole, are you asleep?
"Forgive me for calling you a goody-goody.
That idiot really pissed me off.
I'm glad we met
and I'm sure we'll be good friends.
Sleep well and don't dream of Serge...
you'll just be more frustrated!
Take care, Nicole. "
It's the new girl. Let's try her.
Don't be so greedy!
I'm sorry. Did I scare you?
You sure did! Who are you?
- Are you new here?
- You're very observant.
- Where's Nicole?
- Are you done?
Yes.
Who's there?
- It's the gestapo!
- Be nice, Mr. Jules.
Your sweater is growing.
It's like a revolution: each row
is an army marching onward.
When will this revolution occur?
Imagine a huge army-
an old person, a child,
an old person, a child.
- Interested?
- Yes.
- I'll keep you informed.
- Thanks.
But...
I promise.
Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Sometimes it's dangerous to fall sleep.
Waking up is much nicer.
Thanks.
You can keep the poison
you call coffee.
Luckily, I have my own.
Mr. Flavien.
I wanted to apologize
for picking flowers.
Nicole wasn't in her room
this morning.
Once you've finished breakfast...
Ms. Hélène wants to see you.
What about Nicole?
Hello. Did you sleep well?
Yes, thanks.
And then...
he kissed me.
- Just like that?
- Like that.
She came to see me
right after you left.
We had a terrible argument.
She was unbelievably aggressive
and insolent.
I fired her immediately.
You can have her room.
Was the argument about me?
Obviously.
She accused me of hiring you
behind her back...
and once she'd trained you...
she expected that I'd fire her.
And yet...
What?
I found a letter from her on my suitcase
when I came in last night.
What did it say?
She must have written it
before coming to see me.
Of course.
- Have a nice day.
- You too, ma'am.
I protest! This must change!
Why should you always
get the best piece?
I want the heart too!
I want it! I pay, for God's sake!
Understand?
Who's to thank if you're
able to yell like that today?
Where would you be without me?
What about you?
Idiot!
Can't you lock the door?
You waited until now to do it?
Why not before?
Go on! Hurry up!
- They're mine!
- Liar, they're mine! Thief!
- You're the thief!
- Help!
Let's duke it out!
- What's going on?
- They're mine!
What should I do?
Get Mr. Flavien.
They'll kill each other.
- Where is he?
- In the boiler room, probably.
Jules and Pascal are fighting!
They'll kill each other!
Bastard!
Here's the chain-gang!
Fascist!
Are you avoiding me
because I scare you?
- No, but-
- But what?
The way you treated Jules and Pascal-
They're beasts, horrible beasts.
- They're old people.
- I'll teach you to recognize them.
Maybe. But I didn't like your violence.
Oh! Mr. Jules.
I don't want any more fighting.
Pascal started it.
He stole my slippers.
I'm warning you:
one more fight and I'm leaving.
I hate violence.
We are born into violence.
It's everywhere.
Open your eyes.
It shouldn't exist here.
You're interesting.
Of all the girls who've worked here,
you're the only one who cares about us.
What are we, to you?
Men and women
who've worked all their lives...
and who now deserve
rest and tranquillity.
Is Sunday visitors' day?
What visitors?
Don't your children visit you?
They died a long time ago.
Died?
How old are you?
What's for dinner?
A casserole I invented:
Potatoes, carrots and leeks.
I'm surprised that
you're all vegetarians.
Is it a coincidence?
Here, child, drink this.
- What is it?
- Something to regenerate your cells.
Do you think I need it?
Certainly! Your insides
must be clean and healthy.
- Go on, drink.
- Drink.
That's it!
"My dear Serge...
Just a quick note before bed.
Work is okay.
It's easier than I'd thought,
except that I'm busy every second...
because my co-worker left.
After eight months of unemployment,
it's good to work again. "
Mr. Pascal?
I hoped you weren't asleep and...
And?
Mr. Pascal!
Just a little cuddle.
A few minutes.
Really, Mr. Pascal!
Don't be silly.
What will the others think?
I like to cuddle and no one
wants to cuddle with me.
Okay, but just this once.
But it feels so good!
The heart is gone.
Who stole the heart?
I thought they never ate meat.
Where did it come from?
Thanks, Martine.
I'll take care of it.
That's fine.
That's fine, Martine.
My calories are balanced.
Did you throw something away
by mistake?
- Yes.
- What?
Two pictures of myself.
If you see them-
- Don't worry, I'll give them to you.
- Thank you.
Would you marry a man like me?
I don't mean me, but a man like me.
- Why not? If I loved him.
- Thank you.
It's easy to say,
but can you prove it?
- Prove what?
- That you love me.
You twist my words, Flavien.
MISS HÉLÈNE ROBERT, 20
1886 BEAUTY QUEEN
- Your cleaning is taking forever!
- I'm done.
Tell me, dear,
do you enjoy theater?
Yes, I went to see Boeing-Boeing
with the orphanage.
And music,
what sort of music do you like?
The Bee Gees and The Rolling Stones.
Good Lord!
Spare me from mediocrity.
Mr. Léon! You and your dumb jokes!
Don't ever do that again!
I'll keep doing it
until the day I die.
And that day is far off!
Imbecile!
Idiot!
Moron!
Slob!
You're alive today because of me!
Never forget that!
Without me,
you'd be rotting in your coffins...
so I forbid even the slightest protest.
As for you...
no meat for a week.
No meat for a week?
Hélène, you can't!
Have mercy, Hélène.
Please accept my apology.
Forgive me.
- Go on, forgive him.
- Forgive him.
I don't like Jules, but...
- We must stick together.
- We must succeed in our attempt!
Live for 1,000 years.
I'll forgive you
because we are warriors.
And if one of us falters,
our entire struggle is at risk.
Thank you!
- Hello.
- You always surprise me.
- I like surprising people.
- You certainly surprise me!
Can you mail this?
Does it make you sad?
I'd rather the letter were for me.
- If you want, I'll write to you.
- Thanks.
- Have you been delivering here long?
- Two months.
When was the last time
you went to the movies?
- A long time ago.
- Want to go?
A night out? Why not?
THE GOLDEN NEEDLE KILLER
- When?
- In two months.
- Are you done?
- Yeah.
By the way, bring apples tomorrow.
I'm almost out.
No problem.
Hello, Mr. Jules. Sleep well?
Well, I see the revolutionary sweater
has changed color.
- The revolution is in mourning.
- Really?
Why?
They've got nothing!
Flavien asks if you have any trash.
The garbage truck is here.
I do.
Here, Mr. Pascal.
Take this bucket.
If they have ashes, get them for me.
Tell Flavien it's to clean the pots.
I love to be given a mission!
THE KILLER'S SIGNATURE
A NEEDLE LEFT
IN THE NECK OF HIS VICTIMS
It makes you happy.
Yes.
Very happy.
It reminds me of the orphanage.
Did you like it at the orphanage?
That's a good question.
What memories does an orphan have?
The orphanage.
I've often asked Flavien
and he never wanted to answer.
Oh, I didn't know
Flavien was an orphan.
Not that he talks much...
That's true.
Ms. Hélène raised him.
Flavien?
Yes.
114 YEARS
How old is Ms. Hélène?
I think I'll take a nap.
Keep scrubbing.
"... always young women aged 20 to 30. ''
You've nothing to worry about!
"The women are attacked from behind.
The madman plunges a golden needle
into the area of their cerebellum.
Then he sexually abuses them
and abandons them in the woods. "
He must have a lot of needles.
They can't be real gold.
Who knows. Maybe the killer is rich.
- All that glitters is not gold.
- Perhaps you're the killer.
Armand? He'd love to be able
to abuse women!
I know who the killer is.
It's Flavien.
It's possible.
Where does he go at night?
He goes out every night.
Are you okay?
- What happened?
- You fell off the stepladder.
It's due to a vitamin deficiency.
It affects her balance.
You always seem to be
looking for something.
I'm not looking for anything.
I simply wanted to raise the heat.
It's at 68 degrees. Isn't that enough?
A resident complained.
- Who?
- Pascal.
That's odd. I just saw him
and he didn't mention it.
He's afraid of you.
Are you afraid of me?
No.
I'd like to get to know you.
And you get to know me better
by digging through ashes?
That has nothing to do with it.
I'm not so sure.
Meaning?
You're looking for something
that I assure you doesn't exist.
Since I'm not looking for anything,
it probably doesn't exist.
Exactly.
- Did you know I'm an orphan?
- Yes. Ms. Hélène told me.
Why didn't you say you were, too?
What would be the point?
To establish a contact with me.
I doubt you want to establish
a contact simply for me.
It's just to get what you're after.
- You're lying, Martine.
- I'm not.
I'm just taking an interest in you.
- Also, I'm looking for something.
- I know.
I've noticed it for days.
You're different.
Can I know what you're looking for?
- Where is Nicole?
- She left, you know that.
No one leaves without their suitcase.
Why did you try to burn it?
Why do you have her pen?
Where did the meat I found
in Jules' room come from?
You read too many thrillers
as a teenager.
Something is going on.
I don't know what yet,
but I've got my eyes open.
What do you think could go on
in a place like this?
I'll find out.
Nicole was nice.
- Did you like her?
- Not really.
She was bad at shots.
- You have a gentle touch.
- Thanks.
- Have you been here long?
- Oh, time...
- How long?
- I don't remember.
- Have you had many housekeepers?
- I don't remember!
- Done with the shot?
- Yes!
Still trying to establish a contact?
She found a piece of meat
in that fool Jules's room...
and knows the other girl
left without her suitcase.
That's all.
- She's asking questions.
- No one will answer.
Her questions might
upset the residents.
You're in love with this one, too!
Poor Flavien, you wear
your heart on your sleeve.
We can't fire her now, it's too late.
It's almost the 28th.
We're preparing her.
I've gained weight.
Your mixture is making me fat!
That's good, believe me!
It's better to be envied than pitied.
I don't want it.
You're wrong.
It's excellent for your health.
Is something wrong?
You haven't looked well lately.
What day is it?
The 26th.
In two days, I'll be strong again.
Why? You'll feel better
after the 28th?
- Where are you going?
- To sleep. I'm allowed, aren't I?
You had no right to make me so ugly!
You never grow old. You never will.
I'd like to be old...
very old.
I've got a treat.
Look what I brought you!
Nicole.
Would you marry a man like me?
I didn't say me, but a man like me.
What?
No?
Why not?
Because I'm too ugly.
Poor fool.
Tonight.
- You're always scaring me!
- I'm sorry.
Do you know what day it is?
No.
The 28th.
You've been here two months.
Tomorrow night we're going to the movies,
you promised!
I'd love to. It will do me good
to get out of here.
Are you done?
COMPOSITE IMAGE
OF THE GOLDEN NEEDLE KILLER SOON
See you tomorrow night.
I think I already asked:
Would you marry a man like me?
Let's leave, Martine!
Let's leave!
Don't you understand?
It's not about your looks.
I don't like you! Got it?
Too bad.
Why?
Usually, the difficult part
is dragging them here.
I already asked you:
- Would you marry a man like me?
- Murderer!
Murderer!
The phone, please.
I need to make a call!
- Hello, Serge?
- Yes?
It's Martine.
- Come quickly, they're eating us!
- What?
- It's awful, I ran away!
- You ran away?
They're all totally crazy!
- Did you call the police?
- The line was busy.
- Where are you?
- The café on the corner.
Stay calm and don't leave.
I'll come get you.
Whatever you do, don't leave.
I'm coming.
Hurry!
Roll.
Your turn.
FOR MY BELOVED NICOLE...
MAURICE
- Your fiancé's not bad!
- Give it back.
"For my beloved Nicole, Maurice. "
Maurice is one lucky guy.
- Need a ride?
- The police station. Quick!
- Police?
- Hurry, it's a matter of life and death!
It's not all there.
Yes, it is. As usual.
The price has gone up.
Don't you think that's pushing it?
What about the risks I take
for this bullshit of yours?
They're the same,
regardless of the price.
Money always helps.
Especially when one decides
to do nothing.
Oh, please...
eternal youth is priceless.
You'll grow old, too.
I'll move in here.
- Is the next one ready for tomorrow?
- Yes.
But at double the price, in cash.
Go get her.
Hélène.
Help!
Don't hide.
Look at me...
straight in the eyes.
You tried to make me ugly.
Go!
You're my friend. Save me.
You are necessary.
The revolution...
One child, one old person...
I'm your friend.
I know we're monsters.
But when you think about it...
no worse than those living in the city.
No worse.
She's my Martine. Forever.
Hélène, you lost.
You lost.
So this is Death...
the Big Sleep.
I was never ugly...
just useless.
There are veils one lifts
without knowing
Terrible veils, when pierced
fears growing
Seeking out forbidden secrets
is unwise
We tricked Time, and now,
he'll chastise
Our heroine, beautiful and young
must pay
This fragile beauty will
become prey
She saw Death
And she knew Death
Its secret
Her innocence
Condemned her
To Death
Night of Death
There are veils one lifts
without knowing
Terrible veils, when pierced
fears growing
Seeking out forbidden secrets
is unwise
We tricked Time, and now,
he'll chastise
Our heroine, beautiful and young
must pay
This fragile beauty will
become prey
There are veils one lifts
without knowing
Terrible veils, when pierced
fears growing
Seeking out forbidden secrets
is unwise
We tricked Time, and now,
he'll chastise
Our heroine, beautiful and young
must pay
This fragile beauty will
become prey