Asomidin Tohirov?
I did it yesterday.
It's my third time.
Want me to go?
No, I will.
You can sleep.
Yum... here.
- Hot?
- No, it's not.
I said you could sleep.
I couldn't.
You okay, Leo?
Too hot?
Yes.
This way I see you.
We don't see much of Mommy
these days.
We meet at my mom's or here?
It's tonight?
Virginie, you're a fucking pain.
Is your partner coming along?
No.
Do you have anyone
to accompany you?
No.
Tonight, antibiotics
to prevent infection
during the procedure.
Have a good day.
Thanks.
What's your problem?
You do things offhandedly.
- You're imprecise, careless.
- And on the ground?
Am I a good cop?
Answer me.
Am I good on the ground?
Yeah.
So? Why are you railing?
I'm not Oxford Unabridged!
I'm a cop.
I'm not here to write a novel.
All good, Miss Norway?
What's wrong?
Virginie?
Are you free?
Yeah, why?
To get this woman's belongings.
Violent husband.
He's not in.
Can you come along?
It'll be fine, ma'am.
We're here.
- What the fuck?
- Step back.
Step back.
Sonia, come on...
Sir, over there.
- I can't talk to her?
- No.
Back up and stay put.
Bitch.
Little whore.
Go wash, dirty whore.
Feel better now?
You're cumming, right?
Your uniform gets you off.
Stop pretending you have balls.
I've had enough now.
Let go! Let go, I said!
Will you let go?
Bitch!
Miss Norway!
Aristide, stop calling me that.
What?
Would you prefer Miss Senegal?
I have an important question.
Primordial.
What do we do for lunch?
Kebab or kebab?
Be happy.
I'm leaving you the choice.
I can't. I have work.
Cheating on me?
Eating with another man?
Okay, then.
Backup requested by the riverbank.
36 Quai d'Austerlitz.
Do you copy?
Cool.
Time to kick some ass.
Sounds likely.
Good sex last night.
And a good fight today.
You gonna help?
Don't move!
Nice workout!
What happened?
Rip your pantyhose?
I haven't slept in 18 months.
So?
That's women for you.
You want equality
then you play the mother card
or the period card.
Seriously.
- Leave your ovaries at home.
- Lay off!
Not today, not you.
Why "not me"?
- What did I do?
- You did nothing.
So what is it?
I'm getting an abortion.
I couldn't leave my ovaries at home.
Sorry.
It's not your fault.
I forgot my pill, one fucking time.
Here we are.
You sure it's mine?
I'm sure all right.
I'll spare you the details.
100% sure.
- It won't work!
- Why not?
You can't have
more than one girl in a car.
I know.
It's the rule
but rules change.
Two girls can't patrol without a man.
Am I not right?
It's the rule!
- How do you make a cop?
- Tell us.
One man minimum.
Takes more than a woman alone.
- And two women?
- Not even two women!
You're unbelievable!
Machos like you still exist?
It's the truth.
One man minimum!
I need two officers to volunteer.
It's not our sector
and it means doing overtime.
The prison fire
has Escort Crew scrambling.
Gregoire?
No, sorry.
Aristide?
No way.
I have a life, unlike others.
Erik? Up for it?
Okay, but they have some nerve.
I'll do it. I'll go along.
I had nothing to do with it.
No, it doesn't suit me.
I told you I wasn't sure.
An emergency is an emergency!
Hello?
- You okay?
- Fine.
I need to search the car.
You never know.
See?
This can become a weapon.
Anything can.
What's Herve doing?
Where did you put them?
Not in there.
You're a pain, Martine.
You're a pain in the ass, you know.
Can't you stop busting my balls?
Freezing.
No, cold.
Don't come crying
when you get cancer.
Don't count on me
to take you for chemo.
Why are you always so nasty?
Why take it out on me?
If we'd had a kid,
I'd take it out on him.
But it's all muscle, no balls.
I grab the guy and say:
"I'll whip your ass
next time you call me 'bro'..."
You upset?
His bro?
From what mother?
Can you take it down?
You're not happy?
No, I'm not!
You know why?
Your robbery report is full of mistakes.
Stop nitpicking. They're just typos.
Want me to write my reports
in sonnet form?
Enough already.
What's your problem?
You do everything offhandedly.
You're imprecise, careless.
And on the ground?
Am I a good cop?
Answer me.
On the ground?
Am I a good cop?
Yeah.
So why are you railing?
I'm not Oxford Unabridged.
I'm a cop.
I'm not here to write a novel.
Take her to her place.
All her stuff is there.
All right, I'll deal with it.
Virginie...
Are you free?
Yeah, why?
To get this woman's belongings.
Violent husband.
He's not in.
Can you come along?
Look.
Broken, as usual.
Pain in the ass.
How can we work in a clunker like this?
Sometimes even the automatic locks
don't work.
They want more arrests
for their statistics
but the guys can open the doors and run.
It's wild.
- Step back.
- What the fuck?
Step back.
Sonia, come on.
Sir, over there.
- I can't talk to her?
- No.
Step back and stay put, you hear?
He's not a bastard, you know.
Excuse me?
He's not mean.
He didn't do it on purpose.
It's my fault too.
It'll be fine, ma'am.
A man who hits a woman is no man.
There's no justifying that, ever.
Let go! Let go, I said!
Stay here.
Calm down! You hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
What are you doing to him?
Stop, you're hurting him.
It'll be fine.
You're hurting him.
Leave.
Please...
leave.
It's good.
Take it away.
I need a place like that.
Change scenery, take a breather.
Everywhere in the streets
I want them to talk about me
I want the girls to be naked
and to jump on me
To admire me and to kill me
To strip away my virtue
For the former schoolgirls
I'll be an idol
And every night,
out of breath in their beds
they'll cheat on their husbands
I just wanted to punish him.
I love my son!
I wanted to teach him a lesson,
so he'd cool off.
I'm not a bad mom.
I didn't want to kill him.
Despite the soap, it lingers.
The smell of death.
Ever notice? It sticks.
When I go home,
I stay on the landing.
Till the light goes out.
I undress and count to 60.
So I don't take the shit inside.
I leave it in the hallway.
It's stupid.
For me, it's underwear.
I always make sure
my underwear isn't too ugly.
To be presentable, just in case.
If I end up on a slab at the morgue.
It's stupid too.
So Granny, what's this all about?
Trying to get attention?
Take care of yourself.
Okay?
And go easy on the nurses,
I know you.
I'm coming for Christmas.
So wait for me.
You promise?
There you go.
Love you.
Something between you two?
Yeah, right.
All good, Miss Norway?
What's wrong?
Didn't get your bonus?
- Miss Norway...
- Aristide, stop calling me that.
- Kebab or kebab?
- I can't. I have work.
Cheating on me?
Eating with another man?
Okay, then.
Hello, chef!
Hello.
Today I'm on a diet.
Kebab, no meat, no bread.
Just lettuce and tomato.
The usual?
Just kidding. The usual.
Everything but onions.
No onions.
- For here or to go?
- For here.
All right.
I love my son.
I wanted to teach him a lesson,
so he'd cool off.
I'm not a bad mom!
- I didn't want to kill him...
- Shut up.
Stop now.
Backup requested by the riverbank.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Cool.
Time to kick some ass.
I mean it.
Leave your ovaries at home.
Lay off.
Not today, and not you.
Why "not me"?
- What did I do?
- Nothing.
So what is it?
I'm getting an abortion.
I couldn't leave my ovaries at home.
Sorry.
It's not your fault.
I forgot my pill.
One fucking time, here we are.
You sure it's mine?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I'll spare you the details.
100% sure.
Why did you become a cop?
Don't say you dreamt of it as a kid.
I wanted to figure skate.
Really?
How did you go from skates to guns?
I don't know. It just happened.
Let me guess.
Dad a cop?
Nope.
- Grandfather a cop?
- Not even.
How about you?
Well, me...
My choice was dealer or junkie.
Like my brothers.
What can I say?
I went astray.
You believed me?
It's not true?
- You believed me?
- Yeah.
Nope.
Why not?
How would I know?
- You're so prejudiced.
- Nonsense.
You are.
It could have been true.
I have no brothers.
All right.
Just a sister.
She's a judge.
Okay. Is that true?
No.
- It isn't?
- Nope.
She's a speech therapist.
Which is still cool.
An ice skater.
Yep.
I don't believe you.
When is your curfew?
Is your husband nice?
Yeah, he is.
He's cool.
And the kid?
How old is he now?
Young enough to count in months.
How long you married?
Is this an interrogation?
Can I keep my shoes and laces?
I'm just interested.
I'm not allowed?
Seven years.
Wow, not bad.
I never went beyond seven days.
Bravo.
That's the way I am.
I can't be tamed.
No one's trying to tame you.
You mustn't worry.
Really?
Not even a little?
You're being an idiot.
And I have to tell you.
What?
You skate well.
All right.
I have to go.
Goodnight.
I need two officers to volunteer.
It's urgent.
Aristide?
No way.
I have a life, unlike others.
Erik? Up for it?
Yeah, but they have some nerve.
The fire isn't their fault.
I'll do it.
I have no plans.
We'll meet you at the car.
Still, I don't like it.
Escorting a prisoner isn't hard.
I don't like it.
Neither do I.
I'd rather be with my wife.
Herve!
I was kidding. I can go.
No one's expecting me.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
All right then.
Asomidin Tohirov?
We're sending you to your country.
Understand?
Sit down.
Give that to me.
What is this?
You meant to swallow it?
What are you doing here?
So?
Ready to kick out a foreigner?
Why do you say that?
It's what we're doing.
You hadn't understood?
Erik, is this true?
Yes, because of the fire.
A guy needs to be at the airport.
We're driving him.
It's not our job.
Why do we have to?
Not our job? Why did you offer?
You're funny.
I told you, Escort Crew is busy
transporting detainees.
I didn't know.
You volunteered.
I couldn't guess.
You just didn't want to go home.
Where's an all-night drugstore?
What's wrong now?
I need to make a quick stop.
Can we?
Can't wait till tomorrow?
No. I needed to go after my shift.
I don't know where there is one.
There's one at Nation.
We have time to make a detour.
Quickly.
Anything else?
A glass of water.
Prefab units are fire hazards.
They cram them in
and they're surprised.
That's the way it is
So damn pretty,
when she goes out
I love her so damn much
She has eyes like a gun
She has a killer gaze
She's pulled the trigger first
She hit me, I'm dying...
You're such a cock-block.
You two are so depressing.
It's like being in a hearse.
I won a song contest as a kid.
I had a voice, I swear...
clear as crystal.
Angelic.
My grandma thought I'd be
the next Michael Jackson.
But no... my voice changed.
Who cares about your life?
We don't give a shit.
You're pissing us off.
The reception office?
Down on the left.
I'm here to take the detainee
to the airport.
Follow me.
How did the fire start?
With a mattress.
They have lots of imagination.
Lots.
Some slice open their bellies,
others start fires.
Each one has his thing.
We have nothing here.
No equipment.
Not even an emergency exit.
We had to cut the bars
or they'd all have sizzled.
Guy in the orange sweater.
A Tadjik.
He has his belongings.
- Was he frisked?
- He's clean.
He had a blade on him, so watch out.
For the Deportation Unit at Roissy.
Know where you're going?
Understands nothing.
We're taking you to the airport.
You have a layover in Istanbul.
Then back to Tajikistan.
Any objections?
No?
I'll handcuff you for the ride.
Tohirov?
You're not going to the airport?
We appealed to the European Court
for Human Rights.
They're ruling soon.
I know nothing about it.
They'll kill him back home.
It's not my call.
You may as well let him burn.
Less hypocritical!
Noble profession! Bravo!
So?
It's all good.
I was looking for you.
I'm here.
We saved you from the flames.
- Say thanks.
- No French.
TN12, individual in custody.
Copy that.
He's not too calm?
Keep an eye on him...
Yeah.
Erik...
Why did you open it?
What are you, a cop?
Is your name on it?
No? So don't open.
It was half open.
Mail theft.
Something political?
I don't know...
Understand what you read?
- Did you understand?
- Yes.
And so?
Just words.
Excuse me.
"Men in masks led me
to an isolation cell,
a dungeon.
I was tortured for days.
Very violent.
Groups of 3 or 4, at all hours.
They beat me nonstop.
Fists, feet, clubs.
A torturer asked if I wanted a smoke.
I said yes.
He lit a cigarette
and put a gas mask on me,
so I'd suffocate.
Then they put wires around my wrists
and electrocuted me.
I fainted.
It lasted ten days.
I thought I'd die."
Just words?
A story like that costs 15 euros.
There are tons of details.
He can't have invented it.
What do you want us to do?
Envelopes are sealed for a reason.
They're going to kill him.
A real sob story.
Yeah.
They exaggerate the threat
to get refugee status.
They lie. Embroider.
Why issue an order to deport
if he'd be killed upon arrival?
Think it over.
Enough.
We're not here to chitchat.
We're cops, not social workers.
You never loosen up.
What the hell?
It's okay. He's fine.
What's got into you?
Cuff him.
Go on, breathe.
What's your problem today?
Is he a friend of yours?
Got family in Tajikistan?
He's a shrimp.
Why are you scared?
You're a pain! A real pain!
Isn't she?
Yes. She's a pain.
I'm working, dammit!!!
Why not the flashing lights?
Yeah, run red lights,
take roundabouts counter-clockwise.
Want the engine on our laps?
I said we have time.
What's your problem?
Your mother?
No, my grandmother.
She raised me.
One hell of a woman.
What about your parents?
What about them?
What did they do?
Where are they from?
Do I ask you questions?
I can't know?
They were in France.
I came afterwards.
How old were you?
Do we have to share our lives?
Yes?
No.
We'll have to stop meeting up.
I know.
I don't know, like this anyway...
- I'm trying, I swear.
- Okay.
Trying very hard.
I keep saying it.
I'm also trying hard.
I keep saying to myself:
"Miss Norway isn't for you.
She's not for you.
She's married."
So I try to imagine you old, wrinkled.
Ugly as sin, no teeth.
So you'll disgust me forever.
So I can move on.
But then you laugh...
What can I do?
My heart melts like snow in the sun.
A poet. You kept that hidden.
What do I do now?
Figure it out.
It's a lost cause.
Why are you exiting?
I'm hungry.
Coming?
Hurry up.
Keep it up
and Erik's going to lose it.
What are you after?
Any chance the Tajik can run?
No.
Would you let him run?
I have no idea.
I don't care about him.
Think Mr. Clean would let you do it?
But you...
would you let him run?
You're talking crap.
They're playing me for a fool.
Don't try anything stupid.
I have my eyes on you.
I'm no fool.
You play the victim,
but maybe you came
to blow up a market.
Who knows if you're an innocent lamb?
Refugee or terrorist, how can we tell?
No one is innocent
until proof of the contrary.
3-course meal?
They're fucking in the crapper!
I don't understand what you said.
I don't understand.
I understand nothing.
You're even prettier when you frown.
You're stupid.
I wish.
Wish what?
That I was stupid.
What you told me earlier...
about what you're doing...
I keep thinking about it.
It kills me.
I can't get it out of my head.
When are you going?
Tomorrow morning.
Is anyone accompanying you?
Yes.
I'm going with a friend.
Good.
- Just don't go alone.
- Don't worry.
Corinne is coming along.
Corinne?
You better watch your guy.
He can up and go.
No, no.
He's not hungry.
He'll eat in the plane.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Think I don't understand?
You open the file, uncuff him,
stop for burgers,
stop at every light.
We're asked to take him to Roissy,
we take him to Roissy.
Police, airport, airplane.
Understand?
At least Escort Crew is competent.
Imagine the clusterfuck!
- Someone shit on your brains?
- Enough!
Stop bossing us around.
What do you think?
That your platitudes impress us?
You'll make me gain weight.
Find that funny?
Pain in the fucking ass!
Pull over!
What do I do?
Take the exit.
And he's not cuffed, dammit!
Get up front.
I take the highway?
Yes or no?
So?
Of course. Take the highway.
What else?
Open the door and let him run?
You think it's that easy?
Think so?
Sure, it's romantic,
but you think it's easy.
They wouldn't send a chopper.
He's not a fugitive.
Yeah, he's nothing.
No one cares about him.
If he vanished,
no one would go looking.
He's just a poor guy, not a criminal.
What do you know?
I know, that's all.
And your panic attacks?
Fine.
Still a tranquilizer a day?
I'm down to a quarter.
If it's not enough,
three quarters, or four.
Meaning a whole pill.
Sometimes it comes back.
Especially at night.
I tell myself
his death wasn't my fault.
I couldn't know
the guy had a box-cutter.
Bad luck, that's all.
Bad luck?
Is that what you really think?
I don't think.
I think nothing.
I clear out my head.
It's like there's a desert inside.
I listen to the wind blow.
And I move forward.
That's all.
I move forward.
Look at him.
Look.
Still waters run deep.
Stop with your dumb proverbs.
Look at him.
You two are out of your minds!
We'd be in deep shit
if we let him run.
You have no idea!
You're okay
sending him to die?
I'm the bastard, is that it?
You're humanists.
I'm a dumb, obedient cop.
Yes, I follow orders. It's my job.
It's yours too. Dammit!
You're all pissing me off!
Yes, what now?
Martine, I'm working.
Understand? Working!
Unlike you, on my ass
popping pills and watching TV.
We'll deal with this later.
Okay? Later.
Pain in the fucking ass!
TN12, it's cutting out.
No-signal zone.
You have 6 minutes.
Do as you please.
I wash my hands of it.
You played your game well.
Fuck...
Unbelievable.
It's a topsy-turvy world.
What?
Got a problem with that?
Go on, say so.
Got a problem with alcohol?
Only remedy that works.
Martine, where are you?
Why won't you answer?
Now I'm worried.
Bravo, you won, call me back.
If I ever had to shoot myself,
I'd come here.
What the fuck is he doing?
Enough already, get lost!
Go, we'll keep quiet.
We'll keep quiet!
Wait...
Here, take this.
Go on, run.
Move it, move it!
Beat it!
Go on, go on!
I don't believe this!
Forget it.
Why?
He thinks we want to kill him.
Wait.
Now the airport. Get in.
What's got into you?
Stick your consciences up your asses.
Get in.
- We almost...
- That's enough!
You're fucking pains!
I can't take it anymore.
Enough!
He won't run an inch.
Stop bothering him and get in.
Good dog.
A good little retriever. Great.
Get in.
Stop showing off.
Let's finish the job.
You got no balls, do you?
Not yours, in any case.
Get in.
What if I refuse?
What then?
You'll call the cops?
That's enough.
Everyone, get in. Let's go.
Get in!
The file, please.
Hey. What's he like?
Cooperative.
This way, sir.
Come.
Go inside. We'll search you.
You leave today. Understand?
You take the plane.
We'll search you.
Can we go now?
You must wait till takeoff.
Are you kidding? Wait an hour?
Yes, and I'm being nice.
Rule is you wait 2 hours,
till the point of no-return.
Are you hazing us?
Because we're not Escort Crew?
Not at all, it's just procedure.
- You okay?
- No...
I don't feel well. Can we stop?
Virginie, what are you doing?
We're in charge of security.
It's under control.
He was agitated, but...
Why the Velcro cuffs?
They never come off. Procedure.
- He's calm.
- He's dangerous.
Don't fall for his victim act.
...he's capable of anything...
...want to take that risk?
We'll remove him.
Watch out for mosquitos.
They carry malaria here.
There are rabbits.
I'm so damn stupid.
Talking about rabbits,
not the stuff I want to say.
Like what?
Even if you're crazy,
life is less boring with you.
Remember the schizo who killed his son,
then himself.
Yeah.
Remember the mom's cries?
I still remember the address.
The floor.
I remember the door code.
Want me to tell you?
I'm no retriever dog.
Thanks for calming down
the Customs agents.
Don't exaggerate.
I did damage control.
They'll report us.
A fucking report.
20 years of service, not one blemish
and you stir up the shit.
I feel dirty.
I lied to cover your asses.
What got into you two?
Jesus...
What got into you?
What did you buy him, 2 days?
You don't think
he'll be on the next plane?
You never know.
- If the European Court rules...
- Yeah, right.
Keep lying to yourself.
Not going home, chief?
No, as you can see, I'm not.
See you tomorrow.
Yep.
No use coming home.
I changed the lock.
47, 48, 49...
60.
I'll keep my clothes.
You don't mind?
Just your hands on my arms, my back...
Gently.
Just my back and arms.
Don't bother on my skin.
Subtitles: Andrew Litvack
Subtitling: HIVENTY