Why did you stop me?
Why?
It's all right, Jean.
Everything is all right.
Elliott, why didn't you let me go?
I can't face it...
Like a thousand eyes.
Watching.
The stars?
Oh, Elliott, I'm so frightened!
I'm so frightened!
Thank you.
You're just upset about your father.
It's more than that, it's...
Darling, the stars can't hurt you.
They keep watching.
I said nothing is going to hurt you.
How did you know where I was?
Well...
For one thing... your car.
I didn't tell anyone where I was going.
I was driving around,
and like they kept looking down
hardly I couldn't stand them any longer.
Elliott, ¿how did you know?
I'll tell you all about it.
First, let's have some coffee.
When did you last eat?
- Breakfast, I think.
- Then, a coffee and an omelette.
Oh, here's your handbag...
and your watch.
At least, I made it stop.
They kept right on.
- Could we have the top up?
- Of course.
Good evening.
- That's how you know.
- Would you sit down?
I'll order some coffee and an omelette.
Waiter!
- You needen't bother.
- Why not?
Omelette for mistress.
I think you have quite a bit of
explaining to do, Mr. Triton.
Yes, I know.
- To the police.
- If you like...
Elliott, you don't know
what you're talking about.
I know a confidence racket
when I see one.
Mr. Triton has been trying to help me.
By scaring you into suicide?
Jean, I've been away, but don't forget
I saw all from the start.
I don't blame you for being
suspicious, Mr. Carson.
The facts... well, they're incredible
if they are facts.
I don't know myself.
But I would like to convince you that I
have noticed I had hurted Miss Courtland,
And what you'd even doing to her?
He told me I was to die soon.
At night. Under the stars.
And you believed that?
How did you happen to go to the
switchyard tonight?
He sent me, naturally.
How did he know, when I didn't myself?
Well, I suppose hypnotism, suggestion,
some kind of a trick.
- I believe you are an oil geologist.
- I am.
Would... would you be willing to listen
with the open mind of a scientist
given so doing you might
help Miss Courtland?
Provided I'm free to go to
the police afterwards...
I've no strings to touch.
I'm listening.
I...
I suppose most people are looking back
and see the exact point where
lives were touched by destiny.
A new job, an unexpected inheritance,
a quick decision...
But I can't.
My destiny came upon me imperceptibly.
Like the first thin drops of rain are
noticed on a window pane.
It wasn't until the third, or fourth,
or... fifth drop
that I became aware of this
rain that was to engulf my life.
I remember the date:
August 3rd, 1928.
We were playing a one-night stand
in a small town in Louisiana: Glenberry.
Triton, the Mental Wizard
and Company.
Three 12 minutes shows a day,
sandwiched with
Toto and his Stumbling Dogs,
and a troupe of acrobats.
The act deserved better billing.
It was a phoney, of course, like
most mind reading acts, but
it was a first class phoney, if I do
say so myself.
Nobody knew how we did it.
It was the late show, 11:37.
Jenny was collecting the envelopes
with the usual familiar questions.
"Will I take a trip?" "Is my husband
unfaithful?" "Should I marry my boyfriend?"
I was winding up my spiel.
Yes, ladies and gentlemen.
All through the ages,
there have been men
with mysterious gifts,
men with inner eyes
which enable 'em to pierce the veils that
hide the tomorrows of ordinary mortals.
What is this gift?
Frankly, I don't know.
But the visions come,
sometimes cloudy, sometimes clear.
Strange visions.
- Have you the questions, Jenny?
- Yes, sir.
Would you check the envelopes, please?
You'll notice, ladies and gentlemen
that the envelopes are never touched
from the time that you sealed them
until they are placed inside the globe.
I won't touch them myself.
From where I stand, I should endeavour
to read the contents of each envelope
and identify the person who wrote it.
When I call the name,
would that person, please,
raise his or her hand?
This will enable me
to strengthen the contact.
And I'd like for everyone to refrain
from thinking
of anything that could
possibly disrupt me.
Try to keep your minds blank.
Now, if I might have a little
faint music.
I sense a name. A lady's name.
It's Bryant, no... Byers.
Spelt B-y-e-r-s.
She lives on Revere Street.
Number 1-4-7.
What... That's me!
You... gave your maiden name
inside the envelope which remains
unopened and untouched in the globe.
Your maiden name was... Grayson.
You are very pretty, Miss Grayson
and you came to the city from Virginia.
Also you asked a question.
You...
you asked...
"When will my mother-in-law go home?"
Well, not I am really prognosticate
in domestic affairs,
but I believe that I can say pretty
safe that she will leave very soon.
And... I'm concentrating
on another envelope.
Man's handwriting, formed, angular.
The name is Scottish...
...it's Angus...
MacDougal! Angus MacDougal,
Aberdeen, Scotland!
No, no. Don't tell me.
Just concentrate in silence.
You asked a question,
a business question.
Aye.
You own a store...
in some South Street.
I can't quite make it out.
I have it!
It's a woollen store!
And your question is about the store.
Will it prosper?
Well, I'll try to answer that
question, sir. I feel that...
There are disrupting thoughts connected
to someone here tonight.
Someone in a white hat with... daisies.
That's you.
Madam, go home! Your little boy
is in trouble, in danger.
You must go home at once!
I'm sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
Where was I?
Oh, yes... uh...
MacDougal, prosperity, sir.
You'll own another woollen store
in a neighbouring city.
and they both will go well.
And now, I... I have a question
of another intimate nature.
I... uh... all was through me
on the Scotch one.
He was a Scotch bud, all right,
but how's I'd know that
he had a woollen store?
I played "Mary had a little lamb".
Sure, sure, and I almost said
that he was a butcher.
I bet you think I am a
first class guesser.
That's what you were doing
with that woman?
What woman?
The one you scared the daylights out of.
- Oh, her...
- Why did you do that, Johnny?
I don't know. Sort of just popped into
my head. Ready, baby?
Already. Johnny, what made it pop
into your head?
Oh, how do I know?
Just came.
It won't hurt the dame to go.
Didn't want to be up so late anyway.
Now, look..
What we all need is a big steak dinner
with maybe a bottle of wine and some beer.
Now, what do you say?
- Who's gonna pick up the tab?
- What are you talking about?
- Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
- Good night.
Maybe Jenny could put the bite on him.
No, no, no. I draw the line
on eating with poodles.
What happened with the
fifty we got tonight?
We had a 20-buck for gas when hit town.
Bus fares to New Orleans, hotel bills,
breakfast, to mention a few items..
Well, sort of Jenny has been
elected cook again.
But I don't mind.
It's good practice.
- How much have we got left?
- 22,65.
Give me two bucks.
That's for the license, baby.
Our swing aroung the Middle West
will pay for the ring.
There are rings in dime stores, Johnny.
No, no, no.
My wife has gotta start off marriage in style.
Come on, let's be going.
Mr. Triton, there's a woman
here to see you.
We are so grateful!
He found some matches.
I can't imagine where.
And the bed was on fire.
- He was pretty badly burned.
- I'm sorry.
He's in the hospital
He will be all right, won't he?
I don't know.
That's what I told you, Court, those
things just pop into my head.
The first one that meant
anything was tonight.
Listen, after the show on Arkon,
I checked on the guy you warned
not to drive home.
Yeah?
He was in the hospital with
a broken collar bone.
His car toppled from a bridge.
You are as punch-drunk as I am.
Look...
Let's lay off this so called occult
stuff, and concentrate on the act.
Stand a little work.
You know? I've been thinking
Jenny ought to have a routine.
Maybe a song just as I start
to answer the questions.
Oh, that would be wonderful.
Yeah, they'd think that
you are tipping me off,
but when you finish, I'll go right on.
What do you think, Court?
I think that 10 bucks in Ready Cash
in the fifth of Green Meadows
will do us more good.
No...
No, not Ready Cash.
He'll fall, have to be destroyed.
Peer Gynt, by two lengths.
Johnny, did that just
pop in you head too?
No, no, no...
I was joking, just a gag.
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure. Look,
didn't I tell you to lay off?
- Now, what's the big idea?
- Oh, just curious.
I called the hospital.
The kid is gonna pull through.
We called too.
- I still think...
- Never mind.
- Did you pay the bill?
- No, not yet.
Well, then pay.
Let's grab some lunch. Jenny's hungry.
- I know that, but Johnny...
- What?
I don't think we have any money.
Do you think we have?
Haven't any money?
What happenned with the 20?
- Peer Gynt... at a nose.
- You've done it?
What do you know about that?
Every cent we got in the world.
Well, if that isn't the craziest most
harebrained stunt I've ever heard off.
You're supposed to be a businessman.
Couldn't you've list a better show?
I can make it up, Johnny.
Oh, sure, sure. In the meantime,
how do we get to New Orleans?
I can always pawn the earrings
my mother left me.
No, no no... I wouldn't let you.
Oh, mister, can I see you
a minute, please?
Would you mind checking it in fifties?
- Checking what?
- The 200 bucks he just won.
Rather can you pick horses!
Peer Gynt, 10 to 1. What have you got,
second sight or something?
Seems odd my being frightened
over the bet on a horse race
when I had all these other things
to be frightened about.
I think it was because it had
touched me this time.
Me and the two people I care most about.
Look, this is interesting, but what
has it got to do with Jean?
The piano player was
Whitney Courtland, Jean's father.
- And Jenny was...
- My mother.
- You were engaged to Jean's mother?
- I loved her very much.
- And you didn't know this?
- Dad told me some of it.
Yes, but not everything because
he didn't know everything.
- Would you prefer I stop?
- No, please, don't.
And on the next month, during our
swing around the West,
half a dozen of the hunches
came through.
Another horse race,
a flyer on wheats,
quick stock deals.
Courtland handled the money.
I never touched it.
I was becoming more
frightened every day.
And I began to have a crazy feeling that
I was making the things come true,
like a voodoo sorcerer who kills people
by sticking pins in the doll.
I thought of the man with the broken
collar bone, the boy with the matches...
Would anything have happened to them
if I had kept quiet?
And then one day,
it was a rainy afternoon in Wichita,
as I was leaving the theater
for the hotel,
the answer came.
I've been haggling the
house electrician.
I wasn't quite satisfied with the
way he worked the lights to the act
and I was still wondering if he
understood about the baby spot.
- Paper?
- Yes, sure.
Here.
Mr. Triton, I've seen your picture
on the poster.
Yeah.
Can I ask you something?
Yes, sure, but come in here,
out of the rain.
What do you wanna know?
How is the Saint Louis Cards gonna
make out this year?
Oh, they're gonna be right up on top,
provided their pitching holds up.
That's what I say.
Can't you tell me anything else?
- That's the best I can do.
- Oh, thanks anyway.
- Hey, son.
- Yes, sir.
Be careful today.
Don't cross.
Here.
Blow yourself with some tickets
for the show tonight.
Gee! Thanks Mr. Triton.
I go call my mom.
It had come again.
A hunch or vision or... whatever it was.
This time I hadn't spoken.
I kept it to myself.
- Telephone in there, mister?
- Yes, sure. What happened?
Newsboy. Just been run over.
I'm afraid he's done for.
Johnny, what on earth
have you been doing?
Walking.
In this weather!
Why didn't you take a cab?
I wanted to walk.
And catch a dreadful cold, I suppose.
Oh, silly, give me a kiss.
What you need is a nice hot cup of tea,
a hot bath and change your clothes.
You'll be fine.
- Why were you walking, Johnny?
- I don't know.
- Something is bothering you, isn't it?
- Yeah, I suppose so.
You wanna tell me about it?
It's some kind of mix-up.
Something just happened.
Johnny...
Look at this. Five grand on the cotton deal
and the Western Carbide is up to 70.
We are sitting on top of the world
and the sky's the limit.
I got a new deal, a fellow I met
in the lobby, an oil man.
He has an option in a big tract downside
Tulsa: Comanche Hills is called.
He's willing to sell a half interest.
What do you think?
Can you pull out another one of
those hunches, Johnny?
Comanche Hills, Oklahoma.
We are all washed up of hunches, Court.
- Washed up! What do you mean washed up?
- Just what I said.
Johnny, 23.000 in four weeks,
if we gonna start it.
- I know, I know.
- But why? What's got into you?
Well, I don't suppose I can explain,
it's something I feel.
Bad luck for all us because...
well, because we are fooling around
with something that we oughtn't be.
I'm not afraid.
Why you should be if you aren't
the one who was doing it.
Well, I mean on it and so is Jenny.
Have you thought about her?
Look Johnny, you wanna get married. You
want a home, money in the Bank security,
something you'll never get out
of the show business.
Court, I love Jenny
and I like you.
We've been through a lot.
Never lied, cheated or chiseled.
All has been was the best
for the three of us.
No matter how it sounds,
I'm still thinking that way.
I know what's the matter with you.
You've got the rainy day blues.
Talk to him, Jenny.
I think Johnny is right. I haven't
had a good feeling about this either.
It's scary.
What's scary about making money?
I don't want money.
I just want Johnny.
Hello.
Yes.
Keep your shirt on.
We'll be right over.
Curtain in 20 minutes.
I had no way of knowing
it was my final curtain.
I am concentrating on a
particular envelope.
Young lady's handwriting.
She's shy; she's only written
her first name.
- It's Agnes. Agnes, where art thou?
- Agnes, he's speaking to you.
- Don't be afraid to speak up.
- Here I am, Mr. Triton.
Oh, thank you.
Was I right?
Yes, sir.
Oh, that's splendid.
And now...
The young lady has a problem.
She asks: "Should I marry my
boyfriend or should I get a job?"
I... rarely meddle in affairs
of the heart, but
in this case I should act to show
the young lady that
when the time comes...
when the time comes that she's
really in love,
there will be no questions
to which course to follow.
But until that time...
I am sorry, ladies and gentlemen, but
that's all for the present.
Ring down the curtain.
Ring down the curtain, I tell you!
Ring it down!
Ring down the curtain!
Everything is all right, darling. Court
talked to the manager. He understands.
Why shouldn't he?
Could happen to anybody.
I just felt dizzy.
Couldn't think.
Obviously caught cold
being out on the rain all the afternoon.
Johnny...
Where is Court?
He's on his way up.
It was something you saw, wasn't it?
No, it wasn't that this time.
- Something you saw about me?
- Oh, don't be silly.
I don't mind if you don't wanna tell me,
just if it doesn't make any difference
about our loving each other.
For the heaven's sake, Jenny.
I told you it wasn't anything.
My mind went blank.
I couldn't think, that was all.
- Well, how are you feeling?
- Fine.
That's good. I have an idea
to be completely cured.
A little relaxation at the
Pairie Room downstairs.
Dancing, a little supper...
That would be fun, wouldn't Johnny?
Yeah, I'm all for it.
You deserve a break.
You haven't danced in months.
Have a good time.
- But you're coming too?
- Yes, I'll  joint you in a minute.
Now you order
the best supper in the place
and be sure you get
the best table of the joint.
That's prosperous.
And slip the orchestra something
so they play good
when I charleston through the roof.
- I'll save the first dance for you.
- The first and the last.
Say, Johnny, I was talking to
that man again, what do you think?
Comanche Hills in Oklahoma.
It's one of the biggest oil fields
in the country, Court.
Brother!
We'll see downstairs, Johnny.
Come on, Jenny.
- Bye bye, darling.
- Bye bye.
Somebody once wrote a poem,
something about each man killing
the things he loves.
They might have been writing about me.
What I've seen looking at
Jenny on the stage was her death,
a death through me,
if I had remained with her.
If I stayed, will be married,
it would be a child.
The child would live,
but Jenny wouldn't.
Maybe it was a wrong decision,
I don't even know now.
Jenny would be hurt, of course,
bewildered, but
Whitney Court would stand by.
I knew to save my sanity I had to go.
I took the first train out.
Happing to be westward.
And as I sat on the dusty chaircar,
I suddenly realized it wasn't just
Court and Jenny I had to leave.
It was everybody.
I became a sort of a reverse zombie.
I was living in a world already dead,
and I alone knowing it.
So when the train reached Arizona,
I got off.
I found a deserted gold mining camp.
Lived there for five years.
- What happened to Jenny?
- She died when I was born.
Yeah, I read about it in Variety,
a week after it happened.
I failed!
I wanted to write Court and
tell him how sorry I was, but
I realized that it would
only make more trouble.
I found a sort of peace
on the desert,
but I was lonely.
And then, towards the end of the fifth
year, I picked up a California newspaper
and I read that Whitney Courtland,
the oil man,
was establishing his
headquarters in Los Angeles.
I estabished the headquarters there too,
but on a far less pretentious
neigborhood.
I was drawn by a strange sort
of compassion onto me,
being the only friend I had on earth.
It was an odd part of the city,
but I liked it.
It was a strictly
"no-questions asked" area;
people minding their own business
and letting you mind yours.
In after 15 years my social
conversation
didn't exceed 25 words a day.
Mi work, well it was solitary too.
Parlor magic, disappearing coins,
marked cards.
false bottom water glasses,
things I've learned
to make on my bodeful days,
all sold by mail.
It was a lonely life,
but it was pleasant to be
near Court and his daughter.
I read about them on the papers.
In my room where I ate,
slept and worked,
I could go to the window and
see the skyscraper he built,
the Comanche Building.
Only once in all that time that
I risked fate by going nearhand of you.
It was three months ago.
It was the night of your debut
at the Mayfield Hotel.
I read about it in the papers.
One thousand guests,
two orchestras in the grand ballroom.
orchids brought all the way
from South America.
I watched you leave the limousine
and walk towards the doors
holding tight to Court's arm.
And, for a moment, it was almost
as though the 20 years never been.
as if there was Court and Jenny
going into the hotel.
Then, just as you disappeared,
something happened.
I had a flitting glimpse of a wreckage,
a wreckage of an airplane.
It was a faint impression, blurred, hazy,
like a double exposed negative.
I forgot about it entirely,
forgot about until one night as
I was working lately,
picture jumped into focus.
Now the 11:55 news, brought to you
by your Comanche Oil Reporter.
New York. Flying his
converted Army bomber,
Whitney Courtland, multimillonaire
president of Comanche Oil,
took off from La Guardia field
early today
in an attempt to smash the
East-West transcontinental speed record.
He and his pilot, Captain Martinson,
former Army ace,
expect to reach Los Angeles
in time for breakfast,
if the favorable weather...
It was after midnight when
I reached your house.
I suppose I was an odd looking figure.
At least, the butler thought so.
I was afraid you wouldn't see me,
so when he left to find you,
I followed him.
Your friends were dancing,
I looked for you but,
not finding you there,
I went downstairs
to the lower terrace.
It was a lazy, warm, summer night that
seemed as remote from tragedy
as anything on earth.
I told him to wait outside.
This is important. Miss Courtland,
I am an old friend of your father's.
and I have an urgent message for him.
I'm sorry, he's not here.
Yes, I know, but I've to
switch him at once.
I'm afraid that's impossible.
He's flying from New York.
- Non stop?
- One stop in Wichita for fuel.
Well, then, please call there. Leave a
message for him to halt the fly.
Halt the flight!
He'll laugh at me.
Not if you say the message
comes from John Triton.
John Triton? But dad told me
John Triton was dead.
No, he's not dead.
- Who is John Triton?
- He was dad's best friend.
I'd avise you to call there.
Why should Mr. Courtland
stop his flight?
Because if he doesn't,
the plane will crash!
And... just how do you know that?
Does it matter?
Is it too late to reach him?
- No, I suppose not.
- Well, then, please call.
What do you think, Elliott?
I think it's quite a nonsense.
but, what would you lose
except three dollars on the phone bill?
All right.
Hello. I'd like the municipal airport
of Wichita, Kansas, please.
Do you make a practice of going
around predicting airplane crashes?
No, I don't.
- Maybe just the planes of very rich men?
- No, not even those.
Then, what is it? A bet that
he won't break the record?
The night manager, please.
Hello, this is Whitney
Courtland's daughter.
I'd like a message delivered to
my father when he lands.
Oh, yes...
No, no that's all right.
Good bye.
- He's already taken off.
- Good! That means he's got the record.
Or smashed the plane.
Don't be silly. Our friend here
is just a harmless crank.
Oh, he's gone.
You see?
He got while the getting was good.
Elliott, I remember something
dad said about him,
something about his having visions.
I get them too.
And I'll tell you what I see:
a shakedown that didn't come off.
You were impressed enough
to let me call.
Impressed?
Just wanted to see how far he'd go.
I think we'll have a good laugh
when your father come.
That night I couldn't sleep.
Thoughts wheeled around my head
like pinwheels.
Again the strange feeling that I was
responsible for the things I saw
came to me.
I wondered if I shouldn't remain quiet.
And then, I remembered the newsboy.
In the morning, it was announced over
the radio that the plane was missing.
There it was again, after 20 years.
I made up my mind to leave
before you found me
to bury myself completely this time.
I recall I was packing the same
battered suitcase
when you knocked on the door.
And you, Miss Courtland, asked me if I
knew what had happened to your father.
I couldn't tell you. All I've
seen was the wrecked plane.
I've thinking a lot
about you, Mr. Triton.
Somebody telephoned or
wired you about the plane.
- I assure you they didn't.
- Then, what did happen?
I... had a forewarning, an impression of
the crash about three months ago.
Three months ago!
How much did you see?
Nothing too clear, just an
impression of the crash, that's all.
Look, if you saw all this three months
ago, why did you wait...?
Quiet, please.
Where was the plane?
It seemed to be somewhere
on the mountains.
Your pal didn't send you very much
information, did he?
No. There's no one else
connected with it.
What's the matter?
- You have a maid, a thin dark girl.
- Yes, Edna.
Well, get rid of her before your
brooch, your sapphire brooch...
Doesn't matter.
It won't make any difference.
Look, fellow, I think it's
about time somebody...
We interrupt this program to bring
you a special news bulletin.
Wreckage of the Comanche Angel,
converted bomber
in which Whitney Courtland
and his pilot, Captain Martinson,
were attempting to smash
the East-West record,
was discovered early today by
forest rangers in Gallup, New Mexico.
Both occupants of the plane are dead.
Jean!
For almost a week I hardly left my room.
I busied myself, I tried not to think
of the decision I had to make.
It had to be some way to prevent
the tragedy that I've seen.
My running away, my not speaking
haven't saved Jenny.
Now I wandered if I should try
the other course: challenge fate.
And then, the next morning you
came back to see me.
- May I speak to you for a moment?
- Yes, of course.
As a matter of fact, I was just
touring for your house.
Then, I suppose you heard.
What?
About my sapphire brooch.
It's disappeared and
so has my maid, Edna,
just as you said they would.
I'm sorry, but I imagine
the brooch was insured.
I haven't bothered to find out.
You see, I remembered you said
that it wouldn't make any difference.
You meant I was going to die.,
didn't you?
That's what I thought.
How soon is it going to be?
Quite soon.
Six months?
One month?
Sooner than that.
How soon... and where?
Within a few days...
before the end of the week...
at night... under the stars.
Perhaps it was a mistake...
my telling her.
Not if you were trying to help her.
Oh, I was... and  I am. I do want
to help. I want to help myself.
It isn't easy to live with something
like this,
something that has turned me into
a half-crazy recluse...
robbed me of twenty years.
I've tried to understand it. I've read books
on the occult, on divination, on sorcery,
on abnormal psychology...
but they ain't help.
That's why I told you the story.
Because I thought that you,
with your training,
could help to explain
some of these things
and together perhaps we could do
something to avert what I'm seeing.
- Do what?
- I don't know.
If... if I could only have seen
something beyond the big picture
of her lying under the stars,
if I could've seen the place,
identify it,
then we could keep her
of never going there.
In the meantime, Jean, you need some
rest. You'll be home in bed right now.
You'll help?
Frankly, I am still pretty confused, but
of course, I'll do everything I can.
- You are not coming with us?
- No, you don't need me.
You see it's day again.
The stars are gone.
Elliott, thank you for being
so nice on the way home.
About what?
About not questioning me,
not being angry.
I could never be angry with you.
He certainly had many worries.
My plane landed, I tried the house
but you weren't here.
I went to his place.
He seemed very excited.
He said you were in trouble.
He knew exactly where your car was.
We got there, he sent me all alone, told
me to bring you back to the restaurant.
He's probably seen you from his
window, had you followed or something.
- But he didn't have time.
- I'm not too sure about that.
There certainly wasn't in dad's case.
He warned us some few minutes after
the plane took off from Wichita.
Yeah, that's the angle
I couldn't figure.
But now you believe
You told me you did.
I told I might help and that's all.
Are you ready to get some sleep?
Good night.
I mean good morning.
See you later.
Sort of early, aren't you, Preston?
We were wondering about Miss Courtland.
Operator, give me the police
headquarters, please.
Nobody told us we have
to get a two-license.
We give a man what he asks:
25 dollars. The question is...
Mr. Weston has been
calling you all this time.
I've not asked we got
to have two licenses.
...were concealed under the floor,
...six were uncovered
along with a faro table
and two birdcage games.
Yes, Corporation papers.
Triton Novelty Company.
I've given him the name twice, now.
Come in.
You're bad. We'll ask
for a blanket injunction
as long as the D. A. give us
the green light.
Oh, maybe in the middle
of the week. Good bye.
Courtland report, Mr. Weston.
- Oh, fine, where's Shawn?
- He's on his way up.
Good.
"Mind reading, magic tricks by mail,
watching by clairvoyance,
thefts predicted,
airplane crashed foreseen,
girls frightened to the point of
suicide by autosuggestion..."
Well, it comes to quite a bizarre
little bundle, Mr. Carson.
Yes, sir, I know it does, but...
This morning, when the police
transferred your call,
it sounded like one of the 156 we
get from crackpots every day.
I wouldn't have bother about it.
I would've forgotten it,
except if Miss Courtland hasn't to be
an ideal target for a confidence game.
She's young, she's wealthy,
she's unprotected.
Come in.
Oh, here we are.
Mr. Carson, meet Lieutenant
Shawn of the City Homicide Bureau.
How do you do, Lieutenant?
It was Mr. Carson who called our
attention to the Courtland matter.
Have you read the statement, Lieutenant?
I couldn't make head or tail of it.
I see you are not a follower
of the occult.
Well, I don't mind. And I might as well
tell you right now, Mr. Carson,
we've been pretty skeptical
about this story of yours.
And about you.
I didn't expect you to believe anything.
I don't myself.
Oddly enough,
there's a substantial element of fact
in what you told us.
A match?
See, there was a man, back in the 20's
who built himslef as Triton,
the Mental Wizard.
Whitney Courtland was a
member of his act.
and the Courtland fortune comes from
the Comanche Hills oild field.
On August 4th, 1928 the fifth race
at Green Meadows
was won by a horse named Peer Gynt.
Only he got gypped.
Track odds were 12 to 1.
- Then he was telling the truth.
- To a certain degree.
Horse race results ain't hard to find.
What the Lieutenant means
is that the basic facts
are probably straight, I agree.
but facts are easily distorted
to serve a purpose.
For instance, Miss Courtland being
in the railroad yards
and his knowing about this
is supposed to be
proof for the validity of his visions?
Well, you offered the solution
to that yourself.
Back porch.
It's possible to see the railyway yards
from the back porch
and with a good eye to
spot a parked convertible.
And this prediction about Edna, the
maid, vanishing with the sapphire brooch
was all very baffling until Shawn
here made a discovery.
She used to live on Bunker Hill,
a couple of blocks from Triton.
It's pretty easy to be
a prophet, Mr. Carson,
with a confederate to help him along.
It's still on item, Mr. Weston,
how could he have known
about the plane crash?
Tell him.
We were talking to the police
of New Mexico.
The plane was wrecked in the mountains
but it had not hit a pick, it fell.
- On account it threw a propeller.
- That's not impossible.
No, no if somebody worked
in the shaft with a file.
Which according to the investigators,
it's exactly what happened.
- Then, it's murder!
- It ain't table tennis.
You know?
I'm different from most cops.
Most cops feet hurt, but with me
it's my back.
- Good evening, Lieutenant.
- Hello, Gowan. Everything set?
Half a dozen men around the place
and a couple inside.
It would take a miracle get through.
Maybe it's gonna happen.
You and Bertelli come along.
Wouldn't be simpler to arrest Triton?
For what? Warning people
about airplane crashes?
Good evening, Mr. Carson.
What's this? The Magic Guy?
I just happen to be looking
out of the window, sir.
- No law against that, I guess.
- That's right, Lieutenant.
Wouldn't the evidence of the propeller
shaft be enough to hold him?
Huh-uh, on account that he was in L. A.
Stick around here. I might need you.
- But he knew about it.
- Yes, kind of it certainly.
What's this? A convention?
Some of Mr. Courtland's
business associates.
Elliot!
Excuse me, please.
- Jean, this is Lieutenant Shawn.
- Elliott told me about you on the phone.
Hope my men haven't upset
you, Miss Courtland.
No, they've been very polite
and conforting. Please come in.
These gentlemen with my dad were in
the East completing an oil merger.
Lieutenant Shawn, Mr. Gilman,
President of Mid-Tide Oil.
How are you. Lieutenant?
Mr. Myers, attorney for the estate,
and Peter Vinson, dad's secretary.
How do you do, Lieutenant?
Hello, Carson, how is the
celebrated geologist?
Fine.
This folks are living here?
Why, yes, they've going over
dad's papers.
Some of the merger details were lost.
- The estate needs settling too.
- You know about this psychic business?
Yes, Miss Courtland told us something
about it and we would like to help.
However, if you'd rather, we'll leave.
- I wouldn't think of it.
- Nonsensical business anyway.
Maybe... maybe not.
Don't think you staying will make
much difference.
provided you are willing to cooperate.
Oh, you can count on us, Lieutenant.
Jean knows the way I feel.
- What do you plan to do, Lieutenant?
- Hang around until the end of the week.
- Two more days.
- Don't you worry, miss.
No, I won't. Not with all of you here,
and Mr. Triton too.
- You got him in the house?
- Yes, Lieutenant, I am here.
How do you like that?
Your attitude is natural enough.
I suppose you've been breaking down
my story, finding possible explanations.
We ran on a couple.
Yes, but there are some things
that are beyond explanation;
otherwise, I would be under arrest.
Not a bad idea.
I asked him to come, Lieutenant,
to be with me.
- Yes, you see I think I may be of help.
- Not in my book, you can't.
I'm hoping, perhaps if I... I may see
things more detailed, it could happen.
Oh, no, Mr. Triton, we are adults.
You can't sell us on visions.
Let him speak his piece.
Mr. Carson and I have
already discussed it.
If I see things clearly, it may
be possible to take precautions
Would not be my job?
Yes, of course, that's why I was
pleased when Mr. Carson called you in.
But your powers are limited.
Yeah, I never had much luck
with tea leaves.
Which brings us to a point I'm
very curious about.
How do you account for these...
alleged visions, Mr. Triton?
- I... I doubt that I can explain it.
- I wouldn't mind hear if you try.
Yeah, I... I thought we'd a great
deal on prevision
and somewhere I've come across an
illustration that very nearly covers it.
Suppose you are on a train.
You look out the window
and you see a white farmhouse.
In a minute discard them, you're
watching cattle in a field.
And just ahead it, although
you can't see it yet,
there's a clump of maple trees.
Past, present and future.
But to the man on top of
the train, they're all one.
At one glance he can see
farmhouse, cattle and trees.
Well...
Occasionally, I am like that man
on top of the train,
even though I may be sitting inside it.
How do you get on on top
if you're sitting inside?
You've been there.
All of you. You had experiences.
Telegrams that you knew the contents
are before you open them.
Places that seem familiar, but you
never have been in there before.
And under the emotional
stress of tragedy,
you notice how everything becomes
distorted and unreal
as the mind tries to escape into time.
In dreams it escapes too.
Not always in the fantasy.
- Sometimes the dreams come true.
- Your visions always do.
Yes, they always had in the past.
And out of my asking, I've
no control over them.
They come whe they come.
Where is his room?
In the tower, over the terrace.
He wanted to be away from everyone.
It's 10 o'clock, and according to your
theory, Miss Courtland is in danger
only at night, when the stars are out.
All right, I'll make a deal.
You can stay provided you
stick in you room until daylight.
- Would you like me to go now?
- Yes, I would.
Mr. Triton, you don't have to...
It's all right. I prefer it.
I feel uneasy with people
after 20 years.
Easy, pitching boys, he got a loft
up there. See that he don't leave.
You sure you wanna go into the garden?
I always do when I am upset.
It's a sort of hideaway from trouble.
Besides this has to be,
there's nothing we can do about it.
Jean, it's not inevitable,
it's not even likely.
- He saw it.
- He said he saw it.
I hate this... this terrible resignation,
just as you were half-dead already.
You're like an automaton playing a part.
- An automaton locked down for 48 hours.
- That's exactly what I'm talking about.
Elliot!
- Just checking out, folks.
- That's right.
This is Miss Courtland. I guess it's
all right for her to be down here.
Excuse me.
Come on, Joe.
I wish I could tell what
the police has found out.
- What can't you?
- I promised. They think that...
- Well, they think you'd go to Triton.
- I would.
I can tell you this much
even you tell Triton.
There's a logical and very unpleasant
explanation for the whole business.
For the newsboy?
For my mother?
He has taken a group of half-truths
and wovened them into an overall lie.
You're forgetting one thing.
Dad's told me stories about him.
I've been remembering.
I remember Comanche Hills
and how dad once said that the field
really belonged to Mr. Triton.
Are you sure you remember it? Or is it
something Triton remembered for you?
At least, give me credit for that.
Hey there!
Don't think I'm going along with
this fortune-telling yarn,
but I'd look pretty silly and so will
both of you if anything happened
with all the stars up there.
Why don't you go to bed like him
as the rest of them have?
The windows are all locked,
Miss Courtland.
Thank you.
Would you like me to sleep
in your dressing room?
No, I don't think so.
I'm not afraid.
At least I don't think I am.
You go to bed and get
a good night sleep.
Yes, Miss Courtland.
- All right if I come in?
- Sure, as long as he don't come out.
Is what they think?
Is he kind of strange?
It's pretty close.
Come in.
- I was hoping you'd come Mr. Carson.
- Why?
A moment ago the veil lifted again.
I saw many things,
about Jean, about myself,
strange and obscure things
that I don't understand.
Perhaps as a scientist
you can help to interpret...
Scientists don't believe in visions
and I don't wanna hear about them.
Wouldn't it be sensible even
doubting me to... keep an open mind?
You'd never forgive yourself
if I was right and you haven't helped.
What did you see?
It was different this time.
A series of cloudy flashes,
and then the central vision.
I made notes to make sure
I remember the order.
I saw a flower crushed under a heel,
a sudden hard wind
that shook the windows,
a vase shattered down the floor.
And I heard a voice saying:
"There's no danger now".
And then I saw her again lying
under the stars and... by her
something I don't understand at all,
something that looked
like the feet of a lion.
Oh, I know it sounds ridiculous
but I saw them clearly:
big front paws with curved talons
almost touching her head.
- It doesn't make much sense.
- Yes, I know.
Did you say you saw something
about yourself too?
Yes, I saw...
No... uh... it's not important.
Did you see when the moment was?
Tomorrow night,
as the clock strikes eleven.
- I've been talking with him.
- Yeah, I heard it.
He's convincing.
I went up there to break him down,
and instead he rather shook me.
More visions?
A whole series of them, only one setting
with time. Tomorrow night at eleven.
Well, fine. Now we can all go to bed.
What else did he have?
A chain of small events leading up
to the moment.
The first was a flower,
crushed under somebody's foot.
Then, by Jean's head he saw
the feet of a lion.
The feet of a what?
- Jean, are you all right?
- Are you all right, Miss Courtland?
What happened?
I don't know. Something over my face.
I couldn't breathe.
You had a nightmare.
No, I don't think so.
I've never had one before.
Poor child!
What happened to her?
Do you need any help?
- Jean...
- Get some water.
What is it doing here?
It belongs on the daybed.
Someone or something's been here,
but nothing human could've been;
the windows were locked.
I locked them myself.
Maybe so.
But they didn't stay that way.
Not in that dressing room.
- Where are you going?
- Downstairs. There's something wrong.
Yeah, but we've got orders
to keep you up here.
- Hold, it'll be a minute.
- One more step and I'll wing you.
We are not kidding.
Don't forget I warned you.
First time in 20 years.
Yeah, it's him.
I sensed you were in
some kind of trouble.
I said that in my eye
you are the trouble.
What was going on out there?
How did you get in here?
I walked.
So wanna you don't tell me you flew.
It'd be beyond a purpose...
- What's shooting about? You all right?
- Take it easy. Who is the one shooting?
- You tell him.
- Me.
- At what?
- Kind of the ground.
At the ground?
Well, first at him, but
my gun wouldn't fire.
Then it did, only he was gone.
He jinxed it.
You see, Lieutenant this isn't my time.
Well it isn't now.
That's why nothing can touch me.
That's just dandy. I can hardly
wait to tell the D. A.
we can't touch you because
it isn't your time.
You can trick a couple
of dumb detectives
and hand us a line about crushed
flowers, broken vases and lions feet.
You can try on throw us off guard by
claiming there's no danger
until tomorrow night and you can
shinny down from your window
and do your best to knock off
Miss Courtland.
But we can't touch him.
It isn't your time. Show him.
You are making a serious mistake.
My fate is linked to Miss Courtland's.
Because of that, I'm the only one
who might save her.
Your fate is linked to a pair a
handcuffs. Now ride him downtown.
It's just a waste of time. I'll be back
tomorrow night before eleven.
Throw the book at him.
I've had agree with you if he wasn't
so normal otherwise.
I got a couple of psychologists
in the University
coming in to see him this evening.
About ten o'clock.
I'll keep in touch with you.
One hour left to go.
Oh, it's you Mr. Myers. I don't know
how I'm gonna live through this.
I'm scared half to death already.
And that window!
The police have been up to me all day.
Do you think it could've been him
somehow from the outside?
There's a simple explanation.
You left the window open.
I could have, of course, but I can't
believe that I...
- Where is the Lieutenant?
- I don't know.
- He told us to be here at ten.
- That's to keep us from doing any work.
You don't think this is
important, Mr. Myers?
I think it's all poppycock.
Especially with our Nostradamus in jail.
Intead of searching for a
packet of stock options
that will be worthless in 36 hours,
we fiddle-faddle with a lot
of ghost stories.
You're sure you can't remember where
your father put the papers?
No, I've been trying to,
but with all this...
How you expect the poor child
remember anything?
- What about your father's secretary?
- No, Peter doesn't know either.
- Doesn't know what?
- They're looking for some papers.
Options necessary for
the Mid-Tide merger.
I suggest we forget
business for... 58 minutes
and concentrate on the
so-called prophecy.
Isn't it obvious he's missed the boat
with his chain of events?
A flower crushed under a foot,
a sudden wind, a vase shattered,
a voice saying "There's no danger now".
And it's fresh out of lions too.
We got rid of every piece of junk
in the house with a lion on it:
bookends, lamps, andirons, even the
stone ones which are at the entrance.
Where have you been?
Checking the defenses. I must say it's
a very good show; policemen everywhere.
Not a prowler in sight.
And there ain't gonna be. At half
past ten we've all got places to be.
And we're gonna stay in until eleven.
And then, if nothing happens, I'll go
down to my hideaway in the garden.
What for?
To show the stars they were wrong.
You know, Lieutenant?
I've been thinking.
Since you're operating on the
assumption Mr. Triton could be right,
wouldn't it be a good idea
to remove the flowers,
eliminate the possibility of one
being crushed underfoot?
- Plain nonsense!
- Can't do no harm.
Gowan...
- I'll take them.
- I'll handle this, sister.
Ah, no.
Oh, my God!
Hold it!
Don't anybody move!
Not a one step down.
Take them out and dump that.
For a minute, I almost believed
you gave your real feeling of...
- What's that?
- What?
Under your foot.
Well...
High beguesser our Mr. Triton.
Eight solid hours reading
literature on the subject,
dust covered volumes on soothsaying,
vaticination, augury, prophecy,
and I'm more confused than
when I started.
Walters ought to be able to help you.
Right up his alley.
Not completely.
We have made extrasensory
tests at the University.
the usual ones: selecting cards
from a concealed deck,
And rolling dice...
With some rather astonishing
variations among our control.
But it would take weeks
to examine this man.
First, we'd have to make sure there was
absolutely no chance of trickery,
then, well, the matematical computations
for each single test are staggering.
And generally controversial.
Well, at least, you can give me
an off-the-record opinion
as to whether he's a faker or a madman.
We can talk to him.
- Is Triton here yet?
- Yes, sir.
- Send him in.
I can tell you this: you will find
him about as convincing a customer as...
Mr. Triton, these two gentlemen
are from the University.
- How do you do?
Yes, I have read some of Profesor
Walters' books about on parapsychology.
I found your monograph on mental
telepathy and intuition
particularly interesting, sir.
Oh, I'm flattered.
Mr. Triton, I've asked these
gentlemen to...
To determine whether I'm a faker
or a madman.
And you, sir, have been explaining the
tests of an extrasensorial nature
are lengthy and difficult due to the
mathematical computations
and the possibilities of trickery.
- Send Wilson in here.
- Yes, sir.
Wilson, how long have you been
standing out there?
- Just stepped out of the elevator.
- That's all. Thank you.
Neat piece of deduction. Of course, he
knew we were talking about testing him
and we'd probably bring up
the obvious objections,
but an excellent parlor magic.
I give you my word, gentlemen,
this is not parlor magic.
Yes, I have endorsed myself in a bit
of theatrics but for a purpose:
I desperately need your help to persuade
Mr. Weston to set me free.
As you know, Miss Courtland's life
hangs in the balance.
If I'm allowed to go to the house
to be near,
there is a possibility that I might use
this power of mine to save her.
Very interesting.
And if he goes to the house and
the girl lives, as she will,
he can maintain that he was responsible
and ask for a substantial reward.
No.
No, I'd ask for no rewards, sir.
In the first place,
I haven't long to live.
Oh, I'm not dealing for some pity.
I don't care what happens.
This gift, which I never asked for
and I don't understand,
has brought me only unhappiness!
Over a period of 20 years various times
I've forced tragic occurrences.
And no matter what I did, I couldn't
prevent them coming true.
I thought perhaps you could tell me
something about it.
Why was this gift given to me?
And why was this other power withheld?
This power to turn evil into good.
You gotta let me go. This is
my only chance, my last one.
There is a possibility that this time
I may disrupt this chain of events
that Mr. Weston has told you about.
Defy fate and
save Miss Courtland!
He's put up a good show.
Could you realize we must have
more concrete evidence
before recommendation for release?
Well I hope I've given you enough.
A kind of hallucination, probably not
unknown to people in his line of work.
El síndrome de la bola de cristal.
It apparently passes on some tragic
occurrance, like Mr. Courtland's death,
convinces himself that he foresaw it.
From there, it's only a step
for him to believe that...
Mr. Weston!
You have on your desk some papers
relating to a man convicted
of murder, Amos Block.
You have very good eyes.
He's to be moved to
San Quentin tomorrow.
He'll never make the trip.
I see him in his cell...
suicide.
That's one you can check.
Quinn? Weston.
How's Block getting along?
Oh, you did? Fine.
Oh, just checking up.
Good night.
Well, your man is in a cell all right,
playing solitaire.
When I turned on the radio, someone
was talking about a lion
escaping from the zoo.
I heard it in the 9 o'clock broadcast,
a warning about something,
but I'm not sure.
Well, folks, here's the setup.
Me and Mr. Carson are gonna stick
in here with Miss Courtland.
Gowan will stay on the terrace.
Bertelli, you're to patrol the house,
and the rest of you will go
to your rooms.
Lieutenant, I thought
we were going to be permitted
to assist in guarding Miss Courtland.
Now, what?
- Picked two trying to sneak out, Lieut.
- Yeah?
- What's the big idea?
- We are leaving.
When a person is fated,
others go with him.
- That's ridiculous!
- Ridiculous?
How about Mr. Courtland's pilot?
He got it.
- Let them go, Lieutenant.
- All right.
Ride them downtown.
Turn them loose after eleven.
- No, wait a minute, you can't...
- You want to leave, didn't you?
- I'm sorry, Miss Courtland.
- Never mind, sister.
Come on, let's go.
Now, suppose we all get moving.
I would like to add
my protest to Gilman's.
Both of us, and Peter too, are
perfectly capable of assisting
and we resent being
shot away like children.
Well, Mr. Myers, you got a point.
But, you see, this ain't exactly
like you think it is.
It ain't just a wholesale ghost hunt.
We've got reasons to believe
that somebody tampered with
Mr. Courtland's plane.
- Then, it wasn't an accident?
- Huh-uh.
And we think maybe that same somebody
tried to Miss Courtland last night,
it it was a try.
Would he be fool enough to come tonight?
Oh, it might, at 11:00, hoping everybody
would think it was a supernatural deal.
Just, where does Triton fit in?
He's the smoke screen in all this stuff
about lions and crushed flowers,
and broken vases. He's so much more
lucky. Window dressing to hide...
- Hey, listen.
-...keep doors and windows locked.
Warning to residents of Westwood Village.
Stay inside your houses.
Keep doors and windows locked.
The lion which escaped
from an overturned van
at Wilshire and Sepulveda early
this evening is still at large.
I repeat for the third time: Warning
to residents of Westwood Village.
- Stay inside your houses. Keep doors...
- Turn the radio off!
That's what I thought I heard
at 9 o'clock, but I wasn't sure.
Never mind. Get out of here. All of you,
except you and Miss Courtland.
Go out to your rooms.
- Hey, Bertelli!
- Yes, Lieutenant.
Gotta have a dozen riot guns on the
squad cars and pass them around.
Right.
Tell everybody to keep
their eyes peeled.
Jean...
- I'm all right.
- Sure you are.
It's just one thing...
Is it true what he said about the plane?
I'm afraid so. They found file marks
in the propeller shaft.
- I don't think Mr. Triton knew about it.
- I think he must have.
Elliott, I believe in him, I wish...
I wish he were here now.
I'm afraid that's impossible.
Now we got the big game hunters
out on safari.
I got everything as tight as a drum.
If anything happens around here tonight
my name ain't Shawn.
Let us check the time.
Twenty one minutes, if that's right.
Got a watch?
I make it ten thirty six and a half.
My old turnip is usually pretty close.
Let's make sure.
At the sound, the time
will be ten-thirty-nine and a half.
Ten thirty nine and a half.
Right.
Now, it's official.
Better turn out some of these lights.
No use making targets
out of ourselves.
Sure it's a clear night out..
You can see a thousand...
What am I saying?
- Send Wilson in here.
- Yes, sir.
Have me as heavily guarded as you wish,
but I tell you time is running out.
I'm sorry, but you produced nothing
that would justify our letting you go.
This can't be. I saw myself
at the house, under the same stars.
Hello. Quinn?
Yes. What? Wait a minute!
No, no, no...
Amos Block just killed himself
in his cell.
- Have you ever shot a lion?
- How could I've ever shot a lion?
- Could sneak out of the bushes.
- What bushes?
I was just saying it could.
Look, it broke loose the other
side of Westwood.
That's more than 6 miles from here.
Why, it could never...
- Hey, what's that?
- Sounds like wind.
What's that?
- Gowan...
- Yes, sir?
- What's going on?
- The branch of a tree blew down.
The branch of a tree blew down. It ought
to be a law against things like that.
The sudden wind...
Yeah, another one.
10:57:30.
Two and a half minutes to go.
Funny how it came up so fast, like
as if somebody pushed the button.
Look, you've got education. What are the
odds on this and him being legitimate?
Yesterday I had said a billion to one.
You know? My Irish grandmother
used to tell stories
about banshees and leprechauns and
blind singers with second sight.
I always used to think she was kidding,
but now I'm beginning to wonder.
Well, there is no scientific proof
of such things, Lieutenant.
Some of the big universities are making
experiments in that direction,
which means that scientists
think there's a possibility of...
- Whoever you are, stay out!
- Hey, Lieutenant, it's about the lion.
What about?
I just got a flash over the radio.
A couple of guys from
the Sheriff's office
cornered him out near
the Veterans Hospital.
- What happened?
- They croaked him.
- Yeah? Let us tell the boys.
- Right away, sir.
Brother, that's a load off my mind.
First decent break we've had.
Kinda make this chain
of events look cockeyed.
- Holy smoke!
- The broken vase.
It's eleven o'clock.
- Gowan...
- Yes, sir.
Well, that's over.
Tell the boys to relax.
Get them some coffee and sandwiches.
Coffee...
Hell, I feel good!
Darling, it's all history now.
Elliott, I'd like to be by myself.
For a moment.
I'm not afraid anymore.
You know?
This business almost got me.
He should call it shot.
Flower, wind, broken vase...
even the lion.
Except for the voice saying
"there's no danger now".
Lieutenant...
- How'd you get here?
- I brought him, Lieutenant.
- Where is Miss Courtland?
- Outside.
You let her go outside?
What's the matter with him?
Didn't he say before eleven?
No, it's not, it's two minutes up.
Eleven o'clock.
Looks like your troubles were over.
But the clock inside...
Don't be frightened.
There's no danger now.
- The voice saying...
- Saying what?
There's no danger now.
It must...
Put that down!
Jean!
- Darling, are you hurt?
- No, I'm all right.
- Mr. Triton!
- Jean...
- We took care of him, Miss Courtland.
- But it wasn't him, it...
That's ridiculous,
she's out of her mind.
It was you!
No quería que encontrásemos
las opciones.
What was it?
He didn't want the options found.
He didn't want the merger to go through.
I don't get it.
The options were due to expire the
day after tomorrow,
provided Miss Courtland
didn't find them first.
Go on.
He tried to make sure she didn't.
In that case, he could keep
the options money
and still retain control of the vast
Mid-Tide Oild interests.
Yeah, could be.
And it could be you were the one who
tampered with Mr. Courtland's plane.
Ride him downtown.
The two of them were in cahoots.
I think you're wrong.
I think he gave his life to save her.
No, the whole thing was an act.
Otherwise, Miss Courtland would
be dead as he predicted.
He thought she was.
The visions all came true.
The time, the lion, the stars...
Only they ended with his death.
He couldn't see past that.
Couldn't know that she was still alive.
This letter fell out of his pocket.
It's for you.
"Dear Carson, as you read this,
I will be lying at your feet,
killed by the revolver
that failed to fire last night."
"No one is to blame."
"My death was as certain
as the other events I saw in my mirror."
Some of you, well just
seeing me die, will doubt me.
Will believe these events too
had been contrived by me
or you'll call them a series
of weird coincidences.
But I know that you, Carson,
and some of the others,
will not dismiss it so easily.
My own strange fate must make
you ponder for a moment,
must make you realize that there are
things on earth still hidden from us,
secret things, dark and mysterious.
Subtitles made by gamboler[noirestyle]