♪ ♪
I'm sorry I had to do this.
I know too much, so it's better
I just end it my way.
Everyone will be
in a better place,
happier with me gone.
I hope everyone understands.
Love, Rachel.
♪ ♪
Mrs. Herrington?
Detective Garcia.
I'm Detective Carlson.
Be a sadist.
No matter how sweet or innocent
your leading character is,
make awful things happen to them
in order that the reader
may see what they are made of.
Vonnegut once said this
about writing.
And he was right.
The written word
is a unique way for us
to explore new and exciting,
sometimes dangerous worlds
without having to ever put
ourselves in any real danger.
So that is your assignment.
I want you guys
to write me a story.
And I want you to thrust
your main characters
into an environment
that they're not prepared for.
Something unexpected.
What happens to them?
Do they fail? Do they succeed?
That is up to you.
But I want you to be bold, okay?
Take risks.
Because that is what is
gonna keep me turning the page.
New message.
Zoe, it's me. Mom.
It's about your sister.
Ju-just call me back.
- Zoe.
- Yeah, what's up?
I don't know.
Mom, I told you
not to call me, okay
when you're drunk.
Rachel's dead.
♪ ♪
Zoe!
Rachel was like
the happiest person I know.
Well, sometimes people hide
how they really feel, mom.
You can't hide everything
from your mother.
I-I think she fell
for the wrong guy.
He was rich, he had a wife.
I mean, I think he was messing
with her head.
It's a little early for that,
don't you think?
I just lost my baby girl.
I think I'm allowed
to have a drink.
She left a note at the party.
She was at a party. When she...
♪ ♪
Is there anything
you need me to do?
I'm gonna ask Father McCallan
if we can have a proper funeral.
The church doesn't allow
sacrament
for... cases like Rachel's.
But he's known her
since her first communion.
Maybe you could
inform Rachel's workplace?
Yeah. I can do that.
Of course he would...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on a second.
Ladies, come on inside.
Tell Mickey I sent you.
Yeah, of course I sent them.
I know what I sent.
Bottle service
waitresses can make
between $1000 and $3000 a night.
Which is why a bottle girl isn't
just some waitress
jotting down drink orders.
They look and dress differently
because they are salesmen.
See that curtain back there?
Behind it sits Percy.
Percy is the boss.
Notice Percy is back there
and not out here with us, right?
That's because she leaves the
hiring of bottle girls to me.
If I don't like you,
she doesn't need you.
You two here with Lolo?
I'm gonna need your
Jane Hancocks on some NDAs.
Hey, Bobby, I need some N...
Hi. I was...
Excuse me.
You know we're
hiring bottle girls
not cleaning ladies, right?
No, I'm not here for the job.
I'm here to talk to you
about my sister.
Who's your sister?
Rachel Herrington.
♪ ♪
I'm sorry about your sister.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
So, were you two,
um, friends or...
Uh, we-we work together here
so, yeah, we were friends.
You know? Um, she was, um...
Excuse me.
Here are your sister's things.
Oh.
Okay. Um... right.
And, uh, her last paycheck.
Let us know if there's
anything we can do.
Oh! Wow, Rach.
Huh. Clearly I picked the wrong
profession as a teacher.
- You're a teacher?
- Yes, I'm a teacher.
Oh.
Maybe you should apply here.
- Ex-excuse me?
- Yeah, yeah.
A school teacher by day
a hot cocktail waitress
by night.
Hey, show some respect.
- She just lost her sister.
- All right.
You're right.
I apologize. My bad.
- Sorry about that.
- All right.
- You take care, Zoe.
- Thank you. Yup.
Mo... Mom?
Uh... What are you doing? Mom?
- Hey. What are you doing?
- She didn't do it.
She wouldn't leave me alone.
Rachel kept a journal?
Wait. Mom?
Rachel didn't kill herself.
Does this handwriting
look the same?
Yeah. It does.
It looks exactly the same.
- She was clearly depressed.
- Oh...
Well, if she was clearly
depressed then I would've known.
- I would have known.
- Oh, really?
Why do you think
that you would have known?
Do you think that you would've
even noticed?
When was the last time
you spoke to her?
I saw her two years ago,
but she was barely there.
She came by my work
and she left right away.
- I...
- Exactly.
And I was here with her.
- I was here.
- Okay, you were here, mom.
You were here with Rachel,
and what happened?
She was working
in some sleazy nightclub.
So what? You could just
stay home and drink...
Oh, yeah, that's easy
for you to say
because you left!
I had to.
I had to leave.
Look at you.
You, you're just like him.
When things get rough, you run!
Mom, you are, you're lashing out
at me because you're upset,
but that's not gonna
bring Rachel back.
♪ ♪
Zoe sent me another book today.
Not sure
why she keeps doing that.
I haven't read any of them.
Don't have the heart
to tell her.
People think the club is
some super-glamorous place
where everyone is
beautiful and happy.
The reality is
most people are there
because they want
to escape real life.
Like Zoe does with her books.
Except I prefer interacting
with real people,
not fictional ones.
Oh, thank you.
Rach.
Still obsessed
with books, I see.
Yeah. The classics mostly.
But crime novels are
your guilty pleasure, right?
Guilty.
What are you doing here?
Uh, just thought I'll stop by
and see what's up.
- What's up?
- What's up with you?
Oh, my God. You're here
about mom, aren't you?
No, she doesn't know I'm here.
Mm-hm. I'm sure she does.
You know, Rach,
this is, this is...
This is what she does.
She uses people.
She just wants to see you.
I thought maybe
you could come with me.
We could surprise her
for her birthday.
Not for her to feel better,
but for me, and for you.
- She texted you.
- Don't worry about it.
Rach, I'm your sister. Of course
I'm gonna worry about it.
Hey. Why don't you come over
to my place?
Stay with me for a few days.
We can have a,
a sister slumber party.
Hm? I miss you. It'll be fun.
I miss you, too.
But I have to work tonight.
Rain check?
It's good to see you.
♪ ♪
Excuse me.
Hi. My name is Larry. Uh...
I knew your sister.
I... Man, this is hard. Um...
I'm really sorry for your loss.
- Thank you.
- This never should've happened.
Well, you know, sometimes
you never know what someone's...
No, I mean there's something
you should know about Rachel.
- Get out...
- The night that she died, I...
Excuse me.
This is your fault.
I'm so sorry.
I'm-I'm devastated.
- How dare you come here!
- Rachel was an amazing...
You're even saying her name!
Just get out of here!
♪ ♪
That's Richie Evans!
He was with Rachel!
Stop pushing me!
That's Richie Evans!
♪ ♪
Last night,
I went to an after-party
at a billionaire's house.
His name's Richie, of course.
Weird thing is, he doesn't
live at this house.
It's just a party house.
Richie told me
he wants to leave his wife,
but he's afraid he'll lose
everything in a divorce.
I know Richie is a client
and all,
but I can't help
falling for him.
He told me that he can't
be himself
when he's around anyone else
but me.
Even his wife.
I don't know what to do.
I found out the truth
about Richie.
I hope it's not true,
I really do.
Rachel didn't
kill herself. I can prove it.
Last night, one of her friends
from the club...
Larry, approached me.
And he told me he had something
to tell me about Rachel.
Until I called him,
and he hasn't answered yet.
But I'm betting that he's gonna
tell me something about Rachel
that proves that she didn't
commit suicide.
Good morning.
Thank you for coming.
Mom, what's going on?
Your mother called
to let us know
she has some new information.
- Come in, please.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
...and, uh,
that's when I called you.
Now I'm just waiting
for this Larry guy
to, uh, call me back
because I am sure that he knows
what really happened to Rachel.
I mean, why else would he
talk to me?
- Is this Larry?
- That's him.
Lawrence Reynolds
went for a swim
at Richie Evans' place
last night
and forgot to get out
of the pool.
He was found this morning,
floating face down.
So, first my daughter,
and now Larry?
And that's not enough?
I understand.
And that's why we came over
when you called.
We'll stay on it.
Uh, Larry approached me too.
At the funeral service,
it was about Rachel.
And I didn't think
it was big deal.
I'm sorry.
You see? Larry knew something
that Richie doesn't want
anyone else to know.
We'd have to connect those dots.
Right now, I... I'm sorry.
We simply don't have
a lot to go on.
I have a son. I can't imagine
what you're going through.
If anything else comes up,
please don't hesitate
in calling.
♪ ♪
What if the answer we're looking
for is in these missing pages?
What are you saying?
Mom, what if Richie Evans
did kill Rachel
and made it look like a suicide?
So you believe me now?
Well, I... I mean, I-I have to.
It just makes sense, right?
Larry must've found out about it
and was trying to warn us.
So, Richie got rid of him
to cover it all up.
Well, there has to be
something else in here that
that can help us.
"The house." Yes. Okay.
Richie had this house that
he always throws parties at.
If Richie is responsible,
then there has to be a clue
somewhere in that house.
All I have to do now is
just find the address.
No, Zoe, this isn't one of
your crime books you read.
- Mom, I know that.
- No, no, listen to me.
This is real life.
Mom, the most dangerous thing
I face on a day-to-day basis
are 17-year-old drivers
in a school parking lot.
I know I am
out of my league here, okay?
And, yeah, I-I'm scared.
But you were right.
Rachel deserves the truth.
Rachel met Richie at the club.
He goes to the club
all the time.
Right. The club. Yes.
Yes. That's it.
Then-then that is exactly
where I have to start.
I have to go to the club
a-and find Richie,
ask him questions and then tell
the detectives
everything that I know.
No, Zoe, everyone
at that club is crazy.
Well, it sounds like
my second period class.
I'm gonna be fine, mom.
I have a secret weapon.
Night clubs
are like a foreign country.
They have a language
and culture all their own.
And they don't just
let anyone in.
Sometimes, guys ask girls from
the line to join them inside.
But that only works
if the girl passes muster
with the doorman.
Sometimes, just the guy doesn't
pass muster with the doorman.
Hi.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Didn't I see you at my sister's
memorial service?
Yes.
What are you doing here?
Just... clubbin'.
Uh, hobby.
Photographing the rich
and douchey?
Professional courtesy
prevents me from divulging.
Oh. So, you're like a,
a paparazzi or something, right?
Or something.
So, how do you know Rach?
- She dated a guy I know.
- Yeah. Richie. Exactly.
I'm trying to get in
so I can talk to him.
But it's all, you know
velvet ropey and listy
and stuff.
- Do you have any advice for me?
- No. Nope.
Even if you could
get into the club
you can't just walk up to people
like Richie.
Security is tight and all, so...
Well, I... All right.
Why don't you just tell me
what you know
about my sister and Richie?
Listen, I'm really enjoying
this flirtatious conversation.
But, uh, I just started the car.
- So that means I'm leaving.
- Okay. Wait.
- Have a great day.
- I'm not done yet. I...
- I'm done.
- Are you just gonna dri...
What?
Clubs need girls, and promoters
are the guys who supply them.
Promoters are like vultures
hanging around shopping malls,
coffee shops
and model castings.
But often times, they simply use
good old-fashioned social media.
A promoter's job is to get
pretty girls into the clubs
so that the guys spend a lot
of money on them.
It's a sleazy job and nobody's
better at that than Lolo.
Once a girl DMs him,
he'll set up a meet-and-greet.
And if he likes what he sees,
he invites them
to one of his pre-parties.
That's where he weeds out
the girls.
Figures out which ones
need to be there,
and which ones don't.
Hello?
♪ ♪
Ooh. God, you're sexy.
You my four o'clock?
Yep, that's me.
Hey.
It is you,
I was hoping it was you.
It's me.
Are you like a,
like a librarian?
No, I was a teacher.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Teacher,
librarian the same thing.
No, it's not really
the same thing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Kind of.
Well, no.
No, I-I-I wasn't a librarian.
And I am no longer
a teacher either,
but I am here
and I wanna come to your party.
I don't need
any more regular girls.
I do need more models, though.
Well...
Lucky for you...
I'm not just a regular girl.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hm.
So what makes you so special?
And you're gonna have
to invite me to your party
to find out why.
Okay, whatever.
♪ ♪
So, here you go.
All right.
And we'll see
why you're so special.
You're gonna... Yep, yep.
I'll show you something special.
Okay, so, where were we?
- Rachel actually wore this?
- Yeah.
Doesn't the walk of shame
usually come
at the end of the night?
- Usually.
- Usually. Yeah.
You look great.
Okay.
Ooh, are you sure
you wanna do this?
No, but I gotta
live a little, mom.
♪ ♪
Hi, excuse me,
do you know where Lolo...
Thank you.
♪ ♪
Excuse me.
- Oh, hi... Oh!
- Oh, there she is!
The goddess
I've been waiting for.
- I've been talking you up.
- Oh!
So, uh, do you need
a place to stay?
- Huh? No. No. No.
- Well, let me know if you do.
A lot of models need a place to
stay when they first start out.
You know,
it's a very tough business.
Very, very competitive.
So you're like their...
uh, my agent?
Yeah, something like that.
- Okay.
- So, this is how this works.
- Oh.
- You lead 'em on.
- Yep.
And then we get you both...
- That's how you get paid.
- I see.
You wanna dance?
Yes, I do.
It's not with me.
It's with them.
Oh!
♪ ♪
See? That's what
I'm talkin' about.
How you doin'?
I'm Brad.
You're hot.
I told Lolo
that I wanted a American girl
next full time.
I'm glad he came through for me.
Uh, I just, um...
Sorry.
♪ ♪
Don't you walk away from me.
Don't you walk away.
Fine. Go!
She is impossible.
I knew this was gonna happen.
When I came home,
I knew this would happen
and I came home anyway,
and I shouldn't have
even come home
in the first place.
Where are you going?
You just got here.
- Home.
- This is your home.
Nope, not my home. Not anymore.
Honestly, I-I don't know
how you still live with her.
She is the most
self-absorbed person
I've ever met in my life.
Here. This is for mom.
This is for you.
- Zoe?
- What, Rachel?
- Take me with you.
- Don't be ridiculous.
You know I can't do that.
♪ ♪
Okay.
All right! Okay!
Okay, so who wants to go
to the club?
Who wants to go to the club?
Let's go!
All right, guys. Get in.
Come on, come on, come on,
come on.
All right, guys...
Welcome to Lolo's world!
I'd like to introduce you
to Rachel.
Where do you think you're going?
- Just...
- Don't forget who got you here.
♪ ♪
Go ahead.
You ever been to Ibiza?
I'm going tonight.
I have a yacht.
Just you and I on the ocean.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, it's okay.
It's okay, she's with me.
You're being very rude
to my friend.
Now, get back there
and make me some money.
I quit.
There is another way
into the club.
Work there.
Most people
don't realize that...
a bottle of champagne...
it's like weapon.
You can use it to bash someone
in the head.
Not that I recommend that.
Unless of course, he deserve it.
Or...
you can get a VIP whale
to buy a dozen of 'em.
Jackie, you've been killing it
out there.
Our best bottle girl.
Percy is very pleased with you.
So am I.
Thanks. This job's been
a life saver, Mickey.
I needed the money bad.
Listen, what if I told you
there was a way you can make
even more money.
Making more money is good.
But you gotta work hard.
I'm willing to work hard,
of course.
I like that.
Listen, why don't we
get together after your shift
and talk about your future.
Mm-hm.
Ladies, my name's Mickey.
Thank you for coming.
This club has a reputation.
Beautiful women come here
and beautiful women work here.
My boss Percy over there ha...
- Uh, Zoe.
- Yeah.
What can I help you with?
I think that you
could do me a favor.
You could hire me
as a cocktail waitress.
You remember what Lolo said.
You know he said, "Tutor by day,
hot cocktail waitress by night."
Yeah, let me get this straight.
First, you try to get into the
club the other night with Lolo.
Now you're here
asking me for a job?
Yes, because I am
very ambitious.
Have you worked in a club, Zoe?
No, but I have read
a lot about them.
A lot and I am
a really fast learner.
I-I... Very fast. So?
All right, Mickey, uh,
you know, um...
See, it's just that...
The truth is
Rachel's death really has me
re-thinking my life
and I just...
I feel like
if she could do this...
then I know I could.
Listen, I run a night club
not a charity, sorry.
Ladies, where was I?
My boss Percy trusts
my opinion...
Mickey is the gatekeeper,
but the owner
of the club, Percy,
makes the final hiring choices.
Thing is, Mickey makes it
very hard
to get Percy's attention.
Why?
- My life is over!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing!
- Get up.
I've got nothing!
Shut up!
Get up!
What is all this?
It's nothing.
Got it under control.
Rachel Herrington was my sister.
Condolences. Now, why are you
making a racket in my club?
Look, uh...
Rachel was happiest
when she was here
and I'm a mess without her.
My mom's crazy,
and I have nothing left.
Nothing, truly.
And I just feel
like if I could...
if I could just be here,
I could just be
a little bit closer
to her right now,
and I am just asking you,
woman to woman,
please just,
just give me a shot.
You are...
very beautiful.
Let's try her out tonight.
See how she does.
But don't ever
put that "girl" card
with me again.
Understood?
And tell that idiot DJ
ease off
on the smoke machine tonight.
Last night looked like a damn
forest fire in here.
People need to see
who's in front of them.
Well, now you've done it.
Loosen up.
All right, everybody, listen up.
Meet the new fresh meat.
Her name is Zoe.
Zoe, you'll be trailing
with Missy tonight.
Oh, come on, Mickey.
Wha-what's the point, she's not
even gonna last a week.
Good luck.
♪ ♪
All right, so that table
over there
always orders four bottles.
I-I can't hear you over
this ear shattering music.
Hi, boys, meet you
in four minutes.
Wa-wait, wait.
How did you do that?
It's easy. Here, fine,
I'll do it slow for you.
Got it?
Yep.
Hi, what can I get you?
We'll take five... vodka sodas.
- Okay.
- Actually.
- Make it six.
- Six.
What's the matter with you?
I'm trying to order
six vodka sodas and...
Bitch, we sell bottles, okay?
They make their own drinks.
Here.
One bottle's
over a thousand dollars.
Dorothy, you ain't
in Kansas anymore. Move!
♪ ♪
- Okay...
- Hey, you got it.
Ha!
Yeah, come on, guys,
it's Saturday night.
- Live it up a little.
- Oh, yeah.
Whoo!
Here you go.
- That was gross.
- It's part of the job.
We carry a bottle,
we drop it at a table, make 20 %.
For that kind of money,
you gotta deal with all types.
But you handled it well.
Flirty smile, quick exit.
Most girls would have freaked.
I'm impressed, Dorothy.
♪ ♪
Been watching you.
Nice job out there tonight.
I think you might have
what it takes.
♪ ♪
Hi. New girl.
What're you doing in here?
Oh, hi, I'm Zoe.
- This is my first day...
- No, I know who you are.
Rachel Herrington was kind of
like a goddess around here.
I am sorry for your loss.
Rachel was more than a coworker.
She was a friend.
Thank you.
Yeah, but like, this is random.
Right? You working here.
Weren't you, like, a teacher?
Yeah, I was a teacher,
but, you know, the pay sucks.
So, I'm here now
and I love it, it's awesome.
Hey, um, do you know Richie?
Is he coming tonight?
Why?
- Well, uh...
- Zoe, psst!
- Hi.
- What are you doing in here?
- Uh...
- Get back to your section now.
Yep.
You were good, Missy.
Hey.
Where's the rest of it?
- It was my first day.
- So?
So... Okay, I'll do
better next time.
Don't you ever try
any of that crap again.
You hear me?
You're a waitress,
not a bottle girl.
You gotta earn your way
into the VIP.
♪ ♪
Go!
- Hey, Valerie.
- Hmm?
So, um,
how does someone get into VIP?
Oh, only bottle girls
work in there.
And how does someone become
a bottle girl?
♪ ♪
What are you up to?
What? Nothing.
Just curious how it worked.
Don't kick the hornet's nest.
That metaphor
is slightly overused.
But I think I know
what you're trying to say.
She's right.
So, um...
Do these women actually...
sleep with the men?
Most bottle girls don't sleep
with their clients, no.
But they do flirt with them.
Stay in touch with them.
Make these guys feel
like nobody else matters 24x7.
And if the clients ask for it,
yeah, get them other girls
that will do party favors.
You wanna get into the VIP?
Get your own clients.
The ones that come to see you,
and spend a lot of cash.
Thanks, Missy.
Forget it.
Hmm.
For me, the best way
to find new clients
is to find a unicorn.
♪ ♪
That's my word for a guy
at the club
who just wants a friend
to hang out with.
- Hi, handsome.
- Hi.
What're you doin' over here
all by yourself?
You look like you need
a couple of bottles.
Hmm? What do you think?
Two? Three?
You look like you could handle
that. 500 hundred a bottle.
You get the bottles
and I will get you friends.
♪ ♪
So they said, "How about
a two picture deal?"
I said, "How about
a three picture deal?"
And then...
I'll get you boys some bottles.
Hmm?
Yeah. Okay.
All right, three, three,
you big boy.
And, you,
I'm coming back for you.
Hey, uh, Percy
wants to talk to you.
You wanted to see me?
I started at this club
as a bottle girl.
Years ago.
- Did you know that?
- No.
And unlike the other girls,
I saved my money.
Almost every penny.
And then I invested
in stocks, land.
Made even more money.
And then I waited.
When the previous owner,
this scumbag
with lots of chest hair
and way too much cologne...
You know that nightmare?
Yeah, there's several
here tonight.
When he got arrested
for embezzlement,
I had enough stashed away
to buy this whole club.
You are not
like the other girls, Zoe.
I'm not?
You're hot,
and you've got brains.
I like that, which is why
I'm giving you a promotion.
Now stop fidgeting.
You look terrific.
Gotta say, Percy, I am not a fan
of the cheek-leak.
Please, my cheek has leaked
many times.
Take a deep breath.
Just be yourself.
You're gonna be just fine.
You know, I think
you will do even better
than Rachel in here.
Thanks.
♪ When the DJ starts spinning
♪ All my favorite songs
♪ I'm not quite sure
♪ Exactly what I'm drinking
Here we are. Sit.
Think we'll have
a bottle of tequila.
Maybe two bottles of vodka
and whatever else you think.
Is there a problem?
Zoe, right?
I don't think
we've been formally introduced.
I'm Richie Evans.
- Zoe Herrington.
- Yeah.
Said you'd be working here, I...
I didn't think it was true.
Surprise.
It's just, it's so weird.
In the good way. Good way.
And you know,
I wanna say I was sorry
for upsetting your mother
at the memorial service.
You know, I...
can only imagine,
you know,
what she's going through.
I have two little girls
of my own.
The thought of having
to say goodbye
to one of them...
Anyway, now, I-I just...
I can't believe you're here.
I didn't know
what I was missing.
Richie!
Pleasure to see you.
Thank you for coming.
Absolutely. It's good to see ya.
- See you around.
- All right.
Seems like we will.
♪ ♪
Zoe.
Hey.
You want to make
some real money?
What?
I don't just run this club
for Percy.
I got my own little
side thing going on.
I'm what you call a facilitator.
Wealthy men like to throw
after-parties, right?
And they like to have beautiful
women at those parties.
I have access
to beautiful women.
Thing is,
beautiful women aren't free.
Hmm... How much money?
More than you can make here
in a week.
Crazy.
Richie's having a party
at his house tonight.
He's personally asked
for you to come.
What about his wife though,
right? Uh-oh.
What Richie does
in his spare time is...
none of his wife's business.
Richie's a close
personal friend of mine.
Discretion is valued
above all else in these circles.
So, what, what kind
of party is it?
- House party.
- Well, I know, you said that.
But like what do I,
you know, do?
You ask a lot of questions,
you know that?
You want me to just tell him
you're unavailable?
No, no, no, I...
No, I'm just, you know, nervous.
Don't be.
You're his type.
Just like Rachel was.
This is the address.
And how much I'll pay you.
In cash.
See you later.
Mickey told me
to take care of you.
- Here.
- What's this?
Liquid courage.
- Oh.
- Relax.
It's not like I spiked it.
It's rum and coke.
Jeez, you need to loosen up.
What?
- Let go of my arm!
- Just keep walking.
Let go!
Just take your damn money
and get out.
Be careful, 'cause what they're
doing in there is disgusting.
Get her out of here. Now.
- You're a pig.
- Have a nice night.
Richie's gonna be really pleased
to see you.
Okay.
So lame.
What is?
- You.
- What?
I do everything
Richie asks me to do.
I bring him whatever
and whoever he wants.
And he's never looked at me
the way he looked at Rachel.
Or you.
I'm sorry, uh...
I'm sure you are.
♪ Where have you been?
May I take your drink, miss?
♪ Searching for
- What're you doing here?
- We need to talk.
- I can't tell you...
- Thank you. You can go.
Yes, sir.
I'm so glad you came.
Yeah, me too.
Let's get out of here.
Get out of here?
It's your own house.
Where're we goin'?
♪ ♪
This way.
I'm starting to feel
a little lightheaded.
- Maybe I should sit down.
- Well, we can go to my bedroom.
You are a naughty boy.
He is a naughty boy.
I am not that kinda girl.
I know, that's why
we're going this way.
♪ ♪
Just watch your step over here.
- Yeah.
- It's down. There you go.
- I gotcha. I gotcha.
- You know, I can do it.
You know, I was thinking,
when we go down to the lake
and we are out
to the middle of it.
It's perfect 'cause I...
really wanna talk to you.
You can always talk to me.
You okay?
I think I've had too much.
You just had one rum and coke.
Why're you here?
How'd you know
I had one rum and coke?
Valerie...
Rule number one,
never take a drink from someone
unless you've seen them pour it.
Yeah, you'd know that
if you got this far.
And Valerie, yes,
she, she gets this world.
Rachel did too, she resented it.
But she got it.
And then, here you come,
little miss teacher
tryin' to figure out
this entire world
in just a couple of days
and it makes me think
either you are
a great go-getter...
or you're up to something.
Shouldn't have kicked
the hornet's nest, Zoe.
There's that
terrible metaphor again.
We value discretion.
And you are not discrete.
Did you kill my sister?
No. No. Hold on, hold on.
No, I didn't kill her.
But you I am gonna kill.
And in case you're wondering,
nobody knows you're out here.
And anybody who does
know you're here...
well, they wouldn't say
anything.
And it'll be days before your
body washes up on that shore.
Now, what's that old saying?
Wealth by silence?
And I'm a wealthy man.
♪ ♪
You're okay. You're okay.
I know. The wall's
a bit obsessive.
You feelin' okay?
- Why... Where am I? What's...
- You're at my place.
You're safe.
You, you were drugged.
I checked your glass. Rohypnol.
Heavy dosage.
Someone wanted you out cold
so you'd... peew,
sink to the bottom
of that murky lake.
Fortunately, good Samaritan
happen by.
Saved your life.
You're welcome.
- What is all this?
- It's okay, you can trust me.
- Let me just grab...
- What's there to trust you?
I can't... I don't even know
what you were doing
at that house.
He was working for me.
I tried to warn you, dummy.
Didn't you see the signals
on your cocktail napkins?
Told you, they were too vague.
I'm your yin.
And I'm your yang.
You faked your own suicide?
Rachel...
do you have any idea
how serious this is?
I'm sorry.
I can only imagine what I put
you and mom through.
How is she?
Rachel, she thinks
that your dead.
We all thought
that you were dead.
We had a memorial service
for you. We...
We have to call her.
We have to...
No, this is important.
You cannot tell mom. Not yet.
Not until this is all finished.
You want me to wait
to tell our mother
that you're still alive?
Do you have any idea
what you've put her through?
Do you have any clue?
We've been digging
through your journal
to try to figure
this whole thing out.
There's these-these pages
that are torn out at the end...
That's because
I ripped them out.
I started to get paranoid
that he'd learned
I was writing it all down.
"He" who? Richie?
Mickey.
It looks like her confused face.
Why don't I pick up where
the pages left off?
Yeah, I think
that's a good idea.
"I never wanted to know
the truth about what Mickey
was doing with Richie.
But I had my suspicions
when Richie sent
his right-hand man,
Larry, to pick me up
and bring me over
to his after-party.
I went along.
No questions asked.
I played dumb, kept quiet.
I was paid a lot of money
to party with Richie.
I'll admit it,
the money was extraordinary
and that first night
in the house,
we...
I knew he was married
and that I was insane
and that it was insane.
But there I was.
I've never done anything
like that before.
Ever.
But I kept going back.
I kept getting paid.
And I kept quiet.
Even though Richie tried to keep
what he was doing away from me
I saw things,
but I never asked him about it.
The money was too good."
I had something to tell you.
What was it?
I, uh...
"Then one day
he told me he loved me."
I love you.
"And I believed him."
I love you, too.
"Like a fool.
Because I did love him."
Gentlemen...
I was with Richie now.
I was his girl.
I wasn't getting paid anymore
but the parties at his house
continued.
And I kept quiet.
Mickey kept bringing
new bottle girls
to Richie's house.
They were lied to,
they were told
this was the way
to a modeling career.
Once they were in, they had
no reason to get out.
The money was too good.
Which is how these men were
able to get the girls high.
Made them vulnerable.
But still, I stayed quiet.
I stayed quiet
even when I found out
Lolo wasn't just a promoter.
He had a side deal with Mickey.
He brought girls in
from all over.
Russia, Mexico, Ukraine.
Mickey got them to work
as bottle girls at first.
That kept it legit.
He promised them a better life.
But Mickey was just weeding out
the vulnerable ones.
The desperate ones. The ones
hardest up for money.
Those are the ones
that he brought to the house.
And then we come into this house
and they were selecting
the girls
like fruit
from the grocery store.
They were paying him
for the girls.
They were paying Richie.
Most of them were drugged.
The guys didn't care.
God, it was disgusting.
It was so vile.
And this man that
I thought that I loved...
he was...
he was in charge of all of it.
When I finally confronted
Richie about it,
he lost his mind. I thought
he was going to kill me.
And he told me that he would
if I told anybody.
And then, when I told
him I was leaving him,
he said, "No, you're not.
You can't leave.
You're my girl.
You're not going anywhere."
Later that night, Larry,
who had started feeling bad
for me pulled me aside.
You see, I had been journaling
everything I was seeing.
Everything.
And Mickey found out.
So, of course, he told Richie.
Which meant I'd become
a problem for Richie.
Larry warned me that Richie
was going to kill me
that very night.
He told me I had to run
as soon as I could.
Of course, had Richie found
out Larry was texting me
all that info,
he would have killed us both.
I was terrified, Zoe.
I've never been that scared.
I was desperate.
I needed a miracle.
That's when I heard
somebody coming.
I thought it was Richie.
It wasn't.
Poor girl.
She overdosed.
It was horrible.
She was from Columbia, I think.
Died right there,
in front of me.
I knew Richie
would come for me soon.
I didn't have much time.
♪ ♪
Now, before you judge me
on this next part,
remember, I was desperate.
Desperate enough to notice
that she and I
were the same size.
♪ ♪
So, I switched dresses with her
and I moved quickly.
Oh, God, forgive me.
What am I doing?
Oh, my God.
Rachel!
- Rachel!
- No, no, no.
It's too late. It's too late.
There's nothing you can do.
Rachel!
That poor girl.
I could've warned her.
I should have warned her,
but I...
kept quiet.
Oh, God. I kept quiet.
But as morbid as it sounds,
you know, she...
She saved my life.
It's only a matter of time
before they discovered
that that body wasn't mine.
Do dental records or something.
And it's like a ticking clock.
That's why I hired Vince.
He was one of my clients.
A unicorn.
Um, I know what that is now.
You're some kind of
private eye investigator.
Uh, not "Some kind of."
I was doing recon at the club,
trying to get Rachel's
phone back from the house.
Rachel's phone.
Yeah, Larry and I
had been texting
those last few days.
And he confirmed everything
about Richie.
Since he could track me
with the phone
I stashed it...
and ran.
It's all the evidence we need
to show what
Richie's been doing.
Isn't it all on the cloud?
You don't need
the actual device?
Richie got me that phone.
It's all in his account
and only a few select people
in a circle had that number.
Larry was one of them.
Which is how Richie found out
Larry was talking
to you and your mom
and Rachel, he read the texts.
So then, Richie really did
kill Larry.
Actually, it was his goon
that killed Larry.
Held his head under water.
Richie just watched.
Zoe, we have to get
that phone back.
It's what we need
to take them down
Yes, it does.
I just worked my way
in the house last night
to get it, when you showed up
to take a dip.
So, I have to break
in there, tonight.
Oh, my God, this is...
Wow, this... I'm sorry,
but this is
such a Michael Connelly story.
- Uh...
- Who?
Michael Connelly, the...
the crime novels
that I've been sending you
that you haven't been reading.
Sorry, I've been busy
in Atlanta's seedy underworld.
Right, okay. So then,
what's the plan?
What... When are we
gonna head to his house?
- We?
- What?
You-you thought
you were gonna do this alone?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
You've been to Richie's house.
It's like a, a hexagon, uhh..
And there's, you know,
the rooms.
You're never
gonna be able to find
his bedroom without wasting time
and you're gonna
risk getting caught.
I mean, Rachel,
I mean, she knows
where Richie's bedroom is,
but she's dead.
So that just leaves me.
They think you're dead, too.
I'm really sorry,
I'm not like you.
I'm going with you.
Mom?
Mom.
Zoe.
Oh, thank God.
Oh.
I had the worst dream.
I thought you left me all alone.
Mom, I'm, I'm here. It's okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm just so scared
I'm gonna lose you, too.
You're not. Mom, you're not
gonna lose me.
And I never should have left.
I never should've left
you and Rachel and I'm sorry.
Oh, no. Shh. That was my fault.
I was unhappy
and I took it out on you
and that's just not fair.
I think that we're all
gonna be okay.
I do.
Try and stay quiet.
Last night,
I left the back door open.
Get in, get the phone, get out.
Yeah, I know, I know.
I got it.
Shh!
Just find the phone.
Okay, here.
This is Richie's bedroom.
Okay, Rachel said
it was behind the bed.
I'm gonna look
under the mattress. Here.
You start with
the master bedroom.
It's just down the hall
to the right.
Hurry it up, please.
I was wondering until
you're done...
Where'd you find this?
♪ ♪
- Had we not gone to you...
- You knew there was a chance...
that the phone
wouldn't be there,
that they would've
already taken it.
That's why there was a plan B.
- You knew that.
- Plan B sucks.
Wait, whoa, what's plan B?
You might as well tell her,
I mean,
she's obviously
part of the team now.
Percy is plan B.
Percy? P-Percy,
the owner of the club?
She has no idea what
Mickey's up to.
And Percy would never
get mixed up
in something like that,
and she's worked too hard
to make that club her own.
Yes, but she's
not gonna believe me.
She has no reason to.
Right. So that's why
that plan sucks. Okay.
Oh, no, that's not why it sucks.
Well, guess what?
She will believe her if...
If we can get our hands
on Mickey's ledger.
He records notes, names,
all his business dealings
in there.
And it's enough information
to put him
and Richie away for life.
And that's why plan B sucks.
Wait, I don't know why, why does
that suck? That doesn't suck.
That's a classic
crime novel McGuffin.
A ledger with
all the incriminating evidence?
- I mean, come on!
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Except this isn't like some
novel of you download
on your Kindle to read
during your summer break
from your real job as a teacher.
Easy, Vince.
Easy? You want me...
You want me
to take it easy, Rachel?
Mickey's not gonna just
hand us the ledger,
which means we have
to physically take it from him.
Hence, plan B sucks.
What is your problem? Seriously!
I-I don't know
why you're doing this.
I know why we're doing this,
but I don't know
why you're doing this, and if
you have some kind
of problem just go, okay?
We got this.
- This is personal for us.
- Zoey...
Vincent's sister got wrapped up
in this world last year.
Different club.
She got involved with the wrong
guys, then ended up for sale.
He hadn't heard from her
in a while so
he went to her apartment and...
found her body,
she had overdosed.
So, um, this is personal
for me, too.
So, are we good?
Are we, uh, gonna do this?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, okay.
So, what we do know is
Mickey never parts ways
with that ledger.
So, that's a good thing
because then we always know
where it is at all times.
And if we can pull this off
tonight
it would be a two-fer.
Richie's at the club on Fridays.
We can take them
both down tonight.
Yeah, the tricky part's going
to be getting into the club.
You both...
Journey to
the impregnable fortress.
Classic heist trope.
Sorry. Go on.
You two are supposed to be dead,
so the moment you're caught,
jig's up.
Yeah, I thought about that.
Um, I think I have a way in.
♪ ♪
Hey, make sure
you close the door behind you.
Lolo's taken
so many girls and clients
for the house to the club
he does it all by rote now.
So, I'm betting he won't notice
if I switched
with one of those girls.
Hey, thanks for that.
Believe me, you dodged a bullet.
Hey, Porsche.
Yeah, yeah.
I got a couple of girls.
One's Puerto Rican
and the other one's Chinese.
I think I know a way in.
I'm just gonna
have to get gussied up first.
Me, too.
Hey, what're you doing?
I have been a reader
my whole life,
but I've never written anything.
I'm going back to the club
for one last time.
- Zoe, please don't go back.
- Mom...
- Let me call Percy...
- No..
- And tell her...
- Mom, no.
I'm doing this.
Oh, yes, hello.
This is Barbara Herrington.
Rachel Herrington's mother.
Do you have a moment?
Oh, my God, Zoe.
You're all right!
I was so worried.
Look, I don't know
what Richie told you,
but he and Mickey are mixed up
in some horrible things.
Yeah, I know.
I'm here to stop them.
Oh, my God. I'm so glad.
Look, no one will be
in the kitchen right now,
so why don't you come in
and tell me the whole plan?
Hm?
Oh, you know, I would love
an olive in this.
- Do you mind?
- Nope.
- Perfect.
- Of course.
So, tell me everything
you know about Richie.
♪ ♪
The latest and greatest.
You never cease to amaze me.
Ladies, he's a very important
friend of mine.
Very powerful, very connected.
He'll help you out.
Treat him well.
Mickey! Mickey! Let go of me!
Mickey!
What are you doing?
I've come to
warn all of the ladies
about you and about him.
Oh.
Oopsies. Was that spike drink
meant for me, too?
Val...
Ooh, but thank you
for the olives.
You're gonna regret this.
I swear to God
I'm gonna get you outside.
Move! What are you doing?
What is it that you told me
once about a bottle of champagne
A bottle of champagne
is like a weapon.
Jack!
Go get that girl back.
♪ ♪
Police. You're under arrest.
Kurt Vonnegut one said,
"Find a subject you care about
and which you in your heart
feel others
should care about."
Drop it. Now.
For me, that person
is my sister, Rachel.
She ended up falling in love
with the wrong guy,
somebody dangerous.
Rachel went into hiding
searching for evidence
to put him away.
And when she found
that evidence,
she looked him in the eye
and she never had to hide
from anyone again in her life.
The end.
Well, it turns out
Mickey's ledger
was the hail-Mary pass
we all hoped it would be.
You wrote down everything.
You're an idiot.
An organized idiot.
But an idiot.
You'll find everything
you need in here.
Plus, we have several
eye witnesses willing to testify
against him and Richie.
Oh, and also
uh, there's a co-conspirator
currently passed out
in your kitchen who, I'm sure,
would take a deal
in order to save her own ass.
Don't forget about this one.
He and I had a little chat.
He's willing to tell you
everything he knows.
- Isn't that right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm a witness, I'm a witness.
I'm just a witness.
This is the name and the address
of the girl.
She was my miracle.
I'm sure her family
would appreciate
knowing what happened to her.
I'll make sure I go myself.
Oh...
I took the liberty
of calling your wife.
Turns out she didn't know
anything about your
country house
or your little side business.
She seemed really angry.
Screamed on the phone
something about her lawyer
and taking all of your money.
No one is gonna
be quiet anymore.
♪ ♪
- Way to go, little sis.
- Mm-hm.
Calling the cops?
That wasn't part of our plan.
When'd do that?
- I didn't.
- What?
♪ ♪