It's 9 o'clock...
We're not going to sit here all night
being famished are we?
It's still best we wait for her.
We aren't going to wait all night,
are we?
- [Babbles]
- What did he say?
"What a start to Christmas!"
We won't be eating better
than any other day.
Christmas dinner is not something
...we'll be stuffing ourselves
with tonight.
It's... it's... it's...
- He's saying...
- Hell!... he can talk for himself!
A lot of words aren't going
to fill your stomach.
And all because of that idiot
over there.
Take a look at this...
Not bad, eh?
"Wednesday, January 1...
and for the first time...
"in Courbevoie City Hall...
"The Companions of Song."
I really think
I've captured our energy...
..and our natural sense of fun.
When people see this poster,
they'll say...
"Here are 9 merry fellows...
"with whom...
"...with whom you could be sure
of spending a pleasant time."
What about our kitty?...
Why did we trust you with it?
It's all we've got saved.
What was it meant for?
For Christmas-New Year.
But I thought it better...
He "thought it better"!
He thought it better
to buy this garbage...
...to put his scribbles on.
This is what'll launch our careers!
Right now we'd rather eat!
- All you think about is food!
- Be quiet!
This is the moment of tragedy!
As everyone knows...
hunger can lead to madness.
And one of us is madder
than all the rest!
See for yourselves!
I'll put Christine between Jean-Louis
and Guy...
- Why Guy?
- Why Jean-Louis?
- If that makes him happy, that way...
- Will SHE be happy that way?
But this meal's never going to happen,
is it?
Miracles can happen
on Christmas Eve.
There hasn't been one
for 2,000 years.
Christine might turn up
with her arms full.
She might've got a gig.
Here we are...
the hors-d'oeuvres...
iced pudding...,
...fruit, coffee, liqueurs!
Sit up, please gentlemen!
Charentes butter!
Isigny cream!
- Ducks from Nantes!
- Eggs from Picardy!
Olives from Provence...
cheese from Brie
Meringues from Valence...
Grapes from Chablis...
Oysters from Marennes...
Liqueur from Fécamp.
Currants from Lorraine...
and tripes from Caen.
Pullets from Bresse...
Champagne from Ay.
Here is the wealth...
...of our country.
La la la...
My dear chap...
Come and join us!
My good friends...
...before proceeding further
with this feast...
...I want to raise my glass to the one
we all keenly await.
I want to raise my glass to the one...
...who's soon to be joining us.
I want to raise my glass to the one
who is already with us...
...in our hearts and in our thoughts.
Let the party go on!
He's much admired...
Let's drink to his health!
Let's drink to his health...
We were just trying
to cheer ourselves up.
Just cheering ourselves up.
You understand?
Don't worry about it...
I quite understand.
- Is it the same for you?
- Same what for me?
Are things going bad
for you too?
- We just want to know.
- That's all.
It's not important.
Not in the least.
[babbles]
So... translation?
I'm tired of translating his nonsense.
Besides... it's irrelevant.
Go on... what's he saying?
He said that Christine has an uncle
who works in a nightclub.
Yes. So what?
- Maybe he's the boss!
- You have to go there!
Especially on Christmas Eve.
- You'd be successful.
- You'll get to see the manager.
- You'll get a contract.
- For a year.
- You'll go on tour...
- And to Hollywood.
You see... your uncle
would certainly hire you.
You have to go now...
before it's too late.
Alright, I'll go.
Poor kid.
We should've gone ourselves.
- That would've worked better.
- I didn't dare suggest it.
Especially since we've got
our act perfect.
You mean we're irresistible?
Yes... but it's HER uncle.
Guess so.
I forgot something.
You remember the lucky charm
I gave you?
Could you lend it to me?
I might need it tonight.
Thanks.
I know what her uncle does
at the nightclub.
Why didn't you say anything?
Because then
she wouldn't have gone.
Listen to...
...these cries of joy.
...these happy songs.
Let us all sing...
...Noël...
Glory to the king of Heaven.
This way, madam, sir.
Pardon, madam.
Thank you sir.
As I was saying...
- Are you listening?
- I'm listening.
This little niece of mine...
...as soon as I'd taken her in hand...
it was a triumph!
I adjusted her voice
and I chose her repertoire.
Since then...
...she's had the world at her feet.
London, New York...
Stockholm, South America...
I'd never dare to ask her
to perform here.
Pass me the bowler.
-"Pass me the bowler."
- The bowler!
Sorry... here...
You've got the right sort of body
for the stage...
If I took you in hand,
I could speak to Ferdinand...
"Ferdinand"?
He's the manager...
An old friend of mine.
Would you mind taking care
of our guests, my good fellow?!
If I catch you again,
you'll be out on your ear!
No... there's still a table...
This way please...
- Hello, uncle.
- Ah! That's amazing...
I was only talking about you
5 minutes ago.
Lisa...
This is my niece.
- My pleasure.
- I'm very proud to meet you.
- Your uncle's been telling me...
- That'll do!
We haven't seen each other for ages.
Please excuse us.
You've come at the right moment...
I've been tied up.
- By the way... what do you think of her?
- Who do you mean?
The girl, there...
She's crazy about me!
Completely lost her head!
So, what's new?
I knew you worked here,
but I didn't know as what.
I thought you might do me a favour.
Anything you want...
I'm the man to do it!
The manager does nothing
without consulting with me.
- I'm his right-hand man!
- Really?
Anything you want.
You have only to ask.
You see, things aren't going well
for me at the moment.
And then, you know my boys?
All 9 of them?
- Yes, of course!
- We haven't eaten in 2 days.
I see.
No! I didn't come
to ask you for money.
I came to see...
...if it might be possible to get
a singing engagement.
You want to sing?
Whereabouts?
- Here.
- Here?!
- When?
- Tonight.
Yes... It's possible.
I'll go talk to the manager.
But you have to come to my office...
...so I know what you can do.
Wait here.
Christine!
Come... It's this way.
We shan't be disturbed here.
Well? Aren't you going to sing?
Don't you know this?
What a shame...
It's a pretty song!
Oh, pardon.
So what are you going
to sing for me?
- "A Street Song".
- Who sings on the street?
That's the title of my song.
I have to tell you... I've only a few minutes..
So make it quick.
So..can I hear something?
- Right here?!
You can sing here...
No one will mind.
Go on... away you go!
Go on! Go on!
To be in love, requires pride...
.To know when to be silent...
and dignity...
To know when to leave...
One hot and cold!
- What's hot and cold?
- That was these guys!
Oh yes... go on.
...and keep smiling...
And as I was walking, I said...
That I'd left at the right time...
Is this piece cheerful or sad?
- I don't know...
- Go on... we'll soon see.
If my heart is discouraged...
You see... this thing's sad.
I don't know anymore
if it's sad or gay.
And I can't sing without music!
Even the accordion would help.
An accordion...
Well, if that'll help...
So... go on.
- Well, play it.
- Me? I don't know how to play it!
Wait...
I have an idea.
Wait here for a few minutes.
- Émile, your chicken.
- Thanks.
Just pass me a cover, please.
- And the chateaubriands, rare?
- Well-done.
I found someone, sweetie.
This gentleman took 1st prize
at the conservatory!
- Do you know music?
- Do I know music?!
- Just a bit.
- This is my niece.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Hi!
So tell him what to play.
Do you know a piece
called "The Street Song"?
- Vaguely.
-"Vaguely?"
- What key do you sing it in?
- I don't know.
We're not worried about that!
Go on... sing it to him.
That's tops!
Sit down.
Come on now, my girl...
I'm listening.
To be in love, requires pride...
Stop! Stop! One moment.
- What do you wear, when you sing?
- My dress.
- No accessories?
- No.
You need accessories.
Take off your coat.
We'll find something here.
What's this? No... not that.
Jewellery... here we are!
Give me your coat.
Here. Put on this bracelet...
put on this ring...
...and I'll put on a little necklace.
It gives you a look... dignity...
It gives you... class!
That does it!
Doesn't that make you
feel more comfortable?
- Yes.
- You see... Now...1... 2... 3!
To be in love, requires pride...
To know when to be silent...
and dignity...
To know when to leave...
i>...and keep smiling...
And as I was walking, I said...
That I'd left at the right time...
If my heart is wrenched...
He'll not have seen me crying.
My dress is faded from the sun.
A song that runs in the street...
Jostling the passers-by...
It crept through the crowd...
As a small engaging song...
I followed its journey...
It stopped before me...
There are handsome boys.
Cast your sorrows in the stream...
And turn the back on him...
If this song which runs in the street...
Can chase your troubles away...
Then come join the crowd...
Hey... the manager!
Quiet! It's the manager!
It's alright!
Bravo, young lady!... Excellent!
You'd do an encore, I imagine?
So I might have the pleasure of applauding you
on the stage before long?
Well, I'm delighted.
Good luck, and once again... bravo!
Thank you!
Good evening!
Just keep the beggars
and flower-sellers, out!
Any more chatting with the hat-check girl,
and you're fired!
As for your niece... she can come back
after the holidays.
Very good sir...
thank you sir.
I've just seen the manager...
he told me ...
Don't bother... I heard it all.
- So you listen at doors, now?
- You've been very good to me.
You've done all you could...
Thank you.
- I have to leave.
- But where do you want to go?
You don't know Ferdinand the manager.
But the real manager is me.
For Christmas Eve,
we need a long show.
You'll wait for me here...
I promise you'll sing tonight.
You know I don't believe you.
But it makes you feel better,
I'll wait.
Yes, it WILL make me feel better...
See you soon.
I promise that you'll sing tonight.
I promise... tonight...
Tonight.
I promise you'll sing tonight.
After the holidays!
I said "after the holidays!"
I said...
"after the holidays"!
I said "after the holidays"!
A bell is ringing, ringing...
She's singing in the wind...
Haunting and monotonous...
She says again to us all...
"Do not tremble, faithful hearts...
"God will make you a sign some day...
"You'll be under His wing
with eternal life...
"An eternity of love!"
Come forward!
it's not possible!
You!... Here already?!
- But where am I?
- Can't you see?
- In Heaven?
- Yes.
- I'm in Heaven?
- Yes, you are.
But what is it that YOU do?
I'm just a doorman.
Everyone does the same here
as they did on earth.
I'm the doorman
for the Parisian section of Heaven.
-  That means I can come in?
- But of course!
Wait... show me what you've got
in your hand.
- I don't have anything.
- Please... just show me!
- Where did that come from?
- I bought it.
No. It's useless trying to lie...
I know you didn't have a penny.
Somebody just gave it to me
out of charity.
A man who realised I was hungry.
-"Out of charity"?
- Yes.
- You're sure about that?
- Wait here. I'll go see.
No!... Wait outside.
Wait for me there.
- Excuse me, Miss Lisa...
- Yes?
- Do you have the Paris registry?
- Certainly.
What are the charitable deeds
registered this evening...
...in the 18th district?
- The 18th district....
Yes... we'll soon see.
There are some beggars
who received alms...
- Christmas presents...
- But they're obligatory!
- Nothing else.
- That's all I need to know!
Listen... I can explain...
I was just so hungry...
...and all these food platters
were going past...
I couldn't resist...
so I pinched it.
I'm obliged then, to deny you entry!
There's no place here for thieves.
- Just for a chicken leg?
- I don't want any trouble.
- Even though I've confessed?
- Rules are rules!
Well, that's too bad!
Goodbye.
Hey... wait there!
You ARE my niece, after all...
- What can I do...?
- Nobody need know.
- They know everything, up here.
- It was the first time.
- And the last?
- I swear.
- No swearing allowed here!
- I'll promise, then.
Good... Get rid of that.
Go through.
- What was that?
- The squeaky door.
May I introduce Miss Lisa...
My niece.
Delighted to meet you.
Excuse me... I have a call.
Too bad... we'll make it
another time.
I would have liked you two
to get acquainted.
Miss Lisa is the long-distance operator,
between the different Heavens.
- Between the different...
- Heavens... yes!
One can even make contact
with Earth.
- Really?
- Yes. There's the phone booth.
And from up here we can see
what happens down there.
- Including... that.
- Oh yes!
There's not much
going on right now.
It's not always funny.
Especially with their
so-called United Nations.
Come on... they're waiting for you,
for the show.
What show?
The Christmas Eve show.
You celebrate Christmas,
here too?
Where else, if not here?
This is where it all started.
- Victor.
- Yes?
- Isn't it beautiful!?
- Yes.
Looks like the cabaret just now.
- Can it be the same one?
- Yes.
For you, yes.
You understand...
To each their own Heaven.
And this one's yours.
But the man in charge is the same.
Yes, that's the manager.
I'll take you over to him
- But I'm hungry.
- You'll eat after the show.
Unless he offers you something
right now.
- I wouldn't dare ask him.
- The manager knows all!
-"All"?
- All.
You'll address him as "Your Excellency.
Your Excellency, my niece.
- Hello, Christine.
- Hello, Your Excellency.
How are you?
You arrived a bit late...
We've finished eating.
I hope you can wait until
the end of the show.
- I'm not at all hungry.
- Oh, but you are...
You were complaining to Victor,
just now.
- Over there?
- Yes.
So you DO know everything.
I thought this little snack
would do for the moment.
"This little snack"?
What snack?
Aren't you eating, Christine?
But... it's a miracle!
No, not at all...
It's just how we do things here.
A miracle is achieving
what you desire most.
Is there a thing you wish for
more than anything?
Yes, but I don't dare tell you.
You don't need to tell me...
I know it.
Well, yes, of course...
You know all.
So, Christine...
You shall have your miracle!
That's a shame.
Why?
Because this is not the place
I need it...
It's down THERE!
I'll tell you a secret...
It may be a sin...
but I'm a bit superstitious.
For example...
I had a lucky charm
and I gave it to a...
To a friend... to Jean-Louis.
I've no need to explain...
because you know it all anyway?
Don't get angry...
I like you to tell me.
You know... I only know you
from a great distance.
Yes, of course!
Anyway, I gave this lucky charm
as a present to Jean-Louis.
This evening, I asked him for it back.
I needed it right then
to bring me luck.
Unfortunately I lost it,
and everything went wrong.
But you know all about that!
You'll find your lucky charm...
..later.
The show is about to commence.
Lovely!
Well, Christine... it's all yours.
What's all mine?
You'll give us the pleasure
of singing something.
Me? Singing in front of these...
- They're angels, aren't they?
- Yes. Why not?
I'd be embarrassed.
Don't be like those stars
who have to be begged.
I don't want to be difficult...
...but don't forget my songs
didn't please everyone down there.
What's it going to be like here?
Careful!
False modesty is also a sin.
No, no, no!
- Don't keep us waiting.
- Well... you asked for it!
Christine... you don't need
any accessories...
Make use of the real you.
Your simplicity...
Know what I mean?
You'll do very well.
I know it.
You know?
Then of course you know!
Well... here goes!
I still have stage fright.
I don't have my music.
Some time in your life...
Your name was Sophie...
You were so pretty...
Mademoiselle Sophie
Oh, Sophie, Sophie
Living only for him...
You left your friends...
To think only of him...
But he didn't understand...
And one day, he is gone...
Oh, mademoiselle Sophie
Farewell to your fantasy...
Farewell to your folly...
You enjoyed life no more...
Mademoiselle Sophie
One sad rainy night...
Gave God the desire...
To take your life away...
Mademoiselle Sophie
Oh, Sophie, Sophie
But as he took thee...
To leave us like this...
Without saying a word...
Leaving all your friends?
You have taken life...
Oh, mademoiselle Sophie
Some time in your life...
You were known as Sophie...
And you were
Oh so pretty...
Mademoiselle...
Sophie!
Bravo, Christine!
You were wonderful.
I told you you'd do
really well.
- I knew you would.
- Thank you, Your Excellency.
I'm the one who should be thanking you,
for lending your support...
...to our evening entertainment.
Goodbye for now.
It's all so wonderful!
Like a dream.
Yes... it IS a dream...
Dear God, please let it last
a little longer!
Don't make me wake up, just yet!
Oh, thank you.
Bon appétit!
Of course!
- No... I couldn't swallow a thing.
- Don't you like the food here?
- Yes.
- What's the problem? You were starving.
I'm going to explain...
I left my friends down there...
- As we all do, here.
- Let me finish.
They've had nothing to eat...
and they're counting on me tonight.
- Nothing I can do about that!
- I won't eat by myself.
We're not going to make them
come up here.
Why not?
Just for half an hour.
It wouldn't even be a miracle.
It's never been done before...
And it's against the rules!
So I won't eat anything...
anything at all!
- What if you asked His Excellency?
- I'd never dare.
What if I did?...
He knows all!
If it doesn't work, it's because
he doesn't want it to.
He knows all... If it doesn't work,
it's because he doesn't want it to.
That makes sense.
But it's not regular at all.
But it makes sense.
But Lisa won't connect us.
You'll have to fix that...
She's in love with you.
Where did you get
that idea from?
Down on Earth, you were
in love with her.
I imagine that here she'd love you...
as we each have our own Heaven.
You're the one
who told me that.
Lisa, interested in
an old fellow like me?!
- There is a certain logic to it, though.
- Yes.
Leave it to me.
Miss Lisa, may I put a call through
to Earth?
- Do you have authorisation?
- Authorisation?.... Yes.
- Who from?
- From... From him, of course.
- Christine...
- Leave it to me.
- They don't have a phone.
- Let's leave it then.
What address?
33 Rue Lepic, room 27a.
"33 Rue Lepic, room 27a."
It won't be easy
to get through to Earth.
There aren't enough lines.
So many people are communicating
with Heaven.
Mostly kids, with Father Christmas.
Room 27a is busy.
That can't be...
They don't have a phone.
We'll see.
My God, I'm hungry!
They might think of us,
up there tonight.
You see?!
Oh, yes.
- And on Christmas Eve!
- Are you still complaining?
But it's true.
It's free...
Will you take it in the booth?
This'll really be something!
- Should it take long?
- If it works... right away!
- Do you know where this is?
- No!
- In Heaven.
- In Heaven?!
Come on...
I'll show you around.
This is my Uncle Victor.
And this is Lisa.
- I'm Jean-Louis.
- I'm Fred.
- I'm Jo.
- I'm Paul, and that's  Albert.
Thanks... but I don't need
your help any longer.
I'm Albert.
Pleased to meet you.
- He's not babbling any more.
- Exactly.
Ever since I couldn't put
3 words together...
...I've fallen behind.
Now you're going to hear me speak.
To each his own Heaven,
Gentlemen, go on. '
- I'm Marc.
- Guy.
-  Still going!
- And I'm Gérard.
Yes...This is exactly how
I imagined an angel.
- Hello.
- Hello, miss.
What was that?
Thunderclaps are made by lightning strikes...
and love at first sight!
Well...
This IS love at first sight!
Gentlemen...
You can't stay here...
Follow me... but quietly.
What a to-do!
OUT OF ORDER
Say...
There's a stage through here...
What if we did our act?
Onc upon a time in our village...
A huge bear rampaged through the woods...
He frightened the woodsmen
And ate all the shepherd's sheep....
The mayor and the priest
said in anger...
This can't go on...
"This bear will drive us crazy in a week...
"We have to have its skin..."
The set off one morning into the forest
Which had a lovely scent of pine.
We've been walking all day long...
I left it to you to fix things...
Let's listen to them!
- Open the curtains.
- Yes, Your Excellency.
However at nightfall on the trail...
His eyes could be seen glowing...
And... Bang! The priest fired...
...and scored a hit!
But the bear, who was only wounded...
Rolled into a ditch... just stunned.
He was carried home...
And imprisoned in the cellar.
The whole village rejoiced.
Now the story goes on...
Since then the bear
has been tamed...
...is well-behaved, happy
and well-groomed.
He takes care of a heap of jobs...
Fetches water from the spring...
He knows how to drive the tractor...
At New Year he helps the postman...
...to hand out the prizes.
Yes my friends...
It was his speech
that was best understood.
And the moral of this story is...
Since he is now head
of the court...
It's been found not to do any worse.
Everything works better at the town hall.
If only we had the same bear
in Paris!
It's all my fault.
Be quiet!
but on Christmas Eve...
...I couldn't just leave them there
to starve.
So I had them brought up here.
And then, because you are
so all-knowing...
...I assumed that if it worked,
it was because you wanted it to.
I'm not trying to justify myself...
I'm to blame.
I made Victor do it.
You can't deny I lied to Lisa...
Didn't I, Lisa?
About the authorisation.
You see, Your Excellency,
it's really all my fault.
I DO see, Christine.
You're a good girl... and a salvation
for your comrades.
Besides, kindness like yours...
...is something rare in life.
Promise me you'll go on
being like that...
-...when you return to Earth.
- "Return to Earth?!"
Are you showing me the door?
Couldn't I stay, Your Excellency...
I beg of you.
I'll let you know later.
Lisa, you have to always
see the authorisation...
...and do not leave the switchboard...
...during business hours...
Yes, Your Excellency.
...even for reasons
as important as yours.
Victor, you've broken the rules.
You will need to be more disciplined
during the coming centuries.
Another thing...
Have you verified if Christine
had permission to enter...
...and had definitely
left Earth?
No, Your Excellency.
That's your answer, Christine.
You don't belong here.
Not yet.
You should return to earth...
at some point.
You'll go back some day, later on.
I thought I might have to.
Just now, I got the impression
that all this was only a dream.
Your Excellency, couldn't you
make an exception?
A teeny weeny exception.
Life's so miserable down there.
You're often cold and hungry.
And it's so hard
to make a living.
You have to be very smart
to get by.
But it's especially hard with singing.
Nobody wants to listen.
Whereas, here...
Well, you saw how it was.
Yes, I know.
But you'll see, Christine,
...it will all go better for you now...
And this young man will help you.
You love each other.
Both of  us would
have loved to stay.
I'm sorry about that, Christine.
My authority stops there.
I also have to obey the orders
handed down to me from above.
Your presence here
WAS in fact a dream...
...and every dream
has its awakening.
What a pity.
I wanted so much to stay.
What a pity!
- That's it?
- Everyone's gone. We'll close up
Hurry up!  Get your stuff...
We're leaving.
Get moving!
- Why are we leaving?
- They're closing up.
How come?
You promised me.
I'll explain in the morning.
I'll come over to your place.
Or you come here...
I don't know where you live.
And my chance to sing?
I'm not going before I get it.
We looked for you all over...
We couldn't find you.
You're making that up!
I don't believe you.
I promise you'll sing,
another time.
You don't want to sing
to empty tables.
Get a move on!
I'm in a hurry...
I have to meet that girl.
- The hat-check girl?
- Yes.
She was so insistent...
I couldn't say no.
An old fellow like you with Lisa?
Maybe that makes sense?
Oh...thanks! Good night!
- Hello.
- Good night.
How about a bit of quiet?!
We've nothing to eat...
At least let us sleep.
I hurt myself!
Poor little kid!
Thanks for your sympathy!
Idiot!
I wasn't talking about you.
I was referring to Christine.
It was stupid.
If she hadn't got something,
she'd be back by now.
- That's idiotic.
- Yeah.
If she HAD got something,
she'd be back by now.
She didn't dare... that's all.
- It doesn't make sense!
- No, it doesn't make sense.
Nobody thinks about Christine.
She can't have eaten either.
[Babbles]
- Obviously.
- Obviously what?
- It won't have gone well for her.
- Why not?
Because I know
what her uncle does.
Would you like to know?
I asked you 3 times.
You wouldn't tell me.
- He's the doorman.
- A nobody.
It's a funny sort of job.
What can they earn,
with tips and everything?
- What are you saying?
- I told you an hour ago!
There's nothing her uncle
can do for her.
WE've got an act, but amateurs
can't get in the door.
Don't call her "amateur".
You're only playing white knight
because you're in love with her.
Now we present the greatest attraction
of the year.
You have the privilege to witness
the discovery of Albert the Redhead.
Albert the Redhead,
the man who walks on his hands...
...who sees the world upside down...
which is quite an advantage.
Don't forget to show your appreciation
at the end... with a donation.
Think that'd work?
Yeah.
- It's got to work at Christmas.
- The streets are full of people.
- If we get crowds, we'll do OK.
- We can give it a try.
I'll show you what comes next...
The time has come
to admire the man...
....who defies the laws of gravity.
12 plates in good condition...
2 plates slightly used.
2 plates slightly used...
- Hubert, how many shirts do you have?
- Three... why?
- Put down... one shirt... 39 collar.
- What's that about?
It's the only way
we can raise some money.
The pawnbrokers...
No talent needed.
From Guy...
A brush and 10 tubes of paint?
- Are you crazy? I need that for posters.
- Who cares?!
Stop it! It's dawn on December 25th.
The day begins.
How poetic.
No hock shops are open
until tomorrow.
- This is useless.
- So much the better.
It's a shame.
- So what can we do?
- We can go to bed.
But Christine's not back yet...
Something must have happened to her.
We need to go find her.
Where's this nightclub?
- Montmartre.
- Where in Montmartre?
-Montmartre.
-Montmartre?:
We'll find it...
Are you coming?
What's the point?
Are you coming or not?
Well that's too bad...
I'll go on my own.
So, Your Excellency...
What about my miracle?
I don't do if you can hear me,
or if your switchboard's clogged...
...but your miracle's
a bit slow in coming.
And the lucky charm I lost...
that I'm supposed to find?
But I didn't lose it here..
So I won't find it here.
It's...
Another one.
- What's he doing?
- Nothing at all.
- He doesn't want to be bothered.
- Did you tell him we've closed?
- Yes. But he keeps ordering champagne.
- But he has to...
- He can't sleep here.
- I don't understand...
...He says he won't leave
until the little girl has sung.
Which girl?
- Victor!
- Yes, sir?
That girl you were talking about...
- My niece?
- Yes... Is she still here?
I'll fix it...
She's left.
- Go and fetch her right away.
- Very well. My niece?!
Just do what I tell you!
But I don't know
where she lives.
If you don't bring her back,
you're fired!
Yes sir!
Are you looking for something?
Yes, thanks...
I thought I lost it here.
It was just my little mascot
that I treasured.
I must have been wrong.
It doesn't matter.
- Goodnight again.
- Goodnight.
Hey... wait there...
Come back!
Quick... quick...
It's all fixed...
What I promise, I deliver...
It's all yours in 2 minutes.
But you said...
You asked me for a chance to sing...
You're going to sing.
- The room's empty.
- Don't let that deter you... come on!
- There's no music.
- What do you expect at this hour?!
Hurry up! Go on!
- What are you doing now?
- I'm getting ready.
Give me your coat.
Take it.
- Hold this.
- You're taking off the jewellery?
But that's what gives you...
style... class.
No longer needed...
It's about simplicity... understand?
I just want to get it
over and done with!
Excuse me sir...
- Could you accompany me?
- Do you know what time it is?
Take a look!
How about that!
She was in love...
but she lived unhappily...
He did not return her love
Strange that it was like that.
She ran to the fountain
to drown her pain
and the devil and his crew
encouraged her.
That's the reason
Cupid was crying in his corner.
Heaven understood nothing.
The days still full of light...
The words of the prayers
all rising in procession
escorted her...
But the girl is dead
while crying out "Forgive me "
That's the reason
Cupid was crying
in his corner
That's the reason
Heaven understood nothing
All the flowers withered
as night swallowed the Earth
to sing onf the last day
of this death for love.
Black carousel horses
are the unloved in a cortege
trying to prevent
the sun from rising.
That's the reason why
Cupid has not more friends.
the heavens were seeking shelter
Games and dances...
All the joys of the world
were wanting to leave...
And the hearts of men
like autumn leaves
would wither.
That's the reason why
Cupid has not more friends.
the heavens are seeking shelter.
But now my story
will dance under garlands.
It could not last.
Cupid has arranged everything
and since it is he who sings
it's too bad for the tormented.
You can always cry
but it's better to sing.
That's the reason why
we listen to accordions.
the street bursts into song.
The sorrow of souls
drowned in sound
is heard no more.
Love is a party
that everyone joins
wholeheartedly.
That's the reason why
we listen to accordions.
the street bursts into song.
So what have you been doing?
I take back what I said to you.
Thank you. Why sir?
When we see a talent like that,
we say so.
I'd like you to meet
my nine friends.
Gentlemen.
But...
But I can only see eight.
- Who's missing?
- HUBERT!
- Hubert?  Damn!
He was just the one I needed.
- Why?
- I've got something for him.
Too late.
He's hit it off...
...with the hat-check girl.
- The hat-check girl?
- The hat-check girl!
It WAS love at first sight then.
Really truly!
How do you know?
Were you over there?
I introduced them UP there.
"Up" there?
- I've things to do!
- Victor!
Ye... you're right of course.
Old fellow like me...
Doesn't make sense.
Okay, I'm going.
I'll go out the back door.
Miss, gentlemen...
Can I offer you a little supper?
Can you ever!
Tell the chef to prepare a supper.
Very well, sir.
May I?
Certaunly.
- Miss Christine, gentlemen...
I like what you're doing...
...and I'd be happy to include you
in our entertainment.
I'm sorry, but this will require
some consideration.
How about we say January 1?
January 1...
That's impossible...
We're under contract...
A very important one.
- All of you?
- Yes, all of us.
- Not Christine.
- No, not Christine.
Can you work as a soloist?
I think I can.
You could do the show,
until we were free.
For sure.
That's an idea... Show them
what you can do without us.
Me too.  I'd very much
like to hear you.
-  "La Vie en rose".
- Certainly.
With eyes which make mine lower,
A smile which is lost on his lips,
That's the unembellished portrait
Of the man to whom I belong.
When he takes me in his arms
He speaks to me in a low voice,
I see life as if it were rose-tinted.
He whispers words of love
Words of the everyday
And that does something to me.
He has entered into my heart
A piece of happiness
the cause of which I know.
It's him for me, me for him
In life
He said that to me, swore to me
Forever
And as soon as I see him
So I feel in me
My heart which beats
May the nights of love never end
A great joy which takes its place
The trouble, the grief are removed
Content, content to die of it
to die of it
When he takes me in his arms
He speaks to me in a very low voice,
I see life as if it were rose-tinted.
He whispers words of love
Words of the everyday
And that does something to me.
He has entered into my heart
A piece of happiness
the cause of which I recognise.
It's him for me, me for him
in life.
He said that to me, swore to me
forever.
And as soon as I see him
So do I feel in me
My heart which beats
La la la...
- Where is he?
- Who?
- The manager.
- I don't know.
I lost it, earlier on.
- What? Your lucky charm?
- Yes, near the door.
And now I know
he knew everything.
- Who?
- His Excellency.
Or rather... the "gentlemen".
- Everything is paid for, even the champagne.
- We start on the 1st.
Great, we'll stay here.
- What did he say?
- To leave them alone.
Okay, who cares?
We'll leave you alone.
Up there, he told me
I'd get my miracle.
You poor kid... you're tired.
You're going home to sleep.
You'll see how everything
will be better for us now.
He said that, too.
To each their own Heaven.
That's the reason why
we listen to accordions.
the street bursts into song.
The sorrow of souls
drowned in sound
is heard no more.
Cupid celebrates
and it's mad for us all.
There's the heart
that you want.
That's the reason why
we listen to accordions.
the street bursts into song.