(dramatic music)
(intense rock music)
(suspenseful music)
[Ninjas] Master.
We have finished the mission.
Right, well done everyone.
The traitor has
been eliminated.
Traitors must die.
To live the life of a ninja
is a sacred way to live.
When we take up the mission,
we must succeed or die.
[Ninjas] Born a
ninja, die a ninja.
(dramatic music)
Good morning, everybody.
This special unit
has been formed
to investigate an international
forgery operation.
Interpol wants us to find out
where the money's coming from.
We've made a few arrests,
but they're only small fry.
Most of them posed as tourists
and passed the notes
in shops and hotels.
Circulation of the
money's increasing.
Well, we have some leads.
This is Bruce,
he's their leader.
And Four Eyes, their broker.
His name's Albert.
And a woman, Susan,
their organizer.
They do all the
real monky business.
They bring in the
money for the gang.
Four Eyes is a powerful man.
Susan also runs a training
school for models.
This is Warren,
our contact man.
He's undercover now.
Andy, John, and myself
will take care of Bruce.
The rest of you will
work with Warren.
This is Four Eyes'
girlfriend, Lily.
Susan's brother David is a
playboy and a troublemaker.
Hi there.
I'm sorry, I just
borrowed your bike.
You did?
(laughs)
Why didn't you ask?
I...
Well, you weren't around.
Bullshit.
Listen, I'm warning you.
That bike's like my girl.
Nobody can touch it.
David, why don't you just
buy your own bike, then?
(chuckles)
He couldn't afford one.
(spits)
(laughing)
(shouts)
(grunting)
(dramatic music)
Get him, there he goes,
quick, come on, get him!
Come back here you coward!
I dare you to come back!
There he is!
We'll get you!
Hey!
Hello, Susan?
Look, I've got the stuff,
the quality's quite
good this time.
[Susan] Thanks
Linda, that's right,
(mumbling)
I'll need 100,000
more for the next time.
Do you think you can do that?
[Susan] Sure,
no problem at all.
We'll start at once.
Very well.
I'm going back to
Paris tomorrow,
so please, can you call
me when it's ready?
Of course, a deal's a deal.
Have a nice trip.
Goodbye.
Same deal next time.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Please sit down.
So, you're Warren Lee?
Yes.
Starting salary
is $3000 a month,
then you'll get extra
for each assignment.
Miss Chernoy.
Oh, please call me Susan.
I'll be honest with you.
I have no experience.
Oh?
Nevermind.
[Warren] I know
I told you I had,
but I'm keen to get into
modeling, so I made it up.
I like people to be honest.
And although you lied,
you're being honest now,
so I'm willing to train you.
Thanks very much.
I'll really try my best.
But above board.
No casting couch.
(chuckles)
(suspenseful music)
Something wrong, boss?
It's very complicated.
Warren, our undercover agent,
has got into Bruce's gang.
But he's been bothered by
a lot of personal problems.
Well, what sort of
personal problems?
Perhaps we can help, sir.
You can't do anything.
Got something to do
with his girlfriend Judy
and his brother David.
Oh.
These are Bruce's henchmen.
We have to get rid of
them to get to him.
Right.
Run a check on them.
Yes sir.
(upbeat music)
(suspenseful music)
(phone ringing)
[Andy] Special Unit.
Is that Andy Howe?
[Andy] Who is this?
Go to Green Park,
there's a surprise for you.
[Andy] Wait a
minute, who is this?
Hey...
(steady rock beat)
Hey Andy.
Do you really believe
that strange call?
Hey, it must be
a present for me.
Come on, I love surprises.
Hey, I'm hungry, let's go eat.
Come on, it's about time
we did something on our own.
(dramatic music)
This is my present?
Huh?
It's Black Dog.
Yeah, one of Bruce's men.
But why's he
dressed like this?
[Andy] Who put these on you?
Only a ninja
can defeat a ninja.
What's a ninja?
Not now, I'll tell you later.
(knocking)
Come in.
[Andy] We got him, sir.
Great.
You both did a great job.
I'm sure it wasn't easy.
Why thank you, sir,
but it was all Andy.
It wasn't easy, you're right.
It was pretty tough, he
put up quite a fight.
Huh?!
But Andy, that's not the way.
It wasn't like that.
Shh.
Black Dog said
something about a ninja.
What's a ninja?
(chuckles)
Just a fairy tale.
They don't exist.
Now there, you see?
I told you they didn't exist.
Morning Miss, your mail.
Thanks.
(phone ringing)
Morning.
- Morning.
Susan.
Oh, hi there.
Take a look at these, a whole
bunch of orders for you.
All thanks to you.
I told you we could make
something out of you, didn't I?
Thanks for the confidence.
You're very welcome.
You deserve it, anyway,
you've worked very hard,
and it should get better.
Now then, to show
my appreciation
for what you've done
for the company,
I'd like to invite you over
to my villa this afternoon,
if you're free,
that is, all right?
I'd be delighted.
Well, I'm very
glad to hear that.
It'll be nice for the two
of us to get together.
How about 3:30, huh?
Right, I'll be there.
(cheerful music)
(laughs)
What a beautiful house.
You like it?
Me?
You mean this is for me?
Yeah, sure, you
made a lot of money.
But I...
I didn't make that much.
Well not yet, but I'm
sure you will in the future.
I've invested all I have in you.
So don't you let me down.
You wouldn't, would you?
Am I right?
Right.
Also, I bought a
fabulous new motorbike.
I think your brother
would love it.
Huh?
[David] It's fantastic.
A great machine.
I've always wanted
one like this.
[Warren] Well
then, do you like it?
It's mine?
Yeah.
The keys.
What?
Are you that rich?
Have you won the lottery?
A new house and a new bike?
[Warren] I won the lottery.
[David] You did?
How come you didn't say?
Anyway, whatever.
Thanks.
(engine starts)
I'll try it out.
Be careful.
Bye.
Warren,
did you do something
illegal to get that?
No.
Well I hope you didn't.
You'd better be true.
[Susan] Yes,
who's this speaking?
Listen Susan,
Tiger was killed.
I'll find out who did it,
but tell Albert to watch out.
Oh, all right.
Right, I'll tell him.
I'll see him very soon.
Okay.
Take care of yourself.
(upbeat music)
You'd like a drink?
Huh?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It doesn't matter.
I was wondering what
you're doing later.
Huh?
Warren.
Oh.
Mrs. Phong.
Now don't you scare him away.
He's very young, you know.
Warren, it's time
that you were on.
Oh.
(chuckles)
Don't forget, I'll be waiting.
Miss Susan.
He looks very promising.
Get me $10,000 US.
That'll be no problem at all.
Good, and don't let me hold
you up, I'll just wait here.
Then excuse me.
Mhmm.
Please, sit down.
(laughing)
Hi Albert.
Tiger's been killed, boss wants
you to keep a low profile.
I must rush now.
Hey, Susan.
Uh huh?
Did he say anything else?
You know, about the operation.
[Susan] Not on the telephone.
Let's change the conversation,
or Lily will get bored.
I'm serious, Susan.
I heard you got a model
called Warren Lee.
Is that right?
Why yes.
[Albert] I'd like
to meet him sometime.
Well, when the time is right,
you can use him for
your next collection.
He looks good in
your sort of design.
[Albert] Right, it's a deal.
Right.
(chuckles)
Bye.
Let's go.
[Man] Hi Bruce.
How you doing?
Fine thank you.
Have you seen the stuff?
Yes.
Quality's good this time.
Very well, just see my man.
Okay, it's a deal.
Have a nice time here.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Hope to see you again.
Well, goodbye.
(tires squeal)
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
Wait.
Take him back.
Yeah.
Come on, move!
(mysterious music)
Keep up the good work.
[Andy] Well, it's an easy job.
I arrested another
fairy tale yesterday.
A ninja's supposed
to be unbeatable.
I'd like to meet a
real ninja one day.
Don't tell me you
believe in ninjas.
Of course not.
You said ninjas don't exist.
That's right.
Now Susan's beginning
to trust Warren,
but now he's playing
around with Lily,
Four Eyes' girlfriend.
What a lucky guy.
Do you want to change places?
Oh no no, no thank you, sir.
Right now the important thing
is for Warren to get
evidence against Four Eyes.
(light rock music)
Hey Mister.
You looking for a
bit of company, huh?
(sighs)
Hey Miss, want a drink?
Yeah, come on.
Yeah.
(chuckling)
(drunken muttering)
Hey, wait a minute
guys, wait a minute.
Excuse me.
She's a normal customer.
Oh, what, it won't hurt
her to have a drink with us.
Ah, that's right,
what's wrong with us, eh?
Why not have a drink with me?
Get off!
Hey come on, no
need to be like that.
(shouting)
What do you
think you're doing?
(shouting)
(screams)
(slow music)
Feeling better?
I know you, I saw you
at Susan's fashion show.
(giggles)
(romantic music)
(moaning)
(eerie music)
I hate you.
Warren.
Judy.
Talk to me.
Warren!
(intense music)
(phone ringing)
Yeah.
Hi Philip, Bruce here.
Have you got that
photo of Jason Hart?
Right here, boss.
What do you want me to do, huh?
Go and finish him.
Be careful, he's tough.
Yes boss.
Do it, quickly.
(dramatic music)
(suspenseful music)
(grunts)
Nurse, can you help me?
Where's Judy Chan?
Oh, first room.
[David] Warren.
David.
What's going on?
How's Judy?
Still alive.
Hey.
What's the matter?
It's all your
fault, messing around.
How could you do this?
I've tried all night
long to get ahold of you.
Where the hell were you?
No bloody answer.
(sighs)
You listen.
If Judy dies, I'll
never forgive you.
Brother or not.
David!
Go in and see Judy,
it's the very least
you could do for her now.
Judy.
It's Warren.
Please wake up.
Judy.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry.
So sorry.
(crying)
I tried to call you last night.
But Judy, your phone
was out of order.
I was terribly busy.
The time just went.
Forgive me.
You've changed, Warren.
You never used to be like this.
(crying)
Judy, I love you.
I never realized how much.
Can you please forgive me?
Judy, I'll stop modeling.
We can be together.
You're all I want now.
Forever and ever.
Judy.
Promise me you'll get well.
We'll start again.
Just you and me forever.
All right?
Warren.
(knocking)
[David] Hi.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for Warren Lee.
Is this where he lives?
Yes.
What do you want?
And you are?
I'm his neighbor.
And you?
I'm just a friend.
Oh.
He's gone to see his girlfriend.
She's in the hospital.
I don't know what
time he'll be back.
Sometimes very late.
Why don't you give me a message,
and I'll give it to him?
What's your name?
You could tell
him Lily called by.
Right.
(laughing)
David!
You okay?
Are you hurt?
Never you mind.
Piss off.
David.
You again?
Hey man, you're still here, huh?
David, are these
creeps your friends?
(grunting)
He's my brother.
Really gets up my nose.
Let's go.
David.
You're drunk.
Let us take you home.
What?
(chuckles)
I've got no home,
and neither do you.
That place belongs to
Warren, and his girlfriend.
David.
What are you talking about?
Bull.
Don't give me that.
I'm sorry.
But you've gotta
know, sooner or later.
David.
Right.
David!
Hey, hey.
I'm not gonna tell you
again, you asshole.
(grunting)
Taxi!
Follow that bike.
David!
Wait for me!
(laughing)
Come on, let's go for a swim.
All right.
(laughing)
Whee!
David come back here!
David!
Come on, David!
(laughing)
You gonna swim with
your clothes on?
Oh!
(laughing)
David!
Come back here!
(laughing)
David!
Stop it, get off!
David, don't be so
stupid, come on home!
Get off!
Leave me alone!
Come on, we're going home!
What for?
David!
Come on!
Let go!
David, let's go home, come on!
And you!
(screams)
Judy!
Are you okay?
David!
David, come back here!
[Judy] David, come here!
Stay with me!
David!
(grunting)
Please will you stop fighting?
Stop it!
David!
Get off!
Stop it!
Stop fighting, Warren, David!
Stop fighting please!
Stop it!
You, look at your face.
Huh?
David, Warren, stop it!
No more fighting,
please stop it now!
You dirty bastard.
Look, I don't
want to talk here.
Let's go home.
David, stop it!
Come on, smack him!
David!
Listen to me!
You don't understand.
You're right, I
don't understand.
What the hell do
you want to know?!
Me?
(groaning)
You'll understand later.
(grunting)
Warren.
David!
Warren, wait for me.
You're a real hero, David!
Does it hurt?
(upbeat music)
Warren!
Hold these.
Why are you here?
Well, I missed you.
You weren't in when I called by.
What have you done to your
face, have you been in a fight?
Judy, I...
You've got a nerve, kid.
And so have you.
Just get lost.
Judy!
[Lily] Warren!
Leave me alone!
Warren, Warren I've
got to talk to you...
Get lost, get lost!
Stay away from me!
But that night, you
said you loved me.
(sighs)
Did I?
That'll teach you to
listen to a drunkard.
Anyway, how did you get my
address, and my phone number?
Tell me!
Susan.
[Warren] Warren here.
Warren.
You're doing too much,
so don't go any further.
You could destroy
the plan, understand?
(knocking)
Yeah, come in.
Sir, the trap's been
set for tomorrow evening
at the Gold Pass Park.
We could bag $2 million.
That's right,
it'll be a big haul.
Excellent.
Right.
(suspenseful music)
Very good.
It's a deal.
If you need any
more, let me know.
Oh yeah, one more thing.
You're under arrest.
You!
(coughing)
Well he can't have gone far.
Hey, look.
It's him!
Another one dressed like this.
Who put these on?
Only a ninja can defeat
another ninja, see?
Have you heard that
line before somewhere?
[John] I think I have.
Andy.
John.
What's going on here?
We got this guy, sir.
Well done, men.
It's another one
dressed like this, sir.
Hmm, looks like another
costume party tonight.
Mhmm.
All right, men.
Let's move on.
- Yes sir.
(suspenseful music)
We lost three men, but
our ninja spirit never dies.
To die the death of a ninja
is a glorious way to die.
[Ninjas] Born
ninja, die ninja.
Our birth is at
the dawn of time.
When we embark upon a
mission, we fear nothing.
If our enemies rise, elimate.
If nations, obliterate.
If evil rises, destroy.
Once a ninja, always a ninja.
Judy.
Listen to me.
(knocking)
(suspenseful music)
[Judy] David.
Warren and I have talked
things over, and it's okay now.
He explained that he's
been under pressure,
and things got out of hand.
He's agreed to give up
modeling immediately
and lead a normal life.
Look after yourself.
Love, Judy.
(intense rock music)
Hey, they look great, huh?
(laughs)
I like the guy more
than the clothes.
Oh don't be silly!
This time the
quality's quite good.
Great.
(light rock music)
(laughs)
Susan.
Huh?
Why don't you introduce
your friend to me?
Oh, Albert, this is Warren.
Ah.
This is my card.
Mr. Wong, Mrs. Wong.
(chuckles)
We're not exactly married.
However, we are
very close friends.
(laughing)
Don't be confused.
Lily is his right hand woman.
(chuckling)
Yes.
She's my live-in lover.
It's not confusing.
(laughing)
[Susan] Oh Albert,
don't be so blunt,
you made Lily blush again.
(laughing)
Susan.
Don't be so old-fashioned.
Times have changed.
Anyway, you've been in
this business a while.
You know the score.
Warren, am I right?
(chuckles)
Warren, you can ask her
to dance if you like.
I'm not her jailer, huh?
[Susan] Oh, Albert, stop it.
We all know you're
really jealous of Lily.
No one would dare
dance with her.
(laughing)
[Waitress] Excuse me.
I told you.
You can dance.
I don't mind that.
Go ahead.
[Susan] Go on.
* I can hardly
see in front of me
* At last I am free
* I can hardly
see in front of me
* At last I am free
* I can hardly
see in front of me
(chuckles)
Susan, don't they make
a good-looking couple?
Made for each other.
* At last I am free
* I can hardly
see in front of me
* I can hardly see in front
I've got it here, sir.
* Of me
(dramatic music)
Well, Albert, I was...
Oh.
(crying)
How dare you cheat.
You bitch!
How could you?!
You cow!
Oh you get me mad!
(whimpers)
Tell me.
How many times did you do it?
Huh?
Tell me!
Does he do it better?
Huh?
Tell me!
Talk.
Huh?
You little whore.
You're just a cheap slut.
(screaming)
I'm gonna kill you.
(whipping)
I hate you.
You can't run away.
Come back here.
Please don't.
Help!
Come here.
I'll get you.
Yelling for help, huh?
I'll show you.
I won't forgive you.
How dare you.
(screaming)
You'll never betray me again!
You common whore!
Morning sir.
We caught another
one of those guys
that you said don't exist.
What were they called?
Ninjas?
Possibly he was on his
way to a costume party?
Be serious.
Listen, Warren has
followed our plan.
Four Eyes and Susan are
falling into our trap.
We should be able to
clear this up soon.
(eerie music)
Now get outta here!
(suspenseful music)
The notes?
Yes, you got the money?
Here.
Let me see it.
That's all right.
You're under arrest!
Huh?
Hey!
Let me go, you son of a bitch!
(dramatic music)
(steam hissing)
(swords clanging)
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
Not many people refuse me.
You see, I carry quite a bit
of weight in the business.
Most people want to
succeed, and don't care how.
It's a hard world out there,
and opportunities
don't come easily.
Most people want
fame, money and power.
Usually, people don't care where
the money comes from or how.
And are you really
any different?
Or just a better
line of bullshit?
But I'm sure
you're not like that.
You're too kind.
Of course.
It doesn't hurt to be kind.
But I'm no fool.
I have my motives.
(chuckles)
I find kindness
very effective, hmm?
So Warren, even though you
won't be working for me,
I'd like to give
you a little gift.
There's no need
for that, really.
(laughs)
No need?
Hey, I'd like to.
I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
I ordered it to be sent to
your home as soon as possible.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Oh, you might like to
know what I gave him.
(laughing)
You bastard.
Bastard, bastard,
bastard, bastard,
I hate you!
Judy, I...
Get off.
Don't come near me.
Judy!
Leave me alone!
Judy.
Judy!
How could you?
Go to hell.
(suspenseful music)
David.
Where are you going?
I'm leaving too.
As of now, I have no brother.
David!
(intense music)
(phone ringing)
Hello?
[Jason] Hello?
Warren's that you?
Yes.
Look, I know this
is a tricky situation.
Warren, I understand
your feelings.
But this is a critical moment.
Tell your brother
not to fool around.
Otherwise, our
mission will fail.
Have you got that?
I'll contact you, okay?
He's coming.
All right?
Ready?
Okay.
(yells)
He's out cold.
Now do the rest.
(dramatic music)
Come on.
Go on, faster.
Faster.
Hurry up.
Pull him faster.
Come on.
Go.
Faster.
Hurry up.
Come on, you guys.
Pull.
(shouting)
Get outta here, go!
(whimpering)
[Woman] David?
David!
David.
Oh David, what's
happened to you?
Why've you been fighting?
Hey Mary, he's dead!
You've hurt yourself.
David, what are you gonna do?
David, you'll get into
real trouble, you will.
The other guys will tell
the police, I tell you.
What?
What can I do?
Come on, David,
we'll hide you.
Yeah, come on David!
(suspenseful music)
Yeah.
I'll be waiting for you
at the Fung Chow Hotel.
You can get my room
number from reception.
I want to tell you about
Albert's illegal businesses.
It's the only thing
that's gonna save us.
He'll never forgive
either of us.
I don't care.
[Lily] Oh look,
don't be silly.
You're in danger at the moment.
So what?
It doesn't matter to me.
[Lily] Warren, listen to me.
There you are.
Take the money.
And here's my name card.
Use it if you need any help.
Well go on.
Everybody knows that I like
to help people in trouble.
Here.
Thank you sir.
(chuckles)
It's a pleasure.
Mr. Albert can
settle anything.
(laughs)
Not at all, not at all.
Remember to repay
him when you can.
You owe your life to him.
Of course I will.
I'll pay you back
as soon as possible.
Yeah.
It's okay.
Take your time.
Thanks, goodbye.
Come on.
One moment.
Would you mind
telling me your name?
I'm David Lee?
David?
Do you know Warren Lee?
He's my brother.
Would you mind
sitting down a minute?
Come, over here.
Oh.
I don't know if you know
this, but he's in grave danger.
Danger?
Sit down.
Right.
Her?
You know her?
She's my girlfriend,
but she cheated on me.
You know your brother's
just a gigolo.
He says they're just
business partners.
I expect Lily to be faithful
to me, that's our deal.
But she's made a
complete fool of me.
I don't know how your
brother found out,
but Lily's scared and he's
meeting her at 7:30 tonight,
in the Fung Chow Hotel.
She's planning to kill him.
What?
You're a good boy.
David, you don't want to see
your brother killed, do you?
You could help him out.
You could prevent
him from death.
Great.
(eerie music)
(laughing)
Well I hope he dies.
Why?
He whispered "Anne" to me
right at the wrong moment.
(laughing)
Boss, we beat him up,
just so he could get killed.
Oh, so he can convalesce here.
I'll pay for it.
Thank you boss.
I'll see you in the morning.
Thank you, boss.
(chuckling)
(dramatic music)
Now Miss, here's your key.
Thank you, I'm expecting a
visitor, please send him up.
All right.
(intense music)
Miss?
Yes?
Which room is Lily Mack in?
Just a minute.
305.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
David.
(crying)
Quiet!
Stop crying!
Or I'll kill you!
Now listen.
Stay away from my brother.
If you hurt him at
all, you're dead meat!
(crying)
(eerie music)
Yes?
Who is it?
(dramatic music)
(screams)
Thank you.
Not at all.
I've done it, boss.
It's all over.
Lily's been killed.
Lily?
(dramatic music)
Lily!
Susan, I'm gonna give
you an important mission,
so report to me right away.
Okay, I've got that sir,
I'm on my way already.
(suspenseful music)
This is a blood mission.
We must rise above all emotion
and overcome our desire.
We must devote ourselves
to our sacred cause.
To live the life of a ninja
is a sacred way to live.
This I know.
You are a good ninja.
Remember, the ninja empire
shall be supreme, and righteous.
(shouts)
Judy, still here?
Why are you so late, David?
Something awful's happened.
Really?
Your brother's been
implicated in a case of murder.
He's what?!
He was meeting that creature
Lily at the Fung Chow Hotel.
She had something to tell him.
But just after he left,
she was found murdered!
And my brother?
The police said
Lily was killed
minutes after Warren arrived.
He was still holding the
knife that killed her.
His prints were on the door.
I can hardly believe it.
He'd never do
anything like that.
I've been desperate
waiting for you.
What can we do?
What?
God dammit.
Albert Wong's tricked me.
I'll kill him!
Calm down.
I must equal the score.
(motorcycle revving)
Oh no.
David!
Come back.
Come back!
(laughing)
Warren's been charged,
and I dare say, David will
be involved before very long.
(laughing)
And we can
congratulate ourselves.
(laughing)
Boss, we'd never let you down,
you know us better than that.
(laughing)
Here, go and enjoy yourselves.
You've earned
every dollar of it.
Come on, guys.
Let's hit the town!
Thanks, big brother.
We're off now.
See you later.
Hey, I wanna come!
Mary, stay here.
Now learn from what you
know and don't follow Lily,
all right?
I'm not that stupid.
(laughing)
(loud chattering)
(grunting)
(yells)
[David] No, no.
No.
Please.
(grunting)
(laughing)
(yells)
(dramatic music)
(gun fires)
(yells)
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
No wait.
It's...
It's a misunderstanding.
I didn't know he
was your brother.
Please don't hurt me.
I'll give you anything you want.
I swear to god.
Warren.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
(whimpering)
(grunting)
(dramatic music)
(gun fires)
(yells)
(grunts)
David!
David?
It's all right now.
Please wake up.
David!
It's really interesting,
all these ninjas,
don't you think?
I mean...
(clears throat)
Oh, sir.
You got a gift here.
Who sent it?
[Andy] I don't know.
Hey, they're good
looking swords.
[Andy] Why the red cloth?
It's a ninja legend.
When a long sword is on
top of a short sword,
and covered with a red
cloth, it means a challenge.
No one can turn
down the challenge.
You're gonna
accept the challenge?
You are a ninja, aren't you?
(suspenseful music)
(exploding)
(revving engine)
(engine idling)
(suspenseful music)
(steel ringing)
(steam hissing)
(eerie music)
I am the champion
of the ninjas.
(intense music)