TOEI COMPANY, LTD.
TRIALS OF AN OKINAWA VILLAGE
APRIL 1945 U.S. TROOPS
ADVANCE ON TO OKINAWAN SOIL
THE BOMBINGS WERE SO FIERCE,
IT WAS NAMED THE METAL TYPHOON.
250,00 LIVES WERE LOST AND OKINAWA
WAS TAKEN OVER WITHIN TWO MONTHS.
OKINAWA IN STATE OF RECOVERY
UNDER U.S. OCCUPATION.
Produced by:
Koji SHUNDO and Goro KUSAKABE
Screenplay by: Kazuo KASAHARA
Photography by: Sadaji YOSHIDA
Lighting by: Yoshiaki MASUDA
Sound recording by: Masayoshi MIZOGUCHI
Art Direction by: Takatoshi SUZUKI
Music by: Toshiaki TSUSHIMA
Editor: Shintaro MIYAMOTO
CAST
Junko FUJI
It's car number 2.
Kyosuke MACHIDA, Minoru OKI
Eizo KITAMURA, Kenji USHIO, Toshiaki MINAMI
Shinji, this is no time to be daydreaming!
I'm worried about my gas,
so I can't go any faster.
OK. I'll do something about that,
so just use what you have.
OK!
Don't dilly-dally!
See you later!
Bin AMATSU, Michitaro MIZUSHIMA
Thanks for waiting!
I'll leave the rest up to you!
Bunta SUGAWARA
Directed by: Shigehiro OZAWA
Isamu...
I guess that's where it all is.
Shall we have a little fun?
In other words, he's saying
he can't just give a pig that
wandered into a military zone back
that easily, so how about a date?
I think it might work out.
Let's challenge him
to a barrel with this.
You got a deal.
He said he wants
a date and a kiss and
if he loses he'll
give us two barrels.
Are you sure?
No way!
Is this truck number 32
This is the new addition
to Yonamine Transport.
This one is good.
It's great about getting a new
truck, but we have no gas.
We have to do something.
I told the boss, but...
Hey!
Look, we got three barrels!
Where did you get that?
The boss won it in a poker match.
You did it again. I thought
I told you not to do that.
The new truck is here...
We're going to have a party tonight!
What's tomorrow's schedule like?
This is it...
I'll drive tomorrow, so could
you watch the office?
I can't let you take
all the burden yourself.
Don't worry about it.
I'm just doing what my parents
did to build this company
to what it is today.
But...
If they didn't die in the war,
you wouldn't be doing this...
Don't talk about that!
I thought I made you promise
me that you wouldn't treat me
like a girl until I rebuild this
company to what it used to be.
I'm sorry.
Isamu... you look happy.
Did something happen?
We got a new truck, so I can
drive starting tomorrow.
You're finally a full-fledged driver.
Don't get too close in front
of all these people.
Why?
Our boss lost someone
she loved in the war.
I didn't know that.
Gunso, are you thinking about
the main island again?
I'm fine when I'm working, but
I start to remember the past
when I come to places like this.
Was your home in Kumamoto?
Why don't you go home once?
Everyone thinks I was shot and
killed after escaping a POW camp.
I can't go home now...
I'm sure my wife
forgot about me by now.
Who are those guys?
They're some yakuza that
came from the main island.
They're always like this.
Don't let them get to you.
Would you like some flowers?
Give me one.
Me, too!
They're such cheap flowers.
Is this the only kind of flowers
you have in Okinawa?
I bet you have better flowers...
Stop that!
Are you all right?
You're quite a beauty.
You shouldn't be using
things like that...
The people of Okinawa
fight one on one.
I'm Okinawan.
I can't fight with a woman, but
anyone want to take me on?
I'll take you on.
I'm Daisuke Iba.
Third level Shuriken.
I'm Kensaku Yashiro. Judo.
That's it.
The fight is over.
We fight until someone dies.
Get out of the way.
Are you dissatisfied with my judgment?
Your judgment?
I don't need to be humiliated.
Teach me something.
Very well.
Stop right there.
You're quite the brave one.
I'm Iwamatsu.
I hear you own a trucking company.
I'm Yuri Yonamine.
I run a business as well.
Can we just call it water under
the bridge and talk business?
Unfortunately, I have work to do, so...
I'm sorry we got in
the way of your work.
I'll buy all of that.
I'll hold it.
Thank you.
I wish you would stop
doing this kind of work.
Yes...
But, my village has a lot of
debt and we all have to
work or we won't be
able to repay the debt.
Where is your village?
Aragusuku in Gushikami.
Aragusuku?
Boss, I'll take her home.
I'm fine.
I always walk home when I'm late.
Why don't you stay
at my place tonight?
I'll take you home with
my car in the morning.
Thank you.
What happened to your leg?
I hurt it when I was little in the war.
What about your family?
My grandmother and I
are the only survivors.
Have a good night's rest.
This cave is completely
surrounded by the U.S.
We will prepare ourselves
to proudly sacrifice our lives
for our country.
Follow me!
For those who don't follow me,
I want you to use
the weapons I just gave
you to take your lives.
Father... Mother...
You're still young.
You don't have to die. Escape.
I don't need this anymore.
I have a younger sister that
is about the same age as you.
I was told she died in an air raid.
Don't die.
Be careful.
Thank you very much.
I'll walk you home.
Do you know the house that was here?
No. Did it belong to someone you knew?
It's where my mother was born.
So you're from this village, too.
Yes, but all of my
relatives died in the war.
I haven't been here in a long time.
Sachiko, what happened
to you last night?
Your grandma was waiting for you.
I stayed at her place
since it was too late.
Thank you.
I'm Keisuke Asada, the mayor here.
I'm Yuri Yonamine.
Yuri?
So you're Rika's daughter.
She used to live here.
Yes.
Is that so?
I've heard about you.
I'm glad to see you doing well.
Your mother and I used to play
together when we were little.
This used to be a
quiet village back then.
This became a battleground
during the war where most
of the families in
this village have died.
How about your family?
Yes, my parents and my siblings.
I was away at war...
I'm still happy to be alive
even with this injury.
How about your mother?
She died with my father near Mabuni.
I see.
I'm sure you had a hard
time after the war.
No...
I was preoccupied with work
and never even had time to
think about my mother's hometown at all.
I learned for the first time
yesterday that you're
all struggling here.
Please tell me if there's
anything I can do.
We borrowed a lot of money
to start this sugarcane field.
This land was bare until
last year and we felt we
had to do something, so
we borrowed some money
from a loan company and
planted these sugarcanes
from seedlings that we got from Hawaii.
The sugarcane is doing well,
but we aren't able
to pay the monthly interest
on the loan, and if we don't
do something, all of our profits
will be taken away after November.
I'm responsible for all of this,
but everyone has
been helping selling flowers and such...
How much did you borrow?
12,000 dollars.
Our village is so poor.
We don't have anything we
could soil to make money.
All we have are just these things.
Are there more?
Yes.
We found a lot when we
were cultivating the land.
We put them all at that
garbage dump over there.
Price for scrap has gone up.
Why don't you sell these?
We thought about it, but we don't
have any means to transport it.
I'll help you.
But, you have other
jobs to take care of.
I don't mind. Please allow me.
Yuri...
Hey! The truck is here!
What do you think you're doing?
I'm sorry.
Sony?
We work here. Be careful, you fool!
I'm the supervisor here.
Please have a seat.
You seem quite busy.
Let me get right to the point.
How much per ton will you
give us for today's delivery?
It doesn't look like you have
anything of much value.
It would help us greatly if you
would buy it at market price.
Our village depends on it.
The policy says that we only
need to pay you a service fee
for bringing the scrap since the U.S.
military takes care of all of that.
Yes, but it goes for 50 dollars
per ton when handed off
to the U.S. military and 10 times as
much when it's sold to the main island.
We can have you take it back
if you're going to be trouble.
We're the only ones that have
been granted special rights
to gather these scraps.
You should watch your attitude here.
I apologize if I was rude.
I'm making a request.
We haven't settled our fight
from last night either.
Let me think about it.
Will you be able to pay for it now?
After it sells.
That's fine. Thank you very much.
Aren't you the mayor of Aragusuku?
Yes.
I'm asking you this as a personal favor.
Could you deliver this to my family?
I can't leave this place since
they're watching me.
Watching you?
They're putting the scraps
on a black market ship.
What?
Please...
I heard rumors, but
I can't believe it's true.
Boss, we found this in the
scrap that they just brought.
Is it a live bomb?
No, this is an old Japanese artillery.
It belonged to the Japanese military?
Boss, I heard about a cave
near Aragusuku that they
used as a storage for artillery.
This might be...
Are there a lot of caves near Aragusuku?
Yes.
If the storage is untouched
then there must be a lot.
The U.S. military doesn't know
about it, so this would be a
huge treasure chest to send to Hong Kong.
This is interesting.
Let's get that artillery and
make some money.
Iba, I want you to be the
lead and check it out.
Yes.
Stop.
You can't go through past this point.
On whose orders?
We're representatives of the military.
Just do as we say.
Get out of here.
How's it going?
I want you to be thorough.
What are you doing?
Stop!
The sugarcane is our livelihood!
Please make them stop.
We need to do this for
our excavation project.
I hope you're going to
compensate us for this.
Just plant it again.
You...
There are a lot of soldiers'
remains in this cave!
I'm responsible for this property until
all of those remains are removed!
I won't let you do this!
Just do as you want.
I'm going to go ahead with out plans.
Ma'am!
And you call yourselves Japanese?
Do you know how hard these people
worked to plant this sugarcane?
Mr. Iba, you're an Okinawan.
I'm sure you understand.
Just get out of here.
I'm not going to move until
you leave this place.
Yuri, let me handle this.
Mr. Iwamatsu, if you insist
on continuing your work,
then I have a plan as well.
I'm going to confirm with
the military whether your
actions are legal or not.
That's fine.
I have a friend that's an officer.
Would you like me to
introduce you to him?
I'm going to ask about your black
market in Hong Kong as well!
I don't know what you're
talking about, but do
whatever you want!
Help me!
Boss, it seems he asked
them to deliver a message.
I just wanted to send my
wife and kids some money.
I was paying you so well.
You're such a fool.
I was able to figure most of it out.
How was it?
Toyo Industries is registered
under a foreign name and
it seems Iwamatsu owns
the rights to the company.
It seems they use that
foreigner to get the ship
to transport the scraps to Hong Kong.
Unfortunately, I don't know what port.
What's the foreigner's name?
James Harrison.
That's all I need to know.
I'm going to see the general.
I'll go with you.
No, I'll be fine by myself.
Please pretend that you
don't know anything if
the U.S. military asks you.
Mayor!
Mr. Asato!
Yuri...
Please take care of the sugarcane field.
Mr. Asato!
You must be Mr. Nakagami.
I work for the Iwamatsu group.
I'm here to pick you up.
Please...
Iwamatsu group?
You have the wrong person.
Wait a minute. Just get in.
Sit there and wait.
Are you deaf?
You fool!
Don't be rude to our guest.
Mr. Nakagami, I'm sorry for the
way my boys are behaving.
I'm Gunji Iwamatsu of the
Iwamatsu group of Kyushu.
I guess you know who I am.
I'm Nakagami from Tokyo,
but what do you want from me?
This is a newspaper
from the main island.
There's a huge article.
NAKAGAMI GROUP LEADER...
NATIONWIDE SEARCH!
I received a message from
my office in Kyushu that
you were going to
enter Okinawa illegally.
I thought it would be rude
if we ignored that message,
so I sent my boys to pick you up.
Please enjoy yourself
while you're here.
Thank you for your
hospitality, but I've
been a lone wolf my entire life.
I don't want to be obligated to anyone.
I fought against the Americans
here during the war.
I lost a lot of men...
...And there are those I want to see.
So, please don't worry about me.
I just want to relax
and walk around town.
If that's what you want.
But please let us know if
we can be of any help.
Would you be able to loan me a car?
Sure.
That guy...
Oh, be quiet.
He's so persistent.
Be careful!
Right back at you!
Is there some rule that
says I can't pass you?
We drive on the right
in Okinawa, so if you
want to pass someone
you pass them on the left.
I forgot. I was wrong.
But you sure are rough.
I can't believe you're a woman.
I'm not a woman.
Do what you want.
What's with that guy?
Where are you headed for?
To Aragusuku.
Were you hired by Iwamatsu, too?
No, but I'm surprised
you're so informed.
You're going to help him
dig up some artillery, rights?
Artillery?
I'm going to see some friends.
So you were in the
battle here in Okinawa?
We lost the war while I was
injured in the hospital.
I'm going to see the man
who saved my life.
I heard he's the mayor of Aragusuku now.
Is his name Asato?
Yes, do you know him?
Mr. Asato died.
Died?
We're laying him to rest today.
Hurry up!
Don't dilly-dally!
I know!
Hurry up!
It looks like it would be around here.
Carry this.
That's so dangerous.
So are you saying Iwamatsu's
boys did this to him?
I can't confirm it,
but I'm sure they did.
He was a good man.
He would never have any enemies.
How dare they...
But, aren't you a yakuza like them?
Yoshiko...
Mom...
Mom!
Mr. Iwamatsu.
Young lady...
I need to talk to you.
Let's have a drink.
This is no time to be drinking.
You...
Three mothers have died
because of you.
So what?
Mr. Iwamatsu, let's have you
pay for their compensation
and for the scrap that
we delivered to you.
Unfortunately, we'll be
handing it over to the
U.S. military since there were some
hazardous materials in that delivery.
We have nothing to do
with the three that died.
They were careless, that's all.
You forced them to work there!
We didn't force anyone.
This is the deed for the land that the
mayor used as collateral to get the loan.
I paid it off for them.
We settled it by having the
people of Aragasuku pay
this off by working for us.
We have the new mayor's signature as well.
Do you still have more to say?
Go on home.
Mr. Iwamatsu, I'm still not convinced.
If you insist on continuing
what you're doing, I'll
go directly to the GHQ myself.
I won't die that
easily like Mr. Asato.
You!
Don't be pulling things like that
in front of people.
Mr. Iwamatsu, it looks like you
have a lot going on here.
I know where that storage
that you're looking for is.
You?
I was the leader of the
heavy artillery regiment.
So I've been to the cave many
times to retrieve weapons.
Where is it?
Calm down.
It's been a while, so my
memory isn't too clear yet.
Why don't we sit down
and talk about it?
I have something to talk
to you about later.
Let me handle this and go on home.
Mr. Nakagami, please have a seat.
Please give this to the
children from today...
How about rethinking
what you're doing?
I have a criminal record,
so Iwamatsu was the only
one who would hire me.
I made Iwamatsu agree that he would
stop all work until I finish my research.
He's such a greedy fool.
I don't have to do any research.
And?
I want to borrow your truck.
If my calculations are correct,
we should be
able to transport all of the
artillery in three days
using all three trucks all day.
I talked to Shinwa Industries
to do this sale under the table.
That should take care of the debt.
I understand what you want to do, but
please get the money for the
children that lost
their mothers from Iwamatsu first.
We can use the money that we'll
get from selling the artillery.
I need you to do this or
I won't be able to trust you.
You're in the same business
as Iwamatsu, right?
The village people aren't going
to work for you otherwise.
Yes, I am a yakuza.
But I'm not like Iwamatsu.
I was known as Nakagami of Ginza.
I've never scammed a commoner.
Then I would like you to do
the right thing here.
I want to take revenge for Mr. Asato.
Don't you understand that?
I can't go to that village until
we compensate the children
for losing their mothers.
I was the reason why
this whole thing started.
All right.
I won't ask for your help!
You're so stubborn!
You're the one that's stubborn!
I can't believe you're a woman.
The Okinawan women I met
during the war were much cuter.
I think you should trust him.
The Okinawan women I met
during the war were much cuter.
Who's there?
It's you.
What are you doing here?
You're that girl?
Don't die.
Ma'am.
I have some great news.
The fishermen have been
bringing up loads of
abandoned artillery
that are under water.
They just want the gunpowder, so they
don't know what to do with the scraps.
It seems they have enough
to fill two truckloads.
We can sell that without going
through Iwamatsu.
Yes, it's Shinwa Industries'
jurisdiction, so we should
be able to get enough to
compensate the children.
Let's go!
Thank you.
Gunso! Are you all right?
I can't move my legs.
Hold on!
It's a time bomb.
Boss, get out!
You, too!
It's a time bomb.
I must have triggered the timer.
Hurry! Get out of here.
Tell the everyone to take cover.
Run!
Please run!
What happened?
Mr. Nakagami, there's a man
stuck under a time bomb.
A time bomb?
Boss... don't worry about me.
Please get out of here.
Boss.
Mr. Nakagami..
The timer is moving.
Get me some tools and don't
let anyone come
within 500 meters of this place.
Get out of here.
I'm going to help.
You fool!
I said go!
Gunso, do you remember
any military songs?
Sing it to me.
Ma'am!
It's done.
Thank you, Mr. Nakagami.
Yuri...
I came here because I wanted
to talk to you again.
I've become someone not
worthy of respect, but
you should go back to being
the cute girl you used to be.
You'll be happier that way.
Please don't ruin the dream
of a man who
came all the way here to see you.
I don't like men from the main island.
My late mother always said
people from the
main island were very nice,
but they all just
passed through Okinawa.
They never looked at the
reality of this island.
Those people who just
pass through this island
will never know how we really feel.
But, I'll help you from tomorrow.
It's here.
It's a pit viper.
It's over here.
Some of these still have their fuses,
so tell your men to be careful.
Yes.
Be careful.
Please let us help you.
This is dangerous, so please
don't come near here.
Thank you.
It's heavy.
Please be careful.
The rest of you can come this way.
Thank you.
That Nakagami...
Start the preparations.
Do whatever you need to do
to stop Nakagami.
I won't let you tell me no.
I understand.
Get it ready.
Thank you.
They're coming!
You idiot!
Isamu!
Kanamaru!
Nakagami, I'm here to take your life!
Do you work for Iwamatsu?
Mr. Iba...
Don't kill him.
Please spare his life. Please!
Yuri... He's...
Mr. Iba... Go...
Isamu...
They were going to get
married next month.
Yes?
Is a man by the name of
Tetsu Nakagami here?
He's on suspicion of entering
illegally with a fake passport.
We're going to search the premises.
Get out of my way.
Wait...
Please wait!
There's no one by that name here.
Iwamatsu ratted me out.
Don't be foolish.
Okinawa is not like Japan.
It's controlled by the U.S.
Let me handle Iwamatsu.
You should go back to the main island.
How do I get there?
I guess a person from Nagoya
can't communicate with
a person from Okinawa.
Nakagami...
No, he's not a fish monger.
Be quiet!
Nakagami!
Are you crazy?
That's right! What?
Excuse me. Let me cross.
It's so hot here in Okinawa.
Why I am running?
I didn't do anything.
I'm from Kanto...
Kanto is a big area...
I was born near Sumida River.
My grandparents were born
in Asakusa, too.
Please...
It's here.
Is he really here?
Gunso... this man is
looking for Mr. Nakagami.
Nice to meet you.
Is that the office?
Ouch!
Hey!
Come out here!
Hide!
Boss...
I'm sorry, I didn't know it was you.
I'm so sorry.
Why are you under the truck?
I've come to rescue you.
It's been a while.
That's dirty!
Fool.
Ouch.
Boss, the coast is clear.
This is the only kind of place
I can have a drink
since they're all after me.
Thank you for waiting.
How did you get here?
From Kagoshima...
That's creepy...
There's a hole...
The ear...
I entered here illegally.
I'm sorry.
Yes...
Have some.
This? No way!
How did it go in Tokyo?
The Daitokai group came
to apologize to us.
One of their men testified that
you weren't at the scene.
I see.
Boss... please come home
as soon as possible.
We have more territory and more jobs.
Everyone is waiting for you.
I did it...
It stinks.
I didn't think it would be good
to bring cash, so
I brought the checkbook and your stamp.
I'm not going home to Tokyo.
What did you just say?
I'm leaving the group.
I want you to talk it over with
everyone and manage the group.
Boss, are you serious?
I'll pay my respects
once I'm done here.
I have a favor to ask of you.
Could you let me write any amount
I want as a severance pay?
Please tell them this
is my last request.
Boss... never mind about the money...
I guess it wasn't a good idea to
come to a place that's so hot.
You really do go senile...
Can't you walk faster?
Listen up!
You all have a 12,000 dollar debt!
You better work hard!
Boss, I have a favor to ask of you.
Could you stop making the women
and elderly do this hard labor?
- It's too dangerous.
- We don't have time.
We need to clean it all up
by today or tomorrow if
we want to put it on that
boat to Hong Kong.
But, we've had an accident before...
Who do you think you are
talking to me like that?
You can't even do one thing right.
Boss...
I can't take this anymore.
Please let me leave.
What?
Please...
Boss...
Who do you think took you
in when you were
homeless and made you into
the man you are today?
How dare you forget that.
Iba, I'll take care of you later.
Hurry up!
She was hiding in the village.
What do you think she could do?
What?
She's for our enjoyment!
Get back to work!
Let me go!
Help me!
Stop!
Look over there!
Stay down.
They're threatening the
people with their guns
and doing things I can't bear to watch.
They have the entire village surrounded
and there's no way you can get in.
Here's 20,000 dollars.
Give this to the people of Aragusuku.
Just do as I say.
Mr. Nakagami..
Boss!
Sachi...
Are you all right?
Mr. Iba...
Take him inside.
Mr. Iba!
Where is she?
She's safe.
She's right here.
Thank you, Mr. Iba.
I...
...couldn't even repay
you for your kindness.
No...
You're one of us!
Thank you.
Mr. Iba!
Mr. Nakagami!
Get off!
I'm coming with you.
This is not something
a woman should do.
Fool!
I'm not going back to the main island.
Just let me do as I please.
Boss!
Miss Yuri!
Surround them!
Find him!
There he is!
Mr. Nakagami!
Go!
Mr. Nakagami..
Yuri!
Find him!
Don't let him get away!
Please go back to the main island.
I don't want to be a man
who just passes by.
I came here...
...because I wanted to see you.
Mr. Nakagami!
Never mind about me!
Go after him!
Okinawa belongs to America.
No matter what the reason,
the crimes you have committed
are heinous, however...
Yuri Yonamine, you are
declared innocent and
will be released immediately.
According to Tetsu Nakagami's
statement and our investigation,
we determined that he shall hold
the burden of this crime.
Please wait!
He will be executed.
I did it!
Please wait!
He didn't do it!
Mr. Nakagami!
Don't die!
TETSU NAKAGAMI
THE END