No Big Deal
Really disappointed.
Hey.
Damn.
What happened? on the road.
Such a dog ass day.
The paying time has already passed.
So go to hell.
What's wrong?
You sure are going to die.
Come on, get on the car.
You are performing for kids now?
Right, we do everything.
I got out at the break.
Even Shakespeare was a a walk-on before he's famous.
Yes, and now you are either.
Can't make it.
Morning, morning
Who's he? My brother Charlie
It's real.
Is it colorful?
It always like that.
People already get used to it.
Max, look at that juggler.
We got all those stuff, right?
Yes, and should we start? Alright.
Ok, I see, now let's begin.
Take it.
We deserve it, for our dubbing.
You go that way?
I thinks so, I gotta pick him up.
See, Leo.
What have him told you?
Hey, Leo. What?
What did Pilar tell you?
Not very clear.
But I know his illness had gone more serious.
Gotta see him at once.
Also he told me about the cross which Jesus was nailed on.
And the Virgin Mary, something like that.
The Cross? We should hurry up.
How long is it since you last time saw him.
No idea, maybe 6 months.
And you?
The same, you?
Why so many questions? Are you policemen?
Well, in your opinion, should we come inside?
Do it.
I say no one wants to look at it again.
Yes, I can feel it.
I'm wondering where he found these things?
I think, these were always in his head.
Come look at this.
He is really someone, can do anything.
He used this for what? But not bad indeed.
Such a miracle.
Hard to believe?
He walked from Saintt Mass to Saint Piere.
Since his first sickness.
At the very beginning, I even hadn't notice that.
He didn't wanna talk about it, or I could worry a lot about him.
He alwasy saying hi's fine.
But I knew it's not true.
First, he brought some big stuffs back.
Some priest's things.
One morning, he locked himself in the room.
Just lain on bed for a week.
So It was messed up.
Is he ok?
He slept all day.
Doc says it's very normal.
Ok, go, he's waitting for you.
Go, go.
Pablo.
Alright?
I don't know if she's still there.
I don't know.
The statuary you are looking for, what does it like?
She's pretty.
I know.
You must think about, I got something wrong.
It's not like that.
You'v adopted us for 25 years, we can understand.
But this time, I'll count on you.
Will you?
I can only count on you now.
Don't worry.
Why suddenly talk about statuary?
We'v known him for 40 years, and he never talk about it.
I thought he'd forgotton it for a long time.
But where had he heard from?
He is old now.
Like anyone else, he couldn't help recalling some past.
But that statuary he said.
Could be stolen long ago.
He ask us to find, is him crazy?
He brought you home when you were 6 years old.
In these 26 years.
He treat you like his own son.
He never asks you to be good, be smart.
I don't know why.
He loves you, that's all.
That Tuesday. Rainning.
The first thing he did.
Was buying you new boots.
You are the most important thing in his life.
We didn't get one franc then.
And no house.
No even piano.
It it crazy?
We know no one there.
We'v never been Spain, strange people, strange country, and can't say the language.
Statuary of the Virgin Mary.
An old man wants us to go to Spain.
Get the Virgin Mary back.
Just like Stalin order his followings.
To take one piece land of Africa back.
I won't go.
She's right, he wants that statuary.
Then you go, we don't know anybody there.
Except he goes by himself.
And he should be healthy.
Ok, keep thinking for yourself.
No, I'm thinking for you.
And for you too.
You two want to just watch?
Making money like hell.
Then cast it out like hell either.
It's so crazy.
It's the same reason.
I'll be crazy if i go to Spain.
Think about it, think it over.
You are wrong.
Charlie, you have money?
Some for my coffin.
But nor much
Nothing else?
Yes, I lent some to a friend.
But I think he'd already spent it out.
Then we should make your friend to do a smarter financing.
Hey, Charlie my brother
Are you ok?
Of course, but his brother is me.
We are on a vacation.
The money you borrowed from me.
I'm asking if you can..
listen Charlie, I have money.
But short fo it.
I'm so sorry.
I have a little brother just about to go to school.
I have to give him some money.
A brand new car.
Yes.
So pretty, must be dear.
Yes, but It's divided payments.
That'll be much better, you can send it back if broken.
Never realize it's so slimsy, so bad.
What are you doing!
Let me see the motor if it works.
Seems ok, then the glove.
No, stop, I say stop!
There's some money in my home.
I'll give it to you, but don't touch my car.
You should have told me earlier.
How?
This way.
I follow you.
It's ok, mon.
Good morning, madam.
I'm a revenuer.
He's really something.
In the name of the father.
Look at this stupid hard cheese.
Damn, Damn it.
My car!
I'll kill you, Charlie.
I'll kill you.
Why do you get all your stuff on the car?
I'v never been without this car.
But we'll get in trouble in the border checking.
It makes sense.
There're everything.
But they won't get me in trouble.
Won't
Yes, Max.
You always can play to the score, every time.
Indeed.
I never worry about it.
I can go by myself.
But the problem is Pablo wants us three go together.
Obviously, Two heads are better than one.
One week, not even one day more, ok?
Ok, only if you go.
I love this song.
Good morning, gentlemen.
May I have a look at your Driver license?
Of course.
Have we done something wrong?
Just want you to know there're speed limits.
Alright.
What's in the car?
Nothing speciall.
Ok, let's see.
What does it like where we're heading to?
Must be a outter small town.
We could have a look at the tour service.
Or some place like that.
I think the local product there is tangerine.
You were right.
We should go to the tour service.
Ok, how to find it?
Where should we meet? A bar
I got address, see if we can find it.
Look, there're many people.
They havn't seen each other since the civil war was over.
That should be 50 years.
He's supposed to be very old.
Couldn't recognize hime easily.
Agree, it's such a elder club here.
I think, might be him.
To me, might be a lot of people.
Do you send by Mr Pablo?
Yes, we are his sons.
Very good, Gabo is waitting for you.
Oh?
You have a appointment, I have to drive you there.
Can we go now?
See you.
It was you who slapped my butt?
Not that hard.
Every time where I see a beauty.
I couldn't help touching it.
It's a kind of conditioned reflex.
Correct.
Conditioned reflex
Sorry
So
It can't be controlled.
Have you ever learned that?
You mean this kind of hitting?
You can't imagine that I did something like that, right?
Gabo told me about it.
There have to be actual combat, or it's useless.
You often do this?
No, first time.
But it's very nice.
Hope it wouldn't be rude.
What are Gabo doing now?
Nothing, He's old.
He lives there.
Tell me something about Pablo.
He's old too, right?
Yes, old.
His hair, still that much?
Very good.
He gots a lot of pain?
There're some illness, but no big deal.
I don't care about this.
I'm interested about what's wrong in his heart.
I'm sure he has other pain.
Dose he have prostate?
Yes, of course.
It makes me pain.
I thought he'd already cut it off.
Or at least I live a better life to him.
Or he looks older than me.
Pablo is full of energy.
He's very polite, and don't have to sit in wheelchair.
He could enjoy the sunshine everyday.
He's dying, so we are here.
Where do you sleep at night?
We'v just arrived, no time for finding a hotel.
Angela will help you out.
She knows every people here.
See you tomorrow, then we keep talking.
Your father always likes that?
Yes, what?
No, nothing.
Gabo can't admit that he couldn't walk anymore.
Since he got apoplexy last year, he'v never left the room.
But he's really a vivid man before that.
He loves his friends.
Pablo is his best friend.
He ofther talks about Pablo?
Yes, a lot.
That's why I want to see you.
See what's the differences between us.
Right, that's it.
Coffee plus milk.
Milk?
Milk from milch cow, Milk.
I get it, [spanish]
Yes
Want a tallow cake?
What?
Cake with tallow on it.
and jam.
en?
confiture, jam.
Oh, jam
Yes jam
I can't understand any words
I just know 3 spanish words.
If we don't speak spanish,
Then whatever he say is right.
Nice explanation, thanks.
Tell him we don't get much time.
You think we came here for fun?
Calm down, it's just the beginning.
I didn't mean to camplain.
Are you talking about us?
He told me there're some Frenchmen.
Even can't speak coffee plus milk.
I think you are the frenchmen.
It can't be.
He's very funny.
What did you just call him?
His name is Andre
But you can also calll him Manolete
It's a long long story.
Then tell us.
Next time, I gotta go, Gabo is waitting for us.
Have a good day.
Welcome to Spain.
We'll stay here for minutes.
We know this old man, don't we?
If Pablo's here, he'll be interested in it.
He's Miguel.
Are you really sons of Pablo?
Yes, real.
Then you tell him when you back, Migalrido
Never forget him.
Migalrido?
Last time I saw him is in Sep.
He don't have many days to live.
And he always thinks about the past.
Although it's long ago.
He can't forget it.
As he's at the battlefront.
you tell Gabo, she's at Casanis.
That's 27th Oct.
We had a position there.
We took part in the local army.
Once a night, we came to a villiage.
Have to kill all the people.
There're no amry at all.
Just old ones, women and kids.
I thought Pablo couldn't stand it.
At Casaniss.
There's a purple statuary of the Virgin Mary.
That time.
We had no choice.
He stayed there all day.
Without a move.
Just pray.
We got the bad news.
Every one's died.
It's a heavy strike.
Two months later.
Pablo went to France.
From then on, never come back.
In that times, we can not help doing that.
You'v never seen each other since then?
No, we kept in touch at the very beginning.
But terminated later.
But Pablo, he's always in here.
So that's what we're looking for?
Yes, Casaniss.
In the military area.
Who are we supposed to meet?
Be patient, he'll be here soon.
Listen, she's coming.
She's who we want to see.
Is she great?
Yes,she is.
You got girlfriends in France?
Yes, some.
I spoke for you.
We think it's really crazy.
You? got boyfriend? or alone.
No, for now, I'm too busy.
What do you do?
I'm working in hospital.
chief?
No, doctor.
Yes?
Yes.
I can do surgery.
Like cut someone's bingy open.
And you? What do you do?
We were artists once.
But our father is infatuated with the Virgin Mary.
We got no choice but to come here.
What do you think about us?
I think you are adopted.
Yes.
Good evening, gentlemen.
I'm a policeman, can I have a look at your ID?
This is our captain.
Nice to meet you.
Your performence was wonderful.
I like your new song.
It's always in fashion.
But show a different meaning, right?
It was you who just singing?
You don't like it?
I like it, very much.
It's just, just we don't know.
You couldn't imagine a captain singing like this, right?
A captain should only sit here eating and drinking, right?
Yes.
Then this time I make your friends' eyes open.
Oh my God.
Not very complicated.
See that colonel?
We should ask him
Pablo wants his statuary back.
If he says no, then we talk about another way.
He sure won't give it to us.
When should we get to Angela?
She never told, she got work to do today.
A army car, japanese car.
Let's go to find her.
See what's she doing now.
You want to see her doing operation?
No, but...
Are you looking for Angela?
Yes
She asked me to tell you she's in operation.
But if you want to.
You can join the later part.
It's about to over.
Come. follow me.
Will you come?
Have you ever seen a operation?
If not, now it's your chance.
Close to us.
Nice work?
It's your first time.
So fell in a faint.
Tomorrow, I'll get some invitaion card.
If you want to, you can come with me.
Well, what's your search going on?
Some guards at the door.
And some cars.
Many strong men were running inside.
Now the question is how we can get into it.
sneak through or get a dog to do the search.
One word, we gotta find a way in.
There have to be some leaks.
Even it's military area.
Why did you get in the army?
I'v asked the same question either.
But to be a son have no right to ask his father this question.
We should think it over.
Find a easiest way.
Flawless.
What's your job?
I do investigation.
You are a cop too?
No... I just collect and stat the reports.
See if they are doing legal business
something like that.
You like your job?
No
Who?
a gifed musician, died in his 26.
Wait
Someone should go for a search tonight.
Who's first?
Max and Leo.
It's better for 2 people.
Could sleep in turn.
I learned from movies.
Alright.
You agree? Leo.
Leo?
What?
Watch the door tonight.
Ok
He play it in the same  way you do?
No, no one play it like me.
You are gifted.
Really?
He can play it well, right?
Don't know, I'v never seen him playing.
Let's wait and see.
I like this kind of music.
For a long time.
I havn't listened to it.
At five o' clock, the third change
precisely
Tell me, have your idea changed?
No.
Actually, why do you like that so much?
Not for anything or anyone.
I just like it.
Then you play it now.
Now? no one answer
No need feedback in music.
We create music just want others to listen.
I think we should play it at home once.
I don't like it.
Then where should you play?
Left, right, Cafe, dock
How do you think about music?
As you looking at the newspapers.
Just like that?
Means just one person.... forget it, can't explain.
Ok, now it's 5:51
Let's go back.
Caution, police do checking.
I don't know you are back at this time.
I'm sure you have forgotten everything.
I gotta go.
One hour later I'll back to you.
Tallow cake.
No big deal, she asked for it.
Then it just happenede.
You can imagine that.
You prepared for that.
We can't get into anything else.
Or even 2 years we can't get it done.
And, watch it.
Yes, let's pretend to nothing happened.
I don't care.
I care about our boat.
Could wipe out anytime by you!
You tell me what I have wiped out.
say it!
No, right?
Your question is, you never take responsibilities.
Max just want to you to know that.
The real question is, from the first place.
You two were after Angela.
You didn't?
No, I didn't
Be honest
Let's go for a play.
COme on.
Come, enjoy the sunshine and beach.
It's a long time that I Played in front of people
Hope they'll enjoy my playing.
Captain.
Can you introduce this young man to me?
It's Leo.
And his brothers.
Are you spanish?
We came from a place far away.
Anyway, you have done a impressive playing.
It's the best I'v ever listened to.
Yes, colonel is good in music.
He often came here.
A couth leader.
I have to say.
You can't find many in the country.
I'm thinking if you can come to the military area sometime.
Let our soldiers share the joy,
Which made by your wonderful performance.
I know he'll glad to be there
I'v suggested him to
That'll be great.
This beautiful music.
You'll play for us, won't you?
Yes, we will bring you joy.
What are you saying?
I mean...
We like this kind of music.
Captain.
Arrange the perform as soon as possible.
In fact, I know he's interested in music.
So I asked you to play in front of him.
then we'll get a concert to make in the military area.
And now we can get into it easily.
It's what we thought, right?
Why are you doing these for us?
Why do you take the risk?
I got my reason.
A great soldier.
Came from my hometown
My grandpa was just like your father.
He said to do one thing you should have enough reason
He wanted me to be a military officer.
You listened to him?
It's a torture
I'm poisoned by music either.
Come to music,
Can you do that?
No idea, I'v never done that before.
I need a place to practise
If you don't mind, you can come to my house.
Enough space.
The neighbor get no utterance.
Go
You thinks we could make it?
Maybe, step by step.
Anyway, I like this place.
It's very nice to play it here.
It's poetic
I don't feel the same way.
What?
Why?
A tiger will be bullied by a dog on a treeless plain
Anyway It's not our own place.
Forget it, we come here for business.
I can't stand it.
You wait and see.
Give me your lighter.
I wanna give them a lesson.
Charlie!
Hey, asshole.
Fuck you!
Hurry
I'm washed-up.
We couldn't have made it if a little later.
Are you alright?
Nothing, just never think of you can do it.
It's my first time to do that.
absolutely oringinal work.
Your shoes are broken
Let go, the most important thing is running away.
Seems catch up.
I'm chipper to die.
Good morning, captain.
Good morning, madam.
Were we late?
No,why?
You can stay here for a moment.
Don't be childish，Charlie
Are you sure that we appointed here to see each other?
Yes, she said like this.
She said the place where big ham was sold.
Why do we come to the market?
Did she think that we came to Spain for him?
Where is it?
There's too much stores.
But should at the palace where pork is sold.
Good morning!
We are looking for Angela。
Doctor Angela。
I see, wait a minute.
Angela，you friends want to see you.
Give me 5 minutes. I haven't finished chopping the pork.
It's unbelievable.
I come to help my aunt every Wednesday .
I started to learn to do operation there.
Are you kidding.
I'm not.
Paying my tuition fee, I worked for her shambles for many years.
Then I come to help her for free.
But it's nothing to do with your job.
I don't think so.
It's crazy if I work there for full time.
But it's fun to help once in a while.
You can think like this
there are some benefits
you can eat good pork then.
He stays with these children every afternoon.
A morning many years ago
He left Paris.
And determine to take this career.
Joined in the training.
He was really extraordinary.
He became a matador for the first time.
He showed great courage.
An accident came to him afterward.
But they rescued him successfully.
But he can't go to the bullring any more.
So he went to a coffee house.
worked there
and changee his name to Manolete
Manolete
I didn't expect you to come.
Hi,
Do you want to have a try?
This sport is to keep away from those horns.
It's a character too,
especially in a bullring.
Is it a dream?
It's grand.
Unbelievable?
It's the dreaming place of every matador.
He stayed there for 30 years .
Do you know he keeps down his manteau?
I don't know.
Maybe.
Do you want to see it?
It's the manteau.
glaring
The hat
The dress
and pants
This one has been torn out.
These happened long long ago.
I invite you to drink coffee.
Look
Is he Lopez?
Corporal Lopez，He was once a corporal.
He's a brave man.
Every musician will be welcomed here
I am always willing to do this.
You know
we are not a team.
but we share everything
Those all our brothers.
We pride with this.
I think so.
This is what he said to me.
Well then ，when can we start our action?
We can start at any time.
That's good.
We will practise it next Tuesday.
That will be a big day.
Oh, I forget to show it to you
I must show it to you.
Our cimelia.
A pink Madonna.
The symbol of soul.
Is she great?
She lies in the red.
Do you know what happened?
You also know she is very famous.
I prefer being shutting away.
I will take care of it.
So I won't be bothered by soul.
Haven't you touched gun before?
No.   It's not difficult at all.
Hold it in your hand.
Imagine the target as a bad egg.
Shoot at the bull's-eye.
That's it.
Not bad.
First time at all.
How is Leo?
Fine.
But I think it's not the question you want to ask.
Yes.
No.
Do you often talk about your home?
We don't get so much time.
Listen
Everything is new and happy ,
though I have been married.
But if only you are willing to say,
you could make the story funnier.
If you don't know how to, you should ask.
I'm the shooting champion of Spain.
It's an honor，champion.
Finally I think I should live like this.
Don't open it. keep it closed.
Is it you?
Close it，Charlie
Charlie，close it.
I'm leaving.
Your shooting score is good.
Do you have a lighter.
Pablo adopted us and bring us up.
So we three came together.
We were five then.
Do you know five-aged child?
They are noisy and not lovely children.
We have no special feeling about our family.
Because we always remember that we were adopted.
We went to the Acad.
I like making waves there.
Charles have been to Gaza.
It wasn't easy to make living in those years.
For Max, he doesn't talk very much.
He is a wild oats.
All seems to be the same as those days.
No matter wheather we were adopted,
We are the sons of him.
The question is I am not used to it.
How do you get up with each other?
Very bad, we often fight with each other.
Espcially Max and Charles.
You can't imagine it becomes worse.
We always put my love away,
and don't want to share with others.
Now, We have all kinds of lives.
From our childhood, we have our plans.
I think that we three depend on each other for survival.
Excepting death.
I don't smoke at all, I have talked too much.
What about you?
You make love with any man you know?
No, not all.
The point is that I love freedom.
Unconstraint .
I don't depend on anybody.
Did you learn this from nun.
Why don't be a nun?
I always think of my parents and family.
They always make me feel warm.
I love your grandfather very much.
It's him who teach me knowledge.
Otherwise I would be a nun now.
It's hard to image?
This plan is very good too.
Will it be a litte hazardous?
It doesn't matter, it was just a small concert.
But there is enough time for us to act.
I think Leo can cope with it.
There is a problem with army.
I don't know how many people will be present.
More or less a risk.
Nobody said that we came to Spain for a tour.
If you have fogoten the purpose of the journey,
please tidy up your things and scram.
What a great saying!
Honey, what's the matter? Don't be jealous.
You always look like this.
Can't you just stop saying those turpitude words?
Do they always look like this?
Not too bad, they can deal with it themselves.
I want you say it.
That's enough. Both calm down.
When will you stop?
Shut up! Sissy
Take care of your own bussiness!
What did he say?
Sissy,the man who doesn't have that thing.
I will let them know who is the sissy.
I'm refined and courteous。
But I'm not a sissy.
I remember it.
Yes, that's it.
that's it.
I know...
Here stands a guard .
Here is a washroom.
Then go this way,
The door is open at all times.
Any problem?
What about the key?
The key to the cabinet is in the office.
In the left drawer. Easy to find it.
It is always there.
We must make sure that everyone will go to the concert.
How much time we got?
You have about 15 minutes.
It will be no suspicion in these minutes.
How can we leave after we get the statuary?
That's leo's job. Show it to them.
Look
It's the clarinet case.
Seen it? When I perform the case will be empty.
It is flawless.
I will go with you if I were young.
must be exciting.
Cheers.
To the longevity of Babilo.
It's the falling sickness. Not serious.
Does he often like this?
I don't know.
I have never seen you like this.
It make me psych out.
Take the medicine.
Max
What's wrong?
I don't know. Just feel ill.
Feel ashamed?
Not this reason.
It's natural. It doesn't matter much.
Everyone will be depressed some time.
Don't be this.
Didn't look like you.
Have you seen your own mother?
sure!
When I was ten.
But It has passed .
Our mother is Pilar now.
Why do you ask in this way ?
I don't konw ,either.
Every time when I bring her to my mind .
I wonder if I should go to see her.
And feel hesitating .
Don't you know where she is all along?
I have her address.
She works not far from here.
But I haven't been there. It has been three years.
I put that paper in my wallet all the times.
Sometimes I take it out and have a look.
I understand.
Feel well now?
Yes.
I know that you will feel weel if you speak it out.
Don't hide  it in your heart.
That place is not far away,is it?
In Spain?
Shall we go to visit her?
OK
Good evening!
Here comes our leading actor.
I lead your seat.
Please go this way.
So many people!
That's OK?
I'm not sure. I think it's OK.
I thought you perform alone.
No problem. Do as usual.
I am interested in nothing but musical performance.
Sit down.
Let's go now. OK, you take the case.
Shit, I has been locked.
Surely it is locked.
Find someting to unlock it.
Hurry!
It doesn't work.
See how professional I am.
How can you do that?
It has no key.
Great!
I can't unlock it.
Change another one. You may mistake it.
Don't hasten me.
Someone comes. keep close.
dub!
What is he doing?
We go out after they leave.
Must have been finished.
Why are you back?
I has been locked.
What shall we do now?   I don't know.
Shall we leave now. We can come to see another time.
We can't be absent for too long.
You may have not listened to the following way of performing.
I expect a pleasantly surprise.
He is extraordinary .
Yes, but it is really wonderful.
Great!
What shall we take?
We have done our best.
But Pablo won't understand.
Pardon?
We don't want this either.
Any other plans for us?
Yes, we can change our plan.
What else can we do now?
Shall we expend like this?
Let them sing next time?
Don't say it now.
It's just a Madonna, isn't it?
Don't say unlack words.
They did a lot.
Now we'd better have a good sleep.
We can think clearly then.
It's late at night now.
Max
Where is Angela？
I think she has gone.
She is not here.
She didn't have any operation today.
I don't know where she has gone.
We want to see Gabo.
He is not here.
Do you know where he went?
Where is Gabo
I don't know .
Have you seen him?
They said he got a vacation of a week.
I don't know where he has been.
And we can't find Leo either.
What happened?
Nobody is here.
Miguel
Where did they go?
Even him has disappeared.
What are you doing?
You see clearly what I am doing.
What happened to other people.
They all disappeared.
Our appointment is at one o'clock.
Tidy up your luggage.
Will you go at noon?
Why in such a hurry?
Pablo can't wait that long.
Why don't you return with us?
I want to stay.
I don't want to go.
It's her.
How can you do this?
No need to say.
The point is we get the Madonna.
What about the captain?
Don't worry about him.
You must repatriate quickly. That's the most important thing now.
You take this photo to Pablo as a memento.
Tell him that I have a good time every day.
Better than him.
Won't you go with us?
It's the first time I find a place and people suit for me.
You can understand me,can't you? I think Pilar can.
Tell Pablo that all things go as he expected.
Let's go.
Goodbye.
Take care!
So to you.
Never mind.I'll go with you.
I don't understand why Leo said
all things go by as Pablo expected.
Because it's Leo, who is hard to understand.
I think his meaning is
Madonna isn't the most important thing to him.
Why said that?
Leo think that the reason that your father let you come here
is make you review the past.
You three brothers joined together over again in this course.
Did you said to you like this?
Just my opinion is like his.
Whether or no, it's the end of the journey.
It's over.
My brother's.
Sergent，look this.
If there is something misgivings, Let's go away.
Do yuu think we can escape?
I am …Sergent.
Sergent，listen to me
You must hold your post.
It's an order.
Sergent，are you there?
Great.
If you bother me for thess jackasseris any more,
please stop your job,
and transfer to manage the dirt-wagons.
Is that clear for you?
Now that I say that she is still there.
It must be a copy.
Do you want to explain now?
What should I say to make you happy?
OK, that's enough.
Why can't we regard nothing has happened?
Even if we steal it successfully some day,
captain will know it soon.
He will know it was done by you.
So Gabo ask Miguel to make a copy.
It's a hard work, do you know?
Yes, it is.
It's a copy.
How can we tell it to Pablo.
Don't say anything.
Excepting that he asks.
Why don't you stop here?
You get out here.
Why should I get out here?
Do you see that house?
There lives someone who you keep thinking in these three years.
You really have problem.
Above all, how do you know here?
I saw the paper in your wallet.
Go, there's no problem.
Get in, look at her, and tell her who you are.
I know it is a little difficult.
We are waiting for you here.
Go.
He comes back.
What?
Can we go now?
I want to stay here for a short time.
Have you seen her?
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I think I should stay for a short time.
So we return first.
You want Pilar explain it, don't you?
Don't worry, I think she will understand.
OK, you help me take the case back.
Anybody in?
Pablo. Pilar.
Where are they?
It's too late now.
Where is other people?
Leo stays there.
How are those friends?  They are  fine.
Where's Max? Is he OK.
He just have someone to see.
He wants to see her all the time.
I know that when he was a child.
Yes.
Oh，this is Angela
Gabo's litte girl.
She reminds me of much memory.
It's Miguel's masterpiece.
He is always good that this.
How is Gabo going on?
He is old.
Always try to compare with me?
Doesn't he?
Yes.
Last time  I saw him was on the mountain.
Why don't you see each other any more?
I can take you there now?
There's no need.
It's nice to call him.
Have you called each other?
I thought you haven't talked for 30 years.
We got in touch afterward.
talking the recent situation of each other.
talking about past
You see it?
I'm sure they look older than me.
The End