NO CONTROL
Danilo Porto, after years
of promises of teaching
life to a character,
reveals a confuse story.
A confuse and cold story,
with bad structure
and without conflict.
A fruitless effort.
A disappointment...
A misfortune...
You need to really push
the stool!
Failure...
Go away, now!
Take your script!
Take this script!
Take this script
and go away!
Failure...
Danilo Porto, after years
of promises of teaching
life to a character,
reveals a confuse story.
You need to really push
the stool!
Take this script!
Danilo!
It's a friend of mine, Joana.
It's ok.
Ok, doctor Márcia.
Goodnight!
How are you feeling?
Danilo?
I'm going to give you
some meds, ok?
Here it is.
Try to get some rest.
I'll come back
tomorrow, ok?
Tomorrow morning,
I'll be here.
Good morning!
What a beautiful day!
So, are you feeling better?
Did you put me in your clinic?
Well, here I can
take care of you.
I am exhausted!
Danilo, for how long
have we known each other?
Fifteen years, maybe?
I don't know if I'll manage
to get out of this.
I've seen you do it before.
Do you want talk?
So, let's go
grab some coffee.
Stop it, Danilo! Come on!
Come see the clinic.
Hi, Nelson!
Good morning!
Not everyone stays here.
Some of them attend
the therapeutic classes
and then at the end of the day,
they go home.
They don't receive just
psychiatric treatment, you know?
It's a place
for social reintegration.
- Good morning!
Here, they learn
a bit about themselves.
They make wonderful things
over at the art classes.
Look at how beautiful they are!
They've made all of this!
Tonhâo!
Principal Márcia, look at
the bull I've made in art class!
Heloisa got jealous! She is not
all that good with her hands.
She is not good with anything!
I've tasted her food!
Her cooking is worse
than my mother's.
The crab took the little one on
his back, and entered the jungle.
I think they went
to do naughty things there...
One time, my mom made
scrambled eggs, without the egg.
I think I am going to give
my bull to Heloisa...
Did you like it?
I loved it!
Edmilson, this is Danilo,
a theater director.
Pleasure to meet you, Danilo.
My name is Edmilson.
One time, I went to the theater,
it was that play with that actress
from the soap opera.
It was boring!
I've slept through the whole thing
although I have trouble sleeping!
Sometimes, my mom gives me
chamomile tea to sleep,
but it doesn't usually work.
Chamomile tea
is good for you!
It's good! You should
drink a lot of chamomile tea.
It doesn't really work
all that well...
Tonhâo!
Look at the bull
that I made in art class.
Heloisa was jealous...
Eat something, Danilo.
- Shall we go, Márcia?
- In a second. I'm going!
Ademir!
Hold on! Are you going
to leave me all alone?
They are not going to jump you!
Relax, Danilo.
You are not going to jump
them either, right?!
It's over! It's over!
The cake is finished!
Good morning!
What is your name?
Did you forget, honey?!
It's Vânia.
And the cake,
is there any left?
Isn't there any more cake?
I bought it for you.
Did you like it?
I liked it.
Do you want to talk
about it?
I want to forget!
Forgetting does not make it
go away.
But if you don't want to talk
about it, it's fine.
I need to go.
Bye!
I don't want to!
I don't want to go...
I don't want to go today!
I don't want to!
Please take me home
just for today!
I'll be quiet...
I don't want to...
I don't want to go today!
Come on, Estela.
I have another doll.
Hey! Yo!
Come back, nutty!
Danilo, what is it
that bothers you?
Lack of justice.
Lack of justice
is what bothers me.
Yeah, right.
I've dedicated years of my life
on this project! Many, many years.
And I lost it all,
that I had put it in.
Come on! Motta Coqueiro
was responsible for the end
of death penalty in Brazil,
and nobody knows it!
I was crushed like a bug!
And what are you
going to do about it?
I don't know!
I don't know...
It's funny,
you know Danilo...
You think it is funny?!
I'm sorry! Bad choice of word!
It is interesting
that you feel that they did
you wrong, like your character,
and as Motta Coqueiro.
But I think that at this moment,
you have bigger issues to solve.
What other issues?
Danilo, your wife left you,
you are buried with debts,
your play
didn't turn out well...
Come on all,
last time.
Hold it! Hold it!
You can't even kick the stool!
This way, it is impossible!
Impossible!
Kick it!
Get down! Get down!
You! Get on top of this.
Let's roll.
You guys are playing around!
Playing around!
This looks like school theater!
When one of you find someone
that can kick a stool
we will do
the last scene of the play.
Because without it,
we won't have a hanged man!
Would you like
to participate?
No! I'm Márcia's friend.
Did you know that this book
caused several suicides in Europe?
Thanks for letting me know.
You must be thinking:
"who is this crazy man,
that showed up out of no where
talking about death?"
That did cross my mind.
Nice to meet you.
My name is Danilo.
I'm Márcia's friend.
Aline.
I think he chose to suffer.
What?
Sorry... Werther.
He was never going
to give up on Charlotte.
"We have nothing, when we are
in debt with ourselves."
You know it by heart?!
I've tried to turn it
into a play.
Do you work with theater?
I try...
I direct,
and at times I write.
What are you doing here?
Researching?
No. I am...
I'm resting.
I'm trying to regroup
some thoughts in my head.
Love?
Work...
life...
Things get complicated
sometimes, you know?!
Is he your boyfriend?
They guy that was with you
yesterday?
I'm going to go.
Márcia is expecting me.
I'm sorry for the remark.
That play wouldn't turn out
too well either way.
It was cold...
It didn't reach out to people.
It's nice that you are starting
to see this. Real nice!
People are still torn
about Motta Coqueiro.
Some people fear it,
others are ashamed about it.
My mom was one
that was against it.
She used to say
that it brought bad luck.
So did my parents.
You are such a talented man...
Forget this, Danilo.
I can't!
Didn't bring anything
to read today?
Felipe came for his meds.
Your boyfriend?
Would you like to know?
And the theater?
Oh, the theater...
Well, I'm still digesting
my last big failure.
It was a play
about Motta Coqueiro's life.
It was you
that directed that play?!
Wasn't it he the guy
that was hung
because he ordered the murder
of a whole family?
It was something
like that.
I really didn't want to talk
about Motta Coqueiro right now.
Oh! I wanted so bad
to know more about this story!
Well, I really don't feel like
talking about it. I'm sorry.
Please, tell me!
Motta Coqueiro...
In real life, Motta Coqueiro
was married to a farmer
known as Úrsula das Virgens.
What a name?!
They were both
extremely greedy.
They used to take over
unproductive land,
and used to settle people
there to work on it.
The problem was that those lands
had owners. Powerful ones too!
Motta Coqueiro and Úrsula
made a lot of money,
and a lot of enemies.
There was a massacre
on their farms, wasn't there?
Yes, but two years
before the massacre,
Motta Coqueiro brought
someone to work
on one of those
unproductive lands
a planter called Benedito.
Benedito had
a beautiful daughter.
Although Motta Coqueiro
was dearly in love with his wife,
he was no ángel!
Go on...
Where was I?
So, Motta Coqueiro had an affair
with Benedito's daughter
and she got pregnant.
And so he ordered the murder
of the whole family?
Hold on! What is up with "he
order to kill the whole family"?!
Well, then Benedito started
to blackmail Motta Coqueiro
threatening to tell
everything to Úrsula,
if he didn't register
the farm on Benedito's name.
Did he tell her?
Well, there are some
history tellers that say
that Úrsula was the mentor
of the massacre.
Like it was the revenge
of a betrayed woman,
you know?
I know...
Around that time, it wasn't
all that common for rich men
to be condemned
with the death penalty.
But did he know it was her
that ordered the killing?
I think so.
And he didn't say anything?
I got the stuff.
Felipe, this is Danilo.
What's up, bro?
Chilling?
Chilling.
Let's bounce.
Wait.
I loved the story!
That's good.
Are you coming tomorrow?
It depends on Felipe.
Bye!
Let's go nutty!
Come on, nutty! Bounce!
Danilo?
Danilo Porto!
It's been a while man!
- How are you, Iván?
- Good.
I read the critics
about your play...
A bit harsh, huh?!
Yeah, you know...
But tell me,
what are you doing up here?
Don't tell me
you came to work here?!
I was waiting for you at my office,
so that we could talk...
about the theater project?
I didn't know
that Iván worked here.
Danilo has everything
to do a great job
with us, Márcia.
It was exactly about that,
that we were going to talk about.
Well, I am going head back.
Aggressive, huh?!
Aggressive!
That's a good idea!
What is it?
You teaching theater here.
Great idea!
Don't start, Márcia.
Don't even start, ok?!
I've just said to ditch
Iván's questions.
The aggressive.
Come on, Danilo.
Let's talk about it.
Ok, dad.
Mom has already told me.
Of course...
I know... I know!
Dad, I know it!
Dad, I can't really talk
right now.
I'm working.
I did fix it, dad!
Can we talk later?
I will drop by.
Love, daddy!
Hugs!
I love you too.
Bye!
Father's way,
you know?!
No, I don't know.
Have you thought that it might
be a relation within the stories?
What stories?
Your father was also a victim
of injustice, right?
My father was not condemned.
He died as a scapegoat.
You all think everything has to
deal with father, and mothers.
I think that
pursuing this story
is a way of staying
confined in the past.
The transplant of multiple parts,
like the kidneys,
it's facilitated by the fact that
the donors can be alive.
Could you lend me a smoke?
No, no.
A theater class right here,
it's going to be awesome!
Hi!
I was waiting for you.
"Elective Affinities",
excellent!
You know what gets me
about Goethe?
How well he knows
the female soul.
I'm leaving.
I can't just be sitting here.
I need to get my life back.
But I think I will keep
on visiting the clinic.
Márcia has invited me
to open a theater class here.
How wonderful!
I thought about starting
with improvise games,
body language,
and things like that.
Why don't you work
with a script?
I don't think
they will be able to do it.
Go ahead.
May I?
Call me.
You've missed, Manoel!
Holy cow!
- Mr. Severino?
- Yes?
Do you have my key?
Oh! Your key!
Thank you.
On the way.
"Another one the way.
I am a poor man, with no land,
with 6 children,
and another one on the way.
My agreement with Mr. Motta
Coqueiro, it's a pact with God."
Did I wake you?
I'm sorry!
How mysterious, huh?!
- Are you curious?
- Very!
This is a very special place
for me. Very special.
I hide out here sometimes.
There is a bit about
my story in here.
The Mistake Comedy,
"Tartufo".
And Motta Coqueiro...
Motta Coqueiro?
I've rewritten the play.
I'd like for you to read.
Danilo, I don't know
anything about theater.
Ok. I will read it.
I promise!
Wow! How beautiful!
What do you think?
Sorry...
I was out of it.
Do I look like Úrsula?
I doubt that
she was this beautiful!
Felipe...
He is just a friend.
I'm not wearing panties...
Excuse me?
Come in.
Late!
You are late!
We've already started!
Grab a chair.
Open up a space for him.
It wasn't fair, obnoxiously
unfair, the contempt
of the dramatic talents
here at the clinic.
To open this theater class,
it's an act of justice!
Your name is...
Godofredo.
What about you?
Your name is...
His name is Tonhâo.
He doesn't speak.
At least I haven't seen it. He
just keeps that stuffed owl face.
Always quiet.
He doesn't speak...
My name is Edmilson.
I root for "Flamengo", teacher!
"Flamengo"!
"Fluminense"!
Teacher, I root
for "Cruzeiro"!
I root for "Fluminense", teacher!
My soccer team is "Fluminense".
I'm going to the bathroom!
There's no problem!
Tonhâo, Edmilson,
and you are?
Claudionor.
Forgive me, Claudionor.
No, I am sorry teacher.
It's just that...
it makes me real
happy to be here.
André.
I used to attend the art classes,
but all that paint,
all that clay...
Theater is not like that!
Theater is an art more...
I like that.
I dig it!
My name is Nelson.
I love theater...
I don't know if I like it...
I do not know...
You?
The doctor told me that
this class could help me
improve my social skills,
on dealing with other people.
Your name?
Otávio.
You are Felipe.
Felipe.
My name is Danilo Porto,
I am a theater director.
I am Aline, and I've been
a patient here for 3 years.
This is the first time that I join
one of this therapeutic classes.
Loved it!
Come here.
No more games!
What game?
Why didn't you tell me
that you were one of the patients?
Because you didn't ask me.
We can't cross this line.
Danilo, it happened.
It happened...
I can't get involved
with a patient,
who is going to be
my student.
Why?
I'm trying
to overcome a crisis.
Are you afraid?
We can't do it!
Are you afraid that
it might rub off on you?
That's it.
See you
next class, teacher.
Right!
One, two...
Right! To the right,
Claudionor. Right!
Without fighting, Nelson.
Let's go.
One, two, right...
Claudionor!
He is left-handed.
Claudionor, come over here!
Keep the rhythm!
Come back, Claudionor!
Be careful not
to run into your friends!
Faster!
Faster! Come on!
Let's do the bus exercise.
We need a driver.
Who is going to be the driver?
Cashier?
Who is going to sit? Who is
going to be standing? Come on!
The bus is going to turn
on the left!
This drill goes like this,
I am going to call up someone,
and this person will come over
here on the chair.
Looking at the mirror, the person
will respond to my command.
Happy.
That's right, happy!
This is the first time
I've seen his smile.
Slowing down!
Take it easy.
Come on, Nelson!
What happen, Nelson?
What is the problem?
Let me handle it.
Keep on walking guys!
Keep on, don't stop!
- Do you want me to quit the drum?
- Quit the drum.
So, I will stop with the drum.
The bus stopped.
Who is getting off?
I'm getting off.
Aline got off...
The driver did too!
There is no driver!
I'm the driver!
For the love of God!
Hurray!
Thoughtful.
Very good, Godofredo!
Can I go, Danilo?
Can I?
Not now, Edmilson.
Be patient.
Aline!
Anger.
Anger, Aline!
I can do it much better!
She doesn't know how to do it!
Let's move on.
Next one!
Tell me, Danilo.
How are your students?
Interesting...
To say the least, right?!
The funny thing is that
some of them look normal.
They are being treated:
therapy, medication.
It all helps a lot.
Felipe and Aline are two
that look normal.
They just look normal!
Aline for example,
she is beautiful,
but on the inside
things are much different.
Is that right?
She acts up and doesn't feel
guilt for what she does
Not even the slightest guilty.
It's absurd!
Really.
On her last crisis, she caught her
ex-boyfriend with another girl
and she just cut the girl
with a knife.
She was committed
for sometime and then left
on the condition of continuing
with her treatment, and she is.
You could never tell, huh?!
Danilo, your students might
seem very interesting.
They might even
seem normal.
But you cannot forget
that they are patients
with very delicate issues.
To hell with adaptation, rules,
guidelines... doctor Márcia...
I'm done with these meds!
This is outrageous!
I can't live without my meds!
I rewrote the play
about Motta Coqueiro.
I thought about
rehearsing it with them.
With the patients?
I think that
it might be good.
Right.
It could even result in some
good feedback for the clinic.
Danilo, it's a heavy plot...
people die!
I could leave
the massacre out.
And who are you going to choose
for the hung man?
Oh, I haven't thought
about that yet.
Is that so?!
I could get someone
from the outside.
No way!
Danilo, it's a violent story.
It could affect them.
Don't you get that?
I could be Motta Coqueiro.
A sketch, a lab, it's one thing,
but a whole script?!
You know, watching you
from up close, I can't remember
why we broke up.
Because you chose
another girl with bikinis.
I didn't choose nobody
with bikinis over you.
What a dog!
You are such a dog!
You will do just about anything
to convince me of it.
It will turn out well.
I am sure of it
Ok! So, you think that remaking
the play with the patients
is going to solve
your problem?
I do think so!
Fine! But I am going
to watch you closely, ok?!
And please try to find a way
that it will not set them off.
I will!
No way!
- Just a kiss!
- You fool!
One kiss...
"To stand the darts and throws..."
Pause.
"of the ever adverse load..."
That's right!
"or to be prepared against an
ocean of misfortunes and end it"
That's right!
"while trying to resist.
Period.
"To die, to sleep
nothing more...
maybe to dream."
Good job, Edmilson!
Good job, man!
Excellent job, man!
Thank you, Nelson!
Thank you!
Great rehearsal guys!
Really good!
I am going to
memorize everything!
Do it!
Memorize it all, Vânia!
Did you see, Márcia?
They knew it all!
They are ruling it!
I did. But you cannot forget
that they are on meds, Danilo,
they are molded.
I won't forget
that they are molded
to society's rules.
Don't worry!
That's not what I've said.
The meds stabilizes their mood.
And it doesn't slow
them down?!
It's the side effects.
But they can't be
without their meds.
Do you get that?!
They cannot!
Ok, doctor Márcia.
Bye, Danilo.
Bye, Vânia!
Did you like it?
Can we talk?
No, not really.
Aline, I'm a bit tired.
I need to take a shower,
and relax a bit.
Are you avoiding me?
No! Of course not!
I just have a headache.
Bye!
Danilo? Hold up!
Hold up!
Danilo, how are you liking to
give classes to nut jobs, nutty?
I bet that
it is a real disorder.
I wouldn't stay in a room
with them for nothing!
I'm going to hit
the restroom, guys!
It's not how we expect it to be.
It's interesting, they do learn.
Really?
How did you end up
there, man?
I don't know if
you remember Márcia,
a friend of mine.
Doctor Márcia.
Short girl with glasses?
No! I don't know if you
recall it, she is a...
Are you feeling better?
Yes, I am feeling better.
Danilo, introduce her
to us.
This is Aline, she is one
of my students at the clinic.
Hello, Aline. Pleasure
to meet you, Fernando.
The pleasure is mine.
- Marcos.
- Nice to meet you.
- Glaucia.
- How are you?
- Marta.
- Sit down, have a drink with us.
No, thank you.
Medical orders... I can't mix up.
But it was a pleasure
to meet all of you.
Get well.
What a cute nutty, huh?!
What are you going to have?
Nothing. I've seen
what I came here for. Let's go.
Oh, Danilo.
The nutty is leaving.
It might be a crisis.
Well, I brought you
some scripts.
I want you to read
and memorize the character
that each one of you
is going to play on the plot.
Come on, guys!
Come on! Let's get
this room ready, ok?!
Giris, bring the chairs
down here.
Vânia.
Tonhâo and Godofredo,
go get the structure.
Claudionor.
The curtains -
Edmilson and Otávio.
Give this to Nelson, please.
Did you get it?
Aline...
Come on!
Get up!
André...
Be careful!
And Edmilson.
Take this off, now!
- No, I won't take it off!
- Take it off!
Nelson, yours is here Nelson.
This is Otávio's.
But mine
doesn't have medals!
Don't worry about that!
Look at this one, it's gorgeous!
Fool!
Stop! Both of you, stop!
His is much nicer than mine!
Mine doesn't have medals!
Edmilson, Edmilson!
Come over here! Yours is here!
I wouldn't let it go like that!
- Here is yours, Edmilson.
- Where is mine?
Edmilson, Fidélis, Carolina,
Claudionor.
Try to memorize as much
as you can, ok?
For next class, ok?
"I'm just taking you
as a settler, Benedito
because of this
darn lack of slaves."
"I'm a poor man with no land,
with 6 children to raise
and another one
on the way."
Comma! Comma!
You need to breathe, Edmilson!
I forgot the comma, Danilo!
Without it you can't understand!?
No, I can't understand!
Could I try it again?
Please!
Ok. I am going to give
you the cue, ok?
"I'm just taking you
as a settler, Benedito
because of this
darn lack of slaves."
"I am a poor man,
Comma!
with no land...
and 6 children to raise...
Serious face,
with evil looking eyes! Quick!
and another one on the way."
Period!
"My agreement with you,
Mr. Motta Coqueiro,
Yes!
it's a pact with God."
That's it!
He had a bad guy
expressión!
Guys! Guys!
Please, the play is not over!
Please!
"If in two years you do not meet
with the improvements
that we agreed on, I will
be forced to kick you out...
Vânia?!
Vânia!
Vânia? Vânia!
This is not the time
for make up!
Come on! You should have already
been behind Edmilson.
Please, let's all pay attention
to the cues!
I'm sorry.
"lf... the improvements that we
agreed on, I will be forced
to kick you out
of Bananal's farm."
Who is there behind you?
It's Vânia.
It's Francisca.
It's Vânia!
Edmilson, stay with me.
Focus, please!
"It's Francisca. Francisca
is my oldest daughter.
She is as shy
as a Christmas' turkey!
Chica, come on over to the front
where our boss can see you."
"But she is an adorable girl!"
Thank you, Mr. Coqueiro.
"No formalities!
Call me Motta."
"Ok, Motta."
Wasn't it a French kiss?
It was written!
No, Vânia. It's not
a French kiss! Good job!
He kissed her!
Now, you can applaud!
Great job all!
It was a great rehearsal, Edmilson!
Great job! Don't forget to pause!
Breathe!
Guys, please pay attention!
Tomorrow, we'll do the scene with
Juliâo, Úrsula and Motta, ok?
Let's be prepared!
You are doing a great job!
Excellent!
Good job!
I'm glad you liked it!
I'm going to go change.
"I've came to offer my sincere
wishes of happiness for both.
May you, Motta, have
an everlasting relationship.
"My wish is for you, my cousin,
to have a great trip
back to your farm."
"Motta, that is not how
you should treat our visits."
"Cousin,
I've just came to offer you
my friendship, and one advice."
"So, do it!"
"Dear cousins, you didn't
only unit your farms,
as you have also occupied
other areas."
"And what exactly do you
have to deal with that?"
"Some of those areas already
had owners. Important people."
"I just settle people
in abandoned areas."
"Cousin Motta,
here is my advice"
Stand up, on "Primo Motta",
stand up, then say it!"
"Here is..."
"Cousin Motta,
here is my advice"
Walk...
Turn to the other side,
to the public.
Watch carefully..."
"Watch your steps carefully
Because if some day
you end up tripping and falling,
you won't find a single soul
to help you get up."
"Are you threatening
my husband?"
"I'm not threatening anyone!"
"Juliâo, get out
of my house!"
André, no! André, through
the aisle. There you go!
We wrap it up here,
looking at each other.
Very good!
Excellent, André!
Excellent job, Juliâo!
Very good!
Aline, I need
to talk to you.
Danilo, do I have to wear
a wig? The judge, does he?
We haven't thought
about that yet, Godofredo.
Aline, I wanted to...
I'm sorry.
No worries! Come in.
I wanted to talk to you.
I brought you a text...
About us?
You don't give up, do you?
Never! I always
go until the end.
I would like for you to read
this at the end of the show.
"After the hanging of Manoel
da Motta Coqueiro..."
It's an important text.
Very.
What about our end?
Our end...
Let's take it easy.
Don't tease me.
What's going on, Danilo?
Don't you know it?
Passión!
Put your clothes on,
and leave.
No! I am going to stay.
Leave, right now!
Bye!
I am sorry...
There are no excuses.
It wasn't my fault!
You allowed it, Danilo. You are
not a child. You've allowed it!
I didn't know she was a patient,
in the beginning!
This is very serious.
What you've done is very serious!
I've should had notice on
that day by the waterfall...
Those questions at
the waterfall... At the waterfall!
No! You might not believe it, but
I didn't want
any of this
to have happened!
It's unethical!
She played me!
You've created
a big problem for her...
You've created a big problem
for the other patients, and me!
I am sorry, but you cannot
continue teaching here.
What about the play?
They've memorized the script...
we have a rehearsal tomorrow!
What do you want?
Do you want to ruin everything?
Me?
You've ruined everything!
Tomorrow, I want you to come up
with a great excuse
to say goodbye to them.
You are making a mistake!
Shut up!
I work very hard
to make lifes of people like her
a bit better.
And that, you are not
going to ruin! You won't!
I'm going to leave
town for a while.
It's a complicated
family issue.
So, I hope you
can understand.
Danilo, please!
You can't leave us!
I'm not going
to leave you, Claudionor...
Doctor Márcia is going to get
someone else to work here.
Bad... bad...
It's ok! Sit down for a second,
and we will talk.
I must go.
I've already contacted
another teacher.
We are going to meet
this weekend,
and on Monday he's going to come
by to meet you guys, ok?
I wish you all
a great weekend.
Felipe, close the door.
Márcia, can we talk?
No, let's forget it.
Go away!
Everything is a lie!
Danilo doesn't have
any issue!
Doctor Márcia came up
with this whole story.
I heard them talking
yesterday.
She said that she didn't
like our rehearsals,
that nobody here, nobody,
was capable of acting...
That's not true!
We did it!
We all memorized
our characters!
So, she pretended?
She was pretending
to like it?
She lied.
That's not fair! It's obnoxiously
unfair for her to do that
with us, and for him
to go along.
Teacher, Danilo.
Teacher, Danilo!
Open the door, teacher!
Open up! Open up!
Hello, teacher Danilo!
How are you?
We came over to invite you
to come to your farewell party
that we are having
tomorrow in the afternoon.
Everybody from the theater class
is organizing it.
We are going to have sodas,
juice, and...
Hold on, Edmilson!
We would really
like for you to come.
We really, really do
want you to come, ok?
A party?
I'm not really up for parties,
Edmilson.
Oh, teacher! But we did
everything with so much love!
Are you just going to leave us
out like that, teacher?
Drop by, Danilo.
Look, here is the address.
Ok.
Alright! Alrighty then!
Edmilson, let's roll!
Bye, teacher! My stepfather is
giving me a new pair of sandals
for the party...
Let's go, Edmilson!
Hold on!
Why the hurry?!
Listen, we are going to wait
for you, Danilo!
Please don't bail on us!
Now, you are all in a hurry,
but to come, you were slugguishing
The house is huge!
And it is full of wood!
No, thank you very much.
I don't want any.
Is there any
alcohol, grandma?
No! Only juice.
This house is all of wood,
if it gets termites in here...
Look who is here!
It's so nice of you to show up,
Danilo. I'm so glad!
Thank you, Claudionor.
Look, my aunt gave me!
It's furry!
- It's nice, Nelson.
- Thank you!
Beautiful! Beautiful!
It's a pleasure!
Teacher Danilo,
look at my new sandals.
It was a gift
from my stepfather.
I missed you!
So did she!
I missed you too!
Give me a kiss.
Let me say hi
to everybody, ok Tonhâo?
André.
Did you like
my outfit, Danilo?
Teacher, there is a chair
for you over here
I came by bus with Nelson.
Hi!
Hi...
Grandma! Grandma! Come here!
This is Danilo.
He was my theater teacher.
Oh, ok. Are you
also a patient?
No, grandma! He is my
theater teacher.
Oh... what would you
like to drink?
Nothing, thank you.
Ok, then.
- Is it your house?
- Yes.
Where are your parents?
Traveling.
I was waiting on you!
I want to show you something!
Come in, Danilo.
This party is all on you,
isn't it?
It's a party for you.
Hey, hold on!
A gift... for you.
It's been here for years.
Wow! This is so rare!
Watch out for termites,
this house is made out of wood.
- What about the bread?
- I don't like bread!
Watch it!
Relax, grandma!
We are just talking.
Where is the bar key,
grandma?
I don't know.
I loved it!
Can we go back?
Give me the key!
Hold on! Calm down, Tonhâo!
Calm down!
Thanks, Otávio!
Guys, let's drink up!
Give me the liqueur!
I can't! I'm breastfeeding.
Just a sip won't do you harm.
No! I want real liqueur!
Give it to me, Tonhâo!
Oh, my God! My son-in-law
is going to kill me!
All hell is going
to break loose!
Didn't I tell you that
there were termites in here?!
Mrs. Yolanda,
where is the restroom?
I'm feeling some
pleasure on my genitalia.
Oh, my God!
It's there.
- Can you do it?
- Yes, I can.
- I want to see it.
- Ok!
Are you scared?
I am not afraid of anything.
I just don't feel like it.
Why?
Because I don't want it.
Give me the key!
Because I'm crazy
Insane...
Nuts...
I want to go downstairs.
One moment!
Where is the key?
Hot dog and some juice,
from Mrs. Yolanda.
I don't want it!
Excuse me.
But I brought it for you!
Thank you.
Aline?
What the hell is this?!
Motta Coqueiro!
Motta Coqueiro! Come out of there,
so that we can talk!
It's Carolina.
Benedito wants to talk
to you, Sir.
Where are we, Estela?
Sir, it's better that you know
that he has drunken a few...
Motta Coqueiro!
I've came to tell you that
I'm not leaving Bananal farm.
What's going on, Edmilson?
Don't you try to fool me with
the talk of how it has been
two years and you
haven't seen any changes.
If I didn't raise it for me,
what would my children eat?
Is everybody here?
I'm tired of hearing that to you
there are no advantages
of keeping me as a settler.
Well, do know that all
the advantage that you could have
taken, you have done it.
Chica! Chica!
Come over here, Chica!
Come here, Chica!
For the services executed
by my daughter to you,
I deserve to have the land
that I am occupying
What have you done to her?
Are you threatening me,
Motta Coqueiro?
First, you knock up my daughter,
and now you threaten my life?
That's enough, Edmilson.
Enough!
You are starting
to cross the limits.
I'm going to punch you so bad,
that I will cave your nose!
You are crossing
the line, Edmilson!
You are starting to hurt me.
Stop it!
With no nose, you are going
to look like a dried coconut.
I've already said
that I'm not Motta Coqueiro!
Could someone
please help me?!
I'm going to kill you!
You are hurting me!
That's about enough, Edmilson!
Felipe!
Felipe! Felipe!
I am going to kill you,
Motta Coqueiro!
Fidélis!
Let him go!
Are you out of your mind?
Are you crazy?
You should speak
with Mrs. Úrsula.
Mrs. Úrsula is a mother,
Mrs. Úrsula is a woman.
She is going to understand
the situation of my dear Chica.
Shut up!
What do I do with him?
Get them away from me!
But don't hurt them.
Neither him, nor Vânia.
I heard it all, Motta.
What the hell is this?
You were the one that brought
everyone over here, weren't you?
Manoel da Motta Coqueiro
don't change de subject!
Did you see
what he did to me?
Is the girl carrying
your child or not?
Did you see
what he did to me?
Excuse me, Mr. Coqueiro,
Mrs. Úrsula,
lunch is being served.
If I were you, I would start
looking for a new lover.
Why did you
bring me over here?
There is no need to serve me,
I don't want it!
Are you aware of what
you are doing to them?
No, you aren't!
What did you put in my drink?
Aline... Aline.
Could you stop
messing around?
Motta, your issues with Benedito
are making you so nervous.
I am not nervous!
Can you stop?
Let's end this.
Enough! It's over!
It's over! Over! Over!
Enough with this game, ok Estela?
Quit it!
Your food is getting cold.
Carlos!
Bring your lord's food
to him.
I don't want it!
I really don't want it, Tonhâo!
I do not want it.
Alright then,
I will leave!
Aline!
Tonhâo!
Estela!
Mrs. Úrsula!
- What took you so long?
- It took a while to gather them.
Mrs. Úrsula!
Mrs. Úrsula, you know
that I hear a lot, don't you?
And I've heard...
What have you heard,
Domingos?
I've heard that...
Nevermind, Mrs. Úrsula.
People are talking about a quarrel
among the lord and Benedito.
Let's bounce!
Come on, hurry!
Everybody?
Everybody.
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Let's bounce! Let's go!
Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Benedito, it's Fidélis.
Coqueiro wants to set
a deal with you.
I came to get you,
so that you could talk to him.
Businesses should be handled
at sunlight!
He wants to talk
to you today!
Don't open it!
He is leaving to Rio de Janeiro,
early tomorrow morning.
Open the door!
Edmilson! Edmilson!
Let's get this over with!
Let's do it!
Get her!
The bitch is running away!
Get that bitch!
Get her! Get her!
Die! Die! Die!
Where is everybody?
Estela!
Gather everyone, Aline!
Let's end this.
Let's be serious! It's serious!
They've killed them both!
Are you listening to me?
They've killed Edmilson and Vânia.
Say something!
They killed Edmilson and Vânia.
Aren't you hearing?
If you are speaking about
Benedito and Francisca,
I did what it had
to be done.
Or are you going to tell me that
you would like to have a baby
by that slut and lose our lands
to that drunk man?
She is not a slut!
She is Vânia! Vâ-nia!
He is not Benedito, he's Edmilson.
They've died, beaten to death!
Don't you get it?
They had it coming.
You are losing your mind!
Where is everybody?
André! Otávio! Heloisa!
Everyone.
It's over!
Aline, stop!
Who is Aline?
Who is she?
Why don't you tell me?!
Who is Aline?
I was so afraid...
I was so afraid
of losing you...
so, so afraid!
Are you taking your meds?
I don't need medication.
I am as strong as a horse!
I don't need drugs!
So, let's bounce.
So, let's go!
It's over! Come on!
Come on, gather everyone!
Come on!
Where will we go?
Call Otávio, Estela...
call everyone up! Let's bounce!
It's safe here.
It is safe here,
at our home, on our farm.
Do you know what is going
to happen with me after massacre?
No... how would I know?
I don't have
a crystal ball, Motta.
They're going to want to catch me!
I cannot stay here!
Motta, stay here! Motta!
Motta come back!
Come back!
Motta Coqueiro!
I caught you,
Motta Coqueiro.
My name is Danilo, man!
I am Danilo!
It's useless to try
to use a fake name.
The whole town
wants your neck!
Tell them to get off
from me, Otávio!
Son of a bitch! Come here!
You are going to face trial.
What trial?
You are going to face trial,
Motta Coqueiro.
And you know exactly
what happens to killers.
Nelson! Nelson!
Let's bounce!
Mr. Luiz Tinoco,
as you declares the defendant?
Innocent.
The prosecutor Paulino
has the stand.
We are gathered here
to judge a hideous crime
The massacre of a family!
Your Honor, juries,
please look
at the victim's clothes.
Blood! A lot of blood!
Slave, clean this up!
The police report revealed,
as the killers
two slaves, and two employees
of Manoel da Motta Coqueiro.
And as the mentor of the crime,
he himself, Mr. Coqueiro.
I call the first witness
to the stand,
the slave Balbina.
Object!
That's unconstitutional.
Well done, Mr. Tinoco.
The defender has pointed out
that according to the law,
slaves cannot testify
against their owners.
Your Honor, the defendant's
turned her over to his stepson.
She doesn't live
on his farm anymore.
Denied! Go on.
On the 12th,
early morning,
I heard Coqueiro
calling up four men.
That's a lie!
He wanted to know
if they had done the job.
That's a lie! How would she
see anything,
if she didn't live on
Motta Coqueiro's farm,
but on Carrapato's?
I was visiting my niece,
Did you hear Mr. Coqueiro say
why he ordered the killing?
No, sir. But everybody knew that
Benedito thought he had the right
to keep the Bananal's farm,
because Mr. Coqueiro...
because he had knocked up
his oldest daughter.
No further questions,
your Honor.
Would the defender like
to question the witness?
Carolina, do you confirm what your
aunt has said about
what she had heard the defendant
asking the 4 men about the job?
Everything happened
like she said.
No further questions, and I call
the slave Fernandes to the stand.
Do you belong to Juliâo
Baptista Coqueiro,
Motta Coqueiro's cousin.
My lord prefers to be called by
his new legal name,
which is...
Juliâo Baptista
Pereira de Almeida.
What do you know about
the massacre of Benedito's family?
I heard that...
Testimony of "I've heard"
is not a proof!
Juliâo wanted retaliate
Motta Coqueiro!
He wants to
manipulate this court!
Silence, defendant!
Do you have ways of proving
what you have just said?
The only proof I can give you
is my word.
The word of Juliâo Baptista
Pereira's slave
is good enough
for this court.
The defender may call
his witnesses.
No witnesses?
But to this court it does not
seem fair to allow the jury
to decide without hearing
the defendant's plea.
After the recess, we will hear
what Manoel da Motta Coqueiro
has to say.
Aline!
I loved the story!
They cannot be without
medication, do you get that?
Am I crazy? Nuts?
To insist on this story is
to be tied to the past.
Do I look like Úrsula?
But did he know that she was the
mentor, and didn't say anything?
Couldn't it be a connection
within the stories?
I loved the story!
Danilo, your students might
seem interesting,
they can even look normal,
but you can't forget
that they're patients
with very delicate issues.
You are scared.
To insist on this story is
to be tied to the past.
Your father was also a victim
of lack of justice, wasn't him?
Did you know that it was her
that ordered the murder?
Love, my love...
my love, please forgive me!
I didn't mean
for any of this to happen!
Jealousy! I was jealous!
I wanted revenge...
I didn't know they would go
all out until the end!
But I didn't tell them to kill.
I didn't! I swear!
I'm not going to leave you
alone on this!
I'm going to do everything
to get you out of this mess.
I've spoken with everyone.
It's just a matter of time!
They are going to hang me!
Listen! Listen to me.
Pay attention!
You cannot argue with them!
Are you listening?
What do I do?
I have it all under control.
Trust me!
Trust me! I have to go.
Just trust me!
What do I do?
State your name.
Danilo Maciel Porto.
Bastard!
Evil!
That's a lie!
Order! Order!
Order in courthouse!
If your client steps out of line
one more time, he'll be punished.
Don't try to hide!
You can't run from the truth!
Assume who you are.
Manoel da Motta Coqueiro.
Do you know those
that have accused you?
I thought I knew.
The prosecutor may ask
the defendant a final question.
Mr. Motta Coqueiro,
we are really astound.
Astound!
Your lawyer weren't able
to provide not even one witness!
No friends, no neighbors,
not even your slaves came
to testify on your behalf!
To what do you
attribute this fact?
To injustice.
Lack of justice my ass!
Killer!
The prosecutor may go.
Does the defender has any last
questions to ask the defendant?
The mentor?
Mentor...
Mr. Coqueiro, who do you
believe has ordered the massacre?
I must remind you that the mentor
might be condemned with death,
whomever she may be.
Trust me.
Mr. Coqueiro,
this is your last chance.
I don't know who ordered
the killing of Benedito's family.
Bullshit!
But I am innocent!
I would like for the jury
to state the guilty
or innocence of
Manoel da Motta Coqueiro.
Innocent!
He's not innocent!
Guilty! He is guilty!
He is guilty!
The defendant may go.
No honorable death for you,
Mr. Motta Coqueiro.
It hasn't been that long that
the Emperor has proclaimed a law
prohibiting the torture of
the condemned prior to his death.
Fortunately, we haven't been
deprived of capital penalty.
Death to the beast of Macabu!
Death!
Killer!
Beast of Macabu!
Manoel da Motta Coqueiro,
the Emperor Pedro II has denied
the clemency wish
from your defender.
May the sentence be executed,
and may you die a natural death.
Do you have anything
to say?
I am innocent!
"After the hanging of Manoel
da Motta Coqueiro,
evidences that the farmer
was a victim of conspiracy
were found.
Repenting for not conceding
clemency to a condemned man
without proofs, the Emperor
Pedro II started to accept
the clemency requests
that he did receive.
That's how the process
to extinguish
death penalty
Subs. ripeados por bluciano para
www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar