♪ You won't admit you love me ♪
♪ And so
how am I ever to know? ♪
♪ You always tell me ♪
♪ Perhaps, perhaps, perhaps ♪
♪ A million times
I've asked you ♪
♪ And then
I ask you over again ♪
♪ You only answer ♪
♪ Perhaps, perhaps, perhaps ♪
♪ If you can't
make your mind up ♪
♪ We'll never get started ♪
♪ And I don't wanna wind up ♪
♪ Being parted,
broken-hearted ♪
♪ So if you really love me ♪
♪ Say yes ♪
♪ But if you don't, dear,
confess ♪
♪ But please don't tell me ♪
♪ Perhaps, perhaps, perhaps ♪
You should have been
in school today, Christina,
and every other day.
You'll never catch me,
Inspector Clark.
That's what they all say.
I'll catch you, all right,
and I'll tell the judge to
send you off to Cuan Mhuire,
the old nuns will teach you
manners there.
In your dreams, mister.
There we go.
One, two, yeah.
Well? I won a singing
competition, Dad.
I got a voucher for my dress.
You are going to be a big star.
Do you promise me? Of course I do.
You have a great talent.
And you didn't
lick it off the stones.
Here, did I ever tell yous
about the time,
I won the All Ireland boxing?
Daddy was on the ropes.
Yeah, Dad.
Hilda Brannigan had a weakness,
so I punched him hard
in the ribs.
And he looks at me,
he starts to stagger sideways,
Then the coup de grace, boom...
and he goes down,
like a bleeding stone.
And that made you champion,
did it, Dad?
It did. Come on, get up.
Could have gone to America
myself after that.
All the promoters
were interested.
Why didn't you go, Dad?
Because I met your ma,
and that was the end of me.
Come on you.
If we don't get home,
she'll think we did a bunk.
Come on, Christina.
If we don't go now,
they'll be sold out.
Be careful there, Christina.
Don't worry about me,
Mrs. Doyle.
Aw, good girl.
Thanks, love.
I don't know
what happened to me there.
It must have been the excitement
seeing her all grown up.
♪ No need to speak ♪
♪ No more shall I seek ♪
♪ For my heart
has taught me their meaning ♪
♪ I saw your eyes ♪
♪ Your wonderful eyes ♪
♪ With love, light
and tenderness feeling ♪
Your father isn't coming home
anytime soon.
Christina,
bring your plate over.
I'm not hungry, Mum.
An hour ago you said
you could eat a horse.
That was an hour ago.
Is it horse stew
we're having, Mum?
Have you heard me?
What's this?
♪ Oh, Danny boy ♪
♪ The pipes,
the pipes are calling ♪
♪ From glen to glen ♪
♪ And down the mountainside ♪
♪ The summer's gone ♪
♪ And all the flowers
are dying ♪
♪ 'Tis you, 'tis you ♪
♪ Must go and I must bide ♪
Christina...
come on, get up...
quickly now.
Oh, will you get the children
after school, Mrs. Kelly?
And look out
to the little ones for the day.
I will, love,
don't you be worrying.
That's it. That's it.
Excuse me now.
And he looks like
a complete fool.
Mum.
Look, I wore me dress for you.
I'm sorry I've been asking
too many things.
You don't have to make me like
Dorset, if you don't want to.
I don't have to go to America.
I'll stay here
so long as you don't let me
lovely mum die.
Sure you won't, God?
It's time for you to go
on home now, Christina.
I don't want to go home.
That's as may be,
but your daddy's
waiting on you.
God told me to stay here.
He says
he's going to cure my mum,
if I stay here.
That's enough nonsense.
God can't cure everyone.
You're expected home.
Glasses off.
You don't need to be anxious.
It just takes a long time
to get through immigration.
I'm okay, don't worry about me.
You've been here
before obviously.
Twelve times.
You must like it.
Oh, I love it.
The people are fantastic.
The countryside,
the beach, the food.
What's not to like?
The queues.
All right, the queues.
The music.
Well, it's not Mozart,
but it's atmospheric.
The scary London, nearly
bouncing off the rooftops.
Also atmospheric.
Are you always
such a glass half empty type?
I'm only pulling your leg.
So what brings you here?
I don't know. If I told
you, I'd have to kill you.
Thank you.
Thank you, madam.
That's great.
Hello.
Excuse me?
My name is Christina Noble.
You're expecting me I hope.
We expect all our guests.
I suppose you do.
And what's your name?
My name is Mr. Reception Desk.
That's a nice name.
Passport.
You're English.
Irish, big difference.
Oh, yes, big difference.
Big difference.
How long you staying here
at the Cornett Hotel?
Well, as long as it takes
to make you smile,
Mr. Reception Desk.
Room 204.
Jesus.
Let me go please.
There you go.
It's hot dog?
No dog sorry.
It's not dog?
Not dog sorry.
I don't want dog. Yes, not dog.
Okay, I'll have two not dogs.
Okay, two not dogs.
Thank you.
Do you like to smoke, lady?
I gave them up.
It's never too late
to start again.
No, thank you.
You are on your own?
Yes, on my own.
No husband?
It's complicated.
What is your name?
My name is Meiyang.
Meiyang, Christina.
The truth is, Christina,
sometimes love last same,
same time as a cigarette.
Don't I know it?
I hear you.
Give me, give me.
♪ Red is the rose ♪
♪ That by in yonder
garden grows ♪
♪ Fair is the lily
of the valley ♪
♪ Clear is the water ♪
♪ That flows from the Boyne ♪
♪ But my love
is fairer than any ♪
Yummy.
Dad.
Yeah.
What did we do wrong?
It'll be for the best.
What will be for the best?
What will be,
will be for the best.
Did you ever really
love us, Dad?
It has been reported
by Mr. Clark,
the school's
attendance inspector,
that this has been
a particularly tiresome case
of truancy
and parental neglect.
His recommendation
is that the children be sent
to separate institutions
for their own educational
benefits and welfare.
Daddy!
Hold it down now.
Down the stairs.
Dad!
Good afternoon, sisters.
Well, there is punctuality
for you, Sister Sumta.
4 o'clock the man said,
and 4 o'clock it is.
What way did you come?
The Cong Road, Mother Superior.
And you were right.
They've had terrible floods
in Maam Cross.
Noah had nothing
on the west of Ireland,
isn't that the truth of us?
Take the child, Sister Sumta.
Don't worry about those
frightsy bitches of nuns.
I'll show you how to beat them.
Come on, Christina, quickly.
They're gone.
♪ By the light
of the silvery moon ♪
♪ I want to spoon ♪
♪ To my honey,
I'll croon love's tune ♪
♪ Honey moon,
keep a-shinin' in June ♪
♪ Your silvery beams
will bring love's dreams ♪
♪ We'll be cuddlin' soon ♪
♪ By the silvery moon ♪
Christina, you can come in now.
Take a seat.
Well, you're a tonic,
Mr. Brendan.
You really are.
Now, Christina, I hope you
said thank you to Mr. Brendan
for returning you safely
from your little farlay
into the great beyond.
Thank you again, Mr. Brendan.
He tells me
that you have a great talent.
Want to be nurtured carefully
at this tender age mind.
What with the potential
to blossom
into a wonderful national,
even international career.
Where did you say you had
your contacts, Mr. Brendan?
The Royal Albert Hall
in London,
Radio City in New York.
The Conservatoire in Paris.
Oh, yes, we mustn't forget
the Conservatoire.
There's only one problem.
What's that, Mother Superior?
That... That is...
That is that your name
isn't Doris Day, is it?
Do you actually
love those people?
Because I won't be a friend
for much longer if you do.
I know I should forgive them
but I'm not going to.
I'm going to stand up to them.
An eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth,
a slap for a slap.
Isn't that what you said
about something
that got in your way?
Don't worry, I wasn't
really gonna hit them.
It's just that you know
what's going on in my head.
I know I've taken
a few bad knocks.
I'm not saying
that was your fault.
Because I know you've got
a much better future
in store for me.
Hey, Irish,
you left your book behind.
I'll pick it up later.
Okay, in you go.
Excuse me...
Floor moving.
Yeah, going up in the world.
That's lovely, thank you.
It's great, Meiyang.
Okay, out we go.
Not allowed to bring
these bui doi children
into the hotel. Why not?
Do you not like Vietnamese
people staying here?
Thank you.
Xin chao.
Is that another glass
half empty I see?
Hello again.
Can I buy you a refill?
Sure, why not.
There's a place called Can Tho,
which is like a sort of Venice
in Mekong Delta.
It's quite a site.
You should go there.
To Venice?
No, to Can Tho.
It's only about a day's drive.
Don't worry, I'm going.
I'm going to see
all of Vietnam.
Well, do it before the place
gets developed to death.
It was once the Americans
with their trade embargo,
whoosh, same, same
as everywhere else.
Is that what you're here for,
David, whoosh?
I'm a businessman, Christina.
We all have to take
what we can get.
Do we?
I think we do.
Stand back now, kids.
Very, very hot, hot.
Vietnamese fish and chips.
Do you want salt and vinegar
on those?
Whoa.
Okay, let's go.
Oh, it's perfect.
Let's get places.
You are a tourist, Tina?
No, not a tourist.
What do you do?
I'm just a mother, mama.
Mama Tina?
Yes, Mama Tina.
Mama Tina, Lam.
Hello, Lam,
it's good to meet you.
Where is your family?
Don't know. Where are yours?
Well, my children
are in London.
They are grown up now.
They don't need
Mama Tina anymore?
No, only
when they get into trouble.
Do you have
brothers and sisters?
Two brothers, are bui doi also,
but I don't know
where they are.
What does it mean this bui doi?
It means "dust of life."
The dust beneath your soles.
Ah, I was bui doi also
when I was young.
No.
Yes.
Oh, my God!
What the hell do you think
you are doing?
They are not allowed
in my shop!
Those children are with me,
they are my guests.
But your guests
will ruin my business.
Tell me, Mrs. Noble,
do you know of any city
in the world
where people
want to see the streets
ruled by vagrant children?
No, inspector.
So what makes you,
a woman
newly arrived from Europe,
think that we should
give up our city
to this bui doi?
I don't.
But when I was young
I was also homeless,
without the protection
of parents.
An Irish gutter is the same
as a Vietnamese gutter.
I know how hard it is.
Really?
You must have been
a good beggar.
I've never begged for anything
in my life, inspector.
I always worked
when I was bui doi.
But at least I was allowed
to spend my money in a chipper
or an ice cream shop
without being thrown out.
Mrs. Noble, you are here
on a tourist visa.
And you behave
as if you have a work permit.
If I find
that you have violated
the terms of your visa
once more
you could be deported
and barred from Vietnam.
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, little devil ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, little devil ♪
♪ Hey, little devil,
you're always running around ♪
♪ Hey, little devil ♪
♪ It's time that someone
started taming you down ♪
♪ Hey, little devil ♪
♪ There'll be
some changes made ♪
♪ Your roving days
are through ♪
♪ Hey, little devil ♪
♪ I'm gonna
make an angel out of you ♪
You look good, Dad.
Well, I'm good.
Do you mean that?
They made me a farmer up the
brewery, took the pledge,
haven't had a drink
in a year and a half.
Look at you,
beautiful young woman.
Don't worry, Christina.
Really?
Hungry?
Come on, I'll treat you
to fish and chips.
The nuns gave me £5
to start me out in the world.
I'm gonna get a job
save up for singing lessons.
Then I might be able
to make a goal of it,
you know, professionally.
Didn't I always say
that was your destiny.
Be fair to you, Dad, it is.
Oh, now
there's a load of new houses
going up in Cromet.
I'll get our name
down on the corporation list.
We'll get your brothers
and sisters back,
be a family again.
What do you think?
Here. Here's the five
I owe you.
I just want to get some fags.
I've not any money.
A pint of bottle lemonade, Dad, will you?
Of course.
Back in a jiffy.
Dad, did Mum
ever get a gravestone?
Let's take care
of the living first,
and then, you know...
Would you like
some more water at the table?
Please.
Hey, you can pay at the till.
We close at 6.
Hey, come back here you!
Stop there, will you?
What are you crying for?
I'm the one
who should be bawling.
I said to him, "If you ask me
up to dance one more time",
I'll give you a box
in the nose."
You didn't. I said,
"Did no one never teach you
to take no for an answer?"
Well, he looked to me
like a dodo.
"No."
Ah, the poor fella.
Poor fella me, aye.
He was back 10 minutes later.
"Joan, would you ever
give us a dance
before they stop the music?"
What did you do?
I threw him a punch of course.
You didn't.
I did, he ducked.
Hit his friend,
scruffy little redhead.
I had to dance with him
then to make up for it.
I kissed him and all.
Redheads is good kissers.
More iron in their blood
or something,
but they do taste a bit rusty.
I'll get you one
to have a go-off.
You've done well, girl.
Keep it up now.
Don't let a good beginning
slip away from you,
like so many others.
Thank you, Mr. O'Reilly,
I won't.
That little redheaded fella
must have been contagious.
He would have given me the flu.
Where'd you live, Shoes?
Me?
Um, down at black pits?
You can walk home with us so.
That's my place.
I'll see yous all tomorrow.
We'll wait,
see you get in safely.
Okay.
Shite, I was wrong.
She's not a tanker. Mm-hmm.
Come on.
♪ Sweet dreams
till sunbeams find you ♪
♪ Sweet dreams that leave
all worries behind you ♪
♪ But in your dreams
whatever they be ♪
♪ Dream a little dream of me ♪
Lovely to meet you.
Goodbye now.
How are you, ladies?
You all right, Christina?
You look very pale.
Pale is the in vogue fashion,
Mr. O'Reilly.
Well, just make sure you're
getting enough to eat now.
Don't be spending
all your wages
in the in vogue fashions,
will you?
Ten more payments and you can
choose your mum's stone.
Then I'm going to carve
her name for free.
Oh, thank you.
Excuse me.
Can I help you up there, miss?
No, you're all right.
I can get up on my own.
Put your foot into my hands.
I'll hoist up, no bother.
There you go.
Let go of me. I'm over now.
Come on back down here
for a second, young one.
Let go of me I said.
I'd love to look up
what's up your skirt there.
Let go of me I said!
No! No!
We'll just have a bit
of fun, that's all.
Let's get rid of her quick.
Should we toss a coin, lads?
Head or tail, huh?
Grab her legs, that's it.
Leave the girl, will you?
You've let me down very badly.
And I want to know why?
So you better have something
very good in store for me,
to make it up to me,
all right, God?
I do think
you are a good worker.
It's just you can't go missing
for all that time
without so much
as a by your leave,
and expect your job to be here
whenever you pop up again.
That's just not the way
the world works.
Sweet Jesus!
I need to find a way
to help these kids.
Bui doi, the dust of life.
That's what I was once,
just like Tao and Han and Lam
and thousands of other kids.
I can't afford
to make anymore mistakes,
or I'll get
kicked out of this country.
I need you
to tell me what to do.
I'll tell you what.
I'll walk, you lead.
Kahm uhn.
This is private property.
Can I help you?
Sorry, the kite
came over the wall outside.
Thank you for returning it.
Is this a school?
No, it is
a government orphanage
of Binh Dai district,
private property. Thank you.
Is it ever possible
to visit the children?
Sometimes...
but strictly with permission.
Right,
who do I apply to
for permission?
Me.
The evasive agent arrange.
Up here all the children
brought to us
severely malnourished.
Are you a wealthy woman,
Mrs. Noble?
I wish I could say that I was.
Our history
is full of foreigners
who thought they could help.
Maybe we don't need
anymore disappointment.
I understand that.
What is it that you intend to
do for the sweet children?
I don't know yet exactly.
That is a good start.
When I was much younger
I had a dream
about your country.
I don't know why.
No doctor or psychiatrist
could explain
why I became obsessed
with a country
that I wouldn't have been able
to show them on a map.
Madame Linh,
this may sound mad to you,
but today, right here,
I have my explanation.
Come and see me again tomorrow.
Thank you.
Good morning, Christina,
or should I say good afternoon?
That was a long sleep you had.
Well, rest, recuperation,
get you back
to the full of your health.
That's what we're about here.
So let's just get you
signed in, will we?
A little bit like a hotel.
Now.
Just here.
What age are you, Sister Laura?
Thirty-one. Why?
Did you always
want to become a nun?
Always.
What about you, Christina?
Did you ever think
about a vocation?
Never.
Sorry I had to bring you
to the nuns, Christina.
It's the only place
that'd take you in.
There was no way they would
let me visit you before now.
"Three months of rest,
no excitements."
I told them I wasn't exciting.
"Come back in 3 months,
not before."
I think
you saved my life, Joan.
This lot are grand,
not like those kind
of lunatics.
I'm forgiven so?
Just about.
I'm going to England, Shoes.
Getting out of this
kip of a place.
Where will you go to?
Birmingham, I've a brother
who lives there.
Would you come with me?
I have no penny to go with.
I'll lend you the money.
You can pay me back
when you get a job.
What do you think?
Will there be any excitements?
There will be, loads.
Sister Laura, please!
Don't be ridiculous, Christina.
What's wrong with me
going to England?
There's nothing for me here.
Would you have some common
sense for God's sake.
What do you mean?
You are going
to have a baby, Christina.
Me?
Yes.
Why else do you think
you're excused
from heavy cleaning work?
And you get second helpings
at dinner
whenever you want them.
He's called Thomas,
after my dad.
Hello, Thomas.
He's gorgeous, Shoes.
So I picked up
the ferry tickets yesterday.
What's your plan for Saturday?
I'll tell them, I'll take him
out in the pram
for a couple of hours.
That's my usual.
Then I'll get the bus
to northwall.
I'll meet you there
at 5 o'clock.
Don't you dare be late now.
I'll go without you.
I will.
Someone's moved Thomas.
Was he taken to the nurse
to be weighed again?
Calm down, Christina.
Tell me where he is,
Sister Laura, please.
Thomas isn't here anymore. It's in
his best interest. Where is he?
You're only 17.
You haven't got a husband.
What's that got
to do with this?
Thomas has gone
to a good Catholic family
where he'll get
the very best of care.
So when do I get to see him?
Well, I'll go and get
my things together.
He's been adopted, Christina.
What?
But you can't do that.
But you signed the papers,
that first day you came here,
do you not remember?
No.
No, oh, my God.
Oh.
I forgive you for that,
Christina.
I don't know what to say
to you except that...
now we both know
what it's like to lose a son.
I'm not being blasphemous.
I'm not comparing
myself to you.
It's just that first I believe,
but now I won't be
able to keep going.
I won't survive.
I hope you're gonna explain
this to me, very bloody soon.
So until then you're gonna
have to listen to me
swear and curse and shout,
and I won't be asking
for your forgiveness.
Sorry about that.
This is the name
of the government department
you must contact.
It is forbidden
for any foreigner to work
in Vietnam without a red stamp.
Mm-hmm.
Ask for Mr. Ku
and mention my name.
I will, thank you.
And if you want to help
the street children,
you will need
to understand their dangers.
I would like you to meet Trung.
He will show you what I mean.
I've never
had a bodyguard before.
I never been
a bodyguard before.
What do you normally do?
I used to be a duck farmer.
A duck farmer?
Yes, duck is big business
in Vietnam.
Quack-quack, chop-chop.
I feel safer already, Trung.
What's this building used for?
Not used.
Hello.
It is not usual
to give a work permit
to a foreigner like this.
I do appreciate that,
and I'm grateful
for your consideration.
What will you bring
to Madame Linh?
I will bring hard work,
and passion,
love for the children,
my heart.
Your heart?
And money, I hope.
Oh, yes, and money.
Where will you get
this money from?
You let me worry about that,
Mr. Ku, I have my ways.
Is there anything else
that you would like to say
before we make our decision?
Would you mind
if I sang you a song.
A song?
It's an Irish tradition.
I just give you
the one verse, okay?
♪ Come over the hills,
my handsome Irish lad ♪
♪ Come over the hills
to your darling ♪
♪ You choose the road, love,
and I'll make a vow ♪
♪ That I'll be your true love
forever ♪
Thank you.
Thank you for your application,
Miss Noble.
We are interested
in what you say
and we like the way
that you say it.
You're very kind.
We will give you a work permit.
Oh, that's brilliant.
For 3 months.
Three months?
That's not very long, Mr. Ku.
Let's see what your heart
can do in 3 months.
I'm checking out.
I can see that.
I'm going to live
with the bui doi.
They offered a better quality
of cockroach
than the Coronet Hotel.
Aha, see, I told
you I'd get a smile
out of you before I left.
No smile.
Oh, yes.
You smile like a little baby.
I'll see you around,
Mr. Reception Desk,
don't forget me now.
I forgot you already.
This way.
Judy say, "Cheap, cheap place."
I need to save
all the money I can, Mia.
People here will
think you are insane.
Yeah, well, a little insane
goes a long way.
It's not far from Madame Linh.
It's perfect.
Dear, sir,
I'm writing on behalf
of the street children
of Ho Chi Minh City.
I'm trying to raise funds
for the building
of a Social and Medical
Center in district 3.
If your company will be
interested in helping
to improve the circumstances
of these children,
I will be very grateful.
Perhaps I could
come to your offices
to make a sure presentation
about my plans.
I look forward
to hearing from you.
Yours sincerely,
Christina Noble.
Finished?
Yes, 19 letters to deliver.
You're going to have
a busy day tomorrow.
I dream of a busy day.
What else do you dream of, Lam?
I dream of a busy day,
that's all.
I have always wanted
to rebuild this,
but never had the money.
Hey.
What the hell are you doing,
you mad woman.
You're trying to get
yourself killed?
Are you Irish?
Amongst many other
fine attributes, yes.
I need to talk to you.
What about?
It'll sound better mixed
with whiskey.
All right, I'll see you inside.
And I'm not just talking about
the facility that's so so.
I'm talking about a place
that you'll be proud of
if it was in Dublin or London.
Treating Third World children
the same
as First World children.
BlueRock Oil could be
a founding sponsor, Gerry.
I have to go in.
And what can I say, Christina,
I'll read your proposal.
I'll show it to a couple
of colleagues
and I'll give you a call.
I bet you say
that to all the girls.
No, only the crazy ones.
Okay, Lam?
Okay, Mama Tina,
Lam has another dream.
Do you want to tell me?
When my father died,
my mother was very lonely.
No money,
me and two older brothers
at home, very hungry.
Then Mr. Rat
moved in with my mother.
He beat us, throw us
out onto the street.
I miss my mother.
I dream that one day
I'll see my mother again.
I have the same dream, Lam.
I wish you'd come...
Do you good to get out.
You've been in here
nearly 2 months now.
Any day, Joanny, I promise.
There'll be no holding me
back then.
Stop your nagging,
is that what you mean?
I'll try not to wake you.
Hello, how may I help you?
I'd like to apply for the job
in the Fish and Chip shop.
Do you have
experience working chips?
Well, I haven't, no.
I've plenty experience
eating them.
Three cod large, salt and
vinegar on those? Yeah.
And a smoked herring
and a single for you, sir.
Thank you.
Who's next now?
Yes, Mrs. Hennessey,
the usual, is it?
Well, that'd be lovely.
Underway.
Another bucket of chips there, Jimmy.
We're good.
Now who's gonna play for
a hired working girl?
I will.
Oh, true gentleman at last.
Watch and learn, all you lads.
...you say.
All right.
Two pickled eggs, she says.
Okay. Music is the way
to a woman's heart,
is it not right, Mr. Olden?
Whatever you say, Christina.
♪ Our lips shouldn't touch ♪
♪ Move over, darling ♪
♪ I like it too much ♪
♪ That gleam in your eyes ♪
♪ Is no big surprise anymore ♪
♪ Because you fooled me before ♪
♪ I'm all in a spin ♪
♪ Move over, darling ♪
♪ About to give in ♪
♪ And though it's not right ♪
♪ I'm too weak to
fight it somehow ♪
♪ 'Cause I want you right now ♪
Ugh, Cyprus, that's gorgeous,
I think I'll go in there next.
And sea is so bright blue
just like a...
like... there's nothing
here that blue.
Do you know the color
that is called turquoise?
Where we you come from,
turquoise is big birds you
kill and eat for Christmas.
So what brought you here then,
Mario, to Birmingham?
You maybe.
Charmer, go away back
to the warm blue sea with you.
Don't listen
to a word, Christina.
I'm not so much charmer,
more straight, direct.
You know?
I like you Joan.
You're funny
like comedy, you know.
The house rules, I lock
the front door at 9 o'clock
so you must be in by then.
No exceptions and no late entry.
Breakfast to serve
from 7 o'clock to 8 o'clock.
No pets.
No visitors,
and no inappropriate
or immoral behavior.
The car park's
at your own risk.
Sorry, I'm late, Mr. Olden.
The bus broke down
on Mosey Street,
the whole place
is flooded down there.
Congratulations, Christina,
you got a new boss.
Mario has given me
a very generous retirement.
No, no, no,
Christina is the boss.
They're happy tears.
Mario has been so good to me.
Nobody has been this good to me
since my mum died.
Huh, except me.
Except you.
Oh, I'm gonna miss you, Shoes.
Mario's.
Just the start of my empire.
♪ The man is tall,
mad, mean and good lookin' ♪
♪ And he's got me in his eye ♪
♪ When he looks at me,
I go weak at the knees ♪
♪ He's got me going
like no other guy ♪
♪ 'Cause he's my big, bad,
handsome man ♪
♪ He's got me
in the palm of his hand ♪
♪ He's the Devil Divine,
I'm so glad that he's mine... ♪
The Americans were destroyed.
What they have claimed
to protect.
But Viet Cong
still concentrated in strength
closing around the major
centers of the nation...
What can I get you?
The bulldozers plow
under the rubble of the homes
and the burnt acres
where the Viet Cong
held out for the first days.
The communists have succeeded
in providing
massive new distractions
of re-housing,
and relief,
and rebuilding to add
to the burdens
of a creaking government.
At the moment,
everyone is waiting
for the expected
second wave of attacks.
Viet Cong have taken
heavy casualties
that may dictate a delay
perhaps to intensify recruiting
in new areas
under their control.
Michael Carlton reporting
from the war in Vietnam.
And in another story connected
to that part of the world,
the families
of American soldiers
missing in action
have received the support
of the famous film star,
Doris Day.
Miss Day has agreed
to be a patron
for league of families
of American prisoners
and missing soviets
in Southeast Asia.
It's the bright blue sky.
I've told you before. They're
not bloody well going with you.
Why not? Because I don't have
a good feeling about this.
You don't have a good feeling
about my children,
visiting an 80-year-old aunt
who has traveled all the way
from Cyprus, who will only
give them sweets and kisses?
It's not your aunt
I'm worried about.
What then?
It's all your showing off,
and driving at 100 miles an hour
like you always do.
What do you know
what I always do, huh?
Shut up talking
for once in your life.
Gladly.
You're a stupid Irish bitch,
you know that?
Maybe you also a witch, huh?
Putting spells on people.
My children
would have been killed
or maimed if they'd
been in that car.
I'm gonna do something
about you.
Yeah?
I'm gonna do something
about you too.
Do you know who I am?
I know what you are.
What am I?
A fish wife.
Get your own husband.
He'll come after me, Joan.
He always does.
This can't go on, Shoes.
You're lucky you
didn't lose an eye.
What'll he do the next time?
I need to know
that you're still there.
Have you forgotten me
completely?
I don't think Joan believed me
when I told her
you sent me the dream.
She's more worried about me now
than when I was dead
to the world.
But I know you've sent it
and I know I have to follow it,
just give me
a bit of time, will you?
I will go to Vietnam,
I swear to Almighty you,
when the time comes
nothing would stop me
and You better be
coming with me.
Well, they're rubbish.
Thanks for keeping
them for me, Fan.
No good news?
No, not today.
Maybe it's not your destiny.
What isn't?
Looking after these bui doi,
maybe you can't do it.
There's no such thing as can't.
You tell him, Christina.
You get me this number in Hanoi
and I'll take it in
booth three.
Okay.
Who's this little man?
This is Lam.
He's my new business partner.
We're waiting for everything
to go whoosh.
Very funny. Hello, Lam.
He's got look of a young
Jimmy Cagney about him...
Something in the eyes I think.
Your call.
Great.
Don't let her
work you too hard.
From here
to the end of that wall.
Yeah.
Just having a child
is difficult for poor people
in Ho Chi Minh City.
If there is a birth defect,
they think they are being
punished by fate
and they abandon the child.
Abandon where?
In this place, in the garbage.
We always give babies a name
when they arrive.
We call her Mai,
it means cherry blossom.
Will Mai live?
The infection
on her head is bad.
We will see.
♪ Stars shining bright
above you ♪
♪ Night breezes seem
to whisper "I love you" ♪
♪ Birds singing
in the sycamore tree ♪
♪ Dream a little dream of me ♪
♪ Stars fading
but I linger on, dear ♪
♪ Still craving your kiss ♪
♪ I'm longing to linger
till dawn, dear ♪
♪ Just saying this... ♪
My name is Christina Noble,
and I work
for the street children
of Ho Chi Minh City.
There's a lot of them
as you know
and they need love and looking
after as much as the next kid.
So if you can help us,
we'll be very grateful.
♪ Dream a little dream of me ♪
It's a fair enough proposal
if we can make it...
We make it happen
before the year ends.
Yeah.
Listen, can I call you back?
Something's just come in.
All right.
Can you give me
half an hour, Gerry?
I'm afraid you'll have
to make an appointment
just like anyone else,
Christina.
Do you not take a lunch break?
Texas, Siberia, Vietnam,
or everywhere.
You'd be surprised
how many parties
there are in the oil business.
Why is that do you think?
Because we are
very good at digging.
Years of practice.
I always thought
people drill for oil.
Well, that's exactly
where they've been going wrong.
Digging is the new drilling.
Is it?
It is,
and that is our company motto
and that is why we are
top of the heap.
And what do you see
when you look down, Gerry?
Ah, you don't look down,
Christina.
Isn't that what they tell you?
Because you might get
vertigo and fall.
That's right.
Don't you be worrying,
I'll catch ya.
Hello, Mr. Ban, hello, Wade.
Hello, Mama Tina.
I brought you some rice
and toys on my way.
This is my friend, Gerry.
He wanted to meet you also.
Mama Tina, Mama Tina.
Must come now,
please, must come now.
What is it?
Mama Tina. I'm coming, Lam.
Okay, Lam, you stay here.
You mind the bike, okay?
Don't worry, don't worry.
It is him. Bastard.
How old is that girl?
I would say 10.
So would I.
You better careful, Christina.
This man always dangerous.
Just in here.
A foreigner has just taken
a young girl up to his bedroom.
You call him, tell him
bring her down, now.
What you say? Trung, please.
What are they saying? They're
asking if anyone know who you are.
It doesn't matter who I am. There's a
dangerous man up there with a child.
Get the manager, now.
Come on, come on, for God's sake.
What do you want?
I want you to do something
about the fact
that your hotel
is being used by foreigners
to abuse Vietnamese children.
Get out.
This is a good place,
three stars.
I have just seen one of them
take a child up
in the elevator.
His name is David Summers.
You call him,
you get him down here
or we will go up
and break the door in.
What'd he say?
He says you have to go
or he'll call the police.
Yes, call the police, that's
exactly what you should do.
I ask you
for the last time to get out.
I don't know you,
why are you causing trouble?
Listen to me, I have
been given permission
by the government to look
after these children,
to stop them
from being raped in your hotel.
Now you get that man down here
or I will call
Inspector Bong myself.
Would you do this to a 10-year-old
girl in your own country?
I should've known
you're just a frustrated
old cad the
first time I met you.
Just because
she's a street child
you think you can do
what you like to her?
Mind your own business.
If I see you
with a child again,
I'll splash your ugly face
across every newspaper
in Southeast Asia.
I will get you, bitch!
Oh, you don't frighten me.
I am not a child
that you can frighten.
Look, those kids up there
are the lucky ones.
They've got a roof
over their heads.
What if you're a child
living on the streets?
You're 12 years old and you're looking
after your little sister, she is 6.
Forget about education
or healthcare,
forget about protection
from danger
or a little bit of love
and a cuddle, forget that.
And now count yourselves
in the thousands,
living out there in every
derelict building in this city.
Just like this one here,
except this one is going to be
rebuilt so that you can come
and visit for basic hygiene,
for medicine, for school,
and to be treated
like a kid again.
Because that's the very least
that you
and your little sister deserve.
So it'll go before
the committee up at head office.
Now unfortunately, Christina,
there's a couple of today's
delegates that feel it's...
Feel what?
That it's just a drop
in the ocean
in the context of the overall
need in Ho Chi Minh City.
Now therefore disinclined
to recommend.
But this is only the beginning.
This is just the blueprint.
If we build one center,
we can build ten.
I'm sorry
not to be more positive.
Fight for me, Gerry.
You can bring them around,
I know you can.
Christina, you don't want
to work for me, do you?
No, I want you to come
and work for me.
Is that Carol?
Speaking.
It's Christina Noble.
Yeah, I know that
but if you could just be sure
to tell Gerry
that I called again.
I will, yes.
Yeah, and to make the point that it's
been 2 weeks since the delegation visited
and I was promised a decision
within 10 days.
I will tell him.
I'm sorry to be pushy, Carol, but my
government parameter is running out fast.
I will tell him.
It'll be okay, Lam.
Mr. Rat has gone.
Lam can stay with his mother.
That's great, Lam.
You come and see me
sometime, okay?
Oh, God.
Mrs. Noble,
we are on the same side.
I hate this people
as much as you do,
but I need evidence.
Here. Here's evidence.
There's a photo of him
on this roll of film.
I took it the night
that I followed him.
Illegally? Justifiably.
So what is the photograph of?
Him, David Summers.
Is there a child
with him in the photograph?
No.
I need you to do
something for me, Fan.
You're not going to like it.
Tell me something new.
Don't worry, Mama Tina,
I look after them for you.
I know you will.
And don't be offering
them cigarettes, all right?
I promise.
You promise to come back.
On my mother's grave.
And don't bring any husband.
I would be jealous.
No husband, I promise.
It's fucked up.
Ready?
I may have to be in London
for a few months, Madame Linh.
I know I'll have to apply
for another permit.
I'll...
just have to take my chances.
And I'm sorry
about the typewriter,
I will replace it.
I don't think they will
give you another permit.
The time has passed
and we achieved very little.
Excuse me, Christina.
Your car is here
to take you the airport.
What car?
I didn't order a car.
Jump in and close
the door, will you?
The air conditioning is doing
overtime in this bloody heat.
Hello, Christina. Gerry.
I hear you're on your way back
to the London.
You hear right.
That's a pity.
That's also a pity that
I've been turned down by
every oil company in this city.
Germans, Mexicans, Taiwanese,
and I've been calling
your office for 2 weeks
without getting a reply.
I'm sorry, I've been very busy.
Yeah, that's what they all say.
I wouldn't go to the airport
right now if I were you.
Why not?
Because our committee
has taken a liking
to your proposal for a
social and medical center.
Don't...
Don't mess with me, Gerry.
Twenty thousand dollars
of our liking.
Are you joking me?
No.
Oh, my God.
Congratulations.
I won't let you down.
I know.
That is amazing.
Thank you.
What the hell are you doing?
Leave me.
No. Don't, no.
Mrs. Noble, you have
already met your destiny.
You have nothing left to prove.
You know me a little,
not a lot.
I have everything
left to prove.
You must have a stronger focus
if you are to win the battle.
You forget that
they call us the fighting Irish.
We, Vietnamese, have faced
more powerful enemies than you.
Not all, you've never taken
on the nuns, twice.
We are ready for them.
That's what you think.
And are you ready, Mrs. Noble?
I am, Madame Linh.
Ready, steady, go.
Oh. Ow.
♪ In my place, in my place ♪
♪ Were lines
that I couldn't change ♪
♪ I was lost, oh, yeah ♪
Not today, girls.
I'd rather...
♪ I was lost, I was lost ♪
♪ Crossed lines
I shouldn't have crossed ♪
♪ I was lost, oh, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, how long must
you wait for it? ♪
♪ Yeah, how long
must you pay for it? ♪
♪ Yeah, how long must
you wait for it? ♪
♪ Oh, for it? ♪
♪ I was scared, I was scared ♪
♪ Tired and under-prepared ♪
♪ But I'll wait for it ♪
♪ If you go, if you go ♪
♪ Leave me down here
on my own ♪
♪ Then I'll wait for you,
yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, how long must
you wait for it? ♪
you pay for it? ♪
♪ Yeah, how long must
you wait for it? ♪
♪ Oh, for it? ♪
♪ Singing ♪
♪ Please, please, please ♪
♪ Come back and sing to me ♪
♪ To me, to me ♪
♪ Come on
and sing it out, now, now ♪
and sing it out to me, me ♪
♪ Come back and sing it ♪
♪ In my place, in my place ♪
♪ Were lines
that I couldn't change ♪
♪ And I was lost, oh, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪