Indifferent.
Bloody indifferent.
I am not wise.
I don't know anything.
Can't be bothered t0 do anything.
I don't know how t0 get a grip.
My head is broken.
My body sinks t0 the ground.
My hand is a strange object.
Disorder.
Chaos.
I remove the sheet of paper
from the typewriter.
It's an action.
I smoke a cigarette.
NOTES ON LOVE
A FILM BY JQRGEN LETH
I smoke a cigarette.
I think about you.
I think about your knees.
The way it feels
when I hold you behind your knee.
I smoke a cigarette.
When it rains, it rains.
When it's warm, it's warm.
When it's dark, it's dark.
When I close my eyes
and imagine you, -
- softly, I stroke
your neck and throat.
I can feel your belly, -
- your nipples, -
- and the warmth in your armpits.
And I imagine -
- that this is how you are.
Only this.
And I wonder -
- if I can open my eyes -
- and love you -
- at the same time.
I travel t0 the islands
t0 begin somewhere.
T0 begin somewhere.
70 years ago,
Malinowski was here.
He slept in his tent.
He woke up in the morning.
He spoke with the natives.
He collected his material.
He wanted t0 describe love.
That was his project.
Malinowski is my hero.
Ask them to look this way.
Bossa Nova rhythms
Bossa Nova rhythms.
I don't mind at all.
Bossa Nova rhythms
I don't mind at
I don't mind at all.
Bossa Nova rhythms
I don't
I don't mind at all.
Bossa Nova rhythms
Id0n't mind no.
I don't mind at all.
Bossa Nova rhythms
I can tell you exactly
what I am doing to you.
I am holding you in my arms.
I am kissing you.
I am holding your body
against my body.
And I won't let you go.
That is what I am doing to you.
Tell me
what you are doing to me.
What are you doing to me?
It's more than one aperture.
- It's clear now.
- I can see that.
- Is there a long clear stretch?
- Yes, with one cloud in between.
It was completely clear just before.
- And also now, right?
- No.
I'm taking my jacket off.
I'm putting it on again.
I remember we were standing
in front of the mirror.
Your body.
I'm caressing it.
I'm kissing you.
I like your body.
Are you there now?
We have to end it.
I love you.
I can feel my body
on the rivers.
Everything is just right.
My foot is where it should be.
My hand is calm.
Through the rivers
I penetrate the land.
I lie back -
- and forget everything.
I like it when you say it to me.
I like it when you say
that I am your woman.
And action.
I like it when you say it to me.
I like it when you say
that I am your woman.
That I am your woman.
That I am your
woman.
And action.
I like it when you say it to me.
I like it when you say
that I am your woman.
I am your woman.
Tell me what you're thinking about.
Tell me your thoughts.
I wasn't really thinking.
I was listening
to the sound of your voice.
I was listening to the sound
of your voice.
Subtitles:
SDI Media Denmark