Come, come.
Alright. You want work?
Go make a ladder out of bread.
What's wrong with him?
- I don't know.
Might be because of the rain.
Goddamnit! I used my best tools on him.
It's so beautiful.
Like the Christmas tree in church.
I like slaughtering pigs more.
Based on Andrus Kivirähk's novel "Rehepapp".
Get up! It's All Souls' Day.
Go heat the sauna.
And you set the table.
Let them eat and bathe, the poor beasts.
They're not beasts!
They're mother and grandfather.
How can you say that?
No need to mince words about it.
The dead can't afford to be picky.
They're no longer people.
So why not call them beasts?
When my grandmother was little,
she snuck into the sauna to see
what the dead were doing in there.
She opened the door, and what did she see?
Human-sized chickens
thrashing themselves with birch twigs.
Isn't a chicken an animal?
Are you trying to heat the village?
What did you bring for me?
Hold on. You'll see.
How pretty!
My God! It's so fancy!
Not bad, eh?
- Where did you get it?
>From the old baroness. It's her last one.
I went through all her trunks
but she has nothing left to take.
It's all mine.
I feel bad for the old lady.
She's bedridden and doesn't
even have a night gown to wear.
Once I felt so bad for her
that I gave her one of mine.
Yours? Aren't your nightgowns really hers?
What's in the past doesn't matter.
What do you want for it?
It's a very expensive and nice dress.
What happened to your silver brooch?
I'd give up the dress for that.
For this, all you get is a strip of silk.
She's all tarted up. It's disgusting.
I don't know. She looks beautiful.
You try cooking that beauty in a pot
and see if it fills your belly.
I saw...
your mother by that willow tree.
How did you know I was
looking for my mother?
I'm also waiting.
My mother is buried here too.
The Rääk dead are here.
Welcome! Let's go home.
Come on.
Are you coming? Let's go!
Wasn't that Liina?
Yes.
She's grown into a beautiful woman.
-Yeah.
The sauna is ready.
As always, you'll take the bed
and we'll sleep on the floor.
I'm not worried about my hidden treasure.
But I brought some trinkets home.
Where are they?
- Liina?
Where is it?
Where's the ring?
It's gone!
So that's why the kratt
was snooping around!
Why didn't you tell me? When was it?
The day before yesterday!
I came from the well with buckets
and I saw a kratt
scurry out of the back.
What did it look like?
It had a broom for a tail
and a bucket for a head.
I'm going to find that thief
and tear him to pieces.
Where are you taking that bread?
If she's that hungry,
she can come in with the others.
Father hasn't changed.
How could you bear him?
But I didn't.
Eat, mother.
I had you.
Everyone needs something...
Even better, someone.
I have someone.
-Very good.
Mother!
God speed, dear ghosts!
How's life in the other world?
Get enough to eat?
Can't complain.
Of course not, if you have bread to eat.
All we have is willow bark and slush.
We heard the Rääk silver
is buried somewhere.
I wonder where?
We want to go for a walk
to pick some flowers.
It's so nice out!
We want to make a wreath!
What flowers will you pick
in November, you old hag?
The body and blood of Christ.
Talupojad hakkavad Jumalasõna kuulama.
The peasants are listening to the Word of God.
Mida nad teevad?
What are they doing?
-They use the wafers as bullets
so they'll never miss
when they're hunting.
Mida?
What? - It's the body of Christ.
No beast can resist Jesus.
Jesus will bring it down.
See on ju patt!
That is a sin!
Give me work Sander.
A kratt needs to work.
My master didn't give me work.
So I wrung his neck.
And who was that fool?
- Some shepherd boy.
A child, of course.
A kratt could never get
the better of a grown man.
Stop staring.
You'll never wring my neck.
I didn't make you
so my name's not in the Devil's book.
Why do you think
I pulled you out of the mud?
I came to ask for currants.
Going to the crossroads again?
Well, my last kratt caught fire.
And I'm too lousy of a man
to manage without a kratt.
What do you want?
-To buy a soul for a kratt.
A soul?
Are you eating your kratts?
Eat fish instead,
they taste much better.
My family eats tree bark and bats.
We won't survive the winter
without a kratt.
Write your name here in blood
and you can even make your pants dance!
Shall we make those pants dance?
Leave my pants be.
I have a kratt's body ready at home.
Just give it a soul.
We can make
my pants dance next time.
Blood for you, a kratt soul for me.
Go now. It already lives.
That hit the spot!
Pour me another.
So, how are things
in your neck of the woods?
It's a constant shit storm.
Fucking hard work.
No time to take a dump!
We can have the wedding at Christmas.
The pig, the old cunt,
isn't putting on weight this year.
She should be ready by then.
Then we slit her throat and good to go.
And how will you marry her
with a slit throat?
Who?
-The pig. Your bride.
What is this bullshit?
The pig isn't my bride.
So who is?
- Well, you are.
Me?
Are you sure?
-Very sure.
And I thought it was the pig.
What is this bullshit?
Pig and pig...
I'm leaving.
Everything set?
- Piss off!
The baron's daughter
came to visit from Germany
and brought a suitcase full of under pants.
How many do you want?
How can you take them?
Won't the baron find out?
It's not his business
what I do with my underpants!
How are they your underpants?
Who else's?
This land belongs to Estonians.
Everything on Estonian soil
belongs to us.
Don't you know about King Lembitu
and our ancient freedoms?
How the baron's forefathers
unjustly killed our king
and began ruling over us?
That doesn't give them
the right to our land!
I am an Estonian.
Thus, the baron's underpants belong to me.
Is that what you'll tell the baron?
I'll tell the baron
that his underpants got horny
and ran off into the woods!
How many do you want?
- Wait, Ints. Slow down.
I have another problem.
Can you sneak me
into the baroness's room?
A strange desire.
- Why?
Isn't her room on our land?
Don't I, as a descendant of Lembitu,
have the right to go
in there if I want?
That's right!
And no German thug
can take that right away!
Come to the kitchen door tonight.
Luise!
Hello.
Isa, keegi oli siin!
Father, someone was here!
Rahune. Siin pole kedagi.
Calm down. There's no one here.
See on su haigusest. Täna on täiskuu.
It's your illness. There's a full moon.
I love you. I love you.
I love you.
Move that stump.
Move that by tonight.
Let me help you.
Keep it up.
Well, men, taking a rest?
Let's get to work! Take these...
Arsehole! You can't tell us what to do!
Manor lackey! Arse-kisser!
Hans!
You weasel! Damned prick!
- Hans!
Stop it!
Don't do that!
Hans!
-Your Hans became the overseer!
Liar!
-That maggot!
I want to be his wife.
Witch, can you make him forget her
and love me instead?
One thing we can do
is kill the girl Hans loves.
I'll do it.
Throw this at her window.
When she looks out,
the arrow will hit her head and
spill out her brains.
Uncle! Take me across the river.
I'll repay you with a kiss.
Where's my kiss?
Take your pants off
and put them on your head.
The plague will think we have two arses
and won't dare to touch us.
Drop dead, cretin!
That was close.
Get up! No time to waste.
The plague will be back
and we won't fool it twice.
It has transformed into something else
and we have to find it. Go look!
What the hell are we looking for? Tell us what it turned into.
I don't know. Use your heads.
If you find something unusual,
bring it to me.
That's a nail.
A mosquito.
A button. Haven't you seen a button before?
A snail. - What about the manor?
Will the plague go there?
I hope it goes and
strikes down every one of them.
This is no time
to squabble with each other.
Tomorrow we'll all lie
side by side in one grave.
There's nothing here!
No, Liina, dear. This time,
the plague was cleverer than us.
Well, hello!
This one couldn't bear to
show the coin to others.
But the plague isn't a sausage
you eat alone.
Come on, then!
Why spare the likes of us?
We steal from each other
but bury our haul or gobble it down.
We should be happy
to be freed from our shame.
I only ask one thing of you plague.
Let one boy and one girl live
to keep our race alive.
Do you swear?
Swear it on the Bible!
What happened dear?
Hans loves her.
And he always will.
So you didn't kill her?
-  I can't.
If I did, Hans might die of sadness.
And where would that leave me?
Die of sadness?
Hans seems quite strange
if such a death awaits him.
Yes, he is.
But that's why I love him.
Do you understand?
Maybe. Right now, I'm an old hag.
But I once waited for a boy
to climb into my hayloft.
Did he?
Did you come to cheat me
as well, you scoundrel?
I'll give your kratt a soul
and in return I get yours.
Now your blood is mine!
Here is the soul for your kratt.
Greetings, Master!
And blessed be your home!
I have a job for you.
I am truly sorry to disappoint you Master.
But kratts cannot carry people.
You created me for nothing
and I regret my shortcomings.
I would like nothing more than to
bring two loving hearts together.
Is she enchanting,
your beloved?
Enchanting? No. She is pretty.
I can imagine.
Skin like white marble, lips like velvet,
eyes deep like two dark springs
where the water is bewitched
and drinking it makes you lose your mind.
Where did you learn
to talk like that kratt?
Everywhere. I flowed through old cities as a river,
I burbled in splendid gardens
as a fountain,
I fell as rain and carried countless ships.
Now l am snow and for the first time I have the ability to speak
through the mouth you gave me, Master!
Well, Hans, what is this?
Building snowmen like a child?
This snowman is my kratt.
You won't believe the stories he tells.
Until a few months ago,
I lapped along the Venetian canals
and a gondola carried
two lovers over me.
This is for you, for being so divine.
Now it is time for us to part ways.
We will never see each other again.
Let this ring remind you of me.
I don't buy it.
If he was leaving,
why did he give her his ring?
Was he stupid or something?
If I cannot have you,
then I do not need your ring!
Maybe we can still find that ring?
I'll go look.
Unbelievable stories!
They're so enchanting.
Enchanting?
Where did you hear that word?
Do you want to take a wife? That's easy.
It's about time we had a wedding
and got to gorge ourselves.
The woman... She's the baroness.
You know very well why I'm here.
I didn't come to warm my arse, I want to marry Liina.
I don't have time to wank off.
We made a deal at the pub.
So let's finish the booze and that's that.
Drink this, it'll make your fur shine.
I brought you a roll.
Eat your own rolls!
And I hope you choke on them!
Calm down.
Endel is a good man.
But he doesn't stand for this behavior.
Go away!
- You can't escape Endel.
I'm your father and l decide.
You don't have to get married. You can simply love.
I have seen plenty of young
men who cannot marry their loves
and write beautiful poetry about it.
And when the lovers part ways,
a dagger finds its way
into the lover's heart.
I came to ask you for help.
Liina came to me. She's very sick.
She's in love with a man
who doesn't know it.
A man who loves another.
Sander! We can't let love destroy them.
I don't remember anyone going nuts
over something so insignificant.
I was ready to eat poison toad when you courted another girl.
Did you?
Oh, Minna...
I caused you pain back in the day.
I did the same to you.
- My wife...?
Yes, of course.
Don't bear a grudge.
It's in the past. Let it be.
I feel sorry for you two.
Why is your path so rocky?
You seem meant for each other.
The two of you with your frozen souls.
I'm not jealous.
I close my eyes and pretend
his words are meant for me.
I know that the baroness
will never hear them.
Poor Hans.
Liina, listen.
Do you have a dress
that the baroness might wear?
Why? I could get one.
So this is the kratt
who's been pinching our treasure.
Damn it!
Do not try to hold on!
I am the crumbling sand.
Before the morning dawn
I will be gone from your hand.
Do not try to understand.
I am a primordial being.
Shining down divinely,
in every form and feeling.
I am the echo of an angel. I am true Love.
Wherever you may need me I am in your heart, my dove!
That's good.
If Sander brings us together,
I'll recite it for her.
You can do that.
But it is much more endearing
when a beau writes the poem himself.
I have to write the poem?
I don't know how.
Imagine your beloved.
The poem will write itself, trust me!
You breathe like a calf...
Like a small cow.
How's that?
-Very good.
Old pastor Moses caught me
scraping gold from the altar.
He said he would send me to the gallows.
Why were you scraping it?
You know the altar is sacred.
- Of course! It's sacred gold.
If I pay with it at the pub,
the gold will return to my pocket.
How will it return? Will it walk?
Jesus will bring it. It's sacred gold.
Who told you that?
-A Latvian.
Latvians have an arse for a mouth
and only shit comes out of it.
What's your plan?
To poison the pastor?
No, why? He's the hand that feeds me.
Let's turn him stupid.
I brought some of his hair.
Have mercy... Have mercy...
That's enough. We don't want him too dumb.
They'll only send a new one
and he'll probably be worse.
I'm going home to bed. I was up all night drinking.
What do you want? You can see I'm busy.
I heard... Maybe you have... Well...
What do I have? Speak up, don't mumble.
A love potion.
A potion that makes a girl love you.
You have to make the potion.
Mix your sweat
and armpit hairs with your shit.
And that's your love potion.
Feed it to her
and she'll fall for you.
Beautiful!
My name is Hans.
You're not cold, are you?
Two fools.
Luise!
Look Luise, l brought you a gift.
I baked it myself.
Why does it stink?
It's shit.
- No, it's not. It's... Chocolate.
That is shit.
I made it for Luise.
You disgusting creature!
Eat your own shit!
Those are real feelings.
This man shot Jesus!
My God, you can't melt!
I have to, it must be so.
I understand you perfectly
even when you are silent.
I have heard many passionate promises
and seen storms of emotion,
but here sat two lovers in silence.
And it was beautiful.
Do you really think that she...
- I'm certain of it.
That girl loves you...
Where is your kratt?
- It melted.
Then it is time to pay!
Hans!
Your kind is a burden on humanity!
You don't think twice
before cutting our throats.
It's your own fault! Who told you
to make a deal with the Devil?
Right, we should avoid your kind. We should set you all on fire!
You fool the plague and the Devil
but you don't want to pay
with your soul as promised!
But I don't have a soul.
You'll be boiling
in my cauldron soon enough.
You went to the manor pantry yesterday.
You could've grabbed a dress. It doesn't weigh anything.
Shame on you! I got a sausage and half a lamb!
Where would I put the dress?
Over your shoulder.
- Hush!
Our Lord Jesus Christ,
have mercy on this soul sold to Satan.
May your blood wash us of our sins.
Lord Jesus Christ, Son of God,
have mercy!
Have mercy on us, the sinners!
Gold!
Pure gold!
It's the buried Rääk treasure!
Take this, child.
It'll make a nice dowry for a virgin bride.
Oh, yes,
just what a virgin bride dreams of.