Shochiku-Fuji Presents
A KSS/Shochiku Dai-ichi Kogyo Film
While having my hair cut
I like to think it's a big waste...
to throw away hair
Isn't there a way to use human hair
effectively?
If hair could...
cure cancer and piles
the discovery would bring me a fortune
Won't it raise money?
That's why I still keep it
The same with rocks in a riverbed
How can I raise money from them?
Poverty dulls the wit
How can I get an idea?
SECONDHAND BOOKSTORE
At a nearby store,
I found a book about rocks
It told me that rocks can be...
salable as art objects
I got so excited my hands sweated
ROCKS
Eventually I opened a rock shop
I'd drawn comics,
sold secondhand cameras...
But I couldn't make it
No money to open a shop in town
"NOWHERE MAN"
General Producer: Kazuyoshi Okuyama
Executive Producer:
Toshiaki Nakazawa / Masaaki Sekine
Planned by Yoshihisa Nakagawa
Starring Naoto Takenaka
And Jun Fubuki
Based on a comic series by
Yoshiharu Tsuge
Written by Toshiharu Maruuchi
Producers: Shozo Ichiyama
Hirotsugu Yoshida
Photographed by Yasushi Sasakibara
Lighting by Hiroyuki Yasugochi
Sound recording by Mineharu Kitamura
Production Designer: Iwao Saito
Pass out the leaflets
Directed by Naoto Takenaka
Why don't they sell?
It's still cold, and few people...
Selling those rocks?
Helping your dad?
Good boy!
Take a look, dear
Rocks have beauty, too
Where did you get this?
In this riverbed
I guessed so
Who would ever buy any rocks found
here?
They're different
Oh, in what way?
Their form and elegance
Elegance?
A rock can represent a mountain
a valley, clouds, wind, the universe...
Let's go
Sorry
What's wrong? You keep birds
Dunce! Don't mix rocks with birds
He needs cash. He'd sell anything
Dad...
They don't know how valuable
rocks can be
Lots of cut-rate books
when the boom ended
But they're gone too now
Aren't there good rocks
in that riverbed?
Why not sell your comics?
Actually one of your fans came
He left this
My last one
Your old books get very good prices
Ironical!
He wants to exchange it
for your originals
How about 10,000 yen for
three originals?
No originals
I gave them to charity bazaars
What a waste!
My wife left me
She left home
To women, incapable men are
pure scum
He said they were discontinued
But I found a few
What about the auction?
A Mr. Sekiun said to come
for an application form
"At a temple next month...
"10,000 yen table charge"?
Space for rocks
What if our rocks don't sell?
It's investment
Listen seriously
It's ridiculous!
Where's the cash?
You can't even buy me a skirt
You scrimp on gas and bath water
What can you do?
I hate poverty.
I'm worried about our living
Then draw comics
No orders for five years
You were popular
You're conceited. You think you're...
an artist, but comics aren't art
Self-conceit makes no sense!
Self-conceit? Why belittle me, huh?
Comics aren't my lifework
I'll become a big-shot rock dealer
Massage me
I won't pass out leaflets forever
I tell the neighbors
I walk for health's sake
But I get tired, that's all
Ma'am...
Yes?
Train fare
STONE-FANATICS ASSOCIATION
SEKIUN ISHIYAMMA
Hello!
You must be Mr. Sukegawa
That door's broken. Will you fix it?
Sorry, nails won't work
Sorry to bother you. My man can't do it.
Come in
Excuse me
I'm Sekiun Ishiyama, the president
He's Karuishi, an expert
at finding good rocks
My disciple
How do you do
Write your name, address
and where you get your rocks
Tama River? Natural rocks?
New, natural rocks are popular
They can include excellent ones
I'm just a beginner
I have no good ones
The Tama River sometimes has
good rocks
Only upstream rocks can be good
Downstream rocks are too common
Keep out of this!
I find rocks near a movie studio
We used to go there ourselves
We often went walking
We sure did
We found this
"Water Containing Rock" there
Someone wanted it for 100,000 yen
100,000 yen?!
Rock-appreciating started
in the 14th century
It originated in China
In the 18th century
an appreciation method
was established:
A rock on a sand-filled tray
"Suiseki," or rock and water
"Bonkei" or miniscape,
consists of several rocks
"Bonkei" can use several rocks, but
"Suiseki" must express a landscape
with only one rock
"Bonkei" is human performance
"Suiseki" requires natural beauty
I'll take this
Thank you very much
200 yen
Mrs. Sukegawa
Chinese cabbage is cheap
I'll take pickled cabbage
My shop needs a part-time cashier.
Why not do it?
The more I work, the lazier my man gets
He's selling rocks this time?
While trying out many things,
he'll make it
Lottery's better
I had a Kaji as my senior
A real expert
Karuishi's no match for him
He was a konjak dealer
One day he asked me:
"How many eyes do you use to see
rocks?"
I answered, "Two." Then he said:
"That's not enough.
You need four eyes to see rocks
"And rocks are like konjak"
I said, "Rocks are hard; konjak, soft."
He replied, "You're still a novice.
"Rocks are just like konjak; they are
"warm and very soft."
Lately
I've begun to understand what he meant
Let me show you something
A "Figure Rock," but this type is...
extremely commonplace
It lacks elegance
But the way it gets wet...
It's the best one I've ever seen
How many times have I had to hear
that lecture!
He has only expensive rocks.
Worth a fortune
No, no. They aren't his rocks
We dealers consign them to him
for sales
We use his influence to sell them to...
rich people
And he takes a big margin
And seldom pays us dealers
Business with him is risky
But he has lots of experience
Why not drink?
Not me
Let's drink to our friendship
I'm in a hurry
Where are you going?
Is it money? I have some
Your case is difficult
You look so tender your guts don't show
Show your guts more openly
You sure?
Don't talk like that
Listen
Watch out for Sekiun's wife
She was ogling you with hungry eyes
She's a slut
He booted out five of our fellow dealers
after they had flirtations with her
Sake made him ill,
and he became impotent
She had a reason then
She was the wife
of a public bathhouse owner
It's gone now,
because a bad dealer grabbed it
It was deep in the mountains,
there were few clients
Then Sekiun arrived to stay
for a few days
And he ran off with
the bathhouse owner's wife
Her husband was...
me!
While going to Sekiun's place
many times
trying to get back Tatsuko
he taught me about rocks
I'd lived by catching fish and snakes
and making bird houses
Mine was such a poor life!
So I obeyed Sekiun till I could live on
rocks
But... when I stayed there last night...
What happened?
He made me clean the toilet!
It's love
Love
Sukegawa speaking
Sato from the comic magazine
Been a long time. How are you?
My husband's out now
A job?
No "entertaining" comics, please
He said comics aren't his life's work
Hey!
He's back. Hold the line please
He's offering a job
Speaking
Been a long time.
Has she told you?
We have an original story.
Why not try it?
Thanks, but no more
"entertaining" comics
Hey!
What a mess!
Why not at least read the story?
I'm busy. The auction's coming
You've changed
You're only worsening yourself
I miss the time
you were drawing comics
Well?
I like it
It's almost art
Glad to hear
How's your work?
I've got used to it.
A big hit at my counter
Why don't you try it?
Visit me. I'm lonely
Only a small hole there.
We can't see each other
Just put in your hand. I'll hold it
That's not necessary now
Make sure.
6-6
Mister, snap it up!
Good evening
Why so upset?
I was glad!
I held your hand
It was so exciting!
The ticket lost
You sure it was my hand?
Sure. It was stained with ink
How dull!
I really was glad
Beautiful sunset!
You bashful?
It's dad! He's going somewhere!
It's dad!
Ma'am!
Your family told me you're here
I'm surprised you're doing business
here
I drank too much water
Take your time
A meadow bunting
A gold finch
You know, huh?
I'm a bird-hunter's daughter
A bird-hunter
Really?
My father traps birds...
deep in the mountains
I long for such a life
It wasn't easy for me. I had to wait
He wouldn't come home for a long time
When you first came to our place,
I thought
Your ears looked like my father's
My ears?
Only your ears
Whenever my dad came home,
I cleaned his ears
His ears full of wax
Oh!
How awful!
Lovers are around at night
There are many hotels, too
The rivers made me cold
Why not rest?
Listen, is it okay?
I...
I can't have children
Dad!
I came for you
What poor grub!
Wait till rocks sell
Don't force yourself to eat
I'll eat
Tasty radishes
I picked them at the river
The river?
Then...
A neighbor's crops!
"Stone Hunting: The Latest Fashion"
Renting boats isn't bad
It makes 800 yen in three minutes
A carrier could make only 20 yen
The carrier died
Mister, may I leave these here?
You sell stones?
Why not ask a curio shop to sell
this stuff?
What's this?
"Lone Boat"
I see
Why not buy one?
"Sorrow, Anger, Understanding, Wind"
"Degradation, Despair...
"Uneasiness, Repenting, Tears"
Just like me
See to that
ROCKS
You like it?
You're the first to like my rocks
Keep it. It's yours
I don't want money. Take it
Want to sell that bird?
I don't sell birds
Listen...
You'll sell that bird?
I'm asking you...
if you'll sell that white-eye?
80,000 yen?
I was amazed
Half the money's fine. I'm lucky
You could've sold it for twice that
Twice?
You missed out
So, he's still around
Who?
The man with the white-eye
He's "Bird Man"
A mute would come to sell birds
to a shop...
in back of the bicycle racetrack
He was known
for bringing only good birds
I must pay him. Where is he?
No one knew what he really was
I heard he lived at a shrine then
He was at the river
He received only half the money
I know we need money to live
But we'll invest this in my business
We'll go somewhere to hunt for rocks
No means. No
We'll go together, the three of us
A change of mood
Great! The train schedule
An expert named Karuishi...
will direct us to a river
Already arranged?
We'll take an express train from here
No
Good rocks there
A slow train's better
Why?
We can enjoy the trip more fully
What time do we get there?
After 10
10 what?
10:02
What station?
Oh, shut up!
Let's get ready one station in advance
We'll arrive in 22 minutes
The truck will take us
He didn't come. Why care?
I'm worried about him
Can we trust this Karuishi?
Shut up and hurry!
You sure?
Get in the truck!
Take a look
A criminal case? Don't involve me
Mr. Yamakawa!
Karuishi!
Listen...
I'm sorry... I couldn't meet you
Please come in
A viper?
The doc came too late
I was worried
It's only you who say such things to me
Don't vipers hibernate?
I expect they'll grow fast
if they don't hibernate
So I'm trying to raise them here
Rocks can't make enough money
Vipers make money?
Stop it
What are vipers?
Sonny, roll up that black cloth
Mom!
You all right?
I feel great after...
yelling so loud
Vipers look like snakes
There it is
There was a landslide
Maybe you can get good rocks
Think so?
I'm sorry that I can't go with you
It's because I jerked off last night
When I shot...
I kicked the vipers' basket
I do it often, but it's...
my first time to make such a mistake
What about that?
I stole it from Sekiun's place
Tatsuko always overlooks it
She really is a kind person
So many ups and downs
It's like life
You look cheerful
It's nice to be free from daily life
I hope we can get good rocks here
BLOCKED OWING TO LANDSLIDE
Why?!
To hell with rocks! My shoes are worn
This is how you are
You have no sense
Looks like a family suicide
It won't be bad
We have no bright future
We'll get old, that's all
Hello?
Let's go. Staying makes no sense
We'll stay and relax
Let's go
May I help you?
Let us stay here
Old man!
"I don't think you know
how radishes feel...
"Mom and Dad were scattering
nightsoil..."
You farted
Help yourselves
Let's eat!
It's only 5 PM
There's lots of rice
What's this?
Boiled and vinegared radishes
Radish soup, pickled radish leaves
Humble grub!
The fee's so cheap
Look at that laundray. What a joint!
No TV... even a dresser
Don't gripe
But...
You picked this mill
You've never done me good
Don't blame me!
Some women's pussies bring bad luck
About yours, don't tell me
How crass!
They said mine brings good luck
"They"?
Years ago
A strolling priest. How rare!
Are they still around?
Is he a Buddhist priest?
I don't think so
He's more like a beggar
A beggar?
He's useless
A dropout in this affluent society
Useless and incapable?
Exactly
He's like you
Sukezo...
What are you thinking?
Do priests make money?
I don't want to be a priest
Hear that?
At this hour?
How melancholy!
I feel lonely
I wonder what'll happen to us
Come to think of it.
We have no close friends
We seldom meet our folks
We're isolated
It's like we three are alone
in this vast universe
So what? What's wrong with
being alone?
What kept you?
They asked for a service charge!
They'd done nothing!
Where is he?
Pissing
Be more careful
Sansuke!
Dad!
I found a rock!
The bus is coming
Here's the bus!
Sukezo!
Sorry to make you wait
A rock, Dad! Really!
The bus is waiting
A rock!
Hurry!
Where is it?
That one?
It has nice lines!
Lines?
Looks good
The landslide helped
Name it?
"Waterfall"
Two waterfalls. Called it
"Married Couple"
At the auction
It'll sell for 100,000 - no - 200,000 yen
Too optimistic
Stone-fans are decreasing
People don't know what's good
They think it's old-fashioned
Naming in foreign languages is
the rage
What about your sign?
That? I'm just pretending to be
timeserving
That's what pros do
Is your wife back?
ROCK AUCTION
How many times must I tell you?
Do it carefully
Okay?
Choose an angle so the rock looks best
Like this?
I'm sure it'll sell
Excuse me
Our rocks are just as good as
the others
I hope they sell
If they sell, we'll buy a coat for Sansuke
For you too
Tatsuko wants you
You look lovely
You haven't paid your admission
Sorry
But we paid the table charge
1,000 yen for one, it includes...
lunch and tea
Pay 3,000 yen
If it's for lunch
my son doesn't eat much
so I'll pay for two
I'll give you extra chopsticks
They're 500 yen lunches!
What a rake-off!
Just keep quiet
Pay another 1,000
What a waste!
Let me tell you something:
If your rock sells, you must pay us 10% of...
the price, understand?
I know
What a woman!
Don't say that
Sorry
"Three Waves" from the Kanra River
We'll start with 3,000 yen. 3,000 yen!
See it glitter?
No one wants it?
Next
We should've started with a better rock
A better one, then
Hurry! What's keeping you?
"Crag Form" form the Saji River
7,000 yen!
Only 7,000 yen for that?
And no one buys it
7,000. No one wants it?
Why don't you buy it?
What about ours?
They're special
Quit worrying and wait
It's so dull today
Where to?
"Mt. Fuji" from the Sakawa River
5,000 yen!
Anyone want it?
It's almost our turn
I feel sick
You're timid
Dad...
ORACLES
From the Kamo River. 4,000 yen
Anyone want it? 4,000 yen
4,000 yen? No deal
Next!
Please do your best
Sansuke!
Sorry
Unlucky
"Boat" from the Tama River. 2,000
Anyone want it?
Start with 5,000 yen!
2,000!
Leave the starting price
to the auctioneer
Newcomers have no right to complain
Go away!
2,000 yen
Anyone want it?
Only 2,000 yen?
Only 2,000 yen
Everyone's silent
Next
"Married Couple"
18,000? Do I hear 18,000?
Very well, for 17,000 yen...
20,000!
21,000!
25,000!
26,000!
30,000!
31,000!
40,000!
41,000? Do I hear 41,000?
41,000!
50,000!
Don't do two things at the same time
It went for 50,000 yen
So pay 5,000 yen
Any money left?
We'll take them home ourselves
Let's go
What's wrong?
I'm fed up with rocks!
What are you doing?
Stop!
Why must you do this?
You always cause me trouble
I can't stand it!
You weren't serious about
any other work
I know it
So why do this?
Why? Why must you do this?
All you can do is comics
So draw them even though
no one asks you
Just draw them
You're a fool!
Fool!
What's wrong?
Come in
You all right?
Stay here
I'll get a taxi
I'll be back soon
Fly
Fly!
Sorry to keep you
We'll have him dissected
I'm sorry you're involved
His relatives?
He's unidentified
Maybe he was regarded as dead
Anyone can be regarded as dead
It's often so with bums
7 years after he becomes missing
It'll like they're dead
It's time to go to the shop
Dad...
Shut up!
Got it?
I'm Sukegawa. How do you do?
Mister!
Don't get funny ideas
That's not it
A guy fell last night.
He'll do the same
Don't end up like him
Mom...
Mom, piss
Piss by yourself
I already did
Are you busy?
No
What's the matter?
Say something
What did you say?
Nothing
Liar
Let me keep that
What'll it be?
Coffee
Yours doesn't suit our line
I'm sorry
That's all right. Thanks
Shall I introduce other publishers?
You were the last one
We were?
Today's editors are young
They flatly refused
They have no head
I never thought my work
Do you remember that mahjong story?
Would be turned down
Our desk is interested. Why not try it?
If you make it, they'll accept that, too
I don't want to
I hate to say this
How do you support your family?
But aren't you too choosey?
Hell!
You'll get old, too
You used to draw many kinds.
It's painful to draw
You can do it
You can overcome it
You're lazy
Being lazy is easy
Be more serious!
Dad...
Out!
Get out!
This is my place!
I'm back
Everything's changed
My comics won't sell
The bath is ready
"Fly! Fly! I said fly!"
"Take me with you"
About our future...
We need money for Sansuke's school
I'll work as a carrier
and things
There was an old carrier near...
the cycle racetrack, so I'll do it
Maybe I can get 50 yen per person
1,500 yen a day.
10,000 yen on a race day.
36,000 yen for 24 days
That's 96,000 yen
60,000 for 6 days
You're working, too.
I'll sell pop, drinks and rocks, too
We can earn a living
Multiple management
What'll it cost?
500,000. I'll make the preparations
Where's the cash?
You can do as you like
Sansuke and I will manage
Leaving me?
You want to leave us, right?
Quit drawing comics?
Fly anywhere
Yeah. No more of that
Weakling! You're a worm
Yeah. I'm a worm
6 - 6
No such combination in this race
Give me 6 - 6
6 - 6
Ass! What are you saying?
Your money!
How's the shop?
The worst
Then close it for a while
I'll go home and stay there
My father's ill
Why don't you come with me?
With you?
No one else there
Having a good time?
You look well off. Buy a rock
One for a weight
To hold her down
Some pimp!
Pimp?
Hey, hurry!
Hurry!
What's keeping you?
Let me use the pants
Is it still here?
100 yen for one
100 yen
Don't do that. You're going too far
Looks like fun
I'll ask him
Knock it off!
Sorry, I'm the first
100 yen for one!
Carry me
Sure
Life in the mountains...
If you like it...
you can stay with me as long as you like
Let's go together
Let's go
"A penniless rock vendor
Shall we go?
What does he live on?"
Pay me 100 yen
Thank you very much
100 yen for one
Ass!
Hey, mister!
Snap it up!
I'm back
What's wrong?
Been to the river?
About Dad?
Did he look awful?
Yeah
That awful?
Worse
You hate him?
Yeah
Did he refuse the mahjong story too?
The desk told me to try to persuade him
You refused that one?
That one? Yes
It's too gloomy
I don't dislike it
But the readers want something lighter
Please don't meet my husband
He's suffering. Please let him alone
If he makes it...
we'll publish his old comics again
I'm sorry. I'm fixing supper
as a series
See you again, sonny
Goodbye
Thanks
"Japanese Tradition -
Dad
Rock Appreciation"
I came for you
You smell like the river
You hate it?
Yeah
Shall we go?