Christmas long ago
is the memory of a dream
that seemed never to end.
But somewhere in the middle of that dream,
I always did wake up
just in time to attend
the Christmas Eve party
my Mama and Papa gave for me and my brother, Fritz.
Mama attracted
interesting guests Papa said,
because she was beautiful
and fascinating.
She was, he said,
his wondrous peacock.
How full
of anticipation I was.
"Dreamers need not be pretty,"
my godfather, Drosselmeier
told me so very long ago.
My good, and, sometimes,
very bad, godfather, Drosselmeier
was certainly the very strangest guest at those long-ago parties.
He was a genius, they said.
So it was especially strange to me that he behaved like a silly little boy.
And often, he frightened me.
But more often,
and this is strangest of all,
I loved him
better than anyone.
And I loved
his presents best of all.
For besides being a genius,
he was a very famous clockmaker
and toymaker
and mouse catcher.
Dreams, like all
my most precious gifts,
were from my dear godfather, Drosselmeier.
When I loved him,
he was the kindest creature you can imagine.
He told me stories,
every word of which I still remember.
But when he frightened me with his weird and childish ways,
and I could not bear
for him to be near me,
he would punish me.
It was on such an occasion,
when I was nearly 13 years old,
on Christmas Eve,
that out of spite,
Godfather Drosselmeier gave me
the most wicked dream.
I smile to think of it now,
that a nightmare could bring,
like a sweet memory, such a strange joy.
It is a mystery
I can never solve.
But I can never forgive my spiteful godfather for slipping into that dream
my bad little brother, Fritz.
The Christmas parties
of long ago
all blur and mix in memory.
The real and the unreal becomes one.
How silly
we children appeared.
Gawking and gaping at the Grand Promenade of our mamas and papas.
I will never forget
the envy and delight I felt
at watching my parents.
And how badly I longed to dance with my beautiful Papa.
How my head whirled with the music and buzzed with my bad dream,
not cold enough yet
for me to forget.
And Godfather Drosselmeier
wasn't even there.
The party was incomplete without him and all his wonderful presents.
In that long-ago dream
in an ocean wide with mystery,
my heart beat
with joy and fear all mixed.
But odd to say,
I knew this dreamscape.
Dreams
are strangely familiar places.
They are, not at all,
the land of make-believe,
but only the home
lay inside of yourself,
like the inner lining
of your favorite coat
or the sweet kernel
inside the hardest nut
that only the jaws of my Nutcracker Prince,
could reveal to me.
In the language
of this dream,
in that palace of delight,
we spoke with
our whole selves.
We dream-talked
with hands and feet,
and quick-danced
out our mousey Christmas tale.
And they joined us in a celebration in that palace by the sea.
And my tall Nutcracker cavalier had eyes only for me.
For at least as long as that dream could be.