Hurry up.
So many unbearable pains
for our children!
- Dielika.
- Yes.
Let's go home. You go first.
School is over for you.
Lessons from the garbage
Help me.
No way. Did you help me?
Bala, where is my mother?
You uncircumcised,
where is your 'Hello'?
Your mother is at the market.
Are you crying?
You're supposed to be
at school, aren't you?
We've been expelled.
Already? They were quick this year.
What are you doing here?
Those who don't have a bench
have been expelled.
God!
Bring me a mug.
Take care of your sister.
- Bala.
- Yes.
I'm going to the school.
Come along!
- And Fanta?
- I haven't seen her.
Don't bother me today.
It's here.
Hello.
Teacher, why did you expel him?
It's not me. It's the rules.
What shall I do?
Look, they all have their bench.
My son can sit on the floor.
Impossible!
- What can I do?
- Find him a bench.
Shut up!
I'm begging you...
My son can sit on the floor.
Impossible. There may be an inspection.
He would be expelled and
I would be sanctioned.
God, what can I do?
Find a bench.
Anything to sit on.
So many unbearable pains
for our children!
You mustn't accept such things.
Our children will be ignorant,
like us.
It's so unfair.
Come on, let's go.
Oh! You're not studying.
I need money.
Again! I gave you
3500 FM last year.
- It's annual.
- Sort it out yourself.
Bengali, how many times
did you eat the day before yesterday?
- Once.
- And yesterday?
Once. Without meat.
Today, there is nothing!
I want to go to school.
I won't keep you.
Good riddance.
The director forbid us...
any physical appearance.
Did he? Does he own the country?
Is he a colonel?
He's not a soldier
but he is hurtful.
Does he wipe his ass with an ax?
What? Son of a bitch!
Laugh at your misfortune,
son of a bitch.
Father, you're insulting yourself.
What about the school??
You'll be expelled sooner or later.
Even stuffed with diplomas
you will be jobless.
They can keep their school.
We'll keep our meager resources.
Also, the Franc CFA is back...
we'll tear each other apart.
Kalifa, why didn't
you wait for me?
I've been expelled.
Enough! Fanta, wash the mug.
Mother, did you buy oranges?
Yes. Hurry up.
Hello! Saran, are you done?
Yes.
Mom, I'm hungry.
- Have you started?
- I don't know.
I've been expelled because
I have no bench.
We have everything:
benches, notebooks, books...
Everything is brand new...
Look at my bag-pack.
Of course. Your school
is the one of the rich.
Let's go home.
Bring some water.
Children, how
are your studies going?
Is it ok at school?
Finish your meal.
You may be disgusted.
I am already. You
shouldn't have told that.
Eat it anyway.
Explain yourselves now.
We are poor and once
again victims.
- Kalifa has been expelled.
- God!
There is only misfortune
for us.
They want us dead.
It won't be.
We're not the only ones
in this situation.
What can we do?
Don't give them the
pleasure to see us...
crying, our children
will go to school.
But how? We have nothing...
and you barely earn a living.
Sure.
Here, there are 500 FM.
No, mother, keep it.
We now have 500 FM,
I'll borrow...
- Again!
- We have to.
I'll give half my wage.
- So many?
- It's only 12.000 FM.
And we'll also rent
a cart for Kalifa.
He'll work like his sister.
Can he? It's very tiring.
It's also the learning
process of life.
Mother, can we go?
It's over Mom. Dry your tears.
You're so ugly when you cry.
Get out, duffer.
Are you crying?
Maybe we should all die?
Shut up, crybaby.
Hello Saran.
I come for the ember.
Founé, you should stop
being a servant.
Impossible. I must continue.
Hello, father.
- How are you doing at school?
- The bench is too heavy.
I'll lighten it this evening.
Go meet your mother.
- Father's coming.
- How lucky he is!
It's not in this way everyday.
He works at Bamako,
this is far away.
Mother, what are you saying?
We live in Bamako.
Don't bother me,
everyone say so!
Let's hurry.
I can't go faster.
Let's have a break.
It's too hot.
You made fun of me.
You'll suffer at work.
I am a man.
The work will be easy.
- What a blusterer.
- Leave him alone.
He can't even drive the cart.
Yes. It's an old one.
I'll insure you regular studies.
Because I am playing?
If it doesn't work here,
I'll go to the city.
Be back before twilight.
Oranges! Buy oranges!
I'm going.
Wait. Take the garbage with you.
- It will be 150 FM.
- What? Make it 50 FM.
- It's not enough. 100 FM.
- Let's say 75 FM.
Ok. But I'm doing you a favor.
- Where is your license?
- He's new.
Are you working full-time?
No, I study every morning.
Oh! You'll end up like us.
No more school.
Driver, start the engine.
You, you bought your license. Bye!
Is there any garbage?
Yes, over here.
- How much?
- 150 FM.
No. 50 FM.
Damn! Do you want it free?
- Forget it.
- 100 FM.
Don't call us carrier anymore.
I'll do it again tomorrow.
- I'm exhausted.
- It's just the beginning.
Massage me, please.
I'd rather swallow you.
Stop your impudence.
Bala, this is the boss' food.
Get up, let's go.
Eh! Kalifa, don't make a fool of us.
Saran, you should appoint her somebody.
Father, I have to go.
My friend is waiting for
me to work.
Fill up the bucket.
Your mother must be tired.
Why can't she have a day off?
Servants have no rights.
They are at their boss' mercy.
Can't it change?
It'll change.
When? I don't know.
This kid is talking too much
instead of working.
You want to speak to me.
You'll have to wait.
Hey, old hag! Are you coming?
Rascal, I'll beat you up.
Push it, bloke.
What is it?
"Old woman", is there garbage?
Call me so again and I'll knock you out.
What should I call you?
Aren't you Barou's mother?
No, his mother is my big sister.
- So, mother...
- Get out, Satan's son...
Buzz off!
What's wrong with all these
30-year-old women?
Is it her age?
Buddy, do you know one of them...
who accepts to be called "old lady"?
Let's have a little break.
Bloke, your sex is going outside.
Shit!
You're not wearing pants!
Are you crazy?
I have no short...
and you want me to wear pants.
Pants twist penis anyway.
You don't wear pants neither.
I'll rip your ass off!
You small ass!
Bloke, look at this ass!
This girl's boyfriend is so lucky!
Hey, sweety, come here.
- Me?
- Yes.
- What is it?
- I like you.
- What do you mean?
- I want you.
Let's get laid.
Are you a junkie?
For you, I'll be the fresh
corn from Sahel.
Not like this little whore.
Calm down.
Am I your little whore?
Sure! You made us...
whore for new rich.
Insult me again, I'll beat you.
You'll both be beaten...
if his wife catch you.
He fled. He abandoned you.
Impossible. Man, you're out of your depth!
The village coward has fled.
It's the "old lady" 's husband.
May God give us wisdom.
If the youngest find out about this,
I'll be rotten.
Barou, come here.
Why are you calling me?
Is your mother the "old
lady" of this house?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
She's very black.
She's the only "old lady".
She says you are not her son.
- Mom was joking.
- Not at all.
She says you're her nephew.
- She said that?
- Yeah.
My word! If my mother
do this to me...
I'll disown her!
What a beautiful hairstyle Mom.
It's pretty, isn't it. Be careful.
- How elegant is Mom.
- What do you mean?
- Sorry, I didn't say anything.
- You'd better.
Mom, you're telling
I'm not your son.
God! Why would I do that?
Some boys told me.
These bastards.
- Get up.
- What a story.
Children today are mean.
Making an enemy of my dear child.
You two, are you done?
Here is the coward.
Come with me.
Let's work.
I must bring 200 FM home.
Come with me. You won't regret it.
Climb up!
Mom only loves Barou.
- Him and his big head.
- Leave me alone.
I love you all.
He has his dad's head.
Look.
Go play somewhere else.
I'm ill.
Mom, did you hear Dad's car?
I'll beat you up, idiot.
It hurts all over. Go away!
Sali! I'm calling you
and you don't answer?
I heard, but I'm sick.
What is it again?
My fingers hurt, my head, all over.
This finger? You have fever.
Calm down, little sister.
I'll go buy medicine.
Look, she's not ill anymore.
Impossible.
- Here Mom.
- What is it, this fish?
- It's a captain.
- Well!
Will you have some?
- Why are you laughing?
- Nothing.
What a moron.
Laughing for nothing.
Prepare us a little treat.
Mom, are you healed already?
Stop your impudence.
Come closer, my love.
Dear, put some music on.
Where is Barou?
Forget him and his big head.
If he hears you, he'll be mad.
I can't believe it. I'm dead.
See, I told you.
May God protect me from such a mother!
Still, you do have a mother...
May He protect you from such a woman...
faking and refusing to age.
There is only oddity from the rich.
Like those stupid nicknames
: Dolly Bird, Sweety...
You're right. Barou and his big balls...
is called Sweetheart.
Important dates in Mali's history are...
22 September 1960...
Political independence of Mali.
20 January 1962...
After the French troops leave...
creation of the... national army.
2 June 1962...
creation of Malian's Front.
19 November 1968...
- Get up and go home.
- Leave me alone.
Come on! Get up.
Important dates in Mali's history are...
22 September 1960...
Political independence of Mali.
- Grand-Mother, rub me.
- Stop bothering me.
You've only worked for 4 months.
Fuck you!
Father, I can't study anymore.
I'm second to last amongst 75 students.
You'll rest one afternoon per week.
What about me?
Shut up. Your work is easy.
Fucking bastard.
Enough. She's working hard too.
She's walking kilometers to sell oranges.
She's just sitting in a corner,
nothing else.
No, I'm lying down.
His rest will be a shortage...
we'll lose 1600 FM.
Damn it! You, you're only eating.
Sleeping or talking bullshit.
Give us a break.
Mother is right.
Yes, but let them rest.
You slackers!
Me? I'm feeding you
and you won't even rub me.
You're a coward in this village.
Well! Honey, rub me.
I refuse.
So I don't love you anymore.
Let's divorce.
My mouth is tearing up from laughter...
but there's no blood.
Go to bed. Everybody will rest tomorrow.
Look at those children.
They are from poor families,
like you.
They don't go to school anymore.
This is their lives.
These are peasant like me.
They have emigrated from the countryside.
Selfishness has defeated them...
Them and their lands.
Our society has become a jungle.
We have to fight for our lives.
Waiter! That son of a bitch
fired me.
Pour me a quick shot.
I'm going to beat my wife.
- What has she done?
- It's none of your business.
An arab proverb says:
"Beat your wife everyday."
"If you don't know why, she does."
Bullshit!
You're a bastard with your fucking face.
Pour me one!
I only sell coffee.
Coffee? I'm damned.
Like a monkey's ass!
Chaka, you think I didn't see you?
You're getting drunk with your son?
Your boss is the
son of a bitch.
Say it to him for me.
Me, Bala, I say this to you all:
"Sons of bitches."
Son of a bitch.
They will become beggars...
What about us?
What do you think?
We are tired and we need books...
My sister and I are going to be expelled.
What will you do if you're expelled?
- I'll be a driver.
- Like your father.
Yeah, look!
I'm a good driver, aren't I?
Yeah! I'll be a director so I can hire you.
My ass! Directors are thieves.
Then I'll be a cop to arrest them.
An extorting cop?
You're not safe man!
Here is Fanta.
What is it?
Some boys took my oranges.
Go tell Mom. I have to work.
- Let's beat them up.
- They are far away.
Shut up! Who can you beat up?
I can't beat nobody up?
So I'm a puppet now.
Even worse. You're like a ball.
Have you seen the puppet?
The King of the Puppets.
Stop it or I'll kick your ass.
What? Can't we dance anymore?
Forget it!
Kalifa, your mother is calling you.
Tell her you didn't see me.
I won't play this game.
Go ahead! I'll follow you.
Give me the fire. I'll blow it.
How much did we earn?
350 FM less 150 for the cart.
I told you to be back before twilight.
But I was here!
Stop playing dumb.
Take the money.
You haven't been listening to me recently.
Go on. I'll mutilate you soon.
What did I do wrong?
Kalifa, we are working hard for you.
Have mercy!
I'll talk to his father.
Good night.
Do something.
Kalifa is on the road to ruin.
I'm leaving.
Good for nothing!
If I catch you...
Chaka! Leave my grand-son in peace.
Mother, you know we are
working hard for our kids.
Shut up!
Why haven't you brought
diner yet?
Where is Mother?
Founé is having birth pangs.
Mother!
I heard. I said so.
Saran, go with them.
My friend, did you sleep well?
Leave me alone,
you and your fucking face!
I'm sorry sir.
You can't even speak French.
Where is your father?
They want to bring her to the hospital.
But no car will stop to take her.
What?
Are you okay?
None of these bastards will stop.
Three people to the hospital.
Do you have 2000 FM?
Are you crazy? It's 975 FM.
Go find another one then.
Lean against me.
It's gonna be okay.
Founé.
Big brother, I can't stand it.
I'll get my bike.
Kids, it's reckless.
Let's look for a car.
We can't wait.
She's suffering too much.
She may give birth here.
Make a strong knot.
Go ahead.
Mother is following you.
Bakari, look back frequently.
It's gonna be fine.
Grab onto me.
Do you want me to have problems?
But she is pregnant.
Are you mad?
Why don't you go by car?
Help me.
Doctor, the pregnant woman
is suffering too much!
What can we do?
I'm dying.
Have you seen my bike?
It was here.
It's not here anymore.
Here is the prescription.
22 500 FM of medicines.
We can't see her without it.
- Has she given birth yet?
- I don't know.
- Eat
- I'm not hungry.
Calm down and it.
Mother is with her.
Help me! My money is not enough.
Calm down!
Saran, how much is left?
5000 FM. 2000 FM for school.
Give everything to Bakari.
- What about the children?
- They can wait.
Wait for me. We'll try
to borrow the rest.
Father, what about us?
You'll expelled from school.
Stay here and help us.
You're happy, aren't you?
But I want to study.
Become a director
and help our parents.
It's your problem.
Can't you see we won't be anything.
You'll be like mother
I'll be like father.
What's gotten into you?
My brother and I want to study.
- Make her silent!
- Make her silent yourself!
Do you want to see me dead?
Some people want to see you dead.
Open your eyes!
Get lost, yeah!
Father, don't get mad to mother.
So shut up and eat.
My brother and me want to be educated...
understand the world.
Father, why do some people have everything?
And some others nothing?
The world is changing
Don't worry.
Your mother and I are here.
What will become of us when
you're not here anymore?
Shut up and eat.
Shut up now.
You'll find a husband
who'll take care of you.
Fuck. I'll study.
No husband
will make my life a misery.
Stop that bullshit,
we have to go.
School should be free.
Shall we kill our children.
They have no food,
no clothes, no school.
Where has our money gone?
Where? We're eating it!
As well as your salary and the taxes.
Beat it now!
Now you're insulting me!
Are you crazy or do you want to go to jail?
It wouldn't be worse.
What can I do in this rotten world?
Hang me at your balls.
Poor mustn't be vindictive.
Arse-licker words!
A submissive poor,
is like a sheep in an abattoir.
I won't be somebody's sheep!
- Buy oranges!
- Vendor, here.
- How much?
- 25 FM.
Come here.
Mate, watch out for the tea.
Come closer.
You're cute. In 2 years
we'll take care of you.
Let go of me!
Aren't you ashamed to hit on a little girl!
What you do in your truck is even worse.
It's not true!
Stop it.
We know everything about it.
Can't you see we won't be anything.
You'll be like mother
I'll be like father.
Who is it?
Stop or I'll insult your mother.
Pointless, you don't love her.
It's you Karim. You'll hurt me.
Come on, we have to work.
So kid!
Your father is a kid.
- Let go of me!
- What's the matter?
My father beat me up yesterday
and I worked this morning.
Your father is puny,
his punches must be soft.
Fuck you! I'm serious.
This morning I've been
looking for you at school.
Without the 1000 FM
we would have been expelled.
My father borrowed again.
Let's go!
I beg for charity in Allah's name!
This is our "old lady" 's house.
- Shall we try?
- We're gonna be insulted.
Let me do it.
I understand women.
A big girl like you!
I forbid you to call me Mom in public.
What should I call you?
Don't call me!
What a story!
What is it?
Big sister! Where is the garbage?
Little brother.
May Allah bless you!
Here, 100 FM.
"Big sister! Where is the garbage?"
"Little brother,
may Allah bless you!"
What an old hag!
So Barou becomes our nephew.
Let's call him "sonny boy", like the rich.
I'm hungry. Let's buy food.
- Haven't you have diner already?
- I have.
I give it to my aunt at the hospital.
Also, I'm never sated.
Wait, can we eat for free?
Are you crazy?
It's no time to beg.
You saw the dresser. Come.
Kids, come here.
Give it to me.
Here, candies.
Is this your food?
It's begging!
Patience, mate.
What an asshole!
We could have taken everything.
- Where did you learn this?
- From Segou.
It's great.
But I'm still hungry.
- You're insatiable.
- Let's do it again.
Watch out, the boy want to beat us up.
Hello.
Come here. Give me a feather.
What a jerk!
I'm replete and ready to work.
Son of a glutton!
See, youngs and olds both are vicious.
Yes. But the feather is a terrible weapon.
Listen to this story:
A woman go to the market
with a feather in the ear.
In ecstasy, she walks past and enter...
in a police station.
Stopped by a table, she says:
"Butcher, give me good meat this time."
The police chief answer
: "This if my foot."
"It will kick your ass."
You're going to kill me
with your lies.
My father told me this story.
According to Djeli Baba...
the biggest liar around.
Djeli Baba doesn't lie.
He his a storyteller.
Listen.
- Tell your story.
- Which one?
The pisser doesn't feel comfortable
when it comes to fart.
Listen Kalifa Koné,
brave amongst the braves:
Three people don't like to be greeted.
They are: the one who is taking a dump,
the one who is making a move on...
and the one who is stealing.
Shit! We forgot the woman.
God!
Mother is calling you.
We're going home.
- Already? What's wrong?
- I don't know.
Here, 125 FM. Buy me 1 kg of millet.
Don't cry, think about Allah!
- And Bakary?
- He's gone mad.
He is insulting the administration.
We should have controlled
him back in the cemetery.
He shouldn't insult anybody,
it's God's will.
Founé gave birth in blood and pain.
Mother, she gave birth at 8:00am.
She waited until 2:00pm for care.
When Bakari brought the medicines.
She died at 4:00pm in pain.
Without you, the child
wouldn't have been washed.
Yes, it was atrocious.
Bakari broke doors and windows at the end.
I'm afraid he'll be arrested.
These cowards won't do this.
They know it's a murder.
Saran, calm down.
Cook something for Bakari.
Saran, pray Allah!
It's His will.
Ghaka, we need milk for the baby.
I know. We have to borrow again.
Our misfortune is escalating.
Poor children.
Don't talk like that.
Have faith in God.
Why? With our credit note...
school and medical cares need to be free.
What can these crushed children know?
Apart from tiredness and deprivation.
Father, I don't want to stop studying.
My daughter, I don't want it neither.
- What's wrong?
- We've been turned down.
Sit down. I understand.
This is the result of our way of living.
School is over.
Are you graduating?
No. Leave me alone!
I'm graduating, my sister too.
Our parents promised us presents.
You'll be like mother
I'll be like father.
Buy ice-creams.
Come here, I'll take you to school.
Will you pick me up when I get out?
- This is too much.
- Please, man.
But I have to work!
Tomorrow, she'll ask
for money for her hair.
Young lady, you are lost.
Chaka, I agreed...
you'll go to the city.
Don't forget me and your mother.
Have a good trip.
Kalifa, what did you do?
Get your ass up. Kalifa Koné!
Did you touch my cards?
Kalifa, what did you do?
Nothing mother.
I was hungry and I stole.
Don't cry mother.
Fanta, where are you?
Fanta, what are you doing here?
Mother, let me earn some money.
I can't stand it anymore.
Mother, don't cry.
Saran, what's going on?
- Where are the children?
- They are here, outside.
Mother, go to bed.
You're ill.
We have to go to work.
Father, mother is ill.
She can stay here and take
care of the two babies.
We'll go to work.
Good bye Father.
We should have been stillborn.
Do you know why I'm crying?
I'm crying for several reasons.