O COSTA DO CASTELO
(The Costa from Castelo)
Based on the play
with the same original name by
Production
The moon fades, day breaks
And the street comes to life
to the sound of the reveille
Throughout the blue sky
A flock of larks fly by
Happily singing good morning
Smoke drifts from rooftops
The markets are opening
To the calls of the fish sellers
The town shouts, bubbles and throbs
On its seven hills
And from a beautiful dream,
Idle and smiling
From the Castle to Madragoa
Sweet and beautiful, at each window
Lisbon awakes smiling
Mermaids echoes
Cross the air
And from the beehives
All is put to flight
The morning sun sings in splendour
An anthem of peace and love
A fighting cock sings from its perch
Challenging its rivals
Horns are heard,
Newsagents walk by
- Weighed down by newspapers...
- Milk!
And from a beautiful dream,
Idle and smiling
From the Castle to Madragoa
Sweet and beautiful, at each window
Lisbon awakes smiling
- Good morning, Ms. Rita.
- Good morning, Conceição.
- It seems you put water in the milk.
- Water?! God forbid!
At two thousand 'reis' a metre...
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye, see you tomorrow.
Luisinha! Hurry up!
It's past nine thirty!
- I'm coming!
- Nine thirty five.
- Good morning!
- Good morning, Luisinha.
- Good morning, Ma Rita.
- Good morning.
- Has it got sugar?
- Yes.
- Sit down, girl.
- It goes down better like this.
- What about your toast?
- Leave it for later.
- And the morning snack?
- Save it for lunch,
starvation keeps you slim.
- Come here!
See you later!
- She's off on a drop of coffee.
- It's a good job coffee
is made of beans,
because beans are nourishing.
See you later!
And off she goes,
as light as if she's had lunch.
Rita, isn't this Luisa's briefcase?
- Dear God, yes it is!
- Hell! Call her back!
- Luisinha! Luisinha!
- See what hurrying does?
- She's gone.
- What now?
I don't know!
Of course, there goes Mr. Costa.
Mr. Costa, come here quickly!
What's wrong? Where's the fire?
- She's left her bag. Her briefcase!
- Her "brief-bag"?
- "Suitcase", you mean.
- No. That's not it!
Luisa's left her briefcase behind.
If you could kindly take it to her...
- Me?
- Yes! You'll get there in no time!
The bank's briefcase! Let me see!
My hat! Hell...
- But you won't catch her.
- You can bet people will give way
when they see Costa running
with this briefcase. Shift, Januário!
Luisinha!
What's wrong, Mr. Costa?
Has anything happened?
No. But it could have.
Aren't you missing anything?
- No, nothing.
- Who lost what I've found...
- Ah, my briefcase!
- What an empty head!
- But for me... Who's a friend, then?
- Thank you, Mr. Costa,
you came running for me.
- Not running, flying!
If it hadn't been for the runway,
which is not to be trusted,
I'd have caught up with you before.
- Another reason to thank you.
You're the boss, Luisinha.
As the poet says, he who cannot buy,
is happy to serve.
- Well, I'll listen to the rest later,
- I haven't got time now. Goodbye!
- Goodbye!
Serving makes one happy...
Sure, sure...
No health is better than a little.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Miss Luisinha.
Can you tell me who the little beauty
is who's just come in?
That's Miss Luisinha,
the manager's secretary.
- What time does she leave the bank?
- At six.
Thanks.
Januário, add up the tenants' money.
400 'escudos' from Luisinha,
450 from Mr. Costa, isn't it?
Yes. When he does pay, it's 450.
Well, that's 850 escudos.
If we rent this room for 500,
plus your pension off the Town Hall,
we'll be alright!
- Ah, here you are!
- Did you find Luisinha?
- Yes, but I really had to run.
- Well, then...
This is what happens when I go out,
I've worked like mad.
- You've worked?
- It's not Fool's Day, Mr. Costa.
Honestly.
I went to see Marcolina's dog
and the scamp, who's got mange,
has got a twisted knee.
- Mange? Poor woman.
- Not the woman, the dog!
Then I went off to repair
the clock at the chemist's.
It really needed it.
Yes, it did. At ten o'clock it
showed eight and it was 12:45.
- And now?
- Now it's a lot better.
when it's 00.00 hours, it doesn't
show anything and it's seven thirty.
- So what?
- All I can say is
hadn't I entered the Coal Merchant's
pub for some "carburettor",
I wouldn't be here now.
I wish I was always in such
a good mood, Mr. Costa.
Well, Mrs. Rita,
I have more reasons
to cry than to laugh.
I was everything in life.
I was at the top and toppled.
I saw the seven corners of the world
and all because of a woman.
- It's everyone's Fado (destiny).
- Ah, speaking of Fado!
Rosa Maria
is in your room waiting.
Oh, right!
The guitar and Fado lesson.
I'd forgotten. I have no peace!
Even Rosa Maria!
Even Rosa Maria...
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Mr. Costa.
- I didn't think you were coming.
- You didn't show up yesterday either
Well, I wasn't sittin' at the "winda".
I was workin' all mornin'.
I put ten pairs of shoes together
and took work to the warehouse.
You'll spoil your hands like that.
How will you play the guitar?
But when I 'is' a singer,
I'll quit the job.
Quit the job,
and drop the slang.
You don't say "I is". It's "I am".
- It's not 'aisy'.
- "Easy".
- "Dafficult".
- Another one!
Not that either? Well, if it's gonna be
like that, I dunno how to talk!
How will you sing Fado in public
making such mistakes?
When I got to the "winda",
"I is gonna go to the warhouse"...
What a "zaggeration"!
I don't sing with that hoarse voice!
It's not the voice, it's the lyrics!
Do you know what being a singer is?
'Course I do.
Listen, Alzira had a baby boy.
- What's that got to do with it?
- She married a "pharmist"!
- And I already have my "indeal".
- "Indeal"? So, he's from India?
- It seems he's from the "Ilentejo".
- Is he rich?
- He bought the dining-room furniture.
- You've reached the dining-room?
- Don't go any further!
- No, sir. This is serious.
Well... Let's get on with the lesson.
Hand on your waist.
Head up.
- A smile.
- Like this?
You'll get a chair thrown at you,
like that. A natural air, girl!
What 'natral' air?
You're talkin' gibberish!
Put on the air God gave you.
Sing 'Fado da Saudade'.
Let's see if I can "member".
Go away, sad "fou"...
- "Fou" what?
..."Fought"...
Never mind, carry on!
Again.
Go away, sad "fought",
What takes me "breaf" away
Ya've been treatin' me...
Me fever, me torment,
Escape on the "wingués" o' the wind,
Escapes on the "wettas" of a "say"...
See what happens? Even the cat runs
off on the "wingués" of the wind!
- Hello!
I'm not mistaken.
What are you doing here?
- It's a secret for the time being.
- Oh, is it? Where have you been?
I've been very busy, you know.
You can't imagine.
- Business, I understand...
- Yes. Look, now for example...
I know, I know.
And that's in that building alone.
That depends. I'll tell you later.
Mind what you're getting into!
You're being watched.
STOP
Won't you give me the pleasure
of taking you home?
You look like you live far away.
Where is it?
I live in the same direction.
Well, then? Seize the opportunity.
- Here's the key.
- Very well.
As you can see,
the house is very quiet.
Quiet and clean.
No rats, nor cockroaches...
And the last instalment
on the furniture has been paid.
- Aren't there any more tenants?
- No. I mean, there's a young girl
who's like a daughter to us.
- Luisinha.
- Ah, yes.
- And a bloke. But in reality,
it's as if he is part of the family.
- Is he young or old?
- Good morning!
- Speak of the devil...
Were you gossiping about me?
Carry on!
- It's this gentleman who's just...
- Say no more, I've sussed him out.
- You're the new tenant.
- You've guessed.
I'm a physiognomist. You look like
a tenant. Let me introduce myself,
Simplício Costa, better known
as "Costa do Castelo".
- Pleasure. Daniel Silva, chauffeur.
- In the Square?
No, my car...
...I drive my boss's car.
- Ah, I get it. Rich folk.
- Someone important.
- Precisely.
- Excellent! That's another story!
- Don't you get bed and board?
- He's tight-fisted.
- Yes, he's tight-fisted...
But to make up for it,
he gives you money to squander.
- Do you smoke?
- Yes, but not right now, thanks.
No, that's not it,
I haven't got any cigarettes.
- Here you are.
- Ah, these are good.
They're the boss's, aren't they?
- Oh, Jesus...
- Thanks.
- Does your boss use matches, too?
- Yes, but I prefer this.
Ah, I see...
- Free petrol.
- Of course.
I have a feeling
we're going to get on very well.
I hope so.
You'll like it here.
The air itself...
Have you seen the view?
Come and look out of your window.
There's the castle. There's the river.
On this side is 'Paço Square',
over there 'Trigo Square'.
There are Squares everywhere.
And on the other side... Of course
the other side is... the other side!
What do you think?
Superb!
- I had no idea.
- Look at the trees.
This is where Estoril should be,
but everything's always wrong.
- You're right.
- Mr. Daniel,
come and drink to your health.
- Thank you, but I don't drink.
Don't be shy.
We're all family.
- Go on, just a drink to warm up.
- It would make me ill now. Thanks.
- What a shame.
- I'll make the sacrifice then!
- Here's to us.
- Thank you. If you'll excuse me,
I have to take care of some business,
I'll be back later with my cases.
- Of course, whenever you want.
- We'll be here.
In that case, I'll go with Daniel.
I have business to attend to,
and you can take me by car.
- Of course, it would be my pleasure,
but I can't take you
because I didn't bring the car.
You didn't?
Well, in that case... I'll walk you!
- Fine.
- See you later.
See you later!
- After you.
- Thank you.
- Daniel, you must earn quite well.
- Not bad.
- And you must have some savings.
- Yes, I don't spend all my earnings.
Does my dear friend want to make
an absolutely trustworthy deal?
- Me?
- We could form a partnership.
You, my friend,
could come in with... 5000 escudos.
And I'd come in
to the office at ten o'clock.
I'm not in business.
I like to get all or nothing.
Nothing? We can arrange that, too!
No money can pay
for a good thrill.
I agree.
- Let's not go that way.
- Why not?
I have a bill at the "Coal Merchant's".
He also says there's not enough dough
to cover the wine I drink there.
- Let's go that way then.
I can't, there's the haberdasher.
I owe her three ounces.
And she's worse than a tiger!
One day you'll have to come home
by car!
What?! It'll have to be an aeroplane
so they can't see it's me!
- What is it? Another one?
- Excuse me, I'm going over there.
- Are you going to pawn something?
- No, I'm carrying out a mission.
- You'll soon know.
- See you later then.
See you later, Danny boy.
Din-din's at seven!
- Good morning, Mr. Jacob.
- Good morning.
- Good morning. You? Here?!
- Another con?
- Conman, me?
Yes! Have you forgotten
the last one you did on me?
- The last one... no.
- The last one!
Because you won't con me again.
You pawned a trombone here
for 20 escudos and it doesn't play.
How can you expect a trombone to play
for that price? Not even a whistle!
- A note at least. Which one?
- The last one was 20 escudos,
but it's gone!
But this is something else now.
- How much is the wireless, then?
- Enough messing around!
No credit here,
not even a wire.
But the wireless hasn't got a wire.
I mean, I'm paying for it.
That there costs 300 escudos!
- Cash?
- Of course, cash.
- Here we don't sell by instalments.
- You should.
You could let me have it for 400...
I'd give you 20 escudos,
every other week.
The week I should pay, and don't,
would be paid the week I don't.
- Yes?
- No.
- Ok, then I'll take it to try it out.
- Try it out?
You know... the American way...
You're a well turned out man,
with a modern, well-known
establishment
- very well-known! -
you have to keep up with progress.
Nowadays everything is tried out.
Pianos, radios,
even crockery and women.
- Uh?!
And "linen"!
We try it out.
If we like it, we buy it,
if not, we send back.
It's the American way, sir.
Look here. Do you think
I have a "D" on my forehead?
If you do, I can't see it,
maybe if you take your hat off...
That's it!
You're taking nothing without cash!
Cash? If that's the case...
I'll get it.
See you, Jacob.
- You lost because you wanted to.
- I didn't lose!
- Be quiet, mind the tenant!
- Oh, yes! Shhh!
- What do you mean 'Shhh'?!
- Is he still asleep?
The heck he is! He's wide-awake!
Buddy Silva!
I'm coming, buddy Costa!
- You'll see him, he's very nice.
- Is the cup clean?
- As if!
- Excuse me.
Stop it.
Now it's clean!
- A very good morning.
- Good morning, Mr. Daniel.
- So, did you sleep well?
- Like a log!
Mr. Daniel da Silva,
this is our Luisinha.
Pleased to meet you.
The pleasure is all mine. It's said
you're the light and joy of the house.
- As you can see, they exaggerate.
- And, may I add, the light
and joy of the neighbourhood.
- Well done, Mr. Poet Chauffeur!
- For God's sake, you're very kind.
- Spare me the 'madrugals'
and let's have coffee.
- You don't say "madrugals",
it's "madri", "madrigals".
- "Madri"? Are you madrigal or matinal?
Neither one nor the other,
I like getting up late!
- What time does the bank open?
- At ten sharp.
But in a few days,
I'll be enjoying my holiday.
- Splendid! Are you staying at home?
- No, I plan to go away,
to a friend's on the Costa do Sol.
- Yes?
In a sanatorium like this,
with light everywhere,
fresh air, water on tap...
She's going to a beach!
I prefer Costa do Castelo
to Costa do Sol.
- Well said!
- Why? Do you think so, Mr Daniel?
Yes.
I've only just arrived, and already
I'm losing your delightful company.
- Well, let's go.
- So early?
Early? I'm going to be late!
Bye, Ma Rita! Bye, Pa Januário!
- Mr. Costa...
- Don't forget your briefcase!
Ok, don't worry!
Mr. Januário,
give me a word rhyming with morning.
I've been thinking and thinking
and I can't find one.
I also make up the verses
for the Fados now, do I?
Don't I help you cut paper
for the windmills?
Don't mind my asking...
But, is it worthwhile?
What do you mean?! In a month
I can sell about six dozen, or so.
- Is that all?
- To tell you the truth,
the biggest profit is Luisinha's.
- Luisinha... A charming girl.
She's as good as an angel.
I can still see her
the day she came in...
It's nearly three years.
Her grandmother had died,
she was her only relative.
And she asked me to take her in
while she looked for a job.
- Doesn't she have anyone else?
- No, sir.
- They already knew each other.
- I was her nursemaid.
- I nursed her at my breast.
- Oh, yes?
This young girl is very well born
and her education was excellent.
She can speak French, English...
She can even speak Portuguese...
which few Portuguese can.
- She has a boyfriend of course.
- That she doesn't.
She works night and day, at the bank
and at home. She works too much.
If she were a nincompoop,
she'd already be married.
- Yes, I understand.
- Rita, pass me the brandy.
Brandy? It's long finished!
And get unused to such expensive
luxuries, we must save up.
- Drink water from the jug.
- "Morphine", "benzene"...
- Benzene, drink it yourself!
- It's not that!
"Crystalline"...
Here it is... Found it!
I've made my day!
- The brandy is on me!
- Don't do that.
Buy a bit of cheese instead,
we haven't had any for a long time.
- For me, brandy is cheese.
- Teach them!
- Nothing to say, Mr. Daniel?
- Ah, me? I have the same opinion.
I'll go even further.
Cheese and brandy.
- You're joining the movement, then?
- Of course!
Bravo! You're one of us!
Both? Are you mad!
Do you think
we've won the lottery.
Well... The bell has rung.
No more work today!
Hear, hear!
Give us a kiss, you moaner!
Give over, you sloppy date!
Would you like to visit
the neighbourhood, Mr. Costa?
- Me?
- What? You haven't seen the sights?
It's embarrassing, but I must confess
I'd never been to Costa do Castelo.
I am not fit to go with you.
Look at my trousers. They've had it.
My life's had it!
Even my shoes make fun of them.
Yes, maybe...
Never you mind. I might be able
to get you one of my boss's suits.
- A suit?!
- Eh, you dandy!
He's a good bloke, you know. And if
I ask him, I'm sure he won't say no.
Bless him, poor soul.
Mr. Daniel, does he wear shoes, too?
- Yes, but they'd be too small.
- It doesn't matter,
I'll put my feet in a press
and shrink them.
- Good idea! See you later.
- See you later!
- Danny boy, don't forget!
- I won't. See you later!
See you later.
- Hey, neighbour!
- Yes?
- Can I borrow some parsley?
- Of course, Mrs. Rita.
Its' you, Deolinda. Come in...
What's up?
- Has Luisinha come home?
- No, but she should be here soon.
Was there anything you wanted?
- I've come to try on my outfit!
- Bravo! Long live the good life!
I'm glad you came!
You can help me lay the table.
What's this?
- Good afternoon, Ma Rita!
- What's all this racket?
- You normally knock only once!
- What else could it be?
I'm eager to get home
and give you a kiss!
And I'm so hungry!
Good afternoon, Mr. Costa!
Good afternoon, Pa Januário!
- Good afternoon!
- You're acting very courtly.
- Deolinda! Did you bring the dress?
- Here it is.
Oh, dear... This might not be enough.
It was handed down from my mother
to my sister, and from her to me.
That's not a dress,
it's a ball gown!
"Dear dress, to the ball we go..."
Let's see if I can work a miracle.
You know, Miss Luisinha... You're so
happy, I'd like to ask you something.
Yes? What is it then?
I'd like to go with my Alfredo
to the belvedere.
But my mother won't let us go alone.
- Which is right. So?
- If you went with us...
- I'm going to be the gooseberry?
- Oh, pleeease!
I won't make promises I might break.
So, it has the honours of a general!
"To arms..."
- "Windscreen"!
- And for dessert,
- 'Flamengo' cheese. 3 crowns.
- A kilo?
No, it's the brand.
It means it's good.
Chocolates, cheese, cognac...
What more do you want, 'Rothschild'?
- Is Luisinha back?
- Yes, she's in her room
trying on Deolinda's dress.
Luisinha! Luisinha!
You're back Mr. Daniel?
I didn't know.
- Sorry it's only a trifle.
- For me? Thank you!
And forgive me for interrupting
your work of art.
You're making fun of me.
Making fun of poverty.
What a beautiful afternoon.
The most beautiful time of the day.
I think so, too, because
I'm no longer at the bank.
It's the time for intimacy
and exchange of secrets.
- Isn't your car nice!
- Not mine... It's my boss's.
Of course. Your boss's. You can tell
he has good taste and money.
- Yes, he's wealthy.
- And naturally proud
and difficult to put up with
like every boss.
This one, on the contrary,
is down-to-earth
and treats me as well as possible.
- Then, that's why
he doesn't make you wear a uniform!
- That he does.
But I hate the white overall
and only put it on in the garage,
when I go off to work.
- I thought so.
A question - Are you going
to the cinema this evening?
No. I promised Deolinda I'd go
to Santa Luzia Belvedere.
She's got to go and see I don't know
what that she's very interested in.
- Can I come, too?
- Why not? The streets are free.
- Right beside you?
- Maybe... I'll think about it...
Luisinha!
You were so hungry...
Of course, I'd forgotten!
- Why did you call them, Ma Rita?
- It's dinnertime.
So what? Love lives on embraces
and caresses.
For lunch, three embraces,
and for dinner, four kisses.
- That's a good one!
- You're mad!
How nice.
Four kisses for dinner!
Right, let's have the soup.
- So many lights it looks like a crib.
- Isn't our Lisbon beautiful?
How high up are we, Mr. Daniel?
I don't know. But I feel
we are closer to God
and so, closer to the truth.
- Why do you say that?
Because I need you to believe me.
But... first,
I want you to forgive me.
- Forgive you? What for?
- Forgive me,
because at first I saw you as an
ordinary woman, an object of desire,
but now that I know you
and know how good and caring you are,
I feel I truly like you.
Luisinha, so I do not suffer
all the punishment I deserve,
at least tell me
you're not indifferent towards me.
You must have noticed already
that I like you, too
but we have known each other
for such a short while...
Are you afraid
I might disillusion you?
- Don't you believe me?
- Yes, Daniel, I believe you.
But who is to say your opinion of me
won't change again?
- Yes... Wanting you even more.
- Is it midnight already?
- Deolinda, let's go home!
Already?
- Didn't you hear it's midnight?
- Yes, but it sounded like midday.
Come on,
they must be getting worried.
Daniel! Mr. Daniel!
- What's up, Mr. Costa?
- So you left the little treasure
out all night?
- It doesn't catch cold.
- Are you going downtown?
- Yes, why?
Because, if you don't mind,
I'll accept a lift.
Fine! I'm coming down!
Can I?
Thank you.
I love you, why I don't know,
But frankly
Maybe it isn't love, and if it so
Then, love is quite different.
In vain I try to understand
What is the charm
What is the reason why I want you
With such a strong yearning
When you smile,
The look in your eyes is alluring.
But your nose...
Is like everyone else's
Handsome you are not
However, as soon as I saw you
I thought "why?" I don't know
I love you
- He's full of it, isn't he?
- He's probably won the lottery!
- Where are we going, boss?
- Downtown, Daniel.
Follow the steps.
Handsome you are not
However, as soon as I saw you
I thought "why?" I don't know
I love you
You...
- You've won the game again.
- How lucky!
Mr. Costa! Mr. Costa!
Mr. Costa!
What is it, Rosa Maria?
What's happened?
Here it is!
What's this?
Oh, dear God! What's this, child?
Speak, child!
Contract... Contract... I signed it...
The première is Tuesday evening.
Finally my favourite disciple
is entering the world of showbusiness!
- Congratulations, Mr. Costa!
- Congratulations, Rosa Maria!
- Where is the première?
- At 'Gruta do Fado'.
- Splendid!
I assure you you'll be
well accompanied...
- God forbid. Never ever!
- No, not that, child.
I mean I will personally
accompany you on the guitar!
- I don't know how to thank you.
- And we'll all be cheering!
- Everyone!
Everyone! On Tuesday we'll all be
having fun at the 'Gruta'!
And I'll be getting the bill!
Did I say I was paying?
No, forgive me...
I got carried away.
TONIGHT22:30 THE SINGER
ROSA MARIA'S PREMlÈRE
ACCOMPANIED B Y HER TUTOR
SIMPLíCIO COSTA
Being a Fado singer is my creed
And Fado is a maze
I sing as I can and know
But my feelings I always show
And when it is quiet
So as not to sadden me
I will sing with all my soul
The soul of a Fado singer and woman
Ladies and gentlemen,
after hearing the little princess
of the enchanting Fado
and the heir of the pure Fado,
you will have the pleasure of hearing
for the first time
the lark of true Fado.
That is,
the charming singer Rosa Maria
accompanied by her tutor
Simplício Costa on the guitar,
better known as Costa do Castelo.
Silence... Fado will be sung.
- Go on, Rosa.
- Hold on, Mr. Costa.
At first sight
They'll say I'm a Fado singer
This is not just a voice
It is a song from the heart
I dare not mourn Fado,
Sad and heavy like a lament,
But I'll pray it softly,
From the depth of my soul.
That is why I insist
And will not stop singing
Without a 'viola' or a guitar,
Like a lark until I can no more
With this fragile figure,
Destiny chose me
"Shall she be a singer?"
Be it or not, here I am
And just like Severa,
Oh, how I wish I were portentous
For I am neither tall nor short
And I do not lack boldness
That is why I insist
And will not stop singing
Without a 'viola' or a guitar,
Like a lark until I can no more
- What are you having?
- Champagne.
- Well, Pa Januário?
- Wonderful!
Luisinha, she sounds like a canary.
Come here.
Take this note to the young lady
sitting at the first table
near the stage.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you very much.
Follow that car!
URGENT MATTER. MUST LEAVE.
WILL EXPLAIN TOMORROW.
Go on... Drink your coffee
while it's still hot.
- I don't feel like it, Ma Rita.
- Tut.
Do you want to go to the bank
on an empty stomach? No way!
- And there's the toast, too. Go on!
- No, no. I can't.
- Tut, tut, tut!
- Listen, has Mr. Daniel got up, yet?
- No. He didn't sleep here last night
- He didn't?
- See you later.
- Bye, my child.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Januário.
- How is it?
So, what does the paper say
about her début?
- What should it say? Well.
- What a triumph!
- I'm still dizzy!
- That's the beer... not used to it.
- I don't know how I got home!
- I even slept upside down!
- Upside down?
- With my feet at the head of the bed
and my head at the foot of the bed.
It's hot.
"Markets and fairs."
"Vaccination for dogs."
- "Two escudos for a lion"?
- For a lion?!
"For a lemon".
- 400 run over and killed.
- In Lisbon?
In China.
That's it. If the girl
had done her father in,
her picture would be in the paper.
She was a success, didn't kill anyone
- I mean, she murdered the lyrics -
but, damn it, she was cheered
by 10, 20 thousand people,
she was an enormous success
and not even a word in the paper.
Spit it out woman.
What's wrong with you?
- Nothing's wrong!
- I can tell you Mr. Costa.
- You're really part of the family.
- Go on, Rita. My lips are sealed.
It's because of Mr. Daniel.
After all,
nobody knows who he is.
- He's a chauffeur.
I don't know. He turned up so well
dressed, in such good clothes,
claiming to be a chauffeur!
- Maybe they belong to his boss.
But there's more.
- He keeps giving us presents...
- That's not a fault.
But they cost him more
than the rent for the room.
Would a millionaire
come to Costa do Castelo?
- Should he have gone to the Palace?
- Alright! But he either spends
the evening here playing cards...
- Badly, thank God.
...or he doesn't sleep at home.
Yesterday he vanished without a word.
Forgive me, but there's certainly
a mystery around. That there is!
- Vanished?
- And I noticed
it was when two policemen
went into the 'Gruta do Fado'.
- Oh, heck!
- And he hasn't showed up, yet.
Did you notice if he paid
with good money?
I don't know!
I now remember that his car
is left outside every night.
- Left outside?
- Yes, it's parked at the door.
That's why I'm saying it's a mystery.
But none of this would matter,
if Luisinha hadn't fallen for him.
- There you go.
- Oh, hell... Oh, hell!
It might be him.
Who is it? Come in!
Good morning. My mother is asking
if you could lend her the paper.
Come in, child.
- Lend her the newspaper, Mr. Costa.
- If it's for news of the star,
there's nothing in it.
- None of that.
It's because of a woman
found dead in a car.
- A dead woman?
- Yes, ma'am!
A beautiful blonde girl. Very chic.
- They say the criminal got away.
- Some convict out free.
What convict?
It was some gentleman or other!
Gentleman?
Let me see...
Ah, here it is.
"Mysterious murder".
- God help us!
- "Police in search of the murderer,
"seen yesterday evening with
his victim.
"A tall, well-dressed man,
of uncertain abode
"and very well-known
in Lisbon's bohemian circles".
- When was the crime, does it say?
- "The body was found in the morning
"but according to the experts,
"the crime must have taken place
about one a. m..."
Tall, well-dressed, uncertain abode?
Ah, Mr. Costa...
My heart tells me it's him.
Excuse me, I'm taking the paper.
Sorry, but I've got beans cooking.
- What shall we do now?
- To the beans?
Oh... to the thief?
Let's search his room.
Exactly.
Ah, ungrateful life!
All I needed now, was to be given
the role of problem solver.
Mr. Januário, you're the owner
of the house, open this suitcase.
Ready!
Just look at this!
What beautiful shirts!
- This is 'pitta'.
- 'Pitta'? It's silk.
No, 'Pita Shirts'. 500 escudos!
And this contraption?
That's an electric appliance
for shaving.
You plug it in
and the bristles come out here.
Look, a watch.
And it's working.
- It's next home is the pawnshop.
- This might all be his, but...
But it might have known other owners.
- What good pyjamas!
- This is all good...
There's something in here.
A ring... with a count's coat-of-arms!
- It's true!
- Didn't I say so?
- Ah, now the cat's out of the bag.
- Good morning.
Looking for something?
- What's that, Mr. André?
- This is blood.
But I didn't kill anybody! It's blood
off a rabbit I brought for dinner
which is in the kitchen,
waiting for your attention.
I came up to wash my hands
but didn't expect the pleasant surprise
of finding Mr. Costa
tidying my suitcase.
Pardon me, I wasn't tidying
your suitcase. It was Tareco,
the kitten you've seen around,
that's run away. Wasn't it?
Yes, yes.
We looked for him everywhere,
this was all that was left.
That's why I heard
"the cat's out of the bag".
Right, but it wasn't the cat.
Now I know where it is.
- Oh, you do?
- It's in the kitchen,
it's the rabbit you brought!
How funny...
A cigarette? Thanks very much.
Ah, before I forget,
I owe you an explanation.
Last night,
I had to leave suddenly,
because, as you know,
so as to accompany you,
I had to tell my boss I was ill.
But at the height of the party,
he came into the room...
- Your boss?
- Yes. He'd have fired me.
There then.
We hadn't even thought of that!
- We were very confused.
- You bet we were.
Not to mention poor Luisinha...
Poor thing, she was so sad
on the way to the bank.
Yes, but I can...
Do you want to do a good deed?
Go and wait for her
and explain it all to her.
She was so distraught poor thing,
if you'd seen her...
Thanks, Costa, my friend.
You're straight up.
- I'll go and meet her immediately.
- Of course!
And now let's get a swinging party
ready. Now, listen...
- Great! An excellent, amazing idea!
- What do you think?
How different love is in Portugal.
- Good afternoon, Luisinha.
- Good afternoon, Mr. Daniel.
- I didn't expect you here.
- I came on purpose
so that you wouldn't think wrong
of me for another second.
- Me, why?
- Listen, Luisinha.
I want to explain
what happened yesterday.
- What's wrong?
- Does Mr. André Silveira live here?
No. The men living here are
Mr. Januário, the owner of the house,
myself, Simplício Costa,
and the new tenant, Daniel da Silva.
What's this Mr. Daniel da Silva like?
I'll tell you. He's someone
like myself, but younger.
He dresses like me, but posher.
Nice like me,
but is more... sought after.
Ah, I see, I see.
- And what time is he coming home?
- He should be here soon,
Thank you.
Au revoir, monsieur.
- Well?
- We've got him.
I'm not sure, yet. But it sounds
like him. He should be here soon.
It's him! At last.
- Do you think he'll cause trouble?
- I shouldn't think so.
- So, when are you grabbing him?
- Later this evening.
Silence.
I'll drink to the health and
happiness of our Luisinha,
so that this day
- I mean, this evening -
is repeated for many happy years.
Thank you, Mr. Costa.
And my friend Daniel is also
part of this toast,
because it was he who provided me
- I really must say -
the opportunity to make this toast
and the others that'll follow,
by bringing this bottle of Port,
which I salute.
- Well said, Mr. Costa!
- Bravo!
- Cheers for Luisinha!
- Cheers!
- Thank you, Ma Rita.
- To your happiness, Luisinha.
Attention!
The solemn moment has come
for this evening's big surprise...
Surprise?
- What could it be?
- One of his jokes.
Deolinda, get this ox out of here.
- I spy with my little eye...
- It's a canary.
...that sings but isn't a canary.
Can't anyone guess?
I'll give you one..."Give you one"...
One, two, three.
Oh, a wireless!
Cheers for Luisinha!
- Does it play?
- Does it play?!
You open this... plug it in...
...and it's like a tap with music.
You'll see!
- Oh, there you are!
- Oh, hell,
you're tuned in to the zoo!
- The coils are still cold.
Frappé.
Can't you see that the wave
hits the bulb and goes back
and so the sound can't get out.
You must warm up the carburettor...
Look, look!
It's starting to boil, look.
You can tell
Mr. Costa understands this.
- Hey? What now?
- How nice!
An American-style dinner!
Come on everybody, let's dance!
Deolinda, do me a favour
and give me a hand with this table.
That's it, thank you.
Does your Excellency dance?
- Would you like to dance, Luisinha?
- Of course.
Smile, if a woman tells you
She wants you
Smile,
Even if she swears she's suffering
Don't you believe her,
For she's delirious
To love, to suffer,
What a lie
Smile, if a woman tells you
She wants you
Smile,
Even if she swears she's suffering
Don't you believe her,
For she's delirious
To love, to suffer,
What a lie
Can I help you?
Could you tell Mr. André da Silveira
to come and speak to me immediately.
André da Silveira?
There's no-one here with that name.
What's the new tenant called, then?
- Daniel da Silva.
- That's him.
Just a moment.
- Mr. Daniel...
- What's up?
There's a bloke
who wants to speak to you...
- Did you tell him I was in?
- Yes.
God's will be done.
At last, I've caught you!
- Satisfied?
- Sort of.
This was a difficult case
and it feels good to win.
- Does it? And now what?
- Now I'd advise you
to accompany me.
- And if I refuse?
- It's all considered. I'm not alone.
- And you, my cousin,
practically my brother,
offered to do such a hideous job?
Yes, so that you, a nobleman,
would not compromise our name,
because of some woman
you met on the street.
I forbid you to speak in those terms!
She is an honest woman,
worthy of our utmost respect.
- At least you think so.
- No! I'm sure of it.
- I am the one who is not worthy.
- What are you saying?
Yes, me. To win her,
I did not hesitate in coming here,
using a false name
and claiming to be a chauffeur.
And do you regret it?
I do...
I regret the fact that I have
destroyed a life
that many others depend on.
Because that young girl
is the support of two old people
who treat her like their own child.
Pure romanticism.
You can laugh.
A month ago I would have laughed
like you,
because I didn't know
that this poverty you can see,
is where the happiness is that we,
the rich, are unaware of.
But, why did you feel so attracted?
I don't know...
At first, I was attracted only to her.
But, then to these humble people.
If you saw how they give up all
that is dispensable in life,
and the happiness with which they
receive what they cannot buy.
Some cheese,
a sweet, a bottle of wine...
I see. But how can you find such
discomfort attractive?
I prefer it a thousand times more
to the sad grandeur of our parlours,
where there's no chatter or laughter.
At least here there's sun, optimism,
the joy of living!
- Don't insist on this whim.
- Whim?
- Yes.
But can't you see I'm truly taken
by this woman, and now I couldn't
live without her?
- What? You're thinking of marrying...
- Yes, of course!
Think about what you're doing, André.
I'm leaving Lisbon tomorrow
and I have to sort this problem out.
What do you want me to tell
Aunt Mafalda?
Tell her you didn't find me.
At least give me time to justify myself
before these poor people.
But the problem is she knows
you are here,
and you know her well.
She would climb up the wall.
- Gastão, you could help.
- Me?
Not with that creature!
I'll do the same as Pilate.
I wash my hands of the matter.
Goodbye, André. All the best.
Well... I have to go to the 'Gruta'
to tidy some things up. See you later.
- See you later.
- I'm going upstairs,
because I've got the key with me,
and then my mother can't get in.
- Bye, Luisinha. Good night everyone.
- Good night.
Luisinha. I have to tell you
something very important.
I can't carry on any longer
with a lie, a lie I made up
so as not to destroy a dream
that was very dear to me.
A lie?
Ah! Here he is!
- Aunt Mafalda?
- Yes, it is I.
As the oldest representative
of the Vera-Flors,
it is my duty to watch over you
and your cousin Gastão,
whom I raised as my own children.
It is unthinkable that a nobleman,
my own nephew,
would make me stoop so low,
to come down this ignominy,
to stoop... Get me a chair,
I'm tired from the climb!
Pardon me, my dear aunt,
but before anything else, I...
You listen, first.
What are you doing in this slum?
- "Slum"?!
Aunt Mafalda, this is not my house,
I am only a tenant here.
Ah! We are in a boarding house then?!
How horrible...
- And are you the owner?
- Yes, I am.
- You know this person then?
- Yes. He's Daniel, a chauffeur.
Chauffeur?! What rubbish!
This is Don André da Silveira,
- Count of Vera-Flor.
- Count?
- You must be kidding!
- Step back, old man!
You're speaking to a noblewoman.
What made you take board here, then?
- What else? You.
- Me?!
Yes, I confess. This was the only way
of getting close to you.
Ah, say no more.
A count... A nobleman...
Now I understand...
Your kindness and humility,
so we'd think you were our equal
and would accept you within
the intimacy of our poverty. And I...
...and we believed you were...
- But, Luisinha, listen to me!
Now I know what your intentions were.
You were of course not giving a name
to an ordinary girl,
a modest girl, like me.
- Nor would I allow it!
- I wouldn't accept it, either!
And now, more than ever!
A count chauffeur...
- We didn't deserve this, Mr. Daniel.
- What is going on here, after all?
- Step back, Mr. tenant.
- Not back, I always go forward!
- I was in the infantry.
- Calm down, then.
Right, Luisinha...
I confess I lied...
But never has a lie
served such noble intentions.
And I swear that,
I pretended to be small and humble,
to be able to reach up high
where I placed you.
Now that I have lost all, all I want
is to prove to these good people
that I am still worthy
of their friendship and trust.
Goodbye, Luisinha.
This is how noble people act.
I can't believe it...
He was so good to us!
Well, I'm glad I brought peace
and happiness to this house.
Your arm, Gastão.
"Regarding the state of the car,
"Mr. André da Silveira
only has minor scratches,
"it seems, however, that he is
suffering from a disturbed mind."
Poor bloke.
And I was so looking forward
to my first day's holiday.
And all this
because of that snake of an aunt!
- The devil take her!
- Far away!
If I had known that it was her
in that car,
instead of this photo there would be
one of her flying through the window.
- Hello there!
- If only I knew how he was.
- He's delirious.
- Delirious? Has he got a fever?
Yes, quite high!
He keeps calling for some Luisinha,
who must have something
to do with this.
Yes, she does... unfortunately.
I knew it must be something
to do with a woman.
I'd like to meet her.
Oh, doctor! That's all we needed!
There's been enough scandal as it is!
I mean...
Meet her... clinically!
But I've already met her personally
and I can tell you she doesn't need
your diagnosis.
It's possible, but...
No 'buts'.
You tell me André's story,
and then say I can't go there.
- What? What about the branding
in Benavente tomorrow, uncle?
Until this mess with your cousin
is not sorted out,
I couldn't care less about the cattle
or the land.
Abegão is there,
he can sort himself out.
God willing, André will get over this.
I've even lost my appetite.
Do you know what I had for lunch?
Roast chicken,
three slices of lamb
and two mullet.
- In your case, uncle,
that wouldn't even fill
a hole in your tooth!
I'm feeling really weak.
The only thing keeping me going are
the 4 pints of milk I had a while ago.
- Can you imagine - me on milk!
- Watch out for anaemia!
Look, here comes the doctor.
Well? Did you get anything
out of my sister?
You know, it's difficult.
I didn't dare. She's in such a mood...
The usual.
I've put up with her for 30 years!
My opinion, however,
is that Luisinha should come
and be your nephew's nurse herself.
Of course! And if my sister gets out
of hand, I'll deal with her.
Do you know her, Don Gastão?
Is she an honest person?
- There's no doubt about that.
- Don't hesitate then.
It is absolutely necessary
to calm down such restlessness.
Nothing will deter me.
She'll come. You'll see!
- Is anyone missing?
- The gardener.
When he comes,
tell him he's fired, then.
That's what happens to anyone
who steps out of line.
- Did you hear?
- Yes, ma'am!
Be quiet. No-one's talking to you.
You, José,
when you served tea today,
your bowtie was crooked. I do not want
any abuse or lack of respect.
And you, Amália, do not cough again
in the morning, or you'll wake me up.
- I've got a cold, ma'am.
- Cough silently.
Or cough at some other time.
And you, Josefa,
what are you thinking about?
- Me? Nothing ma'am.
- With that look?
I could swear
it was something stupid about me.
Your button is undone.
- Did you say something?
- I didn't say anything.
Be quiet and button up.
- My lady...
- Button up, I'm telling you!
- Pardon me, My Lady...
- In line! In line, I repeat!
And now, Mrs. Anastácia...
Why did you put eggs
in the white sauce,
knowing I'm on a diet?
Answer me!
I'm sorry,
but I'm the one who put the eggs.
- You?
You agreed between you.
One said yes and the other agreed.
In that case,
at the end of the month, out!
Right, it won't be at the end
of the month, but now! I'm sick of this!
- Educate them!
- Educate? A Marchioness?!
Get out! Get out of my sight!
Out, didn't you hear!
- Just a word, my lady...
- Speak.
I just wanted to say that Don Simão
wishes to speak to you,
and he is waiting in the library.
- Oh, is he?
Just as well,
he hasn't heard me today.
- Did you send for me?
- Yes, I did.
Here I am. Explain yourself.
Well... Let's not beat
about the bush.
As you know,
I don't mince words.
Yes... What's mince
got to do with it?
Mince, no.
Mess. And you made it.
Because of you André is lying
in a bed,
with his face all messed up.
- That's all I needed! It's my fault?
Yes. If you hadn't gone
to Costa do Castelo,
he wouldn't have gone out of his mind
all the way down there.
You might as well say I was the one
who dug the hole he's in.
You didn't dig the hole, but you did
worse, you interfered in his life.
- Me? What are you getting at?
- This is the conclusion,
Dr. Miranda wants us to get
the young woman André is calling for.
- Luisinha? Have you gone mad?
- I haven't. But he might!
Will you take that responsibility?
A stranger in our house...
And a pretty girl, at that.
That's why! What we need here
is youthfulness, joy, light...
Dash it all!
Open the windows, let the air in!
- I'll catch a cold!
- Get rid of those cobwebs!
There! Oh, I'm sorry!
- It's for sure!
- Is it? What did aunty say?
It was a bit difficult,
but she gave me a free hand.
- Do you think Luisinha will come?
- Gastão will go. He's so diplomatic
he would probably carry her here.
- Thanks, uncle Simão.
Don't thank me. You can't imagine
my joy in going against your aunt.
I'm in heaven!
Watch out... She's coming, watch out!
Luisinha...
Luisinha!
Can you hear him? Poor thing!
- The way he calls for her.
- Luisinha...
He doesn't have any strength left.
- Send for her as soon as possible.
- Right away.
You've no idea!
That's all they're talking about!
You and André are today's heroes.
I don't like such publicity at all,
fame without gain...
Can you hear the phone?
It must be the newspapers already.
Come in!
- Who is it?
- Mrs. Manuela de Vilhena.
Ah, put her through.
Give me a cigarette.
What does this nosy parker want?
Hello, darling!
Me? I couldn't be better!
Yes, yes, I already knew.
Darling, I was never interested
in André!
Engaged?! What an idea!
No... It was nothing more
than a joke.
But thanks for the news, anyway.
Bitch!
Hello there!
At last! Come on down!
Give me your bag.
This is Luisinha,
uncle Januário, and Mrs. Rita.
- My uncle, Don Simão.
- For many happy years.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Bravo! So, this is Luisinha.
- My nephew has very good taste!
- Oh, Don Simão!
If I were young, I'd also lose
my mind over such a pretty face!
Come in! Come in!
You'll be well looked after, Luisa.
You'll like it, you'll see.
- What's this invasion?
- It's Luisinha who's arrived.
But Luisinha is one,
and I can see three people!
- This is Ma Rita and uncle Januário.
- I know that very well!
- But what are they doing here?
- Come on, sis'!
Has the whole Costa do Castelo
moved in?
- We came because we were asked to!
- Of course!
Well, I never! We were even told
Mr. André could die,
if Luisinha refused to see him!
And the whole family came
so he wouldn't die!
Pardon me, ma'am,
but I'd never come here on my own.
Of course! Sis', they're here
to do us a great favour.
- And they're our guests, too.
- The three of them?!
No, ma'am,
Luisinha is the guest.
We've come to work.
That's what was arranged.
- Arranged with whom?
- With me, aunt.
Didn't you fire the gardener
and the cook? Voilá, the substitutes!
- Well done.
- Well done, no. Badly done!
Who nominated you trustee
of the servants?
In that case, let's go.
Wait!
Who gave you orders to leave?
- No-one's going without permission!
- Hear, hear!
Firmino,
take them to their rooms.
They can start working.
You, young lady, come with me.
Luisinha!
Thank God,
you're better than I thought.
- Luisinha...
- Come on, calm down.
Promise me you'll do everything
to get better quickly.
I promise I'll do everything...
just to have you near me.
Er... Is this more delirium?
Now that you've got over the accident
mind you don't die of the cure!
One, two, three, four, five...
...47, 48, 49, 50.
The Marchioness's medicines
drive me crazy!
And then, of course,
if they don't get to her on time,
there's hell to pay.
There.
Take this to her ladyship
and don't tarry along the way.
You're two minutes late.
It's what I keep saying -
nobody cares about my health.
You can carry on.
- Good morning, aunt Mafalda.
- Good morning, Gastão.
As I took my medicine
two minutes late,
we'll have to wait two minutes
for lunch.
My day has been spoilt.
I don't know how to get back
the two lost minutes.
I was just thinking about that.
Well, let's sit down.
Where's Don Simão?
Don Simão is having lunch downstairs
with those people.
Yes, sir. I'd seen people eating well
but like you, Don Simão,
I've only met one other person.
- He eats as much as I do?
Even more so! Let me tell you.
More? I don't believe it.
It's not possible.
- Where is such a phenomenon?
- He's our tenant, Mr. Costa.
Mind you, he's a glutton.
Well, bring him here then.
This is something I want to see.
What? More people?
Your sister is ready
to swallow us up.
Send for this hero. As for my sister,
leave her to me.
If that's your wish, Don Simão,
all we have to do is send for him.
Not a scrap will be left!
Well, my dear aunt, I haven't had
such a good meal in a long time!
Yes... The new cook isn't bad.
So it was a good idea
to bring her here, after all.
As she's here,
we might as well make use of her.
But let's not talk about things past.
Yesterday's upsets are enough.
- Mrs. Mafalda.
- What are you doing here?
It's 12:30, time for the medicine
to help your digestion.
Punctual!
But who told Firmino
to find himself a substitute?
Am I not the nurse then?
Go on, open your mouth.
I'm here to look after
those who are ill.
You know, you don't look well today.
No, I don't.
At last,
there's someone
worried about my health.
You've found your guardian angel.
And as you are in good company,
I'll go. Excuse me.
- Goodbye, Luisinha.
- Goodbye, Don Gastão.
Right, I'm going to get
my beauty sleep.
- I like to be read to...
- Oh, do you?
But, unfortunately, in this house...
My brother is only interested
in horses, bulls and Fado singers.
Gastão, as you can see,
tries to get away whenever he can.
If you like, it would be my pleasure
to read to you.
Really?
It's funny,
but I think I'm starting to like you.
Well, I thought you were nice
as soon as I saw you, Mrs. Mafalda.
Oh, you did, did you?
Well, well.
Go and get the book that's on
the bedside table, in my bedroom.
And wait for me in the parlour.
- Deolinda! Deolinda!
- I'm coming Mr. Costa!
- Can I help you, Mr. Costa?
- Yes.
I'm giving you the house key,
you keep an eye on this
and take Tareco upstairs because
I don't trust him with the fish.
- But where are you off to?
- I'm off to the countryside!
- To Campo (country) Pequeno?
- Good heavens! On holiday!
- You're joking!
- Look, with a sealed letter, too.
"When Don Simão found out
you eat more than him,
"he told me to ask you to come here
"and are..."
- Are?
"... are-commended
you bring your guitar,
"as he enjoys Fado very much."
Look, child, I've loosened
my belt by three holes already.
Yes, sir. If I didn't know
Mr. Januário's handwriting,
I'd say it was forged.
Here's the key.
Lock everything up
and be very careful with thieves,
in case they leave what is not ours.
See you on my return.
What's the matter?
- Did I step on your foot?
- No, sir.
It's just that my mother said the
only man who can kiss me is my dad.
Oh, "my daughter"!
Luísa! Luisinha!
'Her Highness' is calling.
She's woken up.
- Did you have a good rest?
- No, I had a nightmare.
- I dreamt of mice.
- Mice? That's your stomach.
Mice in my stomach?
- Maybe. I did eat cheese.
- See?
Don't you think I am paler today?
- It's the colour of your bow.
- Oh, is it?
Purple makes you look a lot...
A lot less younger.
- Do you think so?
- Light things suit you.
Can I?
Do you want to see?
As a matter of fact...
And on such a cheerful lady, too.
Speaking of which,
do you play anything, Mrs. Mafalda?
- No. I hate music.
- I really enjoy it.
Unfortunately, I haven't touched
a piano for more than two years.
- Can you play?
- Yes. Will you let me try?
No. This piano has been closed
for more than ten years.
- Ah, I'd better not then.
- But,
let me see if you really can play.
Go on. Try it.
What's this, Firmino?
A miracle, sir. A miracle.
What's this?!
- That's enough!
- My God!
What are you doing there? Out!
And you - get out of my sight!
Out. I need to speak to my brother
in private.
- I was wondering how long it'd last.
- Brother Simão,
we have to throw these people out
as soon as possible.
Ah! Now you've been served,
André is better
and everyone looks after you,
you want to put them out.
But can't you see
that this girl's presence
could be fatal for our nephew?
- Fatal? Why?
- She's not of the same social class.
- There you are, then.
You destroyed your own life
because of such a stupid prejudice
by not marrying the man you loved
after all.
Let them make a sacrifice as I did!
Out! I said, out!
I don't want these people here!
This is not a hotel!
- But listen, sister...
- I do not want to hear a word! Out!
- My lady...
- What do you want?
Miss Luisinha says
it's time to take your medicine.
See? You see?
And I have to swallow this.
- Ah, it's you, Mr. Costa.
- How do, Mr. Januário!
- Be quiet!
- Is there someone ill?
No, but all hell broke loose,
this morning!
Hell? Oh, hell!
Come through the kitchen
because of the Marchioness.
- Look, it's Mr. Costa!
- Ma Rita!
- Give us a big hug!
- Don't make any noise!
Oh, yes!
The Marchioness is as sore as a bear!
Oh, hell, so there's no talk of food!
What about the patient? And Luisinha?
They're fine!
Be careful, come with me.
- Here's Mr. Costa.
- Come in, come in!
Can we come in?
- Mr. André! How are you?
- Are you getting better?
- Luisinha!
- Hello, hello!
- This here is the phenomenon.
- Mr. Simplício Costa
and Don Simão.
- Gives us a hand, then!
So, you're the man capable
of eating this world and the next?
I wouldn't say no to this world,
but the next is too much.
We'll see that later.
I've had the cook roast
a big lamb, like this.
One? What about you, sir?
No, it's one for both of us...
Oh, he's challenging!
Excuse, excuse me.
And what time is dinner?
- It's at seven.
- At seven? Oh, heck...
Couldn't it be a sort of matinee?
I haven't had lunch, yet.
Uncle, a lamb won't be enough.
How funny,
"matinee" and the bell's ringing.
- It's my sister who's blown her top.
- Oh, hell!
- I'll die on an empty stomach!
- God help us!
- Luisinha!
- Here it comes!
Don't worry.
I've an idea to sort everything out.
I'll introduce you as a scholar.
- What if she protests?
- At scholars? Don't worry, old chap,
let things run their course.
Luisinha! Luísa!
Luísa! Luísa!
- Here she comes! Hide!
- Where? Under the bed?!
Come here.
Don't come out before I call you.
Luísa! Luisinha!
What's this? A man on a perch?!
What are you doing there?
Forgive me, but I don't know either.
Could it be possible?
I don't know. Word of honour.
Simplício!
Mafalda, my love!
Heavens, what are you doing here?
But are you... you?!
Keep your voice down,
you'll get me into trouble.
But tell me, why did you come?
Have you been looking for me?
For 30 years... Are you the dragon...
- I mean, the Marchioness?
- Yes, I am.
But where have you been hiding
to show up only now?
I don't know...
Your parents took you to Spain
and I emigrated to Africa
and died there.
You died?
I died to the world, to come to life now
that I've found you again.
- And are you married?
- No, I'm a widow.
But I have always been true to you,
my first love.
- So have I, Mafalda.
As faithful as a dog to its master.
And have you never forgotten me?
Never. I still keep your picture
of when you were a young girl.
I have kept it here lovingly.
Look.
A reminder of the past.
- And those papers?
- They're tickets.
This is where I keep
all the pawn tickets.
Here's the balcony
where you serenaded me from.
- Do you remember?
- Do I remember?
You even threw a plan pot at me
and broke my head.
That's when I realized I loved you.
Why have we found each other,
Mafalda,
if the reasons why we separated
still exist?
- You're a noblewoman, rich...
- Be quiet.
You know I'll give everything up
for you.
If nobility and fortune
are an embarrassment,
- I'll throw both out of the window.
- No, close the window!
I don't want your sacrifice.
Both, no... You can throw out nobility.
I'm not mercenary.
My God... my brother Simão.
Just pretend nothing happened
and leave matters to me.
- Has this gentleman said who he is?
- Her ladyship has only just arrived.
Let me introduce you
to an old friend, then.
- You know each other?
- Mr. Simplício Costa.
- From a noble family. The Costas.
- Costas do Castelo.
Yes, I know them well.
A large, noble family.
The Costas, on both sides.
I thought of inviting him
to be our librarian.
Well thought of.
You know I love books,
libraries...
- Oh, really?
Speaking of which,
I'd like to ask you a favour.
Your ladyship commands.
Could you look for "The Cats" for me.
In the courtyard?
No. The book by Fialho.
The novel, "The Cats".
I thought it was the mewing "cats"!
- Mrs. Mafalda, it's time.
- To tell you the truth,
I don't need any more medicines.
You can take this too.
I feel I've gone back 30 years.
As handsome as 30 years ago.
Honestly, I don't know why you didn't
visit André straight away.
- Was it because of the typist?
- You know nothing of psychology.
Did you want me to visit him
while he was delirious,
so I could be thrown out
with the usual remark:
"The Doctor does not allow visitors",
which she'd tell me on the phone.
And will she say so in person?
No. he'll have to see me now,
whether he wants to or not.
I swear that girl
is going to pay dearly for this.
I'll stab her in public!
That's a bit much.
Revenge is very ugly.
Yes, it is. But it feels good.
They all say I'm a loser
But the one to lose
Lose...
Mr. José, do me a favour
and call 47273.
7-3. Thank you.
Somebody lost...
Lose...
Bruise...
Die...
I..."l"?
Hello? Who's speaking?
'Gruta do Fado'? Costa here.
Costa do Castelo.
Yes? How are you?
Could you tell Rosa Maria
I'm sending her another song today.
Yes. I'm working
on the finishing touches.
The finishing touches.
You won't forget?
Thank you very much. Goodbye.
Simplício... It's you...
This all seems like a dream.
I should say so...
What a meal! What a cigar!
I haven't enjoyed this good fortune
for a long time...
It's so long since
I last had bicarbonate...
What are you writing? Poetry?
You're still the same poet.
- Let me read them.
- They're not important.
I was only daydreaming.
"They all say I'm a loser,
"but the one to lose
the best in life
"was no-one else but me".
How fantastic!
You can't deny this poem
was inspired by me.
- By you? But it says "lost".
- So what?
Was I not lost for 30 years?
"But the one to lose
the best in life",
which is you, "was me".
- Do you think I don't understand?
- Yes, in truth...
- Who's lost what I've found?
- You're not looking at these.
- They're going into the memory safe.
- Little Mafalda, don't disgrace me.
- I can't lose that.
- Why not?
Because I don't have another one
and I have to rewrite them.
- No.
But I'd like to include some roses.
I know you like flowers so much.
Then, include a butterfly
kissing it, too.
A butterfly, I wish.
And you, a rose to adorn.
So that at the height of Spring
I can, at last, kiss you.
What a pity it's not Spring yet.
Miss Isabel Castelar is downstairs.
Oh, bother! Tell her...
Wait. Don't tell her anything.
Tell Mr. André and Don Simão.
I'll be down in a moment.
Yes, my lady.
That's all I needed!
What a nuisance.
Some creditor?
I mean... Some salesperson?
No, it's Isabel de Castelar.
An intriguer.
She's definitely not here
for a good reason.
- Is she young or old?
- She's young and ambitious
and she's after André's fortune.
- Oh, is she? Leave her to me.
- To you?
- Yes.
From now on I'll be here
standing guard,
to solve this
and other family problems!
Standing guard...
Just like Camões,
a poet and a soldier.
But this is amazing, Firmino!
Flowers everywhere,
an open piano, and wide open windows.
This is nothing, Miss Isabel.
Ever since Luisinha arrived,
this house has had a real turnabout.
- Ah yes, the nurse.
- And then, there's Mr. Costa.
- Mr. Costa?
Yes, Miss, Mr. Costa.
The librarian...
He is amazing.
He's been straightening everything out.
Oh, really? Big news, Firmino.
Mrs. Mafalda is 20 years younger.
- Hello, Isabel.
- Well, André? What's happened?
- Look at you, poor thing.
- Still very weak.
Sit down, sit down.
- Thank you.
- I would have come to see you before
were it not for the "doctor's orders".
- That's not for us.
You were, as they say, unavailable.
Or rather "hostage".
Oh, yes, and the girl? I've really
laughed at such a story.
A real fairy tale.
A prince marrying a shepherdess.
But where is she?
I want to meet such a beauty.
You'll soon have that pleasure.
She's getting cigarettes from my room
- She runs errands, too?
- Yes, yes.
Look, here she is.
- Your cigarette case Mr. André.
- Thank you.
- Ma'am.
- Goodbye.
You know, you need to get some air.
Tomorrow I'm coming to get you
and take you for a drive.
- Oh, thank you very much.
But I still don't have
the doctor's permission.
- Then I'll have tea with you.
- I can't either.
At that time I'll be resting my leg.
- Won't I?
- Yes, yes.
So what?
You can drink tea in any position.
The Chinese drink it crouching.
Yes, but I still can't do
such acrobats.
Ah, I understand.
You're worried in case
your nurse doesn't approve.
- But surely she won't be jealous.
- Me?!
- Oh, Isabel!
- Furthermore,
you know I have special rights
over you.
- Please don't go on.
- Okay, alright!
I'll say no more. Don't get worked up
you might get worse.
Excuse me.
- You're satisfied now, aren't you?
- Satisfied...
No, I'm not satisfied yet.
- Oh, look, our dear Isabel.
- My lady.
- So, what brings you here?
- Two very important matters.
First, to see our André,
who's fine.
- I can see he's been well cared for.
- By the nurse. In my opinion.
Too?
Let me introduce you
to Mr. Simplício Costa,
Our new librarian.
Isabelinha Vila Chã.
Costa? I think I've heard the name.
But I know so many Costas.
You do? I know many 'villas', too.
Vila Pouca, Vila Verde, Vila Franca.
Vila Chã,
I must confess I did not know.
But I am Vila Chã "OF" Castelar.
- And I am Costa "OF" the Castelo.
- Castelo, Castelar...
- Who knows you might be related?
- Maybe.
- Do you any Castelars?
- Castelar?
- Castelar... yes, I know the buns.
- The buns?
Yes, the buns "OF" Castelar.
They're quite delicious.
- Have you never tried them?
- Excuse me,
it's a surname from the old cavalry!
- And this is from the old bakery.
But, tell me, what other reason
is there for your visit?
Oh, yes. I almost forgot.
I've come to invite you for dinner
at my house next Thursday.
I want to celebrate
André's recovery in proper style.
- What a nice gesture.
- You're very kind.
I hope you won't say no to this.
And I want the girl to go too,
she's been so dedicated.
She's been a darling.
Hasn't she, Mr. Costa?
A real darling!
Not that you're not, of course.
But seriously,
do you want Luisinha to go?
Of course. We cannot celebrate
the cure and forget the remedy.
It's not a meal,
it's more like an operation.
There's the nurse, the patient,
the chemist...
And the surgeon - you.
And why not invite
Mr. Costa "of" the Castle.
- Oh, ma'am.
Won't I be one too many?
It's the disappointment that's
the hardest to bear.
But I'll get over it, Ma Rita.
It'll take time but I'll get over it.
- We should never have come.
- You, too? Don't whine, man!
We haven't signed anything.
Let's go and that's it.
Stop thinking about it. We'll be
sleeping at home this very evening.
Alright, Mama Rita.
But I've still a couple of words
to say to that lady.
Be careful, child.
Think of Mr. André.
I don't care about him now,
it's my self-respect.
After all,
they're both laughing at me.
You have no reason to speak
like that of Mr. André.
Maybe, but I'd rather
get used to the idea.
That Miss Isabel will soon
find out who I am!
- Miss Isabel!
- Are you having dinner at my place?
- Yes, but I'd like to say...
- Oh, my head,
I almost forgot the photo I brought
for André.
- Yes, but...
- Luisinha, would you be a darling
and give it to him.
- Me?
It's in my car. Come with me.
Goodbye, Firmino.
You look younger every day.
Forgive me, Luisinha, but had I known
you were fond of André,
I wouldn't have been so cruel
as to say we were engaged.
But who told you
I am fond of Mr. André?
Oh, you're not?
Just as well, then.
If you don't mind...
Give it to André, will you?
- I look good, don't I?
- No, on the contrary.
I think you look so ugly I don't have
the heart to give it to Mr. André.
Excuse me!
- Isabelinha left in such a fury.
- Well, Mr. Costa didn't spare her.
I realized she intended
to make fun of Luisinha.
Even that business of dinner
smells fishy.
- Do you think so?
- I'm sure.
All the Vila Chãs and the Castelars
must be there.
- To pick on the poor child!
- That's something she's capable of.
Yes, but the game might cost her.
A scandal? That's what she wants.
We'd best get rid of her
before she spreads her poison.
- Get rid of her? That's difficult.
- We'd need an excuse.
- Oh, yes? I'm sure we can find one.
- But how?
- I have a plan,
but don't ask me anything else
for the time being. All I can say is...
...Isabel, you're mine!
- Well, hello there!
- Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Don Simão.
- What's up then?
- Nothing, we're leaving.
- What, you're leaving?
- Yes.
The house is there all empty
getting full of dust.
- Is that why?
- And also because
my business will go to the dogs.
But what does this mean, Luisinha?
You're leaving?
Yes. Our mission in this house
is over. Mr. André has recovered.
- There's something going on here.
- It's just not that...
Could you please tell Mrs. Mafalda
and all the others
that we are very grateful
for their kind hospitality.
Goodbye, Don Simão.
But this isn't right.
You're going just like that?
Yes, Don Simão.
Just as we came.
- A very good afternoon.
- Till we meet again, Don Simão.
- Well?
- Three quarters of an hour?
- I should have gone there myself!
- I think so too!
Please, stop it for a while, sister.
- You look like a tiger in a cage.
- Don't irritate me!
Don't irritate me or you will see
a tiger... but out free!
- Well? They're not coming yet?
- No sign.
All we need now
is for him to stay there, too.
That would be a relief.
For me, for the wines
and for the smoked ham.
Don't say that brother!
How can you?
How can I allow such abuse?
After all, I haven't been Don Simão!
I've been the grocery
'Jerónimo Martins and Sons'.
- Here he comes!
- Good!
- Bad, I say!
- Well?
- There's nothing we can do.
But did you tell her it was I
who was asking her to come?
It's useless.
She's locked herself in her room
and neither Januário nor Ma Rita
can get her to at least speak to me.
"No, no, and no"...
She's very hurt.
- But why?
- Hurt? I don't understand!
I do.
This was Miss Isabel's doing.
Is there no way we can get out
of this situation?
Yes, there is. Give me a free hand,
and I'll put everything to rights.
Free hand?
- Is there anything else you want?
- Be quiet, brother!
- Go on my friend.
- Let me tell you.
The one going to Luisinha's house now
is Mr. André.
- Me? No.
If she hasn't acknowledged my request
I will not insist anymore.
I have my self-respect, too.
Why lower myself? What have I done?
- Hear, hear!
- This is nothing to do with you.
- You listen and be quiet.
- Hear, hear.
God knows, I'm very sorry, but
this is what she wants. I give up.
You give up, do you?
So, Miss Isabel has the last laugh?
No. I'll teach that bird a lesson.
You?
You gave you license?
- No-one. I licensed myself.
- I'm on your side.
I had already noticed
you are a daring gentleman.
Well said.
The noble stock of the Costas
has never turned their back
on anyone, whoever they might be.
Luisinha will see me tomorrow,
even if I have to use brute force.
Oh, how I longed for
My happy little house
As modest as myself
Oh, Lord it is so good to live
On the first floor,
Counting from the heavens down
My bedroom is like a nest
And the ceiling is so low
That when I lie down,
I discreetly open the door
And always say
Mister ceiling,
Please let me come in
The noble or the rich
Everything they have
But the home of the poor
Has more joy
- Luisinha...
- Don't go on, Ma Rita.
I've told you
I don't want to see him again.
But Mr. Costa
has never done us any wrong!
On the contrary.
I'd like to speak to Miss Luisinha.
It's from the bank!
From the bank? Who is it?
At last, I've got you!
And now, Luisinha,
you have to listen to me.
You'd better come in, then.
Well, Mr. Januário?
Did I or didn't I do it?
- You're a sly one!
- As sly as a fox!
My dear Luisinha...
...I've come here...
- I can guess, Mr. Costa,
but I can tell you there's no point
in talking about such matters.
Look, Luisinha, I've come here,
because, above all,
I am a man with a heart.
If you only knew the sadness
there is in that house
since you left, Luisinha...
Poor André doesn't even seem
the same.
Poor thing.
I know you're suffering too, Luisa.
You suffer because you love him too.
Me?! Yes, I did love him.
I loved him when he was Daniel.
But André? That two-faced?
That hypocrite?
Well, well...
It's obvious you don't love him.
But in that case,
you're not afraid of going back.
No, no and no!
What for? For more disappointments?
More suffering?
Come on, Luisinha...
I've already said I don't want to!
No-one can make me see him!
I can, Luisinha.
My lady!
"to a fancy dress party
taking place in her Gardens
"next Wednesday, 3rd,
"to celebrate André's recovery."
Look. Here she is.
- And very pretty!
- It's symbolic.
It means her reign
is coming to a bad end.
Here's the roll.
When I give the sign, like this...
- The false notes.
- Yes, Mr. Costa.
- O...
... K.
Luisinha! Luisinha!
We're all waiting.
How beautiful, Juliet!
Romeo will be dizzy.
- Mr. Costa, I'm so nervous.
- Chin up!
The time for revenge has come.
And Isabelinha will soon be sweating!
So, are you cured of your typing?
Completely cured.
On revient toujours.
And is this why
you wanted me to come?
Calm down, Juliet.
That's the rope ladder,
that Romeo will climb
to reach your balcony.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
Ms. Isabel de Vila Chã
e Castelar, here present,
will sing one of her noted songs
for the first time.
Will you excuse me?
Luisinha, come with me, please.
Poor Marie Antoniette...
She's climbed the scaffold.
On a river
Of a dream of love
A
Princess kissed
A ministrel
And never came back
And her heart took
The moon, something rare
From her toast she smiles
She had cruelly sworn
Her dream she betrayed
Come here, Luisinha.
Get ready.
But will I be singing like this,
dressed up as Juliet?
Don't worry,
we'll soon change you into a Juliana.
Look, this goes down.
This goes up.
"Song from the Street".
How horrible, they'll run away.
"Go get undressed!"
Song from the street
Different from the others
Neither yours nor mine,
It belongs to everyone
Song from the street,
To and fro it goes, never stopping
Fickle and insane,
From mouth to mouth, it is no-one's
Song from the street,
Swift swallow
It cannot be yours,
And will not be mine
The song from the street
Cannot remain on anyone's lips
Independent, to all it belongs
It belongs to no-one
Song from the street...
Only words about us
When it possesses...
Song from the street,
To and fro it goes, never stopping
Fickle and insane,
From mouth to mouth, it is no-one's
When the people's song is heard
Banal, it is thought, and yet
It smiles at pain itself
In love songs, so they say,
Deadly destiny
Song from the street,
Different from the others
Neither yours nor mine,
To all it belongs
Song from the street,
To and fro it goes, never stopping
Fickle and insane,
From mouth to mouth, it is no-one's
Song from the street,
Different from the others
Neither yours nor mine,
To all it belongs
Song from the street,
To and fro it goes, never stopping
Fickle and insane,
From mouth to mouth, it is no-one's
Well, what do you think of my idea?
Great, eh?
Why such faces?
What? You didn't like it?
Yes, they did!
Come with me.
You too, my lady, please.
Mrs. Rita! Mr. Januário!
Com on up, come on up!
After the victory, peace.
Go on, explain yourselves.
There's nothing like a good chat
to reach an understanding.
Excuse me.
André, how crazy,
simply crazy I was!
Luisinha...
- But what are they doing?
- A tête-ã-tête,
for the happiness of the four.
May the Lord help them
reach an understanding!
- At last!
- What a lovely couple.
Romeo and Juliet.
Carmen and Don José. Olé!
Song from the street,
Different from the others
Neither yours nor mine,
To all it belongs
Song from the street,
To and fro it goes, never stopping
Fickle and insane,
From mouth to mouth, it is no-one's
Transcription and Subtitling:
Alexandre Bettencourt / CRISTBET Lda.