They’re gonna fall into the water, right?
-She’s back at it again with me.
-Have you seen that childbirth movie?
-No, no.
-The one they show to pregnant women.
They’re shooting a second
The Birth Reborn…
The first one,
they shot it in several places.
And this one they’re shooting here, now.
She’s here, Mom. She’s so beautiful.
She looks just like Juca.
Full black hair.
Big cheeks. Folds of fat.
She’s delicious.
ACTIVIST
PSYCHOLOGIST
LAWYER
INSPECTOR GENERAL
FEDERAL INSPECTOR GENERAL’S OFFICE
OBSTETRICIAN
(GERMANY)
PEDIATRIC DOCTOR AND
EPIDEMIOLOGIST, PHD
OBSTETRICIAN
PHYSICIAN, PHD
OBSTETRIC NURSE
PEDIATRIC NEONATOLOGIST DOCTOR
OBSTETRICIAN
OBSTETRIC NURSE
(ENGLAND)
PHOTOGRAPHER
MODEL AND TV HOST
OBSTETRIC NURSE
(ENGLAND)
OBSTETRICIAN
JOURNALIST
SCIENTIST, PHD
LAWYER
OBSTETRICIAN, PHD
You laugh, right, Fabiane?
What’s up?
He’s biting me.
You wanna see Mommy?
THE BIRTH REBORN 2
Keep going. Keep going.
Come on, Mom! No use
trying to come down, Mom!
Lift that butt back up.
Push! Don’t you come down!
Keep going! Keep going, Mommy!
Put your strength down here!
Keep pushing, keep pushing!
No! Don’t say “haa, haa”.
Keep your mouth shut!
You gotta hold your breath, don’t breathe!
Keep pushing, Mommy!
Come on, don’t stop pushing!
Come on, come on, come on.
It’s stuck.
Come on, come on.
It’s getting out!
Don’t stop!
Don’t open your mouth!
No, Mommy! Help me here, Mommy!
Come on, come on.
Keep going, keep going.
Almost there.
Push, keep pushing!
No, he’s pulling at me.
I can’t do this.
He’s trying to help you.
Stop it, woman!
You’re holding the baby
inside you, look!
She’s pulling it back in.
Come on, Mommy. It’s here, look.
It’s coming, it’s coming now!
It’s coming!
Push, push! Don’t stop!
You gotta push!
It’s almost getting out, come on!
There!
No! Don’t you touch it!
She contaminated everything.
Keep that hand down.
I’m sorry.
You don’t get it, do you?
Look at this!
-You can hold it. Hold it.
-Dammit!
It’s all contaminated.
When it gets infected…
How could I know?
Keep that hand down.
-Mommy, I’m gonna put this here.
-I didn’t know.
Congratulations, sweetie!
You did great, beautiful!
Exactly! I was just giving
you some advice, I wasn’t…
Okay, Mommy? It’s okay, everything’s
under control, okay? Calm down.
It’s just a precaution, because when
you touch it, you contaminate it.
-But I didn’t know!
-I wasn’t yelling at you, woman!
Look at me here,
let’s go up a little.
Relax, sweetie! Relax! Relax!
Relax, everything went okay.
It was great!
He’s okay,
everything’s okay, darling! Okay?
-I was just giving you advice.
-Calm down, he’s right over there.
He’s crying there, very calm.
15 MONTHS LATER
We’re doing a Brazilian documentary
about delivery and childbirth.
Whom might I talk to about it?
According to the doctors, let’s say,
I was already 42 weeks pregnant.
The baby was going to die.
The doctor said, “Let’s make a C-section.”
I hesitated, but, well,
42 weeks and a half.
I went to the hospital, my water broke.
I was left practically
from midnight to 4:30 AM
completely alone in a room
with oxytocin dripping into my veins.
It was like a insecurity, fear actually.
“May I get up?
Am I not allowed to?
I need to go to the bathroom.”
I think I wasn’t even allowed
to drink or eat anything.
They’re prepping you for the C-section.
Not one soul came to tell me,
“Look, this is what’s happening.
We’re gonna do this and this.
We’re gonna wait until such time.” Nobody.
Actually, I only found out
what oxytocin was much later.
I didn’t even know what it was
they were pumping into my blood.
I know the law.
My husband didn’t know where I was.
You know why you can’t?
The hospital director won’t let you.
Wanna know why?
I’m gonna explain.
Here in this hospital,
like in any other hospital,
there isn’t a structure
for every single patient…
-The law…
-Let me finish!
For every little patient
in their cubicle, nice and cozy.
All those women, all of them,
are breastfeeding, naked. That’s why.
Just out of respect for them.
You wanna get in?
A cop comes here at 3 AM.
-We’re just doing our jobs…
-This law was passed back in 2005.
You… We don’t have,
we don’t have…
“Hospitals, maternity wards
and the like are bound by law
to allow the presence of an escort
indicated by the pregnant woman
to assist her during labor,
during delivery and after,
for a period of up to ten days.
This applies to all hospitals in Brazil,
be them private or public.”
I arrived at the hospital
with a nine centimeters dilation.
All of a sudden, a guy came in
pushing a gurney, and he said,
“Hey, why are you still dressed?
We gotta get you to surgery.
Go strip, now!”
The people responsible for
the medical staff, the doctor on duty,
could he come and speak with us?
With PR?
I had a very unnatural
“natural” birth, actually.
Oxytocin and all.
One, two and… Push! Come on!
I was 18 years old,
and I didn’t have any say in it.
How do you do? My name is Anne…
Throughout my whole
pregnancy I’d been told,
“Either you do a C-section
or you’re gonna die.
You gotta do a C-section
or you’re gonna die.”
And I grew up in a family where
doctors are always right.
So I was gonna die. If I didn’t do
the C-section, I was gonna die.
I suffered a lot, because…
“I’m gonna have a baby
and I won’t get to know my baby,
because I’m gonna die.”
Do you want to put a rag under here?
Otherwise it'll make such a mess.
Through your nose!
They kept doing touch exams all the time.
They wouldn’t let me have a sip of water.
They wouldn’t let me eat.
I felt like a caged animal.
“Doctor, must I lie down?
I feel okay, I wanna sit.
I’m not comfortable lying down,
I’m not okay.”
“Sit down, then. Sit down because
we’re gonna give you anesthesia.”
“You chose to deliver this way.
Now live with it.”
Small talk in the delivery room,
people giggling.
They’re recording.
Keep it quiet or it’s not gonna look nice.
We can cut it out in the editing room.
“This is your waiver.”
And Pedro, my husband,
read it and said, “Here says
that I won’t hold the doctor
responsible for anything! Is that it?
If I don’t sign this,
you won’t let me in?”
And the girl said, “We won’t.”
So I signed everything.
I just signed a bunch of stuff,
a huge wad of forms.
It was crazy. And people kept
signing all that paperwork.
So many suitcases,
getting to the hospital was an ordeal.
Check-in ended at 6:30 PM.
It looked like a hotel.
I was there from… I don’t know,
6:30, the time I checked in,
till 10:30 PM waiting for
that C-section thing,
and that late at night, inside surgery,
the AC was freezing cold,
and I was naked, with my belly…
waiting… all alone!
You see a movement in health in
the opposite direction, you know?
Towards afflicting or putting in danger
women’s health, children’s health,
by the doctors, you know?
For ethical reasons,
it’s very complicated.
I’m a doctor, so that’s
a huge conflict for me.
We have an ancestral memory of
what violence is in this country.
We’ve had 500 years building
violence, racist,
sexist, classist violence.
And now, obstetric violence.
Verbal abuse, especially
of a sexual nature.
“You didn’t scream that loud
when you were doing it.
Why are you screaming now?”
Humiliation, shame, degradation.
They’re gonna slice her vagina,
they’re gonna sit on her stomach.
Performing routine episiotomy on all women
or an episiotomy just
to speed up the process.
Many times, these women are cut up
without even being told about it.
Many times, without anesthesia.
They scream then, saying,
“I don’t wanna be cut!” And the
doctor cuts them up anyway.
Incontinence, she won’t be able to
have a pleasurable sex life anymore.
It’s a woman’s right, guaranteed by law.
They want to crouch,
but they’re forced to lie
down, they’re held down, even.
“Cruelty and torture like
a concentration camp”
was a description repeated
by dozens of women
who didn’t know each other
from all over the country.
It’s impossible to understand that
a doctor would lie to their patient
about the effective medication
to perform a C-section on a woman.
Both the C-section and the
episiotomy are surgical procedures.
According to the Criminal Code,
which is already very old,
the Medical Ethics Code
and the Civil Law Code,
a surgical procedure cannot be performed
against the will of the patient,
unless there really is an
imminent risk of death for them.
Verified imminent risk of death and
authorization from the next of kin.
Every person has a right
to life, to safety,
to non-violence, to health. In 2014,
the World Health Organization
released an official note taking
the same position on the subject,
that abuse, mistreatment or omission
of adequate health treatment
constitute a human rights violation.
It is the patient’s right to decide
what they approve or disapprove.
So that’s an informed choice.
The Medical Ethics Code
determines expressly
that it is a doctor’s duty to hear
out their patients, to give them
adequate information based
on scientific evidence.
It is the doctor’s duty
to keep their knowledge up to date.
Some hospitals, in order to circumvent
the obstetric violence issue,
are now issuing a “delivery plan”
to pregnant women,
a document where women say what they
will accept and what they won’t.
But it is a pre-issued adhesion term.
It’s not a valid document
because the choice wasn’t free, clear
and informed, as the law determines.
Enough violent deliveries
to sell C-sections.
-Is it over?
-Yeah.
-It lasted long, didn’t it?
-One minute ten.
I’m already eight centimeters dilated.
I am.
Three at six, then another one at 6:30.
This is a marathon, isn’t it, folks?
There’s still a lot of cervix to dilate,
but her head is very low.
You’re doing fine.
You found your balance, understand?
-And the açaí.
-The açaí gave you energy for sure.
I had an accident when
I was seven years old
and they had to amputate my legs.
And they made me think
I really was in no condition
to have a normal delivery.
My whole life I had
to break barriers, always,
while someone said, “Ah, you can’t”,
or “you’re not capable of doing that”.
The first doctor I went to,
he kinda stared at me
as if he was about to ask,
“How did you do that?
How did you get pregnant?”
I left and didn’t come back again.
So I went through a lot of doctors.
I even had to hear that
my pelvis wasn’t opening,
that my body was too small.
Having a baby was something they saw like:
“Poor thing, she’s gonna suffer.”
My pregnancy was very peaceful,
the only thing I had was stomach sickness,
and they insisted that mine
was a high-risk pregnancy.
And I was like,
“High risk to whom?” Right?
Because I’m fine, my baby is fine.
Like, I used to get sick a lot,
to the point of having to inject
a very strong drug called Zofran.
So Rodrigo had to give me the shots.
I couldn’t even go to the drugstore,
because one day I went there
and I fainted in the drugstore.
So my pregnancy, in the beginning,
was very messed up because
of all the sickness.
And when I went to have
my ultrasound, he was like,
“How are you?”
“I’m feeling awful.”
“But why do you feel like that?”
“Because I feel sick all the time,
just looking at your face
makes me wanna throw up.”
I was in such a foul mood
because I couldn’t do anything,
I was always feeling sick, about
to throw up. I couldn’t eat,
I couldn’t brush my
teeth, nothing, you know?
So he said, “Well, if
you’re feeling so sick,
I suppose there could be even
more than one in there.” And I…
Those two hearts beating like that.
He said, “Look, there’s two here.”
And I was like, “No, not two.”
“No, they’re really two babies.”
Rodrigo was weeping, lying on
the couch, and I was like,
“No, that’s not possible.”
“It is, too. Look at the screen.”
Then I looked and I went, “Damn.
Will I manage to hold these
two little guys inside me,
to deliver and raise
these two little guys?”
So the first thing
I felt was a lot of fear.
But right away you begin to feel
very happy, doubly happy.
LACK OF DILATION
BODY BUILDERS OR ATHLETES
BABY “TOO SMALL”
UTERINE POLYPS
FLAMENGO VS. FLUMINENSE
SOCCER MATCH
PROLONGED PREGNANCY
POLYCYSTIC OVARIES
PREVIOUS C-SECTION
INTERRACIAL MARRIAGE
TWIN PREGNANCY
MOM’S FLAT STOMACH
SEDENTARISM - CLOTS IN THE
AMNIOTIC FLUID - KIDNEY FAILURE
NEAR-SIGHTEDNESS
BABY SWALLOWING AMNIOTIC FLUID
HEAVY URBAN TRAFFIC
The amniotic fluid, at the very least,
by the pregnancy’s third trimester
is basically the baby’s urine.
The baby has to swallow it in order
to form the digestive tract,
the respiratory system,
the baby has to breathe the fluid.
When you have an elective
C-section at 37 weeks,
what the couple is told
is that the baby was swallowing fluid,
so it’s got liquid in its lungs.
Going through labor squeezes the lungs
and reduces the amount of liquid
when the baby is born.
The baby’s feet were
stuck between the ribs,
so it couldn’t be a vaginal birth.
So there’s no uterus or
amniotic sac either, right?
Yeah, the baby’s all loose in there.
Hanging on the mother’s
ribs for dear life.
A friend of mine was also pregnant.
She took a lot of vitamins and
had an ultrasound every month.
“My doctor didn’t prescribe me that.
No, she didn’t prescribe this exam.”
“Don’t you think your doctor is
way too negligent with you?”
I think the retinal detachment
was one of the most…
“You’re 8/20 nearsighted.
If you make any physical effort,
your eyes are gonna pop out.”
He suckled, he was held,
all the procedures
we consider adequate for the baby.
“Shouldn’t we wait? Because I
had to wait for my other kid.
Aren’t you gonna give him a bath?
You’ll leave him dirty? Are you
gonna put his clothes on like that?”
When the mother went to her room,
we quickly went to the nursery
to weigh the baby, measure
him and put his clothes on.
The lady was very nervous and
she asked to talk to me.
“No, I won’t put him in the incubator,
me and the mother agreed on that,
it’s what’s best for the baby,
he’s already been held and breastfed.”
“But what about the incubator picture?”
“No, no incubator picture.”
People have this culture…
Carmem and Tom were born
during the 39th week.
This was all I heard: “A twin
pregnancy is a high-risk pregnancy.”
She was cephalic and he was breech,
60 hours since my water broke:
“Heartbeats are fine,
both babies are fine,
you’re fine, we’ll monitor it.”
Are you having contractions?
One thing I really wanted
to feel was this expulsion.
The passage through the canal,
the crowning.
He came straight into my arms,
it was beautiful,
Rodrigo cut the umbilical cord
and he was like this,
right behind me the whole time.
His presence, his comfort,
so loving, so beautiful, like this.
Held the gauze.
Breathe. Great. Beautiful.
It’s… it’s…
Everything’s okay,
everything’s okay.
Your place is here.
I wanna go to the hospital.
This is what we’ll do:
breathe deep and keep calm.
You eat something and then
we go to the maternity ward.
Okay?
Gently, there’s no hurry.
Okay? We’re right here,
we’ll do it in your time.
That’s it!
The sac!
Beautiful!
That’s it, let her come!
She’s beautiful!
Beautiful!
It’s my baby!
My love!
My little baby!
There’s a tribe where they say that
any baby who is born inside the sac
grows up to be very lucky in life.
Blessed.
Sofia Feldman Hospital begins by meeting
the demands and needs of expecting women.
It’s a counter-hegemonic model,
so to speak.
An assistance geared more
towards the community.
Good practices based on evidence,
which is the way to build knowledge.
Innovative initiatives
that end up becoming public policies.
We’ve always allowed
patients to bring escorts,
way before it was passed into law.
The first child ever
to be born in this hospital,
the whole family was here.
That was more than 30 years ago.
It’s about human rights, so,
how can a woman go through
a moment like that alone?
If she wants to have the baby
at home, we go to her home.
If she’d rather deliver at the hospital,
we assist her in there.
If she wants to go to a birth house,
we assist her there.
It has to be a low-risk pregnancy,
without complications,
be them high blood pressure or diabetes.
We bring all the necessary materials.
The same care we’d give her in a hospital,
we follow the same evidence.
She lives 30 minutes away from
the hospital, from Sofia Hospital.
If she needs to be transferred,
that’s where she’ll go.
In one of the hospital’s ambulances.
I had all the support a person needs
in order to do the antenatal.
And I gave birth crouching, right?
Which really makes it easy.
Alice Jennifer has jaundice,
so she’s in treatment now.
We’re not talking
only about biological health,
a broader vision of health,
with vinculation,
with gentleness, with love,
with affection,
that’s another condition
for this baby to develop
and be a healthy adult as well.
And then I went through
all that again, you know?
There was another one.
After all that,
there was still another one.
Let’s just talk about soccer.
Ah, no. Not about
Corinthians. For God’s sake.
-What team do you support?
-I’m a Corinthians fan.
I was informed that the
doctors were gonna say…
The “normal” delivery,
abnormal, actually…
I didn’t even know what it was
they were pumping into my blood.
You gotta do a C-section
or you’re gonna die.
I know what the law says, son!
The hospital won’t allow it.
Are you gonna go against the law?
Officer, she’s trying
to go against the law.
So the law won’t be obeyed, then.
Yeah, yeah, Jorge.
Director, no one…
Okay, son.
I won’t go against any laws.
He can’t get in, can he? Okay.
Is he going in and he’ll be there
with all the other patients?
The director won’t allow it
just because of that.
Because all the other patients
are in that same place,
all of them naked, all…
that’s disrespecting the other patients.
Unfortunately.
She was born without labor,
at 38 weeks,
from an undesired,
coerced elective C-section… here.
Blue in the face from crying.
But away from my baby.
It’s very, very upsetting!
Monitored visit, right?
May I know how it’s gonna be monitored?
As a mother?
Customer service.
So what’s the number?
Okay.
“You’re not dilated enough.”
They didn’t give me time to dilate.
I didn’t have any contact at all with her.
I only got to see Luiza
12 hours after she was born.
Nine years later, I got pregnant.
“I want a natural birth.”
“You can’t have it.”
-“Why not?”
-“You already had a C-section
and you’re too old.”
“Old?” I was 31.
Look at Luiza.
She’s making faces, look.
Can I schedule this visit with you?
Because then, when I get clearance,
I’m gonna have that ready.
-You have kids, right?
-Yeah, a girl and a boy.
They were C-sections, so it was scheduled.
Did she go into labor? Or was
it a scheduled C-section?
-Was it scheduled?
-It was scheduled.
Were they breastfed, the babies?
In the delivery room?
No. No.
The child only comes to the room
when the mother is also in the room.
Those who come to visit also ask,
“Where? Where is she? Where?”
Was he put in that fish tank,
that nursery? Your babies?
-They did.
-Mine too.
With a little camera on top of him.
And you could look at him
through the camera, right?
-From the room.
-From the room, right?
Yeah, there was a normal TV set in there.
-Did you watch the surgery?
-No, I tried not to look at it.
I saw the baby coming out.
But I didn’t look at my wife,
because of the cut. I kept holding
her hand and she squeezed mine.
Then, when they brought the baby,
she couldn’t hold him either
-because she was strapped, I think.
-She couldn’t.
They broke my water.
Then he actually gets on top of me,
he steps on a stool or a ladder,
I mean, he put the palm of his hand
and pressed down with all his weight
on my belly. It was brutal.
They performed an episiotomy
on me without my knowledge.
Without information or consent.
They cut me up.
Yes, I’d like to take pictures
and record it.
And let me ask you another thing,
would it be possible for me
to sit and talk to a doctor,
to someone in charge of the staff?
About the procedures that are done
in the maternity ward when a baby is born.
A woman doctor came to see me,
there was another touch exam,
then she broke my water,
they did an awful episiotomy
which still hurts today.
I feel pain from my episiotomy,
physical pain.
With my legs up, like this…
and he applied the Kristeller maneuver.
It was ultraviolent.
There was no need for that.
The baby was coming out already.
What’s the director’s name?
Could I talk to him?
In order to talk to the director,
you have to schedule a meeting.
I was four centimeters dilated already,
so I was doing fine.
And I went into C-section.
He said, “we can’t wait anymore,
we can’t wait for a natural birth,
because you might die
if you had a natural birth.
I’m calling customer service
because I want to find out
whether I can make a monitored tour
of the maternity ward, taking pictures.
The line is busy, please try again later.
Thank you.
I remember very vividly the doctor saying,
“Gee, I slit his butt.”
Because when he cut me,
he also cut my baby up.
He’s still got a scar.
He’s got a cut in his butt,
it’s gone up a little.
But it wasn’t a little cut. It was a cut.
The Belém, Pará Convention,
an international treaty
signed and ratified by Brazil,
deliberates that any conduct
which causes physical, psychological,
sexual or moral harm to a woman
is gender violence.
Besides being negligence.
It’s more than malpractice.
It’s more than negligence.
Who are the people who get access
to that kind of information, right?
Are they getting access
to that in the community?
Obstetric violence is violence
against women in the sexual sphere.
Very akin to rape.
The reports that come to us tell that
under obstetric violence, women feel
the same way a sexually raped woman,
a woman who was raped, feels.
No one has rights on anyone else’s body.
Even at childbirth, even babies.
Who wants to be a victim
of sexual violence?
Would you want to acknowledge
your torturer?
Would you want to say that the doctor,
the one who was there at
the moment of your delivery,
the most special day in your life
because there’s also all this
romantization of motherhood
was someone who committed violence
against you and against your baby?
It’s about the struggle for valuing
childhood, for respecting children.
“Why do you wanna keep talking
about that, about black women?
We’re all equal, we want the same things.”
No. Sometimes, what a white woman wants
is different from what a black woman
or what a native Brazilian woman
or a woman in a wheelchair
want, for instance.
She’ll struggle for accessibility issues
which I, as a woman who can
walk, don’t even notice,
because I have all this access.
So my struggle is different from hers,
but I have to take her
struggle into consideration.
Collectively,
I cannot depend on information.
Collectively, what’s going to save us
are public policies.
And mass invasions by
women at those places
where public policies are issued,
which today are dominated by men.
I was already 39 weeks pregnant
and they wouldn’t get out.
My belly was bulging out my back already.
It expanded to the sides, my belly.
Then one day a little liquid came out.
So he said, “Let’s go to the hospital,
because I think we
shouldn’t wait anymore.”
Rodrigo, if he could,
he’d get pregnant for me.
He mounted a camera on his
head, on a baseball cap,
he got it all set up to record the birth,
so we have the whole
process filmed FPV by him.
And it was so moving, it was really great.
I was in labor for eight hours,
I began to feel a lot of
pain with the contractions.
There’s something I would do
differently if I got pregnant again,
which is the anesthesia.
I couldn’t feel my legs.
That was very frustrating,
because I really wanted to…
I mean, I practice yoga,
breathing techniques, I work out,
I’m such an athlete, I bench-press,
I’m always in the gym,
and I think I could have pitched in more
when it was time to push
for the expulsion, you know?
And I couldn’t do it because
I couldn’t feel my legs,
and I found that out when I
wanted to go to the bathroom.
“Can I go pee?”
“I think you won’t be able to.”
Then when I tried to get up
I was like, “Damn.”
My twins were born ten minutes apart.
I didn’t have the pleasure of
breastfeeding them like in the soaps,
which look like they stay
there for hours, swap tits,
then you look at them a bit more.
It’s always very quick,
because you’re breastfeeding one
and the other is already crying,
it’s like they’re always sensing
each other, following each other.
So I’m nursing one baby and
the other one is there waiting,
he’s waiting in line, holding his horses.
That was when it sunk in,
how hard it is to raise twins,
it’s really like running a marathon.
I had children during my
internship as an obstetrician.
I went early to the hospital,
got all the usual shtick
about interventions,
and I saw myself having a C-section.
It was a shock. Very frustrating,
I couldn’t understand what
it was that went wrong,
but now I know that it
was completely necessary.
And that didn’t result in what I wanted,
because I had a second
baby through a C-section.
She was breech, I tried an external
cephalic version before the C-section.
Artificially, from outside the womb,
we turn the baby upside down.
Every four moms we try that,
usually we manage
to turn one baby that way.
If we give her medication
to suppress womb contractions,
we’re able to turn one more of
these four babies, that is, 50%.
And if we resource to anesthesia,
an anesthetic that is similar
to the one used in C-sections, we can
turn the third baby. So, in general,
out of every four attempts of cephalic
version, we manage to do three.
She was turned into cephalic, but then,
next day, she was sitting again.
A scientific paper was just out,
saying that it had to be a C-section.
Let it go slowly. Let go.
When I got my third pregnancy,
my daughter,
I went in search of scientific evidence.
It was a wonderful experience,
every contraction,
every minute was worth it.
I can’t believe I did it.
Hi, sweetie. Evelyn…
Evelyn…
We did it.
What an adventure you had today, girl.
See, love? Didn’t I tell you it
was a good idea to pack a bag?
The English National System
is a value for English society,
so we want to turn Brazilian
public health care into a value,
an unquestionable asset
for the Brazilian population.
Going against
the flow of Brazilian history,
we’re managing to reduce
C-sections in Belo Horizonte.
Death of the mother, death of infants
from birth-related causes.
-It’s a girl!
Oh, my God!
There are places in the world where
they even give money to women
to have their babies at home.
That free childbirth at home may
become a public health policy.
It is the woman’s right to choose
where she wants to have her baby,
if adequate conditions are provided.
It’s not someone in a white lab coat,
all sterile and cold,
but a friend who pushes the piano
to make room for the inflatable pool,
to get you a chair quickly,
to back you up, to warm up the water.
When Ayomide was born, it was…
it was unique.
Men don’t cry.
They say men don’t cry. But…
I can’t compare
that with any other moment.
-The afterbirth.
-Look at the circle here.
-What a beautiful afterbirth, folks.
-Beautiful. Very special.
-Look at this ring!
-So beautiful.
-And my baby is getting her milk.
-Beautiful!
There, like that.
-It feels great like that.
-Great, huh?
-You guys think I’ll manage?
-Of course, you will!
-You are managing already.
-You think?
-Of course!
-I’m beginning to get afraid.
It’s okay. You’ll overcome your fear.
Fear of what?
Of not being able to take it anymore.
If you ever feel you can’t take
it anymore, then we’ll talk.
We’ll cross that bridge when we get to it.
I usually say I don’t make deliveries.
You make the delivery.
The woman makes it.
The more we see science advancing,
the more we tend to do nothing.
Those who do real obstetrics
in its truest sense, practice “obstare”,
“being at someone’s side”.
The births that give me
the most satisfaction are those
where I sit on my hands and do nothing,
I just observe.
You don’t need so much technology
in order to give quality care.
It’s counter-intuitive, because
we used to do things the right way,
then we began doing it all wrong, and now
we have to prove, through science,
that what we used to do
before was the right way.
Let her hold her.
-Oh, baby.
-Look at Mommy, sweetie.
I love you. Too much even.
-My baby.
-You can hold him.
My beautiful baby!
-I can’t believe this.
-He’s here.
-He’s okay.
We did it. Me and you.
With a lot of special guests.
Look at his face.
Look how beautiful you’ll grow up to be.
-You’re gonna be very pretty.
-You’ll be beautiful!
-Gee, bless you!
-He loves his dad.
Are you gonna learn
how to change his diapers?
-I think I’m gonna have to.
-“I think I’m gonna have to”!
NARROW PELVIS BEFORE LABOR
HEART DISEASE
SWELLING
UMBILICAL CORD STRANGULATION
TOO HEALTHY
PREVIOUS ABDOMINOPLASTY
PILES
INSUFFICIENT FLUID DETECTED
IN ULTRASOUND EXAM
TEEN PREGNANCY
OVERDUE
MOM TOO THIN
UMBILICAL CORD STRANGULATION
-AND I WAS BORN AT HOME
PATIENT “DOES NOT HELP
WITH NATURAL BIRTH”
OUT OF ROOM IN THE MATERNITY WARD
All over the world, what do we see?
An attempt not to go over 42 weeks.
Because after 42 weeks, your chances
of having natural birth are reduced.
Here in Brazil, it’s 40.
Forty weeks, you do a touch exam,
“Gee, the baby’s too high,
the cervix is closed, it won’t fit.
It won’t fit anyway,
why would you wanna wait?”
It’s a euphemism to take
the edge off of the word “surgery”.
Birth, the woman gave birth.
“Shall we schedule your delivery?”
You don’t schedule a delivery,
You schedule surgery.
However, I won’t tell
that woman in my office
that we’re scheduling her surgery.
But the crux of the matter is what’s
being sold to that woman: safety.
Natural birth must become again an option
for Brazilian women.
It’s not an option anymore.
Humanized C-section was a
controversy in some courses,
and such humanization is based especially
in putting the woman in the central role.
You go to a C-section
and women often lose their central roles.
When you say “humanized C-section”,
you reinforce the birth industry we have.
In my C-section, they dimmed the lights,
there was music, skin contact.
I’d say it’s a respectful C-section.
Humanization means much
more than something nice,
with scented oils, music playing
and dimmed lights. First of all,
humanization means working with
current scientific evidence.
I only found a doctor in my 30th week.
And he joked about it, he said to me,
“Whales give birth and they have no legs.
So it’s gonna be easy for you.”
They said, “In ten minutes, tops,
the second baby will come.”
Okay, then. Tom, come on.
It took way longer than that.
At one point,
I was begging for a C-section.
“For God’s sake!
I can’t take this anymore!”
“You chose to deliver this way.
Now live with it.”
Touch exams all the time.
“Sit down, then. Sit down, because
we’re gonna give you anesthesia.”
They wouldn’t let me have a sip of water.
Must I lie down? I feel
okay, I wanna sit.
So I was gonna die. If I didn’t do
the C-section, I was gonna die.
…with oxytocin dripping into my veins.
In training hospitals,
we heard a statement from a woman
who told us that eight different
people performed touch exams on her.
And in that same delivery,
she suffered two episiotomies
to practice episiotomy and suture.
Let us build intolerance
to obstetric violence.
It is marked on women’s bodies,
on babies’ bodies, on the soul of
all these people involved at birth.
-I have to schedule a meeting, right?
-You have to talk to his secretary.
It’s even funny,
because they’re already like, “But why?
Why do you wanna record it?
Why do you wanna record it?”
Concerning schedules,
that’s more of a technology thing,
it has to do with the advances
of medicine in that field.
We have a lot of data in Brazil
about iatrogenic prematurity,
as they call it,
which is forced prematurity.
People even think that medication
and medicalization are the same thing,
and they’re not.
Medications exist to help us.
Medicalization is a social construct
that makes us see natural things
from a medical perspective.
That began specifically,
in childbirth management,
in the 16th century, when midwives,
godmothers and healers
were removed from the birth scene
and replaced by men,
who were considered
the recipients of scientific knowledge.
It was an appropriation by men
of science with technique and technology.
During the Fifties, a movement began
against cruelty on pregnant women
in the USA
and Europe, especially in England,
where women gave birth
while they were unconscious,
physically restrained. They didn’t
have any recollection of the delivery
because of the amount
of memory-impairing drugs.
They came back from it with bruises
on their wrists and ankles.
Many times, they had scars
from falling off the bed,
because the medication induced
psychomotor agitation
and they fell off the bed, so they
had to be strapped down to deliver.
They showed me Pedro and took him away.
There wasn’t any skin contact.
“If you don’t tie your tubes
along with the C-section
and you get pregnant again,
you’re gonna die.”
They performed another C-section
because I was gonna die
and they tied my tubes.
And then my baby daughter was born,
I wanted to hold her.
“No, no, no. You can’t…
put down that arm!”
Because I was full of oxytocin and
I didn’t know what that was either.
The marketing department’s number.
They ripped off the afterbirth,
they simply pulled it off.
That hurt a lot as well.
In the Sixties, with the Hippie
movement and the feminist movement,
there was strong contestation
of authorities in general,
including medical authorities.
Childbirth is a moment of
empowerment for the woman,
it’s the moment where she takes
control over her own body,
where she has an active attitude.
My mom was already in the room.
I looked at my mother
and I told her,
“Mom, they cut me up.”
And then my mom said to me,
“No, girl. That’s normal.”
I said,
“It’s not normal. I’m in pain.”
And then, when Mom
took me to the bathroom,
she said, “Look, don’t be scared.
It’s gonna hurt.
Don’t be shocked when you touch it.”
I just kept looking at her
and saying, “Why?
Why did they do this?”
And she couldn’t answer me either.
Feminism is, maybe, the hardcore,
the great inspiration
for this criticism
and for debating obstetric violence.
This knowledge
of medical obstetric gynecology
and of medicine in general is,
to a great extent,
a misogynous one, which stems
from the idea that women are even
incapable of being doctors.
There’s a whole biological explanation
of women being irrational creatures,
incapable of having any
objective scientific thinking.
This is why they need to be
protected by men, by institutions.
Feminism is the struggle for
a woman’s right to decide
about herself, about her own life,
about her own body.
For more protagonism,
for a voice, for space,
for equity, which is different
from equality, isn’t it?
It’s not about being equal to men,
but about having the same rights as men.
Deserving respect
is intrinsic to human beings.
No one should have to earn respect.
That’s a very common mistake,
people thinking
that feminism is
the opposite of male sexism.
It’s an institutionalized model
which is deeply seated
in patriarchal logic
power and domination over women’s bodies.
The medical discourse is impregnated,
most of all,
with fear of the feminine,
fear of childbirth.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
There’s this fantasy that after
such a giant phallus, the baby,
goes through the vagina, the phallus
of the partner will get lost in there.
So the woman ceases to be a sex object
to be a worn-out,
used, loose person,
and that has no basis on the
best of scientific evidence.
Spontaneous childbirth can actually,
according to some,
propitiate a better-toned
vagina than before,
but in the professionals’ view,
the fact of having a vaginal birth
is a threat,
because the woman wouldn’t be able
to satisfy her partner sexually anymore.
Jokes… doctors comment that
they’re gonna close it up more.
With João’s pregnancy,
that was when I found out
that after Juliana’s episiotomy
I received one extra stitch,
the so called “husband’s stitch”.
We mustn’t ruin this amusement park here.
Let’s make the smallest cut possible.
It’ll just squeeze through. Tightly.
Congratulations to you guys.
In order to change the world,
we must first
rescue women’s self-reliance,
because women themselves are the
ones who will change childbirth.
I think this is that
thing you talked about.
Oh, love!
It’s strong!
Beli! Beli!
What’s nice about having staff you trust
is that there’s no frustration
afterward for having a C-section.
Because I know it was necessary.
-Can I try another one, then?
-You can, I told you that.
-Not right away, you know?
-I told you could try again.
-Another natural birth?
-Another natural birth.
We stay about four hours after
the delivery to follow through,
to make sure that the mother-child bond
has been established,
that the baby has been breastfed.
We leave only when everything’s okay.
We’re available on the phone.
If she needs any member of the staff
to go back to her home, it’s all there.
She can make lunch,
she can go up, take a bath
and go about her business
and enjoy the company of her baby.
Public health can work.
It’s still a young public health system
and everyone depends on it.
Anyone who goes out to have
dinner at an expensive restaurant
is depending on public health,
because sanitary inspections
at that restaurant are done
by Sanitary Vigilance,
which is an organ integrated into
the unified public health system.
People forget that sometimes.
It covers, of course, 200 million people
and helps directly in all the phases,
from disease prevention,
promotion and recovery of health,
including procedures of top complexity
for 150 million people.
It’s the largest public
health system in the world!
Not even China’s is bigger.
China has 1.3 billion people,
but it has no public health system
covering 150 million people.
Full of diapers in there.
This little girl made me get to
moments I’d never thought of before.
My deepest fear in childbirth
was that it’d be a C-section.
Then she turned.
I started having two-minute contractions.
“No time to do the version anymore.
Breech she is, and we’ll have
to make the delivery that way.”
That moment was very intense, right?
Two hours. For those who were there,
it felt practically like one week.
And when she was born, of course
that was very intense for me,
and I began to see that things
didn’t look like they were
the way we had planned,
and I became even more afraid.
Mariana!
She’s beautiful!
Look who’s here!
Help me. Why is it like that?
Because she was like that for a long time,
but the swelling will go away.
-That’s the hump.
-Does it go away?
It does.
It’ll be back to normal.
I drove home peacefully,
feeling great.
Next day, I was taking care of my baby.
I gave her a bath.
Even when I’m not here anymore,
a little bit of me somehow will still be,
it’s my Part II.
-Can I take a picture here?
-Of course.
Can I take a picture here?
Show me where it is.
I’m coming, okay?
Now she’ll go to the nursery.
Are we going to shoot here? Her exit.
She’s going away.
We can’t follow them anymore, right?
We can’t.
-Are you going out?
-I’ll go there. It’s better, right?
She needs to change.
This is Aunt Fátima.
Bye, Luiza! What now?
Now she goes to the nursery.
In about three hours,
she should be back in the room again.
-Who?
-The baby.
Four years later, what I still
can’t wrap my head around
is that they fooled me
into tying my tubes.
Just because I had three children,
is it over? Can I not have any more?
One of the most frequent
kinds of complaint we get
is about oxytocin abuse
to make women go through labor quickly,
freeing up hospital beds, even though
doctors, hospitals, won’t confirm it.
25% of all women experience some
kind of childbirth violence,
and many aren’t even aware that
they were subjected to it.
I wanted that to end quickly.
That was my childbirth.
That was my baby daughter, you know?
One out of every four women,
according to a study by the
Perseu Abramo Foundation,
experience natural birth.
Now, what’s the percentage
of Brazilian women
who are having natural childbirth?
It’s a minority.
That means this number is much higher,
because it doesn’t take into
account the number of women
who have C-sections and are
victims of obstetric violence.
Fiocruz’s research
Being Born in Brazil proves
the kind of obstetric violence
that every type of woman suffers.
So, affluent women
suffer the obstetric violence
of having unnecessary C-sections,
but they get a nice room service.
Some people think that having
hotel service at a hospital is good care.
I don’t think women should be
forced to have natural deliveries.
I fight for the right
of women to be well informed
and choose their elective C-sections.
That’s not my problem.
My problem is those who want
a natural delivery and can’t get it.
Vulnerable, I think that’s the word.
They simply strapped me down
and I insisted that I
wanted a natural delivery.
After they stitched me up,
after all the C-section procedures,
they let me loose and showed me
my daughter like this,
10, 15 centimeters away from me.
Don’t finish.
We have to tell two kinds
of violence apart,
a somewhat more subtle violence,
which Marilena Chauí
calls “perfect violence”,
which many people will
not see as violence,
because it’s so well-constructed,
so normalized,
that it’s wearing “protection”
or “care” make-up.
“Look, I’ll just do a little cut,
just a little snip.”
The vast majority of obstetric
violence is perfect violence.
The first delivery
was very traumatic for me.
I became a statistic for
unnecessary C-section.
I got pregnant with my second
daughter and I knew right then
that I wanted a different birth.
Nothing better than Sofia, right?
We perform 1,000 births
a month on average,
and the C-section rate is about 25%.
Everyone, the board
of directors, all workers
know the public health system’s
principles by heart.
If all hospitals in this country
could know such principles,
we could say that every hospital
in the public health system works,
despite all the hardships they face.
Many people say,
“But that’s a structural issue,
what can I do?
I’m overcrowded as it is.
I lack resources.” Actually,
that’s the least important thing
where humanization is concerned.
The most important thing is changing
every staff member internally.
Who wants a C-section?
The C-section is to blame,
because it gets chosen.
Because pregnant women
who want a C-section, they choose it,
they ask for it, they can’t face the pain,
they think they won’t be able to.
It’s the OBGYN’s job to activate their
in-ear Babelfish, and when she says,
“I want a C-section”, they
should hear, “I want help”.
We’ve got auriculotherapy, ventouse,
acupuncture, homeopathy, floral
and aromatherapy techniques.
The basis, the common core is
traditional Chinese medicine.
It’s a new regard for health care.
Peaceful mom, peaceful
baby, peaceful delivery.
It’s about loving what you do.
Sometimes a woman is there,
suffering, because she’s alone.
If you go and hold her hand,
look her in the eyes,
that’s enough. Just that’ll
do a world of difference.
And the public health system
is an option for that,
so you have staff who are there,
and if they’re properly trained,
it won’t make much difference
if you get staff A, B or C.
Two fillings. Delicious!
-Wow, she’s devouring it!
-I am not!
Put it in your mouth!
It’s gonna be all right.
Everything fine so far?
-It’s just anxiety.
-But you get that, you can’t help it.
-Anxiety to see his little face.
-How many months are you?
-I’m in the 34th week.
-Almost seven months.
I won’t hold it together.
I’m gonna scream.
How are we gonna renounce to that?
What are we gonna renounce to
in the public health system?
To defend women’s rights?
To proper treatment during childbirth?
To the right of children to be
born with decent treatment?
We have a natural birth center,
100% public health system,
São Sebastião Birth House,
in the Federal District.
It’s a small space,
as cozy as possible.
We have a whole structure to allow
women to have their babies safely.
We want this public health system to work,
that it can happen to all women.
I’m explaining to this gentleman
since the time he got here,
and his wife’s had her baby,
actually, she’s lying in there
calmly, beautifully fulfilling
her role as a mother,
and you are pestering me
ever since you got here.
You wanna go in?
You may go in.
To me, it’s indifferent if you
watch the delivery or not.
It’s the law.
Okay, then, here, take your nice law,
fold it and tuck it somewhere.
Do you want to go in?
I was begging for anesthesia,
they gave me at the end, and I
didn’t feel my daughter being born.
They tore her from me, they took her away,
I think I was separated
from her for three hours.
Black women suffer much
worse verbal insults,
Kristeller maneuvers,
unnecessary touch exams.
Black women are those who
get the least anesthetics,
they get the least information, and
when they go to a public hospital,
they’re gonna hear:
“Oh, you have large hips.”
“You’re a good breeder.”
“You can stand the pain better.”
Come on, kid!
Thank God, everything’s fine.
Stop the drip.
Beautiful!
Rest, Mom, rest.
Crying nicely!
Naming helps us to remove
the invisibility cloak that
covers this phenomenon.
Research shows: Native Brazilian
women suffer less interventions,
they get less food, because there’s
this idea that she’s an animal
and she knows how to have her
baby crouching. So, if she needs
an emergency C-section,
she won’t have access to it.
These are women whose cultural
values aren’t being respected.
These multi-ethnical strata in Brazil,
they’re being completely neglected.
We’re not lunatics or mystics,
it’s the scientists who agree
with all that, actually.
Belo Horizonte’s Perinatal Committee
works with all sorts of partners.
We gather everyone together,
including the private sector,
Sanitary Vigilance,
law councils, health councils,
women’s representatives, Bem Nascer.
A broad invitation and a regular,
representative, diverse agenda
to build a new differential,
a new paradigm.
And Sofia helps a lot with that.
One of the main safeguards
Brazilians have today
of their citizenship
is the public health system.
This is why we have to
struggle with all our strength
to avoid its elimination.
I think the Brazilian
people still have no idea
of what living without a
public health system is.
Three unnecessary C-sections.
It’s my body.
I was cut up three times
and I didn’t want to.
Three times.
I have a documentary crew here…
-Make him be okay!
-He's great!
My love!
Love of my life!
The term appeared in Brazil,
“humanization”.
There was much resistance because
of that name, “humanized”.
The doctors who didn’t understand
this kind of care would say,
“But I am human, I treat women,
I don’t treat cows and bitches.”
I prefer the term “humanist assistance”,
which covers all areas,
not only obstetric assistance.
Health assistance in general.
Ben, you came at a good time to see
The world spinning fast
And life running too far
Ben, I heard that you wanted to talk
Your mom told me you’re something else
And looking at your pictures, I miss you
Ben, one day you’ll grow up
You’ll get tired of toys and playing
You’ll come back with
sadness under your arm
Because teeth decay
And legs grow too long
Ghosts fly
After the light dissolves
But that’s no mystery
No need to cry
Ben, never stop listening
to the records I gave you
Never miss a nice day at the beach
Don’t forget to come visit me, you rascal
Ben, don’t listen to what they’ll say
And don’t hear too many advice
Not even this nonsense I’m telling you now
That teeth decay
And legs grow too long
Ghosts fly
After the light dissolves
People scream
People talk too much
But that’s no mystery
No need to cry
Life is good
When you play too much
When you sing
And you don’t look back
Just don’t forget
That I’m your buddy and I know more
This pain is impossible to explain.
No matter how much you study,
you read, it’s no use,
you have to live it
to know what it’s like, see?
I thought I was so though,
a Marathon runner.
He’s born!
My love! My love, beautiful!
You’re drowning, love?
Please don’t drown.