[CROWD CHEERING]
Hello. Hello!
Hello-ah!
Aloha!
I can do that all night. Hello!
CROWD: Hello!
[WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
[CROWD CHANTING]
Oasis! Oasis!
LETTERBOXD: DBLHQQ
letterboxd.com/DBLHQQ
[CROWD CONTINUES CHANTING]
And finally, it's been called
the rock concert of the decade.
Quarter of a million rock fans
at Knebworth in Hertfordshire
for one of the biggest ever
open air concerts in Britain.
'96 was just the best year.
We had just
the most amazing summer.
It was cool Britannia.
Had films like Trainspotting.
Some fantastic music out there.
Britpop and the Blur
vs. Oasis Battle.
With all that
garbage going on...
Euro '96.
[CROWD CHEERING]
New Labour
was just about to come in.
It was a good feeling
throughout the whole country.
[CROWD CHEERING]
And Oasis were there
in the middle of it.
♪ Tonight
I'm a rock 'n' roll star ♪
Power to the people!
[CROWD CHEERING]
I remember Noel being on
theBreakfast show in May,
and he announced
this massive gig.
"One night at Knebworth,
"tickets go on sale
this Saturday."
It was a pre Twitter,
pre Facebook age
and pre mobile phone age.
I think I saw it maybe
in the newspaper
or music magazine.
I saw it on Ceefax.
Instead of having the Internet,
you have this crappy teletext.
Getting the tickets
was quite a strange one
because it was back in the days
when you're in a queue
in a venue
or calling in.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Everybody knew there was this
one moment to get these tickets.
We arranged to get up at 3:00.
We all coordinated,
how we're going to do it,
different houses,
different phone lines.
We get to Way Ahead Records
in Nottingham.
Saturday morning...
Up crack of dawn.
Secretly went
to my Gran's house.
I remember the queue going up
the side of the street.
Tickets went on sale 9:00 a.m.
You're there ready.
I used my old man's
credit card.
It was a landline phone
attached to the wall.
Sat on the bottom stair.
On the side of the arm chair.
With an old beige BT phone
on my lap.
Dialing up the same number.
The ticket hotline.
Eep, eep, eep.
Engaged constantly.
Calling and calling.
I made the mistake of going out
the night before.
It was painful.
Redial, redial.
Constantly hitting the
orange redial button.
Eep, eep, eep, eep.
Must've pressed it
a thousand times.
It was so frustrating.
Would've been so easy
just to give up.
One of my friends
had this genius idea
of calling the operator
and saying he was struggling
to get through
to a certain number,
gave him the ticket line.
OPERATOR: Hold the line.
Amazingly, they put him
straight through.[CHUCKLES]
I think by half past 10:00,
it was pretty clear
that we're having
a landsliding result.
It was just blowing every box
office record out of the water.
Two million people
tried to get the tickets
to see the band
of the moment, Oasis,
at Knebworth in Hertfordshire.
You pay the guy 22.50,
probably 50 pence booking fee.
Every single ticket we sold
over that weekend
was either sold in person
or sold over the phones.
I think we bought
a couple of tickets each
and that was it. Job done.
Mission accomplished.
[PHONE RINGING]
Five hours later...
I hear the ring.
OPERATOR: Oasis hotline.
I was shaking.
I remember the moment
so clearly.
Got through,
asked for two tickets.
But they were like,
"No, there's none left."
But she says, "We do have
tickets to Knebworth."
And I just automatically said,
"Yeah, that's fine.
I'll take them."
I run downstairs to my dad,
"Where's Knebworth."
I was running up and down
the hallway going,
"Yes, I've got tickets.
I've got tickets."
I was only 14.
Then my parents, they were like,
"You're not going to Knebworth.
"Absolutely not."
Um, and I think
my brother realized
this as well
and he phoned to say,
"I'll take you."
Like, sure,
he wasn't even an Oasis fan.
Finally got through.
The guy on the other end
of the phone was kind enough
to then give me tickets
for both nights.
The first show that
I booked for Oasis
was a room above a pub,
holds 120 people or something.
That was between
March and May 1994.
By August '96,
they were playing
to a quarter
of a million people.
Nobody thought that one day
we'd have sold
ten million albums
and we would be playing
to 250,000 people
over two days.
Anyone that said that they did
believe that is a liar.
I had a reasonable
degree of confidence
that we'd get to two nights,
but I don't think
anybody thought we'd sell
both of them out on the day.
Oasis could have sold
six nights, eight nights.
Who knows?
The best thing that they did
is they only did two nights,
which makes those shows
even more magical.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
We did go and look
at various places
with the band
and their people,
but we went
to Knebworth last.
I remember Noel bubbling up
in his vintage
chocolate brown roller.
You could tell
from the moment he arrived,
he just went, "Yep."
He liked the whole vibe of it,
just the sense of scale,
it dripped with history.
And, you know, he was
hanging out with the Aristos.
INTERVIEWER:
Are you an Oasis fan?
I... I think I might be
by the end of the weekend,
but I don't know their music
very well at the moment.
- So you've not got an...
- I...
I understand that
they are extremely...
What I've heard of them
is it sounds just right
for this sort of big event.
They are very good on stage.
So I'm sure
it will be a terrific success.
And when you hear
the stats afterwards,
it's about 2.7%
of the population
that applied for tickets
and didn't get them.
Then you realize
how lucky you actually were.
They had a brilliant photo
on them.
They were part of the gig,
they were part
of that experience.
It's literally Willy Wonka
and the Golden Ticket.
REPORTER: Hertfordshire police
have orchestrated
a massive operation
codenamed Operation Gold,
to deal with
a massive influx of fans.
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
They were showing that
you didn't have to be
this kind of big, bloated,
enormodome stadium bands.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
You could be an exciting
rock and roll band
and still play at Knebworth,
where Zeppelin had played,
where the Stones had played.
The people
who played Knebworth,
when you look at them,
they tend to fall
into the legends category.
Just take pictures,
don't ask questions,
cheeky bastard.
And for a band like Oasis to,
at that stage of their career,
have the confidence
and the swagger to put
themselves in the same bracket
as the Pink Floyds' and Led
Zeppelins' of this world,
history will
remember it fondly.
[ELECTRONIC GUITAR PLAYING]
It was like a calling
to those Oasis fans.
This kind of special moment
where these working class lads
were gonna go
and do the biggest gig
that's ever been seen
in the UK.
[STRUMMING GUITAR]
It was that moment in history
where you had to be there,
you could taste it.
NOEL: My whole thing
with that group was rehearsing,
rehearsing, rehearsing,
rehearsing.
I want it to be second nature.
I want to do it
without thinking about it.
So I could fucking do it
standing on my head.
And then we could all
enjoy the gig.
I could be...
I could be like a fan.
[ELECTRIC GUITAR PLAYING]
Yeah, we were tight as fuck.
We were a really,
really fucking tight band.
We never did shit gigs.
It's Getting Better, Man!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ Say something
♪ Shout it from the rooftops
Of your head
♪ Even if you
Mean something
♪ Make me understand
Or I'll forget
♪ The people here
On life's beaches
♪ They wish upon the waves
That hide the sand
♪ Let them know that
Life teaches
♪ You to build a castle
In your hand
♪ Maybe the songs
That we sing are wrong
♪ Maybe the dreams
That we dream are gone
♪ Bring it on home
And it won't be long
♪ It's gettin' better man!
♪ Hey! What was that
You said to me?
♪ Just say the word
And I'd be free?
♪ And when the stars
Are shining bright
♪ We're getting better man!
♪ And crashing in upon a wave
♪ It's calling out
Beyond the grave
♪ And we're the fire in the sky
♪ It's gettin' better man!
[MUSIC INTENSIFYING]
Let's stick it up your arse.
[INAUDIBLE]
♪ It's gettin' better man!
[MUSIC STOPS]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
From the start up to Knebworth
the speed it happened
and the scale it got to,
it probably took me five years
before it actually sunk in,
you know?
And I knew Zeppelin
had played it, you know,
and I knew it was
a massive thing to be doing.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
But my initial thoughts on it
when I saw it
as an empty field is like,
"Yeah, it's just a field."
you know, "It's not that big."
REPORTER:
Quarter of a million rock fans
are counting the hours
to Gallagher brothers
take the stage.
Yes, Oasis are playing
Knebworth tomorrow
in what's being called
"the gig of the decade."
I come from Carmathen,
a small town in South Wales.
[CHUCKLES]
So it was four of us
in this small little
white Mini Metro.
It was on its last legs.
Probably about 20 miles in,
I think, the engine
started steaming.
I was like, "Oh, fuckin' hell."
I think the four-hour journey
took us about seven
or eight hours.
♪ I'm free to be whatever I
♪ Whatever I choose
♪ And I'll sing the blues
If I want ♪
MAN: Yeah, take a look.
WOMAN:
That is my birthday present.
It's my birthday today.
INTERVIEWER:
So what day is it now?
Uh, today... Well, it's
still Friday, isn't it?
And you're queuing up
till Sunday?
Yeah.
♪ It always seems to me ♪
Been working
in Pontin's, Blackpool.
Got the train tickets,
travelled down to Knebworth.
Never booked a hotel.
Never got a tent.
We just had a bitsy rucksack,
some class A's and a few beers.
If you're gonna go all in,
you're gonna go all in,
aren't ya?
♪ Get a grip on yourself
It don't cost much
♪ Free to be whatever you
We wanted to go early,
early as possible.
So round about four o'clock
in the morning
we wanted to get
to the front pit.
♪ You're free to be
Wherever you
We brought a big batch of
bin bags and took it with us.
It was a brilliant idea.
We managed to stay dry
and people were coming up,
"I'll give you £5
for a bin bag."
We're like, "No, it's okay.
You can have it."
Or, "here's a beer instead."
Yeah, it was
a great atmosphere.
♪ You only see what people
Want you to see ♪
MAN: Radio 1.
Hi, this is Jo Whiley
welcoming you
to a rather special event
on Radio 1,
the live gig of the year,
if not the decade.
Between now and 10:30,
we'll bring you Oasis
in all their evening glory
from Knebworth Park,
live and exclusive
on Radio One.
♪ Here in my mind... ♪
JO: We had to be up at stupid
o'clock in the morning
to get on the bus
to come in to Birmingham
and get on the train
to Knebworth.
MATT: We're on this old
rust bucket of a coach
that must have only had
three gears...
No toilet, no telly. We're all
drinking, we're singing away.
It was just
a party atmosphere,
the whole way down.
All singing Oasis songs,
all wearing
the bucket hats,
and these were the days where
you can really smoke in buses.
MARTIN: We decided that we'd
drive as close as we could,
parked in a little lay-by,
and then, basically,
walked across the fields.
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING]
IAN: On the morning of the gig,
I found out my girlfriend
of only eight months
at the time was pregnant.
A bit of a shock,
but yes, spent that full day
coming to terms
with the fact I was going to be
a dad, quickly realized as well
it wasn't going to be as lively
as I thought it was going to be
'cause I had a pregnant
girlfriend to look after.
♪ Whatever I choose
♪ And I'll sing the blues
If I want ♪
- Where have you travelled from?
- Buckingham.
Northamptonshire.
Chesterfield.
Has anybody told you
you look like Liam?
A few times, yeah.
[ALL CHEERING]
Where are you from?
[SPEAKING SIMULTANEOUSLY]
Manchester.
We're fucking cockneys,
we are.
We're cockneys, we are.
Soft cockneys.
INTERVIEWER:
Where are you from?
Birmingham.
Doncaster.
Where are you from, Jim?
Well, Africa originally,
but now North Yorkshire.
Manchester.
Manchester!
Where's the toilets?
We need a toilet.
♪ Everybody knows
♪ But now I say nothing...
[CONTINUE SINGING]
We've doing two concerts,
two nights running.
And we've never done 125,000 in,
125,000 out, in, out...
So, a quarter of a million
people over the weekend.
Knebworth itself is not the
easiest of venues to operate.
It's served by a relatively
small small station
and the roads are tiny.
MAN: 40,000 people
had to come by coach.
So all the coaches, when
they came off the main road,
had to go down these tiny,
little winding back roads
that were only enough width
to get one coach through.
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING]
Then you go closer,
and you see that sign to
Radio Supernova,
they had there own radio
channel, and you're like...
This is something different
from going to normal gigs.
It was a mass coming together.
EMMA: And of course,
when you arrived,
being blown away
by the size and scale of it.
MAN: It's like, wow,
this is massive.
I think I was just happy
to be there.
I've got a ticket, I'm here.
Brilliant.
You could feel a vibe
about the place.
Getting closer and closer,
and the buzz was
getting bigger and bigger.
It was a lovely, sunny day.
People singing Oasis songs...
Everyone was on such a high,
and not from the drugs we were
on at the time...
...but just a natural high
and the excitement!
[OASIS SONG PLAYING]
I want to get backstage.
JODIE: The gates opened,
everyone's putting
their tickets through,
they're just ripping them
and giving you the ticket back.
You almost didn't
want to hand it over
when you got to Knebworth,
because they were gonna
tear a bit off it.
Like, don't tear that off.
That's my ticket.
MAN: Everyone
just started running.
And of course, you just
join in, hundreds of us.
The gates open,
and it's like running down
as fast as you can
to the front pen.
WOMAN: That was your mission.
That's the main reason for
queueing up for hours and hours.
One of my mates
went flying on the way.
Excuse me, out the way, coming
through. Mind your backs.
Like a pair of paramedics.
WOMAN: We just grabbed
each other's hands
and we just legged it so fast
down to that stage.
There's all these security
guards in their high-vis
everywhere going,
"Stop running!"
[OASIS SONG PLAYING]
We were just going for it. And
we just got down to pit one.
We got our wristbands
and we ended up in the barrier.
MAN: You know when you've
got that band on,
that's like the Holy Grail.
WOMAN: We were just ambling,
like, mouths gaping.
And then all of a sudden, the
security guard came up to us.
She had blonde hair. She went,
"You two, come with me now."
[OASIS SONG PLAYING]
And she guided us
around the crowd,
put wristbands on us
and took us
right into the mosh pit.
[SONG CONTINUES PLAYING]
And we were on the front
ofThe Independent newspaper.
So we were there on the
barrier, we're at the front.
We can't leave our spot
to go and get food
or go to the toilet.
So we just had to hold on
to our bladders the whole day.
[INAUDIBLE]
The amount of people
just walking around
looking like Liam was amazing.
It was the greatest gathering
of Liam haircuts in the world.
WOMAN: Did you go to bed early
in preparation for this weekend?
MAN: Yeah, well...
So what we done was,
I've got my mates staying
with us from Manchester.
On Thursday night,
we stayed up all night
and had a bit of a pint
because it was the last one
we were gonna have
for the weekend.
But if we hadn't stayed up all
night till about 7:00 a.m.
we wouldn't have been able
to sleep Friday night,
'cause we'd be like,
too nervous.
[ROUND ARE WAY PLAYING]
♪ Round are way
The birds are singing
The sun shines bright
♪ Round are way
The birds are minging
It's all right
♪ Round are way
The birds sing for you
♪ 'Cause they
Already know you
♪ Yeah, they already know you
[MUSIC FADES]
[UP IN THE SKY PLAYING]
♪ Hey you! Up in the sky
♪ Learning to fly
Tell me how high...♪
MAN: I knew the minute
Noel stepped in
with this list of songs
that he'd already written,
once we'd got together,
as a band and sort of,
figured out these songs
and rehearsed them,
there was no doubt, I don't
think, in any of our minds
that it was going
to go somewhere.
[CROWD CHEERING]
NOEL: If somebody
would have said,
in a couple of years' time,
you're going to be playing to
a quarter of a million people
over two nights,
at Knebworth where Led Zeppelin
and Queen had played,
you were going to fly in
by helicopter,
and all these bands
are gonna be supporting you,
I'd have been, like,
come on, really?
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
There's seven of us
on that flight.
And the reason there's
seven of us
is Mark Coyle is on it,
and Phil Smith.
Outside of the band, they were
the two people who were there
at the very, very,
very, very beginning.
Mark Coyle was our
soundman in the boardwalk
and Phil was
one of our roadies.
WOMAN: Who's your favorite
member of the band?
Liam!
[GIGGLING]
Bedroom eyes.
Noel.
Liam I suppose.
Liam.
WOMAN: Why?
Don't know. Just his attitude.
Liam.
Noel.
It's gotta be Noel. Noel.
Liam. Shit, he's so horny.
Liam is the best.
ALL: Liam.
[SPEAKING SIMULTANEOUSLY]
Liam's an utter bastard.
Got to be Guigsy,
playing top string on the bass.
MAN: Well, I suppose Noel.
Noel Gallagher.
It's got to be Noel.
Liam.
Liam! He's lovely!
He's gorgeous.
The biggest blue eyes
you've ever seen.
I love him. I love him!
Noel. 'Cause he's sexy.
WOMAN: Why?
And he's talented
and he's gorgeous
and I want to marry him.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Loads! [ALL LAUGHING]
[CROWD CHANTING]
Oasis! Oasis! Oasis!
MAN: The Bootleg Beatles
came on.
WOMAN: Ocean Color Scene.
Cast, Manic Street Preachers.
MAN: The Chemical Brothers
were on pretty early.
WOMAN: And the Charlatans.
MAN: Their keyboardist
Rob Collins had died
two or three
weeks beforehand.
Obviously,
an immortal performance.
But you could feel it,
like it was pretty, pretty raw.
They were big groups
in themselves.
They might not
sell out Knebworth,
but they were huge
in their own right.
It was pretty special,
actually.
These tickets for £22.50,
you know,
to see Oasis for £22.50
is a bargain.
To get another
five or six bands every day,
I think it was
pretty phenomenal.
With every band that came on,
you could feel the
energy building.
WOMAN: And then,
The Prodigy came on.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
MAN: I wasn't sure
what to expect going in.
The Prodigy,
it's drum and bass, whatever.
You know,
boom, boom, boom.
And then it's like,
fucking hell.
WOMAN: It was like
nothing you've ever seen.
MAN: They nearly
stole the show from Oasis.
They came on and they
absolutely owned it.
You could feel the bass
pumping through you.
They were full force,
it was like volume 11.
I was scared.[LAUGHS]
You know what I mean?
It was like
who the fuck are these people?
They jumped in the crowd
and everything.
It's like, don't come
near me, like.
You're going to
fucking eat me.
The crowd went absolutely wild
for them.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
We were right at the front,
and Keith jumped into the crowd
and literally landed on me
and I was like, who's this man?
Max has got this massive
glove on, it's all steel.
He's got these
crazy contact lenses in.
I'd never seen
anything like it.
The stage was like 20 feet away
from my Winnebago.
I tried... I tried to sleep
through The Prodigy.
Can you believe that?
WOMAN: I just remember it
going into a bit of a lull,
and then you sort of
became aware
that people were starting
to slowly edge forward.
MAN: The energy pulsating
through the crowd
was unbelievable.
Everyone was so excited.
You see the Marshall speakers
come onto the stage.
You see the drum kit come
onto the stage and you're
screaming with excitement.
Just because you've seen that.
The darkness was coming in.
And just the anticipation
you felt it
building, and building,
and building.
WOMAN: It was just electric.
[CROWD SCREAMING]
NOEL: I don't remember
being in the fucking slightest
bit nervous.
It was just kind of...
go on stage, and you know,
each step of the band,
each six months,
got bigger and bigger.
We'd already done arenas.
We'd already done
a couple of stadiums,
like Maine Road, and that was
just the next step.
[CROWD CHEERING]
The build up to it
was just immense.
I still hear that ringing
"Oasis, Oasis!"
[CROWD CHANTING]
Oasis! Oasis! Oasis!
[CLAPPING RHYTHMICALLY]
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
Oasis! Oasis! Oasis!
[AUDIENCE SCREAMING]
But everyone's getting really
pumped up, ready for Oasis,
ready for Noel,
ready for Liam,
Bonehead, Guigs, Whitey.
WOMAN: I thought I was going
to explode with excitement.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
WOMAN: The crowd
just surged forward,
and we were crushed
into the barrier.
You could hardly breathe.
And you didn't really care.
We were at the front of Oasis
playing at Knebworth.
[CROWD CHEERING]
And then this countdown
starts happening. Ten,
nine.
AUDIENCE: Eight, seven,
six, five, four, three, two...
Tom-tom kicks in.
[MIMICKING HARMONICA SOUND]
MARTIN: That sound
just kind of hit you.
[CROWD SCREAMING]
DANIEL: As soon as
you heard that,
then you felt a wave
of anything just come
from the crowd.
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
The crowd would just go nuts.
WOMAN: Your heart's beating.
Any minute now.
MAN 1: This is what it was for.
That's what you've made
the effort for.
MAN 2: It's this build up.
And you kind of love it,
but you also want it to finish
because you want them
to come on stage
as soon as possible.
[GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING]
Oasis! Come on!
[CROWD CHANTING]
All right! All right!
MAN: Then Liam walks out, and
he's got his white jacket on,
and you're like, "Fucking hell.
Let's rock and roll, eh?"
WOMAN: I was in awe.
I was absolute awestruck by it.
I couldn't believe my luck.
MAN: He just kind of
raised his arms.
It felt like God's calling out
to his disciples.
Here's our rock god.
"Yeah, I'm here.
"I'm gonna entertain you.
"I'm gonna kick the fuck out
of Knebworth
for the next two hours."
Columbia comes on, which is
my favorite song, anyway.
It's like,
now we're having it.
Hair starts coming up
on the back of my neck.
I can smell the hot dogs,
taste the beer... Shivers.
Oh, just... man!
Knebworth, mad for it, yeah!
♪ There we were
Now here we are
♪ All this confusion
Nothing's the same to me
♪ There we were
Now here we are
♪ All this confusion
Nothing's the same to me
♪ I can't tell you
The way I feel
♪ Because the way I feel is
Oh, so new to me
♪ I can't tell you
The way I feel
♪ Because the way I feel is
Oh, so new to me
♪ What I heard is not
What I hear
♪ I can see the signs
But they're not very clear
♪ What I heard is not
What I hear
♪ I can see the signs
But they're not very clear
♪ So I can't tell you
The way I feel
♪ Because the way I feel is
Oh, so new to me
♪ I can't tell you
The way I feel
♪ Because the way I feel is
Oh, so new to me
♪ This is confusion
Am I confusing you?
♪ Oh, I slept with you
♪ This is confusion
Am I confusing you?
♪ This is peculiar
We don't want to fool ya'... ♪
MAN 1: They went from
nothing to...
massive in, like a
couple of years.
It was nuts how quick
it went. Nuts.
MAN 2: To be able to go
from playing
as a snarly, rock and roll
band indoors,
to be able now to do it
outdoors to 150,000 people...
Y'all havin' a good day?
You know, it was quite
incredible in that timeframe.
WOMAN: My favorite song ever
Acquiesce was Number two.
When it came on,
I just remember thinking, "Oh!"
[VOCALIZING]
Life couldn't have
got any better.
My eyes are shut, yeah.
Arms are waving, I've got
my boyfriend to my left,
got a lukewarm, semi-flat
plastic beaker
full of lager,
and I'm singing my heart out.
♪ I don't know what it is
That makes me feel alive
♪ I don't know how to wake
The things that sleep inside
♪ I only want to see the light
That shines behind your eyes
♪ There are many things
That I would like to know
♪ And there are many places
That I wish to go
♪ But everything's depending
On the way the wind may blow
♪ Because we need each other
♪ We believe in one another
♪ I know we're going to uncover
♪ What's sleeping in our soul
♪ Because we need each other
♪ We believe in one another
♪ I know we're going to uncover
♪ What's sleeping in our soul
Supersonic!
Everybody in the back,
off your ass.
MAN: It was banger
after banger after banger.
Hundred and twenty-five
thousand people
singing, knowing
every word of every song.
It's euphoric.
Everybody knows the words
to their songs.
So if you're gonna go to the gig
and you're gonna be part of it,
you best sing along.
♪ I need to be myself
♪ I can't be no-one else
♪ I'm feeling supersonic
Give me gin and tonic
♪ You can have it all
But how much do you want it?
♪ You make me laugh
♪ Give me your autograph
♪ Can I ride with you
In your BMW?
♪ You can sail with me
In my yellow submarine
♪ You need to find out
♪ 'Cause no-one's gonna
Tell you what I'm on about
♪ You need to find a way
For what you want to say
♪ But before tomorrow
♪ 'Cause my friend said
He'd take you home
♪ He sits in a corner
All alone
♪ He lives under a waterfall
♪ Nobody can see him
♪ Nobody can ever
Hear him call
Hear him call... ♪
WOMAN: I idolize
Noel Gallagher.
I have since I was
16 years old.
Noel is the man.
I just love him. Yes!
Oasis were us.
They were literally us.
We were them.
The only difference is that
they were on the stage
making music. We were the
guys listening to it.
You could think they were
into the same things I'm into.
I'm into the same things
that they're into.
They're guys
from a council estate.
That's how they make
their money.
That's their job.
They don't think
they're lucky.
They just know
that they're good at their job.
We're in a privileged position
where the crowd
get to see five fellas
at work.
We get to see 100,000
people a night out.
When the crowd
is bouncing like that,
they don't see that,
they feel it, of course.
Bonehead used to be moved
to tears sometimes.
He gets a bit emotional.
[GUITAR SOLO PLAYING]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Thank you very much.
Cigarettes & Alcohol for every
motherfucking one of you.
[CIGARETTES & ALCOHOL
PLAYING]
MAN: It was the '90s,
you know.
It was a lively time,
wasn't it?
I see you all,
let's have it, man. Come on!
The most hedonistic band,
the most hedonistic audience.
It's a good combination
♪ Is it my imagination
♪ Or have I finally found
Something worth living for?
♪ I was looking for some action
♪ But all I found was
Cigarettes and alcohol
♪ You could wait for a lifetime
♪ To spend your days
In the sunshine
♪ You might as well
Do the white line
♪ 'Cause when it comes on top
♪ You gotta make it happen
♪ Is it worth
The aggravation
♪ To find yourself a job
♪ When there's nothing worth
Working for? ♪
Cigarettes & Alcohol.
Saying so what's the point
getting a job
when there's nothing worth
working for?
And that's the way
me and my friends felt.
We'd all been on the dole
for a few years,
and Cigarettes & Alcohol
captured what we were living,
and what it was to be young
and be in that situation.
Oasis sort of said,
be confident about it,
and go and enjoy yourself.
♪ You could wait for a lifetime
To spend your days
In the sunshine
♪ You might as well
Do the white line
♪ 'Cause when it
Comes on top
♪ You gotta make it happen!
♪ You gotta make it...♪
MAN 1: It wasn't really that
testosterone charged environment
that it became later on
in the later gigs,
it was a really good mixture
of boys and girls.
MAN 2: People were just
chatting and chilling out.
It was a proper nice
summer's day,
just relaxing and having fun.
MAN 1: Whoever you spoke to,
wherever they came from
they would have similar stories
about trying to get tickets,
similar stories
about how they got there.
MAN 2: It was just more
of a happy experience.
Everyone was just pleased
to be there, I think.
The whole atmosphere
was amazing.
♪ You gotta, you gotta
You gotta make it
You gotta make it♪
MAN 1: The police
were gobsmacked
how few people were arrested
over the weekend,
like ten people or something.
It was extraordinary.
Northey brought
some of his special
brownie cakes which were
very well received.
WOMAN:
A bit of a Woodstock vibe.
MAN: It really was sort of
peace and love.
It was absolutely
a coming together
of Oasis fans at the biggest
concert in the world.
125,000 people
were there that day.
WOMAN: It was a collection
of people that
were there with a shared love
of this great northern band.
[CROWD CHEERING]
What is it like
riding away,
out there about
50 miles away?
Is it any good?
[CHUCKLES] You with that
snidey fucking hotdog, man!
[STRUMMING GUITAR]
Freak off!
Right about there, man,
you run around like me in a bit
with your fuckin' kecks
around your ears.
MAN: Just walking around
the site, it was incredible
that people were
enjoying the show
quarter of a mile
from the stage.
LIAM: It goes on forever
and ever out there, man.
MAN: And to an extent part
of that was the knowledge that
a lot of thinking had gone in
to try and make sure
that people in the back
got a show.
You want them to be going home
thinking you had
the best time ever
and I think the vast
majority of people did.
The screens were at the time
absolute cutting edge and huge.
There are challenges of
having a field that big,
you know,
time delay being one of them.
They had a screen on stage
and they dubbed it
theWonderwall.
And looking back now
it's rubbish,
but at the time,
it was amazing.
♪ You only see what
People want you to see ♪
INTERVIEWER: If you could
give something to the band,
what would it be?
Make them invisible for a day,
so they can walk around
something like this.
MAN: And see themselves.
Yeah, and see how
today is really good.
It's brought everybody
together, so.
Yeah, I'd make them invisible.
This next one's for
Richard Ashcroft.
Get your shit together.
Fuckin' Wigan, man!
♪ Here's a thought
For every man
♪ Who tries to understand
What is in his hands
♪ What's in his hands
♪ He walks along the open road
Of love and life
♪ Surviving if he can
♪ Bound with all the weight of
All the words he tried to say
♪ Chained to all the places
That he never wished to stay
♪ Bound with all the weight of
All the words he tried to say
♪ As he faced the sun
He cast no shadow
♪ You can take my soul
Don't take my pride
♪ Pride
♪ You can take my soul
Don't take my pride
♪ Pride
♪ When you take my soul
Don't take my pride
♪ Pride
♪ As he faced the sun
He cast no shadow
MAN: Oasis don't do anything.
They just stand there
and play guitars and sing
rather than putting on a show.
They would have
A big light show
and video and whatever else,
but you're still watching
a static show.
They were just playing rock
and roll music
and the music
did the talking for them.
♪ Here's a thought
For every man
♪ Who tries to understand
What is in his hands
♪ What's in his hands
♪ He walks along the open road
Of love and life
♪ Surviving if he can
♪ But only if he can
♪ Bound with all the weight of
All the words he tried to say
♪ Chained to all the places
That he never wished to stay
♪ Bound with all the weight of
All the words he tried to say
♪ As he faced the sun
He cast no shadow
♪ You can take my soul
Don't take my pride
♪ Pride
♪ When you take my soul
Don't take my pride
♪ Pride
♪ When you take my soul
Don't take my pride
♪ Pride
MAN: If you were to sit down
and write a song
knowing what it will become
25 years from now,
you will never finish that song
because it will never be
good enough.
♪ As he faced the sun
He cast no shadow♪
If this is going to be one of
the great songs of the '90s,
then these words
don't make any sense.
What's a Wonderwall?
Who gives a fuck?
♪ Today is gonna be the day
♪ That they're gonna
Throw it back to you
♪ By now you should've
Found out
♪ Realized what you gotta do
♪ I don't believe
That anybody
♪ Feels the way I do
♪ About you now ♪
[CROWD WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
MADDY: It was just such a buzz
to be there, you know,
it was such an atmosphere.
And everything went
really quiet.
LIAM: I tell you what,
this is the quietest
125,000 people
I've ever fuckin' heard.
It's silent out there.
[CROWD CHEERING]
MADDY: And then they started
to play Masterplan.
This one's called
The Masterplan.
It's about being young.
And you're all young, you're
all making history today.
Never forget that.
[PLAYING HARMONICA]
MADDY: The lights just dimmed,
and everything was coming to
you know, almost like a calm.
It was like
in the still of the night
and that song playing,
just this lovely feeling
in the air.
MAN: Noel sitting down there
with the acoustic guitar,
guy on the harmonica
and the strings,
in front of 125,000 people,
just having
everybody captivated
with such
A slow beautiful song.
Everybody just came down
to that level.
♪ Take the time
To make some sense
♪ Of what you want to say
♪ And cast your words away
Upon the waves
WOMAN: I remembered
looking at my brother
and just thinking I'm never
going to forget this moment.
♪ On a ship of hope today
♪ And as they land
Upon the shore ♪
You're young and carefree
and you have no idea
in the world at that age.
♪ Say it loud
And sing it proud today
♪ Dance if you wanna dance
♪ Please brother take a chance
♪ You know they're gonna go
♪ Which way they wanna go
♪ All we know is that
We don't know
♪ How it's gonna be
You hear the words to Masterplan
and you know what they're about
and you don't know what's
gonna happen in life,
you know, take your chances.
♪ We're all part
Of a masterplan ♪
Life's short, enjoy it. That's
exactly what we were doing.
We had no idea at the time
that my brother
was going to be diagnosed with
cancer within six months,
and his life was going
to change so dramatically.
He was so young.
He was just 26,
and he did go on to live
for another few years.
But, you know, things
were never the same.
♪ ...sing it proud today
♪ I'm not saying
Right is wrong
♪ It's up to us to make
♪ The best of all the things
That come our way
♪ Everything that's been
Has passed ♪
It's such a special memory
it's such a precious,
precious memory
because it really was
the last time
we really spent with Eddie,
just enjoying life and
it was amazing that
I got to spend it with him.
♪ Will dance
If they wanna dance
♪ Please brother
Take a chance
♪ You know they're gonna go
♪ Which way they wanna go
♪ All we know is that
We don't know
♪ How it's gonna be
♪ Please brother let it be
♪ Life on the other hand
♪ Won't make you understand
♪ We're all part of
A masterplan
A masterplan ♪
[PLAYING HARMONICA]
[STRUMMING GUITAR]
Thank you very much.
MAN: It beggars belief,
that song was a good song.
It's insane.
Is anyone coming tomorrow?
CROWD: Yes!
Probably a few of you, I know.
MAN: If you could give something
to the band, what would it be?
[LAUGHS]
- WOMAN: Go on, Jane.
- It's far too X-rated.
The pleasure
that they give to us.
Yeah, they give us so much
pleasure for being here.
It's...[LAUGHS]
[LAUGHTER]
WOMAN: At least it's just
on the spot. It's not funny.
You're a few pints too late,
I'm afraid.
MAN: If you could give something
to the band, what would it be?
A night out with us.
I'd like to shag Patsy.
I'm sorry, what was that?
What would you like to give back
to the band?
A lot of love.
[LAUGHTER]
It is about time something
good came out of Britain.
I mean, it's been
going downhill
for the last 20 years or so.
Oasis came out, and they
bring out proper music again.
MAN: What would you give them?
I'd give them me, you know,
then I could just
be with them all the time.
NOEL: I don't have huge
rock star ambitions
that would come after
writingLive Forever.
Then a fuckin' bomb went off,
and that was it.
♪ Maybe...
We were a pretty decent band
the night before
I wroteLive Forever,
but it was Indie music.
The day after I wrote
Live Forever,
we were going to be
the biggest band in the world.
I knew it. I knew enough
about music
and enough about songs
to know that
that wasn't Indie music.
It was a fucking great song.
♪ Maybe I just wanna fly
♪ Wanna live,
I don't wanna die
♪ Maybe I just wanna breathe
♪ Maybe I just don't believe
♪ Maybe you're the same as me
♪ We see things
They'll never see
♪ I said maybe
Don't really wanna know
♪ How your garden grows
For me, always is Live Forever.
If Oasis were my band,
that was my song.
It's just everything, the words,
the melody and then,
the small, sharp guitar solo.
♪ Maybe I will never be
♪ All the things that
I like to be
You buy a guitar
and then you find out
what chordLive Forever was.
♪ Now's the time
To find out why
♪ I think you're the same as me
♪ We see things
They'll never see
♪ You and I are gonna
Live forever
[GUITAR SOLO PLAYING]
♪ Maybe I don't really
Wanna know
♪ How your garden grows
♪ 'Cause I just wanna fly
♪ Lately, did you ever feel
The pain
♪ In the morning rain
As it soaks you to the bone?
♪ Maybe I just wanna fly
Wanna live, I don't wanna die
♪ Maybe I just wanna breathe
Maybe I just don't believe
♪ Maybe you're the same as me
We see things they'll never see
♪ You and I are gonna
Live forever
♪ Gonna live forever
♪ We're gonna live forever
We're gonna live forever
[CROWD CHEERING]
We were not grateful
to anybody for anything.
Oasis was us, you know.
In a sense, it belonged
to the people.
In a bigger sense, in a more
important sense,
it belongs to us, and...
they were there to see us.
We weren't there
to look at them
and that's what separated us
from most bands.
We flip that, "we are
not worthy" on its head,
but we are worthy.
Enjoy it.
[CROWD CHEERING]
LIAM: Good night,
thank you very much.
GARETH: They were at the
height of their powers.
There'd been this journey
that you felt you'd been
on with them.
You know, they've gone from
being a relatively small band,
and then this meteoric rise
over the space of two years.
They always made you feel
like you're part of it.
And it's a bit us and them.
You're with us.
You're with the band
and don't worry about the rest
of the people out there.
So you really did feel,
you know, you're on
that journey with them.
WOMAN: I remember,
taking stock of that moment
and turning back and going,
"Yes, this was awesome!"
MAN: For us,
we got the two tickets,
so we're going, "I'm fucking
seeing that again tomorrow."
[LAUGHING]
That's what we were thinking.
As we were all going over
the empty pint glasses
and the crackling of plastic,
there's this guy, sat in a tree
and he'd obviously been perched
in his own VIP spot to watch
the gig
and we all started chanting,
"Hey, you, up in a tree,
you wanna be me?"
[SHOUTING] Manchester!
Yay!
Fuck, you're brilliant!
If you'd been at gig all day
and you know,
essentially it's in a field
with a fence around it,
and so you've gotta find
your way back to the station
or your coach,
that's a mile away
and obviously it was dark.
It's not the easiest way
to find your way home, is it,
especially after a few drinks?
On the first night,
the police showed me
the surveillance picture
of all of these Oasis fans
decided to walk back
to Stevenage station,
which wasn't a long walk,
but it's a much shorter walk
when you
cut across the high speed
mainline out of King's Cross.
There were a lots of stories
of people
peeing in people's gardens
and falling in ditches
and wherever else.
Uh, we had very few casualties,
considering the levels
of inebriation.
At that point, I could not wait
to get on the coach,
I was exhausted.
I got on the coach,
I fell asleep.
I was asleep, for about
two hours,
and we were still
In the car park.
When I woke up, I thought,
we'd be half way home.
I couldn't believe it.
I was one of the last people
to leave the site
and, and this limo pulled up
and the guy wound the window
down and he said, "Hey, mate!
Do you know how we get out?
Been driving around for hours.
"I can't leave the site."
I said, "Well, I'm going
the way you need to go.
"Can I have a lift?
You know, I'll show you."
And he sort of looked
over his shoulder
and he was clearly asking
someone in the back
and he says, "Yeah, just hop
in the back."
And I jumped in the back
and it was
Kate Moss and Anna Friel.
So, uh, that was a nice way
to a round off my evening.
I went to the Sunday gig.
I'm thinking, right, I'm gonna
go in a day before,
you know, thinking, who's gonna
queue longer than that.
All I had was what I was
wearing and my ticket,
my wallet
and a packet of Shiraz.
It rained and it was cold
and I didn't take no drink
or food or anything with me.
I think it got to about
6:30 in the morning when the,
you know, the lesser bands
started turning up.
It was daylight the next day
when we got home, like
sort of, half past six
in the morning
and every else had gone.
So it was just me
in this deserted town center
with the Sunday
morning sunshine
and yeah, you sort of reflect
on what you've just done.
I had attended the gig
of my lifetime, probably.
And you sort of sat there,
thinking,
"Where do you go from here?
How do you top that?
"How am I ever gonna recapture
that feeling?"
WOMAN: I remember going home,
but feeling very smug.
Sort of flicking my hair,
nonchalantly, behind me,
as I went into sixth form,
going,
"Yeah, yeah, I went to
Knebworth this weekend, yeah.
"What did you do?"
JO: It's Radio 1 live
from Knebworth
and with one of
the stars of the show...
MAN: What do you mean
"one of the stars"?
JO: The star of the show
joins me now.
Just 'cause Liam's not here,
you're allowed to say that,
Noel Gallagher.
MAN: Uh, hello!
How are you?
Uh uh, a bit hung over after
last night, but...
JO: What was it like
last night for you?
MAN: Yeah, it was,
it was, uh it's hard,
it's hard to put into words,
really.
'Cause, I mean,
it's the biggest gig we've...
It's the biggest gig anyone's
ever played at, anywhere,
in England.
JO: This gig that
you're doing tonight,
is gonna be going out to, was it
40 countries around the world
and 500 radio stations?
Will that be going through your
head when you're playing?
MAN: Well, it will now
you've just mentioned it, yeah.
[LAUGHING]
It is mind boggling.
And it's all about us.
We arrived in London,
early afternoon.
It was meant to be like
a day trip.
And there was this little shop,
that had a sign on the window.
They had one ticket left.
And the guy in this shop,
told us,
"Okay, there's a friend of mine
that might have another ticket,
not far from here, so go there.
So, we ran to the other shop
and we went there
and we took the second ticket.
The guy there was, "Okay,
now you have to go
to Knebworth."
Of course, we didn't have
any mobile.
He told us, "Okay, you have to
go to King's Cross,
then take the train
to Stevenage.
You can do it, you can do it,
but, run, run."
In ten minutes,
we found two tickets.
I mean, it was impossible.
JO: And at the gig tonight,
are there any surprises,
anything for people
to look forward to,
that they're gonna hear?
MAN: We had a mate of ours,
playing with us last night,
during Champagne Supernova.
Um...
WOMAN: Any chance that
might happen again?
MAN: Oh, yes, he's
playing tonight.
MAN: I can't, I can't...
JO: Oh? Say no more!
Look, I can't tell you
who it is though, because...
I'll give you a clue though,
he's on the dole at the moment.
So he's there, but he's gotta
go and sign on tomorrow,
so he might have to scarper
quick after the gig.
Me and my brother, we had
Radio 1 on,
listening to the buildup,
and Jo Whiley was on, waiting.
Aerial sellotaped to the wall
for best possible reception.
Blank tapes, brand new,
out of the cellophane.
Brother snuck me a couple of
cans of Stones Bitter.
I was only 15,
my Mom and Dad knew
not to bother me,
when that concert
would come on.
JO: And how are the rest
of the band at the moment?
MAN: Uh, Liam's still in bed.
JO: Is he?
MAN: Well,
he was last seen, well,
the last I...
JO: I hope he gets up soon.
MAN: He was driving
around the site
at about nine o'clock
this morning
off his head with his,
with his, uh, with his fiance.
JO: Oh, yeah?
In a golf buggy, champing, uh
champing some, I don't know...
It was several people's jobs
just to run the VIP Village,
which was a series of huge,
sort of marquee tents.
Well, it was 7,000 on
the guest list, Jesus Christ!
That's bigger than a lot
of venues,
bigger than Brixton Academy.
Ginormous!
I think you could safely say.
Well, I don't think
he went backstage.
Being so close to London,
it was like the scene on tour.
You know, just decamped from
central London for a day
and into a park
in Hertfordshire.
This was a lively time
in British society, you know.
A lot of, there's a lot
of drug taking.
There's a lot of
heavy drinking.
But it was the biggest gig that
ever happened in the UK.
There was a lot of stars there,
but I didn't experience
any undue diva attitude.
[CROWD CHEERING]
There was so much energy
in that field,
all of a sudden,
it was just like, boom!
You see a shoe
go up in the air
and you think, fucking hell,
whose shoe is that?
Somebody started
a food, rubbish fight.
It just erupted.
Everybody's six, seven hours
of food, cans
just got catapulted in the air.
Shoes, bags, sandwiches,
MAN: Black bags.
WOMAN: Plastic cups.
MAN 1: Trousers.
MAN 2: Bottles.
Toilet paper
rolling in the air.
If it could be picked up,
it was thrown.
A tsunami of litter
flying through the air.
A hundred thousand people
throwing shit around.
And it mustn't have been fun
for the people that went
underneath it.
A guy next to us got smashed
in the face by an orange.
MAN 1: I thought was beautiful.
MAN 2: It was amazing.
Whoever started that, please,
be very proud of yourself.
The clouds went grey, got like
a moody feeling in the air,
once you hear The Swamp Song
tape in the deck
ready to record and play.
JO: What's the last thing
you do before you go on stage?
Do you have any kind of
weird ritual, Noel?
NOEL: Usually get, well...
I usually drink a cup
of black coffee,
'cause it opens up the muscles
in the throat, allegedly,
and just pace up and down
a lot
and just shout at people
to hurry up.
Liam could be
quite entertaining tonight.
JO: You think so?
NOEL: I think, yeah, I think...
JO: He was quite
low key last night.
NOEL: Yeah,
he was sober last night.
so he could actually surpass
himself on the,
on the nob-ometer tonight.
The noise was incredible,
they'd not even picked up
a guitar yet.
[CROWD CHEERING]
And then Noel walks out
and he says,
this is history, right here
right now.
This is history.
This is history,
right here right now.
This is history.
I thought it was Knebworth,
what are you on about?
Are we all going for history for
the weekend, to watch Oasis?
This is history, we are part
of his huge, huge thing.
I think that's the first time
I knew
this was something different.
It wasn't just a normal gig.
That's what
it's all about, innit?
That's why you follow a band,
for them moments.
Good evening, planet Earth.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
WOMAN: It was like a dream.
[HELLO PLAYING]
♪ I don't feel as if I know you
♪ You take up all my time
♪ The days are long and
The nights will throw you away
♪ 'Cause the sun don't shine
♪ Nobody ever
Mentions the weather
♪ Can make or break your day
♪ Nobody ever seems to remember
♪ Life is a game so play
♪ We live in the shadows
♪ And we had the chance
And threw it away
♪ And it's never gonna
Be the same
♪ 'Cause the years
Are falling by like the rain
♪ It's never gonna be the same
♪ 'Til the life I knew comes
To my house and says
♪ Hello
♪ There ain't no sense
In feeling lonely
♪ You got no faith in you
♪ But I've got a feeling
You still owe me
♪ So wipe the shit
From your shoes
♪ Nobody ever mentions
The weather
♪ Can make or break your day
♪ Nobody ever seems to remember
♪ Life is a game so play
♪ We live in the shadows
♪ And we had the chance
And threw it away
♪ And it's never gonna
Be the same
♪ 'Cause the years
Are falling by like the rain
♪ It's never gonna be the same
♪ 'Til the life I knew comes
To my house and says ♪
LIAM: Prince Charles is
lying out in the front
next to the guitar.
I won't do, but I've got
no underpants on.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
To all the people
listening on the radio,
bet you wish
you were here right now.
MAN: That recording I made in
Knebworth, I carried everywhere.
I used to know the inter song,
banter that Liam used to do,
off by heart.
Plant pots, coffee table,
sofas, tea pot, get it.
MAN: I wasn't there.
But it was definitely
the most fun I'd had
in my bedroom
at 15 years of age.
LIAM: What?
What?
Some might say...
[MIC STATIC]
WOMAN: I was there
with my best friend,
and we were living our dream.
We were living the best day of
our life together.
We were so... so happy.
[SOME MIGHT SAY PLAYING]
Come on!
♪ Some might say
That sunshine follows thunder
♪ Go and tell it to the man
Who cannot shine
♪ Some might say
That we should never ponder
♪ On our thoughts today
'Cause they hold sway over time
♪ Some might say
We will find a brighter day
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ 'Cause I've been standing
At the station
♪ In need of education
In the rain
♪ You made no preparation
♪ For my reputation once again
♪ The sink is full of fishes
♪ She's got dirty dishes
On the brain
♪ It was overflowing gently
♪ But it's all elementary,
My friends
♪ Some might say
They don't believe in heaven
♪ Go and tell it to
The man who lives in hell
♪ Some might say you get
What you've been given
♪ If you don't get yours
I won't get mine as well
♪ Some might say
We will find a brighter day
♪ Yeah
♪ 'Cause I've been standing
At the station
♪ In need of education
In the rain
♪ You made no preparation
♪ For my reputation once again
♪ The sink is full of fishes
♪ She's got dirty dishes
On the brain
♪ And my dog's been itching
♪ Itching in the kitchen
Once again
This one's for his mom.
♪ Some might say
♪ You know what some might say
♪ Might say, might say
♪ You know what
Some might say ♪
JODIE: We were
on the left hand side
where we see Bonehead
was stood.
We started shouting,
"Bonehead! Bonehead! Bonehead!"
LIAM: Who shouted "Bonehead"?
JODIE: And then people
around us started shouting,
"Bonehead! Bonehead!"
CROWD: Bonehead! Bonehead!
JODIE: And then,
Liam jumps down,
and he walks directly
in front of us.
So close.
And we just started shouting,
"Liam, you wanker!"
[JODIE LAUGHS]
I don't know why we did that.
[ROLL WITH IT PLAYING]
Jump! Jump! Jump! Jump!
PAUL: Crowd reaction was always
that and just that.
It was just everybody
singing every word.
Every gig was like that.
That was the typical
Oasis gig, times ten.
♪ You gotta roll with it
♪ You gotta take your time
♪ You gotta say what you say
♪ Don't let anybody
Get in your way
♪ 'Cause it's all too much
For me to take
♪ Don't ever stand aside
Don't ever be denied
♪ You wanna be who you'd be
If you're coming with me
♪ I think I've got a feeling
I've lost inside
♪ I think I'm gonna take me
Away and hide
♪ I'm thinking of things
That I just can't abide
♪ I know the roads down
Which your life will drive
♪ Will drive
♪ I'll find the key
That lets you slip inside
♪ Slip inside
♪ Kiss the girl,
She's not behind the door
♪ Behind the door
♪ But you know I think
I recognize your face
♪ But I've never
Seen you before
♪ You've gotta roll with it
♪ You've gotta take your time
♪ You gotta say what you say
♪ Don't let anybody
Get in your way
♪ 'Cause it's all too much
For me to take ♪
You know it's all peace.
MAN: You never knew
what he was gonna do,
but anything could happen
and it did,
nine times out of ten.
I used to love that, and I
think the crowd used to love it,
you know, what's Liam
gonna do tonight?
You just didn't know.
Just totally Liam
being Liam, innit?
This is my mam's shades.
MATT: Seeing Noel
and Liam on stage.
And they're giving it
all the really big bollocks
and you see this stuff
in the newspapers
and everything else.
But at the end of the day,
they're just two brothers,
mucking about,
and I stood there
in the crowd, with my brother,
mucking about.
It just makes you feel like,
"That's me and my brother
up on that stage."
This is going out live
throughout the country.
I just have to say fuck, shit,
cunt, tit, bum, arsehole.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Sorry, Mum.
Cheeky little devil.
[SLIDE AWAY PLAYING]
♪ Slide away
And give it all you've got
♪ My today fell in from the top
♪ I dream of you...
MAN: They were so tight
as a band right then,
at the absolute height
of their powers.
I think, Liam's voice was
probably the best it'd been.
♪ Slide in baby,
Together we'll fly
♪ I've tried praying...
MAN: There's a point
in "Slide Away" where
he almost shouts
"Now that you're mine."
♪ Now that you're mine
♪ We'll find a way
MAN: He sings it
with such passion.
It was incredible.
♪ Let me be the one
That shines with you
♪ And in the morning
We don't know what to do
♪ We're two of a kind
♪ We'll find a way
♪ To do what we've done
♪ So let me be the one
Who shines with you
♪ And we can slide away
♪ Slide away
MAN: I guess it's
no coincidence
that that is the band
at its peak,
because the singer's
at his peak,
you know, you're only
as good as your frontman.
Any band,
you know, and is that is
Oasis at its peak, which it is,
it's because Liam's at his peak,
Liam is at his zenith,
with his voice,
and the way that he looks.
♪ I don't know, I don't care
♪ All I know is you can
Take me there
♪ I don't know, I don't care
♪ All I know is you can
Take me there
♪ Take me there, take me there,
♪ All I know is just
Take me there
♪ Take me there, take me there,
♪ What for?
MAN: Liam's probably the
greatest frontman
of his generation.
Noel's probably the greatest
songwriter of his generation.
They're brothers,
kinda came together
almost as an accident,
as a group.
They came at the North,
and they had something to say.
[ALL CHEERING]
♪ All your dreams are made
♪ When you're chained to
The mirror like the razor blade
♪ Today's the day that
All the world will see
♪ Another sunny afternoon
♪ Walking to the sound
Of my favorite tune
♪ Tomorrow never knows what
It doesn't know too soon
♪ Need a little time
To wake up
To wake up, wake up
♪ Need a little time
To wake up
To rest your mind
♪ You know you should
So I guess you might as well
♪ What's the story
Morning glory?
♪ Well
♪ Need a little time
To wake up, wake up
♪ Well
♪ What's the story
Morning glory?
♪ Well
♪ Need a little time
To wake up... ♪
DAN THOMAS: We were lucky enough
to be in the front, both nights,
in the kinda front row.
[CROWD YELLING]
DAN: A bit of banter
back and forth between
the crowd and Liam.
MAN: Liam!
DAN: Just like, "Liam,
give us your tambourine."
What?
DAN: You could see he was
looking and it's just like,
"Don't you worry, mate,
I'll be down there later
and it's yours."
LIAM: Listen, mate, I'll
be down there in a bit.
Don't you worry about it...
DAN: And all your
mates are like,
"it's not fucking happening."
[ALL CHEERING]
[WHOOPING]
You don't know.
Just calm down on the lager.
NOEL: What the fuck was
all that all about?
DAN: And for the rest of
the concert,
I just have to be
transfixed on Liam.
If he caught me looking
at Noel,
he's not gonna give me
the tambourine, is he?
'Cause he's all, "Why the
fuck you looking at him?
I'm the rock n' roll
star here."
Kids will never know
the pressure you're under
to stop that tape, eject it,
turn it over and press
play and record
all within three seconds.
And I was quite good
at that, honestly.
Oh, you twats in the front,
chill out.
I'll be down there in a bit.
I will come and say hello.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Just cool down, man.
Take it fucking easy.
♪ How many special
People change?
♪ How many lives
Are living strange?
♪ Where were you while
We were getting high?
♪ Someday you will find me
♪ Caught beneath
The landslide
♪ In a champagne supernova
In the sky
♪ Slip inside the eye
Of your mind
♪ Don't you know
You might find
♪ A better place to stay
[ALL LAUGHING]
WOMAN: Again, come on. Carry on.
♪ You said the things
That you've seen ♪
Oh, no, I've got it wrong.
[ALL LAUGHING]
NOEL: My songs are inclusive.
They're about us all.
And for that
to become a reality
when you've got
that amount of people
who believe that and singing
those songs and those songs
from their perspective
are about them in their lives.
That's... You couldn't even
dream of that
at the start
of your songwriting journey.
[STRUMS]
It was my time, you know?
And I was so into it.
I was so driven
with the songwriting.
Imagine writing Wonderwall.
And Don't Look Back In Anger
in the same week.
Mad.
[DON'T LOOK BACK
IN ANGERPLAYING]
[ALL CHEERING]
♪ Slip inside the eye
Of your mind
♪ Don't you know
You might find
♪ A better place to play
♪ You said that
You'd never been
♪ But all the things
That you've seen
♪ Slowly fade away
♪ I'm gonna start a revolution
From my bed
♪ 'Cause you said the brains
I had went to my head
♪ Step outside
Summertime's in bloom
♪ Stand up beside
The fireplace
♪ Take that look
From off your face
♪ 'Cause you ain't ever
Gonna burn my heart out
♪ So Sally can wait
♪ She knows it's too late
As we're walking on by
♪ Her soul slides away
♪ But don't look
Back in anger
♪ I heard you say
♪ Take me to the place
Where you go
♪ Where nobody knows
♪ If it's night or day
♪ But you can put
Your life in the hands
♪ Of this rock and roll band
♪ 'Cause we'll never
Throw it all away
♪ I'm gonna start a revolution
From your bed
♪ 'Cause you said the brains
I had went to my head
♪ Step outside
Summertime's in bloom
♪ Stand up beside
The fireplace
♪ Take that look
From off your face
♪ 'Cause you ain't ever
Gonna burn my heart out
[WHISTLES]
♪ So Sally can wait
♪ She knows it's too late
As we're walking on by
♪ Her soul slides away
♪ But don't look
Back in anger
♪ I heard you say
♪ So Sally can wait
♪ She knows it's too late
♪ As she's walking on by
EMMA ALLONBY: It takes you
back to a period where
you went to a festival or a gig
and you were absorbed
in the music.
There was no one holding a phone
or an iPad in front of me.
♪ I heard you say
I don't know, it just seemed
easier to enjoy the gig,
to sort of just
get lost in the moment
and not think about
proving to someone that
you're at somewhere.
You were there because
you wanted to sing those words,
not because you wanted
to post it on Twitter.
♪ But don't look
Back in anger
♪ Don't look back in anger
♪ I heard you say
[ALL CHEERING]
♪ At least not today
See, that now
would be all mobile phones.
And fucking people filming
and texting some other cunt
who's watching it live
on the internet.
Thanks very much.
From then onwards, the world
changed slightly
and it just felt like
a cutting point
between going to gigs
pre-internet and post-internet.
♪ Who the fuck
Are Man United?
Are Man United? ♪
Oasis is a big City fan.
I'm a United fan.
A big boo for Man United.
A really fucking massive big
fuck off boo for Man United.
[CROWD BOOING]
KELVIN BRIERLY: Whole place
was erupting with boos
for all those United fans.
You wouldn't think I'm a United
fan with this accent, would you?
You're a fucking...
A Scouser United fan,
as rare as a unicorn.
There were a few rumors that
John Squire'd possibly been
playing the day before. But
again, pre-mobile phones.
No one knew around us that
that was about to happen.
LIAM: This is John Squire.
He's gonna play us
a couple tunes.
And here's Johnny!
MAN: I was just like "What?"
Is this real? John Squire's
on stage with Oasis.
It wasn't long after he just
split from The Stone Roses.
Nobody could quite believe
it was happening.
John's a United fan.
Give him a big boo
while he's on here.
Big boo. Big boo
for the United fan.
[CROWD BOOING]
Champagne Supernova.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[ CHAMPAGNE SUPERNOVA PLAYING]
Champagne Supernova comes on.
Everyone loves that song.
And we've got this legend of
The Stone Roses playing as well.
The fact that John Squire was
on stage with Oasis was just...
Phew...mind blowing.
♪ How many
Special people change?
♪ How many lives
Are living strange
♪ Where were you
While we were getting high?
♪ Slowly walking
Down the hall
PAUL ARTHURS: Having
John Squire walk on stage,
being on my left hand side
and playing one of our songs
was a bit of a moment
for me, you know...
Probably was my
Knebworth moment, you know.
Had to... Had to play it cool.
You know, "All right, John, how
was it? Yeah, it was good."
But deep down I was just like,
"Aah, fucking yes."
♪ Someday you will find me
♪ Caught beneath
The landslide
♪ In a Champagne Supernova
♪ A Champagne Supernova
In the sky
♪ Wake up the dawn
And ask her why
♪ A dreamer dreams
She never dies?
♪ Wipe that tear away
Now from your eye
♪ Slowly walking
Down the hall
♪ Faster than a cannonball
♪ Where were you while
We were getting high?
♪ Someday you will find me
♪ Caught beneath
The landslide
♪ In a Champagne Supernova
In the sky
♪ Someday you will find me
♪ Caught beneath
The landslide
♪ In a Champagne Supernova
♪ A Champagne Supernova
♪ 'Cause people believe
♪ That they're gonna get away
For the summer
♪ But you and I
We live and die
♪ The world's still spinning
'Round we don't know why
♪ Why? Why? Why? Why?
You couldn't have asked
for a more perfect moment.
Kind of almost like,
the Stone Roses passing
the baton to Oasis.
Uh, no, we...
The baton was not passed.
We took that...
We took that in '94.
♪ How many special
People change?
♪ How many lives
Are living strange?
♪ Where were you while
We were getting high?
♪ Slowly walking
Down the hall
♪ Faster than a cannonball
♪ Where were you while
We were getting for fuck sakes!
♪ Someday you will find me
♪ Caught beneath
The landslide
♪ In a Champagne Supernova
In the sky
♪ Someday you will find me
Caught beneath the landslide
♪ In a Champagne Supernova
A Champagne Supernova
♪ 'Cause people believe
♪ That they're gonna get away
For the summer
♪ But you and I,
We live and die
♪ The world's still
Spinning 'round
♪ We don't know why
♪ Why? Why? Why? Why?
JO KELLY:
I was a complete Liam head.
It was all Liam for me.
And he was, like,
angelic in that white jumper.
I remember him walking
down off the stage,
and walking
in front of the crowd,
and I grabbed his wrist...
And I'm like, "I'm not letting
go for dear life."
I'm not-- I'm not doing it.
I thought I was in love with
Liam Gallagher when I was 20.
And probably was, to be fair.
I had a life size cardboard
cut out of Liam Gallagher
at the top of my stairs.
[INAUDIBLE]
I loved it. I was proud
of being a Liam head.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
MAN: I've got the opening lyrics
to Champagne Supernova
tattooed on my arms.
How many special
people change?
How many lives are
living strange?
It's like a religion to me.
Something about that band
and that group of people.
Together on the stage,
making that music
that Noel had written,
that was untouchable.
Nice one, nice one. Come in,
take easy. Have a good night.
Fucking live forever
every bloody damn one of ya.
Nice one for the support bands
and all that.
Rocky, John Squire,
Oasis and yeah...
Also to the Charlatans,
the Cast and everyone else
who's played with us.
You all know about that. Let's
do it again sometime, yeah?
CROWD: Yeah!
LIAM: I am the Walrus.
[I AM THE WALRUS PLAYING]
♪ I am he as you are he
♪ As you are me
And we are all together
♪ See how they run like pigs
From a gun
♪ See how they fly
I'm crying
♪ Sitting on a corn flake
♪ Waiting for the van to come
♪ Corporation T-shirt,
Stupid bloody Tuesday
♪ Man you've been a naughty boy
You let your face grow long
♪ I am the egg man
They are the egg men
♪ I am the walrus
Goo goo g'joob
♪ Mister City policeman sitting
♪ Pretty little policemen
In a row
♪ See how they fly like
♪ Lucy in the sky
See how they run
♪ I'm crying
♪ Yellow matter custard
♪ Dripping from
A dead dog's eye
♪ Crabalocker fishwife,
Pornographic priestess
♪ Boy, you've been
A naughty girl
♪ You let your knickers down
♪ I am the egg man
They are the egg men
♪ I am the walrus
Goo goo g'joob
♪ Sitting in an English garden
Waiting for the sun
♪ But the sun don't came, sir
♪ I am the egg man
They are the egg men
♪ I am the walrus
♪ Goo goo g'joob,
Goo goo goo g'joob
♪ Expert choking smokers
♪ Don't you think the joker
Laughs at you
♪ See how they smile
♪ Like pigs in a sty,
See how they snide
♪ I'm crying
♪ Semolina Pilchard
Climbing up the Eiffel tower
♪ Elementary penguin
Singing Hare Krishna
♪ Man, you should have seen
Them kicking Edgar Allen Poe
♪ I am the egg man
They are the egg men
♪ I am the walrus
Goo goo g'joob
♪ Goo goo goo g'joob
[MOUTHING]
MAN: Squire's been on,
Champagne Supernova's happened.
Picks up the tambourine,
walks the front of the stage.
It's like he's looking for me.
He's fucking looking for me.
Points to me and it's like,
"This is definitely
happening now."
I don't know how the fuck he
remembered who I was.
And then, yeah, jumps down.
Security everywhere.
It's like fucking Liam
Gallagher is there.
This is actually happening now.
This is gonna happen.
Then he just walks up and
hands me his tambourine.
I was like, "Fuck."[LAUGHS]
And, like, everyone behind was
going, "Let me have it."
And I was like,
"No one else is touching it."
During I am the Walrus, it was
absolutely bottling down.
I didn't know it at the time,
but it felt sort of like
the end of my youth.
The rain was coming to
wash that away,
so it'd give me a clean start.
Four weeks later, after being
on the dole for three years,
I had a job,
a baby on the way.
So it really was a changing
point in my life.
ROMINA: We really did it.
We had to see Oasis.
Everything was magic,
and when fireworks started
with the rain over our face,
I mean, it was like a movie.
JORDAN: It felt like
a thank you to all the fans
for following
them like a big family.
MAN: Everyone's just like
hugging each other
and singing along,
like a big group like friends
that you've never met.
MAN 2: I just felt
so lucky to be there.
It felt like we're part of
history. Making history.
[CROWD CHEERING]
See you later.
So long.
MAN: I still think that
Knebworth is one of the most
important youth events ever.
This was people traveling
to see one band,
not a whole festival.
No one else could
pull that off.
250,000 people for two nights.
They couldn't do it.
They are rock and roll.
That's what it is.
And as a live band,
they set the standard.
It was that communal feeling of
250,000 people over two nights.
All there for...
For one thing: To see Oasis.
Nothing since
has even come close.
The whole day put together
is probably
the best gig you ever
gonna go to.
It transcends any other gig.
MAN 2:
Five lads from Manchester.
The way that they just brought
everybody together
and gave 'em the best night
of their lives.
It's something I'm very proud
to be a part of.
WOMAN: I have some
great memories from the '90s.
But Knebworth
was the '90s memory.
It was...
A time you just felt...
anything was possible.
It was taking that whole era,
just putting it into just
one great day, where...
it was perfect.
MAN: Now sing.
♪ Today is gonna be the day
♪ That they're gonna
Throw it back to you
♪ By now you should've somehow
Realized what you gotta do
♪ I don't believe that anybody
♪ Feels the way
I do about you now
♪ Backbeat,
The word is on the street
♪ That the fire in
Your heart is out
♪ But I'm sure
You've heard It all before
♪ But you never
Really had a doubt
♪ I don't believe that anybody
♪ Feels the way
I do about you now
♪ And all the roads
We have to walk are winding
♪ And all the lights
That light the way are blinding
♪ There are many things
That I would like to say to you
♪ But I don't know how
♪ So maybe...
NOEL: Oasis was the real deal.
There was nothing fake
about or contrived about it.
It was five lads
from two different council
estates in Manchester.
We weren't really great
at anything.
We're more
than the sum of our parts.
And we were honest.
♪ Today is gonna be the day...
LIAM: You know, you can't
bring that amount of people
in that field and have it
still resonate
25 years later if you
weren't the real deal.
People always ask me what
Knebworth was like,
and I'm always saying that I
can't remember much about it.
But watching this film
brought it all back for me.
It was the Woodstock
of the '90s, you know,
the music and the people
coming together.
It was biblical.
I'll never forget it.
♪ There are many things that I
Would like to say to you
♪ But I don't know how
♪ I said maybe
♪ You're gonna be the one
That saves me
♪ And after all
♪ You're my wonderwall
[CROWD CHEERING]
♪ I said maybe
I said maybe
♪ You're gonna be the one
That saves me
That saves me♪
NOEL: Someone said to me we
didn't doRock 'n' Roll Star,
which I find fucking
astonishing, really astonishing.
The songs pick themselves,
but not doingRock 'n' Roll Star
is pretty fuckin' radical,
it's mad, mad.
We would usually start
with it or finish with it.
Trying to be clever, maybe.
♪ I live my life in the city
♪ There's no easy way out
♪ The day's moving
Just too fast for me
♪ I need some
Time in the sunshine
♪ I gotta slow it right down
♪ The day's moving
Just too fast for me
♪ I live my life
For the stars that shine
♪ People say it's just
A waste of time
♪ Then they say
I should feed my head
♪ That to me
Was just a day in bed
♪ I'll take my car
And drive real far
♪ They're not concerned
About the way we are
♪ In my mind my dreams are real
♪ Now we're concerned
About the way I feel
♪ Tonight
I'm a rock 'n' roll star
I'm a rock 'n' roll star ♪
♪ I live my life in the city
♪ And there's no easy way out
♪ The day's moving
Just too fast for me
♪ I need some time
in the sunshine
♪ I've gotta slow it right down
♪ The day's moving
Just too fast for me
♪ I live my life
For the stars that shine
♪ People say it's just
A waste of time
♪ Then they said
I should feed my head
♪ Well that to me was
Just a day in bed
♪ I'll take my car
And drive real far
♪ You're not concerned
About the way we are
♪ In my mind my dreams are real
♪ Now you concerned
About the way I feel
♪ Tonight
I'm a rock 'n' roll star
♪ You're not down with who I am
♪ Look at you now, you're all
in my hands tonight
♪ Tonight
I'm a rock 'n' roll star