How's the sea?
- This is great.
It's really pretty.
Impressive. Those cliffs...
- Look down there! It's scary!
If you fall down
the current will drag you.
Are you recording, Haruko?
Give it to me for a second.
- No, don't.
- I'll film you. I'll film you.
Stand here by me. Our company's
very own diva, Haruko-san!
And Yotchan! Yay!
What a waste being behind
the camera! - It is, isn't it?
Being so pretty!
Wow, it's amazing.
How high!
It's really high!
Yes, but it's beautiful.
It's sparkling!
Wow!
Come and look!
Super scary.
It's scary looking down.
It's beautiful. So blue.
What? What?
August 12, 2005
A random attack incident
occurs in Myogasaki.
Two people die, one person
is seriously injured.
OCCULT
3 years later.
Koji Shiraishi - Director
I began gathering info on the incident
so that it would be remembered.
Stand here by me. Our company's
very own diva, Haruko-san!
What about the people
who were stabed?
I don't know the exact location
where they were but...
HARUKO TOYODA
FILMED THE INCIDENT
When I looked back from there,
in this area, there was a woman...
SHINOBU KURIMURA,
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR
This is the spot where she was stabbed.
Satomi had a dream.
In the dream she was in Myogasaki.
17 YEARS OLD SATOMI YONEHARA
DIED IN THE INCIDENT
In her dream Myogasaki was so
beautiful. She said that was a sign...
SATOMI'S MOTHER
...that something good would
happen if she went to Myogasaki.
Something marvelous.
That's what she said.
I really had the intention of going
there with her but...
...the timing was bad...
...and she seemed to be
in a hurry to do so...
...so she ended up going alone.
I was intending to marry her...
...so I was buying
this apartment for us.
NORIKO MIGITA, 25 YEARS OLD
- DIED IN THE INCIDENT
One night three years ago,
I was with Migi in her apartment.
HIDEKI TANIGUCHI -
WAS ENGAGED TO NORIKO
By Migi, I mean my girlfriend.
That is what I used to call her.
Migi was looking at a magazine
that had a picture of Myogasaki in it.
She was saying,
"Oh, I'd like to go there."
So we talked about it and got
so excited with the idea,
that we went to a rent-a-car
in the middle of the night,
rented one and took off right away.
Before that I was living
with my parents in Osaka.
I was a temporary worker.
Back then,
I thought they might think
I was f***ng nuts,
so I didn't dare say anything.
About a week before the incident
I was laying down at home.
SHOHEI ENO, 30 YEARS OLD -
INJURED IN THE INCIDENT
When I turned on the TV,
a voice spoke to me.
It sounded like ****'s voice,
and told me to go to Myogasaki.
I heard the voice say that.
- What do you mean?
"Go"
"To"
"Myogasaki"
"Go to Myogasaki"
When you say you heard a voice,
couldn't it have been a hallucination?
That's what I thought at first.
But then there was a family
travel show on the TV.
The show was about Myogasaki.
I was surprised when I saw that.
I thought, "There is such a place!
Such a place does exist!"
So I thought something miraculous
would happen if I went.
So you went to Myogasaki
expecting to see that miracle.
Yes.
Were there many
people here that day?
There weren't that many.
We were walking around,
looking at the ocean...
...and then I had to
go to the restroom.
I told her to wait a minute for me
and went to the restroom.
It took me a little while.
I was walking around for a while,
waiting for something to happen.
As I did, I started
to cross the bridge...
and stopped to look at the ocean.
Then I heard a voice behind us.
When I turned around...
I could hear people screaming.
When I looked behind me,
he was stabbing people.
I was scared, terrified.
So I tried to run away.
But my legs would not respond.
I couldn't move my legs.
So I fell forward.
The man tried to run away,
fell and bumped against me.
When I pointed the camera at him
he screamed at me for help.
Help! Help me!
When I didn't see Migi,
I panicked and started running.
I saw her lying down
near the middle of the bridge.
So I ran up to her and...
...I saw that she was bleeding.
I looked backwards and saw that
the man was coming my way.
He came and stabbed and slashed
me in the back, around this area.
Are you alright?
Haruko-san!
Help me!
Somebody, please!
Somebody!
Isn't that the guy?
That's him, isn't it?
Oh, no!
The criminal jumped into the ocean.
His body was never found.
The criminal came all the way up
to this area, right? - Right.
Why didn't you try to run away
having seen what happened?
Well, I guess...
I thought there was something
important that I...
What did you think was
so important at the moment?
What did I...?
I don't know.
If you think about it now,
you don't know.
You see, when we first started
to make this documentary,
I was thinking that there was an
impending importance to doing it...
...but just like you, Toyoda-san,
I don't seem to know
exactly what it is.
Lately, Satomi...
...has been appearing
in my dreams.
In the dreams she is
ringing the doorbell.
I go to open the door for her
and she is standing there.
Then she speaks to me slowly.
What does she say to you?
"A"
"Hi"
"Ra"
"Wa"
"Ma"
It probably means "I'm home".
At least I thought that is
what she was trying to tell me.
I say "welcome back",
and when I do...
Her... her mouth
opens up this big.
Her mouth? - Yes, her
mouth opens up real big.
And she laughs real hard.
Then I laugh along with her.
You see, at that time I really...
I really suffered.
But ever since I've become
able to see her,
I certainly feel at ease.
Wait...
You mean you're able to see
Migita-san as a ghost, right?
No, not as a ghost.
I can actually see her in reality.
Of course, she is dead,
but I have a picture.
A pic...?
Is that like spirit photography
or something?
No.
This picture is from time
when Migi was still alive.
Oh, the young woman
next to you is Migita-san.
This was taken with friends
I went out to drink with.
PICTURE TAKEN ONE MONTH AGO
You mean, that girl over there?
- Yes.
You mean this is Migita-san?
That's right.
There is no doubt, this is Migi.
When he was stabbing me...
...he looked at me and said:
"It's your turn now, okay?"
You clearly heard him say that
while he was attacking you?
Yes. Would you like to see
the scar? - Yes, please.
I was the only one slashed like this.
The rest of the people
were stabbed in the neck.
That is so weird.
Why didn't he kill me?
Why didn't that man kill me?
What a waste being
behind the camera!
The criminal Ken Matsuki -
31 years old at the time of incident
When you think about the time
before the incident,
do you see anything that would
suggest it would turn out like this?
Tatsukichi Matsuki -
Father of Ken Matsuki
You...
...have no idea, then.
What kind of person
was Matsuki at that time?
Futoshi Kondo - high school
classmate of Matsuki
He was a really...
...normal and kind person.
KEN MATSUKI IN HIGH SCHOOL
- He was into supernatural topics.
You know, things like ghosts.
Supernatural abilities, UFO's.
He used to talk a lot
about those kinds of things.
Did you hear him say
he saw a UFO?
Yes, he was pretty forward
about having seen a UFO.
Oh, and how was that?
He said that at night
there was an object shining
outside his room window.
He said it was flying
in a strange angular motion.
At first he seemed to be
seeing this continually.
Right after the incident
Shohei Eno witnessed a UFO, too.
After the attack, I woke up at night
in a room in a hospital.
There was a window and
there were trees outside.
On top of those trees
there was a huge UFO.
You are saying that you saw
an unidentified flying object? -Yes.
I think it was about
30 or 40 meters long.
It was shedding a pale
orange light on me.
It stayed there for a few seconds,
and then disappeared into the sky.
My mother saw it too.
FUMIE ENO - SHOHEI ENO'S MOTHER
- You mean the UFO we saw?
Yes, that's right. The UFO.
I was watching it above me.
As I watched it,
suddenly it disappeared.
We asked if he had any knowledge
about the Eno-san's wound.
Look at this picture. Sorry for
showing you this all of the sudden.
This was on his back.
There is something
that looks a lot like it.
What looks like this?
There was something on Mitsuki's
body that looked exactly like this.
Oh, wait a second!
Your nose is bleeding!
I'm sorry.
Oh, it's okay.
We couldn't question him
any more after this.
I will show you this. Let me know
if it reminds you of anything.
This here...
...is a drawing of a wound
that was inflicted by your son
on the back of Eno-san
with the knife.
It was a large wound.
Well, in his skin,
this part up here...
Ken had a mark
that looked like this.
He had it since he was born.
- Since he was born?
Since he was a child
he used to say:
"God has put his signature...
...on me."
How did your son react to having it?
He was happy about it.
How many of them are spending
the night at manga coffee shops now?
Akira Wakatsuki - Producer
Hmm, I wonder. I didn't check
the number at the time.
But I think they are
roughly about 20.
Excuse me. I'm here with Eno-san.
- Oh, thanks for coming.
We wanted to show him something.
Nice to meet you. I'm Wakatsuki.
- I'm Eno. - It's a bit crowded.
- Oh, hello there.
- Hello. Thanks for being here.
Are you living here?
- No, this is my office.
This is spacious.
There's another room here.
Please sit over here.
This wasn't very far from Shinjuku.
- That's right.
So you live someplace else?
- Yes. Nobody lives in here.
This was taken by a person who
was filming during the incident.
First we showed him
the footage from Myogasaki.
Oh, I remember
hearing that conversation.
What was happening with you there?
There... I was...
I think I had fallen down already.
Help! Help me!
Now you can see the part
where you are being attacked.
In this area in the sky there is
something dark that flies over.
There!
- Oh, my God!
Help! Somebody, please!
Could you please replay it?
This is incredible.
I hadn't seen that thing flying.
This is a picture of Ken Matsuki.
Then we showed him the picture
we got from Ken Matsuki's father.
His father gave us the picture.
Taken when Ken was a child. If you
look here he has a birthmark...
Wait a second!
This looks just like...
- Your scar, yes.
Is this natural?
Ken Matsuki - 8 months
Ken Matsuki - 5 years old
Ken Matsuki - 8 years old
To be honest, in the moment
when he stabbed me,
I thought it was done with God's
guidance, so it didn't matter if I died.
Up until then I was leading
a crappy life anyway.
I don't hate or resent
Matsuki-san. None of that.
Maybe I should be thankful;
maybe he prepared something for me.
From leading a crappy life
to being here.
It's all because of a series
of miracles ever since.
Could you be more specific
about the "series of miracles"?
I'm afraid I cannot talk about that.
- You don't want to talk about it?
But they're a series of good things
and what you would call miracles.
Do you mean phenomena that
are out of the ordinary? -Yes.
It seems that by miracles
he means paranormal phenomena.
- Can you actually see them?
- Yes, they are visible. And beautiful.
However, he never gives details
as to what these "miracles" are.
So, strange things are happening.
What makes you call them "miracles"?
I have a feeling they are.
Anyone would feel that way. And
you can actually see them? - Yes.
And you believe that
they are miracles?
Can those things be filmed?
Captured on camera?
I'm not sure because they tend
to occur in the blink of an eye,
so I don't know if time allows it.
But they happen every day.
You mean that on average
these miraculous things
are happening at least
once every day?
That's right.
Every day they happen once?
Well, lately yes,
it has been like that.
Then if I were to spend
the day filming you,
and something does happen,
the probability of capturing it
on tape should be high.
Yes, I guess it could
be caught on camera.
I began filming Eno-san around the
clock to get the miracle on camera.
Hello. This is Eno, #5418299.
Every evening, he calls to confirm
appointments for temporary jobs.
About the appointment
tomorrow... Oh, I see...
When you reach 30, temporary
jobs become scarce rapidly.
Do you have anything else available
even if it is for a short time?
This is also influenced by downsizing
tendencies of corporations.
I understand.
I will be standing by, then.
Thank you. Goodbye.
I'm on stand by now.
- What is that?
From tomorrow until another term.
Standing by means waiting
for a call to substitute someone.
In case someone doesn't come to
work, I come in as a substitute.
- Oh, you replace that person.
- Yes, a replacement.
Replacement hours are 6 to 9 am.
If no call comes in, there's no work.
Between 6 and 9?
- Yes.
And vacant positions
don't come often, do they?
That's right, most of
the time they don't.
If there's no work, he doesn't get
paid for his part as a replacement.
They don't pay me.
- They don't?! - No.
He gets most of his groceries
from 100 yen shops.
- 100 yen shops are the best.
- Yes, they are cheap.
Would you care to explain
what you're doing?
I look at the grams of weight.
He buys groceries based on whether
they will fill his stomach or not.
He verifies that by
weighing them in his hand.
He doesnt have his own apartment.
He spends nights at a manga cafe.
He is a so called
"internet cafe refugee".
You eat that often, huh?
Yes, this one has
vegetables in it. See?
It has cabbage.
- Is that all it has?
The miracle still doesn't happen.
To get ready for temporary jobs,
he goes to a fast food restaurant.
Excuse me, do you have 100 yen?
- Ah, sure.
I appologize.
It's 6:04.
3 hours later.
In the end, no calls came.
Could they call few minutes after?
- No, they're not calling today.
- What will you do about money?
- It's gonna be a problem.
I bought him some breakfast
to cheer him up.
Mega Muffin combo set, please.
- What will you drink?
- This is good.
- Is it?
Do you at least have the money to
stay at the internet cafe tonight?
No, I don't have it.
Eno-san has completely
ran out of money.
So, what will you do today?
Not much choice.
I still have a little money left.
But I can't go to the
internet cafe all the time.
That was it, right?
Was this the "miracle"?
Did you make this wrapping move
with your mind?
No, I don't have that ability.
You see? I didn't even touch it.
Amazing.
This has been happening to me
all the time. - What do you mean?
It happens to me everyday.
I've been seeing things like UFOs.
After the incident I've seen them
often, but much more lately.
But not only that,
I've seen ghosts too.
I've seen UFOs and ghosts
at the same time.
And I've been hearing
that voice a lot, too.
A voice spoke to me.
I heard the voice say that.
A voice.
Since when have you been
hearing this voice?
Since I left the hospital.
Would you say it's the same voice...
...that you heard before
the incident happened?
Well, I don't understand it now.
- Is it a voice that sounds like ****?
Yes, you could say
it sounds like ****.
He can't understand the voice
he's been hearing since the hospital.
Can I have a cigarette, please?
- Oh, sure.
- Thank you.
This is the camera
we would like you to use.
We asked Eno-san to film
the miracles by himself.
In case you manage to
get something on film,
we will pay you a fee.
Huh? You will pay me?
- We will pay you a fee.
- You mean I can get money?
- Yes. We will pay you.
- Really? Glad to hear that.
- Do your best.
Wow, this sounds like a job.
Is fee in proportion to the times
I catch something on film?
That seems fair, doesn't it?
Well, if director agrees with it,
then I trust his decision.
So, if I record something 3 times,
I can assume it will be divided by 3.
That's right. We will pay you
if you record something.
Should I point it forward mostly?
- Yes, please. - Got it.
Oh, yes, I wanted to ask...
...if you could have me
for a couple of days? - Huh?
- Just for a couple of days.
- For a couple of days?
- I mean letting me stay here.
- Oh, you mean staying here.
Yes, if you could.
That's going to be
a little difficult. - Oh, I see.
We've just met you, so...
The way I see it,
I think he could get a lot...
...and I mean a lot of things
on camera. - Yeah, I know that.
I spent some time with him.
It takes a lot of time just cheering
him up, no matter what we get.
So if you think about it...
...in total... we could get
lots of direct footage,
and it's quite convenient
for all of us.
If we have you filming
for about a week,
do you think that's
enough time to record
a good number of those
miracles you mentioned?
Yes, I think I could get plenty.
- Alright then.
You can stay here for a week.
- Thank you.
We decided to let him stay
for a week and see the results.
You will stay in this room.
- Here you go.
- Oh, thanks.
We'll be leaving soon.
The cigarettes you had...
- You can keep them.
- Thanks.
Thank you very much.
They decided to let me stay in the
office for a week, starting today.
I think soon I can film
some impressive stuff
that ends up being
used in their film.
Of course, this won't last long.
But while it lasts, I'll do my best.
I'm going to sleep now.
I'm calling to confirm
tomorrow's appointment.
Yes.
Oh, thank you very much!
Five times a week.
Oh, for a month? Thank you.
Okay. Goodbye.
They have a job for me.
A temporary job. I'll work
5 times a week for a month.
Yes. Uh...
Anyway, this is good.
I'll give it my best.
Eno-san made a modest party
to celebrate getting a job.
Cheers! - Cheers!
- We're counting on you!
You're quite a drinker.
- Man, really...
It's been a long time
since I had draft beer.
Let's have premium kalbi,
steak, premium beef tripe,
pork gibblets, pork cheek...
- Look at him go!
...yukhoe, and then some
chicken ginseng soup!
If you drink like that
on empty stomach...
Well, we'll eat a lot today, so...
It's really good.
The good thing about manga cafes
is that you can take a shower,
you can use the air conditioner,
and you don't have to spend money
on things like fuel and electricity.
That's good.
- It sounds good.
They also have beverages that you
can drink as much as you like.
What are you doing over there?
You put your fingers together and
circle them around each other.
It supposedly helps brain power.
That's not what I meant.
We are all talking together,
and drinking and you're
keeping to yourself.
I was listening.
So you say, but you're doing something
else on your own. It's weird.
- Sometimes she goes blank.
- It's the same with her interviews.
She doesn't seem to be
doing them wholeheartedly.
Do you think people will
open up to you like that?
Do you think one has to get
emotional to perform an interview?
I don't mean getting emotional.
But it's important to show
you are trying to get close.
So not getting close to someone
is bad? -Damn right, it is.
If I'm doing an interview
and get emotional about it,
the person being interviewed
will not understand why I...
No, no. I'm not talking
just about interviews.
In general you prefer
not to get close to others.
No wonder you can't
get a boyfriend.
You don't have the right
to talk to me like this.
You don't like to hear it,
but that's the way it is.
Come on, let's forget
the whole thing, okay?
But it's wrong.
Forget about it.
I think it's time for me to leave.
I have to get up early.
That's what I dont get about you.
We're here, your bosses are here...
I think you will enjoy your food
more if I'm not here.
No, no, that's not it.
You see, she's running away.
I'm not running away from anything.
I'll see you tomorrow.
What? What is that?
- Here's the skirt steak.
- Thanks. Do you want some?
- Good night.
- What's with her?
Let's just eat.
What a bitch!
Well, when there is no courtesy...
- Courtesy or not, she's a bitch.
Let's eat.
I'm sorry, could I have
a cigarette? - Sure.
Let's forget about all this.
Could we drop the formal speech?
This is an informal situation.
Let's just enjoy ourselves.
What do you say? Drop the san
and call me kun instead.
"Kun" is a more informal version
of the "san" put after names.
Well, I don't know...
Okay, lets do it!
- That's better.
From now on I'll call you Eno-kun.
- Yes, call me Eno-kun.
When things get informal
people start using dialect,
and there are times when I don't
understand what they're saying.
- Are you from the east side?
- No, I'm from Fukuoka.
From Fukuoka? From the west!
That's great!
How about you, chief?
- I'm from Tokyo.
Nah, he's no good.
We're west guys here.
Shiraishi-kun, how about
you drink it all up?
One more draft beer.
Thank you.
"You should carry on a mission."
I've been hearing something
like that from the voice.
What did it say?
A voice spoke to me.
I've heard a voice.
What is the voice that Eno-kun
hears saying to him now?
What did you say
the voice said to you?
You understand it, don't you?
- No, I don't.
You're not a very good liar.
You do understand it.
Well, I'll tell you this.
When Matsuki-san
was stabbing me,
he said something like
"it's your turn now, okay"?
"It's your turn now, okay"?
By that he didn't mean that
he was going to stab me next.
He meant "I am passing
the baton over to you now."
So this wound is the baton
he passed on to me.
It's the baton I received
from Matsuki-san.
Matsuki-san was
performing God's will.
In a strict sense,
it was a divine ceremony.
They never found his body after
he jumped into the sea, right?
That's because he went someplace
else. Into a different dimension.
His body moved into another
dimension? - That's right.
In other words, you say that
the incident was a ceremony...
...through which
Matsuki-san was able to...
...move into God's realm?
- Yes, yes, yes.
Are you going to do
the same thing Matsuki did?
This doesn't have to be
done by killing people.
There are other means.
But I am not ready yet,
so I haven't...
I haven't said that I'm going to
do something like that, yet.
In case you decide that
as part of that ceremony
you are going to kill people,
then you should know
I will have to stop you.
As a friend it is
something I must do.
But it's not coming to
any of that, of course.
You really aren't gonna do that?
- No, I'm not, I'm not.
I was awake.
I was awake at the restaurant, too.
You were pretending to be asleep?
Let's go over there.
I heard everything.
What we talked about during
the dinner? - I heard it all.
He's thinking of murder or something
that has to do with killing.
He's thinking that, isn't he?
I can't say for sure.
- But it's quite possible.
What he said makes
one think it's possible.
The following morning.
I'm leaving.
Eno-kun leaves for work, something
he hasn't done in a long time.
- Take care.
- I will.
Looks cloudy today,
but it might clear up.
I'm going to a place...
...called Kichiouji.
We'll all meet there.
From Shinjuku, I could get there
by taking the Chuo line.
It costs 210 yen.
But if I take the Keio line,
and then... wait, how is it?
I get off at Meidaimae,
then transfer to the
Keio Inokashira line,
and from there I get
to Kichiouji. If I do that,
it will cost me 190 yen. So...
It means I save 20 yen.
I heard that today's gig
will be vinyl packaging.
I was worried
I might smell of alcohol.
I guess I'm fine now.
I'm going into Shinjuku station.
Oh, a police box. They have
no clue what I'm up to.
I have arrived near the meeting
place. This is Kichiouji.
That is where we are meeting.
But these ones have helmets,
they are doing construction work.
They are not from my group.
They meet here and then take off.
Right now it's 7:15.
I was so excited that I came
here a little too early.
Oh, there it is!
I think I just saw a UFO, but...
It seems he just missed a UFO.
Evening
Today's work is over.
When we finished work
we all came back here.
It was such a liberating feeling.
And somehow,
how shall I put it...
It's like the world has
never looked so beautiful.
Even the cloudy weather
today is pretty.
It's like I could
accomplish anything.
I feel that I have
been blessed so much.
It's like I could
accomplish anything...
I arrived at the apartment.
I can't get carried away too much,
so today I chose to eat
this cup ramen here.
Well, I'm finally here.
I wonder if it's still open.
Yup, it is.
- Welcome back.
- Oh, you're still here?
How was work?
It was over before I knew it.
I didn't get anything
on camera today.
There wasn't anything today.
Wow, look at that.
Was that another one
of those miracles?
No doubt it was a miracle.
Nobody touched any of that.
That scared the crap out of me.
Is there a meaning in Matsuki's
birthmark and Eno-kun's scars?
"Ancient Egiptian
Symbol Dictionary"
"The Sumerians"
"Ancient Japanese Characters"
I did a search on the internet.
I researched a little bit,
and I found one particular thing
that really caught my attention.
This is from someone
who is called Watanabe Peko.
She is a manga artist.
I found this picture.
There are some
strange patterns there.
She says they are from
automatic handwriting.
I was surprised by this.
The left side has
Matsuki's birthmark.
It has a very similar shape.
Now, the right side has a pattern
similar to Eno-kun's scars.
I draw a lot of storyboards...
Manga Artist Watanabe Peko
...and preliminary sketches
for the comics in this store.
Sometimes, when I'm tired,
I tend to doze off,
or I end up falling asleep.
And then, immediately after I do,
it's like...
when I'm in that state between
waking up and dozing off,
my hand starts moving.
It's like it's moving on its own,
and it starts
drawing things by itself.
I have them here.
They're in this area.
- These ones here?
So this is what they look like.
When it moves...
...it feels as if it's numb.
So I'm wondering if
it really is moving.
But it keeps on moving...
...and scribbling things on its own.
It's a strange feeling.
- You're not doing it consciously.
- It's called automatic writing.
Have you written this specific
pattern here before?
No, it's the first time.
Does it make you feel something,
or remind you of something
particular when you look at it?
No, not really.
I'm sorry to bring this up but
three years ago in Myogasaki...
Watanabe-san?
Are you alright?
Watanabe-san, are you alright?
What is this?
This is...
There was something
I recognized in that drawing.
Shiraishi's memo from 2005
"Kutoro Rock at Mt. Ohiruyama"
There was something on
the top of the mountain
I climbed on the day
of the incident 3 years ago.
"Mt. Ohiruyama"
"Kutoro Rock"
Kutoro Rock at Mt. Ohiruyama.
Something must be there.
"Mt Ohiruyama"
There.
You can see it there, in the fog.
"Kutoro Rock"
We are facing this side.
- Yes.
Picture was taken on
the opposite side of the rock.
- So we have to go around it?
- Yes. To the other side.
Let's go take a look.
Oh, that's right.
If you look at it from there...
it's the same.
Three years ago
I went climbing by myself,
and came all the way up here.
I visited places like this during
my mountain climbing trips.
I knew about reports of a, uh...
a rock with a fascinating shape,
so I thought I should climb and see.
When I reached the top at that time,
I noticed something bizarre.
When I reached the top, I felt
something strange on my left leg.
On this leg
there were 9 leeches,
attached to my leg,
all side by side.
It was scary.
I pulled them all off.
"9 leeches"
"9"
"Kutoro" loosely translated means
The Rock of the 9 Headed Spine.
Careful there.
There are some things
like white spots.
There's a hole in here!
Look at that!
Look!
My leg hurts.
- Your leg?
Blood was flowing from the spot
where leeches were once attached.
I am part of a production staff
making a documentary.
Do you have anyone
who has been investigating
writings on a petrogliph
related to Mt. Ohiruyama?
TOURISM DEPARTMENT OF OHIRU
- Yes, we have one person.
But I'm afraid this person
is not a scholar or anything.
He is a horror movie director.
His name is Kioshi Kurosawa.
- I see. Kioshi Kurosawa?
- Yes.
How long have you been
investigating Mt. Ohiruyama?
KIOSHI KUROSAWA
- It's been quite some time.
I suppose I began at the same
time I started making movies.
Kurosawa-san is an autodidact
who investigates historic ruins.
I've learned about Ohiruyama
on my own because I'm fond of it.
Mt. Ohiruyama has been his object
of study for more than 20 years.
He still investigates
there when time allows.
...and sometimes I do
investigations about it alone.
At the top of Mt. Ohiruyama
there is a lot of rocky areas.
Many ancient characters
can be found there.
Characters such as these
are written there.
There are many distinctive
hieroglyphs and ideographs.
Here I have written particular
meanings for each and every one.
I'm still making efforts...
...until I thoroughly
understand all of its contents.
These are all things that you have
come to learn by yourself?
Yes, but they are still in need
of further investigation.
I hear that Mt. Ohiruyama is
a sacred ceremonial site. - Yes.
What kind of deity
is worshipped there?
In a word: Hiruko.
Hiruko (literally "Leech child")
There are many places
where specific gods have been
worshipped for a long time.
Now, Hiruko is a deity that
appears in Japanese mythology.
I'm sure you've heard of
gods Izanami and Izanagi.
The gods that created
Japanese islands.
The first son that was
born of these two gods...
...was called Hiruko.
The story goes that he was
born without any limbs.
He was a crippled, deformed child.
He had no arms or legs,
so he had the form of a leech.
Mt. Ohiruyama takes its name
after Hiru, which means leech.
A-hi-ra-wa-ma
Ohiruyama
The Mountain of the Leech
When we climbed to the top
of Mt. Ohiruyama the other day,
we discovered something that
really caught our attention.
We asked for his opinion on the
figure carved out of the stone.
We brought a picture of it in case
you knew something about it.
We found a stone like this.
Where was this found?
There is an area on
the far side of Kutoro Rock,
that is hidden and can't be seen.
This is really impressive.
I didn't know about this.
Do you have any idea
what could it mean?
Let's see. On the left side...
...we have something like this.
This is called an oracle.
It means divine affairs,
or when a god gives his orders.
This thing here is "sessho"
concept of Buddhism.
It has the meaning
of killing living things.
So, a person gets killed
through god's oracle.
That's what I believe it means.
On the right side
we have the same thing.
This has the same meaning
as it did before.
The oracle of god's orders.
However, this here...
...probably means some
sort of great calamity.
It could be a natural disaster or
something involving human action.
We can say it is a great disaster
that stems directly from here.
A great calamity
that was ordered by god.
I believe that's the meaning.
Later on, Kurosawa-san
went up to Kutoro Rock,
but he said he was unable
to find the hole or the stone.
Production staff came to the office
while Eno-kun was out working.
He's not here.
Can I open it?
We'll search his bag to find out
contents of Eno-kun's "ceremony".
There's something here.
There are several things inside.
He has a lot of money.
There's 700,000 yen in his account.
(Aproximately $8,600 USD)
He can rent an apartment
with 700,000.
So he's making
how much in a month?
He hasn't whithdrawn any money?
- No.
It looks like he's been
preparing for something.
Preparing for what?
Perhaps something
like a mass murder?
Eno-kun is recording after
everyone left today's work.
You, come here.
What's your name? - Eno.
Group leader had
his eye on Eno-kun.
Get your shit together and
start doing your job well.
- I am doing my job well.
- What do you mean doing it well?
If I'm telling you to do it well,
it's fucking obvious that you're not.
You know very well we are falling
behind and it's all because of you.
What are you talking about?
Don't come tomorrow.
I am coming to work tomorrow.
I have been doing my job well.
If you come, you know what's up.
In my head I see him
getting hit by a car soon.
Must be a premonition or something.
But there's no way in hell
I'm letting that fucker
know about it.
Look at that thing
on top of him. Creepy!
What the...?
I could not have done that.
But I knew it was going to happen.
I haven't done anything bad.
I feel something here,
in this area.
I'll see if I can get
something on camera.
There's something
strange in this area.
There, there!
It can be seen clearly!
Whoa, what the...?
It disappeared.
Did you see that, Shiraishi-kun?
That was really something, eh?
I'm here in a shoping area, waiting.
I'll try and look around this area.
Whoa, there they are!
Look at that!
How about it, Shiraishi-kun?
There are so many!
This is great!
There are several.
People don't even notice
but there are many of those.
That was amazing.
Whoa, that's huge!
Did you see that,
Shiraishi-kun? Amazing!
Amazing!
Eno-kun's footage
left us speechless.
- That is...
- Impressive?
Yes, impressive. What happened
to the guy who was hit by the car?
Is he alright?
I don't know what
happened to him afterwards.
I saw an ambulance coming.
- You had a premonition, right?
- That's right, I did.
- You didn't cause any of this?
- No, I don't have that ability.
There was something strange
hovering over his head.
What was that?
I've never seen
those shapes before.
It's a new type of phenomenon?
- Yeah, it's a new type.
But you saw it's real.
- That's right.
It's no big deal, but it
surprised you, didn't it?
Well... yes.
So how about it? - Huh?
How about "it"?
- The fee?
- Yes.
Of course I'm gonna pay you.
You took all this in one evening?
Yes, all in one evening.
Since it took you several hours,
I will pay for those. - Really?
Do you have an envelope?
Don't worry about that.
No need to be formal.
I'm happy just receiving the money.
Did you make a receipt?
Please write in 23,000 yen.
Oh, am I getting that much?
The voice that was
talking to you before,
the one you didn't understand,
was it alerting you to any of this?
No, because I don't
understand what it says.
Can I really keep this?
- It's fine, it's fine.
Since you've gone through the trouble,
I'll treat you to Korean barbecue.
All of us, let's go.
I can't make it today.
I have other plans.
Don't tell me you have a date.
Really, I have other plans.
I already ate. Sorry.
Is it okay if I go with you?
- You're coming?
- Yes, the two of us.
Sure. After all, I got this
money because of you.
This is my chance to get Eno-kun
to talk about his ceremony.
When I saw today's footage,
I was truly able
to believe everything.
Eno-kun, I don't know what
kind of ceremony will take place.
Even if what you're
going to do is something...
...very antisocial or
even if you are going to...
Even if it's something
like Matsuki-san did,
I'm thinking that I would
like to cooperate with you.
Do you really mean it?
Of course, I really mean it.
I really do.
In short, with this production,
with this movie I'm making,
you can see how many things
have become connected.
Once it's completed, I think
it can show a lot of people
that this world beyond ours
really does exist.
I thought that was the order
that was given to me.
I see. I understand that.
Then, finally,
Eno-kun began to talk.
The truth is that
after the incident,
I was hearing a voice.
I told you that I couldn't
understand what it was saying.
But I could understand it.
- I knew it!
That voice that sounded
like **** was saying...
What was it saying?
It said: "a suicide bombing
massacre at the Shibuya station."
Suicide bombing?
Don't shout like that,
people are gonna hear you.
A suicide bombing massacre
at the Shibuya Station
This is my order.
Just as it was with Matsuki.
Remember, he jumped into the sea
and went into another dimension.
It will be the same with me.
Even if I become a suicide
bomber, I will not die.
I won't die, but rather...
go into the other dimension
through the bomb.
So when the bomb goes off,
at that same moment
your body will go into that
other world without harm?
Yes, into the other world. People
around me will be able to go, too.
God's people will be able to go.
Matsuki was a chosen person.
I am a chosen person.
And I'm thinking that
you are chosen as well.
The point is that
as a chosen person,
I must obey that command.
I must apologize to you cause you
let me stay in your office and all...
but I've been saving money for this,
and I have about 700,000 yen now.
You managed to save this
little by little? - Yes, I did.
Now I have enough funds to
walk into the Shibuya station
during the rush hour,
and then boom!
- Will you make the bomb?
- Yeah, I'll make the bomb.
I've been studying
how to make one.
When will you do it?
I thought I'd need more money,
but ever since I met you,
since you're willing to help
and you can film all of it,
maybe now it's time to do it.
Can I eat the last one?
It will go well.
So, you will go to Shibuya...
Eno-kun will blow himself up
along with the people around him.
That is your ceremony?
Yes, that's it.
You know, when I told you
I will cooperate with you?
It was a lie.
I lied to you. - Why?
I lied in order to get
the truth out of you.
You tricked me?
Did you trick me?
I thought you were my friend.
Why would you do that?
As a friend,
I can't let you do that.
I don't want you
to become a murderer.
But I won't be a murderer!
We'll all go to the other world.
You can go over to
the other world if you wish.
But isn't it wrong
to drag along other people...
...who don't want to go?
You're not being my friend.
And those people... they're
not going to die, either.
Even if you say they won't die,
isn't it wrong to take them
with you if they don't wanna go?
You see, this has nothing
to do with dying.
They'll be able to go beyond
to heaven, to god's world.
But you're still imposing
your will on those people.
I told you already.
It's not my will.
They won't know
unless they go there.
Once you get there, what if
it's not what you thing it will be?
That world is much better
than this one.
This world is just shit, isn't it?
Shiraishi-kun, if you try to stop me
you will recieve a punishment.
Something will happen
to you, for sure.
- By whom? God?
- Yes, God will punish you.
I have to tell the rest
of the staff about this.
Do what you want. Tell them.
But something will happen.
Shiraishi-kun, are you leaving?
- I'm not going anywhere.
Something will happen.
Come on! I promise you
that nothing's gonna happen.
Something will happen. Please,
God, make something happen.
God doesn't sympathize
with your feelings, Eno-kun.
Nothing has happened, Eno-kun,
not even a glass has moved.
Shiraishi-kun, that doesn't mean
it will stay this way.
Something will happen.
- Eno-kun?
- Why?
You traitor! You liar!
I know, I know.
What's with you? I told you
everything because I trusted you.
But you... you're so cruel.
I know, I know.
Okay?
Wait!
Shiraishi-kun, a miracle happened.
You know what your mission is.
I don't know for sure, but...
...you too must have
god's mark on you.
My leg. My leg.
See? Just as I thought.
You understand what is
your mission, don't you?
Your mission is to film and
keep a record of everything.
You are to present that
to the world.
Come.
Shiraishi-kun!
And so, I decided to leave a record
of Eno-kun's ceremony.
In order to increase the damage
the bomb will cause,
he buys lots of nails and screws.
He buys chemicals and raw
materials to make a gunpowder.
It's super heavy.
Carrying this I realize that
bombing belt will be very heavy.
That's right.
Like carrying a burden.
Camera will be even heavier.
You! Tell me what are you
carrying there?
It's hell!
I know what's up!
Stop, please!
It's inhuman!
You think yourself a hero?
Are you going...?
Please, stop this!
It's hell!
Why was he trying to take it?
I don't know.
- Does it hurt?
- Yes.
This world is full of...
...fucking loonies.
They're all piled like
a rucksack or a backpack.
I'll try and wear it.
Shiraishi-kun, help me.
You know, like wives helping
their husbands to put on a shirt.
Oh, I see. I can also help you
when we arrive at the location.
Okay.
This is heavy.
Do I pick it up like this,
or from under it?
Pick it up like it is.
Here I go.
Bend a little.
- Does it suit me?
- It does. You look cool.
- Very heroic.
- Really?
Can I borrow a video camera?
I want to bring a camera with me.
I might be able to film
something from the other side.
If I'm able to film something,
I'll send it over to you.
Wait...
Yes? Who is it?
It's Shinobu.
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait a second!
I'm sorry. Just a second.
Oh, you forgot something?
What did you forget?
Oh, your digital camera?
It must be here somewhere.
Wait a second.
There's still white powder here.
Can I come in?
Yes, yes! I'm sorry!
I forgot how to...
You can come in now.
- Was it so difficult?
I'm sorry, I was turning
the key the wrong way.
Weren't you filming outside today?
No.
- Is Eno-san here?
- Today he had the day off.
I was taping his
regular day here and...
Did something happen here? -No.
And what is that?
I made a bed out of
a cardboard box.
I think this camera will do.
Is the battery charged?
Yep, it is.
You seemed very busy.
My day...
Eno-kun had the day off,
so I thought that maybe
he would be lazing around and...
Have you seen any video
tapes lying around here?
No, that's...
- Those are not tapes!
- No, this is not it.
Anyway, I just came
to get my stuff.
Keep up the hard work.
- Thanks.
I'm sorry I spilled the powder.
- You did spill a lot. Look at that.
That looks weird however
you look at it. - Indeed.
I didn't know
how to wipe it properly.
What's this?
Look at this mess!
- Sorry, I couldn't help it.
Man, that sucked! Kuribayashi
coming here all of the sudden.
Look, the switch is hanging.
- Man, yeah it does!
- That's not funny.
I know I shouldn't laugh,
but look at that switch.
It was hanging there in plain view!
You can't help but laugh.
But it's over so don't worry.
It's the morning of
the ceremony execution.
Eno-kun and me spent
the night drinking in Shibuya.
Man, at last!
11 hours and 18 minutes
until the ceremony
- Eno-kun, look at that!
- They are coming our way!
That's amazing, Shiraishi-kun!
They're a bunch!
Wow, they are all coming our way!
- They are coming this way.
- Wow, they're coming.
They are coming towards me.
They're all coming our way.
Why are there so many?
They come this way.
Shiraishi-kun, they are
coming in bunches.
They're all coming our way.
They're all coming in a bunch.
Wow, Shiraishi-kun, they're a lot.
We get breakfast at
a gyuudon chain restaurant.
11 hours and 2 minutes
before the ceremony
He avoids beef out of fear
of the mad cow disease.
We came back to the office
to catch some sleep.
6 hours and 30 minutes
before the ceremony
Can we get a taxi?
5 hours and 13 minutes
before the ceremony
To Shibuya, please.
- Any place in particular?
- Near the train station.
Taxi drivers aren't making
that much money.
Like 3 or 5 million yen.
(36.000 - 61.000 $)
- Annual income?
- Yes. No good at all.
A lot of people are going through
Shibuya Station. - That's right.
It would be terrible if a terrorist
attack was to happen there.
I guess it would.
- Is it right?
- What?
This now.
It is right.
- Are we wrong?
- No, we're not wrong at all.
Thank you very much.
- Where are we going?
- I know a good restaurant.
4 hours and 6 minutes
until the ceremony
- Indian cuisine?
- Yes, I go there sometimes.
I've never tried Indian food.
I recommended that
we have Indian curry.
- Is this it?
- Yes.
All you can eat for 1500 yen.
That's cheap! Shall we?
This is good.
Indian curry is great.
Speaking of India...
...remember Indiana Jones?
- Indiana Jones?
His name has something to do
with India? - India... Indiana...
I think his name comes
from the State of Indiana.
Actually, they are showing a new
movie about him. - Are they?
Didn't you know?
It's one where Indy...
Let's go see it.
I'm a big fan of Indy.
- Really?
- I really like him.
We have to go to Kabukicho
to see the movie.
This is it.
- Wasn't she in "Raiders"?
- She's in this one, too.
3 hours and 39 minutes
before the ceremony
I'll buy the tickets.
- Oh, really?
You've been paying for
everything else until now.
We have enough time.
AFTER THE MOVIE
- It's amazing.
If you hadn't suggested that
we go to the Indian restaurant,
I wouldn't have remembered.
It's all connected, you know.
When I watched it
and saw what was in it,
it made me think that
this absolutely has a meaning.
This is a miracle, too.
- What, the timing?
Of course! You see, the movies
content was already decided,
but through it...
how shall I put it,
through **** I'm pushed
forward to what has to be done.
Really, I'd love to watch it again.
But time doesn't allow it.
- Can't you postpone it a day?
No, I can't.
If I hadn't seen the movie,
I might have thought so, but...
48 minutes before the ceremony
So, shall we go?
Shibuya
25 minutes before the ceremony
6 minutes before the ceremony
I'm going the next time
traffic lights change.
I'll start recording now.
It's recording.
Shiraishi-kun, I never paid you back
100 yen I borrowed from you.
- What 100 yen?
- At the internet café.
I borrowed 100 yen from you.
- Oh, that time in the beginning.
I'll give them back.
Excuse me, do you have 100 yen?
- Ah, sure.
I appologize.
It's a little late, but here you are.
- Well, I tell you what...
You take those 100 yen
along with the camera,
and send them both to me
from the other side.
It will be more fun that way.
It's a deal.
I'm not sure if this will go well.
1 minute before the ceremony
The lights changed.
Thanks for everything.
Shiraishi-san, I've been
following two of you all day.
What have you been doing?
Would you care to explain?
I don't understand any of this!
He's gonna do something, isn't he?
- Get in here!
- Don't you touch me!
What are you planning to do?
I'm gonna call the police.
Don't stand there!
It's dangerous! Get in here!
- I'm calling them.
- Get in here! It's dangerous.
Hello? Is this the police?
I'm calling from Shibuya Station.
The bombing in front of
the Shibuya train station
left 108 people dead
and 245 people wounded.
The remains of Eno-kun
were never found.
I was convicted of complicity.
21 years later
- Hello.
- It's been a long time.
Hello. We finally meet again.
Thank you very much. Cheers!
- Cheers!
Let's cook these.
This redbush tea is very good.
- It is, isn't it?
Nowadays when you order tea
in bars and restaurants,
instead of oolong,
they serve you redbush tea.
So, oolong tea isn't served often?
No, lately it's not served at all.
- This place is good, isn't it?
- This is really good.
It's been ages. Do people
still use that expression?
- Yes, they still do.
- Oh, they do?
- Yes, occasionally.
- Oh, so it has survived?
This place is relaxing.
It hasn't changed much.
It hasn't changed, but...
it will stop serving this month.
They're closing it down.
Oh, is that so?
So I barely made it, eh?
Yes. Well...
The beef imported from the U.S.
was infected with mad cow disease,
and 100,000 people died in Japan.
What... are you serious?
100.000? That's incredible.
So many barbecue restaurants
closed down.
We pray for the souls of those
murdered in Myogasaki and Shibuya.
- That's really sad.
- It is.
My leg!
My leg is bleeding.
What is this?
What?!
Oh, no!
This...
...is the camera that Eno-kun
was carrying at that time.
And this...?
It's a 100 yen coin.
It's an old coin. They don't
issue those anymore.
He remembered.
Shiraishi-kun, I never paid you back
100 yen I borrowed from you.
It's a little late, but here you are.
- Well, I tell you what...
You take those 100 yen
along with the camera,
and send them both to me
from the other side.
It will be more fun that way.
It's a deal.
Thanks for everything.
"It's hell!"
Shiraishi-kun!
Help me!
Translation Montecristo
Transcript AP