In our obsession
with antagonisms of the moment,
we often forget how much unites
all the members of humanity.
Perhaps, we need some
outside universal threat
to make us recognize
this common bond.
I occasionally think how quickly our
differences worldwide would vanish
if we were facing an alien
threat from outside this world.
And yet I ask you,
is not an alien force
already among us?
What could be more alien
to the universal aspirations
of our peoples than war,
and the threat of war?
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Oi, Matt, what's going on?
Shit.
Good day, Arnold.
How are we?
Uh, take a wild guess.
How long?
Well, like I tell you every day,
when I know, you'll know.
- Got any smokes?
- No, mate, I don't. This is ridiculous.
- You know, I've lived here for 50...
- Fifty-five years.
Don't be a... take that bloody
tone of voice with me, boy.
Fifty-five years, and I'll be damned if
I see the point of this bypass, really.
It's progress,
Arnold, progress.
Oh, progress my ass.
I've got fruit in the back
that's about to go bad. I've been sitting
here for 42 bloody minutes, mate.
- It's 2:45.
- All right. Look, I'll...
I'll talk
to my supervisor, okay?
- Yeah, you do that.
- Jesus Christ.
Jimmy, can you take over, mate?
Gotta head off.
Well... Well, Arnold's
giving away free fruit.
Yeah, right, aye.
Hey, does Boss know you're
knocking off?
Only if you tell him.
Tonight. Don't be late.
Good day, Arnold.
Uh, mangoes.
- Mangoes?
- Yeah.
They're out of season,
you idiot.
Who put you in charge? No wonder this
bypass is taking so bloody long.
Now, listen,
I've lived here for 55 years.
- Yeah, it, it... what it is...
- Get away from me.
They build a road and it...
Get back to work,
you mongrel bastard!
What are you
doing off work?
Well, unlike last week,
your sister wanted me
to make sure you
get there on time.
- Last week wasn't my fault.
- Mm-hmm.
Besides, you ever tried
saying no to Amelia?
I'm her brother.
Of course I've said no.
You, on the other hand,
are screwed.
I wasn't gonna say anything,
mate, because she's your sister,
but she does this thing with her
legs, they go, like, right...
Oh, that...
bad mental pictures.
That's what you get, kid.
Pass me the aspirin,
will you?
You playing tonight?
Serious?
Apparently. Pass one.
Come on, come on.
Yeah. Finally get
to see the big man work.
Relax, will you?
- Yo.
- What?
- We've stopped.
- Why?
- To stretch our legs.
- No thanks.
I'm good.
- Fine, Peter.
- Thanks, Bella.
Come on, Samuel.
Give me that. A bit
of real world won't kill you.
Let it go.
- Two bucks, mate?
- Do you know where we are?
- Yes.
- Bella.
- What's with this stupid town?
- I don't know, darling.
We'll have a look around
and we'll find out, okay?
Fine.
I'll meet you back here.
Careful, Bella.
Dinner, back here 6:00.
- Yeah.
- And I don't want any dramas.
Mom, it's a country town.
What's gonna happen?
Thanks, mate.
Let it go.
Hey, guys, it's me.
Thought I'd do a vlog,
considering we've landed
in a parallel universe.
I think this town
still thinks it's 1996.
Probably all use landlines
and all have the same cousin.
That's... that's mean.
- Anyway.
- Do you want me to film for you?
- No, thanks.
- I could do your sketch.
- I do sketches.
- This all seems legit and not at all creepy.
Well, you can't blame a guy for
trying to make an honest living.
- You here on holidays?
- Uh, something like that.
Just passing through, seeing what the locals
do on a Friday night in the middle of nowhere.
- Well, this is it.
- Yeah.
Wow, these are really good.
It's okay.
- Dennis.
- Shit. Yeah, I'm going.
I doubt you've got
a permit for a stall. Come on.
- We were just talking, officer.
- Yeah, well, Dennis knows the rules.
I said I'm going.
- It was nice talking to you.
- Yeah.
Come on, move it.
Keep walking, Dennis.
Uh-uh, hands off the car, go on.
Fifth time this week.
Beef burger, pineapple on the side, and chicken
Caesar salad, no mayo, extra croutons.
Would you like another Coke?
Oh, my feet are killing me.
Um, Bill wants
another milkshake, okay?
One chicken schnitzel
off a heart attack, that one.
"The law presumes anyone entering into a
contract has the legal capacity to do so."
- Hey, Amelia.
- Contract legal capacity to do so. Hey, Marcus.
How was school? Contract law in
business and commercial life.
- Hello.
- Mm, looks good.
- Shut up.
- It's a bit chill for a cafe, isn't it?
- How's the world of the law going?
- Ask me in two years.
Here he is. Traitor,
working for the enemy.
- Job's a job, Mom.
- Hey, Helen, I'm playing tonight.
- Did you know that?
- You sure that's a good idea?
- You're not as young as you used to be.
- Yeah, baby, you...
You sure that's a good idea?
Look, it's one of the last games
of this season, maybe ever.
I promise I'll be careful.
Okay.
Then I'll come watch you.
- Hey, your funeral.
- Thanks, Helen.
Thanks for your support.
Hey, last time he played,
he ended up in a coma, fact.
I'm just saying.
- Hey, baby.
- Hi.
- Oh! No, put me down.
- You missed me, did you?
Put me down, honey.
You know I did.
- So what's the big emergency?
- Um...
Hey, Jack-o,
good luck tonight, mate.
Oh, thanks, mate. We're
gonna absolutely kill them.
Sorry, I didn't... you know
I can't say no to my fans.
Well, I'm your biggest fan.
- Okay, listen.
- I'm listening.
- I just... I'm pregnant.
- I'm all ears, babe.
- You... you're what?
- I'm pregnant.
You sure?
Yes, Jackson,
I'm pretty sure.
- That's... that's amazing.
- Oh!
Oh, wait, wait,
I didn't hurt the baby?
Hey, I'm sure it's fine.
Hey, how you doing in there?
Okay, babe, it can't hear you.
It's, like, the size of a peanut.
- Hey, yeah, but what a peanut.
- Oh.
- What's all this then?
- Uh, we are, uh, starting our own team.
- Oh, hey! Congratulations!
- Thank you, man.
Thank you, Jimmy. Ah!
What... what
the hell was that?
Don't know, but, we, um,
better get going, yeah?
Yeah, I'll see you guys out there.
I just have to change.
- Yeah.
- Bye, baby. Babies.
- Congratulations again, Ness.
- Thanks, Jimmy, good luck.
- Thank you. See ya.
- See ya.
Hello.
Uh, apples?
I wanna reassure you that
a vote for me and my party
will be the best thing
that can happen to this town.
We've got policies in place
and initiatives worked out
to encourage industry back into the
community, which will create more jobs.
Jesus.
Simmons.
Sorry.
Oh, there you are.
Thanks for coming tonight.
People love you
and they need all the
enjoyment they can get, right?
First the factory closes,
and then this damn bypass.
Uh, we all hope you aren't out there
helping in the construction too much.
- Uh...
- Right? Are you?
Uh, how's the, uh, the head?
You gonna be
all right tonight?
Don't, uh, don't
kill yourself out there.
- I won't.
- You, you know... you know what I meant.
And good evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
girls and boys,
you're with Seth Grimes
from 97.1,
the Country Smile on your dial.
Catch me 7:00 to 11:00 weekdays.
Now it's a perfect evening
for our own Drop Bears
to take on the Kookaburras
in this match for charity.
Oh, wait, hold the phone,
ladies and gentlemen.
We have a, uh, special player
out on the field tonight.
A blast from the past,
the big man himself,
put your hands together for the
ex-captain, Matty Simmons.
Go, Matty! Whoo!
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
Go, Matty!
Hey, big man. I think
you, uh, forgot your helmet.
That's funny.
Look, mate, there's a talent
scout up here from Melbourne,
so just stay out of my way,
all right?
Dickhead.
Okay, bring it in, lads!
Bring it in.
I don't know why, why we
let her run off on her own.
Because it's Bella.
What, do you think we're gonna find her under
the grandstand making out with the town hunk?
- No.
- Mom, look.
Anyway, maybe I'll have
a look around for her.
I'll meet you guys
back at the van.
Okay. Bye.
And there's the bounce.
Simmons takes it in hand.
Big kick there
from Jimmy Stiles.
Get up! Get up, baby!
Flying above the
pack there, Jackson! Amazing.
And makes no mistake putting it
through the sticks.
Simmons a little slow to warm up this
quarter, but there's more to come.
Yes!
- Look, you get the teddy bear.
- Thank you.
Everyone's a winner.
Yeah. Cocktails.
Looks like the Kookaburras
are starting to take control.
Simmons, pick it up!
- Okay, go.
- Ready?
Oh!
- Shit.
- What the hell was that?
- Piss off, blondie.
- What?
Whoa. And there's some heated words
there from the old and new captains.
- There's...
- You two break it up. Come on.
We're down by two.
Oh, Bella, there you are.
Have you any idea how
worried your mom is?
I texted her.
Town has no reception.
Well, look, for the rest of the trip,
let's just stay together, okay?
No wandering off
on your own.
Think you can just come back into our
lives and start telling us what to do?
What? What's happened?
Charity gigs.
No more, Seth. No more.
What? What's this? Do you
know anything about this?
No, not at all.
Marcus, what is that?
Take cover!
Stay! Stay here!
Stay here! Matt!
Vanessa, stay there!
Run, Jimmy!
Go, go, go, go! Go!
Matt! Matt!
Marcus!
- Amelia!
- Marcus, come here!
Come on. Hey, this way.
- Bella!
- Daddy!
Bella!
Bella, Bella, let's run!
Let's go!
- Marcus. What the...?
- Where's your mom? Where's Helen?
- Where's your mom?
- Ah!
- Mom!
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
- Where's your mom? Shit.
- Mom, Mom!
Mom! Matt, Matt, let me go!
Let me... Mom!
- Mom!
- Let's go.
Get out of there!
Move, move!
- Where are we gonna go?
- Anywhere but here, kid.
Shit!
Hey! Hey!
Come here! Hey, guys!
This way!
Jenny! Samuel!
- Matty, Matty!
- I'm shot.
You gotta help me. What if it's an artery?
I'm bloody toast.
- Hey, is this your van?
- Yeah.
- Jenny! Samuel!
- Let's go, let's go.
Peter! Peter! Dad!
Hey, is that your daughter?
We gotta go! Let's go!
Yeah. I told them to meet me back here.
I can't leave without them!
Hey, I promise you I'll help you
get the rest of your family back,
- but right now we need to go.
- Dad!
Or she is dead!
Ah! Dad!
Get in.
Saddle up.
Amelia! Come on!
Close that!
- Vanessa! Come on!
- Come on, man! Start the car!
Yeah, man.
I'm doing my best with this.
- Vanessa!
- Amelia!
Over here! Wait!
Come on!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
We're getting close!
- Jimmy!
- No!
Jimmy! Jimmy, come on!
Jackson! Jackson, please!
Jackson, we have to go!
- Jimmy!
- Please, Jackson, leave him!
No, I can't just leave him!
Jimmy!
Jackson, get up! Please!
Come on. Now!
- Jimmy.
- Get in! Get in!
Shit.
Go! Go!
Get out of here!
Careful!
Whoa! Let's go!
Wait a minute! Get out of the way!
I've got this!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Get out of the way.
Left, left, left!
- Hey, what's your name?
- Peter.
- You sure about this, Peter?
- I hope so.
- Hold on.
- Oh, shit.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- No, it's okay, it's okay.
I'm a nurse. Vanessa.
Seth, 97.1, you know,
the country smile on your dial.
- Sorry, I don't...
- Oh, that's all right. No one does.
Can someone tell me
what the hell is going on?
It's a terrorist attack.
Hey, babe, you okay?
You hurt?
- Shit. I don't like the look of this.
- Oh, crap!
- What do we do now?
- Keep going!
- Did anyone see that?
- Shit, it's behind us!
- Can this thing go any faster?
- This is going faster.
Oh, my God! We're doomed!
That was Air Force, one of ours.
Keep the engine running.
Move.
Hey, whoa, whoa.
Hey, do you think
this is a good idea,
just stopping out
here in the middle,
in the, like, in the open,
in the... Jesus.
Jesus.
- What are you looking for?
- Markings.
Pilot.
What if the
pilot's still alive?
I don't think
that's gonna be a problem.
Why not?
It's not a man.
Drone, maybe.
Matt! Amelia!
Get back in the van.
- What are you doing?
- You staying? You coming? What's going on?
- Dude, crap or get off the pot.
- Matt.
Just drive. Drive.
Leave him.
Matt?
Matt, is that you?
Oh.
Bloody good to see you.
We're all up shit creek
now, eh, boys?
Dennis?
What the hell are you doing
in the back of Arnold's Ute?
Do you have any idea how hard it is
to jump in the back of a moving car?
- Are you hurt?
- Huh?
- That's not mine.
- Hey, I know you.
You stole my fruit
two weeks ago, didn't you?
Boy, if I ever
bloody catch you...
Are you seriously blowing up over some
fruit after what we've just seen?
Besides, I know
where we can hide.
Come on, then.
Good luck.
We'll follow you.
Hey!
I used the bypass.
It is quicker.
Hey, you okay?
- Ness, talk to me.
- They just started shooting.
- I know, babe.
- Everyone, our friends, Jimmy.
Jackson,
what are we gonna do?
Babe, it's okay.
All right? It's okay.
It's behind us now.
What about Peanut?
We're gonna be okay.
Just let yourselves in.
What is this place?
Oh, it was an old timber mill
before the town went to shit.
Now, welcome
to Casa de Destitute.
- How many more are there?
- Why so interested?
Hey, quiet.
I want to know
what your plan is.
- My plan?
- Yeah.
You promised, man. You promised
you'd help me find my family.
Ease up, man.
I'm working on it.
Okay. Did you find
anything at that crash?
- Aliens.
- Jackson, I think we've all been through enough tonight.
All right. Just, let's
all settle down, okay?
Let's cover the cars, get some sleep, and
we'll figure out the rest in the morning.
- Mm-hm.
- You guys get some. Someone's gotta stay on watch.
- I'll give you a hand.
- Chin up, everyone.
I got out of worse
situations than this.
Been married three times.
Don't touch my shit.
You mean what you said in there?
Which part?
You all right?
I'm great.
About helping him
find his family.
What do you want me
to say, Amelia?
Yeah, yeah, I will help him
find his family.
That an old bottle of pills
or a new one?
Just give me a break,
will you!?
Fuck.
I'm sorry.
- I'm scared, baby.
- It's okay.
I'm sure our guys
are fighting back right now.
- Let's hope so.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- Building a fire pit.
- No, I mean, here with us.
- Oh, I don't know.
Just, um, lucky, I guess.
- I used to write.
- Cool.
Hey...
What are you
doing there, kid?
No one calls me kid
except Matt. I'm Marcus.
And there's a lot of us and not much
food or water that has to last.
So before you interrupted me, I was
trying to work out our daily rations.
Okay, Rain Man, fine.
Jesus.
What are you doing?
Stripping back the bark
so that when it burns
it creates as little smoke
as possible.
Okay. Let me help.
Hey, Marcus. Wanna come help
find some branches, help Dennis?
Okay.
Matty! Matt!
Babe, are you okay?
What's wrong?
You gotta see this.
I told you it was aliens.
We are toast.
Hey, what are you doing?
Some of those bags are mine.
- I'm leaving.
- We need to stick together.
What together?
Okay, I don't owe you anything,
especially now that
we've got a kid on the way.
No, I just
found out yesterday and...
- Congratulations.
- Vanessa, why didn't you tell me?
Well, I don't even know
if I should have it...
Come on, baby, we'll get
as far away from here as we can.
No, hands off.
These are mine. Piss off.
What if it's
the same everywhere?
Yeah, well, we're gonna
have to take that chance.
So whoever wants to get
out of Dodge, we're going.
- I'll go.
- Arnold?
Can't do it, Jack-o.
You can have my truck
if you want.
I've got no need for it now.
Thank you. Dennis?
With those ships they have, you
two'll be like sitting ducks.
Well, we'll stay
off the road, man.
- What about when the baby comes?
- Vanessa's a nurse.
She can...
What's your plan, Matt?
Stay? Fight?
I mean, I've been in a few bar brawls, but I
doubt anyone here has ever been in a gun battle.
- Huh?
- Peter has.
- Bella.
- He was one of the Bankstown boys.
Great.
Have you ever
killed another man?
- Yeah. He's been in...
- Bella, please.
Well, to be quite honest, I've been
inside for the last seven years.
I've only been out
for about a month.
- Well, that's just perfect.
- What's that supposed to mean, mate?
I've paid my debt. I was in
the middle of moving my family
as far away from that
city life as I could get.
Okay.
Well, I'm no killer,
but I was a crack shot with
a rifle in the army reserve.
Mind you, that was
a good 30 years ago.
- I can fight.
- Now why would we believe anything you say?
- You wanna find out, mustache?
- Anytime..
- What was that?
- Look, we got a murderer and a bum. It's over.
We're going, Vanessa. Come on.
You wanna go, go.
I'm going back
to the town.
Find out what happened
to our families.
Good luck, Jack-o.
- You guys should stay.
- Mm-hmm.
If there's one thing I know
about Dad, he's a fighter.
Yeah, we'll all take care
of each other, right?
Twenty-four hours,
and then we'll decide.
Shit.
All right.
Spread out, be careful.
- This is stupid.
- Shh!
How are we supposed
to fight them if they see us?
Shut up.
Baby, stay.
Take that.
- Here, here, we gotta move.
- Are you serious?
Christ. If we come across
anything, we'll just build a gun.
- What the hell are they doing?
- Making themselves at home.
- Mrs. Kyle.
- Dennis. Matty.
- Get away, as far as you can.
- Have you seen my mom?
They moved her today
with some of the others.
- Have you seen these two?
- Those poor kids.
It'll be okay, Mrs. Kyle.
They're coming!
Go, run, go!
Just stay alive, okay? We're
coming back, just stay alive.
Okay. Go.
How did we end up with
a nurse of our own, huh?
That's...
that's just crazy luck.
Yeah, well, I'm still in my
three year training period,
- so I wouldn't be so sure.
- Oops, amputated the wrong leg.
Don't be so modest.
It's only another year, babe.
What am I saying?
- Try not to dwell, son.
- Yeah, it's hard not to.
I've wasted the last ten years
of my life on social media.
Yeah, yeah, I know, me too.
Hashtag "bestdayever."
Hashtag "TGIF."
Hashtag "it's-the-end of-the
world-we're-all-gonna-die who-gives-a-shit?"
Something's wrong.
They should be back by now.
Easy.
I'm gonna give it another hour
and then we're leaving.
Yeah.
I'm getting a bad feeling.
- We can't just leave.
- I know, baby,
but we have to think
about the rest of us.
Look, take it easy,
all right?
Look, I said relax, mate.
No one's going anywhere.
Take a load off.
What are you doing, Pete?
- Oh, that's just great.
- Okay. Let him go.
Just be cool.
Hey, you wanna go back inside?
I can stay out here.
Where's Mom?
It's us.
- Are you guys all right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, we're fine.
What's going on down there?
- Did you see Mom?
- Thanks.
- Jenny, Samuel?
- No.
Everyone's been taken
to the old factory.
It's like a livestock paddock,
except we're the livestock.
The bastards are here
for the long haul.
What, do you speak alien?
How do you know?
Because we saw them...
You led them right to us.
- Behind here.
- Go, go, go.
Okay. Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on.
You son of a bitch!
Matt, Matt.
You expect
a welcome party, bitch?
Oh! Ah!
Hold him down,
hold him down!
Hold him down, Arnold.
Get his leg!
Grab it! Grab it!
Hold him down. Get his leg!
- Grab it! Grab it!
- Hold him down!
Hold him!
Clear shot, better watch now,
watch out!
Pull his head back,
pull his head back!
Pull his head back!
Die, you son of a bitch!
Well, that was your best
tackle of the season.
Arnold's hurt.
- Oh, God.
- You're crazy, old man, you know that?
Ah! Just got the wind
knocked out of me.
Guys, we gotta go. Now.
And we're taking these bodies with us.
Grab those guns, too.
Thanks, Pete.
Thank you.
Let's get rid
of this thing, huh?
They're
gonna hunt us down now.
We just started a war.
We're already at war.
Son of a bitch.
Oh.
Oh, that's...
- You all right?
- That's just...
- Matty. Matt.
- Matt. No, no, no, don't.
You don't know
what that will do.
What have we got to lose?
Holy shit.
- What do you see?
- Everything.
- And nothing.
- What?
Give me a look?
Careful, baby, it's heavy.
It stinks.
The helmets pick up
anything alive.
Out here there's so much life
that... we're invisible.
Maybe where they're from, there
isn't any other life to see.
These guys are here to stay. We want this
back, we're gonna have to do something.
Hm. Let's do it, then.
I'm with you till the end.
That's more like it.
Invisible, eh?
Bastards won't know
what hit 'em.
These things are a little
different from our rifles.
But the same principle applies.
Anyone's grandma can shoot a target
20 feet away in broad daylight.
We gotta be faster than them,
smarter than them.
And when you're ready,
the shot must be released
without any disturbance
to the firer's position.
Alrighty. Take aim.
Breathe in.
Take 'em down.
Greetings, Earthlings. Come
with me if you want to live.
Always wanted to say that.
You're heavy.
Come on, let's go.
Has anyone seen my mom?
You the last?
Arnold.
Arnold, let's go.
Jackson, come on.
Hello.
Where to start today?
Dad's still clinging
to the hope
that Mom and Sammy
are alive out there.
I'm trying to believe it.
Hey, hey. Here.
I'm not sure
if I'm that naive anymore.
Come on, you must be exhausted,
here, here.
- If you're watching...
- Here. Here you go.
...I miss you.
We're doing good, right?
Yeah.
I'm fighting for you.
The others are kicking ass.
Um, Marcus and I
have been building armor,
repairing clothes
for survivors.
He's a good kid.
I don't... I don't even know
who's gonna watch this.
These are the best
seats in the house, babe.
Yeah, my view
isn't too bad either.
I hope the baby
gets your eyes.
gets your strength.
I couldn't do this
without you, baby.
We're gonna get
through this... somehow.
Yeah.
So you do that,
cut off their supplies,
it also hits their morale.
Now, we just need to figure out
what's strategic to them.
An occupying force can
be brought to its knees,
if you have the will
and the drive to fight.
I just never thought
we'd be the ones occupied.
Okay. Bella, compression
on the head wound.
Bella, you got this.
Okay. Bandages.
Keep that there,
now check her for vital signs.
- Yeah. She's gonna be okay.
- You're gonna be okay.
Yeah.
Guys, they're
poisoning the water.
- Hey, where's, um...
- We're out.
- The creeks...
- Higher ground, boys.
Come on.
We got people here
looking to us to lead.
- You guys wanna get in the fight?
- Yeah.
Just get your
head right, mate.
Let's go!
Move, move!
I guess it's important to
document the end of the world.
If anyone finds this,
we really tried.
Hey, hey.
Matt.
We're not gonna hurt you.
Hey.
I'm Amelia.
- What's your name?
- Chloe.
Where did you get the gun,
Chloe?
Found... found it.
- You wanna put it down?
- No.
- Okay.
- How did you get away?
I crawled.
Hey, hey.
Did they do this?
They've got the rest out here
just planting for their food.
Okay.
Chloe, Chloe.
It's okay. Look at me.
It's okay.
Give me the gun.
They know
everything about us.
Some are slaves.
Some are...
Some are like me.
Okay. Okay.
- Take it, take it. Take it.
- Okay.
- Baby, baby, we got to move.
No, no!
- Go, go, go, go, go!
- No!
Come on!
- This is the place?
- Yup.
Every night this week they've
dropped off more, right here.
- You checked the detonators?
- Yeah.
- And the wires?
- What about the...
- Yeah, man, it's cool.
I got it. Jesus.
We've got problems.
Okay. Shh. Quiet.
Here it comes.
- Yeah! Good one!
- Told you, I told you.
Hello. What...
Slow down, slow down.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, slow down.
You should have seen it blow.
Boom.
Hey, I'll be back.
Dennis, Dennis, Dennis.
Remember, always aim
ahead of the bow.
Hey. You guys better see this.
What have you done?
We've been doing it
your way for months.
It's time we start
listening to someone else.
How do you know
they can't track him?
We're not stupid,
we checked it over.
- Whoa.
- How the hell did you do it?
We caught two of them off guard.
The other one got Amy and Jean
Claude before Bella shot it.
That's not the deal, Bella. You're
not supposed to go after them.
- Relax, Pete, she did good.
- I'm not talking to you.
- You disobeyed me.
- You're kidding.
Who do you think was looking
after our family?
- I don't want to hear it.
- This is bullshit.
What about you?
What were you thinking, hm?
Thinking that I was actually
doing something for once.
I can really help.
I'm not a kid anymore.
They're experimenting
on humans.
- How do you know that?
- I know.
We gotta bust them out of there.
Yeah. I'm with you
on that, Arnold.
And what do we do
with this thing, huh?
You're experimenting on us,
are you?
Get off me, get off me!
- Enemy soldier!
- I haven't finished with him.
Let's just sit on this before
doing anything rash, all right?
Come on, mate, let's go.
Sort your shit out.
Jackson, just put it
out of its misery.
- What?
- No.
Look at it.
This isn't right.
- I don't like this.
- What would you like?
- I need to talk to you, now.
- What?
Why did you
let them do that?
- Can you blame them?
- Hmm.
What good is beating the shit
out of it gonna do anyone?
They invaded us.
Maybe they deserve it.
Yeah. Columbus found America,
Cook found Australia, they were never the
same again. These guys aren't leaving.
So, what? You want
to give up, let them kill us?
- Your mom?
- No. Mm-mm.
I want us to be real
about this, okay?
That big ship in the sky,
it's not going anywhere.
We all know it. We need to accept
that the life that we had is gone.
- Bullshit.
- It's gone.
I love you.
I do not accept any other life
than one we choose for each other.
Vanessa.
Why did you have to bring it
back here, huh?
What? I was trying to help.
Suddenly I'm the bad guy?
You're not a bad guy, but
you have to control your ego.
- My ego, wow.
- You know what I mean.
It's just, like, you're
always trying to be the best,
but this isn't a game, Jackson.
All right?
Slow down,
let them run this.
I need you around
when the baby arrives.
What are you doing?
Bella? Bella.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop, stop, stop.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- What?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Are you sure you're okay?
Yes.
Your dad, he just
doesn't quit, does he?
What's that?
Oh, it's about $9,634.25.
- Dennis?
- No, it's good.
It's good. It's good.
It's a new world, right?
Come on.
I mean, everything we should
value we have here, right?
People, family,
relationships. That shit...
It doesn't matter anymore.
Yeah.
You should try it.
You should try something new.
- What?
- Try something new.
It's a new world. So anything
connected to the old world...
Go on. Try it.
What have you got?
You got a thousand pockets
in this thing.
You gotta
have something in here.
- No. I don't...
- What have... what's this?
Okay, nice. Try it.
Trust me.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Nice.
Actually, I've got
something for you.
It might be of value.
- What is it?
- Open it.
- Is that me?
- Hmm.
So they've been watching us for centuries,
just planning? Why did they wait so long?
It doesn't really
matter what they want.
Their plans don't
include us hanging around.
You know what
we have to do, huh?
What do we have to do?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Peter, what are you doing?
Right, I get you want your family back.
But this is nuts.
Look, the only way to get our planet
back is to kill enough of them
- until they lose the will to fight.
- You don't know them.
This thing has information,
this thing can help us.
We don't know what's
going on out there, Pete.
I know what will happen
if you don't get out of my way.
Matt, Pete, Pete.
Just calm down.
Calm down, all right?
You don't like it?
Piss off!
Are you proud of yourself?
What about you, boy?
Why don't you piss off back
to jail where you belong?
Listen up.
We're going back to the factory.
We're getting our people out.
- Any volunteers to go on a supply run?
- Let me go.
- Got a list of every person from town.
- Where's your sister?
- She left on her own.
- I'm ready, Matt.
That's why you're coming with us.
Get your gear, kid.
So, what are you gonna
say to Amelia, huh?
Amelia's not here.
We've just gotten back
from another all-nighter.
- We're tired.
- Then don't go.
Matt, these guys are exhausted.
They're gonna
make mistakes out there.
We fight or we die.
I'm sick
of digging graves, man.
How about you?
Coming?
Hey, no.
We talked about this.
Yeah. But the baby,
all right?
We need supplies.
- Be careful, okay?
- I'll be careful.
Be back soon, baby.
- You and I need to have a little talk.
- Yeah?
- You done killing prisoners?
- Don't be smart, boy.
- She's my little girl.
- Oh. Oh, right, that.
Okay. What?
Hey, I'm her stepdad, maybe
I'm a little overprotective.
But what I don't like
is some shithead like you
taking advantage
of an opportunity.
Well, I don't know what
you want me to say, Pete.
They're just drawings.
You are this close, mate.
You are this close.
Hey, Ness, Ness, Ness.
- Yeah.
- You all right?
You okay?
Just stay away from her, okay?
It's all right.
You can go inside.
All right. Get inside.
Get inside, please. Oh!
- I got you. I got you.
- Oh.
- Bella!
- It's okay.
Look at me. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
- Oh!
- Okay. Breathe. Breathe.
- Vanessa, over here.
- Okay.
- Breathe. Come on.
- You okay?
- Where's Jackson?
- He's out on a run. They all are.
- It's okay. We're gonna help.
- Seth, Seth.
Go out and find someone who
can help, anybody, a nurse.
She is a nurse. You've had two kids.
You must know something.
Look, I wasn't there
for either of them.
All right. I'm gonna
walk you through this, okay?
Okay.
- I'll go find Jackson.
- Oh! Okay.
Okay. Squeeze as hard
as you like.
- What's going on?
- Her baby's coming.
Whoa. Hey, Ness.
- It's okay.
- Bella.
- I'm here.
- Okay.
Just relax. It's all right. You can do this.
- Vanessa, tell me what you need.
- I wanna wait for Jackson.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Dennis is gonna get him.
- Can I just wait for Jackson?
- This baby isn't...
- Please, I need Jackson here.
- This baby isn't gonna wait.
Bella, have a look.
What's happening?
It's happening.
Come on. Bella.
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
That's it.
- It's happening too fast.
- Good girl. Come on.
Something's wrong. It's happening too fast.
Something's wrong.
It's okay. You're okay.
You're okay.
- No one's listening to me.
- You can do this.
Everything you can carry, kid.
Move it.
I want that 4x4 stripped
in 20 minutes, Jackson.
Matt, the storm's setting in.
We're a long way out.
- Let's just get out of here, all right?
- We're pushing on.
- What?
- Vanessa.
Jackson. Jackson, no!
Jackson!
On your left!
Come on, old man.
Don't you die on me.
- Go!
- Ah!
Matt!
You can do this. Let's go.
- Shit.
- Run.
- Let's get out of here.
- Get me out. Get me out!
- Bella, grab the blaster!
- I've got it!
It's okay.
Seth. Grab the gun, Seth.
- Bella, over here.
- Okay.
You're good. You're good.
Grab his leg!
Move, move, move!
- Go!
- Ah!
Marcus, what's happening?
Marcus!
Marcus, what are you doing?
I can't, I can't!
It's okay. It's okay.
They're killing them all.
- Here, bite down on this.
- I know!
- You gotta keep quiet!
- Stop it!
Please keep her quiet!
- Slow down. Choose your targets.
- Arnold, is he alive?
- Dennis.
- Come here, keep an eye on our six.
It's okay. It's okay!
- Come on!
- No, I can't! I can't!
You can do this.
Keep going. Keep going.
- Oh, my God!
- We can see the head.
- Keep breathing!
- You gotta work with me!
They're gonna hear us!
It's coming.
You're getting there.
Push this kid out now.
Shit!
Shut up!
Get out of here!
It's okay. It's just you and me.
We're gonna be okay.
Oh, my God! It's okay.
She's coming.
- Daddy!
- No!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, a baby!
You've got a baby girl.
It's a baby girl. Oh, it's so beautiful.
You have a baby girl.
Motherfucker!
Fuck you!
Jackson's gonna be
so proud of you.
I'm gonna kill you!
I'll kill you!
I love you so much.
- Tell Jackson...
- Yeah?
Allison.
Vanessa?
Vanessa! Vanessa!
Oh, my God!
There's a lot of blood!
Dad! There's so much blood!
Dad! Wake up!
Hey, wake up!
Wake up!
- Come on. Come on.
- It's okay. It's gonna be fine.
- You're gonna be fine.
- Come on, now.
She's gonna be...
Daddy!
Wake up, please!
Wake up!
Australian Army!
We're gonna get you out!
Come on! Here! Go!
Come on, guys! Get up!
Come on, let's go! Let's go!
Go, go, go! Move out!
Go, go!
Second Commandos,
anyone alive out there?
I said, anyone alive out there?
You guys okay?
Do not move.
We'll come to you.
Trackers are getting good, Az.
What you got, mate?
- 11:00.
Two hundred meters, target
moving from left to right.
What happened?
Bella, what happened?
Is she dead?
Is Vanessa dead?
Do you have a medic?
Is there a medic?
Is there a medic? It's the fucking army!
We need a fucking medic!
Vanessa! Vanessa, no!
Bella, what happened?!
- No, no, no!
- Peter, look at me.
What happened to her?
She's not dead.
Please wake up.
- She's gone.
- What do you mean she's gone?
I'm so sorry.
Oh!
You two, take these guys out.
Do that right now.
Tinned peaches.
For months now,
all we've heard about is
a resistance in the forest.
You kept us going.
That's why we
came back out here.
You guys are heroes.
He took a hit to the head.
Thank you.
How is he?
I found this just
before you found me.
- They cultivated it.
- All right. Jesus, I'll just,
I'll stick with my peaches.
Do you know what's actually
going on out there?
Well...
All our cities are
either flooded or destroyed,
something do with their ship being
too close to our atmosphere.
Government leaders are gone,
everyone's in hiding.
I don't know about all you guys,
but look, the army's here now.
I've got to get out of here.
I've got to keep...
I've got to keep
searching for them.
We're out of here, Bella.
Dad, we can't leave.
Pete?
- Bella, we gotta...
- Peter.
I will go back
to that factory with you,
and we will finish this.
But please, please,
can you stay?
What factory?
The factory's where they're
holding everyone from our town.
I think we should see the CO.
Recon elements indicate that the grays
have some kind of biological weapon.
It's a toxin or pathogen obviously
designed to wipe us out once and for all.
We finally got confirmation it is
at this particular grid reference.
- It's your town.
- That factory is one of the most strategic targets in this war.
Now, our intel suggests that the
weapon's been moved to Sydney,
so that's gonna be the focus
of our major attack. Davis.
During the Sydney assault, we wanna
cause a distraction at the facility
and destroy any means to continue
manufacturing this virus.
Now, your prison break plan
could be that distraction.
Now, your team know the size,
the layout,
the disposition of the enemy
there better than anyone else.
It would help the situation if you were
to assist Major Davis and his men.
Our first priority
is to get our families out.
Well, my priority
is to save as many civilian
lives as is possible.
And there are currently 500,000
innocent people living in Sydney.
They're living like rats.
We are moving against
the factory at 1400 hours.
If you're in,
you have our thanks.
If not, then we understand.
The decision's yours.
So this is it, everybody.
Months of planning
with every fighter, trooper, fucking
pilot, goddamn sapper we have left,
and it all comes down to today.
This day.
No mistakes.
Let's make it count.
Look after your people.
Good luck.
She's a ball buster, no doubt. But
she got us through dark days.
But listen, we're in a bit
of a rush here, okay?
So if you're gonna join us,
there's an orders group
in one hour at the motor pool.
One hour.
I like it. Let's do this.
Not with your wing clipped,
old man.
Jackson... where are you going?
- I'm done.
- What?
I'm done.
There's something I have to do.
I think you'd approve.
God, I love you so much.
Please find your way back.
Nothing on TV tonight, huh?
- Thought you might join us.
- No one else?
Turns out, we're all
with you till the end.
What do you
think you're doing?
- Coming with.
- I don't think so.
He's a fighter.
He saved my ass.
We're all in this together.
All right.
- What's the plan?
- Cause a distraction,
break your people out,
and save the fucking planet.
That's the plan.
- Let's do it.
- Okay.
Hope you guys
are sure about this.
It's everything we got left.
That's my family.
Two minutes!
Everyone sharpen up!
- Ready to deploy, men?
- Copy that.
Armor-piercing rounds!
Listen up. There's a lot more
of them. Intel is off.
Az, patch me
through to the colonel.
I know a vantage point.
Left up here.
Okay. It's a straight run through
the crops to the facility.
On foot, 40 minutes.
They're our people.
Amelia, that's right, isn't it?
I think so.
Can I borrow those?
Be careful.
I got them for Father's Day.
- You have kids?
- Not anymore.
- Dave-o? I've lost comms.
- Keep trying.
Look.
Ah!
- That's a commander.
- Commander?
Yeah, tough sons of bitches.
Yeah, I barely
got away from one.
- We need to get them out.
- You heard the colonel.
There are bigger things
at stake here.
Look, there they are.
That's them. My family.
Bella!
- We're staying.
- Okay.
Something doesn't
feel right here. Az.
- Yeah.
- Get the boys out and on rec-y.
I wanna know what
we're up against.
Grays moving
into sector 545.
Cag reports the enemy air strength
is much higher than anticipated.
And the boys are taking a hell of a
beating over the skies of Sydney.
- What are your numbers?
- Unknown. At 1345, Major Davis
reported the grays are fortifying
all along these lines.
When was the last report by Davis
before we lost radio contact?
Same as everyone else,
ma'am, about 30 minutes.
I think it's
a goddamn trap.
- Colonel!
- This is a restricted area. You cannot be in here.
Colonel, what's happening?
Colonel, what about my friends?
The attack has suffered major losses.
There's no sign of the bio weapon.
The virus was never moved.
It's still in your town.
What are you gonna do?
Well, sending what's left of my
men would be a suicide mission.
Your friends
are on their own.
Hey, hey. Hey, hey.
I need to wake him up.
He's off the machines
and breathing normally.
- It's just a matter of time.
- No, no, no.
Sorry.
Matt! Come on, Matt. I need
you to wake up, all right?
Get up. Matt, get up.
Come on!
Matt, come on!
I need you to wake up, buddy!
All right. Come on!
Wake up!
Matt! Matt.
Get up, get up, mate, come on.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey. Look at me. Matt.
Marcus and Amelia
are all gonna die
unless we do
something right now.
- Where are they?
- They're in town.
- The factory. Come on.
- Where the hell are we?
We're in a military camp.
- Get us a car.
- All right.
From glen to glen
and down the mountainside
Can I trust you
with her, mate?
Where do you think
you're going?
I'm going out.
I'm not letting
you go alone.
This is the most important
thing I can ask of you, mate.
- Please?
- Yeah.
No, it's okay. Come on.
Daddy's gotta go away
for a little while, okay?
Here you go, mate.
There we go.
He'll be back soon.
- What the hell is this?
- What? Think you can do better?
Let's go.
- Roomy.
- Yeah. Well, how about a little bit of gratitude, huh?
- Thank you.
- You all good over there?
- I'm fine. Let's just go.
- Seat belt.
Davis,
we've got eyes on you now.
- Targets are clear to engage.
- Roger that.
We're set.
Engage targets when ready.
Well, this is nuts.
Yeah.
Thanks for waking me up.
Bioweapon's in the factory,
detonator doesn't have much range.
No idea
of the welcoming party.
Hey, you listening?
Bioweapon's in the factory, the detonator has
short range and a possible welcoming party.
And it's just
the two of us.
At least they
won't expect it.
You got your helmet?
Dick.
It's okay.
Jesus.
They found us.
Take cover!
Move! Move!
Let's do this.
Okay. Let's go.
Move, move, move, move.
- Amelia.
- Matt, Matt, Matt, come on.
There's no time, all right?
We gotta go. Look at me.
Come on.
Hey, Tin Man.
Take that one. I got this.
Nothing's working.
Screw it!
Jackson!
Set the explosives, be careful!
All right.
You're free, let's go.
We're blowing the building,
get the hell out!
Henderson's farm, move.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Take it easy, take it easy,
look after each other.
- Helen, are you all right?
- Matt, you're alive.
Big fella,
come here, come here.
Stay with her,
and keep your heads down.
Henderson's farm, go.
Shit.
I should have worn a helmet.
I need you to cover me.
You're going alone.
You don't want help.
Not this time.
Cover fire!
Here. You want this, huh?
Come get it.
Rookie.
Enough.
- Hand it to me.
- English, huh?
Well done. That was sarcasm.
You haven't learnt that yet,
haven't you?
We have learned many things.
The universe
grows smaller every day.
Good for you.
Uh-uh!
You shoot me, I smash this,
and you start again.
Learned we want you gone yet?
You understand nothing.
You have no power
and we have no choice.
There's always a choice.
I've seen your world,
what's left of it.
Humans.
You cling to a planet
you insist on destroying.
We learned from our mistakes.
Our world is gone.
We need this one.
If we must kill to survive,
we will.
- Not today.
- Humans!
Comms back up. Get
those choppers over there now!
Peter!
Ah!
Go get your family, Pete.
I'm not leaving you.
- Come on.
- Ah!
Peter, get down!
Colonel's sending air support!
Tigers are inbound now!
Demon call sign, this is 91-Charlie.
Fire mission, over. Hot smoke!
We see your call sign,
send, over.
Fire mission, call sign
is in the center
of the cleared field in craters.
Danger close, over!
Roger that. Danger close.
Keep your heads down. Over.
Take cover!
Come on!
Yo!
Shit.
91-Charlie, we see you have a
large alien force coming from the west.
- Come in. Come in, this is Matt Simmons.
- Over.
I'm in the factory, I have the weapon.
Is anyone out there?
Repeat, this is Matt Simmons,
I have the weapon.
We're in the factory, our escape
is blocked. Can anyone hear me?
- Matty?
- Amelia?
Oh, baby,
it's so good to hear your voice.
Okay, listen, I have the weapon,
I'm in the factory.
- I could stop them.
- No.
No, Matt, you put that down.
You put it down
and you get out of there.
Wait, just... listen.
Your mom is at Henderson's farm.
Matt!
I love you!
- Matt!
- I love you.
Shit.
Matt!
You cannot kill all of us.
You cannot escape.
Let us finish this now.
What? And ruin
this great conversation?
Jackson!
Shit.
- Just go.
- Trying to take the glory again?
Vanessa needs you.
Vanessa is dead, man. Go.
See you soon, mate.
You take care of
my little girl, Matt, okay?
You take care of Allison,
you hear me?
Matt, you hear me?
You take care of Allison, okay?
Move. Move.
Take care of my little girl!
You take care of her!
Something is up!
Let's take them down!
Put your weapons down.
Put them down!
Jenny! Samuel!
Dad!
Oh!
How are you doing?
- Outstanding work.
- Thank you, colonel.
The, uh, Sydney operation
also broke through in the end,
so, yeah,
we're starting to push back.
Matt?
Hey.
Where's Jacko?
What now?
There's not many
of their species left.
They came here because it was
their last chance to survive.
- Amelia.
- Davis.
Can I have your knife, please?
Trust me.
You have nothing left here.
But you can.
Will you help us?
Will you help us
stop this war,
and share this world?
Do you understand me?
Am I wasting my time?
The war is changing now.
There are still
rogue alien units
who don't want to join us,
but we've got inside
information and ideas.
The galaxy just
became a much smaller place,
but I know the only way
to see this through
is for everyone
to work together.
Go! Go! Go!
We'll push on.
We'll pull through.
We'll survive.
We'll keep fighting.
And I know we'll be victorious.
Subtitles by explosiveskull