[CHILDREN CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING]
A boy comes running up, and he asks:
"what exactly is the ocean?
what is the sea?"
You could hit him with a lot of statistics
and Latin names.
But the answer isn't something
you'll find in a book.
To really know what the ocean is,
you have to see it for yourself.
You have to hear it
and taste it.
You have to feel its power.
To really know the ocean,
you have to live it.
The ocean is vast,
and most of us
only ever experience a small part of it.
One point of view,
like that of a marine iguana
gliding through the water
off the coast of the Galápagos Islands.
Born of a miraculous mixture
of matter and energy,
the ocean is an ancient place.
But it is more than just a place.
In a very real sense, the ocean is alive.
In fact, it was already brimming with life
for billions of years
before ancestors of the horseshoe crab
first crept up on the beach.
All manner of creatures followed,
gazing toward the heavens
with prehistoric eyes.
Then, in the span of one lifetime,
as the human race
reached for the stars,
it seems like all of nature
got out of whack.
[ROCKET ENGINES BLASTING]
As hard as we try,
as long and as far as we look,
no one's ever spotted an ocean
like ours out in space.
But we have discovered new galaxies
right here where we least expected,
within our ocean.
Get deep enough and close enough
inside a drop of water,
the larva of a sea urchin
is like an asteroid,
and a crustacean egg
resembles some exotic
and uncharted planet.
In the beating of a newborn heart,
a world begins.
If you take a step back,
it's easy to see how life itself began:
in a pulse of water
and a splash of sunlight and color.
A little at a time,
new forms of life came rippling through
the waters of the world,
spreading and multiplying,
adapting and evolving.
As far as the eye can see,
north and south and east and west,
the ocean smiles at the sky.
Barely scratch the surface
and you will find charging herds
in a breathless chase
near the coast of South Africa.
when it's all over,
the dolphins, the birds, the sharks
and the whales have had their fill,
but plenty of sardines survive,
so life can go on.
when explorers crossed oceans
in search of a new world,
they hardly knew what wondrous events
were taking place
so close below them.
Below their hulls,
Mobula rays went soaring
through the very currents
that bore their ships along.
As the wind rippled
through their sails overhead,
how could they imagine
the unseen silk scarves
rippling through the water below?
The exquisite blanket octopus.
How could they imagine the beauty
and grace of the ocean's bounty?
A few short centuries ago,
huge territories were the domain
of marine animals.
The ocean belonged to them.
[BARKING]
Sea lions basked in the sun
on pristine beaches.
And ever since,
the ocean has continued to feed us,
body and souI,
the source of our greatest stories
and legends.
Humpback whales sleep peacefully,
side by side and upside down
in their crystal-clear waters.
[WHALES CALLING]
Massive and majestic,
they glide along the ocean floor
without disturbing
a single grain of sand.
One generation follows the next.
And each mother gently nudges her baby
to the surface,
helping him along
on his way to breathe.
Merely knowing these creatures exist
isn't enough to tell the stories
of their lives.
For that, you've got to get a little closer
and stay a little longer.
You've got to see them jump
and turn and swim,
hear them breathe and move.
A sea lion's life is as much about playing
as it is about hunting.
A cormorant may be looking for lunch,
but chasing a porcupine puffer fish
is all about fun.
Time creeps slowly by
on a lazy afternoon,
and the Sally Lightfoot crab
tiptoes past the sea lions.
[SQUEALING]
South African fur seal
on their way back from the hunt.
The great white shark
knows their habits well.
On the beaches of South America,
a select group of orcas
have developed a method
for hunting young sea lion.
The blue whale,
half a block long
and weighing in at 120 tons,
gobbles healthy helpings
of a tiny shrimp-like creature called krill.
On a clear night,
as the ocean draws her secrets close,
the moonlight dances on the waves
and filters down to the coral reef.
Already the crab is on the prowI.
Some peep out from behind their shells
to check if the coast is clear.
Others have found a hiding place
to settle in for the night.
Sound actually carries farther
and faster underwater.
Every crackle and click
is registered and understood.
The first flap of a baby shark's fins.
The brush of sand as a moray eeI
slides along the ocean floor.
Some go scuttling about.
Others seek cover.
A hermit crab
who has put on a little weight
needs more spacious accommodations.
Some dine.
Some try to blend into the landscape.
Some stake out their territory.
Busy taking out the trash,
the mantis shrimp keeps a sharp lookout.
He doesn't take kindly to trespassers.
So if he finds one,
look out.
Meanwhile, a sea slug
called the Spanish dancer
cuts a swath through Australian waters
like a whirI of a flamenco skirt.
For many creatures on this planet,
life began in the sea.
Some have returned to the sea.
The dugong's ancestors lived on land.
Now he grazes in underwater pastures.
And the plants and flowers
and grass he eats
once grew on dry land as well.
The green turtle, too,
returned to the sea.
Of course, every once in a while,
they have to come up for air.
From the sea to the shores,
and back to the sea.
Sea turtles lay their eggs on the beach.
Hatched by night, baby sea turtles
can make it to the water, no problem.
But born in broad daylight,
it's a different story.
One in a thousand may reach the sea,
enough for the species to carry on.
Baby turtles don't make much of a meal
for frigatebirds,
so they share an entrée
with the sailfish.
There is more than sharing
going on in the ocean.
Some species depend on one another.
Immune to the paralyzing venom
of the sea anemone,
clownfish hide in her tentacles.
Down here, it's like nature
has given everything a try.
Every color,
every way of life,
every shape.
Now, the venomous stonefish
isn't very fast or agile.
But patience and disguise
make him a fearsome predator.
The lionfish goes still and silent
when he's hungry.
Both make fast food of damselfish.
Big fish eat little fish,
but not always, and not everywhere.
There are fish-operated grooming stations
under the sea
with patient customers
and busy cleaners.
As tempting as it may be,
it's never a good idea
to swallow your dental hygienist.
Some need a whole team
for a full-body scrub.
Sweetlips just needs a touchup.
The ribbon eeI can come unraveled.
The cuttlefish is a master of illusion.
After the magic show,
time for a garden eeI
and a razorfish ballet.
Like soldiers marching into battle,
spider-crab battalions face off
in Australia's Melbourne Bay.
There's a time to dance, a time to fight.
There is also a season for traveI.
Humpbacks set out
on their long journey
to their summer feeding grounds
near the polar regions.
The blue whale, the largest animal
in the history of the world,
is on the move as well.
The ocean sunfish is a vagabond
who doesn't mind a few horse mackerel
tagging along for company.
The blue shark's passenger
is a stowaway.
Sperm whales gather in families.
when the males grow up,
they leave their mothers
and traveI on their own.
A cloud of shad rides in the wake
of a whale shark
as he roams the open ocean
for as long as they can
stay away from his mouth.
The yellowfin tuna
can make some serious time,
speeding through the ocean
from east to west and west to east.
Dolphins are more acrobatic.
They race, feed, leap and play,
seemingly all at once.
Hang on tight. It's gonna be quite a ride.
As the sun sets over Costa Rican waters,
the dolphins are still living it up.
All that strength and energy depend
on a healthy, thriving and resilient ocean.
One good sign of health for our oceans
is the mere existence of older fish,
like this Asian sheepshead wrasse
in the China Sea.
To wear that mask of wisdom,
you have to survive in unspoiled waters
for a very long time.
Of course, if you've seen
one elderly Asian sheepshead wrasse,
you've seen them all.
There are still unspoiled places
where the sea is wild and clean.
There are places
where every strange face tells a story,
with some unexpected twists.
There are places
where winged dragons really do exist.
The leafy sea dragon lives his whole life
in the same patch of water
at the same depth.
Try to move him and he'll die.
There are places where aliens gather,
no makeup or costumes needed.
when it comes to more practical matters
like using tools,
the sea otter is front and center.
They use rocks to crack open shells
and get at the tender morseI inside
while soaking up the rays
in Monterey Bay.
The sea provides not only food
and shelter, but wide-open spaces.
So every community is free to swim
just as far as their flippers or feet
or fins will take them.
Alaskan feeding grounds
still await our weary travelers.
A few orcas live here all year round.
After thousands of miles,
the humpbacks finally arrive.
Here, the fishing is good,
and there's plenty of room to live large.
They make bubbles in the water
to form a fishing net.
when everything's ready,
a cry rings out,
and it's time for the feast.
Human nets are not made of bubbles.
The great bluefin tuna
of the Mediterranean
is now in danger of extinction.
Through overfishing
and bottom trawling,
staggering numbers
of unwanted creatures
get caught and killed.
Bycatch.
Throwbacks.
Discards.
Travelers who will never reach
their destination.
Though in the space
of one human lifetime
countless species
have been threatened,
the ocean fights on.
And anyone who knows the sea
will tell you of her power.
The human race reached for the stars
and paused to look back
at the ocean's blue waters
from outer space.
we watch her now all the time.
we see how she moves
and we take her temperature.
And when she hurts,
we can measure her pain.
Using satellite imagery,
you can see how pollution
runs out of rivers,
penetrating like veins into the deep,
spewing poison all around.
we have littered the ocean
with hundreds of millions of tons of trash,
human objects
which challenge each creature
to find a new way
or a new place to survive.
Human indifference
is surely the ocean's greatest threat.
Yet even now,
at opposite poles of the Earth,
animals thrive in the icy wild.
The leopard seal still reigns supreme
in the Antarctic.
Penguins still waddle
over the frosty landscape,
searching for a break in the ice.
They still fly gracefully
through the freezing waters.
Though as figure skaters,
they leave something to be desired.
This is the ocean too,
where flightless birds soar
under a blanket of ice.
Here, the mother seal
still coaxes her child
into the water for the first time.
Parenting takes a lot of patience.
Near the North Pole,
another seemingly untouched Arctic vista
where all kinds of creatures
depend on the sea for nourishment.
If dragons really do exist,
this is where you'll find the narwhal,
unicorn of the sea.
[WHALES CALLING]
Beluga whales vocalize,
each expressing himself
with his own sound.
The story of the ocean is one of fierce
and natural struggle for survival,
but also surely one of tenderness.
with rising temperatures,
massive sections of ice floe
are melting away.
Arctic waters will soon be open
to commercial navigation.
what will become
of those who live there?
The animals themselves
cannot stand up for their survival.
The cries of endangered species
will remain unheard.
Yet never has the will to protect them
been so strong.
More and more, people all over the globe
slip into that weightless world,
crossing into a universe
of wonder and mystery.
A magical world
where even the tiniest of creatures
may shed some new light
on how our universe came to be.
They roam through dense forests,
flourishing in the depths.
They look and listen,
searching for answers
to age-old questions,
discovering brand-new mysteries
instead.
They marveI at a world
where giants can fly.
A world where our greatest fears
may prove unfounded.
where the most gruesome face
may just hide a smile.
where presumed enemies
could turn out to be harmless neighbors,
even companions
for an afternoon swim.
Now you've met them.
Now you know them,
not as mere specimens
or concepts or lessons,
but as living beings
who share a fragile planet with us.
Every breath we take
and every drop we drink
depends on a healthy ocean.
Now her life depends on us.
So instead of asking
"what exactly is the ocean?"
maybe we should be asking:
"who exactly are we?"
[DEMI LOVATO AND JOE JONAS'
"MAKE A wAVE" PLAYING]
[WATER BUBBLING]
[WHALES SINGING]