Coming!
- Hello.
Come in, Paula is in her room.
Hold on,
I want to talk dates for the holidays.
We already discussed it.
I know.
OK, what?
This year,
I'd like to swap July for August.
- What for?
- So Paula can go to Ojos Negros.
You haven't been there for years.
I'd like her to stay with my mother.
- She barely knows her.
- So they can get to know each other.
I don't know...
We've already made a plan...
See if you can go some other time.
I think it's easier for you
to change dates.
Easier for me?
The deal was she's with you in July
and with me in August.
In August...
There are the festivities.
So what?
Well, there'll be more going on,
she'll have more fun.
I'll be 8 months pregnant by then,
I'm not sure I'll be able
to spend time with her.
So she'll be on her own?
Not at all!
She'll be with my mum and my sister.
Oh, fantastic...
- Fuck, Miguel...
- No, not "fuck", Celia.
I'm not changing my plans
just because it suits you.
- It's always about you!
- I'm asking a favour.
OK, and I'm saying no!
That's it.
Don't yell at me.
Mum is old,
she wants to see her granddaughter.
You've never shown
any interest in your family!
Not once.
You want to fix everything now?
- Yes, I do!
- That isn't how things work.
- Miguel...
- Get your coat. I'll call Paula.
- Get your coat and get out!
- Don't shout.
I'm not shouting!
You're making me angry.
I said no.
What can't you understand?
Take your coat and bag, please.
I'll get Paula.
Then you'll figure something out.
Do you remember the house?
You were a kid last time.
Not much.
But Mum showed me pictures.
Close the trunk.
Your room.
This is your bed.
It was your mother's.
You can start unpacking.
Put your underwear in the top drawer,
the two bottom ones are full.
Celia, Mum and me.
Mind out the way.
There are more photos in the attic.
You can go up and see them.
OK.
Elba...
Where's the bathroom?
I'd like a shower.
It's upstairs.
Go slowly, Mum.
Look, Mum. There she is.
What do you say?
She's all grown up.
Give me a hug!
I'm so happy to see you.
You've grown so much.
Eat up, Mum.
Did you clean Celia's sheets?
Yes, Mum.
And it's Paula, not Celia.
And the nightdress,
is it clean and pretty?
Yes.
I've been so looking forward to
seeing you sitting here at the table.
Well, Mum, she's here now.
She could've come before.
I'm not the one
you should be telling.
- Wait, she might wake up!
- Don't worry, it's fine.
Would she be scared?
- Wait, wait...
- OK.
How did this tree grow?
It grew because a fruit fell,
and a small tree grew from it,
but look how big it is now.
It's a loquat,
or some name like that.
The fruits had stones inside
and were a bit tough.
And what's this tree?
That's a loquat.
And that other one is...
- Do you know what this one is?
- What?
- What sort of tree is this?
- I don't know.
It has these little things here,
but I don't know what it is.
I can recognise a fig tree.
- Are these fruits?
- No, they look like grapes.
But I don't think they're edible.
I don't think so.
This one here has grown so big.
It used to be small,
but look how big it's got.
- This one?
- Yes, yes.
You know,
that's the thing about trees.
You plant them and then
in a year or two, they grow big.
Give me your bike!
My cousin's in that car!
- He could kill someone!
- Carlos, stop!
Stop him!
Are you crazy?
Let's go.
Thanks.
- How did you do this? Did you fall?
- I fell off my bike.
Fell off your bike?
It’s good that you came to see me.
It could've got worse.
- Are you going to tell your grandma?
- No.
- Do you often hit him like that?
- He's a kid.
He has to learn.
And you're not a kid?
No.
And neither are you.
See?
It doesn't hurt anymore, does it?
He's my son.
His name's Carlos.
I don't believe that.
- Why?
- Because it's a lie.
Don't you ever lie?
- Not much. Do you?
- I lie all the time.
- Why?
- Because it's funny.
- Here's another quail.
- I have enough, Rodrigo.
There are three of you to eat them.
Jara!
Stop it! Jara!
Let me introduce a family friend.
- This is Rodrigo.
- Hello.
- Here for a few days?
- For the summer.
Nice.
She'll probably want to stay.
Ladies, I have to go.
Come on, Jara, let's go.
Up you get!
Alicia!
You first.
Now the new girl!
Go, Alicia!
Is that her?
Yes.
She doesn't look like you at all.
She doesn't look like my mum either.
Is she with that guy?
I know him.
His dog ate my grandma’s chickens.
What do you think of him?
I don't like him.
Your grandma wanted to see you.
Go see her now
and leave this to me.
I'll do it.
Grab the collar.
I'm scared.
If you hold her like this,
she won't hurt you.
Come on.
Let's go.
Hurry up!
Here.
Come on, move.
Come on.
Push her.
- What now?
- Wait, I'll throw something.
Let's go!
Is that a fish?
Paula! Did you see that fish?
What fish?
Jara!
Jara, come here!
Paula, I need to come in.
You need to shower faster.
We only have one bathroom.
And you don't need to lock the door.
- Are you going out?
- Yes.
Take care of your grandma.
Do they hurt a lot?
No.
Do you want to stop?
This place looks familiar.
Maybe you've seen photos of it.
One time, my mum showed me
pictures of her when she was young
and I started crying.
Why?
Because so much time had passed
and it meant she was getting older.
I had something similar.
What?
I asked my mum
what happens after we die.
She told me some people believe
that there's another life,
but we don't remember this one.
So I was sad because
I thought I wouldn't remember
my family or my friends.
I cried for like three weeks.
Heels was a stupid idea.
Yeah.
I won't wear them when I grow up.
Yeah, sure.
I'm never going to grow up.
That one. That one!
Quick!
One, two, three!
I won again.
Mine was much heavier.
No. I won.
What do you do
with your mates in Zaragoza?
Nothing much.
I hardly see them.
Why not?
They're a bit boring.
I'm not interested in what they do.
So I'm not boring?
Well...
You're different.
And you do cool things.
You're cool too.
Luckily, it wasn't serious.
Yes, but she still had quite a scare.
Don't put it there,
you'll stain the cloth.
We brought roast chicken.
Not much though.
I wasn't expecting you to be here.
Where are you going?
Pass me the plates, please.
Hold on.
Do you need anything else?
Is she home?
Yes, Mum. She's in her room.
Hold on, I'll help you lie down.
My back hurts...
OK, Mum,
we'll soon be at the hospital.
Let me close the door.
What are you thinking about?
About the party.
No, you weren't.
I know.
So what is it?
Nothing.
Aren't you going to tell me?
I remember the first time we spoke.
I knew then we could be friends.
I was thinking that next summer
I could bring my dad's tent
and we could stay longer here.
Would you like that?
Yes, but I'm not sure
I'll come next year.
Why wouldn't you?
You come every year.
But it's not up to me.
It's up to my parents.
Will you definitely come back?
I don't know.
But you could always come visit me.
I don't think they'd let me.
- Why not?
- Because they don't know you.
Yeah, but my dad could talk to them.
But I don't know if I want to.
What's the problem?
I don't know, Paula,
we live so far away.
- So what?
- We won't see each other.
We'll end up forgetting each other.
What makes you think that?
I won't forget you.
You don't understand, Paula.
Hi, Celia, it's me.
Mum is very ill.
When are you coming?
I see.
Can't it be any sooner?
- May I come in?
- Yes, sweetie, come.
Sit here with me.
You haven't come to say goodnight
these last few days.
- Are you angry with me?
- No.
- Have you made some friends?
- Yes, a few.
Do you like them very much,
and do they like you?
Yes.
And which one likes you most,
and who do you like the most?
Well, there's a girl
I get on well with.
What's her name?
Alicia.
Well, now that you have friends here,
you'll come back...
next summer...
and you'll come to see me too,
won't you?
Yes.
Come and dance.
You know you want to.
No, I'm fine.
I don't really like dancing.
What's wrong?
Are you tired?
A bit.
Come on.
We all know you want to dance.
- Wow, Alicia.
- Nice one!
Fuck!
Not this weekend,
but maybe for the party.
So has she been good?
Yes, very good.
She adapted really well.
She's very polite.
Made lots of friends.
Well, a few.
She's a sweetheart.
Aren't you going to ask me about Mum?
Yes, of course.
How's Mum?
Don't bother, Celia.
Don't give me that!
I'm tired too, you know.
- You haven't helped at all.
- Don't say that.
I say what I want in my own house.
You're so ungrateful.
- You poor victim.
- No, poor you!
You turn up like a princess
expecting everyone to admire you
and your wonderful life.
You don't care about us.
There were other options.
Not here there weren't.
A sick woman
can't be left alone here.
You've never once asked
if we needed help
with the bills,
or anything for that matter!
That's just pure selfishness.
No other name for it.
I don't feel guilty
for choosing to live my life.
You could've done the same.
- Don't blame me.
- As I said,
you've lived your life
and done what you wanted.
You decided to take
and I decided to give.
No, wait, I had no choice,
because you never helped,
despite being her daughter too.
Did you expect me to stay
where I wasn't wanted?
Come on, Elba.
Darling! There you are.
How are you?
Fine.
- I thought you were coming next week.
- I took my holidays early.
- Why? Want to come home already?
- Yeah.
A friend of yours came by earlier.
I think she wanted to say goodbye.
Alicia?
I don't know.
I don't know her name.
A blonde.
Is she leaving?
Looks like it.
Can I go out for a while?
Wait until after lunch.
I need to go now.
Paula, don't be stubborn.
Wait a while, OK?
- I have to go now.
- Paula!
- Do you want sugar?
- No.
We're leaving now.
Have you packed your suitcase?
No.
We're not leaving until after lunch.
We can do it together.
Goodnight, sweetie.
Goodnight.