Hey, coach,
uh, it's Penelope.
Just calling to say, um
that I'm freaking out
a little bit.
I think, just basically,
I feel like
I've prepared for this,
obviously, my whole life.
And now that I am here, um,
I just really wanted to be,
exactly what I hoped
I would be, you know?
'Cause, otherwise,
what are you doing
with your whole life
up until that point?
I just really, really
wanted to be,
that thing that I,
that I wanted to be.
If not, then that's
the hard part about,
having a dream come true.
Sorry, you know what?
I'm squeezing too tight again.
But, I hope I really feel
like an Olympian,
when it's done.
I mean, I don't know
how much of that,
is in my control or not.
It seems like it's gonna be
really cool,
so, I probably shouldn't
freak out so much,
but, just being here alone
is sort of like,
you just have
a lot of time to think.
And, um, I guess just today,
is one of those
sensitive days, you know?
And, 'cause, yeah...
just call me, um...
...if you have time.
Uh, and if not, that's okay.
Um, I will...
...like, talk to you later.
Okay, thanks for everything.
Bye.
Stupid.
Yes, um, I'm registering, uh..
Okay, I'm a dentist.
A volunteer.
Do you know where I register?
- No, I don't know. Yeah.
- You don't know? Okay.
Excuse me, do you know
where the medical center is?
- I'm a volunteer dentist.
- Ah!
- Go inside and..
- Yeah. Ask there?
Alright, I'll just keep
wandering.
Thank you.
- Oh! Hi.
- Hey! Hey.
Um, I'm Maggie.
I live down the hall.
- Penelope. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Um, so you're an athlete too?
Yup, I'm an athlete.
Cross-country skiing.
What about you?
- Uh, Mogul skiing.
- Cool.
I was gonna grab some food.
- You wanted to join?
- Oh, cool.
Um, cool, but I'm gonna just
take a nap because my race
is in--
It's right after the opening
ceremony.
So, I just gotta.. - Ok.
- You know, like, get the..
- Yeah. I got you.
- Rest.
- I'll let you have your space.
- Okay, cool, thanks.
- Um, nice to meet you.
- Yeah, but after..
I'm gonna take you up
on that meal.
- Okay.
- Okay, Yeah.
Um....
Okay.
Hey, Kristi, um, ahem.
Good, uh, morning
or... goodnight.
I don't know what time of the
day it is where you are
but, um, I just wanted
to let you know
that I, um, have settled in
and set my office up,
and, um, I know that,
we are like on a break,
and not supposed to be talking--
I can't remember
what the rule was.
But, if I'm breaking the rule,
then I'm sorry.
Um, but, just, uh, the
CliffsNotes is..
It's bananas.
Anyway, uh,
yeah, give me a call,
if you're around and we will
catch up at some point. Bye.
So my name is Dr. E.
It's Ezra,
but you can call me Dr. E.
- How do you feel?
- Excited.
- Yeah? Are you nervous?
- Yes. A little bit.
- Is this your first Olympics?
- Yes.
You want to go
in circles like that, you know?
And you want to get
up into the gums.
But you don't want to go
too hard into the gums, right?
Some people don't like flossing.
My fiancee-- My ex... blah, blah,
whatever you want to call it,
Kristie.
She doesn't like flossing,
and I'm like,
"Can you just get in there
a little bit
every once in a while,
it's preventative."
But that is not your problem.
Your problem is making sure that
you take care of your gums.
And if any of the Estonians
need any dental care
tell 'em to come
to Dr. E.
- Dr. E. Okay.
- Okay. Alright.
Thank you.
Um, can I have some chicken,
please?
Are you a..
You're a oral surgeon?
- Yes, I'm oral surgeon. Okay.
- You're a dentist?
I'm just a dentist.
Is the money better?
- Yeah.
- The money's better.
Altogether we'll do a selfie.
We'll do a selfie. Ready?
Hey!
Thank you so much.
Ladies and gentlemen, the
athletes of the Pyeong Chang
2018 Olympic Winter Games.
Greece.
Switzerland.
Ireland.
Republic of Korea
marching together as Korea.
Hi, uh, is this seat taken?
No.
- You like bananas?
- Sorry.
You like bananas?
Yes.
Are you competing?
- What? Yes.
- Are you competing?
- Oh, awesome.
- I'm competing.
What's your, uh..
I'm sorry.
I'm a cross-country skier
and I'm competing today.
- Wow! How do you feel?
- I feel good.
Yeah? Is there..
Are you nervous? Is it like...
- I'm so sorry. I totally..
- It's okay.
Like it's.. It is totally fine.
I just,
I got to do what I'm gonna do.
- I like, I have to do this.
- I know, I know, I'm sorry.
Well, just my last thing
is that, I'm a dentist here.
So, like, I would be remiss
if I didn't give you some of
these little floss things.
They're really good
for blood flow when you floss.
So just think about it,
consider it.
No pressure. I'm so sorry.
- What's your name?
- Penelope.
Penelope, I'm Ezra.
- You're gonna kick ass today.
- Thank you.
And I'll leave you alone
and I'm so sorry
for screwing up your stuff.
- It's okay.
- Good luck.
I believe in you
and I'm rooting for you.
- Okay. Break a leg.
- Bye. Bye.
You idiot.
There was a race I think today.
Um, this girl, Penelope raced.
You don't know how -- how
she did, do you?
No, I don't. The weather's
pretty brutal out there.
Maybe, I don't know
if that maybe would have,
been a factor in her race.
But I haven't... haven't heard
much. - Yeah.
Is it super cold
up on the mountain?
Oh, it's cold and so windy.
There's a cross-country meet
in the women's,
do you know,
I don't know if you saw,
how a girl named Penelope did?
No, I don't, I don't.
Cause I've been in the office
all day.
I think she was racing today,
so I'm just --
- I don't know Penelope.
- Alright, okay, man.
Hello? Hey, coach, hey.
I'm, actually,
with all my new friends.
Yeah, we're in the locker room.
All the girls from my race
were all, like, hugging.
We've been, like,
hugging each other,
for a really long time
since the race.
All together. So cool.
I kind of wished I'd placed
higher, to be honest.
But I know, like,
I did my best.
It just went by
really quickly, I guess.
So, I'm still taking it all in.
I just don't know if it feels
how I wanted it to feel.
Come in.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How are ya?
- Good.
- Whatcha reading?
- Just a GRE book.
What's it about?
Oh, it's really boring.
I went to a medal ceremony.
Um, just to watch
and it was, like..
I felt, like, kind of selfish.
Because, I was, like,
happy for them,
but, then I wasn't happy
for them.
I didn't feel like
I would ever be up there.
Yeah, I definitely feel
that selfish feeling
of being lost
and knowing that, like,
that could've been me
if I did something else.
If I could have changed
something.
I want right now
to know what's...
...next,
and I don't.
I know what you're feeling.
I don't have it together either.
I just, I'm making sure that I
don't ruin my own experience
by letting that one run,
gonna dictate how I spend
the rest of my time.
And, I guess,
I just wanna make sure,
you know, like,
this isn't the end.
You too. You too.
Can we stay friends,
like, after this?
- Yes, please. I like that.
- Okay. Okay.
Oh! Ooh!
- Hi.
I'm Ezra, the dentist guy,
I met you. How..
- How are you?
- Good.
- Can I sit?
- Yeah.
I came outside and I saw you
sitting alone,
and, uh, I swear I'm not, like,
a creep, I just, uh...
I just don't know that many
people and I talked
to you already, and so I felt
like I could talk to you again.
I'm never outside.
It's so cold.
Do you wanna get, like,
a hot chocolate or something?
I'm glad, uh....
Thank you for getting, uh...
I'm sorry they
didn't have cocoa
they just had coffee, but,
- That's okay. I'm..
- It's warm.
It's warm and I'm not gonna
sleep anyway.
I...
...got you this.
- You got me a stuffed animal?
- I got you a stuffed animal.
I, uh--
You looked kinda bummed out.
And, so, I thought that
would maybe, like,
make you feel
a little bit better.
I...
...want to feel like
this person.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I get it, I think.
I mean, it's got goggles.
- How old are you?
- Thirty-seven.
- Twenty-two.
Twenty-two, wow!
That's, like..
- Old.
- Young.
I got here yesterday evening.
But everyone else got here a few
days before that, right?
Yeah, well,
they called me two days ago.
Really?
'Cause someone got injured,
and so I gotta replace them.
Did you always know you wanted
to go to the Olympics?
Yeah, it's like
every child's dream.
- Oh....
- Hey!
- Hi.
- Hi, how's it goin'?
- Good.
- I'm Penelope.
- Seamus.
- Seamus. Nice to meet you.
- Yes. Pleasure, Penelope.
Part of the reasons
why I started snowboarding,
was to catch air
and be in the sky,
though, like,
that sense of flying.
And if I can do that
every day for a job,
then I think I, you know,
sweat to have.
Camaraderie at its finest.
What's your-- What are you
guys, what's your sport?
- We snowboard half-pipe.
- Snowboard half-pipe.
And you guys all know each
other a long time?
- Yeah, we're homies.
- You guys are homies?
- Yeah.
- That's nice.
I got a group of friends
that I've been tight
with since college.
We all kind of live
in different cities now.
Just about everybody's married.
One of my buddies is divorced.
He's got a kid.
Just don't wanna make that
mistake and then end up,
in a position
where you're, like,
did I marry the right person?
- Right.
- Are you guys married?
Any of you guys together,
you guys..
- No? Single?
- Single.
How is the single life
here at the games?
- It's good.
- Pretty good.
Say brah. I'm joking.
Penelope, I'm Anthony.
Nice to meet you.
How it works in skeleton is,
you literally have to lay there.
Naturally, you have to steer.
And like a lot of people ask,
like, how do you steer?
And you know, like,
you know the song,
"Head, Shoulders,
Knees and Toes?"
- Yes.
- That's how we steer.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Straightaways, head steer,
is just tilting your head
this way.
Curves, shoulders.
Hard pressure curves is knees
and shoulders.
And then emergency steers if you
need to do something immediate
with your sled, drop a toe.
That's so cool.
That's so weird.
So, but, you know,
you overthink it too much
you'll drive yourself
into a wall.
That's why I'm here,
just trying to
forget about some things
so that I can go
and enjoy it even though
it's the biggest
race of my life.
Nico. From New Zealand, huh?
So, I'm just gonna check your
lymph nodes.
- Cool, sweet ass.
- What does that mean, sweet as?
It means, I don't know,
I guess, cool.
- How old are you?
- Sixteen.
Sixteen. Are you,
are you the youngest Olympian?
Mm-hmm.
Youngest male, I think.
- Have you broken anything?
- I've broken my pelvis.
- It's, it's heavy.
- I know. Yeah.
What did it feel like when it
was on you?
Well, yeah, a dream came true.
A dream did come true.
This is, like, it's beautiful.
I mean, you're very
beautiful too,
so, I'm sure it looked very--
I'm sure it looked like it
belonged on you.
Thanks.
I mean it.
Oh, I think we have to go.
- Can I have my --
- Okay. Yeah, of course.
- Thanks. Sorry.
- No problem.
Congratul--
Congrats again.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Okay, bye, have fun.
Bye. Bye.
Hi.
I don't have an appointment,
but, I was hoping
that I might be able to,
see the dentist?
- Yes. When?
- Now.
- Okay.
Come and sit.
Hi.
Nice to see you again.
How are ya?
- I am well. How are you?
- What brings you here?
- I'm here to see the dentist.
- Hey!
- I'm the dentist.
- You are.
Nice to see you.
I said that already.
Uh, okay, take off your glove.
And, you know,
lose the jacket.
When was, uh, your last
dental checkup?
- Two months ago.
- Two months ago, so you --
But, but I've been,
since my race, eating...
an obscene amount of brownies.
- Right.
- So I may have..
How quickly can you develop
a cavity?
Can you have one in a day?
No, you can't get one in a day.
But I'll check you out.
It's better safe than sorry.
That's what I always say.
Always--
Getting a checkup
never is a bad idea.
So let's take a look and --
Why did you decide to come here?
To the Olympics?
'Cause, um...
I love the Olympics.
Like, it's like,
since I was like--
I mean, I remember the
'88 Olympics, it was in Seoul.
- I wasn't even born.
- You weren't even born yet.
I read somewhere that, like,
they have volunteers
who are doctors and dentists,
and I had to apply,
and then I didn't hear anything
and I assumed I didn't get it.
And then like a month ago
I heard, like, you --
- A month ago?
- Yeah. "You've been accepted," so..
How did you just come here then?
- You just left? Do you work?
- Do I work, yes, yeah.
I mean, are there people that
are sad now that you're gone?
Are there people that miss you,
whose teeth are--
That I couldn't tell you. Those
other people could tell you.
I mean, are there patients,
my patients?
No, the truth is I work at,
like, a clinic
where we get assigned patients.
I don't have that many recurring
patients.
I mean, I think people like
coming to me.
What about your family?
Oh, my parents were really
psyched.
They knew I loved the Olympics
and they were thrilled
that I was gonna go do this.
What about your kids?
Oh, I don't have any kids.
Um, do you have a wife?
I do not have a wife.
Um, I have..
A girlfriend?
- Um, I have a --
- Boyfriend.
No, no boyfriend.
Um, there's a woman
um, in New Jersey
named Kristi who is...
- Does she know you're here?
- She does know I'm here.
But she doesn't know that,
I can't seem to do my dental
examination, so...
Everyone in New Jersey's asleep.
Great. Good to know. Okay.
What I'm doing now is checking
your lymph nodes
and your thyroid
to just see if there's any sort
of, like, oral cancer.
- Um..
- What are you doing later?
Uh, later I'm gonna
open your mouth
and see if you have any
cavities.
And what are you doing
after that?
I'm gonna see if there are any
more patients and then close up
and probably get
some food or something.
I don't know.
Do you wanna go to
the game room?
Um...
Uh, yeah. Sure.
So, this is, like, where
everybody, like, hangs out, huh?
Yep. Yeah.
- Do you wanna play foosball?
- Yeah.
Great. Um...
- Or we could play air hockey.
- Or --
Tiny pinball?
Oh, you don't seem--
Oh, you wanna get a massage?
Ooh, they've got those massage
chairs over here.
Do you wanna,
do you wanna get outta here?
Like, go to, like,
the dining hall or, like...
No, like, leave.
Like, leave the Olympic Village?
Yeah, like not, like,
change out of my--
out of our uniforms
and go do something.
Like, go have a night out
together.
- If you're free.
- In, like, like, in Korea?
Yes. Let's go out in Korea.
- And I...
- Like, I haven't seen anything.
Thank you.
- You wanna go this way?
- Yeah.
Yeah, why would you wanna look
at Olympic rings
when you could look at
human skulls?
You think we're allowed to
light these things on fire?
- Look at that.
- Well, have you done art stuff in the past?
No, I haven't done any art.
I have no creative side to me.
But I like art.
I have an idea.
Let's go eat Korean food.
Okay.
Anything but the dining hall.
You got it.
- Well, what do you think?
- Yeah.
Two people.
Can we sit here?
Thank you.
What about spicy noodles,
is that spicy?
The noodles are no spicy.
Is this spicy?
Whoa.
This is so hot.
This is great.
You wanna race?
Oh, I bet you do.
I bet you kinda wanna race.
I will beat you.
- What is this?
- Let's go in.
What is it?
They're like athletes
in the computer world.
Come on.
This is, like,
their training center.
What I'm wondering is where are
all the girls?
Like, are there any girls here?
- I don't know.
- I see one. I see a girl.
I mean, this reminds me of,
like, the saddest years of my,
like, middle school
and high school.
Like, playing video games
with my friends.
You don't get it.
You really don't get it.
I guess they're, like,
super-competitive like you are?
Yes! And they're dedicated.
Like, they're down here doing
whatever their thing is.
Like, it's awesome, right?
It's, like, so cool.
Like, are--what are you
laughing--
- Are you laughing?
- I just get a kick out of you.
She was in college.
But you came home from school
to go to prom?
Yeah, I had a crush on her.
I thought maybe
if I went to the prom with her,
you know...
something would happen.
But it didn't.
- Didn't happen.
- It did not happen.
- Did you go to your prom?
- No.
I, I had a race
in New Zealand and I--
I didn't feel like
missing the race for prom.
- I missed every homecoming.
- Oh, man.
I missed homecoming.
I missed everybody's
birthday party,
everybody's Bar Mitzvah,
everybody's everything.
But you've competed in the
Olympics.
Like, wasn't this like--
- It was awesome.
- Yeah.
And now it's over.
But, like, is it over?
I mean, does it have to be over?
- You can go back, right?
- Yeah.
I've no plans and--
That's okay.
No, it's not.
People who don't have plans
end up, like--
- Becoming dentists?
- No, you went to school.
People without plans end up moving back in with their parents.
Can you imagine moving back in
with your parents?
- Free food.
- I am not--
- Laundry.
- You don't know my...
I love my dad but I'm...
Don't need to move back
in with him.
I can't, I don't know
what the fuck I'm gonna do.
How old are you, 22?
- Twenty-two.
You got your whole life ahead of
you to figure it out
like, maybe you're gonna become
a professional dancer.
Perhaps you'll go off and become
a StarCraft East Board Champion.
Or maybe you'll just,
like, go, like
work in like a chicken factory,
or like--
- Flowers.
Maybe you'll grow flowers
in like
an old storage container
that they've transitioned, like,
an organic flower thing.
Or, maybe, you'll work
for a food co-op or,
maybe you'll go become a
high-powered executive
for a sneaker company.
Or maybe you'll just, like,
sit at home and eat Doritos
for, like, two years and put on,
like, 300 pounds.
Or maybe you'll
make fake throw vests.
Or just be okay.
Hey, exclamation point.
I just saw your text,
exclamation point.
Sorry about that,
Everything is cool here
and I am really happy
to hear from you
exclamation point, exclamation
point, exclamation point.
Is this too many
exclamation points
question mark,
exclamation point?
Uh, bye.
But also, hi.
Exclamation point.
- Ezra!
- Hi.
I see you everywhere.
Do you wanna come with me to
some games or something?
Like, some practices,
sneak around a little bit?
Oh, that sounds awesome.
I feel like I should just
take care of, like
laundry-ish kind of
stuff today, but--
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
- But thank you, that's so --
No, it's not like you can't
do laundry at any other day
of your life.
But today I am inviting you to
literally go backstage
on the ice, like, whatever
you want with my athlete pass,
and you're saying no.
- Okay, okay, I'll go.
- Right?
Whoa.
I can't even fathom doing this.
- This is crazy.
- This is, like..
Do you think anyone watches me
race and thinks
this is amazing?
Yeah, those ski jumpers,
they can't do what you do
and you can't do what they do
and that's what makes this all
so special.
Could you imagine,
like if your life depended on it, could you do that?
Oh, I definitely couldn't.
You know, this guy I sat next to
in the dining hall
the other day he does this.
And he was just sitting there
eating a hamburger.
These are the bravest women
in the world.
Like, they are so committed.
Like, once they go,
they are going.
- Yeah.
- They can't stop.
They're just gonna throw
themselves down
like an ice slide head first.
Also, who knows what they're
like in their personal lives?
Like, maybe they're scared of
stuff in their real life.
But on, when they're
doing skeleton
it's just balls to the wall.
I would just, like, fall.
I feel like I would fall before
I even got on the ice.
No, I feel like I get it.
I feel like I--
- You feel like you could do it?
- I don't know.
I just, I know that feeling
a little bit of, like,
- I know that feeling.
- Yeah.
Everything has a purpose in this
sport. Each shoe has a purpose.
The broom, like,
they're like little well-oiled machines with each other.
And two people who know,
like, who they are
and they're there for each other,
but they also are confident.
I'm reading a lot into this,
as you can see.
It's good, it's not bad.
And you know that they work
full-time
right, a lot of them?
So you could do it,
you know, like, you..
Sorry.
Do you think that they're
banging?
Do you think that they ever
have, or do you..
I mean, you've gotta figure
some of these couples
are together, right?
Come on.
- I've made dinner.
- Okay.
No, we're going out tonight.
- Cocoa.
- Hot chocolate.
- Thank you.
- Hot chocolate!
It's like... It smells like
a cartoon of hot chocolate
you know, it smells, like,
perfect.
- Cheers.
- Thank you.
You're very good at making
people feel
good going to the dentist.
- Like, I had...
- You had a pleasant experience?
I had a very pleasant
experience.
Your experience with me
at the dentist.
- Yeah. It's like, you're not afraid..
- Thank you.
- So I'm not afraid sort of thing.
- Oh, good.
That's nice.
That's nice to hear.
I just don't like my office.
Why, 'cause it's
not really yours?
I don't like where I work.
I don't like... I'm not...
- What do you want?
- Um, what do I want?
I would like to have like
a family practice that I,
you know, start with a kid
who's, like, little,
and watch him grow up
and send him off to college,
and, I mean, not personally.
Like, I'd let his parents send
him to college.
But, like,
I want like a Ms. Pacman
in -- in the waiting room.
And, that feels more, like,
personal.
That's awesome. That's--
I feel like you can hear someone
say something and you can be
like, he has a complaint
or he has a goal.
And I'm choosing to hear that
you have a goal.
That you have your own thing
one day.
- That's--
- What about you?
I'm also figuring out
what my goal is.
Like, it can be that I commit to
another Olympics cycle
and do it for four more years,
or I don't.
How could you not?
You're like a total badass.
Like, you're like this, like..
Like this, like,
warrior princess.
So whether you decide
to go do the Olympics
or go do something else
like, you know,
you're just, like--
You'll be able to do it.
'Cause you're...
very talented.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Is everything okay?
- Well, it was, uh, was fine.
- Okay.
Uh...
Do you wanna kiss me?
It's not quite that simple.
- It's pretty simple.
- It's kinda not.
I have, like, a fiancee.
- I thought you were on a break.
- We are, we're on a break --
- So then this is all good.
But I don't know what
it's gonna be like!
Yeah, but it's like, who cares?
Like, we're just hanging out
and...
I know. It's just, like,
not as simple as, like,
'what do I want', like--
No, it really is.
You just, like
pick things that you
wanna do and you do them.
It's easy for you to
have that philosophy,
because, you're, like,
this Olympic athlete
who's, like, sort of
gets to be a little more
selfish with how you choose to
do the things you do,
where you're, like,
I need to eat, I need to sleep,
I need to kiss,
I need to do whatever.
And you, like, go after your
goal and you do your thing--
That's, like, so insulting,
Ezra.
I'm telling you what I want.
And I'm getting back from you
that you don't even know
what you want.
And that's really dumb,
and not brave.
- It's like, it's cowardly.
- Okay. Okay.
Well, if you decide, like,
you don't wanna continue going to the Olympics,
you could maybe become
a psychotherapist,
'cause, you've clearly diagnosed
me.
No, that is really mean.
But, calling me not brave isn't?
I wanna go home.
Great. Well, you're leaving in
three days, so...
- To the Village.
- Even better.
- Excuse me, can I sit here?
- Yeah.
- Hey!
- Hey. Did I forget something?
- Yeah, I know, here's a--
- I'm in a rush. I need to re--
Yeah, no. I just wanted to give
you a toothbrush.
Oh, thank you, so kind.
So, if you've got
anything you need--
- Okay, I'll just walk with you.
- Alright.
Does the Turkish team
need a dentist or anything like
a full-time dentist?
No, no, sorry.
- I like your boots.
- Oh, you like?
Yeah. They're cool.
This is a Japanese
official uniform.
Okay, yeah.
Do you know is the Japanese team
looking for a dentist?
No, no, sorry.
Nobody wants a dentist now.
- No.
- Sorry.
That's okay.
Nobody wants a dentist.
Except when they got a cavity.
- Do you speak English?
- Yes.
- You do?
- Is anyone sitting here?
- Nope.
- Do you mind if I do?
- I don't mind.
Okay. Or laying down here,
I should say.
That one is, like,
pre-loaded for you.
Take a nap really quick.
- How's it goin'?
- Good.
- I'm Gus. - Penelope.
- Penelope.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, too.
What sport are you?
Ski slope style. And you?
I am cross-country skiing
and I feel embarrassed,
but, have you...
- Competed yet?
- Yeah.
- No, a couple of days.
- Okay.
- Have you?
- I'm done.
How did it go?
Uh, it was-- It was...
Sorry, this thing is..
Do you know how these..
I get--
I think I just turned it off.
Um, I don't speak Korean, no.
- I will figure this out.
- I just pushed some buttons.
Okay, yeah, I'll just,
whatever. Um, I..
I feel like this is a good
choice.
Yes, the neck massage.
- I did a personal best.
- That's awesome.
Yes, it is all I can ask for,
I think.
- Congrats.
- Thank you.
Well, if you feel like
celebrating
a bunch of guys in my building
are having a party tonight.
Um, I don't know if that
interests you
but I was sent out to bring back
cute girls.
So, I figured at the least
I could invite you.
- I would come.
- Yeah, you wanna come?
Yeah, yes, I do.
- Hi.
- I know.
I'm gonna do another one.
- How's it goin'?
- It's good.
- Are you done competing?
- I have one more event.
- We figure earlier today.
- Oh, my gosh.
It was frickin' crazy.
Fell on my first run.
Was just, like,
a little shooken up.
And then, thankfully, put it
down on my second run.
I'm done competing and I'm
gonna try to enjoy tonight.
Well, good!
I'm so grateful my boyfriend's
here, so I like --
- Oh, he's a snowboarder?
- He's a snowboarder.
So I feel like that would be so,
like, hard, but awesome..
- Because they get it, you know.
- Exactly.
We live such different lives,
it's hard for people
to really comprehend
what's going on.
Yeah, it's a lifestyle and not
everyone understands it, right?
Maybe you'll meet your future
man here.
Maybe I will.
It's hard to miss when you're
putting your face into stuff.
Yeah, but, like, come on.
Like, I'll get the next one.
That's what I do.
I'm happy to be here, but I'm not, like,
super thrilled with my race.
And I feel like I can admit that to you 'cause you probably get it.
- Not everyone gets that.
- I mean, that sucks.
That's how, that's like the
hardest part of the sport thing.
- You get it.
- Yeah..
I mean, you work four years,
longer than that.
You have to remember that you
made it. Like, you did it.
- You're an Olympian.
- That's true.
- You'll always be an Olympian.
- You too.
I got the, I have a tattoo,
so I'm always--
- An Olympic one?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Let me see it.
- Do you--
- Where is it?
- It's on my arm.
Oh, I have one on my arm, too.
- Oh, my God, same.
- That's where yours is?
Yeah, but I'm wearing
a real bra
because I never do.
Oochie. That's okay.
Okay. Um, it is..
- Oh, yeah.
- Not bad?
That's awesome.
- Twins.
Is it okay, um, if I...
Um...
- I'm-- I'm gay.
- Oh.
- I-- I'm sorry, I thought--
- I didn't even see.
- I wouldn't have even known.
- I thought maybe you realized.
I-- I'm sorry.
- I hope I didn't lead you on.
- No, it's okay, you didn't.
Um, I just...
I'm having a really hard time
here and I just really...
I really need someone to kiss me
right now.
Like, I really need
someone to kiss me.
I know that you're not
attracted to me and it's--
Thank you.
That's what I needed.
- You okay?
- I'm good.
I'm sorry that I asked you
to do that.
That's okay. I'm sorry if I gave
you the wrong impression.
- No. Are we cool?
- Yeah, we're cool. You good?
I'm good if you're good.
I'm really good if you're good.
- I'm good.
- Okay.
- Do you wanna go get food?
- Yeah. You're really good.
There are so many people out
tonight.
I know. Like you'd think it'd be dead after 9:00,
but it's, like--
Most people are probably done
competing.
- Are you just having milk?
- Yes.
You don't drink milk?
Not after I've been drinking
other stuff.
- How 'bout this guy?
- Cross-country skiing.
Cross-country skiing,
I agree with that.
I can identify
my own very easily.
Guy right here, this guy.
Right here, Norway.
Aerials. He's tiny.
Okay, you're better at this than me.
Because, like, I wouldn't have--
I mean, I don't know,
but that's my guess.
This guy, skiing...
- He smiles, yeah.
- Oh, he just smiled at you.
I don't know.
Hey, what about this guy?
- He's very strong.
- Honestly, I would.
- What? Really?
- Yeah, think so.
- What's your type?
- Like, kind of that.
At the last Olympics
one of the guys on my team
lost his virginity
during the games.
- Really?
- Yeah.
That's awesome!
That is so--
Is it awesome
or is it embarrassing?
No, that is, like,
way cooler than, like
on your parents', like,
floor or some, I don't wanna--
Like in the bathroom
at some high school party.
Yeah. It's so romantic.
Like, this place is romantic.
- Hey, are you the dentist guy?
- Yeah.
Ah, you, do you have any more
floss on you, by any chance?
Oh, sure. Yeah.
- Um, have you guys..
- Whoa!
- Yeah, maybe you could split those up.
- Thank you.
Have you guys
competed already? Or...
No, we're, we're going to,
we gotta run. We're kinda..
- Oh, cool! Well, good luck to you.
- Thanks.
- What's your race, what are yo --
- Skeleton.
Oh, wow, that's so cool. Wow.
Alright, well, good luck.
And maybe I'll come see you guys
at the race or something.
In a couple of days.
We gotta jam.
Okay, alright.
Take care, guys.
Would you hook up with that guy?
- Um, that guy.
- With the coffee?
- I--
- I think he's cute, actually.
He's kind of looking at you,
too.
That guy is a--
Named Ezra.
- He is a dentist.
- So you know him.
Ezra!
- Hello.
- Good evening.
- You're here late.
- Hi.
How's it goin'? I'm Gus.
- Hi, I'm Ezra.
- This is Gus.
Oh, what happened to your hand?
I just broke my thumb
the other day.
- It's not a big deal.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Good.
- Hi.
- Good to see you.
- Are you okay?
- I'm great.
- It's late.
- Yeah.
You have a good night?
- How many teeth did you clean today?
- He cleans a lot of teeth.
- So strange.
Ah, alright,
I'm gonna leave you guys to it.
You don't have to,
you're welcome to join.
- It's okay.
- Do you have any floss on you?
I don't have any on me,
I'm sorry.
It was really nice to meet you.
Yeah, it was nice to meet you,
too.
- Have a good night.
- Okay.
You too. Bye.
- Oh, my God.
- I know him.
- You were so rude.
- No, I wasn't.
"How many teeth
did you clean today?"
He cleans teeth.
It's like saying how many runs..
- I know, but...
- How many hours did you train?
No, if you said how long did you
work today,
that would be the same thing.
But how many teeth
did you clean?
It's so patronizing.
- You totally like him.
- No.
I got crazy energy.
Or you guys are hooking up
or you already did or something.
No. No.
None. None of the above.
Only... Nothing.
- Only floss.
- I don't believe you.
Oh, my God, you're blushing.
Soy milk.
Not my favorite kind of milk.
Yeah, it's soy milky.
Ah, Kristi. Hi.
Oh, I can't,
I can't hear what--
I can't hear--
I, uh, it's very bad reception
in here, let me...
Hi! Sorry, the reception's
terrible in there.
So, just, um,
it's wild over here.
I mean, it's freezing,
but it's been really..
Oh, um, oh, yes.
Ah, it's not broken,
you just need to unplug it
and then plug it back in.
And then there'll be, like,
a yellow light.
Um, so, how's that going, good?
Okay, great.
So, uh, how've you been?
How -- how are things? Oh.
Oh, yeah, no, I'll let you go.
Okay. Ah, sure.
- So you're from Greece?
- Yes.
As you see, a lot of blue,
white, everywhere.
- That's so cool.
- Yeah.
I've always wanted to go
swimming in Greece.
And my-- and my fiancee, my--
Yes, I understand.
She, I, she loves,
she says she loves the beach,
and I'm, like,
"Well, let's go to Greece"
and then she's like,
"Let's just go to Miami."
- Oh, no.
- And it's like, I don't wanna go... I wanna go to Greece.
- Can I ask you honestly?
- Yes?
So, we were together
and then we were engaged,
and then I said, "I might wanna
go to the Olympics."
Asked if she wanted to go.
She doesn't, she never wants to
leave the country.
She's scared of going to other
countries.
- And you like traveling.
- I like to travel.
Oh.
I don't know, I think you didn't
choose the right girlfriend.
Yeah.
So what's going on?
Why are you here?
Okay. Well, you've got a,
so for the... What's the...
Okay, that tooth is..
Sorry.
It's molar hurts.
Molar hurts.
This, which one?
When was the last time
you saw the dentist?
- What does that mean?
- It's been a long time.
- You speak English?
- Sometimes, yeah.
But you understand Italian,
so it's not a problem.
Yes, you're kind of just messing
with me a little bit.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Okay.
- It's good?
- Yeah, it's funny.
You really also should,
you should go to a dentist regularly.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry. I'm having a--
I'm not having a great day.
- So, I apologize.
- Me too.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Hey.
Funny running into you here.
- Everywhere.
- Yeah.
Ah, can we chat
for a few minutes?
Ah, I don't...
I was gonna go in there
and just kinda wander around.
Yeah, I-- I found like
a pretty cool spot.
I think you'd really enjoy it.
Hello. I just a..
I'm a volunteer.
I -- I left something in here
that I need to get.
It's pretty cool out here,
right?
It's, like, check it out,
it's still going.
It's like Hanukah!
The, the Festival of Lights.
Um..
If you can believe it,
I didn't bring you out here
to talk about Hanukah.
- Okay.
- Um...
I, I wanted to
apologize to you..
...for how things went down
the other day
at our chat,
whatever... that was.
Um..
In going back through it
I didn't really like
kinda what I said
or how I said it to you.
And I realize you were just
trying to encourage me
and I've been trying to
figure out why
I kinda said what I said.
And I think it's...
probably 'cause
I'm just sort of...
scared or afraid of stuff.
Ezra, do you think
I'm not afraid?
Like, I wasn't trying to say,
"Don't have fear."
Like, I wake up every day
a little bit afraid.
But it's the good fear.
It's like afraid for how well it can go.
And what I was hearing from you
very and clearly,
is that you want things.
You have goals
and you are not...
able to take them seriously.
And even the way that your
shoulders are.
Like, look at the way
you're walking.
Do you feel your shoulders?
They're like to the ground.
Your nose is to the ground,
you're not even on your own team.
Of course, I-- I understand
that.
Like, yes, I see that.
I don't like how I...
Don't tell me how to walk, okay?
'Cause I know how I walk,
and I don't like it, alright?
This is not stuff that is,
like, new to me, okay?
I wanna walk
with my shoulders back.
That's why I came
to the Olympics.
That's why I have been, like,
running around with you.
That's why I just snuck
into an Olympic stadium,
because, I wanna take more
risks.
And I wanna go home
and-- and start my own practice
and-- and follow through
on the stuff that I dream about.
And you inspire me to do that.
And that's,
that's what I wanna do.
I-- I wanna change things.
- That's awesome.
- So, yeah, thank you!
- You're welcome.
- Great!
- That's amazing.
- Yeah, it is amazing!
- So, we agree.
- We agree in an empty Olympic stadium!
We're on the same page!
So, like, let's enjoy our time
together, okay?
Okay, let's do it.
- Deal?
- Deal.
Okay, can we, can we go?
Why, are you so scared of
getting caught, 'cause I'm not.
- You're not fearful anymore.
- Let's get outta here.
I'm not afraid, I am Ezra.
I am--
- Look at this, like that.
- There you go! - Like that.
Have you ever seen
one of the athlete dorms?
- No, I haven't gone into any.
- They're very cool.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Are you inviting me in?
- Yes, I am.
- Okay. Alright.
- Okay.
Oh, uh... Sorry.
It's okay.
- I was--
- That is my secret.
- GREs, huh?
- Just in case.
- I don't know.
- Is this 'cause you're, like, what am I gonna do?
Yeah,
this is, like, just in case
I... am not qualified for a job,
which I'm not.
I will take a test, which will
allow me to apply for school,
which will qualify me
for a job, that is not--
So somebody's playing it a little safe, huh?
- Being--
Or somethin', no. You're keeping,
you're keeping your options open.
- Yeah, I'm just like, I don't know.
- I got it.
I didn't think you were gonna
find this, that's all.
- So, I'm gonna put it back under my bed.
- I hear you.
Did you think I would find
this little guy? Who's this?
It's like new to the family
and somebody delivered him.
Oh! Someone gave you this?
Someone thoughtfully gave you this?
Somebody, I was crying a little bit until somebody handed that to me.
- Can I ask you something?
- Yes, anything.
Will you take me skiing
tomorrow?
- Yes. Have you skied before?
- No.
Okay, that's... Yes.
However, I'm leaving tomorrow
so we'll have to go early.
- Great.
- Okay.
I'm just,
I'm just laughing at...
Um...
What?
It's just sort of, um...
Like, I don't even know if I'm
gonna tell my friends about you,
because, I don't really know
like what--
What is that? I don't know.
What are you gonna say?
I don't know, um, just like...
What?
You think I'm like
I'm gonna remember this.
Uh-huh.
- Well, I am.
- Yeah.
I figured. I will.
- I am, I'm gonna remember it.
- So will I.
Yeah.
You tired?
Don't be tired.
Okay.
Don't! Why?
- 'Cause... Yeah.
- It's my last night!
So you should just stay.
You should just--
- Okay.
- You don't have to lay here.
Just -- just lay. Just stay.
I'm not gonna do anything
to you.
I will even put these on while
you lay down. Then you won't--
- Just stay.
- Okay.
Oh, you wanna stay? Okay.
Then stay.
Okay.
I will put them in between us
so that nothing happens.
'Cause I know that,
like, makes you very nervous.
No, stop talking about that.
I know that you're--
Sorry, it's just like,
I think I, I think it's fine
to make a joke of it.
It's stupid.
- I can't really --
- Sleep?
I can't sleep.
I can't be still.
Well, how about, do you wanna
just sit here and talk?
- How about that?
- Okay, for a little bit.
- Give me your hand.
- Okay.
Your hands are very warm.
I am a very warm-blooded person.
I think I'm cold.
So this is good.
- No, your hands are warm.
- Really?
That's,
means this is very rare time.
- Oh, no.
- What's happening?
- Is someone--
- Oh, my God.
Is someone challenging me
to a thumb war?
- Someone is challenging you to a thumb war.
- One, two, three, four.
- Now I declare a thumb war.
- A thumb war.
This is like..
You're using your bicep!
That's not fair!
I'll do that, too.
No, you can't use your--
It's thumb war.
- Okay.
- Okay?
I'm sleeping. I don't know
what you're talking about.
That's cheating.
Arm down, thumb only.
You have such,
like, adult hands.
Like they've seen,
they've done so many things.
They have been in
so many mouths.
That's true.
That's so weird.
It's like,
have you touched more mouths than you've kissed people?
- And don't even answer that.
- That's for sure.
- Is that you?
- Mm-hmm.
Little skier?
You look so cute.
Aww..
Girl Scouts.
Talk about a happy little girl.
Oh, my God!
You're so cute.
And it's still you.
That's the,
that's the weirdest thing
about seeing pictures of people
when they're, like, little.
It's like, yeah, same person.
I'm gonna become an Olympic
cross-country skier, I think.
Watch, I'll show you right now.
Okay.
You're a star.
- Hey, you're like... Yeah.
- I did it.
I fell on an Olympic
cross-country course.
Oh. I feel good though.
- It feels good to fall?
- Yeah, oh, it feels good to fall.
My dad took me
for the first time.
And I thought
I was gonna hate it.
- And then you didn't.
- I didn't hate it.
This place is like my place.
The cold, but fresh...
Like, that's my smell.
I'm not done.
You're not done?
I'm not done yet.
I'm just really happy
right here.
I don't wanna be anywhere else.
And is that okay?
It's great.
It's the dream.
You've found something
that you like doing,
and you wanna keep doing it.
What more could you ask for?
Okay, let's...
Do you wanna go ski?
Alright, I should warn you.
I'm probably gonna
kick your ass, so...
Ezra, I'm leaving.
Oh. Ah...
Well, thank-- thank you
for coming by.
- Yeah.
- Um..
How are you go--
How are, how are...
Do you fly to Seoul?
Yeah, we take a train there
and then...
just straight shot...
Yeah.
...from there.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Ah, okay. Well...
I know I didn't have
a pin for you, but, of my own.
But I, um...
I thought you would
like this one.
- Whoa, a snowboarding pin!
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, that's awesome. Thank you.
I'd, I never wanted to, like,
ask the athletes for 'em
'cause I felt
like they were for--
They're so cool.
Well, they're athletes.
Thank you.
Come in.
Hi.
Thank you.
No problem, no problem.
Um, yeah, they've gotta..
Can you check my teeth?
Well, I checked your teeth,
they're fine. They're, you're...
I know, just in case.
Yeah, okay.
Um, please have a seat.
You've got your, uh,
snow globe ring again?
You've got a really nice teeth.
Do you know how I can keep them
this way forever?
You could see a,
a dentist regularly.
Um, can you do the thing
where you check my jaw?
T-M, TMJ?
- Uh-huh. Okay.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Open your mouth wide.
And close it.
I'm just looking to see
if the alignment is good.
And it really is.
- You got a good, healthy mouth.
- That's good.
And I'm just gonna check
your thyroid
your lymph nodes to make sure...
everything's okay.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
It's the best thyroids
I've ever seen.
Thank you.
You've got a good heartbeat.
I hope so.
Can you just check
one more time, please.
Please?
Can you please just check
one more time?
Please?
- Just in case?
- Um...
Actually, I think you're gonna
miss your bus.
I'm not gonna miss my bus.
Please.
Please?
Yeah, I have...
I have another patient, so..
Can't they wait?
No.
Okay.
Okay, bye.
Penelope!
Hi. I'm--
I-- I'm sorry that I...
I'm just sorry.
But I-- I want you to know,
like... you're the--
- What?
- You're the best thing that happened to me at the Olympics.
And that I think you're, like
amazing and you're,
you're so special.
And I just--
I just wanted to let you know that...
You're an Olympian!
You kicked ass at the Olympics.
And... just...
It's so cold here,
and you,
you made me feel so warm.
I can--
Thank you.
Excuse me, sir?
- Do you know this? Okay.
- I don't know, sorry. Sorry.
You're very helpful, you know?
- Really helpful.
- And, uh..
Look...
I'll see you in four years,
okay?
Deal?
Deal.
Okay.