CENTRAL PARTNERSHIP
TELESTO
FILM COMPANY
SVETLANA KHODCHENKOVA
STASYA MILOSLAVSKAYA
SERGEI PUSKEPALIS
ALEXEY BARABASH, KILILL DEGTYAR,
EVGENIY SYTIY
SOFIYA ERNST, HILDA KARMEN,
KRISTINA KUCHERENKO
WRITTEN BY EDUARD BORDUKOV,
ALEXANDER EGOROV, MIKHAIL KAKUBERI
ANTON SHANIN, ANNA SOBOLEVSKAYA,
IGOR GORDASHNIK
MUSIC BY:
OLEG BELOV, DMITRY EMELYANOV
OPERATOR:
MIKHAIL MILASHIN
PRODUCTION DESIGNER:
DENIS ISAEV
COSTUME DIRECTOR: NADIN DAY
MAKE-UP ARTIST: ALEXEY KLIMOV
MUSIC PRODUCER:
ALEXANDER FEDENEV
PICTURE EDITOR:
ALEXANDER KOSHELEV
EXECUTIVE PRODUCER:
IRINA MEDVEDEVA
CREATIVE PRODUCER:
ANNA GUDKOVA
PRODUCERS:
ELENA GLIKMAN, MIKHAIL DEGTYAR
FILM DIRECTOR:
EDUARD BORDUKOV
ON THE EDGE
We're at the Russian Fencing Cup
with only minutes
to go until the Semifinals.
Women's Sabre is ballet with a blade.
Fencing is the second fastest sport.
Only a bullet is faster than a Sabre.
Come on. Hey. Wake up.
They've announced you twice already.
Kira Yegorova. Where's she from?
Do you know of her?
Yeah. She's only done junior competitions.
This is her first senior championship.
So, did you sleep well?
U-huh.
I'll briefly go over the basic
rules. The bout lasts to 15 touches.
A point is awarded to the
one who touches first.
Only the touches
above the waist count.
On guard! Ready?
Excuse me.
What on Earth's the matter?
I'm sorry.
Is she stalling on purpose?
-Good strategy!
-I like her more by the minute.
And Nina is getting annoyed with her.
-Do you mind our presence?
-No.
On guard! Ready? Fence!
That... What was that right now?
An impressive speed.
Fence!
It's the second one-light action and it's
impressive.
She's not bad. Huh?
Halt!
She's lacking versatility though.
She's got just a handful of means.
Her technique is weak too.
Fence!
And what are you going to do about her
speed?
I'll drag her into a positioning bout.
Uhm. Well, go ahead, try it.
I'm intrigued to see it.
Fence! Halt!
I think we're witnessing the birth of a
new star here.
but watch the debutant annihilate her.
Pogodina can't seem to do
anything about it.
Looks like we have a sensation.
The debutant shamelessly beats the
national team's second-best fencer.
And goes to the Final
to have a face-off with the team's leader.
So, it's the Final.
Our national team's leader
is Alexandra Pokrovskaya.
She's a legendary Sabre fencer.
At 34 years old, she's a multi-time World
and European champion.
And the only summit she hasn’t been able
to conquer is getting the Olympic gold.
Go on.
The highly experienced Pokrovskaya
versus nineteen-year-old Kira Yegorova.
(breathes heavily)
Fence!
Pokrovskaya's attack is impeccable. It's
truly textbook stuff.
I think this bout's outcome is
as good as determined.
You are being way too assumptive here.
Halt!
It's three nil for Pokrovskaya. It
exceedingly looks like a wipe-out.
On guard! Ready? Fence!
Halt!
Woah-woah-woah!
Yegorova miscalculated her attack
and accidentally hit Pokrovskaya
in the face with her guard.
Let me see.
It's alright. I just need to stop the
bleeding, that's all.
She hit through the mask.
Is your head hurting? Are you dizzy?
Can you continue?
U-huh.
Alexandra's courage is certainly
praiseworthy.
It takes a lot to decide to continue
the bout after a hit like that.
Fencer on my left, it's the yellow card.
I'm not so sure Yegorova
really deserved this yellow card.
Are you alright?
After all, it was just an accident.
1:3
Yegorova's first hit.
Kira finally opens the score.
Wow, an immense speed, just take a look
at her. This girl in on fire.
Fence!
Another attack by Yegorova.
It certainly looks like the fall
has thrown Pokrovskaya off her stride.
She finds it hard to get back on track.
That was a hit!
This is the Pokrovskaya we know.
Fence!
Just take a look at how one second
has changed everything.
What a fantastic Final.
I've got to say,
watching their face-off
is a real treat.
Fence!
Halt!
Well, well, well. This should be
interesting.
Who will the referee give this point to?
Probably no one as the replay clearly
shows that it was a double hit.
Attack from the right. A hit to the left.
Hmm. Strangely the point is awarded to
Pokrovskaya.
How's that fair?
It was clearly a double hit.
Was that a point for her
lifetime achievements?
Kira, quit that. Or you'll get a red card.
Left fencer. Mask on.
Experience beat youth, after all.
Pokrovskaya takes the gold.
The Final is sure controversial.
Yes, but in terms of how emotionally
charged and intense it was,
this fight was one of the best I've seen.
Congratulations.
Why don't you just
skip the next championship altogether?
They'll give the victory
to you all the same.
Well, it is likely you won't even be at
the next championship
to see it happen with your own eyes.
DAD
Watch where you're going!
What is it that you want?
KIRA YEGOROVA
KIRA YEGOROVA 19 YEARS OLD
LEFT-HANDED
Oh, hi, Kira.
Hello. What took you so long?
I'm sorry, they held me back
at the championship.
Where is your medal?
Well, I threw it away, you see.
If you lost, why not just say so?
Will it take you long
to change your clothes?
The swimmers are partying already.
They're waiting for you.
U-huh. I'll go pick a swimsuit, shall I?
Kira.
Come on, don't get offended, ok?
I was just kidding.
I am not offended. I am just allergic to
chlorine.
How is this my fault?
I am also allergic to morons.
Oh, I see.
If you keep swinging
your Sabre like that,
you'll scare away
all the men around you. U-huh?
Woah-woah-woah. Is that an attack?
I’ll go see the swim team. You're coming?
No, I don't feel like going.
Oooh, well, I sure will go. You see, I'm
not allergic to chlorine, not me.
Besides, Semyonov is going to be there.
Be careful or you might get wet too
soon.
Ah. Don't you worry.
Stop staring.
Ah! Kostya.
- Sorry.
- You startled me.
Considering how quick
your reaction is, I guess
I can almost call it a compliment.
Hello.
Indeed, you're very lucky that my sport
is not boxing.
Yeah.
A good concert?
Well, there was everyone but
Beethoven.
- Uh.
- What's the matter? Let me see.
I cut my finger, that's all. I need a
bandage.
Don't tell me you started cooking 'cause
I won't believe it. Here.
Just leave it to me.
I just cut my finger. It's nothing.
Hmmm.
I can do it all myself. Do you mind?
I don't mind. Take it.
Congratulations, you won.
Thank you.
This is... What cup number was it?
Seven.
I was wondering, why don't they just
give it to you to keep, for good?
Has there finally emerged someone
worthy of a mention in your diary?
Well, who is this girl?
This girl right here is someone I almost
lost to today.
Is she really that strong? She doesn't
look it though.
If anything, she looks frail.
Maybe it's just me who became weaker.
Oh, come on. How many of these girls
did you face throughout your life?
I'm not so sure.
She's nineteen years old.
Has neither brains nor technique
and just charges at you like mad.
Without even knowing what
her next move will be.
But there was a moment there
when she just started killing me.
A cut then another
a cut then another a cut then another.
How pretty.
Yeah, I do indeed look just like a zebra
now.
U-huh. A bar-code. A very trendy look.
Damn, I'm sick and tired of people
posting their seaside picks.
That's it, girls, I've realized something.
I want to have a rest.
Why don't you tell Gavrilov about it?
He'll easily organize a seaside and
a good rest for you.
With no right to return
to the national team.
By the way, I wonder,
who will go to the Grand Prix?
Alexandra?
-Huh?
-What do you think?
In Belgium we'll have a day between
the individual and the team contests.
So what?
What? Chocolate and waffles, of
course.
Aren't you worried that your pants
might tear at the seam?
With the training Gavrilov makes us
do? Are you kidding?
Gavrilov's coaching someone? I wonder
who got the honor?
Halt!
So what? Are you tired?
Not at all, I just warmed up.
So, I suppose, now it's clear who will
go to the competition.
Alright then, let's proceed, shall we?
So, it's the tierce, then the quarte
followed by an advance-lunge, got it?
- U-huh.
- Go on.
What did I just tell you?
Do not attack me, you should parry.
Do not try to be faster than me.
Try to trick me instead.
Understand? Go on then.
Halt, halt.
You are too hasty again. There's no need
for you to show me how fast you are.
I already know you're fast.
Understand that we're not playing
whoosh-whoosh-whoosh here.
Here, we are playing jazz.
Can I try again?
No, you can't. There are no second
chances here. Certainly not in a fight.
Right, that's enough for today.
My greetings to the national
Sabre fencing elite. Congratulations.
The Olympic season was started
with an appalling level of fencing
at the national championship.
As a result,
I've got two bits of news for you.
I'll start with a good one.
No one is expecting us to win.
Now it's time for the bad. I am not
taking any tourists to the Olympics.
I'll either take there a
team capable of winning it
or I'll simply take no one.
Now, the Olympic race has begun.
For some, it's their first time.
Others have already been on this journey.
I hope it won't come as a surprise to you
that this will be a tough journey.
Your opponents come with an intention
to take away your victory.
I want you to be merciless
when dealing with them.
But first and foremost I want you
to show no mercy to yourselves.
Alexandra, catch up with her,
go on.
Halt!
Now, put on all of your electric
gear, pair up and proceed to sparring.
Today I want you to start
training on the first piste. Right there.
You referee, I'll start.
So what, are you going to waste time again
or shall we just start?
It's alright. Today I'll beat you as is.
Ready? Fence!
Look, Sergey, she will injure her
at this rate.
It's okay. Let them figure it out.
Ready? Fence!
Are you alright?
Yes, never better.
Do you want to stop the bout?
Let's keep going.
Ready?
Fence!
Ready? Fence!
How are you?
Wonderful. That was quite an awesome
training. It's fun here with you.
I mean, how are your wounds?
They are pretty cool scratches.
They are straight, red and they ache –
just the way I like it.
Now, listen... You can't impress
anyone here with your strong will.
Since this is clearly not
some amateur fencing club.
This is national team.
We are a team here. We are more than
just a team though. We're a family.
Right. Some family you are. I just can't
wait to become a part of it.
Well, it's not up to you to decide,
but the team.
By the way, you could have
stopped the bout. I did offer you to.
Yeah? And what was the point of your
being there? To look pretty?
Listen, give me this.
You can keep trying to show-off your
strong will for as long as you want.
Yes, hush-hush-hush.
I know it really hurts.
But then make sure
to stock on bandages.
It sounds like a threat.
It sounds the way that
you want to hear it.
As for threats, one needs to grow up
before starting to receive them.
One might find acting on one's threat
is impossible due to one's old age.
Now, listen, little one. Without you
here, we’ll manage perfectly fine.
However, without the team
there'll simply be no you.
You won't manage.
And that's why you keep holding on to
each other and to all your accolades.
And keep talking about
how your team is your family.
I came here for my victories.
And to achieve my goals I don't need
a team. All I need to win is my Sabre.
Everyone here has a Sabre.
And you already saw what they're
capable of.
She moves pretty well, doesn't she?
Her speed is the only thing she's got,
actually. Just that, nothing else.
You're wrong though.
This girl has a very good instinct.
She's a predator. And she knows how to
kill it on the piste.
While your killer instinct
has somewhat faded.
Are you actually admiring her, huh?
It's not her we're talking about right
now, it's you.
Hmm.
The Olympic season is in full swing.
And you're out of shape.
The Olympic season has only just
begun. I've still got plenty of time.
No, you've got no time at all.
And besides, these Olympic games
are going to be your last.
While right now you're - let's
just be honest about it.
Alright.
Right now, you're much weaker that you
were before the previous Olympic games.
So, how exactly are you
planning to win, huh?
However, you could achieve it
with the help of this girl.
She's way too impertinent.
She's too cocky for the team.
She's way too unruly.
Well, that's good she's impertinent.
And it's actually good that she's unruly.
A wild and cheeky monkey
is just the one you need.
You've got to learn
to make her play by your rules.
You've got to make her do the work
for you. You are the team leader.
Have you gone completely mad? What
if it did actually hit me?
It didn't hit you though.
Did no one ever tell you it was rude
to look through other people's stuff?
Well, in fact, when it comes to parties,
it stops being just your business.
Did you stop to think about me at all?
What do you care?
I care because the invitation clearly
states it's a plus-one.
Alright, it's all yours. Happy now?
Well. Kira, I'm sorry. But this plus-one
thing won't work unless you come.
Oh wow. You look like a lady.
Do you really want me to go there
dressed like this?
Well, if you really don't like
it,
why don't you pick something
from your own clothes?
But you should know, that this
is a very expensive dress.
I bought it at a sale when the
discount on it was 70 percent.
I basically pried it from
the hands of one crone.
Wait, what is this thing here? What is
this stain? Did you eat a burger in it?
Well, as I've just told you, I bought it
at a sale with a discount and a stain.
That's why it now comes
with a pretty little
clutch that you can
use to cover the stain.
Like that.
Alexandra Pokrovskaya, the best athlete
of the year.
Thank you.
Alexandra, you've got so many awards that
you could open your own Sports Museum.
Thank you. Of course I'll strive not to...
become one of the exhibits of this museum.
Alexandra, this is a present
from me personally.
It's a seventeeth century Spanish sabre.
Oh. I'll put it here for now.
Thank you.
It's utterly surprising,
isn't it,
how a whole life can fit into a twenty-
second-long video clip.
I think I would like to add to this video
all the training, injuries and defeats.
Then we'd all have to stay here and
watch the video for twenty years.
Thank you all.
I'll go to the table
before it's all cleared out.
Do you want
some sparkling wine?
No.
That's a beautiful dress.
You've got a stain on
it lower down there.
I just put on the first garment that I
grabbed.
But thank you for
this information.
You are welcome.
I understand that it's probably not often
that you get to go to
this type of parties.
Strictly speaking it's
an honorary retirement
send-off so I wouldn't
call it a party.
In fact, I would love to retire, you know.
But there's no worthy successor.
Hope you have a great evening.
Thank you.
…gladly…
She's such an old bitch.
But she's still very good at fencing.
Good job you had no sabres on you
otherwise you'd have started
fencing here and now.
My congratulations.
Sure, I'd do it.
So, you've decided you want to rock our
little fencing world?
No, the world.
Where did a girl like you come from?
From Grizovets. Do you have more
interesting places here, in Moscow?
I'm terribly hungry now.
Do you have any food?
Did you have a fight with a bear?
No. With my teammates over a locker.
If I don't eat something right now,
someone will get in trouble.
Here's some food for you.
Do you ever go anywhere
without your Sabre?
Not without this one.
Was it a present?
My dad's gift to me.
Was it him who got you into fencing?
U-huh. He called me D'Artagnan.
Promised me a hairclip.
So I agreed to go.
And when I found out you were allowed
to hit people with sabres there,
I loved it even more.
Because I was a wild child, you know.
And now you've calmed down, is that
right?
U-huh. During my first year of fencing
training I would just accost people.
I would chase them down the piste
brandishing my Sabre.
They would just
disqualify me.
My dad would go argue
with the judges… and defend me.
So, you are your daddy's little girl then?
I didn't have much of a choice though.
My mom... One morning she
just woke up and suddenly
realized that she was
way too good for our little town.
She just packed her bags and left.
I never saw her ever again.
A daddy's girl is not a bad title though.
U-huh.
If only he'd stay off the booze.
This one's mine.
I'm beginning to understand why
Pokrovskaya is so afraid of you.
I can slow down a bit.
She's got a fast attack. Her high speed
allows her to cut down the distance,
her counter-time is always short,
one thing she never uses
is compound attacks.
Positioning bout is her true weakness,
how do I drag her into it?
One year is not enough to prepare
an inexperienced girl for the Olympics.
Gavrilov... what are you playing at?
WORLD CUP PARIS
She’s the best newcomer
at the World Cup in Orleans.
An up to now unknown Russian fencer
Kira Yegorova makes it to the Final.
Yes! Yes!
It's a resounding victory for Yegorova.
What an amazing performance
for a debutante.
Alexandra Pokrovskaya,
Russia's national team leader
loses to the young Korean Sabre fencer
and is out of the competition.
Kira Yegorova bags
a sensational victory
for her very first
international competition.
Here, she was already nicknamed
Russian Panther
for her remarkable speed
and rapid attacks.
The pace. Keep the pace. Alexandra,
keep up with her. Come on. Keep up.
That's slow. Way too slow, Pokrovskaya.
Do you need a ride?
No, thank you. I'm not
that tired actually. I'll walk.
Go on. Get in. Or are you scared of me?
You did a very good job in France.
A surprisingly good job.
- Surprising to whom exactly?
- Everyone.
At your age it's really more...
of a coincidence.
So, don't relax just yet.
That's right.
I'm not at that age yet
where they give you awards
for your lifetime achievements.
You know, in this field, your lifetime
achievements are all your victories.
Anything else is just cheap popularity.
It must be easy to
philosophize about things
when you drive an expensive car
and live on Tverskaya.
It's on Kutuzovsky.
I don't give a monkey's.
You know what though?
I didn’t come all the way here
for no reason, on a whim.
I'm going to get what's mine. Trust me.
In the professional... sports,
those who just seek perks,
are highly unlikely
to stay there long.
Stop the car. I’ll take a subway train.
I've been meaning to ask you...
How expensive is your car?
I don't know. It was a gift for my
winning silver at the Olympic Games.
Ah! That is, for losing. That's cool, hey?
- What?
- What is it you're listening to? Doping?
U-huh.
You want a dose?
GRAND PRIX
GENEVA
I've got to say, you have
a rather aggressive fencing tactics.
It would be interesting to know what you
think about when you get on the piste?
- To kill the opponent.
- That sounds quite cruel.
I don't believe you would accuse
a predator for killing its prey,
now, would you?
It's the same thing here, really.
Careful, don't get crushed.
It's your fault for winning
so many prizes.
Come here.
- What for?
- A photoshoot with a star.
Oh!
Right. Now say cheese.
Come here.
You know, I've been thinking...
How would you like to join me on my tour?
We'll arrange a few days' holiday for you.
You'll relax,
we'll finally spend time together.
What for? I'm not tired at all actually.
I am in great shape.
Do you know what nickname
they've given her?
Russian Panther.
Everyone's talking about her.
I simply must defeat her.
And what if... you can't do that?
How's that?
Well, you can't
always be number one.
Sooner or later there'll come a time
when you'll have to go.
U-huh. Yes. I'll have to.
I'll have to go.
But I, Alexandra Pokrovskaya,
will decide for myself
when it's time for me to go. Understand?
It won't be up to some useless
little punk. Skank.
A self-important nobody.
You're a nobody. You're...
She's a nobody.
Do you get it, she's a total...
nobody.
It's only a victory
at the Olympics that truly matters.
And you won't be anywhere near there.
Do you hear me?
She won't even be anywhere near there.
Because these are going
to be my Olympic games,
and this is my medal, this freaking
gold Olympic medal is mine to take.
Alexandra. Hush, hush. Just calm down
please. Please, calm down.
U-huh.
This... medal... is just a piece of metal.
What's important... is... us.
This piece of metal is...
my entire life’s goal.
Understand?
Hello.
Oh! Hello there.
Well, hello, Sabre girl. So what...
are you ready to be the cover girl?
Moscow Grand Prix is one of the
most important contests of this season.
The tension is so thick one
could almost cut it with a knife.
Well, it's not surprising really.
The stakes here are just too high.
Today's results will
determine who of the fencers
will go to the Olympics
and who'll stay home.
Support your daughter
from the bleachers.
I'm asking you to put yourself
in my shoes.
I simply can't understand why it is
that you won't let me go in there.
I'm just here to see my daughter.
Kira Yegorova. She's an athlete
here, she's my... I'm her dad,
you see? I just want...
I can't go there and call her.
Please, show understanding to my
situation, let me in.
Phone her on her mobile.
You basically took the world of fencing
by storm. Can you reveal your secret?
There's no secret at all.
All it is, is that I want to win
more than any of my opponents do.
Look, there's your daughter.
Is it hard for you to perform today
being this contest's favorite?
- No. On the contrary, it's quite nice.
- Kira!
Kira.
Well, it's not exactly what I meant to
ask. You are a star now...
Kira. Hello.
Who knew you had
such strict rules here. Heh.
I was telling them,
my daughter is there, I'm her father.
I just want to see her.
That's why I came to Moscow.
What did you come here for? Huh?
Who on earth let you in here?
Who did? Well,
a lady came and showed me in. I'm sorry...
if I arrived
here at a bad time but...
So what?
So what? Well,
I just wanted to come and see you.
I... just saw you on TV,
there was a news program.
And, well,
you know what's happening at home...
What did you barge in here for? To beg
me for money, eh?
Kira, I... I'm here now... I'm in Moscow,
I've got a job here now.
What do you need Moscow for? What
do you need Moscow for?!
Well. I apologize if you are...
Here, take this money for the commuter
train ticket just make sure to get lost.
Just get lost, will you!
Kira, why are you like that?
We've reached the Final
where we'll see the fight between
our two best female Sabre fencers,
Pokrovskaya and Yegorova.
Alexandra looks simply fantastic.
She has in cold blood defeated
all of her opponents one by one.
Kira, on the other hand,
seems to me a bit worked-up.
Yes, but I'm sure that Yegorova
will pull herself together in the Final.
Since the winner of this
fight will go to the Olympic games
in the rank of
the national team's leader.
Kira, didn't your dad stay here to
support you?
Pokrovskaya deals the first hit.
Just look at it, Pokrovskaya scores again.
So far this fight has been going
according to her plan.
I don't understand what's going on.
Kira is simply not herself today.
Yes! There's no way this girl is going to
give up so easily.
Pokrovskaya is gaining an advantage.
Kira's fencing speed
is simply fascinating.
Wow, what an awesome hit.
Wow. Defence and retaliation in a jump.
Great job, Kira.
Finally, we see Kira that we know and
love.
Kira is catching up.
What a great fight this is.
Neither of them wants to give in.
Could it really be that Kira will end
up beating Pokrovskaya
and taking her place on the throne?
Oh, wow. This is truly unfortunate.
How are you?
My leg.
- Your knee?
- U-huh.
- Does this hurt?
- And now?
- No.
Give me the deep freeze spray.
Unfortunately, situations like
this often happen in fencing.
Regardless of all the
protective clothes the athletes have,
it is still a combat
involving serious weapons.
The injury is not too serious,
but I'd recommend playing it safe.
If it's nothing serious,
then I will go on.
All I can say is, well done,
Yegorova. Despite her injury, she decides
to continue the fight.
That takes a strong will.
En-garde, pret, allez.
Well, it looks like her fall is taking
a toll on Yegorova after all.
She's definitely having problems
with her knee.
Yes!
Alexandra Pokrovskaya wins
this highly important competition.
Now the Olympic Games await her.
Unfortunately Kira couldn't
overcome the consequences of her fall.
Yes. While Pokovskaya has once
again proven that she is not going to give
her throne to anyone without a fight.
Oh well... your ligament is
ruptured. That's a nasty injury.
Alright then.
You'll need physiotherapy for a while.
Yes, I got that part but when
can I resume my training?
I need to prepare for a
competition that's in two weeks.
Kira, you didn't get me...
You'll need three months for the
injury to fully heal. At the very least.
This season is over for you, Kira.
Wait, what? It's not over.
It just makes no sense.
I don't even feel any pain at all.
Of course, you don’t. But just
because you've taken painkillers.
Take one every morning and evening. We'll
start with these and see how it goes.
I don't need these pills,
I'm totally healthy.
Listen to me, Kira. Right now,
any sharp movement that you make,
can cause your ligament
to tear completely.
And then you'll need a
surgery. The best case scenario?
Your career just ends.
What you need right now is just to calm
down and have some rest.
And later on we will
think of some solution.
I need to be at my training.
Didn't you hear what
the doctor just told you?
Don't you understand that you
can develop a permanent limp?
I don't give a monkey's.
To get to the games,
I’ve been swinging my Sabre
in a lousy sports hall since I was eight!
The winning place is mine! I won't
give it up to anyone.
- Do you understand?
- Listen, what are you stupid?
Right, I'm already running late for my
training.
Look, I'm sorry. Please, wait.
That's not how I meant it, you know.
Everything’s fine.
Kira, listen. Could you just
calm down a bit, please?
But I am calm. Let go.
- Are you leaving right now?
- Yes.
I don't know how I forgot that it
was today. The time just really flies.
Would you like me to
drive you to the airport?
No, don't bother. I've called a taxi.
Hm.
Hmm. Thank you.
Look, Kostya.
I understand that I’ve
always been a difficult person.
Especially lately, to be fair.
You have never been like this before.
What do you expect? I simply had
to fight for the right to keep my place.
There is just no other choice.
Well, I believe...
one should remain a good
person no matter what.
Is that right?
Well, it's easy for you to say, you know.
You don't have to fight to keep your place
as the first violin in the orchestra.
Keep your hand steady!
Oh! Yegorova. Hello.
Hello.
How are you?
I'm okay.
That's good news,
I'm glad for you. Now go do the work.
Vasily Ivanovich there is free.
Come on, come on, everyone, keep
training, go on.
Halt, Yegorova.
Are you sure you're alright?
Come on,
let’s go get on the piste.
Inside cut with a
lunge. Parry of prime.
Then, riposte with cut at
the right flank. Understood?
It’ll be fine now.
You've got a ligament rupture. It will
take it at least three months to be fine.
And that's when
you should return.
Can I, please, give it another go?
Didn't I tell you,
nobody gets any second chances in here.
Right, everyone else,
get back to your training, come on.
Aren't you sick and tired already
of Gavrilov's tyrannical ways?
Well then,
why didn't you tell it to his face?
Everyone's brave in the locker room.
Alexandra could have said something
since she's our team's captain.
We don't have any team to talk about.
We're all on our own here.
So what, let's proceed?
U-huh.
Come on, as always.
Stop, stop, stop, stop,
stop, wait a minute.
Is there a problem, hey?
I got distracted. Everything's fine.
Alexandra, having trained you for
twenty-five years, I can tell by your hits
what you've had for breakfast
so don't tell me everything's fine.
It was me who broke her.
Oh, I see.
It was a fight.
And you defeated her in it.
I just went and pushed her off the piste.
You did see that!
So I did.
Listen, you've worked so
hard to get where you are now.
As a result,
you're at the top of your game now.
You've become much stronger.
Your instinct has finally awoken.
Well, what did you expect?
Did you want to become strong but
also remain nice at the same time?
That's just not how it works.
Everything in life has its price.
So, quit complaining.
And thinking of others.
Right now, there's just you and your
future win at the Olympic Games.
Or am I being wrong here?
On guard.
When you do it like this,
it really suits you.
- Like this?
- U-huh.
You've got about half an hour
to change your mind
and thus avoid completely
merging with this bed.
Hello.
You should have warned we that you'd come,
then I would put on some
make-up and a dress.
It's fine like this.
Can't you bend your leg at all?
Should I, maybe,
wag my tail for you as well?
If this is weighing on your conscience,
you can just apologize and get lost.
I do believe you realize that fencing is
very different from ball room dancing.
People get much more
serious injuries here.
Well, you can go back to
your room and pity yourself.
You still have a chance
to rejoin our national team.
Gavrilov doesn't
give second chances.
It's fine, I'll get over it. It
could happen to anybody.
You're not just anybody, you know
that yourself.
What you need is to keep training.
How? I feel pain just
getting out of my bed.
I will help you with it.
You can go and stick
your help you know where.
-Let down your hair.
-Like this?
Hey, wait for me there.
I'll quickly get ready.
So what, I thought it was really cool.
- Yes, it was.
- How about going to our place?
- Nuh, guys, let's not.
- Oh, come on.
- The girls must be wondering where I am.
- We’ll get some alcohol, it will be cool.
Hands off. Alright, guys, it's been fun
partying with you, but I'll go home now.
- Hey, give me a kiss.
- Hey now, what do you think you're doing?
That's it, calm down.
I said, get your hands off me.
- Calm down.
- I said, get your hands off me!
Shut up!
Shut up you bitch!
I told you to calm down.
Listen to me, you bitch,
if you put up a fight...
I'm ready to resume training.
What has happened?
You gave me your promise that you'll help
me with it. I'm going to keep training.
Do you understand me?
Here, hold this.
Here... it's here that I've
trained throughout my childhood.
Rock-n-Roll's hall of fame?
Right, first of all... you need to
learn how to go easy on yourself.
There's no one here you need to impress.
And you could easily tear your ligaments.
You sure know how to pep-talk.
Is it psychological support that you
need or shall we start training already?
I wonder what you're capable of.
I sure can hold a Sabre in my hands.
Wonderful. Now all you
need is just to learn to fence.
Get comfortable. This will be your
workplace for the following month.
- Are you serious?
- Absolutely.
I need to find out whether Russian
Panther knows how to defend herself.
Are you scared that I might bite you?
Are you okay?
We should proceed.
I don't need any of it.
Do you want to know if I can defend
myself? I can't do anything anymore.
Got it? I can't do
anything anymore!
Is that all?
Now listen to what I will say.
I'm not here to pity you
or be a shoulder to cry on.
All fencers get injured and
keep fighting through the pain.
So just get used to it.
Either that or, if not, then just leave.
On guard.
You must adapt to your injury. You
must completely change who you are.
Pain is a good thing. It helps discard
irrelevant thoughts and be more focused.
You must learn to use
this pain to your advantage.
You won't be able to
jump like you did before.
So, you'll need
to alter your fencing style.
And this is akin to
learning to walk again.
But this is your only chance.
To win, you don't need to be
stronger or faster than your opponent.
What you need is to be smarter.
You must trick your opponent.
Make them believe that you're weak.
Fencing is about trickery.
Trick everyone else and
don't let them trick you.
Hello.
Hi there. What are you doing here at
this late hour?
And you?
- We are training here.
- Can we have your autograph?
On the condition that you won't tell
anyone that you saw us here. - Come on.
Alexandra.
- Take it. - Thanks a lot.
-Dasha.
- Will you sign it for me too?
- Okay.
Why did you have to tie her up here?
She wouldn't listen to adults.
So she needed to be disciplined.
So cool.
We'll be rooting for you
at the Olympic Games.
Do you still remember
your first Olympic Games?
All that was so long ago.
So much so that back then, Russian Panther
was knee-high to a grasshopper.
Seriously... what's so special about
the Olympics? I don't understand.
Well... The Olympic games,
they're like...
Mount Everest.
Everybody wants to conquer that
summit but main thing is to make it there.
I know about Everest. I have read...
there're all these corpses.
They lie there frozen and nobody
even remembers their names.
Yeah. It's the same
with the Olympics.
They only remember champions.
This is quite sad. Also, not helpful.
It never gets any easier.
When I first started up in fencing,
in the beginning,
I was too afraid
to touch a Sabre.
And of course I wouldn't dream of
hitting an opponent with that thing.
- What? No way.
- Yes.
Gavrilov even wanted to make me
leave. He'd say, 'If you can't hit anyone,
why don't you go to
the class next door
and learn gymnastics
instead and do splits'.
But I would return every day.
And every day Gavrilov
kept on telling me,
'You're not the right
monkey for this sport.
So, why are you here?
You are not going to succeed in it.
I would cry my eyes
out after each training.
So why didn't you leave back then?
Because I am very stubborn.
And you're just like that.
So, it's Everest?
Alexandra, can you explain it to me...
what for?
It was my idea, I asked her to.
You?
Did your mentor explain to you the reason
why I took you on the national team?
No?
I only ever took you on
the team so that Alexandra
could have a sparring partner so
that she would become stronger.
You happened to be perfect for that
role. A wild and talented little monkey.
Of course, you could have made it to the
Olympic Games, but then you got injured.
That's unlucky.
These things happen.
So... That's it,
you've played your part here.
Is that yours?
Alexandra. So,
you haven't actually answered my question.
What for?
If only you knew just how much I hate all
these talks of yours about monkeys, huh.
My whole life I've been the most
obedient little monkey for you.
Do you remember what I
told you when you came to me
as a little girl and asked to
teach you how to fence?
Yes.
Do you remember what your reply was?
- I'd do whatever it takes.
- What else?
- That I'll do whatever it takes.
I said, I was ready to be a bad person.
That. Your problem, Alexandra,
is that you're constantly trying
to be good for everyone.
To be kind. Being a good person
is not a profession though.
People don't win Olympic games by
being kind-hearted. This doesn't happen.
Understand that this girl still
has her whole life ahead of her.
But for you this is
the very last chance.
These will be your very
last Olympic Games.
Yes. It is indeed my last chance. Yes.
And, trust me,
I am actually going to take it.
But the way I want to do it. With dignity.
So that I don't feel ashamed later.
Ashamed is what you'll
be when years from now
you'll be retired and
telling your grandchildren
about the time when you had your very
last Olympics and you failed to win it.
It's been a while since you and I
had a meal together.
I never fed you something as awful as
this junk food.
Do you remember when... you made
soup for me for the first time?
That time I... put way
too much pepper into it.
- It was all pepper.
- I took it stoically.
Dad, let's just go back home.
Who needs this Moscow
or the national team?
Let's just live like
all normal people do.
Let's go then.
I bet... I can find work
in our Grizovets too.
They've got a factory.
We'll go for barbeques in the pine grove
just like we did before.
Just don't get rid of your Sabre,
alright?
We'll use it as a skewer to put meat on.
Aren't you ashamed to be mocking your
daughter like that?
Aren't you ashamed to be
saying such utter nonsense?
'Who cares about this Olympics?
Who cares about this Olympics!'
Was it in vain that I sacrificed my sleep
on weekends to take to your trainings?
Actually, I went there by myself.
That’s more reason to be ashamed now.
And by the way,
I... have started saving money now.
To be able to afford going
to your first ever Olympics.
You're my D'Artagnan.
Well.
What are you standing?
Start the warm-up.
Oh! Look, who's here.
Mademoiselle Yegorova.
Is there something you want?
It's just that we have
a national team's training now.
And you're standing here,
looking reproachful.
Yes. I want to prove
that this place is mine.
Yeah? That's interesting.
Alone on the piste, with no partner?
I'm afraid that's not possible.
I'll be her partner.
Well, what can I say to that, Alexandra.
What a fantastic performance.
But if it's alright with you,
I'd like to continue our training.
Come on. Well, ladies,
approach your targets.
Right.
OLYMPIC GAMES
RIO DE JANEIRO
Kira, don’t you run a risk by coming here,
by coming here,
to the Olympics with an
injury that hasn’t fully healed?
I am totally fine.
Actually,
I think you are risking even more
trying to tease
the world-famous Russian Panther.
Okay, the last thing I would wanna do is
to tease the world-famous Russian Panther.
But if it’s all the same to you,
I’d like Kira to answer the question.
How did you manage
to recover so quickly?
That's all thanks to the fact that we've
got the best healthcare in the world.
Okay.
Your team had a pretty tough season.
Problems with injuries and team line-up.
Has it been hard in this situation
to motivate the team
to stay focused on winning?
No, it hasn't. These are Russian women.
If they lack anything,
it's definitely not motivation.
I see.
Kira!
You did very well back there. Awesome job.
You helped me quite a bit too. Thank
you.
So, you got what you wanted, then.
You're at the Olympic Games.
Yes. Even though many doubted I would.
I didn't doubt it.
It's just that I was worried for you.
I didn't want you to run such risks.
I will be rooting for you.
This is the biggest moment in an
athlete’s life. This is the Olympics.
This is the summit that someone
will conquer today.
This is the strongest competition line-up
in my memory.
Excuse me, please. Could we switch
the channel to women's fencing?
Huh? Switch to what?
Guys, his wife is performing
at the Olympics.
Yes, we're expecting
today to be very tense.
The strongest Sabre fencers will be
fighting for the right to go to the Final.
Nina Pogodina, Kira Yegorova,
Alexandra Pokrovskaya.
Today we have to support
all of our female athletes.
There are no opponents among them.
They'll be fighting there for us.
Pokrovskaya is a true legend
of Russia's national team.
Well done you.
From the get-go, in the very first bout
she's showing off her fantastic skill.
Yes, Pokrovskaya's
confident attacks
leave us no doubt regarding
her ultimate goal of coming here.
She won't settle for anything
less than Olympic gold.
Kira Yegorova. She is that very girl
who recently took
the world of fencing by storm
and has already managed to stir things up.
Kira looks very confident.
Victory goes to Kira Yegorova!
Yes!
Russian Sabre fencers
are performing remarkably.
If that's their coach's strategy,
he must be ingenious.
Good job, Alexandra.
Look at that! The Russian Panther
keeps winning on one leg.
As the saying goes,
a wounded animal is very dangerous.
Pogodina makes an unfortunate mistake
in the second half of the bout.
Sadly, it means the end
of these Olympic Games for her.
The Russians suffer
their first losses,
while they still have their main
opponents to look forward to.
I wonder, can anybody stop them?
Well, we've made it
to the semifinals.
Here, Pokrovskaya will face
the legendary de Galier.
It was her who snatched the gold from
Alexandra at the previous Olympic Games.
De Galier is in impeccable form.
She is the World Champion
and the main contestant for the victory.
And she’s got a lot of confidence.
Pokrovskaya has no chance.
This will be the end of her story.
De Galier deals a blow.
Sooner or later Russia’s
luck had to run out.
Alexandra's main task now is
to control her emotions.
Pokrovskaya is taking a pause
after the first period.
Why are you afraid of her?
Stop overthinking it.
- I can't.
- But you have to.
Break through this barrier.
Just smash through it.
If you're losing, just keep going.
You got it? I can't hear you.
I got it!
And move smoother. Come on. Do it.
Look at that, Pokrovskaya is now angry.
Good.
Yes!
Yes! Pokrovskaya is catching up
to her opponent!
A hit by de Galier.
And by Pokrovskaya again.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
It's a win!
That's amazing.
The bout seemed as good as lost.
But Alexandra by some miracle managed
to change the tides and won the fight.
What an incredible bout that was.
Pokrovskaya goes to the Final.
Indeed, Pokrovskaya
is a remarkable fencer.
Russia! Russia! Russia! Russia!
That's it. Well done! Well done you!
You beauty!
- I actually beat her!
- You beat her beautifully.
Right. Go have a rest.
Restore your energy for the next fight.
Alexandra. You really need to stop...
overthinking it.
- U-huh.
- Do you hear me?
U-huh. In just fifteen cuts
you'll become an Olympic champion.
Do you hear me?
Fifteen cuts, Alexandra.
You let in way too many of her hits.
It's all because you just barge forward.
Without watching your opponent.
What else? Why don't you
just tie me to the piste?
I would if I could.
Ok now, listen to me.
I know this fencer.
She's going to provoke you.
It's crucial that you stay calm.
And just keep doing what we've practiced.
Focus on her torso, and pay attention.
Kira will be fighting an experienced
Sabre fencer from South Korea Kin Gan Xin.
Before Yegorova came into picture,
Xin was deemed the fastest
female Sabre fencer.
Xin scores the first point.
Yegorova keeps getting hit
again and again.
Yes! Yegorova scores.
Don't you take your eyes off her.
Xin prevents Kira from catching up.
Come on, come on.
It's a shame that Yegorova's injury
stops her from giving it her all.
I don't get how they let her perform
in the Olympics if her knee's injured?
Because it's different from your
football where a slightest touch
makes you fall down on the
ground and start crying.
Kira now has a short pause to regroup.
Calm yourself down.
Just take a good look at her.
And she scores.
Yes!
Now this is the Russian
Panther we know and love.
Attack her. Attack her.
Yegorova is on a roll.
Nobody can stop her now.
Yes!
You can call it whatever you like:
a big surprise, pure luck, a coincidence.
But she did it.
Now this nineteen-year-old
girl from the town of Grizovets
is in the Olympic Games final.
It is common for athletes to be
dissatisfied with their coaches.
They consider them bad. That's inevitable.
And I'm ready for that...
But I just want you to know
that all I've ever done...
I've done it for the sake of your victory.
You're a fighter. You know it yourself
there can be no friends on the piste.
The piste is the place
for just one thing and it's the fight.
It's quite simple:
either kill or be killed.
I am begging you, please,
just switch off your feelings.
And switch on your instinct.
Remember what you were like
when you defeated her in that fight.
This Olympics is yours, Alexandra.
And you must win it.
So, it's the Olympic Games Final.
And it's going to be Russian.
Yes, these are Alexandra
Pokrovskaya and Kira Yegorova
who will fight for the title
of the Olympic champion.
Thank you.
Words simply can't describe it.
Everyone is so excited to see the Final.
Regardless of this fight's outcome,
it will definitely make history.
And look, the coach of Russian Sabre
fencers goes and sits in the audience.
I suppose, it's the only right choice.
It's up to Pokrovskaya and Yegorova now
to decide which of them is the best.
Go on, girl.
Thanks to all the drama of this fight,
for one day,
sabre fencing has become
the most popular Olympic sport.
The entire world is waiting to see the
outcome of this face-off.
Wow, who would have thought
I’d root for Russians so much!
Can I have some water please?
Yes, it really looks like it's going
to be a very difficult fight
and most of all emotionally difficult.
There's no 'us' and 'them' here.
Both of the fencers
are certainly worthy of this victory.
Yes!
So, it's Pokrovskaya who scores first.
Pokrovskaya is off
to a very confident start:
her experience really shows.
Meanwhile, Yegorova is not her usual self.
As she lets in the third cut in a row.
Yes, but Alexandra too seems
to be unhappy. What's going on?
Although I don't quite understand
what Pokrovskaya could be
unhappy about in this situation.
Pokrovskaya scores again.
She's obliterating her.
What's up with Kira?
Don't you dare doing that, you understand?
- But these are your Olympic Games.
- I don't need a victory of this kind.
Fight me!
Throwing fights is not what
I taught you to do. Fight me!
Yes! Good job!
And it's Yegorova's first hit.
Has Kira awaken from her sleep?
Yes!
Yegorova scores once again.
An awesome hit!
A splitting attack from Pokrovskaya.
Kira just can't seem
to break into the lead.
Yegorova scores again!
And again! Kira narrows the gap.
Come on, darling, come on.
Pokrovskaya retaliates.
And Yegorova scores again!
Yegorova evens the score.
Yes!
It looks like Kira's knee injury
is giving her trouble.
The timing couldn't be worse.
Yes!
Pokrovskaya takes lead.
The score is 14:13.
She's just one hit away from victory.
You must not just
adapt to your injury.
You must completely change who you are.
You must learn to use this pain
to your advantage.
Yes! Yes! Well done!
Kira successfully overcomes her emotions
and lands a very important hit.
The current score is fourteen all.
Now it will be this final hit
that will determine
who the gold medal will go to.
Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes!
Your daughter is an Olympic champion!
Do you understand it?
Thank you so much. Thank you.
What a great fight. Go on guys.
The award ceremony completes
the first stage
of the competition.
The final was just fantastic!
But the Olympics aren't over yet
for our atheletes.
And tomorrow our female Sabre fencers
will have a team competition.
This is a chance to win
another gold medal.
We congratulate Kira Yegorova,
who earned her gold medal
in a tense fight
with Alexandra Pokrovskaya.
And we understand how Alexandra feels.
But tomorrow they have
a team competition.
So Pokrovskaya and Yegorova
will have to get past today's rivalry
and perform as one team.
Congratulations.
You deserved this gold medal. You did.
If it weren't for your help,
I would have never made it here.
May I?
This is the thing I've spent
my entire life on.
I was always afraid
this moment would come.
The moment when I'd have to leave.
Damn. Why is this so hard?
- There's still a team competition.
- Yes, I know that.
Now you've become the team's leader.
- No.
- Yes.
No, I'm just a girl who knows how to
swing her Sabre, that's all.
You are the team's captain.
Alexandra, we won't manage without you.
We really need you now.
- Hello.
Hello. Kostya. I'm very glad
to hear your voice.
Alexandra, wait. You know,
I can't even imagine
how you must be feeling right now.
Or what you're going through.
I just want you to know
that I believe in you
even more than you do.
Thank you.
Pokrovskaya scores a point.
Well done. Alexandra is on fire today.
It's the final fight
of the Olympics
and Russian female team is fighting
the French fencers for the gold medals.
Yes!
The emotions are running high!
It's amazing what's happening
on the sports arena.
The fight is continued by Kira Yegorova.
Come on, come on, till the end!
The match is extremely tense.
It's Nina Pogodina's turn.
Come on, Nina! Well done!
It's back to Pokrovskaya. She lands a cut.
Good job, girls!
Our girls are the best today.
Alexandra Pokrovskaya
is back on the piste.
Right now, the fate of the Olympic gold
can be determined by just one cut.
- Yes!
- Yes! We are Olympic champions!
We are Olympic champions!
And Alexandra Pokrovskaya
receives the award
she's been striving for her whole life.
Yes!
That's it! We are Olympic champions.
We are Olympic champions!
And Sofiya Velikaya receives the award
she's been striving for her whole career.
Time's up, time's up, time's up,
time's up, time's up, time's up!
Yes! We've got a winner!
Inna Deriglazova.
Oh wow! Yana Egorian!
Getting gold
at the Rio de Janeiro Olympics.
It's a win for Sofia Pozdniakova
and she cries with joy.
It's a happy ending.