-Merry Christmas, Elizabeth.
-Merry Christmas, girls.
Merry Christmas.
This will never wear out on you,
Mr. Speak.
Hi, Frankie.
Mims, I'll be right with you.
Merry Christmas, sir.
Thank you, Frankie.
Merry Christmas.
Hello, Frank.
Hello, honey.
I brought you some food
from the restaurant.
Oh, thank you, darling.
All right, Mims.
Have a nice Christmas.
A Merry Christmas to you,
Mr. Horace.
So, what do you think,
Mr. Speak?
Come in.
Hello, Mary.
Hello, Bessie.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you.
I brought you a present
and I brought the baby
a present.
Oh, thank you.
There's a present for you, too,
under the Christmas tree.
Sit down and visit, Bessie.
I'm so glad you came by.
-Merry Christmas.
-Thank you.
I'm here all alone
in this big, old rooming house.
Horace is workin' late
at the tailorin' shop,
and then, he's workin' tonight
at Mr. Dixon's store
to earn a little extra money,
so I'm all alone.
Well, you have a piece of candy,
Bessie.
I don't mind if I do.
Hello, Mr. George.
Is Horace here?
No, sir.
He's still at the store.
What time do you expect him?
Not for a while yet.
You tell him
I was askin' for him.
-Yes, sir.
-Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Mr. George Tyler's off again,
Mama says.
Are you scared of him?
No. He looks harmless enough
to me, poor thing.
Mama says he's gonna kill
someone if they aren't careful.
She says he's rich
and kin to everybody in town,
and that's why everybody
looks the other way
no matter how he acts.
He's not kin to me.
Is he kin to you?
No. He's kin to Horace,
but only by marriage.
This is the first Christmas
I've spent away
from Mama and Papa, Bessie.
Is that so?
Yes.
Last Christmas was, I think,
the most unhappy one
I'll ever know.
At least, I hope I'll never know
one more unhappy.
Why was it so unhappy?
Well...
Papa, by then,
was so determined
that I wasn't to marry,
and was so unpleasant
and in such a bad temper
anytime Horace came
near the house.
I finally asked Horace
not to come anymore.
And that's when I started
slippin' around
and meetin' Horace
at the ice cream parlor
and the picture show.
Of course, Mama always
found out about it
every time I did
something like that,
since she has spies
all over this town.
Mrs. Cookenboo was her main spy,
but she had her lieutenants
all around.
They sent me to Galveston
in the summer to visit my aunts.
Mama and Papa kept hoping
if they could get me away
long enough,
I would meet someone else
and forget Horace.
And then, Allie Douglas
married Hector.
And she was almost
my closest friend.
Allie Douglas?
Is that Allie Dockery?
She was Allie Dockery.
She's Allie Douglas
now that she's married.
-I know her.
-Of course you do.
-Her papa's state senator.
-Yes.
So, Horace and I
decided to run away and marry.
The day before we were to elope,
Papa came early.
And he was all nervous
and excited.
Well, I almost had
a heart failure.
But it wasn't about my elopin'.
He was upset because a sheriff
had come to him
about the hangin' of that man
that robbed Mr. Azerley's
grocery store and killed him.
Do you think Allie Dockery
is pretty?
Yes, I do.
Do you think she's beautiful?
I think she's beautiful.
Anyway, as much as I am
against public hangin',
I was glad, let me tell you,
that he had this on his mind
that night
and wouldn't be payin'
any attention to me.
Goodnight, Papa.
As the night grew nearer,
I began to get waves
of almost nausea,
and I swear I had a fever.
I went to bed as soon
as I could,
but I couldn't sleep at all.
I began to think
of Clark Ferguson then.
She was the first friend I had
that died.
Do you remember Clarkie?
-No.
-Sure you do.
No, ma'am.
Well, I don't see how anybody
in this world that knew her
could forget her.
But I never knew her.
Oh, you were bound to.
You've just forgotten is all.
Anyway, I heard
the courthouse clock strike 11,
and I began
to think of Clarkie then.
So pretty and sweet,
dyin' at 16,
and here I was,
about to defy my parents
and run off and marry.
And I began to cry.
And I was sobbin' so...
...that I was afraid
I would wake my Mama and Papa
or my brother.
So, I got out of my bed
and I opened the window,
and I looked out at the night,
and I thought,
"I'll never be lookin'
out this window again any more
after tonight.
I'll never be in this house
anymore
until after I'm married."
What's your papa's name?
Vaughn. Henry Vaughn.
My mother's name is Mary.
Maybe that's why
you call me Mary.
You get my first name
mixed up with my mama's.
When do you open the presents
at your house?
In the mornin'.
That's when we open them
at my mama's and papa's, too.
-It's a lovely supper, Charity.
-Thank you.
-Papa.
-Yes, sir?
May I-- may I borrow
the car tonight?
-What for?
-I wanna visit some friends.
-No.
-Papa, please.
No, Brother, I want you home
on Christmas Eve.
Mama.
No, Brother.
You heard your papa.
We got a letter
from Laura and Dora.
And they seem well and happy.
Did Clarkie Ferguson
have black hair?
-Yes.
-And curls?
-Then I knew her.
Of course you did.
Mr. George is back.
Mr. George?
Can you tell me
how to get to town? I've forgot.
Why yes, sir. You turn right.
Where is the train bridge?
Well, that's to your left.
That's where the town
used to be.
Yes, I've heard that.
Before your time and mine.
Yes, sir.
I heard that you and Horace
eloped.
Yes, sir.
And your mama and papa
still haven't forgiven you?
No, sir.
I hear you slipped off
to Allie and Hector's house
for the wedding.
Yes, sir.
And I heard the Methodist
preacher refused to marry you
out of friendship to Mr. Vaughn,
your father.
You and Horace then asked
the Baptist preacher
to marry you, and he agreed.
But first, before the ceremony,
he said he wouldn't perform it
unless you called your father
and told him
what you were about to do.
And you phoned him.
And he begged you not to do it.
He said you'd live to regret it.
Well, Papa,
I'm sorry you feel that way.
Goodbye.
You married on Valentine's Day.
Yes, sir.
At 1:00 in the afternoon
on Valentine's Day.
I turn to the right?
Yes, sir.
How many blocks to town?
Two and a half.
Do, uh-- do you have the time,
kind sir?
Headin' toward 5:00, Bobby.
Hey, do you want
a drink of whiskey?
I don't drink.
Uh, do you mind if I have one?
No.
Well, here's to your health.
Mr. George Tyler
is on the phone.
He wants to know if you remember
the name of the man
who killed Mr. Buck Davis.
Les Freeman-Constable.
He also wanted to know
if he was black or white.
I said he was white,
but he wanted me to ask you.
Well, tell him
I said he was white.
Yes, sir.
He also said for me to tell you
that he thought you were
the conscience of the whole town
as well as the county.
Well, tell him I think
he's very kind to think so.
♪ O little town of Bethlehem
♪ How still we see thee lie
♪Above thy deep
and dreamless sleep ♪
♪ The silent stars go by
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to disturb you
at this time of the night,
but I'm lookin' for my mother.
Oh, Mr. Bobby, she's gone
to your brother's in Bay City.
Is it Christmas?
Christmas Eve.
-Uh-huh. Christmas Eve?
-Yes.
What's the year, please?
1917.
-Are we at war?
-Yes.
He's drunk.
Horace?
-Hmm?
-Are you goin' home?
Oh, yes. I sure am, Miss Ruth.
-I'll walk with you.
-Mmm, all right.
Are you busy?
All day and night people
were spendin' money
like it was goin' out of style.
I know.
-Hello, Cousin George.
-Hello, Horace.
-Merry Christmas, Cousin George.
-Merry Christmas.
Well, I am glad
that I don't have to clerk
in a store every day.
-It's a godsend.
-Yeah.
I don't know that I could
stand it much longer.
How do you stand it, Horace?
Oh, I don't mind it,
especially when we're busy.
When it's quiet
and there's no business,
I don't care for it too much.
Well, my feet are killin' me
from standing all these hours.
Don't your feet hurt you?
No, not too much.
I'm gonna soak mine in hot water
before I go to bed tonight.
Oh, um, did Elizabeth hear
from her mother and father?
No, not unless she heard
this evening.
Oh, I was so hopin'
that the spirit of Christmas
would embrace them
and they would forgive you both.
I saw Miss Vaughn uptown
this afternoon
and I almost took it upon myself
to tell her
that I thought
since it was Christmas,
surely she and Mr. Vaughn
could find it in their hearts
to forget and forgive
their daughter,
but then I remembered
that Miss Maddie Darling told me
that she had seen the Vaughns,
uh, just before Thanksgivin',
and she said to them
right on the steps
of the Methodist church,
"When are you gonna stop
this nonsense
and forgive Elizabeth?"
And she said
that Mrs. Vaughn said,
"I thank you very much
to mind your own business."
Hm!
Don't you think they know
that Elizabeth is expectin'?
I don't know.
Well, surely they've heard
by now.
Someone must have told them,
don't you think?
I don't know.
Oh. All right.
I'm certain that the birth
of the baby will reunite you.
Well, I hope so
for Elizabeth's sake.
She doesn't ever talk about it,
but I know she misses
her family.
Oh!
♪ Silent night
♪ Holy night
♪ All is calm
-♪ All is bright
-BOBBY: Mama?
Mama?
She's not here, Mr. Bobby.
She's in Bay City.
She's gone to your brother's
for Christmas.
What a pret--
uh, pretty Christmas tree.
Could I-- could I come in
to see it?
Why certainly.
I don-- uh, I don't believe
we have a Christmas tree
this year,
'cause I've been
all over the house.
I can't find it.
I hope to get what I want
for Christmas,
but I know I won't.
What do you want?
I want some guinea pigs.
Mama says I'm too old for them.
I was married
to the sweetest girl, you know.
She, uh-- she was
quite a bit taller than me.
She was a real treasure.
Uh, she--
she left me, though.
She couldn't stand the climate
in this part of the country.
"It rains so much here,"
she said,
"it's a wonder that you all
don't have webbed feet."
I came home one day
and she was gone.
And it-- you--
it was many years
before I could find out
where she went
or I'd have gone after her,
try to get her back.
She broke my heart.
Mama says that's what I get
for marrying
somebody beneath myself.
She said it never works out.
Mama says bein' born common
is like a, uh--
like a curse,
'cause you can't do nothing
about it.
Well, common or not,
I said I loved her.
I loved her so.
Where's Horace?
He's still workin', Mr. Bobby.
He's always runnin' somewhere.
Here, there, and everywhere.
"What's he work so hard for?"
Mama said.
"To get in the good graces
of Mr. Henry Vaughn,"
I told her.
Mr. Henry Vaughn,
his son drove by here
as I was, uh, leavin' home.
His son drinks, you know?
Drinks like a fish.
I said, "Does your daddy know
that you drink like that, boy?"
He said, "No."
Said,
"He'd kill me if he knew it."
Brother Vaughn is her brother.
Whose?
-Mary's.
-That's right.
And Mr. Henry Vaughn
is her father.
And Mrs. Henry Vaughn
is her mother.
Oh?
They don't speak to her
because she eloped.
That's right.
I remember that now.
-Merry Christmas!
-Merry Christmas. Mm.
No, no.
-Merry Christmas.
I have a little something here
for you, Elizabeth.
-Oh, why, thank you.
-There you go.
There's a present for you, too,
under the Christmas tree.
Oh, how nice!
Oh, how sweet.
Oh, why, Mr. Bobby,
what are you doin' here?
Why aren't you in Bay City
with your mama?
We were reminiscing here
about the old times.
Oh.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, why thank you.
That's sweet.
I think I'll just sit a minute.
Uh, did Mr. George Tyler
ever find you?
He came by here twice
lookin' for you.
I passed him
on the way over here.
And I said, "Merry Christmas,
Cousin George,"
and he said-- he said,
"Merry Christmas" to me.
He said nothin'
about comin' here.
When they wouldn't take me
in the army,
I went down and I tried
to join the volunteers,
but they wouldn't have me
either.
They said I'd never
stay sober long enough
to teach me anything.
"Hell, Bobby," they said,
"if we had to depend on you
to guard this town
from the Germans,
we'd be in a bad way."
Horace, you think we're
gonna win this damn war?
Well, hello, Cousin George.
Why don't you come in?
No, I can't stay.
I'm on my way to church.
This isn't Sunday,
Cousin George.
What day is it?
It's Tuesday. Christmas Eve.
Oh, yeah.
I forgot. I came here
to wish you Merry Christmas.
Well, thank you.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
You know, I bet Horace
has lived in more houses
than any one of us.
Hey, Horace, how many, uh,
places have you stayed in?
Bobby, I couldn't begin
to tell you.
It would take me a night
to remember them all.
Mama used to worry
about you growin' up.
"What's to become of that boy?"
she said.
"He-- he lives like a orphan."
"Why, he's no orphan,"
I told her. "He's got a mama."
"She's-- where is she?
Why isn't she here
taking care of me?"
Has he gone?
Hm? Yes.
Steve came and took him away.
Hey, Horace, how long has
your daddy been dead?
Well, let's see, uh, 16 years.
Ah. What, 16 years?
Well, my Daddy's been dead
a lot longer than that.
I don't know how long,
but I was a baby, they'd say,
when he died.
Oh, you weren't a baby.
You were a grown man.
-I was?
-Yes indeed.
Miss Elizabeth, how old were you
when your father died?
He's not dead, Mr. Bobby.
He's still alive.
That's right, yeah. No, but he
don't speak to you.
No, he doesn't.
-Hey, Steve.
-Uh, Horace, can I--?
Um, uh, Papa sent me in here
to ask you over to the house
later on tonight.
Well, he says he wants to have
a long and private talk
with you.
Uh, Steve, it's Christmas Eve.
I've been workin' all day.
Yeah, I know. I told Papa that,
but he says to tell you
it's life or death.
All right, all right.
I'll be over in a little while.
Thank you very much.
What's goin' on?
-We'll go up the street.
-No. Home's over--
-I don't wanna go home now.
-Papa--
"And in the sixth month,
the Angel Gabriel
was sent from God
unto a city of Galilee
named Nazareth,
to a virgin espoused to a man
whose name was Joseph
of the house of David...
...of the house of David,
and the virgin's name
was Mary.
And the angel came in onto her,
and he said,
'Hail thou
that are highly favored.
Blessed art thou
among women.'"
Horace.
I called over to your house
just now to try to stop you,
but you were already gone.
Papa's fallen into a deep sleep
and we don't wanna wake him.
And he hasn't been
sleepin' much lately.
-I'm sorry.
-Oh, no, that's all right.
Well, Merry Christmas.
Oh, Merry Christmas.
Mmm!
How sweet.
Let me have two cards.
Christmas gives us joy.
Thank you, sir.
♪ Soft o'er the fountain
♪ Lingering
for the southern moon ♪
♪ Far o'er the mountain
♪ Breaks the day too soon
♪ In thy dark...
♪ Weary thoughts so tender
♪ Farewell
♪ Nita
♪ Juanita
♪ If we should part
♪ Nita
♪ Juanita
♪ Lean thou on my heart
Hello?
Uh, yes.
Yes.
Yes, I'll call her.
It's for you.
I think it's your mother.
Oh, heavens!
Hello?
Of course I do. It's Mama!
Well, it was. It was Mama.
She said, "Do you know
who this is, Elizabeth?"
And of course I did,
and I said, "Mama."
And she said, um, "Yes."
And then, she said,
"Merry Christmas."
And I began to cry,
and she began to cry.
And then, she said, "May we
come over in a few minutes?
We have a few presents
we'd like to bring you."
And I said, "Yes,"
and that was it.
Oh, Horace. We have to get
presents to them some way.
I'll just die if they come here
and we have nothing for them.
Well, we can't do anything
about it now.
All the stores are closed.
Didn't you close up
for Mr. Dixon last night?
Yes.
Then you must have the keys
to his store.
Oh, that's right.
Hurry down and--
and get something
for Mama, and Papa,
and Brother.
-What shall I get them?
-I don't know, Horace.
I can't think, I'm too excited.
-Use your own judgement.
-Well, honey, I can't--
I-I don't know--
I don't know what to get them.
I mean, your Papa doesn't smoke.
Uh, no. He likes Big Red
Bandanna handkerchiefs.
Get him some of those.
Get Mama some toilet water,
and get Brother some
linen handkerchiefs. Hurry.
-Mary!
-Come in, Bessie.
-Merry Christmas.
-Mary, I got my guinea pigs!
-Oh!
Mama said she just said
I was too old for guinea pigs
to throw me off the track.
I can't ask you to stay
because my mother just called
and-- and she and my father
are on the way over.
-Did you have a happy Christmas?
-Oh, yes.
My Mama didn't get a thing
she wanted for Christmas.
She said that the housecoat
Papa bought her
was the ugliest thing
she ever saw
and she got so mad,
she threw it at him.
I bought her a pair of bloomers,
and she said that four of her
could get inside of 'em,
so I have to return 'em
for a smaller size.
Papa has a headache.
He says he's never known
a happy Christmas,
and this year's no exception.
Thy-- thy-- thy kingdom come,
thy will be-- kingdom come.
Now I lay me down to sleep
and I pray the Lord my soul to--
-Elizabeth.
-Come in.
Elizabeth, is Horace here?
No, he's gone to get presents
for my family.
They just called to say
they were comin' over.
Oh! Oh, how nice.
Oh, well, I wonder
if when Horace gets back,
he could look in on Mr. Bobby.
I think he's sick.
Well, I wouldn't wonder.
He was very drunk last night.
He is moanin' so loudly,
and then, every now and then...
-...he lets out a scream--
-Is Horace in here?
No, Mr. George,
he's gone to the store.
Brought him
a little Christmas present.
Well, thank you.
Not much, you understand,
just a little remembrance.
-It's very thoughtful of you.
-Yes.
Oh! Hello, Cousin George.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
Horace, your cousin George
brought you a Christmas present.
Well, that's, uh--
that's very kind of you,
Cousin George. Thank you.
Why don't you come on in
and visit?
Oh, no, no, no, no. I can't.
Merry Christmas.
-Well, Merry Christmas to you.
-Oh, Horace...
Did you know
that your Aunt Mary and I
were in love with each other?
If we had married,
you would call me Uncle George
instead of Cousin.
Well, no, sir.
I-I didn't know that.
I wonder if that's true
about your Aunt Mary.
Well, I wouldn't know.
I'll open this later.
I think it's a handkerchief.
Well, it's the thought
that counts.
I got the presents
for your family.
Oh, good.
Now, Brother's handkerchiefs
are initialed.
Oh, yes.
I got 'H' because Henry's
his name,
though everyone calls him
Brother.
Well, that's what
I would've done.
Um, Horace, you didn't hear
Mr. Bobby as you came in?
No, ma'am.
Oh, I was just tellin' Elizabeth
that he kept me awake
half the night with his moans.
Uh, would you come see
to Mr. Bobby? Please, Horace?
I don't like to go in his room,
you know,
because sometimes he sleeps
without his clothes on.
Uh-huh.
And take this trash
on your way out, Horace.
-Oh!
-Okay.
Brother!
You better get down here
right away
if you want a ride with us.
I'm comin', Papa!
Bobby?
Oh, how sad.
And on Christmas Day, too.
Brother!
Will you get in this Buick now?
If you wanna get along in life,
you'll have to learn
to be on time.
Well, he's quiet now.
Elizabeth, look at this.
What is it?
It's ten one-hundred
dollar bills.
Mercy!
They're here!
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Mama.
-Merry Christmas, Papa.
-Oh, Lizzy.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Brother.
Merry Christmas, Sister.
Oh, my goodness.
Who are all those for?
Well, they're not all for you
and your old man.
There's some presents here
for a future member
of the family.
Hello, Horace.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
Merry Christmas, Mr. Vaughn.
Well, uh, thank you.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
Our room is in here,
Mr. Vaughn.
Oh.
I'm so embarrassed.
I've never seen so many things
in all my life.
Uh, we just got simple things
for you.
They're mostly things
for the baby.
I see you have a crib already.
How nice.
Yes, they had a sale last month,
so we decided to buy one then.
I'm glad
we didn't get one, then.
-Do you have a buggy?
-No.
Then don't get one.
Your Papa and I
have one put aside.
Oh, Mama.
These are for the baby,
and this is for you.
Thank you.
-And this is for you.
-Oh, thank you, Brother.
Oh!
Oh, how lovely!
Oh, my, my.
I thought you should have
something pretty to wear
when you stay in bed
after you have the baby.
What do you want,
a boy or a girl?
-Oh, I don't care, really.
-Huh.
Oh, this is very nice.
Thank you.
Oh, it smells nice. Yes.
Oh, Elizabeth, look.
My, aren't they pretty?
Sure are. Thank you.
Well, they're my favorites.
Thank you.
You can never have too many.
I hope the shirt fits.
Mr. Lewis said it would.
It's a 15 neck.
-Well, that's my size.
-And a 34 sleeve.
Well, it's perfect.
Oh, thanks. I can never have
too many of these either.
It's got my initial on it.
How's college, Brother?
He doesn't apply himself.
I would've thought
that he would've learned
at Allen Academy,
that you have to study
if you wanna make grades.
But they're too lenient
at Allen Academy.
A&M is not lenient.
If you don't study
and make your grades,
you'll be kicked out.
There were so many rich boys
at Allen Academy.
There was a great deal
of gamblin' goin' on,
and carousing.
I'm afraid Brother sometimes
gets the wrong idea of things.
But his Papa let him know
he was not gonna be
like the Darst boys' father
and spend his life
gettin' him out of scrapes,
that if he makes his bed--
Why, Bessie!
In all this confusion,
I didn't see you standin' there!
Merry Christmas.
Yes, ma'am. Merry Christmas.
I have to go home now.
All right, Bessie.
She's over her a lot.
She's been a lot of company
to Elizabeth.
Mr. George Tyler is off again,
they said.
They can't get him to eat,
he accuses his wife
of poisonin' his food.
It's so sad for them all.
He went runnin' out
in the front yard late yesterday
with no clothes on.
-Naked?
-Naked.
A fine Christmas
they will have.
Oh, he's had these spells
many times before, you know.
They try to keep it quiet,
but of course they couldn't.
Well, he was just here.
He seemed all right to us.
He brought Horace
a Christmas present.
Did he? What did he bring you,
Horace?
Ten one-hundred dollar bills.
My goodness.
Wasn't that generous of him,
Mr. Vaughn?
Yes.
I attended the last public
hangin' in courthouse square.
They don't allow 'em there
anymore.
If they hang you now,
it's in the jail.
Yes, sir.
Merry Christmas, Mr. George.
-Merry Christmas, Sheriff.
-Merry Christmas.
You remember the year
they freed the slaves in Texas?
Oh, no, sir.
It was a long time ago, though.
I know that.
Before I was born.
June 19!
That is the day that
you celebrate your emancipation.
I remember that.
Yes, sir.
That's the day all right.
It sure is.
Yeah.
Well.
Here's a Christmas present
for you.
Thank you, sir.
How is your mother, Horace?
Oh, she's, uh--
she's well, last I heard.
Horace's mother's
not much of a letter-writer.
No. I've never met
your stepfather.
Have you met him, Elizabeth?
Oh, yes.
Uh, just after we were married,
we went down on the train
to Houston
and spent the Sunday with them.
I had a fine Christmas.
I got $20 from Mama and Papa,
a set of military hairbrushes,
a wristwatch, cufflinks,
a pair of gloves.
Look what I got.
Oh, Mama, it's beautiful.
Cost a lot of money.
I'm sure it did.
I know what it cost.
Well, how do you know? Huh?
Saw the price tag
before you took it off.
Well, what did you get, Papa?
Nothing as handsome as this.
Oh, I'm pleased.
An umbrella,
which I badly needed.
Bedroom slippers, a nightshirt,
socks, and a tie.
What did your Mama
send you all?
Well, their presents
haven't arrived yet.
You know the mails at Christmas.
Nothing is ever on time.
I'm sure they're sitting
in the post office right now.
They know, of course,
about the baby?
Oh, yes. I wrote them.
I'm sure they're pleased.
Oh, I'm sure they are.
Um, they haven't written back
yet.
Like I said, they're not
great letter-writers.
Oh, dear. Oh.
I remember my brother Billy
worrying so about you
on Christmas, Horace,
when you were a boy.
I was very close
to my brother Billy, you know?
Oh, yes, sir.
Elizabeth said you were.
He was very smart.
It's tragic he died so young.
I always had hopes that Brother
would follow in his footsteps
and study law.
Papa, I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to disappoint you.
I want to make a lot of money
just like you have.
Did you know, Horace,
that before Mr. Galbraith
shot Mr. Mason,
and his bank was so unsteady
because of all the money
they had loaned the farmers
during all those years
when they had
so many crop failures--
What's the point of your story,
Brother?
The point of my story, Papa,
is that the bank
would've gone under
with all the money owed it
they couldn't collect
if you hadn't taken
$50,000 of your own money
and given it to them to use.
You have to see how they act
when Papa walks in.
They just jump up and dance
when they see him.
I guess you both are plannin'
to go to Mr. Galbraith's trial?
That's gonna be a good one.
I bet $2
Mr. Galbraith will be convicted
and sent to the pen.
-You bet?
-Sure I did.
Easiest $2 I ever made.
He's guilty.
He shot Mr. Galbraith
and killed him.
They're gonna send him
to the pen.
I am not discussing his guilt,
I'm discussing your betting.
I thought you'd learned
your lesson at Allen Academy.
I thought you'd given me
your word
when you were suspended
from there
never to gamble or wager again.
Please, Mr. Vaughn,
let's don't spoil our Christmas.
Well, it's spoiled for me,
thank you.
To think he's not learned
his lesson about gambling.
I have, Papa. I won't ever
go near dice or cards.
I swore to you I wouldn't,
and I won't.
You can gamble without the use
of dice or cards, you know.
Well, my God,
I'm sorry I mentioned it.
I didn't mean a thing
in the world by it.
If I win,
I won't collect the bet.
We all know he's guilty.
He's going to the pen.
Well, let's change the subject,
for goodness sake.
It's Christmas Day.
Elizabeth!
Oh. I hate terribly
to bother you all, but, well--
Well, I'm sure that, uh,
Horace and Elizabeth
have told you
about poor Mr. Bobby.
-No.
-No?
Oh, well.
He is D-R-U-N-K.
Uh, did you call the doctor?
Yes, I did, but as you know,
he's so small and slight,
he feels he can't handle
Mr. Bobby by himself.
So, he says he needs the help
of two strong men
to help hold him down.
-I'll give you a hand, Horace.
-Oh, thank you.
Oh.
-Merry Christmas.
-Merry Christmas, Bobby.
Hey, uh,
I'm lookin' for my mother.
-Yeah, she's in Bay City, Bobby.
-Oh.
-Merry Christmas, Bobby.
-Uh--
-Is this Christmas?
-Yes it is, Bobby.
-Oh. What's the year, please?
-It's 1917.
-Are we at war?
-Uh-huh.
Uh, Mr. Henry Vaughn, uh,
he wouldn't take me
when I volunteered my services.
He said I wasn't good enough
to serve my country.
Uh, that's not true, Bobby.
You're certainly good enough,
but you see, we have
certain physical standards.
-Who are you?
-Henry Vaughn.
That's right.
And he did try to join
several times,
and that's certainly
commendable.
It makes you sick the way
some of them do anything
to keep out of it.
Lonnie Bigelow shot his toe off
to keep out of the army.
We can't be sure of that,
Brother.
It might just have been
an accident.
Wasn't no accident.
It was deliberate.
Lonnie Bigelow told Steve Mason
if shooting one big toe off
didn't keep him out,
he'd shoot the other one off.
Here you are, Bobby.
I've been lookin' all over
for you.
Who are you?
Why, I'm Dr. Goodhue, Bobby.
Now, you know who I am.
What do you want with me?
I want to give you something
to quiet you,
make you feel better,
maybe even sleep a little.
You're not giving me anything.
You're not making a dope fiend
out of me.
Uh, you made a dope fiend
out of Harry Newsome,
sticking him with needles,
but you ain't doin' it to me.
Now, Bobby, that's not true.
You know that's not true.
Harry Newsome says it's true.
He's a dope fiend.
And he says
that you're responsible.
Bobby, Bobby, you're drunk.
You don't know
what you're saying.
I know what I'm sayin'.
I was in the saloon the night
Raymond Happ came in,
and he walked over to Briggs,
the saloon keep.
He says, "I told you
if you sold my daddy
another bottle of whiskey,
I'd kill you."
And he, uh, uh--
He took out his gun,
and he killed him,
and they let him go free,
'cause they said Briggs
had made a drunkard of his daddy
by sellin' him whiskey.
And, uh, uh, they're gonna let
Mr. Galbraith go free, too,
'cause I-I bet Brother Vaughn
$40 they would.
-Bobby, Bobby--
-That's $40 final.
I'm sure, I'm sure.
Now, come with me now.
Oh, take your goddamn hands
off me.
You son of a bitch.
Hey, Bobby.
There are ladies present.
Horace,
I'll need some help here.
-Come on, Bobby.
-No, let go of me, goddamn--
Oh!
Bobby.
You drunken bastard.
You're drunk as much as I am.
Isn't it sad?
He's so gentlemanly, too,
when he's sober.
I hope your brother
gets his eyes opened by this.
Preachin' doesn't do
a bit of good, you know,
but, uh, sometimes
when they actually see
something like this happenin'...
No.
-Come on.
-No!
-Come on, Bobby. Come on.
No, goddamn it!
Goddamn it.
Elizabeth, I'm worried
about your brother.
You heard what Mr. Bobby
said about him just now.
Well, he was drunk, Mama.
He didn't know
what he was sayin'.
They've just gotten him
on the bed.
He fights like a wild man.
Your Papa is workin' so hard,
Elizabeth.
Everyone calls on him
when they need something done.
When the bank reorganization
is done,
I am gonna make him go with me
to Mineral Wells
and we'll take the baths
for a week.
Please, don't ask Horace anymore
about presents from his family.
You know, I don't think they've
ever exchanged gifts with him.
He's extremely sensitive
about it.
I know this year he thought
they would send something,
because he kept goin'
to the post office
and lookin' for something
from them.
Did he send them anything?
Yes, he did.
He acted like he might not,
because, like he said,
they've never exchange gifts.
And I thought
he wasn't goin' to.
So I went down and bought
a few things without tellin' him
and sent them on.
And then, he bought some things
and sent them on
without sayin' anything to me.
And Miss Virgie
was in Houston last week
and she saw his mother,
and she said she was
very confused
because she'd gotten two boxes
of presents.
She told Miss Virgie
she was worried
about our bein' extravagant.
She said it put her
in a terrible position,
because, um, his stepfather
never sends anything
to his people at Christmas.
And she doesn't like to ask him
for the money
for her people at Christmastime.
I think he's a very strange man.
The stepfather?
Yes. I don't think Horace
cares too much for him.
I'm sorry.
They never go near him,
you know?
And it hurts him.
I tell him it shouldn't,
but it does.
It would hurt me.
Wouldn't it hurt you,
Mr. Vaughn?
I guess, but my God,
he should be used to it by now.
He's never had a home.
Has he ever had a home?
He has a home now.
Oh, this isn't a home.
It's a rented room.
I think it's very nice.
Well, that may be,
but it's still a rented room.
A home is something you own,
that belongs to you.
He has the strength of ten men.
He wore me out.
-Did he give him a shot?
-Uh, yes, sir.
-Hey. Where's Brother?
-Well, he's on his way down.
He was helpin' Miss Ruth find
where Mr. Bobby has
all his whiskey hidden.
She's afraid
that when the dope wears off,
he'll start to drink again,
unless they can find
the bottles.
I'll get him for you.
-Phone for you, Horace.
-Thank you, Brother.
Hello.
Hello, Steve.
-Is Bobby quiet?
-He's calmer.
Now?
He wants Miss Ruth to sing
the song she sang
at the soldier's benefit.
Is she going to?
I guess so.
She says she'll do anything
to keep him quiet.
Mr. Bobby is wrong
when he says that I bet him
$40 about Mr. Galbraith.
I never said anything about $40.
It was $2.
I didn't wanna correct him,
though,
because drunk as he was,
I knew that it would probably
just start an argument.
Goodbye.
Excuse me.
Steve Tyler says he's, uh,
comin' over to talk to me.
Why does he wanna talk to you?
I don't know.
We'd better be getting
back home, Mary.
It's almost time for our dinner.
-Bye, Lizzy.
-Goodbye, Papa.
♪ After the ball is over
♪ After the break of morn
I'll call you, Elizabeth.
-♪ After the dancers' leaving
-All right, Mama.
♪ After the stars have gone
-♪ Many a heart is aching
-Bye, Horace!
♪ If you could read them all
♪ Many a hope
that has vanished ♪
♪ After the ball
-Goodbye.
-Bye.
Bye!
I'm so glad we've all made up.
Yes.
That-- that was the nicest
Christmas present of all.
Mm-hm.
I don't understand
my mother or my sister.
Would've thought
they would have sent
some kind of present
to you at least, or the baby.
I don't care about myself.
It doesn't matter to me.
Yeah, well,
I wish I could say that,
but it does matter to me.
I'm--
I'm ashamed of myself,
Elizabeth,
but I felt such envy just now.
I looked at your father,
and I thought,
I envy him, his success,
his well-being, his affluence,
and I envy his children
having a father like that.
Sending them to college.
I-I-I don't understand
your brother
not taking advantage
of an education.
Sometimes I think
that if I'd had someone help me
get through high school
and college,
my whole life
would be different.
Well, I think you've done
very well.
I'm very proud of you.
We've been married less
than a year
and you have money saved.
Well, I-I'm not complaining.
I know I've got a lot
to be grateful for, but...
...who isn't doing well now
with the war on
and the world needing
our cotton,
and cotton selling
for 40 cents a pound?
I mean, if you can't do well
now, when can you?
Suppose the war isn't over
next year,
or the next,
and all the unmarried men
are taken,
and they need more men,
and they start draftin'
those of us that have children.
I worry how long the few dollars
I've been able to save
will take care of you
and the baby.
I mean, imagine being able
to walk into the bank
like your father did, and say,
"Here's $50,000.
Use it to save your bank."
God help me, Elizabeth.
God help me, I am jealous
of your father. Forgive me.
When I was nine years old, I...
...I had some chickens
that I raised as pets.
They were the--
the only pets I ever had.
And I loved them.
They used to eat out of my hands
when I fed them
and follow me
around the yard like--
like dogs do their owners.
Mama had a boarding house then,
and on Christmas
of my ninth year,
she had no money
to feed her boys,
so without telling me,
she went out back
and killed the chickens
for their Christmas dinner.
When I found out, I became ill.
Had a raging fever for a week.
Mama says the illness
was never diagnosed.
When I see her now,
well, she's--
she's all smiles and honey.
She doesn't know the pain,
or the unhappiness,
or the bitterness
that she's caused me.
Sometimes when I'm around her,
I have to get up
and walk out of the room
to keep from tellin' her.
I'm no orphan, but I think
of myself as an orphan,
belonging to no one but you.
I intend to have everything
I didn't have before:
a house of my own,
some land, a yard.
And in that yard,
I will have growing things:
fig trees, and pear trees,
and peach trees.
Some chickens.
And I do believe I might now
have all these things
because you married me.
I said to myself--
Before we were married,
I said to myself,
"She will never marry you.
No matter how much
she loves you,
her father will stop us.
He's a powerful man.
And he will prevail
as he does in all ways."
But he didn't stop us.
You did marry me.
And I tell you,
I have begun to know happiness
for the first time in my life.
I adore you.
I worship you.
And...
I thank you for marrying me.
Horace?
Yes, Steve?
Was my father here earlier?
Yes, he was.
Did he, uh, give you a present?
A Christmas present?
Well, yes he did.
Was it money?
-Yes.
-My God.
Well, it seems
the day before yesterday,
he had taken out $15,000
in one-hundred dollar bills
and had told the teller
it was for Christmas presents
for his colored friends,
and Daddy said
you were one of 'em.
And the tellers said,
"I didn't think Horace Robedaux
was colored,"
and he said that Daddy said,
"Well, he's not,
but he's my cousin."
Teller said he thought,
of course,
that he wasn't makin'
a great deal of sense.
Oh, thank you.
You don't know
where else he went to?
No, I don't.
-Merry Christmas to you both.
-Merry Christmas to you.
♪ That made me love Mary
♪ The rose who...
-Good morning.
-Morning!
I-I'm takin' a walk uptown.
Do you need anything?
-Not today, thank you.
-Oh.
I hope I'll get a letter today
from Mrs. Pate or Mr. Bobby
from Galveston.
I sure hope Mr. Bobby
sticks with that Keeley Cure.
I haven't heard a word yet.
I hope they're all right.
Well, no news is good news,
they say.
-Bye.
Good mornin', Henry.
Oh, good mornin', Ned.
You know where Horace is?
-No, I don't.
-I wonder if he's sick.
Oh, I don't believe so.
I think Elizabeth
would've told us if he was sick.
-You wanna buy something?
-No.
Got a bill I wanna collect.
Is it a large bill?
No, no.
He always manages
to pay his bill on time,
regardless of what they are.
Well, I'm certainly pleased
to hear that.
Is Mr. Horace not back yet?
Uh, no.
Hm.
Come to get a suit for Easter?
No, I'm just here
to collect a bill.
Hm. Is that so?
I come to spend some money
with him,
and you come to take
some money from him. Hm.
-Good morning, Horace.
-Morning, Steve.
Papa's upstairs in his room.
-Thank you.
-All right.
Come in, son.
How are you this morning?
Pretty well, thank you.
Hasn't this rain been something?
Mm.
Terrible for the cotton.
What's it like today?
Oh, it's, uh--
it's very pleasant.
May we have nice weather
for Easter for a change.
Easter Bunny gonna be nice
to you this year?
I sure-- I sure hope so.
Son, I called you over
'cause I want you to go
to your family for me,
and I want you
to ask their forgiveness.
I've done 'em a grave injustice.
How's that, Cousin George?
'Cause I was in love
with your Aunt Mary,
and she was in love with me,
and I broke her heart.
How is your Aunt Mary?
Why, Cousin George,
Aunt Mary's dead.
Has been dead for 12 years.
I thought you knew that.
Where is she buried?
Out in West Texas.
Where in West Texas?
Bandero.
I wanna go there right away.
Where's Steve?
Well, he's--
he's out in the gallery.
Will you go?
Please.
Won't you go out there,
tell Steve to go to the bank
right away,
get some money for my trip?
Did you hear from Mr. Bobby?
Oh, just his mother.
-She sent a card.
-Oh.
Um, "Everything well here.
Hope all is well there.
Isabel Pate and son Bobby."
See?
Oh, and it's a pretty picture
of the Galveston boardwalk.
Have you ever been to Galveston?
-Oh, yes. A number of times.
-Oh.
I have two aunts
that live there.
-My father's sisters.
-Yes, of course.
I love Galveston.
Well, I've never been there.
I hope to go someday.
In the summer,
they have excursions
that leave from here
at five in the mornin',
get you to Galveston at eight,
and then, bring you back
at ten that very same evenin'.
My aunts live near the beach.
They have a wonderful house.
Did it last
through that 1900 storm?
-Yes, it did.
-Mm-hm.
Well, then,
it'll last though anything.
Was there anything worse
than that 1900 storm?
Well, it must've been terrible,
but I really don't remember it.
Oh.
Oh!
I almost forgot,
I saw your father uptown,
and he asked me
to give this to you.
-Thank you.
-Mm-hm.
-Is that the time? Good Lord.
-I'm afraid so.
I have not made my bed yet.
I'm glad I've had no callers.
Papa!
Papa, where you goin'?
Mr. George?
-Elizabeth.
-Yes, sir?
What you reading?
Holland's Magazine.
Interestin' stories?
Well, I think so.
I'm not lookin' at the stories,
I'm-- I'm lookin'
at the house plans.
-Elizabeth?
-Yes?
I can't go uptown.
Could you call Horace
and tell him to meet me here
in an hour or so?
All right.
Holland's Magazine.
Magazine of the South.
-You subscribe?
-Yes, sir.
Horace gave me a subscription
for Christmas.
You recommend that I subscribe?
I think you might enjoy it.
I subscribe
to National Geographic.
I always planned to travel,
but I've gone no place.
You have a good recipe
for Dixie biscuits?
Well, I think my mother has one.
Would you ask her for it,
please?
I asked my wife...
Hey!
...to fix some Dixie biscuits
for me this morning.
She said she didn't know how.
Can you believe that?
I come from a family of cooks,
you know.
My mother was a great cook,
my grandmother even better.
You a good cook?
Well, I hope to be.
Uh, we-- we don't have
a kitchen here.
We take our meals out.
I'm goin' down to the river
for a swim.
Will you join me?
No, thank you.
Never go down there
without a gun.
Alligators down there.
Poisonous snakes.
Coral snakes, moccasins,
cottonmouths.
Yes?
He was just here
lookin' for you.
He's gone down to the river.
Mr. George Tyler's off again.
I know. He was just here.
Whoo!
Ah!
Ha.
Well, Mr. Galbraith walked away
a free man.
He's not free.
He got a suspended sentence.
Yes, ma'am,
but he didn't go to jail.
I wonder if Mr. Bobby
collected the $40
from your brother.
I don't know. Brother claims
the bet was only for two.
Ah!
Papa!
-I think I see him over there.
-Where?
Back yonder.
Mr. George!
We know you're there,
Mr. George.
Now, why don't you answer us?
Papa, it's Steve.
Can you hear me?
Where's Horace Robedaux?
He's right here beside me.
We've come
to take you home now, Papa.
Horace.
Yes, sir.
I want you take me to Bandero.
I wanna visit Mary's grave.
Yes, sir.
Is there a train
from here to Bandero?
I guess so.
Well, would you please find out?
-Yes, sir.
-You go on home now.
But tell him you're finding out
about the train.
-Horace!
-Yes, sir.
Did you find out
about the train to Bandero?
Not yet.
Well, hurry and find out.
Yes, sir.
Papa?
Papa, come on out now.
Did you hear what I said?
Papa?
Ruth Amos is learning
a new song.
Mama said she did so well
at the soldier's benefit,
she's learning a new one
in case she's asked
to sing again.
Look here, Bessie.
Do you like this house?
Yes, I do.
I got a note today from Papa
sayin' Mama wanted
to give me a house
and to call him about it.
And I did.
And he said she had in mind
a house costin' $4,000,
which is exactly
what this house costs.
Bessie, I'm a nervous wreck.
I want a house so badly
to bring the baby to.
But I don't wanna cross Horace,
and I don't know
how Horace will feel
about takin' something like this
from Mama and Papa.
Did you find your cousin George?
Yes.
He's hiding in the woods.
He wants me to take him
to Bandero.
I don't know how Cousin Sarah
would take his visiting
Aunt Mary's grave.
This is from Mama.
All she does, poor thing,
is apologize
for not having gotten us
anything for Christmas.
Well, this came early
this afternoon.
I called Papa.
I told him you'd saved
almost enough money
to buy us a house.
He said to tell
you could take that money
and use it to buy war bonds.
You think he believed
I had enough money saved
for a house?
Why shouldn't he?
Did you tell him
you'd accept his gift?
No. I thanked him,
but I said I would have
to talk it over with you first.
He said to tell you
it was a gift from Mama
and not from him.
If you take it, the deed will be
in your name.
I don't want anyone around here
insinuating
that I married you for a house.
-Well, who would say that?
-Everyone.
Well, I won't take it, honey,
if you don't want me to.
Where is the house to be?
Right behind theirs.
Well, I don't mind
you accepting it
if you make it clear
it is to be in your name
and no part of it
to belong to me.
But it will always be your home.
I hope you'll always be able
to think of it as your home.
Well, I'm sure I will.
I just want everyone
to understand
who the gift was for.
-They meant it for us both.
-No, I don't think so.
It says very clearly here
in the note
that, uh, your mother wishes
to give you a house.
Horace, please,
don't be sensitive.
Our lives will be miserable
if you are.
Look, I'm not. Believe me.
If-- if it had been offered
to both of us,
I would insist it be
in your name.
Horace.
Hello, Cousin George.
This your wife?
Well, yes, sir. You
know Elizabeth.
Mr. Henry Vaughn's
oldest daughter.
Did you find out
about the train to Bandero?
Oh, yes, sir.
Uh, there's none.
None at all?
No, sir. Not from here.
-It's in the middle of nowhere.
-Man!
It's all right.
Too tired to go anyway.
About to fall over,
I'm so tired.
Been walkin'
through the river bottoms.
This your girl?
Oh, no, sir.
She lives down the street.
Just a neighbor.
-Who she belong to?
-The Stillmans.
This your house?
Oh, no, sir.
This is Mrs. Pate's house.
Where is Mrs. Pate?
I'd like to say hello to her.
Well, she's not a home.
She's, uh, over in Galveston
with Mr. Bobby.
He's, uh--
he's taking the Keeley Cure.
Oh.
Was he drinking again?
Well, yes, sir.
Ah, that's too bad.
Daddy drinks, son.
Yes, sir.
-Killed him.
-Yes, sir.
How's your mother?
She's well.
Father sent for me
just before he died.
-I ever tell you this?
-No, sir.
Yeah.
He said,
"George, I'm gonna die.
Promise me
you'll look after my children.
Promise me you'll never
let them go hungry."
Well, didn't keep my promise.
I'm sorry.
Didn't keep my promise
about a lot of things.
You say Mary's dead.
Yes, sir.
They won't let me die.
I wanna die.
They've been chasin' me
all through the river bottoms.
They give me no peace.
First they wanna kill me.
My own wife tried to poison me.
And then, when I wanna
take my own life,
they do all in their power
to stop me.
I've had a difficult life
since I betrayed Mary.
I've had no happiness.
I've been punished unmercifully
for what I done.
-You know the way to my home?
-Yes, sir.
Will you take me there?
I'm very confused.
-Tried to get there twice.
-Yes, sir.
How old was Mary when she died?
She was 40.
She had long, blonde hair
when I last saw her.
Did she when she died?
I believe so.
I married her cousin
from Kentucky.
Now, what the hell's her name?
Sarah.
Sarah, yeah. Sarah.
Are you the son I had by Mary?
No, sir.
Where's the son I had by Mary?
I don't believe you had one
by Mary, sir.
-I didn't?
-No, sir.
-I have children.
-Oh, yes, sir. You've got four.
Mary ever have children?
No, she didn't.
Poor Mary,
dyin' without children.
They think I'm crazy, you know.
I do get terrible headaches.
I can't think then.
But I wouldn't harm anybody.
Once I tried to kill Sarah.
I didn't mean it.
I don't know what I did.
Took a butcher knife
on Christmas Eve,
chased her all around the house.
Yow!
I'm glad I didn't kill her.
I'd have been sorry if I had.
I need help, but nobody here
can help me.
Gonna go out there now.
And I want you to go with me,
son.
I want you to tell 'em for me
I need help.
And if I can't get it,
I want them to kill me.
'Cause I don't wanna go on
like this.
You tell 'em that for me?
Yes, sir. I will.
Let's go.
Can you see them, Bessie?
Yes, ma'am.
They're on the porch.
Are they talkin' together?
Were you scared of him, Mary?
I don't know.
It all happened so quickly.
Was that Mr. George
I saw with Horace?
Yes, sir.
What is it, Lizzie?
You're trembling.
Is Horace in danger?
No, sir. I don't think so.
Oh, Papa.
Mr. George Tyler is so pitiful.
He doesn't even know
who his own wife is
half the time.
You love your husband,
don't you?
Yes, I do.
Mary, I'm goin' home.
-Goodbye.
-Goodbye, Bessie.
I wonder
how he got past the sheriff
and the others in the bottom
and got in here.
He told Horace
he wanted to get back home.
All he wants to do is talk
about Horace's Aunt Mary.
-Were they in love, Papa?
-Oh, God knows.
That must have been
30 years ago at least.
Anyway, he's had four children
by poor Miss Sarah.
I expect she wanted to go
running through
the river bottoms many a time.
These the plans
for the new house?
I got your brother's mid-term
report card today from college.
It's just terrible.
I've never seen such grades.
What am I gonna do with him?
You say you can get this built
for $4,000?
Yes, sir.
You mind if I take it with me
and study it some?
No, sir.
You have a chance
to speak to Horace?
Yes, sir. He says
it's all right with him
as long as the house is--
is put in my name.
He doesn't want anyone here
thinking
he is taking help from you.
I think he's awfully sensitive.
He still thinks
that you don't like him, Papa.
Oh, I like him all right,
Elizabeth. Give me time.
These things take time.
I sometimes think I should take
your brother out of college,
put him on one of the farms.
Let him learn
how difficult it is
for an uneducated man
to earn a living.
I was determined
not to raise him
as a rich man's son.
But he has no ambition. None.
And I hate to say this
about my own child,
but he's a terrible liar.
You know that bet
with Bobby Pate
that he says was for $2
and still swears it was?
Well, Bobby was right.
It was for $40.
There were
four reliable witnesses
that heard him make that bet.
So, I sent Bobby a check
for $40 today.
Well, maybe that's a mistake.
Maybe if he had to pay back
that money himself--
Where's he gonna get $40
goin' to A&M College?
No. I paid it.
And I'll see to it that he works
around the house,
around the farm,
until I'm paid back.
You know
I'm not a very sociable man.
It isn't just with Horace.
I don't have an easy time
talking with my own son.
Yes, sir.
You see, Horace's father died
when he was 12.
Well, I was 12
when my father died.
I went to work soon after.
I put myself through college.
I realize that, Papa.
I haven't stopped working
for a second, since I was 12.
I resented Horace,
I resented him very much,
coming into my home--
But I'll get over it.
Time heals all that.
Oh, honey,
I'm so glad you're back.
I was worryin'.
Did he go on home?
I don't know.
I only walked halfway with him
when Steve and the sheriff
drove up.
And Steve got out of the car
and came over to us,
told Cousin George
he was gonna take him home.
I didn't think Cousin George
would go at first,
but finally, he did, and got
in the car and drove away.
I don't know
where they'll take him.
Oh.
You know,
it all happened so quickly,
I forgot to tell Steve
what Cousin George asked me to
about his needing help.
My God, you don't have to tell
anybody that.
He's needed help for years.
Who could help him?
I showed Papa the--
the plans for the house.
Uh, he's taking them home
with him to study them.
By tomorrow or the next day,
I'll drive you out
and show you where your two lots
are to be and your new road.
I'll show you where I think
you should plant some trees.
Lizzie.
Where you goin'?
I'm going to get you something
for your headache.
No, I'll get it myself.
You rest now.
You've had a rough mornin'.
No, I'm goin' with you.
Want to be sure
what you're givin' me.
Might be trying to poison me.
You can do a great deal
on two lots.
You can have all the trees
that you want.
And you can have chickens.
I can feel the baby movin'.
Can you feel it?
Oh. Yes.
When I was three years old,
my baby sister Jenny died
with diphtheria.
Mama was pregnant then,
and they had her
in bed restin',
and Papa's sisters from Brazoria
came to stay with us.
And one of them took me
in her arms
and showed me Jenny
in her coffin,
and I got hysterical.
I fought to get away,
and I raised such a commotion
Papa ran in,
and his sister told him
he had an unnatural child...
...that refused to look
at her own dead sister.
Mama doesn't even have
a picture of Jenny any longer
where you can see it.
It's hidden away at the bottom
of her cedar chest.
Papa. Papa.
Papa.
Papa?
Papa!
When I was five
and Laura was two,
I told her I wanted to show her
where our dead sister was.
And Mr. Billy Lee,
a friend of Papa's,
saw us walkin' down the road,
and he asked
where we were goin'.
And I said,
"Lookin' for our dead sister."
And he said,
"You can't find her."
And I said, "Why not?"
And he said, "Because she's
not there, she's in heaven."
And I said, "No, she's not.
She's shut up in a box
and buried in a graveyard."
And he took us both,
and he put us on his horse,
and he took us
out to the graveyard,
and we found her little grave
with that lamb on it.
He said, "She's not in there.
She's in heaven."
And I said,
"Who's in there, then?"
And he said, "No one."
"Well," I said,
"How did she get out of there?"
And he said,
"God took her home with Him."
Mary! Mary!
What is it, Bessie?
Mr. George Tyler.
Mr. George Tyler
got away from them
when they were
takin' him out of the car.
He started runnin' back
towards the river,
and then, he stopped.
-What? Did they catch him?
-No, sir.
He took out a knife
and stabbed himself
before they could get to him.
Oh, my God!
He was dead by the time
they got to him.
And I saw Mr. Bobby
down there, too. He's drunk.
Mama said that he slipped away
from his mother in Galveston
and got drunk
and came on back here.
Mrs. Pate's comin' home tonight
on the 11:00 train.
Well, I better get over,
see if I can be
of any help to Sarah.
Well, what about your supper?
Well, I'll get something uptown.
You go on and have something
by yourself.
Horace!
Come back!
Don't leave me!
-Did he hear you?
-No.
Do you want me
to go fetch him back?
No.
I told Mama about Miss Mary
being buried in Bandero, Texas,
and she said it was Junction
as near as she could remember.
She says it's just as desolate
out there.
Do you think they'll bury him
out there next to Miss Mary?
I doubt it.
Will they bury him here?
I don't know.
Aren't you gonna go out
and get your supper?
No. Not tonight.
I'm not hungry now.
Are you mad at Horace
'cause he went off without you?
No.
You're upset about something,
though, aren't you?
Yes.
Mr. George Tyler,
I can't believe
he was just here,
and now...
You'll be married a year
on Valentine's Day.
Are you glad
you married Horace?
Yes, I am.
Do you love him now as much
as when you first married him?
Yes, I do.
Do you think in 25 years
you'll still love him
as much as you do now?
Yes.
Do you think he'll still
love you as much then?
Oh, I hope so.
-More?
-More.
What about in 50 years?
Do you think you'll still
love each other then?
If you're still alive.
You could both be dead
in 50 years.
How old will you be when you've
been married for 50 years?
Seventy-four.
And Horace?
Seventy-seven.
You'll have gray hair then
unless you dye it.
Yes.
And my baby will be 49.
And you'll have grandchildren.
And maybe even
great-grandchildren.
What's the matter?
I don't wanna get old, Bessie.
And I don't want Horace
to get old.
I want everything to stay
just as it is.
When I'm 74,
Mama and Papa will be dead,
unless they live to be 100,
and I don't want anybody I love
to die.
Not Horace...
Not Mama, not Papa.
Not my brother, not my sisters,
and not the baby
I'm gonna have.
What about me?
Do you want me to die?
Oh, no, I don't.
I don't want you ever to die.
I'm sorry, uh, ladies,
for not knockin'.
I forgot this room was rented.
This used to be the parlor.
I, uh-- I had a lovely time
in Galveston.
It was-- it was a little cool
for bathing,
but on sunny days,
we sat on the boardwalk
and enjoyed the sunshine.
My mother sends her regards.
-Oh, hello, Horace.
-Hello, Bobby.
Hey, did you hear
about Mr. George Tyler?
He took a knife
and he stabbed himself
in the heart.
You were kin to Mr. George,
weren't you?
Yes, by marriage.
Bessie, I-I passed your mother.
She said you were
to come on home.
Yes, sir.
I, uh--
I wanna show you good people
a check that I got today.
It's for $40.
It's from Mr. Henry Vaughn,
and it's in payment for--
We know all about that, Bobby.
We know all about that.
When Miss Ruth, uh,
sang at the soldier's benefit,
they announced her
as the Songbird of the South.
Did you go to Miss Sarah's?
Yes. Steve said there wasn't
anything I could do.
He said they have had
Cousin Sarah under sedation
ever since Mr. George ran away.
He said she wouldn't see
anybody.
Sheriff said Cousin George
wasn't quite dead
when he got to him.
He said he had asked for me.
He said he had promised my daddy
he'd look out for me.
-You heard about Mr. George?
-Yes.
It's just terrible, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
It's terrible.
It's terrible. Terrible.
I brought some books over
I thought you should have,
Horace.
Some volumes of Bulwer-Lytton
and Thackery, Wilkie Collins.
They belonged to your father,
I believe.
He had his name written in 'em.
I got them years before
from Senator Dockery.
I said to my wife
the other night,
"I... I think Horace
should have them."
Oh, well, thank you, sir.
Elizabeth says you think
I don't like you.
Papa, I never said
he told me that.
I only said I felt
he felt that way.
Well, I do like you.
And I respect you, and--
Well, I hear you've been
over to the bank
about a loan
for opening a store.
Yes, sir, but, uh,
I won't need their help now.
I can use the money I have been
saving to buy a house.
Well, I don't want you to spend
all the money you save.
Now, let me loan you the money
to help you get started,
and you can take whatever
you have saved
and buy liberty bonds.
That way you'll be helping
your country, too.
I can let you have the money
for your business,
no interest at all,
and you can pay me back
whenever it's convenient.
Well, yes sir, thank you, sir.
I appreciate it,
but I can't accept it.
Well, I want to help.
You've done enough for us
already.
Thank you, sir,
but, uh, I can't let you.
-Well, if you change your mind.
-Thank you.
You know, I think
an unhappy marriage
is the worst thing in the world.
I'm happily married, thank God,
and I trust you will be.
Like I said to Mrs. Vaughn
when Elizabeth asked
about marrying you, I said--
Well, um, that's all water
over the dam, isn't it?
All water over the dam.
Everyone says to me,
"Poor Horace.
Never had a father."
Well, like I told Elizabeth,
I never had a father either.
And now, I have no son.
I'll hate myself tomorrow
for saying this,
but God forgive me,
I have no son at all.
He's a stranger to me.
I don't know which way to turn.
There's peace in this room
and contentment.
That's why I like to come here,
I think.
I said to Mrs. Vaughn
the other night,
"They don't have much,
but they're contented.
You feel that."
I hope you find contentment
in your new home.
I'd buy that for you if I could,
but things like that
can't be bought.
Uh, Miss Ruth's in her room,
cryin'.
And I asked her what was wrong,
she said her heart was broke.
Do you think
I should go see about it?
Oh, I don't know. I--
I explained to Miss Ruth, uh,
that I was still married
to a lovely girl
in the sight of God.
Elizabeth, I, uh--
Oh. Excuse me.
I didn't know you had guests.
Come in, Miss Ruth.
I'm not staying long.
Mrs. Vaughn is coming in
on a Houston train.
-Oh, oh.
-Sit down.
Uh, it's, uh, too bad
about Mr. George, isn't it?
Oh, yes.
Oh, I just heard
about your new house.
Uh, did you hear about
their new house, Mr. Bobby?
Uh, well,
they'll be leavin' us soon.
Well, we'll miss
Horace and Elizabeth,
won't we, Mr. Bobby?
They had to elope
to get married, you know?
Uh, Elizabeth's
mother and father--
That's all in the past now,
Mr. Bobby.
Everybody has forgiven
everybody now.
Papa is givin' us
this lovely new house.
Oh, that's nice to hear.
I'm always happy
when things turn out well.
When did you all
forgive each other?
Last Christmas.
Oh, in this very room.
Uh, how long
have you been married?
It will be a year
Valentine's Day.
They're, uh--
they're a very happy couple.
Uh, you know, I-I remarked
to Mama the other day,
I said, uh, "I believe that's
one marriage that'll take."
I remember the day
Horace eloped.
It was Easter.
Easter Sunday.
No, no, Mr. Bobby.
It was Valentine's Day.
Ah.
Y'all have a family, uh, plot
reserved at the graveyard?
I told Mama the other night,
"We don't have a family plot.
We have to get one,
'cause I want us together
even in death."
Miss Ruth, uh, here's the house
we're giving the children.
We hope to have it ready
soon after
their new baby is born.
Mr. Billy Lee was by my office
this afternoon, Elizabeth.
He was remembering the time
he found you and Laura
lookin' for the graveyard
to see Jenny's grave.
This is gonna be lovely.
Hey. Mr. Billy Lee's oldest boy
was a sissy.
He had a lovely singin' voice,
though.
It was very high. A tenor.
Uh, he dresses up
in girls' clothes.
Mr. Billy says he whips
the devil out of him
every time
he catches him doin' it,
but he can't break him.
Jenny would've been 22
if she had lived.
Twenty-three.
Her birthday was last week.
Jenny was frail from the start.
You were always healthy,
Elizabeth.
Well, that's how it goes.
One lives and one dies.
That Valentine's Day,
uh, the whole town was excited.
Everyplace you went,
that's all they talked about
was Horace and Elizabeth
eloping.
It, uh-- it was romantic.
It was a warm and lovely day.
You remember?
No, Mr. Bobby.
It was cold and windy.
♪ Oh, promise me
Was it a large wedding?
No.
Just Allie, and Hector,
and the Baptist preacher--
And I was there.
I sang "Oh Promise Me"
as they walked across the room
to face the preacher.
Betty Norton carried a few roses
we had picked in Allie's yard.
I began to cry
in the middle of the ceremony,
and I think Horace thought
I was sorry we were marryin'.
Why were you cryin'?
I don't know.
What kind of flowers
did you say the Norton girl
carried at your wedding?
Roses.
Your Mama planted
sweetheart roses last fall
next to Jenny's grave.
She planted a red rose
by Jenny's grave
and a pink one by Daisy's.
Have any of you heard
when Mr. George Tyler's funeral
will be?
I'm sure it won't be
for a few days.
He's got relatives
all over the state,
and, uh, they'll wanna be sure
to give them time to get here.
Mama saw Mr. Billy Lee
whip Edgar once.
She was over to Mr. Lee's
visitin' one day.
Mr. Billy came home and she--
she heard him say,
"Take that dress off."
And then, she said Edgar,
he ran across the front yard
in his sister's dress,
and Mr. Billy,
he ran after him.
He, uh-- he caught him
halfway across the front yard,
and he, uh-
he had, uh, his buggy--
Whip.
He beat him.
She thought he'd kill him.
She said Mrs. Lee--
Mrs. Lee just sat there talkin'
like nothin' had happened.
You know, I think I am gonna
rent me a house of my own.
I am tired of tryin' to live
in that one little room.
I hope to have all kinds
of roses growin' in our yard
after our house is built.
Red roses, yellow roses,
pink roses,
sweetheart roses,
and climbin' roses.
♪ Oh, promise me
♪ That someday you and I
♪ Will take our love together
to some sky ♪
♪ Where we can be alone
and faith renewed ♪
♪ And find the hollows
where those flowers grew ♪
My Mama was, uh, an aristocrat,
you know?
♪ Those first sweet violets
of early spring ♪
Her-- her daddy had millions,
you know?
♪ That come in whispers
Uh, they were blue blood.
♪ Trill us both and sing
♪ Of love unspeakable
♪ That is to be
♪ Oh, promise me