This is it?
Yeah, sir.
You are calling
that piece of shit a plane?
Yes, sir.
It can fly over Mountain Everest, sir.
It can fly over Mountain Everest?
What? Are you kidding?
Luosang.
Come back here!
- Stay awayfrom that witch.
- Stop!
- Get him back here.
Don't run.
Let go of me.
- Let go of me.
- Go back.
Go back!
- Let go of me.
- Go back.
Let me go.
Don't you ever go near her tent again.
- I told you she will jinx you.
- Get back.
Let me go, let me go.
Witch.
- Witch.
The witch is here. Quickly! Run!
I told you to stay away from that tent.
Why wouldn't you listen to me?
Go home now!
Orthe devil will come.
Yongcuo.
You are so beautiful.
Here, take the meat.
Eat, Yongcuo.
And this.
Yongcuo, and this lamb too.
Yongcuo.
Can I be the child's father?
Can I, Yongcuo?
Yongcuo, don't you want it?
- Luosang!
- Here you go.
- Get back here.
- Take it.
You can't go there.
You should watch out that witch.
Who's there?
Hello?
I saw the devil by the lake.
Over there.
Here comes Grandpa Danzeng.
Devil! He must be the Devil!
He is no devil. He's a foreigner.
I saw them once in India
when I was young.
He's still alive.
The British.
The damn British are here again.
What should we do?
Where can we hide him?
This is the only way out.
Grandpa Danzeng.
He is either the devil...
...or coming out of the snow,
or falling from the sky.
Ask him yourself when he's awake.
Come here Yongcuo, quickly!
Here, give me your hand.
Don't go. You gotta help me here.
I only have one pair of hands.
Yes that's it.
Rub gently just like
the way you spin the Prayer Wheel.
Do it until his skin gets
as hot as fresh cow muck.
Oh, my head hurts like hell.
You owe me three sheep.
Two.
We are 26 degrees off
from our original course.
I am trying to recalibrate
the navigation system.
It's not responding!
We are falling fast!
Now! Now! Now!
Huang, help me!
I can't move this one.
Robert.
Get a hold of yourself.
We are going to be joining him very soon.
Grab a parachute
and jump out of the plane.
This is yours.
Goodbye, buddy. Good luck!
What? You...
Ouraltitude is already
too low to parachute. Jump!
Don't be stupid, Jack.
One... Two... Three.
Don't touch my stuff.
Where am I?
You still owe me two sheep.
This man's eyes
have seen too much filth.
They could be easily
damaged by the snow.
We can treat his eyes using your breast
milkwith the medicine I have blessed.
Then he could be cured.
My breast milk is for my child.
Here's the medicine; give me two sheep.
Two! You can't afford it, can you?
Poor Yongcuo.
What are you doing?
Excuse me, sir.
You don't have any identification,
so this is an illegal immigration.
And who are you, sir?
I am a special officer,
SuoLang Wangdui.
This is Major Sun.
But, butwe can't
stay in a place like this.
We just want to go home,
we want to go home to our home countries.
Sorry. Here is not neutral in the war.
You are in the land of China.
A country that's hostile
against your countries.
Where are you sending us?
Unfortunately you have to go
back to where you came from.
No, no! Please don't send us back.
You can't send us back.
Please, sir. I beg you.
It will be inhuman.
I'd rather die, please,
I can't go back there.
Good job.
- Return to your own tribes.
- Yes, sir.
Jiangcuo.
Yangjin.
You are great.
Everyone is praising your bravery...
...for capturing so many
red haired devils this time.
Those red haired
devils aren't real devils.
They just wanted to go home
but ended up in the wrong place.
Does it still hurt?
In a few days,
I will be returning
to the tribe with Madam.
Be sure to drop by and visit me,
Jiangcuo.
Yangjin.
The Chief wouldn't let me see you
when I go back.
I would be locked up in a hut to tan hides.
I will be satisfied if I could just
get a glimpse of you from afar.
Yangjin.
I can see! I can see!
I can see!
So this is you. You are very beautiful.
Where'd your beard go?
Yeah. I can see.
You can see now?
I can see.
Sorry for the trouble.
Thank you for curing my eyes.
Can I help you? I can help you.
- Witch.
Red haired devil.
- What's happening?
- Get inside.
What are they doing here?
The witch brought
the red haired devil here.
Move! Move!
- Away from her.
Thank you forsaving me.
I'm very honored to be here with you.
I'm an American.
I need to get to Lhasa.
Lhasa?
Lhasa.
He wants to go to Lhasa?
Chief, he wants to go to Lhasa.
This can't be done.
You want to go to Lhasa?
Lhasa.
Can you? you can take me to Lhasa?
This is the order issued by the Dalai Lama
under the authority of the Qing Emperor...
...that forbids foreigners from
trespassing into the sacred Tibet.
Forty years ago,
you British raided Tibet,
murdered countless our people,
and even plundered the most
sacred treasures of our religion.
You should not even be here.
Go! Leave now!
This is a waste oftime.
- You can't leave now. You can't go.
- I have to go.
- The snow will seal the mountain off soon.
- I am a military officer.
- You can't go. You can't.
- I can't stay here. I can't stay here.
Thank you.
Chief, look!
The red haired devil is leaving.
Do you think he could make it
crossing the snow mountain?
No one can cross
that mountain in this season.
Lord Constable,
the shepherd reported that
a red haired devil murdered a woman.
Where did this happen?
The tribe of Kaluo.
Have you heard of it?
A red haired devil killed one ofus.
So I've heared. The government's
people are hunting him down.
Our tribe would rather
pay more taxes as a penalty...
...than having more people drafted
to serve the government.
- Master.
What's the name of your slave again?
Is she your woman?
I'm waiting for the Chief's
permission to marry her.
Find me the foreign murderer,
then you will redeem your freedom,
and marry that woman.
Lord Constable,
thank you so much. Thank you.
You could get up now.
Yes.
Lord Constable,
I vow to bring him back...
...even if it will cost my life.
Go.
Let's go.
Grandpa Danzeng,
please save him. Please.
What's wrong? Let me see.
Yongcuo, your child's gone.
He didn't like it here.
This place is too poor.
There's no temple, no Lamas.
Even Buddha drifting pass here
would refuse to stay.
The Buddha will bless you
as long as you believe in Him.
Will the Buddha bless my child too?
Buddha bless all.
- The bandits are here. Run!
- The bandits are here.
Don't be afraid.
The government sent us here.
Hey! Get back here.
Please eat.
The journey must have been exhausting.
It must have been exhausting.
Jiangcuo.
Yangjin, what brought you here?
Let's go.
You guys moved as fast as the wind.
It took me days to catch you up.
Yangjin,
when I get the red haired devil this time,
we can stay together forever.
Really?
May the Buddha bless you.
Yangjin, wait for me.
I'll wait for you.
I can't go.
I can't get through. It's too cold.
So cold.
The path is too cold.
Can't get anything through it.
Where's your kid?
I am sorry.
Don't touch me.
I'll bring bad luck to you.
I know this is hard,
but it's not going to be the last
hardship you are facing in your life.
There, there.
It's my mom.
My mom.
Mama!
Mama.
My mom loves me very much.
When I signed up for the military
and went away to war,
she was worried
that I was going to get killed.
That's the sadness
that I never want my mom to feel.
I'd imagine that your son in heaven...
...wouldn't want you
to feel that either.
This must be the fairy's clothes.
It's so pretty.
Her name is Lisa.
My dad was a military man.
I think when I joined the military too,
it just gives her another
life to have to worry about.
I am still alive.
Big guy! Big guy!
What are you doing here?
This is how we greet
each other around here.
Let's sit down. Please sit.
I've got something tasty.
See, this is for you. Eat.
Eat. Help yourself.
It is delicious.
Good.
Is it good?
One day Yongcuo's
husband went to shepherd...
...and was killed by a falling rock.
On the very night, one of her sheep returned
with the thigh of a wolf in its mouth.
A lama from Lhasa declared that...
...Yongcuo is a witch
who has been cursed.
I am afraid of no witch.
Hey. Do you understand
what I am telling you?
You still don't know
what I am talking about.
This is Yongcuo, this is me.
And this is you, big guy.
We can both marry Yongcuo.
What do you think?
No?
Come on, let's both marry her as our wife.
- Okay.
- You agreed? Yes?
That's great. This is great.
Let's go, big guy.
- Robert.
- Lo Bu?
Robert.
Lobu. Lobu.
Lobu. Lobu. Lobu.
What's her name?
Her name is Yongcuo.
Yongcuo?
She is my woman. Mine!
- Yongcuo?
- Yes, Yongcuo.
Yongcuo.
Robert.
Lobu?
Chief, Where do you suppose
the red haired devil could be hiding?
It's been so long.
I think he might
have easily starved to death.
Even ifhe's dead,
I have to take his corpse back.
If he did try to cross
that snow mountain,
we won't even be able to
find his dead body.
Take it.
Can I exchange the pot
for your cloth?
You have quite the eye.
This cloth is the latest
merchandise from India.
Thank you.
Where did you find him?
My lord, it was on the way to
the Sacred Moutain of Danla.
This is an American pilot.
Send a telegram to Lhasa immediately.
Yes, my lord.
That's a plane.
You hear it?
Jack! Hey! It's got to be Jack!
He's looking for me. Huh?
Jack, Jack, Jack.
Here, Robert. Here you are.
OK.
Is this enough?
Okay.
I'll get some more.
Luosang, what are you doing?
We are gathering stones...
...to catch the attention of
the big bird in the sky.
Do you know what that is?
Robert, why hasn't
the big bird come this way?
Big bird! Come this way now, please!
Fly this way!
Go. Go. Go.
Why here? Jesus!
It's my signal!
Fuck!
That's great! Yeah?
What are you doing?
Where's my bag?
There were a lot of people here.
Take my bag?
This, this is my bag.
You don't touch my bag!
This is clothes?
Yongcuo.
Your shepherd is herding your
sheep by the lake.
Go take a look. Go.
You made a dress.
It's beautiful.
Give me this hand.
It's okay.
Put it here.
There you go.
Here. Give me your hands.
We have finally made it
across Mount Qiongbala.
Boss, which way should we take?
This way leads us to Saiba Tribe.
That one takes us to Sangguozi.
Sangguozi.
Let's go.
Yongcuo! Yongcuo!
I heard some herders are searching
for the foreigner for the government.
It seems he had killed someone.
Hide your shepherd quickly.
What would happen if they come here
and find Robert?
If they find yourshepherd,
he would be squashed like a bug.
Go!
Kids!
Hi!
Have you seen any red haired devil?
- Yes. There.
I have confirmed it.
This man is the American pilot
we are looking for.
Ma.
Yes.
Please distribute this to
all shepherds in the area.
If you find anyone with this insignia,
inform me immediately.
There was indeed a foreigner
near the tribe of Sangguozi.
I was informed of that.
But I heard he killed someone.
Unless you have confirmed the story,
otherwise I want you to do everything
in your power to rescue this man.
I will.
Yongcuo.
Are you okay?
Yongcuo, what are you doing?
Go Go.
Yongcuo.
Go. Go.
Chief, look!
Boss. It's the red haired devil.
Lobu.
Yeah, what?
What?
- May the Buddha bless you.
- What is this?
Leave, now!
Go!
Get on the horse?
Go, now! Go!
What do you want me to do?
I don't understand.
Go, now! Go!
What? What are you...
Yongcuo, you come with me.
Yongcuo!
Stop right there! Don't you move!
- Stop right there!
- Don't you move!
Freeze! Don't you move!
I'll shoot if you keep running.
Don't you move!
Stop right here!
What? Okay. What!
Stop running. Take him away.
Fast! Keep going!
Let's go. Come with us.
Is this the murderer?
It took us a long time...
...to catch this man.
He's the murderer.
You said murderer?
You can speak English?
Don't play game with me.
Do you understand?
I can speak English. You understand?
Yeah. I understand.
Just please tell me.
I tell you.
That night you killed a woman.
So many people
saw your face very clearly.
Now everyone is going to look for you.
There, the notice is very clear.
Dave, tell him what the notice says.
If the murderer is still breathing,
he should be caught alive;
If he is dead,
his dead body shoule be found.
Woah. Whoa. Whoa. Hold on.
You're saying I killed a woman?
It's impossible.
I'm a United States military officer.
I'm not a god-damn killer!
I need you to translate this for me,
alright? As clearly as you can.
Okay? I need you to translate this.
Word forword, Okay? Okay?
Boss.
My name is Robert.
I'm a United States 14th Air Force
Second Officer Pilot.
Get up! Please get up! Get up!
Just one sentence.
- Go.
- Just one sentence.
One sentence. Just one sentence.
My jacket.
Look!
- Take a look at this.
- Let me try it on.
- I saw it first.
- Give it to me.
I need the jacket.
It's my proof; It's who I am.
I am not your murderer.
You got the wrong guy.
Kedi.
Boss, have some more.
Boss, Wangdan is too ill to continue.
Kedi, take these men back with you.
No. I am following you.
Wherever you go I'll go with you.
Fatty, take him back with you.
Alright.
Let's go.
Kedi.
May the Buddha bless you.
Boss. The red haired devil is dangerous.
Why not finish him off here?
Go to sleep.
Now, you should be on your way home.
Go! Go!
I just wanted to kill him for you.
So you could be free.
You want me to leave? Fine.
Why didn't those people say a word?
They have taken the Vow of Silence.
They won't talk on their pilgrimage.
It was you that took Robert away
the other day.
Where's he now?
Him?
He's already dead.
He is not a murderer.
He didn't kill anyone.
Every night before he slept, he would
stare at the talisman that you gave him.
Lobu.
Yongcuo.
Don't move!
Lobu.
What are you doing here?
British?
American;
Robert;
United States Air Force.
Patrick, Italian;
North Africa Force.
I got shot.
You okay? You okay?
I think I'm dying.
You stay. I am going to get water, okay?
Lobu.
My child, you have broken
the Vow of Silence.
And you will be punished for that.
The gun is not loaded.
Don't worry, okay?
What happened to you?
How did you get here?
I was in a prisoner camp.
German prisoner camp in India.
And I escaped, came here.
Help! A thief!
No. No. No.
The red haired devil has killed someone!
The red haired devil
has killed someone! Get him!
Someone come here! Get him!
You killed the woman?
Yeah, yeah!
I didn't want to kill anybody.
I didn't want to, but...
It's okay.
But the woman was...
Here, have some water.
It's okay.
Hey. Hey. Hey. Patrick.
Patrick.
I just want to go home.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Okay. That's okay.
Lord Constable,
please have mercy on me.
I saw the red haired devil.
Where's he now?
He escaped.
MajorSun.
I just received a confirmation
on the plane's crash site.
It's to the north of
the Sacred Mountain of Danla.
This year happens to
be the zodiacal year.
It will be crowded with pilgrims.
What's the captain's name
of your search team?
His name is Jiangcuo.
Jiangcuo.
The American is in great danger now.
Attention!
Head for the Sacred Mountain!
Look! It's the red haired devil.
He is a murderer.
That's him. Get him.
Don't let him run away.
Hey, big guy.
What are you doing? Let him go.
He's my friend. Stop hitting him.
Don't do this to him.
Luosang, take me to find Yongcuo.
Yongcuo? Go to find Yongcuo.
- Get off the horse.
- What are you doing?
- Don't do it.
What are you doing? Who are you?
He's my friend. Don't do this to him.
- Tie yourself up.
- You want to do it again?
Do it!
Put the gun down, put the gun down.
Watch me! Watch me! Hey!
Hit him.
Hurry! Run! Fast! Run!
Yongcuo.
Yongcuo, where are you?
Where are you?
- Yongcuo.
Yongcuo.
Lobu.
Yangjin.
Jiangcuo.
Yongcuo Yongcuo.
No. Hey. Oh God, No!
Yongcuo.
Yongcuo. Oh God!
You are finally free.
Lobu
Robert. It's Robert.
Oh my God! Please! No, Yongcuo.
Don't leave me, Yongcuo.
Yongcuo.
Yongcuo. Don't leave me.
I love you. I love you.