movie info: XVID  624x352 25.0fps 699.8 MB
Once.Fallen.2010.DVDRip.XviD-RUBY
Me and Beat grew up on
the shores of San Pedro.
lt's a harbor town
south of Los Angeles,
populated with
the families of hard
working blue-collar men
who live and die by
the codes of the Union
and the bosses who
controlled the ports.
My dad was one
of those men.
l always imagined
that l would some
day be one, too.
Beat got his name
from the kids at school
who pushed him around.
So l started
pushing back.
But no one pushed him harder
than his father when he came
home from the bars at night.
We'd smoke the cigarettes
l'd stolen from my dad.
Talk about the days
in front of us.
Places that we'd go.
Ships we'd sail.
And ports with girls.
That thing was crazy.
Look at this.
Hello?
Hi, Rose, it's me.
ls everything okay?
No, everything
is not okay. Have
you heard from her?
No.
Rose, it's been two weeks
What the fuck's going on?
What did you
do, Liam?
I didn't do anything .
Something
must've happened.
I swear to God ,
I didn't do anything.
You must've
said something.
I didn't say anything .
I thought we were doing fine.
And then she just, I mean
I-I know you and Chance
wiII be fine without me.
What am l supposed
to tell Chance?
Just tell him that
you went to San Diego.
lf she does, could you
ask her to call me
at least?
You know l will.
You take it
easy, Liam .
Thanks, Rose.
I appreciate it.
Call me if
you hear anything.
Yeah , aII right.
Bye.
Actually, you
know, it was
Hey. Where have
you guys been?
We were at the beach.
You better be carefuI . You're
gonna kiII yourseIves Iike
that. Come here.
There you go.
AII right.
Give me a coupIe.
Left. AII right,
aII right.
Beat. Beat.
Can we see
the new move?
Okay, okay. Good.
Let's get something
to eat. Come on.
Ouch.
Hey.
Dad, he hit a rock
when he jumped in
the water.
PIease, don't
hurt my dad.
Are you sore
back here?
No, it's okay.
Son of a bitch.
Dad! Dad!
You boys stay
right there.
Come here. I'II get you.
Why the fuck have
you kiIIed him?
I need some heIp!
He'II never
hurt you again.
Fucking get away
from my son.
You're fucking done.
You'II fucking pay for
this. I swear to God !
Get up. Get up. Get up.
Somebody cIean up
this garbage.
That's Bookman .
He took me under
his wing.
He kept me out of
the shit details while
he trained me to fight.
When l was ready,
he set up the fights
that he and the guards
ran in the boiler room.
My dad taught me
to box, but Bookman
taught me to fight.
He was the closest
thing to a friend
that l had.
Fucking off somewhere.
Davis!
AW.
Saving Bookman
cost me eight stitches,
but it bought me
five years.
ln a couple of months,
finally l get to go home.
Saying goodbye was
harder than l thought.
He said we'd
stay in touch.
But l think we both
knew we wouldn't.
Sue?
Are you aII right?
I'II be right there.
Don't move.
Ha-ha. Like you can.
Okay, roII over.
Jesus, Mary
and Saint.
Use your arm !
Push , push !
Let's just stay
Iike this, Rose.
God !
I'm sorry, Rose.
Aw, Jesus!
Where's your stuff?
Right below you .
Thank you.
Sue. If you wanna go
on kiIIing yourseIf,
that's fine.
WouId you stop
incIuding me?
Do you think Chance,
he'II stay here with you?
No.
Chance aIways has
some pIace to stay.
It's just the wrong
pIace, that's aII.
Sounds Iike most of
the men I've known.
I'm making you somethin'.
Oh.
What coIor is it?
Green . You'II Iove it.
Why don't you move
your fucking bike?
Why don't you come
over here and make me?
Fuck you.
Hey, fuck you.
No, fuck you.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no!
Fuck you !
No, fuck you .
Piece of shit.
Oh, my God.
Ready for a rematch?
Yeah, I can give you
a fucking head start.
Is the pier
okay with you?
How does it feeI
to have something
big between your Iegs, huh?
Why don't you
Iick me?
Are you good?
My fucking shrink's
got me on a new
one now.
Gravi-siI.
Ugh.
So, what do you wanna
do first, man?
I gotta go
see Kat.
See where I stand .
Have you seen her?
She hasn't been around much
since you've been gone.
Where is she staying?
Down by the docks.
Eddie put'em up.
One of his pIaces.
Them?
I mean her.
Hey.
I missed you
so much .
I missed you, too.
HaiI HitIer.
I toId you not
to say that shit.
What's the word
on my son?
He's out. He was
reIeased this morning.
I don't wanna be
out of Iine.
Some of the men think
it might be a good idea
to Iean on him.
Look. I mean, he did
stop a head on the
marked nigger.
If anyone in the brim
taIks or even thinks of
putting hurt on my bIood,
you are going
to teII me. Hm?
Correct?
Yes, sir.
Go change your pants.
You're a fucking disgrace.
Who the fuck are you?
Who is it?
Hey, Kat.
August, this
is your daddy.
He's been away
for a Iong time
and now he's back.
That's funny, Kat.
Whose kid is it?
Look, I didn't wanna
teII you when you were
on the inside, okay?
Uh, look, l'm gonna
go get a drink
or two
And why don't you get
to know your kid? I'II
be back Iater.
Don't you wanna
catch up?
Kat, come on.
You can't just Ieave
me with this kid.
Whose kid is it?
Oh, Jesus.
l only wanna do this
if they throw down .
Hard and bIoody, huh?
WeII the Lt say they're
gonna bust him and bring
him for questioning?
WeII, Lts have a
tendency to forget.
Every once in a whiIe
in the fieId, things
don't go that smoothIy.
I wanna make
sure things are
gonna be cooI.
Benny, Benny, what you
have to make sure of
in your heart
is that you trust me,
okay? That you trust us.
You're the new kid here.
All right? So let's
get that straight. You
have to trust me. Okay?
AII right.
Okay?
Okay.
Who's throwing
the switch?
Put the gun down.
Put the gun down,
motherfucker!
What, a bIack?
Dan.
Let me talk to
MC nigger here
for a second.
Are you okay?
Fuck you, man.
Arrest me so I can
caII my fucking Iawyer.
Shit!
Come on!
Shut the fuck up!
Shut up!
This is buIIshit.
Watch my fucking back.
Sorry.
Now, where is it?
If I taIk, I waIk.
If you taIk,
I'II Iet you waIk.
Yeah. CIean
and free of nothin'.
You got it.
Now, where is it?
It's right there.
Fuck me.
WeII, that is a
Iot of cocaine.
Rath, let's
call it in, man.
Your name is Rath?
l heard about you.
Yeah? What you hear?
Heard you was
a fucking faggot.
That's right.
A crooked cop,
fucking faggot.
I'II never have
any kind of Iife
if I stay here.
I just can't
do it anymore.
You know, Eddie was right.
Like father, Iike son.
Oh, what do you
mean Eddie's right?
Have you been fucking
Eddie to pass the time?
Hey, Kat.
Un-fucking-beIievabIe.
What the fuck am I
suppose to do, Kat?
You have to take
the kid with you.
No, no. I've been
waiting too Iong
for this.
You know, you're such
a selfish bitch.
You haven't changed , either.
Why don't you give me some
time to catch up
Time? You had
five years.
You think you
got it rough?
I've been trying to stay
aIive for the Iast
five years.
Don't talk to me
about time!
Your stuff's
over there. Okay?
Here are your Ietters.
I never read them.
Take care of him, okay?
Mommy Ioves you, okay?
You be a good boy. You're
gonna stay with daddy
for a whiIe.
Be a good boy.
Okay. Kat, Kat,
Iet's just taIk
about this.
Don't touch me.
Let's just talk--
Let's just talk
about this.
I-I can't raise
that thing on my own.
I did. Maybe you'II
grow up this time, huh?
Grow up? Kat, why don't
you--Look who's fucking
walking out now, huh?
Fuck! Fucking
kidding me.
You know, your mom is
a reaI fucking bitch ,
you know that?
Un-fucking-beIievabIe.
What?
Son of a bitch.
Fucking bitch.
Just play.
Bring it
to--Shut up.
PIay 2-5-1.
PIay it 3-1 -7.
Take it. 2-5-1 in
G-fIat, man. Stop trying
to reinvent the wheeI, man.
You can't pIay
it, Iay out.
One, two,
A one
A'right, take five.
And another thing, Rico,
when I say dress rehearsaI,
it means dress rehearsaI.
lf you wanna wear denims,
go get a gig at a rodeo,
brother. What's that shirt?
l don't give a fuck
if you like it or not.
Go get a gig with Don Ho.
Look at this.
Iook at this.
Look at you , man .
Give me some Iove.
Five years ain't done
you no harm at aII , man.
If you were a chick, weII.
Show your dad how
to hug , Chico.
Come on.
Give an aging
hipster a big kiss.
WiIIow! Listen ,
I gotta taIk
to your daddy.
I'm gonna put you in the hands
of a very beautifuI girI . You
gotta be nice. WiIIow!
Come and take care
of Chance's face.
And another thing . That
motherfucker comes in here
with bIue jeans, I'm gonna
I don't give a shit
if he bIows Beethoven's
Ninth out of his butt.
You fire him .
Do you hear me?
OK, I got it.
Let's go, Chance.
We'II be back, Chico.
Stay here.
So, Chance, your boy
Beat's been bIowing
some very Iame changes.
He teII you about
his situation with me?
No, what situation?
I'm hoIding his
marker for 50 K.
Jesus, Eddie. That you're gonna
Iook after him , that'II put him
in debt the rest of his Iife.
What do you want me to do?
SIeep under his bed ,
hoId his hands,
serve him cookies
and cream? The boy's
an aduIt, Chance.
Besides, bad jazz
that Kat bIows is
a soIo, baby.
I can't heIp if anybody
Iies now with dogs.
This is a IittIe somethin'
the girIs put together for
August. Take it. About $ 1 ,000.
Take it, take it.
Everybody knows your
oId Iady spIit on you.
Down to business.
The word is that you
got pretty tough
in the joint.
Anyway, that's
the buzz cuz.
So, this is a new
cat, AxeI. ReaI thug.
And everybody digs.
I wanna put you together
with AxeI, bare knuckIes.
Odds will be sky high,
high as the moon, baby.
High as a Chinaman
in Beijing.
Now, you do this,
we get the things
straight with Beat
and put a IittIe gin
in our pockets. What
do you say?
You're fucking
kill me, Eddie. You're
really fucking kill me.
How am I supposed to get
ahead when I got 50 grand
stacked against me from you?
'Cause I got
a pIan, man.
Before we talk about
your little plan,
you wanna taIk about
how you fucked my girI
whiIe I was gone?
I'II come over there
and kick your nasty
oId ass.
Stop the buIIshit.
I fucking know it.
I own this cIub.
She worked here.
I fucked everybody
worked here. Once.
It's Iike punching
a time card, baby.
Besides, you ain't
gonna put a hurt
on my ass.
Because, A:
you Iove me.
And B : you need me
Iike you aIways need me.
You got a pIace
I can crash?
Absolutely. You can
stay at Kat's crib.
I own the buiIding .
It's the Ieast
I can do.
What's the catch?
Catch? There Ain't no
catch . Just think about
this fight, baby.
I'II think about it.
You know what, Eddie?
I wouId Iike to do
something with my Iife
other then fight
and deaI drugs.
Why?
Mommy, mommy, mommy!
Mommy, mommy!
What?
What? Fuck kid , what?
May I have
some water?
Yeah. A gIass
of water.
Here.
Thank you, Daddy.
Can you go
back to sIeep now?
Yes.
Mommy isn't coming
back, is she?
No.
But, hey, it is time
for you to go to sIeep.
So, Iie back down there
and I'm gonna teII you
a story, okay?
Just try to cIose
your eyes.
Hi.
I just heard you guys
moving in and I just
wanted to say heIIo.
I'm, uh, Chance.
I'm PearI.
PearI!
Hi, hot shot.
How you doing?
So you know
the kid, huh?
Oh, yeah. Um,
I wouId watch
him at Eddie's
when Kat wasn't
around, which was
most of the time.
Right, right.
You want a soda?
Yeah, sure!
Hey, why don't you run
and give PearI a soda?
PIease. Thank you.
Take a seat.
Okay.
So, how Iong have
you been here?
Um, a year.
Cheap rent.
Yeah, yeah . It's just
temporary for me
tiII I figure out
what I'm gonna do next.
Funny. That's what I said.
Didn't mean it
to sound Iike that.
It's okay.
Thanks!
So, you must be one
of Eddie's girIs, right?
No, I am not one
of Eddie's girIs.
You?
One of Eddie's
girIs? No.
No, I meant, are
you friends with him?
Not exactIy. You?
Not exactIy.
I shouId go.
I'II see you
guys around.
FeeI free to go.
You don't have
to rush off.
I-I shouId.
Thanks for the soda.
Yeah.
God bIess you !
Okay, bye. Thanks.
Wow.
Hey, what's up?
Hey, Sonny.
M ind if I come in?
Yeah, come on in.
How are you
doin', brother?
AII right. You
got some business?
Just a coupIe
of things.
Contract got pIayed ,
so that's one Iess
name in the hat.
And, uh, your
boy, he's gone.
Yeah , that was oId
business. Not my caII .
What eIse do you got?
Listen, man, I've been
giving this a Iot of
thought, aII right?
Your son.
If we give him
controI over San Pedro,
and with his network,
aII the probIem
I foresee is,
we can keep in the product
store to keep up with the
demand. What do you think?
No.
You know, I wouId think
that you wouId want your
son to have a post
as opposed to being
in an earIy grave.
No one goes
near my son.
End of story.
Listen. You know,
when I go through
out there,
taking out my ass
here for you,
it's Iike covering
for your ass, okay?
You're making us aII
Iook fucking bad.
Making who
Iook bad?
Hm?
We got a probIem
here, Sonny?
No, I ain't got no
probIem . You're
the boss.
I ain't got no
probIem.
It's been so Iong
I don't even know
how to say hey.
Hey, I got some Iunch
for us. Let's go grab
something to eat.
I'm Iate for
an appointment.
That appointment
you got with Ted,
that's been canceIed.
See, I had Ted
take you off
the computer,
so now you don't have
to check in with Ted.
You have to
check in with me.
Consider this your
first check-in.
Get in the fucking car.
Man, you Iook good.
That port over there,
that's where l get a
lot of my stuff
coming from the last
five years. l kinda
own this place.
l don't have
to pay for parking.
So, I heard you won some
pretty big fights inside.
StiII fighting dirty?
I shouId ask you
the same question.
Listen , I got
merchandise, man.
I-I don't wanna know.
I'm not interested.
Chance, you gotta
start over, man.
I mean , you gotta
have money. You got-
you got a boy to feed.
How the fuck do you
know I have a kid?
How about your daddy,
you taIk to him?
Why?
Why? He just became
one of the heads of
the Aryans, that's why.
So?
So? He's under tremendous
pressure to bring you
into the foId.
And why fuck
wouId I care?
Because I have a deaI
pending with the Aryans
and it might heIp
soIve the situation.
Because Iet me teII you,
if the Aryans Iose controI
of the prison drug trade,
your dad's reign of the top
is gonna be one of the
shortest in history.
I'II show you something.
Come on.
Leshaun. Hey, man,
this is Chance.
Chance, Leshaun .
Leshaun, Chance.
That's fucked up.
Leshaun here and the BIoods
were trying to hoard in
the Aryans turf.
Bookman was their
Iiaison inside.
It was brave shit
of you , man , jumping
for him Iike that.
He's my friend.
I'm your friend.
Friends don't Iet friends
do five fucking years.
Are you bIaming me
for you getting set up?
Is that what aII this
fucking attitude is about?
I had to deaI with the DA.
Beat was supposed to go
down , not you .
You didn't have to put
yourseIf under the bus.
It's your buIIshit sense
of IoyaIty that Iocked
you up, not me.
You taIk to me about
fucking IoyaIty?
Beat was steaIing
from me. From us.
Beat wanted
what he deserved.
What was that?
More.
WeII, I got more.
I got 25 keys.
We gotta move
them right away.
It's a big one, Chance.
We can retire on this
and we can fucking go
to the South Pacific.
We can spend the rest
of our Iives tanning and
eating fucking mangoes.
Took five Iong years
to think about you
aIright.
Five very Iong
fucking years.
Chance, Iet me
drive you back.
I'II waIk.
Chance!
Fuck.
Fine fucking cop
and San Pedro's.
l heard about
your new post.
Mazel tov.
I'm here
about your son.
And considering
your new post and my
reIationship with Chance.
Your reIationship?
Yea, we're,
um . . .cIose.
I'm offering you
the opportunity
to heIp Chance
start over,
and to fIex your
new muscIes, huh?
I got a Iot of product
that I gotta move right
away. About 25 kiIos.
That's interesting .
The word is 25 keys just
got ripped from the BIoods.
ReaIIy? WeII , I don't
do business with niggers.
Like it showed up
on your doorstep.
Liam, you don't want the Aryans
to find out that you passed on
this deaI. It's bad business.
Fucking son
of a bitch.
AII right, have it
your way, asshoIe.
That guard Chance saved
was marked to go down.
By who?
ABs in Riverside.
Bookman was up and
moved dope for the
BIoods in Long Park.
And your point?
My point is,
you fuck with Chance,
I drop a photo of you
for circuIation . Your
name goes in the hat.
You think you're fucking
bulletproof in here, huh?
I can have you shipped
and stripped in about
six fucking minutes,
and somewhere where the
Aryans don't have as much
suck as they got here.
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
Liam,
I'm just trying
to teII you that if you
wanna keep your new post,
you gotta consider
doing business with me.
Huh? Huh?
You wanna stay aIive?
You better Iook every
each way before you
cross me.
Okay.
And one, two,
three, four.
♫ You go to my head ♫
BIess me.
♫ And you Iinger Iike
A haunting refrain ♫
That's beautifuI.
♫ And I find you
Spinning round
I n my brain ♫
Yeah, Baby.
♫ Like the bubbIes in
A gIass of champagne ♫
Less piano is beautiful
for a beautiful baby.
One more time here.
♫ You go to my head ♫
♫ Like a sip
Of sparkIing
Burgundy brew ♫
BeautifuI, beautifuI.
♫ And I find the
Very mention of you ♫
♫ Like the kicker
I n a juIep or two ♫
Hey, baby.
BeautifuI, baby.
That is beautifuI!
Take five, man .
Take ten.
A'right, here, uh.
You gonna fight AxeI?
I haven't
decided, yet.
Eddie said it can
be more than 50.
Just do it. You're gonna
like to fight this guy.
l'm telling you.
How do you know?
You've been seeing
this guy?
Hey, PearI.
Wow, you sounded good .
You have a great voice.
It's aII right. Thanks.
No, it's good .
How about I take
you to dinner?
l don't think that's a
good idea. Plus, who's
gonna watch August?
WeII.
Are you kidding?
No, God, no
fucking way.
It's okay.
He'II be fine.
Right, Beat?
Yes.
I'II think about it.
You're gonna
think about it?
Yeah.
How is it going?
Good.
WeII.
Look at me.
She's not coming back.
Are you gonna go
see your dad?
Why do you bring up
the heavy shit, huh?
Are you gonna go
see your daddy?
I don't--I-I-
I don't know.
I saw him.
You saw him . When?
When did you
go see him?
Last year.
The fucking shrink
thought it wouId be
a good idea to stop
the nightmares.
Chance?
He doesn't Iike me.
Did you mean it?
Mean it?
Did you mean
to kill him?
I wanted him
to stop hurting you.
I was so scared of him.
You know your father
was a very sick man.
I aIso know that you
were nothing Iike him.
You are nothing
Iike him.
You're good.
I don't feeI
that way.
Come here.
You are more of a dad
to me than that fuck
ever was.
Listen to me.
Put aII that shit
behind you. Okay?
You bring that
shit up right now.
Debbie. Fucking bitch.
Are you fucking
kidding me? Are
you serious?
You know what?
I wiII take
August home.
No, no, no, no.
Come join us.
Fuck you .
Enjoy your
boyfriend, faggot.
PearI, August is fine.
He has a coIoring book.
I taught him to coIor
between the Iines.
Come here.
Come here, faggot.
Looks Iike it's you
and me tonight.
What do you
feeI Iike doing?
I don't know.
Are you hungry?
Come in.
What the fuck do you
want from me, Chance?
What do you mean?
I mean what is
your agenda?
I-I'd just Iike,
I just came to.
You just what?
I just came.
Oh , you-you
want this?
Is that what
you want? Hm?
WeII, then just get over here
and do it. Stop taIking. Just
get over here and do it.
I just came to.
You just what?
You just wanna fuck me
Iike everybody eIse!
Get over here
and do it.
Be a man . Get over
here and do it.
Come on !
Get it over with!
I just came
to apoIogize.
Where are your
fucking keys?
Take them.
You know what?
l am so sick of
you so called men
who wanna do what
the fuck they want.
Get out!
Listen , l don't know what
you've been through with
other men , but l'm not them.
I'd Iike to take you
to dinner. What do
you think?
I don't think
it's a good idea.
Now we're
fuII of shit.
Come on , it's
just dinner.
Take me on
your bike.
DeaI.
Say goodbye to PearI.
Who's there?
Cocksucker, l got a gun .
Who the fuck is there?
Rosie, Rosie, Rosie.
lt's me. Put that
piece away.
What took you so Iong?
Go to prison for five
years. Shit stacks up.
You going to bust my baIIs
or give me some Ioving.
Oh !
Who did you
bring with you?
Rose, I wouId Iike for
you to meet August.
This is my son.
Did you say
this is your son?
August, give me
your hand.
I'm gonna use my other
hand so I can see what
you Iook Iike, okay?
WeII , you want a beer?
You know I do.
I got something
for you , too, August.
The pIace Iooks great.
Thanks. l've been doing
a lot of decorating.
Here you go, August.
Okay.
Nice.
Ah , what a sound.
Wait, one.
Two.
Shit!
I can stiII drink you
under the board.
That you can.
What the hell is
going on here, Rose.
You gonna introduce me?
Sorry. Chance, August,
this is Sue, my neighbor
and my best friend.
Hey, Chance.
Hey, Sue. Sorry
about the company
you have to keep.
It wouIdn't be so bad if
she'd just hop in bed
every once in a whiIe.
She's reaIIy
hot for me.
I don't bIame her.
I'II see what I can
do to heIp you out.
Thank you.
Look at these.
This is blooming cactus.
Shit!
Anyway, wait. I've
been coIIecting them,
I don't know why.
They're just dangerous
and beautifuI, and I Iove
them. I want you to touch them.
You want me
to touch them?
Yes. Put your
fingers on them.
Touch it.
Squish it reaIIy hard.
Ah, fuck.
I'm bIeeding
here, Rosie.
Hey. Hey, what about
some more beer? It's
best two out of three.
All right, l'll
get you a band aid.
Hey, you wanna
watch some TV?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah . Come on in
and watch the tube.
Come here.
Oh, honey.
Here.
Why didn't you
caII me sooner?
Sit down.
Don't faII . I don't
wanna take your ass
to the hospitaI.
Sue what are you drinking?
You guys go ahead .
I'II see you Iater.
You got a boy.
I don't know what I'm
gonna do with him though.
Fucking messy nigger.
You want a foot?
I think we're out
of Leshaun . There's
no more Leshaun.
Hi , Rose.
Hey, Ken .
Hey, Annie.
Is he sIeeping?
Yeah , he's crashed
up on the couch.
You want a smoke?
Smoke.
Have you taIked
to your father?
No.
You know, he actuaIIy
wrote me a coupIe of
times through the years.
Yeah , well, l don't really
give a shit about him.
Yes, you do.
When you're through trying to
convince yourself that you're
never gonna be him , well.
Those mistakes that
he made and continues
to make, he's gotta survive.
Those mistakes as
you caII 'em , fucked
aII our Iives up.
What wouId you have done
in his shoes?
Don't answer me.
Just think about it.
Have you heard
from your mother?
No. Not in a Iong time.
She's just Iike Kat.
A whore who ran away.
Besides, you're my mom.
Don't you taIk
that way about her.
She's your mother,
and more importantIy
that she's my sister.
What is it? What-what
makes you think you're so
much better than everybody?
I know.
I know what you do,
mister drug boy.
You gotta go see him.
WouId you mind watching
August for a whiIe?
You know, I think
that's a heII of
an idea.
He can drink Red BuII
and I'II teach him how to
pIay cards in the porch.
You take aII
the time you need.
Okay, hipsters
and chipsters.
and todos eI mundo.
Ready to open a jump? Don't
worry about the scratch .
It's in the Good Book.
And remember the ruIes.
The ruIes are, there
ain't no ruIes.
Hit it.
WeII , that didn't
quite work out, did it?
lt's better this way.
Eddie, now you set up
a re-match
and we'II make
some serious money.
Serious money? You're gonna
pick up a fight on the Wall
Street Journal.
There's no serious money.
That gIobe's in a shit.
Everybody wants the big dig.
No wanna lickety split.
Real match is gonna take
40 days and 40 nights.
MeanwhiIe, I need my scratch
so the cat in front of Iine
gets his scratch.
So come manana.
I don't see some
Ioot and scoot.
Somebody's gonna get
their young ass scaIed ,
and it ain't gonna be mine
'cause my ass
is ancient.
No.
No? Is that
the existentiaI no,
or does that refer to
something specificaIIy
I just said?
I'm fucking done.
Done?
WhiIe you were weII done
right here, motherfucker,
I gave you a home.
I gave you the Iife.
You were happy with
the scratch we made.
But you wanted the flash
and dash . You wanted
the razzle dazzle,
some twisted
punk DEA agent,
and you get five
long hard time.
And while your absolutely
certifiable girlfriend
with that stupid gash
is trying to find herseIf,
who the fuck was taking
care of your face? Huh?
Who's taking care of your
son? Let me give you the
facts of life here, brother.
You show up and
you pay up. Dig it.
Okay. Eddie,
it's no probIem.
WouId you shut
the fuck up? What
do you mean no probIem?
No probIem .
That's a sentence.
That's where
a period goes.
Report from Beijing
is on the phone.
Every fucking night?
TaIk to Eddie,
you fuck.
The guards fucking
rained down on me.
Are you fucking crazy?
lt's gonna be smooth
with this run . l'm
telling you.
Eddie is up
our asses. Okay?
AII that we have to do
is make a few caIIs
to the oId gang,
and you and I we can
move this IittIe brother
in no time.
Where did you get it?
Beat, where the fuck
did you get this?
The Iess you know,
the better. AII right?
Listen to me.
This gives me a way
to make up to you for,
for the Iast time, you know.
You didn't, you didn't
roII on me and I owe you
fucking forever
for that, okay?
Do you know
the definition
of insanity?
Dude, that is a stupid
question to post
in me, man.
lt's doing the same thing over
and over again expecting
different results.
Who said that?
My oId man.
How Iong has it
been? Ten years?
EIeven.
And what are you
doing with yourseIf?
You know,
this and that.
You cIean?
Yeah.
Good.
You?
As the driven snow.
I thought I toId you
never to come back here.
Yeah , you did .
Rath toId me you
cut a deaI with him.
I never did a thing
for that twisted fuck.
You stay away from him .
He's not gonna last.
So, I got a kid now.
His name's August.
How oId is he?
Five.
Sometimes he fucking
Iooks at me. I don't know
what the fuck he wants.
That sounds famiIiar.
You know, I have
met this new girI.
Yeah? What's
she Iike?
She's teIIing me.
It gets better. BIack.
Jesus Christ, man .
If you haven't given
me enough troubIes.
Holy shit.
I got to go.
Guard.
Housekeeping .
Leave me
the fuck alone.
What's going on , paI?
What's up, man?
Where are your piIIs?
I don't want anymore
fucking piIIs. Just
wanna be fucking normaI.
I don't wanna take
anymore piIIs.
You gotta take
your piIIs, man.
Yeah , but when
I take them , I don't
get to feeI anything!
And if I don't
take them,
what I feeI is
too fucking much.
I'm so sorry.
I though I couId
Iet off the medication .
Now you're back,
but you're just-you're
gonna Ieave me again.
Look at me.
If I go, you go.
You understand?
Sure.
Yeah.
Is everything eIse aIright?
Fine, man . I'm fine.
I just need your heIp.
I can't--I can't
do this aIone.
You're not aIone.
I'm here.
We just gotta me smart.
We gotta make the
right moves.
I know.
I am , after this
Ioad , we're done.
I promise.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
My dad was pushing
a lid open with
the Aryans
making a deal
with the Bloods.
l didn't know it then ,
but my dad made the
deal to protect me.
That sure pissed off
Sonny, who was next in
line under my dad.
How did it go?
You stiII got aII
your fingers and toes?
For years I practiced
what I wouId say to him .
I didn't say any of it.
You said it aII
just by showing up.
He Ioves you.
Just Iike you Iove
August, onIy you don't
know it, yet.
What do you mean?
What am I gonna do?
I mean , I-I'm a deaIer.
No. You were a deaIer.
You deaIt drugs.
That's in the past.
That's not who
you are.
Yeah , but that's
aII know how to do.
It's what I'm good at.
When you were a kid,
what did you wanna be?
What was like your dream?
l don't know. l always
thought that l would work
by the docks like my old man.
Oh , that's perfect.
That is so perfect.
There is Iots of water
where we're going . Lots
of boats. Yes!
Boats? You want me
to go to the South?
Yes, pIease!
I'm in.
As Iong as I'm with
you , I don't care
where I'm at.
Oh , when?
When do you
wanna go?
Now. Yes.
We couId enjoy it
sitting out here.
No, come on ,
seriousIy.
There's a few things
I gotta take care of,
but then I'm aII yours.
I'm stiII in it.
Okay, I know you've been
invoIved with some shady
shit in the past.
That's aII
behind you , right?
You've got nothing
to worry about.
Okay.
Nothing to worry about.
Come on , motherfucker.
Go. Come on.
What the fuck
do you guys want?
August, run! Run!
Nine-one-one. What
is your emergency?
Why do you make me
keep doing this to you?
My money isn't in Chance's
apartment. Where is my
fucking money?
Where is it?
I don't fucking
know, man . I don't know.
TeII me where it is.
I don't know.
Okay. AII right.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
AII right.
I just--I-I Iose my
patience sometimes.
I'm sorry.
TeII where my
fucking son is.
I'm not fucking around.
I don't know where
your fucking kid is.
Why in the fuck would
you think l know where
your kid is?
'Cause of the money
we fucking owe you.
It ain't that much
fucking money, man.
I got a kid of my own .
You know that. I don't
take kids.
Go ahead and shoot me,
motherfucker. Runs in
the gene pooI , don't it?
Christ.
I need your
heIp, Eddie.
What?
I need your
fucking heIp.
WhiIe you are sitting
there thinking about
this stuff,
I want you to run these
changes by Beat, hm?
See what he has
to say about this shit.
Give me the rest
of my money.
Here's the money
l owe you.
I'm done
fighting for good.
You piece of shit!
Come on . Come on !
You Iike that?
Don't you?
l will tell you
about my kid.
lt's just some girl l knew
from home and left me with
a kid and disappeared.
I didn't think there was
much I couId do for him so
I put him in a home
for the retarded.
But there was hell
of a lot l could've
done for him.
By the time I reaIized
that, he was gone.
Died at eight
years oId . AIone.
In some home.
When your fIesh and bIood
needs you, man, and you
cut for the taII grass,
everything else just
seems like some farce.
So, if you don't wanna fight
more, Chance, okay, that's
cool by me.
But if you cut and run,
if you cut
for the taII grass,
take your boy
with you.
It's safe there.
That's all anybody wants.
To be safe.
Thanks, Eddie.
Funny how it goes.
Oh, no.
No.
Oh, God.
Hey.
Hey, buddy.
I'm here.
Yeah.
Take my hand.
Okay.
Rath took August.
He's a son
of a bitch.
Let go.
You're okay now.
You're okay.
Where's my son?
I got him .
I got him.
I want my son.
Okay, l'll get him.
I'II get him.
Every body
settIe down , okay?
lt's all cool.
All l want is
the money that you
and Beat skimmed from me.
That's it.
You give me
my money,
I'II give you
back your son .
Okay?
I'm not giving you shit.
You owe me.
Five fucking
years you owe me.
What do you think l'm doing?
l'm setting all this up. lt's
for you , it's for us.
It's what we've
aIways wanted.
That's what you fucking
wanted . I just wanted
something for myseIf.
I wanted you to have
things for yourseIf, man.
Not unIess I
owed you for it.
That's not true.
Jesus Christ!
Okay.
SettIe the fuck down.
We're okay.
Do you think
I care about this?
This Iife?
I don't care
about any of this.
I just care
about you.
Boss, just let me
shoot this asshole.
Don't Iook at him ,
don't Iook at him .
Look at me.
I don't care
about these guys.
You see?
I just want
what's best for us.
I just want my son.
Okay.
I'II get him.
Here we go August.
Come on , your
dad's here.
Are you okay, buddy?
Of course he's okay.
I wouIdn't
Iie to you.
lt's all right, man.
I can't do
this anymore.
You don't have to.
l just wanna give
him a better life.
And I don't want this.
I don't want the drugs,
I don't want the fighting.
Okay. Okay.
Listen , I'II set it up for
us. We can go anywhere
we want now, okay?
Anywhere in the worId.
Okay.
I got you now.
Yeah.
Yeah?
Okay?
Okay? Okay.
Motherfucker. I'm
gonna fucking kiII you.
You fucking kiIIed Beat
so I'm gonna make you pay.
l didn't kill him.
Twice in 11 years.
Meet your
grandson. August.
Hey.
What the heII
happened to you?
Rath's men.
Kidnapped August,
aImost kiIIed PearI.
I found out Beat
was running with Rath.
It was too Iate.
Beat's dead.
Hey, August, who is
our favorite superhero?
Aquaman.
Why fucking Aquaman?
Did you hear me?
Yeah . Not in front
of the kid.
Hey, Keyes, take August
down to the other room.
See if you can find him
a SiIver Surfer comic.
But I hate
SiIver surfer.
WeII , I hate
fucking Aquaman.
Go outside, all right,
buddy? l'll be out
there in a minute.
Oh , that's nice.
Did you kiII him?
No.
Why the fuck not?
'Cause I wanted to make
the right fucking decision
for once in my Iife.
Sometimes your right
fucking decision is
the wrong decision.
Like you know
the fucking difference?
What the fuck is
that supposed to mean?
I never shouId've
come here.
Sit your ass
right back there.
Fuck you ! You're
the one who toId me
that I had a choice.
This time I made
the right fucking choice.
I chose to end up here
the rest of my Iife and
I chose my fucking son.
Do you think I
wanted this? Huh?
You think I
wanted this shit?
I wanted to be with you .
It just didn't work out.
After aII these fucking
years, it just didn't work
out? What the fuck is that?
I think about punching
that fucking guys
Iights out,
I think about crushing that
motherfucker skuII every
day of my fucking Iife!
What do you
want me to say?
I want you to say
you're fucking sorry
you did it.
Yeah , weII , I can't.
I cannot undo what I did .
Why did you fucking do it?
He was raping Beat.
He was raping him !
Can I ask you somethin'?
Sure.
Remember that day?
You whispered
something in my ear.
What did you say?
You need anything?
Not anymore.
TeII your grandpa bye.
Bye, August.
You take care
of each other.
AII right? Good.
I'm making
a presentation now.
PearI , this is for you.
This is some--Ouch !
Shit.
Would you like
a band aid?
Yeah . Thank you.
AII right, gang ,
we gotta get
on the road.
Come here.
I'm gonna miss you.
Is there anything
I can do for you ,
before I Ieave?
You just take care
of your famiIy.
l can teach your girl
friend here. l got a beer.
Yeah , no kidding .
Come on , get
out of here.
Get the fuck out
of here. Go on.
Go on . Get going.
We're going to
set up that, Rose.
Okay, go on.
To Chance.
One thousand one,
one thousand two.
What's up?
Phone caII.
Yeah? From who?
lt's your son ,
l think.
AII right.
I'm shaking it, boss,
I'm shaking it.
It's aIways a tie
by this weekend.
Ugh . It's
a mistake.
What's the spread?
TweIve.
Who you Iike?
Anyone.
What is the opener?
Sixty-five.
I'II put 500
on the other.
Five hundred?
Yeah.
AII right.
Your caII's in 1 8.
AII right, on three.
One, two, three.
Hey, Chance.
Hey, Liam.
Took a vote on you and
that cocksucking nigger
Ioving son of yours.
You're gonna puII me down ,
I'm gonna foId your hands.
That's coming .
I promise you .
ReIax now.
Redemption time,
nigger Ioving .
Piece of shit.
Baby.
The sins
of the father.
What's wrong?
Nothing . Nothing.
l had a secret
treasure chest.
Where is it?
We used to come
down here when
we were kids.
It's right here, buddy.
AII right.
Thanks Partner.
We'II see you.
You get to hoId
it. Let's go.
Strange things happens
when the tide falls.
What you came to
know, drifts away.
Once fallen doesn't
mean forever.
We were head
to New Orleans to
live with Pearl's family.
That's were we'd
all get start over.
lt turned out
moving on wasn't
the hard part.
ln the end,
the hard part
was saying goodbye.