What’s the true meaning of inner peace?
Is it perhaps being
successful in our projects?
Or is it overcoming a phase of pain?
Maybe it is to understand that
every single second of life matters.
Yes, I know, it sounds cheesy, childish.
Fortunately, that's how it is.
There aren’t bad moments.
There are only moments.
And those moments define our future.
However, ten days ago I was
feeling like there is no future at all…
But my life was about to change.
Is that all?
Tatiana? Is this all?
Yes, Mr. Juan Carlos. You know, I’ve had
troubles finding resources about this topic.
No, Tatiana.
I’m sorry, but you got plenty of time to do this.
I don’t see anything good or clear on these papers.
Well Mr. Juan Carlos, I have been
researching, trying to get more sources...
I don’t want to talk just from my perspective.
I don’t want to reach just sources...
You are not being asked to do a microbiological
study of the origin of life, Tatiana.
The topic is “Inner Peace”
It’s really simple.
Nothing complex.
You don’t need many
sources. Everything is here.
The thing I’m missing here
is your personal branding.
We need five writings,
we can't start like this.
Well, I know it is very personal.
I haven’t found arguments…
- I’m delayed, yes.
- Alright.
How much time do you need?
- Twenty days, maybe.
- Twenty days?
There are just five writings, you
must upload a writing every two days.
We should have this entire
blog finished in ten days.
At this speed, we are
not going to achieve it.
Well, I thought I got the
same time as Alex to finish it.
Do you know how many curriculums
from journalists, we daily receive here?
Some of them maybe would
have finished this by now.
Yes Sir, I know.
No, Tatiana. You don’t know it.
If you would know that, I would
have three writings at least by now.
Well, Mr. Juan Carlos,
I’m sure you understand.
But, this is not as simple as it sounds.
There are different approaches to this topic.
For example, we can talk about
peace of mind, serenity, inner peace…
It is a social complex meaning,
actually, it is a personal topic too.
Tati?
Are you listening to yourself?
Please listen to me carefully.
Isn't the content that worries me. Is
the lack of your personal branding.
This thing I’m reading could be written by a student.
A good one, to be honest. But it isn’t enough.
Do you know what
happened last week?
People are getting fired. Do you
want to bring us into that situation?
No, of course not.
In the past, you
proposed projects, ideas.
You used to finish your
writings before the due date.
What happened Tati?
What is going on?
It has been a
very difficult month.
I’m stressed.
Mr. Juan Carlos, I’m sorry, you
should be the last person to know this.
I know.
We all go through these things.
But Tati… I must finish my
duties. I must do my job.
I can’t risk the results because you are
not in the mood, or depressed. I just can’t.
Ten days.
You’ll have the
entire blog in ten days.
I don’t want to be
the villain of this story.
This is my offer.
You will go to your home.
You’ll focus on this blog.
And you’re going to
send over the writings.
That said.
I want to feel your
personal branding.
I want to listen to you. I
want to read your DNA.
I know how you feel
about your father’s death.
But, life goes on.
Ten days.
Focus on experiences.
Make a map of content. But please, take
a look of the tools people use to be happy.
But the most important thing…
Be yourself. That’s
the ingredient I need.
I don’t know where it is.
Then find it. Please do it.
Because.
This is not you.
Spit it out.
What?
Marisol must upload that today.
On social networks of course.
Well, someone else please take
that role, just take the damn computer.
What are you telling me? Can’t you do your job? I
can’t solve everyone’s troubles, come on Lorena.
That’s your responsibility.
Alright, then let’s
fire her. I don’t care…
- Hi daughter, the plane just
landed. Let's talk tomorrow -
Alright mom, good luck with the shopping.
Please stop calling me, Alonso.
No, Alonso. I already told you.
Are you listening to yourself?
Is it my fault, then?
Despite ruining everything,
now you want me to get fired.
I’m almost there!
What an asshole!
I can’t believe he talks to you
like you were the one who failed.
But.
The important thing is that
you told him to stop calling you.
Rachel!
When everything got so bad?
This is life. I hate
when it happens.
Is really weird.
Like nothing makes sense.
For some time now,
nothing works for me.
First, my dad.
My mom is not
even in the country.
Now, Alonso.
My job.
I’m very stressed about my job.
I don’t get promoted.
Now they ask me to write
a blog about inner peace.
Inner peace? Seriously?
Do you remember Marcela?
So much I criticized
her. Now I am worse.
Don’t compare to her.
You have your life in front
of you. You’re just stressed.
I mean, you can feel sad.
I know your dad was a very special
person and that makes you feel bad.
But it’s been over a year.
What have you done to move on?
Alonso? Let’s not
talk! He's an asshole.
You are a beautiful
professional intelligent girl.
He is a jerk!
You can go out to exercise,
go to eat, go to the movies.
To the movies?
By myself?
Isn’t just that!
I can’t do those things alone!
I used to do everything with
Alonso. With daddy. Even with you.
For how long we haven’t
hung out the two of us?
I know you're very
busy, believe me, I know.
But I can’t do those
things just by myself.
You've always needed
someone to do things with.
You have to learn to
do things by yourself.
Without depending
on anyone else.
I really would like to spend more time with you.
But my mom needs me, and I have to work too.
No. I’m sorry
Raquel. What a baby!
Why don’t you spend this time
doing things you've never done before?
- You are home working, that’s amazing.
- Have you lost your mind?
I shouldn't be home working.
- What am I supposed to do here all day?
- You’re confused!
You need time for yourself.
Without thinking about
Alonso and nobody else.
You can go to the beach, to
different places, get some air.
Rachel? Seriously!
What is going on with you?
I can’t go anywhere, I must
finish the blog in less than a week.
And how is that going?
I've seen you writing over
30 pages in less than a day.
You perfectly can go to the beach, get some
rest, and then you just write it in one day.
- I don’t even have a car.
- You can rent one.
I’ll be back.
You should eat something.
Tati, everything is
going to be alright.
Rachel, I can't go
right now to any place.
And I never thought we could be friends,
and look at all the years we have been.
I’m going to prepare the food.
So, I proposed some ideas,
very crazy, my mind was exploiting.
I was inspired.
I calmed down and I presented
to them. I was nervous.
One of the CEOs was
there, but I was prepared.
Then, he asked me how we would save money, especially
with all the taxes and expenses, you know...
So, I breathed for a bit.
And I explained to him.
So?
Well...
You, my children, are looking at the
youngest and handsome manager of the company.
Thank you very much!
- Congratulations!
- Great news!
- That’s really good! Ah?
- I think so! You as always!
Alright, so now…
How did this thing happen?
I was at the Pet Shop.
And, there it was this cute cat.
Suddenly it said “daddy”
You know Nati loves cats.
She has one actually.
Obviously, I adopted it.
Instead of the plate of the
necklace, I replaced it with the ring.
I knocked on the
door, she opened it…
And she fell in
love with the cat.
But she didn’t notice the ring. So,
she held the cat like the “Lion King”...
So, she noticed the
ring, I knelt down.
And, I proposed.
Look, girls!
It was amazing, I held the cat. It was really
romantic because I didn’t notice the ring first.
Franco was on his knees,
and I said “Yes”... Then I cried.
Rockstar!
It was the best thing ever.
- Guys get a room!
- Stop!
- What happens?
- Where is the cat?
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday dear
Franco! Happy birthday to you!
Congratulations, Franco!
So. Who is going to
watch the game with me?
What the hell is with the national
team? Always the same players.
Don’t talk about it, because you’re
going to be the first one at the game.
- She has some pants!
- Well, she's right.
I’m patriotic, I love to sing the
National anthem at the game.
Come on, dude! Didn't you
check the list of the players?
I don’t care who they called.
Alright, I don’t like the players but…
- I’m going to get a drink.
- Are you alright?
Totally.
- Well I’m going to join you.
- Great! We can do the “cha-cha” together.
- Thanks guys, have a good night.
- Thanks for coming!
- Congratulations Franco!
- Thank you for the party.
- Don't you want me to stay over?
- No, no, I’m alright.
- Sure?
- Totally.
They are a nice couple.
Well, yes. It's time.
Two years together.
I'm so jealous.
I'm so far from that.
Are you still with that?
I already told you, Alonso
wasn’t the right one.
Please get over it.
You have everything
in front of you.
Why don’t you rent a car
and take a little vacation?
Relax your mind and
clear your thoughts.
Maybe you can find something
you weren't looking for.
Anyway…
I must go, otherwise,
the guys will leave me.
Thank you very much!
- Are you sure you’re going to be ok?
- I’m sure!
Just go, or you will
have to call a taxi.
Oh, dad!
What should I do?
So many memories.
- Pardon me! Did I know you?
- No until today.
But, I was a great
friend of your dad.
Well, I’m a good
How did you know him?
Before you were born, your dad
and I worked in a shoe factory.
We made the best shoes.
We weren’t more than just
two employers without study.
But, we really
enjoyed that time.
However, you want to know
what was the worst thing about it?
We made the shoes, but we never saw
the faces of the people who bought them.
Their happiness of buying
a brand new pair of shoes.
Or the anger for paying
more than they were used to.
It was a great time.
I'm really sorry!
He never mentioned you.
Your father had
amazing thinking of life.
He used to say that moments are in
the present and they remain there forever.
I never understood that.
I think he tried to say that we
should take time for ourselves…
You know, without people we
actually don’t need in our lives.
That phrase! Very common.
Rogelio! Nice to meet you.
- Tatiana!
- Yes, I know.
He always loved that name.
I used to tell him “Gertrudis”
was better, but he never went for it.
- I rather prefer Tatiana.
And I ended up
married to "Gertrudis".
How is Maria?
She's fine.
She is traveling a lot to
the States for business.
But...
I can’t help her
the way I’d like to.
I’m stuck to my work every day.
Honestly, I don’t know why.
By the way. What do you
meant by “that phrase”?
It's nothing.
Lately, I’ve been feeling
stressed and lost in a way.
You’re the third person this
week who have told me that.
I didn’t say that,
your father did.
We think too much about
what others would say about us.
We’re attached to everyone.
That's illogical, because
real peace depends on us.
Nothing and nobody
can ruin your happiness.
Life is...
Life is a celebration of love.
Alright?
Alright!
- Thank you very much, Mr. Rogelio.
- Just Rogelio.
Look.
This is for you.
This rubber is from the first pair
of shoes your father and I made.
I think it is time to leave
the closet it was hidden in.
The happiest moments...
come from the best memories.
So nice!
- Thank you so much.
- My pleasure.
Mr. Rogelio?
What would you do?
I simply would do it.
- You're right mom, thanks.
Rachel?
Guess what?
Yes!
I decided. I need to get
some fresh air. Totally.
You're absolutely right.
I know.
All these years doing everything for
everyone without thinking about me.
My mom. My family.
My friends. Alonso.
I forgot about myself.
You’re totally right about this.
So ironic.
All these years writing and writing stories
for everyone, but I haven’t lived for myself.
Exactly.
I know, I sound very dramatic.
But I’ll do it.
I’m about to purchase it.
I'll let you know.
Bye!
- Seven days then?
- Yes!
Alright, I need your
driving license, please.
Mr. Juan Carlos?
How are you?
Good, much better. Thank you.
Yes, that's why I'm calling you.
The home working offer.
I'll take it.
Yes, you’re totally
right. I need it.
Alright. You’ll get the
writings every two days.
Thanks!
Alright! We agree on that.
- Are you okay?
- Yes, totally.
Perfect! Let me tell you that
you got the total insurance...
That means that your car
and you will be protected...
- Welcome to Wyndham Tamarindo.
- Thanks.
- Reservation?
- Tatiana Valle.
Great, here it is.
Just one person?
- Yes.
- Alright.
Just let me check you in.
Sometimes we must leave our
comfort zone to find inner peace.
Do I have to go to a beautiful
hotel to leave my comfort zone?
Well...
To me, it is, of course.
Now what?
I wasn't in my comfort zone.
It must be a great story!
Excuse me?
Yeah, the story you’re reading.
Why?
To be reading in the
middle of this paradise.
These are notes.
I’m working on a blog
about inner peace.
I'm a journalist.
You’re a stranger, I don’t
have anything to explain.
Sorry, my bad. I
was just wondering.
Why does someone like you read
instead of being in the pool or something?
- Someone like me?
- I mean you’re pretty, and you’re here...
Do I make myself clear?
Don’t try to fix
it. It's alright.
Where’s your girlfriend?
No. I’m here by myself.
One of those impulses and...
Here I am.
Really?
Yes, I was looking at Yuplon's
discounts and I found this package.
I took some days off. This
is the third time I do this.
What do you do
on a trip like this?
I mean, besides talking
to the first girl you see.
No. That hurts!
There are plenty
of things to do.
You can talk to people
you aren't used to talking to.
Everything is better when
you're traveling alone.
Don’t you think we are losers and we
just made that thing up to uplift our mood?
Well, that works for me.
What else do you do?
Do you spend your
time at the hotel?
Do you take a tour or what?
Haven't you traveled before?
Well, yes. But, not by myself.
Besides, not inside Costa Rica.
What a star!
Anyway.
You can do tours, or just get
some rest under a palm tree.
Taking the sun, feeling
the breeze of the sea.
There’s so much you can do.
But.
There’s nothing else to do if
you keep behind on a notebook.
Well, maybe.
What's your name?
Rachel.
I'm Jason. Nice to meet you.
How much time are
you going to be here?
Same as yours. I
purchased that offer too.
We're going to keep
seeing each other then.
- I think we do.
- What are you going to do tomorrow?
Honestly, I have plenty of work
to do. I’ll stay here at the hotel.
Maybe I’ll take the
sun, just for a while.
Boring!
I’ll go to the beach tomorrow.
You know this beach, right?
You don’t know this beach.
It’s really close to here. We
can meet there by 9:00 am.
Alright.
Let's meet there tomorrow.
Great!
I’ll let you alone…
Because I’m going to seize
this amazing pool we have here.
Hello, Rachel.
It’s been amazing. This
place is beautiful and comfy.
Of course, a little
weird at the beginning.
But, I’m kinda getting this.
Yes, I’ll let you know.
Thanks for calling.
Good night!
This is beautiful.
See.
I told you.
I’ve seen some photos of this
place. But, it’s never the same.
I feel a tremendous peace
every time I come here.
There's nothing like this.
I don’t get why you people take a plane
instead of traveling your country first.
I'm on top of the list.
May I see it?
- Outstanding photo - Thank you.
Why don’t you use
your eyes this time?
We pull out our phones every
time we watch something beautiful.
Look.
All this time...
Traveling around the world.
But not where I belong to.
Maybe because it is my
first time traveling alone.
Or being with
someone I barely know.
But, I feel a tremendous peace.
What’s the blog about again?
It’s about inner peace.
Serenity, mental
peace, that stuff.
I must write from
my point of view.
But, I’m not used
to it. I prefer not to.
I'm used to finding sources,
witnesses, you know.
Inner peace is a decision.
You have it or not.
- Just like that?
- Just like that.
- This blog is not worthed.
- It is not like that.
You can have inner peace
at the worst moments ever…
Or you can lose
it at the best ones.
I should write that down.
I’m a “source” then.
I must confess something.
My name isn’t Rachel.
I must confess something too.
I knew it.
Now you just know everything.
It was clear that
wasn't your name.
How did you know?
Your name is on the
back of your notebook.
I’m so embarrassed.
Why didn’t you tell me before?
I was waiting for you to do it.
Well, you know my name. Tatiana!
I’m Jason. Glad to meet you.
Should we go now?
Let’s meet at the
hotel in the evening.
- I’ll be here for a while.
- Alright.
The moments by
ourselves are important.
Having inner peace means appreciating
every second of life. Doesn’t matter where.
However, a beautiful sunset at
the beach can change everything.
By the way.
You haven´t told me
what do you do in life.
I´m a graphic designer. I
work in a local government.
Since I've traveled, these are
the moments that I really enjoy.
Don't you think this goes against
all the purposes of our trips?
Why?
I mean...
We are here to
disconnect from the world.
But, we spend the
whole day together.
So I think...
It doesn't make much sense.
Well, one thing is to disconnect from
the world metaphorically speaking...
And the other one is to
literally disconnect from it.
Unless you are going
to a desert island.
Where you don't have any
contact with any human being.
Maybe, not like this either.
But still.
I think in the end, the goal is
to enjoy those moments alone.
Yes...
But I mean away
from our daily lives.
There is a writer who
always talked about it.
He said that our worlds
depend on our perspectives.
- I think this has something to do with it.
- Why?
Well, because you have a
perspective, very different from mine.
And it is valid. As a matter
of fact, it seems right to me.
I believe, to have a position...
You must live all
possible perspectives.
That's a very deep thought.
Excuse me, but I have
to ask you something.
Do you have a boyfriend?
I had one.
I don't want to go into details.
That is precisely why I am here.
Got it.
Now I have to ask you something.
And I don't want to sound
childish. That isn't my intention.
What do you want with me?
Honestly
I think you’re an
incredible person.
As perhaps I have
never met someone.
Everything feels so natural.
We can talk about different
topics, nothing is being forced.
Even if I barely have
a day of meeting you.
It seems impossible not to think
about wanting to know you more.
Look, Jason.
The least I can do is start
meeting someone else.
Especially for what
I've been going through.
But I'm not going to lie.
Yes, I’m having a good time.
In fact, I never thought to have a conversation
with someone else like y in a long time.
We cannot generalize
all the people for one.
However, it’s good
that you take your time.
As I told you, all good.
What are you going to eat?
I don't know yet.
I just know the food of
this place is amazing.
They have a delicious
tamarindo sauce.
Unique!
But.
I go to the bathroom for a moment
if you want to check the menu.
Rachel, I'm going to get
out of here. This is stupid!
I don't know what I'm doing here alone. I'm
spending money, I have a lot of work to do.
This is not me. Who
Am I trying to cheat?
I met this guy. He's an asshole.
Seriously, Rachel...
I'm out of here.
I'll let you know once
I'm back in the city. Bye.
Don't be such a child,
Tatiana. Seriously!
Please focus on your trip.
You're not going to quit this trip
because of a guy you just met.
You didn't make this trip for him,
nor for Alonso, you did it for yourself.
Get it in your head.
Take advantage because not everyone has the
means and a job that will allow it as you do.
You're right, Rachel.
I'll let you know
how the trip goes.
What did happen?
Oh, Jason.
I didn't think well.
But what happened?
Nothing. I mean it.
- I don't want to argue right now.
- I am not here to discuss.
I respect that you have left.
But, I'd like to know why.
I'll be at the lake in case
you want to talk or explain.
I'm not angry or anything.
No worries.
I'd like to apologize if I did
something that made you feel bad.
You told me that I was special.
All the story that you had
never met anyone like me.
And the first thing I
saw when you leave...
Is a photo of who knows who...
In a bathing suit.
She's Katherine, my sister.
She is a model who is doing
some photos for a clothing store.
I'm the graphic designer, and she
sent me the photos to make the art.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, she is my sister. That's all.
What a shame!
That man left you
traumatized, definitely.
Anyway.
You got your reasons,
and I respect them.
I can't believe
I'm acting like this.
I think...
I really needed this trip
to understand many things.
Don't worry!
Forgive me for not having told
you anything about her before.
No, come on. Isn't your fault.
If it helps...
I think it has to do
something with your blog.
Leaving our daily lives
and finding ourselves.
It is a good opportunity to correct
our mistakes and learn from them.
I asked you for your
intentions with me.
I told you, I don't want
anything with no one.
And I went crazy
because of a photo.
Oh God, that's how crazy I am.
What is for to
connect with nature...
To travel, go to the sea,
and try to clear yourself...
If we don't connect
to ourselves first.
I don't know how to
talk to you anymore.
For better or for
worse, we are here.
We got the same
package. Who cares.
However, something
must be happening.
The "me" from the past, wouldn't
have sat here looking for answers.
Things happened to me...
I used to judge people.
I kept people away from me.
As I told you.
You've only been around for a
few days and you're seeing changes.
I'm sorry, Jason. I mean it.
You really have to tell me
what happened with your ex.
No way. I said no.
Although...
You must already be deducing it.
Kinda.
- You owe me a dinner.
- Yes, you're right. I promise.
- Everything okay?
- All good.
We stay here?
Yes, this is nice.
The weather changes
here a lot. Right?
Yes, but it wasn't
too bad either.
No, this is amazing.
Peaceful.
In fact, you knew this is one of
the cleanest rivers in Costa Rica.
You really don't know
your own country.
You're right. I don't.
- I must go out more often.
- You bet.
Well.
My room is over there.
Do you want to go with
me for a walk tomorrow?
Maybe, yes.
Jason, wait.
I must apologize.
I'm sorry I left that night.
I behaved like a child.
In fact, I learned from it.
Good night.
Rachel!
That too.
Are we cool?
We are.
Do you hear that?
What?
That.
The peace.
I've been writing about
peace all these days.
Now, I can feel it.
And hear it.
Do you not hear it?
I think everyone should hear
this at least one time in life.
Tati!
Where are we?
Casa Luna.
No, no.
Where are you and me?
Jason, we are
where we need to be.
Two people who
took the same trip.
We're just relaxing.
Yuplon's guilt.
Yes, guilty number one.
If I had asked you
this a few days ago...
Would you have
answered me the same?
No, I don't think so.
It's hard to believe that two
people who are attracted...
Have not crossed
that line on a trip.
- Why do you ask me that?
- Nothing.
I'm just curious.
But, if we are
attracted to each other...
And have such a good time.
Why can't we cross that line?
Because I'm not ready.
What did happen with your ex?
I already told you I
don't want to talk about it.
Please tell me.
I think it's about
time to overcome that.
Besides.
Part of this trip was about it.
That was the main reason
I ran away from San José.
Why running away?
You should feel happy and proud.
Also, it is part of the
blog you're writing.
To find yourself and peace.
You really want
to know. Don't you?
Alright.
Let me see where to start from.
I met Alonso two years ago.
- I was interviewing some people.
- No, no.
Tell it to me with energy. You
criticized the the story I told yesterday.
I met Alonso two years ago.
I remember I was in the
park doing some interviews.
We were doing some articles about
the employment situation in Costa Rica.
I saw him.
It was impossible not to see
him. He was talking on the phone.
I remember I finished the
interview and I sat next to him.
I waited.
Then he looked at me. It
was a beautiful connection.
Very strange but beautiful. I
felt something I can't explain.
I tried to interview him, obviously,
it was very difficult for me.
I felt too many butterflies, he
noticed it. I was so nervous about it.
I was asking about his job. I
wanted to know if he was unemployed.
He ended up telling me
that he was an architect.
However, his life's dream
was always to be an actor.
We spoke about everything.
Once we finished the interview
I asked him to sign the paper.
He wrote down his name.
But his phone number too.
Old school.
Obviously, that's
where it all started.
At first, everything was super
nice. We got along really well.
I loved the way he talked
to me. I felt like a princess.
In five months, we
were inseparable.
We loved to watch
movies. It feels like I'm there.
We loved those absurd comedies.
Horror films too. Very good.
We loved doing everything.
We went out to eat, working out...
We talked about life, we
thought about the future.
Sometimes just having
coffee, being there together.
Then it came our first February
14th together, shopping in Miami.
Birthdays, the first Christmas.
He always helped
me with my things.
He was always very
involved with my work.
Sometimes I wanted to die, I had
no ideas, the articles did not come out.
But he was always were there
giving me super smart ideas.
Everything was amazing. Everything
was laughs, it was all good time.
We had a good time.
He was my soul mate, we even thought
about our future and how we would live.
Until.
Who the hell is she?
What the hell is this, Alonso?
Who is she?
- Why are you doing this?
- Please, calm down.
I don't want you
here. Get out. Get out.
In the photo...
Well, you know.
That was all.
Just like that.
What a jerk!
I started this journey alone...
- I think this is how it should end.
- But, Tati.
Wait.
We have had a great time.
I have been very
well, seriously.
When I was telling
you about Alonso.
I realized that obviously,
I am not over him.
And I'm not going to get over
it If I stay with you these days.
Because I feel
things for you, Jason.
And I start to remember how
everything ended up with Alonso.
I can't. I really can't.
That's not the
purpose of this trip.
I need some time for myself.
That's how I want the
rest of the trip to be.
That's what I did it for.
Look, Jason.
I don't want you to be
upset with me. Please?
Who knows.
Maybe we can go out
in a few weeks in the city.
Perhaps.
But I need to be
by myself for now.
I'm sorry.
I understand.
I'm happy for you.
That way, nobody gets hurt.
I want you to enjoy these
days as there's no tomorrow.
You deserve it.
Thank you.
Because this has been
the best trip after all.
How did you feel?
It was great. Thank
you very much.
- In fact, this goes into the blog.
- That's good, really good.
However.
We shouldn't wait that something
happen in our lives to do things like this.
What you are doing...
Everyone should do it. Regardless
of what is happening in their lives.
And these exercises...
Are precisely for it.
When did you decide
on this lifestyle?
I think...
I realized I don't
depend on anyone else.
I was done.
Not only in the city
you can live a hectic life.
What is the secret of all this?
The secret...
I'll say it to you
in the fifth class.
Actually.
I think you know the secret.
Have you suffered for someone?
Of course, like everybody.
This is not about gender.
Did you know that people...
Very often do not realize the
wonderful things they have in life.
They just see what
is in front of them.
In my case...
I met God.
And these wonderful exercises
that gives me inner peace.
I hope not to stop doing this.
I have met so many people.
But they don't know.
Or maybe they
don’t understand this.
They think this is
all a waste of time.
The worst thing about this...
They carry so many negative
things that they don't even realize.
So much hate.
So much...
- Disappointment.
- Fears.
Correct.
You know what?
I have some friends in San José who I
think could help you with this process.
Yes!
Good news, of course.
That's awesome.
Could I ask you some
questions to use in my blog?
Yes, go ahead.
What are three elements that you
consider are needed to find inner peace?
Let me see.
There are many elements, including
all the exercises that you already know.
But I would believe
that, at least for me.
The most important one.
It's forgiveness
Tatiana.
We want inner peace. Right?
But we can't forgive ourselves.
In fact.
We keep reminiscing over and over again
the images of all the people who hurt us.
We can read all
the self-help books.
We can do all the
classes we want.
We could visit all
the psychologists.
We can pray all day.
All that helps.
But you have to forgive
yourself from your heart.
You have to forgive all the
people who have hurt you.
Also, from your heart.
That's the only way to
find inner peace in your life.
It's the only way.
Any other questions?
That's all.
Thank you so much, Elena.
Good.
Excuse me.
Tatiana?
Yes?
Tatiana Valle?
- Yes.
- What an honor!
Thank you.
I've been reading your blog.
- It's really good. Great work.
- Thanks.
How do you recognize me?
You know the photo of the
team on the website, you're there.
Yeah, that's true. Good memory.
- In fact, I am writing the last part.
- It's definitely great!
Thank you!
- What did you like the most?
- Actually, everything.
But especially yesterday.
It’s very personal. You write a lot about
your experiences and I identify myself.
That's quite a topic because...
I don't usually write like
that. That's not my style.
It has been a bit difficult.
But yesterday's one was so good.
You talked about forgiveness and how you
forgave a person who had treated you badly.
I am from this town.
My family has a
life-long business.
My parents have always
told me since I remember...
That I have to manage
the business here.
But.
Two years ago.
I fell in love with photography.
So they decided
not to support me.
I hated my mom.
We couldn't even see each
other. We fought too much.
Whenever we talked,
we ended up arguing.
One day.
She came asking
me for forgiveness.
But I didn't want
to forgive her.
Until yesterday
when I read your blog.
You wrote about forgiveness.
You forgave that person.
And it brought you
so much happiness.
So I came early.
I'm going to have
dinner with her.
I'm going to talk to her.
If you had not written about forgiveness
and how you forgave that person.
I would not have the courage
to do what I going to do tonight.
Are you alright?
Yes.
All good.
Actually. Thank you!
For telling me this.
I have to go.
I'll wait for the last
part of the blog.
Alonso?
Yes, it's me.
I just want...
I'm just calling to
tell you something.
These days...
I have been to different places.
I learned a lot.
There was one in particular.
I cannot hate someone
for my entire life.
No matter how
much you've hurt me.
You know everything
we had ahead of us.
You were the love of my life.
You made a huge mistake.
That's something
I cannot change.
I can't go back to you.
You know that won't happen.
But I want you to know.
Despite everything,
you put me through.
I forgive you.
Well, just that.
Nothing more, and...
I really do not wish
for you or her any harm.
I hope everything
goes well in your life.
Alright.
All that's good.
Thank you.
And thank you for
everything we lived.
Bye!
What is the real
meaning of inner peace?
Is it perhaps being
successful in our projects?
Or is it perhaps
overcoming a stage of pain?
Or it may be to understand that
every second of life is a privilege.
A good man told me that
you have inner peace or not.
Simple as it.
It is not something
you get on a journey.
It is not something you
only get by forgiving.
It is not something that
grows as you do new things.
It is a lifestyle for
each one of us.
One in which despite
difficult or cloudy times.
Our mind, soul, and
heart remain steadfast.
I started a journey to
forget about the world.
But it reminded me that I
live surrounded by people.
People I can learn from
them if I only listen carefully.
Places where I can fill myself with energy
if I just enjoy them without a cell phone.
This trip reminded me that
happiness is in ourselves.
It's impossible to let ourselves be loved or to
love others, if we do not love ourselves first.
It's such a hackneyed phrase.
But I finally get it.
If you are reading this blog, ask yourself.
Do I have peace?
If you cannot answer,
I recommend you to discover it.
Because in my case...
The peace I was looking for
was only One Step From Me.
Mr. Juan Carlos. How are you?
I'm doing good.
Really?
So many views?
What a relief!
This is so good.
Thank you so much.
Yes, for sure. Tomorrow Saturday?
If it can be better on Monday.
There is something I want to do before.
Alright!
Sir?
Excuse me!
I just...
Thank you.
Thank you so much for...
Giving me the opportunity
to write the blog.
It changed my life.
So, thank you so much for it.
I'll see you on Monday.
Alright!