Hey! I found something cool!
Come and see! Hey!
What's he so happy about now?
Sorry to keep you waiting, Nami-san~!
Then, If I may...
Oh~! Nami-san! Your skin is so smooth~!
Your hand slips even
once and I kill you, okay?
Man, this is one great vacation!
That's fine, but just remember that
we've got bounties on our heads.
Hey everyone, come look! It's really cool!
But aren't you the one
relaxing most, Miss Nami?
Hey! Heey! Come look! It's the Going Merry!
It's okay for now. We re
not in any hurry to get going.
I agree with Nami-san!
Our ship is really somethin'.
What're you talking about, Luffy...
GOING MERRY!!
Our pirate mark is so cool!
You moron! How can you be so calm!?
Our ship just got stolen!
WHAT? STOLEN!?
YOU DIMWIT!!
Hold it, thief!!
The Going Merry is the soul I got from Kaya!
Being robbed by a fellow
thief? This is a joke, right?
GIVE IT BACK!!
THE CLOCKWORK ISLAND ADVENTURE
It's been a whole week
since it was stolen...
But you know, couldn't we
have found a better ship?
Not to mention clothes.
Quit complaining.
The only place open was a rental
store for wedding ceremonies.
By the way, where are we?
I don't know!
My maps and compass were all stolen
with the ship, remember?
And my katana too, damn It.
I don't even have a pair of shoes.
It's good we're going
after the theif and all,
but why'd you set out to
sea without any preparation!?
Hey look, there's a kid over there.
Is he drowning?
Guess I gotta do something...
Hey, you alright over there?
Thanks for asking!
What?!
Akisu. Good work.
Easy victory, piece o' cake.
ldiots like them are easy to trick.
Damn It, you little brat!
But they're only a gang of poor folk.
You can tell they don't have any
money just by the look of 'em.
Duped, eh?
A group of paupers, huh?
Who the hell are you?
Us?
Those sailing in search
of a mountain of treasure!
The Thief Brothers!
Borodo and...
Akisu!
Thief Brothers?
What's that?
It's just a bunch of trash!
Well, well... They're
nothing but scavengers.
That's not true! Watch
what you say about Borodo!
Borodo is the man who will steal the Diamond
Clock from Clockwork Island,
and become the greatest thief in the world!
You mean the famous Diamond Clock?
What's that?
The finest jewel and
greatest artifact ever crafted.
The most valuable clock in the world!
That s our knowledgeable Nami-san!
Ah, so If someone was able to steal It,
he really would be the
world's greatest thief.
Oh, then he's just like me!
I'm aimin' to be the greatest pirate
In the world, the Pirate King!
P-Pirate King...?
With this ship?
NO WAY IN HELL!
Our ship got stolen.
But we don't know the shithead who did It.
Does your ship...
have a pirate mark wearing a straw hat?
You've seen It?!
I saw it with the Trump Kyoudai.
Trump Kyoudai?
They're a nefarious group of pirates that
have a stronghold on Clockwork Island,
and terrorize the surrounding area.
And the Diamond Clock that I'm
after is also in their possession.
They don't look so tough.
This bear guy is too cool! Awesome!~
Why did you say that?! I'M the one
that said that they were nothing!
What are you so happy for!?
They stole your ship!
You're supposed to be pissed!
You're supposed to wanna
beat the crap out of 'em!
B-Borodo, over there!
That's..!
The Trump Pirates.
Hey, Trump Kyoudai!
That is one sexy lady!
And what might you want?
Give us back the ship you stole from us!
Your ship? I've never seen It.
Like hell you haven't!
Alright! Time for a riddle!
Riddle?
1. Who will become the greatest pirate
In the world, the Pirate King?
Come on now, Boo Jack.
That one's way too easy.
Me!
Boo-boo! Wrong!
The answer is our boss, Bear King-sama.
No, you're wrong.
No common knowledge, I guess.
What?
What kinda riddle was that anyway?
I knew these guys were nothing special.
Boo-boo! Mocking the Trump Pirates, eh!?
Well then, it seems we
have to explain it to them.
They're out.
Not much choice.
Right, let's see it!
Hold this for me.
GOMU GOMU NO PISTOLET!
These guys... really are strong!
Oh... So they can fight.
Here I come!
That's my Boo Jack!
What is that guy?
He might be a bit tricky.
Yosh, leave this to me.
My famous "Escaping is Winning" master plan!
RUNNING AWAY!?
Oh my...
STOP!
W... what... happened...?
It's safe!
Now, It's riddle time again!
What is it want most?
Nami-san!
Yes, you're right.
We'll be taking her along with us.
What did you say!?
She'll be a souvenir for
Captain Bear King-sama.
After we take her away,
It'll be fun to see him
do this and that to her.
This and that!?
Shit.
Are we really going to struggle
to Clockwork Island with this.
Just keep quiet.
Borodo is a genius at
manipulating the wind and waves!
What're you so proud of, damn brat?
Just so you know, Nami-san was taken 'cause
you had to go and jump in the ocean.
After all the trouble I went
through to escape from them...
Is that your treasure?
That music box is the only thing
Akisu has left of his hometown.
His hometown?
When Akisu was an infant, I
found him floating on the sea.
He was listening to that lullaby.
That song was the only thing
that would calm Akisu down.
So, you're not real brothers?
We're brothers even If
we're not blood related!
Right!
I'm gonna become a cool thief like Borodo
and never be hungry again!
A whirlpool!
Yeah. We're approaching Clockwork Island.
So that's...
Clockwork Island.
So, what should we do now?
We want to steal the Diamond Clock...
and you want to get your
nakama and ship back.
Either way we're all going to Trump Castle.
The base of those shitty
pirates who took Nami-san.
And Going Merry's there, too.
And my katana.
Then let's go together, to the Trump Castle!
Yeah!
What? Say that again!
You've occupied this island for 7 years now.
The weapon you are forcing us to build...
Has spilled too much blood.
And when that horrible weapon of
mass destruction is completed...
You've done enough!
Please don't taint the sea with more blood!
Good citizens, have you forgotten?
This island's main key is
under my complete control.
You know what'd happen to the island
If I were to break the key.
Even If you don't like It,
you should just keep quiet.
Show them out.
Aye!
Let me go!
I can walk on my own!
Once the "King Cannon" is completed,
everything will be in place.
And then I, Bear King-sama,
will control the entire sea!
And I will be the Pirate King!!
Ah! Welcome back-gas! Honey Queen-chan!
Oh? It's a young lady-gas!
Did you kidnap her-gas?
Stop it already, Skunk One.
This woman is Bear King-sama's sou-ve-nir.
Oh! is she my bride?
What're you lookin' at?
She's my type!
P-P-Please marry me!
Oh? After just meeting you only once?
Unfortunately, I hate hairy men.
I'll shave it all off!
But I hate weak men even more.
I'm super strong!
But I know you can't win
against Luffy and the others.
Luffy?
This girl's nakama.
He's a freak whose body
can stretch like rubber.
Nothing to worry about.
This guy...
Would he be Straw Hat Luffy?
Eh? That weak little guy has a bounty?
And I expect Roronoa
Zoro was with him, as well.
Stick out your "flute" before you fall.
You mean "cane".
In any case, we should be cautious.
Heh! Caution, you say?
For this little twerp?
Alright then.
As you requested,
I'll show you how strong I really am.
His bounty is $30 million.
It will fund our...
Wedding party!
Too cool! Too cool!
How the hell did they
set up something like this?
They made it to defend
themselves from enemy invasion.
If someone tries to
invade up the stairway...
...they'll be killed before they
even reach the town above.
Traps, huh?
So how do we climb It?
There's an elevator running
through the center shaft.
When they come out to terrorize the seas...
...the secret door will open.
So until then, we'll...
WAIT!!
You IDIOTS!! Weren't you listening?
Those stairs are full of traps!
We'll just tackle them one at a time.
Waiting here's too much of a pain.
We'll just go right up.
This'll be fun!
You'd better listen to Borodo!
Guess I gotta do something.
Amazing!
Let's get going!
Yeah!
We finally reached the town!
What's that?! What is that?!
It's so cool!!
What kinda city is this?
This is Clockwork Town.
And that must be Trump Castle.
There's the Diamond Clock!
Yeah. The most valuable clock in the world!
And look at the top of the castle!
It's the Going Merry!
You can see It?
Yeah, I'm sure of It!
It's on top of the castle.
I can't tell It's so far...
Hey.
Hm?
It's interesting that you could tell where
our ship was from down here.
Well, thanks.
Shit...
Your feet...
Nah, It's nothing!
Alright! Let's move!
Yosha! We'll attack Trump Castle, right?
Eat... Change clothes.
W-What?
Hey, you okay with this?
Your nakama has been kidnapped.
Aren't you going to attack?
You're not going to attack?
Since It's Nami we're
talking about, she'll be fine.
Ah, this is much easier to move In.
Alright, take care of the bill, okay?
Hey, wha...!
Here you go.
Come again.
Excuse me, can't I get a discount?
No.
I'm short on money this month.
I said no.
Hey Luffy, what're you standing there for?
Remarkable workmanship!
All wind-up crafts?
Ah, what're you saying?
Clockwork...
Clockwork Island is...
Clockwork Island is a very fun...
Clockwork Island is a very fun island.
Strangers. You know nothing of this place.
The time for calling this
island "fun" is in the distant past.
There was a time when
this was an island of dreams.
We created an autonomous clock to
commemorate the birth of our child.
We were congratulated by
all the people of the island.
Wow! So you two made the Diamond Clock?
But...
Ever since the Trump
Kyoudai occupied this island,
we've been living through Hell every day.
Now... we're only making tools for killing!
If we rebel, Bear King
will destroy the island.
By occupying the castle that houses the central
key, there is no limit to their control.
That's cruel!
Fear not, for your problems
shall soon be solved!
Because the Trump Kyoudai,
will be defeated by these guys, the
greatest pirates in the world!
Hey, we haven't agreed to anything.
That's right!
We only want to get our stuff back!
Can't we just do that?
But didn't that just make your blood boil?
Doesn't it make your blood boil?
As long as those bastards are here,
Nothing can help this island.
Nothing can save It!
Well, well!
Aren't you just thinking the Diamond Clock
will be easier to steal without them around?
Ah! Hey!
I see.
We won't mind.
We'd be grateful If you
were to take it away.
Whenever I see It...
it only reminds me of a painful past.
However...
It's quite impossible to steal.
Those who have tried
before have all perished.
It's not impossible!
There's nothing Burodo can't steal!
Y-Yeah!
You just don't understand just how
terrible the Trump Kyoudai are.
If you don't want to die,
please leave this island at once!
We can't do that.
We've got some private business with them.
Death creates no future for you!
If you don't risk your life,
you can't create a future.
Right?
Let's go!
Yeah!
Please wait for me, Nami-san.
What're you doing now?
Akisu, let's go!
OK!
You people...!
That boy was...
Akisu...?
I win again!!
It s too bad, huh?
T-This girl's good...
If this keeps up... I'll soon be naked-gas!
But I wonder what's going on out there.
Could it be that none of her
friends are coming to save her?
They must've gotten killed
by the traps along the way.
Those guys won't die that easily!
It just wouldn't be a challenge then!
The "kakefu" in the well
does not see the wide ocean.
"Frog".
Well, I think I'll take a
look at what's going on.
What's this? Running away?
Do you know how much you owe me?
Or will you pay me with your body?
W-What-?
Well, I'll go, too.
That woman...
Did she...?
Sweet! We've got a bird's
eye view of the whole place.
Don't get too carried away.
There's a field of landmines down there.
Eh? Those windmills...
They look just like this thing.
Maybe it floated away from this island.
Eh? It's not working.
Let me look at it.
You're pretty slick!
Akisu is something else.
Even though he's never practiced,
he can fix of all kinds of machines.
Alright, fixed now.
Whoa!
It's working! You're great!
Thanks!
Oh my, you're still alive?
It's that sexy lady!
What should I do first~!?
Get a grip already!
She's ain't no normal human!
She has the powers of the Devil's Fruit!
Pin Pon! Quite right!
The Toro Toro Fruit to be precise.
Boo Jack, reward them.
Waaaaai~! Reward me~!
Like hell!
Take this!
Sanji!
It went straight through his foot!
You saved him...!
HOW NAUGHTY!
SANJI!
Sanji-kun!
N-Nami-san...
I feel ashamed to look this way.
Sanji-kun...
See how kind I am?
I didn't kill him because he's your nakama.
Hmph. I don't care about him anymore.
A strong man like you is better!
Didn't I tell ya?
But, marriage is a very
important event in a girl's life.
I know.
So in exchange, my nakama...
Oi, Skunk One!
Aye! I'll help her decide-gas!
Wait! That's not what I meant!
So what shall we do next?
Shit, how did it end up this way?
It wouldn't have happened If I had
my pachinko balls and slingshot.
Don't make up excuses!
You just aren't brave enough.
What?
If it were Borodo,
he'd try to save me even If his hands
and feet were chopped off.
Your hand...
For you?
That's right! Borodo is amazing!
He risks his life to protect
me. He's a great man!
Hey.
What're you bragging about If you
always need him to save you?
Well... I'm just a kid.
I'm not strong enough.
Man or child.
Strength or none!
It doesn't mean a thing
once you're out at sea!
That's enough!
What do you know about Akisu?
I DON'T!
I just hate those who always think that
It's natural for others to save them!
It's not like I want to be!
What was that?
Well, let's get going.
Hey kid, If you're afraid of dying, go home.
What?
'Coz... I ain't gonna
save a weak little crybaby.
Who's going back? I'm...
Okay. Then, don't hold back!
GOMU GOMU NO PISTOLET!
Here I go!
Ah! They're after me!
You think you can do it alone!?
Oi, Zoro, what do we do now!?
Leave it to me!
And thus Roronoa Zoro has arrived.
What?
It's completed! Finally!
As expected of our Bear King-sama!
So much better than our last boss El
Drago-sama! Even your weapons are special!
The great killing machine, the
"King Cannon", has been completed!!
Like a "cotton swab" for an ogre!
You mean an "iron club"?
The King Cannon...
Hrmm... That's It!
And now our legend shall begin.
With me as ruler of the
world's oceans, the Pirate King!
Sanji-kun!
Nami-san. Sorry...
It'll be alright. These guys
are idiots, I can handle...
That's no good.
I...
I wanted to save Nami-san
with only my own strength.
And then...
"Thank you, Sanji-kun~!!"
Nami-san would embrace me, And then
we'd do this, and that together!
Hey now...
Hey, you letch!
What's your relationship with my fiance!?
The relation being I have rubbed suntan
lotion on her smooth skin.
WHAT WAS THAT?!
We'll crucify this one!
Even If you are her nakama,
You're gonna die in a public execution!
You should watch your mouth!
Weak pests like you can't be called nakama.
There's no way you could save her!
You freaking pig...
I'm gonna make you eat those words.
This reeks, what is It?
Welcome to Trump Castle!
Your nakama have been
waiting for quite some time-gas.
What?
Sanji!
But Bear King-sama seems
to be in a good mood-gas.
Now, who shall be next to be captured-gas?
Gross!
What's this smell?
It's Devil Gas-gas.
If it get's in your system,
you'll soon be paralyzed...
...and totally helpless-gas.
I'm full, FULL of gas-gas!
Hey, he's not joking! If
he lets out that much...!
Luffy!
Ah~ It's no use.
I don't feel like doing anything...
Oi!!
Akisu, you said I didn't have
any courage before, right?
Then you better watch
me carefully now, brat.
And see just how great
I, Usopp-sama, can be!
Usopp!
Hey! Let go!
N-N-No way I'm letting go!
He's insane.
I'll take care of him!
Don't worry, just hurry and go!
Usopp...
Have you realized it yet?
Usopp!
Let's go, Akisu!
But...
Don't waste his courage!
Move It, Akisu!
Damn you!
What a nuisance!
He should've been unconscious ages ago!
Usopp!
You worried about that man?
Of course! He's my nakama!
The only person you need to worry for is me!
Crucify and execute him too!
Aye!
Hoi, gas!
And what were you trying to do, gas?
Hey now, you're going to
get your lovely dress dirty.
Fighting's of no use, my dear.
Hey, up there!
Usopp!
What's this?
It's the island's main key.
It supports the whole
island from this castle.
Hey, let's get going!
Akisu?
Akisu!
What the hell's going on!?
I had to rely on you again, Borodo.
Akisu.
Don't worry about those stupid things.
We're... brothers.
Why is this so heavy?
It's a trap, we won't last long!
Borodo, help us out!
Well you guys sure are in a predicament.
What a disappointment.
Looks like even with all of you together,
you can't beat the Trump Kyoudai.
What?
I even stole your ship and brought you here.
You're the one... who took our ship?
So that's It. I knew
you were fishy all along.
So it was you!
You deceived us so you
could steal the Diamond Clock!
I never wanted that from the start.
What?
What I wanted was for you guys
to defeat the Trump Kyoudai.
To free this island.
That was all.
W-Why?
For him...
I wanted to see him return to
his family living on this island.
So, this island is Akisu's...
It's his hometown. I'm sure of It.
Sorry to have dragged you into this.
I've got another favor to ask.
If something happens to
me, please take care of Akisu.
Wha...?
As things are, looks like
It's up to me to fight them.
ldiot! You know you can't win! Come help us!
Leave it already.
If I risk my life, maybe
I can create a future.
Right?
Borodo!
That fool. Does he want to die?
Hey Luffy! Can't you do
something about this ceiling?
There'll be none of that.
Are you doing this?
Roronoa Zoro, it has been quite a while.
You gave me this scar,
right here on my face.
I shall never forget that!
You...
Who are you?
What? Don't you remember?
Not a bit.
I don't etch weaklings in my memory.
That's for sure.
Then I'll make you feel It.
The "technique" your mouth brings upon you.
Don't you mean "catastrophe"?
Silence! Hissatsu!
HARI HARI KEN!
Zoro, why the hell did you say that!?
Zoro... You...
That was dangerous.
They all got me.
Sorry, Luffy, can you hold on a bit longer?
I'll clean up here.
Don't try to hide it with that cool face!
I put some of the poison from Skunk
One's gas on those needles.
Your body will soon become unable to move.
Dammit!
There!
Zoro!
While you were crying,
a "bridge" came to you.
A... A "bee".
ZOROOO!!
What's going on?!
Where's the $30,000,000 guy?
By now he's been crushed under the ceiling.
We were able to show Bear King-sama's
genuine strength without him fighting!
And now you can marry her, right?
I'll go immediately to
prepare the wedding party-gas.
Alright!
The main attraction will be the testing our
ultimate killing machine, The King Cannon!
The targets will be those three!
What did you say?!
And then you'll become
the bride of the Pirate King.
How's that? You must overjoyed.
Who the hell would marry something like you?
Are you aware of what you're saying?
Compared to being married
to something like you...
I'd rather be killed with them!
That can be arranged!
Cancel the wedding party and make
It a memorial to my broken heart!
And execute this woman along with them!
Aye!
Luffy, what're you doing?
Where's Borodo?
He went to face the Trump Kyoudai.
What did you say?
Borodo!
O-o-oi! What 'bout me?
Don't leave me like this!
What? You?
Sorry. I went ahead and
stole all of your dynamite.
That voice!
Borodo?
He really does want to die!
This is how I work.
You'll all die with me!
Heh, are you an idiot?
What?
You can't use something like that here.
Look here carefully.
Do you want to destroy the island's key?
T-The island's key...
Do it If you dare.
The whole island will be destroyed.
You know that right, boy?
BORODO!
Like "dried bits of fish"
flying into the flame.
Heh, It's "summer bugs".
You cur!
Borodo... Don't you lay a finger on Borodo!
Akisu!
You... little...!
He...
W-What's the?
I'm finally here!
What's that sound?
It's Trump Castle!
Let's move!
Those poor children.
LUFFY!!!
Took you long enough, jerk.
LUFFY!
Slow ass.
So you're Straw Hat Luffy?
Huh? Where is everyone?
I found something cool!
What the...?
- What?
- You IDIOT
- Drop It!
- Let it GO!
I should get rid of It?
Okay.
Let go of it!
Say, where are my nakama?
YOU JUST BLEW THEM UP!
WHAT?!
Luffy! You're always so reckless!
Forget about It. He got us out, didn't he?
Yeah, seems that way.
What? You all came out fine.
You're disappointed!?
Usopp!
I won't let you touch Nami-san...
And I'll kick the shit
outta your riddling ass.
You're going to kick me?
What can you possibly do with
feet as badly injured as that?
Bast...
What the hell are you...?
Usopp!
HISSATSU TAMAGO BOSHI!
It reeks! A rotten egg-gas!
I can't stand smelly things-gas!
You're one to talk.
You bastard!
H-H-H-Here! Catch these!
Thanks!
Zoro!
Attacking from behind. Bad form.
GOMU GOMU NO GATTLING GUN!
Eh?
N-Not a scratch!
My body is strong as steel. The
power of the Kachi Kachi Fruit
A flimsy little rubber twerp like you...
...can't beat me.
I see. That's how it Is.
So, it's possible.
YOU'RE AGREEING WITH HIM!?
Heh, admitting defeat already?
Nope. Not at all.
We never lose, you know.
What?
Hmph. What difference will
it make by putting those on?
A weak guy like you can't protect anything.
Hey, got a light?
Just die against my toge-toge armor!
What is it...
...that I can't do!?
That guy's really great!
I told you before!
I'm gonna make you eat your words!
He did it!
Shithead.
Roronoa Zoro. I admire you.
You can still stand
after taking my dokubari.
But merely standing
takes up all of your energy!
Doesn't matter.
I'll tell you up front.
I won't ever lose to anyone.
Because losing is...
Absolutely unacceptable!
Stop struggling, gas!
You've got nowhere to run, gas!
Have you forgotten, gas?
The power of my gas?
And now it's over-gas!
Stop! No! Stop! Stay back!
Yeah, right!
KAEN BOSHI!
YOU GOT WHAT WAS COMING TO YOU, DAMMIT!!
GOMU GOMU NO MUCHI!
Well... this isn't going so well.
Watch out!
Looks like you're in a great deal of pain.
It's just "shrimp" coming out of you.
Heh, it's "rust".
You wretched knave!
HARI HARI KEN!
Awesome!
Cur!
You should be paralyzed by now...
How!?
Unfortunately for you, I can't fall here.
Because at the end of a distant road
there's a man waiting for me.
Dying before I face him is...
OUT OF THE QUESTION!
ONIGIRI!
He did it!!
No! This is bad!
Hope you had fun!
N-No way!
Hey, let me out! Let me out!
It's no good~
Crap, what's with this guy?
Luffy!
HOT BOILING SPECIAL!
GOMU GOMU NO...
HOT!
That won't work!
Heh! Rubberman, it's over!
BEAR KlNG!
Wow.
Borodo!
This one won't miss.
Bastard. That's my great King Cannon!
Akisu!
AKlSU!
I guess this makes me a real man of the sea.
AKlSU!!
Akisu! Hold on!
Heh, how nice of you to shoot yourself.
Though why you'd want to save someone
that much is beyond me.
What an stupid, pathetic little brat.
You...
What did you just say?
I said that he's a stupid, pathetic brat!
I am gonna make you PAY!!
How dare you...
...grab me like that!
You will be a victim of the King Cannon!
Die!
LUFFY!
What?
GOMU GOMU NO...
SCREW!
W-What the?
It can't be! The island's key!
The key!?
H-Hey... This isn't good!
What's going on?
Let's just get outta here!
Yeah!
Hey, Luffy!
Luffy!
The island's key has been destroyed.
The island is destined to crumble with it.
Is everyone ready?
Akisu...
Akisu!
Akisu... you...
Are you alright? Akisu?
It only hurt a little.
You had me worried there.
Borodo...
I can hear something.
The Diamond Clock is chiming.
It hasn't chimed for so long.
This melody...
It sounds like Akisu's music box.
The one who made that
music box... could it be...
...you, Miss?
Could... you be..?
Yes.
There's no other way!
What are you up to!? You can't run away!
Live! Survive!
In a place where the Trump
Pirates can never reach!
I could only hope...
that my child wouldn't die.
Then you are... Akisu's...
His mother.
It's so ironic.
The weapons we created...
Destroyed our island.
It couldn't be helped.
It was fate.
With it go our dark
memories of the past 7 years.
As long as we still have our skill,
we can build a new island!
Yes.
This is the future that we
opened by risking our lives.
We will gladly take it.
Oh no, you're bleeding.
I'm fine! I'm a brave man of the sea!
Mom.
Mom,
Your hands are warm.
Akisu.
Hey.
You okay 'bout this?
Yeah.
His folks are great people.
Akisu will be the
happiest guy on that island.
I don't feel the least bit lonely.
In fact, I'm relieved to be alone.
He's always tripping me up.
Now I can keep all this treasure I took
from the Trump Kyoudai for myself.
But, will you really be alright alone?
You've lost your only partner, right?
You can't call yourself a
"gang" of thieves anymore.
I'll find someone someday.
I don't think you have to.
Hold up, Borodo!
Akisu!
How could you leave me behind!
I knew you'd go and try something like this!
But you finally met
up with your folks and...
Don't talk stupid!
I'm a brave man of the sea now.
I gotta risk my life to
finish what I want to do!
But, you...
We're the world's best,
the Thief Brothers, aren't we?
Akisu...
Right.
Okay. Let's split the Trump
Kyoudai treasure now.
Hey now.
50/50 right?
I'm an adult now, too.
We agreed 70/30!
What? Don't be so stingy!
I'm not being stingy!