[Wind blows]
[Wind intensifies]
[Wind blows faintly]
[Indistinct, loud chatter]
[Women laugh]
[He breathes heavily]
[Dogs bark in the background;
Loud chatter fades]
[Man] Yang He, you're leaving?
[Yang He] Mr. Movie is on my ass.
Who would go this late?
[Insects chirp]
[Man] Let's drink.
[Dog barks in the distance]
[He breathes heavily]
[Man] Which Yang?
[He whispers] From the collective farm.
Who else could it be?
Supervisor Yang is your elder brother?
[Yang He] Yes.
[He spits, gags]
[Insects chirp]
[Door slams]
Is the movie over?
Yes.
Did it have the newsreel?
What?
The newsreel.
Go see for yourself.
Where can I see it?
[Man] Tomorrow, the second unit.
How do I get there?
Head East.
[Soft banging]
[He gasps]
[Dog barks;
Insects chirp]
[He breathes heavily]
[He grunts]
[They breathe heavily]
[He breathes heavily]
[Wind blows]
[He scoffs]
[Wood scrapes]
[He sighs]
[Wind blows]
[She grunts]
[Metal scrapes]
[She groans]
If I knew you were a girl,
I wouldn't have hit you.
Why did you steal this? To sell it?
None of your damn business.
Who are you?
[Zhang Jiusheng] Buzz off.
How about we split it?
What kind of girl are you?
Running around at night,
and carrying a knife.
Give my knife back.
[Zhang Jiusheng] Where do you live?
[Orphan Liu] Hey, I mean it.
Let's split it, alright?
How about give me 12.5 meters?
12.5 meters? What for?
Nothing. Just give it to me.
[He breathes heavily]
[He breathes softly]
[He moans]
[He groans]
[He breathes heavily]
[Wind blows]
[Truck engine rumbles]
[He breathes heavily]
[Rumbling intensifies]
[Truck rumbles]
[He exhales heavily]
You're from the second unit?
Yes.
I'm from the fourth unit.
Why are you by yourself?
I'm looking for someone.
Who are you looking for?
I'm telling you,
you can't just roam around here.
It's an empty desert.
If I didn't pick you up,
you'd have died of thirst.
[Horn honks loudly]
Pick that person up.
- No, not enough room.
- She's the one I'm looking for!
Who is she?
My daughter. She ran away three days ago.
Hey, stop the truck!
Alright. Hurry up!
You think you can run?
This kid.
Terrible.
[Engine revs]
Did you steal something and run away?
[He scoffs]
How can you be so crazy, kid?
Your dad has chased you for days.
Who?
Your dad over there.
Him? My dad is dead to me.
I should slap you.
How can you say that?
He's been worried sick about you.
Did you know that?
You're lucky you ran into me.
What if he died of thirst?
You'd have no home to cry in.
Kid, I don't know your family business.
But no matter how far you run,
he's still your father.
You only have one father. Right?
Don't do something you'll regret.
Alright.
You two are in my truck,
so you have to listen to me.
Say sorry to your dad.
Fine. Sorry is sorry.
He is my dad.
You know what kind of guy he is?
What kind of guy is your dad?
He has a mistress.
Our family doesn't have enough to eat
but he took a whole year's harvest
and gave it to his mistress.
My mum tried to stop him
and they argued.
He threatened to divorce her.
My mum got ill.
She couldn't afford medicine.
It's just me and my little brother.
Now that she's dead.
My brother is still young.
I don't have a job.
We can't go on like this,
so we went to look for him.
He wouldn't open his door.
We knocked on the door for ages.
Finally his mistress
came out, fists flying.
Beating me and my little brother.
Enough.
That's just like my dad.
Are you human?
Totally heartless! Worse than a dog!
Actually, I'm not her father.
Now, you're in denial?
He chased me all this way
just to take my can.
Inside is the money and food stamps
my mum left me.
He even wants to take that.
Give her the can!
[Driver] You hand her the can now!
Damn thug!
[Man] You believe her?
Stop!
Quick, stop the truck!
Telling me to stop?
Fuck off!
[Motorcycle engine revs]
[Zhang Jiusheng] Hey! Little bastard!
[Motorcycle approaches]
[Zhang Jiusheng yells]
I can't stop! If I stop, it will break!
[Zhang Jiusheng] Stop that truck!
It has the film!
Stop it!
The film reel!
Stop that truck!
You idiot!
[Indistinct chatter in the background]
NOTICE: HEROIC SONS AND DAUGHTERS
WILL BE SCREENING AT 8PM TONIGHT
[Woman] Mr. Movie,
what time is the screening?
The film hasn't arrived yet, calm down.
- Have some peanuts.
- Alright, alright.
- [Woman] Eat some seeds.
- [Woman 2] When does the film arrive?
That depends on whether Yang He
screws up or not.
[Man] Heroic Sons and Daughters again?
What about Fighting North and South?
Heroic Sons and Daughters is better.
[Woman] Definitely.
We like Heroic Sons and Daughters.
What's so great about
Fighting North and South?
- Mr. Movie, noodles?
- [Mr. Movie] Yes.
[Waitress] Mr. Movie is here. Have a seat.
Mr. Movie.
[Man] Mr. Movie is here.
Have a seat, Mr. Movie.
I'll sit over there.
[Bicycle bell rings in the background]
[Waitress] Here are your noodles.
"Dad" is eating your noodles.
Is it tough to watch?
Sit.
[He slurps]
Reporting, comrade projectionist,
the film!
What film?
Reel six of Heroic Sons and Daughters.
It really is Heroic Sons and Daughters.
Where did you get this?
I'm just returning it.
Come back.
Sit.
Sit down!
I know you.
Aren't you Orphan Liu
from our second unit?
Comrade, you're not
from our second unit, are you?
I'm from the first unit.
The first unit?
Then how do you two know each other?
And how did the reel end up in your hands?
Am I wrong to return the reel to you?
Of course not.
Good comrades should explain good deeds.
- Waiter.
- [Waiter] Yes.
- Bring two more bowls of noodles.
- [Waiter] Okay.
It's on me.
And bring my stuff over.
Okay, coming.
[Mr. Movie] Your noodles. Okay.
I put extra hot peppers in the noodles.
Please get me a good seat
at the screening.
Consider it done.
[Mr. Movie] Do you know why I get
extra hot peppers?
It's because I'm highly respected
by the revolutionaries of the second unit.
Do you know why everyone
calls me Mr. Movie?
Because I've been screening movies
my whole life.
And I've never made a mistake.
Screening movies here is serious business.
It's a tough crowd out there.
They've been waiting for months.
Each time it's like
a New Year celebration.
Film reels are treasures to us.
However many come in,
the same number must be returned.
We check the count several times.
This is called taking responsibility.
THE WORLD'S BEST PROJECTIONIST
How did this reel get separated?
How are you two connected to Yang He?
The guy on the motorcycle?
That's right.
He transports the reels.
His name is Yang He.
Hmm.
How did this reel end up in your hands?
We picked it up on the road.
Which road?
The road from the first unit.
This must have been poorly secured
and fell off the bike.
And Yang He wants to be a projectionist?
If he were the projectionist,
it would be a nightmare
for our second unit comrades!
- Was this the only reel on the road?
- Yes, just this one.
Comrade, what's your name?
What do you do in the first unit?
She could have brought it back alone.
Why are you here?
He's a bad element. A vandal.
Who?
You.
I'm what?
I said you're a bad element. A vandal.
- What makes you think I'm a bad element?
- You are a vandal!
Why don't you tell him
about your business?
- You're a vandal.
- When did I sabotage...
[Mr. Movie] Shut up.
I knew from the start you're bad.
- Alert the Security Division.
- Right. Alert the Security Division.
[Mr. Movie] What are you doing?
Why are you alerting
the Security Division?
- What did you do?
- Why are you...?
- Why did you come here?
- I came to watch the movie.
My daughter is in the movie.
I came to watch my daughter.
Your daughter
is in Heroic Sons and Daughters?
Your daughter plays Wang Fang,
the protagonist of the movie?
You're a liar.
Go talk to the Security Division.
Before the movie, the newsreel!
My daughter is in the newsreel!
[Mr. Movie] Wait a minute.
The newsreel reports national affairs.
The great achievements of Chairman Mao.
We must study the newsreel.
Should we study your daughter?
Her school teaches labour and farming
to serve the people.
Someone saw the newsreel
and wrote me a letter.
What letter?
- Your daughter is a student?
- Yes, a student
[Boy, shouting] Mr. Movie! Big problem!
We can't watch the movie!
Ah? What happened?
- [Boy] We can't screen the movie!
- [Mr. Movie] What?
[Indistinct chatter]
[Man] Mr. Movie is here!
[Mr. Movie] Oh, shit!
Big problem.
Yang He!
Where's Yang He?
Where the hell is he?
Say something.
Dad.
It was me, dad.
- You drove the carriage?
- Yes.
Why are Yang He's reels on your carriage?
His motorcycle broke down again.
It wasn't repaired.
He insisted I bring the reels to you.
[Mr. Movie] And this is how
you carried it?
You think you're pulling a donkey?
You got it all twisted up!
Like a donkey's intestines!
I don't have eyes in the back of my head.
Who knew this stuff could roll out?
Where's the tape?
- The tape sealing the can.
- I wrapped it around my whip.
[Mr. Movie] Why the hell did you do that?
[Mr. Movie's son] My whip
was falling apart.
You're afraid the whip will fall apart.
But you're not afraid
the reels will get damaged?
What are we supposed to watch then?
You shithead!
Isn't that a reel in your hand?
Just switch to that one
and problem solved.
Switch them my ass!
This is a drama.
That's the newsreel.
They're totally different.
You think men and women are the same?
You really have shit for brains.
No. 22.
The letter said Newsreel No. 22.
Now it's just like twisted up intestines.
It doesn't matter who is in No. 22.
[Wind blows]
Comrades, no screening today.
[They grumble]
We can't watch the Newsreel,
but we can still watch the movie.
[Crowd] That's right.
Under this situation,
how could we screen the movie?
Everyone can see.
No movie today.
But it's not our fault.
You can screen it.
There is a way.
How?
Don't you have fluid
that can wash this?
- You mean cleaning fluid?
- Yes
I don't.
And it's way too dirty!
How can I clean it?
You tell me!
Do you understand?
[Mr. Movie] You think you're smart.
Nevertheless,
..we could make one last attempt
and try to rescue it.
Do you all want to watch the movie?
Yes, yes!
[Mr. Movie] Alright.
If you want to watch the movie.
Please come forward
and be the witnesses
that today's big accident
is Yang He's sole responsibility.
[Crowd] Right, it is!
Additionally, I have two requirements.
If we succeed, we can watch the movie.
If we fail, no screening!
[Crowd] We can do it! Alright!
First, we all
have to keep quiet about this.
This incident cannot leak out.
Otherwise, our second unit
will never screen movies again.
We will all suffer.
Second, superiors will deal with Yang He
I will deal with the reel.
Female comrades, go fetch bed sheets,
masks, and gauze,
steamers, chopsticks and basins.
Male comrades,
go fetch cleaned size 12 steel wire.
Alright?
[Crowd] Alright!
[Mr. Movie] Get me these things
right away!
Action.
[Crowd chatters, indistinctly]
Get out of here.
Walk around. Don't damage the reel.
[Wind blows]
[Chickens cluck]
Put the film down!
I picked this up!
- You took the part with my daughter!
- Impossible!
Impossible or not, just put it down!
[Dogs bark]
[Insects chirp]
[He pants]
[Wind blows]
[He wheezes]
[Distant chant]
[Chanting intensifies]
[Wind blows]
[Chanting continues]
[Wind intensifies]
Show yourself!
Give me the film!
Give me the film of my daughter!
Come out!
[Chanting fades]
This doesn't have your daughter.
Not there, right?
It's all white.
It's just the beginning part.
Take it. I don't want it.
It's ugly.
What do you want film for anyway?
And why does it matter how it looks?
To make a lampshade.
A lampshade?
My little brother is a good student.
He loves to read.
But our lamp at home is too dim.
I'm afraid he'll damage his eyesight.
So I borrowed a lamp.
The lampshade was made of film.
He accidentally burned the lampshade.
Now they bully us.
We're in debt everyday.
He's too afraid to leave the house.
He is so scared
and helpless.
[Chanting resumes]
So what you said on the truck is true?
What's your name?
Orphan Liu.
I know you're Orphan Liu.
I'm asking your real name.
It's just Orphan Liu.
My little brother is Little Boy Liu.
Is that his real name, too?
We have no parents.
The police station
just gave us these names.
[Chanting continues;
Wind blows]
Don't cause trouble tonight.
Let me watch the movie.
After that, I'll help you.
What can you do?
[Orphan Liu] Hey, what's your name?
Why are you afraid
of the Security Division?
[Indistinct chatter]
Steady.
Take it up the stairs.
Good.
Careful.
[Chatter continues]
[Mr. Movie] You all
follow my instructions.
Come on, turn it over.
Step aside.
Come on.
A little more that way.
Release your hands.
Good.
Very good.
This end cannot be moved.
Chopsticks.
Get chopsticks.
Follow it from the start
and find the other end.
Whatever you do, don't scratch it.
Okay.
Raise the screen
and keep everyone outside.
[Man] Alright.
[Crowd cheers]
[Mr. Movie] What are you
clapping for?
We still haven't found
the start of the reel.
[Crowd laughs]
Here, straighten it.
[Loud choral music;
Indistinct chatter]
[Mr. Movie] Hold the sides,
not the middle.
Wash both sides. Remove the dirt.
[Children chatter, indistinctly]
Distilled water only.
The condensation creates distilled water.
Don't get it dirty.
[Mr. Movie] Great, steam it!
Careful, careful, step aside!
The distilled water is here!
You, careful where you step.
Don't spill anything.
Move aside, make way up ahead!
[Mr. Movie] Squeeze excess water out.
Then we start to wipe.
Not too loose, not too tight.
Wipe downwards.
One direction only.
Remember this point.
Repeat this action.
Wipe it in sections.
- Got it?
- [Group] Got it.
- [Mr. Movie] Okay, let's start.
- [Group] Alright.
Hey!
These aren't pig intestines!
Let me see your fingernails.
No, stop, stop, stop!
Female comrades, stay.
Male comrades, leave.
Quickly, quickly. Children leave too.
Bring fans over.
[Man] Alright.
[Mr. Movie] It's delicate work,
not like separating noodles.
I know...
I know how to develop photos.
- You?
- [Zhang Jiusheng] Yes.
- You've developed photos?
- I can also enlarge prints.
Go wash your hands.
- Use soap, twice.
- Okay.
- Wash your face too.
You've really done this before.
After it's cleaned, you can screen it?
As long as it's clean, I can screen it.
Look everyone.
It's hard work to rescue a reel.
So many people want to be a projectionist.
Like that Yang He.
That bastard was a pig farmer
leveraging his brother's position.
Trying to replace me.
I won't let him.
[Women] Right, definitely not.
[Bicycle bell rings in the background]
[He whispers] What did I tell you?
Are you making trouble again?
[She whispers] Who's making trouble?
I came to help clean the film.
Get lost.
Why?
Can't I help?
You just wait!
[Dog barks;
Insects chirp]
Little brother.
Sister.
Where have you been these days?
Did our neighbour feed you?
[Little Boy Liu] Yes.
She asked where you went.
[Orphan Liu] It's got extra hot peppers.
Smell good?
Eat up.
Sister, you eat too
I've already eaten.
We'll watch the movie later,
Heroic Sons and Daughters.
[Little Boy Liu] I'm not going.
[Orphan Liu] All the kids are going.
I'm not going.
Did they come harass you again?
[Insects chirp]
- [Door slams]
- [Zhang Jiusheng] Let's go.
What's holding you back?
Why are you here?
[He breathes heavily]
Little Boy Liu...
..your sister told me you
burned a lampshade?
It's alright.
You can still watch the movie.
No need to fear.
The bullies are going too, right?
What are you going to do?
If they bully you again, tell me.
- [Door opens]
- What can you do?
Fight them off. What else?
Sister, who is he?
A bad element.
[Indistinct chatter]
Now.
The film is clean!
[Crowd cheers]
But, before the film is dry,
don't move around too much,
otherwise, you'll stir up dust.
Those with fans, raise your hands
[Woman] I have two!
[Mr. Movie] Come up here.
Stay in order.
Make a line.
Be careful, everyone.
Don't touch the film, it's not dry yet.
Too many people creates poor circulation.
Film dries too slowly.
If you fan, it will dry quickly.
But remember, gentle breeze.
Feather-like.
- Understand?
- [Group] Understood.
[Mr. Movie] Okay, spread out.
Let's try.
Feather-like.
Very good.
What are you doing?
- Think you're the Wind Goddess?
- [Women giggle]
Fan too hard and it will stick together!
Gentle breeze.
Feather-like.
Don't use your arm.
Just your wrist.
Hey!
Where did you go?
Help me roll the film up.
What are you doing?
Don't touch it!
The film contains our model citizens.
Their faces cannot be smudged
by your dirty fingers.
Keep fanning.
Feather-like.
Right. Nice and slow.
Circulate the air.
And the film will dry quickly.
[Indistinct, loud chatter]
Okay, that's about enough.
Everybody, go back.
[Man] They're back!
- [Mr. Movie] Put them on.
- [Cheers and applause in the background]
[Projector creaks]
[Mr. Movie] Careful. Don't tangle it.
It's tangled. It's tangled.
Didn't I say not to tangle it?
Hold it level. Make it flat.
Hold it level.
Hold it flat.
[Projector creaks]
Sorry, I forgot.
I knew a part was missing
I sent others to find it.
Turns out you had it.
Where did you get it?
- Orphan Liu gave it to me.
- [Mr. Movie] Bullshit!
I know a film thief when I see one.
- Making lampshades, mending bicycles...
- I didn't.
You're busted.
Let's go to the Security Division.
- It was given to me.
- Who gave it to you? Yang He?
- Huh?!
- Trying to ruin the screening?
[He grunts]
Let's go to the Security Division.
Otherwise, I'll alert them myself.
[They breathe heavily]
You were just released?
I fucking escaped.
From a labour camp?
Yes, escaped from a labour camp.
Do you know why I broke out?
To watch your daughter in the movie.
No. 22.
How long will you screen it for?
- About ten minutes...
- I mean when will you send No. 22 back?
Sending it back after tonight.
Then two months later,
we will screen newsreel No. 23.
So you understand this is my only chance.
If I can't watch No. 22,
I'll slit your throat.
If you tell anyone else,
If you report to the Security Division
and I get caught,
when I'm released,
I will not spare you.
And I'll still slit your throat,
understand?
Yes, you'll slit my throat.
I'm not here to slit your throat,
I'm here to watch No. 22!
I understand. You're here to watch No. 22.
[Indistinct, loud chatter]
Have a seat.
You'll see your daughter soon.
How old is she?
14.
She was eight when I went in.
Can I ask you something?
Why were you sent to a labour camp?
For fighting.
I punched a Red Guard.
You were framed.
For just one fight.
Don't you understand politics?
Your wife and daughter didn't visit?
My wife divorced me.
My daughter doesn't want a father like me.
I can understand.
It's not just you.
Don't beat yourself up.
It's tangled. Slow down.
I... I apologise.
I'll roll it slowly. Nice and slow.
I was too fast.
Is this okay?
[Indistinct chatter]
Stop!
[Boy] Let's go.
Faster.
[Boy 2] Hurry up.
[Boy] Don't lollygag.
- Faster!
- [Boy 2] Go!
[Boy] Hurry up.
[Boy 2] Inside.
Go, hurry up.
So?
I tried so hard, but didn't get a chance.
- Please wait.
- [Boy] Wait for what?
The movie is gone tomorrow.
Your little brother is really clumsy!
I'm losing sleep over my lampshade.
If I could buy one, we wouldn't be here!
I'll think of something.
[Boy 2] Think of something?
How long do you need to think?
[Group] When do we get the lampshade?
When?
We'll hit you each time we see you.
I'll turn on the projector.
[Mr. Movie] And then wrap up the film
and bring it when you finish.
It's just opposite here.
And don't forget to turn off the light.
Thank you.
[Mr. Movie laughs, softly]
[Indistinct, loud chatter]
The rescue mission was a success!
[Crowd cheers]
We can screen the movie!
[Indistinct, loud chatter]
- [Woman] Turn off the lights!
- [Man] Turn them off!
[Bicycle bells ring]
[Crowd whistles, boos]
[Crowd yells, lively]
[Indistinct yelling]
[Zhang Jiusheng] Hold this.
What do you want?
Who the hell are you?
- Do you know Little Boy Liu?
- Yes.
He's under my protection.
You can't touch him.
- Come with me.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Who are you?
- I'm not going.
What the hell?
[They yell, excitedly]
[Yelling continues]
What's the fuss down there?
Are we watching a movie or fighting?
[Mr. Movie] What's more important to you?
The film teaches us to be better,
and you should work on that!
The revolutionaries of the second unit,
separate them.
[Indistinct yelling]
Let me go!
Where's the newsreel?
Aren't we going to watch your daughter?
Why are you getting all worked up?
Everyone, I have an announcement.
Because it's getting late,
we're directly screening the main feature
Heroic Sons and Daughters.
- How does that sound?
- [Cheers]
Great!
[Orchestral film score plays]
CHANGCHUN FILM STUDIO
HEROIC SONS AND DAUGHTERS
BASED ON THE NOVEL REUNION BY BA JIN
[Film characters speak in Mandarin]
Don't. You can't lift it.
Can't lift it? Give me some space.
You're blocking us. Move over.
Get moving.
Out of the way, quick.
[Insects chirp]
[He breathes heavily]
[Film track plays in background]
Where's your sister?
I don't know.
You don't know where your sister is?
Where did your sister hide the can?
The can, did you see it?
Did she hide it here?
Is it here?
[Little Boy Liu sobs]
Did she come back?
You are a bad element.
Tell me where...
You're a bad element.
[Insects chirp]
[Orchestral score plays in the theatre]
For victory, fire in my direction!
[Dramatic film score plays]
[Character in film]
Dear Leading Cadre, comrades,
Commissar Wang,
victory will always belong to us!
[Triumphant score plays]
[Crowd] It's burning!
The film is burning!
[Mr. Movie] Shut the door!
[Projector pops]
[Projector whirs]
Hey, you!
- Don't leave after the movie.
- Huh?
You just wait.
Wait? Wait for who?
Wait until I find the reel.
As soon as I find it, you'll screen it.
You got it?
- What reel?
- No. 22!
Isn't that No. 22?
Isn't that on the table?
Didn't you send it over with Orphan Liu?
[Zhang Jiusheng breathes heavily]
Where is she?
She went to watch the movie.
What did she say?
She said the lampshade looks pretty.
Isn't this lampshade made of film?
That's right. It's very fashionable now.
Not even 12.5 meters worth.
Mine is more. Over 20 meters.
And colour too.
Technicolor.
Better than anyone else's.
When are you coming back?
- Raging flames roar into an ode
- [Crowd sings along]
Heard by the world to heroes, to heroes
The thunder of guns rattles
Rough waves thrust high and echo
Fight for people, against our foes
Live for peace, die a hero
Crimsoned by the blood of heroes
Banners in sunlight brightly glow
- Nourished by their lives below
- [Children sing along]
Spring flowers everywhere grow
[Audience applaud]
[Song continues in the background]
Why aren't you watching the movie?
I've seen it many times.
The song is really good.
I've been looking everywhere for you.
What for?
- I thought...
- I thought you are tough.
That everybody is afraid of you.
Your second unit guys
only help yourselves.
The next time I see those thugs
I'm going to kill them.
There is no next time.
Hmm...
You didn't go home yet?
THE END
YEAR 1964
[Audience cheer and applaud]
[Distorted newsreel music]
NEWSREEL NO. 22
[Music distorts]
[Newsreel narrator] The whole staff
of the Eastern Road Grain Store
always remember the spirit
of Chairman Mao.
Under the guidance of Serve the People,
they study the advanced work
of the 19th Grain Store
and practically implement the spirit
of Serve the People in their work.
They don't fear hardship
and they don't fear death.
Party members take the lead role
to greatly educate
the young students who come to train.
Everyone in the store
competes to do the best work.
[Distorted music continues]
UNITE FOR INNOVATION
LIAONING PROVINCE
[Newsreel narrator] Shenyang Heavy
Machinery Factory
develops its mass movement
for industrial production
while adhering to socialism.
They strive for greatness.
Their revolutionary
production is booming.
EQUIPMENT UPGRADE FOR SUGAR PRODUCTION
GUANGXI PROVINCE
The Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous
Region is rich in sugar cane.
It is a national base
for sugar production.
In recent years,
sugar production
had many large developments.
[Projector whirs]
[They yell, happily]
Did you see your daughter?
She's in there, right?
Screen it again.
Wait a little longer.
If I screen now, they won't leave.
Whatever you screen, they'll watch.
They'll watch all damn night.
[Mr. Movie laughs, softly]
After they are all gone,
please don't hurt me.
Why would I hurt you?
I'll leave after I watch it.
Thank you.
You drink tea?
Have some tea.
It's high quality.
[Bicycle bell rings in the background]
The newsreel is a mess.
Sound and image are scratched up.
Dragged for miles behind a carriage.
Will your son...
..take your position?
Do you know...
..why I don't have cleaning fluid?
Why?
When my son was four,
he drank the cleaning fluid.
He had diarrhoea and vomiting,
and a high fever.
I didn't take it seriously.
But it gave him brain damage.
[Tea pouring stops abruptly]
He can only drive a carriage now.
- [Newsreel music distorts]
- NEWSREEL NO. 22
[Newsreel narrator] The whole staff
of the Eastern Road Grain Store
always remember the spirit
of Chairman Mao.
Under the guidance of Serve the People,
they don't fear hardship
and they don't fear death.
Party members take the lead role
to greatly educate
the young students who come to train.
Everyone in the store
competes to do the best work.
Is it the part about studying
the 19th Grain Store?
[Mr. Movie] The youngest student?
It's only about a second.
Is she the young girl
who's competing to lift the flour bag?
[Softly] She shouldn't have to compete.
She's only 14.
Why does she have to compete with adults?
She must compete as long as you compete.
It is considered a good performance.
Only then can she remove
your political influence.
[Mr. Movie coughs]
You've seen your daughter now.
Shouldn't you be leaving?
[Zhang Jiusheng exhales]
[Mr. Movie inhales deeply]
But I'm not leaving yet.
You can't spend the night here.
Screen it again.
It's only a second, it's not enough.
If I screen it again,
it's still only a second.
Then screen it for me ten times.
Ten times.
That's still only ten seconds.
If we keep reloading it,
it will take all night.
The sun will come up.
Fine, I'll screen it for you 100 times.
I'll make a loop.
[He whispers] Knock yourself out.
This is called a loop.
From all four units,
no one else can do this but me.
Careful, don't block the path.
Go under.
Under.
Okay.
Now you can watch.
[Projector whirs]
- [Distorted newsreel music]
- Brother,
go down and watch.
It looks better from down there.
As long as there is power,
you can watch it as long as you want.
[Distorted music plays]
[Newsreel narrator] The whole staff
of the Eastern Road Grain Store
always remember the spirit
of Chairman Mao.
Under the guidance of Serve the People,
they study the advanced work
of the 19th Grain Store
and practically implement the spirit
of Serve the People in their work.
They don't fear hardship
and they don't fear death.
Party members take the lead role
to greatly educate
the young students who come to train.
Everyone in the store
competes to do the best work.
[Distorted newsreel music continues]
The whole staff
of the Eastern Road Grain Store
always remember
the spirit of Chairman Mao.
Under the guidance of Serve the People,
they study the advanced work
of the 19th Grain Store
and practically implement the spirit
of Serve the People in their work.
- [Projector whirs]
- They don't fear hardship
and they don't fear death.
Party members take the lead role
to greatly educate
the young students who come to train.
Everyone in the store competes to do...
[Newsreel continues in the background]
And practically implement the spirit
of Serve the People in their work.
They don't fear hardship
and they don't fear death.
[Insects chirp]
[He whispers] Officer Cui.
Officer Cui of the Security Division.
What took you so long?
I phoned you many times.
[He whispers] How could
I have come earlier?
So many people were watching the movie.
He has a weapon.
What if he went crazy
and injured anyone?
- You're right.
- Where is he?
Per your instructions, I've kept him here,
inside, watching the movie.
- Does he still have the knife?
- Yes.
You should all beware.
He has a nasty temper and loves to fight.
Be careful, don't be afraid.
Officer Cui,
did I do a great deed?
Of course.
Then please tell our leader.
There's no one capable
of replacing me as projectionist.
[Newsreel narrator] Party members
take the lead role
to greatly educate
the young students who come to train.
Everyone in the store competes to do...
Why did you go to my home?
It was a mistake, I'm sorry.
A mistake?
What are you watching?
Isn't it No. 22?
Didn't I bring it over?
Let's discuss it later.
Let me finish watching my daughter.
You only care about your daughter.
What did you do to my little brother?
He's still crying at home!
I'll apologize to both of you, alright?
No!
- Then what do you want?
- Go and talk to my brother.
Tell him that you wronged me.
That you are a bad element!
That you won't scare him again!
And the Security Division
is taking you away!
Fine, but let me finish watching her.
Then I'll go.
When I get to your home,
I'll apologise to both of you, okay?
Which one is your daughter?
[Zhang Jiusheng] She's coming on.
The one carrying the flour bag.
Move over, she's coming on soon!
This doesn't have your daughter!
Why would I lie to you?
She's coming on now!
Look, now.
- That's her?
- Yes.
- Your daughter?
Lifting the bag didn't kill her?
- How dare you!
- [She cries out]
- [Zhang Jiusheng] Are you hurt?
- Fuck off!
- [Zhang Jiusheng] Get up first.
- Don't touch me!
[Zhang Jiusheng] I'll help you up.
- [Orphan Liu] You kicked me.
- [Zhang Jiusheng] Please sit.
Back off.
Take it easy.
You can't leave today.
I'll get you. I won't spare you.
You made a mess at my place,
bullied my brother.
Is that fair?
Don't run! Stop running!
[Officers] That's him! Let's grab him!
[Orphan Liu] What the hell?
Why are you hitting me?
[Distorted newsreel music continues]
[Officer] Don't run, block him! Quickly!
[Officers yelling in the distance]
[Indistinct yelling]
[Zhang Jiusheng] You've got the wrong
person! I'm the one. Come after me!
It's him!
Let's beat him!
[Officer] Guys, go get the rope,
tie them up!
Didn't you hear me?
Quick!
Hurry up, dummies!
[Distorted newsreel music continues]
[Insects chirp]
[Officer] Mr. Movie, screen the movie!
Okay!
[Orchestral film score]
[Film characters speak in Mandarin]
Are mum and little brother okay?
Yes, they're all fine.
Take a look at this.
Little brother.
[Characters continue speaking]
He's our Commissar Wang,
of course I know him.
He's Wang Dong,
your biological father.
[Dramatic music]
Wang Fang.
It's the truth.
[Characters' conversation continues]
Do you understand now?
Father.
To be honest,
I miss my father a lot.
[Birdsong]
[Cockerel crows]
- Did you contact the labour camp?
- Yes.
Were they surprised?
Of course. They've only searched the train
and bus stations.
What did they say?
They are sending a car over.
Have some soup.
Alright. We'll help ourselves, thanks.
We caught him.
And we are sending him back.
Shouldn't the labour camp's comrades
treat us to a good meal?
Of course.
[Officers laugh]
[He sighs]
I didn't know they would beat you.
A memento for you.
Mr. Movie,
thank you.
Wait.
I have a request.
[Wind blows]
[Orphan Liu yells in the distance]
Go.
[Yelling continues]
Stop looking, let's go!
[She yells]
What did Mr. Movie put in your pocket?
Left pocket.
Don't move! Be still!!
What is it?
My daughter, that's my daughter!
That's bullshit!
- Give it back!
- [Officer] Let's go!
I need that!
- Hurry!
- I need that!
Give it back!
Shut up, let's go! Behave!
[He breathes heavily]
[Wind blows]
[High-pitched chanting]
[Chanting fades]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Officer] I heard you're not leaving
for another two days.
I have some things to do.
What things?
Everything is fine now.
We've expedited the new policy for you.
Times have changed.
Hurry home and enjoy your life.
Of course, I'm going home.
[He breathes heavily]
[Indistinct chatter;
Rhythmic drums in the background]
[Bicycle bell rings]
[She pants]
[Wind blows]
[High-pitched chanting]
Right here.
[Chanting continues]
[He sighs]
[Wind blows]
[Chanting continues]
[Chant fades;
High-pitched instrumental music]
[Music continues]
[Music concludes]