¶ I'm gonna live my life
just like a holiday ¶
¶ I will not work, no,
not for another day ¶
¶ Since I met you, I will
not waste a single day ¶
¶ From now on, my life's a
holiday ¶
¶ The wind it's cold outside, ¶
¶ And a gloomy sky ¶
¶ But inside of my mind, ¶
¶ Oh, the sun is shining ¶
- Zoe?
Hey.
- Hi.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Good, good, oh.
- European.
- Yeah.
- Sorry I'm late.
- That's all right, I just got
here.
- Cool.
So, finally.
- Yeah, you were tough to get a
hold of.
- Yeah.
- Do you live far away?
- No, just a couple miles away.
- Oh cool, yeah, me too.
- Great.
- Cool.
- Tickets?
- Yes.
- Let's go get' em.
Okay.
¶ Since I met you, I will
not waste a single day ¶
- Hello.
Hi, just picking up
tickets I booked online.
I got them here, actually.
Hang on a second.
- There's no signal in here,
you're gonna have to go outside.
- Okay yeah.
Just give me a second.
- Okay.
Long night, huh?
- Yeah.
- Crossword, yeah that's hard.
- Yep.
- Found it.
Voila.
- Yeah, you're good.
- Great.
We'll also take a medium
popcorn,
and what do you want to drink?
- Water's fine.
- Make that two waters, please.
- No more popcorn, we're closed.
- What do you mean no more
popcorn?
There's a machine with a
bunch of popcorn inside of it.
Can't you just serve it to us?
- See the clock?
It's 10:15.
- I can't see a clock.
- No popcorn after 10.
Rules.
- Right.
It's not a gin and tonic.
It's popcorn.
- Jerry, can I sell the popcorn?
Jerry says no popcorn.
That's a negative.
Rules are rules.
- I didn't hear his answer
clearly.
Are you sure?
- Nevermind.
Haven't you heard? Popcorn's
dangerous after 10.
What are you thinking?
- Who knows what I was thinking.
I don't know what to say.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy your movie.
- So many questions.
Who's Jerry, where's the clock?
I think we're in this row.
- Yeah, 'cause there's
so many people in here.
I don't care.
- One, two, three, four.
Yeah.
- Do you mind?
Just in case
someone else sits there.
- If you prefer, we can go back
there.
- No, no, that's fine.
You're fine.
We're fine.
I've been looking forward
to this movie for a while.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah, I saw the
trailer three months ago.
- Cool.
- Big DeNiro fan.
- Yeah.
Hathaway's pretty clutch.
- Clutch?
- Yeah.
- I don't know this word,
clutch.
- Where did he get the popcorn?
- Just stay leave it, just leave
it.
- I need you to clarify.
I'm gonna go back.
- Look.
- Why?
- Just leave it be.
He needs it more than you do,
okay?
- Oh.
- Wow, that's horrible.
- I'm gonna--
- No, look, the movie's about to
start.
- Seriously?
All right, fine, sure,
I'll just have a water.
I love water.
- Me, too.
- Mmm.
- What?
- There's so many other seats.
- Just wait, just leave it.
Are you enjoying the movie so
far?
- Yes, it's good.
- That transvestite
DeNiro twist was weird.
Didn't see that sex change
happening.
- No, it was cool.
- I just want to watch the
credits.
Got a friend of mine.
He's a dog handler.
- Sure.
- I just wanna see his name.
It's just coming up.
- No, it's fine.
- Also, it might be like,
one of them deleted scenes.
- Mmm.
- Always happens.
- Yeah sure, sure.
- Must be a different film, I
guess.
- Good to go?
- Yeah, we're good to go.
Did you lose something?
- My phone?
Oh.
- Maybe it dropped out
when you were snoozing.
- Okay, I was thinking,
and I can't think when
it's too bright, so.
- Gotcha.
- I was resting my eyes.
- Yeah, yeah.
Ow.
- Ooo, careful.
Did you like the film?
- Come on, I mean, who buys the
story
of an 80-year-old grandpa who
gets an unpaid internship,
and then still gets to
bang the massage therapist?
I mean, completely logical.
- Did you check your jacket?
I thought there was a
lot of hope in the movie.
I mean, that you can
still get the masseuse
even though you're 80.
- Hmm, that's fair, I can see
it.
Oh here.
- Oh, oh good.
- Great.
That was fun.
- Yeah.
- Ready to go?
I gotta get going.
- Yeah, I've gotta go as well.
I haven't fed my dog.
I forgot to, didn't have
time, and feed the plants.
- Yeah, I really need to pee,
so.
Let's go.
- Pee away, yeah.
Not here, but yeah.
I think let's leave.
- Here, in case you get bored.
You know what, I'll just hang
onto it.
- Okay.
I'll meet you in the lobby.
- Cool, I'll just be a minute.
He's cute.
Ish.
This is the last time I date
anybody from a frickin' app.
Oh, my God.
But what is up with that stupid
accent.
I do not why people are into
that.
I mean, "I'll wait for you in
the lobby,
"would you like some popcorn?"
Just stop complaining.
Think of Trench.
Ready.
- I've got good news,
and I've got bad news.
- Okay, can you tell me outside?
I have to get going.
- I should probably tell
you the bad news, then.
We're locked in.
- Yeah, right.
- No, unfortunately, we are.
I've tried every door.
But it's not working, so.
- Are you serious?
This isn't funny.
It's not romantic, either.
- Look, I don't wanna be here
just as much as you don't.
- Who even still goes to
the movies on a first date?
Is that even a thing?
A dating tip from your
grandma, or something?
- No, she passed away before
she could give me any tips.
Jesus.
Well, the good news is,
eventually they'll let us out.
We might as well grab a
drink, have some gourmet food.
Security cameras will pick us
up, and someone will find us.
Dinner's ready.
So, on tonight's menu, we have
two gourmet hot dogs, with a
ketchup and mustard blend,
with poorly chopped onions.
And for desert, you're gonna
like this,
an assortment of chocolate bars.
- Alex, this isn't funny.
I need to get back to work.
- Work?
Who goes on a date before the
night shift.
Really?
For the appetizer, I was
thinking, you know, popcorn cup.
But as you know, no popcorn
after 10, so.
- Make some.
- It is a bit messy.
- Hm, first.
- Really?
Okay, yeah, yeah, sure.
Jean Raffanier, 2000 and
something.
Good year.
- Classy.
- Yeah.
- Now, I'm a little hungry.
- Good.
- Well, I assume my
cooking isn't that bad.
- Do you cook, except for, you
know?
- Now and then.
- Don't ask.
I know, I have a
microwave, so why would I?
- Your health.
- Let's not even go there.
I love all things gluten, sugar,
palm oil and Nutella, caffeine
and dairy.
- Well, add a bottle of red
wine,
and I'd consider another date.
- So, when did your grandma pass
away?
- Like 22
years.
22 years.
- Years?
You made it sound like it was
yesterday.
What is wrong with you?
- I know how to calm people
down, don't I?
- You psycho.
How 'bout that popcorn?
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
You can't keep pushing
buttons and expecting popcorn.
It takes finesse.
No, leave it.
We need three tablespoons of
popcorn oil,
otherwise it'll burn.
- How do you know so much
about making popcorn, nerd?
- My parents had a popcorn
machine when I was growing up.
Assuming that the universal law
of popcorn-making still applies.
- Do you get to see your parents
often?
- Not as much as I'd like.
Wanna try?
- How hard can it be?
No one ever burns popcorn,
right?
- Take this in here.
- All right.
- Right.
Two scoops.
Just don't make it messy.
There we go, that's it.
- Oops.
A little clumsy.
Relax, it's not like
we have to clean it up.
- There we go.
There we go.
Okay.
For your safety.
- Thank you.
Now we wait?
- Yep.
Suspense.
It's actually a
science, really, making popcorn
- Is it?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
- It's an art.
Very cool.
Pop art.
- That's it.
That's it.
So then, you just dump it all
in.
- Well, look at that.
- There we go.
- We made popcorn.
- We did.
- Ah, thank you.
- No problem.
Nice and clean, there we go.
Can you pass me a cup, please?
- Yeah.
- Oh, there we go.
Thank you.
- Sure.
Ow.
Could you not do that, please?
Please don't do that.
Really?
Ooo, sorry.
Oh, my bad.
Ooo, sorry, beg your pardon.
- Oh, whoops.
My bad.
- Come on, come on.
- Oh, got it in the eye.
- How you like me now?
Oh, oh.
- Oh, he means it.
- Here we go, go on, hide.
Can't hide from me forever.
- Watch me try.
- Oh, it's coming raining.
- Oh.
- It's raining.
- Okay, all right, relax, relax.
- Bam.
- Oh.
Wow.
A gentleman, I see.
- Wow.
- Do you think we'll ever get
out of here?
- Why, you got somewhere to be
tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Wow, made a mess.
And no help.
I need a piece of paper.
- Okay.
Here we go.
- Great.
- I can't read what that
says, and I'm two feet away.
I don't think security's gonna
read that.
Plus, if anyone was
here, we'd be kicked out.
- You got a better idea,
smartypants?
- Well, there must be a
spare set of keys somewhere.
- You look on your
side, I'll look on mine.
Boom.
My way.
Is that supposed to be a clue?
- Well, let's try and see.
- Yeah, right.
That's when we split up in
the dark, and then one of us
gets savagely murdered, probably
me.
Thank you very much, but I am
staying
right here, in front of the
cameras.
- Oh.
Miss Concerto chickens out.
Don't be a baby.
Look, it's better than,
what, just staying here?
- Okay, will you hold on?
- Finally.
I'm coming.
- Come on.
- Okay.
It's kind of exciting.
- Ah ha.
Yes.
- Wow, you really know how
to entertain a girl on a first
date
I warn you, if anything
or anyone pops out,
I'm on their side, not yours.
Why do you think it says
my way, dot dot dot?
- I don't know.
They must be a fan of Sinatra.
- Right.
Fly Me to the Moon.
- Or Come Fly with Me.
- So cheesy.
Oh.
Sorry, that's probably something
stupid.
- Yeah.
Oh yeah, just go ahead.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Oh.
All clear.
Thought I saw something.
- Such a freak.
What was I thinking?
Only weirdos have online dates.
- Oh come on, silly, we can
share
online dating stories later.
- Hmm.
- All right.
Hm.
You need a code?
- Huh, weird.
I mean, it looks like it.
- Hm, well, find it.
- Fine, I will.
Hm.
Well, it's not up here.
- Here?
Let's find out.
Hm.
Don't tell me you've never been
locked in a theater before.
Oh, come on.
You've never been to an escape
room?
- Escape what?
- Room.
You pay $100, they lock
you in a staged room,
and you solve a bunch
of clues, and escape.
It's pretty cool.
- Why would I pay to be
locked inside a room?
- Isn't that what you did
tonight?
- Smart ass.
Come on, whenever you're ready,
Macgyver.
- Six time seven?
- Numbers not your thing?
- Okay, I have discount-chulia,
it's a disease.
So, I would I appreciate it if
you wouldn't be so sarcastic.
Thank you.
42.
- Times eight?
- 336.
- Times five.
- Really?
- Mmhmm.
- Times five.
1480, no, no, 1680.
Wow.
Really?
- Uh-huh.
- That's pretty good.
I'm impressed.
- Mmhmm.
All right.
- Oh.
Got a short here.
- Short film.
- That's what it looks like.
- Are you trying to kill me?
- No.
No, shorts are boring.
- Actually, incorrect.
Boogie Nights would not be
Boogie Nights
if it didn't have the short
start, so.
- Touchy.
- It's about to start.
We got 30 seconds, come on.
Go, go, go.
Key.
- Boogie Nights, really?
That's all you got?
I swear, you're killing
me with this right now.
- But do you have a better idea?
- It's starting.
- Is that the guy from Big?
- You know, we don't need to
whisper.
We're alone in here, so.
Talk normally.
- Thank you.
- Unless Jerry's here.
- I never saw that guy.
She was bonkers, wasn't she?
Zoltar's doing a good
job, yeah.
- Is it just me, or does he
kind of look like Tom Hanks?
- Who, Zoltar?
- No, the big guy.
Yeah, I can see it.
- 'Cause he's giving me a vibe.
- Yeah, it's a show, actually,
it's a good observation.
Kinda like boy-ish charm.
- She's like, quality.
- Yeah yeah, no, I get it.
- Exactly.
- Ruggedly handsome.
Is that how you'd describe Tom
Hanks?
More like straight man,
actually, more like, you know.
Yeah.
You're right,
he is the guy from Big.
Yeah, he is, yeah.
He was great in
Riding in Cars with Boys.
Did you see that?
No.
- It's a good movie.
I studied at the university.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
- Studied Riding in Cars with
Boys?
- It's a great movie, okay?
Drew Barrymore's tour de force.
Should have won an Oscar,
Steve Zahn's wonderful.
You probably know the movie
he was in called Honey.
- Missed that one.
- It's a classic,
it's a dance movie classic.
Dance movie classic?
- Yeah, that's right.
Jessica Alba plays a
street dancer named Honey.
Gets into some bad problems.
- I do love me some Jessica
Alba.
- Exactly.
- Who doesn't?
- Apparently we agree on that.
- Good.
Ooo, what's this?
She is pissed.
Well, wouldn't you,
if someone took your chair?
Obviously she's got a dodgy knee
or hip.
She didn't take her
chair, there are other chairs.
Yes, but it's
obvious she's an elderly lady,
who needs some sort of
assistance.
What's happening, what's that?
I don't know.
It looks like
she just hit her there.
It's about young people
responding not well
to the elderly ideologies of
what has come from the past.
That seems like a
stretch.
But then, she's
blocking her now,
so she's also not helping.
You're agreeing.
Just booted her out.
Well, we need to work
together.
That's the whole point.
- No, you're.
- Tete-a-tete, you know?
Tete-a-tete?
See, he's gonna let her win this
one.
Oh.
Is this gonna be a
whole movie about tic-tac-toe?
Would you let me win?
Not a chance.
Good to know, thanks.
What's your type?
- Tom Hanks.
- Right, that's good.
- What were you looking for?
- I don't know, something
flattering.
- Colin Firth?
Hugh Grant?
- Yeah, there we go, that's
okay.
Hugh Grant, yeah, a little less
foppish.
- Foppish, what is foppish?
- Just, you know, a bit foppy.
- That doesn't explain it.
You can't use the word in the
definition.
It's not actually a thing.
- Okay, fine.
Foppish, to be fop, slightly
dandy, but sort of pathetic,
you could say.
- Slightly dandy?
- Dandy.
- What's dandy?
- Sorry, we found the language,
not you.
Now, let's get back to the game.
Ostentatious.
Ooo.
- Do you know what that means?
- Yeah.
Do you?
- Yes.
- Cool, I'm glad we both know.
- Good, okay.
The ability to attract
attention to oneself.
Ostentatious.
- Oh, so you've been familiar
with that word for a long time.
- Hmm.
So, she almost
gave him her number.
See, she's got the hat, she gets
it.
It's the same dress
as the seven year old, the
pigtails.
Oh.
- Oh.
No.
She's cramping his
style.
Yeah, I know what
that's like.
I don't know if I get it.
You're not meant to get
it.
Me personally, or
everyone?
- No, just in general,
you're just not meant to get it.
That's the whole point of it,
it makes you ask questions.
There's no answers.
It's like a bad episode of Lost.
Actually no, it's like
every episode of Lost.
- I haven't seen Lost either.
- Don't bother.
- I don't have a TV.
- I lost three years of my life
to it.
- 10 minutes of tic-tac-toe.
Some writers definitely lack
imagination.
- But it's not about
tic-tac-toe.
It's a modern vision of
the sprayed sprinkler.
- Oh, of course, right.
You're a writer wannabe, right?
- Thanks for the wannabe.
- Sorry, I mean a writer
soon-to-be, is that better?
Okay, so, if we were to write
this, wouldn't you want to be
more universal, talk
about the big picture?
- You work in a book store,
right?
- I'm a literary specialist.
- Okay.
Well, you should try and write
yourself.
And then you can judge.
- Wow, okay.
So, we're gonna elude this
topic.
Remind me not to debate with you
again,
you really go for the jugular.
- Whoa, whoa, what were
you writing on the notepad?
- Oh, I don't know, just notes.
That they might be useful.
So.
What brought you to LA?
Wanted to be an actor?
- Oh, God no.
Much worse.
I followed a girl who
wanted to be an actress.
- Oh.
What happened.
- Well, she followed a guy
who will make her into an
actress.
- Oh, do I know her?
- Maybe.
Are you familiar with the
Starbucks on 4th and Highland?
She makes the best frappuccinos.
- What's your story?
- Oh, I moved here to go to law
school.
And?
- Well, I decided that
my life was worth more
than just being a
lawyer, so I dropped out.
- Not as glamorous as Legally
Blonde?
- No.
I actually created my own
handmade custom t-shirt company.
You contact me on my
website, pitch me your idea,
I design it, send you back three
options,
you pick, and for $29.99,
you get it in your mailbox
within 14 days, and you pride
yourself on quality materials
and outstanding customer
service.
- Wow.
- Hey, come on, give
it back to me, please.
- I just wanted you to play
something.
- It's not tuned.
- Well, we can tune it.
- No.
- But you're wearing a yes
t-shirt.
- What, you speak French now.
- Of course.
I'll give it back to you in a
minute.
- Alex.
You're meant to be a
product.
Meant to be a player?
Come on, seriously.
- Yeah, a player.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Come on.
- I'll give it back.
- Thank you, come on.
- I'm gonna give it back.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Wow.
I always thought a violin
was a string instrument,
not a woodwind.
Are you in an air guitar band?
'Cause that makes a lot of
sense.
- It was a prop at my old job,
okay?
A prop?
- I thought it would look cool.
- I don't understand.
- Listen.
I have no special skills.
I'm 28, and I have no idea
what I'm doing with my life.
I print t-shirts in my
free time, and I pretend
to know everything about
literature,
even though I barely read
Alice in Wonderland as a kid.
- What do you mean, you barely
read Alice in Wonderland?
- Like, I mostly read it, but.
- What about Animal Farm.
- Mmm mmm.
- You must have read The Hobbit.
- No.
- The Harry Potter series?
- I missed it.
The Goosebumps
anthology.
- Okay, that's a guy's series.
Girls don't read that.
- Okay, Sweet Valley High.
The Babysitter's Club.
The Bible?
What about Tom Sawyer?
- I read Tom Sawyer.
There we go.
- 'Kay, I saw the cartoon, but.
- No that's, well, at
least it's the same story,
but you didn't really
put the work into it.
- Mmhmm, yeah.
- Did you use the violin to
impress me?
It worked.
Mission accomplished.
Look, honest.
- Stop, in the name of the law.
Dumb
Pull.
- Did you hear that?
- No.
- Come on, the footsteps.
I swear I heard something.
- So, why choose the violin?
Did you steal it from an
old granny, or something?
- I told you, it was a prop at
my old job.
And it looks cute.
- You're such a hipster.
Was this at the bookstore?
- No, actually, I used to
work at an escape room.
- Have you ever seen a taser
that you couldn't handle?
Broke it.
Yeah, that was so sweet.
Oh, my gosh, that was so sweet.
Okay.
It is time to get the bad guys.
- Where are you going?
- Don't worry, I'll be back in a
minute.
Go back to sleep.
- Don't leave without me.
Promise.
- Promise.
Come on, Taryn.
Take off your earbuds
and answer the phone.
- Who's there?
- Your brother, popcorn freak.
What was that about?
- I don't know, I just
thought you should be healthy.
How's it going?
Actually, very well.
We just finished the short.
- Did she like it?
- She doesn't understand art.
- Yeah, right.
Good thing you didn't
show her the little guys
on the traffic light, or
whatever the fuck that shit is.
- Yeah, yeah, well one
day, you'll thank me
for being part of my adventures.
Yeah, doubtful.
- Anyway, look, I need
a couple of hours, so.
- Oh, come on.
I have a life.
- Please.
Look, I'll make it up to you.
Promise.
- Is she even worth it?
- She was.
I mean, she is.
I mean, she could be.
I think she's overall pretty
clutch.
- Clutch, that's so romantic.
Thank you.
- Always a pleasure.
- Oh, oh, and remember
to tell Escott, yeah?
- Shit.
Pick up.
Voicemail?
Useless.
Pay him to sit in his chair
and watch the monitor.
And answer the phones.
Oh, my God.
Mmm.
- Hey.
You don't move, you don't speak,
and you do exactly what I say.
Escott--
- What did I just say, no
talking.
Now, put your hands up, or I
tase you.
Up, up, up, up, up, up, up.
Oh, a bottle of wine
and some chocolate bars,
and oh, my favorite, Twizzlers.
That sounds like jail time to
me.
- Escott.
- Listen, if you say one
more word, I am gonna stick
a charge into you like
you wouldn't believe.
Wait, how do you know my name?
- And now the penny drops.
What the fuck, Escott?
- Oh, mt God.
I'm so sorry, I never,
the thing just went off,
and I didn't know that that was
you.
- I was sitting behind you.
No, but I thought you
left.
But Taryn told you
I was staying here tonight.
- No, no, no, no, Mr. Porter,
she did not, I promise.
- She said that I was
gonna be staying here
for a couple more hours.
No, no, not
tonight, she didn't.
Oh, God Taryn.
So, how long have you had this
toy for?
- Well, since last week.
It makes me feel safer.
- Yeah?
Maybe you could do a
little bit more practice.
- Yeah, well, I know, but
it's really hard to practice,
and I didn't know that
it was gonna be so fast,
and if it makes you feel any
better,
you were my first.
- Great.
Great, okay.
Listen to me, Escott.
Yes, Mr. Porter?
- You can leave, but you must
lock the doors before you go.
- Right, okay, yes.
- Don't worry about security.
I've got your back.
But Escott?
Quiet.
- Got it.
- Okay?
- Quiet.
- Good.
- Yes.
- Have these.
- Thank you.
I get to keep the taser, right?
- Yes, you can keep the taser.
- Yes.
- Just keep it away from me.
- Got it.
- Quiet.
- And now.
- Perfect.
Okay.
- You were gone a while.
- You already can't be without
me.
- I may have missed you a
little.
- I brought more supplies.
- Ah, wine.
I need wine.
- I bet you do, Sue Ellen.
More red wine.
Oh, make yourself at home.
- Mmhmm.
Just getting more comfortable.
We might be here a while.
Wow, you don't need to get me
drunk.
- I'm sorry.
I think I'm in the wrong
theater, I was looking for Zoe.
- Hmm.
You know, I'm really, really
tired.
- Then you should go to bed.
- Mmm.
But, when I'm tired, I
get very, very horny.
- Well, maybe I can help with
that.
- Hmm, I'm sure you would
be very, very helpful.
Do you think we'll ever get out
of here?
- Hopefully not.
I mean, we have wine, we
have food, and I have you.
Sounds like paradise.
- Yeah.
That sounds marvelous.
But, if that's so, then maybe,
we could have Escott join us.
Wouldn't that be fun?
I mean, the more, the merrier.
- Escott, what?
- What was the rest of the plan?
You take advantage of me, and
then,
you suddenly find the key
somewhere?
- No, listen to me, listen.
- Hey, no, you listen to me.
I have been listening to
your bullshit all night.
How many ladies have had the
privilege
of being stuck in this shit
hole?
- It's not like that.
- Yeah, right, okay, you know
what?
If I ever hear from you, see
you,
or even smell you again,
I swear to you, I will,
chop your balls off.
¶ You say that you change, ¶
¶ That you were a better man ¶
¶ But I've heard it all ¶
¶ What have took me for ¶
- Ah, some popcorn, or,
whoa, calm yourself, woman.
I knew something was
wrong with that chick.
¶ Oh no ¶
¶ You're not the one I need ¶
¶ And you're not the everything
¶
¶ Oh ¶
¶ Oh no ¶
- I'm sorry.
- Eh, it was coming.
I can't believe she was the only
one
that thought my film was not
good enough.
Fine, apart from you, Roger
Ebert.
- What the hell did you guys do?
- She did have a
different way of thinking.
- Well, it looks like she
knows how to have fun.
- Oh yeah, I'm sorry, I'll clean
up.
- Miss Taryn, you really
should have called me.
- Thanks for the heads up.
- Yeah, no problem.
- Did you guys know the
cacklet sleeps standing up.
They dive down to grab snatches
of sleep that last about 12
minutes,
and then they slowly drift to
the surface.
Head first.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
- That's fascinating.
- Mmhmm.
- I'm gonna get some sleep.
I think you guys should, too.
If you want to do it standing
up,
sitting down, or lying
on the couch, I'm out.
- Wait.
I'll give you a ride.
- Yeah.
Okay guys, I'll lock up.
18th hole.
Augusta National.
For the masters.
Get in your hole.
Let's go for a new personal
record of 403 in a row.
Oh, that's short.
Gosh.
Okay.
I think it's the ball.
I had a personal record going,
and then, I just go, and I screw
it up.
And now, I'm back at it.
And that is what you call a
victory dance.
- Thanks a lot, enjoy your
night.
- Bye.
- So, how many people.
- Four, plus two, plus three,
plus four,
so--
- 13.
- We need to do something.
We can't carry on the way it is.
- Maybe I have an idea.
- Okay.
Do tell.
- Okay, you can't compete
with the multiplex.
So, why don't we do something
different.
- Right.
Your plan does have a stage two,
right?
- Do a themed theater.
- A themed theater?
- Okay.
So, today we had 13 customers.
$10, that's,
- 130.
- Smart ass.
So, what if we have five
screenings a day,
but only two customers per
screening?
Now, you're thinking,
that's less than now.
But no, not if we charge $50 per
customer.
Why 50?
Because the price of the
movie date experience.
- Okay, continue, go on.
- All right, so, for two hours,
the theater is theirs, entirely
theirs.
No employees, no popcorn
girl, no projectionist.
They have entry, and then the
whole place to themselves.
Basically, it's home at the
theater, or theater at home.
The first DIY theater.
- That's great.
No, that is an unbelievable
idea.
I could kiss you.
- Don't kiss me.
- No, I'm not going to, but
that's still a great idea.
- And last but not least, we can
supervise
from the security room, so
if they have any issues,
we can interact with them from
there,
just like in an escape room.
- What is it with you
girls and escape rooms?
- Hm?
- Nothing.
No, I really like this.
This is great.
Okay, let's start it
tomorrow morning, 8:00 a.m.
- I'm sorry, eight?
- Well, great entrepreneurs wake
up early.
It's a compliment.
You'll get used to it, relax.
- I should have kept my mouth
shut.
Yo, the towel, you're bringing
it home?
- Yeah, it's a white flag.
- He just took a left.
Deli meat, eight letters.
What have you got?
- Salt beef.
What?
- Salt beef, that isn't a thing.
- It is a thing.
It's a deli.
Good evening, welcome,
how you doing tonight?
- How the hell wrote a movie
about this stupid game?
- Great choice.
- In a world of war and
injustice,
Bruce has found a way to
bring back peace on earth.
Tic-tac-toe toe toe toe.
- You know, I was thinking, T,
you should apply for a job at
Disney Land.
I mean, your
be much valued over there.
- Honey.
- Was salt beef right?
- Salt beef isn't a thing.
- It is a thing.
You have it on rye bread.
It's taking you this long.
- Hello.
Anybody here?
It's your lucky day.
You have a customer trying to
buy a book.
- Yes, yes, coming.
Hi, I'm here, how can I help
you?
- Back there, like, working out?
- Long story.
So, what is it you're looking
for?
- It's a gift.
Something readable.
Yeah, readable is a good start.
Fun, but dramatic at the same
time.
I don't know, something new.
- Hm.
How 'bout US Weekly?
- Oh, she's funny, too.
- Wait a minute, you look
familiar.
You're the popcorn freak.
- Guilty.
Okay, but just listen to me for
a second.
- Look, I don't have time for
this.
I have work to do.
- No, it'll just take a minute,
I promise.
All your customers can wait.
- It's the holidays,
people buy food, not books.
- Oh, of course, it's the
holidays.
All right, so Alex has this
new concept at the theater.
It was actually my idea.
I am the brains, after all.
But you would like it,
so you should come by.
- Look, popcorn.
- Taryn.
- Look, Popcorn Taryn, I know in
a romcom,
that would be the perfect time
for me to start missing Alex,
having remorse and run to him,
but--
- Hm, she's an expert of the
cinema, too.
- I know my classics.
But the fact is, I'm really over
him,
if I was ever into him in the
first place.
So, I appreciate the thought,
but I think I'll pass.
- You guys are both so stubborn.
- Look,
I have to get back to working
out.
- Be careful carrying on like
that.
I might start to like you soon.
If you ever change your mind,
text me.
Don't call me, speaking on
the phone gives me anxiety.
- Looks like you're gonna need
more time
to find the right book.
- No, you're right.
I'll stick with US Weekly.
- Bye.
Let's go out, meet
fresh meat.
No, I can't go,
I have work tomorrow.
Come on, where's the
stool?
- Yeah, I know.
Seriously, no one
will notice, it's dead empty.
Anyway, what's the plan for
Halloween?
- Of course, I'm not doing
anything for Halloween.
A costume.
- Nope, not negotiable.
- Boring.
- Yeah, I know.
Well, I guess
I'm just gonna sit here
and stare at my cat.
- Okay.
I have a pile of t-shirts to
finish up.
You can come help me instead.
Halloween's overrated.
Get yourself
a boyfriend to help.
- A boyfriend?
Yeah, right.
- Netflix and--
- I do not not have Netflix.
I do not wanna chill.
- Hey, they're not all twats
like Alex.
I mean, they almost all are.
- Hey.
I gotta go, Thai food's waiting.
Okay, enjoy ironing.
- Okay.
Bye bye.
- Bye.
¶ I want to walk with you in
moonlight ¶
¶ And I know you're not in
heaven ¶
¶ Go on and pretending ¶
¶ That I really thought this ¶
¶ Oh, when you're with me,
darling, ¶
¶ You mean more to me than
anyone else ¶
¶ I'm so confused by you ¶
¶ I don't know what to do ¶
- What time are they coming?
- The first couple are coming at
six,
then we have 30 minute break.
Second one comes at nine.
- That's exciting.
- Yeah.
- Is the security room ready?
- All ready.
- All right.
Everything's fine.
Let's go get a beer, we have an
hour.
- We have beer here, I don't
need a beer
- Well, let's go get some fresh
air.
- T, I was thinking, when are
you gonna get a proper job?
- I could never stop working
with you.
- You can't really call it work.
- Let's go.
- Fine, okay.
Just for an hour, though.
Can't be late.
Taryn, what are we doing now?
- Please, it'll just take a
minute.
- I don't think they sell
gossip magazines here.
- Don't start.
Hello, your favorite customer is
here.
- Oh, you again.
- Ah.
- Look, if you need a
copy of Harry Potter,
even signed by JK Rowling,
maybe I can help you.
But if you're here to talk
about him, I think we're done.
- Oh, I promise, I'm not
gonna talk about Alex, but,
yeah.
- What the hell, Popcorn?
- Taryn, it's Taryn.
- Yeah, what the hell, Popcorn.
- You don't start.
We're all here because of you.
- Me?
I didn't ask to be here.
- Yeah, right.
- I've got much better things to
do.
- Mmhmm.
- This is going well.
- So, why are you here?
To apologize, to beg me to
give you a second chance?
Tell me how much you love me?
Why?
- No, I'm here because I got
tricked.
- Oh, another of your little
games?
- No, Taryn said we were
grabbing a drink to relax,
and instead, she brought me
here.
- Oh, like a date?
Have you ever thought of dating
her?
You two would make a great
couple.
Kant.
- I don't really think that's
legal here.
My sister.
Sister?
- Well, half-sister.
Same dad.
He passed away three years ago
before we inherited the theater.
- Wait, so that's your theater?
- Yeah, all mine.
Mine and Taryn's.
We have a new concept, so I
really need to get going, so.
- New concept?
- Yeah.
You seen Taryn anywhere?
No.
- Taryn?
You have keys, right?
- Oh, shit.
- I really don't have time for
this.
Taryn.
I took her keys.
- Taryn, what the hell?
- Yeah, what the hell?
- Oh, calm down.
Get back to work, guys,
figure out more clues.
All you've done is put up
cameras
and shitty instructions
on how to make popcorn.
Tell me you got a plan.
- She's probably right.
- Look, I'm not gonna tell you
again.
Let me out, come on.
- You said she was the
queen of escape rooms.
Figure it out, and I'll open the
door.
Whatever.
- No, no, no.
Okay, hey, maybe you can help,
okay?
Remember our little
adventure at the theater?
- Do I remember?
- Okay, poor choice of
phrasing, fair play.
Well, it inspired me.
- I'm listening.
- You guys love your dating
adventures in this country.
- Dating adventures?
- Yeah, you know about
dating, it's not about
who you're with, it's about
having fun on the date.
- So cliche.
- Well, I made a new adventure.
- What, you're selling your
services at the theater now?
- Ha ha, very funny.
No, it's a dating concept.
A couple come to the theater,
and they get locked in
for a couple of hours.
- What, an escape room?
- Exactly.
- That's my idea.
- God, it is crazy in
this city how many people
think it's always their idea.
- Right, my idea.
- Ah, nice t-shirt.
Anyway, we have our first
customers in a couple of hours.
And if I'm not there, my idea--
Hey, I can hear you.
- Taryn's idea,
okay, your idea, whatever, it'll
be gone.
- You had the popcorn figured
out.
- Yeah, but we need a puzzle or
something,
a more mysterious element to it.
- What about the projector,
how hard is it to load a film?
- Pretty easy.
I mean, even Taryn can do it.
- Okay, okay.
- Sometime today, please.
- What about the projection
booth?
We needed a code to get in
there, right?
Come on.
- Maybe we can hide the code
somewhere?
I don't think the answer's
gonna be in a book.
- Tah-dah.
- Great, now she thinks she's
Houdini.-
- Open it.
The cards are numbered, two
through 10, with four suits.
Right?
- Zoe, it's now not really
the time for strip poker.
- Two through 10 can be our base
numbers.
Jacks, queens, kings, and
aces are mathematical symbols,
and the equation can be laid
out in sequence of suit.
We just need to come up
with another equation that
equals 1680.
- Sure.
- And the cards can be taped
to the bottom of the chairs
in the theater, and it'll be
like a scavenger hunt, too.
And the seat number on the
ticket
can be the first clue
of the scavenger hunt.
- Yeah, yeah, perfect.
Right, yeah?
Okay, good.
Let's go, come.
- Hey, we have your idea, open
up.
- Yes, great.
Okay.
Where is she?
- No idea.
- Well, we don't have time.
Come on.
- No, I'm going to call her.
- No, no, no, Alex, come one.
No, let's just take this.
- Yeah, I'm not gettin' on that,
thanks.
Look she's gonna answer,
I promise you, I swear.
- Can you ride a bike?
- Yeah, I can ride a bike, it's
just,
I haven't in a long time.
- You can't.
Oh, this is so good.
Okay.
- It's ringing, it's ringing.
- Alex, just get on the back.
- She's gonna answer.
- You know you don't have time
to wait, she's not answering.
- No, it takes her a while.
- We don't have that much time.
Do you want to be late?
Come on.
- It's still ringing, she's
gonna answer the phone.
- Oh man, you are scared, you
are scared.
- I'm not scared.
- Yeah, you are.
It's fine, you're scared.
- There you go.
- Will you get on?
- I'm getting on.
- All right, here we go.
- Okay.
Whoa, okay.
You'll be fine.
This is really not fun.
We're gonna make it,
don't worry.
Oh, the bike
doesn't sound too healthy.
I'm too scared to look down at
my watch,
but I really shouldn't have
enough time.
We're running late
- We're fine, we're going
as fast as we can.
Do you wanna drive?
No, I really don't
wanna drive.
- How much do you weigh?
- I don't weigh that much.
That was my knee.
- Stop complaining.
- Okay, here we go, nice and
easy.
- Ooo, I know a shortcut.
- What?
Oh, my God, it's going so fast.
Tree.
Okay, anywhere around here,
stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Okay.
- Got it.
How you doing?
- Yeah, great.
Never again.
That's why I don't get on bikes.
You're welcome, by the
way.
Yes, for hurting me.
- Hey, slow down.
- Now's really not the time to
slow down.
This is it.
- Okay.
- Four, five, six.
- Ah.
Looks familiar.
- Yeah, just like the good old
days, huh?
- Mmhmm.
- So, who's this mystery couple?
- Actually it's a friend, I
guess.
- Oh, first date?
- Yeah, we've been with
her talking for ages.
- Mmm.
Who'd put their faith in you?
- I mean, it's obviously
working.
- Mr. Porter?
Miss.
- Is that?
- Yes, it is.
- Oh, you look handsome.
- Thank you, Miss.
- Zoe.
- So, who's the lucky lady?
- Oh, just someone from my old
work.
From my corporate days.
- Oh, that's exciting.
- I'm a little nervous.
- Oh, don't worry, it can't
go worse than it did with me.
- Thanks, just standing here.
Escott, everything's gonna be
fine.
I made it very easy.
Just remember, be a gentleman,
and treat her like a lady.
- Got it.
- Wow.
I wish you would have applied
some of that good advice to
yourself.
Oh, burn.
Yeah, like do what I say, not
what I do?
That's what I should listen to.
Right?
- Yeah.
- Right, be a gentleman, be a
lady.
Treat her like a lady.
Yes, got it, thank you, Mr.
Porter.
Zoe.
- Well, okay, chop chop,
she's waiting for you.
- Oh.
- Escott.
No weapons tonight.
- Oh, no, no, I returned the
taser.
It is way too dangerous.
- Yeah.
- I got an Airsoft pistol
instead, so I can stay protected
on the job, and do
paintball in my free time.
Double whammy.
- This should be interesting.
- Yeah, very interesting.
Okay.
- Let's go.
- Yeah, we should go.
Yeah, yeah, we should go, okay.
- Good luck tonight.
- Thank you, Miss Zoe.
- So the trick is to take the
suction cup.
- Mmhmm.
There we go.
Hold the letter, and then, place
it
where you want it to go, just
like that.
And then, the trick is, with
a little twist of your wrist,
lift the letter off the suction
cup.
- Yeah, it looks easy.
Here, give me the stick.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- There you go.
- So you--
- Take it there.
- Grab the letter.
Okay, got it.
- That's it, that's it.
- And then,
- And then hopefully place it.
- Like that?
- Yeah, yeah.
- It's not sticking.
- That's it, no, no.
- Just finesse, just with the
wrist.
- Like that?
- Like a slight turn here,
just a slight turn.
- Perfect.
Could have done it myself, you
know.
- Yes, you could have, for sure.
- We should get going,
she'll be here soon.
- Yeah.
- No, no, no, this can't be
happening.
- Oh.
- Can't be happening.
- Looking for this?
- How?
- You know, Escott is a really
great guy,
but he is a terrible security
guard.
- You're amazing.
Come, come on.
- Okay.
Okay, here we go.
- Yeah.
- Here we are, in the theater.
- The theater.
- So, we're looking for 15, 14.
- Oh.
- Oh, after you.
- Oh, well, thank you.
- Yeah, okay.
What does the next card say?
- A movie you want to see,
jack and queen you got to be.
- Exclamation point.
- Mmhmm.
- It's never gonna work.
Jack and queen you
got to be.
- Who thought up of
this crazy idea, anyway?
- Oh, my new boss.
Yeah, he's a very great man.
Very wise and gentle.
I mean, not gentle, per se.
- What is he even talking about.
- Oh, yeah.
And you're happier here than
when you were
sitting behind the desk?
- Oh.
- That is true, yeah, I confess.
And then,
- Yeah.
- Well, your new boss is very
creative.
- Okay, maybe it wasn't the best
idea,
but, you know, I'm just
a literary specialist.
- I told you.
Maybe we should give
him a hint or something?
- And I caught him when he was
trying
this whole thing out with
Miss Zoe the firs time.
So, like, oops, my bad.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Wow, so, you're telling me,
that if we're here tonight,
it's a little bit because of
you.
- We could definitely say that.
It's a little bit because of me.
- Well, back to work.
- Right.
- Yeah.
- Okay, I don't know where.
- Wait.
- Oh.
Jackpot.
- Oh, yeah.
- What?
- The name is Scott.
Escott.
- Boom.
- I can't believe it.
- So, Escott.
- Okay.
- What do we do with these cards
now?
- I don't know.
Jack of spades, queen of
hearts, ace of diamonds.
- Hey, what movie are we
gonna see tonight, anyway?
- Oh no, I can't say that, it's
a secret.
- Come on.
- No.
- Come on, am I gonna like it?
- Well, okay, it's this
wonderful movie.
It's about an elder man who
starts a new job, and he
- Falls for the massage
therapist?
- I love that movie.
- Yeah.
- When do we actually see it?
- I dunno.
It's kind of a new concept.
Maybe they're working out the
kinks.
- Why have they stopped?
- I dunno, maybe they're stuck?
- Jack of spades, queen of
hearts, ace of diamonds.
Wait a minute.
Look.
Your under seat.
Oh.
Under your seat.
So.
- Oh.
Oh.
- You're a genius.
No, honestly, that's amazing.
- You know, people are pretty
intelligent,
if you give them the benefit of
the doubt.
Don't worry, you'll get there
someday, if you work at it.
Thank you.
So, what's next?
- Well, the movie is
about an hour and a half.
So, that gives you some
time to surprise me.
- Do you think they forgot about
us?
- Now, that's good popcorn.
- Oh, it's always better
when you make it yourself.
- You know, I'm actually not
this easy.
- Yeah, right.
- No, no, to be honest,
I actually wanted to show you my
new film.
- Please, don't.
- No, it's really good, I
promise you.
It's about the guys who
live in the dope walk.
You know, traffic lights.
- Mmhmm.
- The big bread hand, and his
friend, the little white guy.
Oh, do you what you want.
- No more festival films.
- Not even at least one a month?
- Year.
- Year?
I'm a film connoisseur.
It's my work.
- We're ready, okay.
You can start the movie now.
Thanks.
And now, for
our feature presentation.
Go low, deep voice, manly.
- Now that you have this new
concept,
you'll probably need a project
manager.
- Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
Do you have any ideas?
- I know a girl.
- Okay.
- And her first mission
as project manager,
is to pick a better film.
- Oh.
Yeah, yeah.
I actually watched one the
other day, it's really good.
The Girl with the Invisible
Violin.
- Oh, really?
- Really good.
- Missed that one.
- You should see it.
Yeah, it has a really strong
female lead.
- She sounds great.
- Yeah, very great.
Lot of depth, lot of conviction.
- Mmm.
- Her violin playing, a
little left to be desired.
But, you know.
- I'll have to see it.
- Yeah.
It's great.
- Sounds like my kind of film.
- I think you'd like it.
Super charming.
- Witty?
- Very.
- Hilarious, probably.
- A laugh aloud caper.
I love a bit of fake violins.
Who doesn't, really?
Fake Yo-Yo Ma.
Sounds quirky.
Fake Bach.
Fun.
Fake Mozart.
Charming.
Know any other
violinists?