Justice.
Justice!
Who are you to speak
of justice?
All of you out there.
Staring at me as if
I were an inhuman monster
A grotesque beast.
You there, smugged
and self-satisfied
Now that I've been captured.
You will learn
of true justice.
And you will get it.
[Speaking in foreignlanguage]
Even now, at this moment
While I stand here
Forced to perform
in your circus
Your travesty of a trial.
We are rising again.
Once more, growing
in strength in Germany
In Argentina
In America.
You will put me to death.
But you will stop nothing.
Hang me, but watch.
As you spring the trap
on the gallows
Look at my dangling feet
and you will them dancing
Above the millions
I've sent to their graves!
Heil Hitler!
[Dramatic music]
(David narrating)
My name is David.
I'm one of the survivors
of the hell and holocaust
That was Nazism.
These memorials will
stand for all time
In memory of its victims.
Even now, so many years later,
I still must remind myself
That Adolf Eichmann
was not only a beast
And grotesque monster
But the final end product
of a political process.
Eichmann was a Nazi.
An important incident in the
career of Adolf Eichmann
Was a secret meeting
called by him
At SS headquarters
in 1941
During the early days
of the war.
- Good to see you.
- How do you do?
- How are you?
The news is good,
gentlemen... very good.
Ja, we can anticipate the fall
of Moscow in a couple of days.
Today Russia.
Tomorrow the world.
(All)
Heil Hitler.
Hoss, good to see you.
Manz.
Felsner.
Captain.
Ah, Kessner.
How are you, sir?
That's a beautiful ring
you are wearing, Captain.
A token of appreciation.
Someone who's suffering, you put
to a miserable end, no doubt.
[All chuckle]
Perhaps you think a jewel
cannot be contaminated
Since there is no blood
in a stone.
Please be seated, gentlemen.
I would not have called you
from your duties
Which you're performing
so efficiently
In your respective camps
were it not for
A matter of
the greatest urgency.
The continuing victories
of our armies
Bring us not only
greater glory
But greater challenges.
As our armies penetrate
deeper and deeper
Into enemy territory,
where food supplies
Are being destroyed
before we can capture them
We face the possibility
of great shortages.
We've found a solution
to this problem.
One which is in
complete harmony
With a long
established goal.
Gentlemen, I have been
honored by the Fuhrer
With the responsibility
for our supreme task.
The final solution
of the Jewish problem.
Colonel,
if you don't mind...
The Arithmetic
is quite elementary.
Within our area
of protection in Europe today
There are over
six million Jews.
The food they now consume
will feed our army
And the workers
in our factories.
It is our task
to bring that food
To those who require it
in the shortest passage of time.
Six million
to be eliminated?
At once?
But it is impossible.
We couldn't even handle so much
beef in slaughter houses.
It's a problem of transportation
Not only here in Germany
But in Romania, in Hungary
'In-in Poland, in Russia.'
We could use machine guns,
line up hundreds at a time.
Think about man power
to bury them.
Not to speak
of the ammunition.
It'll take years..
The war would be over...
Gentlemen, gentlemen, I did not
summon you here to advise me.
You will recall,
I said that the solution
To this problem
was put into my hands.
What I expect from you
is not wisdom.
But complete loyalty,
efficiency
And absolute secrecy
in carrying out my orders.
Transportation plans
for the operation
Have already been completed.
As you can see, Col. Hoss
Auschwitz is ideally located.
Rail roads converge form
all strategic areas.
Czechoslovakia
Hungary
Romania.
We will also develop facilities
for extermination
In Dachau, Bergen-Belsen,
Buchenwald.
Our first experiments will
take place at Auschwitz.
It is a question
of man power, Colonel.
At the present
we are eliminating
An average of 50 enemies
of the state daily.
We already have
a shortage of labor.
Within a week, we will eliminate
ten, twenty times that number.
Within a month
ten times that number.
Gentlemen,
time is of the essence.
I plan to conclude
this task within two years.
You mean three million
a year?
Our goal is victory,
nothing can impede us.
- With due respect, Colonel...
- It will be done!
We will eliminate thousands
with less expenditure
Of material, or manpower,
that it now takes for hundreds.
You will receive precise
instructions
Upon the completion
of our first experiments.
Hoss, I will accompany you
to Auschwitz.
That will be all, gentlemen.
Heil Hitler.
Pardon me.
But to attach a shower head
to pipe with no water
Seems a bit peculiar,
nicht?
It is so indicated
on the blue prints
Without explanatory
footnotes for workmen.
How much longer,
until you're ready?
- One hour, maybe.
- Good.
Zyklon B. But that
is a disinfectant
To kill roaches and rats.
'A gas to fumigate.'
(David narrating)
It was my 14th birthday.
For more than a year
I'd been at Auschwitz
Each day from dawn
until dark
I worked on the cleanup gang.
It would be a day to remember.
[Melancholic music]
[Speaking German]
Bigiano spoke a language
I couldn't understand.
But even without words
he taught me
How to hide my hatred
To keep the flame of hope
for freedom alive.
[Melancholic music continues]
Unload the cargo.
[Speaking German]
There was nothing unusual
about the arrival
Of another truckload
of prisoners.
But why were
the high officials here?
Who is that officer
giving orders to Hoss
The commander of the camp?
It was my father and mother.
We'd been separated
for more than a year.
I thought
I'd never see them again.
David!
[Speaking German]
Attention!
Welcome to Auschwitz.
You have become inmates
of a model camp
For efficiency and cleanliness.
'It our intention
to keep it clean'
'And free from
the lice and vermin'
'You have brought here
on yourselves.'
You have 15 minutes in which
to take showers in there.
"'And clean yourself thoroughly"
After that living quarters
will be assigned to you..
And then jobs.
At Auschwitz, everyone works.
'Quick now.
Into the shower.'
Quickly.
[Melancholic music]
[Motor chugging]
[Suspenseful music]
Mama, it smells like peaches.
[Screaming]
[All screaming]
[Coughing vigorously]
[Screaming and shouting]
[Melancholic music]
[Sobbing]
It was a day..
To remember.
Aren't they perfect, Adolf?
Aren't they just perfect?
(Hoss)
Now, don't be so modest.
[All laugh]
Just like their mother
A beautiful bloom
of the third Reich.
You know, Tessa,
in your charming home
Time passes much too swiftly.
Oh, thank you, Adolf.
- A little more, Colonel?
- Yes, thank you.
Tessa, please.
Ah, Lisa.
You know, Colonel.
There is a new program.
One element
which is genius.
- Shear genius.
- Yes, what is that?
It is humane.
Yes, the victim anticipates
nothing. On the contrary...
No no no.
I mean, that I'm talking
about the humanity..
To our man, the SS.
(Hoss)
'After all, it is not easy
day after day personally'
'To eliminate not only man,
but women and children.'
Eventually, it might
affect their morale.
- Yes.
- But this way, it is unseen.
What you do not see,
you do not know.
[Rudolf and Tessa giggle]
Unseen. And clean.
Cleaners.
I admire cleanliness.
- It's perhaps a whim of mine.
- Oh, it's a virtue, Adolf.
Thank you.
- Prosit.
Finish your dinner children
[Band music]
[Phone buzzing]
Yes.
Ah, Felsner.
Yes, put him on.
And see if you can get through
to my wife again.
Good morning, Felsner.
I have studied your report
very carefully.
A most unpleasant surprise,
Felsner
That you're production is down
over 15% for the month.
Felsner, you have
a quota to fill.
This is no time to relax.
Perhaps in Berlin there is
relaxation, Herr Colonel.
Here at Dachau,
we have no theaters
No actresses
for cultural activities.
Have I heard you correctly,
Captain?
'Do you wish me to repeat,
Herr Colonel?'
Here at Dachau
there is no relaxation.
The reports indicate
that over 15% did not reach
The destination
that we have assigned them.
- 'Perhaps you could explain.'
- Certainly.
As each train load arrives
A medical examiner
from the labor ministry
Selects the healthiest personals
and takes them away
To the munitions factories.
Men and women.
Every day.
They are to select laborers
from the prisoners of war
Not from the Jews.
The plan has been approved
by Herr Himmler.
I want an appointment.
Reichsführer-SS Himmler.
At his earliest convenience.
(Male on intercom)
'Yes, Colonel.'
'Frau Eichmann is on the
telephone from Munich.'
Munich? Put her on.
Hello, Melissa?
I've been trying to reach you
for the last three days.
The children, are they alright?
Good.
No, no. You cannot come
to Berlin.
We have air raids every day
And the bomb shelters are not
adequate, except for officials.
Yes. Yes I will come and visit
you at my earliest opportunity.
Goodbye.
[Female singing in German]
Russians cannot hold out
much longer Stalingrad.
Day by day, we decimate them.
Any hour now, you can expect
to hear of victory.
And then, Adolf?
Another jewel added to your
string of victories.
While poor Anna is yet to see
her first pearl
From all this glory.
You're like all these others,
aren't you?
I cannot wear a
necklace of victories
As you wear you medals.
For me there are
only two goals.
Victory..
And love.
To achieve victory, you bring
food to our soldiers, Ja?
To keep love alive
you must nourish it also.
But not with jewels, Anna.
That would be corrupt.
Oh, Adolf.
How could it be?
Look at all these women
with their
Beautiful diamonds
and emeralds.
Where do you suppose
they got them?
Heaven?
That is illegal.
How could it be?
Adolf, the previous owners
of these jewels
Are no longer interested
in legality.
Anna,
let me tell you something.
Today when you take one penny..
You take it from
the Fuhrer.
You take it the Third Reich.
Yes, Lieutenant?
The Reichsführer will see you.
The car is waiting, Colonel.
Thank you.
Adolf... victory
without fruits is like
A bag with a big hole
in the bottom.
Hmm.
I better forget
what you just said.
How can I level acquisitions
at such youth, such beauty.
You'll wait for me, hm?
[Dramatic music]
- Heil Hitler.
I anticipate you, Adolf
Herr Reichsführer, it is about
the Ministry of Labor
Arbitrarily taking
prisoners for workers.
I said,
I anticipate you, Adolf.
But, we have
another problem.
We've just received some news.
It is so bad that Herr Goebbels
Has not yet figured out
how to release it.
We've just had a word that our
armies before Stalingrad
Has been routed.
That is impossible!
Decimated.
Destroyed.
Ragged remnants
retreating in panic.
We've lost over a half a million
men with their equipment.
It could mean,
that we'll lose the war.
No!
I said, "it could".
Then, Reichsführer,
we must fight a defensive war
From now until victory.
We shall put the enemy on his
knees on our own soil.
Or he will bring us
to our knees.
Since either is possible,
we must change immediately
Our policy for the final
solution of the Jewish problem.
You mean, discontinue?
On the contrary.
But it is imperative
that every trace
Of our activities is removed
Not one shred of evidence
must be found.
Herr Reichsführer we could ask
the Ministry of Agriculture
To plant thousands of trees
above the graves.
[Scoffs]
Skeletons can be exhumed,
they can be evidence.
But not ashes.
Ovens, crematorium.
All traces removed against
the remote possibility..
Of defeat.
We must still device some method
for concealing the mass graves.
All graves will be opened, and
the remains will be cremated.
Good. Even brilliant, Eichmann.
Construction must
start immediately.
But to exhume over a million
corpses, Herr Eichmann
'Where will we get a labor force
of such magnitude?'
Naturally, the work will be done
by the new arrivals.
Precisely, Herr Reichsführer
Oh.
Will you join me, Adolf?
There is no hot food,
the last air raid damaged
Our ventilation system.
I should be delighted,
Herr Reichsführer.
Thank you.
To the Fuhrer.
Uh, Heil Hitler.
[Phone buzzing]
Hello.
Goebbels?
Eichmann here, Auschwitz.
Goebbels, oven 3 has been out
of commission for three days.
Yes, yes, but the train on which
replacement parts were shipped
Was destroyed by enemy bombers.
It will be another week,
perhaps two.
My interest is in
Why the machinery breaks down
so frequently?
It's over used. All the camps
have been instructed
Not to run the ovens
more than 16 hours a day.
If engineering principles
are disregarded..
At Auschwitz at present
We're eliminating at the rate
of ten thousand a day.
This requires our ovens to be
working 24 hours a day, not 16.
Now don't tell me again
that it cannot be done.
Now, the question
of morale among our guards.
Now, how widespread, Hoss,
is this corruption that
Captain Galfas
has been caught?
Fear of defeat
is causing it.
Stealing from prisoners,
taking a bribe
Permitting two of them to
escape. These are the facts.
I regret to admit it.
We shall discourage
such temptation
Both among the SS men
and the prisoners.
[Dramatic music]
[Commanding in German]
Forward march.
Lieutenant.
Would you permit the insignia
of the SS to touch the ground?
Never, Herr Colonel.
Since Captain Galfas has already
besmirched it by his actions
I suggest that you retrieve it
before it is further smeared.
Colonel, the man feels
he should be given a pistol
To himself
to wipe out his dishonor.
After all,
it is an official tradition.
I am not interested in him
regaining his honor, Hoss.
But, to see to that those who
remain do not lose theirs.
Suicide is such
a private affair.
A public disgrace is
a much more efficient deterrent.
Please proceed.
Proceed!
Ready.
Load.
Aim.
[Speaking German]
I did nothing that
none of you have done.
My only crime is
that I was caught.
- Please!
- Fire!
[Gunfire]
Tessa.
Tessa! Tessa!
For goodness sakes, Rudolf, you
are frightening the children.
- What is it?
- When Eichmann was here..
You wear nothing
but this wedding ring.
Nothing of the other,
nothing but this wedding ring.
Oh, I'm not such a fool, Rudolf.
Stop trembling.
- Everything is safely hidden.
- Nothing is safe.
Tomorrow, I want you to
go to the country
To my brother for a few days.
Somewhere behind the barn.
You bury everything.
You understand, everything!
You think Eichmann
suspects you?
He suspects everybody.
You bury everything
we have deep, very deep.
- You understand?
- Alright, Rudolf.
The persistent attempt on the
part of prisoners
To corrupt guards
in this prison camp
Has not stopped
despite warnings.
Perhaps this new method
I'm about to introduce
Will prove more effective.
Among you there are two
representatives
From each barracks.
Bring forth
one from each barracks.
Guards.
You. And you.
[Speaking German]
Line them up over there.
(Eichmann)
'Here after, for each prisoner
who seeks to bribe, or corrupt'
A prison official,
there will be this reward.
[Gunfire]
Enemy troops advancing on
Auschwitz-Birkenau.
Three train rows of prisoners
in the yards for two days
Screaming loud enough to be
heard in London and Moscow.
You've shipped too many
to us to handle.
Two ovens are out
of commission.
Evacuate in three days.
In three days. And remove
all traces of all work.
That is impossible.
All freight trains in the yard
are to be re-routed at once.
Divide shipment
of prisoners between
Dachau, Bergen-Belsen
and Schrobenhausen.
These locations will remain
free to operate
For at least two weeks.
We must complete our work.
Get me the traffic manager.
Auschwitz rail-road terminal.
Transportation minister,
Berlin, please.
Dachau, prepare for
receiving emergency
Train loads of prisoners.
All shipments
are being re-routed.
You'll operate
your remaining two ovens
At maximum speed
for 72 hours.
The remaining ones will be
shipped to Dachau by trains.
No trains are available to us.
We'll use trucks, order trucks.
That was Stutzheim
we just passed.
Less than 100 kilometers now.
Would it disturb you, Herr
Colonel, if I turn on the
radio?
The news.
The news has been, uh..
Interesting. Yes, the news
has been interesting.
Yes, very interesting.
(Man on radio)
'Attention, all units.'
'Our troops are making an
orderly retreat'
'To create the conditions
for a smashing cover attack.'
'In the vicinity of Bellheim.'
Bellheim? Herr Colonel.
Colonel Eichmann.
'Attention. All traffic
along the highway'
'Travelling either direction'
'Is here by ordered
to turn back.'
'All traffic
is ordered to turn back.'
Back a kilometer,
we can make a turn.
- We can back up that far.
- Quiet.
Five or six kilometers ahead,
there is a secondary road
To the right. That will be
a safe route to Dachau.
It is too risky. It is insane
to take a chance like that.
What did you say?
[Dramatic music]
To call you insane
is a generosity.
I only take orders
to live, not to die.
[Gunshot]
You heard the news?
Six kilometers ahead
there is a turn off.
A safe road to the Dachau.
Stop.
It's impossible to go on.
We must abandon
the equipment.
Yes, the equipment.
But not the cargo.
The cargo has reached
it's final destination.
Understand?
[Speaking German]
(Male #1)
'Ready fire.'
[People screaming
and shouting]
[Screaming continues]
The secondary road.
There is still time.
[Melancholic music]
[Melancholic music continues]
Jacob. Sarah.
Jacob?
It's me, David.
[Baby crying]
There are others.
Stay here. Wait.
[Melancholic music]
(David narrating)
It was V-E day.
The day of victory in Europe
Came to a people
hungry for peace.
For the first time
in almost five years
The lights came on
again in London.
People celebrated and rejoiced
almost everywhere.
And everywhere they prayed.
Their hearts overflowing
with gratitude
With joy and hope.
But there were also
prayers from
Hearts overflowing
with sorrow.
With grief that
could not be contained.
[Singing in foreign language]
[Song continues]
(David narrating)
Some great Americans came.
They came, they saw
And they wept.
[Intense music]
[Knocks on door]
'Anna.'
Tch. Go away.
Whoever you are go away.
'It's me Anna.'
Adolf.
They said
you were dead.
No, you've gotta
get out of here.
I don't care where you go,
but you can't stay here.
I've had enough trouble. They'll
kill me if they find you here.
They won't find me.
Nobody can escape them.
I'm taking no any chances.
Are you so stupid? Can't you
see that I have escaped?
What you were followed?
No, no. You can't stay here.
If I tell you that I have
a fortune hidden away.
Enough to take you out of this
filth and rubble
To another country
Where you can live
in style and luxury
Will you still tell me
go away? Hmm?
You really have money?
Jewelry?
Gold?
Enough for a long time.
For both of us.
Well.
Thank God you got smart
before it was too late.
I have stolen nothing.
I've taken what is necessary
for the cause, not for myself.
Any self-respecting man
Could do no worse
under the circumstances.
I am not ashamed.
Ashamed?
Adolf, it's wonderful.
I love you for it.
Uh, you must be hungry.
There is no water.
No soap.
It is impossible for a person
to get clean anymore, Adolf.
It's terrible these days.
The people we know, our friends,
they're all being caught.
Ah! Far from everyone, Anna. You
have no idea how many've escaped
And they are right back
here in Germany
Working for the cause.
They'll help us.
- You think so?
- I know so.
Who knows better than I.
Who they are, where they are
And what they've done.
They'll be happy
to help me with passports
With important work,
in any country I choose.
I am a power, Anna.
How did you escape?
When you match intelligence
against stupidity
There is no contest.
I am not Adolf Eichmann.
My name is Hans Schmidt.
Private first class,
15th Infantry Division.
I have his papers,
his identification.
I'm in his uniform,
these rags and tatters.
Along with my
disillusioned comrades.
'We surrendered to these
stupid Americans.'
Comrade! Comrade! We wish only
peace, we meant no harm.
We are about common soldiers
forced by our superior officers
At gun point to fight.
We mean only peace, peace..
[Both laughing]
Oh, my SS number, 888653.
It's gone.
I cut it out with a knife.
I escaped from the American
prison camp at Leighton's Park.
Now, Han Schmidt, not
Adolf Eichmann is missing.
Adolf Eichmann is dead.
Everyone knows that.
His body was found
in his uniform
With all his identifications.
Yes, that is what
I read in the papers.
But why did Han Schmidt exchange
papers and uniform with you?
How could he object?
I found him lying dead in a
ditch for at least a week.
Hans was a true patriot.
[Anna laughing]
This is slop for pigs.
We had better
in the American prison camp.
They will pay
for their cruelty to us.
Someday, there will be justice.
There is justice already, Adolf.
If you have money.
Not only justice, but..
Fresh bread,
sausage, even wine.
Nothing, but the very best.
Occupation money.
They very best kind
of money.
Oh, Adolf,
life will be good again.
We will have food,
real food.
Real food, Anna.
(David narrating)
The land was rocky and arid.
Water was scarce,
the heat intense.
But for the first time in
2000 years, we had a homeland.
Israel.
From the Holocaust of Europe,
we'd come as decimated people.
Old and young,
sick and wounded.
Deeply scared
in body and heart
To build a nation.
In a few short years,
we left behind forever
Despair and hopelessness
that had been our heritage.
A new concept of life
had grown in Israel
With it's promise of peace
and freedom and dignity.
Yet, for some like myself.
Despite all the future
held for us
The wounds of childhood
would not heal.
For more than ten years,
we had been searching
For Eichmann in every
part of the world.
We were a group
of volunteers
Who had dedicated
our self to this search.
Eichmann had to be caught.
[Symphonic music]
[Bells clinging]
Senora?
I would like to have
this watch repaired.
Si, senora.
Will you please,
put your name down?
I think, it only
needs to be cleaned.
No, senora.
The spring's gone.
The main spring.
Could you please,
come back in a week?
Thank you.
Main spring, I think.
Wait, Sanchez.
- Yes?
- Look here.
[Dramatic music]
Senora Anna Krauss.
What do you think?
Hebrew.
I think, we'll be
interested in her husband.
[Speaking foreign language]
It's time to go, Anna.
Concert starts in 15 minutes.
Oh, Adolf,
concerts are so dull.
Yes, I know. You only care
about your bullfights.
Few pictures,
Senora, Senor?
- Lovely picture.
- No, gracias.
Few pictures?
It's not only
the bullfights, Adolf.
It is the spirit of people.
It does something to me.
You will be pleased
with the photographs.
[Symphonic music]
You were restless
tonight, Adolf.
Didn't you enjoy
the concert?
No. That woman
with the camera
I could not get her
out of my mind.
She tried to take
my picture, why?
To earn 20 pesetas,
what else?
It could be quite
different, you know.
They are looking for me,
they have never stopped.
(Anna)
'I've seen no one.'
Of course, not. You see
nothing, but your bullfights.
- I like them.
- Ha!
The bulls or the men
who fight them.
[Laughing]
Anna, is there nothing
in life for you but sensuality?
Have you no capacity
for music, books
The stimulation
of the intellect.
Keep away
from them, Anna.
If ever you let one of them
put his filthy hands on you, I..
Senor.
Sí, senor.
Senor, that girl who takes
pictures. Where can I find her?
That girl
with the camera?
Ah, sí.
I don't know, senor.
- She works here for you?
- Only tonight.
I've never seen before.
She paid me a percentage
of her earnings.
But she
did not do well.
And she will not return.
I do not think.
- Thank you.
- No mention, senor.
- Gracias, senor.
- Driver, lets go.
- Yes, I'm holding on.
- Adolf, what is it?
I'm calling
Kessner in Paris.
Anna, that woman.
I was right.
Hello.
Ah, Kessner.
Eichmann here in Madrid.
What's is the news about
my transfer to Kuwait?
Yes, Colonel, your suggestions
are being studied
With great interest.
I must leave here at once.
That isn't
possible, Colonel.
The Middle East
must become our
Center of operations.
That is clear.
'Now, how many months do these
idiots require for study?'
Colonel, they are
our leaders today.
No! Not so, Kessner.
They are lucky.
They weren't force to flee.
There's only one leader, today
Wherever I may be forced
to set up headquarters.
'Now, listen to me.
I want a passport, credentials'
And official business
connections arranged, at once.
Tell them
that is an order.
Adolf.
Must we go
to the Middle East?
Perhaps, you prefer hell.
[Knocking on the door]
- I'll get it.
Get it.
Hello, Sara.
Uri.
What are you doing
here at this time?
David, something
has come up.
Finally. At least,
I think so.
Here. This just
came from Spain.
[Intense music]
That's him.
I know him.
Are you sure?
I can see him at Auschwitz.
Can hear his voice.
I'll never forget
the moment when my mother was..
Millions..
Millions of mothers, David.
Where is he?
- In Madrid.
- Madrid?
A letter that came
with this photo.
A man who calls himself
Lopez, a refugee.
He wants to know
if we know who this man is
And he writes if we can
positively identify him
As a Nazi war criminal
He will be very happy
to have him assassinated.
How soon do you
want me to leave?
As soon as possible.
Jacob is going with you.
- Good.
- David.
Sara, I've been living
for this moment.
Sara.
This is a moment
of happiness.
Not one for fear.
Goodnight.
[Dramatic music]
I'm not a frightened
wife, David.
I've served with
our army for two years.
- I've learned to conquer fear.
- Sara.
I know you, Sara.
I love what I know.
You knew this day
would have to come for me.
Ten years ago, yes.
When we still lived
with that nightmare.
We have just begun
to live again, David.
We are building a new nation.
We are Israelis, now.
Your energy belongs
to the future.
Don't give it
to revenge and death.
I must go, Sara.
You can't repay murder
with more murder.
But we must
have justice.
Justice.
That's for humans, David.
This is beyond anything
any human ever knew.
The man has killed
six million people, David.
Men, women, children.
What justice is there
for a man like that?
What punishment
fit such a crime?
What will you do?
Have six million trials?
Six million executions?
Our ancient laws have changed.
'We don't want
an eye for an eye.'
'We are opposed
to vengeance.'
David, please.
Let's just be grateful,
let's thank God we are alive.
Sara, you're alive because,
that night in Germany
On that truck,
your father and mother
Covered you
with their own body.
David, please.
I don't wanna remember.
You must remember.
We must all remember.
Listen to me, Sara.
The stranger
who covered me.
The man who took
into his own body
The bullets that
were meant for me.
As he absorbed death
to give me life.
I saw his face.
The language
he spoke was foreign
But the words
he was trying to say
What his eyes were trying
so desperately to tell me
I understood.
Never forget this night.
Never let the world forget.
Sara.
I must go.
My love goes with you.
[Doorbell ringing]
- Benjamin Lopez?
- Yes.
Please, come in,
gentlemen.
This way.
This is Senor Sanchez.
- How do you do?
- Good evening.
My name is David.
This is my co-worker, Jacob.
- Glad to know you.
- How do you do?
Please, sit down
I'll get some wine.
Why did you come from Paris?
What is wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing, that I know of.
I was told to come only
to urge the greatest caution.
Everything is arranged
for you in the Middle East.
You've been so slow.
It is almost too late.
I've been followed now
for two weeks. Anna, too.
Everything is in here.
Your passport,
your ticket to Kuwait.
- Am I not going, too?
- You will come later.
But why Kuwait?
It's an important island
on the Persian Gulf.
It's perfect
from every point of view.
Kessner, what about
my flight time?
Tomorrow morning at 8.30.
That is if the plane is on time.
(Eichmann)
'Anna.'
'You go to the airport now.'
They will follow you.
That's good.
'Now, in a clear voice,
loud enough to be heard'
'Ask for a flight
to Rio De Janeiro.'
'Then order two tickets
for the day after tomorrow.'
Tell them you'll pick up the
tickets tomorrow afternoon.
They will watch
for that plane.
Go, Anna.
- That is excellent.
- Of course.
Now, order a taxi for Anna.
Well, it's
our hope with..
With careful preparation
To get him out of your harbor
on one of your fishing boats.
From there we will be able to
transfer him into our boat.
The entire operation
should take exactly one week.
Señores.
Why take him to the middle of
the Mediterranean to kill him?
When we can do it
magnificamente, right here.
Señor Sanchez.
We don't want
to kill him.
Ah, I see.
You want perhaps,
to give him the Nobel Prize?
'You think, death
is too great a penalty?'
No sir.
Not great enough.
[Phone ringing]
- Yes?
- We have waited too long.
- I am going to pick her up.
- Listen, Juanito.
No, Juanito.
Do not touch her.
Juanito.
That fool.
'Eichmann's woman reserved
two tickets on a plane.'
- "'They're leaving in two days"
- Oh, no. They will not.
Sanchez, you don't understand.
We need him alive.
We are not assassins.
But we can't
let him get away.
If we must have a trial,
we'll give it to him here.
Jacob, we are not assassins.
We are judge,
and he is guilty.
There is nothing
you can do.
Be assured.
We are judges of high quality.
Let us go.
We must wait for Juanito.
Then, we will go.
No, David.
I'm glad.
His day has come at last.
It is straight, amigo.
Come, let's drink
to ourselves.
May we prove to be
as efficient executioners
As we are honorable judges.
What is keeping her?
Two hours.
She should have
been back before now.
It is not two hours, Eichmann.
It is not yet
an hour and a half.
Even if they follow me
to the airport tomorrow.
They'll think that
I'm picking up my tickets.
I'll be on that plane
before they know it.
They'll never know
where I got off.
Oh, never, never,
you'll be absolutely safe.
I'm not interested
in safety.
It's important that I live only
to do the work for our party.
Oh, that is exactly
what I meant, Eichmann.
Now, if that foolish
woman would only hurry.
- You are stupid, Juanito.
- Why?
- We do not want the woman.
- But we had to have her.
We needed these keys
to get into his house.
I could not take them
from her and then let her go.
And now, can you let her go?
Will you be her judge
and executioner, too?
Let us go.
He would begin to suspect
when she doesn't come home.
Jacob?
David, there
is no other way.
It has taken us more
than ten years.
- To fail.
- Fail?
Jacob, if we kill him,
we failed.
You will.
Not I.
[Dramatic music]
[Phone ringing]
Yes.
Anna?
Adolf, they have
my keys to the house.
Get the police.
Protect yourself.
They would be
there any minute.
Why did you do this?
Never mind that.
Get out of here, quickly,
before they come back.
Quickly!
[Dramatic music]
All those years
of searching.
Months of planning, raising
money from friends, all gone.
Because of him,
a betrayer.
We were under orders
not to kill.
We were not under orders
to help him escape.
'We were not under orders
to be informants.'
To notify him,
so he'd call the police.
Jacob, we're
not murderers.
Sara, David did not
have to kill him.
There were others of us who did
not share his delicate feelings.
He had no moral right to prevent
others from doing what is right.
Alright. Suppose,
we had killed him.
The newspaper here would have
carried an item this big.
This big. Announcing the
mysterious murder
Of an unknown foreigner.
Not Adolf Eichmann.
An unknown foreigner
named Krauss. Krauss.
What would
we've accomplished?
We could let the world know
he was really Eichmann.
And would they have
necessarily believed us?
I say, that if we kill this man
without due process of law
The world will brand
us as murderers.
We will bring him to trial.
Never worry.
We'll never get him.
We've chased him to Kuwait.
He plans to make
the Middle East
The center of
a new empire of murder.
With Israel,
the first victim.
By letting him live,
you are his accomplice
In future murders.
You.
- We'll run him out.
- You'll run him out?
Out of a country
you can't even get into?
[Instrumental music]
In the two years
that followed
Contributions came
from all over the world.
Only vast sums of money could
move Eichmann out of Kuwait.
Now, we had it.
We were ready.
[Instrumental music]
It was decided that
Jacob and I would go.
Our differences
were long forgotten.
Patient and painstaking work
had gone into our preparations
For this moment.
And we believed we'd found
An answer
in Eichmann's early history.
We were going to bring it
back. Now. To haunt him.
Our passports were good.
But we didn't have much time.
The ship would only be
in port 48 hours.
No, no, there is no need
to be apprehensive.
Your shipment of cars has left
Germany over a month ago.
Yes, I can assure you.
My gratitude will be expressed
In a most
substantial fashion.
Thank you.
Hakim Benahmed
is here to see you.
- The police?
- He said it was urgent.
- Urgent?
- Hmm.
Show him in.
Ah, my dear Hakim Benahmed.
What an unexpected pleasure.
Won't you join me
in some coffee?
- No, thank you.
- Sit down, won't you?
No, thank you.
Well, now, let's see. You were
here last, about a month ago.
I didn't expect to see you
again for another week.
Herr Brunner, I'm here
to protect your life.
If necessary,
with my own.
My life?
You're in great jeopardy,
Herr Brunner.
I don't understand.
An official in my department
has received evidence
That you are
an agent of Israel.
'A Jew.'
I? That's preposterous.
Such information could...
It's not information,
but evidence.
Nonsense.
That's outrageous.
Your dossier indicates
you speak Yiddish and Hebrew.
You lived in that, uh,
obscene country.
Yes, yes, yes.
But that was years ago.
It was then, Palestine.
I was a German agent for the
National Socialist Government.
I know that..
Herr Eichmann.
That is why I wish,
to save your life.
The report
branded you as a Jew.
It's already known
by many people.
Too many.
As a Jew..
'...you will be
assassinated in 24 hours.'
I represent three of
the largest German industries.
They will defend
their representatives, here.
- Get in touch with them!
- I have.
I've cabled to ask
if they knew you were a Jew.
They have not replied.
I'll have a passport and get you
away safely in 24 hours.
You are thinking, perhaps,
if you revealed yourself
To be Eichmann..
'...you would not
remain alive very long.'
There would be
a high price on your head.
My people,
well... to my regret
We have many
impoverished people..
To whom money
is greater value than life.
That is when
the lives are not their own.
But be at peace, Eichmann.
I will protect you
as if your life were my own.
Until, you're
on the plane.
[Dramatic music]
At last, we had given him
the taste of terror.
That cold sweat
of his own fear.
Eichmann was on his way
to South America.
Buenos Aires.
From now on there wouldn't be a
moment for him without fear.
Our plan was to keep him
within reach
Until, we were ready
to take him.
You received my cable.
That's good.
What has happened to you?
What has not happened?
I did not think I would
ever be glad to see you again.
But I am.
Come, Anna.
You live here?
You do not
have to stay.
That's not
what I meant.
In your letters, you never
said anything about why you came
To South America
in the first place.
They would not let me
back into Germany.
But I have a job,
I get by.
Once I am settled, we'll move
into a more befitting place.
But first, I must telephone
Senor Santez.
He's in charge here
of everything.
You don't have to, Adolf.
He's on his way here to see you.
How could that be?
As you said, "He's in charge
of everything here."
I told him
you were coming.
You know him?
[Knocking on the door]
You know him also.
Adolf, be careful.
They're angry with you.
[Eichman laughing]
Kessner.
When Anna told me
that you were coming
I cabled immediately
to Europe for instructions.
You've made a mess
of things, Adolf.
You better explain.
You let the Jews,
run you out of Kuwait.
(Eichmann)
'That is not true.'
There was an attempt
on my life and I was caught.
You were caught...
by fear!
No. There's been
a tragic mix up
And I shall write
an explanation.
By all means.
Give me your communication
and I shall forward...
No, no, no.
Your fear has forced
headquarters to change
Their address. So... now
we understand each other.
They have instructed me
to get a job for you.
Inconspicuous, modest.
Out of public sight.
'You're to refrain from all
organizational activities.'
As long as you obey orders,
you will be safe.
You will hear from me
about the job through Anna.
Little Kessner here
in Argentina giving me orders!
I must find out
the new address of headquarters.
Why, Adolf?
Why?
Can't you forget the past
and all the glory?
You could stop running.
We could live.
They would give you a job.
Nobody would know you.
No!
I will never tolerate that.
I am the leader of the movement.
The movement?
Adolf, the movement
is in other hands.
- Your day is over.
- Never.
They will learn that Eichmann
cannot be disposed off easily.
I don't
want you caught.
You're afraid
to have me here?
[Dramatic music]
Adolf, for so long
I have been afraid.
I'm tired now.
I want to know
which is worse.
Fear or loneliness.
What's the job?
The last few months have been
busy with personal matters.
The menial job does not
bother me anymore.
There was an interesting item
in the newspaper.
- So?
- This anniversary here.
This would be an International
Industrial Agricultural fair.
Delegation from Israel
is coming.
And Kessner is worried
that there may be agents
Among the delegation, hmm?
Kessner is worried
about many things.
He also would like to see you.
Come on over.
You're letting vanity and false
pride lead you into trouble.
I am grateful for the concern
you show about my welfare.
Serious charges
have been made against you.
In the factory,
at social gatherings
You're talking
carelessly, dangerously.
You give me
the address of headquarters.
I want to communicate
with them directly.
Despite my instructions
and then my warnings
You have written to Von Mayers
in Egypt, to Kretel and Mario.
'Your letters have been
turned over to headquarters.'
'Many people are demanding
that the strictest measures'
'Be taken against you.'
I will stop when you give me
the new address of headquarters.
You're endangering
the entire organization.
Not I.
It is you.
You cannot take away
my proper position.
You've heard of this delegation
of Jews arriving here?
There would be
agents amongst them.
They will get you, Eichmann.
Hitler and Himmler
entrusted me
Only me, with the final solution
of the Jewish problem.
Ah, only you.
After Himmler
and Bormann, I came next.
I am now the new leader above
everyone else at headquarters.
You, sitting there in my seat,
behind my desk.
You cannot gag me
with threats of strict measures.
(Eichman over recorder)
'Wherever I am, there
are the brains, the power.'
'Only I can rebuild
the organization.'
'Our National
Socialist power.'
'Now, you tell them, if I go
down, it will not be alone.'
"'All of you here and those
in Egypt, in the United States"
'And those
who had it easy so long'
'Secure and well protected.'
'If I go, I will take
them all down with me.'
Gentlemen, I think,
it's clear what must be done.
Anna.
Anna, they're here.
The Israel delegation, by plane.
They're after me.
Adolf, they're
not after you.
Now, will try
to get some rest?
We're safe. We're safe.
Kessner will deliver my message.
I still have power. Power.
What message?
What are you talking about?
Blackmail?
That's the only language
they understand.
They're degenerate.
They're corrupt.
But I'll fix them.
They'll never find me.
They'll never find..
'I'm not afraid of them.
I'll fix them.'
[Dramatic music]
[Door opening]
[Music continues]
[Softly]
Adolf.
Adolf!
The Star of David.
What did you expect?
We'll dump him
on the steps of the synagogue.
Klaus!
Little Kessner is trying
to make the world believe
That the Jews
killed me, hmm.
[Doorbell ringing]
Klaus?
[Intense music]
The routine never varies.
He takes the bus here
every morning to the factory.
Here, and every night after
work, he returns back here.
What does he do
with his nights?
He stays in the house.
Never goes out.
From the empty bottles
we find in his trash can
He probably,
drinks himself to sleep.
We'll have no trouble
picking him up.
Good.
[Phone ringing]
Yes?
Speaking.
I see.
Alright, stick with him.
We'll get word to you.
Well, he didn't go
to the factory today.
They've traced him to
the house of a German here
Who goes by
the name of Santos.
Oh, what are we
waiting for?
I've sent your
message to Europe.
They apologized for their
underestimation of you.
And I too,
of course.
After all, little Kessner
is only a messenger boy.
I think, you'll be pleased
with their decision.
They've decided
to appoint you
General Co-coordinator
of all North American affairs.
Your headquarters
will be in Mexico City.
Here's your ticket
and your new passport.
You'll leave at once.
- I will need some money.
- Everything has been arranged.
You will be met at
the plane by Señor Valdez.
Is that all?
- Good luck.
- Oh, Kessner.
It's too bad
about Klaus.
'I'm sure that
you'll miss him.'
Don't underestimate
the enemy.
You're right.
In order to avoid
underestimating the enemy
One must know him.
It shall
never happen again.
That's comforting.
After you're settled,
arrangements will be made
For Anna to join you.
Oh, such kindness.
I'm sure
you will enjoy Mexico City.
Good luck.
Hans.
Follow him.
His ticket is for Flight-321
Leaving for Mexico City,
tonight at 7:10.
He's no fool.
He may suspect.
If he does not
get on that plane
We will be forced
to eliminate him here.
Anyway, do not let him
out of your sight.
They think, I am an imbecile
who can be fooled like a child.
But why to Mexico City?
Not Mexico City, Anna.
Hell.
Their method, tricking a victim
to his unsuspecting doom.
[Laughing]
They forget, it is I,
who invented such methods.
So, what is their plan?
I'm to be met by one,
Señor Valdez at the airport.
He's to drive me away.
Drive me where?
Mexico is one of our graveyards.
A graveyard without a headstone.
And then, where will you go?
To Europe.
I have no other choice.
I must tell them what Kessner
is trying to do to me.
- To all the others.
- But, Adolf.
You'll hear from me
When I'm back in power,
where I belong.
[Dramatic music]
[Music continues]
[Speaking Spanish]
Pleasant journey.
Cancel this flight, please.
Instead, I must go
to Europe. Immediately.
Spain or Portugal.
Do you have anything leaving
before 7 o'clock this evening?
- I'll see what I can do, sir.
- Thank you.
Can I have a reservation
for this afternoon to Madrid?
Yeah.
Yes, thank you.
Yes, I have space for one.
Flight 6,
5:30 this afternoon, to Madrid.
I'll take it.
Uh, sir, your flight
to Mexico City is tourist class.
'The one to Madrid
is first class.'
Oh, that's alright.
How much is the difference?
Uh, 23,406 Pesos.
Twenty three thousand..
Oh, oh, I'm afraid, I..
Here take this
and reserve the seat.
I will be back
with the balance in an hour.
Uh, yes, sir.
May I have your name, please?
My, my name..
Uh, it must be on
the ticket to Mexico, here.
Here's my name.
Oh, yes, of course.
Señor Wittnauer. I'm sorry.
I will be back
in one hour.
Wittenauer.
Herman Wittenauer.
[Dramatic music]
[Phone ringing]
- Who is it?
- Anna, I need 15,000 Pesos.
Bring them to me
at the airport, right away.
You didn't kiss me goodbye.
Come back
and I give you everything.
Anna?
Alright, Anna, I'll come.
I'll get there,
right away.
[Sobbing]
[Dramatic music]
[Music continues]
- Who's that?
- I don't know.
[Music continues]
You're making a mistake.
You must take orders from me,
not Kessner.
Look, if you kill me,
you're betraying your own cause.
You're not Kessner's.
You're my men!
Once we were
almost yours.
Almost!
My name is Adolf Eichmann.
I regret nothing.
I do not repent.
Kill me!
No. That's too easy,
too quick.
You're gonna
stand trial, Eichmann.
People are gonna see you.
They're gonna study you.
They're gonna learn,
how one man
Can become responsible
for the torture and murder
Of six million
human beings.
Six million!
The world will learn,
and they'll remember.
[Intense music]