Come, there are limits to
what the human mind can bear.
Father.
A turkey, turkey with chestnuts.
And Bellerophon became melancholy.
Alone he readied
the bank of the Allion...
devouring his soul.
Fleeing the roads
frequented by men.
It's always the same.
Every boss is the same.
Nothing new under the sun.
But it's not the same.
This one's harsher.
For me it's the family.
The family Lesurf.
They say he drives a hard bargain,
like the other one.
Yes, but this one knows we
want to strike
and he's afraid.
He tries to protect himself.
He's has guards.
- Guards?
- Armed.
A small beer.
A small glass of white wine.
I haven't paid.
The man's afraid, the mother lies down,
and the son's completely...
What are you reading?
“Kidnapped on her wedding night."
It's beautiful.
Kidnapped on her wedding night.
"It's beautiful."
Butterfly.
Dragonfly.
Grasshopper.
It's not a compliment, it's an insult.
Tell me the price of my drink.
Mr. Ivan, I never know
how to take you.
I'm strange, aren't I?
- Now tell me the price of my beer.
Here's the price of my beer.
What's your name?
Don't tell me you don't have a name.
- My first name?
It's Ginette, Mr. Ivan,
you know that.
Well, Ginette...
Here's a tip for the service.
10 %.
What?
- What did he say to you?
- I don't know.
- Did he say something mad?
It's not dirty if you don't
know what it means.
The death of his father,
the new marriage...
All the same, they keep it
in the family.
It doesn't surprise me.
His head's empty now,
he wasn't prepared for this.
He's had to grow up, all at once.
That's how it is with the Lesurfs,
The man's good for nothing,
The wife's a beautiful whole.
As for the son...
Why such a pure manner,
when the messenger deliver the most
ignoble words pronounced by Man?
Earth is more beautiful
than asphalt.
Man destroys everything he touches.
I must have been born
in the wrong century.
I should have existed in a lime
where it was possible to live.
Now we've got crows.
Filthy beasts.
What do these crows want from me?
What do they want?
Locked?
I'm locked out.
Even iron slowly rots.
Come on, open.
If you shout you'll frighten them,
and you'll be outside all night.
Who's there?
- Me.
- The password.
I tell you I'm Ivan Lesurf.
You know me, don't you?
- You've got to know the password.
- What does that matter?
I'm the master here.
I won't say another word.
You've got to know the password.
Such are the orders.
I refuse, imbecile.
And I'll throw you out of here.
You'll throw me out? That's good.
You didn't hire me,
how can you throw me out?
Let me in, in the name of God.
What's all this noise?
- He didn't give the password.
- Are you completely mad?
Don't you know that's Mr. Ivan?
Quick, open this gate.
I'm only doing as I was told.
I'll fire him.
Excuse him, Mr. Ivan, he's new.
He's replacing Maximilian,
who broke his leg.
Mr. Lesurf has given strict orders,
and he didn't know,
- but he's good.
- He's stupid.
He's not stupid.
For him, discipline is a religion.
Orders are orders.
We must really be on our toes now,
you know.
The strike probably won't end soon.
Mr. Lesurf fears agitators,
he's received death threats.
You think he's in danger?
Well you know,
there's always
a risk of dying.
You clowns there.
You're not paid to beat up weaklings.
“When I'm alone with you,
my thoughts and memories,
"your hand in mine,
“seated at your side I abandon
myself to soft pleasures
"I let the hours pass
into oblivion.
"When in the depth of the forest,
I take you by the hand,
"when your soft sighs alone
beguile my ear,
"I repeat the promises
of the night before,
"I swear to worship only you.
“When finally content
in your sweet rest
"my trembling knees
your only support,
"And with a gaze as
steady as your own
"like the greedy bee
on the leaves of the rose...
Adrien, how well you read.
I read well because I love you.
And because you love me
to read to you.
It isn't just that.
You read well.
- Better than...
- Yes, better than Gabriel.
Hello, my darling.
Did you have a nice walk?
I saw some crows.
- You seem preoccupied.
- No, not at all.
They didn't want to open the gate.
They're so loyal they're stupid.
- Sparkos says you're afraid.
- Not afraid, but taking precautions.
- Afraid of what?
- Afraid of the workers.
What's happening, Adrian?
I'm not afraid of the workers.
Only among them there are instigators.
It isn't that I'm afraid...
but that they want to break me.
Don't worry.
"... And with a gaze
as steady as your own
"like the greedy bee on
the leaves of the rose.
"Often In the depths of
my heart penetrates a sudden terrible wave. "
"... you see me tremble,
“I shudder and, troubled, bound
"suddenly with true happiness...
"I feel your tears and
my soul's amazed...
"I wrap you suddenly
in my affectionate arms...
"You question me... "
Are you trying to keep me from reading?
Me? No. Why?
You could play some other time,
couldn't you?
I regret this is the hour
when I love to play.
Ivan, you want to play?
Then I leave it to you.
Never mind, I've finished.
There's a film tomorrow. Try to get out
of guard duty, we'll go together.
- What's playing?
- I don't remember the title.
A strange title.
- An American film where they fight with swords.
- You like that?
Fights, I love them.
What a lovely beast.
Bravo, Paul.
Give my compliments to Marie.
I hope you haven't spat on it?
Pay no attention, Paul.
- You've been  a big help.
- Please, Ivan...
I'll have more later.
That's not the same thing.
Marie will think
you detest her cooking.
That's how you antagonise
the servants.
- That's enough, Ivan.
- But it's not enough,
you have to taste it first.
- What's the matter?
- Don't you want some fish?
No, I'm certain Paul spat on it.
- Ivan, this is intolerable.
- I agree with you.
Paul is well paid,
lodged and fed.
There's no reason why
he should spit on the food.
Ivan, this foolishness has gone
far enough.
But it's not foolishness.
Paul spat on the food.
Isn't that right, Paul?
Don't deny it, I saw you.
You don't have the light
to say such things, Mr. Ivan.
I don't hold it against you,
Paul, because I know you.
You wouldn't have done such a thing
if you didn't have a good reason.
I suppose that my uncle committed
some injustice against you...
And has no doubt had
spoken to you rudely,
reproaching you for some fault
of which you weren't guilty.
- That's so, isn't it?
Ivan... this game is intolerable.
I command you...
I don't take orders from you.
Besides, Paul knows
I was only joking.
Paul likes me.
Isn't that right, Paul?
I know that your fish is as
good as it is beautiful,
give my compliments to Marie,
but I don't want any.
I don't want anything.
I'm not hungry.
I won't permit games
of this kind.
Forgive me.
- You know what I'm thinking?
- No, my darling.
What are you thinking?
I believe I'm not
comfortable in my skin.
Ale you leaving?
But the meal is not finished.
Excuse me, I have to meet someone.
In any case, you'll find it
agreeable to be left alone.
Eat well, eat a lot,
don't get on each other's nerves.
- Where are you going?
- To Youth.
Youth goes to youth as sin goes
to sin
and as money goes to money.
I'm going to meet Lucy.
- Claudia, my darling.
This can't go on.
Ivan is becoming odious,
as much with you as with me.
- I know.
- Well then?
I can't much longer endure
scenes like this.
Did you understand
his allusion to money?
He thinks he's been robbed.
As if he was capable of handling
what's happening at the factory.
I should have sacked him.
Fortunately you haven't.
You know exactly why I haven't.
Your patience has been wonderful.
And you know perfectly well why
Ivan is in such a state.
L-le can't bear the death
of his father...
and our love, our marriage...
have shattered him.
Of course.
Would you like more fish, Madame?
You must try to understand.
The way he carries on,
for the love of God.
What's wrong?
My dear Claudia, you can see
how upset I am.
Don't be so agitated,
take a chair and sit down.
So, is there a problem?
What's the matter?
Certainly it's not serious.
It's not what you think, Adrian.
The tenants have been dealt with.
And that's not so bad anyway.
No, it's something else.
What's happened, Andre?
You're so distressed.
Distressed? I'm not distressed.
I'm afflicted, that's what.
Listen...
Could I have a glass of wine?
Of course you can, go ahead.
Pardon me, Claudia,
but it's about Ivan.
Yes, Ivan and Lucy.
He's after her.
I can see it. He tries to conceal
what he's after... Telling her stories.
What is this nonsense?
It isn't nonsense, Claudia.
He's got his eye on her.
He's always watching her.
It frightens me.
Ivan and Lucy have known each other all their
lives. They practically grew up together.
I'm not mad, Claudia.
Things have changed.
Ivan's never been that interested
in Lucy.
Or girls in general...
But for some time now...
He looks for her. I tell you...
They're together fight now.
She didn't even finish dinner.
I tell you, something must be done.
I like Ivan a lot.
But he's
a riddle, all that with Lucy...
Since her mother died, she's all
I have and I intend to keep her.
I've been devoted to this family
for fifteen years.
Understand my anguish seeing my daughter
deflowered by your son.
- Come now, Andre.
- Deflowered.
If you don't put a stop to this,
she'll be deflowered.
We'll take care of it.
So I'll return to the main point.
You're disturbed by man's pursuit
of your daughter in general...
And that at this particular moment
he's with her.
Very well.
On your first point we
shall take stock of the situation.
As Claudia says,
we'll take care of it.
And the second point is simple:
You'll find Ivan and tell him
to come back here immediately.
Look at how the light pays homage
to the shapes of the trees.
Look.
The sky is part of nature...
and completes the landscape
with the light and the trees...
Not with men.
- Do you understand what I'm saying?
- Perfectly.
A leaf such as this one...
summarises all the beauty of nature.
Look.
Laugh again, Lucy.
But I can't.
I beg you.
Excuse me for interrupting you...
- but I can have a laugh too.
Don't play innocent with me,
saw you, you were touching her.
How delightful to meet you.
And you let him do such things?
You think it's funny?
Your uncle demands your presence,
if I were you I'd come immediately.
- Your duty is done.
- Immediately.
Your zeal will be appreciated
in high places.
- One minute.
- Leave me alone.
Aren't you ashamed?
Come on, aren't you ashamed?
What did he do to you?
What did he do?
He described to me
the beauty of nature.
Nature? Yes.
He didn't touch your backside?
No, he smiled at me.
He was touching you, I saw it.
I put out my hand and he took it.
Understand me, my daughter,
you're all I've got.
I can't bear him running after you.
I don't want to lose you
Slut.
Peace be with you.
I tell you I understand people.
But if he continues to subject us to
more and more of his outlandishness...
- You're exaggerating, darling.
- He's the one who exaggerates, darling.
He's odious.
I met her so simply
Without ever trying
to please
All the same
I adore myself
with such a burning love
That there's nothing that could...
displease...
There's going be fights, look.
It's not disturbing, is it?
No, it's a love story. It's starting.
Good Hamlet,
cast thy nighted colour off
And let thine eye look like
a friend on Denmark.
Do not for ever with
thy veiled lids
Seek for thy noble father
in the dust.
Thou knowst 'tis common:
All that lives must die,
Passing through nature
to eternity
Aye Madame, it is common.
If it be...
why seems it so
particular with thee?
"Seems", Madame?
Nay, it is.
I know not seems.
'Iis not alone my inky cloak,
good mother...
Nor customary suits
of solemn black
Nor windy suspiralion
of forced breath
That can denote me truly.
These indeed seem
For they are actions
that a man might play.
But I have that within
that passeth show
These but the trappings
and the suits of woe.
11s sweet and commendable
in your nature, Hamlet,
to give these mourning duties
to your father.
But you must know your father
lost a father,
that father lost, lost his.
- Come to my room in a little while.
I'll wait for you.
Caligula.
Death.
- Come, let me show you the mirror.
- What are you doing?
Making faces. Look.
Paris needs a Mass.
It all began with the
reign of your brother.
By the name LaGrange,
I know my daughter.
I used to be like you,
I didn't suspect anything.
But she's with him in his room.
They're having a rendezvous,
it's certain.
What's going on up there?
Horrible things...
Won't you do something?
You're being ridiculous, Andre.
Ivan is a gentleman.
Of course he's a gentleman,
I haven't said otherwise.
But even a gentleman...
has his instincts...
That's enough, Andre.
You're acting like a fool.
I order you to be quiet.
But Adrian... it's the honour
of my daughter that's at stake.
The honour of your daughter
is in no danger.
Look.
It's done.
See you later, Ophelia.
- I'm not Ophelia, Ivan.
- If you aren't Ophelia,
you won't kiss
my hand where everyone can see.
I'm Lucy. See you later, Ivan.
To be or not to be.
You're going in there?
The beer is disgusting.
I'm not here for the beer.
Come.
- Hello, Mr. Ivan.
- What have you got there?
It's a mouse. In its trap.
Give me this little beast.
Death.
Don't you recognise Death?
Come sit down.
I was waiting for you.
No, leave it with me.
François my friend, my brother...
Let there be no "Monsieur"
between us.
Have something.
What do you want?
- A glass of red.
Two glasses.
François, you're my only friend.
- You are my friend, aren't you?
I carry a secret that's stifling me
and I can only confide in you.
- Do you accept?
I must unburden my heart.
- Do you know what a murderer is?
- What is it?
- It's someone who kills.
I know a murderer.
I think I know two...
and that each of them has
committed an atrocious crime.
Who?
- My mother and my uncle.
- But that's impossible.
They have.
They killed my father
and then they married.
They killed him so
they could get married.
That's what I think.
I want to unmask them.
Do you know about Hamlet?
He was a prince.
His father the king had died.
He returned from the kingdom of the dead
to tell Hamlet
his brother and wife had
murdered him in the most cowardly way.
You understand?
It's exactly the same situation.
I have clues and evidence that
the same story has repeated itself.
I must act as he did:
To unmask this criminal couple,
I must pretend to be mad.
He terrorised them
until they confessed.
The only means I have
to unmask them...
is to create the same circumstances
that Hamlet did to simulate madness
Some of these circumstances
have already shown themselves.
You could help me create others.
I don't understand any of this.
I'm not asking you to
understand, only to help.
The character I must play is
that of Ivan becoming Hamlet.
The simple fact of his presence,
the fact that I play him,
will in itself be
a clear accusation.
First I must trouble them.
First trouble them, and then
make them worry.
And then they'll be terrified
They must understand they
cannot escape punishment.
They'll understand the failure
of the crime,
their defeat. They'll realise justice
will catch up with them,
and this shall be
a horrible nightmare.
From which they will try to awake,
but they cannot remain awake,
for I will stand before them.
Listen.
This is what I have to do
and this is how you'll help me.
- Are you listening?
I'll set a trap for them.
In order to unmask his mother and
his uncle,
Hamlet set a trap.
So he could trap them like rats.
This will be mine:
You and I will make a film.
- We'll make a film?
But tell no one the reason for it.
The subject of the film,
in disguised form,
will be the murder of my father by
my uncle and my mother.
When we show the film...
the mousetrap will enclose them.
- Do you want to?
Really?
Can Ginette be in it?
Very well, but don't tell her the reason.
You must not tell her the reason.
I promise.
What do you want?
I'm going to make a film with Ivan.
Do you want to be in it?
A film? I don't know.
We'll be the stars.
What are you doing?
You've lost it.
What are you men doing?
You talk, you walk but
you're so soft about it.
Act like men, for Christ sake.
Who laughed?
Me.
What makes you laugh, Matton...
with your voice like a Virgin's?
Nothing, nothing.
We're not paid to sit around
doing nothing.
It could happen at any moment,
understand?
Lsurf sleeps and we're awake.
That's what we're paid for.
And he's too afraid to sleep
with his eyes closed.
Monsieur is a rich man...
And the rich are afraid of
being robbed and killed.
That's what politics is all about.
So Lesurfs afraid of the strikers?
It's all the same.
They strike because
they need money.
And Lsurf doesn't want
to give it to them.
He's afraid the others
will kill him to get his money.
And he pays us to prevent it.
He'd do better
just to give it to them.
No, idiot.
Because he's afraid that they'd
just want more.
There's someone
in the woods.
Come on. The hunt's on.
Search.
Spread out.
Cretin. You dumb animal.
Trying to get yourself killed?
This way.
What's happened“?
- An alert. There's a man in the woods.
- What?
Quick, close the door.
What's going on?
Why are you wearing that cap?
Didn't you hear the gunfire?
Is that all you can say?
It made me turn my head.
It's me they're after.
They thought I wanted to kill
the beloved Adrian.
Because of the cap and the scarf.
If I'd worn my bowler hat...
They wouldn't have worried.
People always confuse things
with their appearances.
don't start that again.
I know the story of Hamlet.
Ophelia was a blonde.
I love your blondness, Ophelia.
Behind Lucy stands
the blonde Ophelia.
Ivan, I think I know what
you have in mind.
- Really?
And I'm afraid it will make you...
I'm afraid you're going mad.
On the contrary...
it's everything else
that will make me mad.
- To endure all this and do nothing...
You want to have your way
in my house now?
Not at all.
I came on behalf of my uncle,
that is on behalf of my father,
that is on behalf of Adrian,
to invite you to lunch,
you and your Channing daughter.
- But I just saw him, he said nothing.
- Because he left it to me.
Then I thank you, Adrian...
I mean Ivan.
I accept with pleasure.
See you soon
- Well?
- He vanished like a puff of smoke.
Incompetent.
Good for nothing. Idiot.
Go on, keep looking.
What's going on, Smurkos?
I heard gunfire.
"Smarkos", Mr. Ivan.
We're hunting a fleeing suspect,
always on the lookout.
My uncle will be happy.
My precautions were for nothing.
Those bastards.
What happened?
I heard gunfire.
A strange man invaded the park.
And your uncle's received
another threatening letter.
Letters have never been
that important.
The man hasn't been caught?
I don't think so. He got away.
Perhaps it was a ghost.
I've invited Andre and Lucy on
your behalf to have lunch with us.
Are you mad?
This isn't the time.
What's done is done.
Could you pass me the salt...
Polonius?
- Polonius? Don't know him.
- Obviously not.
You've got other things to do.
Eat, for example.
One cannot eat
before reading
the poet's letters.
Isn't that right, Papa?
You're awful.
You're stupid.
You're old.
You're vulgar.
That's enough, be quiet.
Leave me alone.
When I'm assailed on all sides,
I must speak.
But what possesses him?
Do you know where
Mother spent Christmas?
In a cabaret.
They threw streamers.
They put on turbans.
They broke plates over
each other's heads.
And she danced.
Christmas,
The holiday of God...
and of children.
It's enough to make you sick.
Everything should be forbidden.
Under pain of death.
Under pain of being
kicked in the arse.
This time I think
I finally understand.
He's a drunkard, a degenerate,
completely mad.
You'll never see him again.
I say you'll never see him again.
You hear me?
You understand?
- I forbid it.
- Or else what?
Aren't you sleeping?
You can't stay here.
It's forbidden.
I love you, Ophelia.
Ivan, I've got something
serious to say to you.
Say it.
I can't see you anymore if
things remain as they are.
If they remain how?
You know very well.
You're bitter, cruel, unbearable.
You think so?
You've been listening to Lagrange.
My father has forbidden me
to see you anymore.
Obedient little girlie.
You know it's not that.
An obedient little girl who no
longer wants to be my friend.
No, I don't want to be your friend.
And I don't want to see you either.
Not because my father orders me.
- But for my own reasons.
- Why?
Because you hate people.
On the contrary, I love them.
But I can't bear their turpitude.
They ruin everything,
they break everything.
Evil is hidden in them.
It makes their actions vile,
it infects their thoughts
I don't know what to tell you,
but I'm sure you're wrong.
I love you, I love being near you, .
But you frighten me.
I fear for you.
- You fear for me? My angel...
Even if you're light, you act
strangely, and it frightens me.
There's something bad
in how you behave.
No, it's what surrounds me
that's bad.
It isn't me.
Become yourself again,
don't evade reality.
That's what I'm looking to do.
Do as you please.
For now leave me alone.
my love.
Here I see you descend into
your tomb
in the first light of day?
Here in your madness
you are dead, Ophelia...
because I am just?
Or, if I am not just,
is it because Evil is
all around me?
I've known those who were
gracious and amusing,
good and just.
But who are now
nothing more than dust.
How could you not think of it?
Life is good.
- You like this work?
- Certainly.
You're outside,
you breathe the fresh air...
and nobody bothers you
while you work.
And then it's good soil,
like butter.
Have you been a gravedigger for long?
This is my first grave.
But my father dug graves for thirty years.
An excellent gravedigger,
well-known around here.
With him, never any problems,
infiltrations, nothing like that.
Never.
He's the one who taught me.
I hope to keep at it.
For whom are you
preparing this grave?
I'm digging without digging,
you could say.
In short, I'm digging.
The lease has expired,
so I have to remove the cadaver.
And where will you put it?
In potter's field.
Nobody wanted to
pay for another lease.
And you can't just leave him.
Would you like to act in a comedy?
I'm making a film.
Would you like to be in it?
I was in the choir in school.
Why?
Because I must make a film,
and I'd like you to act in it.
You have a cheerful air.
I'm not the sad type.
I'd love to, as long as it
doesn't interfere with my work.
- Absolutely not.
- Alright then.
Sir, you'll have to excuse me,
but I have to get back to work.
- These things don't wait.
- Go right ahead.
You're dead.
No, I'm not dead.
Don't fight.
Don't fight and don't argue.
Imagine that Death is standing
up there at the turning.
Be good...
And be good to yourselves.
Forget that you're acting.
Forget yourselves.
Don't gesticulate merely for
the pleasure of doing so,
but then don't forbid
yourselves either.
I chose you because I want you
to play yourselves.
Don't imitate other people.
Don't try to make your
audience understand.
Only make them understand
what you're saying.
And that you understand the
nuances of your characters.
Your characters don't exist.
Only you do.
- Understand?
Another thing.
Be modest:
Don't try to get yourself noticed
on the screen or elsewhere.
There is nothing important
about the actor.
Acting is honourable. Nothing more.
So no plunging necklines
or funny get-ups.
No laughing out loud...
or listening to us talking.
Finally, no quarrelling over
the opening credits,
over the size and order
of your names.
That would be
perfectly ridiculous...
and perfectly vulgar.
- Yes, but...
- Silence, not a word. .
We'll begin.
- Mother, Uncle...
- What is it?
I'm making a film with young
people in the village.
It's to surprise you.
Would you like to see it?
- You made it?
That's very good.
Bravo, Ivan. Congratulations.
I never thought you were
capable of such work.
You seem very mysterious
these days.
- You really want to see it?
- Certainly darling, with pleasure.
Not only do we want to see it...
but we'll organise a party
in your honour.
And we'll invite all our friends
to come see your masterpiece.
Plus the servants, Sparkos and
his men, everyone will be invited.
How wonderful.
I didn't realise,
I didn't hope for so much.
- Are you pleased?
- I'm delighted.
Kiss me.
- Is it good?
- So, this film...
- You'll be seeing it, Madame.
- What type of film is it?
That depends on the audience.
You could find it funny, or
you could find it painful.
But we won't know how to react.
Laugh only if you feel like it.
Is it going well?
- Very well, Mr. Ivan.
- Is it ready?
- Ready.
- Then let's go. My friends,
the show is about to begin.
We'll move to the parlour.
Ladies and gentlemen...
allow me to present
the cast of the film.
Dear Andre.
If you would be so kind
as to sit there.
Ophelia, I want you to
stay near me.
When the decisive moment comes,
the light will finally break.
It's ready.
Put out your cigarettes.
M. Ferlus, grocer,
doted upon by his wife,
does the monthly accounts.
For some time now, the store
hasn't prospered.
Madame Ferlus isn't happy.
Fred, the brother of M. Ferlus,
drops by to say hello.
But he has another end in mind.
M. Ferlus is stubborn.
Madame Ferlus is sensual.
And Fred knows how to
make the most of it.
They must remove the obstruction.
How great is
woman's treachery.
As great as the treachery of men.
So impatience has paid off.
Crime has paid.
But your story is horrible.
Very well, very good.
My compliments.
I found it a little... twisted.
Very funny.
That really made me laugh.
Crime has paid.
That's normal.
- I liked the beautiful girl.
- It was funny.
And what should I do, Mr. Ivan?
Nothing.
I know it's late...
But what do you think of
my cinematic talent?
- Go away.
- Didn't you like it?
You're a fool.
What you have done
is contemptible.
How could I have been so blind?
You hate everyone.
You're a monster.
You'll be cast
out like a dangerous beast.
What you've done to Adrian,
my husband...
Adrian isn't your husband,
he's the brother of your husband.
You know what that's called?
Incest.
Did you give your mouth, your body
to the other while my father lived?
Ivan, I beg you.
He killed my father
for money and for lust.
It was no longer enough
to have you in his bed.
What is this nightmare? Where do
you get these frightful visions?
I accuse the two of you
of incest
- and murder.
- Be quiet.
Why, my God, why?
We are only animals...
and our hearts rot
before our bodies do.
The solution is simple.
He's gone mad.
You can't let a madman go free.
I don't like speaking like this.
But in my opinion,
he must be watched.
But it's impossible.
Have you got another idea?
We've got to do something, Claudia.
Perhaps at this very moment
he's preparing more mischief.
Who knows what's
going on in his head?
His solitary walks worried me.
And I was right.
Did you talk to him about
his charming film?
- Where is he now?
- I don't know.
He's certainly going to
meet someone.
- But who?
- Not my daughter at any rate.
She's locked up, well locked up.
I interrogated her last night about that film.
I promise you, she had nothing to do with it.
She didn't even know about it,
- She hadn't seen him for two weeks.
- What does that matter?
- I defend my honour.
- Your name is spotless, Andre.
- Could you do me a favour?
- Don't you treat me like a friend anymore?
What does that matter?
I'd like you to watch Ivan.
What do you say?
- Could you do this for me?
- Gladly. What do you think?
Spend all your time on his trail.
I'm afraid he'll
find out something.
And I can no longer live in fear.
Go.
It's succeeded beyond
my wildest hopes.
But I'm alone now.
I've got no one but you,
Dear Horatio.
The bastard.
My poor heart.
A nest of jays.
Things don't mean the same
to you that they do to me.
You're brave, kind.
You can bear the faults
of the world...
for you don't see them.
But for me, they burn my eyes.
Everyone says you've become mean,
but for me it's the opposite.
Dear Horatio...
What's he doing up there?
Good Polonius.
Are you getting closer to Heaven?
Mr. Ivan, I think he's dead.
Trees bear strange fruit
these days.
Rats.
Rats in the trees.
- Go and get help.
Poor Lucy.
Look at me.
I'm sleeping.
Look how I sleep.
I sleep, but I can see you.
You stroke your hair.
You take off your coat.
You arrange flowers.
Stop it, you're frightening me.
I wanted to frighten you.
To keep you from crying.
Your father is dead.
Paul, have you seen Andre?
It's the first time in 15 years
he's been late.
- He won't be coming.
- Why not?
- He's at supper.
- He's eating supper?
I didn't say he was eating supper,
but that he was at supper.
Not when he eats...
but where he is eaten.
I don't mean to bother you, but
I found M. Lagrange in a tree.
Did you say diamonds?
Stop talking rubbish.
It's up to you.
- Good play.
- You're playing for sous?
- What do you expect?
- You playing?
1 am.
"All professional categories. "
"Stop the massacre,
that's all that matters."
- Are you having a drink?
Leave me, I have to think.
Alone won't do.
Fine, I'll be upstairs.
Forgive me,
I have to think things over.
More than anything,
we need to pray.
You can't protect yourself.
Why should I have to protect myself?
I've done nothing.
No more than the others.
And no-one's a saint.
Why am I hounded?
I need to forget.
Why do I suffer?
Why does he make me suffer?
His madness infects me.
Claudia abandons me.
I can't take it anymore.
I'm going to kill him.
Sparkos... I want to talk to you.
Sparkos, give me your revolver.
My revolver? What for?
Because I need it.
I depend on my revolver, sir.
I need it.
Lend me your revolver, I'll give
it back. That's an order.
- But why do you need it?
- Come on.
These things aren't for you, sir.
Leave it to me.
Give it to me.
You're making a mistake, M. Lesurf.
Not a word.
You know me, sir...
At least I paid for it.
Understand Elise,
with what
goes on in this house...
we won't be servants much
longer, soon we'll be the masters.
You've come to kill me, uncle?
What's happened?
M. Lsurf
took poison. He's going to die.
Get out.
I don't want you to look at me.
I hate you.
- My darling...
- I hate you.
I don't want you to look at me.
I feel like I'm abominable.
Monster. Don't stay here.
Well?
You're dying?
I'm dying.
Are you happy?
Less than I imagined.
I wanted to tell you...
It should make you laugh:
that you'll be damned.
It hurts.
You die like a rat.
Why like a rat?
- It hurts.
- And as for me...
I suffer too.
To the point I can't
stand it anymore.
What?
I can't live for long.
How death hurts.
Don't speak.
I have to.
I must tell you...
that you were wrong.
That you've been completely wrong.
And that you'll always
suffer for it.
I only killed myself.
I couldn't hurt a fly.
And yet...
I feel like a criminal.
Why?
Yes, why?
You don't know.
I feel the same way and
I don't understand.
What?
Do you think that Death...
is the end of this pain?
Of all my pain.
I don't know.
Do you think that I'll be happy?
My Ivan.
My son.
What have I done?
Why did I want justice?
I judged him, I condemned him.
And I killed him.
He loved me and
I killed him, Ophelia.
What have I become?
You're what you've always been.
You're Ivan.
And I'm not Ophelia, but Lucy.
It's Lucy who is next to you.
Lucy, my love.
Support me, protect me, defend me.
I love you.