- Humus, fries, salad?
- Lots of fries.
Can I have the bottle?
Sure.
Mom!
I brought you a sandwich.
- I've been waiting for an hour.
- I brought you a sweater too.
Fine, give it to me.
- You have money for a cab?
- Yes.
- Why don't we take the bus?
- No, I'm too tired.
What's this on your face?
You're dirty.
I'm so tired.
I found ajob for you.
A friend's mother needs a cleaning lady.
Not again...
Drop it, would you!
Why not, Mom?
You could try.
- I don't want to.
- You can't go on like this.
- Just try it.
- Leave me alone!
I'm going to the restaurant.
Get some rest.
OK.
- You're not going out today!
- Mind your own business.
Where are your keys?
Let go of my purse! Let go of my purse!
Give me some salad for Or.
Thanks.
Here, eat.
Sa'I'd!
Put this aside for washing.
Here.
- Sa'I'd, the potatoes!
- They're coming.
Hi. How's it going?
- Fine. And you?
- Good.
How's your mother?
OK.
She came back from the hospital
a bit depressed.
Why?
Because it's depressing.
And now she's at home alone.
Then why did you come to work?
It's alright.
I'll see her later on.
If you want to go home,
I'll cover for you.
No.
Don't bother.
Bye.
Goodbye.
What's up? Cool.
How's it going?
- Hi, how are you?
- Fine.
- And you?
- Good.
- So...
- What?
I think noa is here,
she's waiting for me.
- Oh, yeah?
- Never mind.
- Go around the back...
- I know.
When was the telephone cut off?
Two days ago.
- Did Avi call before that?
- No.
He might've tried when I was out.
He might've tried...
OK.
This...
Is for your yeast infection.
And this, you take one now,
and one in the morning.
This one...
Two pills, twice a day.
This...
is your gel.
Viox was too expensive,
I got Optalgin instead.
He didn't even come to see me
at the hospital.
Maybe he didn't know.
How could he not have...
You think so?
How could he have known?
- Stop it, Mom!
- I don't want this.
Stop it... silly.
I don't want to.
- Why not? Mom!
- What?
- Come back here!
- Why?
- Give it a try!
- I don't want to.
Why not?
She's nice. Try, at least.
OK. But then I'm going out.
- Why?
- Because!
- Call first.
- I have to go out.
No, you don't have to.
What do I say to her?
You say...
"Hello..."
OK, dial.
- No answer.
- Wait a little.
Hello.
Yes, hello.
Yes, my name is Ruthie.
Yael, I'm Or's mother.
Yes, sure. No problem.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow at four o'clock.
Perfect!
Fine, thanks.
Thank you very much. Great. Thanks.
Mom...
Fantastic!
How was I?
You were wonderful.
- Did I say anything dumb?
- You were great.
I'm going to Rachel's.
I'll bring you something to eat.
There weren't enough girls to play.
- Your team is better?
- Yes.
Of course!
They lost against Even-Yehuda.
135 to nothing.
I have to go.
Already?
I want to spend some time with Mom.
OK.
I'm going too.
- You didn't eat a thing.
- I'm on a diet...
I have to go too.
I have an exam.
- Are you going to study?
- Yes.
OK.
- Dinner was delicious.
- I'm going to the movies.
- And so I stay here all alone?
- Yes.
Rachel, may I take some food
for my mother?
Of course you can.
Mom.
Hello, sweetie.
What's going on?
I want to go out tonight.
Why?
You found ajob.
- Just tonight.
- No, you're not going out!
Hello, Ido. How are you?
- We brought you some food.
- Really?
OK.
Your mother made it?
- Yes.
- OK.
Want me to serve?
Just one last time,
to pay our debts. Alright?
Mom, that's enough.
Sit down!
Give yourself a chance!
OK, fine. Fine.
Is the food hot?
Have a seat.
Get me a glass of water, sweetie.
- How was school today?
- Fine.
I'll eat this...
I'll eat it tomorrow, OK?
Why?
I'm not hungry right now.
What's so funny?
I don't care about the principal.
I'm worried about my grades.
She won't do anything to you.
She can't flunk you.
- What happened?
- The principal caught her smoking.
It's too late to educate us now.
I'm scared about my grades.
Don't worry...
Hi, girls. How are you?
Gal, Judith will see you
in a few minutes. Alright?
Big deal for nothing.
I found ajob for my mother.
Really? Doing what?
- Housework.
- Excellent! Congratulations!
When does she start?
- Tomorrow, I think.
- Great!
OK, I hope everything goes well.
- We see each other...
- On Thursday.
- Good. Excellent news, Or.
- Bye.
Hava?
Hello.
Can I have some henna?
Black... 20000 grams.
- Four shekels' worth?
- Yes.
It's raining out and...
I'm not going out...
Stop moving around.
Stop it!
What'll you wear today?
For who?
Avi or the interview?
- Avi?
- Yes.
- He's coming over.
- So, what'll you wear?
- A new outfit.
- What do you mean?
Very chic.
I just bought it.
Come on, today I deserve it!
And I got a few T-shirts for you.
- Is that Avi?
- No! Avi's coming over tonight.
- Who is it?
- Ido.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- What's that?
- Henna.
What is that?
Hello, Ido.
Hello, Ruthie.
Come in and say hello!
- How are you?
- Fine.
- What did your mom make?
- Mafroum.
I love it... I love it!
One day I'll make your mom...
Some jam.
It's out of this world.
Have you ever tasted my mother's jam?
I'll make some for her one day.
OK, I'm going to the restaurant.
- Are you coming later?
- Yes.
Don't work too hard!
Mom, you're moving around.
What a cutie, that Ido!
He's so sweet. He loves you.
- He loves you.
- Stop it!
I'm telling you, the boy loves you!
Come on...
- Are you done?
- That's it.
Where's the cap?
Stop moving...
I'm so happy.
Hold on a second!
Get this thing off me!
How do I look like this?
What do you mean?
With the cap on...
Give me the laundry.
Did you get it everywhere?
Yes.
Even the ends.
Good.
You can't...
Just go like this...
It's raining out
and you're staying with me
Even if you said...
No, I don't have time
You'll earn 2,000000 shekels
with your newjob.
Peanuts!
No, it's not.
- How do I look?
- Perfect!
Nice, huh?
Look at these jeans.
- Am I pretty?
- Gorgeous!
Hello. Ruthie?
Pleased to meet you, I'm Yael. Come in.
Diva! Where were you?
Diva came to say hello.
Isn't that right, Diva?
Right, my pretty?
Diva eats over here.
I'll show you
how to prepare her food in the morning.
One and a half cups of dry dog food.
I said a half.
Be very careful with the "half".
Don't give her too much,
she has a weight problem.
OK. After that, you add
two or three spoonfuls of gravy.
I use the sauce
from whatever I'm cooking.
Got it?
OK, let's start over. I want to see
if you understood the portions.
Yes, one cup.
- Does the smell bother you?
- It's OK.
You'll get used to it.
- Show me. A tad less.
- I'll take some out...
Perfect. Like that, yes.
Very good.
Now you add the gravy.
Yes, you can put one more in.
Excellent!
Yes, that's good.
Diva! Come here, my lovely.
Your food is ready.
Good.
Tell me about yourself.
What?
I understand you've never
done cleaning before?
I've done a little.
It's not very complicated.
We'll work things out.
- I'm going to play soccer.
- Bye.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- What's new?
- Nothing.
Anyone got a cigarette?
Here you go.
Thanks.
Want to come up to my place?
No, forget it.
Mom.
He didn't come?
What's it look like?
He can forget about me, that dog.
How did the interview go?
You want to sleep in the bedroom?
No, sweetie.
- Good night.
- Good night, sweetie.
Hold me tight.
- Georgetta...
- OK...
Georgetta... OK...
Get out of here.
Where are you, Georgetta?
Be gentle... Alright?
Or.
- Or.
- What?
Are you up?
So, how did it go?
What's wrong?
- Why are you sitting down?
- I'm too tired to clean.
Stop it, Mom. Get up.
It's all going to work out.
Hi, Ido.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Let's go.
OK, I'm off.
- You're not coming to school?
- Later.
You need some help?
No, that's OK.
Bye.
Ruthie, hello.
Shmuel?
I didn't see you. How are you?
Fine. Say...
Do you have my money?
I've got some, here.
- What's this?
- It's what I've got.
Next month's rent is coming up soon.
And?
- What do you say?
- About what?
- Let's have some fun, like we used to.
- No, no.
Leave me alone.
You know how good I can make you...
Hello.
Come on, leave me alone.
You're not interested?
No, I'm not.
Too bad for you.
Who is it?
Moshiko.
What's going on?
- Who is it?
- Moshiko.
Moshiko! Hi, honey!
Shit. I don't have the key.
One second, I'm looking for a key.
How are you, honey?
- Hi.
- Took you long enough.
Sorry, sweetheart. How are you?
- Fine.
- I couldn't find the key.
Come on in.
Sit down, I'm coming.
Mom.
Sweetie, give me 100 minutes.
Go for a walk, OK?
Mom!
Who's with you?
Open the door!
Mom!
What's he doing here?
How did you get in?
- Get out, Or.
- No, he's leaving.
Get out, Moshiko.
OK, OK.
Go to your bedroom.
Let me get my shoes on...
I'm sorry, Moshiko.
Go to your room.
Get out!
- Bye.
- OK, OK.
Don't look at me like that!
Get out of my face,
I don't want to see you!
- I thought you stopped.
- You thought I stopped...
How can I?
You think you can just up and stop?
- Just like that?
- That's what you always say.
At least I know him.
Is the street better?
You know the entire street too!
Leave me alone...
Leave me alone now.
You don't understand.
What do you know?
What?
Yes, what do you know?
You promised me!
How could I promise you?
How could I promise?
What did I promise you?
You can go back to the street.
- Isn't it a little late for cleaning?
- No.
You shouldn't work so hard.
I don't want to preach,
but at your age,
I knew that work
was very important.
But that schooling
was even more important.
You have to think of your future.
Even today, I still...
I'm not ashamed to admit it...
Even on TV, I watch
national Geographic.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Stop it, Shmuel.
Leave me alone, go to bed.
- How are you?
- Fine.
How's it going?
- Fine. And you?
- Good.
Got a cigarette?
Yes.
I'm coming.
Want to have a smoke?
Mom.
Get up.
Mom, get up.
You'll be late.
I'm not going today.
Yes, you are.
I'm tired.
Mom.
Get up.
You'll be late.
Come on, get up.
OK...
OK, OK...
You think I should call her?
Orjust hurry up and go?
Just go.
- OK?
- Fine.
- Are you going?
- Yes.
You promise?
Yes. What's with you this morning?
Why are you all...
- What are you so happy about?
- Bye.
Ruthie!
Hi, how are you?
Avi...
- You going out?
- What are you doing here?
I brought you some croissants.
So... you want to come up?
Aren't you going somewhere?
It can wait a while...
Don't bother with that.
Come on.
I'll bring some hooks over.
OK.
You brought me croissants.
I have something to tell you.
- Something good?
- Yes.
I found ajob.
- Really?
- Yes.
Cleaning.
Or found it for me.
With a lady named Yael.
She's a nice lady.
Yes.
- Really? Or like usual?
- No, really. Really...
Do you believe me?
Sure, why not?
I want to stop...
All the rest.
Stop my work.
- Well?
- I'm glad.
- I'm glad. Real happy...
- no...
Really?
- You're in love.
- Knock it off.
Who is it?
Rachel.
- Rachel!
- Hi.
Come on in.
Thanks.
It's been ages.
- Would you like some coffee?
- No, thank you...
- Some juice?
- No, I want to talk to you.
- Oh?
- Yes.
- Sit down.
- How long have we been neighbors?
I don't know. I moved in here...
When Or was 2 years old, right?
- Yes.
- A long time ago.
I'll be frank with you.
I've always been straightforward, right?
Yes.
OK, listen.
Or and Ido spent the night together.
I know.
They're so cute...
Real lovebirds.
This morning they left together...
Yes... But...
I'm not comfortable with it.
You see?
- I...
- What?
They don't fit together.
It's not right.
Or is a lovely girl.
- Did I say the contrary?
- And so?
And so, it's just not right.
What more can I say?
But, he...
Ido loves her.
'Ido lovs hr"?
Yes. He loves her.
He comes here and picks her up.
He calls her,
they go to school together,
he walks her to work...
He's with her all day long.
They spend every minute together.
But he's not the only one.
Everyone else loves her
and she loves them.
Guys traipsing up and down...
Do you understand?
Hi.
Is something wrong?
No.
- Well?
- We were just talking.
About what?
We were talking... about you and Ido.
What about us?
Or... come here.
Look, I know that you and Ido...
Spent the night together.
Isn't that true?
Isn't it true?
Tell me...
now listen.
I don't think it's right.
Why not?
Because...
Because you're older than him. Right?
- Six months. Does that count?
- Yes.
At your age, it counts.
Why?
Mom?
What, sweetie?
I don't know...
Maybe Rachel is right.
What do you mean "right"?
Lt'd be a shame...
to ruin our friendship.
- Why would it be ruined?
- Or.
Nothing will change.
You can still come over for dinner...
You can continue working for Ha'I'm.
There's no problem.
You know I care about you?
Alright?
- I'm going now, Ruthie, OK?
- Yes.
Don't you dare start crying on me.
Sweetie. Honey.
- Dad, get their bill.
- See if they need anything else.
- Sa'I'd, I need the big pot.
- It's coming.
Eat.
Is everything OK?
Yes.
Ido, clear the table over there.
Are you sure you're alright?
- Dad.
- What?
Give me the bill.
They're done over there.
Dad.
I'm leaving.
Or, I'm going now.
- Bye, Sa'I'd.
- Bye.
- You coming over later?
- Of course.
You sure?
I'll come over after soccer.
- OK?
- OK.
Bye.
How's it going?
- What are you doing here?
- I'm on leave.
Really? How's the army?
"How's the army?"
Come on, let me in.
I was on my way out, so...
What's going on?
I just got here.
- I have to go...
- Go where?
- When was the last time I saw you?
- It's been a while.
- That's right.
- Then why are you running off?
- I can't.
I can't right now.
I don't want to.
- You know I like being with you.
- Yes...
Yes?
But I don't want to.
- Yes you do.
- Leave me alone.
No.
Yes.
You see?
- No, leave me alone...
- Come on.
Come on, let's go to your room.
You coming?
I have to go now, OK?
I'll see you later?
- Maybe.
- OK, bye.
Mom?
- What happened?
- Don't come in.
Are you alright?
Does it hurt?
A little.
Do you need anything?
No, I just want to take a bath.
It's OK...
That's enough. Turn it off.
Mom.
You're never going out again.
Look at me.
You're not going out again.
Don't worry.
You can count on me.
Everything will be OK.
Don't... Don't...
Don't...
It'll be OK.
You can count on me.
It's OK.
- You want the light off?
- Yes, sweetie.
Tomorrow you'll stay home and rest.
What about Yael?
We'll find something else.
- Really?
- Yes.
You're my little treasure.
No one has a treasure like I do.
You're my sunshine.
Good night.
- Good morning.
- Did you bring the rent money?
- No.
Can I come in?
You're so beautiful...
So I'm sitting there on his couch...
He's so excited he doesn't know
what to do with himself...
And I take off my T-shirt.
I don't have to lift a finger...
He just jerks off.
All I do is make noises likel
'Oh... Y s... Com on."
- Gross.
- Why? I couldn't care less.
He was so excited
he came right away.
Cool, huh?
You coming?
I think I'll go home.
Yes?
- Hello.
- Or, sit down.
No, I...
I'm going.
Everything's fine
I just have a headache.
Then sit down. Drink something.
No.
- Are you sure you're OK?
- Yes...
You don't want to talk?
No. Everything's fine, I'm fine.
- How is your mother's job going?
- Fine.
What if we talked on Monday?
Anat, I need to see you.
- Just a minute...
- It's OK, go on.
- We'll talk soon, Or.
- Sure.
Hi.
What's going on?
Is something wrong?
Wait.
- What?
- Where were you yesterday?
When?
When we were supposed to meet up.
I forgot, I had something to do...
What's wrong?
Nothing!
- We'll talk about it later, OK?
- No... Wait.
Ido, look, this isn't working out.
No, leave me alone.
It's just not right.
- Wait a second.
- What?
- Where are you going?
- Stop it. I don't love you.
How are you, honey?
What did the doctor say?
My wife will take care of you. Iris.
Hang on,
I have nathalie on the phone.
I'll be right with you...
Perfect. The girls say hi.
Yes. I'll put you back
on the schedule next week.
Don't worry.
Get better, I'll pay your expenses.
OK, rest up. Bye.
Honey!
Sacha called. It's urgent.
OK.
- What's your name?
- Or.
- I'm Iris. How are you?
- Fine.
You'll need a pseudonym.
You have one?
Something Israeli...
Sivan?
I'll start from the beginning.
We run an escort service.
Clients call. We send them
the girls they ask for.
How are you, honey?
How'd it go?
- Like usual.
- Perfect.
We take 1500 shekels.
That's for the escort service only.
After that it's your business.
You understand?
How much?
Girls!
Be quiet two minutes, OK?
The girls get 20000 for 2 hours.
You negotiate with the client
over the phone
before you leave here. OK?
You must leave from here
and come back here.
OK? It's very important.
What did Sacha want?
I don't know, love. Call him.
The drivers who work with us
take you to the hotel
or the apartment...
You only tell the cab to go
if everything's OK.
If you don't like something,
you come back.
But you should try and avoid that.
One second.
Sexclusive, good day.
Shlomo? How are you, darling?
Svetlana isn't working today.
Shlomo... I've got something new...
that you won't believe.
- Hello.
- Hello. Come in.
- Sivan, are you OK in there?
- Yes.
What's with the towel?
Relax, like me.
That's better.
- How old are you?
- 18.
18!
I like 18.
I adore 18...
What a beautiful ass!
You know what?
I want to fuck you in the ass.
What do you say?
It makes you laugh, does it?
I like that.
So?
We didn't discuss it on the phone.
I didn't know
I'd be getting such a nice ass.
Don't worry. I've got Vaseline
and everything else we need.
OK? Alright?
OK.
Wow... What an ass.
Wonderful.
Just what I need.
You look hot tonight.
- How's it going?
- Great!
- Want some cigarettes?
- Yes.
What's new?
The usual...
See ya.
Mom?
Hello.
Hi, sweetie.
How are you?
Fine.
Sweetie.
You look pretty like that
with a dress on.
What about my shoes?
Are they new?
They're nice. Very nice.
Don't cry, my love.
I'll be OK.
I'll see you tomorrow?
Bye, sweetie.
Mom!
Don't go.
I don't want you to go!
Let go of me... Let go, sweetie.
No.
Sweetie... Come on, let go...
I'll be back in the morning, OK?
No...
I'll see you tomorrow morning, sweetie.
No.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Let go of me.
Iris?
Hello, it's Or.
Hi.
Do you have anything?
Then I can come?
OK.
Cool.
It's this way... Come on, girls.
A lesbian act!
Down here is just for kicks.
The real action takes place upstairs.
Come on, come on.
After the striptease,
once things get going,
you bring the groom up here.
- He sleeps with one of you... or both.
- No problem.
OK, perfect.
Some of the guys
are gonna be real horny...
Is what we arranged
on the phone OK?
1,000000 each?
Cool. I'm going back down.
Everyone has a good time. OK?
We'll be waiting downstairs.
- Where's the restroom?
- Here.
OK? We're waiting.
- You alright?
- Yes.
I'll get ready.
Translationl Julie Meyer
Subtitling TITRA FILM Paris