[music playing]
REPORTER (ON TV): The
National Football League,
the Rams could clinch
a divisional title
with a win over the 49ers.
The Raiders shouldn't have
much trouble with Seattle,
and the Patriots
are still 14 point
favorites to defeat the Colts.
11 other games are--
Five game slate last evening.
The frontman--
[dramatic music]
With the Sabers 41-3.
The Canadiens got
past the Flames, 7-6.
Helping the Penguins
pass the Jets--
Game with the Capitols.
A win for the Caps would--
For Sunday's-- belongs
to Danny Sullivan,
after being clocked 219.35
miles an hour in the trials.
Next in line was
Alanser, followed
by the favorite, Rick Mears.
Race time is--
What the hell's
going on out here?
[dramatic music]
[gunshot]
Find him!
[birds chirping]
Willie, how many times do I
have to tell you not to throw
your wet towels on my bed.
Sorry.
I can't believe my
mother's going to Hawaii.
She promised she'd be
here for visiting day.
I'd rather go to Hawaii, too.
Thanks.
Will, have you seen my compass?
What, are you blind?
It's right in front of you.
You know, Greg, if I
was you, I wouldn't
worry about anything right now.
With those three days
alone in those mountains
you're about to do.
Yeah, I guess I kind of
have my head up my ass, huh?
Willie, is it really that tough?
Well, let's just
say, I wouldn't want
to do it again unless I had to.
Yeah, well I'm ready for it.
You better be.
See you in a few days, Willie.
Hope you don't get too lonely.
[music playing]
[crunching leaves]
[bird chirping]
[gunshot]
[grunting]
[music playing]
[beeping]
[typing]
Thank you.
[beeping]
Shit.
Mr. Quill?
Something strange is happening
to my computer terminal.
Lisa, just call somebody and
have them look at it for you.
LISA: Yes sir, it's
just that it seems
to be locked onto some
kind of priority message.
Well, tell me what it says.
LISA: Priority level one,
missing signal property number
N1708A, contact reestablished.
Hi, Lisa why don't
you take a break?
Thank you.
[phone ringing]
[typing]
Son of a bitch.
This is Quill, is Jack back yet?
Well, then send Leo to meet
me in tracking, right away.
Dump whatever you're working on.
Don't be ridiculous, I've
been working on this program
all morning.
I want property
tracking on N1708A, now.
Yes sir.
[typing]
Here's the good part, sir.
[buzzing]
[beeping]
[fast beeping]
[music playing]
Hey, Monica, you
need some help?
Hi Michael.
No thanks, I can manage.
How's things?
Good, I can't complain.
Even if I did, nobody
would listen to me.
Aren't you up here
a little early?
You know hunting season doesn't
start for another three weeks.
Yeah, well I figured I'd get
a head start on some cleaning.
Besides, I promised
Billings and Freddie I'd
come up early this season.
Do they know you're here?
They always know
when I'm here.
I never could figure that out.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
I'd love one, thank you.
I'll be damned.
[music playing]
Monica, I think you've
got some company.
[laughing]
[kissing]
Freddie!
Good to see you again, Mike.
Billings!
Hello Freddie.
Don't you hello Freddie me.
OK, what did I
do wrong this time?
It ain't what you did,
it's what you didn't do.
What?
Signs, mister, that's what.
You promised to post
those no hunting
signs near our property, and
you haven't posted one yet.
Just take it easy, Freddie,
I made you a promise,
and I'll keep that promise.
Come on inside for
a second, Freddie.
I've got a surprise for you.
You'll have to
excuse Freddie, Mike.
He hasn't had anyone to
yell at all winter but me.
Oh, that's all right.
If he wouldn't yell at
me, I'd think the old kook
was coming down with something.
Look Billings, Monica just
bought old Freddie a new hat.
Ain't she sweet?
She sure is, Freddie.
I've got some fresh
coffee on the stove,
why don't I cook up some
ham and eggs for you fellas?
That sounds good to me.
Sounds great.
How about you,
Mike, breakfast?
Oh, I'd love to
baby, but I've got
a million and one things to do.
Y'all have a good day.
Take care of yourself.
I do hope one of those
you've got to do today
is hanging them signs.
[printing]
Mr. Quill?
Leo.
Come with me, please.
You're probably
wondering by now, Leo,
why a company like Defsat
would spend such a large amount
of money to hire a man with
your particular experience
to do simple security tasks.
It's crossed my mind.
Well it's very simple.
We've been anticipating
an event that seems
to have finally transpired.
As you already know,
Defsat Corporation
holds all the contracts
for the research
and development of the
Star Wars defense system.
These contracts are
due to the efforts
of one man, Charles Biggums.
Two years ago, somebody
attempted to assassinate
Biggums, he obviously escaped.
Now our problem is that no one
has seen him or the designs
since.
Do you think he's in
less than friendly hands?
No, but I made the decision
to keep his disappearance
extremely confidential.
So nobody knows he's missing?
No one.
If his disappearance
was made public,
it would mean the end of Defsat.
And I won't let that happen.
What's the situation?
We finally located
the computer disk
containing Biggums' designs.
I need you to get them, no
matter what the expense.
Do you have any idea what
I should expect to find?
This is all the
information you will need.
Yes sir, that was a
fine breakfast, Monica.
I'm glad you
enjoyed it, Freddie.
Any time.
You know it's important
for a man of my age
to get a proper meal,
once in a while.
You complaining about
my cooking again, Freddie?
Well, not exactly.
Well, maybe if you
ask Monica real nice,
she'll come up tomorrow
night, cook us some dinner.
I'd love to.
Tomorrow night it is.
Come on, Billings,
let's get a move on.
I'm going to shoot
us a wild turkey
for tomorrow night's dinner.
[laughing]
Tomorrow night.
I hope these nights feel as
well as they did last year.
I'm sure they will, Freddie.
[ominous music playing]
Senator, it's time we started
heading back to our designated
security area.
Well, the deer
don't know that.
And I'll be damned if I'm
given up a twelve point
buck for security.
Yes sir, we understand,
but we do have certain safety
precautions to think about.
Then you think about them.
I'm gonna get that buck.
[arrow shooting]
[choking]
[typing]
[beeping]
Hey, where's my artillery?
Time you showed me the money.
Well, we got a
problem about that.
Shit happens.
Guns are expensive.
Firing pins are cheap.
[gunshots]
[laughing]
You tell them that
if they want to hit me,
they'd better send a
professional next time, hm?
[grunting]
I'll tell 'em myself.
[explosion]
You got the money?
Yeah.
Good girl.
[screaming]
Police!
I didn't do nothing!
Shut up!
Not bad.
This'll get a pretty good price.
What kind of cop are you?
A bad cop.
[gunshot]
Good morning.
Morning.
It looks like the beginning
of a beautiful day, doesn't it?
Can I help you.
Well, that all depends
on how well you know
these mountains around here.
I'm familiar
with certain areas.
What area are you looking for?
I'm looking for an area
called Dark Water Canyon.
We were told it's ideal for
the type of hunting we do.
Are you familiar with it?
Yes I am.
You cross that
mountain over there,
points yourself south, and
travel six, maybe seven miles.
Thank you.
Whoever told you about
Dark Water Canyon forgot
to tell you that
hunting season doesn't
start for another three weeks.
Three weeks, is that right?
Well, we, wouldn't want to
break any laws, would we?
We'll just take in some of
the sights, thanks again.
Shit Leo, how much
further do we have to go?
What do you got, a
lunch date with somebody?
Stop breaking my
balls, will you?
Edwards, we still going south?
Still going south, Leo.
You think that
bitch lied to us?
If she did, I'll
cut her throat.
Look, she said six or seven
miles, we've only walked about,
what, five?
Well, we're not getting any
closer sitting on our asses.
Let's go.
Leo, over here.
Looks like somebody
beat us to it,
there's footprints
all over the place.
Now what?
You find out where
these tracks are leading
to, you search the plane.
[gunshots]
What is it?
Snake, big one.
Relax!
Everything's all right.
Just search the fucking plane.
Leo!
These tracks lead to
the top of the crevasse.
Nothing, a first
aid kit and a blanket.
Shit.
Edwards!
You take Peterson and O'Neil
and follow those tracks.
Check the bodies, see
if there's some ID.
I'm not touching that asshole.
You work for me,
you do as you're told.
Now do it.
[music playing]
Well?
I'm looking, all right?
Bingo, let's go.
Hello?
[gunshots]
Don't shoot!
You could have killed me.
No shit, sit down.
You alone?
Were those your tracks
back at the plane?
What's your name?
Who are you guys?
Answer the questions.
What is this?
I told you guys to
follow the tracks.
We did, they belong to him.
Careful, Leo, he looks
a little dangerous.
If you say my name once more,
I'm gonna blow your face off.
Sorry.
Did you find a
plane back there?
Yes, sir.
Now, this next question
is very important.
And if I think
you're lying to me,
I'm going to have that man
put a bullet in your head.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Did you take anything
from that plane?
No, sir.
The little bastards lying.
Boy Scouts don't lie, do they?
No, sir.
I didn't think so.
How much time's
left before dark?
About four hours.
OK.
You four stay here,
you come with me.
What's happening?
We're going back to
the car and report in,
we'll be back in the morning.
Morning?
We'll freeze to death out here
without sleeping bags and shit.
He's right.
Hey, you've got a Boy Scout.
Have him build you a fire.
[laughing]
What an asshole.
Mm-hmm.
You're up to your ass in
it this time, Billings,
and you know it.
There's an old Taoist saying,
Freddie, that attention centers
not on things in
their state of being,
but upon their
movements and change.
Horse shit.
Check mate.
What?
You're a back shooter, Billings.
That's what you did, I
left my back door open,
you shot me right in the back.
Mmm, you smell great.
Oh?
Mm-hm.
Your cooking smells good, too.
Two out of three isn't bad.
What's number three?
You'll find out later.
Now if you don't
stop kissing my neck,
dinner is never
going to be ready.
Why don't you go in there and
cut up those vegetables for me.
That should keep those hands
of yours busy for a while.
That's a lot of
vegetables for three people.
Oh I forgot, I'm sorry, John.
What?
I invited Mike up to
dinner, I hope you don't mind.
- No, not at all.
- Are you sure?
I should have asked you and
Freddie first, I'm sorry.
Don't be silly.
Mike's welcome here any time.
What time did he say
he's going to be here?
Well, he said he'd be up
after he finished posting his no
hunting signs for Freddie.
Unless he went over
to Dark Water Canyon.
What would he go down
to Dark Water Canyon for?
I called Mike this morning
about a group of strange men
I talked to that wanted
to do some hunting up
around Dark Water Canyon.
When I told them hunting
season hadn't started yet,
they went up anyway.
What do you mean by strange?
I don't know, I guess
the way they acted.
They had a real
city way about them.
One of them had a
.45 under his jacket.
I mean, what do you
hunt with a .45?
[music playing]
Hey Boy Scout, you got
food in that pack of yours?
Yeah.
Well fix us something to eat.
You got a problem with that?
[unzipping]
Hey I'm freezing
my ass off over here.
Put some more wood in the fire.
Man what I can do with
a nice porterhouse
steak, a baked potato,
and a cold beer right now.
Hey shut up, will you?
Hurry up with that food.
You know I remember once
eating nothing but rat meat
and cold rice for
three months straight.
Why?
I was a POW in Vietnam.
[cocks gun]
You ever eat a rat, boy?
No, sir.
Hey Boy Scout.
What brings you up in
these woods, anyway.
I'm working on a badge.
What kind of badge?
Survival batch.
It's called the
Order of the Eagle.
I was a Cub Scout once.
I got kicked out,
for eating a brownie.
[laughing]
Now that's good
one, I like that one.
Huh?
You get it, for
eating a brownie.
[laughing]
MIKE: Hello?
Hello out there.
Put 'em down, put 'em down!
Relax.
One word out of you, and I'll
blow your fucking brains out,
understand?
- Good evening.
Been up here doing
a little hunting?
No, no.
Just doing a little
camping, Ranger.
Mm.
You know there's
no camping up here,
and that mean no campfire,
so put out your fire.
What's your name, son?
GREG: Greg, sir.
You all right, son?
Get lost.
What did you say?
I said get lost.
Turn around when
you talk to me.
I said, turn around!
[gunshots]
[music playing]
My fucking leg!
You stupid son of a bitch.
[gunshot]
[gunshots]
Oh!
- You see which way he went?
- No.
Go to the left,
you take the right.
Fuck.
[thud]
[gunshots]
Got a hit.
Logan!
Hey, what are you, deaf?
[punch]
[thud]
LEO: (ON PHONE) Yes
sir, we found the plane.
Biggums is dead.
We didn't find
anything in the plane,
but I have reason to believe
that the Boy Scout did it.
I see.
Well, that's not
very good is it?
Where's the Boy Scout now?
LEO: (ON PHONE) He's
with the rest of my men.
He's not going anywhere.
Good, see that he doesn't.
Now here are your instructions.
You are to be at the pickup
location in the morning.
I will have a man by the name
of Jack LaRouse flown in,
you will take him to the
wreckage, at which point
he will take over the operation.
Is that clear?
LEO: (ON PHONE) Yes, sir.
Oh, by the way
Leo, Mr. LaRouse
is to have full cooperation
from you and your men.
Am I understood?
LEO: (ON PHONE) Yes sir,
everything's under control.
Good.
I'm starving my ass
off, standing out here.
Are you sure there was no
one left in that trading post?
I'm positive.
[airplane approaching]
Well it's about fucking time.
[music playing]
Jack, Leo.
I--
You'll have to
excuse my tracker,
he's not much of a
conversationalist.
I'll say.
Are you Jack LaRouse?
Why, is someone else
getting off the airplane?
I'm Leo, this is O'Neil.
Pleasure.
Excuse me, will you?
You won't forget what we
discussed about the pickup,
will you?
Well, let's get on
with it, shall we?
Jack, you might want to
know where we're going.
Why?
My track seems to know already.
Don't look at me.
[birds chirping]
Well, good morning.
Welcome back to the living.
Where am I?
Never mind where
you are right now,
let's just take a look
at that head of yours.
You know, you remind me of
a little dog I once found,
that had been beaten so much,
that when you tried to pet it,
it tried to bite your hand off.
I think a proper
introduction is needed here.
I'm Freddie.
Greg.
Now that wasn't
so bad, was it?
Let's see what we got here.
Ah.
Easy does it, now.
Old Freddie ain't ate
a young boy like you
for breakfast in a long time.
[laughing]
GREG: How bad is it?
Well, let's put it this way.
It ain't nothing a good
old breakfast won't fix.
You get some rest,
while Freddie sees
about rustling up some grub.
Freddie?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Shit, save you
thanks for Billings,
he was the one that got
you out of that rash
of shit last night.
[monica humming]
Oh, you're up.
Good morning.
Morning.
So you're the one who
spoiled my dinner last night.
- Sorry.
- It's OK, I'm only teasing.
Hi, I'm Monica.
I'm-- I'm Greg.
Do you know where
my clothes are?
Well, yeah, your pants and
your shoes are right here.
I'm afraid your shirt had
quite a bit of blood on it,
but I can get that out.
I can find you an old t-shirt
to wear in the meantime.
OK.
Don't worry, I didn't
undress you, Freddie did.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'll get you a t-shirt.
[laughing]
O'NEIL: (VOICEOVER) You alone?
You alone?
Are those your
tracks back there?
Just answer that questions.
Are those your
tracks back there?
LEO: (VOICEOVER) Now this next
question is very important.
And if I think
you're lying to me,
I'm going to have this man
put a bullet in your head.
MONICA: I found an old
t-shirt of Freddie's for you.
Greg?
Freddie, run and
get Billings, quick.
Hey, I think you
better get back in here.
He's just been
standing there, staring.
Let me have some
time with him.
Here, come on, Freddie,
let's go get breakfast.
- They killed him.
- Who?
The Ranger, they killed him.
OK, relax.
No, you don't understand.
If they find me, they're
going to kill me too.
I should have never taken
that stupid briefcase
from that plane.
We've got to call the police.
There's no phones here.
What?
I got to get out of here.
- Take it--
No, I got to go!
Let me go!
Listen to me!
Running around in an
area that you don't know
isn't the smartest thing
to do right now, is it?
Is it?
No, but if they find me,
they're going to kill me.
Hey!
Who saved your ass last night?
You did.
Yeah.
And I'm not about to let
anything happen to you now.
OK?
Why don't you tell
me how you got
yourself into all this trouble.
Come on.
While you're over there,
loosen that tourniquet.
What do I look like, a nurse?
What's so funny?
The look on Leo's face
when you tell him a Boy Scout
took us down.
You got a real stupid sense
of humor, you know that?
Hello Greg, have a seat.
I hope you like eggs.
How would you like your
eggs this morning, John?
Oh, I won't be eating
this morning, thanks.
I'll be back in a while.
Would it be too much for
me to ask where you're going?
Yes, it would.
Can I expect you for lunch?
You bet.
Come on.
Excuse me.
Billings.
Look, Freddie.
Look, Freddie, my ass.
Where the hell you get
off leaving me in the dark
when there's trouble?
There's no time to
explain right now.
Bullshit.
Either you tell me, or I'm
going in and getting my gun
and go with you.
All right.
The men that were
after Greg last night
may still be out there.
I want to know where they are.
I need you here.
Have a gun ready, just be ready
to move out if we have to.
You get your ass back here in
one piece, do you understand?
I plan to.
[music playing]
[beeping]
Come on.
Did you hear that?
What?
It better be Leo.
Maybe it's that Boy
Scout, come back to get us.
Relax, it's him.
What the fuck happened to him?
Where's the boy?
He got away last night.
He what?
Excuse me.
It wasn't our fault, Leo.
A ranger showed up to
the campsite last night,
he had to be dealt with.
Bastard tried to kill
Johnson, so I shot him.
That's when the kid got away.
And just like that,
you let him get away.
We ran after him
all right, but there
was somebody out there waiting.
What the fuck is
he talking about?
It's no bullshit, Leo.
Whoever they were, they
tore into us like a shark.
Yeah but the kid isn't
going to get far on his own,
we found blood.
It was a definite hit.
This is great.
Leo, you are certain
this is the scientist.
Yeah, it's him, all right.
I've got his ID in my pocket.
Who is this guy, Leo?
My name is Jack
LaRouse, and I'm taking
charge of this operation.
From here on, you will be taking
your instructions from me.
Is that clear?
Is that right, Leo?
That's what the
man said, isn't it?
And now, if you'll
be so kind as to
show me where it was
that you lost the boy.
You think you can make
it back to the cabin?
I think so.
Well, tell Freddie
and Monica to get
everything ready, because
they're gonna have to move out.
All right?
- OK.
Go.
[music playing]
What are we gonna
do with Johnson?
My tracker will see to it
that he's made comfortable.
We'll pick him up
on our way back.
Get me out of these
fucking mountains.
It won't be long.
Logan, you lead the way.
[grunting]
This is where we
lost sight of them.
So you got a hit?
We did.
There's more leading
in that direction.
And where was it that you
were attacked last night?
About 25 yards over there.
Edwards went right, I went left.
Track.
[music playing]
Where's Billings?
He's watching those men.
I'll get my gun and
you show me where he is.
No, he told us to pack
up and get ready to move.
Damn.
What's going on?
Billings wants us to pack up.
That bad, huh?
I guess so.
Here, I got the blood
out and it's almost dry.
Thank you.
No, that's OK, you keep it.
You might need it.
Monica, you get the packs, and
I'll get my gun from the shed.
OK.
Greg, you get the
shells from the mount.
How many do you
think there were?
Couldn't have been
more than three.
[music playing]
Do you know what those are?
Yeah, they're
Purple Heart medals.
Are they yours?
No, they're Billings', they
were given to him in Vietnam.
How'd he get them?
I'll tell you that
story another time.
Come on, let's get
those shotguns loaded.
How many?
Five men, well
what do you expect?
I don't think you understand.
My tracker indicated five,
that included the three
of you and the Boy Scout.
That leaves one.
That's bullshit, Leo, no
one guy's gonna take us out.
It's quite obvious,
Mr. Logan, that you
are not qualified to make
that affirmation, now are you?
Are you sure he's
not making a mistake?
A mistake has already
been made, last night, Leo.
All right.
I don't want to
discuss this anymore.
Let's just find the kid,
and get this shit over with.
I believe it's this way.
Freddie?
Why do you think Billings
come up here to live?
To get away from
all the bullshit.
See Greg, up here
you ain't got nobody
to answer to but yourself.
Down there, you got a
whole world of assholes,
trying to tell you what to do,
how to do it, when to do it.
And if you don't do it,
you ain't got the rent.
Living like that will make
you old before you die,
and that's a fact.
You listen to old Freddie.
[music playing]
You and Billings been
friends a long time, huh?
Billings and my boy used
to raise hell together
when they were teenagers.
Where's your boy now?
Dead.
Died in some rice paddy,
that lousy Asian war.
Billings is the one that
brought my boy's body home.
Never forget the
day we buried him--
cold, raining, and Billings
standing there with his uniform
on, three Purple Hearts.
He was a hero, huh?
Yes he was.
Captured three times,
escaped three times.
Freddie, he's been
gone a long time.
Don't you worry
about Billings.
MIKE: Canteen's full and
I'm working on a pack.
You a good shot?
[gunshot]
[music playing]
Freddie, Billings is back!
What's happening?
We're getting the hell out
of here, is what's happening.
Where we going to?
You know those big rocks
we found last spring?
The ones by the lake?
I want the three of you to
go over there and wait for me.
What are you planning to do?
I've got to buy a little time.
I don't suppose you'd
want me to go with you.
I do not.
I didn't think so.
Ya!
How much did you pack?
Enough for three days.
You want me to pack more?
No, I don't have time.
OK.
If we need food, I can
catch rabbits with this.
Can I stay and help?
No, I'll be there soon enough.
Well, Greg, let's
get a shake on.
I'll see you soon?
Yeah.
Go.
That, gentlemen, is
your night stalker.
Let's see how he
does during the day.
Excuse me.
I was hoping perhaps
that you could help us.
Depends on what it is.
First off, let me
introduce myself.
I'm Jack LaRouse, you are?
John Billings.
We've already met.
I believe we have.
Lower That rifle,
mister, or use it.
There's no need for
that, Mr. Peterson,
I think Mr. Billings understands
the potential of the situation.
Now then, if you'd be so kind
as to tell us the whereabouts
of the Boy Scout?
Sent him in that
direction on a horse.
That wasn't very good
of you, Mr. Billings.
Well, it seemed like the
thing to do at the time.
If you'll excuse me,
I've got some work to do.
You're gonna let him
walk away like that?
Relax Mr. Peterson,
everything is under control.
Mr. Billings!
Jack, what the
hell is going on?
Leo, would you bring Mr.
Billings back outside please?
O'Neil.
[crashing]
[music playing]
[gunshot]
[gunshots]
[cocking gun]
He's only got a fucking
Winchester, let's rush him.
[gunshot]
Splendid idea, Mr.
Edwards, be my guest.
We gonna sit around
all day and play
with this asshole or what?
We're going rush
this son of a bitch!
Now!
[gunshots]
[crashing]
He went out the back
window, he's got a briefcase!
[gunshots]
[grunting]
[groaning]
[gunshots]
[splashing]
All right, cut it.
Hold your fire, damn it!
He's not coming up.
Where the hell is he?
He's dead, he's
got to be dead.
Oh, you think so?
This guy don't
got to be nothing.
This is just beautiful, Leo.
No Boy Scout, no
mountain man, nothing.
Not a fucking thing.
JACK LAROUSE: We should
look elsewhere, gentlemen.
I really don't think
he'll be coming up here.
No shit, Sherlock.
Shut up.
Which way, Jack?
Is your bloodhound
still with us?
[music playing]
Indeed, he is.
Indeed my ass.
How long do you think
we'll have to stay here?
Well, that all
depends on what Billings
finds out about those men.
We'll be all right.
There's plenty of fresh
water, and enough food to last
us for at least three days.
If we're lucky, maybe Freddie
will catch some rabbits,
and make us some
of his rabbit stew.
Right, Freddie?
He's taking too long.
I don't like it.
No sir, not one bit.
Freddie, why don't you come
over here and keep us company?
John will be here soon enough.
Yeah, come on, Freddie.
He's in trouble,
I can feel it.
And I'm standing like some old
woman watching her laundry dry.
I'm going after him.
Freddie, John told us
to wait here for him.
That's right, Freddie.
Well he ain't here.
And if he does need
my help, I'm gonna
shoot some son of a bitch.
Freddie, don't wander too far.
So stubborn sometimes.
Make me leave
my home, I'll blow
that damn fool's brain's out.
[gunshot]
Show your face, you
silly little bastard.
Drop the shotgun, or
I'll blow your brains
all over these woods.
Now.
Somebody's coming.
Where's Freddie?
He went looking for you.
He what?
I told him to stay here.
That's what we told them,
but he wouldn't listen.
You know how he gets.
I'll go get him.
No, you stay put.
Those men will be combing
this are in no time.
They won't be able
to find us here.
Don't bet on that.
I knew they weren't hunters.
Oh, they're
hunters, all right.
How long's Freddie been gone?
10 minutes.
OK, I'm going to try to go
and find Freddie before they do.
Is there anything I can do?
Yeah, hold onto these,
be ready to move out.
I don't think we're gonna
be staying here very long.
[music playing]
I tell you, man, I'm
living up here by myself.
That's not what these
tracks say, old man.
Damn it, Freddie.
He's back.
Oh no.
Where's Freddie?
- They've got him.
- We've got to save him.
We're not gonna
do it staying here.
Leave everything
but the shotguns,
we've got to move
fast, let's go.
Leo, have some of your men
circle out about 70 yards
or so, just in case.
Peterson, you and Edwards.
No need, they're not going
anywhere without their friend.
Mr. Billings!
I know you're watching.
You won't keep us waiting
long, now, will you?
How many men do
you see down there?
- Five.
- There were seven before.
Where are the other two?
That's a good question.
How are we going to
get Freddie out of there?
don't know, but it's
not going to be easy.
How fast can you run?
Fast.
Good, because the
Ranger's station
is a mile east from here.
I want you and Greg to make a
run for it while I try to get
Freddie out of that cave.
So that's what you
were trying to do,
you were going to have them
chase us right to the Ranger.
Yeah, well it seemed like
a good idea at the time.
What are you going to do?
I'm gonna see if I can't
draw them out of that cave.
Knock them off one
by one like Rambo?
Like who?
You know, Rambo.
The guy who runs through the
jungle and kills the enemy.
There were guys in
Nam like that, right?
Yeah.
What are they called?
Dead.
Well, this ought
to be high enough.
Yeah, I'll stay here.
Why don't you go check
some lower ground.
Man, I can't wait to
get back to the city.
Hey, Peterson, you
got an extra clip?
I'm a little low.
There's no such
thing as an extra clip.
Thanks, asshole.
Don't mention it.
Mr. Billings!
Time is running out!
For every 10
minutes that I wait,
your friend inside will suffer
considerably, starting now!
Listen to me, both of you.
I'm gonna run in that direction.
When those two men open fire at
me, you'll know where they are.
That's when you run for
the Ranger's, understand?
Now Greg, I want you to stay
a ways back from Monica, that
way you can cover her back, OK?
Yeah.
Good.
Give me the disks.
Now, Freddie's life
depends on this, you ready?
[music playing]
[gunshots]
[gunshot]
Drop the weapon.
Well, if it's not the
trading post lady.
Where'd you think
you were going?
To get some help, huh?
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
Run, Greg.
Yeah, well, what about you?
There's not enough time, run!
You got the guts
to pull that trigger?
Don't take another step.
Shotguns are awfully messy.
You pull that trigger,
you're gonna splatter me
all over this forest.
You want to see that?
Yeah, I didn't think so.
[gunshot]
[grunting]
[gunshots]
Hey Tracker, you want to eat?
I've never seen
him eat, nor sleep.
He doesn't speak much either.
I think you'd
find it difficult
talking without a tongue,
don't you think, Leo?
Leo, what time is it?
3:30, why?
Not long before
our pickup time.
Uh, Jack, 10 minutes is up.
I'm sorry to hear that.
So what are you going
to do with the old nigger?
I never cared much
for that expression.
Neither have I.
My mistake.
Very nice.
Very nice, indeed.
Where did you get it?
I made it.
I commend you on
your craftsmanship.
I, too, am an admirer
of the cutlery weapons.
Do you like it, Freddie?
No.
Seems that your friends
don't care that much about you,
do they?
[groaning]
Hang in there, Freddie.
[grunting]
Is the old man dead?
Is that a conscience I hear?
No, I was just wondering how
our ace in the hole was doing,
that's all.
The pilot's on
the walkie talkie,
he wants to know the
location of the pickup.
Thank you.
[groaning]
[music playing]
Are you ready for
another session, Freddie?
LOGAN: This is a bunch
of bullshit, Leo.
We're wasting time.
LEO: Jack.
Yes?
LEO: We've tried this before.
It's not getting us anywhere.
Leo's right.
We've got 12 minutes
before the pickup, Jack.
Perhaps you have something
more persuasive in mind
for getting Mr.
Billings to come down.
I do.
[music playing]
Billings!
This is your last chance!
I want the boy and the
briefcase down here now,
or I'm going to put a
bullet in this old man.
You've got three
minutes, starting now.
Do you hear me, Billings?
[gunshot]
Give me the gun.
Give me it.
Leo!
O'Neil?
Don't shoot, we're coming in.
You owe me one, Leo.
I stopped him from putting a
bullet in your head just now.
[smack]
What are you doing?
- That was for last night.
That'll be enough, Mr. Logan.
I found Edwards, too.
He was hanging upside down in
a tree with a bullet in him.
[grunting]
- You've been busy.
Your tracker's dead, too.
[grunting]
Search him.
I'll take those, thank you.
We got what we came for,
let's get rid of these two,
and get the hell out of here.
Where's the boy?
He's dead, one of
your men shot him.
Why don't you show
me where the body is?
Suit yourself.
Forget it, Jack.
If we're not at that pickup
site when the pilot gets there,
he's going to leave without us.
I suppose you're right, Leo.
Why don't you and your men
leave for the plane now.
I'll be there shortly.
Whatever you say Jack,
just don't be late.
[music playing]
This way, please.
There it is.
I can't wait to get the
hell outta these mountains.
No shit.
That'll be far
enough, thank you.
Friendly little
asshole, isn't he?
That thing's kind of
small for eight men.
You're right.
What the f--
[gunshots]
Your turn.
Got any last words?
Who do you really
work for, LaRouse?
That all depends.
I suppose one could call me a
custom-approved representative,
of shall we say, a country
with opposing political views.
At the moment, these disks
are worth a great deal.
On your knees, Mr. Billings.
No.
Very well, good
bye, Mr. Billings.
[gunshots]
Drop it, mister.
[gunshot]
Freddie!
It's all over, you're
going to be all right.
Where's Monica?
Monica.
RECEPTIONIST: Mr. Quill,
the FBI is here to see you.
I'll be out in a moment.
[music playing]
[gunshot]
To get away from
all the bullshit.
I thought I saw
somebody come in here.
Monica.
I've been wondering
when you'd show up.
It's been a while.
I know.
After the hearing, my mother
sent me to Europe to live
with my sister for a while.
Where are they?
They went away, higher
into the mountains.
I feel like it's all my fault.
Some things happen
for a reason, Greg.
You can't change that.
You think you'll
ever see them again?
Yeah.
How do you know?
They always seem to
know when I'm here.
I never could
figure that one out.
Come on, let's go for a walk.