Cowards!
Reactionaries!
Geezers!
Morons!
Assholes!
Weaklings!
...let me...
let me redo that bit...
Should I?
Shadows!... VADE RETRO!
Virum vireta
Shut my mouth
Virum virarum
They've already shut it
On our dear old bitch of an Earth
in the year 2000 and something...
On our dear bitch of an Earth
in the year 2000 and...
Our dear bitch of an Earth,
depopulated, big explosions
Great powers agreed on lasting peace
Two wires wrong connection
... BOOM!
ZOHOMMM
alias "Laser-in-the-Eyes"
SHUICK
alias "Radioactive-Petal"
GRRR
alias "Loose Screw"
there will be a time...
The road of excess leads
to the palace of wisdom. - W. Blake
: for instance, Chuang-tzu's dream
ZOHOMMM:... Borges
is a great writer...
GRRR:... yet he positioned himself
against the Cuban Revolution...
24 centuries ago he dreamed
that he was a butterfly
ZOHOMMM:... but
he is a great writer...
GRRR:... yet he positioned himself
against the Cuban Revolution...
when he woke up he didn't know
if he was a man dreaming
that he was a butterfly...
...or a butterfly dreaming
that it was a man.
ZOHOMMM:... but
he is a great writer...
GRRR:... yet he positioned himself
against the Cuban Revolution...
neither I nor anyone else
can travel this road for you
GRRR: Don't take a single needle
or piece of thread from the masses
THE THREE MAIN RULES OF DISCIPLINE:
1) OBEY ORDERS IN ALL YOUR ACTIONS
2) DON'T TAKE A SINGLE NEEDLE
OR PIECE OF THREAD FROM THE MASSES
3) TURN IN EVERYTHING CAPTURED
GRRR: Don't take a single needle
or piece of thread from the masses.
THE EIGHT POINTS FOR ATTENTION:
1) SPEAK POLITELY.
2) PAY FAIRLY FOR WHAT YOU BUY.
3) RETURN EVERYTHING YOU BORROW.
4) PAY FOR
ANYTHING YOU DAMAGE.
5) DON'T HIT OR SWEAR AT PEOPLE.
6) DON'T DAMAGE CROPS.
7) DON'T TAKE LIBERTIES WITH WOMEN
8) DON'T ILL-TREAT CAPTIVES
GRRR: Don't take a single needle
or piece of thread from the masses.
"Instruction of the General Headquarters
of the Chinese People's Liberation Army"
(October 10, 1947) Mao Tse-tung, Vol. IV
GRRR: Don't take a single needle
or piece of thread from the masses.
GRRR - Good...
ZOHOMMM - Evil...
GRRR - Very good!
GRRR (he speaks in Basa, then translates)
- I say to my friend
that this Shuick
I know a lot, starlet,
made a screen test... science-fiction,
a film about the past, about '68...
people in trousers, shirts,
really funny thing...
me work interplanetary drive-in...
no problem...
I'm sure I can bring her to you
ZOHOMMM - Good...
GRRR - Aren't you convinced?...
ZOHOMMM - My grandfather told me
that at the explosion of the Great Mushroom
no one wanted to believe it...
excuse me, one question...
no, nothing...
nothing?
that's it
to you, sir... a very simple question:
do you think...
no sir, please...
okay, you can move, sir...
do you think that
the atom bomb could explode or not?
Let's hope so!
today?
not today...
...tomorrow yes
...please...
it's a question,
can't I ask?
no, nothing, nothing, nothing,
this is how
liberty gets abused,
this man is sitting there peacefully...
GRRR - My grandfather also said
that in these years '66-'68
he was a guerilla with Che Guevara
in Bolivia... (he cries)
GRRR - Here is my pledge of friendship...
in case you die
to die together
GRRR - the girl...
I'll bring her to you...
THE STALLION AND THE GAZELLE
This is Shuick!
This is Zohommm!
I wonder if stars
really have little points?
No, that's due to our astigmatism,
it's an optical illusion
caused by irregularities of the cornea.
My optometrist says that
mild astigmatism is normal
and keeps us from seeing
stars as round points of light
Your optometrist has ruined
the joy of looking at the stars for me.
IN A PLANETARY WEEKEND
IN A PLANETARY WEEKEND,
but...
Where are we?
Diagram on the fall of a head
...and to this end we formed
an army of robots." (noises)
CYBERNETIC PROPHETESS (OFF) -
Beautiful fool
Beautiful fool Beautiful fool,
what are you doing?
what are you doing? what are you doing?
Problems problems problems
much more difficult
much more difficult much more difficult
than yours than yours than yours
we have resolved
we have resolved we have resolved.
But but but
the whole truth
the whole truth the whole truth,
only the truth
only the truth only the truth
and nothing but nothing but
nothing but the truth
but the truth but the truth.
Perhaps perhaps perhaps
I could help you
A RECURRING DREAM
THE ACCUSED
THE TRIBUNAL
THE SENTENCE
WE THANK ALL THE MOST FAMOUS
INTERNATIONAL BANANOLOGISTS
WHO HAVE OFFERED THEIR COLLABORATION
IN CROSSING
MORE THAN 500 TYPES OF BANANAS
TO CREATE A
BANANA MASTERPIECE
CHIQUITA EXCELLENCE PRIZE
END
THE TRUTH!
CYBERNETIC PROPHETESS (OFF) -
For me For me For me
that is a problem
of normal administration
But But But, my dear
my dear my dear,
on thing one thing one thing
you must you must you must
promise me promise me promise:
start over
start over start over
a normal life
a normal life a normal life
with Zohommm
with Zohommm with Zohommm.
There!
There is the formula
That is the magic formula!:
"I came to tell you this:
we don't care
what you do on your planet,
but if you try
to extend your violence,
your Earth will be reduced to ashes.
ZOHOMMM
Shuick is mine! A man is his head!
GRRR: Shuick is mine!
A man is his cock!
May I?:
ALL-THE-MEMORY-OF-THE-WORLD,
Professor and hibernator...
the great refusal
ALL-THE-MEMORY-OF-THE-WORLD (off):
...a rag picker of memory...
GRRR - You...
ZOHOMMM -...give us...
SHUICK -...solution!
GRRR - We come You Great Master
expose great problem Stop
he cut head friend
I cut head friend his fault
she coquette marries friend
stick his head my body
my head his body Stop
to who belong Shuick?
ZOHOMMM - Me cut off head
jealousy him Stop
evaporated Shuick
stick mixed up heads Stop
without cut head him
she stick head good Stop
SHUICK - Great Greater
Greatest Master
Illustrious Excellent Commander
Professor Honorable
Excellence Holiness
he Zohommm he Grrr shameless! Stop
me Shuick poor thing
Stop Stop Stop Thank you
ALL-THE-MEMORY-OF-THE-WORLD (off):
... real debris
of this scientistic,
scientifascistic humanity,
mechanistic and explosionist...
MARCUSE CONTESTED
BY... COHN-BENDIT
knowledge in a dizzying way
and thus confusion
beyond the fear and the desire
the impulse to know
Irrationality of acculturation
the image can be a method of
general orientation
a new dramaturgy
Hollywood or Moscow
the same thing
one is a traitor in the cinema
as in politics
the recorded image belongs
half to the one who made it,
half to the one looking or listening to it
technology today
(8mm, magnetic tape)
is simpler
New Cinema
made
by those who have never made cinema
no one
may speak
in place for others
(absent)
to experiment on the technological vocabulary
Underground: It's important,
that it's not important.
just playing
the camera on your friends
on things you love
without
submitting yourself to
stressed out productions
money
XXX people
wretched fraud
just playing
the camera on your friends
on things you love
you make a film
the current revolutionary moment
is heterogeneous
internationally coherent
not perfect
"perfect" cinema = reactionarY cinema
the linguistic trap:
the cinema in the cinema
a new filmmaker
has to commit suicide as a filmmaker
Cinema Nôvo
question of style
not New Cinema:
New Cinemas
everything is permitted
16mm and Cinemascope
Underground and the big markets
break
with revolutionary cultural politics,
that have become stratified
we have decided
to be militant in cinema
(personal expression of the author)
Latin America
200,000,000 hectares
Masters neither of their own land
nor of their own ideas
everyday reality = violence
cinema of class
cinema-act
cinema-action
cinema-liberation
Every spectator
is either
a coward
or
a traitor
F.Fanon
Cinema of decolonization
subversive creativity
against alienated imagination
Third world
Third cinema
DEATH TO YANKEE IMPERIALISM
ALL-THE - Virum vireta
Shut my mouth
virum virarum
They've already shut it
ALL-THE - OPUS! POCUS! MOCUS!
ALL-THE-MEMORY
(declares ambiguously, to Grrr):
Man has two heads.
Head cock order body,
body order head man
: she be yours.
ALL-THE-MEMORY
(declares ambiguously, to Zohommm):
Man has two heads.
Head man order body,
Body order head cock (he sneers)
: Shuick be yours, Yours, yours.
GRRR (off) -
Then I'm leaving... alone...
at the edge of the galaxy
of the uncommunicated...
very, very far, veeeery far away...
...mama...
ALL-THE-MEMORY-OF-THE-WORLD
Contest, contest, children, contest
we're cont...
I'm contesting myself...
you're contesting yourself
they're contesting themselves
I'm cont... cont... cont...
you're contesting yourselves
they're contesting themselves
UNDER AGE 21
here is your BALLOT
(Contest! Contest! Contest!)
we're contesting ourselves
bourgeois left
I'm contesting myself/everything
we're ourselves
yes yes I agree...
BOURGEOIS
YOU HAVEN'T
UNDERSTOOD ANYTHING
YOU
...that with leftist kulture
The Kulture!
I have nothing more to do
with the bourgeois left...
THE IMAGINATION TAKES POWER
...
TO INVENT MEANS TO TAKE
THE POWER OF THE FUTURE
bourgeois
I have nothing m...
The metaphor! Imago... there!
Is it the alchemist's stone?
which is to be understood as
the dream of humanity that empties
conventional poetic language,
in a revolutionary way...
primitive
old dream!
ulture... cult... ture... ture... ture...
babbles or...
(UNTRANSLATABLE
NEAPOLITAN SWEARING)
do we have?...
and corporate prid...
ains the grotesque... the grotesque?
attains the grotesque?
fascist action...
fascist...
fascistish...
(fucking virgin!...
we left that too...)
fascifying
and then for help
provocations of fasci...
fascistisants
he called for help
he called the police for help
he conducted repress...
called for heeeelp!!!
the polic...
...pression
our contact... and...
occup... first the poli
and then he called on the workers
his contact
our contact
with the working class
came about
at two...
yes
at two o'clock in the morning in front
of a bar of the intelligentsia
yes yes
an intellectual as such
should kill himself
a thought
(End - 4)
thinking, interrupt...
interruptus
interruptus thinking
my ass!
and defended by the workers,
while he sipped his coffee
and we contested it
Kulture! KULTURE!
expression of a frankly reactionary
vision of the world
either it...
and of sensible notions...
sensibiblomysticontstipants...
Art!!! Art???
we were not capable
we werrrre nooooot caaaapable
in our discourses
we have tried
even accepting the provocations
of the student movement
his contact
our contact???!!!
our contact!!!
his contract
our contract
our contract with the working class
came about
at two o'clock in the morning on the terrace of a bar
occupied by the intelligentsia
and defended by the workers,
sipping their coffee
Psssttt
we were not!
we were not
did we get further?
we got further,
even accepting the provoc...
ShiT
"CINEMA ONLY FOR THE INSANE"
The Dark Room
liberty equality... that's enough
AT THE EDGES OF THE GALAXY
OF THE GLOBAL CONTESTERS
EX-GALAXY OF THE UNCOMMUNICATED
UNIVERSAL HISTORY OF VIOLENCE
The one aimed at us
...and the one we contest with
"For our people now understand
that violence
can take on many forms.
It is violence to sterilize people
as has been done in India and Bolivia,
it is violence to oppress people
by plundering their natural resources,
by compelling them to live in misery.
The day that our people
accept the principle
that imperialism
by its very nature
is violent,
they will know how to justify
physical violence rationally as contestation.
One of the most important
struggles of the Third World
is the struggle
to legalize violence,
for the West has convinced the people
that violence is bad."
ZOHOMMM - What should we do?
SHUICK - I could kill myself...
GRRR - Keep calm, okay...
The 3 - COMMUNISM
WILL NOT BRING ASCETICISM,
BUT JOY OF LIFE, POWER OF LIFE,
AND A SATISFIED LOVE LIFE
WILL HELP TO DO THAT.
LENIN.
ZOHOMMM/MARIO - I, Mario,
would have done everything
that the character did.
I could go away and live alone,
but, really in history,
I would lose
Either kill one and leave the other two
or one kills himself
and the two others remains
or one goes.
Killing is also a problem.
That's also a difficult solution
The best solution,
even in this situation,
is really to stick together always.
Perhaps we can change
the mentality with time.
I don't know if I expressed that well.
SHUICK/LIDIJA - I would be happy
to live with two men...
even with more than two...
even with several women...
GRRR/ISAAC -
... even a billion...
The 3 - COMMUNISM
WILL NOT BRING ASCETICISM,
BUT JOY OF LIFE, POWER OF LIFE,
AND A SATISFIED LOVE LIFE
WILL HELP TO DO THAT.
LENIN.
SHUICK/LIDIJA -
Isaac: do you love Shuick?
GRRR/ISAAC - Now that the mess
has been made... not any more
ZOHOMMM/MARIO - If you leave
she'll be sad.
GRRR/ISAAC -Zohommm
no chance for two men,
to live in one woman
SHUICK/LIDIJA - Why should I
feel guilty?
Because normally...
I introduced you.
You didn't know each other before.
Afterwards they even got married.
SHUICK/LIDIJA -
What does that have to do with...
ZOHOMMM/MARIO - Be quiet...
married or not married...
I'm happy that you made love
to her with my body.
What happened to me
could have happened to anyone.
That's not my fault.
Of course it's perhaps
a physical weakness...
SHUICK/LIDIJA -... so...
The 3 - COMMUNISM
WILL NOT BRING ASCETICISM,
BUT JOY OF LIFE, POWER OF LIFE,
AND A SATISFIED LOVE LIFE
WILL HELP TO DO THAT.
LENIN.
ALL -...yes, Yes, you said it:
but you didn't understand it.
...our homeland is the whole world
our law is liberty...
... future humanity...