[film reel clicking]
[fast instrumental]
♪♪♪
[The Marquee "One Last Time"
playing]
♪ Walking, wandering ♪
♪ Across the ocean
Shore again ♪
♪ When I think ♪
♪ Of the sunlight
in your hair ♪
♪ Then you're here
For a while ♪
♪ Ever questioning ♪
♪ Brings me back
Down to Earth again ♪
♪ And as I stand around ♪
♪ So build me up and just ♪
♪ Take me there
For one last time ♪
♪ Reaching out for you ♪
JIM: Hey,
I appreciate that, thanks.
Yeah, it was--
it was quite a shock.
I mean, we didn't even know
Dad had heart problems.
Well, they're saying
natural causes but I want
to check out
a few things while I'm out here.
I tell you what, though,
you ought to see this place.
I mean,
there's stuff everywhere.
It's like he didn't take care
of anything once Mom died.
I mean,
there's an arrowhead collection.
There's so much stuff,
this is going to take forever.
Yeah.
Well, hey, man,
I'd love to see you, too.
Hey,
we'll talk about Bosnia.
Strictly on the down low.
That's right.
Well, at ease
Staff Sergeant.
We'll catch you later.
All right,
thanks for calling, bud.
[street din]
[footsteps]
-ZEKE: Oh, hey, Jim!
-Zeke. Long time no see.
Yeah, man. Sure enough.
Are you doing all right?
-Doing good. Thanks.
-Good, man. Good. Uh...
Oh, hey.
Um, sorry about your dad.
-Thank you. Appreciate it.
-He was a good dude.
-He was.
-He was, man.
You need anything,
give me a holler.
-Will do! All seeing eye.
-All right, man.
Zeke,
you haven't changed a bit.
-You know me, man.
-Good to see you.
See you, buddy.
Hey, Major Powell.
It's good to see you again.
You too.
Man, store manager now, huh?
Yeah.
Bringing in the big bucks.
I hear you.
Place looks great, though.
Thanks.
Hey, I'm sorry
to hear about your dad.
I'm going to really
miss seeing him in here.
Yeah, I appreciate that.
Tell me something,
he show any signs of a--
-of a heart problem?
-No.
He always seemed
as healthy as a horse.
Actually, I was surprised to
hear he died of a heart attack.
-Yeah, me too.
-Hey,
he had an order
come in today.
It's already paid for.
Do you want it?
-Yeah, might as well.
-All right, give me a second.
So no warning signs, huh?
No, he was actually really
excited to get this order.
Talked about
some sort of adventure.
Why would dad order
all this camping gear?
You order
stuff like this often?
No, just a couple odds
and ends here and there.
-But--
-Well, hey, I appreciate it.
Of course.
It's good to see you again.
Yeah, you too.
See you.
Hey, Jim.
Sorry to hear about your daddy.
Hey, I appreciate that.
Thank you.
Good to see you again.
[wrapper paper crinkling]
Is that all?
Excuse me,
can you, uh, pass me
that silver thermos?
[quirky instrumental]
Don't I know you?
No, I--
I know I know you, we--
We used to have
a class together, that's it.
♪♪♪
You know,
I know I'm right.
I mean...
I could have sworn
we had chemistry.
[cashier giggles]
That didn't go
so well.
Yeah, you got
to stay away from that one.
But chemistry was
my favorite subject.
Yeah, I'm sure it was.
I had lots of lab partners.
-Anyway, thanks.
-No problem.
Hm...
I didn't know this kind of
thing happened around here.
-Excuse me?
-"Raven County woman
still missing.
Sheriff's department
still searching
Peddle Creek area
where she was last seen".
Used to not but it's been
happening more and more.
Strange.
-Anyway, thanks.
-I get off in an hour.
I can walk you home
and protect you.
You have a nice day.
You too.
[footsteps]
JIM: Dome tent.
[camp supplies rattling]
Where were you going, Dad?
Hunting? Camping trip?
Okay.
Instant mashed potatoes.
Go, Dad.
[mystical instrumental]
[rattling]
[metal clanking]
What you got
going on, Dad?
Indians and
some kind of map?
♪♪♪
[chair creaking]
-[fervent knocking]
-[dog barking]
-Jimmy! Oh!
-Hey, Squirt!
-I know.
-Mm.
I'm sorry
I wasn't here.
-[sighs]
-Dad knew we loved him.
Yeah, I know.
Gosh, I mean,
I just miss him so much.
Yeah, I do, too.
What'd Dad
used to say, though?
"You never know
how strong you are..."
"...Until being strong
is the only choice you have."
-That's it.
-DEB: You're right.
Oh! [chuckles] Sorry.
-It's okay.
-This is Janie.
-Hi.
-She's a friend.
-JIM: Hi Janie, Jim.
-Nice to meet you.
I'm so sorry
to hear about your dad.
-[Deb sighs] Yeah.
-Y'all come on in.
So uh, you and Deb
been friends long?
Mm,
a couple of months now.
-Yeah.
-We met... Deb?
-We were fighting.
-Mm.
-Fighting? Who won?
-Yeah.
-We both did.
-Uh-huh.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
-There was this guy.
-He was trash.
-Uh-huh.
-So what happened?
-We realized that we weren't.
-No--
-Hey!
[laughter]
-DEB: Yes, that's what happened.
-Yeah.
Um.
What's with all this?
Are you going off the grid?
No, that's all Dad's.
You have any idea
why he ordered all that stuff?
DEB: No,
I don't have a clue.
And his heart attack?
Yeah.
I don't know.
He had been so distant.
-Distant?
-Yeah.
Like, short tempered.
When Mom died,
he really changed.
Short fuse, you know, for Dad.
Even shorter than usual.
I don't know.
He was acting so weird.
Like how?
Just going on
and on about, like,
Native Americans
and their culture
and burial grounds
and folklore.
I don't know, I guess it was
just something he was into.
All righty, then.
Well, anyway, thanks
for being such a good friend
-to Squirt, here.
-Oh, of course. I just love her.
[chuckles]
And Squirt, huh?
So were you little kids, or...
-Yeah, that's exactly right.
-Let's just say
it was more of
a nighttime problem.
-Oh.
-Shut up! Really, Jimmy?
Well, I guess I've done
my official duty
as big brother
embarrassing my sis.
-Okay.
-I got to head out.
That's fine, because Janie
and I are going to go now
and I'm going to tell her
every embarrassing story
of Major Jimmy
in the history of Ever Dumb.
-[laughter]
-Oh, great.
[door clicks]
-Well, it was nice to meet you.
-Likewise.
And don't worry,
whatever she tells me,
my lips are sealed.
♪♪♪
[bell jingles]
Good afternoon, Sir.
How you doing?
You're Mr. Grady, right?
I'm Jim Powell.
I know who you are.
Mind if I, uh,
drag up a chair?
[chair clanking]
So Mr. Grady,
I think you knew my father.
We're going to
miss him around here.
Yeah, I think
a lot of people will.
So listen,
I was kind of hoping you might
help me with something, I was--
been over
at my dad's house,
going through
his stuff and...
he seems to have had
a lot of interesting hobbies.
You know
anything about that?
[street din]
Did Dad
hang around here a lot?
Okay,
I'll take that as a no.
He was
kind of a homebody.
Listen, boy.
Somebody that goes
looking for trouble
never misses.
-What do you mean?
-I mean,
have more sense
than your daddy did.
Pay your respects
and leave
what needs leaving alone.
Okay.
Was Dad in some
kind of trouble?
Gerald was messing
with some things that...
just ought not be.
That's what I saw.
[road din]
I did find
one odd thing.
It was a uh...
it's kind of
a piece of paper with a...
hand-drawn
arrowhead on it.
The letters O-R-O.
Does that mean
anything to you?
-Looks like a--
-Don't ever
say that
out loud around here.
Ever.
I don't understand.
[motor revving]
♪♪♪
[keyboard clicking]
Gold arrowhead.
A mountain,
an arrowhead...
and gold.
A mountain shaped
like an arrowhead
that has gold in it?
[chair creaking]
A golden arrowhead...
stuck inside of
a mountain?
[mutters] No,
that's not right.
Gold.
[scoffs]
Just not making any sense.
♪♪♪
[phone ringing]
[paper rustling]
Jim Powell.
Hello?
[beep]
[sighs]
[Steven Philips
"Lightning Road" playing]
♪ On the lightning road ♪
RADIO SHOW HOST: Stephen
Phillips with "Lightning Road".
And we are were playing
all kinds of heart, soul,
rock 'n' roll right here
on Lake 97.7--
[outdoor din]
[car door latches]
[suspenseful piano music]
♪♪♪
This is ridiculous.
Hey, Squirt,
I got a question for you.
Do you know of any,
uh, path or trail
that starts out around
mile marker one on 180,
right off of
76 there?
DEB: No, if there is one,
I've never noticed.
Okay.
Yeah,
I was just out there,
Dad had it marked
on a map I found.
It's uh, probably nothing.
Just wanted to check it out.
DEB: Well, he made a lot of
trips out into the woods
but I figured he was
just hunting or fishing.
Well, did you ever see
him bring anything in
-that he shot or caught?
-DEB: No.
Honestly, I never
even knew when he went.
He just got to the point that he
wasn't talking to anybody much.
He did meet up
with Terry here and there.
-Terry?
-DEB: Yep. Terry Gort.
I'd call and he'd be like,
"Can't talk. I'm with Terry!"
But I don't think
you'd know him.
No, don't,
but I'm about
to introduce myself.
You know
where he lives?
♪♪♪
[car engine rumbling]
[dog barking]
TERRY: You lost?
Nope, I don't think so.
I'm looking for
a man named Terry.
Do you know
of a guy named Terry?
Nope.
Never heard of him.
There you go.
What do you need
this guy for, anyways?
-He owe you money?
-No, it's nothing like that.
My sister said
he was friends with my dad
thought
I'd come by and say thanks.
-Who's your dad?
-Was.
Unfortunately
he passed away recently.
Recently.
-Gerald?
-That's right. Gerald Powell.
-You said that--
-I know what I said.
I'm Terry.
Apologies
for all the foolery.
People come up
in here unannounced.
We usually shoot them.
-Careful sort.
-Yeah, I can see that.
Y'all had trouble?
Well young-ins,
they come up in here.
Steal everything you got.
Guess you looked the type.
[laughs]
What can I
do for you?
Well Dad,
he had interests that
were quite frankly, strange.
-Meaning what?
-Meaning
Native Americans,
arrowheads.
Gerald uh...
Gerald had
a lot of ideas.
Fixations on...
tribes.
I was just hoping that
since y'all
spent time together,
you can tell me
if he was in ill health
or had any heart problems.
Well, I'd not go
poking around in things
Gerald was involved in.
Empathies for your loss.
You know the way out.
Okay.
-[dog barking]
-One more thing.
Ya'll do
any hunting around here?
Sure, we're up
in the area all the time.
You ever find yourself around
mile marker one on 180?
No.
That's what I thought.
Y'all have a nice day.
♪♪♪
[Palmer "Nowhere" playing]
♪ Five o'clock in the afternoon
When I first heard of you ♪
♪ But I'm not running scared ♪
♪ Even though
You might be dead ♪
♪ You can try to stop me ♪
♪ Lock me down ♪
♪ You call me... ♪
-MAN: Forestry service.
-JIM: Hello, yes,
is this the forestry service
for the Towns County area?
MAN: Towns County
and Union.
What can I
help you with?
Yeah, are there any trails
that lead off Highway 180
going South
around mile marker one?
MAN: Not that I recall
but let me look.
Let's see,
I don't see anything there
but there is
an Appalachian trail bed
about three miles South of you
on 76 going towards Helen.
May I ask why, Sir?
Yeah,
I was just wondering.
Have a great day, thanks.
♪♪♪
[eerie instrumental]
[thumping on door]
[moody hand drum instrumental]
♪♪♪
[moody & whimsical instrumental]
That's it. I'm done.
You got to be kidding me.
A kid's drawing
with an unnamed trail
marked with
a red crayon.
I'm out.
I had more intel
when we looked for Bin Laden.
[sighs] This is ridiculous.
I could be
here for weeks.
Even if I did find something,
it's probably Dad's stash
of fishing lures
and beef jerky!
Stupid.
Although,
if there's nothing to it...
then why is everybody
acting so tight lipped?
Why are they asking me
to mind my own business?
I've been out
to mile marker one.
There's nothing there.
Even if that
trail was there,
it'd go out
to middle of nowhere.
Why the camping gear?
Why the camping gear, Dad?
Well, I'm just
going to have to find out.
[rapid knocking]
[keys jangle]
Well, if it isn't
the golden arm of Towns County.
If it isn't
the slowest running back
in the history
of Towns County.
-It's good to see you, Jim.
-Glenn, great to see you.
-I heard you're back in town.
-Yeah, just back here
for a few days, taking care of
Dad's arrangements.
Yeah, I heard about
your dad and I'm sorry, man.
-He was a great guy.
-He was. I appreciate that.
Listen, come on in.
I'll get you something to eat.
-Got some cereal or something.
-Uh, I can't stay around.
I've got to go head out
to Landers' Farm.
We've got a fence issue
so I can't stick around.
[scoffs]
Look at you, Sheriff.
Remember
back in the day
when you and I
used to run from the law?
-Now you are the law.
-[laughs] Yeah.
We don't talk
too much about those days
-anymore around here.
-Yeah, I guess not.
So, Jim.
Terry Gort.
What were you doing over
at his place the other day?
What are you talking
to Terry about?
Well, Sheriff,
did this visit just go
from cordial
to an interrogation?
-Jim, I'm just doing my job.
-Uh-huh.
Well, Deb said that Dad and
Terry were pretty good friends.
So I went over there
to ask him a few questions.
-Such as?
-Hey, look, if you got
-a question to ask, just ask it.
-Nah, I'm-- I'm good.
I'm just
checking on you.
Listen,
when you leave, look me up.
And you're
going to be leaving when?
-I'll be home by Sunday.
-Sunday. Good.
-It's good seeing you, Jim.
-Uh-huh.
Take care.
[muffled music]
Hey. Cosmopolitan, please.
Coming right up.
Hi! Baby!
Can I get a beer?
-Another one?
-BARTENDER: Sure thing, bud.
-Well, hey, little lady.
-Hi. Nu--
You look like
you need some company.
-[laughs]
-Back off pal, she's with me.
-Thanks for that.
-No problem.
Although I'd hate it
if you can't mark off
your bucket list
getting picked up at a bar.
[laughs] Did Deb tell you
that's my number one?
Wait, I can do this.
-Let's see, um-- How about...
-Thank you.
"Excuse me, Miss,
can you step away from the bar?
You're melting the ice."
[laughs]
Oh, I see.
Well, how about this?
Well. Here I am.
What are
your next two wishes?
What's a smart,
attractive man like me
doing without your number?
[laughs] Sounds like
somebody loves himself.
Mom always said there'd never
been anybody good enough for me.
So are you
not wearing a ring
because you're hiding it
or is that legit?
There's no
tan line here.
[laughs] True.
Yeah, I was married once.
But as they say,
the grass is always greener.
She ran off with our attorney
about eight years ago.
-Sorry.
-Mm.
Yeah. Don't be.
Yeah, he's already
moved on to a newer model.
-[laughs] Wow.
-And--
And I hear that she's back
living with her parents.
Oh.
Debra told me
you might be here.
-Really?
-JANIE: Yeah.
And how would
she know that?
She found your phone.
She knows wherever you go.
I'm just joking.
I saw your car when I drove by.
How are you doing?
It's just all, uh,
it's just all so confusing.
Deb filled me in.
Yeah.
Something's off.
What do you mean?
I mean, Dad died.
Got these hillbillies
coming out
and tell me
to mind my own business.
Dad's got these
mysterious maps and drawings.
And the Sheriff
comes by my house today.
[chuckles] What did you do?
Nothing!
-Sorry.
-That's okay.
It'd all be different if people
weren't acting so weird.
It's been like that
for a while.
Everyone's on edge,
ever since
that woman
went missing in Raven.
Yeah.
Well...
thanks
for talking with me.
Been alone for a while.
Of course.
You know, there's only
one thing left to say.
Really? What's that?
Does your
left eye hurt?
Because you've been
looking right all day.
[laughs]
How about this one?
Hey!
Are you two going to kiss?
-Back off, pal.
-Oh, my God. [laughs]
I'll have another.
He won't.
[gunshots blasting]
-I surrender.
-Rangers never surrender.
I taught you that
the first day, son.
Sir, yes, Sir.
-Little Cherry Barry.
-[chuckles]
I do believe you wet
yourself that first night.
Ah, you kicked my butt,
that's for sure.
[birds chirping]
[gunshots blasting]
[laughs]
You tell anyone about that,
I'll kill you.
[sighs]
I didn't expect
to see you out here.
I came here
to warn you.
I just hear
you've been asking questions.
What, was some kind of
small town law passed
when I wasn't here that says
you can't ask questions?
From what you've been
talking about, yes.
You mean I'm going to get
arrested for asking questions
about my father
and how he died?
This place has changed,
People go missing
and nobody asks questions.
-Nobody.
-You mean like
-that Raven County woman.
-Exactly.
When did this all
start happening?
I'm not sure,
but what I do know
is that people whisper,
but they never talk.
Well... [clears throat]
...last I heard, you were
involved in some wet work.
-You still active?
-Oh, no.
Buried my last one
outside Atlanta three years ago.
I work in my
uncle's barber shop now.
Still using blades.
Nice.
Yes, Sir, but now
they're just for shaving.
It's not really
the people up here--
Well,
some of them have turned.
It's really the people
who don't belong here.
I'd like to see someone
keep me from talking
while I'm holding
my loudspeaker.
Yeah, they've got
loudspeakers too.
[tin dings]
[gunshots blasting]
And they don't like
you asking questions.
How do you
know so much?
You're one of those
townspeople that's turned?
Nah, man.
When you're a barber,
you hear all kinds of things.
I know more about this town
than the Mayor or his wife.
Well,
thanks for the heads up.
Yeah, well,
keep your head down, Major.
Some of these
boomerangs can take it off.
Well,
what they're forgetting is this.
I'm a loudspeaker.
[gunshots blasting]
♪♪♪
[birds chirping]
[door creaking]
["Just Be"
by Cherish Alexander]
♪ If it comes
Just let it come ♪
♪ If it goes
Just let it go ♪
♪ If you're a doer
Then just do ♪
♪ If you're a loser
Then just lose ♪
♪ Just be ♪
You and I.
We have a trip to take.
♪ Just like a bird
That's in flight ♪
♪ The stars up in the sky ♪
♪ Just like the Sun and Moon ♪
♪ Just like the flowers bloom ♪
♪ So just be ♪
He's at the portico.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll go get the boys.
♪ Just be ♪
[ominous music]
I was right.
He knew something.
Find it!
["Somewhere In Between"
by Fields and Fortresses]
♪ Information flows
Like open waters ♪
♪ We're chasing headlines
Down like Fool's Gold ♪
♪ We're quick to speak, slow
To learn, and never wander ♪
♪ If all the lines were sold
Or as proposed ♪
♪ 'Cause we placed our trust
In a tin of rules ♪
♪ Somewhere in between ♪
♪ You and the other side ♪
♪ There's a truth we deny ♪
♪ It's fighting
For our lives ♪
♪ Oh, this black and white ♪
♪ This bipolar state of mind ♪
♪ It's eating us alive,
Yeah, yeah ♪
[water rushing]
Hey, buddy.
Where are you going?
Where you
headed off to, huh?
Yeah, it's a nice day to
go hiking or hunting
but by the looks of you,
I say
you hunting something.
Tell me,
what are you hunting, huh?
You know,
pig's in season right now--
-[grunts like pig]
-[laughter]
Just doing some research.
-[laughs]
-Research?
Oh, we got
a professional here.
What you looking for?
Something like a bird?
HAWK: Yeah, maybe we can
help you out with that.
I don't need any help.
Uh, thank you, though.
I'll be on my way.
I wasn't done
talking to you. [groans]
Easy there,
big fella, easy!
You pointing a dangerous--
[indistinct]
All right?
I don't want any trouble.
Just a bit curious
is all, okay?
I think
our conversation's done here.
All right!
Y'all have a nice day.
[grunts]
[aggressive pop plays]
Yeah, this is Hawk.
Yeah, I got him.
He's at 34 degrees,
51, 11.9 North
by 83 degrees 44,
54.7 West.
You got that?
[chuckles] Good.
♪♪♪
[birds chirping]
[chirping continues]
[delicate music]
[gently] GP.
Gerald Powell.
[wrapper crinkling]
♪♪♪
Find another clue.
Leads to more questions.
At least
you left me a snack, Dad.
[wrapper crinkling]
♪♪♪
[thunder crackles]
[distorted synth
instrumental rumbles]
♪♪♪
[forest din]
[thumping]
[twigs cracking]
[suspenseful music]
♪♪♪
[forest din]
[eerie music]
♪♪♪
[grunts]
[indistinct shouting]
Over there! Let's go.
[tribal drum instrumental]
♪♪♪
[thunder crackles]
[panting]
Shh! Let them pass.
[thunder crackles]
[rain trickling in distance]
[thump]
You come here often?
Whoa.
Did anyone ever tell you
you're kind of scary?
[rain trickling in distance]
Guess you have a tough
time with the guys, huh?
Oh, no.
Whatever will I do?
My life has no meaning.
Wah! She speaks!
I hope that hurt.
Don't worry, it does.
You don't belong here.
JIM: Yeah. So they tell me.
I think
everyone's cleared out,
so,
I'm going to head out too.
You're injured.
Yeah, well,
I tried to do a cartwheel
and, uh,
it didn't work out so well.
[rain trickling in distance]
You're a tough
nut to crack.
If you're making
dinner over there,
I'm allergic to shellfish.
This is for your injuries.
You can eat it.
It's not made
from shellfish.
What's it made out of?
My grandmother
taught it to me.
It's been passed down
through our tribe
for generations.
And it'll
stay in our tribe.
Okay.
Just trying
to make conversation.
What tribe?
Or is that a,
uh, secret too?
Cherokee.
I'm half-Cherokee,
my mother's full blood.
Not so bad.
[Jim sniffs]
It smells like that stuff
doc used to put on me
when I was in a--
Never mind.
No. Continue.
That was the first
interesting thing you said.
Sorry, I can't.
My secret
has to stay with my tribe.
Oh, yeah?
What tribe are you with?
Major Jim Powell.
75th Ranger Regiment
at your service.
Wonderful. US military.
Well, I'm not here
on official
business, ma'am.
My, uh,
my father just passed away.
Sorry to hear that.
Yeah, thanks. Ah.
Thanks for that.
Powell.
I knew a Powell,
-Gerald Powell.
-Yeah.
That was my dad!
Did you know him?
He sought after me
and wanted
to know about the area.
Cherokee lore and legends.
Oro?
Yes, Major Powell, Oro.
Gold.
White man's greed.
Whatever you want to call it.
It's still the same thing.
[solemn flute instrumental]
Can you tell me
everything you told him?
1838.
President Jackson
sent troops and militia
to forcibly
remove the Cherokee
and other tribes
from their homelands.
My great great grandparents
lived in that land
before the Great Spirit
breathed life.
They were
forced from their homes
to walk thousands of miles,
having to bury their family
along the way
in shallow graves
because the ground
was too frozen
and the soldiers said
it took
too long to bury them.
Trail of Tears.
Not America's
finest moment in history.
One of many.
Oro?
[laughs]
Right.
The gold.
You know, 3,000 of us
died on that trail
-all for some--
-Sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
Please continue.
Please.
So you know
about the Trail of Tears.
Did you know
that the Cherokee found gold
in Dahlonega
10 years earlier?
Really? My dad.
He used to take my sister
and I down to Dahlonega,
pan for gold.
Never knew
the Cherokee found it.
Yes,
my great great grandfather
was one of the tribesmen
that found it.
Knowing
white man's desire for gold,
he and the other tribesmen
started mining it and hid it.
And then word got out
and people started to swarm
the area for their fortunes.
Anybody ever find the gold
that your
great great grandfather did?
No.
Because President Jackson
passed the Indian Removal Act
and the leaders got together
and decided to hide it,
to never be found.
So you know where it is?
Is that a, uh,
family secret
that's passed on
for generations?
You hear
about thousands of people
forcibly removed
from their rightful homelands
and it's like,
"Oh, that's such a sad story.
I'm sorry
to hear about that".
Then you hear about
a gold mine and it's like,
"Oh, hey, yeah,
show me the money".
No, I just want to find out
what happened to my dad.
I could tell you
what happened to him.
-He was murdered.
-What?
How?
He wasn't
the only one looking for it.
SABAL: With what I'm paying you,
I expect results,
not excuses.
If I wanted excuses,
I'd still be married
to my second husband.
How hard can it be
to find one man?
He took
all of Gerald's research.
You find him
or you won't be found.
[grunts]
That idiot is the reason
we had to get rid of Gerald.
[grunts]
That old man
knew too much.
Go back to the compound.
If Gort heard something,
I want to know
what it is.
Yes, Miss Fade.
[digital tone plays]
Hey Sabal.
You don't look happy.
Again.
I'm surrounded by idiots.
Talk to them.
I refuse to have a battle
of wits with unarmed men.
-Well, talk to me.
-We've got a problem.
I thought
we got rid of the problem.
No, not him. His son.
He came for the funeral.
He's been poking around.
How much does he know?
I'm not totally sure.
We almost had him the other day
but then he disappeared.
I could have
Donia there in two days.
-She can find him.
-No, not yet.
I think we've been
going about this all wrong.
We've been
getting rid of the competition.
Maybe we just
need to get out of their way.
I think
you're taking a big chance.
Well,
when and if he finds anything,
we can just
take it from him.
True.
If anything goes sideways,
let me know.
I will.
[forest din]
JIM: So who is
this Sabal Fade?
-And why'd he kill my dad?
-GOLA: She.
JIM: You think
I care about pronouns?
Why did it kill my dad?
That's closer
to the truth.
She's not human.
She killed my uncle
and anyone else
who'd take up the search
to find what my ancestors left.
Does she have
people looking?
Always.
They're all around town,
threatening families,
trying to squeeze
information out of people.
She bought up
the land and businesses,
trying to corrupt
the politicians.
She'll do
anything and everything.
Explains why people
were treating me so weird.
I just don't understand
why dad would take up
something so dangerous
and not tell me about it.
I could have helped him.
Protection, probably.
The woman is pure evil.
And she'll
stop at nothing
to get what she wants.
Sounds like she has
enough money already.
It's about the power,
not the gold.
JIM: Right.
Wait, what? What power?
Gola.
-GOLA: Got it.
-Got who?
GOLA: Breakfast.
How do you
like your squirrel?
I don't.
I prefer beef
or deer.
You ever had squirrel?
JIM: My dad and I
used to go camping all the time.
And when we did,
we always hunt.
I learned a lot
but I never had to eat squirrel.
-Let me guess, though.
-Please don't say "chicken".
Tastes like chicken.
So predictable.
Really?
Did you know
I was going to do that?
Well?
You lied.
Tastes like chicken.
You were saying.
What?
Before you went
all squirrel hunter on me,
you were saying
something about power.
I asked grandmother, Elisi,
if there's so much gold,
why hasn't anyone ever found it?
Right.
Exactly what I was thinking.
Elisi told me
the tribe shaman
traveled to the great
Tennessee River
to perform a ritual.
JIM: Tennessee River.
How would that help?
GOLA: The Cherokee view
the Tennessee River
as a kind
and helpful spirit.
His head rests
in the Great Smokies
and his feet
touch the Tennessee River.
JIM: So the, uh,
shaman went to this
Tennessee River spirit
to get some help.
-An immortal.
-Right, immortal, okay.
You know, like a--
Like a vampire.
Really?
[chuckles]
I'm sorry.
Look, go ahead. Immortal.
There are a group of spirits
known as the Immortals.
They're invisible
unless they want to be seen.
They drum
and they dance and--
Now when do we hear
all this drumming and dancing?
You do.
In the rumbling
of the mountains,
in the sounds of the wind.
JIM: Well, did this
great Tennessee River Immortal
help the shaman out?
GOLA: He did.
He asked him
for an object.
The only thing he had
was an arrowhead
that he wore
around his neck.
It was passed down
through generations.
The great spirit held out
the arrowhead and he prayed,
"May every path
that you travel
be a wide field.
May every secret
kept from you be revealed.
May the winter
of your years never be sealed."
Wow. That's beautiful.
It's beautiful.
But it's also dangerous.
The arrow head turned to gold
and the shaman headed back home.
Along the way, the trees
and rocks moved out of his way
and the hills
parted for him to pass.
After a few more steps,
he realized that old age
no longer kept him from running
and he felt young again.
And he ran
all the way home.
JIM: So the, the wide fields
allowed him
to pass through anything
and the sealing of his age
made him young again?
But that's not
the worst part of it.
When he returned
back to the village,
everyone came out.
But not to greet him.
To tell him about
every deed they'd ever done.
[chuckles]
Every secret
shall be revealed.
What'd he do?
He hid the arrowhead
and the gold,
vowing
to never use it again.
Wow. You believe?
I believe
Sabal Fade believes.
anyone who possesses it
would be unstoppable.
-And I believe my grandmother.
-Mm.
What are you going to do?
I know
she's looking for it
and I want to find it
before she does.
If the wisest
of our tribe thought
it was
too powerful for him
and grandmother thought
he was the best of us all,
it's the least I could do
to protect the world
from someone
like Sabal Fade.
Well, I agree.
I'm with you.
You know, I don't know if my dad
knew about this arrowhead or not
or if he was
just in it for the gold.
But I'm not
about to sit back...
and let some witch
that killed my dad
get away with it.
I've watched you
in the woods.
You're pretty good.
Well, I'm good with guns.
Good with knives.
-Really?
-Yeah.
[forest din]
[chuckles]
Wow.
That's impressive.
I'm so glad
you were here to protect me
from the big,
scary tree.
[rustling]
Easy.
Easy, easy.
[tense music]
See?
She just wanted
a little breakfast.
Most important
meal of the day.
Just glad
we're not on the menu.
It's time to go.
It does
taste like chicken.
[blues rock riff plays]
♪♪♪
[footsteps]
How do they
know the path?
By accident.
They don't know
exactly where they are.
Well, the four wheeler's
going to get here fast.
GOLA: Let's grab our stuff.
I have an idea.
[ominous instrumental]
♪♪♪
Terry! I want to talk!
Terry!
[dogs barking]
Is this any way
to greet a friend?
You ain't a friend.
Boy, don't you know
what happens
-when people drive up in here?
-I ain't just anybody, Terry.
-You know it.
-What do you want, Vant?
You know why I'm here.
Sabal wants
to know if there's been
any new rumblings
around town.
-Why's Sabal asking me that?
-You know why.
Well,
I know that Gerald
ain't around anymore.
I do know that.
And I know
his boy's in town
asking a lot of questions.
That's all I know.
VANT: You sure
about that, Terry?
I'm sure
Sabal wouldn't take too kindly
to her best ear to the ground
being split ear to ear.
♪♪♪
All right, boys.
We're good here.
[grunts]
Now, we're good.
You better be right.
Both our sakes.
We'll be dead.
Ruby ain't got
the guts to send Donia
up in here to see me.
♪♪♪
[quirky instrumental]
[pants gently]
You ever go four wheeling
and shooting at the same time?
Yeah. In a video game.
I didn't know
this will be part of our day.
It might be.
♪♪♪
[motor whirring]
[forest din]
This should be it.
I told you, I've been through
here many times and nothing.
[paper crinkling]
Hey.
[footsteps]
[forest din]
What does this one mean?
Those are--
Those are carvings of animals
that our hunters would,
would do as they were resting
and waiting
to pass through.
What kind of animal
leaves wavy line tracks?
Why is this here?
JIM: What?
A-R-A.
It's the Cherokee
word for water.
-Well, is it A-R-A or O-R-O?
-GOLA: Yes!
It's water.
I don't want her here.
She scares you?
You said not to send her.
Well, things have changed.
-So you want him dead?
-Well. Not yet.
Then what do you want?
I want her here
just in case.
It's my checks she cashes.
If I want her here
to clean the litter box,
then she'll be
on the next plane.
I don't explain
myself to you!
I'll get her on it.
-VANT: He was in this area.
-SABAL: Was?
Our boys
have found his trail,
make it easier
to follow him
and to get
to where he's going.
Well, that's good,
because I'd hate
to have to put you
on Donia's list
-when she gets here.
-You really need her here?
She makes
everyone uncomfortable.
Oh, she makes you
uncomfortable?
Ma'am,
she's associated with
at least
four open homicides.
That's because
she's a professional.
I'm beginning to think
she's the only one!
I really think we could--
Any more suggestions?
No, ma'am.
We have a long history
of successful transactions.
I'm sure
I can keep her under control.
-She'll be invisible?
-Yes, she will.
[water rushes]
Wow. Thirsty?
Water.
Which you've been saying.
I just knew that I used to
swim here as a kid.
I knew I knew this place.
So, what do we do now?
Dive in?
Kind of wishing you were
a Navy SEAL now, Major?
[chuckles]
♪♪♪
[bright synth instrumental]
[delicate piano instrumental]
♪♪♪
GOLA: I know this place.
Hey, you okay?
You look weak.
I remember this place.
Okay, it's enough
excitement for one day.
Let's head on back.
But I know this place.
Hey look,
I know a place too.
Some food, hot shower.
Come on,
we come back tomorrow.
♪♪♪
[motor revving]
HAWK: Well, well, well.
Lookie what we have here.
Hey, not so fast.
How about you, uh,
take that piece out slowly,
two fingers.
Toss it to the ground, huh?
[gun clicks]
That's it.
-I owe you one, buddy.
-Yeah.
I see you got four of you here
to try to fulfill that fantasy.
Why don't you
let the girl go here,
you can give it a shot.
How about you shut up
and show us the map?
Well?
All right.
Got it right here
in my pocket.
Hey! Slowly!
-It's right here.
-Give me the map.
Wait a second.
This is a forestry map--
[grunting]
Gola I--
I was coming to help.
This guy's [indistinct]
ice in his head or--
Let's go.
-JIM: You're shot.
-You're driving.
♪♪♪
Hey. You feeling better?
Much. [groans]
Let's take
a look at that wound.
-Hey, is that--
-Thanks.
I think I can manage.
Okay.
Well, anyway,
I think I found
that waterfall field
we were in.
I can see why
nobody knows anything about it.
Unless you knew
exactly where to look,
you'd never find it.
I told you
I knew that place.
Yeah, you did.
And that's about all you said.
Jim.
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm just confused,
irritated, tired.
I didn't mean
to take that out on you.
Look, you said you knew
something about this field.
Yeah, but I haven't
been there in over--
Um, I-- I haven't
been there in a while.
[delicate piano instrumental]
My uncle used to take me
there when I was little.
This is the uncle
that Sabal Fade killed?
Yes.
Uh, he used to
take me to the falls
and we would swim
and he would tell me
these great stories
about battles
and great spirits
and ancient spells.
And then
we would go behind the falls,
to the fields
and past the fields
were these whispering rocks.
Whispering rocks?
[scoffs]
It was the coolest place.
My uncle would have me
stand on one end
and then he would go
all the way to the other end.
And then he would whisper
these silly things
that would
just make me laugh.
And I could hear it just
all the way from over there.
That's amazing.
You think we can
find that place tomorrow?
Yeah, I--
I remember it now.
My uncle would say,
"Be careful Usdi Gola.
Remember, there are
no secrets in the rocks".
Usdi.
What is it, like your
first name or something?
No, uh,
it means little.
-Little Gola.
-Hmm.
Well, your uncle's right.
Shouldn't have any secrets.
Maybe we should try that.
All right.
No secrets.
No secrets...
No secrets!
[thwacking]
What's the matter, Hawk?
Can't you be a man?
Take care
of some little girls
pound you into shreds?
She wasn't alone!
Your men
are supposed to be trained.
They're supposed
to be able to take care
of some little girl
and some old soldier.
What's the matter, Hawk?
Can't you talk?
Well, how about
we play a little show and tell.
-Did she hit you?
-Oh!
-Did she kick you?
Actually,
it's the other way around--
Shut it!
Well, isn't this sweet?
If this isn't the stupid
leading the stupid.
-Donia.
-Vant.
Can't say
it's real good to see you.
That's the thing, [indistinct].
You wouldn't ever see me.
You'll just be walking along,
being an idiot.
And then, boom.
Have you address for me?
[snaps]
By the way,
orders have changed.
She wants him dead.
I'd be careful.
He's combat trained.
I am not planning on
getting closer than 900 yards.
It's all making sense now.
The secret rocks.
The white rocks.
I mean,
everything that my uncle said.
Gola, Gola. slow down.
Slow down. Take a breath.
Now, your uncle.
My uncle took me when I was
young to all those places:
The fields,
the white rocks,
the secret rocks.
The white rocks--
Are we talking rocks
-that are painted white--
-Ah, Jim--
Or rocks
that are actually white?
The-- the fields.
The-- the white rocks.
-The secret rocks.
-Okay.
Oh, okay, um,
do you remember
the blessing from the long man?
The long man.
Yeah.
Tennessee River. Immortal.
The shaman.
He visited him.
-He gave him an arrowhead.
-Right. Right.
And-- and--
and the blessing went,
"May every path you travel
be a wide field.
May every secret
kept from you be revealed.
May the winters
of your years never be sealed."
Gola.
You did it.
That's it!
The blessing!
It not only describes
the power of the arrowhead.
It's the map itself.
That's it!
Yeah, that's it, Jim.
And now you can go
and get the gold.
I don't care
about the gold.
The gold
doesn't belong to me.
All I care about
is getting that arrowhead
before Sabal Fade.
That gold, it belongs
to the Cherokee Nation, not me.
Thank you.
Thank you
for thinking of my people.
Of course.
Yeah. Your people.
Just wish your uncle
could have been around
to see you find it.
-And your father.
-Yeah.
You know,
they liked each other so much
and um, they used to pick on me
a little bit, actually.
Wait a minute.
You told me
you barely knew my father.
I know.
I did, Jim.
-I-- I--
-Well, what is it, Gola?
I mean,
now I'm sitting here finding out
that not only
did you know my father,
your uncle did too.
I'm sorry, I'm--
Sorry Jim,
but when I met you,
I didn't know
who you were.
Yeah, well, what did you think
when you found out who I was?
Okay. All right.
Just calm down, Jim.
Sabal Fade has been
after anybody who was helping
your father
and my uncle from the moment
that they started searching.
And then
when she murdered them,
I-- I got so scared
and I hid
up in the mountains
and, and I--
I was so alone.
And I was alone
for a long time.
It was just me
and [speaks Cherokee word].
I'm sorry.
I Just don't do
surprises well.
Look, we're both tired.
Let's just go
get some rest.
♪♪♪
Goodnight, Usdi Gola.
[sighs]
[birds chirping]
[door creaks open]
[door clicks shut]
[birds chirping]
Listen.
I'm sorry
about last night.
You were right
not to trust me.
You didn't know me.
I do now.
Jim.
[shot cracks]
That's a 308.
We've got to get out of here.
I want to find something
for this guy to shoot at.
Hang on. Here.
Listen,
when you hear the shot,
you get in the house
as fast as you can,
get everything
we need, and get out of here.
We are not coming back.
You ready?
All right.
[gun clicks]
Go!
Let's go.
[fast instrumental]
[engine revving]
You okay?
Are you hit?
No, I'm fine.
Who was that?
Had to be Sabal.
Sent a sniper.
Small town,
broad daylight.
She's desperate.
We need to find that arrowhead.
Now more than ever.
We know exactly
where to look.
♪♪♪
SABAL: Just get it for me.
I don't care
how much it costs.
Just. Get. It.
Don't be scared
of doing something illegal.
Not that illegal.
That's why
the check's so big.
If you do a good job,
I'll double it.
How do you know
I'm trustworthy?
Because if you weren't,
you'd be dead.
It's just
that the entire area
that you want
is county land.
In fact, I think it may be
protected by the Cherokee--
I'm sorry,
but did I just hear
you say the word, "think"?
Because it is
already well known that
that is not your mouth,
it's mine.
And it will say
whatever I want it to.
Hmm.
Now.
Say, "Yes, Mrs. Fade.
I'll take care of it."
Yes, Mrs. Fade.
I'll take care of it.
Good. You're excused.
[footsteps thumping]
-VANT: Donia's here.
-Ugh.
Finally, some good news.
♪♪♪
Dear Donia.
So now do we have
two dead Powells?
I was unable to confirm.
Ha! I told you she'd miss.
Vant!
Go now and find her.
I want to know
what she knows.
-Who?
-You know who.
Go find her and tell her
I want to talk to her.
And as for you.
[speaks another language]
-English!
-I will kill both.
I will find him,
I will take him
and his
little girlfriend down.
No charge.
Two for one deal.
Girlfriend. Sister?
No,
they're definitely not related.
Hmm.
What does she look like?
She has dark hair.
Part Cherokee.
And she doesn't
look so pretty.
-Hmm.
-You know her?
No, but I knew her uncle.
Briefly.
We're almost there.
Just a few more miles ahead.
Should we--
Hey, that's the truck
from the other day.
We can't lead it
to the waterfalls.
Let's see if he drives
as bad as he fights.
Hang on.
[action instrumental]
♪♪♪
JIM: I think we lost him.
[car passing by revving]
So what do we do now?
Well...
dad's house is compromised
so that's not an option.
And Deb's house--
Deb, I got to call her.
Listen, she's not involved
with this right now.
Remember, your dad kept this
from you to protect you.
Maybe that's
the best thing for her now too.
Okay.
Well, it's quite a hike
up to that waterfall.
Even if we could
double time it,
we'd make
easy pickings for a sniper.
We need something
four wheel drive.
Like what?
And we need reinforcements.
Listen, we can't get
anyone else involved
-with this--
-Cherry Barry?
Yep.
Yeah, grab your kit.
It's time.
Cherry Barry?
Jim, this isn't--
I need you
to trust me, okay?
I've got a lead on something
to get us up to the waterfall.
I want
to drive you into town.
I need you
to check on my sister.
You don't
have to talk to her.
I just need you
to see if she's okay.
Get eyes on her
and call me.
Okay.
I trust you, Jim.
[engine revving]
[birds chirping]
[dramatic blues rock plays]
You wanted to see me.
He's got a girl
with him now.
She goes
by the name, Gola.
Her uncle was the one
we removed
with Debra's father, Gerald.
[classical music plays]
[sighs]
Debra has been more
than helpful
with information.
I'll continue
being her friend until--
As long
as possible, I guess.
[sighing]
[sighs] I've also
been able to make
a possible
compromising relationship
with her brother, Jim.
I think next time I see him,
I can seal the deal.
♪♪♪
[sighs]
Have I done
something wrong?
I've done
everything you've asked.
Would you just tell me
what you're thinking?
I'll do it.
Just tell me.
I'm thinking,
"Why do I still need you?"
Did you know I swam
competitively as a child?
I did.
My father
was very hard on me.
I could
never do anything right.
My form? Pathetic.
My strokes? Embarrassing.
My speed? Lethargic.
One day my friends
were all gathered around
and we were celebrating
because after a meet
I had taken first.
First place.
And with all
my friends around,
my dad came up to me
and grabbed my sides
in his fists
and he said,
"You've got
to cut the fat Sabal,
it's slowing you down."
I need
to cut the fat, Janie.
You're slowing me down.
[hyper-ventilating]
Sabal, hold on. [chuckles]
Just wait a minute.
I-- I'm very valuable to you.
Just let me prove it.
Just tell me what you need.
I'll-- I'll do it.
I need Jim Powell!
♪♪♪
[crickets chirping]
-BARRY: Whose is this?
-It's mine.
BARRY: Then why are we hiding?
JIM: Because this guy stole it
from me several years ago.
Why don't you
just take it back?
Because I stole his girlfriend
and then he stole that.
[Barry laughs]
Trust me,
he got the better deal.
All right,
shh, shh, shh, shh.
Listen, I need
that RTV and I need to know
he's still not sore
about that old swap.
He used to work nights
so chances are
he's not here right now.
BARRY: Well,
I don't see a car here,
so I think we're good.
JIM: All right, good.
Let's move stealthy.
Come on.
[strings instrumental]
-[deep barking]
-Shh. Shh.
[speaks indistinctly]
[shot blasting]
[barking]
JIM: Stop shootin', Hank!
Yeah, I will stop shooting
when you stop breathing.
-[gun cocks]
-Now identify yourself.
JIM: Jim Powell, Hank.
Jim Powell?
The last time I saw you,
you was a little bit whiter.
JIM: That's my partner.
Put the weapon down.
I got something
to talk to you about.
Well, I will as soon
as I can lay eyes on you.
JIM: All right.
♪♪♪
Hey, Hank.
It's been a while?
Yeah.
Has been a while.
JIM: Hank the Tank!
HANK: Yeah.
The golden boy.
The golden arm
with the golden smile!
JIM: That's it.
HANK: Heard
you were dead, man.
-Nah, not yet.
-Well, it's going to happen
if you keep sneaking
in people's backyards at night.
-I hear ya, I hear ya.
-Hey, I'm Barry.
HANK: Hey Barry,
sorry about earlier.
-It's okay.
-Hey, hey, listen.
-I need to borrow the RTV.
-It's mine.
I won it fair
and square, remember?
JIM: You and I both know
you did not win
that fair and square.
-But it's still mine.
-I hear ya, but listen,
I don't want to keep it.
I just want to borrow it
for a couple of days,
just for
a special project of mine.
I don't even want
to know why, do I?
Probably not.
Well, there's no tag on it,
so you don't have to worry
about getting traced.
Okay, cool.
All right.
Thanks, Hank.
Talk to you soon.
HANK: All right, hey, Barry,
find some better friends
-to hang out with, okay?
-Shut up, Hank.
[street din]
JANIE: I mean, we've looked
everywhere for Jim.
What do you--
where do you think he'd be?
DEB: I don't know.
What about the cabin?
JANIE: Well, what cabin?
[thwack]
[eerie noise]
[street din]
[vigorous coughing]
[grunting]
Come on, come on, come on Jim.
Pick up.
-Oh, Jim.
-JIM: Hello.
Jim. Jim, I--
I need you to come get me now.
Hey. You okay?
Is Deb okay?
Did y'all get
in some kind of trouble?
Not that I can't handle.
All right,
how far out are you?
JIM: We're just
around the corner.
-We'll be there in just a sec.
-Okay.
Hey, it's Gola,
she's that way,
around the corner,
let's go that way.
Okay.
Gola!
Have you seen Deb?
Yes, she's fine.
She's with some--
Barry? Barry.
Cherry Barry, th--
this is your reinforcement?
He's the barber!
Hey, Gola,
looks like it might be time
-for you to come see me.
-Hey Gola, get in the back.
We gotta get out of here.
So your dad
and your uncle were killed.
Then you were chased.
Then you got into a fight--
-Don't forget the wolf--
-Right, the wolf.
And the chicken squirrel.
There was a sniper.
A car chase.
I almost got shot
by some yahoo with a 12 gauge.
And don't forget,
I was attacked earlier today.
So why are we not leaving?
Because I'm not going
to let some old,
mean, crusty woman
get her way.
Really?
Shut up.
Think you can do better?
No...
soul sucking,
pantsuit wearing,
frosty tip,
manipulative defiler
of all things
good and holy?
She did not get those
frosted tips from me.
[laughter]
Seriously, though,
I am a little
concerned about my uncle.
If it's all right
with you, Major,
I'd like to go
over to his place to tell him
to keep his head down
for a couple of days.
Maybe get him to stay
with his cousin, Silva.
Yeah, man, I'm sorry.
It's fine.
I think
we're doing a good thing.
It's dangerous but good.
You know, Barry,
I'm sorry about earlier today.
I really
appreciate your help.
Yeah.
Honestly,
if it wasn't for you and Jim,
I-- I would have
no one to trust.
You know, ever since
my uncle was killed...
Never shall I fail
a comrade, right, Major?
Oo-rah, staff sergeant.
[romantic harp instrumental]
You okay?
I'm getting there.
Jim. I...
-I--
-It's okay.
We can take it slow.
We've been
through so much, and I--
It's not that.
It is that
but it's so much
more than that.
Look, there's so much
about me you don't know.
And I want to be
completely honest with you.
You can tell me anything.
I mean...
You're the most
amazing woman I've ever met.
I feel the same way.
♪♪♪
So here it goes.
[exhales] Okay.
-So my uncle and I--
-[car doors clicking]
Shh.
Did you tell someone
we were here?
Who am I going to tell?
Maybe Barry's coming back?
No, he'd have known
to announce himself.
[suspenseful
instrumental playing]
[screaming]
-DEB: Oh, my God.
-JANIE: It's us!
God. Geez.
Oh geez, Jimmy,
gave me a heart attack.
JIM: Come on in,
come on in.
[door shutting closed]
We were so worried.
Janie insisted
on coming to help me look.
I'm just glad
to see you're okay.
Oh, hello over there.
DEB: Sorry. Are we--
Are we interrupting?
No, that's--
this is Gola.
Gola, this is my sister, Deb.
-Nice to meet you.
-Friend, Janie.
I've been busy.
I can see that!
[Jim scoffs] It's not
what it looks like.
Her uncle
was good friends with Dad.
Deb, so Gola and I,
we've been kind of
looking at some things
that her uncle
and dad were into.
Like, what?
Do tell, please.
Well, at the moment,
there's not a lot
to talk about, but...
for now, kinda got
to keep things on the down low
so the less people know,
the better.
JANIE: Don't worry.
Your secret
is totally safe with us.
Yeah, I don't like
the sound of that, Jim.
Some things
are better left unsaid
and Jim will explain
it to you later.
Be careful.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Well, tomorrow we've got
a few things to finish up,
-so...
-No, I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah?
[door clicking closed]
JANIE: She's been
kind of worrying
a lot these past few days.
JIM: I know.
I know exactly how she is.
She's just like my mom.
She's a worrier.
But you need
to help me out and remind her
that I'm never
going to dig a hole deeper
than I can crawl out of.
Well, do you need somebody
in the trenches with you?
I make
a really good partner.
[chuckling]
No, but thanks for asking.
Gola and I
are just about finished up.
Hmm. That's sad.
You said you had something
to finish up tomorrow?
Why do you ask?
I don't know,
I just thought we could
get together for dinner.
Maybe we can do something.
[chuckles]
Well, not tomorrow.
Maybe some other time.
[sighs] Okay, fine.
Rain check?
Well, you better hurry.
Sugar melts in the rain.
Ha-ha.
Sure it does.
It was nice
to meet you, Gula.
It's Gola.
Right. Bye.
Bye.
Sugar melts
in the rain. Really?
[laughs]
I just could
vomit right here.
I don't like that woman.
What? Shut up.
How do they
even know about this place?
She didn't. Debra did.
We used this place
as kind of a party house
when we were kids.
-I don't like it, Jim.
-Like what?
Them knowing where we are.
Sabal has people everywhere.
Deb is not
a Sabal Fade secret agent.
Okay, fair enough.
But still,
don't you think it's dangerous
they know where we are?
All right. I agree.
I-- I know it's a hike
but nobody knows
about my place.
That'll work.
I'll just call Deb
and let her know
-we won't be staying here.
-Right.
Yeah, yeah,
we're at the location.
Yeah, we're about to move in.
I remember.
All right.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay, love you, sis.
Good night.
[uptight instrumental
music playing]
♪♪♪
[music continues]
[car engine revving]
It's just
a matter of time now
before you have
possession of Jim Powell.
I know I took my time
getting close to Debra
but when you wanted Jim,
I gave him to you.
I knew when he came in town
that I should keep tabs on him.
So I cloned his phone--
Oh, shut up, Janie.
It's annoying to hear you
so pleased with yourself.
Sabal, I don't know
what I did to--
I don't care
what you don't know.
I only care
about one thing.
The gold.
No, you moron.
The arrowhead.
Arrowhead?
There are thousands
of arrowheads.
Farmers find arrowheads.
Can those arrowheads
tell the future?
Can they tell you privileged
or confidential information?
Can they stop time?
And you think
an arrowhead like that
is in Towns County?
I don't think it.
I know it.
How?
[sighs] Well.
In 1974,
Daddy had a breakdown.
I loved it.
There was no one else
I would rather
see it happen to.
But Mother was concerned.
Oh, oh, not for his health
but his wealth.
You see, she couldn't possibly
drink herself to death
in anything
but designer shoes.
So Mother sent him off
to a sweat lodge in Oklahoma.
And she said it was--
Oh, how did she put it?
"So that he could become one
with his inner spirit animal."
What?
Like most addicts,
mother went through
an experimental phase.
Daddy, well, he became
friends with the locals.
And he started smoking
the peace pipe with them.
They would tell him
crazy stories
about magical
and golden arrowheads.
They thought,
"What can this hurt?
Some white guy
up for the weekend on a romp?"
Yeah, but they
didn't know Daddy.
Once he set his mind
to something he didn't let up.
And you really think
that story is true?
That an arrowhead
with all that power
would be in this county?
Yes.
[buzzing]
Idiot.
Hello?
What?
[sighs]
It's time
to get personal.
♪♪♪
I told you, Sabal Fade
has people everywhere.
Who? Janie?
Yes, Janie,
or whatever her name is.
What about Debra?
With Sabal Fade? No way.
It was obvious that she's got
Janie staying close to Deb.
And you.
Got to get
her away from Janie
before she gets hurt.
[notification sound]
-What?
-Too late.
Jim. I'm so sorry--
[notification sound]
GOLA: Wait,
there's another text.
Debra is safe for now
but they want the arrowhead.
Jim, we can't give
Sabal Fade the arrowhead.
-With it, she could--
-I know,
-I know.
-[notification sound]
GOLA: It's a location.
A barn at the end
of Farmington Road?
Why? Where is that?
It's on
the other side of town.
There's nothing around it.
It's a perfect place
for Sabal.
There's nobody
around for miles.
What are we going to do?
[notification sounds]
-[scoffs] One hour.
Can't plan
anything in one hour.
I think
that's the whole point.
Jim, I don't want
Debra to get hurt.
But...
I know
what you're going to say.
Just let me say it.
Sabal Fade
cannot get the arrowhead.
-No matter what.
So what are we going to do?
You go get
that arrowhead and hide it.
And you?
I'm going to go
get my sister.
♪♪♪
I need to know
where Jim is.
I already told you.
I don't know anything.
Please let me go!
SABAL: Okay, Vant.
That's enough.
Go check
on Hawk and his idiots
and make sure
they're where they need to be.
And tell Donia
to come in here.
[cheerful voice] So hard
to find good help these days.
Debra, dear little sweet,
naive Debra...
I need to know
where Jim is!
I told you,
I don't know--
Know where he is?
Yes, you said that.
I'm getting bored with this.
So here's how
it's going to be.
Tell me where he is now
and I'll let him live.
If not...
You can watch him die.
Die?
What is going on here?
What does Jim
have to do with any of this?
He knows
where the arrowhead is!
Arrowhead.
This is all
about a stupid arrowhead?
There's thousands
of arrowheads around here.
-That's what I said.
-Janie, please help me.
They've got me
tied up, please.
Janie.
Sorry, babe.
It's just business.
Jim's on his way.
Well, at least his phone is.
Okay, Vant.
Go get ready.
Jim's on his way.
And Donia, pick a spot.
Get him in your sights.
Don't kill him.
I still need him.
And the Indian girl?
I don't need her.
Good.
I didn't like her anyways.
[M4tt & Zara Taylor's
"My Heart"]
♪ You always want ♪
♪ What you can't have ♪
♪ And what you have ♪
♪ You can't ♪
♪ You're still in my heart ♪
♪ The moment
I laid eyes on you ♪
♪ You can't ♪
♪♪♪
[eerie piano instrumental]
[night din]
[Barry's voice] Hey,
this is Barry the barber
and I want
to cut you. [laughs]
Cut your hair, I mean.
Leave your name and number
and I'll call you back.
Style you later!
[beep]
Barry, it's me.
I'm in the weeds
I need backup
at the old barn
out on Farmington.
Bring everything you got.
We're going to need it.
[eerie piano music]
[shots blasting]
[Hawk laughing]
DEB: Jim.
HAWK: Now try to get away.
-Deb, are you okay?
-I'm okay.
-Are you hurt?
-No, I'm okay.
Ah, Jim, Jim, Jim.
So exciting
to finally meet a man
who's going to give me
a present I don't return.
Sorry. I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Oh, no?
Oh, Janie.
Fill him in, Janie.
Oh, you do
remember Janie, don't you?
Vaguely.
Reminds me of a call girl who
tried picking me up at a bar.
Honey, please.
Like you could afford this?
Yeah, medical bills
would be staggering.
Enough, Jim.
Where is the arrowhead?
Arrowhead?
Vant, cut off
his sister's hand.
JIM: Whoa, whoa.
What happened
to our witty banter here, huh?
-Okay. Okay.
-[she screams]
Look, I don't know
where this arrowhead is.
But if you give me
just a second,
let me work something out.
Hmm. Interesting.
Nah. I'm tired
of this, Vant.
[screaming]
Hey! I'm going
to need everyone
to stay
right where they are.
Sheriff!
They kidnapped me, please!
Is that true, Mrs. Fade?
[gasps] Guilty as charged.
What are you
waiting on, Glenn?
Yes, Glenn.
What are you waiting for?
Glenn. No.
I'm sorry, Jim.
I'm just--
just in too deep.
-But the pay sure is good.
-You're late.
Sorry, ma'am.
Police business.
But I did
bring you a gift.
Hey, Hawk.
[grunting]
JANIE: Oh, goodie.
-JIM: Do you have it?
-GOLA: No.
Did you find it?
GOLA: I did. I hid it.
-So it's not here?
-GOLA: No.
Good.
Then I have a plan.
Okay. Now that we've had
our little reunion,
it's time to get
down to business.
Now, I don't want
to have to threaten you
and have Vant cut you
and blah-dee-blah-dee-blah,
all that.
Anyway, why don't we just
all act like adults
and someone tell me
where my arrowhead is?
I'm kind of
tied up at the moment.
Mmm.
Just how I like my men.
I'll get it
for you, Sabal.
Last chance, Jimmy.
You and I
can make the perfect team.
There's no "I" in team
but there's a "U"
in "Screw you".
Jimmy,
don't have to be so vulgar.
Oh, honestly Janie,
get your loins under control
and bring me the map!
[ominous music playing]
Start talking.
I want to make
a promise first.
-Oh, really?
-Yes, really.
Oh, well,
this ought to be fun.
I'm going to kill you
for murdering my father.
[laughs]
Oh, Jim.
Oh, I thought we decided
not to threaten anymore.
What are you going to do?
-Shoot me?
-[laughs] No. No.
[shot blasts]
Gola!
[grunting]
[panting]
Okay. Any more threats
or are we ready to talk?
[strike on table]
[pants]
We didn't
find the arrowhead.
[gun cocks]
JIM: But we did
find the trail.
We were going to go
out there in the morning.
SABAL: Good.
Thank you, Jim.
So now show me
on the map where it is.
And we'll go there tomorrow
and look for you.
And just to show you
that we're
a full service resort,
we'll give you
an extra night with full access
to all our staff.
Until I have
the arrowhead in my hand.
It was there.
Sheriff.
Yeah, I know it.
I never been
there but I know it.
There's a waterfall
and some fields.
All right, take Hawk
and the others and go there.
-Now. Get it for me.
-Hawk, let's go!
[Hawk] Roger that.
I can't believe
my search is almost over.
It's been so long.
You've done
a lot of horrible things
through the years.
All those innocent lives.
You're going
to burn for that.
I agree.
But the good news is
I'll live long enough
to forget
what I've done.
And you'll live just
long enough to see me get it.
[epic music playing]
Oh, you're gonna get it.
This is for my uncle!
[Will Van De Crommert's
"Not Our War" playing]
♪ Now I'm down on my knees ♪
♪ Begging for
What God can only know ♪
♪ What are we fighting for? ♪
[grunting]
The arrowhead is mine.
Stop Sabal. It's over.
Oh, it can't be over.
I promised my daddy.
And I always
keep my promises!
[gunshot]
No.
But I always keep mine.
♪♪♪
How?
I saw you get shot.
I told you that we had
to talk about something.
Yeah, I'd say,
you first start
with telling me
how you're still alive.
-Well, I--
-[Barry yelling indistinctly]
Hey. I heard shooting.
Is everyone okay in here?
Got it all handled,
Cherry Barry.
Well then,
I got someone that's here
that wants to say "hello."
[night din]
[speaking Spanish]
Raul!
The one and only, papi.
[laughs] What?
How?
Barry told me
you have mucho problema.
So don't be a fool!
BOTH: Call Raul!
[quiet laughter]
Good to see you.
So I take it you guys
know each other?
Oh, yeah.
We go way back.
I can't tell you
how we met.
Or where
or what we were doing but si!
BOTH: We know each other!
So I couldn't find out
more than legends and stories
but I found this picture
and I don't know what it means.
[ominous instrumental]
Are you all right, papi?
You look
like you see a ghost.
It's not
far from the truth.
Thanks, man.
Thanks for everything.
Always, brother.
GOLA: I never did
like that picture.
[emotional
piano music playing]
So the shaman.
Was my uncle.
When he removed the arrowhead,
it left a drawing
tattoo on his chest.
Like yours.
Yes.
Once everyone
started traveling
on the Trail of Tears,
my uncle stayed behind.
He needed to keep
the arrowhead safe.
And grandmother
wasn't going to leave him.
And I wasn't going
to leave grandmother.
And she passed away
shortly after that.
That was over
150 years ago.
The arrowhead
kept my uncle young.
He still aged.
In fact,
the arrowhead drawing
would run low,
like a-- like a fuel gauge,
and he would get older,
but it was like every
year was seven years.
And when he realized
it was just him and me,
he put the arrowhead on me
so that we can age the same.
But my dad.
My uncle
really liked your dad.
And he was close
to telling him the truth.
And then
they were both killed.
My uncle
was a private man
and he didn't even tell me
about the arrowhead.
I-- I guess he left me
these little clues
along the way
so that I can figure it out
in case
he wasn't here to tell me.
So you surviving
that gunshot?
I-- I kind of
put the arrowhead on
so I can do a recharge.
Looks like it's almost
back to where it was.
So you're,
like, 200 years old.
Give or take
a couple of years.
Wow.
Well, I...
always liked older women.
♪♪♪
Major. Gola.
Have you seen this?
-[chuckles]
-It's another legend
about a Navajo headdress.
And get this.
When you put it on,
you can time travel.
So I guess
we'll have to find it.
-I'm in.
-Oh, I am not in.
I've had enough
excitement for one day.
But Major,
we need a lot of money
for an adventure like that.
I think I can dig up
a little inheritance money.
[laughter]
[heavy rock electric
guitar instrumental]
♪♪♪
[music continues]
♪ Open up, use your eyes ♪
♪ Looking around realize ♪
♪ Could be all gone tomorrow ♪
♪ Could be you or anyone ♪
♪ Oh, it makes me cry ♪
♪ It makes me ♪
♪ It makes me cry ♪
[eerie instrumental]
♪♪♪
[music continues]