The legend of Orpheus
is well-known.
ln Greek mythology, Orpheus was
a troubadour from Thrace.
He charmed even the animals.
His songs diverted his attention
from his wife Eurydice.
Death took her away from him.
He descended
to the netherworld,
and used his charm
to win permission
to return with Eurydice
to the world of the living
on the condition
that he never look at her.
But he looked at her
and was torn away from her
by the Bacchantes.
Where does our story
take place...
and when?
A legend is entitled to be
beyond time and place.
lnterpret it as you wish...
Heurtebise, help Cegeste
across the square.
I'M not drunk!
Yes, you are.
Orpheus!
- Greetings!
- You're sMashed.
Sit down for a Minute.
- I've driven everyone away.
- You've entered the lion's den.
I wanted to fiind out--
- What will you have to drink?
- Nothing, thanks. I had a drink.
It was rather bitter.
You're brave to speak to Me.
I'M no longer in the battle.
I gave up writing at 20.
I had nothing new to say.
They respect My silence.
No doubt they think
I have nothing new to say,
and that a poet should not be
too faMous.
They're not very fond of you.
Actually, they hate Me.
Who's the not very aMiable
young drunkard
who doesn't seeM to be
averse to luxury?
That is Jacques Cegeste.
A poet.
He's 18 years old
and adored by all.
His coMpanion, the princess,
fiinances the review
that published his fiirst poeMs.
The princess is very beautiful
and very elegant.
She's not froM here,
but she needs to be aMong us.
Here is her review.
Every page is blank!
It's called ''NudisM.''
It's absurd.
Less absurd than if it were
full of absurd writing.
No excess is absurd.
Orpheus, your gravest fault
is knowing how to get away
with going too far.
The public loves Me.
The public is alone.
They're talking about us.
It seeMs they change everything
and publish texts.
I have his poeMs.
Hold on to theM. In his current state
he's apt to leave theM anywhere.
Jacques, give theM back!
I'll knock you out!
Will you calM down?
I hate scenes.
Of course.
Police?
The Poets' Cafe.
There's a brawl.
Good-bye.
Your cafe aMuses Me.
It thinks it's the center
of the universe.
It is.
You know it,
and that annoys you.
Is My case hopeless?
No. If it were,
they wouldn't hate you.
What should I do?
Fight theM?
Astonish us.
Your papers.
My apologies, sir.
I didn't recognize you,
though My wife's rooM
is full of portraits of you.
- The gentleMan is with Me.
- My apologies once again.
You're in too well
with the police.
- Me?
- I advise you to disappear.
You Might be blaMed
for this unpleasantness.
That's too Much!
Let Me go!
You have no right
to treat hiM like this!
- He has no papers.
- I vouch for hiM.
- You can explain it at the station.
- This is outrageous!
We're just doing our job.
Let Me go!
ScuM! Swine!
- The little bastard bit Me!
- Watch out!
- Get the license nuMbers.
- We couldn't see theM.
Put the other units on alert.
Put hiM in My car and take care
of this pathetic crowd.
Heurtebise, help theM.
And to think it happened here,
where no one even passes through!
Don't stand there
like a laMppost.
Yes, you!
Make yourself useful.
I need you as a witness.
Get in. Quick!
Give Me your handkerchief.
He looks badly wounded.
Don't Make useless reMarks.
The hospital is behind us.
You don't think I'd take
this child to a hospital.
Don't touch hiM!
But...
this young Man is dead.
Will you Mind
your own business?
When will you stop Meddling
in other people's business?
It was you who told Me
to coMe with you.
Will you please be quiet?
Take the usual route.
The radio.
Silence
goes faster backwards.
Three times.
l repeat.
Your attention, please.
A single glass of water
lights up the world.
- Where are we going?
- Must I force you to be quiet?
A single glass of water
lights the world.
Twice. l repeat.
Hello there!
But... those are the Men
who knocked this boy down.
You're being stupid.
Please, ask Me no More questions.
Get out and let My Men work.
Take the body out of the car
and take it up there.
Are you sleepwalking?
I Must be.
Everyone is dawdling.
I don't like it when people do that.
Wait for Me here,
young man.
Lay hiM on the floor.
Follow Me.
You're clearly asleep.
Yes, I'M asleep.
It's very strange.
- You Must explain--
- No, I won't.
Sleeping or dreaMing, the dreaMer
Must accept his dreaMs.
I have a right
to ask for an explanation.
You have every right, My dear Man,
and so do I...
so we're even.
Turn off that Music!
There's a dead Man in the next rooM
and the Men who killed hiM.
- I repeat... I deMand-
- And I deMand you not touch that radio!
- Message.: The mirrors would do well...
- CalM down and have a seat.
to reflect further.
Three times.
You're unbearable.
Sit down.
Wait for Me in this rooM.
My servants will bring you
soMe chaMpagne and cigarettes.
Make yourself at hoMe.
You try too hard to understand
what's going on, My dear young Man,
and that's a serious Mistake.
But they expect Me at hoMe.
Let your wife wait.
She'll be all the More pleased
when you return.
- Is everything ready?
- Yes, Ma'aM.
Cegeste, get up.
Hello.
- Do you know who I aM?
- I do.
- Say it.
- My death.
Good. FroM now on
you will serve Me.
I will serve you.
- You will obey My orders.
- I will obey your orders.
Excellent.
Now, coMe with Me.
Hold on to My dress.
Do not be afraid.
Don't let go.
Where are we?
- I said where are we!
- I don't know.
I'M supposed to wait for you
and take you back.
Where is the princess?
Where is the villa?
Sir, if you will kindly
get in the car--
Yes, yes!
The woMan was staying
at the TherMal Hotel.
Call the Manager for Me.
They want to speak
to the Manager.
This is the chief inspector speaking.
I'M sorry to trouble you again.
Have you conducted
your investigation?
Hello? Hello?
I can only repeat
what I've told you, Inspector.
There is no woMan here
fiitting that description,
nor have I seen any Rolls-Royces.
I'll drop by at 2:00.
It's unbelievable.
Not at the TherMal,
not at the Fabius,
and not at the Two Worlds.
He'll never coMe back.
There, there, calM down.
Men always coMe back.
They're so absurd!
But where is he?
Where can he be?
There's no point in lying to you.
He's with that woMan.
No, no! I don't believe it!
Inspector, tell her it's not true.
You know Orpheus!
- Tell her it's not true.
- It's diffiicult to say.
Yours is a perfect Marriage,
but soMetiMes Men lose their heads.
- It's a Messy story.
- Will the press create a scandal?
No, I gave strict orders.
Besides, the reporters
don't know anything yet.
- It's a reporter, Inspector.
- What?
What is it?
I've been sent by the Sun.
Is your husband in?
My husband can't be disturbed.
He's sleeping.
He worked all night.
I caMe by to see hiM,
but I didn't want to disturb hiM.
Fine. I'll go then. Can I drop you off
soMewhere, Inspector?
- Not necessary. I have My car.
- What was it you wanted?
I wanted to talk to hiM
about the accident.
The young Man is not at the hospital,
and his friends are concerned.
Everything's fiine.
I'll stop by your offiice.
Well done!
This is terrible!
Let's not panic.
I'll stop by the offiice
and speak with theM.
CoMe now. Be strong.
Follow Me, and be as quiet
as possible.
I'll open the garage.
Then it's agreed?
My wife would never understand.
I'M a reporter froM the Sun.
So you're asleep, huh?
I'll let you sleep on, Orpheus.
Pleasant dreaMs!
Get out of here!
My newspaper will take
your attitude into account.
Clear out.
- You'll regret this!
- To hell with the press!
- That's soMething new.
- Yes, it's new.
Eurydice, he's back!
- What are you doing here?
- CharMing!
Orpheus, if you abandon your wife,
it's only norMal
that she should call on those
who love her.
I was frantic with worry.
I called Aglaonice.
And the inspector?
I don't think you realize
how serious the situation is.
What I realize is that I coMe hoMe
and fiind the police
and a woMan whoM I've forbidden
to ever enter My house!
You've gone too far
with your bad Manners.
You'll live to regret
those words!
CoMing, Inspector?
You seeM as unwelcoMe
as I aM.
Go on. I'M not detaining you.
You're to coMe to My offiice
toMorrow.
Aglaonice is dangerous!
Her League of WoMen is powerful.
You're crazy!
Perhaps I aM going Mad.
- Where were you!
- Oh, that!
No cross-exaMinations, please!
But you've never stayed out all night.
It's only natural that I ask you--
Nothing!
Ask Me nothing!
Orpheus, you never drink!
I do now! Do you Mind?
And here I was waiting
for you to coMe hoMe
to tell you soMe great news!
I don't want to hear
any More stories!
I especially don't want to hear
any news!
The news I get is always bad news,
and I'M tired of it!
Leave Me alone.
I want to sleep!
- Who are you?
- I brought your husband back.
Where was he?
I'M the chauffeur for the woMan
whose car he got in yesterday.
Did he spend the night
with her?
No, Ma'aM.
My eMployer was transporting
a badly wounded Man.
Your husband was at the scene
and got in the car.
But My boss doesn't like
people Meddling in her affairs.
And so?
She left us on the road.
She had a sMall car waiting for her
near her villa.
She drove off on her own
with the wounded Man.
And My husband?
I had a probleM
with a loose connection.
It was better to wait
till day.
Your husband slept
in the car.
He was very worried
about you.
I'd like to believe it.
I Might lie to you if I were
a real chauffeur, but I'M not.
- What are you?
- A student-- without a penny.
I only got the job
two weeks ago.
My naMe is Heurtebise.
You Make Me feel better.
- Do you know My husband?
- Who doesn't?
My husband adores Me...
and now we've had a fiight.
He's not hiMself.
He's been drinking.
You dropped your work.
I was going to tell hiM
the big news.
He wouldn't listen.
He saw nothing and heard nothing.
He stepped right on it
without even noticing.
He's tired.
It's hard to sleep in a car.
Perhaps it's that.
He said he wanted to sleep.
But you Must be exhausted.
I'll Make soMe coffee for you.
Where are you supposed to Meet
your eMployer?
Forgive Me-- your ''lady.''
Sit down.
I have no orders.
I'll wait for her in town.
Stay here if you like.
There's a little rooM
above the garage.
It's not Much,
I'M warning you,
but you can park your car
next to ours and wait.
Tell the truth.
You want Me under your thuMb
because I'M part of the story.
Nevertheless,
you are charMing.
You're wrong.
I'M very ordinary.
You Must realize
that woMen like Me
have Much to fear
froM certain people.
Your husband wouldn't
lose his head easily.
He's very handsoMe
and very faMous.
It's a Miracle that he's still
faithful to Me.
- Please, forgive Me.
- The gas!
- What about it?
- It's still on. Be careful.
I dislike that sMell...
and for good reason.
I coMMitted suicide
by gassing Myself.
Since My death,
the sMell has pursued Me.
Your death?
I Mean... since I alMost
coMMitted suicide.
You don't look like a ghost.
I was in love with a girl.
She was quite Mean.
It's a pity
she wasn't like you.
- Your naMe is Eurydice, right?
- At your service.
But I've forgotten yours.
Heurtebise, at your service.
The bird sings with its fingers.
Once.
l repeat.
And that first night
Orpheus'death
entered his room
and watched him sleep.
Two days later...
There are other radios
besides this one.
I can't get this station
anywhere else.
I see I'll have to live
in the car.
- Nobody's forcing you!
- Darling--
38...
39...
40.
Twice.
l repeat.
SeeMs like nothing
but Meaningless words to Me.
But there was
a terrifiic Message yesterday.
Rest awhile.
So the Messages can start again
as soon as I turn My back? Thanks.
You can't spend your life
in a talking car.
- It Makes no sense.
- No sense?
My life had begun to pass
its peak.
It was rotting,
stinking of success and of death.
The least of these phrases
is Much More than any of My poeMs.
I'd give all that I've written
for even one of those little phrases.
I'M on the trail
of the unknown.
Orpheus, little phrases
won't feed our child.
There's a woMan for you,
Heurtebise.
You discover a world
and she speaks to you
of baby clothes and bills.
I adMire Orpheus.
I could have listened a thousand tiMes
and not paid the slightest attention.
Where could they be coMing froM,
Heurtebise?
They're on no other station.
I'M certain they're Meant
for Me.
Orpheus, nothing Matters
but this car.
I could die
and you wouldn't even notice.
We were dead
and we didn't notice.
Beware of the Sirens!
It is l who charM them.
Your voice is very beautiful.
Be satisfiied with your voice.
Attention.
2,294. Twice.
What fascinating poetry!
Who can say what's poetry
and what isn't?
Besides, if you're not happy,
you don't have to stay.
I just want to be left
in peace, that's all.
Take her away.
She'll drive Me Mad.
That car will drive you Mad.
Take her away, Heurtebise,
or I'll do soMething I'll regret!
Orpheus was horrible.
No, he's a genius,
and every genius has his Moods.
It's not that talking car
that I fear.
It's what he's looking for.
But he'd be the saMe
with that woMan.
All he's interested in
is those phrases.
Heurtebise, I May be silly
but I feel things.
It's the fiirst tiMe
he's treated Me like a dog.
Don't exaggerate.
It's just a little faMily quarrel.
It starts with little
faMily quarrels.
You're going to lie down
and close your eyes.
Would you answer it for Me?
Yes, this is Orpheus' house.
No, this is not Orpheus.
Yes, Inspector.
Yes, I'll give hiM your Message.
The inspector called.
He's expecting you.
- And your wife doesn't feel well.
- It's natural in her condition.
- Go see her.
- All right. Would you get the car out?
- My car?
- No, Mine.
No one Must suspect
the other car is here.
The whole town knows
that car.
What's wrong?
- Don't you feel well?
- Very well.
- Would you like Me to get you a nurse?
- A nurse?
I can't leave you all alone.
I have to go into town.
I won't be alone.
Forgive My bad teMper.
I've been resting
on My laurels.
I've got to wake up.
CoMe hoMe quickly.
Do you forgive Me?
I'M all nerves.
What is it?
Did I scare you?
I'M all on edge.
I couldn't drive.
Aren't you afraid they Might
recognize Me if I drive?
You can drop Me off and wait soMewhere
where no one will recognize you.
I'M going to the police station,
and then I'll be back.
One never knows if one will return
froM the police station.
Very funny.
Excuse Me. Have you seen
a dark-haired woMan pass by?
Hello, Orpheus.
Hot under the collar?
Excuse Me--
Have you seen a young woMan
pass by?
Chasing girls, Orpheus?
She's very thin and very sMart,
and she walks very fast.
That's Me!
- Orpheus, your autograph, please.
- I don't have the tiMe.
- Please, sign My book!
- I don't have anything to write with.
Monique, lend Me your pen.
It's hiM, it's hiM!
Let Me go!
Idiot!
Over here! CoMe quick!
I see why he steers clear of us.
Read this.
A very annoying article.
Speak one at a tiMe
or we'll never get anywhere.
You were saying, sir,
that this phrase is a poeM.
No one should know
better than you.
Go ahead and speak.
Orpheus sent Me the texts
yesterday Morning.
I found theM
quite astonishing.
I showed theM
to My friends.
I noticed that one of theM--
quite an astonishing one--
reMinded Me of soMething.
I believe this is the text.
''The bird sings with its fiingers.''
I believe that's how it reads.
On the day of the accident,
the guy was sMashed.
Are you speaking
of the victiM?
Jacques Cegeste.
He was to give us a poeM.
After the brawl, l found these pages
at The Poets' Cafe.
He wrote the phrase
you have in your hand.
Orpheus didn't know Cegeste.
He was sitting with Me when he saw
Cegeste for the fiirst tiMe.
The young Man disappears
under tragic circuMstances,
and his poeM coMes back to us
through Orpheus, who was in the car
and who claiMs he doesn't know
what becaMe of Cegeste.
MadaM, you run
a woMen's club, ''The Bacchantes.''
There's late-night drinking
that goes on there.
-Just chaMpagne, Inspector.
- That's right.
What can you tell Me?
Orpheus Married
one of My forMer serving girls.
We're very fond of her.
When she's sad,
she coMes to us.
She told us
she was very unhappy.
Ladies and gentleMen, I don't doubt
your good faith for a MoMent,
nor your wish to assist justice.
But this evidence is too fliMsy
to accuse a national hero...
Orpheus!
Don't forget we call
a fanfare of truMpets
''Orphean Music.''
Ladies, gentleMen--
To hell with national heroes!
We'll take care of justice ourselves!
I'M expecting Orpheus at any MoMent.
I'M sure he'll explain--
If justice refuses to intervene,
then we will.
Good-bye, Inspector.
GentleMen, gentleMen!
Did you read the article?
- No, and I won't read it.
- You're right. It's horrible.
Don't Mention it to My wife.
Did you see a lot of people?
It seeMed to Me that the streets
were oddly eMpty.
All I found were girls
asking for autographs.
- And you?
- No. Wait-- yes! My eMployer.
She passed by
in a convertible.
She slowed down and shouted to Me
that the Rolls was fiine at your place,
and that I should wait for her.
You should have gone after her,
shouted for her to stop.
A chauffeur doesn't give orders.
He only takes theM.
Did she give you any orders?
No. She told Me to wait for orders
at your place.
- What did the inspector tell you?
- I didn't go to see hiM. He can wait.
Each night, Orpheus'death
returned to his room.
- No, Eurydice, no!
- I Must go, Heurtebise.
I'll go to Aglaonice.
I Must!
She's the only one
who can advise Me.
Orpheus would not like it!
He doesn't care about anything
but that woMan's car.
Even if I drove you, he'd see you.
He's in the garage.
I'll take My bicycle.
I do it all the tiMe.
- In your condition it's crazy!
- I'M going!
I don't have the authority
to forbid you,
but what if I begged you?
I'd still go.
It wouldn't stop Me.
I'M going Mad!
Aglaonice can't tell you
anything new
and you'll be dead tired.
Hello.
CoMe along, Cegeste.
Get used to following Me.
- Close the door.
- What door?
The Mirror! You never understand
what you're told.
The Mirror and the trapdoor.
Is everything all right?
That depends.
What do you Mean by that?
Nothing, Ma'aM.
Good.
I can't stand iMpertinence.
Is Orpheus in the garage?
Yes, Ma'aM.
Well, now, Cegeste,
what does that look Mean?
Perhaps you expected to see Me
with a scythe and a shroud?
My boy, if I appeared to the living
the way they portray Me,
they would recognize Me,
and that wouldn't Make
our task easy.
Heurtebise will help you.
You'd never Manage on your own.
I'll close the curtains Myself
since none of you have bothered to.
Leave nothing on the table
except the transMitter.
Cegeste, send the Messages.
CoMe on, get a Move on!
Not drinking doesn't suit you.
I have no tiMe to lose.
''The Mourning of young widows
is as brief as a noonday candle.''
Once. I repeat.
Your phrases are an exquisite
stroke of inspiration.
Thank you.
- Where are My gloves?
- They're not in the bag.
Did you forget theM?
That's the last straw!
Yes, Ma'aM. I'M sorry.
I knew it. Give Me yours,
Quickly!
You know I deMand
absolute discipline
like on a ship.
Do you have orders?
What did you say?
I asked you
if you had orders.
When I carry out My orders,
I expect Mine to be carried out.
That's exactly why I ask
if you have orders.
You dare to ask?
If you had had orders, your butchers
would have coMpleted their task.
Are you in love
with this idiot?
What if I aM?
You have no right to love
in any world.
- Nor do you.
- What?
- You can't escape the rules.
- I order you to be quiet!
You're in love with Orpheus
and you don't know how to handle it.
Shut up!
TransMit your Messages.
Make soMething up--
anything!
Could I appear and disappear
like Heurtebise?
You're too cluMsy.
TransMit.
''Jupiter gives wisdoM
to those he would lose.
I repeat.''
Orpheus! Orpheus!
What? Can't I ever
be left alone?
Your wife is in great danger.
- Follow Me.
- Be quiet!
I'M telling you,
your wife is in great danger.
- I can't hear.
- Will you listen to Me?
Let Me fiinish writing this.
Orpheus, your wife is dying!
You don't know her.
It's just a trick to get Me
back in the house.
Get up.
Do you know who I aM?
- I do.
- Say it.
My death.
FroM now on
you belong to the other world.
FroM now on I belong
to the other world.
- You will obey My orders.
- I will obey.
Excellent.
Ah, there you are.
Orpheus Must have refused
to follow you.
I will report this.
And so will I.
I have a lot to say.
Don't forget the apparatus.
You forget everything!
I suppose, Heurtebise, that you want
to stay on Earth?
You look like a gravedigger
in that trapdoor.
You are quite ridiculous!
I'M not the only one!
I'll Make a note
of your insolence.
Cegeste!
Won't you ever learn
not to look back?
People have been turned
into a pillar of salt for that!
Let's go.
I warned you.
You're too late.
- Too late?
- CoMe up.
What are you doing
in My rooM?
CoMe in through the window
you fiind so handy for cliMbing out.
I asked you what you're doing
in My rooM.
- Your wife.
- What about My wife?
Your wife is dead.
You're joking.
That would be
a strange joke.
You refused to listen to Me.
Eurydice.
Orpheus, listen to Me.
It's too late for regrets.
Listen to Me.
But how...
and why?
She had a bad fall
and, I suspect,
other things as well.
But what?
It's not possible.
Talk to Me.
Look at Me.
There's one way to undo
your foolishness.
This is part
of the saMe dreaM,
the saMe nightMare.
But I'll wake up--
SoMebody wake Me up!
Listen to Me.
Will you listen to Me,
Orpheus?
It's all useless.
You have one chance left.
What chance?
Orpheus, you know Death.
I've spoken of her...
I've dreaMt of her...
I've sung about her.
I thought I knew her...
but I didn't know her.
You know her... in person!
In person?
You have been with her.
With her?
In her rooM.
In her very rooM!
- The princess?
- That's right.
My God!
The Mirror.
I'll give you
the secret of secrets.
Mirrors are the doors
through which Death coMes and goes.
Look at yourself in a Mirror
all your life...
and you'll see death at work
like bees in a hive of glass.
How do you know
these frightening things?
Don't be naive.
Could I be her chauffeur without
learning certain frightening things?
Heurtebise, there's nothing More
to be done.
Yes, there is.
Find her again.
No Man can do that
unless he kills hiMself.
A poet is More than a Man.
But My wife lies dead
there on her deathbed!
It's one of her faces,
as the princess is
one of death's faces.
It's all false!
Your wife is
in another world.
I invite you
to follow Me there.
I would follow her to hell!
You needn't go that far.
I want to fiind Eurydice.
You don't need to beg.
I'M offering it to you.
Look into My eyes.
Is it Eurydice you wish to fiind,
or Death?
But...
I'M asking you very clearly:
Is it Death you wish to fiind,
or Eurydice?
Both.
And, if you can, betray one
with the other?
Let's hurry!
I aM delighted
that I aM no longer alive.
SoMeone left their gloves.
- Gloves?
- Put theM on.
CoMe on, put theM on.
With these gloves you will pass
through Mirrors
as if they were water.
Prove it.
Try it.
I'll go with you.
Look at the tiMe.
Hands out in front.
Perhaps you're afraid?
But this Mirror
is a Mirror,
and in it I see
an unhappy Man.
You don't have to understand.
You just have to believe.
Where are we?
Life is a long death...
This is no-Man's land.
Here are Men's MeMories
and the ruins of their beliefs.
Does every Mirror in the world
lead here?
I suppose so.
But I wouldn't want to be
in your gloves.
Don't think I know Much More
than you do.
CoMe on, keep Moving.
It's hard to follow you.
You Move,
but you're Motionless.
It's different for Me.
Glazier!
Why are these people prowling
around? Are they alive?
They think so.
There's nothing More habit-forMing
than habit.
Are we going far?
The words you use
have no Meaning here.
There's no wind.
Why do you seeM to be
heading into the wind?
''Why?''
Always ''Why?''
Ask no More questions.
Keep Moving.
Do I have to take you
by the hand?
Did you receive orders
to transMit your Messages?
Yes.
Did you receive orders to transMit
certain Messages?
Didn't you have to subMit
the texts fiirst?
Be careful how you answer.
No. I invented the phrases
and nuMbers.
I Myself sent soMe phrases
I had written earlier.
Did you notice
anything peculiar
about Heurtebise's behavior?
I adMired how he could
coMe and go at will.
I wished I could do that,
but Death told Me
I'd never be able to.
- That I was too cluMsy.
- Go on.
Take the young Man away.
Bring the other person in.
May I sit down?
Be seated.
May I sMoke?
If you wish.
Having been given orders--
or at least perMission--
to take a young Man
into your service...
you are accused of having taken
his wife as well.
FurtherMore, of having undertaken
a private enterprise,
and of having used
initiative.
What do you have to say
in response?
Nothing.
It was a series
of circuMstances.
There are no circuMstances
allowed here.
There are only orders.
Did you have orders?
The laws of the other world
are so different froM ours.
Perhaps I overstepped My authority
without realizing it.
Before continuing the enquiry,
we Must wait for another suspect
and a witness.
They're here.
Hello.
We're caught like rats.
Make no Mistake, gentleMen.
These are my judges.
Stay calM.
CoMe forward.
So, Heurtebise...
now is the tiMe to say
what you have to say.
I have nothing to say.
You are accused of taking part
in an intrigue
in which Death was involved
without perMission.
Do you have a good excuse?
I was her aide.
I followed her.
You lingered in the huMan world
for personal reasons,
which you had no right to do.
Perhaps.
There is no ''perhaps'' here.
Answer.
I didn't Mean to disobey.
CoMe forward.
You. You!
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Your naMe.
- Your profession?
- Poet.
The card says ''writer.''
- It's alMost the saMe thing.
- There is no ''alMost'' here.
What do you Mean by ''poet''?
To write,
without being a writer.
Do you know this Man?
Yes.
Do you adMit
you took his wife?
Yes.
To get her out of the way
and have this Man for yourself?
- GentleMen--
- Silence.
CalM down.
- Keep calM.
- Do you love this Man?
Yes.
Is it true you entered his rooM
to watch hiM sleep?
Yes.
Sign this paper.
Do you have a pen?
I forgot you're not a writer.
Show these two people out.
Not you.
You stay.
CoMe forward.
Do you recognize
this Man?
Of course. It's Heurtebise.
Did he atteMpt to speak to you
in your husband's absence?
Did he say anything
shaMeful to you?
ShaMeful?
Of course not.
It's Heurtebise.
Heurtebise, do you love
this woMan?
I repeat:
Do you love this woMan?
- Yes.
- That is all we wanted to know.
Sign here.
And you told theM yes?
One cannot lie here.
My love.
I loved you
even before we Met.
I Must have seeMed
very stupid to you.
What can we say
to each other?
I don't have the right
to love anyone...
and yet I love.
You are all-powerful.
In your eyes.
Here death takes on
innuMerable forMs.
Young and old,
they receive orders.
And if you disobeyed
those orders?
They can't kill you.
It is you who kill.
- What they do is worse.
- Where do the orders coMe froM?
They are sent back and forth
by so Many sentinels
like the toM-toMs
of your African tribes...
the echoes
of your Mountains...
the wind whispering
through your trees.
I will go to he
who gives those orders.
My poor love,
he exists nowhere.
SoMe say he thinks
of us...
others, that we are
his thoughts.
Others say he sleeps
and that we are his dreaM...
his bad dreaM.
I'll take you away froM here
when they set us free.
Set us free?
I never want to leave you.
I Must leave you
but I swear I will fiind a way
to bring us back together.
Say ''forever.''
- Forever.
- Swear it.
I swear.
But now--
- Now their police are here.
- A Miracle will happen.
Miracles only happen
in your world.
All worlds are Moved by lovers.
In our world no one is Moved.
One goes froM judge to judge.
CoMe.
Go on. I love you.
Do not be afraid.
I don't want to lose you
again.
If you resist,
you will lose us.
Follow Me.
GentleMen.
I shall now pronounce
the verdict.
''We, this tribunal,
release Orpheus' death
and her aides on bail.
Orpheus is free
on condition that he never speak
of what he has seen.
Eurydice is free to return to life
in the other world
on condition that Orpheus
never look upon her.
A single glance at her
and he will lose her forever.''
- But--
- Silence!
Here is your wife.
Be careful!
Don't look at her!
You've Made a good start.
May I be perMitted to accoMpany
Orpheus to his house?
I'M afraid his coMpliance
May be diffiicult to Monitor
without supervision
by one of our people.
You May accoMpany
the couple.
Under our watchful eye,
of course.
- Do you have the gloves?
- No.
- Oh, yes. In My pocket.
- Put theM on.
Close your eyes.
I will guide you.
It will be easier that way
in the beginning.
And... her?
May I look at her?
Under no circuMstances.
You Must not open your eyes
under any circuMstances!
Take hold of hiM by the shoulders.
It will be safer that way.
CoMe.
Where are the judges?
The swine!
Cegeste...
If I were of our forMer world,
I'd say
let's have a drink.
How could it be 6:00?
We entered the Mirror
at 6:00.
You Must not speak of these things.
You gave your word.
There's a letter.
I'll go.
Call out froM the garden,
''I'M coMing back in...''
and Eurydice will hide.
- How convenient.
- What a nightMare!
Be careful!
Why shouldn't I look at Myself?
If Orpheus coMes in,
he Might see you in the Mirror.
It's a good thing you caMe.
You're not angry with Me
for what I said at the tribunal?
What did you say?
Excuse Me.
When Orpheus coMes in,
hide under the table.
An anonyMous letter,
written backwards.
Look out, Eurydice!
He's coMing!
Be careful, Orpheus.
- Eurydice, are you under the table?
- I aM.
Where is he?
- Where are you?
- Over there, under the table.
That's great.
''You Are A Thief And A Murderer.
We Will Meet On Your Grave.''
Beware of Mirrors.
- No need to tell Me.
- I Meant her reflection.
Heurtebise forbids Me
to look at Myself in the Mirror.
Get rid of that stupid letter!
May I coMe out?
Just a Minute.
Turn your back.
You can coMe out.
I can't even say
how diffiicult this is...
the tension such an absurd thing
causes!
It'll becoMe a habit.
A strange habit!
It's better than being blind...
or losing a leg.
We don't have Much choice.
It even has its advantages.
Orpheus won't see
My wrinkles.
Fine!
It seeMs you think
it's all a joke.
I don't see what else
your wife could do.
- What else she could--
- Careful!
You're dangerous, My friend.
I'M not going to live
with blinders on!
I'll get you a drink.
Close your eyes.
Heurtebise will sit you down
while I'M in the kitchen.
I'll tell you what else
My wife could do:
She could realize
the awful position I'M in.
You think she doesn't suffer too?
You're wrong.
WoMen adore coMplications.
Close your eyes.
- What if I put on a blindfold?
- That would be cheating.
It's wiser to get used to it
right froM the start.
It won't be easy, I know,
but we'll Make it.
Bring a chair.
Sit down.
I'll turn My back.
It's when you're Moving around
that you're dangerous.
A picture of your wife
is not your wife.
I'M so tired.
A decision has to be Made
about how to handle this situation,
and it's up to Me
to Make it.
We can't spend our lives
playing hide-and-seek.
Do you want Me to go live
soMewhere else?
- Always exaggerating!
- CoMe on, Orpheus.
We can't share
the saMe rooM.
I'll sleep here on the sofa.
Now who's exaggerating?
Be careful!
It's her fault! She could provoke
even a corpse to turn around!
- I should have stayed dead.
- Tell her to be quiet!
I'M incredibly on edge.
I could do anything!
You've Made your wife cry.
Since I annoy everyone,
I'll leave!
- Where are you going?
- To my rooM.
Try to calM down.
He hates Me.
If he hated you, he would not have
snared you froM death.
For that he will always
be reMeMbered.
He didn't coMe for Me.
You know that.
Just like you know
where he's going
when he goes to the car.
Orpheus was lost to Eurydice.
She could not bear
to live this way.
She wanted to save him
from herself...
and there was only one way
to do it.
Do you love this Man?
I'M asking you
if you love this Man.
What is it?
Is that you?
It's Me, Eurydice.
I know you often fall asleep
with the laMp on,
but since the electricity has been
cut off for an hour,
I caMe down
to fiind a book.
A book?
To read in the dark?
Try to understand.
Think of the risk you're exposing us to
with your foolishness.
Go upstairs
and close the trapdoor.
You gave Me a bad scare.
- Do you forgive Me?
- Of course.
Go upstairs
and get soMe sleep.
A short black-out
had made her miss her chance.
She had to go on living,
and the next day--
You've coMe just in tiMe.
Do you understand the code?
Stock Market quotations.
- What about this?
- Be careful, your wife is coMing.
Don't push her too far.
- May I coMe in?
- Close your eyes for a Minute.
Yes, coMe in.
Your husband was listening
to the stock Market.
- Get in the back.
- AM I bothering you?
I was listening out here
so I wouldn't disturb you in the house.
- That noise frightens Me.
- Don't take risks.
What risks?
Orpheus can't see Me,
but I can touch his cheek.
It's wonderful!
The Mirror!
That was bound to happen.
It had to happen.
It had to happen, Heurtebise.
I had enough of half-Measures
and arrangeMents.
There's no getting adjusted to that.
You have to go all the way.
Stones. You can Make
a statue of Me with theM!
You Mustn't stay outdoors.
There they are, the swine!
I've been expecting theM.
The letter, Heurtebise.
The anonyMous letter.
I'll talk to theM.
What does Marble think
when it's being sculpted?
It thinks, ''I aM struck,
insulted, ruined, lost.''
Life is sculpting Me.
Let it fiinish its work.
- The swine!
- Threaten theM with this.
This is your house!
Give Me that revolver.
I'M ordering you to give it to Me.
And I order you
to get off My property.
I forbid you to coMe back
on My property.
- I'll enter your property when I like.
- Do you want to kill Me?
We want to know
where Jacques Cegeste is.
- Is he here with you?
- Stay back or I'll shoot.
I'll shoot!
- Step away froM the door.
- Keep calM.
He's only wounded.
No one will harM you.
Is it done?
It is done.
- Cegeste.
- MadaM?
This is the fiirst tiMe I have alMost
understood the notion of tiMe.
Waiting Must be frightful
for Men.
I no longer reMeMber.
- Are you bored?
- What's that?
Forgive Me.
I was talking to Myself.
lt's not the same journey
this time.
Heurtebise leads Orpheus
where he should not lead him.
No longer the wonderful
motionless journey,
Orpheus and his guide
trudge on,
at every turn forced back
and forced on
by a great
and inexplicable breath.
They are here.
I found a way to coMe
to you again.
I called out froM within Me
for so long that you fiinally caMe.
I heard you
and waited for you.
I did not want you to stay
among men.
- Where shall we hide?
- We no longer have to hide.
- We are free.
- Forever?
Forever.
Hold Me, Orpheus.
Hold Me tight.
You burn like ice.
You still have
a huMan warMth.
- It's nice.
- I love you.
I love you.
- Will you obey Me?
- I will obey you.
- Whatever I ask?
- Whatever you ask.
Even if I passed sentence on you?
If I tortured you?
I belong to you
and I will never leave you.
Never again.
- You know what I expect of you.
- But MadaM--
It's our last hope,
and we don't have a second to lose.
- Reconsider--
- There is no need to reconsider.
There is nothing worse
in any world.
Are you a coward?
The death of a poet
requires a sacrifice
to render him immortal.
For the last tiMe,
I beg you...
do not try to understand
what I aM going to do,
for in truth it would be diffiicult
to understand even in our world.
- Stand here.
- Quick.
Cegeste, to work!
Orpheus, don't Move.
Stay still. You proMised.
Work, work!
Heurtebise, I'll help you.
I'll work along with you.
Don't weaken.
Count... calculate.
Labor as I labor.
Seal hiM off. You Must!
Without willpower
we are cripples.
I can do no More.
You Must will it, Heurtebise.
You Must!
- I can't.
- You're not trying.
Don't speak.
Go deep inside yourself
and escape froM yourself. Run!
Overturn all obstacles!
You're nearly there.
You're there.
I see it.
I'M alMost there.
A fiinal effort, Heurtebise.
Do it.
Are you there?
Answer Me.
I'M there.
Then set out.
Go back in tiMe.
What has been
Must no longer be.
- I'M very tired.
- I don't care!
Work.
Work, I coMMand you!
Where are you?
In the rooM.
The gloves.
Get the gloves, quick!
Were you watching Me sleep?
Yes, My love.
- I had a terrible nightMare.
- You don't feel ill?
- No. A little headache.
- I will cure you.
- Were you working?
- I was working.
You work too hard.
Try to rest.
My books don't write
theMselves.
- But they do!
- I help theM.
How is the young boy
behaving?
- It Might be a girl.
- It's a boy!
He's kicking Me.
- He'll be as unbearable as his father.
- Unbearable? You?
Many people fiind Me
unbearable.
Poor you! They love you.
- They loathe Me.
- That's a forM of love.
There's only one love
that counts:
ours.
Is it done?
It is done.
MadaM, your own aides.
They're here to arrest you.
Yes, Cegeste.
Flee!
Where?
When they arrest you here...
what happens?
It's not pleasant.
It's never pleasant.
Here less than anywhere else.
Thank you.
It was nothing.
We had to return theM
to their swaMp.
Farewell, Cegeste.
THE END