Our Land
This is Telangana.
The feudal system of the Hyderabad
State has occupied half of Telangana.
The Nizam,
a puppet of British Imperialism...
...rules this land.
This is Siripuram, a village
in the district of Nalgonda.
Hundreds of landless peasants live here.
Ramayya is the son of one
such poor farmer.
This story begins with Ramayya...
and follows him,
taking new turns.
Irayya, give me a beedi.
Dawdling like bridegrooms,
are you! Get going. Get up!
Sailu, get some water for
The Master.
- Hey you, Iriga!
- Yes, sir.
Hmm, go!
Your son has grown.
Starting tomorrow, send him to
mind the Dora's cattle.
All right.
Father...
- Father...?
- What is it?
I won't go to mind cattle.
What'll you eat if you don't work?
Are you a Dora's son?
Look my son, you're the child
of a hired hand.
A hired hand's son will
only ever be a hired hand.
It's our fate.
You must go to work,
even if you're dying.
How can it be otherwise...
Producers:
Ravindranath, B. Narsing Rao
Based on Kishanchander's
"Jab Khet Jage"
Script: B. Narsing Rao,
Gautam Ghosh, Partha Banerji
O village lad,
O able little cow-herd...
How long ago was it
since you tasted milk?
Camera: Kamal Nayak
Editing: D. Rajgopal
O fresh-faced lad,
when did you begin working?
Art: T. Vaikuntham
You perch on the high rock
by the curving path
Have you indeed become
lord of the pastures?
Music: Vinjamuri Sitadevi,
Gautam Ghosh
Does your little belly go hungry?
Your tears stream down
and your hands rub the eyes
Why do you sob so pitifully?
O my fresh-faced lad...
Will you say who hurt you,
little one?
A measure of grain,
is that all of your wage?
And when you measure,
is the amount even less?
And when you think of it,
are you overcome with grief?
Director: Gautam Ghosh
Hey, Rangadu!
Where are you all off to?
Gopayya died.
- How?
- I don't know.
Wait, I'm coming!
Oh my God! Oh, God...
What have you done to me?
How did Gopayya die?
The cart got stuck and
he fell into a ditch.
The cart ran over him,
and he died.
A man our own age died
before our very eyes...
Here is Jagannath Reddy,
Zamindar of all this land.
He is the overlord of
50,000 acres.
Earlier, all the Zamindars
of Telangana...
were only tax collectors.
The Nizam later granted
them titles and jagirs.
They have seized thousands
of acres since then.
And all the farmers who
tilled the land...
...were forcibly turned into tenants.
These Zamindars took law
and justice into their own hands.
They became the pillars of
Hyderabad's feudal system.
They determine the fate of
the thousands who live here.
Well, how are the
collections, Lakshman Rao?
Almost over. Only two or three
still have to pay up.
Why haven't they paid?
How will they pay if you sit
twiddling your thumbs!
But I've told them...
So, you told them, did you?
You must hound and harass
them into paying taxes!
He is here, Dora (chieftain)
You think bowing and
scraping will do?
Who'll pay the tax,
you bastard!
Will your wife's pimp pay?
How will I pay, Dora?
When I harvest the crop...
Don't give me excuses,
you dirty son of a whore!
Think you can cheat
the Nizam Government?
I beg you, Dora...
I'll sell what I can and
pay the tax.
I'll break every bone in
your body if you don't pay!
What is she waiting for?
Hey you! Why are you dumb-struck?
Speak up!
What can I say...?
He died, leaving me high and dry.
Help my child and me!
I'll serve you dead or alive.
Each one to his own fate.
We can't change it.
Look, let the girl serve
the Mem Sahib in the Gadi.
And you can get by on daily
wage somewhere.
I told you to bring me
those papers.
Are the pots good?
How many?
You've brought less!
No need for all that.
Hey Iriga! Come here.
Get going! Go on!
What are you standing for?
Get going!
Today is the fair!
You talk big, you little bastard!
A coolie whore-son wants
to enjoy the fair?
You dare to hit me?
Go! I won't follow.
Think new clothes make you a Dora,
you thieving bastard?
You dare attack him?
Come on, get going!
Go!
Please, sir. He's only a
boy. Don't take him amiss.
What else can he do but
serve the Dora!
He has to live by the Dora's
grace. Please don't be angry!
Come on, you!
- Is everything ready?
- Yes, sir.
How many did you bring?
I brought 38, Dora.
Don't stare at him!
Look down!
Go on, quick now!
Why are you staring?
Get moving!
Admiring yourself like a
bridegroom, are you?
Get going, you whore-son!
Oh village lad,
Oh able little cow-herd
How long ago was it
since you tasted milk?
Oh you fresh faced lad!
I wanted to ask...
How long will you put off marriage?
I won't marry, Father.
No, son. A home needs a
woman even to light a lamp!
Say what you will.
I won't marry now.
Father...
At least drink this rice gruel.
Look, son...
Sit here by me.
I'm old...
I'm waiting for the graveyard.
Not this now!
Let me say it...
Why don't you sleep quietly,
as I said?
Why don't you listen to me?
Drink some gruel first.
In my grandfather's time,
we had some land.
Only two acres of it remained
in my father's day.
I couldn't even hold on to that!
Nor have I been able
to get you married.
Anyway, you know all this...
Not a morsel in our belly
until we work.
Our lives will pass on
serving the Doras.
Hey Rama!
You're supposed to be working,
but you keep looking elsewhere!
I know what's up!
Don't to try to fool me.
Hey Malli! Where are you
off to? Come here!
I'll feed my baby
and come back, sir.
How often do you go,
you thieving bitch?
I really must feed my baby.
Please, I'll be right back.
You're saying you really have milk?
Let me see!
Okay. Go, you bitch.
Come back before this spit
dries up!
Oh! It's Ramulu.
Hey, Ramulu!
How are you?
I'm doing fine.
What dowry did you get?
Ah, what can poor folk give?
They just gave the girl.
It's up to me to look after her.
It's a pretty girl you
married, Ramulu Bhaiyya.
Pretty, isn't she?
Well, Ramulu! That sure is one
pretty wife you have! Eh?
Wonderful! That's some fine stuff,
Pratap Reddy Sahib.
It's all by your grace, sir.
Mastan, get another glass
for the Sahib!
You know about this Sangam?
There's a lot of talk about
it nowadays, I hear.
Sangam! Here, in our area?
Who will dare do it here?
Talk of Sangam? We'll
beat up the bastards!
Tehsildar Sahib, who can
even talk of Sangam here?
- May I recite a verse?
- Please, do!
You are a flower,
yet why do you bring me flowers?
Overcome with love, I said:
you are the flower.
Lovers don't die,
but are buried alive.
Dig up the grave,
you will find...
They are waiting for
their beloved yet!
Mastan, is everything
ready?
Almost done, Dora.
Ranga!
Any new bird in the village?
- Why don't you speak up?
- Yes, there is a new girl.
- Then bring her!
- As you wish, Dora.
Bring her into the room.
Ramulu! Ramulu?
- Coming...
Dora asked me to fetch your wife.
Oh brother, I beg of you...
I'll be your slave!
I'll be reborn as your son after I die!
Just don't take her.
Come on, get going.
- Please...
Come on! I said get going!
Leave me! Let me go!
Did you bring her?
- Yes, Dora.
Stop crying, Ramulu...
Crying won't help.
These things happen so often.
How will our lives go on if
we brood over these things?
Go...go and sleep now.
Ramulu's wife just stepped
into her in-laws and...
...the vulture swopped in!
And folks here don't bother!
- Why are you concerned?
This Nagayya has no sense!
He brags to the Sangam.
And now, not a word!
If it had happened to me...
Damn son of a donkey!
Chandri!
You won't ever leave me, will you?
Sometimes, I'm afraid.
How close we are now!
Hey, Rami Reddy! Come here!
How often must I tell you
to get off this field?
I must come all this way
to remind you, huh?
You've got a swollen head, it seems!
Why the sarcasm, sir?
You asked me to come here.
Where will I go now if you
send me away?
I don't know about all that.
Don't try to wheedle me!
I have court orders,
I'll have you know!
Will you vacate?
Or shall I throw you out?
You want us to starve and
die because you have papers!
You may behead us but
we won't budge!
You talk big, don't you?
Maqbool, beat up Malliga.
We harm no one.
Let us live.
What're you waiting for?
Throw him out!
You may bring the Devil,
but we won't budge.
I'll see that you pay for this!
Get lost!
Whatever you may say,
what we did wasn't right.
He'll take revenge!
So what then, we keep quiet?
- How will we withstand his fury?
He has strong backing!
- But we can't keep quiet!
What else can we do but bear it?
I don't like what Bapi Reddy did.
What happened is done.
Let's decide what to do next.
Who will keep quiet if
your land is taken?
Do they give charity when we starve?
You folks will not listen to me...
Wait! Listen to what
I have to say.
What's the point of arguing?
It's better to tell
the Sangam folk.
They're educated folk.
They'll go to court for us.
What do you say?
What else? Who will say
no to a good thing?
You're quiet, Hanuma.
You have said nothing.
What will I say?
Who will listen to me?
All must speak!
Tell us what you think.
What he says is good and right.
Let's tell the Sangam folk.
Let's do as they say.
What about you, Veerayya?
Let's do it. We won't
loose anything.
And you, Ranganna?
I think it's a good idea!
You're quiet,
Rami Reddy Uncle.
What's there for me to say?
Why should I stop you? Do it.
Whatever you do, do it soon.
The bastards have grown arrogant!
They dare attack him!
Mastan, what were you doing
when all this happened?
I told them we had court
orders but they would not listen.
You were all idle?
You were away. Nor was
the young Dora here.
So what could we do?
So, Mastan! You stand
twiddling your thumbs!
Don't let me hear of such
things ever again!
Go! And see to
the guys who did it.
Stop, stop!
All of you, hear me!
Look at those three.
That guy Bapi Reddy ran
away with his father.
Or his fate would have been the same.
Go on, beat them.
Thieving whore-sons!
Dirty rogues...
Come, Ramayya. Sit down.
Things all right with you?
- Yes.
What're you putting in,
by the way?
Betel leaves and cloves.
Gives gruel a good flavour.
Why not ghee instead of all this?
How can we afford real ghee nowadays?
I heard
something happened in the village.
Nothing new.
They paraded Rami Reddy's
sons on donkeys.
I expected something
like this to happen.
No sign of Chandri?
She's at the Gadi.
Pratap Reddy has come.
Wait. She'll be back.
Hey, Baginayak, come over...
- Coming.
When did you come?
Want some water?
I'll fetch it.
Where did you go?
- To the Dora's Gadi.
Why?
- Pratap Reddy sent word.
So, you go when he calls?
- Can you dare disobey the Dora?
What happened there?
Speak up!
What else?
What always happens.
But believe me...I didn't
let him touch my breasts.
So?
They'll have milk later...
I told him not to touch them.
May you rot in hell!
Ramayya...try to understand!
You seem new around here.
Will you fill up?
The water's over.
What caste are you?
- Telugu.
Where are you from, son?
Siripuram. I told you.
I forgot. Why did you come
to this far off Suryapet?
What else but for livelihood?
I couldn't live there.
Rama, someone's at the door.
Go see who it is.
You fool. Is the Seth in?
Yes, sir.
Sir, Amir Sahib has come.
How come you graced my poor
home so early in the day?
No special reason.
I felt like seeing you.
So here I am.
Rama, get some snacks for Amir Sahib.
I told you! Find all details
before buying that land.
Why are you bothered?
I'll talk to Amir Sahib.
Give him something and
everything will be fine.
I don't know. He seems very greedy.
Seems to be expecting a lot.
We're getting such good land
so cheap. And you grumble!
Don't worry. We'll contact
the police when taking claim.
One word from him
and it's all done.
Rama is a good boy.
He is good at house work.
Don't send him on errands.
Let him be at home.
All right. How can
I say no to you?
Give me another pan.
No, brother no!
- Go on, smoke.
Please brother, no.
I must go. My Seth is
going to town.
Madam, you called me?
Ramayya, let down
the mosquito net.
Did you eat?
- No. I'll eat now, Madam.
I left you some sweets.
Eat it.
All right.
By the way, are you married?
- No, Madam.
Any kept woman back home?
Well, wait...
Come, sit here.
Here, some closer...
Madam, what's this?
Don't tell anyone.
It's all right, come here.
What a chance! And you
lost it!
You let go a willing bird!
You're a useless guy!
Drink.
No.
- Have a drink, you fool.
Give me some money.
Why did you leave her?
- My god, she's the Seth's wife!
So what? She is a woman, too.
She'd have given you money
if only you'd obeyed her.
You ruined it all.
Just look at me!
Three burglaries!
I went to jail ten times!
I was working for a Seth, too.
He had a daughter.
She was 14, a real juicy girl.
One day, with her...
You thieving whore-son!
Up to your dirty tricks, are you?
Brought a beggar home and
what does he do? Steal!
Where have you hidden it?
Tell me!
I didn't steal. I don't know!
Then who stole it?
Did it walk away?
Look at that ugly
thieving mug!
I know who you are going
round with!
Answer me straight. Or I'll
have the police beat you up!
Madam, I found the plate...
...in the puja room.
Were you blind all this time?
My god, you think this
dirty son of a bitch is any better?
Sir...
What's the matter?
I won't stay here anymore.
I'll go.
Why? Is your belly
getting too full?
I beg you, Sir.
I won't stay here.
Give me my wage.
It's a topsy-turvy world,
my friend.
I told you then but you
didn't listen.
You did nothing, gained
nothing. Only got a bad name.
I don't want to live in
Suryapet anymore.
Where will you go?
Back home?
My village!
What's left there for me?
Go there and you'll be
Dora's bounded labourer.
Wonder how my father is.
Chandri...I thought
she was mine.
The Dora called her...
and she went to him.
Why should I live there?
I have nothing there...
Absolutely nothing...
Where will you go then?
Anywhere...
What's it to you?
Come with me...
I'll show you what fun is.
Where's Lachi?
- How should I know?
- Ask over there!
He has come for Lachi, I hear...
From where?
- Seems like a smart guy!
Lachi? Lachi!
You have to wait a little.
Take care of him...
What are you staring for?
Come, sit close to me.
Can I touch you?
Your friend has paid me.
So do what you want! Come...
Ugh! Drunken bastard!
Hey, stop!
Not that way! This way.
No, not that way...this way.
What is this? You're making
me go around the world.
Haven't I paid you?
Go on, go!
Where have we come to?
To the same place you got in!
There's the liquor shop!
Good, I'll get off.
Some fare you are...
Take it.
Let's go to the cinema.
We'll go straight to
the theatre.
Stop...I'll get down and walk.
No, sir. I'll take you.
No matter. You stop.
Let's go.
How long have you had
this cough?
About a month.
Haven't you seen a doctor?
What's your name?
- Ramayya
Where do you stay?
You know the chabutra over
there? Next to that...
By the way, Ramayya...
Have you joined the Union?
What Union?
- The Rikshaw Union
Why do I need Unions and stuff?
- Why?
We're just day labourers.
Why do we need it?
It's very wrong to think
this way.
Why are there Unions?
to help and look after you!
It'll help if you're in
trouble tomorrow.
A Union will safeguard your rights.
Get in, sir.
Breathe in.
Take a deep breath.
What's wrong with my friend?
Hakim Sahib says your pain will
increase if you operate a rickshaw.
No rickshaw pulling, he says.
- How will I live, then?
Stop for a few days, bhai.
You'll get better.
Radayya, Maqbool Sahib
will speak. You must come.
Ramayya...
Come to the gate-meeting
this afternoon. Don't miss it.
What good am I there?
Don't say that. Come and hear
what he has to say.
They're depriving us of all
our rights. Sucking us dry!
When we ask for a raise, they
say yes but never raise wages.
The wage they provide doesn't
even meet our basic needs.
We must be united if our lot
is to be improved!
Nothing is impossible
to achieve if we are united!
Long Live Revolution!
Long Live the Workers' Union!
Workers of the world, unite!
I feel we must talk to the
owners before the strike.
Carry on with that,
I told you.
Peaceful means may not work...
- Let us come to a decision.
Don't you recognize me, sir?
You look familiar.
You got into my rickshaw,
and then walked when I started to cough.
It was I, sir.
Are you OK now?
- Yes.
When did you join here?
- A month ago.
Have you joined the Union?
No, but I'll join right away.
You must. The Union is
for you all.
Yes, kill me and my kids!
Then you'll be happy!
When my kids and I die,
you can get happily drunk!
No one can stop you then,
go on! Kill us!
You're getting too big
for your own good!
Naturally! With you feeding
me so well!
You keep talking and I'll kick you!
One more word and I'll kill you!
I earn the money,
and it's mine to spend.
Who are you tell me how to spend it?
You talk like your father's
the one feeding you.
You didn't say it was
your father's money.
You've no shame while
raising kids!
You whore! I'll break your
bones if you say anything!
Yes, kill and eat me!
You hungry bastard.
I'll teach you!
You feel nice when you
fight this way?
Did I say anything to her?
You make my name mud!
Look at him! If he drinks
away his wages...
What will my kids
and I live on?
Who cares about me? All anyone
cares about are themselves.
My body, my heart is on fire
when I work near the boiler.
Do you care?
Sure, you do.
She only knows how to nag.
The factory owners make
a lot of profit.
Let's see how they do it.
Let's take our factory
as an example.
To manufacture goods,
the factory needs...
...machines, fuel, raw material
and labour.
Machines, fuel and
raw material depreciate.
Let's take the above cost
to be Rs.3000.
Now, another value is
added to the cost.
That's labour.
It's value is Rs.1000.
So, the total cost is Rs.4000.
As far as raw material, fuel
and machines are concerned...
...the owner pays the correct price.
Do they pay labour its
right value? No!
They give workers
only 500 rupees.
What's the total?
Depreciation, fuel plus
raw stock is Rs.3000.
Add 500 for the labour.
It all adds up to 3500,
right?
Where has the other 500 gone?
That's called surplus value.
The surplus value goes right
into the owner's pocket.
If a worker works half a day
for his own livelihood...
...he works the rest of the
day for the owner's profit.
Yes, this is exploitation
from within.
How do we stop it?
Good question. The state of
the villages is atrocious.
You've seen the cities, too.
It must change radically.
How can that happen?
- Why not?
For instance, take the
People of Russia.
They fought and liberated
themselves from landlords...
...and capitalists.
Similarly, other people are
fighting this exploitation.
I'll go, sir.
Come in.
Have some tea before you go.
Want some water?
- No, sir.
Sit down, Ramayya.
Surayya, let's have some tea.
What's this?
- I must send it to my father.
Oh, to your village.
- Yes, sir.
Your father's name?
- Irayya.
Name of the village?
- Siripuram, Nalgonda Zilla.
What shall I write to
your father?
Well, that I'm okay here.
Why don't you learn to read?
- Me?
Yes, I mean you Ramayya.
Look, the world of tomorrow
is yours. Of workers.
What you're learning now
is through experience.
If you're educated...
You'll learn about society
and the world.
Your skill will improve,
and shine.
Concede our just demands!
- What can I do?
We'll stop working if our
demands aren't met!
Come what may, we must win
our rights.
Give me a beedi.
Ramayya...
Let's go and talk.
How are you in here?
What happened to you?
Oh, that.
It's a long story.
Forget my affair.
Why are you here?
We had a strike at our factory
and I was arrested.
I want some water.
Mallayya, get some water.
How's my father?
- He's fine.
We didn't know where you were
until you sent money.
Your father misses you.
Is Chandri there?
She married and went away.
I couldn't think properly then.
I came apart because
I was angry at Chandri.
Now I know how wrong I was.
What's the point
of repenting now?
I heard there was a big
struggle in our village.
Tell me about it.
Our village is really not
the same anymore.
The entire village is as one.
It's joined the Sangam
and stands united.
Those who had terrorized us
can't sleep now!
For fear of the Sangam.
Really? Are you telling me
the truth?
Would I ever lie to you?
All are one, whether dobi,
barber, potter, or cobbler.
No bonded labour or tax!
Do what you will, we said.
We were all one.
The Doras were raging with fury.
They got us beaten by goondas.
Did we take it lying down?
We gave it back to them!
One day...
We must all stand united
and face any hardship.
But we'll not tolerate
their tyranny.
We must all be together.
Sathi Reddy is like a father
to us all.
The Police Patel came
at that moment.
A meeting, is it?
Sathi Reddy, come here!
What's the matter?
Come, I must talk to you.
How often must I tell you to
stop this Sangam nonsense?
Came all this way to tell me this?
Dora asked me to tell you
to come back to work.
Tell your Dora we won't
dance to his tune now.
Come! All of you!
As he ran, Mastan turned
and fired.
Our Rangadu died.
Almost a hundred were
badly injured.
They called the police and
got four of us arrested.
And then, they took us away.
Beat us up like hell.
They branded me
with an iron rod.
While branding me,
they said:
"We're laying the road to
Moscow on your head."
You're going the right way,
they said.
What's this Moscow?
Moscow is a city in Russia.
The poor there fought and won.
I'm just an ignorant
shepherd.
I don't have an inch of land.
But when I see him,
I just fell this.
Every man must have
some land.
We're all attached to this
land till we die.
What's that ruckus?
Shut up!
Nagayya, I'm thinking of
going to our village.
Yes, you must.
Go and met the Sangam folk.
When will you come?
I don't know
But tell them all:
I will be back.
What're they saying, Sir?
- Lies. All lies.
They say the Sangam members
are all goondas.
That they loot and
burn villages.
They are spouting lies
by the mouthful.
Sir, I want to know:
do you think people believe this?
Yes. There are a few
who believe it.
Anyway, you decided
as I had hoped you would.
I'm very happy you are
returning home this way.
You'll have to go home
via Alipuram.
You remember Yella Reddy,
don't you?
Yes, didn't he come to our
meeting in Murshidabad?
That's right. You remember well.
Give him this letter.
His house is by the fort.
Remember all that I told
you and keep it in view.
Understand the conditions
of the village well.
We'll surely win.
The final victory is ours.
Red Salute!
Halt!
Come up this way.
I've come from Hyderabad.
I have a letter for Yella Reddy
from Maqbool Sahib.
But when I went there...
Yes, I know son.
I'm Yella Reddy's mother.
But...how did it all happen?
Last night, Razakars and the
police attacked the village.
We didn't know what to do
and ran helter skelter.
Whoever they caught,
they killed.
They molested the women.
Others they tossed
into the garbage.
They may come again at any time.
Can you spare some water?
Did you see Yella Reddy?
Were his eyes open?
We had beaten back two
earlier raids.
But couldn't withstand
yesterday's attack.
We don't know what to do now.
We must get more guns...
Form more groups.
Distribute Zamindars' lands
amongst the people.
Our people in the cities
suffer the same.
That's what Maqbool Sahib
wrote to Yella Reddy, too.
We'll not stop the fight now.
In Telangana,
by the end of 1946...
the Nizam government
carried out mass arrests.
And let loose police terrorism.
Under the pretext of
"Law & Order,"...
...Razakars raided villages.
Their means of terror were
burning, looting, killing...
...raping women, and extortion.
Telangana oppressors redefined terror
and blood baths in history.
The raids continued
day and night.
People were victims of torture.
Some who were captured were
tortured into betraying the Sangam.
People were imprisoned,
spies were let loose.
Dark clouds of fear and
terror enveloped Telangana.
Father...
How are you?
I'm here, Father. All our
troubles are over now.
Where's the gun?
Hand it over.
Telangana is awake.
Resistance started
everywhere.
Andhra Mahasabha and
the Communist Party...
...formed groups to resist
the terror.
The people of Telangana
took up arms to liberate...
...themselves from an evil
feudal rule.
Guerilla groups were formed
in villages.
People began to collect arms
and make country guns.
The armed resistance of
the people...
...shook the foundations
of feudalism.
Will you eat?
- No.
Why don't you eat a little?
I'm not hungry now.
You're here and back in
the jungle within an hour.
You don't tell me where
you are or what you do.
You know everything, Father.
The villages are up in arms.
All the Doras have fled
to the city.
Our Dora has gone
He may be gone, but his son
Pratap Reddy is here.
The whole village is united.
Let's see how long he stays.
I don't know. I'm afraid
for you sometimes.
You are my only son.
It's not as if I had four
and could afford to lose one.
What better life is there
than working for the people?
You know what our life has
been like here!
Time is on our side now.
All of Telangana is aflame!
Don't ask me to give up
my work.
What you're doing is good.
I didn't say it wasn't.
But you roam all over. I'm
afraid of what may happen.
Why fear? What's meant to happen,
will happen.
Dora, the Sangam folk are
making bombs and guns.
We can't fight them during the day.
What do you mean?
- What I say is true.
They are very strong.
- So, then we are weak like women?
You cowardly bastard!
Sir, we don't have to be afraid.
Who is afraid?
I beg your pardon, sir.
It's better to heed Durgayya.
Yes, Dora. You have fed us
and we're afraid for you.
All the Doras have gone away.
It'd be better if you too
went to the city, Dora.
We will come with you, too.
Who are you to tell me?
What's life without guts?
I'll send for more police
and Razakars.
Let's see who dares come here!
I had my say.
It is as you wish.
There is no wishing. I'll not
leave the Gadi, never.
Well, Mastan?
If the Master permits...
You head over there.
I'll approach from here.
You know what to do.
Throw the bomb from
that corner.
We must get down after
they go to that side.
All the others will rush in
when the bomb goes off.
Mallayya, bring the papers.
Throw them into the fire.
Wait!
These papers held us in
bondage all these years.
The Doras could play their
ruthless game.
They sucked us dry.
Their game is up.
Our hardships are over.
Go, set fire to that heap.
Victory to the Sangam!
We still have the problem of
land in spite of all this.
All this land was ours once.
Then the Doras exploited it.
Now, we have our land back.
Uncle Sathi Reddy will preside
over the land distribution.
Why me? there are other
elders in the village.
It's not a matter of big or
small, but for the benefit of all.
Yes, what we want
is distribution.
In the Telangana struggle...
...30 lakhs of people in 3000
villages were liberated.
They established
a people's rule.
People's committees brought
about massive land reforms.
Nearly 10 lakh acres
were redistributed.
Bonded labour was abolished,
along with exploitation.
Look, my Ramayya is
giving land to everyone!
Whenever I ask, all he says
is wait. And wait!
Others matter to him
more than I do!
What is this, Irayya?
You're being childish.
We are giving to everyone,
one by one.
You're so impatient! You want
to harvest before sowing!
That's not it...
- Don't drone on in my ear.
You called me. I suppose
everyone's got land now?
Well, what of these people?
Let's see. How about land
beyond the village for them?
Listen, all of you.
You will all get land,
as Ramayya has said.
Don't worry.
All of you will get
land sooner or later.
And Ramayya, we must also
distribute...
...the cattle and ploughs
we found in the Gadi.
Yes, Uncle. I hadn't
forgotten that.
Ramayya, why don't you give
me some land now, at least?
I'm tired of asking.
Wait, Father. You are
driving me crazy.
See how he brushes me off!
Listen, Irayya.
You take the two acres next
to the Dhobi ghat.
I'll tell Hanuma. You go and
tend your land.
May you live to be one hundred!
God bless you! Your words
are sweet music.
I'll go see my land.
I wonder how my folks are.
There's been no word from them.
I keep thinking about them.
My brother hasn't come by
even once.
Don't you worry.
They'll all be well.
I met a farmer from there
the other day.
All the Doras have gone
to the city.
That so?
- Yes.
You know, over there they're
fighting hard and well.
We're teaching our members
rifle shooting there.
Why don't you learn?
Why don't I learn, if only
some would teach me!
One...Two...Three...
August 15th, 1947
India gains Independence.
Power was transferred from
the British Viceroy...
...to the Indian National
Congress led by Pandit Nehru.
The entire country
celebrated Independence Day.
People danced with joy.
But conditions in the State
of Hyderabad were different.
The Nizam refused to join
the Indian Union.
He declared that Hyderabad
would be free.
Demanding that Hyderabad
accede to the Indian Union...
The Indian National Congress,
the Communist Party...
...and other National Parties
held demonstrations.
The disturbed situation
and public pressure...
...forced the Nizam Government
to free political prisoners.
The white man's rule is over.
It's our own rule now.
We're free.
They've released prisoners from
jail. We were freed, too.
Sattayya here has been released.
Yes, I too am coming
from prison.
Why not come to our village?
- Shall I?
Sing for us.
Cart yoked to cart, we will
build a caravan of 16 carts.
And which cart will get you,
Oh Nizam of ruthless rule?
You've worsted the Nazis,
Oh Nizam of ruthless rule.
The police and the army,
you think they are mighty.
You turned them loose,
to loot our villages.
Oh Nizam of ruthless rule
All the landlords and
all the feudal lords, too
They cower and seek your
shelter, oh brave protector.
Men and women both,
and all the children, too...
We collected cart loads of
stones and pelted your army.
And into their eyes,
we threw chilli water
Your mighty army turned tail
and ran, oh ruthless Nizam
Sprawling Suryapeta is ours
as is Nalgonda in the Center
You're in far off Hyderabad
and Golconda towers above
Under the ramparts
of Golconda fort...
We build you a grave!
O Nizam of ruthless rule
The Nizam's official called
the landlords and...
...title holders who had left
the villages...
...to an emergency meeting.
Speaking to them, he said:
"We are all in an extremely
difficult situation."
"On the one hand, there is
the Indian Union..."
"...and anti-social forces
on the other. You know it all."
"You must all go back and
protect peace and order."
"Foreign powers have
promised us weapons."
"Similarly, the Government will
also provide full support."
Generation after generation...
...under the kindness of our
gracious Nizam Sarkar...
...we have been the owners of our lands.
Our beloved and noble state
is threatened by danger now.
We'll not resist any
sacrifice asked of us.
Yes. This is what I expected
of all of you.
Return to your lands and
help us quell this rebellion.
Hark, oh victorious son of
India, victory is ours!
In the North is a hamlet.
Rampuram is its name, oh son
In that hamlet are
only hovels and huts
It's the home of workers
who labour day and night
The sweat of share-croppers
water the crops, oh son
Whatever the crop,
unjust levies are their lot.
Thanedar and Tehsildar,
all must be given their cut.
Get up! Run! The police
and Razakars are coming!
From where?
Which side?
We must stop the police and
Razakars! You, go over there!
September 13th, 1948
The Union Government took Police
Action against Hyderabad
Within five days,
on September 19th, 1948...
The Nizam surrendered
to the Indian Government.
The Indian Army entered
Hyderabad and Secunderabad
It was commanded by
General J.N. Chowdhry
The people hailed the army.
The State of Hyderabad
was declared...
...part of the Union of India.
You were saying something.
Tell us more.
The Congress held a meeting
in Pirlapelli.
All went well. I'll tell you
what happened there.
The Nizam is gone. No more
trouble from Razakars or cops.
Our land is now part of
the Indian Union.
We, too, must join the Union.
We must return the lands
to the Zamindars.
The people and Zamindars
must live like brothers.
We must stop the struggle
and maintain peace.
This is what was said
in Pirlapalli.
We must think about it.
What's there to think about? Think!
Might as well garland the Doras!
Carry them in a parade!
Wait, Nagayya. Why get so impatient?
Elders say impatience gets
you nowhere.
Ugh, Elders! We'll not give up
land nor let the Dora return.
Listen well to what I say.
Even if God comes down,
I'll not give up my land!
We're not waiting with
folded hands to welcome them.
This concerns us all.
We must all stand united.
What do you think?
It's like we climbed up a
ladder only to be pushed off.
It's back to misery again.
A three-day wonder,
as I expected!
We fought hard to reclaim our
land. And now, you talk this way?
Some integrity!
Stop being impatient.
Let others speak.
Yes, how can all of us
get so carried away?
We must weigh
the pros and cons.
You speak, Sathi Reddy.
We're all pulling in
different directions.
We can't be hasty. No point
in being wise after the fact.
The Nizam is gone anyway.
How many have we lost
in this struggle?
Our life is so hard
and brutish.
I think it's better to stop
the struggle.
Why get into this at all, then?
You should have kept mum.
Is this some practice fight?
Stop, he says!
We shall never give up our land.
Think! How can we
retain it?
You know, Uncle.
That villain won't let us
live if he comes back here.
We'll die twice!
Then let's die now.
That's true enough.
Our life will go back to
misery if we let the Dora return.
He's right.
That's true.
No giving up our land!
- Or letting the Dora back in!
What's destined will happen!
- Wait!
What will be, will be.
Your thoughts, Elder?
So be it.
We can't stop fate.
Though the guns boom...
And bombs rain down...
Don't lower the flag
we hold aloft
Hail, our flag of victory!
Dedicated to all who died
in the Telangana struggle.