OUTSKIRTS
A story by K. Finn
Script by B. Barnet & K. Finn
Directed and produced by Boris Barnet
Cinematography: M.
Kirillov & A. Spiridonov
Music by S. Vasilenko
Sound by L. Obolensky
Costumes and design by S.
Kozlovsky Produced by A. Dmitriyev
CAST
E. Kuzmina, M. Zharov N.
Bogolyubov, N. Kryuchkov
M. Yanshin, G. Klering
A. Chistyakov, S. Komarov
In the backwoods of Tsarist Russia...
Good Lord!
What is that?
The Kryakovskys.
And which are those?
The Syshchovskys.
Here are the Syshchovskys.
Those are the Fylonovskys.
They're going on strike!
Where are you going, Nikolai?
We have to support them.
Who do we need to support?
Well guys, let's go to the factory.
Wait, Kolka, I'll teach you a lesson.
What?
I'll teach you a lesson.
Boss, I won't take any lessons from you.
Let's go, guys.
Brothers... what are you doing?
Where are you going?
What the hell are you doing?
Let's go, let's go.
I order you to disperse immediately.
I give you one minute to think.
Those arrested will not be released.
Hey!
Guys, have mercy!
Beat me instead, you scoundrel!
You're beating students!
Beat me instead! You're
beating educated people,
damn it!
Wait, guys...
What's going on?
Robert Karlovich. Hey, Robert Karlovich.
Would you like to play checkers?
Mit grossen Vergnugen!
With great pleasure,
Alexander Petrovich,
but give me a minute.
I have to finish the
letter to my son in Germany.
Please, have a seat.
Anka.
Are you running around
again? Can't stay at home?
You have a nice girl,
Alexander Petrovich.
- Go, go.
- Goodbye.
I got yours, Alexander Petrovich.
Hello, Alexander Feodorovich.
Alexander Feodorovich!
How long will it last?
- Will what last?
- The strike.
God knows!
So, that's the situation.
And who is Alexander Feodorovich?
Our new tenant.
Social revolutionary
democrat... a striker.
He is one of those who
organized a strike in 1905.
And this one as well.
Look, he went somewhere again.
Daddy.
- Something happened.
- What do you want?
Get up, Senka.
Sen.
You sleep like hell. Senka!
Get up, Senka.
- I'm talking to you.
- Why should I get up?
Dusya came.
Get out.
Let's go, let's go. I'm talking to you.
Guten Morgen, Robert Karlovich.
Hello, Alexander Petrovich.
Hey, Robert Karlovich,
shouldn't we go get some beer?
Alexander Petrovich, don't you
know what is whistling over there?
They are whistling.
Maybe something has happened.
Let's go have a look and
get some beer on our way.
With a great pleasure,
Alexander Petrovich.
I am getting ready.
What's going on, Robert Karlovich?
Where is my hat?
One minute.
Try this on.
What do you think, Alexander Petrovich?
I think it's fine.
I think so, too. Let's go.
URGENT TELEGRAM Germany
Has Declared War On Russia
Germany Has Declared War On
Russia Departure Of Ambassadors
Departure Of Ambassadors
To Russian People!
We'll win easily.
My dear Robert Karlovich,
we'll easily defeat those scoundrels!
What are you saying,
Alexander Petrovich?
I'm saying that we've got it won.
You won't win, Alexander
Petrovich, we can fight pretty well.
You know me.
We have always fought
together for your rights.
And you have trusted me and
you should trust me again.
Now, in this fateful moment
when the Germans have
conquered our borders...
what should we do?
You should look for the
answer to this question
in the heart of the Russian man.
In the face of the external enemy,
let's forget internal class strife
and stop the strike.
Let's bravely go to battle
believing in victory.
Go to battle!
What are you doing?
What are you doing? I am asking you.
- I'll go.
- Where will you go?
He won't go anywhere.
- No, I'll go.
- Where will you go?
Volunteer.
If I said so, it means I'll go.
I'm telling you, I'll go.
What are you doing?
You're taking everything with you.
I'm telling you, let me go!
Wait.
Cowards.
I'll show you! You're
not going anywhere!
Cowards, I told you to let me go!
What a fool.
So, Petrovich,
I am leaving my horse with you.
Take care of it.
I'll pay you when I return.
If I don't return, keep it.
It's war. Band together, brothers!
They want to enslave and destroy us.
For our Father Tsar, for our Motherland,
for Orthodox faith, let's fight.
All of us will go for the purpose of...
Lord, bless us to win.
Hurrah.
Hurrah, hurrah, hurrah.
God bless you, sons.
"Contract".
"Authorized representative of the
Union of cities in the person of...
on the one hand,
and merchant of II Guild,
Mikin, on the other hand.
The present Contract on the supply of
boots to the army at the price of..."
With a rasp, with a rasp.
Clean harder, harder.
Move like that, like that.
# And the German infantry #
# Faces the "Fortress on the Rhine" #
# And our brave cavalry #
# Is finally chasing after them #
# The artillery, with 10 big guns #
# And courage like old Fritz #
# Cannons rumbling by one by one #
# A forest full of bayonets #
# Slash like lighting through the air #
# And finally they call halt. #
- Hello, Robert Karlovich.
- Hello.
Be so kind as to accept what I owe you.
That's very kind of you.
Anichka.
No more checkers.
Daddy, Daddy, are the Germans...
"Daddy, Daddy". What do you want?
Hey!
Robert Karlovich!
Oh, son, son! The years you've wasted!
One, two, three, four, five.
Six, seven, eight...
Cut it out!
Does someone need this?
No.
Kolka.
Kolya.
Nikolai... Kolka!
What do you want?
Go to the front line!
Quickly!
Why did you stay here?
I am asking, why?
- My tooth hurts.
- Get the hell out!
- I'll show you.
- What did I do? What?
- What have I done to you?
- I'll show you.
What have I done to you?
What for? Leave me alone...!
Are you alive, or what?
It's okay. It's okay.
This means you're in
captivity. Hey, you...
OUR VALIANT TROOPS HELD
THE FRONT LINE OF THE ENEMY,
HAVING SEIZED RICH BOOTY AND PRISONERS.
You scoundrels, betrayers of
Jesus, you're all around here...
you have to be shot.
You dirty Russian pigs.
You will have to pay
the price for all of us,
you no-good bums.
To the camp for prisoners of war:
Due to difficulties with food,
as of today prisoners of war
are permitted to leave the camp
and go into the city to look for
work from 10:00 a.m. to 7:00 p.m.
Signed by Colonel...
How much is the watch?
No, no, how... how much?
What time is it?
What time is it, sir?
7:00.
It's 7:00 already.
I have to get back to the
base. They lock it at 7:30.
After work, we can go to town,
but we have to be back on time.
I asked for work all over
town. I am a shoemaker.
Do you understand?
But everybody tells me, "We
don't have any work for Germans".
Russian soldiers at the
front were not as hostile
as the people here in town.
Do you understand?
You look a lot like my little sister,
but she's shorter than you.
I haven't heard from her in a long time.
I think my little brother
will soon have to join up.
I hope he doesn't end
up on the Western Front,
but in Russia instead.
That's better than Verdun.
Do you understand?
No, I don't understand.
It's okay.
I have to go. It's late.
Goodbye.
- Who's here?
- Keep it down, for God's sake.
It's okay.
Keep it down.
- Would you like to eat?
- With great pleasure.
- What? What?
"With great pleasure. Pleasure".
"With great pleasure".
Do you speak German?
We had Robert Karlovich,
an elderly German.
He left a long time ago.
They played checkers with
my father all the time.
He was the one who taught me.
Why didn't you tell me
earlier you could speak German?
We could have had such a
nice conversation coming back.
I thought you didn't understand a word.
- Yes.
- What, yes?
- Do you have a knife?
- Right away.
Would you like some tea?
I didn't come to have tea. What's
the last name of your guest?
- Mueller III.
- What?
Mueller III.
Third... they had three
Muellers in their army.
Look, dear Third.
Do me a favor, turn around and get out.
I insist that you leave.
Get out of here.
He is a shoemaker as well.
Get out of here, ugly German mug.
It's a shame, Alexander Petrovich.
Stop teaching me! I have
teachers better than you.
Where's the way out?
- The way out?
- Yes, yes.
There.
Anka.
Thank you for everything.
So long.
Hey!
Take it out and show it.
Are you a shoemaker?
Yes, I am a shoemaker.
You know what? Let's
go. You'll work for me.
I used to work from home as well.
Let's go, let's go.
You shouldn't cry now.
Now we're in war,
and before we win...
we can't feel sorry for our enemies.
You should be with us body and soul.
We are doing the right thing.
Hello, hello.
- Maybe you'd like some tea?
- I don't feel like it.
Why is he here?
Listen, give me the horse.
- Have you seen my folks?
- No, I haven't.
Go on, sew.
Boy, what's wrong with you?
Master, his legs are
broken. What a hell.
Master, what should we do now?
If he dies, I'll die, too.
Why are you talking about
the horse and yourself,
when all of Russia is crying?
The entire Russian nation
doesn't spare the power
and lives of its best sons
in the great heroic war
to defend our Motherland.
Russia will come out of that great
struggle revitalized and strengthened.
It's not the time for despair,
when our hearts are full of joy,
and the idea of victory near.
The victory is close, victory only.
Hit the Germans, defeat the Germans...
complete and definite victory.
We'll get you out of this dirty hole.
There is no other way.
Mail.
You've got mail.
"To Peter Ivan Gadkin"...
for me.
"Dear Peter Ivanovich,
with deep sympathy,
we inform you that your
older son, Nikolai Petrovich,
is in the hospital with minor injuries
and your younger son, Semyon Petrovich,
was killed during an attack".
# When the soldiers march through town #
# The girls will open
windows and doors... #
Stop singing.
I told you to stop!
What did you do?
Get out! Get out of here!
I'm talking to you. Get out.
Hit the Germans!
Beat the Germans! Beat him!
Beat the Germans!
Stop, scoundrels.
So what if he is German? He's
still a shoemaker like us.
What do you want? You should disperse.
Go, go.
My Senka was killed.
Take him to the bed. Move, move.
He's not permitted to go out
anymore, since it causes a big ruckus.
Go away, go away.
Pick him up.
Anka, come home, you brat!
I was knocked down...
simply because I'm German.
Then a girl came,
she was nice to me.
If it hadn't been for her,
they would have killed me.
Compatriots, have you heard?
Our Tsar has abdicated.
- You're lying.
- Who's lying?
What a rush!
Brothers, friends, citizens...
the rising sun of revolution
has destroyed the tyranny.
Hello, Alexander Feodorovich.
I don't have time, I don't have time.
I greet you on behalf of
the Provisional Government.
Free citizens of free Russia, hurrah!
Now the Duma of people will govern.
Duma...
To hell with the Tsar.
We can assume that there
will be no war anymore.
We can assume that
from the landowners...
the land...
What a rush!
War is over.
The land will be...
Attack.
Well... okay, attack.
Fire, fire!
Brothers...
when will this be over?
Don't save me.
I have a wife and child at home.
I think he doesn't want to fight.
No, he doesn't.
Explain to me, my dear...
we don't want to fight,
they don't want to fight,
but still, this is the fourth
year that we've been fighting.
Where are you going, Nikolai?
Let me talk.
Every scoundrel, German agent,
Bolshevik, spy and traitor,
is appealing for
fraternization on the front.
At this very moment, when
the country, covered in blood,
is fighting against
the external enemies,
the Bolsheviks betray the Motherland.
The Bolsheviks disintegrate the army.
On behalf of the Provisional
Government, I declare...
- Shoot those scoundrels!
- Don't disturb me, let me talk.
On behalf of the Provisional
Government, I declare,
with no mercy, we will destroy soldiers,
traitors calling for fraternization
and disintegration of the army.
Nikolai!
Artillery, shoot the
traitor of the Motherland.
Shoot!
My dear Nikolai...
Don't give rifles to the commanders.
Deputies, soldiers...
the Winter Palace has been captured.
Anka!
Sit down and play!
Stop!
What's the matter?
- We've arrived, get off.
- Go to hell!
- I told you, we've arrived!
- I won't get off.
We kindly request you to get off.
- I'm submitting to violence.
- As you should! Peter, arrest him!
Get up.
Get up, Kolya.
Kolechka.
Kolechka!
Kolya.
- What do you want?
- Get up.
Now.
What a rush!
THE END