And if you're a
Pink fan, don't forget she'll be
touring the UK
and Ireland next week...
- Pink is coming to Wembley.
- That's right,
Pink and her Beautiful Trauma
tour are coming back
- to Europe and the UK.
- Rolling into London
with two massive shows
at Wembley Stadium.
♪ I'm coming up ♪
♪ So you better
get this party started ♪
♪ I'm coming up ♪
♪ So you better
get this party started ♪
♪ Get this party started
on a Saturday night ♪
♪ Everybody's waiting
for me to arrive ♪
♪ Sending out the message
to all of my friends ♪
♪ We'll be looking flashy
in my Mercedes-Benz ♪
♪ I got lots of style
with my gold diamond rings ♪
♪ I can go for miles,
if you know what I mean ♪
Come on!
♪ I'm coming up ♪
♪ So you better
get this party started ♪
♪ I'm coming up,
said I'm coming ♪
♪ I'm coming up ♪
♪ So you better
get this party started ♪
♪ Pull up to the bumper,
get out of the car ♪
♪ License plate says
"Stunner Number One Superstar" ♪
♪ Hey, I'm coming up... ♪
Ah, thank you.
- Hi.
Hi. Thank you.
All right. We've made it.
Rock and roll. Rock and roll.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Wow.
Come look, buddy.
How cool is this?
Isn't it awesome?
No!
Do it. Put it on.
- Hey. Reel it in.
- Look what we have.
Champagne.
This is a celebration.
Aren't you excited
that Mommy's playing stadiums
this summer in Europe?
- Wanting to say yes.
- I don't.
What if I let you roller-skate?
- Roller-skate?
- Onstage.
- Onstage?
- Would you do it?
- No.
- In your tutu we just made?
- Why not?
I already go onstage.
Yeah, but you could come on
and sing something
- with an actual microphone.
- With an actual...
You could get a record deal.
Or I don't want one.
Probably smart.
Okay. Cheers.
Hi.
- How you doing?
- Ah, here we are.
How are you?
Mmm.
Me, too.
Hi, everybody.
Really small.
I enjoy getting up
and going and seeing the world
with my kids
just as much as I enjoy
nailing it onstage.
Why?
- You can play when we get back, though.
- No, I'm...
There are many reasons
why moms don't do this.
I know that it's a lot easier
for men, just primally,
to just walk out the door
and not look back.
- It-it just is.
- Hold on, buddy. Hold on.
Hold on. I'm gonna hand you to Mama, okay?
There's no way a mother
can walk away from her babies
and not think about them
every single second
of every single day
and not worry
to the point
where you can't sleep.
- For a lot of moms...
- Cheers.
...when they become moms and
they tour, they stop touring,
because you can't imagine
being able to do both.
The only way I can justify
dragging my family
all over the world is that
we're making memories together.
I want it to be worth it.
I want tour to be perfect for
every single person that walks
through those doors
with a ticket in their hand.
- And then get a small one.
- Can I have a medium one?
You can have that size, yes.
But I also want it to be
perfect in my kids' minds.
And I kill myself to do both.
There's a boat.
It feels like 18 lifetimes ago.
- Hi.
- Did I want to end up here?
Yeah. Absolutely.
Did I think I would end up here?
Yeah.
I feel like you sign up for
this life before you get here.
You choose your parents.
You choose your obstacles.
You choose the lessons
that you need to learn.
But, also, I was just trying to
survive my day-to-day situation.
When I first went onstage,
I was not exciting.
My parents had just split up,
and my dad drove me,
and I still remember
that car ride.
I want to reach inside me
and hug that little girl
and just let her know
it's gonna be okay.
♪ You can't hurt me now ♪
♪ I got away from you ♪
♪ I never thought I could ♪
♪ You can't make me cry ♪
♪ You once had the power... ♪
His thing was always... from the
very beginning, he said to me,
"Just put your head back,
spit in the wind
and show 'em what you got."
Get to
your opening spots, please.
- Hey, Wills, move, please.
- Where?
Uh, anywhere outside
of the taped area.
Oh.
Go straight through
all the new stuff first.
Uh-huh, yeah.
- Uh-huh.
- Just to get it.
Just to walk through it.
- So you can just feel this space.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, that way,
it's not your first time
on Friday night, you know?
- So that's all the same.
- Yep.
- Lamps, chandelier, the travelator.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh.
- So they kind of just pop up on the different runways,
but the scale of it
actually looks really nice
for the new stage that you have.
But I won't be anywhere
near Justine, either?
- No, it's more like...
- She'll be far away.
Uh-huh. They're not
gonna be as close to you.
Okay.
- So, act one, two and three I've done.
- Yes.
- So that's already in my body.
- Yeah.
Do we have any backup
Bob Mackie clothes here?
We also have the thing
that Toni made for the Brits.
Oh, we do. Yes, we have that.
- Which could be...
- That could work.
She could tea-dip it overnight
and make it a little redder.
If not, I have to go
to the red-light district
- and find myself an outfit.
- Okay, that's it.
Okay.
We like to say, "Good morning."
- Good morning.
- It's just a...
- Only when you have healthy hips like this.
- Yes.
♪ They are falling
on deaf ears ♪
♪ It won't do no good at all
to try to work it out ♪
♪ How can you replace
all these years? ♪
Hey!
♪ Now you've gone
and thrown away... ♪
Hi, Jamesey.
How you doing? It's everybody.
- Okay.
- Can I say hi to you?
Hello. Hi.
Come on.
♪ Don't hustle me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
♪ Don't mess with me ♪
♪ Don't hustle me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
- ♪ Don't hustle me ♪
- ♪ Whoop, whoop... ♪
Great. High five.
- You don't want these?
- No.
Okay. "No, thank you"?
No.
"No, thank you"?
Can you say "No, thank you"?
- No, thank you.
- Thank you.
Mama.
Mama. Mama, Mama, Mama.
Two, three, four,
five, six, seven...
♪ I think I finally had enough ♪
♪ I think I maybe
think too much ♪
♪ I think this
might be it for us ♪
- ♪ Blow me one last kiss ♪
- ♪ You think I'm... ♪
I always say there's
no door that I walk out of.
Like, some people walk out
the door and they go to work,
and they leave
what's at home at home,
and they go and do their job.
I don't walk
out of a door, ever.
♪ I've had a shit day ♪
♪ You had a shit day... ♪
Everything is melded into one,
and that is both beautiful
and incredibly overwhelming.
How are we supposed to have
the... all of this under control?
♪ What about us?
What about us? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
It was real.
You'd get fired for that
in a Madonna rehearsal.
I think. I heard.
Okay.
♪ We were on fire... ♪
Hit those notes.
You better get
those fucking notes.
♪ It's like we burn so bright
we burn out ♪
♪ I made you chase me ♪
♪ I wasn't that friendly ♪
♪ My love, my drug,
we're messed-up ♪
Sing it!
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ 'Cause we've been on the run
so long they can't find us ♪
♪ Who's gonna have to die
to remind us ♪
♪ That it feels like
we chose this ♪ - ♪ Blindly? ♪
♪ Now I'm gonna fuck up
a hotel lobby ♪
♪ 'Cause these ♪
♪ Tough times,
they keep coming, last night ♪
♪ I might have
messed it up again ♪
♪ Some days
I can barely breathe ♪
♪ After we were high on the
love, don't doubt it was you ♪
♪ Well, I keep taking ♪
♪ Nightmare I wake in ♪
♪ There's nothing, no, nothing ♪
♪ Nothing but you ♪
♪ My perfect rock bottom ♪
♪ Beautiful trauma ♪
♪ My love... ♪
I kept a journal every day
that I was pregnant
and for the first year
of Willow's life.
I've written letters to Willow,
like, on all major occasions.
I wrote her a letter
the day she was born.
I wrote her a letter the day
she went to kindergarten.
Every birthday.
And I keep it in a book.
I'll give it to her one day.
It's interesting
when you're a kid, right?
You think your parents are God.
Like, they're your first idols.
And they're not human beings.
They're just these parents,
the perfect parents.
They're supposed to be perfect.
And their one sole purpose
is to love you perfectly.
And then that fall from grace,
whatever age you are,
it's like
your first heartbreak, right?
Realizing your parents are human
and they have their own lives
and their own faults
and their own mistakes
and they can't
love you perfectly.
They can't even love themselves.
And then you go through
that struggle
for about ten years.
And then you become
their parents.
And you realize, like, "Wait...
"have you always been this way?
Is this why
I think like I think?"
Willow's never gonna feel
that way about me.
- Willow.
- I want cuddles.
- What?
- Oh, let's cuddle.
- Are you coming to the venue with me today, buddy?
- Yeah.
Yeah? Then I have to go get in
the shower and you have to eat,
so we can put clothes
on your butt,
so you can come with me
in the car to the venue.
- Ow.
- 'Cause it's almost rehearsal, so...
Ow, ow, ow.
Everybody eat.
Come eat, dude.
Try this, Jameson, here.
Go eat fruit.
Come on. Go eat fruit.
- No. Oh, no.
- It's an orange.
It's yummy.
No, look, try it, dude.
Jameson, hey.
Hey, look at me.
- I really want you to come with me.
- Uh...
So I need you to be ready.
And I know
you don't like being rushed.
- Ah!
- Are you listening to my words?
- Yeah.
- Okay, go.
I'm gonna give you eggs,
but try this. It's sweet.
- Come on.
- No.
- I am effective.
- How good is that?
That's good, right?
Tell Will to get dressed.
Get dressed.
Willow, go get dressed.
That's too big.
Too big? Okay.
- You ready to go?
- Yeah.
Are you ready for the big day?
♪ Yeah! ♪
Awesome.
♪ Dun, dun, da! ♪
♪ Dun, dun ♪
♪ Da... Willow! ♪
You want to bring that?
- Okay. Come on.
- ♪ Dun, dun, da! ♪
Long as it makes its way home.
All right,
get a sweatshirt, kiddo.
All right, baby,
I'll see you in a few.
- Okay, bye.
- Love you.
- Later, dude.
I'll see you at the venue, okay?
No high five?
- Thank you.
- Yeah, buddy.
Ready?
Is everyone ready?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Try to leave it.
Don't pull it off.
Why?
Because it needs to heal.
- Why?
- That's your body's way of healing itself.
- 'Cause you're a strong boy.
Why?
And the body is a miracle.
- Why? Why?
- And resilient.
- Can you say "resilient"?
- No!
Yes, you can.
- I... can't, Mama!
- Try.
- Try it. Say "resilient."
- I can't!
Say "resilient."
I... can't, Mama!
Okay, say "res."
"Res."
- "Il."
- "Ient."
Yes! You did it.
Say "resilient."
"Resilient."
What do you think?
- Is it big enough for ya?
- Yeah.
Do you know all these people
are coming just to see you?
You know, I was in the bar
last night with Jon Bon Jovi,
and he was giving me advice
on stadiums.
Yeah.
He said, "Everyone's looking at
your eyeballs
through the screen."
It's so far.
"They're all...
they all are with you
"'cause you're this...
you're huge.
"So, if you connect with
the people that you can see...
"the front row, basically... then
everyone in the back is gonna be
having that same experience
through them."
You can't touch anybody, so,
I don't know, it's a mindfuck.
♪ No one's gonna panic ♪
♪ No one. ♪
It's like you're torching.
- It knows me.
- Not you.
I did the whole stage.
No.
All right.
- Ready.
- Yup.
♪ Don't fuck with me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
- ♪ Don't hustle me ♪
- ♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
It's really hard to sing
this song and do all that shit.
♪ Oh, no, oh-oh ♪
♪ Try to hustle me. ♪
Let's start over.
Can we start over?
The singing and the dancing
are doing two different things,
and that's really difficult.
I may not, like...
♪ Don't try to hustle. ♪
It's...
All right, let's try again.
♪ All these years ♪
♪ So now you've gone
and thrown away ♪
♪ The very thing you need ♪
I need drums out here.
♪ Don't try to hustle me ♪
I can't hear a beat.
♪ Don't hustle me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
♪ Don't mess with me ♪
♪ Don't hustle me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
♪ Don't hustle me... ♪
- Uh-huh.
- Doing choreography down this
after doing
the craziest dance ever...
- Totally.
- Right.
...and then having
the hardest part to sing...
- Do you just want to...
- ...is like...
- It is crazy town.
- Do you want...
I think, once I'm done with
Jenny, I'm just gonna walk.
- Yeah, just walk down.
- So they should go slower.
- 'Cause I'm gonna need to...
- Yeah. They're gonna follow you.
♪ Till my patience is done,
oh, no ♪
♪ Don't try to hustle me... ♪
It's an interesting line
as a woman... as a young woman...
being the boss, to be respected
and to not have to be
a "see you next Tuesday"
to get people to respect you.
You just have to lead
by example.
You just have to work hard and
have a high bar for yourself,
and others will follow.
♪ Don't hustle me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
♪ 'Cause it won't do
no good at all ♪
♪ To say you're sorry now ♪
♪ Your words, they are
falling on deaf ears ♪
♪ And it won't do no good at all
to try to work it out ♪
♪ How can you replace
all these years? ♪
♪ Now you've gone
and thrown away ♪
♪ The very thing you need ♪
♪ Bitch, please,
don't try to hustle me ♪
- ♪ Don't hustle me ♪
- ♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
- ♪ Don't mess with me ♪
- ♪ Don't ♪
- ♪ Don't hustle me ♪
- ♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
- ♪ Don't mess with me ♪
- ♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
- ♪ Oh, don't hustle me ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ Don't hustle me ♪
- ♪ Whoop, whoop ♪
- ♪ Don't mess with me ♪
- ♪ Don't hustle me ♪
♪ Whoop, whoop. ♪
Thank you.
Fuck yeah, man.
- You watched me?
- Yeah.
- Did you like it?
- You like seeing the whole show?
- We have a lot of things to talk about.
- All right.
I was out, I was out of my body
the whole time.
See you at the hotel.
Tell you what,
if I were in the audience
and I were a ticket buyer and
I paid for parking and a meal
and schlepped all the way
down there and saw that show,
I would be disappointed.
I think you're
way too hard on yourself,
'cause the show was great.
- People were stoked.
- What?
How did it feel
back where you were?
Insane. People were going nuts.
Didn't you feel
super far away from me?
No. It feels
absolutely massive, hon.
We added
85,000 square feet of stage
- and kept the timing all the same.
- Oh, gotcha.
So we're expected to do
double the work...
So you're sprinting. Yeah.
...in the same amount of time.
- Yeah.
- And it is literally impossible.
Yeah.
I couldn't breathe
until I got to "90 Days."
I gotcha.
- Mama?
- Yes, baby?
Why did you take
a breath out me?
Why did I what?
Why take a breath out me, Mama?
- Why take a breath out of you?
- Yeah.
Did I take a breath out of you?
- When?
- I took one of your breaths?
- Two.
- I took two of your breaths?
- Yeah.
When did I take
your breaths away?
Oh, you're saying
I took your breath away.
I get it.
He's saying he liked the show.
- No.
- I can't have it?
Come on.
Jameson, can I have a kiss?
Can I have some ketchup, please?
- Do what?
- Thank you.
- What you need, Willow?
- Where did Roger and Baz go?
Are they out, like, powwowing
on how to attack me
from both sides?
We're here. We were just,
we were just waiting for you.
Come on.
Oh, there's nothing like
a moldy, wet cork.
Okay.
- Can I cut right to the hard stuff?
- Mm-hmm.
I didn't know
that those three forks
were not gonna be connected.
I wasn't in my ear four times.
That suit
was six sizes too big,
so if they take it in,
it might look better.
And I think "Revenge"
doesn't work at all.
Can we send
the blow-up doll to Eminem?
I think he would love it.
The "Try" dress?
- Noted.
- The tit bit nipply?
You said,
"That's what the people want."
And Stephanie goes,
"That's sexual harassment."
That's not what I said.
I said it's sexy.
The black leather jacket
didn't work?
- Personally, I thought...
- 'Cause it's so sparkly...
But no one wants to see this.
- No, no, no, no.
- No, a lot of fucking...
That's what the people want.
That's what they want.
- Every time I go out...
- Yeah.
...I have to run all the way
up that fucking ramp,
I have to run all the way down
the stairs and again and back,
and then I have to run
all the way back again.
You know in your head, like,
which songs that is...
It's the whole show.
I can't run that fast
for two hours.
Yeah, a hundred percent.
And if I don't, the whole show
has to get reworked.
I get where you're coming from,
but people have to see.
Can we connect the stages
and cut out my main problem?
We're trying to do that.
We might have a problem
with Wembley...
I talked to Ed about it.
I need a pen.
Can it do this?
Here's the tip.
Ramp down here, ramp down here
and have it be lower.
- More height?
- Just like three feet.
And so I have something
to run down and run up.
It's just that... if they're
connected, I can find my times.
I can find the space
that I need to live.
I just don't know
if Wembley will allow that.
- We're sold out, so...
- I could just draw it up
first thing tomorrow morning and
send around to all the councils,
- and we get their approval.
- Please do.
I will. Absolutely.
Just tell them
that the singer will die.
♪ I can't stay
on your life support ♪
♪ There's a shortage
in the switch ♪
♪ I can't stay on your morphine,
'cause it's making me ♪
♪ I said I tried
to call the nurse again ♪
♪ But she's a little bitch ♪
♪ I think I'll get out of here,
where I can run ♪
♪ Just as fast as I can ♪
♪ To the middle of nowhere ♪
♪ To the middle of
my frustrated fears ♪
♪ And I swear
you're just like a pill ♪
♪ Instead of making me better ♪
♪ You keep making me ill ♪
♪ You keep making me run
just as fast as I can ♪
♪ To the middle of nowhere ♪
♪ To the middle of my ♪
♪ Frustrated fears ♪
♪ And I swear ♪
♪ You're just like a pill ♪
♪ Instead of making me better ♪
♪ You keep making me ill ♪
♪ You keep making me ♪
♪ I can't stay
on your life support ♪
♪ Just like a pill ♪
♪ I can't stay
on your morphine... ♪
This is what my heaven
looks like.
Just add cheese.
That's a good piece of heaven
right there.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Tracy ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
I love everybody!
No!
- Oh, wow.
- Where you going, dude?
This way.
- Perfect.
- We're in.
Shoes off
and everyone on the Biomat.
- Why?
- Because you guys need some zen.
No.
Here he comes.
Oh.
I want Willow's trumpet.
You want to have
a trumpet lesson?
Yeah.
Okay, ready?
It's not working.
Want to try?
No, you don't, you don't...
Not like that. Like this.
- I'm getting good, aren't I?
- No.
Yeah.
Nice. That was strong.
That was close.
No.
Should we cancel tour, you guys?
I'm not going.
I mean, maybe, yeah, sure.
- Yeah.
- You want to cancel tour?
Hmm?
- Truly?
- No.
I just want to go to summer camp
and have a bouncy house.
You just want to go to summer
camp and have a bouncy house,
- but you can't.
- Yeah.
Because Mama's on tour.
- And you're sad...
Like, at the worst time
possible.
- And you're sad about that.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Do you want to go home
for a week?
- And go to camp?
- A week?
- Yeah.
- When?
Tomorrow.
No.
I want to stay for London.
But after that, sure. Yeah.
Okay. I'll ask Papa.
But then I could
come back, right?
No. Once you leave tour,
you're-you're off it forever.
Yeah, that's how it works.
You leave the circus,
they never let you back.
Okay, let's not do that.
Babe, of course
you can come back.
What do you mean,
"Can I come back?"
If you want to go home
for a week, go home for a week.
You're gonna miss me terribly.
You're gonna miss
my musk especially.
- Ew.
- But you'll get over it.
You'll be with
your friends for a week,
- you'll go to summer camp...
- Can I go to summer camp?
- Yes, and then you'll...
- On Monday?
Yeah. I will sign you up.
- Okay.
I'm not gonna cry.
- You're gonna cry.
- No. You are.
- I can see it.
- I'm not gonna cry.
Yeah, you are.
- No, I'm not. No, I'm not.
- Yeah, you are. Yeah, you are.
I don't want to talk
about this anymore.
Where is the other cup, Papa?
What other cup?
Well, next time
you won't splash.
You were not doing
good listening.
- Do you understand that?
- Yes.
You do understand that?
Really?
Okay.
I need you to take
your punishments
- a little more seriously.
- I want to go.
Hold on, you're not done.
I'm upset with you.
Sorry, Mama.
What are you sorry about?
Because I hit you.
You didn't hit me, though.
- Why?
- What did you actually do?
What?
Listen to me.
Look at my face.
I'm upset with y...
Do you know what I love?
Everyone always says, "I love
Pink 'cause she never takes any,
she never takes any shit."
I eat shit for breakfast.
Which hand? Which hand?
Watch the wall. God.
Here. You got it.
Here you go.
So close to bedtime.
Did you get your hair brushed?
Nope.
Did you use conditioner?
You did, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
- Can you look all the way up?
Thank you.
- I love you.
- Good night.
Willow, put your retainer in
and leave it.
- Is it in?
- Yeah.
Let me see.
- Good job.
- Good night.
I love you. Good night.
♪ Tales of an endless lie ♪
♪ Cursed is the fool
who's willing ♪
♪ Can't change the way we are ♪
♪ One kiss away from killing ♪
♪ Don't you say,
don't you say it ♪
♪ Don't say, don't you say it ♪
♪ One breath,
it'll just break it ♪
♪ So shut your mouth
and run me ♪
- ♪ Like a ♪
- ♪ Run me like a river ♪
♪ Shut your mouth, baby,
stand and deliver ♪
♪ Holy hands,
gonna make me a sinner? ♪
♪ Like a river, like a river ♪
♪ Shut your mouth ♪
♪ And run me like a river ♪
♪ Choke this love till
the veins start to whither ♪
♪ One last breath
till the tears start to ♪
♪ Whither ♪
♪ Like a river, like a river ♪
♪ Shut your mouth
and run me like a river ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh. ♪
All right,
I'm turning right up here.
- Papa's happy.
Papa's definitely happy.
We're on bicycles.
- You think Willow's happy?
- Yeah.
Flowers and water.
Look at the boats.
Those are all houseboats.
No, I think...
What is his feet stuck in?
Ah, these two here.
- Thank you.
- Here you go.
- Enjoy.
Thank you.
Jameson.
- Good.
- Yeah, that's a good one.
That's the keeper.
- That's the keeper.
- I didn't even see that.
All at the same time.
Can I take a picture of you two?
- We saw you at your show tonight.
- You did?
- Excellent show.
- Yes. - Thank you.
Ma'am?
Yeah.
You're so cute.
Uh-huh.
Thank you.
We saw you. Thank you. Bye-bye.
My God, they look so rad.
- Why won't you dress like that with me?
- What?
In matching outfits
with different color hair.
We are. We're matching.
We're both wearing black.
- Score. Boom! Give me some!
- Hi.
Hey, look at that.
We didn't even plan that.
- Mama, watch.
- I'm watching.
Yeah, big girl.
Willow is my soul child.
Her and I are so connected
on such a deep spiritual level.
She's my straight man.
Like, she-she gets the joke.
She's super smart.
She's super witty.
She's so self-possessed.
Which is so cool.
She's always been.
She doesn't care
what anybody else is doing.
She is her own bird.
Especially with people her age.
She could care less.
She's so fearless.
But she...
she's internal
with her feelings,
which unnerves me,
and I don't understand it.
And she goes quiet
sometimes, and I...
Yeah, Willow!
All right, doors are open!
Time to come down!
My show!
It's so incredibly healing
to watch her
walk through the world
wild and free
and with no armor
and no heartbreak.
No one's... no one has
taught her who and how to be
or broken her spirit
or broken her heart.
Ow.
He's kind of blind,
so he mistakes my finger...
Or he might need glasses.
Oh, my gosh, Carlos,
you missed it.
Great.
I have to have faith
in the sarcasm and the strength
and the... the sort of weirdness
that we've celebrated
her whole life,
so far, that I think
she will be a nonconformist,
and I think she will care
a little bit less
what other people think
because she knows
how small the world is.
Or how big the world is.
And that there's people
that can be carnies and run away
and do what they want.
Be around people they like.
Willow told me last night
that, um, she feels invisible
around Jameson.
Broke my heart.
Two-year-olds get more attention
than eight-year-olds.
That's just the way it is,
because, at the end of the day,
two-year-olds are
helpless little psychopaths.
And they're narcissists,
and it's developmentally correct
for them to be that way.
And it doesn't help when...
with Jameson...
commanding that much attention.
And Willow was never like that
when she was his age.
She never wanted
that much attention.
She was shy about it.
For five and a half years,
it was just her and I.
And having him was...
like ripping a Band-Aid off.
Or ripping off a limb,
more like.
And it's been hard for her
the whole time.
It's never been easy for her.
But if she didn't have that,
what the fuck
would she complain about?
I did tell her, at one point,
I was like,
"Well, your mother is
a performer who takes
"all the oxygen out of the room.
And then in comes your brother,
who's the mini version of me."
I was like,
"How could you be
anything but invisible?"
What'd you say, buddy?
Are you happy?
Yeah. I'm happy.
Jameson is
a walking, breathing,
naked, loose screw.
And he's as equally committed
to his anger
as he is to his joy.
In that way, he's also like me.
But he scares the shit
out of me.
Okay.
One down.
They look like they know
what they're doing.
God bless you. God bless you.
God bless you.
What happened?
He sneezed into the wall.
Oh, no, buddy.
- Mommy.
- Let me see. Let me see.
Look down. Look down. Look down.
Yeah.
They're all nuts.
My whole family's crazy.
I'm the normal one.
♪ Run it, run it ♪
♪ We came here to run it ♪
♪ We came here
to run it, run it ♪
- ♪ Run it ♪
- ♪ Hey ♪
♪ Just like fire ♪
♪ Burning up the way ♪
♪ If I could light the world up
for just one day ♪
♪ Watch this madness ♪
♪ Colorful charade ♪
♪ No one can be ♪
♪ Just like me anyway ♪
♪ Just like ♪
♪ Magic, I'll be flying free ♪
♪ I'm-a disappear
when they come for me ♪
♪ I kick that ceiling,
what you gonna say? ♪
♪ No one can be
just like me anyway ♪
♪ Just like run it ♪
- ♪ Run it ♪
- ♪ Run it, run it ♪
♪ We came here to run it ♪
♪ Run it, run it ♪
♪ So, look, I came here
to run it ♪
♪ Just 'cause nobody's done it,
y'all don't think I can run it ♪
♪ But, look, I've been here,
I've done it ♪
♪ Impossible? Please,
watch, I do it with ease ♪
♪ You just gotta believe,
come on, come on with me ♪
- ♪ Oh, what's a girl to do? ♪
- ♪ Fire ♪
♪ Oh, what's a girl to do? ♪
♪ Fire... ♪
On my fifth-grade birthday party
that never was.
It was the year
my parents split up, too,
so it was, like, a crucial year.
Maybe this was
why they split up.
And my mom and I
spent all day decorating,
and we put streamers up
all over the walls,
and she gave me her ER pad
that I could write out
doctors' orders on,
and we put out cheese puffs,
and... no one came.
No one showed up.
I guess there was,
like, some coup
I didn't know about...
Really?
...where I was on the outs.
But my mom,
desperately trying to turn
around the day, danced with me.
And we ate all the cheese puffs,
and I wrote
all the doctors' orders.
And as an adult now,
I remember that day as, like,
being one of my favorite days
with my mom.
♪ I wish I could go ♪
♪ Back to playing Barbies
in my room ♪
♪ They never say ♪
♪ That you gotta grow up
quite this soon ♪
♪ How fast things change ♪
♪ And now I'm here
and all I wanna do ♪
♪ Is go back to playing Barbies
in my room ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah... ♪
My mom is an ER nurse
and, you know, was a single mom
from the time I was nine
and was getting into Broadway
and singing lessons.
And every year,
she would save up her money,
and we would get dressed up,
and we would go into the city,
and we would watch
off-Broadway plays.
We would go to
La Cage aux Folles
and The Phantom of the Opera
and Les Mis
and dinner
and all the fancy things and...
You know,
she can't afford this stuff.
And part of what we do today
on my stage is because my mom
saved up her money to take me
to see Phantom of the Opera.
My parents really did
support my passions.
When I wanted to sing,
they said yes.
When I wanted to take
gymnastics, they said okay.
They taught me what it meant
to work for something
and to take lessons
and to practice.
So I was a gymnast.
I used to work out
like five days a week,
eight hours a day.
I would miss school.
I had no summer camp.
It was just gymnastics
all the time.
I went to a Cher concert,
and I saw everything
going on behind her
and all of
these incredible acrobats
having the time of their life.
♪ Do you believe
in life after love... ♪
And I thought to myself,
"Could I do that?
'Cause that looks really fun
and no one else is doing it."
So I met Drea, and I asked her,
"Why can't a singer do this?"
She's like, "You know, you're
using your diaphragm to sing,
and I'm using
my diaphragm to twist."
And I love a challenge.
So we went to the jungle gym,
and I hung upside down,
and she just started
punching me in the stomach
and told me to start singing.
♪ Sweet dreams
are made of these ♪
♪ Who am I to disagree? ♪
I have found that it's much
harder to just stand there...
♪ I traveled the world
and the seven seas... ♪
...than it is
to hang upside down and spin
at 30 miles an hour.
♪ Looking for something ♪
♪ Get this party started ♪
I'm a better singer upside down.
Watch out.
It just became my thing.
They want me to sing, too.
You know I've got the asthma.
We're clear on this, right?
I've got the asthma.
Thought it was Harry Potter.
God bless you.
Can you just say, um,
"I'm just gonna take a video
with Tracy Heart"?
- Hart? H-A-R-T?
- E-A, yeah.
- Oh.
- Just say...
Hi. Is Dr. Gordon in today?
Willow has a 104 temperature
out of nowhere.
I don't know what to do.
Like, I-I... nothing's helping.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Yeah.
When I gave you the
Children's NyQuil last night,
did that help your cough?
I don't know. I was asleep.
Okay.
How long ago
did she get her Tylenol?
'Cause I think
it already is working.
Yeah, you already don't have a fever.
Hey, if you don't get
better soon, we're gonna have to
put you in, like, a
plastic tent and quarantine you.
- Like E.T.
- Just part of it.
- Why?
- So you don't get anybody else sick.
Spread your cooties.
I have to at least try
not to get what you have.
Are you, like, hallucinating
- or seeing any weird objects?
- No.
- No? Okay. That's good.
- I see a TV.
That's good.
So are you milking this
right now,
so you can just, like,
binge-watch movies on the couch?
- No.
- Okay.
Okay. I'm gonna spray
some Thieves oil.
Let's roll.
The next city.
Ready, Willow?
She is at her neediest
when she's sick,
and I am her mother.
I want to care for her.
And if I get sick, I'm...
fucked.
I'm just trying
to keep you warm.
Do you... are you cold?
You are?
Papa!
I'm gonna save you!
You're gonna save me?
Thank you.
Good? You good?
I don't think Carey and I...
I don't think either one of us
understand what it is about us
that makes
our relationship work.
Oh, just like hitting
a brick wall, isn't it?
What's funny is,
after 19 years, today,
right now, I've never been
happier with someone in my life.
- There it is.
- Aw.
When we started dating
at a very young age,
I think it was one of
the best lessons I learned,
where I could be a big fish
in my little pond,
but I go to the red carpet,
and if they even know my name,
they screw my name up
and call me Corey and Casey
and everything in between.
And it's like, wow, it's...
it's a lot bigger world
out there than just dirt bikes.
I also think, for you, as well,
you know, you're kind of
a-a star in your own world.
And to jump in,
especially as a man
supporting a woman on tour...
I think it's impressive
that you're able
to support me
the way that you do.
If it were someone else
that needed more ego stroking,
I don't think it would work.
So we always have
an extra room for necessities,
but I only bring
the bare necessities.
I used to bring 24 suitcases.
But to keep that number, I had
to give the children a couple.
So I had to downsize.
- Hey, baby?
- Yeah?
I was showing them
how I downsized.
- Where?
- On my luggage.
- Come on.
- Since I had kids, I used to have 24 bags.
- How many you have now?
- 17.
- 17. Ask Stephanie.
- Okay.
Yeah, okay. I'm proud of you.
Good work.
- I left...
- Good work.
- ...seven bags for the kids.
- Good work. Yeah.
And one, two, four...
dude, you've got a lot of bags.
- Two. I got two bags.
- Three. Three.
And it's the same clothes
I've had for
- two and a half years.
- That's not mine. That's not mine,
- and it's in my way.
- Okay.
See? What if you need
a beanie at 2:00 a.m.?
- Hey!
- Papa's gonna drag you by your ankles.
Drag me by my ankles.
Let's go.
- Ow, that's my shin.
- Not my fault.
I want to do that, do that!
All right.
You want to get thrown one time?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Relationships are interesting.
There is
no perfect relationship.
Families are interesting.
But part of the joy
that I get out of parenting
is watching him be a parent.
Come here. That's one.
Two. One more.
And then it's to bed, okay?
Okay?
I knew he would be
a fantastic dad.
I knew it because
he had a fantastic dad.
Come on, meatball.
But he's way better than
I thought he would be.
He is incredibly patient.
Otherwise, how could he be with
someone like me for this long?
He steers Jameson in
completely the wrong direction.
It's unsafe. It's unsmart.
He hurts Willow's feelings
every single day.
But he is a great dad,
and he's consistent.
And he always shows up.
He always says yes.
Like, when I'm exhausted and
I don't want to do something...
I don't want
to play in the dirt,
I don't want to play
with trucks... he's like,
"Yup, whatever you want to do,
I'm there. Yes.
"I want to do that with you.
I'm here right now.
Let's do it."
And it's really, really sweet.
Love you, dude.
I love you.
- Sleep good.
- Are you gonna lay down?
I'm gonna lay down with you.
Of course.
Get in your cage.
I really wanted to be
a young dad, in theory.
In reality, I would've
been gone all the time,
which would've sucked.
There's definitely
a part of me, like, Willow...
I think my last contest,
Willow was a year old,
so she'll have
no memory of me competing.
And Jameson only has
old videos to watch.
No, no, no, no!
- You've got to be kidding me!
- Yeah!
Carey Hart has done
the unthinkable!
Like, I wish there was a
piece that they could remember,
like what they're experiencing
with Alecia.
You know, being on tour
and seeing what Mama does,
like, I-I wish I had that.
But at the same time, like,
I'm so happy I get to spend
so much time with them, 'cause,
you know, ten years ago,
I wouldn't have been able to.
We live on this amazing farm
where, you know,
I never had this before
in my life.
So to have the experience
of where
my kids can ride
their own BMX track...
Me and Willow
go tear motorcycles around.
Jameson will start riding
later this winter.
And it's really fun
to kind of nurture that along
and to kind of pass the torch
and expose them to BMX
and, you know, going out
and pump around the pump track
and watching Willow
kind of start to jump the jumps
and Jameson just being
so fanatical about BMX as well,
it's-it's fun to kind of sit
shotgun on-on their experience.
He's that rock,
and he keeps me from myself.
I still get to do
whatever I want
and be who I am
and chase the rainbow, but...
I have a rock to come back to.
A lot of people in my position
like to circulate people
in and out.
They like to find what's new,
what's hot,
what's the bigger, better deal,
um, and they audition
constantly.
And I just...
I-I can't stand auditioning.
I am of the mind that
if you find a really good person
that's really good
at what they do
and wants to work really hard,
then you keep them forever.
Let them be 85 on that stage.
Uh, 'cause I'm gonna be.
And it's not hard to keep
those people once you find them.
You just have to
treat them well.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
I think that's part of
why people like being
on the road with me
is because they feel safe
and they feel like
they can be themselves,
I really want them
to bring their full self
and their whole heart.
And I think one of the reasons
I'm successful is because
I surround myself with people
that are better than me.
I'm not intimidated by
other people's greatness.
I want all of us to be great.
And that's why we have
such a rad tour.
It's because, if you're not
looking at me onstage,
if you've had enough of me,
then you can look anywhere else
and you're gonna see
the best of the best,
and you're gonna see people
that are lit up with joy,
that are fully alive
and fully in their light,
and it's-it's a beautiful thing
to behold and to share.
Hi, guys!
Go faster!
No, I'm good.
Okay, never mind.
Yeah, I'll stay on.
Oh, yeah, I'm staying on,
just like this.
Oh, no, no! We're going down!
It's fun to watch
the relationships,
the different kind of
relationships that Willow has
on tour with my village.
There's a lot of bumps.
And then how Jameson
just entertains everybody.
I worry, actually, about
taking them on the road
and having the...
the tolls of that,
uh, them not having
a normal life.
But I look around at the people
that we're surrounded by,
and we're surrounded by people
of all walks of life,
incredibly diverse,
and we go all over the world,
and we have culture
around us all the time.
And it's all people
that are incredibly passionate
about what they do,
fearless in
their choice to do it,
and they get to be around
these people all day long.
There's people that you can
just really want something
and go after it,
and then you'll find people
that you're surrounded by
that are amazing.
And that's what
my kids get to see.
Every door they walk through,
every room they walk into,
they're like,
"Wow, there's another person
that followed their dreams."
I think that that's more of
an education than I got.
Now do a cartwheel.
- Yeah, backflips.
- Oh, you got the backflip.
- Do the cartwheel.
- How?
Just literally turn yourself
sideways and do a cartwheel.
Use your arms.
- Yeah.
- There you go. -
This is our second with kids.
The first one was
a huge learning curve.
It was a lot different than just
partying on the road
with my girlfriend,
or wife at that time.
And kids add
a crazy extra layer,
but, you know,
it-it is a family.
I mean, these people have been
touring with Alecia
for over a decade.
Just a traveling gypsy family.
And, I mean, it's literally
as fun as it could possibly be.
The kids absolutely enjoy it
and love everybody on tour,
and I would call
everybody on tour my friend,
and I think that's pretty huge
in this dynamic.
I try to allow
for everybody on that stage
to be human and not robots.
And, no, I don't want anyone
to be perfect.
I want everybody to have
their own personality
and their own moment
to just let their hair down.
That's what it's all about.
It's about being free and wild.
You know, we have to be
a bit rehearsed, but...
We have to know
kind of what we're doing.
♪ What about us? ♪
I think that's why people like
being on the road with me, too,
is because I really want them.
I don't want just
a keyboard player.
I want Adriana and Jason.
I don't want just
a guitar player. I want Justin.
♪ What do we conceal?
What do we reveal? ♪
♪ Make that decision every day ♪
♪ What is wrong with me? ♪
♪ It's what's wrong with you ♪
♪ There's just so much
I wanna say ♪
♪ I like to make-believe
with you ♪
♪ Da-da-da-da, do-do-do ♪
♪ That we always speak
the truth... ish ♪
♪ I like how we pretend
the same ♪
♪ Da-da-da-da, do-do-do ♪
♪ Play this silly little game ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ I got some things to say ♪
♪ 'Cause there's a lot
that you don't know ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ It's written on my face ♪
♪ It's gonna be hard
to swallow ♪
♪ Everybody's got a secret ♪
♪ I got some things to say... ♪
Yay. That's fun.
There's Mama over there.
This is, this is the one?
Okay.
There's no precedent
for any of this stuff
that we're doing.
I'm the first person that's
doing a lot of these things.
Mama! Mama!
What is that?
I'm gonna go fly now.
- Why?
- 'Cause it's so fun.
There have been
many close calls.
The 360 has been the only thing
where I really got hurt.
I've got my two dancers ready
to grab the carabiners
and hook me in.
Are y'all ready?
And one of the carabiners was
pointing the wrong direction,
which made Nikki
really, really uncomfortable,
and she kind of froze.
I'm fine.
Oh, fuck, that hurt
like a motherfucker.
Sorry for cursing.
Fuck. I fucking did that.
Who the fuck was watching?
Holy shit.
- Let's get her out of it.
- I can't feel anything.
Normally, I'm connected
by two carabiners,
so if it pulls you,
it pulls you equally.
If you don't have one carabiner,
you get pulled off the stage,
into the barricade
at 30 miles an hour.
I was really scared
to keep doing it after that.
I was shook. That shook me up.
Got to get back on the horse.
Let's go.
I'm not gonna miss
a beautiful day
just 'cause the day before hurt.
- Do you know what I have to do?
- No.
I have to do my vocal warm-up.
Something like...
Hey. Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Papa can take you.
Where is Papa?
Let's go find out where Papa is.
- Stephanie.
- Hi, sweet boy.
Mom fail.
It's okay. I'm a Jew.
I don't really know anything
other than guilt,
so... it's fine.
It's all good.
♪ La-da-da-da-da,
la-da-da-da-da ♪
♪ Da-da-da ♪
♪ We are searchlights ♪
♪ We can see in the dark ♪
♪ We are rockets ♪
♪ Pointed up at the stars ♪
♪ We are billions
of beautiful hearts. ♪
I think,
before I became a parent,
I didn't want to be a parent,
'cause I didn't want to have
the kind of relationship
that my mom and I had.
And I was terrified of it.
So I think
my initial motivation was:
"I'm gonna do everything I can
to be close to this person
and to let this person be
whoever they are."
As it happened, it just...
It's like saying,
"If I win that Grammy,
"I'm gonna get up there and say,
"'Fuck my high school principal.
I fucking told you
I'd get here.'"
But by the time you do
all the work and you get there
and you win the Grammy,
you get up there
and you're just happy
and grateful,
and you're just like, "I'm not
even thinking about that guy."
So when you become a parent,
it's the same exact feeling.
It's like, "I was gonna do
everything different,"
and, blah, and you just...
The thing that
surprised me the most
was that none of that mattered
and I really loved being a mom.
I loved being a mom.
My mom said to me...
it was one of the greatest gifts
of my life...
she said to me, when Willow was
about three and a half or four,
she looked at me with tears
in her eyes and she said,
"I just never knew
"that parenting could be
this enjoyable
until I saw you do it."
Willow!
This person wrote, "Live from
Wembley Arena in 2007
"made me fall in love with Pink.
"Now she's playing
two Wembley Stadiums,
"140,000 people.
"For some, it is unbelievable
how far she's come.
"For her real fans,
"it's not such a surprise.
"Talent and hard work
will always win.
Enjoy it."
That's really sweet.
"Hey, Pink,
it's our 50th show tonight."
Wow. That's a lot of shows.
They could pretty much
do the show.
"I'm with my daughter
for her first Pink concert."
Aw.
"Tonight, I'm seeing Pink.
"Only been waiting since '93.
Never been so excited."
"Meet Kirstie Wendy.
She is your biggest fan,
"and she's been waiting months
to come from Yorkshire
to see you."
"If you're browsing Twitter
from your makeup chair,
"please give
this girl a shout-out.
It'll be amazing to see
a Northern girl faint."
- That's funny.
- It is funny,
'cause they know I do that.
Done.
"Ever since I saw her
playing Reading Festival,
"I've been jonesing
to see her full show.
"Well, tonight's the night.
Pink at Wembley.
"If I die under the weight
of the musically expressed
fuck-the-patriarchy-ness, know
this: it's how I wanted to go."
Okay, this is cool.
I got this letter tonight
when I was in makeup,
and I was reading it
out loud to Yvette.
"With a head of frizzy ginger
hair and big front teeth,
"I was the kid who never felt
as though they belonged
"in any of the friend groups
at school.
"A little bit of a loner,
"I often dreaded going
to school, as I was bullied.
"I was skinny, pale
and flat-chested.
"I remember wishing
I was invisible
"because I hated
the way I looked.
"Rushing back home at 3:30 p.m.,
I would stick to a routine
"of comfort-eating chocolate
and watching fuzzy VHS versions
"taped off the TV
of your 2002 concert
"at Scala, London,
"and a documentary you made
promoting Try This...
"Off the Record
I think it was called.
"This was the first time
anyone had really told me
"it was okay to be different
"and going against the grain
is actually better.
"I finally had someone
on my side.
"Sitting down to watch
the concert and the documentary
"made me feel calm.
"They were my escape from
reality just for a little while.
"On 5th November 2006,
"I went with my mum and sister
to see your show in Manchester.
"We were so far back.
You looked so tiny on the stage,
"but it was the best night
in my 16 years.
"At this point, I was very much
fighting my sexuality
"and wouldn't dream of
coming out.
"Way before I began
going to gay bars,
"your concert was
the first time I'd seen
"so many lesbians
all in one place.
"Some even gave me the eye.
"I remember feeling like
I had finally found my people
"and I belonged.
"Eventually, along the line,
"somewhere in the early 2010s,
I came out.
"It was your attitude and spirit
that helped me get there.
"Fast-forward ten years.
"I had grown into
those massive front teeth.
"I had boobs. I felt pretty
and had lots of friends.
"My life was so different from
"the girl who hated herself
in 2... 2003.
"January 2018,
utterly crippled by heartbreak,
"I spent every evening
curled up in bed.
"I drove to work each morning
contemplating stopping the car
"to jump off
the motorway bridge.
"I fantasized all day about
which way I would end my life.
"Here I was, a fully grown,
27-year-old adult
"needing your help once again,
"this time not from the bullies
but from my own head.
"I went into the garage
"looking for something
to hang myself with.
"Then something stopped me.
"I just imagined
how disappointed you would be
"if I let myself go
all because of one girl
"after surviving everything
I'd ever gone through before.
"Crazy, I know.
We've never even met.
"Pink, you really did give me
the strength to carry on
"during these dark times
in my life.
"For that I'm so thankful.
"Please don't ever listen
to the Internet trolls,
"the critics
or the voices in your head.
"You're a marvelous role model
to young and old alike.
Keep that fire burning.
You're bloody brilliant."
- That's awesome.
- Sweet, huh?
Yeah. You make a huge impact
on people's lives.
Yeah.
- I do.
- I know you do.
- Especially yours.
- That's true.
Especially mine.
And it's really the only reason
I still do this.
'Cause the... the chasing
the carrot game is stupid.
- Mm-hmm.
- But the fulfillment in that...
- Even the shit we've been through.
- Yeah.
Like, writing about all of that.
- Other people are just like...
Somebody's in
their kitchen somewhere,
staring at their husband,
going, "Yep.
Yep. I feel that, too."
But then they want
to fight it out another day.
It's cool, man. Music is cool.
That's why I've always said
you're the people's champ.
- I'm Rocky?
- You are.
I hope I'm a little more
attractive than Rocky.
No, you're the peop...
Like, no, I'm serious.
You're the people's champ.
- Like, you're...
- Do I give you Sylvester Stallone vibes?
Or Charlize Theron? Huh?
♪ The whole world's scared,
so I swallow the fear ♪
♪ The only thing I should be
drinking is an ice-cold beer ♪
♪ So cool in line,
we try, try, try ♪
♪ But try too hard,
it's a waste of my time ♪
♪ Done looking for the critics,
'cause they're everywhere ♪
♪ They don't like my jeans,
they don't get my hair ♪
♪ Exchange ourselves
and we do it all the time ♪
♪ Why do we do that?
Why do I do that? ♪
♪ Yes ♪
♪ You're perfect to me ♪
♪ Pretty, pretty please ♪
♪ Don't you ever, ever feel ♪
♪ Like you're less than ♪
♪ Less than perfect ♪
♪ Pretty, pretty please ♪
♪ If you ever, ever feel ♪
♪ Like you're nothing ♪
♪ You are perfect to me ♪
♪ Yes ♪
♪ We're perfect ♪
♪ Oh, we're perfect ♪
- ♪ To me, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Pretty, pretty please ♪
♪ If you ever, ever feel ♪
♪ Like you're less than ♪
♪ You are perfect ♪
♪ To me. ♪
Two.
Three.
Four.
Four bus rides.
I'm so tired of traveling.
♪ I'm tired of being inside. ♪
I'm making Willow a blanket.
Her favorite color is purple.
But it's taking forever.
Tomorrow, what Willow and I
are gonna do,
we're gonna go have high tea
and... see Matilda.
And then Saturday and Sunday,
we're shooting.
And then Willow and Carey
go home.
And I made a little
sad face with tears.
And then, uh, we go to Paris.
And I'm just trying
to wrap my head around,
'cause Carey usually does
the morning time with the kids,
'cause I don't get to sleep
until really late.
So I just have to figure that
out and wrap my head around it,
'cause it just changes things
a little bit.
Is that true?
The Smurfs are Belgian?
- Wow. They are.
- Yeah.
Where do french fries come from?
Gonna say France.
Belgium!
Did chocolate originate
in Belgium?
If this comes back Belgium...
Latin America.
All right, we're good.
Mama, you excited?
- Oh, you look super excited.
- Ha. Well...
- Look at that excitement.
- I just woke up.
Come on! Get hyped. Get psyched.
Come look out
the window with Mama.
Look at that.
- Mama.
- Look at that horse over there.
- Where?
- On the balcony across the street.
This way.
What's he doing on the balcony?
That's the queen's horse.
I know.
She only has one?
- Times are tough?
- No, she has two.
♪ All these... crawl ♪
♪ Till all skeet, skeet ♪
- ♪ All skeet, skeet, goddamn ♪
- ♪ Goddamn ♪
♪ Till all skeet, skeet ♪
- ♪ All skeet, skeet, goddamn ♪
- ♪ Goddamn ♪
♪ Shorty crunk... ♪
- Willow.
- What?
I can see my bus.
- Where?
- You see your bus?
That's not our bus.
That's our right bus.
No, it's not.
That's mine bus.
Okay, maybe you're right.
It is, actually.
Let's do it.
Can I carry you?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Hey, Pink.
- Hi, everybody.
- Thank you so much.
- All right.
Thank you.
- Yep.
- Okay. Vitamins...
There you go.
Candy water for you.
- No, my other cup, Mama.
- Vitamins are over here.
Food is right here.
But, baby, that's the only cup
that we brought.
Yep, that's what we got, dude.
Buddy, I have meatballs
and bell pepper and tomatoes
and hummus and pita.
Mama.
Yes, buddy. You hungry?
I want waffles.
Oh, buddy, I can't make you
waffles on a tour bus.
I love hummus spot.
Oh, the hummus spot?
Aw, yeah, you do.
Well, he can eat the salmon.
I'll eat the meatballs.
I don't care.
Stuff's a piece of cake.
Yeah.
This whole touring thing.
Place is huge.
Are you gonna sing here?
I'm gonna sing right there.
- Right here?
- Yeah, to all the people.
Why?
'Cause singing
makes people happy.
Cool.
- Okay.
- Nice, we got our...
- We made it.
- You made it.
We made it
to the big time, Jamesey.
- Yeah.
- Guys, I really love this stadium.
- I know.
- Can you fucking believe it?
- Oh, my God.
- Get in here.
Big hug. Oh!
Careful that don't whack you
in the head.
It's a, it's a bucket list, man.
Yeah, this is definitely
a bucket list.
Oh, my God. And two nights.
- I know.
- No, not just one. It's two.
My kids have never seen me
as anything other than this.
They've only ever
known me as this.
Mama.
They grew up with
the hotels and the jets
and the never having
to worry about
things like money and safety,
and I'm their mom,
I'm their friend,
but one day, you know,
one day, they're gonna
see through all of it.
They're gonna see the act.
They're gonna see
through the strength,
and they're gonna find
the truth underneath, I hope.
And they're gonna discover
little Alecia,
who's still hiding in here,
who's still learning
how to heal.
And I just hope they have
the grace and the heart
to accept my mortality and to
accept that I'm human like them.
And then they'll have
their own kids,
and so the cycle continues,
all of it.
The multigenerational pain,
sure, but also...
the damn beauty of it all.
That's cool.
I'd like to
have time to do the moonwalk.
I used to do
my own hair and makeup,
but I realized that I need help.
I do my own hair because, number
one, I don't have that much,
and number two,
it's pretty much the only time
I get to be alone...
in my world.
And...
it is meditative.
It's... it's a ritual.
I enjoy rituals,
and that's my ritual.
And, also, no one can do
this hair quite like I can.
♪ There's a road
that takes me home ♪
♪ Take me fast or take me slow ♪
♪ Throw my head out the window ♪
♪ Feel the wind, make me whole ♪
♪ Write my name up in the sky ♪
♪ As we contemplate goodbye ♪
♪ I don't know, we don't know ♪
♪ Where we go. ♪
There are so many
excited people out there.
Yeah.
People from Greece,
came from Lithuania,
- came from Australia...
- Oh.
- Japan.
- Yeah, I saw that.
- What?
80,000.
Wow.
I think it's hilarious.
I was supposed to be
a rock star,
so I never had to be
anywhere early,
I never had to do anything
I didn't want to do,
and now I'm in charge of 225
people and two insane children
and all of this
mega, mega responsibility,
and it's all worked out okay.
- Mom!
- I'm busy and important.
You have to make
an-an appointment to hug me.
- I'm important now.
- Appointment made.
Get off me.
Did I mention
how important I am?
- I'm gonna get up.
- Okay.
If you're gonna do that,
then just get on this way.
Okay.
- Seriously?
- Yeah, 'cause I need you on my back.
- All right, everybody!
- Nope. Oh, yeah.
Have a wonderful show.
You, too. You, too.
- It's just another show.
- - Yeah.
- What you got?
- Big, I guess.
- It's all good.
- You got one, too.
Wow!
All right, I would
like to say thank you
for bringing us together
and keeping us together.
- We're all incredibly blessed to be here.
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
- We're blessed to be here together.
We worked really, really hard
to get here.
All those times,
all those journeys,
all those obstacles,
all those roadblocks,
all those voices saying, "Not
enough, not enough, not enough,"
we're here.
All those times you didn't
listen to your own voices,
"Not enough, not enough,
not enough," we are here.
But it's
Wembley fucking Stadium!
I respect all of you so much.
Thank you
for being here with me.
Bless that stage with
safety, love and light.
Bless our crew with safety.
Bless our apparatuses
with safety.
And let us just continue
our journey
of balancing good and evil.
For this
and a katrillion, gazillion,
gabillion more things,
we are grateful.
Amen, a-lady!
One, two, three!
Spread the love!
- Have a good show, everybody.
- Have a good show!
- Give your best, baby.
- Thank you.
Come on,
let's go watch the show.
Hi there.
Do we have to drive
to the stadium?
Have fun, okay? I love you.
All right, Mama, kick ass.
Thank you. I'm planning on it.
- Mama?
- Yes?
During the show a little bit,
um, can I come back
to the ball pit?
- You can live your best life.
- Okay, good.
But if you leave the show,
you ain't getting paid.
- That's how it goes.
- Sorry, buddy.
All right, have fun.
Can't leave work.
Either you're working
or you're not.
All right, here we go.
Let's go shoot some shit.
- Coming out this side?
- Some stuff.
Yeah. Sure.
Bad words.
Go. I know. Tour language.
Get out.
A long time ago, I decided
that no matter where I went
or what I did with my life,
I was always gonna be
very true to myself.
I have always identified
with people that struggle.
With all the strife
and economic woes in the world,
religious intolerance,
global warming,
it boggles my mind that we're
spending time, energy and money
trying to ban love.
I don't want there to be
gay marriage.
I just want there to be
happy marriage
and lasting marriage.
I will do everything I can
to open people's hearts,
ears, minds.
- I love you until the world blows up...
- And I have
to believe
that change is possible,
because if I stop
believing that,
- I love you until the world blows up...
- then it's just
a little too much for me.
So I have a pen and I write.
I write about that.
♪ La-da-da-da-da,
la-da-da-da-da ♪
♪ Da-da-da ♪
♪ We are searchlights ♪
♪ We can see in the dark ♪
♪ We are rockets ♪
♪ Pointed up at the stars ♪
♪ We are billions ♪
♪ Of beautiful hearts ♪
♪ And you sold us ♪
♪ Down the river too far ♪
♪ Hey, oh ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about all the times
you said you had the answers? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about all the broken
happy ever afters? ♪
♪ Hey, oh ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about all the plans
that ended in disaster? ♪
♪ Oh, what about love? ♪
♪ What about trust? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ Hey, oh ♪
♪ What about all the plans
that ended in disaster? ♪
♪ What about love? ♪
♪ What about trust? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ Sticks and stones,
they may break these bones ♪
♪ But then ♪
♪ I'll be ready ♪
♪ Are you ready? ♪
♪ It's the start of us
waking up, come on ♪
♪ Are you ready? ♪
♪ I'll be ready ♪
♪ I don't want control ♪
♪ I want to let go ♪
♪ Are you ready? ♪
♪ I'll be ready ♪
♪ 'Cause now it's time
to let them know ♪
♪ We are ready ♪
- ♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about all the times ♪
♪ You said
you had the answers? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about all the broken
happy ever afters? ♪
♪ Hey, oh ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about all the plans
that ended in disaster? ♪
♪ Oh, what about love? ♪
♪ What about trust? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about us?
What about us? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
♪ What about us?
What about us? ♪
♪ What about us? ♪
Thank you.
♪ I open up my heart ♪
♪ You can love me or not ♪
♪ There's no such thing as sin ♪
♪ Let it all come right in ♪
♪ I wanna make some mistakes ♪
♪ I wanna sleep in the mud ♪
♪ I wanna swim in the flood ♪
♪ I wanna... till I'm done ♪
♪ I like whiskey on ice ♪
♪ I like sun in my eyes ♪
♪ I wanna burn it all down ♪
♪ So let's start a fire ♪
♪ I wanna be lost ♪
♪ So lost that I'm found ♪
♪ Naked and laughing
with my blood on the ground ♪
♪ My blood on the ground ♪
♪ I am here ♪
♪ I've already seen the bottom,
so there's nothing to fear ♪
♪ Know that I'll be ready
when the devil is near ♪
♪ 'Cause I am here ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I am here ♪
♪ All of this wrong,
but I'm still right here ♪
♪ I don't have the answers,
but the question is clear ♪
♪ Let me ask you ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go... ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go? ♪
♪ So let me ask you, yeah ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go? ♪
♪ Where does everybody
go when they go? ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 'Cause I can think of ♪
♪ 1,000 places ♪
♪ Much worse than this ♪
♪ I am here ♪
♪ I've already seen the bottom,
so there's nothing to fear ♪
♪ Know that I'll be ready
when the devil is near ♪
♪ 'Cause I am here, yeah ♪
♪ I am here, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ All of this wrong,
but I'm still right here ♪
♪ I don't have the answers ♪
♪ But the question is clear,
let me ask you ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go? ♪ - ♪ Yeah ♪
when they go? ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Let me ask you ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go? ♪
♪ Where does everybody
go when they go? ♪
♪ Where does everybody go
when they go? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
Come on.
♪ I am here ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I am here ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪
♪ I am here ♪
♪ Hey, yeah ♪
♪ I am here. ♪
Thank you.
I feel better.
My cheeks hurt from smiling.
Mama, do this.
Okay. I can probably do that.
I'm ready.
- Okay, ready?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Do... this.
You know what?
I did a whole show tonight.
Mama, do this. Mama, do this.
Okay.
I'm coming.
All right. Here we go.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Was that it?
- No.
- This part.
- Oh, this part.
- And this part and this part.
- Okay. Okay. This part.
- This part.
- No.
This part.
Where you going?
I was throwing out
the booger diaper,
getting my wine
and joining you on the couch.
Guess what, buddy.
- What?
- I think I hurt my shoulder.
- Sorry.
- It's not your fault.
This part.
I think I did it in the show.
- Sorry.
- Aw, thanks.
- Ow.
Oh.
Thought he was coming
to try and make me feel better
for a second, but he wasn't.
- Hey, you, come here.
- No. Why?
- Come here.
- Why, Papa?
- 'Cause I got to talk to you.
- What?
So sit down.
So you know me and Willow
are leaving tomorrow, right?
So we're gonna be gone
for 12 days.
Why?
Well, 'cause Willow wants
to go home for a little bit
- to go see her friends, okay, buddy?
- Why?
'Cause she misses them.
I know.
- So, hey, here's what I need of you.
- Yeah.
- I need you to be a good boy for Mama.
And I need you
to FaceTime me and Willow.
Yeah.
And I need you to have fun
while we're gone, okay, dude?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
I'm really excited for you.
- You know what I'm most excited about?
- What?
That you were able to tell me
that you wanted to go home
and be with your friends
and have camp.
I'm really proud of you
for that.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
That was really brave
and awesome.
And I love you.
And I'll miss you,
but I'll be totally fine.
- I'm gonna be okay.
- I bet.
I'm not gonna hyperventilate
and cry tomorrow.
I'll be fine.
I'm not gonna text you
every five minutes.
You might hyperventilate.
Every six. How is every six?
Does six feel good?
Six minutes feel good to you?
Sure.
No. You have fun.
I love you.
Jameson?
- What?
- Willow really wants a cuddle
from you before she leaves,
'cause she's gonna miss you.
Can you give Willow
a cuddle? 'Cause Willow's
- going with me tomorrow.
- Can I have a cuddle?
Aw.
That's really nice.
That's it.
It's about all he's good for.
He's a boy.
This is gonna be Jameson's
first trip away from Willow.
Good night.
- Good night, Mama.
- Good night, buddy.
Hey, do I get a kiss?
- Yeah.
- - Yeah.
Love you, buddy.
Don't you wipe my kisses off.
You're gonna be just fine.
Okay?
I love you.
- Bye.
I think a bit of codependency
is very healthy.
I don't care
what the doctors say.
Yeah.
♪ Na-na-na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ I guess I just
lost my husband ♪
♪ I don't know where he went ♪
♪ So I'm gonna drink my money,
I'm not gonna pay his rent ♪
- ♪ Nope ♪
- ♪ I got a brand-new attitude ♪
♪ And I'm gonna
wear it tonight ♪
♪ I wanna get in trouble,
I wanna start a fight ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ I wanna start a fight ♪
♪ I wanna start a fight! ♪
♪ So what? ♪
♪ I'm still a rock star ♪
♪ I got my rock moves ♪
♪ And I don't need you ♪
♪ And guess what,
I'm having more fun ♪
♪ And now that we're done ♪
♪ I'm gonna show you tonight ♪
♪ I'm all right ♪
♪ I'm just fine ♪
♪ And you're a tool ♪
♪ So, so what? ♪
♪ I am a rock star,
I got my rock moves ♪
♪ And I don't want ♪
♪ You tonight ♪
♪ Uh, check my flow, uh ♪
♪ The waiter just took my table
and gave it ♪
- ♪ To Jessica Simps ♪
- ♪ Shit ♪
♪ I guess I'll go sit
with drum boy ♪
♪ At least he'll know
how to hit ♪ - ♪ Oops ♪
♪ What if this song's
on the radio? ♪
♪ Then somebody's gonna die ♪
♪ I'm gonna get in trouble ♪
♪ My ex will start a fight ♪
- ♪ What? ♪
- ♪ Na-na-na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ He's gonna start a fight ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ We're all gonna get
in a fight! ♪
♪ So what? ♪
♪ I'm still a rock star ♪
♪ I got my rock moves ♪
♪ And I don't need you ♪
♪ And guess what,
I'm having more fun ♪
♪ And now that we're done ♪
♪ I'm gonna show you tonight ♪
♪ I'm all right ♪
♪ I'm just fine ♪
♪ And you're a tool ♪
♪ So, so what? ♪
♪ I am a rock star ♪
♪ I got my rock moves ♪
♪ And I don't want ♪
♪ You tonight ♪
♪ You weren't there,
you never were ♪
♪ You want it all,
but that's not fair ♪
♪ I gave you life,
I gave my all ♪
♪ You weren't there ♪
♪ You let me fall ♪
♪ So, so what? ♪
♪ I'm still a rock star ♪
♪ I got my rock moves ♪
♪ And I don't need you ♪
♪ And guess what,
I'm having more fun ♪
♪ And now that we're done ♪
♪ I'm gonna show you tonight ♪
♪ I'm all right ♪
♪ I'm just fine ♪
♪ And you're a tool ♪
♪ So, so what? ♪
♪ I am a rock star ♪
♪ I got my rock moves ♪
- ♪ And I don't want you ♪
- ♪ I don't want you tonight ♪
♪ Ba-da-da-da-da-da. ♪
How's my hair?
Good?
Thank you!
- How did it feel?
- Amazing.
- Yeah?
- Amazing!
- Congratulations, baby.
- Thank you.
- You kicked ass.
I usually can't feel anything
like this, you know?
- No!
- Like, nothing touches you.
It's just not real.
But onstage tonight...
Like, even driving here,
I was like, "Whatever."
- Yeah. Just another night.
- It's not real.
It's just, it's not...
well, it's just not real.
- It doesn't register.
- Yeah. Yeah.
It's just like,
"Okay, we're doing a stadium.
Why? Who? What?"
By "Who Knew," I was like,
"Wow, this is powerful."
And they all sing along
on that, too.
They know every word.
And it's from so long ago.
Yeah.
And "Pill," too.
- Like, all those old songs.
- Yeah.
- No. I want...
- And people just...
But then, when I was onstage
and I was looking out,
I was like, "Wow, this is major."
When's the power
gonna come back on?
Let me see.
It's the outfit.
It's because I look like
a Snapchat filter.
- I love you!
- Oh, my God.
He's like
a junior high wrestler.
Love you!
Damn, I'm good.
Hey, look, it's me.
What if it goes out
- for the whole night?
- I'm not getting anything.
Who's Kiki?
That's... the people
that the doggy is.
- Oh.
- What?
The people and the doggy.
Nope, still nothing.
- Kiki.
- Who is Kiki?
Do you have a girlfriend
named Kiki?
- Yeah.
- Jameson.
No, Kiki!
- She's Kiki?
- Yeah.
Willow is Kiki?
Okay.
Stop, stop.
What?
Did you just say "stop"?
- Are you listening?
- Yes.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
So much.
I'm proud to be your mother.
- Please get off my stage.
- Why?
Willow, get off it.
- Get off the stage.
- Willow.
- Come on, sing with me this summer.
- Mm-mm.
It might be a long time again
before I go on tour,
and then you'll be older
and you'll hate me
and you won't talk to me.
- Do it while...
- That's excessive.
Excessive?
Of course you can do that.
This one's fine.
Can you hear me?
Exactly. "Oh, no."
I know this part.
"Don't try to hustle me."
And then boom.
And we had been saying,
every night, "Phoenix!"
"Phoenix!"
Second show,
we were in Las Vegas:
"Phoenix!"
In my head, nailed it.
Microphone drop.
No one's ever done it like me.
I walk back,
the whole family's there,
and Carey turns around and
before saying anything to me...
"good show,"
"congratulations"...
"Phoenix."
It was like, "Phoenix."
Since that night, I've never
said the name of a city.
"Hello, you."
I'm here
to keep you humble, baby.
Where's my lipstick bag?
- You have a lipstick bag?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God, get out. Get out.
- Lipstick and perfume...
- Get out.
- You can't swim with lipstick.
- Why?
You look so beautiful,
it makes me want to punch you
in the left elbow.
I would like someone
to acknowledge
how well I'm handling this.
Bye, everybody.
Rock and roll.
Rock and fucking roll.
♪ I haven't always
been this way ♪
♪ I wasn't born a renegade ♪
♪ I felt alone,
still feel afraid ♪
♪ I stumble through it anyway ♪
♪ I wish someone
would've told me ♪
♪ That this life is
ours to choose ♪
♪ No one's handing you the keys
or a book with all the rules ♪
♪ The little that I know
I'll tell to you ♪
♪ When they dress you up
in lies ♪
♪ And you're left naked
with the truth ♪
♪ You throw your head back ♪
♪ And you spit in the wind ♪
♪ Let the walls crack ♪
♪ 'Cause it lets the light in ♪
♪ Let 'em drag you
through hell ♪
♪ They can't tell you
to change who you are ♪
♪ That's all I know so far ♪
♪ And when the storm's out ♪
♪ You run in the rain ♪
♪ Put your sword down ♪
♪ Dive right into the pain ♪
♪ Stay unfiltered and loud ♪
♪ You be proud of
that skin full of scars ♪
♪ That's all I know so far ♪
♪ So you might
give yourself away ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ And pay full price
for each mistake ♪
♪ But when the candy coating
hides a razor blade ♪
♪ You can cut yourself loose
and use that rage ♪
♪ I wish someone
would've told me ♪
♪ That this darkness
comes and goes ♪
♪ People will pretend,
but, baby girl, nobody knows ♪
♪ And even I can't
teach you how to fly ♪
♪ But I can show you
how to live ♪
♪ Like your life is
on the line ♪
♪ You throw your head back ♪
♪ And you spit in the wind ♪
♪ Let the walls crack ♪
♪ 'Cause it lets the light in ♪
♪ Let 'em drag you
through hell ♪
♪ They can't tell you
to change who you are ♪
♪ That's all I know so far ♪
♪ And when the storm's out ♪
♪ You run in the rain ♪
♪ Put your sword down ♪
♪ Dive right into the pain ♪
♪ Stay unfiltered and loud ♪
♪ You be proud of
that skin full of scars ♪
♪ That's all I know so far ♪
♪ That's all I know ♪
♪ Hey, that's all I know
so far ♪
♪ That's all I know ♪
♪ That's all I know so far ♪
♪ I will be with you ♪
♪ Till the world blows up. ♪