Mr. Wooten?
Are you all right?
Yes, I think so.
Why don't we talk over here.
So you knew both the victims?
Yes, yes.
Actually,
I was there when they first met,
oh, must be 20 years ago now.
I was managing Bae Connelly at the time.
I discovered Bae in Berlin,
she had a marvelous eye.
So I brought her back to New
York and under my guidance.
Hey, how ya doing?
She quickly became
the top fashion
photographer of the time.
See you later.
Everyone
wanted Bae's photographs.
Oh, please give him that.
I'd convinced her
to shoot the first Sauvage campaign.
Oh Christine, forget about your hair.
Please go out for the
rare one, yes, thank you.
Hey, yeah!
Henry!
Christine, hey!
Hey!
Mm, wow, you've gone all native.
Oh listen here, a
souvenir from last night.
Oh my.
Remember Sauvage, the scent
that drives your lover wild.
Oh, they haven't sold it
now for what, 10 years.
Made a big splash back then.
My old pal, Nino Barrachi's
first hit fragrance.
Check the flood lighting
again, please Vince.
- Hello, beautiful.
- Woo!
That's not bad, that's not bad.
What the hell are you doing here?
I thought I'd give you
a little moral support.
I think it's you who need
the moral support, my dear.
God, what the hell is this crap!
I asked for Pellegrino, Jesus!
That bitch, Christine cut
it out, let's get going here!
Louis, go and get her the Pellegrino.
Please!
Okay.
Okay, positions
everybody, let's get moving.
Hit those drums.
Oh, here we go everybody.
Come on, loosen up a little bit.
Please some more, that's
better, now get into it.
Listen, I want you to be wild.
Come on, think Sauvage,
give to that to me.
Yes, and more.
Perfect, you look beautiful.
Okay now all together,
yeah, come on, be wild!
Yes, once more!
Simmer everybody, loosen up please.
Come on, I said loosen
up a little bit more.
Yes, okay, let's try it together again.
Oh, come on you can loosen more.
Yes, please don't smile, I
don't want you smiling, okay?
So, please, yeah, that's great.
Now think Sauvage, do that, will you.
That's right.
Perfect, that's beautiful.
Okay, now together, yeah.
I knew in that first moment,
he was something special.
As you can see, he had quite a look.
Go on, Mr. Wooten.
Well, after Nino's shoot had finished,
I went over to Dorian
and introduced myself.
Good shoot Bae, good shoot,
I'll see you tomorrow.
We'll get the contacts, mm?
Bye.
Louis, right?
How do you do?
Henry.
Hi, nice camera.
Oh yes, old faithful, be my guest.
Thanks.
Have you been working for Bae long?
Oh, just today, they
needed an extra gofer.
Low guy on the totem pole.
Is Bae a friend of yours?
Old friend and client.
Actually, I'm her manager.
So, you like photography, do you?
Oh kind of, I'm more into the
street stuff, mostly people.
Ah, well are you
showing in any galleries?
I'd love to come down and take a look.
Well, I've been in a
couple of group shows,
that's about it, for now.
For now?
Well, I've got plans.
Excellent, a young man with plans.
I've always maintained that one's aim
in life should be self-development.
Realizing one's
potential to the maximum.
I mean, that's what we're
here for, right Louis?
Yeah, yeah I guess so.
Then, why is it, Louis, that nowadays,
young people are afraid
to show their feelings?
And why do they forget to live life
to its fullest and have no fear?
Well, I don't know if
I could really answer-
Pay no attention to him, Louis.
Henry's always going on
about something or another.
Thanks for the gig, Bae.
Welcome.
Good to meet you, Henry.
Yes.
Oh.
Oh, thank you.
Bye.
Louis, you ought to try
getting in front of the camera.
Right.
I learned from Bae that Louis
and his girlfriend Sybil
were considering marriage,
an institution I'm not a champion of.
Marriage makes one unselfish
and unselfish people are colorless.
They lack individuality
and above all, they aren't egotistical.
The quality that I have every intention
of nurturing in Louis.
Sybil, Sybil, how are you?
Hey, I'm sorry I missed you.
So long, hey.
Listen.
- James, I've gotta go.
- Can I help you, please.
Sybil, come on!
No, no I can't.
- Hey hey!
- Just lend me 10 bucks.
- You gotta go.
- Be back!
Hey, get out of the purse!
Come on!
I can't!
Look Sybil, hey.
Louis.
You've been there, help them!
Look, here this is all I got.
- Louis, come on.
- I'm sorry.
25 cents!
What am I supposed to do with 25 cents?
I can't get high with 25 cents.
Hey, just go pick that up.
Garbage.
That's all there is.
This is bull.
Neighbors.
They stink.
I showed Nino Barrachi the photo
of Louis that I had
taken at Bae's shoot.
Nino agreed with me, Louis
was the face of tomorrow
and the perfect image for
his Sauvage fragrance.
Go on.
Then, with a little
persuasion made to Bae,
and a lot of flattery
directed towards Louis,
I was able to get them
to give it a whirl.
Come one Louis, yes.
Once more and come on, once more.
Yes, yes, go on like that.
Just a second, great.
Okay.
Yes, okay once more.
Okay and,
come on, let's try to have some fun.
Yes, that's it.
That's great.
Oh!
Ow.
Are you okay?
Yes, yes.
Just a second.
Listen, your tomorrow kid needs
to relax and get natural.
Being natural is just a pose Bae,
and the most irritating one I know.
Louis, just take a break.
Yeah.
Good work.
Here, wet your whistle with this.
I don't know, man.
Go on, just knock it back.
I can't relax, I-
- It's all right, don't worry.
You'll get into it.
I think maybe you'd be better off.
Ah ah ah, please Louis, do not think.
Intellect destroys the
harmony of any face.
Beauty is a form of genius
Louis, it needs no explanation.
It's one of the great
facts of this world
like sunlight or springtime
or the reflection
in dark waters of that silver
shell we call the moon.
Beauty cannot be questioned.
It has the divine right of sovereignty.
It makes princes of
those who possess it.
You wanna be a photographer right?
Right.
Well this is what you do.
First, we establish you as
a world class supermodel.
Well then you could do
whatever the hell you want.
If it's photography, fine.
Of course, it's up to you, Louis.
You have to take that first step.
Supermodel.
Okay, oh.
Okay.
Fine, fine, Bae!
Back to work.
Yes, here we go.
Yes.
In front of the camera,
he was a natural.
He was born to be looked at.
That's it!
He loved to be
photographed, to be watched.
It made him feel alive.
Beautiful.
Okay, now you're into it, that's great.
Okay, that one looks great.
You're great, man.
Whew!
Yeah?
That was great.
All right!
That was great, I'm
just gonna pick a light.
I got Bae to blow
up the shot I'd taken
of Louis and then invited him
over to my place for drinks.
Yeah, oh, I could come by
this afternoon, five o'clock?
Yeah, good!
Yes, yes, yes.
Well I told you he really
is the face of tomorrow.
And you got him first, Nino.
Well, just have the papers ready.
Certified check, yeah.
Thanks, Nino.
Okay, ciao.
Congratulations Louis, you're now
officially the new face of Sauvage.
You're kidding me.
Well done.
Nino sends his congratulations, too.
He thinks this is some of the best work
that Bae's ever done.
I must say, I tend to agree with him.
She's really captured something.
What's wrong?
Nothing, hm.
Age,
makes me rather sad.
Why, is it all that terrible?
Hm, by 50 every man
has the face he deserves.
How's that for terrifying?
You know, I think that Bae
must be some kind of sadist at heart.
Oh you wait, when you get
old, wrinkled, and gray
you'll curse her every
time you look at this face.
Henry, are you tripping out on me?
Come on, let's have
a drink to celebrate.
Of course you could always
turn the tables around like Dorian Gray.
Like who?
The hero of a brilliant
Oscar Wilde novel.
Champagne?
Yeah.
Yes, Dorian was so handsome.
Huh, glasses.
He was so handsome that an
artist painted his portrait.
So Dorian made a wish.
Ah, whoa, whew!
He makes a wish that
the portrait grows old
while he stays young forever.
Oh, like a pact with the devil.
Yeah, kind of.
So what, it works, Dorian
never gets any older?
Yes, but it doesn't
have a happy ending.
It sounds great to me.
Well, you like the idea, do you?
Wait a minute.
If this picture changed instead of me,
yeah, I could deal with that.
Well then, I guess that makes you
the perfect candidate
to be the new Dorian,
what do you think?
What do I think about what?
Your new professional name, Dorian.
Dorian?
A little pretentious.
Dorian,
but I kinda like it.
I thought you would, hmm, well.
Here's to you Dorian, a star is born.
Age makes me rather sad.
By 50, every man has a
face that he deserves.
How's that for terrifying?
You know, I think Bae must
be a kind of sadist at heart.
Now you wait, when you get
old, wrinkled, and gray.
You'll curse her every
time you look at this face.
Dorian made a wish, that the portrait
grows old while he stays young
forever, forever, forever.
Like a pact with the devil.
Yes.
But it doesn't have a happy ending.
Sounds great to me.
It's a deal.
A bargain then.
Forever.
Dancing with Mr. D, huh?
Hey there's Dorian.
Oh, he so hot!
So what do
you think of all this?
Decadence fascinates me.
Yeah?
What about art?
Art?
Art is a sickness.
And love?
Love?
Yeah, what about love?
Love is an illusion.
Wait a minute, then what
do you believe in, Henry?
Cheers.
Let me refill your glass.
Louis!
Champagne, please.
Hey, where's Sybil?
She was around here somewhere.
Louis!
Henry.
Oh, hello Trina, how are you, darling?
Good to see you.
Louis!
Hey.
You gonna introduce me?
Hi, I'm Trina Rousch.
Hi.
Are you as good as you look?
I think so.
Louis!
Dorian!
I like a man with a future,
but not a woman with a past.
Trina baby, you're hogging our star.
Okay, you want 10% of
this action too, Henry?
Oh, what did the poet say?
Shove it where the sun don't shine.
Henry.
Ugh, Dorian!
Where'd you say you saw her?
Um,
here, there she is.
Syb!
Sybil, what's wrong?
I have to get out of here.
What are you talking about?
Look we're going places together.
No, we're not.
Listen, look, the doors are open,
we're in, we are on our way.
No more hassles, no more
struggles, the world is ours.
No Louis, the world is yours.
Look, nothing can stop us now.
I can't-
- No stop, listen to me, I love you.
Okay?
I love you, too.
Let's get out of here, okay?
Okay.
So I was thinking of
taking Syb away for awhile.
Now wait a minute, we
just got some momentum here.
The Sauvage campaign is
just the beginning for you.
I know but this modeling thing,
it isn't for me,
I want to take pictures.
Wait a minute, we had an agreement.
This is just the first step, Dorian.
It's not just that, it's Syb.
She doesn't like what's happening.
Mm mm mm.
She's afraid of losing me.
Yeah, well you remember last night
every woman in that disco wanted you.
Yeah, I felt like a piece of meat.
Now wait a minute,
you just listen to me.
You stop thinking like that right now.
The gods have been so kind to you.
For what they gave, they
can soon taketh away.
Don't squander the gold of your days.
For a season, the world belongs to you.
I don't know what I wanna do.
That's why you've got a manager.
What is this for?
Oh, that looks like
the key to your new loft.
Yeah, can I get the door for you?
Say goodbye to Brooklyn,
say hello to Manhattan.
Top floor, and you're very
lucky you bought it cheap.
Friends of mine are
renovating the building.
Looks like a great place.
Ah.
Think Syb will like it?
Yeah, yeah, of course she will.
Open the door.
Well at least check it out.
I just don't
want to move right now.
What, you like this junkie
infested pit better?
What's that supposed to mean?
You think I'm back on the needle again?
Look, maybe I oughta just
get outta your hair for awhile.
And go where?
Henry's, he's having a few
people over for dinner tonight.
Louis, it's after midnight.
So what?
Come with me Syb.
Come as what?
As Dorian's girl?
Another joke for Henry's
snob friends to laugh at?
Hey they're my friends, too, you know?
Friends, Louis, they drool
over you like some pinup boy.
God, is that all you want to
be, some mindless model toy?
All right, right,
I'm not a real artist.
Not like you and your
performance theater, right?
You're pathetic, go on,
forget your photography,
forget your dreams,
just throw it all away
and go uptown to your jerk-off party.
You know what?
That's where you belong, up with Henry
and all of his sell-out phonies.
Louis, if you really think
that this modeling crap
is gonna be some short cut to success
as a photographer, then you are a fool!
Shut up!
'M sorry, I'm sorry.
Baby, come on you know.
No!
Get out!
Baby, please you know I wouldn't-
Oh, Louis.
Oh Louis, Louis!
I'm afraid not, my dear.
Dorian.
Hi, Trina.
It looks like I'm kind of late, huh?
It depends what for.
I'm the last one here.
Yeah, where's Henry?
He offered to take Nino
Barrachi back to the Hamptons.
He won't be back 'til tomorrow.
But she's all ours.
You want it?
Sybil.
Stop crying, man.
Here take a toke of this.
I scored some real good smack.
Some real good stuff.
I got no patience with you, right now!
I called you, I called
you, man, I called you.
She messed up, man,
she really messed up!
What?
She asked for it.
Ow, you're hurting me,
man, you're hurting me.
She asked for, ow!
Sybil!
You're gonna have to
say goodbye in the morgue, bud.
- Sybil!
- That's where she's going.
What happened?
She OD'd.
Hey, aren't you that
guy in all those ads?
That's right, officer.
Actually, I'm his manager.
Okay.
Nice if you can keep
a lid on this, huh?
Tragic, tragic.
Just another OD,
that's the way I'll write it up.
I really appreciate that.
No problem.
How many times
I got to tell ya, move.
Dorian,
I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
Go upstairs and get
your things together.
I'll wait here for you.
I'll take you up to the loft.
I'll be right back.
Yeah!
Yeah, come on, I'm on my way!
Syb.
What?
It can't be.
No.
Can't be.
Dorian, here let me help you with it.
No, I've got it.
I can handle it.
Is there anything else?
No, just leave it
all, let's get a cab.
You're telling me
he thought the picture had changed?
That's what he told me.
I know it sounds bizarre.
No no no.
Go on Mr. Wooten, I want
to hear the whole story.
Well for the next few years,
Dorian threw himself into his career.
Managing him became a full time job.
Oh, oh, we had some fun.
Made lots and lots of money.
Something was missing.
He grew increasingly more paranoid,
the more successful he became.
Nevertheless, wherever you went,
Dorian's picture was there.
The more famous he grew,
the more impossible
he became to manage.
People began to gossip
about Dorian's escapades.
I however, rose above it all.
Never once publicly approving
or disapproving of anything he did.
Jeez, I'm coming.
Coming, jeez!
What the
hell's going on, Dorian?
You were due at the
studio two hours ago.
Yeah.
Overslept.
Tell them I'm, tell them I'm sick.
It's too late,
they canceled the shoot.
And there'll be no check in the mail!
Oh, yeah I need a shower.
Whenever interviewed I'd say,
we're not sent into the world
to air our model prejudices.
Hence, I never take any
notice of what the press
or common people say.
And I never interfere with
what common people do.
You make any coffee?
Not me.
Hey, do you mind?
No.
Are there any more?
I gotta split, have a nice day.
Have a nice day.
And I will see you later.
Hey, wait up, I'm coming with you.
What?
Dorian, I'm worried about you.
You're out partying every night.
Yeah, I still look
okay, don't I, don't I?
Yes, yes, of course, you're just not-
- Not what?
Not as good as when you first met me?
No, you're fine.
That's right, I'm fine
because there's no bags
under my eyes and no lines up
here, right?
What the hell is going on with you?
You want to know what's going on?
Come on Henry, I'll show you.
Come on!
This, this is what's going on.
Oh my God.
What happened to it?
When did it start transforming?
I saw it first just
after Sybil passed on.
It's gotten worse.
It's truly amazing.
It's like that bullshit
story you told me.
About the other Dorian.
I know it's hard to believe but it,
it's like it's happening to me.
I can believe anything
providing it's truly incredible.
This is not what I wanted.
You can have whatever you
want, Dorian.
Life has everything in store for you.
With that face, there's
nothing you can't have.
You're the luckiest man
in the world, Dorian.
There are no limits
with that sweet smile,
the boyish grin,
forever Dorian, forever.
We can go all the way, we
can rule this business!
Now it's up to you,
do you want to play?
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
Go on, go get dressed, go on.
We have to go see Bae.
Why?
I've got a deal with Diana Baxter.
Ever heard of her?
No.
No, no, Diana publishes
books, coffee table books.
Elegant, yuppie very expensive.
So?
So I've convinced her
to do a book about you.
You know, top model's real life,
the naked truth behind the
glamor, that sort of bull, ha.
I think she'll go along
with it under one condition.
She wants Bae to do the photographs
so if we can sign Bae on,
we've got ourselves a
six figure deal.
So what's the title of the book?
Hold on, "Dorian, A Model Life."
Diana thinks it's going to be huge.
Especially if you do the photographs.
Me?
What?
No, no, no, I want you Bae.
You're the best.
Your tastes, your aesthetic.
Come on, I really wanna
work with you again.
What do you say?
All the artistic
decisions will be yours.
And Dorian's of course.
No interference from anyone.
Please.
Okay.
There you go, there you go, come here.
We're gonna have a great time.
Dorian and Bae
got to work together again.
It was heaven for them.
Somehow, Bae was able to
help Dorian temper his ways
and bring out the Louis that
was buried deep inside him.
What do you really want, Dorian?
To finish this book, mm-hm.
And then?
Sell a billion copies,
get rich and famous.
License my name out to
sheets, towels, underwear.
Retire to a life with pure access.
That's what Henry wants.
I thought you wanted to take pictures?
I do.
So what changed?
Nothing, I'm still going to
but not until the time's right.
When would that be?
I'm not sure, Henry-
Henry.
How long have you known Henry for?
Hm, for an eternity.
I was one of his first clients.
Really?
Has he had many clients?
Only a very select few.
I guess that makes me one
of the lucky few, right?
Guess so.
Henry says you're a hermit.
And me I've got to stay out there
and make the scene be visible.
Sure thing.
Look, we're a team.
I'm happy right now having fun.
Good times, excitement.
Dorian.
That's what I like, Bae,
it's what comes easy for me.
Walk into a room, and I can
feel people's eyes all over me.
It's what Henry says
the world's all about.
Be careful.
I thought you liked Henry.
I do.
I do, but what?
I don't like what he does to you.
What he wants you to be.
You're better than that, Dorian.
Henry's all right, he
only offers me choices.
I'm the one that makes the decisions.
Are you sure of that?
Yeah, of course I am.
He works for me.
I wonder what Henry would think?
He wouldn't be happy.
No, no he would not be happy.
Enough about Henry.
Maybe you need to be in another world.
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe.
Please promise me, that if you ever
need to speak or whatever,
you'll come to me.
Yeah, yeah sure, I promise.
What can I say?
I love her.
In love?
With Bae?
Are you insane?
What?
It just happened.
Working together on the book.
What do you want to do, marry her?
Why not?
I love Bae and she loves me.
I'll show you, why not.
Henry!
Stop it!
Here, this is why not.
Has Bae seen this?
Or does she think that face
you're wearing is your real one?
Hey, she loves me!
Loves you?
What are you talking about,
she doesn't even know you.
That is you!
Henry!
Oh, let's show Bae the
real you, mm, shall we?
Should we call her
up, get her over here.
Yeah, I'll get her over here right now.
- I'll just call her.
- Henry!
I know she's in.
- Got to get her over now.
- Henry, give me that!
Look, I like working with her, okay?
You know how great Bae is.
Oh, I see so you want a new career
as Bae's camera assistant?
No, she's gonna help
me with my photography.
Look Dorian, you've got a book
coming out at the end of next week.
50,000 copies pre-sold worldwide.
That's your career, that's what,
that's what we both worked for.
Enough, enough.
I just want a normal life.
A normal life.
Ah, you want a nice normal life.
Yeah.
Mm, mm.
Ah, so you're gonna marry
Bae and move to New Jersey
have a couple of sniveling kids?
Yes.
So, you want to be ordinary, Dorian.
All right, well,
I can make you ordinary.
I can make you completely,
inescapably ordinary.
Henry, Henry, don't, Henry!
Take one last look at that picture.
Because in two seconds flat,
that's gonna be your face.
No!
Leave it alone Henry, that's my picture!
It's me.
Of course, Dorian, anything you say.
Thank you.
So what do we do about Bae?
Oh, don't worry about that.
I'll take care of her, my boy.
Looks like we got a winner, Henry.
Oh, I hope so.
Thanks for convincing
me to publish it.
I still don't understand why you
didn't want your name on the book.
It's Dorian's creation, Diana.
You created Dorian.
If you say so.
Take the credit.
Reveal the art, conceal the artist.
That's the trick Diana,
that's the trick.
Dorian's your work of art?
Yes.
Just look at him.
Dorian, it's been years.
You haven't changed a bit.
Trina, baby.
I am pissed off at you.
Really?
Really, I checked the index,
and I'm not listed anywhere.
Baby, count your blessings.
Oh and Bae, the photos are gorgeous.
Nobody's ever captured you like that.
It's like you two were
meant for each other.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, I didn't realize
you two were an item.
Fling.
Henry!
Dorian, Trina.
May I introduce you to Mariel la Steiner,
she's married to one of
my oldest friends, Rolf.
Oh good for you,
honey, one of the richest
men in Europe, very impressive.
Dorian, Henry told me this would be
the book launching of the season.
Well, we certainly hope so.
- Enchante.
- It's quite the book.
Oh, you've read it?
No, I looked at the pictures.
Oh, you must meet the photographer.
Yes, unfortunately our
dear Bae had to leave.
Well, I think it's going
to be a huge success.
Everyone loves to read about
the dark side of New York.
Oh, so it's that kind of book, is it?
Well, I just might have to read it then.
Why read, when I can
show you the real thing?
Are you offering to be our guide?
Our guide?
Yes, my husband is coming to
pick me up in a few minutes.
Rolf, don't think you've
had enough to drink?
No, I'm fine thank you.
I'm sorry I missed your
book launching my friend,
but, you know, in my world
business always comes first.
Well.
Business always comes first?
First after you, mein Schatz.
You're a wise man, Rolf.
Yeah, let's have a toast,
to whatever the night may bring.
Yes, indeed.
Dorian!
Dorian?
- Hello.
- Henry.
Oh, and where have you been?
I'm taking a vacation.
What are you talking about?
You've got a screen
test at Fox next week.
Not to mention the LA
launch of the book.
You haven't got time
for a goddamn vacation.
Yes, well I need a vacation,
so I'm taking one, understand?
I see, so where are you going?
Germany.
Germany, well why not?
Oh, I see, so you're going
with that Eurotrash bimbo
and her billionaire
impotent husband, are you?
Look here Dorian, we have a contract.
Body and soul, Henry?
Body and soul, Dorian.
So he just walked out on you?
Yes.
But you were still handling
his dough, the book, modeling?
Well, I still had
power of attorney, yes.
He didn't need any money.
He was living in a huge mansion
in the Bavaria for God's sake.
I even heard that he
tried photography again,
but without my influence,
that got nowhere fast.
He reverted back to being the toy boy
he was always meant to be.
That's how Dorian spent
the next few years.
He lived like kept
man, a two bit gigolo.
And made out like a bandit.
He should've realized there was a catch.
He wasn't really in the
driver's seat, Rolf was.
Mariel la love, my sweet.
I wanted to talk with you privately
before our guest joins us.
Very well Rolf, about what?
You know,
sometimes what you want and
what I need are not the same.
And I think that our dear friend Dorian
has fallen into that category.
What do you mean?
I put a sleeping pill in his drink.
He'll be sleeping for hours.
Mm, absolutely beautiful.
Gracias.
You know that I'm always happy
to give you whatever your heart desires.
Yes.
But to put it delicately, I feel
that Dorian has overstayed his welcome.
Are you saying you want him to leave?
I'm afraid so.
- Dorian.
- Yes.
Fly away with us.
It's time for us to say
'Auf wiedersehen' to Dorian.
I don't know if it's such a good idea.
When are you leaving?
Another week.
Hmm, a nice sophisticated,
Euro triangle.
Sounds cozy.
Rolf, please don't.
Please don't?
I know the two of you
have gotten rather close.
But it's not-
No buts.
Rolf likes you.
Oh, and I like him great.
He's my husband and I
love him, but I want you.
Do I detect a schoolgirl
crush on Dorian?
Grow up,
he's not worthy of our attention.
He's so common.
He is our friend.
I got contracts, Mariel la,
obligations.
I know.
I am your husband,
and I want him to leave.
Mariel la.
But he-
Don't ever contradict
me, you understand?
Yes.
Now compose yourself
before he arrives.
Let me show you something
I'm sure you'll find interesting.
Dorian, come in.
Sit down.
Enjoy the show.
How about some sound?
Rolf.
Turn it off.
I said turn it off!
Impotent son of a-
You don't deserve her.
I'm taking her with me.
You really think so, you fool.
You really think she'll
leave all this for you?
Take a look at her face,
tell me if I'm wrong.
Look at her!
I wish for once, you will
stop deciding things for me.
- Oh my!
- After all I've done for you.
This is how you'll repay me?
Please, please!
Please.
Whoa!
Stop!
Stop it!
This is crazy, stop it, please!
Stop!
No!
Stop it!
This is crazy, stop!
Please, please!
Oh!
No!
No, no!
You okay?
Henry!
Dorian, Dorian!
Dorian, what are we going to do?
Rolf is-
What, what?
Get out, get out!
What is this?
Oh my God, it's blood, the
picture is bleeding, Dorian.
It's Rolf's blood.
What?
The picture is bleeding Rolf's blood.
What, Dorian, Dorian!
Listen to me.
Who is it in this picture?
Who is it?
It's me.
Me in the picture.
No, no.
No, oh no!
Mariel la!
No!
- No!
- Mariel la, Mariel la!
Mariel la, Mariel la, no!
He didn't even wait for
the funerals, just took off.
That was about 10 years ago.
Do you ever hear from him?
No.
What about Bae, Ms. Conick?
I don't think so.
She would've told me if she had.
Of course, there were rumors.
Someone would run into him
at some flesh pot
somewhere on the planet.
Some dive where they sell
any kind of pleasure.
You know, boys, girls,
whatever they like.
Pretty sordid stuff.
From what I could gather,
Dorian was caught in a mad race that
took him spiraling into
the depths of hell.
Eventually landed in the midst
of a perverted sex scandal
in Bangkok, but charges
where never laid against him.
I then heard that he
left Thailand soon after,
to continue his depraved ways
in other remote parts of the world.
And then about a week ago,
Bae had a big retrospective in Tribeca.
So I hosted a party for her at my house.
Bae darling, I loved it.
It was just fabulous.
Thank you, Diana.
And you're taking it on the road?
Yes, LA, Chicago, Dallas
and maybe even Paris
- and London in the fall.
- Oh.
Oh my God, look.
Dorian.
Hello, Bae, Trina, Diana.
I don't believe it.
Dorian, look at you?
Dammit, he's still gorgeous.
Dorian, I'm gonna Kill you,
you haven't aged a bit in 20 years.
Who'd you go to, that Brazilian doctor?
Good Lord, look
what the cat dragged in.
Hello Dorian.
Hello Henry.
It's good to see you.
And you.
Honestly Dorian, look at yourself!
How do you look so good?
Genetics, I guess.
Look, I'm going for a drink later on,
would you care to join me?
No, I can't, I just
dropped by to say hi.
Glad you turned up.
Well, where are you staying?
In the loft, just got
the place all cleaned up.
Henry, we have to get going.
Mm, oh, some things never change.
Well, I'm going to drive Trina home,
so will you be here when I get back?
No, but I will call.
We have to talk, Dorian.
Henry, would you mind dropping me off
along the way, I need my beauty sleep.
Of course not, Diana, oh Bae tomorrow.
Yes, goodbye.
Bye-bye!
Great to see you, Dorian.
You're looking great, hm.
You must have a lot of
these from the old days, huh?
Every shot I ever took of you.
I'd like to borrow your proofs.
Which ones?
All of them, just for a little while,
it's really important.
Well okay, are you all right?
Yeah, yeah, it's
just, it's kind of weird
being back after all these years.
What are you going to do with them?
I'll tell you what, I'll
show you when I'm done.
So I can drop by tomorrow
and pick those up?
Of course, call me, same old number.
I remember.
Spread, excellent.
Here.
Excuse me, aren't you Dorian?
No, no pictures, no pictures.
Hey Louis, you don't remember me?
James, I used to live next
door to you and Sybil?
You, you're the guy who Killed her!
Hey!
You're the guy who put
the needle in her arm!
I couldn't say no to her, man.
She was hurting too much and
after that guy came to see her.
What guy?
- The gray haired guy.
- Who Henry, Henry?
Yeah, was freaked out, man.
She came to me for help, and
he paid for her drugs, man.
It's all right, it's all right.
I can believe anything.
Get out, get out!
There are no limits,
with that sweet smile, the boyish grin.
Forever Dorian, forever.
You'll go all the way.
We could rule this business.
What do you do?
You want to play?
No, no!
Get down!
Yes, yes!
No!
Go on, forget your photography!
Forget your dreams,
just throw it all away
and go uptown to your jerk off party.
Look here Dorian,
we had a contract.
Dorian came to Bae's studio
and took away all the photographs
that she'd taken of him.
Then on New Year's Eve,
Bae had a premonition
and she insisted that I call him.
Nothing.
Good luck.
Dorian?
Hello, Bae.
Dorian, what-
I've been working for
days, then I crashed.
Why is it so hot in here?
I love the desert.
Have you ever seen two
scorpions fight to the death?
It's beautiful.
Let's get some light into here.
No, I like it dark!
No, no, you're hurting me!
Ow!
What's wrong with you?
Dorian.
My pictures.
Yeah, I've got some shit to work out.
Don't like what I did with your shots?
I've got you!
What have I done to you?
Remember this, recognize
your great work of art?
No, that's not mine, Henry shot it.
Henry!
I tried to warn you.
Warn me, about what?
Henry, you knew.
Ow, you're not the first
caught in Henry's trap.
He's been hunting forever.
You promised me, Bae.
Ow!
What did you trade your soul for, huh?
I did it for my art.
Your art?
Was it worth it?
Why Bae?
Why?
Dorian, I'm so sorry.
I have to set you free.
No!
I have to do this!
It's between Henry and I.
I have to go!
Come on Bae.
Damn.
Ah, there is someone home.
Ah.
I thought you had a key to this place.
Where's Bae?
Drink?
I lent Bae my key,
she wants to see you.
Of course, naturally, you
weren't answering your phone.
What's that smell?
Oh, just a little eating in.
So you went to see Sybil,
the night she died, didn't you?
Did I, huh?
Did Bae come over here?
Yeah,
you want that drink?
Well, where is she now?
She's over there.
Bae?
Death is the only thing that
ever terrifies me, I hate it.
She tried to cut my picture.
Poor Dorian.
It's a good thing you stopped her.
When that picture dies, so do you.
What are you gonna do,
Henry, call the police?
The police, good Lord
no, of course not, no.
No, actually, I was looking
for that drink you offered me.
We can toast our future together,
because this goes on forever, remember?
How does that quotation go?
What does it profit a man,
if to gain the whole world and lose his-
Soul.
Oh Dorian.
How lucky you are.
What an exquisite life you've had.
You've drunk deeply of everything.
Nothing has ever been hidden from you.
And it's all being no more
than the sound of music to you.
But it hasn't marred you,
you're still just the same.
No, I am not the same, Henry.
Yes.
Yes, you are.
You are perfect.
Flawless.
I wish I could change places with you.
The world cried out against us both.
But it has always worshiped you.
I'm so glad that you
haven't had any talent.
You never carved a statue
or painted or picture
or produced anything outside yourself.
Your life has been your art.
Your days are your sonnets.
No!
Dorian, stop
it, Dorian, stop it!
Give it to me, Henry!
Stop it, no!
Henry, it's over!
Don't be a fool, no!
Dorian!
Henry!
No!
Yes, can you send an ambulance
to 122 Spring, top floor loft.
Yes, yes it's an emergency.
Mr. Wooten.
Where's the picture?
- Do you want to see it?
- Yeah.
Son of a bitch.
I think we're gonna
wrap this up for now.
I may have some questions later.
Would you like a lift home?
Thanks, I'll take a cab.
All right.
Mr. Wooten.
Happy New Year.
Taxi!
- Hey.
Deliver this to 354 East 83rd.
Yeah, right.
Here, give it to the door
man, keep the change, huh?
You got it, pal.