Panelstory
Or the genesis of a community
What are you doing, you idiot?
Listen, where's No. 2786?
Haven't a clue.
We'll be late for school.
Madame, where's No. 2786?
That could be block D.
Rubbish! 27 must be E.
Where's Block E?
Over there.
No it's not.
Try the orientation panel.
If you can read it.
Hey! I can’t find 2786.
It's near the self-service.
There's a laundry on the balconies.
She's crazy!
There's a laundry everywhere.
Do they ever do anything else?
It's those automatic machines
Quite good fun, really.
I would have thought
you know Prague.
Today it's child's play for a woman...
the washing...
not like old times...
You'll drive me crazy today.
Get up!
Are you going to the nursery?
I can take him.
Don't leave me, mummy!
I won't leave you either.
Block 2786, please...
That's near your place.
I can guide you there.
I'll be sad mummy.
Daddy's going to be sad when
he finds out.
I'll run away.
The police will pick you up.
Look out! He's going to fall over.
Watch out for that weirdy
What would he do to me?
If he's the devil he'll chop you into sausages.
Why are you terrifying that child?
Why don't you ensure law
and order?
What do you mean?
Have you got SPARTA's?
There's only twenty a packet.
Is that some kind of joke?
You said it!
Look what everyone throws away.
They probably aren't very hungry.
Maybe today
but what about tomorrow?
Why don't they use their brains?
If only my rabbits
could see all that bread!
Can I come and see your rabbits?
I would love to give daddy
a rabbit.
That's very sweet of you.
I need a present for dad in a hurry.
In a hurry!
You always want
everything in a hurry.
Everyone's in a hurry...
What a beautiful pair of antiers!
They should make somebody happy.
What a dreadful path!
It'll be ship-shape in a week.
I'm booked for 11 o'clock.
Do you think you I'll make it?
We're not interested
comrades in holding up proceedings
What happened to the door?
Broke this morning
The kitchen.
Is it the same everywhere?
Of course.
The quality of the painting
You won't find the like anywhere today
It turned out better
than I expected.
Shall we go down to the basement?
Let's look at all the
flats first.
We'll be here till midnight.
It's really wonderful.
According to the regulations,
something's missing here.
Cutlery drawers.
Ready for the house-warming.
We're wasting time.
You won't find flats
of this quality
anywhere else in the vicinity.
There's no stove!
Damn... Oh yes...it's
been reported...undergoing repairs.
Isn't that the gas-pipe?
You could at least have it painted.
Sir...excuse me, Comrade,
has the construction actually been finished?
Just a few minor details...
But this is horrible
It was designed that way.
Was it like this in the other flat?
Of course.
Listen why isn't that a little further away?
You can't even fit a table in here.
Some architects!
I bet there wasn't
a single woman among them.
Come on, lay off!
You’ll be re-sealing
this of course.
The water's been cut off.
Come and have a look.
The lino is full of bubbles.
Watch it! That's my hand!
Shit! Let me go!
The basement is all right,
just sign the dotted line...
I can't afford to waste my time
When will it be repaired?
Where a I supposed
to find labourers?
It would upset our plan.
That would take at least two months.
He’ll never make it
I'm going to be living here too.
I want my flat to be perfect.
This is the boiler-room.
That's rather colourful!
There's paint missing here.
They must have run out.
The insulation is defective.
Who closed the door?
Me.
Why?
It was draughty.
We're in the shits.
Why what's the matter?
The door handle's on the
other side.
Mummy! Help!
You ought to do the door-bashing.
It's your bloody shambles!
Always me! You
keep putting pressure on us,
and we end up
in impossible situations.
I'm going to tell on you
for stealing.
I don't believe
in impossible situations.
Things could be much worse.
Are you normal?
I've just washed that.
Why shout at us? We didn't do it.
I'm meant to have a child in this?
Who started the fire?
What a mess!
You still haven't got any mail?
Ever seen him without his pyjama.
Yes, on T.V. In a series.
"The Driver".
Have you seen it?
I'm dead beat in the evenings.
I can't laze around
bed all day
and show myself off
in the evenings.
Well? Any letters?
Hang on a minute.
Haven't I got a right
to do my own shopping?
They've just got in some
sausages.
Hello!
What a lovely little boy!
It's a girl!
No kidding? How sweet!
I bet she is a good girl!
Good morning, madam.
What’s wrong with the old lady?
Nothing.
You don't know her?
I mind my own business.
But you live in the same building.
Let me go!
You're not my mother.
Stop arguing.
We're going to your mother's.
I know my own way.
Just look at my hair!
You should have come earlier.
I can't take you now.
My God! Where's that boy?
There he is.
Where can I get a pedicure?
You have to have an appointment.
For a pedicure? What do I do?
My God!
Someone must have used a razor.
It was you, wasn't it?
No.
How come you're not in
the nursery?
A pedicure, please.
Hand me the razor.
You've had it, haven't you?
Coming home from work?
No from a dance.
Do you know what's wrong
with the old woman up there?
Nothing, she's always like that.
Doesn't she go out at all?
Doesn't she need anything?
Why don't you mind
your own business?
If only I could sleep
as much as she does.
Hello.
What are you doing here?
Come to watch you work.
Aren't you pleased?
Of course.
How come you're not at school?
Does it make any difference?
What happened?
I want a bread-roll.
Go and take one.
A lot.
Is that what you’d like?
Certainly not!
That's pretty hopeless then.
What's going on here?
Trust you to go
tidying up shelves!
Sonia! You looking for me?
No.
How come you aren't at school?
What do you mean?
You're not going to start
wagging school?
First sick, then the doctor's.
Did you really see the doctor?
Yes.
What sort of check up was it?
You didn't just make up?
You can be quite sure of that mum.
What's wrong with you then?
You never told me anything.
You never asked.
When was I meant to?
You're always sleeping.
I was tired.
How do you expect
to get through med school?
You've got the brains for it.
Do you know what it means
to be independent
to be in a good position?
I don't want be independent.
Would you prefer to be
a maid or a cook
slaving away
for a good to nothing?
Could be quite fun.
If you are not independent
you are worthless
in the eyes of men.
I don't get you.
Are you soft in the head?
What’s on your mind?
Marriage for example.
Just drop the idea!
I won't have such nonsense.
But you'll just have to,
mother.
The doctor told me I'm pregnant.
Do you realize
what you are saying?
Of course.
Please, don't make a scene.
One lot comes today,
repairs something...
tomorrow another lot comes
and digs it up.
If they'd only plant
vegetables instead
we'd have something to eat.
Something for our health, eh?
Carrots, celery...
They wouldn't last long.
Stolen overnight, I'd say.
Just don't start getting
in their way.
Getting in whose way?
I'll do the shopping...
and the pub' not far.
The main thing's the lift.
But it's calling for trouble,
to mix the young with the old.
You think so?
If I was you,
I'd mind my own business.
And if I fall ill?
Who's going to bother about me?
You think those young ones will?
If they start quarrelling
I'll just move out and make room.
I'll go and join my friends
in the pub.
You've got some friends here?
Of course.
Today one has friends everywhere.
Good God! Wait a minute!
I've been looking for you
for over an hour.
Impossible.
We've only just arrived.
Gentlemen,
that was quite an achievement!
What do you mean?
No 305.
A first-class balls-up!
A work of art!
Impossible!
You've got one week to fix it up.
That's ridiculous.
Pay the bill
and don't forget to smile.
We didn't balls it up.
No back-chat, thank you!
Who forced us into building
these mock Potemkin villages?
You knew all along we'd never make it
if we're to build it properly.
How come the others managed?
Probably by not haunting the pubs.
We're always left
to fend of for ourselves.
You're just interested
in the bonuses.
We're not soft in the head.
Just don't push me, gentlemen
- Wait a minute!
You keep your hands off our income
and we'll keep our hands off yours.
I've heard that one before.
The bill's on me.
Now you're talking!
Good morning.
Bottoms up!
I'm sure we can reach
an agreement.
You don't expect
all hours accredited?
I'm not soft in the head either.
- That's a dirty trick.
Last time you gave us
only rotten ones.
We sell what we get.
We had to throw half of them away.
What difference does it make?
Your children use them
as ammunition.
That's a good excuse.
I saw them with my own eyes.
Get a move on!
What's going on here?
You're still not finished?
Go on, hurry up!
You copped a beauty!
Still hurting?
Mind your own business!
I'll probably cop one today, too.
For stealing.
I have to find a present for daddy.
You're kidding?
We haven't got a single space free.
I don't want it for nothing.
I'm not an idiot.
I know it's going to cost something
I don't quite follow.
You think I don't know the ropes?
That you can make an exception.
Out of question.
How come you took
Sarah K. immediately?
As soon as they moved in?
Her mother greased 500 crowns,
didn't she?
That's got nothing to do with me.
Of course
we do have a few reserved,
but that's for
extremely urgent cases.
I'm one of them.
You want to earn yourself a crown?
-Just one?
O.k. Two.
What do I tell him?
That I'm waiting for him.
Three now and one later!
Hey!
You trying to steal something?
I've gone and lost my crowns.
Just look at that kid!
I know him. Quite a character.
From our block.
Do you want that paper?
You can sell it as waste-paper.
Look, fill up that carton.
You sure know how to pass
the buck.
You got to use your brains.
It's good training for him.
God knows what's
in store for him.
Sonia?
Is that you?
Fancy, meeting you here.
Don't tell me!
A little boy?
No. It's a girl.
It's just that she's a bit bald.
She's a darling.
So you married John?
No. Frank.
How are things?
Fabulous.
Take my advice - do what I did.
Like what?
Forget all the brain-washing.
You dropped out of secondary?
What the hell's good about school?
I've got a flat,
a fridge,
an automatic washing machine,
tons of time in the morning.
And Frank's fantastic!
What if he turns
out like my father
and you end up like me and my mum?
Can I help you, mummy?
Quiet!
I've got to concentrate.
They want me to be systematic.
It's driving me up the wall.
A system in this shambles?
I'd love to know how.
Ouch!
I burnt myself.
That's their stupid system for you.
The old bag's bound to gossip.
How the hell are you meant to cope?
If the milk's gone sour
I'm in the shits.
Jesus Christ!
I'll murder you!
Who mucked up my laundry?
Not you again!
Don't know if I'm coming or going.
You might at least answer.
Look, I need some sleep, understand?
This racket's driving me
up the wall.
Nothing could drive you
Mummy's going to see it
that her little boy's all right.
She never burns anything like me.
Her cakes are better than mine
She'll be happy - I'll be happy.
It's what she always wanted.
Just look what your daughter
has gone and done to me.
All she can do is cry.
I've had a gut's full.
Aren't you feeling well?
Mummy's going to die.
Isn't that normal?
She's telling the truth.
I can feel it.
Where?
Here!
For all you care!
Our poor children!
It'll be better that way.
At least we'll have some peace.
The splitting image of her father.
Couldn't care less either.
But I do care.
Stop lying!
Promise me when you re-marry
you'll marry a good woman.
Don't talk like that.
But I'm so scared!
You weren't the first time.
I wasn't so alone then.
There's someone at the door.
I don't want to see anyone.
I'm from the insurance agency.
How did you get in?
You just can't imagine
what can happen to you.
Do you have a life insurance
policy?
Just imagine this wee girl
at the mercy of social welfare!
Or perhaps Madame...
since your son refuses...
Get out!
Mummy are you dying?
Did you tell him?
And?
He hasn't got any time.
He'll never see me again.
Come on! I'll miss the doctor.
You promised me one more crown!
That's just too bad.
Stupid cow!
Where is she?
At the doctor's.
You'll never see her again.
I'd like the line 10cm
from the ceiling.
Where would we come to
if we had to paint stupid lines?
My God!
Come on, wait your turn.
I only need a certificate.
Get ready, Peter, we're next.
Anyone could say that.
I've got a child with fever.
Just try and push in!
The lady with the baby.
-Just a certificate for the creche.
Can't you see the queue!
I can see how long you take
for coffee.
Don't we deserve a break?
Do you have to make such a racket?
Just look at our working conditions.
Come and watch us cleaning up
after the painters have finished.
When will that be?
They didn't show up today.
What's he so good at to keep such
a pretty woman to himself?
Wouldn't you like to know!
May I correct your opinion?
Would you fetch us that beer?
You're crazy!
Go fetch it yourself.
Would you happen to jug?
Take a bite while
you're down there.
I'd like to be done today,
gentlemen.
Your wish is our command.
This way please...
Karel!
Where's Vilda?
Why doesn't he fetch his own beer?
Vilda's quite a guy!
You guys working for the other side?
Don't forget your buddies.
Shit. I fixed his heap for him.
You know something about cars?
I'm in a bit of a jam.
You see, this morning
I was meant to see a mechanic,
we're doing Macbeth tonight
and I over-slept.
You've got a Saab, haven't you?
A yellow 99 but it's not running.
Can I count on you?
Sure thing.
What do you do actually?
I'm a plasterer.
I thought you were a mechanic.
Jack of all trades.
Is that it?
I've seen better.
Start the motor.
You crazy!
You'll ruin the battery!
I said start it not demolish it.
It's hopeless.
What are we going to do?
Did you have to muck around
with it?
I never touched it.
I can't bear getting dirty.
Perhaps it's just the ignition?
Got any alcohol?
What for?
Do you realize the responsibilities
I have on this construction site?
Take it easy.
Soviet or Polish?
Makes no difference.
Both.
Can't get it to start?
That's right, Grandpa.
If I was you I'd fix it.
Watch it, Grandpa.
I know quite a bit about cars.
It's dry!
I'll go get some distilled water.
Jesus, my magazines have gone!
They were in big parcels.
Didn't anyone see them?
Do I have to look after you as well?
Don't keep dawdling off shopping
and no one will steal your magazines.
Here’s the key.
You're to wait for him.
I'll take you there.
Why always us?
Why don't they do it?
Stop arguing!
Why not Jarda and Joey?
Last time they repaired your mess,
this time you repair theirs.
For the last bloody time.
Law and order!
Magazines stolen
and not a single clue.
At least no one stole
the policeman.
Leave my waste-paper alone!
I know where you got it.
Catch them!
It was just lying around!
Who on earth threw it out?
It stinks!
You stink!
Is that your pram, lady?
Sweetheart,
look what they have done!
You stole it from me!
Arrest him!
The pram was just lying around.
In front of the dispensary!
My sweety had her vaccination
look, it hurty hurts here...
and they just flog your pram,
the naughty naughty people.
The little boy yours?
Let's take it back.
You're just going to let them go?
I'll lodge a complaint.
Damn it,
the lock's broken.
Someone's gone and janned it...
The key’s inside!
Some idiot's
slammed the door shut.
But there's someone inside!
One of the boys.
Trust us to come
at the right moment.
Who could it be?
Leta's give them a fright.
Pass us the hammer!
Break down the door.
No!
She's already been done!
It's my flat.
What do you mean?
No one's moved in yet.
I've done my own moving in.
How did you get the key?
Just try and move me!
That's out of the question.
In socialism one simply doesn't
throw people out on the street.
No one said anything like that.
We don't give a stuff
when people move in.
You don't, but we do.
We've been waiting five years for this flat.
Take it easy!
We just dropped in to see...
I said No!
We won't bite.
So you'd like a bite, would you?
What else?
Just have a look.
At the taps.
Dirty pigs! Shame on you!
You won't be seeing any taps here
least of all mine!
Everything’s O.k. then?
I'll give it to you in writing.
Home and hosed!
I'd submit that
for an innovation bonus.
Just let everyone move in
who hasn't got anywhere to stay.
Save ourselves this stupid work.
Sure, no more complaints,
they'd be only to happy
to do the finishing themselves.
They won't pass that.
Sorry.
Not at all, Maestro...
You recognized me?
Everybody knows you.
My private angel from heaven...
Beg your pardon?
My guiding light...
I hardly deserve such...
Have you seen the old hag?
The postwoman...the old witch?
Without you life is a black desert.
Could you lend me 300 crowns?
Like a nut-house here!
Like sleeping under the bridge!
Tony! Come back to bed!
Shit! What a life!
If you don't
I won't let you back in.
I just love getting bossed about.
You bastard!
Christ! What a life!
Has the postwoman been...?
Haven't a clue.
Bloody woman!
Doesn’t what’s his-name
live here?
"The Driver"?
You some sort of wise guy?
I mean the guy from the series.
Go jump in the lake!
You’ll burn a hole in the carpet.
You’re Misa, right?
What Misa?
What are you doing here?
Cleaning up.
O.K. Clean up and I’ll watch.
I didn't believe you at first
but considering your clumsiness
I guess you must be a charlady.
What else could I be?
You might have been Peter's girl!
Only she's more clever.
Your Peter's a bit thick, is he?
No, just a little lazy.
How come?
Because he can afford to be.
I thought he gave you the keys.
We already had a similar affair.
What sort of affair?
-An accident.
That sort of accident men have.
Why don't you stick
to your cleaning?
Does that idiot live here?
The actor, that is.
I don't know.
Stupid cow, knows fuck all.
Hello.
I live on the third.
Which floor, Madame?
The sixth.
What a pity!
That's a great perfume.
Really fantastic!
What brand?
"Je reviens".
You speak French?
Is that so surprising?
Just imagine where I could be
if I could speak French!
I got a letter from Paris
a couple of weeks ago.
I still don't know what's in it.
The lift has stopped.
What a pity.
The shape of your lips...
Using a letter as bait?
I wouldn't dare.
But could I invite you for a cup of tea?
Just a couple of steps from here.
We could take the lift.
That's very kind of you
but I can't spare the time Mr.
Jiri Kodes.
We’ve met before?
You've probably seen me playing.
Oh, you're the tennis champion!
Where's the lift?
The mail’s here!
My Money!
My humblest respects, Madam.
Don't forget, the third floor.
Hello. What do you want?
Could I speak to Mr. Novak?
He's not in.
Where is he?
I don't know.
When will he be back?
Who's that?
I don't know.
If it's Peter, I'm not in.
Stuffy old bitch you got a letter!
Did you ring?
Here's a letter for Mrs. Kudlackova.
That old lady downstairs?
But she's home.
I saw her through the window.
She didn't open when I rang.
Perhaps she's sick.
I don't like the look of that.
...there are still a few men left
with whom you can spend
an evening
without regretting later...
How old can she be?
I'd say 15...perhaps 50?
A talent destroying illusions!
Are you taking
this letter seriously?
Why not?
It's flattering for you.
Don't you tolerate emotions?
Like you, huh?
Why does such a charming woman
have to keep pretences?
What do you mean?
You don't even know me.
Down-to-earth...
ironic...
redheaded...cold-blooded...
That's me!
Don't you like it?
On the contrary.
It's precisely what a woman needs
to remain independent.
Pleasant things don't count
just the useful, right?
I don't quite get the picture.
That's precisely the point.
People lack imagination.
See all those right angles?
Those straight lines?
Not a single redundancy.
Architects adore economy.
Man mirrors his surroundings.
I'd never thought of that.
See that patch on the lawn?
Someone does some planting
everyone else's taking a short-cut.
In other words,
the quickest way to your goal.
Haven't personal relations
also begun
to take vulgar short-cuts?
People like to know
what they can expect.
When they do get there
it doesn't give them any pleasure.
Without harmony and beauty
life would be meaningless for me.
And tomorrow?
Don't spoil this moment
pussy cat.
Open up!
Don't knock so hard.
Break the door down!
She's scared of me.
Because you are black?
No... No...
Did you ring?
Yes, Maestro, me...
What do you want?
The little girl...
What actually did you want?
Mummy's terrible sick.
She's dying. Please help.
Me? Maestro, couldn't you...
What happened?
- No idea.
What's your name?
Helena Vondrackova.
Where do you live?
Upstairs.
Mummy. Please don't die!
Please help.
What was that?
-I don't know.
Let's have a look.
Listen, you live here, not me!
It's nothing to do with me.
Tony, what have you done to me?
Mummy. Please don't die!
How frequent are the pains?
They don't stop!
Stop that!
Get that child out there!
Is there a phone?
I've got to call an ambulance.
You expect me to wait here?
-One day it'll be your turn.
-Me? Never!
Is there a phone somewhere?
A telephone? Here?
That's terrible.
It's me, Peter... open up!
What's going on?
Not a single phone anywhere!
I know you're in there!
It’s me, Peter
...quit fooling!
What happened?
The young woman's in labour.
Run!
Good God! No!
That's you men all over.
What could I do to help?
I've got to phone an ambulance.
Jesus! But I'm an actor!
I mustn’t get injured!
We're doing Macbeth tonight.
Ah, Sonia!
I didn't think you'd make it.
I'd say she's kicked the bucket.
Who?
The old bag, that's who.
Your wife?
No. I didn't even know her.
Then it isn't your flat
we're going to break into,
Grandpa?
No but.
Whose is it then?
She just keeps sitting
by the window.
And you don't know her?
I've just moved in.
You could mind your own business!
Come back!
I don't want to go to court!
I'll take full responsibility.
Just go right ahead.
You're pensioned off,
I'm still employed.
You're not getting me into the shits.
Who's going to open the door?
Call in the authorities.
I know where it is, Grandpa.
It's so cosy here.
But it's still not finished.
Want coffee?
It's like a castle.
Don't you feel like a princess?
When it rains I spend days
looking out of the window.
Don't you have anything to do?
I don't do out much.
And your husband?
They've turned off the water!
Just in time for dinner! Damn!
Frank will be furious.
What are you doing?
I have to now and then.
They say it's the pressure.
Yvetta's woken up
I'll do it!
Hi, honey!
I could eat a horse.
Of course, what else?
Come on. I'm in a hurry.
I've had enough.
You're out every night.
What about your shoes?
Stop pinching my backside
and clean up the mess.
Welcome home bread-winner!
Keep your hands off!
No bloody food. No affection.
How come you're wearing
stockings?
You know I can't stand them.
I'm going to have a bath.
There's no water.
So the outsiders won again.
Shift!
You gone crazy!
I'm going to find a job.
I've heard that one before!
I'm not a maid
always tidying up, shopping,
cooking, washing...
and getting screwed by His Lordship!
I get the message!
Just as well you told me.
But you'll never make good
what I'll lose on the deal.
Couldn't give a stuff.
The bank loan, the car,
the country house you dreamed
up for me to build?
You want to stuff the lot?
You're nuts!
How you going to cope, baby?
Like a charlady?
How dare you, you bastard!
Without you I could have...
I could have done
my school cert!
Only you didn't
so stop bragging
and let me eat in peace.
You're inhuman!
I hate you!
I hate these four walls!
It's useless.
But they're inside.
It's outside office hours.
Why are they there then?
Only Wednesdays 2 p.m.
Stop! You can't do that!
Imagine if everyone did!
Come on get a move on!
But I need an ambulance...
Why did you do that?
Everybody would have done
the same.
But that's incredible!
Such a gigantic community
and not a single doctor?
The old lady in the window...
Perhaps there's a doctor there.
Wait for me here.
Didn't you break the window?
Name and address...
Leave me alone!
I'll scream you're a kidnapper.
This isn't a barnyard, Grandpa.
But it's an emergency!
We only take appointments.
Where is it?
No. 2756.
Floor?
First Floor.
Fever?
I don't know.
Name?
Koblizkova.
How old's the child?
It's an old woman!
But this is an infant centre.
Where am I meant to go then?
No one cares about old people.
Just let them perish!
Take it easy, Grandpa.
We'll send an ambulance
Where've you been?
You know she's in labour!
Take it easy! Careful!
I've had it!
Thank God!
Mummy! I'm coming with you!
Do something!
You are a woman, aren't you?
I haven't got any time.
Something happened?
I've brought your kid.
He'll tell you
what he's up to!
Where'd you find him?
Come on, out with it!
Daddy doesn't want me.
You won't believe
how much trouble it took me
to find out the address.
Daddy doesn't know about me!
All because of a present for Daddy!
Is Mr. Novak at home?
Daddy hasn't seen me
for a long time.
Hey, you lying again?
But you know this lady?
This old rat-bag?
Delightful manners.
Just wait till he grows up.
You're in for a shock.
You'll have to pay for the window.
What window?
I'd stuff the window if I was you!
Just try and you'll see.
I'll have your husband summoned.
You want to do something?
Wait!
Stop that!
They just can't stand still!
I can't get through.
We've got to get a car.
They've already taken her.
Is that your car?
Sure.
Why didn't you offer to drive her?
But she could have given birth...
Aha, you've got new covers.
I forgot your love of beauty.
The painters have finished.
Something wrong?
You liar!
It's him or me. Choose yourself.
I don't understand.
What happened?
So that's the accident
you've had to pay off. Alimony!
I should have told you earlier.
Let me explain.
I'd love to know how.
Sinking my cash into this flat...
What cash?
The painters for example.
Wore myself ragged for your sake.
Pepicek's here?
You want to see him?!
I'm to mother a criminal?
What do you mean?
The cops ran him in for you.
Daddy I'm so happy to see you.
But that's not my son!
The old cow locked me up.
Please, let me explain.
Get out! Both of you!
Where've you been?
I've been looking for you.
Keep him out of my sight!
What happened?
Got to speak to you about the flat.
No one's shifting me!
Come on scram!
Where did you find Joey?
Get that bastard out of here!
I've had the guts full of him.
What's on her mind?
She hasn't got a mind.
My sweety!
You gave us such a scare!
I've found a daddy for you.
Say that again?
Let him finish.
Daddy, give Mummy a kiss!
You're Mr. Novak?
You seem more like a Novek to me.
Sure, sure, I'm Mr. Novak...
That's not very nice of you...
I honestly don't know
what I did to get this boy...
I quite believe you don't.
I don't know how long
you've been away from home.
The kid's five, isn't he?
Stop confusing matters.
Our block has been standing
for two years.
I don't even know him!
Never seen you in all my life!
What! I'm the caretaker here!
You ought to be ashamed!
Which one's my father Mummy?
I've brought him a present.
Boy, have I had it!
Look, she's still there!
Wasn't the ambulance here?
Ambulance?
Sure, they took Memi and Bebi.
Someone made a mistake.
No mistake, it's too true.
Go and have a look.
See if she's still breathing.
The window's open.
Climb in.
Mummy, stop writing you're alone.
I am alone as well.
Don't worry.
I'm getting on fabulously.
What does one need in life?
A roof over your head...
We sleep two in a room.
It's an excellent district...
that's very important over here.
Please don't think I lied before
but the other district
wasn't quite as good.
There were blacks living there.
Leave me alone.
People think you belong to them.
But they have fabulous music.
Don't hurt me. Go away.
Not be frightened. Me doctor.
I don't want to see anybody.
I want to be alone.
I'm afraid of you.
I have nothing to give you.
Not be frightened.
You too much lone.
I don't need anyone.
But you needing peoples.
I don't need anybody.
South Africa is a paradise.
If your skin' the right colour.
Your son?
Me too from Africa.
C'est vrai, from Mozambique.
This is Mozambique.
He lives here.
Quite close really.
His name is Jiri Kudlacek.
Do you know my little Jiri?
You mad at me?
Have I done something to you?
No, not to me.
To the little boy then?
Forget it, will you?
Look at me, Joey.
As long as we're together
Lay off.
That kid got me thinking.
Let's get married then.
I have already got a son.
Not another word about that!
You'll just have to listen.
Either him or me.
Farewell.
You can't do that to me!
You know what you once said?
You only have to slam the door.
Where've you been all day?
What's wrong?
I'm not going to tell you.
Just look at yourself!
Leave me alone, Mummy.
What happened?
Just leave me be.
How dare you speak like that?
So what? Something happened
that shouldn't have happened.
I'm worried about you.
You must understand.
You're my everything.
That's just too bad then.
I'm not yours anymore.
But you'll find a substitute.
What do you mean by that?
I don't meddle in your affairs
so stop meddling in mine.
Is that what you want?
Quit school, have a child
and get married?
I'm not getting married.
Brilliant!
So you'll get rid of the child?
I don't know yet.
What?
I've got to think it over.
Think what over?
Do you think it was fun
bringing you up all myself?
Bugger my leg!
Everything's close at hand
including the pub.
I know.
Main thing - you're not alone.
Damn my leg!
Look, there's a lift.
Nothing but peace and quite!
You don't have to shout.
Will you turn it off?
What's all this racket?
None of your business.
Don't be rude, Grandpa's here.
He's deaf anyway.
What a shambles.
You still haven't unpacked?
Hardly worth the trouble.
Saturday we'll shift your things.
I'll make room in the wardrobe.
Listen, someone's knocking.
Another idiot caught in the lift!
What do you mean - another?
You're late again.
You know you have visitors.
Do something!
Calm down and get out!
Hands up!
I'll murder that child!
Stop shouting! Poor Helen's...
damn it... she's fallen asleep.
Who left the bloody lift open?
Where are you?
Here!
Helping strangers as usual
and totally useless at home.
Shout your mouth. And the door.
Frank for example.
There's a smart guy for you.
And don't be rude.
Stop it! At least for tonight.
Grandpa...
Without me he'd be on a shovel.
What's wrong with that?
The stupid supermarket
wasn't my idea.
I can walk out tomorrow.
And what will you do?
Easy! You'll have a stroke.
No trade, never lasts anywhere.
Such a shortage of people
in vegetables!
If you use your brains properly-
I'll stay in vegetables!
Isn't it for him to decide?
What do you mean - for him?
He's old enough to marry.
He's just a child, aren't you?
There's a child somewhere else.
I refuse to listen!
I'll murder him!
He can be sure of that.
Where are you, Peter?
Leave me alone!
Grandpa, don't you think
Doubt if I'll stay on, daughter.
But you promised.
I don't feel at home here.
That's not surprising.
Shut up! I'm warning you!
Grandpa's going to think
that we don't want him here.
Grandpa's O.K.
It's you I can't stand.
Keep quiet!
And you shut up!
It's the truth!
Grandpa ought to know,
you want to swap his house
for a new car!
You bastard! Get out!
Grandpa!
I've been looking for you.
I was at home.
I thought you knew.
I thought I don't have to hurry
if I don't want to.
You don't have to do anything
if you don't want to.
Why are you crying?
I don't have to have the child
if you don't want to.
I was beginning to look
forward to it.
Wouldn't you prefer to fly
to the moon?
Like hell!
I'm not budging from here.
The End