Stay awake!
Jaya, stop.
We're in the same team.
Stay awake.
Do I have a choice?
Papa, got kicked
again last night?
Quiet!
Eat your breakfast.
Mummy loves to serve.
Kicks for you at night.
And breakfast for me in the morning.
How about a shoe?
Please get them.
I'll wear them after breakfast.
Hurry... get your school bag.
We're late.
We can't handle this boy
and you wanted another one.
If you kick me in the wrong place,
another one won't be possible.
Adi, you haven't
finished your milk.
Prashant, the plates...
I'll close the windows,
turn off the taps and lights
and put the plates inside.
Take the helmet.
I'm considering wearing one
to bed, too.
Bye.
Bye, love.
Bye, Adi.
Bye, papa.
Adi, wait.
Here, eat this.
Adi, just two basil leaves.
Mummy, why do you
kick papa every night?
I also whack people with silly questions.
Finish your lunch.
Drive slowly.
This bus doesn't go faster than a snail.
-Adi...
-I know, mummy...
I'll wash my hands before I eat.
I won't eat the canteen food.
I won't eat fast.
I won't play in the mud.
I'll come straight home
from school.
-I love you.
-Okay.
Your turn to say it.
I love you, mummy.
Please go now.
Move!
Isn't your mom very hyper?
It's not her fault.
I was pre-term.
So, the doctor took advantage
and scared her.
-You're a weakling for sure.
-Want proof?
Good morning, ma'am.
-How are you, Neelam?
-Great!
Enjoy. You're off
five minutes early today.
Do you even issue tickets
to passengers
or only speak to your girlfriends
all night?
Girlfriend. Just one.
I'm a one-woman man.
Bye.
I've messaged you.
One to Itarsi.
What's for lunch?
Hello.
Look.
We haven't eaten out in a while.
Shall we go?
Yes?
I was...
Do you want something?
No.
They did not recognize you?
Who recognizes a kabaddi player?
Hello.
Adi, why weren't you
answering the phone?
I was in the toilet, mummy.
I needed to pee.
Couldn't you talk to me first?
Mummy, the dam would've burst
in two minutes.
It would've flooded the house.
You know I get stressed.
Why?
When I'm late from school.
When I eat less for lunch.
When I sneeze
more than twice in row.
What can this little child do?
God has made me both,
poor and helpless.
Can I help that?
But you can.
By giving me a mobile phone.
Just say yes, mummy.
Homework done?
Bye.
Papa, I'm the big daddy
of this game.
Wait.
I'll prove you wrong.
Take that!
You were saying?
Who's the daddy?
Son, the biggest daddy
is your papa.
There are games on every sport.
Why don't they make one on kabaddi.
Even if there was one,
who would play it?
Son, never joke
about three things.
You, me and kabaddi.
Your turn.
Sure, I'll talk
to the gaming industry
to make the hottest game
on kabaddi.
Would you like a shoe?
He says he'll have anything
you're serving.
Anything's better than her kicks.
Bam!
What's the gossip on your school
moms' WhatsApp group?
Rihaan's mother is worried
about his English grammar lesson.
Smriti's mother is ecstatic.
Her child topped the Math Olympiad.
Charts on living and non-living things
is needed for Monday.
Leave it. I am so bored.
Who's calling?
Meenu.
Meenu!
I'll tell her you are bored
and don't want to talk.
-Wait.
-Prashant!
You can't do anything
without a beating.
-Hello.
-How are you, my love?
Will you fill the empty spot
in my heart?
I'm coming to brighten up
your sleepy town.
-Prepare a grand welcome.
-Are you coming to Bhopal?
-To meet a prospective boy?
-Not a boy... but some girls.
I knew you swung the other way.
Shut up!
Duggal sir and I are shifting to Bhopal
to represent the association there.
To look for fresh kabaddi talent.
Can't you see her ankle?
Why aren't you grabbing it?
Afraid to break a nail?
What was I saying?
I miss you terribly.
You and our glory days.
-So, let's meet on Sunday.
-Sunday is Adi's...
The husband can look after the child.
And God will look after the husband.
I'm not listening to any excuses.
Or I'll come to your house
and kidnap you.
Bye for now!
Later, alligator!
Mummy, are you going somewhere?
Who will help me
with the spell bee?
I will.
Okay.
Bye.
You're looking very cute.
Where's mummy going
on a Sunday?
Son, I told you mummy's
touchy about three things...
You, me and...?
Kabaddi.
What's this?
Baulk line.
Don't Bhopal girls have any power?
-What's this?
-Bonus line.
Very good.
Your family will pressure you
to get married soon.
They tried it with me, too.
But, this is the age for kabaddi...
for education.
How will you get out
of the trap?
Raiding in kabaddi
is like refusing a proposal.
Shall I show you?
Let's go.
Cross the baulk line
and affirm your stand.
Make a shy entry.
And on the bonus line,
get the point.
Now, you're in the game.
Now, you can claim dibs
on any member of the guy's side.
His uncle will try to befriend you.
But they really want
to grab you under this guise.
For instance, she tries to catch me.
She's got my ankle.
What shall I do?
I'll free my ankle, use the lobby area
and return to my end line.
Got it?
Girls, warm up. I'll be back.
Start.
Jaya.
Welcome to the City of Lakes.
You have a garden now.
I don't play kabaddi anymore.
Got to do something with my time.
I can't believe it has been 7-8 years
since we played competitively.
I haven't played kabaddi
since seven years and two months!
Did you know that I requested the team
to hold your spot for an entire year?
I thought you'd make a comeback.
You know Adi's health.
Then, Prashant got transferred
to Bhopal.
I got so involved in being
a home-maker
that I could never return
to professional sport.
Truthfully, I'm involved with kabaddi
to give the team
a national player like Jaya Nigam.
-You've never complimented me before.
-Honest truth.
But, seeing Bhopal's talent,
it seems tough.
-You're quite the motivational coach.
-I'll introduce you to the girls.
Line up, girls.
On the double.
Do you know who she is?
Jaya Nigam.
India captain, 2010.
And the best raider to date.
Take her blessings.
And give me 50 rupees.
How about a quick match?
I'm very rusty.
I won't be able to raid.
You guys practice.
We'll raid the snack bar, instead.
Snack bar?
We're in the canteen.
Continue with your practice.
Preeti, take over.
I'm watching even from outside.
Adi...
Is it true that if a pizza
isn't delivered in 25 minutes, it's free?
-I don't know. Why?
-Fine. We'll find out today.
Adi. Hello?
The pizza gave you a free bug, didn't it?
You get ready. I'll handle this.
There are two slices from last evening.
Would you like some?
Sorry, mum...
Prashant, we'll have to take Adi
to the doctor.
I'll take him.
No. I'll take him.
Drop us on your way to work.
Alright.
Adi, open your mouth.
Say, 'Aah'.
Your tummy's as small as an ant.
But, you want to stuff yourself
like an elephant.
There's bound to be an overflow.
Get up.
Come, sit.
Generally kids of his age
can handle junk food.
But, you know his immunity.
Doctor, he doesn't listen.
Prashant and he only want take-out.
You've troubled your mummy.
Now it's payback... medicine time.
He should settle by tomorrow.
Mrs Pandey!
Jaya, come in.
I'm late for office.
What happened?
He's been vomiting since morning.
I'll watch him.
Please give him these pills
after lunch.
Adi, take it.
Will he have lentil rice
for lunch?
Absolutely.
With pickle!
Don't trouble her.
Bye.
Okay.
Lentil rice with pickle?
Get better and I'll get you a tub
of ice cream.
The vomiting has stopped.
I gave him the medication.
Yes.
I'll check on him in a bit.
I'm in the office.
I'll call.
Rupal, is everything okay?
He's been asking for you
since the morning.
Greetings, sir.
You asked for me?
So... you've finally found the time.
Do you realise how inconvenient it is
for passengers
if one counter remains closed
for an hour?
Where were you?
Sir, my son was sick.
I took him to the hospital.
Jaya, gone are the days
you represented the Railways in kabaddi.
You're a regular employee now.
If you want a day off,
you have to apply for it
or you can say goodbye to this job.
Get this into your thick athletic head
as quickly as possible.
Yes, sir.
Since you're late by an hour,
you will stay back for two.
-Has Adi gone to sleep?
-Yes.
Without speaking to me?
He's sleeping, but I'm awake.
Speak to me.
There was a time
when I could walk in and out
whenever I pleased
and still got applauded.
Today I was late by an hour
and the boss hurled a string of insults.
When a person's circumstances change,
so does people's attitude.
I haven't changed.
You were a dodo before
and will always remain one.
Madam, this flightless bird
was blinded by your love.
Else, there are other beauties in line.
Where is the line?
I can't see them.
-Forget it.
-Have you seen your belly?
No.
-Pot-bellied oldie!
-Feed me less.
-It's your fault.
-Stop eating so much.
Mummy, I think I'm in better shape now.
No junk food.
Come on, mummy!
Think beyond food.
Thursday is my sports day.
Can I participate in the race?
One race. 100 metres only.
With my force adding to the wind's,
I have full chances of coming third.
Papa has agreed.
Fine.
Thank you, mummy.
Babloo, I'm participating
in the race, too.
Just one race for now.
You see I want to concentrate
only on one race...
What can the poor boy do?
Sports is in his blood.
Come early or you won't get to sit
in the front row.
All the best.
Thank you.
He was livid the last time
I was late.
He won't spare me this time
if I ask for half a day off.
Why can't school
host sports day on Sunday?
What will you do now?
Adi will be heartbroken
if you don't come.
I'll try.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Javed, how's the boss' mood?
Explosive as ever.
Final round - 100 metres.
Tanuj Chandra from Yellow House.
Adi Sachdeva from Green House.
Balwinder Singh from Red House.
Daksh Mittal from Blue House.
Get set... go!
Come on, Adi.
Run!
Yay!
Well done.
I can't believe that Adi came third
and I missed it.
It's alright.
Is he still angry?
Yes, he is.
Don't worry.  Come home.
We'll pacify him.
Alright.
Bye.
Adi, you came third!
Prashant.
I saw the photographs.
You were so good.
Adi!
I've brought you games.
You never came.
Sorry.
I got stuck at work.
Would the trains stop running
if you had left, mummy?
Everyone's mums were there.
Even Rihaan's.
Daksh's mother came
half hour earlier.
Your job isn't even that important.
You're just a ticket-teller.
And you couldn't leave?
Prashant...
where did I go wrong?
What did I not do right?
Am I not a good mother?
Jaya, it isn't like that.
Did you hear how Adi spoke to me.
He's a child.
He is angry.
Does being a child give him the right
to speak anyway he pleases?
And instead of correcting him,
you're pacifying me.
Is it solely my responsibility
to understand everyone?
Adi, you, the boss...
And no one tries to understand me?
Prashant, what opportunities I had
and look at what I'm doing?
You think mummy
doesn't do anything important.
But, do you know what's the most
important job in this world?
A mother's.
Your mother had many options.
But, she sacrificed it all
for two people.
For whom?
Us.
You know your mother
since seven years.
But, I know her for 10.
You know her as she is now.
I've known her
of how she was then.
Kabaddi...
4 points, Northern Railway.
Bye.
Jaya, ready?
Let her enter.
Don't let her get away.
2 points, Northern Railways.
Jaya Nigam.
Reetu Negi.
Yes!
Meenu said that there were many
kabaddi players but only one Jaya.
Through kabaddi Jaya got a job
in the railways.
And through the railways we met.
-Hello.
-Mayank.
Jaya.
Prashant.
I'm getting some tea.
Want some?
Yes, okay.
I'm not free now.
I have practice till seven.
-Book tickets for the night show.
-Fine.
-Will your mother agree?
-His secure government job will win her.
Prashant.
This is my best friend Meenu.
And this is Prashant. My...
Your?
Shall we go?
Yes.
Jaya, you play fabulously.
You're so fit.
Seeing you play
I've started loving the game.
Mother, this is Prashant.
He's an engineer.
He works with the Railways.
He makes a good living.
He'll keep me very happy.
Will he let you play kabaddi
after marriage?
-Yes.
Right.
Hello.
You're so lucky.
Your husband allows you to play
even after marriage.
I don't need Prashant's permission
for anything.
Very lucky. Let's go.
Come on, Jaya.
That's my wife. Mine!
Stop.
Romeo, don't get so excited.
Juliet, concentrate.
Come on, Jaya.
Prashant, your favourite aubergine.
Give him some more.
Don't you love aubergine?
Mummy's made it,
specially for you.
That's true.
A Volkswagon Polo for all-rounder, Jaya Nigam!
-May I come in, sir?
-Yes, Jaya, come.
-How are you?
-Very well.
A player gets to play for herself
or her team.
Only a few chosen ones get a chance
to play for their country
and truly shine as a sports champion.
There's only one-and-a-half year left
for the Asia Kabaddi Championship.
The country wants this cup.
Congratulations.
Sir! Thank you, sir.
Jaya, what happened?
Are you okay?
Chandni Chowk street food
is no longer the same quality.
Jaya?
It's not the food.
It's you!
I'm pregnant, you fool!
Mummy, I'm in the hospital.
Get ready to become a grandma.
What!
Seriously?
So now it's time for you
to say goodbye to kabaddi.
That will never happen.
Let's see.
Baby is playing kabaddi kabaddi?
Hello, sir.
Hello, Jaya.
How are you?
Fine, sir.
I'll have the baby in two months
and I'll return to kabaddi in six.
Prashant's very helpful.
He wants me to continue playing.
Let's see. Take care.
Thank you, sir.
There's no complication.
We had kept the baby in the NICU
for precautionary reasons.
He was born very weak
and was little underweight.
His oxygen concentration
was also low.
You will have to be careful with
the baby for a couple of things.
His immunity is not upto the mark.
And because of that,
he may be prone
to fever and coughs frequently.
He'll take some time to gain immunity.
And you'll have to be patient.
Someone will have to
constantly be around.
Take care of him.
Doctor... Jaya... I will be back.
Who'll take care of you?
Mumma.
Who'll make you strong?
Mumma gave up
her first love for us.
Even if we thank her everyday,
it's not enough.
Sorry, mumma.
Adi.
How old is mummy?
Why?
Tell me.
Eat.
Thirty two.
Can't a player
make a comeback at 32?
Have you heard of Serena Williams?
Mother of a child
and queen of tennis.
If you want her to make a comeback,
you must convince her.
Why are you shooting off my shoulder?
You're avoiding the topic
and it'll catch up with you again.
Come now, sit.
Roger Federer.
He's getting more agile
with age.
Your mother huffs after climbing
the stairs for five minutes.
How will she manage
two 15-minute halves?
Tiger Woods. Michael Jordan.
Yuvraj Singh.
Petr Cech. Muhammad Ali.
No.
-It's your fault.
-How?
You should've taken the responsibility
of looking after me.
Mummy must have got emotional
and said,
"Baby, I'll take care of you."
You could've said, "Jaya,
I'll take responsibility for our son."
You failed to make the score.
A little support from you
and mummy would've still been playing.
Why are you
making me feel guilty?
Children are God-like.
We never lie.
You've sinned.
I'm giving you a chance to atone.
Think about it.
That should be all.
Me and comeback?
Listen carefully.
I'm asking you to fake an attempt.
Prashant, neither is my gait
nor my weight kabaddi ready.
Try for a month
and say that you can't do it.
He'll be happy seeing you try.
Please! Adi's hounding me.
Please?
How is it possible?
With a little bit of truth
and a lot of lies.
You want me to go back to kabaddi
for the very people I left it for.
Why can't anything in my life
be normal?
I am.
Am I not normal?
No way!
I get kicked by my wife
everyday. Isn't that normal?
It's done.
Papa, I respect you a little more now.
Mummy, wake up.
Adi.
Get up!
You get up, too.
Adi's homework must've kept her up.
This doesn't look like a child's homework.
No one will ever believe
you were a kabaddi champ.
And you've to go to office, too.
This is all you'll get today.
You can order take-out.
Adi, eat these.
Even Bhopal's slowest train
is faster than you.
Drink up.
You've to build your strength.
It should go in one gulp.
Move!
It's not that I miss kabaddi.
I'm doing this for Adi.
If I'll come to your club,
he'll think that I'm practicing.
My legs aren't
kabaddi-friendly anymore.
I can barely handle a morning walk.
You didn't take long to turn those
deer-like legs into tortoise legs.
And when will you change?
You'll are snacking here?
Push harder.
Don't you have any strength?
Come on.
Let's have some tea.
Have you heard
of the Keto diet?
This stops. Keto starts.
I'll have this.
The gym's nice.
Check it out.
Get up!
Prashant, wake up.
I can't do it.
You go.
Down slowly.
There's one advantage.
I'm getting slimmer.
That's great.
My wife's getting hotter.
Give me the ticket quickly.
I'll miss the train.
Don't try and catch
a moving train.
You need to be fit
to do so.
I'll see you.
Want to play?
Frightened of these kids?
Kabaddi...
Not "Kabaddi kabaddi." Say "Oldie oldie."
She looks rusted from the outside
but strong from inside.
Jaya, you lost badly to the girls.
When are your selections?
Rupal was late, too.
Jaya, we agreed on this act
for a month. It's been two.
I know.
The longer you continue this charade,
Adi's hopes will rise higher.
Let's go.
How's your training?
What did Adi say?
Don't worry.
I'll speak to him tomorrow.
I couldn't say anything.
Why?
The child thinks that you're really
going to make a comeback.
Prashant, I feel immensely happy
when I see you.
I also feel the same
when I see Adi.
But, when I see myself
I don't feel anything.
In the past few days I've felt
an inner spark of happiness once again.
I don't want to let go
of this feeling so easily.
I know it won't last long.
But I also don't want to regret that
I didn't even try.
You're joking, right?
I'm not, Prashant.
Of late, I've been feeling
that I can make a comeback.
I want to play kabaddi once again.
What's wrong?
Where are you lost?
Nowhere.
Is everything okay at home?
We're going to be hit by a storm.
You've lost it!
When players retire
she wants to make a comeback!
Mummy, why're you mumbling?
I'm not asking for your support.
I'm not supporting you.
I don't want it.
You don't have it.
-Sweets?
-I don't want it.
You won't get it.
Move on, folks!
Quiet.
And I don't think anyone here
is supporting you.
Isn't it, Prashant?
Actually, mummy...
I think she's doing
the right thing.
She stopped living her dream
because of us.
The least we can do is support her
to fulfil it now.
Very good.
Very good. All you mad people
support each other.
I'm not getting involved in your madness
and ruining my life.
Support, my foot.
How much longer is grandma
going to live anyway?
Do you want a whack?
Jaya, call Meenu.
-Has she ever listened to me?
-You forgot my favourite sweet?
Why is this with sugar?
I had said, use jaggery.
Why are you grumbling?
What's wrong with the sweets?
My favourite ones, mummy.
The last batch was rotting away.
I had to throw the entire jar away.
Jaya, you think you can come back
into the Indian team
because you won against
a bunch of girls from Bhopal?
They're amateurs.
They don't even shave their legs.
And your real competitors are pros.
How will you make a comeback?
I have to try.
I have to challenge myself.
I'll at least be able to sleep in peace.
Sleep over it. Please spare me.
Do you remember this?
2006. Best raider.
North vs South Central
Inter-Railway final.
We played so well!
But, that was another lifetime.
We killed the internationals, too.
Nothing has really changed.
I couldn't play without you then.
Nor can I now.
And you're as stubborn
as you were then.
If you try to enter with these girls,
it'll take you forever.
We don't have that luxury.
Even today, the best way to enter
the Nationals team
is through the Railway team.
And for that,
you've to convince Duggal sir.
And don't expect any brownie points
based on past performance.
You've to prove yourself... again.
Got it?
The girl wants to challenge herself
once again!
It's tough on the mat.
We used to play on mud.
Stop whining!
You'll have to learn.
Sir.
-Greetings, sir.
-Greetings, Jaya.
It's impossible to keep you away
from kabaddi.
You're right, sir.
-Are you ready?
-Yes, sir.
-Let's go.
-Yes. Come on.
Kabaddi...
Without practice, the first thing
a player loses is agility.
What do you think, Duggal sir?
She slipped plus her leg twisted.
She's used to mud. She'll gear up quickly
to play on the mat.
She needs a major overhaul.
Sir, one word from you
and there will be hope.
She needs one spot in the Northern
or Central Railway team.
Jaya's good.
But not that good to get picked
for the Railway team.
Northern, Central, South Central, Western
Railway all have seasoned players.
She won't make it there.
Sir, please.
Go for one more raid, Jaya.
Kabaddi...
The other girls may have agility.
But Jaya uses strategy.
She plays with presence of mind.
She should get a spot on the team.
Duggal sir, what should I do?
Something can be managed
in the Eastern Railway team.
It's a new team.
The coach wants to make a good team.
He's touring the country
to find talent.
He's currently in Mumbai
making selections.
I can talk to him.
Jaya, I can only recommend you.
The rest depends
on how you play the game.
-Thank you, sir.
Jaya, you'll have to go to Mumbai.
At least we got to see Mumbai.
Let it not just end up as a city-tour.
This is your only chance
towards a comeback.
You lack speed.
Make your brain work double time
to make up for it.
Prashant.
Is he your husband or a boyfriend?
Does any husband call his wife
so many times?
Go ahead!
Prashant?
Jaya, you reached?
Yes.
It's a big day.
Put your best foot forward.
I'm a little nervous.
There's neither a kabaddi player
like you nor will there ever be.
Play confidently.
Thank you.
Bye. Call me after the match.
Love you.
Okay. Bye.
Thank you.
Bro, where does Amitabh Bachchan stay?
Can we see his house?
Or should we visit Salman Khan?
He's single. Like me.
Kabaddi.
Sir, we won't take up
much of your time.
Just one or two moves.
No problem.
You are doing well, Jaya.
Kabaddi... kabaddi...
Jaya, very good!
-Well played, Jaya.
-Thank you.
We could use an experienced player
like you in the Eastern Railway team.
-Thank you, sir.
-Not at all.
You're welcome.
You'll play for the Eastern Railway
and also work for them.
You must report in Kolkata
in two weeks.
We'll see to
your transfer formalities.
Sir, I can't shift to Kolkata.
I can go back and forth.
But, I will train in Bhopal.
How will you practice?
I'll practice in Bhopal.
Definitely.
I have a little child.
I won't be able to manage.
-Jaya...
-I coach my team.
I want to see you play and
practice everyday.
This is not a correspondence course.
Sir, I understand.
But I have a child
and I cannot leave home.
-Meenu.
-Yes, sir.
-Both of you need to decide.
-Sir...
If the team is from Kolkata,
they are not going to practice in Canada.
I don't get it, Jaya.
Along with your body
even your brain is rusty.
You're not married.
You don't have kids.
You won't understand.
Then why are you wasting my time?
I've paused my life, for you.
Sorry. I'm sorry I asked you to come.
And wasted your time.
But, I can't leave
Adi and Prashant.
Jaya, I'm not asking you to.
All I'm saying is
focus a bit on your dream.
I'm a mother.
And a mother cannot dream.
They neither have meaning
nor any value.
If I tell my family that they'll
have to do the dishes, cook...
watch their reaction.
All big talk about
women empowerment,
mummy's dreams, kabaddi,
will all vanish.
A mother has no right to dream.
And if I still dream, I'm selfish.
A cruel mother.
God!
Then why did you bother
coming here?
To test my limits.
This is the maximum I can push.
Sit!
Let's go.
Selfish mother
will sit alone at the back.
It doesn't look like
you've been selected.
Why should I smile
when I'm not happy?
If I go to Kolkata
how will you manage?
Adi, meals, Adi's school,
homework, medicines,
your work, home.
If I start to list down chores,
even 200 pages won't be enough.
How will the house function without me?
Tell me.
Don't bother.
I can clearly see the answer
on your face.
One ticket to Sanchi.
Give me two minutes.
I'll serve you.
I'll manage.
I have to get used to it.
You're going to Kolkata, right?
At best what will happen
without you?
We won't get food
made by you.
There'll be many problems
which neither you nor I
will remember after a year.
The only thing we'll remember
is that you had a chance
and you let it slip away.
Jaya, don't make
the mistake again.
Prashant, how will Adi
stay without me?
I'll be sad, mummy...
if you quit kabaddi again.
And finally we're getting a little freedom.
Don't take it away from us.
Right, Adi?
Yes. Mummy, please go.
Made these sweets for you.
There was no need.
Thank you.
I'll miss you.
Make us proud.
Take care.
You too.
-Tell the boss.
-Sure.
Bye.
I'm stocking some essentials.
They'll be alone.
Please keep an eye.
Don't worry.
You're lucky to get a second chance.
See you soon.
Take care.
Prashant, let me know
if you need anything.
Sure, thank you.
Only someone as wise as Prashant
can handle a crazy one like you.
Ask God for a similar one
for yourself.
Right now I'm praying that
you make a mark in kabaddi once again.
Take care.
Will you miss, mummy?
No.
Liar!
What time does Adi's school bus come?
7 am.
What's on 15th August and 26th January?
Independence day and Republic day.
Prashant! No-worm day.
You have to deworm him.
What medication does he take everyday?
Zincovit.
How much?
5 ml.
Adi, if papa forgets, remind him.
What do you have to do everyday?
Video call.
Take care.
Bye.
Come, Adi.
Prashant.
Yes, Jaya?
Call me as soon as you reach.
If you can't call from the train,
message me.
And don't worry about Adi.
I've spoken to your mother.
She said that she'd drop by as and when.
But I can manage alone, as well.
Ask me anything if you're still unsure.
How many whistles do lentils take
to cook?
Jaya, there's the train's whistle.
Go, sit.
Don't worry about us
and concentrate on your practice.
Water the marigolds every alternate day.
-Okay.
-I love you.
Love you, too.
-Bye, Adi.
-Bye.
Prashant, I got a cab.
What have you guys cooked?
Potato curry?
I hope you haven't used too much oil.
I'll call you once I reach the hostel.
Here you go.
-Greetings.
Jaya Nigam.
It's fine.
-Where's my room?
-Straight, up the stairs.
Take a left.
Go to the first floor.
There's a door next to the stairs.
Go there.
Alright.
The second door.
The corner room...
Room number 21.
Got it?
Hello.
Too old to be a player
and too young for a coach.
Who are you?
-Is this how you speak to your coach?
-Sorry, ma'am.
Get the bags inside.
You keep the room so untidy.
Do you sleep with the lights on?
Sometimes.
Very bad.
I won't anymore, ma'am.
Prashant...
-What's your name?
-Nisha Das.
We're about to eat.
Potato curry sans oil with flatbreads.
And Adi?
Has he gone to sleep?
Jaya's a new player.
From today she'll be playing
for Eastern Railway.
That was quite a fast one
you pulled on me.
I only swung to the full toss
you threw at me.
The next time it will be a googly.
Don't give out your strategy.
Are you only interested in cricket
or does kabaddi interest you, too?
Till that line.
This is known as a catch in both,
cricket and kabaddi.
Again.
You've been the Indian team captain!
Yes. I'm also mother to a 7-year-old.
You're great, sista!
You can fall at these feet now.
I can't reach.
Kabaddi...
Concentrate, Jaya.
You can do it.
Kabaddi...
You have to work on your speed.
I'll try defending.
The team's zooming like a bullet train
and I'm crawling like a tram.
At this rate, you won't make it
to the Railways team or the Indian team.
Thank you.
I suggest a personal coach.
Everyone has one.
When the journey's long
and you're strapped for time,
you need a double engine.
Do you have someone in mind?
Why haven't you got married
till now?
I never wanted to.
Then why bother now?
In a few years,
my eggs will not deliver.
These guys want a grandchild next year.
So, here I am!
Excuse me.
Hello, darling. How are you?
Will she continue with kabaddi
even after marriage?
What harm if the daughter-in-law
earns as well?
Really? Is kabaddi a lucrative sport?
Absolutely.
I'll be in Kolkata soon
to drown you in my debt.
So, we'll get them engaged
in a couple of weeks.
And then we'll find an auspicious day
for the wedding.
Later, alligator!
Dude, you've lost your chance.
Eat the snacks and leave.
They're really fresh.
I haven't made them.
I'm off to Kolkata.
I'll call you.
-What's this, papa?
-Stuffed flatbread.
Sure, it looks a little scary.
I'm stuffed just looking at it.
I haven't seen Jaya lately.
Is she fine?
She isn't even active
on the WhatsApp group.
-Jaya's in Kolkata.
-What's wrong?
You both seemed very happy.
It's not what you're thinking.
She's started training
for kabaddi again.
Please add me to the WhatsApp group.
The big door, isn't it?
I have arrived.
Who have you come to meet?
I don't go to meet people.
Even the big guns come to meet me.
Meenu...
This is Meenu!
Nisha suggested a push start.
I thought of an even better idea.
A rocket start!
Who's Nisha?
My roommate.
Hi, Ms Roomie!
-Let's go.
-Put some meat on those bones.
Why did you have to tell them?
They'll make a mountain of a molehill.
No way. They're decent ladies.
It was easy to slide and get up
on the mud.
It's easier on the mat.
Try again.
Come on, Jaya.
Slip under the chain.
Mat is easier, but it slows you down.
Come on.
And your speed was always a weakness.
Why're you staring at me?
Get up.
Speed isn't your forte.
Figure out your strength.
Your strength is your strength.
Correct!
I won't go under the chain.
I'll break the chain.
-Let's go.
-Who'll clear up?
Later this evening.
Hurry.
What was that?
Holding one leg won't work.
What would Prashant do
if you left him?
Why do you want me divorced?
Give me another example.
I'm only asking you to imagine it.
That's it!
Is mummy here?
No, your mummy's mummy is here.
Grandma, this is the first time
I'm ecstatic seeing you.
Want a whack?
I'll go straight to the food.
-What will you have?
-Cottage cheese.
This ankle lock's a problem for me.
I'll have to figure a solution.
Nisha, get the laptop.
Here.
Seriously?
This Tiger Chan move?
How can I do this?
Only guys can pull this off.
Tiger Chan.
Tiger Chan?
Tiger Shroff and Jackie Chan's
surrogate child.
Jaya, have you called me from Bhopal
to waste my time?
Try it, at least.
I'm barely managing to play.
I'll break my bones.
Try, sista.
I have a little child.
What if I break my back?
Nisha, she won't play.
Make me some tea instead.
Go make some tea.
Hello, Mrs Pandey. I'll be late today.
Please could you give Adi dinner?
Eat first. Do your homework later.
Dinner first.
Papa, I can't go on stage like this.
Don't worry.
Let's video call mummy
and get it sorted.
I'll call her.
If you get selected in the Railways team,
then the sky is the limit.
All the best.
Ready?
Just a minute, sir.
Prashant, I told you my match
is about to begin.
Mummy, look what papa has done.
Jaya, it's a mess.
Can you do anything?
He has to go on stage
in a couple of minutes.
Prashant, you've ruined his face.
Didn't I explain to you last night
how to do the face?
Jaya, tell me what to do.
Wait... I'll...
I asked you to do one thing
and you couldn't even manage that.
And now you're asking me
to find a solution?
I'm managing everything without you.
But, I can't do some things
without you.
It's quite clear how you're managing.
I shouldn't have listened
to you guys.
I should've never come here.
Prashant, you only talk big.
-But, when it comes to reality...
-Stop taunting me.
I'm managing somehow.
Clearly.
Go to hell.
I'm his father.
We've been okay so far.
I'll figure something.
Jaya.
Jaya, go live your dream.
We'll manage.
Prashant!
Jaya, come.
Kabaddi...
Raider safe! 3 points.
Raider safe!
3 points, Eastern Railway.
Kabaddi...
Raider safe, 4 points.
Half time.
Change the court.
Everyone's laughing at me.
Everyone's going to tease me
at school.
Adi, forget it.
What do you care? Be quiet!
I don't want to talk to you.
Call mummy.
-Mummy's playing a match, love.
-I don't care. Call her.
Call her back.
I don't want to stay with you.
I want to stay with mummy.
You don't know anything.
Fine!
I'll call your mother back.
Jaya, I was about to call you.
Prashant, I got selected!
What?
I've got selected
for the Railways team.
Nisha, Jaya, well played.
Adi, mummy got selected.
Talk to her.
Congrats, mummy.
Thank you, Adi.
I'm sorry your function
got ruined today.
Mummy, my performance went off
very well.
Do you know the applause I got?
Papa fixed everything
at the last minute.
-Really?
-We'll see you soon, mummy.
Excuse me.
Are you Jaya Nigam?
Hello. I'm Samarth Joshi,
reporter, Zee News.
I'll call you back.
How do you know my name?
Who doesn't know the former captain
of the Indian kabaddi team?
At least someone does.
Why did you leave kabaddi
after marriage?
At the peak of your career!
Family pressure?
When a girl takes a break
from her career,
it's not always the family's fault.
It can be my decision.
As for my family...
I didn't leave kabaddi
because of them.
In fact, I came back
Ma'am, can I record this?
-Okay.
-Sure.
Thank you. One minute.
I'm very happy
that I've reached here.
But, I want to achieve more.
I'll be honoured
if I can represent India again.
Adi, I saw your mummy
on television yesterday.
"I'm here today
because of my husband's support."
Unbelievable.
First, my wife used to say,
"Be romantic like Shah Rukh Khan."
Now, she says,
"Be supportive like Prashant."
Where's the party, dude?
Right here. Eat all you can.
That's it? Fine.
This is new-age India.
We must support her.
There are so many women like Jaya
who want to make a comeback.
Why should we question their capability?
People say she'll leave office at 6 pm
because she has a child to care for.
Why? Why should they even say that?
That's not a consideration at all.
How does a woman being a mother
affect her capability?
Look at the corporate sector.
There are many cases where women
have made a comeback
after becoming a mother.
Why not sport?
Keep watching Zee News for more.
Cheers.
Every sportsperson dreams of playing
for their country.
The Asia Kabaddi Championship
selections begins soon.
And as always,
I want at least 3-4 players
from the Railway team.
Okay?
Jaya, that's Sinha sir.
Do you think we'll find good players
from the Railways this time?
He's the Indian team coach
and chief selector.
We want all of them to be selected.
Kabaddi...
Yes!
Raider safe. 2 points, Railway.
What do you think, sir?
Hello, mummy.
Listen... when you get selected
and give an interview,
don't just credit Prashant.
Talk about your mummy, too.
How I raised you.
Changed your nappies.
And helped you with your son.
Cleaned my puke. Made my braids.
Two of them.
Okay, my child.
Alright.
Bye.
Kabaddi...
2 points, Tamil Nadu.
-She's the Jaya Nigam from 2011.
-Yes, sir.
She used to be a star player.
Sakshi, steady.
Grab her.
Sir, this is Nisha.
Today is the last day
of the Asia Kabaddi Championship
selections in Delhi.
The country has their eyes
on Jaya Nigam.
Let's wait and watch if she makes
a comeback into the national team.
The selections are underway
for the Men's team.
Will Praveen Singh make team captain
once again?
In the next few days,
we'll announce the selections
for the Indian Women's kabaddi team.
We have to wait and watch
if Jaya Nigam will make the team.
Sir, the media's showing
a lot of interest.
Perfect, Mr More.
This benefits Women's kabaddi.
Saba Desai
Rimpi Dewan
Neha Ghadge
Sweety Singh
and Pooja Jadhav.
This is our final team.
Any comments?
Sir, I feel this list is missing
an important name.
Jaya Nigam.
Do you think Jaya can replace
any player from this list?
Sir, I'm not suggesting a replacement.
All I'm saying is that she should
be in the team as a substitute.
How can that happen?
Mr Sinha, what're you saying?
Sir, have our girls ever lost at kabaddi?
In spite of which
our women's kabaddi team
has never got the popularity
it deserves.
Suddenly, the whole country is interested.
Sir, let's give Jaya a spot
in the team.
Everyone wants to see
a mother's comeback.
Let's show them and our sport
will reap the benefits.
If our sport is popular,
only then will we get good players.
Sir,
let's give her a spot.
For sure it'll mean the extra cost
of a player.
But think of it as an investment
for the future of women's kabaddi.
Please, sir.
What?
Jaya got selected?
Adi, mummy is selected.
Yay!
Jaya is selected!
What happened?
Mummy's been selected.
We're off to Delhi.
To see the Asia Kabaddi Championship.
I'll call Jaya right away.
Have you met Mangal?
She's a superb raider.
In the white shirt?
Captain.
-Sir, is everything okay?
-The one who's standing.
I'm just waiting for someone.
Madam, why aren't you eating?
I'll say hello.
Hello, Smita.
I'm Jaya.
I've been a captain before...
Who doesn't know you.
You're the player who has been
selected to warm her seat
but go back with a gold.
Pass me the curry.
An auspicious start
to the 19th Asia Kabaddi Championship.
A big round of applause
for the women's kabaddi team.
Teams from eight countries.
28 interesting matches.
And one prestigious tournament -
the Asia Kabaddi Championship.
And we start this tournament
with host country India playing Thailand.
-That's mummy.
-Yes.
While the reigning Champions, India,
will try to strengthen its position
in this group,
Thailand will strive to put up a tough fight.
And the referee has invited
both team captains for the toss.
The winner of the toss
will choose a side or raid first.
Choose.
-This side.
-Toss win by India.
-Choice - side.
-And team Thailand
is invited to raid first.
All the best.
Come on, girls.
Jaya!
Playing seven come on the mat.
While the substitute players
heads towards the dugout.
First up is Thailand's best raider,
Saowapa.
She looks for a chance
but the Indian team is fully alert.
Why isn't Jaya playing?
She's a substitute.
Saowapa looks for an opportunity.
Saowapa tactfully gets Thailand two points.
2 points, Thailand.
That was a cross!
The Indian captain looks unhappy.
And the coach looks angry.
India's top raider, Kalpana Juneja,
looks for a chance.
Kabaddi...
Thailand tries to catch Kalpana,
but she breaks the ankle hold
and beautifully tackles her way out
to get India four points.
Super raid, 4 points, India.
India - 4, Thailand - 2
A few seconds left in the first half.
Thailand's last raid.
First half ends.
India in the lead.
Second half starts.
India's Kalpana Juneja
trying to increase the lead.
Our team's killing it!
Kalpana Juneja turns swiftly.
Kalpana Juneja is a fantastic raider.
The Thai team tries to close in
on Kalpana Juneja.
But, she cleverly scores
four more points.
Wasana from Thailand
is ready to raid.
Opposite her are
India's top defenders.
Rimpi goes for an ankle lock.
Nisha and Smita block her.
The Indian team displays
exemplary defence.
-Super tackle, 2 points, India.
-The Thai team appears quite weak.
Few minutes left
for the match to end.
And India's raid.
She's been sitting for so long.
When will mummy play?
Soon.
India has a good lead
and a win is certain.
Bimla Jain looks for a chance.
And a fantastic touch point
from Bimla Jain.
And with her slide,
India wins two points.
2 points, India.
Match over.
With this effortless win, India has made
a clear statement in this tournament.
The points scored by India in this group
will help them in the knock-out stage.
We won!
India will tackle Bangladesh
in the next match.
Well played.
Nisha.
-Shall we go?
-Let's go.
Prashant.
Adi.
Your team played very well, Jaya.
Whose team, after all!
When will you play, mummy?
Maybe the next one.
Have you met Nisha?
Say hello to her.
-Hi!
-That's my mother, Prashant and Adi.
Hello.
What did you'll eat?
Nisha!
The bus is here.
We have to go.
I have to go.
Sir, please comment
on the Indian team's performance.
We played well.
We've got the right spirit.
It should continue this way.
India has secured a win
in group A,
while Iran beat South Korea
in the group B match.
Iran won the match by 38-20.
-They're strong.
-They sure are.
Do you want to get strong?
Eat well.
Have some cottage cheese.
The second match in group A -
India vs Bangladesh.
The last seven minutes remain.
India ahead with a strong lead.
Salma's double ankle-hold attack.
Kalpana jumps and...
It looks like Kalpana is hurt.
-Kalpana has twisted her ankle.
-Point, Bangladesh.
-Kalpana?
-Tough times for Kalpana.
Her ankle took the hit,
didn't it?
Official time out.
Gauri ma'am.
Substitute player Jaya Nigam
and assistant coach Gauri Wadekar
come forward to help Kalpana.
Kalpana seems to be in a lot of pain,
and might not be able to play
the rest of the match.
Some excuse to come on the mat.
She had to injure herself!
Referee, time out.
Second half.
First time out, India.
I think now mummy will play.
She will.
The coach has chosen Hemlata Kumari.
India's youngest player is about to play
her first international match.
She may not be able to make
such an impact in this match
because India has nearly won the match.
If an experienced raider is hurt,
shouldn't she be replaced
by an experienced one?
Why an amateur? Dammit!
Last minute of the match.
Orpa from Bangladesh.
Bangladesh is far from its goal.
Indian fans won't be disappointed today.
Orpa's touch point.
Smita's block.
She has grasped Orpa.
The team supports beautifully.
Orpa is down.
India shows excellent teamwork.
They've earned another point.
Looks like Bangladesh
will exit group A.
-Here's the final whistle!
-Match over.
Bangladesh - 22, India - 30
India has won today's match
but let me remind you
it's not going to be easy from here.
We won.
When will you play, mummy?
Is it important for you
that I play or India wins?
Both.
What if you had to choose one?
Just one...
Ms Jaya, the country is waiting
to see you play
but you haven't yet got a chance.
Please comment.
More important than my playing,
is winning the cup.
That's the way!
Learn the sport from me,
but sportswoman spirit from her.
In their last group match, India
is almost certain to win against Sri Lanka.
But without Kalpana Juneja,
the team seems to have weakened.
2 points, India.
Our train has been in waiting.
When will it get the green signal?
Bro, my train is here.
Please give me a ticket.
Pressure's on the defense
to make all the points.
While Bimla Jain
must win the raid.
She seems tired.
She slips trying to get a touch point.
Bimla Jain seems to have injured
her elbow.
Bimla Jain seems badly hurt.
What now?
This isn't good news for India.
Kalpana Juneja and Bimla Jain, injured.
Let's see how India strategises the semis
after losing two star raiders.
We've struggled to reach the top
of this group.
It seems tough ahead.
We have to play South Korea.
It's going to get messy, pal.
Use this.
Tell Adi that I'm in a team meeting
and that's why I can't meet him.
Or he'll ask me again,
"Why aren't you playing?"
It's fine.
At least the team's playing well.
Give me the phone.
Why aren't they
letting you play?
Mummy, how should I know?
Find out. Ask the coach.
He has his own stress.
And you want me to add to it.
Mummy, you're talking like a child.
Why are we coming to the matches
when you aren't even playing?
Don't come.
None of you come from tomorrow.
You're giving me unnecessary stress.
She's still angry.
She's always in a huff.
She can surely ask the coach.
South Korea plays
with a lot of speed.
We have to slow them down.
Sir, isn't it better
that we up our speed?
What if our girls forget
their technique in trying to speed up?
You're the captain.
Think like one.
Sorry, sir.
What are you staring at?
Write it down.
Can I say something?
Not if you want to talk
about your position in the team.
Not at all.
I have a suggestion on how to
improve our chances with South Korea.
If we don't extend the cover
bonus points will tempt the raider...
Aren't you a homemaker?
Fill the players' bottles.
Take care of them.
Don't meddle in the team's strategy.
-Captain.
-Sir.
Come here.
Yes, sir.
Do you have anything personal
against her?
She's not taken anyone's spot.
She's here on her own merit.
In spite of not playing,
she's still thinking about the team.
And instead of listening to her,
you're insulting her.
What should we do?
Just a minute-and-a-half left
in the first semi-final.
With great difficulty, India has managed
a lead of two points against South Korea.
Mink from South Korea.
South Korea keen on closing the gap.
India strives to increase that gap.
A super move by Kim.
2 points to Korea.
India has no answer to Korea's speed.
And Korea manages to equalize
the score at 34 all.
Just a minute to go
and the score is 34 all.
Will mummy not play today either?
I don't know, son.
Grandma?
You can ask me anything
about biology.
Not kabaddi.
Neha Ghadge coming up
from India.
Without star raiders Kalpana Juneja
and Bimla Jain,
India's attack seems slightly weak.
And that is clearly seen
in today's match.
Neha Ghadge tries desperately
to get a lead.
An attempt by Neha Ghadge!
South Korea's defenders
beautifully tackle Neha Ghadge.
India gives away a crucial 1-point lead
to South Korea.
Mummy's still not playing.
I don't want to watch anymore.
-Adi, wait.
-Adi.
Adi, wait.
I'm coming, too.
I'm going.
I'll join you in a bit.
30 seconds for the match to end.
South Korea takes a time-out here.
South Korea - 35, India - 34.
Neha.
Adi, look they're taking a selfie.
Let's take one of yours.
The last raid of the match.
South Korea only needs to spend
a few seconds in India's side
and return to their own.
Their win is almost certain.
The Indian team is focused
on catching her.
A very good attempt.
Let's see if it was a super tackle
or not.
That was a close win for India.
With a lead of 1 point.
It seemed India would lose this match.
We can't continue like this.
We barely scraped through in this match.
How can we go back
before the final match?
What are you saying, Jaya?
Adi's very hurt.
I can't see him like this.
He still thinks that I will play.
These things happen in sports.
Plus he's missing so much school.
Jaya, but we're here
to see the finals.
Prashant, please take Adi
and leave.
Jaya!
What a farce!
What's a comeback without playing?
You'll leave without seeing
the finals?
It's better than going there
and not seeing mummy play.
Adi, you didn't answer mummy.
What is more important for you?
That mummy plays or that India wins?
Iran has won the semi-finals
very easily.
They'll now take on India
in the finals.
Iran's team has played
exceptionally well, Mangla.
Something will have to be done
to stop them.
Sir, I'm at my wit's end.
We need players for any strategy to work.
And we don't have any.
Captain, may I say something?
Sure.
Sir, we need a player who has played
an international match to support us.
Are you talking about Jaya?
Yes.
No one has international experience
like her.
Thank you.
She's right, sir.
You're agreeing?
You've always been anti Jaya.
I'm not prejudiced against Jaya.
I want what's best for my team.
I still feel she isn't capable enough
to be part of this team.
But, that's my opinion.
Right now, it's not about me.
It's about the team.
S. Jeeva.
Sweety Singh.
Neha Ghadge.
Jaya Nigam.
Come on, girls.
Come on.
When will you play, mummy?
Prashant, please take Adi
and leave.
Asia Kabaddi Championship's
final match.
India vs Iran.
First raid by India.
Iran wins the toss and invites India
to raid first.
Come on, girls!
We have to win the game.
Send Jaya in.
India is feeling the pressure.
It'll be interesting to see
what strategy India will adopt.
Applause!
Both teams, get ready.
Raider, you take raid
after the whistle.
Jaya Nigam from India,
for the first raid.
Game on!
Iran will thrash us and Jaya, them.
After an 8-year sabbatical,
Jaya Nigam returns.
She looks to earn a point
for her country.
She shuffles, waiting
for the right moment.
Jaya Nigam.
Iran giving her no chance.
Crossing the bonus line,
she tries to make her way back.
Bonus!
She believes she's got a point.
But the referee denies it.
There seems to be some confusion.
Smita Tambe argues with the referee.
Smita.
The replay will confirm
what happened.
Clearly, Jaya Nigam's foot
didn't cross the bonus line.
No point for India.
Iran - 0, India - 0
Latifi from Iran
comes for a raid.
Latifi has played brilliantly
in this tournament.
She shuffles.
She dodges smartly.
Latifi tries to grab points.
An ankle-lock.
But, a failed attempt by Smita.
Latifi back to her side.
Three Indian players out!
Iran starts with a bang.
What are you all doing?
A bad start for India.
The Indian coach clearly upset.
Raider safe.
Super raid.
3 points to Iran.
Just five minutes left
in the first half.
Iran - 12, India - 7
As predicted at the start of the match
Iran gives India a tough fight.
Stick to the right.
Mummy's playing!
Mummy's finally playing.
India in a tough situation.
Nisha Das, India's raider.
Iran's defense looks strong.
There's a lot riding on Nisha.
She looks for an opportunity.
A fantastic touch point!
Nisha skillfully dodges her way out.
She safely lands on her side!
She earns points for India.
Nisha Das.
For first half.
And this completes the first half.
India still in trouble.
India - 12, Iran - 18
Both teams switch sides.
India needs to restrategise.
To look for solutions.
Jaya! Here!
Grandma, let mummy play.
Don't disturb her.
Quiet!
Ten minutes to go.
And once again from Iran,
Latifi raids.
She's looking for a chance.
She breaks away and
makes her way through the lobby.
Has the line been touched?
Super raid! 3-points, Iran.
The referee gives Iran the points.
The Indian team is not convinced
by the referee's decision.
-Line touch...
-It's out.
The replay confirms that Latifi
touched the line.
Well played.
It's a super raid.
Three players from India out again.
Neha should've pulled as well.
She was clearly out.
What happened?
Mummy's out again.
This final is slowly slipping out
of India's hands.
Time's running out.
So are their options.
Jeeva raids.
With no raiders,
India doesn't have many choices.
Jeeva tries, Iran doesn't give an inch.
An empty raid.
India is in trouble.
Spectators losing hope.
Nothing's happening.
Jaya is also not playing.
We're stuck with an empty raid.
-Iran's thrashing us.
-What?
I mean, Iran's playing very well.
Just two more minutes
in the second half.
Latifi from Iran returns.
Latifi intends to further strengthen
Iran's stance.
India is far from its goal.
A back kick attempt.
Jeeva's block and a fantastic raid.
A great raid.
Latifi manages another point.
India has no response.
The cup looking unlikely for India.
Just a few minutes left
for the match to end.
Iran - 31, India - 29
Captain Smita comes for a raid.
Diversion technique!
Neha Ghadge raids.
She tries to score a point for India.
Neha's back kick.
No... a touch attempt.
Neha, tries very hard.
But, fails.
Another empty raid.
A second failed attempt.
India in trouble.
The score hasn't changed.
Only two Indian defenders
on the mat.
Tough!
Yousafi attempts a raid.
This could be India's last chance
if both players are out.
India in its weakest position.
An ankle-lock by Neha.
Smita tries to block.
Yes!
They've got 2 points.
Super tackle, 2 points, India.
Great move by Smita.
Score - equal.
India still has hope.
And with that,
Jaya Nigam's back on the mat.
This is our last chance...
This is a 'do-or-die' raid for India.
We have to score.
Since the last two raids by India
were empty,
if this third attempt fails,
India loses.
Jaya, this is a 'do-or-die' raid.
It's all up to you now.
Jaya Nigam gets ready for a raid.
She has a big responsibility.
India's final hope.
Jaya Nigam.
Can Jaya do it?
Jaya tries her best.
She has to score one point
at any cost.
Jaya.
I have a child.
What if I break my neck?
Why did you come here?
To test my limit.
Jaya's getting breathless
while the line seems further away.
This is my limit.
I can't go beyond it.
Will Jaya touch the line?
Jaya lunges!
And it's a touchdown!
Super raid!
India wins the Asia Kabaddi Championship!
Team India, who were on the back foot
and struggling to survive against Iran,
have finally emerged triumphant.
What a comeback for India!
And what a comeback for Jaya Nigam.
Well done, girls!
-Sir, can I have your phone please.
-Of course!
Today you deserve it.
Well done.
Good, girls!
Prashant.
I shouldn't have sent you all back.
We'd never leave you alone so easily.
Prashant! Adi!
Mummy!
You were here.
Prashant, listen...
I'll turn off the taps, light, gas.
I'll eat home food.
Enough!
I've had 5 ml Zincovit.
I've filled my water bottle.
I'll finish my homework
and then go to play.
I love you.
Your turn.
Love you, too.
At least take a look.
He's too skinny!
Have you buttered it?
Here are my blessings.
You'll find a good man.
Then why have you got me here?
It's teaming with oldies.
Tell me when you need me.
I'll be there.
What are you getting me
for my birthday?
Just two months left.
I gifted you the guitar.
Give her the guitar.
This one.
No way!
I've had a change of heart
and I feel that I can stay here
after marriage.
Do you accept?
Shall I call Jaya
and give her the good news?