No. Alaric, no!
Forgive me
Unfaithful bitch!
You must die
But simple death
is too good for you
Her lungs are fine
The problem is something else
The last tests were not good
Paul...
Your wife is not well
Her heart has become weakened
And getting worse every day
I'm afraid it's serious
What can I do?
Get her out of the city
She needs rest and fresh air
And to relax
I'll give her a strict routine
that she must follow
Will it cure her?
I'm afraid not.
It's very serious
But if she takes care of herself,
she should live for many years
You have a big part to play
Yes. I know what I must do
She's my number one priority now
I couldn't live without her
Do you still have that house
near Perrouze?
Yes...
I almost had to sell it.
The last remains of the Marnac estate
My family's final resting place
Now, of course,
I don't need the money
Me, once a poor architect...
Marrying one of the
richest women in the country
Remember how they behaved
at the wedding?
Like I was an ignorant peasant
A fortune seeker
Paul, you have to move on.
Forget about them
Really...
You think it's that easy?
You've done well for yourself.
Made a lot of money
Everyone respects you
Come, come...
Stop tormenting yourself.
Now listen...
That house is ideal for your wife
It's quiet there, the air is clean
It's in the mountains,
but not too far above sea level
She might not like it
It's not exactly luxurious there
But it would be good for her.
Try to convince her
I will, but she never
went there before
I always had to go alone
You know, to check
the state of the place occasionally
...that sort of thing
Don't worry, we'll think up
some way of getting her there
Paul...
Pierre says that you need
peace and quiet
He suggests my holiday home
So I get to see that place at last
We'll leave tomorrow.
Soon you'll forget all about Paris
Very good, Mr Marnac, sir.
Whatever you say...
What a face that guy has.
Not what you'd call handsome
Sort of mean looking
Auntie, those old stories about him,
are they true?
Of course they are
Your grandmother herself
saw those weapons...
...covered in blood
Blood stains that stay fresh
for 500 years?
Hard to believe
The legend says Alaric de Marnac
slew his wife...
and three of her five children
Only the two he spared were his
What a monster
Then he took to witchcraft
and devil worship
Finally he went mad
He committed many horrid crimes
He even drank human blood
And his disciples did
as he commanded
Finally he was brought to trial
and the king ordered him imprisoned
There was a huge battle
Alaric was killed
by his wife's brother...
...with an arrow through his heart
He was damned then to eternal torment
Just an old wive's tale
Why?
Really auntie,
it's too ridiculous
What's so terrible about her
having a lover?
I'm not trying to excuse him,
but he found her in another man's arms
So?
If every man killed his wife...
because their marriage
wasn't working...
Where would we be?
And that beast killed children
No matter whose they were,
they were innocent kids
He died in mortal sin
His soul can never find peace
People must have been really dumb
back then
Enough talk
We have a lot of work to do
upstairs
Come on!
Don't you give me that look
I'm not your wife!
Tonight we'll be in Perrouze
I'm happy, Genevieve
At last you'll see my holiday home
I have such happy memories
of childhood days there
Memories I want to share
with you
Maville's great.
She's been like a mother to me
I know you'll like her
Genevieve, my love,
I know you'll get better here
We can walk in the woods,
visit the sights
We'll be really happy here
Paul, as long as you're here,
that's all that matters
- Is this him?
- Yes, that's right
Not bad looking
What's he like now?
Like that picture
It says 1965...
He looks about 30
I'm good at ages
So he's getting on now
You know...
He looks a bit like that man
in the painting
I hope he's not
such a beast
Look, I brought you here to help me
Not to gossip all day
All right! Keep your hair on
Get to work
I want everything gleaming!
I'm glad the house
will finally be lived in
Maville wrote and asked if her niece
could move in with her
She's a young girl
with no other family
We can use some help
around the place
I'm glad I agreed to come
I feel we're going to be very happy
here
I wish I'd come before
Don't worry.
We'll make up for lost time
Now I'm starting to see
how shallow my life was in the city
Surrounded by false friends
only there for the money... not for me
It was all so superficial
This is our new life
But for how long?
We'll work it out together
Now what's up?
I think we're out of gas
What a disaster.
What are we going to do?
There's a town not far back
I'll get some there
I'll come
No, it's too far for you
Can't we wait?
A car might come by
Not much traffic come this way
It's the scenic route.
That's why I chose this road
Damn it...
Don't leave me here
I won't be long.
Relax
Don't worry
Put the radio on.
Just close your eyes and relax
You'll be fine
See you soon
So his wife's really ill?
Heart problems.
She's coming here to rest
She'll stay here
when he goes to Paris on business
Then we'll have to look after her
Great! Not just servants
but nurses too
Listen, we don't do what we want,
but what we're paid to do
Maybe I was better of
in that school in Toulouse...
That school was a jail
Now you're my responsibility
I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to upset you
Think before you speak
You're just like your mother.
God rest her
Tell me about her
She was my sister,
but totally different from me
Auntie,
I promise I'll try to be good
Really
I know, Julie.
Deep down you're a good girl
Don't you dare move
Get out
Just behave and you'll be fine
Get the luggage out
Are you mad, stopping out here?
This place is like the jungle
Survival of the fittest
Come on lady
We only want to see
if you've got anything worth having
You're rich and we're poor
We're just trying
to even out the odds
Shit! Let's go
This way, come on
Paul! Be careful
I'm worried
They should be here by now
It's very late
Midnight...
Listen to that wind
All through the house
The sort of night when
Alaric de Marnac rises from his tomb
There's someone
Downstairs...
at the servant's door
Who could it be?
Who else? Obviously the master.
He's here
He finally arrived.
Come on
I'm so glad to see you at last.
What happened?
- We had an incident
- An incident?
I had to go to the police
in town
Police!
Maville, don't worry.
It's all sorted now
And your wife?
In the car.
Waiting with the luggage
This is my niece, Julie
Pleased to meet you, Julie
Me too, sir
Let's go
I really like Maville
I know we'll get along great
I told you so
She'll take really good care of you
You'll see
Her niece is a pretty girl
But I didn't like her
Give her a chance.
We only just met her
I know, but there was something
I didn't like about her
Something deep down inside her
Maville has her faults too
Like what?
She tells stories
Stories of ghosts
and horrible monsters
Used to give me nightmares
when I was a kid
Lots of them
were about this ancestor of mine
Sounds like that book Rebecca.
Do you remember it?
Except here,
Maville is a good housekeeper
In the book, the monster was
a beautiful woman
Here it's the ghost of a knight
who turns up every now and then
I never saw him, of course
Who was he?
Alaric de Marnac.
The man in the painting
He looks like you
Hardly surprising,
since we are related
Maville used to scare me with him
He has a satanic look
It freezes the soul
Nothing like you, thank God!
Well, let's talk about happier things
I have no problems
with old legends
What happened earlier was real
I thought those thugs
were going to kill us
It was horrible
Darling, I'm here to protect you
Yes...
And as long as you are,
I won't worry
Julie, calm down
It's me... Paul
You were screaming
I had a nightmare
That man in the painting
came to life
He tried to kill me
I heard a scream
and came to see what it was
I know.
I heard it too
I dreamed about that picture
It's you and your horror stories
Well... good night
Goodnight.
I'm sorry, sir
Good night
It's wonderful
Julie, every day I feel better
A month since we came
and it seems like yesterday
How time has flown by
I'm glad you feel better
I feel stronger every day
And I'll tell you a secret...
I'm falling in love with my husband
all over again
Maville is nice, of course
but do you know what?
I didn't like you at first
Now I feel really close to you
I didn't like you either
I hope you do now
Of course I do.
I'm really glad we met
Dear Pierre...I am happy to say
that Genevieve is getting better
The clean air, the slow pace of life,
it really seems to be good for her
Every day she gets stronger
I really hope it lasts
On the way here something happened
that could have been serious
I was worried about Genevieve
and didn't think she would recover
But to my great surprise
she didn't ask to go back to Paris
But she's really enjoying it here now
Truly, my life has never been better
I think things really started
to go wrong for me at school
My dad worked in a factory
in Toulouse
He got in a mess
and killed himself
My mother was an alcoholic
who died in a car crash
They put me in a reform school
A bad place.
Worse than jail
My aunt came and rescued me
Julie, you poor girl
I've wasted too much time.
Now I want to do things
I won't be a maid all my life
Look at Maville, she's grown old here
She's wasted the best years
of her life in this place
Her ambitions never went
beyond these mountains
Julie, I want to help you
find your dreams
Thank you, madame
Hello?
Ah, yes
OK...
The day after tomorrow
Yes...
I'll come to Perrouze
Anything wrong?
It's the police. They have
some information about that robbery
They want to see me.
I have to go into town
I've never come here before
It's a gloomy place
This is where Alaric de Marnac
is buried
The man in the picture?
Yes
He was a total monster
This house is the site
of his former castle
All I know about him
is what my husband told me
He killed his wife
for being unfaithful
The legend says
he rises from his tomb
to punish any Marnac woman
who lives here
He comes back every hundred years
What a horrible story
They say he's due to return soon
I suppose you'd be his first victim
But don't worry
It's only a legend
An old wives' tale...
Come on,
I want to show you something
Here's his grave
Alaric de Marnac.
1515 to 1565
"Only he
will hear the trumpet of Hell..."
"Only the Devil will be his friend"
Here, take this
I don't understand
I told them to stop all this nonsense
about Alaric de Marnac
And now this
It was horrible... that snake.
It was such a shock
That stupid girl's fault!
I'm kicking her out
Paul, please don't
Pail, let's make love tonight
Well... I don't know
Go on! Get out of here!
What did the police want?
To show me some pictures
See if I could identify
those thugs
Did you?
Yes...
seems they were quite well known
Looks like they might
catch them soon
Maybe even tonight
Paul, how long will you be in Paris?
Shouldn't be more than
3 or 4 days
I won't stay long
Please, darling.
Don't worry
I'll be back before you know it
And you've got Maville
I know. I'm being silly
I'll be as quick as I can be
I won't be gone long
Please don't be.
I need you
Genevieve, just take care of yourself
Remember, I love you
Paul, it's just that sometimes...
I get depressed
But darling...
Don't worry, I'll be all right
But hurry back
I will
Where's Julie?
I haven't seen her all day
She's in bed.
She had a headache
I think she's got a cold
Dear me, what a night.
It's going to be stormy
Storms round here can be bad.
Sometimes the power goes down
I think I'll go up to bed
I'll go with you
No, please. I'm all right
Very well.
But if you need me for anything...
...just call
The bell in your room
also rings in the kitchen
Thank you, Maville.
Goodnight
Goodnight. Sleep well
The knight...
Death...
God bless us
How is she doctor?
I think she's over the worst of it
I gave her a sedative
It's a heart problem
That's out of my league
When's Mr Marnac back?
Probably tomorrow
I'll talk to him about it
She might have to see someone
in Paris
Well, I must be off.
I have another call to make
I'll show you out
Stay here till I get back
She says it was a snake in her bed.
And she saw the knight
Then the lights went out
But the electric company say
there was no power cut last night
So it's impossible
I told you and Julie
to keep an eye on her
Julie was ill in bed
And where were you, Maville?
She didn't want me with her.
I stayed in the kitchen
I tried to keep awake,
but somehow I still fell asleep
This is all wrong.
I don't like it at all
Julie, sick; you asleep.
And my wife left alone here
What do you mean?
Nothing, I'm just thinking out loud
But I don't like it
Good evening, sir
Hello, Julie.
How's my wife?
Much better. She's asleep
Believe me, Paul. It wasn't a dream.
It was real
That's impossible.
That story is just a legend
I saw him, I tell you
It was just a nightmare.
Forget it
Don't take it so seriously...
please
I know you're right.
I'll try to be strong
Good. We'll go back to Paris soon
I'll have Pierre run some more tests
Tomorrow I must see the police
in Perrouze again
Again?
I think it's just routine
Come in
Here's your dinner
I'm not hungry
But you must eat
And Maville's made something special
Why did my husband have to go
back to the police?
I think they might have found
those men who tried to rob you
They've been arrested?
Not exactly, no
What do you mean?
I believe they were killed
resisting arrest
Maybe he went to identify
the bodies
Now try to eat something
Come on, I know you'll like it
It's your favorite.
And Maville cooked it specially
Blood!
What is it, Madam?
What's wrong?
It's only...
Only a fish
Take it away!
Go on, take a look.
It's nothing...
Mireille, you shouldn't have come.
It's crazy
People know me here
I had to come.
I had to know what was going on
I told you not to contact me.
Not to follow me
You left so suddenly
I'm sorry, but you must be patient
Listen, Paul Marnac...
I know about you.
I could cause you a lot of trouble
I've worked for you
for a long time
I know all about your business
Maybe more than I should
Are you threatening me?
A friendly warning
Just don't forget about me.
Alright?
Blackmail...
Call it what you like
You've got no class
I found you in the gutter
and you're still trash
I gave you five years of my life
You always knew what I wanted
Just be patient
Soon we'll have everything
we planned for
I promise
Maville, I have a bad feeling
I sense that my life
will soon be over
Oh, Madam...
When I die,
I'm going to die alone
Please don't say such things
My heart is sick
and now my mind is too
I see things that aren't really there
- Maybe I'm going mad, Maville
- Come now...
Completely mad
It's 9 o'clock.
Where's Paul got to?
Don't worry,
I'm sure he'll be back soon
Poor Paul.
I've not been easy to live with
First of all my moods
and depressions
And now this illness
But I do love him
I always have...
I always will
And he loves you too
Paul? Is that you?
Paul! Maville...
Please help me!
Take the body upstairs
We'll settle up later
From Paul to Genevieve,
with all my love
On our fifth wedding anniversary
I couldn't do anything.
She never even woke up
Cardiac arrest in her sleep
At least she didn't suffer.
I'll fill out the death certificate
Now what can I do?
I feel so empty
I'll take care of things
Thank you, doctor
It's no trouble
Poor lady.
How sad to die alone
Paul, do I look good?
Fantastic
Better than her?
Well?
Of course, much better
You look great
That first time I saw you I knew
my life would be empty without you
And I knew I would kill
to make you mine
How long will you be in Paris?
Long enough to arrange things
Getting the funeral sorted.
Telling all the friends and family
Then the legal stuff
has to be sorted
The factories, the houses,
the business, the bank accounts
It's all mine now!
Soon it will be all ours
Yes, very soon.
When you're my wife
Hello lover
I knew you'd be back
I have some things to pick up
Your pyjamas?
The silk robe I gave you
on your birthday?
I told you, it's not good
for us to meet right now
Nobody saw me.
I'm very discrete
The perfect mistress
But I'm tired of being perfect
At least say you're happy to see me
Listen, Mireille,
it's all going according to plan
In a few days I must return
to the country
A few things to sort out there.
Then we can be together at last
Just a body.
No class...no style
What a mess I'm in
You sleep well, my girl
You think you've finally got me
where you want me...
But your death will solve my problems
Your death...
Paul, can't you sleep?
No... l'm a little restless
Maurice, at last
Drink some coffee.
It'll do you good
Christ in heaven knows,
I'm dying inside
What's wrong, Paul?
Nothing. Just thinking out loud
I know this is hard for you.
Let me help
It's like a poem
A poem that doesn't rhyme
Death is the only solution
I'm trapped
But I must be myself
I don't understand you.
What is it?
Sometimes I'm hard to understand
But if the poem doesn't rhyme...
If it doesn't fit in the house...
Now the house is empty
I'm here for you.
I'll always be here
We'll work it out together
Yes, of course we will
Paul, please...
Can I come to the country with you?
No, Mireille
It's not possible right now
We have to wait
We're safe here
My aunt sleeps like a log
I usually slip some pills
in her milk
Knocks her out for hours
So it's just you two?
The gardener comes every two weeks
But he never talks
Apparently he's worked here
more than 30 years
He's deaf as a post
Maurice, I really want this
lt'll take time,
but we can be rich
Really rich...
Important people
I hope so
Trust me
Mireille, damn her!
What to do?
I must find a way out
Where's Maville?
In town. She'll be a while
Then we have time
It's all fine.
Nobody suspects anything
When I first heard that story
of the knight
I had nightmares
- do you remember?
Now he's like an old friend
The perfect partner in crime.
A partner who makes no demands
What shall we do about Maville?
Nothing.
She won't be a problem
If she is, just give her some pills
and she'll sleep like a baby
I don't know.
You might be right
Of course I am.
I've known her since I was a kid
Your wife was a tough bitch,
she took a lot of scaring
Julie, I bought something from Paris
What?
I hope you like it
Paul! It's beautiful
Anything for you, Julie
How could you do such a thing, sir?
I don't know.
Sometimes we act on impulse, Maville
Julie is a bad girl.
She has no conscience
I think she drove her father
to suicide
She's taken drugs,
been a prostitute
She used to hang around
with a thug called Maurice
A drug addict
who'd been in jail many times
He was her lover.
She ended up in reform school
I convinced the judge
to let her stay with me
I thought I could change her
I really did try
But all I did
was bring evil into this house
I decided to kill my wife
long before I set eyes on Julie
I hated her...
Her superior ways, her demands,
her impossible moods
How her friends used to laugh at me
She deserved to die
But she really loved you.
She told me that many times
When she got ill she changed,
because she needed me
Then I hated her even more
But her illness gave me
the perfect solution
You've changed.
I no longer know you
You're not yourself
So what are you going to do?
You're like a son to me
I watched you being born
and growing up
But I don't think I can forgive this
I can't...
Yes? No, he's already left
I don't know. I told you
All right, I'll give him the message
Mireille?
Yes. Says she's coming here
to see you
Damn bitch!
She's real trouble
Don't worry.
Just let her come
I hated doing that.
Maville was a good woman
But she had a conscience
And because of that,
she was dangerous
We should call the ambulance
Tell them about Maville's...
terrible accident
Wait, she's not dead yet
Now what can we do?
I'll get that
Is Mr Marnac in?
No, he's not
I'll wait. I need to see him
It's important
Hold on, where are you going?
Clean it all well.
There must be no traces
The doctor and the police
might be dumb...
But we can't take chances
Don't worry. I'll do a good job
I'll dump the car in the lake
tonight
Could anyone know she's here?
She was always very discrete.
Never discussed our affair
No, there's nothing to worry about
OK...
First I'll hide the car
Then we'll put Maville
back on the stairs
And call the cops
Along come
Sherlock Holmes and Dr Watson...
and believe everything we tell them
Keep calm, Julie,
and everything will be fine
Our luck's in
I am calm, lover...
...very calm
I thought the honeymoon
would never end
Thank God it has
That bastard wanted it
day and night
And every time I felt more sick
Every time I just hated him more
He's such a kid,
he's easy to fool
I can make him do anything
Soon we're going to be very rich
After the honeymoon,
I made him come back here
That makes ourjob easier
Soon we can be together, Maurice
I love you...Julie
Thanks, it's cold in this house
It's been empty for a long time now
Tomorrow I'll call the engineer in
To see if we can
get the heating fixed up
Come on, get in the bath with me...
You're all wet! Stop it
The big bad dragon will leave you be,
but you have to scrub my back
Julie, we'll always be together,
know why?
Why?
Because you and me, we're both alike
- two monsters
Aren't I right?
Well... maybe you are
And sometimes
even monsters need love
You're very deep tonight
Fuck you!
We're both evil...
But I'm more evil than you, idiot
Maurice?
It's all over, my love
I played the part
of the grieving widow
I was perfect
Do you have the tickets?
Tomorrow then,
to New York
I really need a holiday
I earned it, right?
I'll be waiting
Yes... at dawn
Best no-one sees us
Bye now. I love you
What's going on?
I'm starting to see things
Must get out of here
Hello? Who's there?
Say something
Somebody's trying to scare me,
that's it!
Trying to drive me crazy
It's all in my mind
This is my house
They can't get me
Maurice! It must be...
I must escape
Get out of here...
Ripped by smokey888
http://tehPARADOX.COM