Subtitles by explosiveskull
Is it on?
Yeah, this red light
here means it's on.
Today
is October 14, 2011,
uh, 3:21 p.m.
My name is Detective Jack
Scott, this is my partner
Kim Martin of the Leon
County Sheriff's Department.
We were assigned to
investigate the Debate Bus
Incident near
Moccasin Gap, Florida.
Case number DTI-875.
We've been reviewing the video
footage that was retrieved
from the site, as well
as forensic reports
and other investigation
data so far received.
We're making these video
reports because we have
now become concerned our
investigation may be compromised.
We feel that this event
must not be suppressed.
The public needs to
know what happened
'cause it may happen again.
And we'll send this video file
and all other documentation
to the appropriate party
when we feel it's necessary.
Other video reports
will follow as needed.
What the...
What the heck did you hit?
We just hit.
Are you all right?
What did we hit?
Everybody just stay
down, stay in the bus.
Coach, come with me.
What'd you hit?
Kids get, get back, get back.
Don't get too close, you
don't know what's under there.
In case you haven't
been following the story,
the Key West debate
team bus has been found.
I repeat, the bus
has been found.
No word yet on the 11 students,
bus driver, or
documentary cameraman.
The Leon County Sheriff's
Department found the bus
this morning neat Moccasin
Gap here in northern Florida.
This is a largely unpopulated
area of the county.
The police aren't allowing
reporters near the bus,
however, I see it about 50
yards or so down the road.
There appears to be a lot of
broken glass and other damage.
On screen is a photo
released earlier
from the Sheriff's Department.
The surrounding area is
considered a crime scene,
and here with me is
Sergeant James Monahan
of the Leon County
Sheriff's Department.
Officer Monahan,
what can you tell us?
Well it's still pretty
early to draw conclusions.
I see fire department
personnel in hazmat suits,
what can you tell us about that?
Well there appears to
be some unknown chemical
on the bus' windows and
floor, the forensic team
is taking samples, we
should know more soon.
I understand there were
cameras discovered on the bus.
There were six video
cameras installed on the bus,
still functioning, we
understand they were
filming some sort
of documentary.
The video footage is being
analyzed, we're getting
excellent assistance
from the Florida State
Highway Patrol in this process.
Any idea what's
on these cameras?
Not at this time.
Is there any evidence of the
students or other passengers?
No, we have officers
and dogs combing an area
within the 25-mile
radius of the bus.
Thank you Sergeant Monahan,
Officer James Monahan
of the Leon County
Sheriff's Department.
The students were traveling
to the National Collegiate
Debate Tournament in
Birmingham, Alabama.
I understand that the
tournament has been postponed.
We hope to know more soon, a
$25,000 reward has been posted.
This is Karen Carson for
Nine News at Moccasin Gap,
Florida, now back to the studio.
♪ I'm livin' on Key West time
♪ I'm livin' on
♪ Key West time
Hey,
good morning Key West,
it's 7:30 at Pirate Radio,
Key West, so wake up.
It's a little windy at
the tip of the Keys,
but another great day
in the Florida Keys.
Hey, if you see a big shiny
motor coach this morning
leaving Key West State College
marina, get out your pom poms
and cheer 'em on, it's our
own Key West debate team,
they're heading to the
national debate championship
in Birmingham, I understand
there's a documentary
in the works too, so
Key West debaters,
good luck, and
this one's for you.
♪ It's a pretty good
life I'm livin' ♪
♪ Won't hear me complain
♪ I'm just hopin' tomorrow
Oh, look at Diamond, she's
wearing a debate doggy shirt.
♪ Let's do it all over again.
I am Dr. Ronald O'Neil
and my wife Emily and I
are debate team coaches here
at Key West State College.
We are also professors in the
communications department.
For the past six years,
our teams have won
the state championships,
but never the nationals.
This is going to be our year.
Our program produces
mental acuity,
discipline, and character.
Every team member's
on full scholarship,
that's how good they are.
About six months ago, Key
West College received a grant
to produce a documentary of
our progress through the state
competitions and on to
the national championship.
A cameraman from Coral
Reef Productions has been
traveling with us,
capturing all the events.
Oh, we are very excited.
Put your camera
down, Shane, I'm making
my own documentary, and
I'm interviewing you.
Okay, whatever.
This is Shane Walker,
award winning documentarian,
and how many awards
have you won?
Besides my Oscars
and my Emmies?
And why am I interviewing you?
That's
a good question.
What the hell is this?
DJ Brown, DJ Brown Trucking
Company, the bus company.
You put cameras in this?
That's the
one you contracted.
This is not what
we contracted.
I know, I know but
she's a reliable bus,
she'll get us where we gotta go.
Isn't there
something else, this is...
Welcome aboard.
Ron, you're gonna
have to accept it,
come on honey, come on.
No, I can't get a
PO now, Shane look,
I don't need this filming now.
No, what?
- Just doin' my job.
- It would take to,
yeah, yeah, I'm tryin'
to do my job too, Shane.
It would take two days to get
a PO, I can't wait that long.
- You, oh Sara...
- Ron, we have to
go with it, please honey.
- Put it past us!
- All right,
I'll talk to you later, Sara.
We don't have a lot of
choice, we have to do it.
Our Florida state champions
and soon to be
national champions!
Julie Jorgenson and Josh Martin!
His lovely wife Jaiden Martin,
and Madison Jackowski,
her partner.
Connor Wagner, Alisha
Carter, AC to her friends.
Gail Stevens.
- Yee haw.
- Devon Rogers,
and last but not least, our
alternate, Carlos Montoya.
- And Pepe.
- Hey, let's get on the bus!
Oh good there's...
This sucks.
Well, home sweet home.
Okay, Captain DJ Brown
here welcoming you all aboard
flight 52 to Birmingham,
we're gonna be traveling at
50 miles an hour, about
10 feet above sea level,
and oh by the way, we can't
go any less than 50 miles
an hour 'cause there's a bomb
on board and it'll explode.
All right now, listen up,
we do have some strict
safety policies on
board this flight.
You can get up and move
around all you want,
but don't use the bathroom
at the back of the bus,
'cause we ain't got one.
Oh, oh and one more
thing, as you can see
we got this nice stereo
system, all decked out,
did this just for you
folks, but there's one rule
on this bus, when I play the
music, I choose the music too.
We know
what we're gonna be
- listening to.
- That's not music.
What're we
gonna be listening to?
It's a little
bit boring, but you know.
Does he like that?
- Shane!
- Excuse me.
never change.
Yeah, but check
this out little sis.
- I don't know.
- I'm sorry.
Remote control.
I'm not
your little sister.
Yes, but I own
your image forever.
- Creepy.
- I don't think he's
- very happy.
- All right,
pay attention everybody!
The lights, the cameras,
don't mess with them,
don't touch 'em, it's no touchy,
no bumpy, that's the rule.
Oh jeez!
Well I guess
we're ready to go.
Yee-haw
my favorite song.
DJ!
♪ Nine to five living
ain't a living to me ♪
♪ Put me out of my misery
♪ A big house right
up there in suburbia ♪
♪ You got my stuff
Maybe it's
working through you!
- Come on Gail.
- That's crazy.
- Don't say things like that.
- Or you!
- It's okay.
- Turn off the damn
camera, man!
- It's all right.
- Or you!
Gail, calm down.
♪ I've had to bag it up
♪ I've been edging
the fan too long ♪
♪ And I need to follow
♪ 'Cause I'm blind
child junkie ♪
Music with more muscle.
Amazing.
♪ Lookin' back in the
rear view at the places ♪
Can turn turn it off?
♪ That I've been
♪ And the roads
stretches long, long ♪
♪ Yes I think of all
♪ The faces and the
places that I've seen ♪
♪ There's a way back to
the pen a mile long ♪
♪ It's all about the journey,
not the place you're headed to ♪
♪ Kick it back and
just enjoy the ride ♪
We're gonna be doing
some rapid fires later,
can we get some rest now?
I'm Professor Emily O'Neil, I
work at Key West State College
and I have been the debate coach
with my husband for nine years.
The team that we have
today is exceptional,
they're very unique,
and they are at a level
that they're gonna
go all the way.
The motto that we have that
the students came up with
is focused, motivated,
and prepared, so FMP.
And they're all saying
it on the bus, FMP,
focus, motivated, prepared,
they're ready to go.
Oh, I'm just getting, oh goosebumps,
just thinking about it.
Hey, what's up?
No, just chillin'.
Yeah, I'm sitting down.
What?
No, Rachel, what?
Don't tell me to calm
down, what's wrong?
How bad is she?
Is it life threat...
Are you telling me...
For real?
Okay, can you post it?
Are you okay, honey?
AC, what's goin' down?
It's cool, my grandma
was rushed to the hospital.
Do you think, maybe...
AC flat
out, we're family.
They don't know what's wrong.
They said she'll
be all right but
don't they always
say that though?
I seen combat soldiers
on their last leg,
they tell them
they're doing great.
Dammit all.
I'm Alisha Carter Guttierez
and I get it, I know.
Am I black or am I Latina?
Back in PR we was all
mixed up, Puerto Cubicans,
Puerto Coricans, and we
moved to Miami, downtown.
Got my GI bill of rights
after two tours in Iraq.
And I learned so much
from my soldiers, so much,
so this champ knows how to
kick major debating butt.
semper fi, whatever, out.
♪ On the tip of my tongue
♪ Just like leaving
keys in the car ♪
This might get 'em.
♪ We knew before it begun
♪ We both would
take it too far ♪
♪ It's a mountain to climb
♪ It's a time on the blind
♪ It's a place we can find
♪ And I'm ready, I'm ready
♪ Are you certain that
you're feeling to tell me ♪
♪ Are you feeling to be me
Yes.
Is this the wild west?
No believe me, you
don't, again.
Well let's do it
again, let's play with my name.
I wanna.
Hey, can anyone play?
♪ Eyes up in the sky
I'm gonna
pick, how much do you win?
Oh!
♪ In a million tears
♪ Rainin' down and
I don't know why ♪
♪ And the good times are
just a coming for the stone ♪
♪ Just a coming for the stone
Well, my name is
Madison Jackowski,
I'm from Kansas City, Missouri.
I really don't like the
limelight, except in debate.
Then I actually morph into
Superman, like Clark Kent.
It's a kick, I'm
never lost a debate.
I'm not bragging, just a fact.
Thank you for making
me start, Coach Emily,
you really are a
blessing in my life.
All right folks,
the Cobblestone Cafe
is just 10 minutes away!
- Woo!
- Time for...
- It's double dog.
- I think if you ski it.
Dective Jack Scott,
October 15th, 1:15 p.m.
The kind of damage this
bus sustained, along with
the slime residue deposited,
amongst other things are,
to say the least, very
difficult to evaluate.
They are so far unprecedented.
We have received a chemical
analysis of the white
substance found on the
bus, this substance,
which we are calling
slime, has so far shown
no chemical properties
and is made of nothing known.
It also does not seem to
react to certain stimuli,
like hot and cold, or even
some other caustic chemicals.
Detective Martin.
Carlos.
What?
Stop it!
I'm Carlos Montoya,
and I'm the alternate.
Which means, I
don't debate often,
unless someone breaks a leg
or, and if I don't debate,
I don't get awards, and
if I don't get awards,
I don't go to law school.
If I don't go to law school,
I don't become a law partner.
And I'll never marry Shakira.
Pepe, you find something funny?
No.
Because I could tell
Diamond that you know,
you like Puppy Chow,
Chaquita bananas.
It's not so funny
anymore, is it?
Thought so, anyway,
I'm not a war hero,
and I ain't no jock,
sorry.
But I don't worry
about it though, 'cause
♪ My day will come
I know it will, anyway
Pepe, say goodnight Pepe,
be, be nice, say goodnight.
Pepe no, no cursing, no cursing.
♪ What would John Wayne do
♪ Standing with
a girl like you ♪
♪ Would he kiss
you along the way ♪
♪ What would the Duke say
Oh my goodness, you guys
listen up, you hear this?
This song was written
especially for me by an old boy,
well, he was a friend anyway,
it's about John Wayne.
- Uh.
- John Wayne.
Well you know I
love John Wayne,
I named my horse
after him, Duke.
All right so, Gail Stevens, I
was born in Mobile, Alabama,
moved to Lander,
Wyoming when I was 13.
My parents own a horse ranch
there and I love rodeo,
even more than
debate, it's a close
second though, so don't worry.
I hold the county record in,
I hold the county
record for barrel racing
and I owe it all to my horse,
Duke, he gets all the credit.
And I named him after well,
you know, The Duke, duh.
This year's national championship,
Birmingham, Alabama.
I owe it all to
Coach Ron and Emily,
they are absolutely the best.
It's 21-21, nine minutes
left in the third quarter.
So it's still...
Hey, remember
your blood sugar.
I was just
reinforcing, you know the stuff
we already knew
about the bull there.
- A big chunk out of that...
- Yes, she did.
Oh, Carlos, I oughta
lasso you up and feed you
to the bulls, give
me back my chips!
She loves me,
she truly loves me!
- Oh my goodness.
- I knew it, I knew it!
Somebody get Pepe.
♪ You just got to stomp
♪ Get on up and stomp
♪ Make it, make it louder
♪ Gonna bring the
house down, stomp ♪
♪ Get on up and stomp
♪ Make it, make it louder
- Hey Julie?
- Yeah?
Can I get the salt, please?
Yeah.
Uh, and the
pepper too, please.
Yeah, is there
anything else you need?
♪ And I don't know what to do
♪ 'Cause it's been so long
since I fell for you ♪
♪ What to do
That's fine but, I know,
look how...
WQXY, Latin rock...
Who in the hell
left the door open?
I closed the door,
now it's open.
- Who left the radio on?
- I didn't do it.
All this stuff on the
bus, the door was wide open!
Damn, Carlos.
- Maybe you left the door open
- Where's my...
What's goin' on, what's up?
Carlos,
- Carlos, did you do this?
- Wow.
Well Carlos
thank you for nothing.
I did not!
What is goin' on though?
- What?
- Seriously, Carlos?
- Carlos!
- I didn't do nothing!
- Wait...
- That's not cool!
I didn't do nothing!
Look guys,
just give him a break.
You
didn't do anything.
Carlos, we're
not gonna take this
for the next two days while
we're going up and back
- from Alabama.
- It wasn't me, it wasn't me!
- I wasn't even here.
- Yeah, very funny, man.
- Give it a rest, Carlos.
- Guys I'm serious,
- it wasn't me.
- It's not funny.
You're
shooting some things right now.
Oh
he's just shooting that.
Jeez, what's going
on, someone touched my hair!
- It's just a dream.
- calm down,
you scared the life out
of me, what's wrong?
No, I know the difference!
- No one was there!
- It wasn't a dream!
There's nobody here,
nobody was behind you.
No.
- You're fine, I promise.
- It's all right, Julie.
I promise.
Oh jeez, where do I begin?
Well, I always loved
school, loved competing.
I was honored just to be
considered for team captain,
and student body pres,
oh, I'm Miss Congeniality.
Until victory is on the line,
then as Coach Emily says,
time for the
daggers to come out.
Earned a scholarship to
Key West from Minnesota.
Are you kidding
me, yay sunshine!
And now wow, we're the one's
making the Ivy League shake.
Go Raptors, whoo!
Man we just hit somethin'.
What happened?
- What is that?
- No, don't touch it!
My hand,...
Come on, let's get back
on the bus, you okay?
- What was that?
- Wow, oh, hold on, hey!
Let me take a look at this,
I'm pre-med, I'm pre-med.
You look like
about the kind of doctor
- I'd get!
- Take a seat, take a seat,
take a seat!
All right, I'm just gonna
clean out this cut, okay?
With just a little
bit of antiseptic.
Oh my god, you'll
be okay, all right.
Yeah, easy, easy,
it's okay, all right.
Hold that right
there, okay good.
Are you all right?
- He'll be fine he'll be fine.
- Oh my god.
- What's going on?
- Don't worry.
Oh my god,
that looks really bad.
Oh god, okay, what happened,
- what happened?
- Just stop the bleeding,
- will ya?
- All right, I will, I will.
Okay, all right now.
- What happened?
- Let me take this off.
Uh, somethin' got
him I don't know what it was.
All right, hold that right
there, I'm gonna bandage
- this up, okay?
- There's some nasty stuff
- on the front of the bus too.
- Yeah...
- What kind of stuff?
- Uh, eh, I don't know,
some type of slimy
ooze or something.
- Eww...
- It's like we hit something,
- uh like...
- Um, um gosh, hurry Devon!
We need some
Band-Aids, yeah...
- Oh do you?
- Oh yeah...
Oh I don't know
what I'm doing here!
- Stop yelling!
- I just can't stand this!
I'm Connor Wagner, I am
the track star of the school,
and the debate star.
At Key West we have three
sports, we have track,
track, and track.
So, naturally, I chose debate.
And track.
You know I guess debate's
sort of like a sport anyways,
I mean, we compete, we
work out, and we win meets,
you know, that's what we do.
That's why y'all are
here, 'cause we're about
to go to Nationals and
we're about to win.
That's all we do is win.
I mean me and AC we were
already talking about how
we were gonna take down
National's me and her.
So I mean, that's the whole
reason you're all here.
♪ Broke down in
this little town ♪
♪ I'm just trying
to make a name ♪
♪ To get myself up
off the ground ♪
♪ And since I was a little
boy I've been making noise ♪
♪ Hoping it would find a way
♪ To take me to the
places in my dreams ♪
♪ It's always been
a long dark road ♪
♪ That I've been wandering on
♪ I've never known
where it goes ♪
♪ But I kept moving on
♪ Don't want to want
to waste more time ♪
♪ Following dead end roads
♪ So I'll find a way
♪ I'll make my own
about
dinner, and a polar bear,
in the snow,
what does that signify?
- Come on!
- It's important to enforce
the good on the regency.
Excellent, let's try
some more, over on this side.
- Quick!
- The world's gonna go around
without polar bears,
- so what's the point?
- There's more than one
polar bear species,
not important.
- Okay...
- Yeah but...
Hey you guys, hang
on just a moment.
Hey guys.
Oh my god, coach!
The Heritage Park
Inn is 45 minutes away.
RR and R, Poppa John's Pizza!
Right on!
Hey we're here!
Um yeah, we'll take 'em.
Yeah we'll take 'em.
Hey, let me give you your key.
- Aw!
- He's a hotel cat,
we found him as a stray,
and then he just stayed.
Took care of him
from here on in.
Here we go.
I'm
the bathroom!
I call the toilet!
Really?
Oh , Shane.
Well, Shane, far
enough, far enough!
Privacy, privacy!
- Oh!
- Whoo!
Take it over
here to the table.
- Grab a piece off of it.
- Grab a piece.
Okay all together you
guys, come on, get in here!
One, two three, pita!
Pita!
♪ Take a look around you,
see what's going on ♪
♪ Some people see a
♪ Still wouldn't
get off the floor ♪
♪ You could be
bleeding to death ♪
♪ And they'd act
like nobody's home ♪
♪ Yeah
♪ yeah, you got
to give him some more ♪
♪ You got to give him,
you got to give him ♪
♪ Losing all the money on
this little ♪
♪ Oh and all
♪ Who the hell is
minding the store ♪
♪ I ain't got the answers,
but I know just what to do ♪
♪ Whenever it gets
me feeling blue ♪
♪ I feel the groove
♪ All you've got to do is just
♪ To lose yourself
to the blues ♪
♪ Aint' no day to excuse
yourself from the blues ♪
♪ Give yourself a notion,
to cause a big commotion ♪
♪ Put yourself in
motion at ♪
♪ To the blues
Attention, attention everyone!
Today is very special,
coaches Emily and Ron O'Neil
are celebrating their
36th wedding anniversary!
- Thank you.
- Thank you kids!
Now we all chipped in
and got you this gift
and deep, deep heart
felt, really gratitude,
- Aw...
- from everyone!
Thank you guys, you've
worked hard for it!
- Oh, thank you guys!
- Oh look at this!
- Ooh.
- Very nice.
- Very nice!
- It is nice.
- Can I see it?
- Nope.
- No you can.
- Thank you guys.
- That's awesome.
A good looking group that is.
It is a good looking
group, and smart and
- dedicated, and gonna
- And so fun to work with you
- at the end.
- be national champions.
We have found, Ron and
Emily's favorite song
- from their high school years.
- Oh...
- Oh!
- Whoo!
Hope the vinyl
wasn't!
Oh shush up!
Now we invite you two to
dance just like you did
during your senior prom,
- Hey.
- when you fell in love.
Come on!
You guys thank you
for the nice gift!
- All right!
- Yeah!
- That's good!
- Whoo!
You guys mean so much to us!
So, I know we've
worked hard and,
this has been a long,
long grueling road
but we're almost there.
It was a nice ,
the song and the nice
gift and everything,
it was so nice.
Now, I think it's
prudent for us to retire.
- Oh whoo...
- Long day ahead.
That's right, big
day tomorrow, hmm,
onto the championships!
Let's do it!
This looks
like you're having fun.
Baby, wake up.
You listening?
Not really, I'm sleeping.
I have something to tell you,
are you happy you married me?
Yeah, life's perfect.
- You're great.
- Well what if things
were more perfect?
Oh uh, perfect is perfect.
Yeah but what if there
was something more?
Uh, more of what?
Well, one plus
one equals three.
I'm having our baby.
Did you hear me?
I'm pregnant.
You're
having our baby?
Yeah I'm pregnant.
Hi my name's Josh Martin.
A little bit about
me, I grew up on the
west side of Los
Angles my entire life.
My father is an
investment banker,
and very successful.
A little bit of him
rubbed off on me I guess,
I'm pragmatic, centered
and serious I suppose.
The only impulsive thing
that I've ever done
in my entire life
was to marry Jaiden,
but they say that love is
blind but I went into it
with my eyes just,
just wide open,
which was the best
investment I ever made.
About our trip here, we
just can't wait to get,
to get this debate championship
off, to a good start.
Wow.
That's awesome, babe.
Aw that's awesome!
Congratulations you guys.
- Hey!
- Thank you!
Thanks man.
Oh, we're having
a baby.
Oh my goodness,
she's have a baby!
Well um, a little
bit about me,
my name is Jaiden Martin.
My father, he was a
diplomat to Brazil,
Japan and South Africa.
Um, I speak Japanese the best,
I absolutely love
it it's so fun!
Um, I got to travel a lot
before I came to Key West.
I wanted to join their
elite debate team.
The greatest thing
was meeting Josh.
I love him so much, it just
keeps getting better and better.
Wow, it's
been about a year,
and I never thought I would
meet someone like him.
And I'm must so
happy that I did.
Hey everybody!
Listen up, come close!
Come close!
- What's going on?
Uh, my dear wife,
has just told me,
the best news since the
creation of the universe!
What?
We're gonna have a baby!
[clapping
Congratulations!
- Thank you, thank you!
- That's awesome!
Thank you, thank you!
Nice man!
Thanks, I appreciate it!
Congratulations!
You all I take this as an omen
for a sure victory at Nationals!
- A toast,
- Right on, right on!
To Josh and Jaiden,
and their new baby!
- Get me out of here!
- Look I'm gonna protect
you, I'll protect
you, and our baby!
How are you gonna
protect me from them?
Oh, thank you guys!
- You guys are the best!
- You guys!
Thank you!
You stupid little idiot!
Hey,...
- Shut him...
- What's going on here?
Carlos is
giving me a heart attack!
Get out!
- Get the fuck out!
- Devon you too?
- Fuck off!
- I'm gonna call the cops!
Oh no the cops!
- here!
- Get out!
Hey, , Carlos!
Hey guys let's go,
get there on the bus quickly.
- Thank you sir.
- You're welcome.
I couldn't sleep at all.
Devon look, I
forgive you, but don't
ever let it happen
again, all right?
Scout's honor.
My name is Devon Rogers.
A little bit of
background on myself.
I grew up in the Windy City.
My father is a
biological engineer,
and my mother is
an endocrinologist.
Um, I was home schooled
most of my life,
and then I got into college
when I was 14 year old,
where now I'm a pre-med
major in my junior year.
So I'm 17 years old, I'm kind
of the baby of the group,
you know, some people kind
of like to kid with me,
I'm like the child
genius as they
call me sometimes, but,
you know, you know,
I just works out that way.
Um, yeah I can't really
take all the credit for
my ability, you know,
heredity did have
a good part to play in it.
Um, I'd definitely say
I'm a good debater.
I'm probably the most
rational of the group,
I can definitely
articulate very well.
Uh, when I do debate,
I like to conclude,
I really like to have
my facts straight,
I like to study, I really
like to have it ready,
'cause when I do go in
I want to be able to
go in for the kill.
I do love debating and
I really want us to,
you know get this win,
'cause it definitely
would look good on the, you
know the resume one day, so...
Damn, it's the alternator.
I just replaced that thing too.
The competition starts
tomorrow at 10 a.m.!
I know coach, I got, ,
parts store's looking,
hold on, hold on.
You know sometimes
parts for these old,
the engine's bus is
like Thelma, here,
could be a might
touch hard to find.
Yeah, yeah I'm here.
You got it?
W-Well good, well
get on out here!
Thanks darling, you
made me happier than
a tornado in a trailer park!
Okay, yep, bye!
All right, 60 minutes, tops.
All right.
Okay you guys we're
broken down, one more time,
let's do rapid fires,
one more time before
we get on the bus, okay?
Here's the last one
of the nine statements
that at the National
Competition, if you
don't know which one your
gonna get for your team.
Resolve, the US government
should enact regulation
to preserve the
climate and habitat of
all polar bears and
enact prohibitions
against human encroachment
into their domain.
Now start with the con,
- Oh!
- Josh!
In 2009, the PBSE
reports that of the
19 sub-population of polar bear,
eight were declining,
three were stable,
and one was actually increasing.
Can't say what's happening
to the remaining seven,
so the data on the 25,000,
- Wait, wait wait wait wait!
- or the 25,000 polar bears
- is inconclusive.
- Slow,.
- Ready coach.
- Ready go!
Okay, we know that
extent,
this forces these bears,
the only bears who don't
truly hibernate, to
seek more land bases,
and come into
contact with humans.
Food hunting, home
protecting mammals,
the only mammals with guns.
Okay, let's not go
to the guns right now.
Let's just stick with the
facts with the polar bears.
- Okay.
- Got that?
- Yes.
- Okay, team member
will pick up, the guns,
when her, her part,
- All right.
- at the second part, okay?
- Okay.
- Excellent, good guys,
- excellent.
- Hey how's it going?
Having a little problem here?
Yeah you might say.
I cut my hand.
Yeah, there's salt and...
What the hell?
That alternator was fried,
that shouldn't be running!
Carlos, you in there
messing up the cab?
- Watch them.
- That was dirty.
Let's get going DJ,
let's get going DJ.
You still want
- the part, or not?
- Time is of the essence!
Yeah, uh, just throw it in
the back for me.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Well round 'em up
coach, round 'em up!
Let's go folks, be
careful on the road!
Detective Martin.
Kim is en route
from the hospital.
We found out her sister
and family's motor home
was attacked and damaged.
Slime deposits were
found on the scene.
This occurred just
three miles west of
the Moccasin Gap Incident.
Kim's sister, brother-in-law
and one child,
are currently missing.
Another...
Another child, a five year old,
was found unconscious
about a mile from the site.
And she is currently in
Tallahassee General Hospital,
suffering a coma.
She may not make it.
- Hey.
How's your niece?
Touch and go.
Jack, What the hell
- is going on here?
- Get over here, come here.
Come here.
It's gonna be okay.
Hey look I have been
working most of the night.
Okay, come here,
let me show you.
I have found out some
more information on these
invisible creatures, I've
been calling them entities.
- Okay.
- All right now what
I've discovered, is that
there were a variety of events
that all occurred on the
morning of October 11th.
Now these events, every
one of them seemed to all
just center around the
debate bus location and,
and branch out into
multiple directions.
Now here, let me pull it up.
Uh, there, okay, on
this CNN news report,
a downed aircraft was
found about six miles
from the bus sighting,
you can clearly see
slime here on the
front of the plane.
The highway patrol also
found a destroyed home
not far away from this, with
slime deposits all over it.
Yeah, there's
definitely a pattern here.
There's obviously a
pattern, we just
need to find out what
that pattern is though.
Most definitely.
Detective Martin.
Yes, okay.
See you in a minute.
- What was that?
- Hmm guess.
- Hmph.
- The Sheriff.
- Uh-hmm.
- He wants to talk.
Yeah I
bet he wants to talk.
All right, fine, you know
what, we're just gonna
keep the camera rolling,
this should be interesting.
Get it on tape that
he's gonna come in here
and tell us we can't do
this anymore, you watch.
Exactly what we
thought this whole time.
They know it there's no
way the federal government's
gonna keep their
noses out of this,
oh, there he is.
All right.
- Sheriff.
- Jack.
- How are ya?
- Great how are you?
Good, good, good.
I am, I am very sorry
about your sister,
and your family.
If there's anything I can
help you with any way...
- I appreciate that.
- You're welcome.
How's the investigation coming?
Nothing concrete.
In all my years this
is the damndest thing.
You needn't be
concerned anymore.
You're off the case.
The state police and FBI...
Aw,
, the FBI?
- Of course.
- And we've been on top of
this from the start, Sheriff,
and we are making progress!
- Well...
- This has become
- so personal to me.
- Her niece is in
- the hospital!
- Calm down detective please,
calm down!
The reason to be
separated, you're too
personal, too involved!
Of course we're,
it's personal!
When told to back
off, we back off.
- I'm sorry.
- Fine!
Fine, fine fine.
Whatever you say, I'll
have everything on
your desk by tomorrow morning.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
Guys we win
some, we lose some.
And I'm very very sorry.
Yeah, you're sorry, yeah.
What the hell, tomorrow?
Just, wait,
look, listen to me,
listen to me okay,
we're not gonna let
him do this to us, okay?
Do not worry about it we
are gonna keep pushing,
I promise you that.
We just need to be
damn sure we keep
a backup of everything,
every one of those files!
Okay, all right.
- All right?
- We'll just keep going.
- Yes we will.
- All right.
Come on get on the
bus we gotta get going,
we're behind schedule!
All right.
- Thank you.
- It's about time.
Let's go,
let's go, let's go!
Nearest gas.
Wouldn't
it be ironic...
Shane come on
please, give it a rest.
Uh I'm
not just filming,
I'm immortalizing history here.
You have the Hindenburg,
first walk on the moon,
all those people are dead.
All we got left is
film it never dies.
But for you I'll, I'll
give it a rest this time.
Thanks.
Madison!
- You awake?
- Yeah.
Who can sleep in these,
whatever this is.
Yeah.
You feeling okay?
It's tough to control
blood sugar on trips,
but thanks for asking.
You and Julie are like,
well, you watch over me.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
No problem.
We should hang
out, when we go back.
We should, at a bar?
Um, I was thinking of
church group.
It's not really my thing but,
for you, for a good friend yeah.
Sounds like fun.
And uh, I'll keep
watching an eye on you,
with my little buddy
over there, so,
if you're feeling bad
I can check you out.
Oh good.
All right can I have
your guys attention?
We have 10 hours to showtime.
Come on let's try to
- get some sleep!
- 99.
- tired!
- Come on, get some sleep!
- Sh!
You're kidding me.
- Don't worry about it.
- Cell phone hasn't worked
for hours, is
anybody even through?
Make it, this time, on time.
Yeah, about three hours coach.
We're gonna take a
shortcut down Highway 51,
through Moccasin Gap.
- Okay.
- No worries Coach.
The rest of this trip gonna go
quicker than 5th Grade recess.
- You'll see.
- Oh...
Jack Scott, October 17th.
3:47 a.m..
The more I review the
video footage of the
bus incident the more it
is becoming very clear
to me that there is something
much deeper going on here.
I'm afraid the government
is gonna bury this thing.
I don't know how they're
involved, if it's alien,
paranormal, some
experiment gone wrong.
I just hope, and I
pray, the right people
see my findings and
continue this investigation
because we owe it to
every single one of those
people who lost their
lives, I owe it to Kim,
and to her family.
So don't stop, no
matter what you do,
do not stop until
this is solved.
We just hit...
- What did we hit?
- Everybody just stay down,
stay in the bus!
Coach come with me!
Looky here!
- Hey, what's under there?
- Kids, get, get back!
Get back, don't get too close,
you don't know
what's under there!
Might have hit a
deer or a bear!
- Maybe a polar bear.
- Could still be alive!
Yeah why don't
you go take a look?
- Get back on the bus!
- Hold on...
To me it looks like...
Now what are you doing?
- Come on!
- What's going on?
- What's that?
- What's going...
Oh, you found something!
- What is that?
- Oh!
- What the is that?
- That is the damnedest thing...
- Don't touch it,
you don't know what it is!
- What is that?
- It's nasty!
- It's under the bus.
- Get on the bus!
- Let's go!
- That looks nasty!
Hey guys, guys quiet!
Quiet, I heard something!
Quiet!
Sh!
Stop it, wait a
minute, it's not...
- What's going on man?
- Everyone on the bus!
On the bus, on the bus,
on the bus, everyone on the
bus now!
On the bus!
Something's
on the roof!
Get in the bus!
On the bus, on the bus!
Get on the bus now!
Shut the windows!
- Shut the windows!
- What's out there?
Can't see anything.
- Anyone see anything?
- You can't see anything...
Nobody leave
the bus until we
- know what's out there.
- what's this thing?
Wait, wait!
Listen, is that Diamond?
That is
Diamond, isn't it?
- Oh my.
- Ron, where's Emily?
- Oh my god!
- Oh my god...
Wait, Emily...
Where's Coach Emily?
- Where is she?
- Emily!
- We need to open this door!
I'll go find her!
- Close that!
- DJ!
- Close the door behind me!
- Nobody open a window!
Don't open the window!
Oh my.
Anybody see him?
You, get away
from the window man!
Ow.
I can't see a thing.
Give me that flashlight,
give me that flashlight!
- Calm down!
- Where'd he go?
- See him?
- I don't see anything!
- Where did he go?
- It's too dark!
- What's going on man?
- It's pitch black!
Anyone see anything?
It stopped, it stopped.
Shut the window!
I see DJ, and he's being,
he's being dragged
into the woods!
Carlos, shut up
this is no time for jokes!
But honest!
- You heard her!
- Hello?
Hello, hello?
Can anyone, can
anyone hear me, hello?
Yes, this is
Ron O'Neil, come in!
- My ,
- Sh!
- Stop it!
- something is trying
to break into our motor home.
Martin,
they're breaking
the windows!
Please send
some help, but, the police!
We're at mile marker
36, on Highway...
Kids get under the table,
hide!
Oh...
It stopped, it stopped.
- I'm going out!
- No, no, no!
- No, no!
- Stop!
shut the door!
Shut the door!
What the hell?
The trees are moving!
- The trees are moving!
- What the hell's going on?
- Oh my god...
does
anybody see anything?
I think I saw
something out there!
- Gotta see, gotta see.
- Oh man,.
Really no I gotta
see, we gotta see this!
What the is that?
What, what is on the
side of the bu...
Oh my god, what...
- What's going on?
- Shane!
- Get the window,
- shut the window down!
- Shut the window man!
Close it!
- You all right?
- What's out there?
- Are you okay?
- Sorry...
What were
you thinking man?
All right so, his
pulse is pretty high.
Are you feeling all
right, are you okay?
- I think I'll be okay.
- Are you sure?
- I think so.
- What was it like,
- I mean...
- I don't know, it just,
it was like it just
grabbed my camera and,
there's something on
the side of the bus.
Keep your breathing normal,
- Sorry.
- Keep breathing in and out,
in through your nose,
out through your mouth,
out through your mouth.
Everything's gonna be
all right buddy, okay...
Oh my god it's
Coach, it's Coach!
- It's Coach!
- Coach!
- Come on man!
- Get him up here!
- Come on!
Oh my god, Coach!
- Coach!
- Oh, god!
Oh my...
- Oh my...
- Oh my god!
Coach
are you okay man?
Back up, ,
back up please, come on!
Hey Shane be sure to
apply pressure to that
wound, I'm gonna give
you a gauze pad okay?
- All right.
- Coach!
Oh my...
- Emily...
- Stay with us!
- Coach!
- Emily...
Oh my god what
am I doing here?
Stop yelling!
I can't take this!
Those things out
there, they want us,
they want us!
- Not now man!
- What are we supposed to...
No!
What are we supposed to do?
What the hell is going man!
No, no, no, that door!
What the do
you think you're doing?
Look I
heard DJ say there's
a place right there
called Moccasin Gap.
It's maybe three
or four miles away.
I can do that in less than 30.
- We need help.
- You're insane!
Everyone that's left
this bus is dead!
- Shut up AC!
- Look, we don't know
- if anyone's...
- Yeah well they're
not out there having
a picnic are they?
Yeah I hate
this macho bull!
- You're not going anywhere!
- Let's just wait!
Someone will come by soon!
They must patrol these roads!
Hey, I'm not
having a debate with you all,
all right?
I'll be back in
less than an hour!
Don't do it man!
Hey, this is my
call all right?
Devon no!
- Fuck man!
- Oh man!
You don't know what's
out there!
- Don't go!
- It's not that serious!
- You saw what happened!
- Let's just wait!
- Don't do it man!
- Please!
- I'll be right back.
- Please, dammit!
What the
is that?
I don't anywhere.
- see!
- Where is he?
- I don't see anything.
- Did he just drop
the flashlight?
Hey.
- What happened?
- Where's the...
Didn't
you, is he down there?
Stop it!
Dammit!
Carlos, are you okay?
- Oh, okay?
- Yeah.
- Seriously okay?
- Carlos don't worry,
somebody will be here, okay?
Jaiden nothing's okay!
Somebody will
drive by and see us,
don't worry, okay?
- Enough of this.
- Baby where are you going?
Stop!
- All right.
- What are you doing?
Come on, DJ already tried
to start it.
I don't care.
Come on
baby start the bus!
Move, come on, move, move!
come on man, start it!
Start it!
It's running,
you had!
Come on!
- Come on!
- Come on man!
Fuck it!
Emily...
Emi, Emily...
Whoa Coach what are you doing?
- Emily...
- No that was ,
- Devon.
- He's disoriented.
- Hey Coach!
- Coach, you need to sit down.
- Oh my god, man!
- Go get him I!
Shane I'm
right behind you!
- Coach Ron!
- Stop!
- Coach!
Coach come out!
- Wait a minute I think I,
I think I heard a, Coach!
- Coach!
- Emily!
Oh Coach!
Over here!
Over here Shane!
Coach!
Coach, where are you?
Coach, where are you Coach?
Coach!
- Emily!
- Coach where are...
Coach!
Oh my gosh, they got him!
Oh,!
Get off of me!
Shane, Shane!
Shane!
Lets get the hell out of here!
- They got him!
- The
- shot the killer!
- No!
This
can't be happening.
This can't be happening!
Please Jesus, no,
- no!
- Sh, sh, sh, sh...
Just get me out of here!
- We're here!
- Not yet, no, no,
- this can't be happening!
- Sh!
I don't want to die!
Not yet ,
no god please,
don't let him take me no!
be fine!
It's not fine Julie no!
I don't want to die!
This can't be happening!
Not yet, not yet!
My god no no no,
- no no...
- Sh!
No, no God please no!
Shit...
Why don't we just get
out and push the bus?
- That's insane Josh!
- That's ridiculous.
- That's not even the point!
- Can I finish please?
- Carlos.
Look, those things have not
bothered anyone on the bus.
Anyone that's gone out
there, they've gotten hurt!
- Hmm...
- In their territory!
- He has a point.
- They're the encroachers,
- we're the polar bears!
- Wait wait, I, I ,
shut the hell up, please!
In combat it's rule one,
secure your perimeter,
protect your wagons, its basic!
This couldn't come from
Seriously?
Why don't you go say a
prayer, or something?
Carlos!
What the fuck you
I'm trying to help
each other out here
- are you serious?
- not now!
Fulci, you've been out
there, what do you think?
I really think that
we make our stand here,
we make this our Alamo.
- I agree.
- Wait a second guys
- are you serious?
- I'm not going out there.
We don't even know
what we're up against!
I mean, they could honestly
be animals, think about that.
Hold it, wait a minute,
listen to what he has to say!
Devon, go on.
Guys, the only thing I'm
trying to say, is what do
we know scientifically
what's real, okay?
AC, can they even be killed,
I mean do they need oxygen,
nutrition, substances to
survive they're nocturnal so,
what if it's dawn, what do
they go away, or what else...
Who care, who cares why
they're out there, who cares?
He's right, these things,
they're not demons from Hell
or voodoo spirits!
I say they're biological.
Maybe, that's not
necessarily true though.
But everything on
this planet that has
ever lived, dies.
Everything on this planet,
even that's another
assumption that we're trying...
- Wait wait wait wait...
- Basically you're saying
we have to discover
their weak point, right?
Exactly, so guys, what
do we know about them?
Think about it, just think
about it for a second!
For number one,
they're tangible.
When Carlos was under the
bus, he felt something.
Right, something
touched my hair!
this
area, this road, uh...
Hey hey Kapax, maybe we're
in the Twilight Zone!
- Oh...
- Shut up!
Hey hey!
- Guys guys guys!
- Hey!
- Ridiculous!
- Even if he's right,
what are we gonna do
about it because we're
stuck on this bus!
- We have to a plan!
- There's nothing we can do!
- ridiculous!
- I'm not going anywhere!
We have to stay here.
I mean look what
happened to Connor.
- It killed two of us.
- Does anyone have a plan?
- Stay on the bus!
- Get off the bus!
We...
If we don't get off this bus
- we're all gonna die!
- Get off the bus!
- We have to Jaiden!
- Just be quiet and think!
- Thanks, calm down!
- Stay positive!
- Positive?
- So you want positive?
Positive okay!
So that's it, calm down!
Let's do!
Circle our wagons, ridiculous!
- Secure our...
- Yeah right.
- Stupid.
- Whatever.
Oh my god!
What is that?
Did you guys see this?
This is...
Man I can't believe
the damage it did here.
This is ,
this is crazy.
I'm
gonna shut the windows now.
Come
and look at this!
Do you see this right here?
Oh my god!
How many of these
things are there?
What the fuck!
Close the window!
Get it, close it!
- Oh my god!
- Those damn things
are strong!
- I know okay.
- You okay?
Come on.
You okay?
- That was too close.
- Yeah.
Are we keeping,
the window locked?
The window's
locked,.
You okay?
What if,
what if this is all a plot?
What?
What if they're working
through one of us?
Well DJ!
He brought them on
this piece of crap bus!
Maybe he was one of them!
DJ's gone,
why would they take him?
- Exactly!
- Yeah calm down!
I get it!
- Gail,!
- We're your friends!
Yeah calm down!
It's crazy,
we're your friends!
Well maybe they're
working through one of us!
- No of course not!
- Come on...
Maybe it's
working through you!
Come on
Gail, that's crazy!
- How about you!
- Turn off the
camera man!
It's all right!
- Gail calm down!
- I know how you feel!
How can we be sure?
Get back!
We need to
block these windows!
- They're all blocked?
- You all right?
- Everything's blocked.
- For now.
Gonna have to, stay
away from the windows!
That's it bro!
It's all dead!
- You okay?
- You gonna be okay man?
- I'm okay,...
- Are you sure, you sure?
- Look...
- You're all right?
- Look, ew!
- Devon was right!
He killed it man,
that's it!
- What is that?
- Yes!
Listen, listen, we need
to find anything we
can use to kill these
things!
Let's go, let's go,
let's find something!
Watch out
the windows doll.
Carlos!
Carlos don't move!
It's, what it's not a weapon!
It's dangerous!
- I found it!
- It's!
What the...
Whoa easy guys!
- Easy, calm down!
- Calm down, take it easy!
AC!
These things
keep trying to confuse us.
Yeah well they're
doing a great job!
- Just stay focused.
- Look guys, I really
don't think these things
are that smart I mean,
they keep on making new entrances
and they already have 'em!
- Right, yeah.
- Wish I could see these
- things!
- And they're so quiet,
when they want to be!
Oh my god!
Oh god I hit
Devon, I'm so sorry!
- Okay,...
- Oh jeez I'm sorry...
- Okay, okay, hold on..
- Keep applying pressure.
- Sorry, sorry, sorry, okay...
- Oh, okay...
God dammit!
I think they're dead!
Or at least, it drove 'em off!
Or it couldn't handle
the fire extinguisher!
Mom...
Dad.
This is Julie, please
pick up, please!
On second thought...
Please pick up!
We're being attacked by...
By some, by something...
I just want to tell you,
I love you both, I
love you so much!
Hug Bobby for me.
Please pick up!
Did you get through?
Just a voice mail.
AC you awake?
Yeah.
What's worse?
The silence, or the noise?
Do you think they're gone?
They've been quiet
for so long now.
Not really.
They're a warrior like,
attack, retreat, regroup.
Attack, like they
have a mission.
So you don't think
they're done yet?
They don't
know how to quit.
I guess there's no hope.
Army 101, be a realist.
Know what can happen,
how to handle it.
Live in the moment.
What's that?
Listen!
It sounds like a panther.
Do you hear that?
No mercy.
The survival of the fittest.
You win or you go extinct.
Does anything
really matter anymore?
It's a long way from yesterday.
Tell me about it.
Babe, hey!
Hey!
We won't, we won't, we won't,
just calm down, please!
gotta get me
out of here,!
Give me a second, calm down!
- We're gonna be all right!
- Get me out of here!
Look I'm gonna protect you,
I'll protect you, and our baby!
Nothing can
protect me from them!
Just,
please, come on,
get away from the door,
- come on, sit down!
- Oh my god!
Oh my god, our baby!
I'm gonna
protect you, and the baby!
- Just...
- Oh god!
Just,...
Oh my goodness!
the extinguisher!
Don't lose our!
Get down!
Oh god!
It's not over.
- Is it?
- These, damn things
just keep coming and coming.
I just wish things
would have been different.
I mean, you guys are the only
real familia I've ever had.
You.
You in pain bro?
I'll manage.
Is there anything else I
can do for you, anything!
Well, about 1000 milligrams
of morphine would be nice.
- Oh...
- Or maybe a fifth of vodka.
Well I'll just
call in for delivery.
Yeah you do that.
It's gonna be okay.
I just, feel
like I can't save anyone.
What's gonna
happen to you, us?
I don't know,
maybe if someone...
It's so awful, so random!
I don't know.
Do you believe in well,
in God or anything?
I, I do believe that
there's something out there,
I just don't know what it is.
I mean I think
about it a lot, I do.
What's it all mean?
Is it fair, or
just, just random?
And what comes next?
Does anything make sense?
Right now nothing makes sense.
- Medikit!
- Madison, something's wrong
- with Madison!
- Oh god Madison!
It's Madison,
she's crashing!
Medikit!
- Well what color is it?
- It's black!
- We're gonna be okay.
- Oh my god!
We're gonna be okay.
- Julie I think I got it!
- Come on,.
Calm down...
Hurry!
I got it!
No!
Madison!
- Madison!
- Madison please...
- Where are you?
- Shane, come back!
- Madison!
- Come back!
- Shane!
- Come on, come on...
- Get back in here!
Madison!
None of
you care about me!
Carlos, we are your friends!
Take it easy Carlos,
we're not the enemy man!
You are not the enemy.
But you're not my
friends either!
All, always the alternate!
Do you guys see that?
None of you love me!
None of
you care about me!
Carlos, Carlos,
wait, it's okay, okay?
We're family, we love you.
Remember in state championship?
We wouldn't have won
without you, okay?
- Liar.
- We love you so much!
- Really?
- Debates wouldn't be the same
without you, you're so funny,
you're the funniest we know!
Okay, just calm down,
it's gonna be okay.
Look, yes,
- Sit down, sit down.
- it's okay.
No, we're gonna make it,
- we're gonna live, okay?
- No...
Please...
Guys listen up.
I have a plan.
Not again.
Come on Devon,
whoever has the
gun is next to go!
Don't you get it?
I've been timing it all right?
I think we have a few
minuets in between attacks,
where we might be able to
get off this bus and live.
No.
No, please listen to me guys.
I'm gonna go out the front door.
I'm gonna shoot, I'm gonna yell,
and I'm gonna distract
them while you guys
go out the back door.
And then I'm gonna circle around
and meet you on the other side.
Does anybody else
have a better idea?
Please,
no more heroics!
So we should just
sit here, and wait?
Devon!
I'll take it with me, thanks.
Josh, Jaiden, good luck.
I hope you make it out
of this because your baby
definitely needs you guys.
We need good parents
in the world.
And one more thing,
it's now or never I guess.
I want you guys to know I
had you in the debate team
in the first place.
I know I'm a geek
and I know that
and I have those tendencies.
But I wanted to be with
someone so special, so...
Amazing.
It was because of you Julie.
Maybe some way, I
understand what love is.
And, I just want
you to know, I just,
wanted you to know.
Devon.
I, I never...
Devon don't do this.
Sorry.
Yes I have to before
I change my mind.
Gimme 15 seconds guys.
See you guys on the other side.
Let's get out of here!
Oh my god!
Josh, we gotta go buy
a stroller for the baby.
It's October 20th,
2011, 12:43 a.m..
I'm fearing for my safety.
These creatures seem
to be everywhere.
Jack is missing, he went
to the site yesterday
and hasn't been seen since.
I've collected all documentation,
including video file,
and I'm sending it to
Coral Reef Productions.
They'll know what to do with it.
I'm leaving the
Sheriff's Department.
If I stay I know I'll
get fired anyways.
I will continue to
investigate on my own,
for as long as I'm
alive.
I'll keep searching.
Maybe I can find some answers.
That's all I can say.
♪ This place is getting cold
♪ This place is getting lonely
♪ Time's ticking slowly
♪ Hear my heart beating
♪ The bliss of yesterday
♪ Fades into the shadows
♪ Will we ever be the same
♪ Hold me now don't let
♪ Me go
♪ Can
♪ You hear me
♪ Will you save me
♪ My fate is in your hands
♪ I'm losing
♪ Hope
♪ On the trails
♪ I hear the screams
♪ The moon shines its light
♪ I call out one more time
♪ I'm afraid
♪ For my life
♪ And afraid
♪ Of the night
♪ Can
♪ You hear me
♪ Will you save me
♪ My fate
♪ Is in your hands
♪ I'm losing
♪ Hope
♪ On the trails I
hear the screams ♪
♪ The moon shines its light
♪ I call out one more time
♪ I'm afraid
♪ For my life
♪ And afraid
♪ Of the night
♪ It's baby
♪ I want this moment to last
in the still of the night ♪
♪ Ain't anything
around us that's left ♪
♪ But it will be all
right long as you ♪
♪ Let me hold you tight,
with all my might ♪
♪ We are here for a
reason we might as well ♪
♪ Use our foresight
♪ And my aura light can
make any darkness bright ♪
♪ I know I had a divine
purpose all my life ♪
♪ Even if I lose I'm gonna
fight a purple heart fight ♪
♪ This is the true story
of the dark night ♪
♪ Dark night
♪ In the dark night
comes God's enemies ♪
♪ And entities that know only
hostility and negativity ♪
♪ But I got that energy to
overcome them spiritually ♪
♪ Let me and my spirit
be, doing synergy ♪
♪ Alabama dreaming 'cause
I must be in a dream ♪
♪ But believe it a night
like this is Ripley's ♪
♪ 24-7 is when my aura shines
♪ So when all hell breaks
loose it's metamorphing time ♪
♪ When things disorganize,
that's when I organize ♪
♪ Yeah I'm a leader,
so prize ♪
♪ I ain't saying I wanna die
♪ It's just I ain't
scared at all to die ♪
♪ I've got the
faith in this dark night ♪
strength in this dark night ♪
♪ Yeah one thing you learn is
patience in the hard life ♪
♪ Everything is much
so it's all right ♪
♪ It's all right
♪ I want this moment to last
in the still of the night ♪
♪ Everything around us has
left but it will be all right ♪
♪ Come here let me hold you
tight, with all my might ♪
♪ We are here for
a reason we might ♪
♪ As well use our foresight
♪ And my aura light can
make any darkness bright ♪
♪ I knew I had a divine
purpose all my life ♪
♪ Even if I lose I'll fight
a purple heart fight ♪
♪ This is the true story
♪ Of the dark night
♪ No one told us
life was fair, but ♪
♪ Faith can move mountains in
the still of this nightmare ♪
♪ Nightmare
♪ When you die it's
♪ Evolution it's not all black
♪ And even a debate team
couldn't argue that ♪
♪ The circle of life's
in need of a tire iron ♪
♪ I'm gonna protect you
no matter how tired I am ♪
♪ I may not be prepared
but I'm aware ♪
♪ And my
♪ We gonna need
someone to fight ♪
♪ And I
♪ And I go out like I'm
the only one here, yeah ♪
♪ These things gotta
pay, like bus fare ♪
♪ Man but you would
be unlikely to ♪
♪ Show us bus fare
on this dark night ♪
♪ I want this moment
to last in the still ♪
♪ Of the night
♪ Everything around us has
left but it will be all right ♪
♪ Come here, let
me hold you tight ♪
♪ With all my might
♪ We are here for a reason
♪ We might as well
use our foresight ♪
♪ And my aura light can
make any darkness bright ♪
♪ I knew I had a divine
purpose all my life ♪
♪ Even if I lose I'm gonna
fight a purple heart fight ♪
♪ This is the true story
of the dark night ♪
♪ Dark night, dark
night, dark night ♪
♪ It baby
Subtitles by explosiveskull