- Good morning.
What's the mother's name?
Erna Sveinsdottir.
- Hold on.
PARENTS
Are you having it like that?
- Isn't it cute?
No,
let's skip the candy.
It's nice as it is.
The guests will arrive soon.
Mom, are you trying to kill me?
This is really uncomfortable.
Baldur!
What are you saying child?
It's just for today.
Sit down and take a load off.
Grandma's going to
get you something special.
Listen Baldur,
I was thinking-
This is from grandma.
Wait, wait...
There you go.
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday dear Baldur.
Listen Baldur,
I...
I ordered mine from abroad,
but it hasn't arrived yet.
Is that okay?
- Sure.
Great...
I'll help you blow out
the candles later.
That's a lot of candles, huh?
- There are eleven candles!
- Don't touch
the icing Baldur!
Wait, not just yet.
I forgot the camera.
Katrin dear,
come take a picture.
- You should take the picture,
"The Family Photographer".
There you go dear.
Just push the 'on' button.
Push until the focus is clear,
then you push...
Push again, but you have to
wait for the focus.
How's is it going abroad?
- Just great.
It demands
a lot of my time.
Thank you.
It's great to see you guys.
- You too. You look great.
Thanks.
- How's Sweden these days?
- Same as always.
I've been there so long.
Katrin...
Yes, right.
What?
For me?
Hi?
- Katrin, Katrin..!
Johan?
- You fucking cunt!
I... I can explain-
- I stand here waiting for you.
Yes, sorry. I can explain.
It's my son's birthday.
- What the hell
is wrong with you!
I have to be here-
- You fucking cunt!
I'm sorry, so sorry.
- Fuck.
- I trusted you to return,
but you have betrayed me!
No, I haven't-
- You have betrayed me!
Understand?!
- I go to the airport
and you don't show up!
I'm sorry, I meant to call.
- You whore!
I...
There you are!
You have to say goodbye.
- I'm coming.
The guests are leaving.
Simmi and Pala are waiting
to say goodbye to you.
Come on then.
- Yes.
- Hear what I'm saying!
Johan,
can I call you back-
- You take the next plane
to Stockholm, understand?
I can't do that.
- You will come tomorrow.
- Understand! Tomorrow!
- I can't come tomorrow.
- This is the last time
I'll wait for you.
- Do you understand?
- The last time!
- Am I making myself clear?
- Yes... Yes, I understand.
- Say: I'll come tomorrow Johan.Say it!
- Say it!
- Johan... I'll come tomorrow.
- Breathe in...
And now we're flying.
- We're flying as a group.
- The young in the middle
and the strong keep point.
- Elvar, I need to use
the bathroom.
It's me.
- Oskar? I really need to go.
Use the one downstairs.
- Mom is in the shower.
This one's occupied.
Just, go outside or something.
- What's wrong with you?
Oskar, can you pick me up
after gymnastics?
When are you done?
- About five o'clock.
Sure, I'll be there.
Mom, can I get
a new swimsuit?
Swimsuit? Isn't the one
you have good enough?
No, it's ugly.
- Don't be silly. It looks great.
Mom?!
- Not now.
You can, when we go
to Italy next summer.
This one will do for now.
End of discussion.
Can you do a somersault?
Learnt that in gymnastics?
Yeah.
- Really?
You should have
seen her the other day.
I couldn't make it.
- That's okay.
They're happy with
the current terms.
Yes.
I told them
it was binding, so...
We need to get it
in writing.
No later than
tomorrow.
Hey. Twelve grand
on one hand.
On just one hand.
- Yes... Exactly.
Well...
Are you going to
show dad your drawing?
Want to put your jacket on?
- I'm so tired.
I think your dad
is on his way.
- It's on the top shelf.
Do you see it?
Bottom of the heap.
Nine- thirty...
You have to be there.
Gauti doesn't know anything.
I won't worry about it then.
Bye.
Do we need to go to grandma?
- Yeah, come on.
You're a bit late.
- Yes, couldn't make it sooner.
This happens a bit too often.
- What?
That you arrive late.
Yeah,
I was busy at work.
I should be busy too.
- Yes, but you work here, right?
Yes, but we're closed now.
I'm here on my spare time.
Okay.
It can't go on like this.
It's not an option for parents
to be repeatedly late.
Not an option?
Okay.
- Fine by me.
Hello!
Welcome.
I'll just pick her up
Monday morning.
First thing.
- Einar?
What's going on
with you?
I'm not-
- Halla called me.
And what?
- What are you thinking?
This isn't your problem.
She needs a little space,
A little time to
get her head straight.
Everything will be okay.
Don't get involved!
It's none of your business.
Seriously.
Can you take care of
the girl over the weekend?
Of course I can honey,
you know that.
That's what I need,
Okay?
People are waiting for me
at work. See you later.
All right dear.
- Bye.
Oskar Sveinn?
Do you have the...
Yeah...
Thanks.
- Sorry!
Dear Lord, that was clumsy.
No, it was my fault.
- I'm sorry.
Do you have something
to clean this up with?
Of course.
Excuse me.
I'm so terribly clumsy.
- I'll do it.
This is so embarrassing.
It's my entire fault.
It wasn't your fault.
I'll bring
a new one tomorrow.
That'll be no trouble.
Can I borrow that?
- Yeah.
Listen...
If you want to
get it over with today...
Then...
I'll take that.
You can have privacy,
in the bathroom there.
- That is, if you want
to finish this today?
Yes, I'll do it now.
Do you have a new container?
Certainly.
Good morning.
Morning, how do you do?
You're the new one?
Yes. Katrin Rose.
- I'm Oskar Sveinn.
I'm the other dentist.
- Right...
Orn told me you might
start today, I just forgot.
How's it going?
Getting into swing of things?
Yeah, it's going great.
- Good.
Listen, I feel like
I know you from somewhere?
Do you recognize me?
Are you a former patient?
- No...
Are you from Hunavatn County?
- No no.
Okay, sorry about that.
- Hi!
- Hi! You are early.
Is is Arnor?
- Yes.
- Hi.
- My, how you've grown!
- Take a seat for a minute.
I need to prepare.
Won't take a second.
- No problem.
Do they call you dad yet?
- They don't have to.
Sure.
I was just curious.
They're so grown now.
They meet their dad regularly,
don't they?
Of course.
- From time to time.
- No plans on having
one of your own?
Well,
who knows.
- Johan.
- Hi, hi.
Did I wake you?
Sorry, I didn't mean to.
- Who is this?
Sorry... What?
This is Katrin.
- What do you want?
I...
I need to tell you something.
I have decided...
I've decided
to stay in Iceland.
I think it's best that I
take care of my son and...
Johan?
- Think I'm just
waiting for you?
- I don't need you.
No?
- Stay in Iceland.
I can get any woman I want.
- Do you think you mean
so much to me?
No, I'm not saying that.
I just thought-
- Right.
- Just do
what you will.
Trunk's out!
Everyone's there, the principal,
his wife next to him.
Guy was expelled on the spot!
We had a guy that was always
hanging around our team.
We duped him into
being a sort of a "helper".
We made him do
"The Elephant"-
A Sidekick.
- Yeah, a Sidekick.
And as he was
pulling his thing out
someone had a camera
and took a picture of-
Isn't that you wife?
Yeah...
The guy was sort of...
His name was Orvar-
Aren't you going to talk to her?
- Yeah... In a moment.
Can you order me a coffee?
Sure. A double Espresso?
- Yes.
The grammar's hard so...
- I think you're doing great.
Thank you.
Hi.
- Hi.
How's everything?
- Good, I'm in a meeting Einar.
A meeting? For what?
- Work.
Hi.
- I'm John.
I'm Einar,
her husband.
Don't you need papers
if you are having a meeting?
Einar, this is a meeting.
- Why here?
Why not here?
- I'm always here for lunch.
Oh come on, Einar I-
Don't tell me you did
come here on purpose?
What's wrong with you?
- Just admit it!
You knew I'd be here
having lunch.
Einar, no!
Don't act this way.
What do you do?
- I direct...commercials.
You're not Icelandic?
- No, I'm from Ireland.
Ireland? OK.
Don't let me interrupt,
just continue.
I'm just checking up on you-
- I can see that you are-
You knew I'd come over, right?
- Of course not, I-
You knew
I'd be here!
Don't pretend
you didn't know.
Einar, would you stop this-
- What's this bullshit?!
This isn't a meeting.
Where did you find this guy?
Coffee?
Why don't you get Irish coffee?
Aren't you Irish?
Einar, don't!
- You knew I'd be here!
That's why you are here!
Why are you provoking me?
- Why don't we talk,
instead of this provocation?!
You knew I'd be here!
You could have called!
I wait by the phone
weeks on end.
Why can't you just call?!
Would you please stop!
- Why are you doing this?!
- Not so loudly!
Don't dare provoke me!
Do you hear?
One phone call!
Kids!
- Yes?
Don't play on the street.
- You can pass by us.
You should be
at the playground.
It's so boring there.
You shouldn't play here.
- Just drive past us.
Hello?
- Hi there.
The designer stopped by
to check out the bathroom.
He said the tiles would
be in on Monday.
Then we can get
the ball rolling.
- Great.
I decided on
the lighter color.
I trust you implicitly.
What's the occasion?
I thought we'd have some
Champagne. It's five o'clock.
What..?
I just got some test results.
- Is everything okay?
- Everything is terrific.
I've got...
great sperm.
Great.
Congratulations.
I have incredible virile
and vivacious semen.
Great.
- In no way sluggish.
And because of that
I wanted to celebrate.
I'm not drinking now.
- Why not?
I have to pick up Elvar.
And I have work tonight.
Oh?
That's too bad.
We're just too tense, Oskar.
And I'm too old.
I'm not tense.
And you're
not too old.
Are we trying to
have a baby together, or?
Yes, we are.
Wouldn't it be clever
if you'd have some tests done?
I already have Oskar.
I'm fine!
We're just getting too old.
- No we're not. We're young.
Okay, I'll go and have
another checkup, okay?
I'm going to pick Elvar up.
That's a foul, referee!
Are you asleep?
- Put on your glasses!
You were great, the best!
I'll wait by the car, dear.
I think it'd be best if
Baldur came to live with me.
It's time to
take that step, mom.
You and Baldur?
- Yes.
Don't you think
he's suffered enough?
Are you going to
uproot him now,
when there's finally
some balance in his life?
"Come home,
I miss you."
It's been four years
since your last checkup?
Yeah...
Maybe not four exactly-
Aren't you notified
every six months?
Yeah,
but they call...
Why don't you show up
when you get a call?
This look awful,
holes everywhere.
- You should floss.
- Yes...
You have to floss.
- I'm off then.
All right. Bye.
I've tried flossing, but...
Listen...
It hurts when I floss.
And it bleeds.
Should it bleed?
- Baldur?
Listen...
I was thinking...
If we'd move
into a new place together?
Just me and you?
Then you could...
You'd get
your own room...
And a new bed,
maybe?
No... Grandma
would be all alone.
I don't want that.
Can't we just
skip bowling?
I want to go play soccer
with my friends.
I asked, what you wanted to do,
and you said bowling?
I'm trying here.
Can't you just go
back to Sweden?
No...
Why are you
making this so difficult?
Don't you like
having me around?
You know I'm your mom.
I want to be your mom.
Why are you
acting this way?
- Wait,
don't go...
- You're not right
in the head!
- You fuck up every time
they visit you.
- Yes, damn it!
- You're just lucky I could
pick them up at the airport.
- And what about that woman,
was she with you?
- She's pregnant?
- Oh, really,
you always wanted more?
- Fucking bullshit,
you're lying through your teeth.
- It was you
and your family...
that convinced me
to get my tubes tied!
- And I was stupid enough
to listen to you fucking idiots!
Is there a problem?
No, just the same old story.
Addi and the kids...
He sent them home by plane...
All alone.
They're completely devastated,
and I'm really upset.
I think I'm going
to go for a swim.
- Get the hell out Oskar!
- Hi.
Hi.
Where's Baldur?
He's not here yet?
I thought he was
with you?
He was acting
a bit childish...
He should be home
soon enough.
What do you mean, childish?
Where is he?
We went to the docks
and he became a bit upset.
The docks?
- Yes.
You left him at the docks?
- No, I didn't. He ran away.
Dear Lord...
At the docks?!
He could fall
into the ocean.
He's not used to
being at the docks.
You're a completely
unfit mother!
I'm an unfit mother?!
- Yes, you-
Are you completely senseless?
Try to be a little helpful!
I didn't leave my son.
Do you think I'm insane?
What's wrong with you?
- What's wrong with me?
Yes, you leave your son
at the docks and...
I didn't leave him there!
Didn't you hear me?
Yes, he ran away
and then you come here-
Yes!
That means he's alone,
wandering-
I'm an unfit mother?
What about you?
Do you think you're
The Perfect Mom?
I'm considered a...
Maybe not perfect.
No one is perfect.
But I've been considered
a competent mom.
That's what you think?
God, how happy am I?
See how bloody well
you did with me?!
It's not my fault that
you're not happy now.
You were happy as a child,
got everything you asked for.
Baldur!
- Baldur, my dear Baldur!
How did you get here?
Did you take the bus?
You hitched a ride?
He hitched a ride!
I heard.
- You should never hitch a ride.
It's very dangerous!
- Aren't you cold?
Who gave you a lift?
- Some old lady.
- Some old lady? Thank God.
It was just
one weekend!
And you go
and throw a party?
Not a real party?
What was then?
Oh yes, yes it was.
You were dead drunk!
Elvar didn't sleep all night,
he was so scared.
Yes...yes...yes.
No...No!
Your son had
a bad asthma fit.
Hi.
- Hi.
Thanks for coming.
- No problem.
Are you okay?
I've tried listening
many times.
She's the one
who doesn't listen.
Wait a minute.
You know...
There's your side of things.
And then there's hers.
Which is just as important
as yours.
You have to tell your side.
And she has to tell hers.
And you
have to listen.
You can also,
you know...
Use your daughter
as leverage.
Especially now when
she's accusing you...
Of not being there
for the family.
You can try, while
she's thinking things over,
to get close
with your daughter.
Then she'll see
your nice side.
If you connect better
with your daughter... like...
You can take her to...
I don't know...
Maybe buy her...
A puppy or something...
To make a point of...
And that would mean,
you know...
Each time
she sees that puppy...
She'll think of you.
And she'd see
your new side.
Yeah.
- Get it?
Howdy.
Where's your car?
- The car?
I don't own one now.
This is the real stuff.
You bought this?
- Yup, isn't it great?
You're not driving
the kids on that?
On this? No.
- Phew, for a moment there-
No, no, that's too dangerous.
It's just for me.
A buddy of mine
is on his way.
He'll take the bike
and I get his car.
Shouldn't I just
give them a lift?
No, he's already
on his way.
He's probably lost
or something
Do you have
some cash on you?
I'm a bit short
at the moment.
Just to get me
over the weekend?
Just 'til I get paid?
It's always the same
with you, Addi?
I have my ups
and downs.
I wanted to do
something with the kids.
- according to Matti Vanhanen,
the Finnish Prime Minister.
- Finland will lead the ESB
from the 1st of July...
Finland..?
Finland!
See what daddy brought you!
Don't I get a kiss?
Look at him,
isn't he cute?
Hi.
- How are you?
Did you just bring a cat?
- Yes.
Have you completely lost it?
- What do you mean?
What are you thinking?
She's wanted a pet
for such a long time.
No, she hasn't.
- Yes, she has.
Yeah, he's cute!
Einar, what's wrong with you?
- What, come on.
Miniature hamster?
- Yes.
You're putting me on!
- No, I'm not!
You're not allergic to cats.
- Yes, I am!
Since when?
What's wrong with you
Einar?
Don't be this way.
Can't she play with it today?
I can pick it up
later tonight.
Allergic?
- Katrin?
I've got an awkward thing
I need to get over with.
I suddenly recalled where
we've met before, and...
I'm really sorry,
I didn't remember.
It's no problem.
Yes, it is.
To explain
why I couldn't remember...
Well...
I was so drunk.
Also, it's such
a long time ago.
About eleven years,
Right?
I'm not sure.
- Right.
Well, those parties
can get crazy.
It's why memories
get a bit messed up.
And Finland of course.
Finland...
Well anyway.
I apologize.
Bjarni is here.
I'm going to
grab an apple.
You get him ready.
I'll just be a minute.
Bjarni?
Come on in.
Just take a seat.
Can I put my jacket here?
- Yes.
Do you think he'll fix all
the holes now, or just one?
I have this presentation
later at work, you see.
It would be bad if
my whole mouth was numb.
If the tongue was...
It's an important presentation.
So it'd be best if
he'd do just one now.
I could come back
for the rest.
I won't feel a thing will I?
- No.
There'll be no pain?
...What's that?
It's just a cover to go
over the tooth. Open up.
Keep still...
There.
- What are you doing?!
There is blood everywhere?!
What happened?
- Did you cut my tongue?
My god!
This is like a slaughterhouse!
Are you spastic or something?
Let me take a look.
- What is this place?!
She cut off my tongue!
- No, of course not.
What happened?
- I'm so sorry.
Can I go?
- Did I upset you?
May I leave?
- Of course.
Are you okay?
- I'm so sorry.
Hello.
Katrin!
- Hi.
I had to come...
- Yes.
I've longed to see you.
- Yes, me too.
You look really good.
Why haven't you...
Why haven't you told
your mother about us?
I'll just leave
you two alone.
Thanks mom.
Johan,
you can't be here.
You can't come here!
- But I was so worried.
Yes, but you have to leave.
- What's this?
Johan,
you have to leave.
Please do that, for me.
I have to speak to my mom.
I was so worried...
Are you angry with me?
No, I'm not angry.
I promise...
Have I done wrong?
- No...No.
Sure?
- Yes, but you have to leave.
I brought you something.
- What?
No, Johan...
We can catch up later...
Johan?
Can we meet later tonight?
- See here, see.
Try it on.
- I don't want to!
Try it.
- But...
Do you like it?
- Yes.
Listen...
Can we talk later?
Shall I go?
- Please.
We'll talk tonight.
I can't right now.
Tonight.
I understand.
- Thank you.
I'm very grateful.
Hello?
What's wrong?
You're late.
Late?
You promised to
pick me up from school.
Dad?
Don't you know me?
It's me, Oskar.
Your son.
Yes...
Dad?
- Yes?
Should we go for a walk?
Get some fresh air.
Where are your shoes?
- Somewhere around.
I...
I just don't know
what to do...
Dad?
It was never this way
with you and mom, was it?
There are so
many things...
Our heavenly father's
gentle hand.
Shall lead us through
this troubled land.
He comforts those
whose hearts are sad.
Tormented souls.
Good or bad.
O father though
you do as you please
We pray you will
our troubles ease
and give our souls...
your heavenly peace.
Baldur!
Hi!
Where's grandma?
Grandma is a bit busy
so I'm here to pick you up.
Jump in.
Fun in school today?
What did you do?
This and that...
Why do you have
suitcases?
Are you leaving?
Well. I...
I've got a
surprise for you.
Do you like
amusement parks?
Yes?
But have you been to
the one in Copenhagen?
No.
I was thinking...
of inviting you.
Today...
to Copenhagen!
Just the two of us.
We'll have a great time
There are a lot of
cool rides.
Like the one, that-
- Can you stop the car?
Seriously, there's one
that goes straight down-
Stop the car!
- Let's talk about this.
Baldur?!
Baldur,
come back!
Sorry!
We don't have to...
We don't have to go!
Come back.
Please!
I'll drive you home.
What was that procedure
your ex made you have?
What do you mean?
When you were arguing
on the phone.
You said...
You had "your tubes tied"?
Is it true?
Oskar,
I...
You have to
understand...
I was young,
I didn't know...
Why the hell
didn't you tell me?!
I was afraid.
Afraid of what? Me?
- Oskar, listen to me!
Sure, I'm listening.
I was fearful
that...
Look-
- Oskar, listen to me!
I was afraid...
You'd leave me if you knew.
This is a huge breach of trust.
Do you understand?
You let me think
all this time...
that we can have
a child together.
I don't like this
at all!
Maybe they can
fix it?
Yes!
I'm certain of it.
Oskar...
Doctors today
can do miracles.
- Listen to me!
Doctors can...
- I can't ever have children!
They took away
my ovaries.
- Now you know.
- I'm sorry.
Listen honey...
We'll go out to dinner.
Everything will be fine.
Let's just relax...
Forget about-
- What's wrong with you?
- Aren't you even angry?
I've lied to you for years
and you're not even angry?
I never know where
I've got you!
I'm furious!
I want to smash everything.
I'm incredibly angry...
and disappointed!
But I'm going to
control myself.
I want to enjoy life,
with you...
We'll go out,
together
and everything
will be fine!
I'll see you later
honey.
Bye.
Hi.
How are you?
Oh, I'm fine.
Papers..?
What papers?
Without...
You know...
Without talking to me first?
I just thought...
I didn't realise
we were at that stage...
Signing some papers?
Well, you could've
called me.
The phone is always on.
Well, I&
I'm not coming home
to sign any divorce papers.
That's for damn sure!
I just don't
agree with you...
If you want to meet with me,
you can come over.
I'm staying at...
Hotel Iceland.
Yes, I am!
Yes, hang on...
Out, get out.
What?
No,
just someone asking...
I'm busy at the office
as usual.
Like I said...
If you want to meet
you can come over.
I'm still at work,
I have to finish up here.
I'll be at the hotel around ten.
Room number 203.
Can I offer you something?
- No, I'm good.
What's this
Cocos Parfait?
- Cocos Parfait?
It's a fromage.
- With dried fruits,
strawberries and blueberries.
And this, number 25?
- Vanilla and Chocolate souffle?
- It's a warm
chocolate mousse.
It's French.
What do you recommend?
- Cocos Parfait.
Is that good?
- Yes, very good.
I'll have one of those.
What about you Oskar?
What are you having?
What are you-
- Nothing, nothing for me.
Yes, coffee and Cognac!
- Any special brand?
Just, surprise me.
That would be great.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
I was thinking.
You know...
What we've been
talking about.
Know what?
These days, women can...
...get help.
You know.
Science has progressed
so much that...
We could get
a donor egg.
If we would get one...
I could fertilize it...
with my stuff.
Then you would carry it...
In your womb
for nine months.
And it would be ours.
Where would you get one?
At the supermarket?
No, not at the supermarket.
I don't know...
Sonja, for example,
your daughter.
- She could donate
an egg.
Genetically speaking...
She's your flesh and blood.
You can't be serious?!
She's sexually mature, right?
Isn't she?
She must be, you know,
girls mature much sooner.
- So then...
I'd be the baby's
mother and grandmother?
Yeah...
- Realise what you are saying?
Yes, sorry.
Forget I said it.
Sorry, I just...
It was just the first thing
that came to mind.
I'm sorry.
But...
One of your friends.
They could give you one?
This is crazy talk.
You're obsessed!
Alright, okay...
You just don't want
to have my baby, that's it-
Thanks...
Thanks for coming.
I couldn't talk at home.
You have to understand,
the situation is complicated.
My mother, she's so damn-
No, I don't want...
Thanks.
- You don't want one?
No, thanks.
It's like I said-
I've been
thinking things over.
And I understand
how you feel.
I can change.
I know I've made promises
but this time it's for real.
I'll change, I swear I will.
- Yes, but it doesn't-
I promise. Things will get
so much better.
No, it's-
- Much better.
Wait...
I love you.
Hi.
- Hi.
Come on in.
Come in.
I found a bottle
of red wine.
Do you want a glass?
- No thanks, I'm driving.
Well, what's up?
Have you been here
for two months Einar?
That sounds about right,
two months.
It's a pretty long time.
- It's no home.
You've got to get
some help, Einar.
Staying here
like some fool.
We're all worried
about you.
Maybe I'm worried
Maybe you need
to get some help?
No, please...
I admit
I have my faults.
But so do you.
.
I am...
These are the papers.
Einar, you need to sign them.
I'm thinking...
it would be best
if I'd decide this.
I... I don't think this is
something you really want
and that you're doing it
out of pure stubbornness.
Einar, you don't function
in a normal household.
That's just bullshit
and you know it.
Don't drag up this crap.
Not here, not to me.
Are you sure you don't want
a glass of wine? We can talk-
- No thanks.
It would be good if you
would give me a moment.
Just have a seat,
and a glass of wine.
I will set you straight
within thirty minutes.
Well, the papers
are on the table...
I'll have someone
fetch them for me.
Don't be this way.
Halla, please stop!
Please don't do this!
Don't leave me.
I'm hopeless
without you.
I understand you want a child.
All women do.
It's the mothers's instinct.
I don't want
you to be sad.
I really don't.
You're strong and look nice.
It's like you said, you can
get any woman you want.
You have money
and a fantastic apartment-
Blow me.
Can I get you anything?
- Sorry?
Can I bring you
something?
Sparkling water.
Blow me!
Or, should I
ask you mother to do it?
Piece of shit!
So, Mr.Shit...
Champagne?
I think it's time
you went to bed.
Why?
Let's talk a bit.
I'm off to bed.
- Erna!
Erna?
Talk to me.
We have to
communicate more.
I need to
tell you things...
From back in the days...
You're absolutely right!
- This is excellent
Champagne!
- I'll drink by myself,
then.
Here you go.
Enjoy.
Hello?
- Hello.
Do you have an appointment?
- No, just looking for my mom.
What's her name?
Katrin Rose.
She's your mom?
- Yes.
I haven't seen her
all day.
Oh...
Hey champ?
What's your name?
- Baldur.
When did you last see her?
- Last night.
Last night?
Were you up late?
No, I just woke up
when she was leaving.
You don't know
where she was going?
Maybe she went
on a short trip?
Well...
She had a suitcase.
Do you have an uncle or
an aunt in the countryside?
Yes.
Maybe she's visiting family?
Could that be the case?
Then she would have
told me.
Yes. It's weird.
Are you feeling sad?
- No. What's that?
It's a kind of a...
...Television.
Shall I show you?
Have a seat.
Do you go to a dentist?
- Yes.
Have you seen one of these?
Know what it is?
- No.
It's a...
Camera.
It takes x- rays.
And afterwards...
I see the pictures
up there.
Then I can show the patients
how their teeth look.
I could also
show them movies.
If I had any.
But I don't.
What school do you go to?
- Fellaschool.
And which school
did you go to in Sweden?
I didn't go to school
in Sweden.
Oh..?
Were you just slacking?
No?
Oh, you mean,
when mom went to Sweden?
I didn't go with her.
I stayed with grandma.
Is that so?
But what about your dad?
- I don't know.
I kind of don't know
anything about him.
So it goes sometimes.