PARKING
.:: P r i j e v o d i - O n l i n e ::.
Adrian, what happened ?
Nothing.
I didn't hear from you.
You said you'd call.
-Yeah, well.
I have something I can't get rid of.
I have some urgent business.
I've had enough of this place.
Any problems ?
No.
Well, one morning
I found the fence cut.
They probably wanted BMW wheels.
But it was fine.
Nobody better steal that Porsche.
I bet you were fast asleep.
Rafa, I didn't hear a thing.
It was at the far end.
And even...
Good, keep your eyes wide open.
I told you these Sector Sur guys
don't mess around.
See you tomorrow.
What's going on there ?
I'm calling the police.
You motherfucking thieves !
Look at that.
He's one of us.
You motherfucker.
What ? You're Romanian ?
Well, what the fuck are you ?
And where are you from ?
-Teleorman. You ?
Singeorz-Bai.
Alright, man.
-You're all Romanian ?
Yeah, man.
Come on, turn off the headlights.
What are you taking ?
-None of your business.
Don't come after these cars. Got it ?
Relax, man.
We don't want your cars.
Give the poor bastard a box
and let's go.
Here, man !
You're in luck.
We've all got to get by.
Close it up !
Come on !
What about the rats ?
They're everywhere.
What do you think the gun's for ?
How many do you think I can kill ?
They come from
the parcel warehouse next door.
We've plenty of rats and roaches.
With customers it's a different story.
But good times are coming.
I'll get you a bigger trailer,
you'll have a proper home.
It's not good being alone.
A man needs a woman.
I told you, I've got a woman.
In Romania.
It's so stifling back home.
And not just because of the heat.
What's up ?
I'm divorcing my wife.
It's a living hell with her.
I might lose Rafaelito.
How come ?
She's a real snake.
You know the type.
Leave her for another woman
and she makes your life hell.
You have no idea
what she's capable of.
A woman can make you
or break you.
That's what my dad used to say.
-He was right.
Come on, go.
Let's get some sleep.
It's three o'clock,
two in the Canary Islands.
Four in Romania.
What's up ?
Come and meet Mercedes.
I need a favour.
You have to take an Audi to Candás.
To Candás ?
And how will I get back ?
Come on...
Don't worry about that now.
Mercedes, this is Adrian.
Hi.
Hi. Rafa told me lots about you.
He says you're the best
security guard he had.
Yeah. Let's sit down.
Darling, do we have any wine ?
-Course.
I'll bring it.
-Where is it ?
I'll get it, sit down.
Eat.
Try some quince jam.
So how come you came to Spain ?
After 30 years
in the same hole in the wall,
you kinda need a change of scenery.
How long have you been here ?
Almost six months.
-Your Spanish is great.
Is it ?
-Yes !
Rafael said you didn't speak
a word of Spanish when you arrived.
I had a note that said
"looking for work".
All I knew was
how to wave and say "hola".
I learned all my Spanish
from Rafael and the radio.
He's hardly an ideal teacher.
Rafa, I mean.
No, he's great.
He always spoke to me
as if I'm Spanish.
Yeah. You can learn any language
if you've got somebody beside you.
Cheers.
Noroc.
What ?
-Noroc.
I understand you want to bring
your family here.
Is pretty much told.
You have a wife ?
Yeah.
What does your wife do ?
-She's a teacher.
I don't know what
she could do here.
You have kids ?
No.
Then it should not be so difficult.
How much it would cost
to bring her over ?
It's not just about money.
Time flies !
Darling, I'm almost done.
Yeah, let's go.
It's OK, I'll go alone,
the car's here.
Sure ? You don't mind ?
We can at least see you out.
Did you know Adrian and I
have the same birthday ?
Really ? What a pair !
Of course business is slow !
I'm crazy about you.
Just four more cars to sell and then
we get out of here. A year off.
You've become such a poet !
I get it from him.
I asked why he came to Spain
and guess what he said ?
That he wanted to read
some writer in the original.
Roberto Bolaño.
-Roberto Bolaño.
Have you ever heard such a thing ?
Bye, Adrian.
See you soon.
Take care.
-Yeah.
That's it. Two. Two.
With your index finger.
And the fingernail.
I told you wouldn't get
it straight off.
Yeah, what is it ?
Stop a second.
Yeah, I can talk.
Don't worry, Carlos.
The car will be in Candás in two days.
Adrian will bring it.
I trust him with my life.
Hey !
-Hey !
What floor ?
Hey !
Did you want to ask me something ?
I think I've seen you somewhere.
You did. It's true.
4 hours ago.
Where are you from ?
I'm Romanian.
But I live in Cordoba.
I see.
You ?
-I'm not from here either.
Do you have anything to do
with that band ?
Nunatak ?
Or something...
I saw they've got a concert here.
You've heard of us ?
Hardly anyone has.
I've got one of your CDs.
Really ? And ?
And I like it.
-You have good taste.
Can I have an autográf ?
-What did you say ?
An autograph ?
Sure I'll give you an autograph.
Your name ?
For Adrian.
Adrian.
Thanks. -You're welcome.
-Can I sit with you ? -Yeah.
It's... it's nice here.
The ritual and everything.
In Romania you do the same on
the night of Saint John ? -Yes.
But we call it the "Night of Sânziene".
Night of... ?
"Sân-zi-e-ne."
-Sâzâne... What ?
Impossible to say. How can you
understand words like that ?
It's not like Dutch.
Like they say: Dutch isn't a language,
it's a throat disease.
And what happens on that night ?
They say the gates of heaven open.
The other world comes
into contact with ours.
And the "Sin-zi-enele"
or whatchama call it ?
The Sânzienele are...
Say it in your language.
I'll get it eventually.
What did you understand ?
-Did you smoke something ?
Why did you come to Spain ?
For a change.
To learn Spanish.
I didn't have a clear goal.
No direct road to follow.
But what's your job ?
What can you do ?
Pick grapes, olives...
Change tires...
-Olives...
And ?
When it comes to me, I write.
Well, then ! Some kind of loser...
You act as if I've got
some terminal disease.
It's not that bad.
If I were a mountaineer, or a gymnast,
or a miner, it'd be no better.
What do you write about ?
I had to choose between
a story about smokers
And another one about suicides.
And ?
-I chose the suicides.
I did research. In the end,
I felt a real connection with them.
I knew it from start there is was
something wrong with you.
Thanks for making it clear.
I've got to get ready for the concert.
Bye ! Keep writing !
Thank you, Candás !
You're wonderful !
Enjoy the night of Saint John !
And now, the last song of the night !
Thank you !
Hey !
And your boyfriend ?
How are the suicides ?
What's the best method ?
Hard to say.
You can jump from high up,
but it's a gamble. You might survive.
You can jump in the Guadalquivir, but
have to fill your pockets with stones.
You can shoot yourself but
you might miss.
Hanging works best with steel cable,
it's safe, it doesn't break.
If it's about slashing your wrists,
you really need to know how to do it.
I wouldn't suggest it.
Pills are better.
-Pills ?
50 pills.
-Won't it work with less ?
No, you need 50 pills, dissolved
ten at a time in a glass of water.
But the best of all is throwing
yourself in front of a train.
Unless you care about
how you look afterwards.
There will be bits and pieces of you
spread over a 100 meter radius.
But at least it's certain.
What if I jumped into the sea ?
Not very heroic.
Want another idea ?
Would you jump in after me ?
No !
-No ?
I can't swim.
Run !
-What's up ?
Come on !
-You're crazy !
At least we'll have good luck all year.
You'll finish your book
and I'll be very famous.
What ?
Didn't we jump into the sea
after midnight ?
You'll see...
I'll dedicating it to you.
Dedicate !
How come a big man
like you can't swim ?
I swear I don't know.
I grew up in the mountains.
I first saw the sea when I was 14.
I just liked splashing around.
What if a big wave swept me away ?
I'd vanish.
But I'd have been
the main character in your book.
No ?
-No, no.
If you vanished,
there'd be a huge fuss the next day.
The police, the TV.
Headlines with
"Singer vanishes. Romanian guilty."
"Famous singer."
He probably raped her first.
-Raped ?
We're guilty until proven innocent.
That's how we're seen.
You love playing the victim !
You're not the only one who suffers.
I could write a book.
You're married ?
No.
Let's go somewhere warm.
Thanks !
See the woman at the bar ?
What about her ?
I saw someone dressed
just the same at the concert.
Perhaps it's the fashion round here.
I think women who dress like that
are crazy about making love.
Good in bed, so to speak.
And the others ?
One more cigarette ?
One more, then I'll go, it's late.
There's something else
about Sanziene.
What ?
If you roll naked
in the morning dew as the sun rises,
you'll be beautiful and loved all year.
Right now I wouldn't roll in the dew
not even for a million euros.
I have to go.
Hello.
Morning.
You slept well ?
Like a baby.
Truth is that I've a strange
relationship with hotels.
Meaning ?
I stayed 10 months in a hotel room.
My dad was a security guard there.
What did you do all day ?
Write.
That's where I got the idea
to write about the dead.
How do you mean ?
It was full of pensioners,
there for treatment.
So it wasn't a hotel.
More like a spa center, right ?
Something like that.
I'm going.
I've a concert.
I'd like to see you again.
Think we could get a coffee together ?
I can't. I have to go.
Hey !
-Hey !
"Happy birthday ! Wish I was with
you..." Cristina.
Adrian...
Happy birthday !
You shouldn't have. Thanks.
You're welcome.
Open it. It won't explode !
T-shirts.
You like them ?
I'm totally predictable, right ?
You caught me unprepared.
Wait a minute.
It's a mess here.
Shall we go to the living room ?
Let's.
Rafa said you spend all day
in the trailer, writing.
I'm curious, what do you write about ?
Does it matter ?
I mean there is nothing
to blow you away.
It's nothing spectacular.
Don't be so modest.
You, writers, always
see the world differently.
Look around.
I swear you could write pages about
this trash and turn it into a story.
You could really imagine it as
a sort of magical place.
You mean, turning this place
from a cemetery into...
a place where the rats, dogs,
cats and locusts talk among themselves
and come up with the idea
of starting a war against people !
See ? I was right.
Cheers.
I swear I don't get
this attraction to writers.
Our lives are so dull !
We're boring.
No. My life is boring.
And you ? Who are you really ?
I mean, besides Rafael
and your relationship.
A locust !
A migrant one.
That can fly for 2.000 km
without stopping.
But you can also be greedy
and ravaging.
Oh, no, then I'm wrong !
In Romania we have this game,
"Truth or dare". You know it ?
We have it as well !
"Beso, verdad o atrevimiento".
Want to play ?
-Sure.
Me first.
If you could go back in time,
what would you change ?
I wouldn't work for 15 years
in the same place.
I wouldn't live in the city.
I'd build a house
with a garden and a vineyard.
I'd find someone to teach me to fight.
For love. For my folks.
Ah, and I'd get a tattoo.
What kind of tattoo ?
You only get one question.
My turn.
What would you change ?
You know, when you're an immigrant,
you get suspicious.
You think everyone's out
to exploit you,
because you work your ass off
for almost nothing.
You're frustrated and screwed up.
If people are whispering and laughing,
you're sure they're laughing at you.
Have you ever thought Rafa
or somebody else
was exploiting you here ?
It's not about this.
Adrian, Mercedes, come here !
What are you doing ?
I don't know what came over me.
All those sleepless nights alone.
I dreamed of writing a book,
but I've not written a word.
You know my biggest fear ?
Getting sick.
I don't want to die here.
And I don't want anyone
in my family to die.
I feel a jolt of fear every time
someone calls from Romania.
Is my father dead ? My mother ?
It drives me crazy.
You see ?
Why don't you leave ?
Why torture yourself ?
For the  300 Rafael gives you ?
You wouldn't understand.
You can't go back ?
Hello !
Is Rafael there ?
-No.
Can I come in ?
No. Sorry.
Nobody can come in at night.
Wasn't there a Porsche Cayenne
for sale ?
No.
It was sold.
Ah, so it sold.
Listen, jerk. That car was mine.
Tell Rafael I want my money.
I'll be here for it on Friday.
I've had enough of calling
and looking for him. Get it ?
It's none of my business.
But I'll tell him.
Don't act smart, you Romanian.
I'll take you down with him.
Tell him Carlos is coming
for his money on Friday.
I miss you ! So much !
MARIA
I can't pay your whole salary.
You know the trouble we're in.
No matter who comes asking,
I'm not here.
"The number you have dialed
Is not available".
"Please leave a message".
Shoot, Rafa !
Rafa ?
It's not Rafa.
Maria ?
How are you ?
Fine... I miss you, too.
Where are you ?
Still on tour,
with the guys, in Salamanca.
It's endless...
I had a dream about you last night.
Really ?
What was it about ?
We were at a hotel in Asturias...
Again ?
And you had the room
next door and...
Oh, no ! That's silly...
We were both on a rusty ship,
making love, while some guys
were taking the ship apart
and selling it for scrap.
No way !
Yes. And we danced the bolero
as the ship went down.
"I don't want to die
without being with you."
Adrian, was Rafael here ?
No. I came last night
and didn't see him.
Is that Pilar ?
-Yeah, sleeping.
Rafael is crazy about her.
Yeah. When he's home.
Rafa, Rafa.
He vanishes into the night.
If only he'd say something.
If I call him, he doesn't answer or he
picks it up when he feels like it.
If I confront him,
he gets angry and we end up fighting.
It's not right.
I think he knows what he's doing.
I'm not making excuses,
but he's probably trying to sort out
something for the dealership.
I know he cares about you a lot.
I know.
But he's driving me crazy.
One minute, he wants
to move into a bigger house.
How could we afford it ?
The next, he wants to repair
the abandoned house in the country.
The other day, he said he wants to sell
everything and start farming lavender.
At least he wants to settle.
He's come to his senses.
It might all work out.
I'm tired, Adrian.
I love him but he involves us
in his impossible projects.
I'm scared. About tomorrow,
about the day after, about everything.
You see, that's why
I'm scared to go back.
I don't know
how I'd manage day to day.
I live for the moment.
It's easier for you.
I have a mother and grandmother
to take care of.
Plus a child. Two, in fact.
My grandmother started
mistaking me for my mother,
she's no idea who I am.
Want a beer ?
Yeah.
Besides that ? How are you ?
You seem well.
Yeah. Kind of.
Like Rafa says: I have
everything I need, besides money.
I started writing again.
Really ? Read me something.
Oh, no !
I'd rather sweep the grounds.
I don't like reading out loud.
Then I'll read.
But it's in Romanian.
Let me read it.
Then we'll see what I understand.
I translated some of them into Spanish.
As best I could.
Immigrating song ?
Look at me here,
in Córdoba of the three cultures,
all of them dying.
Me, a former runaway
dreaming of the Mediterranean,
its beaches with
the flattest stomachs in Europe.
"Mowgli, Mowgli,
what's up, you bird-brain ?"
"What are you looking for in Spain ?"
Salmon ! Salmon ! Salmon !
I dreamed of a barbeque
the size of a truck,
full of sizzling salmon,
perfect like American actors.
I dreamed of a girl
with salmon-colored labia
and I was so hungry.
But she taught me Spanish,
which was like
a plume of smoke over rusty cars.
Spanish of the immigrants,
of the romantic dogs,
of the night guards, Spanish
of the countries with no salmon.
Mowgli, Mowgli, one day we'll run
high with this trailer,
your "Romania",
with its pressed-sawdust walls.
We'll say salmon ! salmon ! salmon !
and we'll shake hands
like chickens learning to fly.
So you wrote a poem
about Mowgli and salmon ?
Incredible.
Rafa...
Hello, my darling !
Where did you get to ?
Your phone died ?
I was on a mission.
Top secret !
I'm looking for a castle for my queen.
Didn't you dream of a prince
when you were young ?
Here I am, prince of Asturias !
Well, Andalucía.
Come down, you're drunk.
And you ?
What's new ? You're strutting like
a rooster. Fuck anything in Candás ?
What kind of jokes are these ?
But look who's here.
It's Pilar !
I don't want to !
Let her sleep.
Want to go horse riding ?
You'll love it !
Rafa, calm down. You're not
going anywhere. You woke her up.
I'll wait for you at home.
What's her name ?
Who ?
-Mother Teresa !
Her name's Maria.
Is it really so obvious ?
You can see it a mile away.
And that means it's serious.
No more peace and quiet.
And you ? How are things ?
Shitty.
I spent all my money
just when I need it most.
Can I help ?
I've got some money.
Tomorrow night I need to pay a loan
for this place. I'm  1.200 short.
Wow. I don't have
that kind of money.
I thought you might need
two or three hundred.
And you call that money ?
When do you need it by ?
-Now.
Friday I get the cash from the Porsche.
Ah, right.
Carlos was looking for you.
He came here and asked
about the Porsche.
He seemed angry.
He'll be here Friday for the money.
Don't worry about, he's a clown.
I'll deal with him.
Rafa ?
-What is it ?
Do you think you could
give me a few days' holiday ?
Are you crazy ? Holiday ?
Did you smoke all that weed ?
What's got into you ?
I want to see Maria.
Why didn't you say, so ?
How many days ?
One week.
It's a lot.
Let me see what I can do.
Wait. Don't go.
There's something else.
I need a car and a full tank of gas.
A car from here ?
That's your responsibility.
You know they're not insured.
OK...
Thanks !
"I hear the Sanzienele have come back
and will be in Salamanca this evening."
"You ready ?"
"Of course ! I can't wait
to dance naked in the wet grass."
You know I've not made love
in months.
It shows.
What do you mean, it shows ?
What ?
Are there no women in Córdoba ?
Sure. I'm surrounded
just by women there.
Yeah ?
Kia.
Toyota,
Lancia.
Can I come in ?
Let me in !
Don't worry, I won't make a fuss.
I came to have a drink with you.
We're colleagues.
Not drinking ? Fine.
Still, let's smoke together.
Here.
You don't smoke ?
Whatever.
Read me a poem, then.
A love poem.
You came in the middle
of the night just to hear a poem ?
I'm honored.
One of those
you read to my wife.
She said you're romantic.
What do you want ?
What were you thinking ?
That you'd give her a good fuck
and she'd stay with you ?
You'd get married
and have your papers in order ?
Or you hope you'd make
a fortune with her ?
Only thing I want is
you to leave her alone.
You're so naive !
She'll milk you dry
and throw you away like a rag.
So you're just concerned about me ?
Don't act so cocky,
there's no need.
You really want to know
where she came from ?
The shit-hole I dragged her from ?
You're not the first or the last
to fall madly in love with her.
Life's not all love
and poetry, you Romanian !
There are other things.
We're not all priests,
singing and fucking all day.
Great. Anything else ?
-Yeah.
Look at my fist.
I could hammer your face
like a rock.
It doesn't matter how big you are.
You have no idea who Maria is.
This'll end badly, you Romanian !
Hello !
Where are you ?
I want to tell you something.
-A secret ?
Let me guess.
You'd like to move in together...
Not a bad idea.
I can offer you a large duplex
with a view of the highway.
Tell me the truth.
So we'll live in a trailer, right ?
Why not ?
A Chilean poet
who emigrated to Spain
lived for more than a year
in a trailer.
And I don't think
he lived alone all that time.
So living in a trailer
is what poets do, right ?
I think I love you.
You think ?
I love you ! There you go.
Clear and unambiguous.
Why didn't you tell me before ?
Well, I was busy with other things.
Welcome to Romania !
I like this "Romania"
of yours very much.
High population density.
But I like it.
And this ?
John Wayne.
Want a drink ?
-Always.
The National Library, right ?
The ceiling's pretty low.
And who's that ?
Leonora Carrington ?
Looks crazy.
Look at those two
playing ping pong.
Who is she ?
A great artist, you know !
She never explained
her work in public.
She said that mystery
lies in the things unsaid.
Things beyond words.
This way.
Take care, we're getting close
to a very dangerous area.
Ready ?
One, two...
Surprise !
We can turn this place into
heaven on earth. I've a few ideas.
Such as ?
Well, for the time being...
we could fuck.
Fuck ?
Fuck in every car.
But there are two hundred cars here !
Exactly.
We need to start right now.
Adrian.
Hello !
Keep your distance,
I don't want to give you my cold.
I'm immune, don't worry.
How are you ?
I brought you something.
It was sent to our address.
I think it's from Romania.
I don't believe it !
They published my book.
What book ?
I gave some friends
some of my scribblings
and look what happened...
You mean... Mowgli,
the salmon and all that ?
Incredible ! They never told me.
Your first book, right ?
I'm so pleased ! Congratulations !
What's the title ?
It's called
"Above man, the woman soars".
How do you mean ?
I dreamed one night
that I was in an aerodrome,
holding a burning book to my chest.
And a woman flew over me.
Really fast.
Like a locust.
Want to celebrate ?
-Yes.
Noroc !
-Noroc !
Strong stuff from Transilvania, no ?
What's up with you ?
You're driving me crazy
with your calls, firing off threats.
You threaten the guard,
call my ex-wife... What's up ?
My money. I don't want excuses.
I want my money.
I told you I'd give it you.
It's late, I know.
But did I ever not pay ?
Forget it. I'm not someone
you can make a fool of.
You don't have the money.
You spent it. Just say it.
It's not like that. Listen.
Next week, Wednesday,
you'll have it.
Just tell me you fucking spent it.
My share, Rafael.
You spent my share.
Let's do it like this.
Under certain conditions, I could
pretend I forget about my share.
Meaning I'll do you a favor.
But I need a favor in return.
A favor ?
Nothing much.
Just driving some cars
from here to there.
Can I help ?
-No.
It's better that way.
You didn't even notice
I brought you a present.
A present ?
What's this ?
A talisman. To protect you
from those who wish you evil.
Good thing it doesn't sing.
That's all I need.
Wait !
I want to send my mum
a photo of the fridge.
She'll calm down
and see I'm doing OK.
And how lucky you are
that you met me !
One, two...
Yes.
I have problems with this fucking
Carlos. I don't know what to do...
What happened ?
I told you I don't like this guy.
He's dangerous.
It's about a Mercedes with
some stuff... I need your help.
You're the only one I trust.
-I don't know what to say.
You have to do it.
Deliver it straight at the address
and split. No complications.
I told you I'm done.
No more shit like this.
It's not my business
you spent all the money.
Please ! I'll pay you well.
What's up ?
Nothing.
What is it ?
Who is that guy ?
No one.
So what does Rafael want now ?
He's in some trouble.
I don't like how Rafa treats you.
What can we do ?
We can't spend our whole lives here.
I'll work, I'll make money,
it'll be OK.
And until then ?
How do we live on what
Rafa gives you ? I don't have a job.
I don't know what we'll do.
Don't be a pessimist.
We'll find a solution.
Why don't we go to Romania ?
I could finally see
that Sangeorz of yours.
Think I wouldn't like to ?
You can show me the spa center,
the resort.
The meadow of the Sânziene.
Hey ! Hey !
Who's there ?
Catch him !
Quick !
Bastard ! Motherfucker !
Don't run ! Asshole !
You could have been so relaxed,
but, no, you were curious.
What did you think it was inside ?
An elephant ?
Rafa, this isn't funny at all.
They weren't kidding.
So, what do you want me to do ?
I told you to be careful.
I should've stayed away
and listened to Maria.
Well, well, now you we have
to ask Maria for all !
I want my money for the trip.
For this transport. Fuck it !
You know I'm a man of my word.
OK but when ?
I can't live on promises anymore.
I'll take care of it. Sell some stuff.
Sell what ?
There's nothing left to sell.
Trust me ! for God's sake.
Yeah, there on the left.
There's a stone.
We'll make paella there.
Who wants wine ?
-Me, please.
There's beer in the fridge.
How are things, Maria ? What are
you up to ? -Not much. But it's fine.
That's what happens if Adrian
keeps you locked away among the cars.
He thinks everyone's like him.
Always with their nose in a book.
It's not like that.
Last night we visited Córdoba.
What do you mean ?
I told you never to leave
the dealership at night.
We left for an hour, Rafa.
That's all.
Come on, Rafa, don't be ridiculous.
That place was left for nights
on end and nothing happened.
You could leave the gates open
and nobody would go in.
What could happen ? -Ok, leave it.
He's right. -Of course I'm right.
If you were paying him properly
you might have a point.
What did you say ?
If you were paying him properly
you might be right.
So this woman here thinks I'm
exploiting a poor immigrant ? -Maybe.
What's up ?
-Nothing.
But nobody else
would get out of bed
for the shitty  300 you pay him.
I'm not responsible for anyone's life.
If he doesn't like it, he can leave.
I'm not keeping him there, understand ?
Rafa, calm down.
-I am calm. It's her.
She suddenly stands up
for human rights
because her man doesn't give
her what she needs.
Let's calm down.
-Rafa, stop it, man.
We're calm.
Just one more thing.
Then we eat and have fun.
Loads of fun.
You want to ruin my day ?
Me ?
-Want to ruin everyone's day ?
Why would I want to ruin your day ?
You don't get that she's the one
ruining the day !
You get your first sniff
of pussy for months
and let her walk all over you.
If you care about Adrian,
come and live with him for good.
Who do you think you are, speaking
like that ? You think you know me ?
Must be nice to fuck a Romanian
and live off your husband, isn't it ?
Come and live with him, snob,
instead of giving me lectures.
Moron !
-Unionist ! Poser !
What the fuck !
What's got into you ?
Why are you like this ?
With me, with Maria ?
She's right. You should pay me.
-You'll get it in a week.
No. Not a week.
Today.
What the hell is going on ?
What's the thing with Adrian ?
He reads you a poem and then it's:
Adrian this, Adrian that.
"What a great guard you've got !"
He bent you over, too ?
Rafa, if you don't calm down,
I'll leave.
And I won't come back.
Come on kids, let's eat.
I don't know what's got into him.
Adrian, you know he's not like that.
Let's eat.
I'm a fool.
I'll pay you this evening
when we get back.
Adrian, I'm sorry.
It's a shame.
This paella is delicious.
It was made with love.
It's good.
Listen. Everything you can see here
has been mine for a week now.
I want to bring this place to life.
You started with a bang !
-I've already said I'm sorry, OK ?
I'll end things with the dealership
and renovate the house.
I'd like us all to move here.
With the kids, with everyone.
I'll sort out the washing machine
today. I'll go with Rafa to change it.
It's not about the washing machine.
It's everything. This isn't a life.
We're locked up
day and night in this shitty place.
So what do we do ?
We leave this dump.
Maybe you can live like this.
But I've had enough.
You want to leave now ?
-Yes !
Right now ?
We've still got cars to try out !
I'm serious.
Let's go to Madrid !
We can stay with a bandmate
until we find something.
Maybe I'll get a few concerts.
Don't think it's a good plan ?
No, it's great !
Hello.
I'm looking for Adrian.
What are you doing ?
I came to see you.
I brought you something.
A surprise for Christmas.
My mum didn't make zacusca,
but there's everything else.
Sausages and cabbage rolls.
And the fruit-cake turned out
really good. You have to try it.
Cristina !
And your dad sent plum brandy.
-Cristina, stop a minute !
What ?
How are you ?
Ok ? You settled in ?
I made room for you
if you want to move your things in.
Maria, let me explain.
-I don't want you to explain anything.
I just want to smash
your stupid Romanian face in.
She just appeared here,
what could I do ?
Ah, now I see.
He says it's your fault you came.
-What's she saying ?
You forgot to tell me you have a wife?
-I tried, but...
Who is this woman ?
-I'm speaking to him now ! OK ?
Once I'm done,
he can tell you what he wants,
but for now this is
between me and him.
Why didn't you tell me the truth ?
I was a fool.
That's a shitty excuse.
I don't give a damn !
Maria, forgive me.
There's nothing between me and her.
No, no ! You listen !
I left everything for you,
I left my life behind
just to come in this shitty dealership.
And what do I find here ?
Fuck you !
Maria, I want us to live together, but
let me solve this the way I know how.
I don't want you
to solve anything. Moron !
What is this ?
I carry cabbage rolls
across Europe for you.
I thought you were all alone, that
we'd celebrate the holidays together.
I came here because I love you, and you
tell me there's nothing between us ?
There hasn't been for a while.
Oh, yeah ?
Don't tell me
you were happy with me back there.
Yeah, I was.
What was missing ?
"The number you have dialed
is turned off or out of service."
"Please leave a message."
Please, come back.
I love you !
I'll keep it.
But you need
to give me an autograph here !
No.
I'll write you something...
right on your skin.
You wrote a poem ?
No. I'm not that cool.
It's by De Ory,
a poet who's from this area.
Read it to me.
They live the horizontal dance
And no longer wander at night
They are possessed by desire
and say nothing
They don't write letters anymore
They leave, run and fly
Together, always together
Leave it, you're suffocating her.
Come on, we've got things to do.
I need to ask you something.
I need you to take this car right away.
I can't do it, I've got an appeal
in the case for Rafaelito's custody.
Where should I leave it ?
How do I get back ?
Come back by bus.
I've written it all down,
it's in the car. I drew you a map.
Rafa, I'm not sure I can.
I don't like it.
You think I like it ?
It's the last time
I'll ask you anything.
Then it's over.
With the cars and everything.
Hey, you looking for something ?
Hello !
Do you have the key
to the bathroom ?
Here.
Thanks.
Hey !
My God.
Oh God, I fucked it.
Oh, I fucked it.
Answer the phone, Rafa !
I'm fucked !
Answer the damn phone !
God. Motherfucker !
We need to leave, now !
Pack this !
I'll tell you later, Mercedes.
Can I help ?
-No !
Come in. Come in !
Adrian, what's going on ?
Stay here.
No ! Adrian !
Rafa, where are you ?
Get into the car.
Don't be scared.
Where's Rafa ?
To turn off the lights
and call the police.
Where's Maria ?
Rafael, where are you ?
Come out, you bastard.
Hey, stop !
It's me.
Rafa...
Look at me !
Here...
Come quickly...
Rafa !
Look at me !
PARKING