(upbeat techno music)
(pensive music)
- [Narrator] In America, one
road has fascinated travelers
from all over the world
for almost 100 years,
a unique and mythical road
that is part of the folklore
and even the great
American dream, Route 66.
In the land of opportunities, this road,
also known as US Highway
66, Will Rogers Highway,
or the main street of America,
originally stretched
over 3,800 kilometers,
connecting small towns and big cities.
The eight-state snake starts in Chicago
and runs through Illinois,
Missouri, Kansas,
Oklahoma, Texas, New Mexico, and Arizona,
before ending at Santa
Monica in California.
Since its establishment in 1926,
Route 66 has grown with America,
being a part of many obstacles
the country has gone through.
Poverty-stricken families
escaped their former homes
off to a better future on Route 66
during the Great Depression.
Later, Route 66 became a
military transport corridor
during the Second World War.
And during post-war years,
Americans prospered, bought more cars,
and went on vacation on Route 66.
But Route 66's fame ultimately
led to its downfall,
when in 1956, U.S.
President Dwight Eisenhower
supported the construction of a new system
of high-speed, limited-access,
four-lane divided highways,
today's interstates.
Route 66 remains an
American historical landmark
where traces of the past
lie all along the route.
The old cars, the diners,
the motels, the neon signs,
and all its memorabilia
of the 50s and 60s,
this highway museum not only
attracts nostalgic Americans,
but people from all over the world.
With most of the original
roads still functional,
let's take a road trip back in time
through America's most iconic highway
with Big Brown, a 1976 AMC
Matador Brougham station wagon.
(upbeat music)
The trip down memory lane starts
on the intersection of
South Michigan Avenue
and historic US 66 in downtown Chicago.
(upbeat music)
The first stop is at Lou Mitchells' diner,
a family business that's
been up and running
even before Route 66 was even created.
Since 1923, U.S. presidents,
mayors, governors,
senators, and athletes have been to Lou's
for top-quality food at affordable prices.
Sharon Wasberg, an employee at
Lou Mitchell's for 38 years,
tells us more about the
iconic diner and Mr. Mitchell.
- Mr. Mitchell and his
father built this place.
He came to work every morning.
He went in the market before he came here
and picked out the fruits and vegetables.
He used to stay here all day long.
At two o'clock in the afternoon,
he used to have his lunch.
He used to come at five in the morning,
at two in the afternoon, he had his lunch
and then he smoked his cigar.
He had a cigar everyday.
- [Narrator] The restaurant
has been welcoming commuters
from all over the world for a
good old American breakfast.
- Saturday was one of our busiest days,
and now it's still a Saturday
and Sunday, very busy days,
as you see a line out the door.
- [Narrator] Delicious
donut holes are handed out
to customers waiting in line.
- People come and they eat, and the leave,
because they know it's busy.
When Mr. Mitchell was
here, he used to say,
"Doesn't anyone ever go back to work?"
(upbeat music)
It's fun to work.
It's nice meeting people all the time.
We have lots of people
from different countries.
They come her to do the Route 66.
They used to come here
from different countries,
Germany, whatever, on their
motorcycles, and do the route.
There'd be like 25, 30 at the time,
but now they find out
it's stupid to come here,
rent their motorcycles,
and then do the trip.
We've had people from every country.
I had three this morning,
three different tables
that were doing it today.
- [Narrator] Little ways down Route 66
to Chicago suburb of Cicero,
Henry's drive-in offers the best
Chicago-style hotdog around,
which are best-known for
being a meal in itself.
This classic hotdog stand was
started in the 50s by Henry,
and has survived through the years,
unlike other hotdog
stands erected later on.
(upbeat strings music)
About 50 kilometers down the highway,
in the city of Joliet, you can get dessert
at the Rich & Creamy ice cream store.
The monument has been restored
to its original appearance
from the booming days of Route 66.
(upbeat strings music)
Jake and Elwood, the Blues Brothers,
dance on the roof of the store,
representing a part of history
where Broadway was at its peak popularity.
(upbeat music)
Across the street is Dick's Towing,
with the original building still standing,
surrounded by a series of classic cars,
including a tow truck perched on the roof.
Farther down in Wilmington
stands the Gemini Giant statue,
which has been the
Launching Pad restaurant's
main decoration since
1965, and is recognized
as one of Route 66's historical landmarks.
Unfortunately, the restaurant
has been closed since 2010.
(mellow percussion music)
Be mindful of the speed
limits in the area.
You might wind up in jail like Jake.
Nearby in Joliet
is the Will County Adult
Detention Facility.
You probably already
recognized the establishment
that was used to film this
classic film, The Blues Brothers,
where we saw Jake Blues
getting out of jail.
In Odell, Illinois, Standard
Oil gasoline station
has been there since 1932, and has kept
its original look with minor adjustments.
(upbeat percussion music)
For car enthusiasts, a
small break-in Pontiac
is a must to visit a recently opened
and entirely dedicated museum,
the Pontiac Oakland brand.
(upbeat music)
Strolling through the land of Lincoln,
you will see the tall Paul Bunyan statue,
one of several molded fiberglass
sculptures of its kind.
The first Paul Bunyan
character was holding an ax.
Then, using the same mold,
other characters were created.
At least three of them
are still in Illinois,
along Route 66.
This particular character was originally
at a hotdog restaurant in
Cicero, named Bunyan's.
In 2002, Bunyan's closed and
put the figure up for sale.
The city of Atlanta in Illinois
made a long-term loan
arrangement with the owners
to display the statue on Arch Street
as a symbol of Route 66.
(upbeat music)
Across the street from
the Paul Bunyan statue
is the iconic Palms Cafe.
Once closed down and
reopened 10 years ago,
this Route 66 staple is a must-go
for classic Route 66 fare.
- The Palms Brew Cafe
actually opened its doors
first, in August of 1934,
ran through the late 1960s,
and then it closed down.
This building was completely gutted,
and it essentially
disappeared, until 2008,
and that's when the Atlanta
Public Library decided
it was going to reopen the cafe,
make it operational again, and hopefully,
help use it to attract
visitors and tourists to town,
because they owned the building.
The building happened to be donated.
(upbeat music)
I, at the time, came off
with the idea and said,
"You know, if we really want to use this
"for the benefit of the
town, let's recreate the cafe
"and turn it into an operating entity."
So we did, it opened in, I
think it was April of 2009.
So we're almost 10 years in operation now.
And it's been wonderful.
Our goal is to provide
folks with a little taste,
literally, of what it used to be like
to stop in a small town along Route 66.
We have several really
interesting items on the menu
that they used to serve back in the day,
fried bologna sandwiches,
fried spam sandwiches,
homemade pie, and everything that is done
here at the cafe is homemade.
That's one of the things
that distinguishes it.
(upbeat music)
We really didn't know what it looked like
when it first opened in 1936,
until I happened to be out
mowing my yard one day,
it was one of those small
town kind of things.
A woman I didn't know
pulled up in a pickup truck
in front of my yard,
rolled down the window,
and she had known that we
were going to reopen the cafe.
She handed me this picture, and she goes,
"Here, I think you're going to want this."
(chuckles) So we had this
guide all of a sudden
as to what it looked like
when it first opened.
The reason she had the photo,
the women standing
behind the cash register
in the photo, is her grandmother.
(upbeat piano music)
If you really wanna walk in the door,
and all of sudden see, and
smell, and taste, and feel
what it used to be like
back in the 30s and 40s,
this is the place to come.
(upbeat music)
- [Narrator] Midway between
Springfield and Saint Louis
is the town of Litchfield,
tucked away in fields of corn,
soybeans, and wheat principal crops.
(upbeat music)
The Ariston cafe was founded by Pete Adam,
a Greek immigrant in
Carlinville, Illinois in 1924.
The cafe was originally
located on Route 4,
but the restaurant was
relocated in Litchfield in 1929,
and moved to its original
location in 1935 along Route 66.
- So working here at the Ariston Cafe,
I believe that it's a lot
more than just a restaurant.
It's a business that's been here
even before 66 has even been started,
and it's just been evolved,
just as 66 has evolved
throughout time, so have we.
I feel like when we have
travelers that come in,
it's our job to make sure
they have a great experience
as they come from different countries,
coming to America, bringing business,
keeping the small businesses alive.
It's amazing just how
many different places
people are from.
Just last week, I had people from Japan,
a couple from Italy on their honeymoon.
(mellow music)
- [Narrator] The town
came close to disappearing
back when the railroads
were under construction.
There was a debate upon which town
the railroad was going to pass through,
coming from Saint Louis,
Litchfield, or the town of Hardinsburg,
two miles southwest.
When it was decided that Litchfield
would have the railroads pass through,
the residents of Hardinsburg
had prepared for the worst,
and had their houses built on skids.
They hooked them up on oxen,
and dragged them to Litchfield.
(upbeat music)
As Big Brown passes through
Litchfield, another restaurant,
the Cozy Dog Drive In,
is a good place to stop
for a delicious hotdog on a
stick, an American classic.
(upbeat music)
In Mount Olive, the
Soulsby's Service Station
still stands since 1926,
with its house and canopy
gas station design,
a popular style in its time.
Unfortunately, it no
longer serves gasoline,
much like the other historic
gas stations along Route 66,
but it is a sight to see.
(upbeat music)
The last stop in the state of Illinois
is Country Classic Cars in Stanton.
What began as a hobby
for a mid-western farmer
grew into a collection
of over 630 classic cars.
- As the owners started in
probably around 20 years ago,
actually at his farm selling cars,
and he just kept growing,
and then he finally
had to buy some property somewhere else.
It got too big there at the farm,
so he found this property.
And it started with, I
think, 20 cars or so,
something like that, and just kept growing
(laughs) to what it is now today.
- [Narrator] Country
Classic Cars isn't just
a museum for car fanatics to visit.
You can buy them, from road-ready
classics to muscle cars.
You can find it at this
family-owned business.
(upbeat music)
But, the journey has its ups and downs.
- Last August, we had a fire here.
We're not sure what started it,
but we're thinking it was a car,
possibly electrical (mumbles).
And it started in the middle
of one of the buildings
and just spread out, you
know, it was in the evening.
We actually had 13 fire departments here
from different areas, to get it out.
I mean, it was a total loss.
We lost 142 cars there.
And of course, the complete building,
so we had to rebuild the building.
And as you can see now,
we've got most of the cars
replaced with different cars.
- [Narrator] The
collection of classic cars
has travelers from all over the world
coming to visit through their
road trip on the Mother Road.
- There's so many people
that drive by here,
turn around and come back and look at it.
And there's people from all
over the world, actually,
the planned trips, you
know, to do Route 66
from Chicago to Los Angeles.
This is usually one of
their stops on their trip.
In the summertime, it's
just people non-stop,
coming in here.
(upbeat music)
- [Narrator] The Mississippi River divides
the state of Illinois and
the state of Missouri.
Crossing the river, you'll take
the new Chain of Rocks Bridge.
This bridge has two versions.
The older version was used
for Route 66 prior to 1970,
but now, it serves only for
pedestrians and cyclists,
as a historical landmark.
Once you've crossed the river,
the Gateway Arch welcomes travelers
to the city of Saint Louis.
Standing 630 feet tall,
it's the tallest arch in the world.
The design was thought up
by Finnish-American
architect Eero Saarenen.
The Gateway Arch was envisioned to revive
and stimulate the economy of Saint Louis.
Its construction was finalized in 1965,
and remains the tallest
man-made structure in America.
The memorial monument was
dedicated to the American people,
honoring the development
of the westward expansion
of the United States.
It is a must-see for
travelers on Route 66.
After seeing pre-boarding
exhibits featuring
60s-era animation and Gateway Arch trivia,
take a tram ride to the
top for a beautiful view
stretching up to 50 kilometers out.
(upbeat music)
In Saint Louis, Ted Drewes Frozen Custard
has become a popular treat amongst locals
and tourists traveling on Highway 66.
The store was built in 1941,
and has kept its original design
down to the serving cups.
Due to the success of the business,
Ted Drewes Jr. decided to expand
the size of the store in 1985,
having 12 serving windows instead of five.
The family business' signature
treat is the concrete,
which was created in 1959.
The concrete is a custard so thick
that it is served upside down.
Only two stands out of four,
and are still up and running,
both on the south of Saint Louis.
(mellow saxophone music)
Big Brown strays away from U.S. 66,
three miles off the
highway down a winding road
in the woods of Stanton, Missouri.
Down a valley lies a hidden treasure
beneath the ground, the Meramec Caverns.
Time has allowed limestone formations
to create some of the most beautiful
underground wonders in the world,
which stretch across 7.4 kilometers.
- Most folks that come to
visit the Meramec Caverns,
a lot of them are left in awe.
The don't quite know what to expect.
When they leave here, they're
basically reminded of how
there's so much beauty beneath the Earth
that they didn't really expect to see.
- [Narrator] The
400-million-year old caves
made of limestone have
served multiple purposes
over the years, from
sheltering Native Americans,
to becoming a saltpeter plant
for the manufacturing of gunpowder,
to serving as a ballroom
for square dancing events
in the late 19th century.
The cave system is one of
Route 66's biggest attractions.
- It's quite rich in family history
as well as Missouri history.
The Caverns has been used in
numerous Hollywood movies,
and then dating back
even further than that,
our cave was used during the
Civil War in the United States.
And even prior to that, it
was used for exploration
and in the hopes of
finding valuables, gold,
but none was ever found in our cave.
- [Narrator] In 1935, Lester B. Dill
opened the caves to tourists.
Dill was the sole creator
of the bumper sticker,
using the stickers as a means
of promoting the caverns,
along with billboards.
- My great grandfather first purchased
this area where the cave is.
What he knew that was going on
was square dancing inside of the cave.
It was a weekend hobby, and he used that
to fund his exploration of the cave.
He did weekends (mumbles)
during the week as well.
He went on to discover
the entire seven levels
of Meramec Caverns.
We call ourselves the
oldest staff on Route 66
because we've been here for
thousands of years, literally.
- [Narrator] Back on the main street,
Big Brown heads down 23
miles to Cuba, Missouri.
The Wagon Wheel Motel was built
in the chaotic times of 1935,
when the nation was barely
out of the depression,
and the Dust Bowl had
destroyed millions of acres.
It included the cabins, a
cafe, and a gas station.
Robert and Margaret Martin
were the first owners
of the Wagon Wheel Cabins,
purchasing the land in 1934.
The Martins hired Leo
Friesenhan to do the building.
Local farmers carried the stone to him
to build the indestructible cabins.
There are 14 cabins at
the Wagon Wheel Motel,
with 12 car shelters
and two locked garages,
but due to the increasing
length of automobiles,
tourism trade, and military
traffic, the garages
and the buildings were
converted into units.
After World War II, the cabins, the cafe,
and the gas station were split
and sold to different owners.
It's still there, bearing
its original look.
(upbeat music)
It isn't uncommon on Route 66
to bump into friendly
travelers like Vincent Daino,
who is traveling Route 66
entirely on his motorbike from California.
- What I'm learning the
most, I think, on this trip,
aside from the noted structures
and the iconic symbols
and visitor points, is the personalities
and the people that I have been meeting,
the people that, for instance, run
this establishment, the Wagon Wheel.
I spent last night at the Munger Moss
and got to know Ramona, she's an angel.
They still have the essence of Americana.
They still have the essence
of friendship and neighborly love,
and between Santa Monica and here,
I have had issues with my motorcycles
where I've had people on
Route 66 seeing me stop,
and they'll come out and render aid.
It makes you feel you're back in the 50s
where people who lived in the areas
wanted to make sure that their travelers,
if you're a traveler and
you got stuck in their area,
they were your guests.
So I would say pulls of
Route 66 are the people
that live and work in those communities
and treat us like we're family
members, not even knowing us.
State by state, venue by venue,
each one is the course of the meal.
I wouldn't do justice by elevating one
and not comparing it to the other.
There is no comparison.
But if I did that and
wind it down to one thing,
it's the human interaction of the people
who are keeping Route 66 alive,
adding and maintaining the
structures and buildings.
There's an element where I'm on the road
in these open stretches
and you're enjoying
this Route 66 pavement where
you're lost in your thoughts.
But I would have to say the
(mumbles) of my experience
is the personalities, the human contact,
the human element that really bring,
what really bring that,
that movie car and Walt Disney alive
is that personality and humankind.
- [Narrator] Not too far down the road
is the Missouri Hick for a
choice of different meats
that have been smoked
overnight for 12 hours.
It's worth the stop to grab a bite,
to eat at the Missouri Hick.
The two-story barbecue
shack with a hillbilly theme
is the pride of Dennis Meiser,
a master barbecuer and woodworker
whose skills are displayed
all over the place.
From the handmade tables and chairs
to the cedar stairs
leading up to the balcony,
there is no mistaking the skill
that went into this place.
(upbeat music)
7.5 kilometers down Will Rogers
Highway in Fanning, Missouri
is where you can see what used to be
the world's largest rocking chair.
(upbeat music)
Built on April Fools Day in 2008,
Dennis' mighty chair is 42 feet,
four inches high on rockers
each tree 1.5 feet long.
It lost its title as the
world's biggest rocking chair
in 2015, by a 56.5-foot
tall chair in Illinois,
but is still a part of
Route 66's hall of fame.
(mellow music)
The main street of America went through
various modifications to meet the needs
of the U.S. military
routes during World War II,
as well as when the highway
was decommissioned completely.
Hundreds of businesses fought to survive.
This was the case for
the Munger Moss Motel.
It all began at the
Munger Moss Sandwich Shop
in Devil's Elbow, Missouri,
built in 1936 by Nelle Munger
and husband Emmett Moss.
Unfortunately, business drastically slowed
due to the relocation of Route 66 in 1942
to accommodate heavy military traffic
going to and from nearby
Fort Leonard Wood.
The business was sold to
Jesse and Pete Hudson in 1945
and moved to the town of
Lebanon, 30 minutes away.
They built a sandwich
shop and a gas station,
and a year later, built
the motel during the time
when rationing was still enforced.
Some tales say the lumber that was used
to build the motel was
purchased off the black market.
It seems as though construction
went on day and night.
The Feds could not stop the construction
if there was no sign of the owner,
so Mr. Hudson stayed hid most of the time.
The new four-lane Route
66 was opened in 1957,
and bypassed the booming motel,
threatening its survival.
But that did not stop Mr. Hudson.
He went down to the corner
and placed wood plank
across the ditch and
formed a makeshift bridge
to his motel, along
with a big painted sign.
Munger Moss was not going to be bypassed.
And it worked.
The business lives on.
The last stop before heading
off to the state of Kansas
is Gary's Gay Parita.
- This place was founded in 1926
by Fred and Gay Mason.
All the buildings here were put up
between 1926 and finally finished in 1930.
Would have been the
garage, the gas station,
the house on the hill, and
the white building over there
was a grain and feeds store.
In addition to that, they had three cabins
where people could stay
and spend the night.
- [Narrator] The owner,
Gary, was always excited
to meet the travelers coming
through and stopping by.
- Gary loved to see everyone on the Route.
For him, he wasn't just talking to people,
he was making friends.
And his motto for this
place and ours as well,
friends for life.
Once you come to Parita,
you're friends for life.
- [Narrator] Route 66 only goes on
for approximately 20 kilometers
in the state of Kansas.
If there's something worth stopping for,
it's that the cars on the Route
66 that showcases replicas
from the famous cartoon movie, Cars.
By the way, the original
version that was used
by modelers at Pixar created (inaudible)
who stands proudly next to
the version that we all know.
(upbeat music)
Now in Oklahoma.
The first stop is at
the Afton Gas station.
This station was neglected
by its previous owner for many years.
It was only in 1998 that David Kane
bought the station and renovated it.
Over the years, the building
has housed multiple enterprises,
including 24-hour gas stations,
a large service garage,
a beauty parlor,
a western auto store,
a boat manufacturing plant,
and many other businesses.
The buildings today serve
as a visitors center
and an extensive collection of Route 66
and auto memorabilia,
and houses an eclectic
collection of Packard automobiles
along with other significant classic cars.
(mellow music)
(mellow strings music)
30 kilometers down Route 66
is Allen's Conoco Fillin'.
The tiny station was built
out from the exterior wall
of the final building on Main Street.
It now serves as a museum and gift shop.
(mellow music)
(upbeat music)
Off the Main Street
road, a lot of travelers
on their roadtrip down Route
66 make a detour to Foyil
to see Ed Galloway's world's largest
concrete totem pole at the Totem Park.
- It started with Mr. Galloway.
He is the totem pole creator.
When he was a young man,
he was always interested in woodworking,
that's why he has fiddles,
the beautiful furniture pieces.
But I think the totem
pole actually started
when he was a very young man.
He was in the Spanish-American War,
and he was in the Philippines.
And that was a particularly
hard war that hurt his heart.
- [Narrator] The totem is 60 feet tall
and 30 feet in circumference.
Inside the locked totem is a ladder
that climbs up four stories.
(mellow music)
Ed Galloway was born in Missouri,
fought in the Spanish-American War,
and while on his way to
California with his family,
he took a temporary job in Foyil.
- He built it as a way for people
to enjoy each other, to fellowship.
He wanted to build beautiful
work in art and give it to us.
Some of his last words were,
"I did the best I knew how,
"built these things by
the side of the road
"to be a friend to you."
And that's what he did,
he shared his artwork
with the world, it's what his goal was.
- [Narrator] He then spent
20 years teaching young boys
woodworking in the Children
Home Orphanage in Sand Springs
and retired in Foyil.
(upbeat music)
Some might think the large totem he built
was in honor of Native American tribes,
but he said it just gave him
something to do when he retired,
and would probably be a good
attraction for young ones,
boy scouts, in particular, to visit.
It took him 11 years to
complete the large totem,
which was finalized in 1948.
Ed built several other
sculptures around his property
but none bigger than the totem.
(waves lapping)
(gentle music)
Some people give flowers to
their wives on anniversaries,
but others give 80-feet
long concrete sperm whales.
The Blue Whale, one of Route 66's icons,
is built along the shores of
a pond in Catoosa, Oklahoma.
Hugh Davis unveiled this
mastodon to his wife, Zelta,
on their 34th wedding
anniversary in the 1970s,
which he originally built
for the use of just the Davis kids,
with a diving platform on its tail
and a slide coming out of its head.
On their property, the Davises
were operating an alligator farm.
But David eventually closed
the attraction in 1988.
For a decade, the whale
fell into disrepair,
but it was too visible and
too beloved to be left behind.
Now, every few years, whale
boosters converge on Catoosa
to patch its concrete and
give it a fresh coat of paint.
Next stop is at Pops, a modern gas station
and restaurant where you can find
a signature collection
of 700 kinds of soda,
sparkling waters, and other
ice cold refreshments.
It's hard to miss the huge neon sign
in the shape of a soda pop bottle.
It stands 66 feet tall,
in honor of Route 66.
- We carry anywhere from 750
to 800 different flavors of soda,
all different brands
from different countries,
different places.
There are some that we do not
get anymore at quick bottling.
A lot of bottles you
see on the shelves here,
they've been up for 11 years.
The only time we really change
is when the color goes out.
Bottles, that's one of our biggest sale
as other people come from all over
just to (mumbles) selection of bottle.
So we have all brand which
we have a great plains soda
which is basically great.
Then we have our orange crane (mumbling).
Then we have the Round Barn root beer
which is our brand as well,
which we bottle (mumbling).
(upbeat music)
(mellow strings music)
- [Narrator] Many villages
along the route try
and take advantage of the
renewed excitement for Route 66.
It's the case of Elk City,
who has proposed a museum
that will please and impress the true fans
of this mythical road.
If you do decide to take on
the entirety of Route 66,
stray away from fake attractions,
and take advantage of the real ones.
(upbeat music)
The last stop in the state of Oklahoma
is a shop where nothing is for sale,
and its greatest
curiosities are its owners,
Harley and Annabelle Russel,
the Mediocre Music Makers.
If you're interested in
a personal music concert,
you might get lucky
at the Sandhills Curiosity Shop in Erick.
In the shop, you'll
find old oak furniture,
a variety of artwork, and
vintage music instruments,
along with other curious
and fascinating object.
Entering the land of the cowboys,
in Shamrock lies the U-Drop Inn.
This gas station and
restaurant was built in 1936
for the amount of $23,000.
The design for the place
is said to be drawn
by a friend of the owner,
who picked up an old nail
and scratched out the plans
for the building in the dirt.
The local newspaper said
it was the swankiest
of swank eating places,
and was the most up-to-date
edifice of its kind
on U.S. Highway 66, between
Oklahoma City and Amarillo.
It happens regularly today for customers
to stop and say that they ate in the cafe
20, 30, 40, even 50 years ago.
In 2003 and 2004, the building received
a 1.7 million federal
grant in which the city
was able to hire a firm specializing
in historical renovation.
The building has since been
restored to its original glory
and adapted into a museum,
visitors center, gift shop,
and the city's Chamber of Commerce.
(upbeat strings music)
In Groom, Texas stands slanted
one of the most iconic
attractions of Route 66,
the Leaning Water Tower.
It is a strange sight to see,
unsettling, yet fascinating.
Unfortunately, this Leaning Water Tower
was an ingenious marketing ploy.
Ralph Britten, a man
who wanted to start up
a truck stop and restaurant
off Route 66 in Groom,
bought the water tower
from the town of Lefors
to attract new visitors.
He towed the enormous thing
55 kilometers to Groom,
wrote Britten USA on top,
and then, using a bulldozer,
elevated two of its legs off the ground,
dangling them in mid-air without support,
so that the water tower
made an 80-degree angle
with the ground.
Passersby would think that the tower
was in the process of collapsing.
Worried route takers
often swerved off the road
and into his truck top,
shouting, "Watch out!
"The tower is about to fall."
Britten would say that it
had been like that for years,
and invited them to have
some food and drinks.
It worked very well to attract customers.
Unfortunately, the truck
stop burnt down and closed,
but the Leaning Tower is still there.
There is no way to miss the
Big Texan in Amarillo, Texas
when passing by Route 66.
The Big Texan is a restaurant, brewery,
motel, gift shop, and even horse motel.
- It was my father that came down.
He was from Chicago and
he didn't know anything
about being a cowboy, what
western was really all about.
And he came down here
and he wanted to open up
a cowboy restaurant, so he did everything
in his power to make it
cowboy, it wasn't working.
But the thing that did
make it cowboy was the fact
that the original Big
Texan was right next door
to the stock yards, and there was hundreds
and hundreds of cowboys
that worked there everyday.
They would come into his
place everyday after work,
and he would cash or pay checks
and sell them nickel beer.
And they started acting like Texans do,
so he put them at the very
center table of the dining room
and allowed them to do
whatever they wanted to do,
and if you will, paint
the wet canvas at Texas,
so (mumbles) would come in
and see this table for the cowboys,
watching them act like what they expected,
and that's what gave the
Big Texan its personality,
was the people coming here,
not really what he thought
he knew about being cowboy.
(chattering)
Well, the 72-ounce steak challenge started
with the same thing with my dad
about these cowboys that
are in his restaurant,
they were acting like cowboys
and they were always
trying to outdo each other.
"My muscle's bigger than yours.
"I'm smarter than you.
"I can eat more than you."
And the eat more than you
appealed to my father,
and he was smart enough to say,
"Next Friday, I got 12
seats at this table.
"I'll give everybody one-pound steaks
"for over an hour period of time,
"and whoever eats the
most one-pound steaks,
"I'm gonna give it to you all free."
So one cowboy ate four and
a half one-pound steaks.
He was a big show-off, so
he ordered a baked potato,
shrimp cocktail, tossed
salad and bread with it,
and he ate the entire meal.
And my dad said, "From this day forward,
"in 1960, whoever can eat four
and a half pounds of beef,
"a baked potato, a shrimp
cocktail, a raw butter,
"it's for free."
And 58 years ago, it hasn't changed a bit.
It's still the 72-ounce steak challenge.
The quickest was by a lady
who also owns all the record sport.
She weighs 128 pounds, and she ate
three 72-ounce steaks in 20 minutes,
the first one in three and a half minutes.
A lady, a 128-pound lady,
three 72-ounce steaks in 20 minutes.
But it's still (mumbles).
Everybody else comes in to try it,
and it's still the same percentages.
One out of every six
men will take it down.
One out of every two women will eat it.
So the percentage hasn't changed
and it's not about the big
(mumbles) that comes in here,
or the little tiny guy.
You never know who's gonna do it.
20 minutes into this contest,
you can usually tell.
Route 66 gave the Big Texan its birth.
It's because of Route 66, it carried all
the east-west travelers
through this part of Texas.
And when they come through here,
they wanted to see cowboys,
like if you go to Hawaii,
you expect to see a girl in a grass skirt.
When they come to this part of Texas,
they want to see the cowboy,
they want to see the big steaks,
they wanna see people on horseback.
And that's what my father
was smart enough to realize
and that's what they get to see.
And if it wasn't for Route
66, it wouldn't have happened.
(mellow strings music)
- [Narrator] The Cadillac Ranch,
one of Route 66's attractions
west of Amarillo, Texas,
was invented and built by a group
of art hippies from San Francisco.
The group called themselves the Ant Farm
and created the piece of work
for their silent partner,
Amarillo billionaire Stanley Marsh 3.
He wanted an art piece
that would turn heads.
And the hippies came up with a tribute
to the evolution of the Cadillac Tailfin.
10 caddies were driven into
one of Stanley's fields,
then buried, nose down, in the dirt,
supposedly at the same angle
as the Great Pyramid of Giza.
They faced west in a line,
from the 1949 Club sedan,
to the 1963 Deville.
Their tailfins held high for all to see
on the empty Texas Panhandle.
Since the creation of the art piece,
many who've come to see
it have taken the liberty
of grabbing a piece and
taking it home as a souvenir.
This did not bother its creators,
and they actually encouraged it.
But as everyone took a
little piece with them,
the 10 Cadillacs became
almost unrecognizable.
Only their carcasses
remain, stained by graffiti.
In fact, they've been in the ground
longer that they've been on the road.
The art piece is now seen
to represent America's hopes and dreams,
art and commerce,
materialism and spiritualism,
all the infame.
(upbeat strings music)
The last place in Texas worth seeing
is the Midpoint Cafe
in the town of Adrian.
- We're famous for the pies,
and I think, very friendly people.
We try to make everybody feel like
they're special when
they come to the door.
(laughing) Yeah, and we
have a great gift shop,
and you can get pretty
much find anything you want
at Route 66 here in the Midpoint Cafe
or the midpoint period.
There's great photo-ops
here, and good food.
- Yeah, and great food, yeah (laughs).
They bring a lot of fun,
that's what I think (laughs).
We enjoy visiting with them
and having a good time.
And that we do, it's like a great job.
We literally have fun everyday.
(upbeat music)
- [Narrator] The first break
in the state of New Mexico
could easily be at night.
The Blue Swallow motel is a must-stop,
if it isn't for the kitsch in the outside
that lights up the night.
Originally built in 1939,
it keeps up with the original
style inside and out.
It feels like a walk back in time.
(upbeat music)
Near Grant, we stumble
upon a treasure trove
of classic cars waiting to be refurbished.
An incredible selection,
from Chevys to Fords,
and a few imports like the
famous Volkswagen Beetle.
Any classic car enthusiast would revel
in such a sight, with hundreds of vehicles
as far as the eye can see.
(upbeat music)
A quick stop before hitting
the road with Big Brown
for a small transmission tune up.
As always, the people along Route 66
are always friendly and helpful.
(upbeat music)
15 minutes later, we're ready to roll.
Making its way towards Arizona,
Big Brown makes one last stop
in the state of New Mexico,
in Gallup, at El Rancho Hotel.
El Rancho was built in 1937,
originally as a base camp for movie stars.
Brother of film director
David Wark Griffith
built it to accommodate actors
when they were shooting
films in the wild west.
(mellow music)
During the 30s and 40s, 100 western films
were filmed around Gallup,
with their stars staying at the El Rancho.
Guests included stars
such as Ronald Reagan,
Humphrey Bogart, Katharine Hepburn,
May West, and over 150 others.
The place still looks and feels
as it did back in the day.
(mellow music)
In Arizona, the state best
known for the Grand Canyon,
hidden gems reside along Route 66.
The Wigwam Motel, a
distinctive historical landmark
built along Route 66 in
Holbrook, was built in 1950,
one of seven Wigmam Villages.
(upbeat music)
The units are teepee-shaped,
but were mistakenly named wigwams.
The Pixar film Car Story is entirely based
on the Route 66 experience,
and one of the characters
owns a motel called the Cozy Cone Motel,
which is clearly inspired
by the Wigwam Village
in Holbrook, Arizona.
(upbeat music)
The first Wigwam Village was
built in 1933 by Frank Redford.
It was located on the corner of US 31E
and Highway 218 in Horse Cave, Kentucky.
Redford created the village
after adding teepee-shaped units
around a museum-cum-shop
he had built to store
his collection of Native
American artifacts.
He applied for a patent
on the ornamental design
of the teepees, and was
granted design patent in 1936.
The original drawing includes a swastika,
at the time, a symbol
associated with Native Americans
or often often worn as a good luck charm.
(upbeat music)
For all the Eagles fans, the
best spot to stop on Highway 66
is on the corner in Winslow, Arizona.
The English setting of
the Take it Easy song
of the famous rock band,
Standin' On The Corner Park,
has become a tourist attraction.
The town of Winslow used to be
the biggest town in the state of Arizona.
That is, up until the late 1970s.
When the town was bypassed
by the new transcontinental highway,
tourism-based businesses
downtown closed up shop,
and for the following 20 years,
the town was frozen in time.
All of this changed when in 1994,
La Posada Foundation put efforts
into refurbishing the La Posada Hotel,
a hotel built in 1930.
This revived the town.
Seeing the success it
had brought to the town,
La Posada Foundation changed its name
to Standin' On The Corner Foundation,
and decided to build a park
dedicated to the Eagles song.
They hired artists to paint a mural
and make a sculpture of a man
standing on the corner of the park.
(upbeat music)
About 177 kilometers down Route 66
is another historic
eatery called Delgadillos
Snow Cap drive-in in Seligman, Arizona.
The drive-in was built in 1953
by local resident Juan Delgadillo.
Delgadillo built the restaurant
mostly from scrap lumber
obtained from the nearby
Santa Fe railroad yard
because he was working on
an extremely tight budget.
John Delgadillo, son of Juan Delgadillo,
tells us more about his
family and the drive-in.
- My father built it with his father
and his brothers in 1953.
He opened in June of 53.
And we've been here ever since.
- [Narrator] Juan
Delgadillo's brother owned
a 1936 Chevrolet hard
top and cut the roof off,
adorned the vehicle with paint, horns,
and various other items,
including an artificial Christmas tree
in the rear of the car.
And they would it around
to attract customers
to the restaurant.
The old Chevy is still
there parked in front.
Today, people come from all over the world
and stop at Delgadillo's Snow Cap drive-in
for the 30s and 40s experience.
Part of the service at the
drive-in are the jokes.
There are jokes for everything you order,
which extends to the building itself.
The restaurant is filled
with humorous decor
and comical phrases.
In the back of the restaurant,
there is a collection of old automobiles,
which has its humorous touch as well.
Nevertheless, running a
drive-in is a lot of work.
- It's work, a lot of work,
and talking to people,
having fun with people,
because they come back,
they bring their family,
they bring their friends,
because we have fun with them.
- [Narrator] At Delgadillo's
Snow Cap drive-in,
it's the perfect place for someone
with a good sense of humor
and an appetite for great food.
(upbeat music)
The last stop in Arizona
is at the El Trovatore Motel in Kingman.
This historic Route 66
motel started in 1937
as a service station,
with a tourist court added later in 1939,
and was first owned by John F. Miller.
You can spend the night
in the motel's Hollywood-themed rooms,
which remain in the original
decor of when it was built.
Mr. Fisher knows exactly
what Route 66 today
is all about and why it
remains an iconic route.
- People come here for
their bucket list 66.
Let's say, younger people
will come here to do this.
Older people come here and say,
"We used to drive the station
wagon with my grandfather
"all the way across Route 66."
And the original people
that left Oklahoma,
because they lost their farms,
because they (mumbles) the field too much,
and they drove across Route 66
to California for a better life.
So that's a part of Route 66.
- [Narrator] In the town of Kingman,
classic cars are not uncommon.
- Just in this town alone,
there is over 350 classic cars.
Once a month, they go to
downtown and they drive around
in procession like this for four hours.
It's called Chill on Beale.
Once a year, there's a
thousand cars come on Route 66.
They do a fun run.
But every few months,
there's another group
come here from Australia, New Zealand,
either with motorcycles,
and it's fun to be here.
It's fun to meet the people.
The fun part was not remodeling it,
doing all this work.
The fun part is meeting people
that have in their eyes,
this yearning to see this,
and they come all the way from
the Czech Republic.
Why would they want to come here?
That's because there is a road like this.
(mellow strings music)
- [Narrator] Reaching the Black Mountains
of Mohave County, Arizona,
a small town resides called the Oatman.
The town started as a small mining camp
soon after two prospectors tracked
a $10-million gold mine.
The town was named Oatman
in honor of Olive Oatman,
a young Illinois girl who
had been taken captive
by Indians during her pioneer
family's journey westward
in 1851, and forced into slavery.
She was later traded to Mohave Indians
who adopted her as a daughter
and had her face tattooed
in the custom of the tribe.
She was released in 1856
at Fort Yuma, Arizona.
(firing)
(clamoring)
(upbeat guitar music)
After the district had
produced 40 million,
or approximately 2.6 billion
in today's market price in gold by 1941,
all of the gold extracting
operations ceased,
and the town changed its business
to cater to travelers on Route 66.
(upbeat guitar music)
In 1953, the new highway was built
and bypassed the town,
and Oatman was all but abandoned.
But as Route 66 gained
recognition worldwide,
Oatman revived.
It is well-known for its wild burrows
wandering the streets,
the descendants of pack animals
abandoned by early
prospectors in Sitgreaves Pass
which tops out at 3,550 feet.
The pass was named after
Captain Lorenzo Sitgreaves,
who traveled through the area in 1851.
Old Route 66 did not cut through the land.
It moved with the land,
unlike the new interstate.
The last state sliced by the pavement
of the Mother Road is California,
gifted with spectacular scenery,
diversity, and wonderful weather.
It is best known for its
standing in show business,
its premises filled with movie stars,
musical artists, and popular culture.
It is a place where dreams
come to life for many.
(upbeat music)
The first stop in California
is Elmer's Bottle Tree
in Oro Grande.
Elmer Long's two plus acres are crowded
with hundreds of metal sculptures
adorned with colored bottles,
and just about anything
else one could imagine.
Elmer was only a boy when he
started collecting bottles.
He found a dump with trash
that went back to the 1800s.
And as far as Elmer could tell,
the stuff he found in them were priceless,
which included bottles.
Elmer has been collecting
bottles for years
and found a way to display them.
It started with one bottle tree.
Now, hundreds are planted on his land.
(upbeat music)
(pensive piano music)
At the pier is the Pacific Park.
Several restaurants and
loads of smiles and fun.
You've reached the finish line,
but the fun does not have to end there.
(people squealing)
(pensive piano music)
Driving down Route 66 makes
for a humbling experience.
It shows you that happiness
is in the little things.
People don't go through
Route 66 to make good time.
They go through it to have a good time.
And once in a while, it's
kind of nice to slow down.
(lighthearted piano music)