- Thank you.
- Shall I come up?
No. You've already done enough.
A BREAK
No. I'm out of gas.
I'm at a garage.
There's nothing.
There's only...
There's no diesel.
You'll have to come and get me.
I'm stuck otherwise.
I'm in a filling station
with no diesel.
Shit!
My battery's nearly dead!
Quick!
Shit...
Can I borrow
your mobile for a second?
Haven't got one. Sorry.
Do you know
where the new squat is?
No, I don't. Sorry.
Are you sure?
Yes. I'm sure.
It's nothing.
- Pardon?
- It's nothing.
I didn't catch that.
I said "it's nothing".
Hang on.
I've got a map in the car.
Do you live in here?
My girlfriend
threw me out of our place.
Well, her place.
So I'm dossing here.
I don't know why...
It doesn't matter.
Shall we look for this squat?
It's not a problem for you?
No.
What's your name?
- Sami. And yours?
- Julia.
- Can I smoke in your place?
- Yeah.
- Do you make music?
- Yep.
Can I listen?
What happened with your girlfriend?
It lasted 4 years.
What does that mean,
"it lasted 4 years"?
Ever been with someone 4 years?
Well, no.
There's generally
a good reason for it.
No more than for meeting.
Sniff it!
4 years later
Yes. Fine.
Just one thing.
About dinner, Wednesday night,
I can't make it.
Can you do tomorrow?
Wait, I'll check.
He's coming tomorrow.
Wednesday's off.
- Who?
- Lionel, my boss.
Oh yeah?
- Does it suit you?
- Why shouldn't it?
I don't know...
You alright?
- Yes. 7 out of 10. And you?
- 8.5.
We got the Co-op contract. Yes!
How's Fernand?
Same as ever.
What time's your meeting?
Nothing's fixed.
I've got an idea for a song.
Here it is.
"When the stars are shaking."
Nice, eh?
I'll drop you at Celine's,
you'll come to the concert?
- Will you eat tonight?
- No. Thank you.
- Hi, Sami.
- Hi, Sarah.
Is he there?
Fernand!
Fernand, your jab!
Bloody prostate!
Take my advice,
piss sitting down.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't worry.
Lionel came to Celine's.
He left late.
Why at Celine's?
To... celebrate the contract!
Are you drunk?
A little bit.
The Madras suppliers
are coming to Switzerland.
Prat alert.
Hi, guys!
Just brilliant.
Sami, you've got an ear for a hit.
Shame you only play country.
Let's fix a date.
I've got a slot...
on Tuesday morning.
- Can you make that?
- Not Tuesday.
I've got a prostate thing.
Right, then...
Right. Then forget it.
OK. We'll make it happen.
Yeah, guys!
- Tuesday!
- Yep.
See you then!
Ciao, Rudi!
You good, Big Chief?
- Cool, and you?
- Not bad, man.
Julia.
You're really crazy.
No. I'm just polite.
You're beautiful.
In this light, it's unreal.
I'm not in the mood.
Can I...
While I look at your bum?
No.
It's peaceful here.
I'd take a room,
if I could afford it.
- Shall we play?
- I'd rather drink.
It's a nice Burgundy.
And some more!
More?
Hi!
Join me? It's still warm.
My boss is coming tonight.
I asked you to tidy.
Shit, yes.
Where are the 2 bottles of Burgundy?
Artistic inspiration?
I'll go and buy 2 more.
- Try to avoid plonk.
- OK.
Here.
Thanks.
- What's that?
- A decanter.
Don't use a water jug!
Take a carafe!
Yeah.
Why Australian wine?
With prawns, it'll look bad.
You won't get an official warning!
Being this ecologically correct
is crazy.
Really, it's a pain.
- Is this on purpose?
- I'm handling it.
Don't use the curtains!
Are you stupid?
- Get out!
- I'll do it...
Stop. You're annoying me.
Go and change.
Shall I wear a tie too?
This new job's driven you mad.
It's better than writing crap
with a senile mate!
Julia, Thank you so much
for a delicious meal.
- The prawns are superb.
- Thank you.
I've been looking forward
to having you here.
When I was a kid,
I dreamed of being in space,
looking at earth,
which shrivelled to
the size of a pinhead.
The infinitely large
to the infinitely small.
And I woke up screaming.
Why are you saying that?
I don't know.
It's the prawns.
They reminded me of it.
Are you acting?
Yes, I am.
What is it?
A poetic fable on the impact
of global warming.
Show her.
It's a metaphor on sexual politics.
No dialogue.
Right.
It's full of surprise elements.
The actors change their character
within the play.
What's that Brechtian technique?
Verfremdungseffekt.
The V-Effekt.
What is... What?
Hang on.
I know that...
The idea is to make...
the spectator realise
that he's in the middle...
In the middle of...
watching a play.
- Exactly. That's it.
It gives a sense of
political distance.
Yes.
You really must come.
The opening's next Friday?
I'd love to.
- You don't have to.
- No. I don't.
But however it's presented,
it's good that theatre
is talking about the planet.
Sami, you play guitar, don't you?
- Yes.
- May I?
Feel free.
It's not easy to play.
What else do you do?
Not a lot. Small jobs.
I'm not ambitious.
Each to his own.
At the moment,
I'm in local commerce...
Could you pour us
some more wine?
Yes.
It's Australian.
But no kangaroos were harmed
during its making!
- A drop?
- Yes.
But for fundamentalists,
there's some local plonk left.
Can we talk?
- Right now?
- Yes, but not here.
Sorry about earlier.
You angry?
No.
What's up?
It's not working any more.
How do you mean?
There's no understanding.
What?
What don't you understand?
Everything.
A couple's never all plain sailing.
I screwed up earlier.
Is it about Lionel?
No, it's not.
So explain.
I don't know you, Sami.
5 years now.
You don't know me,
or what I like.
You don't like my friends.
We choose to do different things,
don't we?
Yes. But I've had enough.
Your freedom is vital to me.
If you've had enough,
you should leave me!
But 4 years on...
That suits you fine!
That history repeats itself?
My leaving you, prat!
It doesn't suit me at all.
Finding someone else,
the initial jealousy,
awkwardness, passion, all that...
No, I don't need it.
So...
So do something then!
What do you want?
Well, you could say:
"Julia...
"I'm scared of losing you,
so I've kept you away.
"Then if it goes wrong,
it'll hurt me less."
Yes... It must be that.
- What's "that"?
- What you just said.
Do you want to have a child?
Julia!
It's your hair in the plughole.
"Yesterday, around 5pm,
"an Airbus A330
crashed into the Atlantic.
"The flight,
between Montreal and London,
"was carrying 2 classes
of school children.
"The Canadian prime minister said:
"this is a national tragedy'"
What do you want?
I've got cognac, armagnac, vodka,
absinthe,
red wine, white wine, beer.
- The Macallan?
- I'm not thirsty.
You're lucky, Fernand.
Why?
It's behind you.
All the stupidity,
It's finished for you.
It depends how you look at it.
What's happened?
I've fallen out with Julia.
Over a bath.
Shall we play?
I need to fill the gap.
I'm doing dinner
and can't find the sieve.
Where did you put it?
It'll be ready soon.
Just say if you're coming or not.
Sorry.
Big hugs and kisses.
Look, I really like your music,
but I'd like you
to consider the other residents.
They're deaf and half blind.
With no marbles!
I don't know what's wrong
with him today...
I'll deal with him.
Could you apply his cream, please?
- What?
- Nothing.
She's not back yet.
But it's alright.
It's rather a good sign.
"Good sign"?
- You joking? What do I do?
- Nothing.
Not straight away, anyway.
Let her stew.
She'll realise that she cares,
then she'll fall in love
with you all over again.
I know women.
You've got to make her miss you.
Look, Sami. All I know,
is that it's been a while
that Julia's been saying
that it's not working.
Besides that, she's said nothing.
Honest.
I don't know what to say.
Is there someone else?
- Is that what counts?
- No.
- That's not the case.
- You said you knew nothing?
Look. I've got a pile
of exam papers to mark.
If you want my advice,
think about your senile mate.
What's he got to do with it?
You think it's fun?
A guy who spends his time
in a retirement home,
and hasn't got a job?
On page 2, article 5...
The best thing,
is that the dockets
are certified by customs.
Then the whole process
is traceable.
Excuse me, please.
Sorry.
You can't just turn up here.
We're with clients.
I can see. I'll wait
Sami, I know
it's none of my business,
but I think you should
leave her alone.
It's best.
Correct.
It's not your business.
- What do you want?
- To know.
It's a bad time.
You haven't called for 82 hours.
Are you deaf?
Not yet.
Sign the contract, I'll wait.
Julia...
have you got a paper?
If you want to see me again,
just leave. OK?
You crazy or...?
It's over, Sami.
Got it? "Over."
Don't worry.
It's not serious.
She didn't say she needed a break.
When they say they need a break,
then you've got a reason to worry
as they're trying to protect you.
But if she only said it was over...
It's OK.
You just arrived at a bad time.
Go on.
It's certain,
that to make her miss you,
you mustn't see her.
Frankly...
I had doubts over your country crap.
But the record industry
is in such a state...
Your Willie Nelson cover
appealed to the English.
Well, he was totally pissed!
We really caned it!
Whisky...
No, no...
It's not very rock'n roll,
but you can't smoke.
So, this is the score...
You're booked on a short tour.
Support act for the English group.
Good, eh?
Brilliant!
It's good.
Hello!
I bought some beer.
Want one?
Sorry to have vanished for 2 days.
I should've let you know.
It doesn't matter.
Shall I cook something?
Look, Sami...
I think we need a break.
"A break"? In what way?
Well...
I'm going to stay with Celine.
Have you met someone?
You can tell me. It's OK.
Don't you love me anymore?
I don't know.
I'm searching. But you're not.
- What's going on?
- It's Julia's mail.
But Sami, it's 6 in the morning!
Shit!
What is it?
I wanted you to have
your Elle at breakfast.
and your other mail.
- Sorry.
- What do you want?
Sorry for my attitude recently,
I'm really not happy
with this situation.
You're right, things are bad.
We must do something.
So... What do you plan on doing?
We could go walking,
go into the valley.
"Go into the valley"?
I told you I wanted a break.
How does it work?
We avoid each other for a bit.
- Until when?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
- I've no idea.
- Why not?
I'll call you. Goodbye.
OK. I'll be waiting.
- What is it?
- Blood test.
You missed the 'genius at work' sign?
Sing it more laid-back,
with a bit more soul.
Got sticky fingers.
I don't believe
this affair with Lionel.
What affair?
It's a fling, purely sexual.
She wanted to have
a fling with her boss.
What?
You said she wanted
a fling with him.
No, I didn't.
I said that I thought
something might be going on.
Right. Excuse me.
Write. You're in the mood.
It's an ideal time to compose.
Imagine her screwing this bloke.
I've got an idea for a song.
"When the stars are shaking."
Nice, eh?
Big Chief, you OK?
- Yes, and you?
- Cool.
- Is that a new song?
- Yes.
Is it for Julia?
Sorry, Rudi.
I've got to finish.
Thanks, dude!
Shit, Rudi! Shut it!
Quiet! Good. Come here!
Good dog! Come here!
What's going on inside?
You mean the weight in my heart?
I mean your writing.
It's coming on.
- Yo, bro.
- Hey, bro!
Have you chosen?
The big one.
We're on tour.
We'll take the finest,
which means...
the most expensive.
The Lamothe Despujols 1989.
We can do even better.
A Pouilly-fuissé
and a carafe of château H2O.
- What?
- Water, I mean.
- The biopsy result?
- Don't worry.
I haven't breathed my last yet.
Milano, Torino, Chiasso, Lugano.
A southern tour.
Rivette's a prat,
but he can hire a bus.
Wow.
- A double decker?
- Yes.
Can you be away that long?
I'll sort it with Sarah.
It'll do you good.
- Are you pleased about it?
- Sure.
Still no news?
No.
It's alright. Stay strong.
- Bravo. It was really good.
- Thanks.
- Has Julia been, by any chance?
- She was here last night.
- "Last night"?
- For the opening night.
Of course.
The opening night.
Yes.
I heard about what happened.
You seem to be
taking it really well.
What do you mean?
We went for a drink
at her boss's place.
She explained a bit.
It's a wonderful flat.
I think she'll be
really happy there.
I want you to meet the actress.
- Eva...
- OK. I'm off...
What a bitch!
She's taking the piss!
With that dickhead!
I'll tell her what I think about it.
You'll do no such thing.
But get the enemy out of the way.
She can sleep with someone else.
But moving in's another matter.
Sleep elsewhere.
Then she can return home.
To have organic orgies
with her green chums.
Run into her,
tell her you've moved out.
Give her back the keys.
Hand over.
Thanks. Good
Like that.
Yeah...
So I've had some time
to consider it.
We needed a break.
You were right.
But...
I think it would be better
if you kept the flat.
It was yours in the first place,
all your gear is there, and...
Here.
So...
I found myself a room.
I needed to.
I want you to feel at home,
at home... your home!
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Right...
Whatever you're up to,
it's come in handy.
You're broke.
It's good for everyone.
- Yes. I know, but...
- But what?
What about a hotel?
- No. Too pricey.
- Why is it "too pricey"?
It's too pricey.
And they can cook here.
Yes, alright.
- Alright, what?
- No, nothing.
Since we're taking a break,
let's avoid seeing each other.
Yeah, yeah.
You can tell me, you know.
Call you in 3 weeks.
Thanks, Fernand.
Very smart move
"I've moved out".
She's moved in with that prat,
and I've got Sikhs in the kitchen.
"Sikhs"?
Calm down.
I don't understand.
She's rented our flat
to her Madras suppliers.
Shit! Don't panic.
We'll get them out.
No, no.
Bet you a case of the best
that she'll call during your break.
Just keep making her miss you,
She'll understand
what's important for you.
I love you too.
- Bobby.
- Kretchmann.
- You OK?
- Yes.
You living in there?
Yes. I'll get you a coffee.
Mi casa es tu casa.
Bobby, you're a life-saver.
I've known you since the infants.
You know Luft?
Listen to this.
It's a pity.
You went well together.
You're using the past tense.
I'm only saying it because...
You looked so cool together.
- Are you sulking?
- No.
Don't wait around forever.
A break shouldn't last too long.
I don't want to dash your hopes.
No. I've still got some.
Sorry.
Make me a filter.
Here.
It's true.
You know the statistics.
What statistics?
Don't know exactly.
Off the top of my head.
I saw a report about it.
It's not hopeful.
I feel bad. I'm going.
- Where to?
- The home. To sleep.
I'm not letting you rot
in that morgue.
Old chat-up lines bore them.
Get straight to the point.
Excuse me.
You're pretty. I'm Bobby.
I'd like to make love.
Is that so? That's wonderful.
- Now? Here? On the ground?
- No. It's a bit dirty.
We can go to mine, or yours.
I'm open.
Can I buy you a drink?
Stick it up your arse!
I was direct, frank.
I told the truth.
Unlike sweet talkers
who just talk crap.
She just walked out, eh?
You sure it was her?
- What a shit night!
- Want some?
- What is it?
- MDA.
I'm against drugs.
Sorry.
I'd forgotten: "against drugs".
Drugs aren't a problem.
Addiction is.
Go on.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Me too.
God, this music's brilliant!
Yeah! Absolutely brilliant.
We've already met.
- What's your name?
- Virginie.
- That's lovely.
- Why?
Virginie, virginity,
virgin forest. All that.
Wow.
Didn't understand it all.
But it sure came from the heart.
It's really good, Sami.
This one will be a hit.
I tell you.
- The new one.
- Don't know the words.
Sing anything you like.
They're Italian.
Come on.
For the first time on stage...
Mamma mia! My Italian...
It's embarrassing!
It talks about
how much easier it is
to seduce 50 women
than to seduce
your own woman 50 times.
Hey, Sami...
I don't know why you're with her.
It's great just now.
She's funny, pretty, clever.
She smells nice.
But in 4 years, it'll be over.
A waste.
The statistics are terrifying.
You said?
Alright. It's organised.
Cool it, Sami!
Ritchie Blackmore's got a demo first.
Blackmore?
Ritchie Blackmore
of Deep Motherfucking Purple.
I hope he leaves things intact!
Isn't this a good place to record?
I think the home would be better.
We need that raw sound.
Our music's simple.
It makes no sense to wait
3 months for the studio.
But it'll give me time
to work on the lyrics.
- It's not necessary.
- It is for me.
Not for me.
But it is for me.
I can't wait 3 months.
Cool it guys.
We'll think it over, OK?
We'll lose this energy.
Let's use it while we can.
Excuse me. I need a piss.
A case of Pouilly-fuissé...
Sami?
Organic or not?
It's been faked.
Calm down, Lionel.
I'm calm.
It's not my business,
but if you want my advice,
we should all sit down
and discuss this peacefully.
You were right, Sami.
It's all rotten to the core.
But it's all relative.
A guy on the radio said...
- don't know who -
the anti-globalisation movement
had no...
no... it slips my mind.
That the movement had
had absolutely no effect
on globalisation.
But without it,
the world would be so much worse.
It all seems so pointless sometimes,
but there is a point to it.
You know what I'd really like,
just now?
A bloody Big Mac!
Not all of it!
Right.
I'm going.
Shall I see if he's alright?
No. I'll deal with it on my own.
If there's any problem, call me.
Julia...
Can I take you to a real restaurant?
Will you call?
- Again.
- But I was into it!
- You want her back?
- Yes.
Doesn't show.
Not convinced.
I should've re-written it...
Rubbish!
It's the blue note that counts.
It's when you play without thinking.
You're in harmony
with the universe.
That's what it's all for!
- The rest is crap!
- Alright, I get it.
Go on then.
Start again, give it everything.
OK. Let's do it.
You'll be the death of me.
Jesus would've have
taken you to task.
Screw Jesus!
And albino nurses.
Sorry.
Have you been here long?
No. No problem.
- You OK?
- Yes. I'm alright.
How much?
- What?
- On a scale of 1 to 10.
Will you have an aperitif?
Yes. What she's having.
I've got you a gift.
It's not much,
but I put my heart into it.
Well...
It's odd to see that because...
No. You don't have to say anything.
I thought you were with Lionel.
Pardon?
Someone drugged me.
Who drugged you?
Polanski?
We didn't have sex.
I'm 90% certain.
I'll get a test if you like.
I'm giving up the flat.
Cheers.
"A young arts post-graduate
photographed her...
"her erotic adventures."
A personal reflection on polyamory.
Bloody idiots.
- What about the cassette?
- What about it?
Has she got it?
It's just sentimental crap.
Statistics show that
77% of couples fail within 10 years.
Running your life by statistics
is a mug's game, my lad.
I'm not your lad, Fernand!
If you knew women,
you wouldn't be here alone.
"In Nan Goldin's footsteps."
Can I help you?
I know the photographer.
She'll pay.
Julia...
I love you.
I'm here, Fernand.
Do you remember saying,
that I was lucky.
Lucky to have life behind me?
Well, if you want to swap now...
I'll sign up.
It was my grandma's, I kept it on.
- The rent's cheap.
- It's just brilliant.
I love the furnishings.
It's yours if you want it.
I think we could say that
we absolutely love it, eh, Willy?
It's a dream come true.
A real dream.
- Shouldn't we consider it further?
- Pardon?
Think about it a bit?
If you want us to take the furniture
or buy the cooker,
or pay more rent, say the word.
Does noise bother you?
The 4am goods train is no fun.
And the Wednesday morning market
with the Peruvian pan pipes.
And Rudi?
Our junkie.
Leaves syringes lying about.
Julia, I love you.
I was so lucky to meet you
in that filling station.
I love you, Julia.
You're my sunshine, my muse.
I don't know what to...
Julia, will you marry me?
Just 3 letters.
Say yes and I'm yours forever.
You gave her the cassette?
Did she like it?
Yes. I gave it to her.
She loved it.
We hugged and she cried.
You know women.
Before the resurrected Christ,
left this world,
he said he would prepare
a place for his disciples
in a world with neither death,
nor pain, nor grief,
nor suffering.
Every time we are confronted
with the loss of a loved one,
we are equally in a state
of pain and interrogation.
Throughout his often difficult life,
Fernand was in search
of recognition,
love and friendship.
It is with this thought
that we leave him
in our Lord's merciful hands.
Now, as requested by Fernand,
who wanted people to remember
the good times shared,
we will celebrate him in music.
Bastard.
Thank you for the song.
You're welcome.
So when's the wedding?
Shall we think it over?
Subtitles: Eclair Media