When the lamb opened the sixth seal,
there was a great earthquake.
The sun turned black like sackcloth.
The whole moon turned blood red.
The stars in the sky fell to earth, -
- as figs drop from a fig tree
when shaken by a strong wind.
PEOPLE IN THE SUN
-For you, my love.
-Oh, thank you!
-Svein, why do you never do that?
-Do what?
-You never give me roses anymore.
-Anymore?
I've never given you roses.
Are we going to the beach, or not?
This looks like a good spot.
Svein?
Svein!
Careful you don't have a heart attack.
Are you out of your mind?
-Come on, give me a kiss.
-Cut it out! This is a public beach!
Didn't you shave?
You look like a monkey.
I didn't have time.
Really?
You're on vacation, aren't you?
Stig, look at this lovely weather!
Don't you agree that it's lovely?
I told you to book early
to get the best view.
-I know, I'm sorry. My mistake.
-Yes.
-Candy?
-Yes, please.
God, this feels good!
-Can you feel the sun burning?
-Yeah.
It's probably the greenhouse effect.
I'm not sure I'm against that.
If you rent a cabin for two weeks,
you want the weather to be hot, right?
In 2000 years
everything will be desert anyway.
I used factor 12,
so I can lie here for 12 hours.
With all that hair,
you don't need sunscreen.
True.
-Ingrid, don't sing.
-Sorry.
-Can we go to that Midsummer party?
-Someone was mugged again.
-Where?
-In town.
"A gang of kids
beat a 35-year-old man unconscious."
-Why do you read things like that?
-"They stomped on his head."
"He is still in a coma."
Well, there you go.
I wonder...
I wonder what their brains look like.
I mean, stomping on the head
of someone you don't even know?
-Would it help if they knew them?
-I could at least understand that.
-Fucking view.
-I know. I'm sorry.
Stig?
I'm sorry!
-Hey.
-What?
This doctor said it's OK
for white people to lay in the sun, -
- but only for half an hour a day,
or they'll die.
A half-hour in the sun,
after last winter? We'd die anyway!
Only Negroes should live in
Scandinavia. They can handle the sun.
We whites can't handle anything.
Christ!
What the hell?
What's that?
A fish?
Look, Simon has caught a fish.
He has a disgusting fish...
What are you going to call it?
Nemo, maybe?
Didn't you like
that Nemo movie, Simon?
Didn't they tell us
he liked that Nemo movie, Svein?
Simon, who do you love more?
Mommy or daddy?
Mom comes first, then dad, right?
Come on.
Give mommy a kiss, Simon.
Yech!
What's that in your nose?
A booger! God, that's gross!
Get rid of it!
Did you get rid of it?
Is it gone?
Where did you put it?
In your mouth?
Gross! I can't deal with this.
Don't kiss mommy. Kiss daddy instead.
I feel nauseous.
-When's the bus leaving?
-There's still time.
Stig, everyone's leaving
for the party!
Stig!
Ingrid?
Beach tennis?
This will be fun!
It isn't stupid at all.
-It's a blast! Come on.
-But I'm no good at it.
-This is a good spot.
-I'm no good at ball games.
-Take this. Don't be silly.
-I don't know how to play.
Nonsense. It doesn't matter
if you're good or bad.
-Don't get mad.
-I won't.
-This is about having fun!
-Just don't get mad.
-I won't get mad.
-You will get mad.
-I won't!
-Now you're mad.
-Christ!
-I'm sorry!
Just shut up, you stupid cow!
Jesus!
Stig!
I apologize.
Cut that out!
Stop it.
Fix the radio instead.
-It's probably just the batteries.
-We got new ones yesterday.
Maybe it's that knob?
That one, back there?
-Fix it!
-We can enjoy ourselves in other ways.
We're on a public beach!
Stop...
-Simon's right there!
-Hi, Simon. What's up?
Why don't you go buy some ice cream?
Here's some money.
-Off you go!
-No, Simon.
-Have you lost your mind?
-Christ! Please, Siv!
The therapist said that we...
That we need to try. Right?
Svein?
What are you doing?
I'm being erotic.
This is...new, Svein.
It's just you and me.
And the sea.
Stig!
-Hi.
-You coming to the dance?
-No, I'm looking for my husband.
-This is the last bus. Join us!
It would have been nice, but...
-OK. Have fun.
-You, too.
-Anything else before we close?
-No, thank you.
Stig?
Stig!
I'm sorry! I didn't see anything.
I didn't think anyone was here.
I'm looking for my husband.
Stig.
Have you seen him?
He's about this tall.
-Have you seen him?
-No.
-You're Norwegian too?
-Yes, there are a few here.
You renting, or camping?
We're renting a cabin.
Maybe we're neighbors.
We've been here many times.
I'm not really sure why.
But you have to do something
during summer vacation.
I teach primary school.
-And your husband?
-He's a professor.
-Interesting. What does he teach?
-Psychology.
There he is!
Stig!
I'm sorry I shouted!
Stig says my voice is so ugly.
-Stig, look what I found.
-Hello.
-Svein.
-Stig.
-We also have a cabin.
-Which one?
The one with the gorgeous view.
-So you're in our cabin.
-That's the one we always rent.
But I forgot to book it.
I'm sorry.
Well, better luck next time.
It doesn't matter where we live.
We're outdoors all day, anyway.
So we can take your cabin?
-Do you come to the beach much?
-Oh, yes.
-There are lots of flies.
-That's true.
-But it's nice and warm.
-In the sun.
That's true.
Yeah.
Right, Stig? Stig is very concerned
about climate change.
-Global warming.
-That's what I told Svein.
I'm not sure it's a bad thing.
We like warm weather.
The end of the world is near, and all
the ladies worry about is getting tan!
Look, there's Simon
with his ice cream!
Can mommy have a taste?
-Simon. Mommy's little darling.
-Hi. Ingrid.
-This is Stig.
-Hi, I'm Stig.
Let mommy have a taste.
We paid for it!
Give me a break, Simon!
Fine, then say please.
Say please!
He's a quiet bastard.
He actually hasn't said a word
in three years.
He's not retarded,
he just doesn't talk.
You're not stupid, are you?
Just on the quiet side?
Fine.
Take it.
He's a wise boy. People are full
of shit, anyway. Isn't that right?
Would you like to play beach tennis
with Uncle Stig?
It's Midsummer Eve, and since
we have a nice view and you don't...
Why don't you bring some food
and celebrate the evening with us?
-Want to?
-Sure.
-We have to eat, anyway.
-Great!
Six o'clock, sharp.
Make sure everybody "cums" on time.
Get it?
-Svein...
-I said "cum".
-It was a joke.
There sure are lots of flies here.
-You got it, right?
-What?
The joke.
"Cum" on time?
I'm so slow on the uptake.
See you.
Stig!
Great.
Cum as you are!
-What the hell did you do that for?
-It'll be fun. Trust me.
-Simon? Where is Simon?
-Probably playing somewhere.
Simon?
-Do we have everything we need?
-I'm sure we do.
-Do we have parsley?
-Do we really need parsley?
-Maybe there's parsley at the store.
-Don't make a fuss.
Remember to hang up the towels
when we get back.
Hi there.
Hi.
You eating wild strawberries?
I'm not sure they're ripe yet.
You don't want a tummyache, do you?
Where are mommy and daddy?
Are you lost?
You don't know where you are!
Here. Uncle Stig will help you.
Look at this.
Here is...
Here's Europe.
And tiny Norway.
And across the border is Sweden.
Where we are.
So now you can run on home!
"You can't have my swim ring!"
You sure don't talk much!
Well, you're probably better off.
This was fun!
Here, have some candy. Go on!
Have some candy!
-Is a storm on its way?
-There isn't a cloud in the sky.
Right.
Never mind.
Do you have parsley?
Fresh parsley?
Parsley?
Sure.
There aren't many people here tonight,
so it will probably be...quiet.
Would you like anything else?
Ouch!
CLOSED
-Hi, Stig.
-Hi.
Some view, isn't it?
Stig, check out the view!
-Stig?
-Fucking view!
I'm sorry.
-Have you seen Simon?
-No.
-Darling, look at this.
-Is it Simon?
Look!
The sea!
What?
What about it?
It's the sea. It makes you
feel so small. And humble.
Simon?
-Simon?
-Siv, look at the sea.
The view.
All the blueness.
-I feel like painting.
-You can't paint.
-I'd like to.
-No, you wouldn't.
-No, maybe not, but...
-Simon?
-There must be something I'd like to do.
-Look at postcards?
-Yeah. With pictures of the sea.
-Right. Simon?
There you are.
Be careful not to fall down.
Siv, if I just swam
straight out here...
-You can't even swim.
-Just imagine!
You cheated to get your swim badge.
You walked on the bottom.
-But still...
-Did you hang up those towels?
-I haven't had time.
-Haven't had time?
Were you planning on letting them
marinate in the bag until tomorrow?
Come on, Siv!
-Relax. We're on vacation!
-You might be!
Should we bring some food?
We could bring a melon
and the bread rolls.
That Svein is quite a flirt,
have you noticed?
Stig!
Stig?
Simon, come here.
Simon, what do you think
if daddy swam straight out here?
Where do you think I'd end up?
Scotland?
America, maybe!
I don't know, either.
Simon, are you still wearing
that swim ring?
There's no risk of drowning
here on shore, so you can take it off.
-Talk to him, Svein.
-Simon, take it...
-Just let him wear it.
-He's had it on since we got here.
Sometimes it feels like
he's drifting away from us.
He's going to be with us 24/7
for the next four weeks.
-It isn't our fault he's like this.
-I know! It's nobody's fault!
I just want him to take off that ring
because it looks so damned idiotic!
Siv.
-Siv...
-Never mind!
What is it?
Your eye is drooping.
Drooping?
Don't say it's drooping!
Is it drooping a lot?
-You should see a doctor.
-There aren't any doctors here.
There aren't any doctors here!
Fine.
Let it droop.
Svein? Isn't it weird that
that cabin isn't in use?
-Maybe someone will come next week.
-Do we have everything we need?
Melon, ham, sausages, shrimp...
-Are you wearing that?
-What do you mean?
That!
There's hair sticking out everywhere!
If only some of that hair
was on your head.
-Hi! Welcome.
-Thank you!
What an amazing spread!
We didn't have a lot.
Just a melon and some bread rolls.
-Are you on your own?
-No, Stig's...there!
Look at this spread!
-Welcome!
-Thanks.
-He's so incredibly cute.
-Thank you.
-Simon, would you like some melon?
-No, he wouldn't.
He hates it.
Have a seat! I gave you the view,
since you don't have one of your own.
Let me propose a toast.
There's schnapps for everyone.
-Cheers!
-Cheers.
Svein, 16.
What do you mean by that?
We always say how old we are,
when we were born, stuff like that.
I thought we could reveal
when we had our sexual debut.
We need an ice-breaker.
It'll be fun!
Come on, let's toast.
Svein, 16.
Cheers!
You're next, Siv.
Siv, 18.
Really?
That was late!
-Stig, go ahead.
-Stig. Cheers.
Stig, you party pooper!
Ingrid, your turn.
Ingrid, 14.
-Christ!
-That early? How did that come about?
I was raped.
Well, shit happens.
All right, let's sit down.
-Maybe we shouldn't do this.
-No, it's fine.
She says it's fine. Sit down.
We can handle this.
-I remember Midsummer as a child.
-Really?
Dad was always drunk
and mom always cried.
-Cheers.
-Cheers!
-Anyone know any summer songs?
-No, no.
-I know one.
-Let's hear it.
Ingrid...
Don't sing.
-Did I sing out of tune?
-No, it was great!
-I'm sorry.
-Don't bite your fingernails.
-Christ!
-She does it constantly.
She always does it in public.
Doing it in your room is fine, -
- but in the company of others,
you must realize it looks idiotic?
-Sorry, I do it all the time.
-It's OK, Inger.
- Ingrid.
-That's what I said. Inger...id.
-Cheers, everybody.
-Cheers.
Do any of you have any hobbies?
Mine are smoking and tanning.
Both give you cancer.
Just my luck.
I gave up smoking.
But I keep thinking
about starting up again.
Especially if something bad happens,
like Stig dying.
-But I can't hope for that.
-Why not?
Yeah, why not!
I'm sorry. I apologize, Stig.
I don't know what came over me.
Dig in before the flies do!
-Is that bread fresh?
-Yes, sir.
-Stig, no white bread for you.
-One slice is OK.
He's on a gluten-free diet.
White bread makes him angry.
I've never heard of that before.
Anyway, help yourselves.
-Maybe this was a bad idea?
-No, it'll be fun.
Nothing will happen. Trust me,
I know what I'm talking about.
-What was that?
-Nothing. Eat!
-Maybe they need help?
-No one here needs help.
Help!
-There's someone there.
-Just eat.
-Don't look at me, I don't work here.
-Button your shirt.
-Can someone help me?
-Crap, she's Danish.
Hello!
-See what it is, Svein.
-Why me?
-Because you're a man!
-Of course.
Hello?
-Finally!
-We thought we heard something.
-The reception is closed.
-They closed early today.
That's OK. I'm staying in Cabin 11.
Do you know where it is?
-You are very kind.
-My pleasure.
-They're quite heavy. Need help?
-No, I'm fine.
Would you like a caramel?
Simon doesn't accept candy
from strangers.
Of course not.
How silly of me.
Svein, what's that old hag doing here?
I'm staying in number 11.
We're neighbors. Won't that be nice?
I'll just lift -
- these suitcases onto my terrace.
Please keep eating.
My name is Mrs. Sorensen.
It's strange -
- that they weren't waiting for me
at the reception.
They knew I was coming.
They must have been busy.
OK...
Here I am.
With a locked cabin and no key.
-Don't you have a key?
-No, but that's OK.
The reception will open in the morning.
It's warm out, so I'll be fine.
-You going to sit there all night?
-What?
-Are you going to sit there all night?
-Yes, I'm fine.
30%% of all people get cancer
at some point in their life.
-Should we invite her over?
-Why?
It isn't our fault she has cancer.
Please dig in.
We have salmon, shrimp, ham...
-I'd love some salmon.
-I told you this would be nice!
-Cheers, everybody.
-Cheers!
Svein, 16.
Isn't it incredible how the sun
is shining, even though it's so late?
-Isn't it lovely?
-Yes, the sun is wonderful.
I read in the paper that a man was
scorched to death lying in the sun.
It's true.
He was actually fried to death.
Please eat!
Don't let me disturb you. Eat!
-Why don't we invite her over?
-No way!
She can buy her own life,
like everyone else.
Some people
simply lack social antennas.
This is the Midsummer from hell!
Simon, come eat!
Come on.
Come and eat, Simon!
My love, he isn't a dog.
Here.
You look so nice.
Families are a great thing.
But I'm sure it's very demanding
to have children.
Simon doesn't live at home
during the school year.
We couldn't handle
that responsibility.
But he's with us every weekend.
Help yourselves!
We have ham here, too.
Go easy on the shrimp, Simon.
Simon, easy on the shrimp.
Put some back.
I said no more shrimp!
You'll get a tummyache.
Mommy wants to party and have fun
for once, not take care of you!
Do as mommy says.
Don't put all of them back!
You have to eat!
-Svein, do something!
-Do as mommy says.
It's hotter out now
than it was at midday.
And take off that swim ring!
You can't eat with...
Take it off, dammit!
Let me pull it over your head.
Take it off!
Don't move!
Calm down, Siv.
Don't just sit there!
Talk, chat, converse!
-Is that too much to ask for?
-Not at all.
Imagine that it's summer.
Time sure does fly!
-Last summer wasn't long ago.
-A year.
Has it been that long?
There you go!
We can't do this all summer.
He needs to eat.
-Don't worry. He'll be fine.
-Fine!
Simon, you just ruined
mommy's Midsummer Eve.
Now mommy will be upset all night.
I hope you're happy!
Time sure does fly!
I think it does, at least.
-We're getting older.
-Yeah.
Saturday night
is no longer parties and fun.
-Instead, it's doing laundry.
-Don't be so cynical.
Your only worry is what kind
of charcoal the barbecue needs!
Simon, come taste this lovely ham.
Open your mouth, Simon.
Open it.
Just open it.
Open it!
Open your mouth, Simon.
I said, open it!
You will eat this ham!
Open your mouth!
-Can't you see you're hurting him?
-He would have said so.
-But he can't talk.
-Yes, he can! He just chooses not to.
Let's see if this hurts!
Stop it!
He doesn't have to eat right now.
Fine, but it's your responsibility if
the doctors ask why he doesn't eat.
Fine by me.
You're witnesses.
-Where were we?
-Time flies.
Nothing works out as planned and all
you want to do is die. Cheers!
Cheers, everybody.
Svein, 16.
-Take me, for example.
-Not now, darling.
I never got to attend art school.
Instead, I took the safe route
and worked in an office for 17 years.
Not that it was my dream.
Then I mustered up the courage to
quit my job and apply to art school.
400 applicants.
Six were admitted.
I was one of them.
Then what happened?
I got pregnant.
I got pregnant
with mommy's little Simon.
Mommy's little Simon.
-Remember what you said, Svein?
-No.
"You always get a second chance."
But I didn't.
Stop biting.
Anyway...
Cheers, everybody.
Cheers!
She's actually right.
We never have enough time.
Yesterday was Christmas,
today it's Midsummer, you know?
Cheers.
Perhaps God is in heaven
pushing the fast-forward button.
What did you say?
God is tired of the world.
So he's fast-forwarding us to the end.
What a horrible thing to say.
-I can't understand Danish.
-Who can?
Look at the sky.
Look at the clouds. Look at that sky!
This is what it looks like when
God arrives with his heavenly host.
-Down the hatch!
-There's that rumbling again.
-It's done that for days.
-Probably just thunder.
Probably just a phenomenon.
Look at the sky! The clouds! Imagine
how exciting if he came tonight.
That would suck.
We have three weeks of vacation left.
Like I care, with the view we have.
Who's this "he" you referred to?
God!
That's either Mozart or Beethoven.
Aren't we humans extraordinary?
We always think we have a choice.
Just like the Jews.
First, they await their savior
for thousands of years.
And when he finally arrives,
they crucify him!
Then they sit and wait
for another 2000 years! Great odds!
Like someone will volunteer when they
know what happened to the last one!
I don't get it!
-Are you talking about Jews?
-Some characters, huh?
-I'm Jewish.
-I see.
-A Polish Jew.
-Polish!
I live in Denmark. But don't think
I clean houses for small change.
I was in Auschwitz as a child.
You could call that an experience.
-I'm sorry.
-It's not your fault.
Auschwitz isn't your fault.
You weren't even born.
You got that right.
It actually isn't our fault.
Right.
But the Serb concentration camps
in Bosnia, -
- or Guantanamo,
are harder to dismiss.
Give me a break!
It isn't our fault
that they keep bickering!
Fine.
Have it your way.
But I can understand God
fast-forwarding, to find the culprits.
-Excuse me, what damned God?
-God! You know who!
Here we're expected
to believe in a God -
- who will return to judge
the living and the dead.
-I don't believe in God.
-Me neither!
What do you believe in, then?
If you don't mind me asking.
I have no clue.
I don't know what I believe in.
-What about you?
-I... It's difficult to explain.
I believe in...
Summer?
Fine.
So that's what you believe in.
I guess that's settled.
I just felt a raindrop.
It can't start raining now!
She was mistaken.
I guarantee it won't rain. Trust me!
Christ!
The food. The food!
Ingrid!
Ingrid, don't sing!
Don't sing!
I'm sorry.
-Where are you going?
-To take a shower.
Where did Simon go?
Simon!
-Simon?
-Simon!
-Simon, where are you?
Simon?
-There he is!
-Has he been there all along?
-I don't know.
-At least he's here now.
It was raining blood!
Talk about bad weather.
They didn't mention that
in the brochure.
They could have put that under
miscellaneous: "Rains blood".
I'm sure it was just
some...phenomenon.
What kind of phenomenon?
Probably iron particles in the air
that turn the rain red.
-Seriously? Could that explain it?
-Yes, I think so.
What a relief!
In that case
I'll go in and get some more food.
-It's so light out.
-Maybe it's the midnight sun.
This far south?
Look!
A shooting star!
Look how beautiful!
Finally something nice.
It's just a meteorite
hitting our atmosphere.
Sorry.
I didn't know.
Or it could be a space station
that dropped something.
Like a bag of astronaut excrement?
Give me a break!
Astronaut crap?
Some people say all that space debris
is dangerous for space shuttles.
If a bag of crap hits a shuttle,
the shuttle will be disintegrated!
-Come on!
-Isn't that funny?
I'm sure you're right, but I've always
felt there was someone out there.
Whether it's God, Buddha
or a spaceship, I don't know.
It's probably Elvis.
-Did you know Elvis had a brother?
-He did?
Twelvis!
Get it?
Elvis, twelvis, thirtis...
-Sure you need more to drink, darling?
-Go screw yourself, darling.
-Hear that?
-What?
Locusts.
Weird, they normally occur
later in the year.
Look!
-The lady!
Hey, lady!
Lady!
-Maybe she's asleep?
-No, she'd fall off the chair.
-We can't leave her there.
-Maybe she isn't asleep.
-Maybe she's had a heart attack.
-You mean she's dead?
Typical! We're finally having some fun
and the old hag dies on us.
That is so typical!
In this heat she'll start smelling.
-Svein, do something.
-Why me?
Because you're a man.
-I'll wake her up.
-Good for you, Stig.
Hello.
Wake up!
Rescue me from the mire.
Deliver me from those who hate me.
Do not let the floodwaters engulf me -
- or the pit close its mouth over me.
Answer me, Lord,
out of the goodness of your love.
In your great mercy turn to me.
Do not hide your face
from your servant.
Answer me quickly,
for I am in trouble.
Make haste to answer me....
Is it you?
All of you?
She wasn't dead.
Cheers, ma'am.
-Are you going to drink more?
-Till there's nothing left, my dear.
Sometimes I wish I didn't know you.
Look! Another shooting star.
Or whatever it is.
And the stars in the sky fell to
earth, as figs drop from a fig tree -
- when shaken by a strong wind.
What is that?
I watched as he opened the sixth seal.
There was a great earthquake.
The sun turned black like sackcloth,
the whole moon turned blood red.
That's so beautiful.
-Don't sing!
-Sorry.
What seal is that?
When he opened the seventh seal, -
- there was silence in heaven
for about half an hour.
The Book of Revelation,
chapter 8, verse 1.
I have no clue what
that old hag is talking about.
I have a great idea.
Let's go for a swim! A midnight dip.
Give me one good reason.
It's a sinful summer night.
A little bare skin. Come on, Stig!
Let's do it now!
It's Midsummer and all!
See some pussy and titties,
know what I mean?
Yeah, fuck it!
Let's go cool off.
Go ahead, so Ingrid and I
can get some peace and quiet.
You can't stay here! It can't just be
us two. You have to join us.
I'd love to join you.
-You?
-We won't need bathing suits, will we?
Hang on.
I feel a little queasy.
A little weak. And my throat's sore.
Maybe I shouldn't swim.
I'm ready!
Stop!
I know what you're up to.
I don't understand.
I know your type.
A lonely old hag like you.
You rent a cabin and expect
everything to be nice.
You couldn't be more fucking wrong!
We've rented cabins,
but we're not together!
-I thought we were swimming.
-Like hell!
The line goes right here.
You're there, and I'm here.
-Enough is enough!
-I didn't mean to upset you.
-Don't take it that way.
-Don't be so fucking sentimental.
And stop biting! That's how
you put someone in their place.
Are we going swimming, or not?
Grab that bottle. Come on.
-Jesus Christ.
-I know. I'm sorry.
How can you stay with him?
Mother always said
you eat what's on your plate.
That's how she lived her life,
and the same goes for me.
We live 70-80 years. It's just
a matter of enduring those years.
Give me a break!
Never mind what he said.
Come and eat with us.
If there's some left over,
I wouldn't mind a little bite.
Weren't you a little harsh with her?
-Don't be so sentimental.
-I'm sorry.
-Holy shit! That's disgusting.
-And they say there isn't enough fish?
-What are we waiting for?
-Nothing.
So have you known each other long?
Who, us?
No, we just met today.
You don't know each other?
I've been married to Svein
for 20 years and hardly know him.
But you love him.
Love Svein?
I don't know.
I guess I do. Probably.
He was the one I chose,
so he became my life.
He was the one that ended up
on my plate, so to speak.
-Cheers.
-It sure is hot.
-Yeah.
It's like a free jacuzzi!
-Doesn't it smell strange?
-The water, you mean?
I was just thinking...
No, never mind.
-Ready?
-Sure!
Three, two, one!
-Strange light!
-Maybe it's...
-Astronaut poo!
-That hit a space shuttle?
What did you call those little red...
-Iron particles.
-Right! Iron particles!
And you don't have any children?
No, we've tried many times
but without success.
I think there's something wrong
with me. Ever since my abortion...
I didn't mean to...
It's OK.
It was a long time ago.
It's all right.
I was only...
17 years old.
The doctor said
everything would be OK.
When I came to,
they gave me a glass of juice.
And two sandwiches, cut diagonally.
Then the doctor came and said
there had been some complications, -
- but that she thought
everything was OK.
But I don't think everything was OK.
I never was able
to get pregnant again.
Fuck!
That doctor should have been killed!
Maybe you're right.
What about you?
It's a long story.
We have plenty of time.
Don't we, Ingrid?
Yes, perhaps we do.
Or perhaps not.
It's sticky.
-It's so damn quiet.
-Yeah.
-Like being alone in the world.
-Yeah. Imagine if we were!
If that were the case,
we should swap wives -
- and nail both of them. To get
more genetic variation, I mean.
What did your wife see in you?
I worked in the home help service
for 30 years.
And for 15 of those 30 years
I took care of a woman called Karin.
Karin would wait for me
at her kitchen table.
She'd sit there
with her big, black, inquisitive eyes.
Every morning,
she got out of bed and got dressed.
And then she sat down and waited.
When I came she would smile,
as if saying, "Have you come for me?"
And one day it hit me.
I could never go back to Karin again.
Because it wasn't me
she was waiting for.
She was waiting for someone
to come for her, but no one came.
Like it says in the Bible. This is
what the end of time will be like.
Two men will be in the field.
One will be taken and the other left.
Two women will be at a mill.
One will be taken, the other left.
What are you talking about?
Two men at the beach.
Two women at a table talking.
It may be too late. God has come
for those who belong to his flock.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
I don't understand anything.
But that's nothing new.
Ingrid, let's go inside
and do something nice.
This weather
is totally fucking unreliable.
-Where's Stig?
-Stig and Svein went swimming.
-Where did the lady go?
-The lady... I don't know.
I'm so scared.
Siv, hold me!
Sorry, but I'm not
a very cuddly person.
Maybe you'd rather...
Maybe I can get you a sweater?
Or a blanket?
How about some cognac?
Let me get some cognac.
Stay here.
-It wouldn't take long.
-Shut up.
We're talking about
the future of mankind.
-You're not fucking my wife!
-I'd consider it my duty.
I can't fuck,
I have prostate cancer!
It's spreading rapidly.
I can't bring myself to tell her.
I'm sorry to hear that.
-Don't be so sentimental.
-I'm sorry.
But on average,
intercourse only lasts two minutes!
Simon?
Help!
Get them off me, Siv!
That's all I needed.
-Do something!
-Like what?
Get them off me!
They're disgusting
Cognac.
Cheers, nice to meet you.
Likewise.
Stig!
Oh, Stig!
What a mess!
This party sucks.
Is something wrong?
I'm turning in.
-Did you put Simon to bed?
-Didn't you?
Cut it out.
You put him to bed.
-Is that my job, suddenly?
-I'm asking if you put him to bed!
What the fuck?
You talk like it's my responsibility.
It's just as much yours.
You blame me for everything!
-Simon isn't there.
-What are you talking about?
-He isn't there.
-Of course he is! For fuck's sake.
-Simon!
-Simon, answer us!
-What happened?
-Simon's gone.
-He was sitting on that rock.
-Simon!
-Wait! We have to think rationally!
Think rationally! There must
be a reasonable explanation, OK?
-Let's start with where!
-He might be hiding.
Where?
-Jesus Christ.
-We have to think. Think.
He can't be far off.
The lady!
The lady took him!
-The lady!
-To the reception!
Stig!
Where is the reception?
Did we run the wrong way?
No, this is right.
Simon!
Stig, hold me.
-Simon, my boy! Are you here?
-Oh, my God.
-I want my baby!
-Simon!
Simon, where are you?
Maybe they're down by the cabins.
-I wouldn't know!
-But maybe they are!
Svein!
Svein, you have to wake up!
We have to look for him!
-Find him!
-What the hell is going on?
I don't know.
I'm not a scientist, I'm a humanist.
Simon!
Answer when mommy and daddy
call for you!
Don't go.
Don't go!
I've never felt safe on my own.
What is it?
-Stop biting.
-Sorry.
Simon!
Simon, where are you?
-I don't understand this.
-Everything's gone!
Daddy's beloved boy, come out!
This isn't funny anymore.
Daddy loves you, Simon.
I love you so much!
-Simon!
-That isn't how you pronounce it.
-You pronounce his name wrong!
-What are you talking about?
-You can't pronounce your son's name!
-What is your problem?
Our Father, who lives in...
Our Father, who art in...
-Where was he again?
-In heaven.
In heaven.
So this is where you are.
Come.
It's time to go.
Hold my hand, and you'll see
that everything will be just fine.
-I'm holding your hand.
-Indeed you are.
You are holding my hand.
Subtitles: Tor Overbo
and Nick Norris