PEOPLE OUT THERE
Go on.
Yan, c'mon...
Yan, hurry up!
Keep a client on as long as possible,
every minute costs money.
Don't be rude to a client
and don't fall asleep while working.
What if she needs to strip?
- That's the most she'll have to do.
She'd smile nicely,
keep conversation going.
And when he comes
ask how's he feeling.
Say you'll miss him. Got it?
How much you gonna pay?
I'm just starting my business.
Prices are low so that we can compete.
60% for you, the rest is ours.
Still got any questions?
I've heard clients often fall for girls,
take them on and get married.
So don't forget about your own prospects.
Hey, Chocolate, you promised, no fucking...
- Have you lost your brains?
How they gonna screw your sister,
through the computer?
OK, Chocolate, I gotcha.
You still here? Get lost.
What am I paying you for, Sanya, for what?
Do you hear me?
Go back to work!
I need fifty sacks by the end of the day.
This scene really cracks me up!
Is he Bullet's bro?
Shorty, you watching this
for the first time?
I forgot it.
What's so hard to answer?
Yeah, it's his bro.
Shut up and let us watch the movie.
Chocolate, what are we
gonna do with the camera?
I got a buyer.
But I can't do it tonight!
Who killed him?
Shut up. Why can't you?!
No, seriously, who killed him?
- That's the last time you're coming over.
And take off your hood.
You are not at home.
Listen, Chocolate,
when can we sell the camera?
Can you for once
do something without me?
Then why are you
pulling a fucking scam on us?
I've got the new business now,
I can't deal with you morons.
Why are you freaking out?
I got a buyer,
you just need to show up.
But we're always doing it together!
- Chill out, we'll go over there.
Just don't harass him too much,
I owe him one.
What if he harasses us?
Chill out. We'll do it as I say.
Look.
- Put that shit down.
We're coming from Chocolate. To you?
- To me. Come over here.
What do you have there?
- A camera.
How much do you want?
- Thirty.
Thirty-five.
- Thirty-thirty-five.
Forty.
- Thirty and we go our separate ways.
It's ridiculous.
Give us forty or we're gone.
Thirty-five. Make up your mind!
Forty.
- So is it forty or thirty?
Forty... I can give you thirty
and you leave it here.
Bye.
- Bye.
Yan, what the fuck?
Thirty it is.
Deal. If it's thirty, then thirty.
Done. It's a deal.
What are you doing?
What is it?
- Look at it!
Let me help you.
Is it working?
It's working!
Now I'll know everything about you!
I turned on this youtube...
Fucking shit...
And I see Emelyanenko there,
he's this wrestler. And then...
Russian?
- Sure, he's Russian.
What he was doing...
He was not even speeding up.
He just stood,
hard as a rock, to fight...
What you looking at?
- Pedestrian crossing.
What's that?
For real pederasts!
Listen, eh... So I watch him...
There's this really fat dude,
dunno, kinda American.
Sowhat?
Fat like all the Americans.
And there this black guy, really dark...
Hold on... Look at that creep.
May I ask you?
Can you tell me, what time it is?
I don't have a watch.
Look on your cell.
- I don't have a cell.
Such a pretty girl, modest, too.
Got any cash on you?
Look, the cellphone! C'mon!
So maybe you've got money, too?
Don't bullshit me. If I find it
I'm gonna smash your cunt face!
Give me back the phone!
- What's that?
If you got it out,
so fucking stab me now!
That's it! Let's get lost!
Shorty, go home!
Got the cell? Where the fuck is it?
- Let's go, I got it.
Yan, what's wrong?
Why did you have to fuck
this shit up in our neighborhood?
Just ripped this sucker off.
C'mon! Did you see that fuck-face?
'Got some cash?'-'No, I don't'.
Like a dumb mummy. A dumbass.
Hey, Yan, why'd you split yesterday?
Ilona was pissed off.
I told her, we are over.
Cause of her new job.
She's no hooker!
Not a virgin, either. I'd never
let my sister work for Chocolate.
She's not fucking anyone there,
so she's no slut!
We all need some cash.
Look at your gramps-
he's worked his ass off all his life!
My grandpa is a scientist!
He hasn't shown his ass to anyone.
Without your sis, this fat Chocolate
is not gonna get any damn dough.
Ilona is getting more cash for a week's job
than my mom, who's slaving away 24/7.
I'll get some cash and leave for England.
Then you'll see me making dough.
He'll buy himself a new wheel and a crib
using your sister's and your bitch's ass.
And you'll be left with rubber dicks.
I've got to take a piss.
Go around the corner.
Chickening out?
Let's bet five Lats,
you can't take a leak in that house.
C'mon, old man...
Well?
Everything's fine?
Did you see the loaded bitch coming in?
Really! They came by that car.
What? Didn't see shit.
So, did you piss?
- Leave me alone!
She looked like a queen.
Like she didn't give a fuck about me.
Checked me out... But turn round
the corner, she'd fuck me gladly.
You wanna rape her?
- Are you a total dickhead? Why rape?
I'd kill all those mother-fucker rapists!
Shoved it up their asses hard.
What's wrong with you?
Move it.
You don't have enough cash anyway,
unless you lift some shit... Let's go!
In London only Indians
are wearing this crap!
You piss me off with your London!
You haven't ever been there,
you don't know shit about it!
Hey, Yan!
Recognize me?
It's me, Robert.
You used to call me Robot at school.
Ah, Robert, hey!
What's up?
I'm cool.You?
Come and sit with us! We'll chat.
Sure, just a bit later.
- Ok, but do come over!
Yeah, sure.
- Long time no see!
Man, 'long time no see'...
Who's this Robot guy?
- My classmate. Just a regular guy.
Regular guy. 'Listen, come over'...
- My favorite song! Let's dance.
Let's dance.
Nope, I don't dance with hookers.
Have you lost it totally?
I'm not a hooker.
Oh, yes, not a hooker...
Look at yourself. No bitch will put out
for you, either! You look like a hobo.
And what do you think you look like?
Fuck you!
Fuck yourself!
Asshole!
You wanted to rape my sister?!
I'll kill you, motherfucker!
What's your fucking problem?
I'm not your friend anymore, prick!
Let's go!
Here, have some!
How you feeling?
- Awesome.
She's my best friend's sister.
I know him for years.
How could he believe that whore
that I could do something like this?
It beats me why you got
involved with that scum at all.
At school you were just a regular guy.
At school...
Gonna take a leak.
Here's our pretty boy. Cute, eh?
Why did you stare at me?!
I turn you on?
Oh, the dude looks dumbfounded!
Are you mute, faggot?!
Shit...
Hey Yan, what happened?
It's him!
Stop, stop this, it's my turn!
I'm gonna finish him off.
Do you know who you are fighting against?
Run, run, run away!
Robert, come on, let's go.
Hey you, come here!
Me?
Yes, you come here!
But I've done nothing.
C'mon, hurry up!
I failed to bring you up as a decent man.
It's my fault.
You didn't make a good grandson,
me, a good grandpa.
At least your mom didn't live to see it.
Why are you so upset?
It's just a regular roundup.
I just happened to be there.
Don't smoke in front of me.
Gramps!
Yan, why I can't get
a decent night's sleep?
I really need to talk to you.
- I'm so fed up with you.
Please, it's really important.
Yan, I'm cold!
Are you making fun of me?
Grandpa, I'm scared.
I can't go on like this...
The older I am, the harder it gets.
Drop this nonsense.
For starters, don't spend
any more time with those bastards.
Eat like a man, you are not a pig!
Why are you not eating?
- I've had enough for a lifetime.
Sit down, tea's getting cold.
Just by chance I found
a photo of your mother.
Wanna hear a funny story?
It was in '83 or in '86.
Our boss, the head of laboratory,
sent us on a business trip.
Not to Ukraine or Kazakhstan
but to Belgium.
We had to participate in a symposium
about the latest achievements
in rock and soil science.
In those times taking a trip abroad,
say nothing of Belgium, was quite an event.
Your mother asked me
to get her a dress in Antwerp.
I spent a whole day
looking for a cheap store.
Don't think I was a cheapskate
but our daily allowance was 10 rubles.
And for that money you couldn't
get even a can of beer.
Then I bumped into some store-
the clothes there cost pennies.
So, I got myself a suit
and a dress for your mom.
Week later she called me
to tell that she washed the dress
and it turned into a mush.
Later somebody told me the store
was really meant for...corpses.
What do you mean-for corpses?
Well you can buy
disposable clothes for the funeral.
They were made of paper.
Where did you get your new cell?
- Bought it.
Hey, Chocolate, cool!
Nothing really, chewing...
No, not today.
My grandpa got into the hospital.
No, nothing serious.
Sure, I'll go there.
OK, see ya tomorrow, bye.
Gramps!
Wait, where are you going?
Shit, tastes like pig's barf.
Shorty, tell me something, eh?
So listen, we have a guy in our class.
He's in the seventh grade,
but he's almost 18 now.
No, really?
He's a weirdo.
No brains whatsoever.
Takes him five seconds
to figure out how much 9 times 9 is.
So once, in gym class,
we had to run around the park.
We run and run,
passing a kids' playground.
And then I see him
with the friend, he's 16, too.
But it's 7th grade,
so he should be like 13.
I run and I saw them
smoking under the apple tree.
Oh, check it out?
It's Chocolate.
He's got new wheels! C'mon!
Man, you like my new car?
See the multi-function steering wheel,
tiptronic and carputer...
Stop bugging us!
You gonna break it!
Beats me,
why you gotta touch everything?
Got itchy fingers?
I'll scratch them for you!
A CD player for 6 CDs,
you can turn it on like this, whoops!
I can listen to 6 CDs or like
two songs from each disc at the same time.
Hey, it's Yan!
Fuck, why did you slow down? Go!
Chocolate, keep moving!
You two had a fight?
- Yes.
He wanted to rape Ilona!
Are you a total retard?
You are all just fucking morons!
Sabina, what does it matter
who's driving the car!
If Albert sees this, he won't like it!
That's my problem, not yours!
Why are you so worried
what he's gonna think or say?
Sabina, please sit in the car!
Well, Ok!
I really don't understand
why you wish him bad.
I'm not asking you
why you have to kiss his ass, right?
It's enough.
We are going out of town tomorrow.
Remember? I'll pick you up.
I do remember I have my birthday tomorrow.
I really hope he won't show up there.
Don't talk like this about your father.
He's almost a saint!
You do believe in it?
Saints don't get married a second time.
Pull up right here.
I want to take a walk.
Hi, I think you've dropped your key.
- Thank you.
This young man
found my key and returned it.
Thank you so much!
May I walk you to your place?
You can leave your coat
in our coatroom.
No, no, I'm fine like this!
Is it your first time here?
- Yes.
How did you find out about us?
- I have lots of friends here.
There.
Holy Spirit, give us the Word of God
to strengthen our faith.
Enter deeply into our soul and spirit.
Let us proceed to the Throne of Grace,
so we can be blessed with your help.
We need You, Lord.
We come to You and plead You-
share this night with us.
Lord, give us Love.
We ask you in the name of Jesus:
touch each one of us.
Fill us with wisdom and strength.
Make us victorious in the name of Jesus.
Bless me, Jesus!
Now shake hands with your
neighbor and say 'Welcome!'
Good evening.
- Hello.
This year is proclaimed as the year
of prosperity, influence, and growth.
We are positive that this year
will bring us lots of surprises
because God has prepared the reward
for those who are humble before Him.
Our new government has declared that
we are a European democratic society,
based on Christian values.
Christianity is our wealth and redemption.
The one who deeply believes
in God Almighty and in himself
will be successful in this life
and the devil will not seduce him.
You may ask what is evil?
And I will give you an answer:
poverty is evil, disease is evil,
everything that makes
human beings unhappy.
Lies, betrayal, greed...
All these are deadly sins
described in the Bible.
But there are always people who are lost,
who need our help and the help of God.
Beloved brothers and sisters,
a man has came here for our help.
He wants to learn how to live.
Yes,Yes! God has kissed his son
and brought him to our church.
Son, don't run away
from your redemption!
My son!
Yes, you!
Don't be afraid, I don't bite.
Come up to the stage.
I want to help you, I see
that you are lost and scared.
Release your heart
from poison and come on up!
Brothers and sisters, let's show
our support to the prodigal son!
Take off your baggy sack,
show us, as you are.
This young man has done many wrongs.
Brothers, this young man is lost,
his life lacks any sense.
He's a thief!
- What you doin'?
Yes, yes-he's a thief!
But, my dear friends, don't plant
seeds of fear and hatred in your hearts.
Don't let Satan enter your hearts.
We have to love him in the same way
we'd love our friend, brother or son.
God guided him here, to us,
cause everyone needs help!
This is our mission-
to teach this lost soul
the path of Truth,
just like anyone else who seeks it.
My son, what's your name?
Don't worry,
it's not a police interrogation.
Petya!
Petya! Like Apostle Peter.
He too renounced God,
but Jesus forgave him
and I'll do the same!
Now repeat after me:
I'm a sinner, a thief,
I've done many wrong things.
I'm a sinner, done many wrong things.
I'm a thief, I'm a sinner,
I renounce Satan and everyone
else who was my friend.
I'm a sinner...
- I'm a thief!
I'm a thief and I renounce Satan
and everyone else who was my friend.
I open my heart with love to Jesus
and promise to lead a decent life.
Hallelujah!
Brothers and sisters,
within these walls, Jesus is among us!
Wanna see something cool, Cracker?
Watch this... Here's a movie, whoops!
Split screen, whoops,
and you can watch a concert.
Look, what a pretty woman.
Whoops! A pause!
What a cunt, eh?
Why d'you fucking need it?
You're not gonna watch it.
I've got the sameTV at home,
only a bit bigger.
I've got a new girl starting tomorrow.
Looks exactlylike her!
And your baby girl? When she grows up,
you gonna hire her, too?
My favorite scene with Tupac!
I heard his last song yesterday.
Don't bullshit me, he's dead.
- Think I'm fucking with you?
They told on the radio,
it's his new song.
Stop talking shit at my house!
Chocolate, you really think
I'm total moron?!
Think I heard a corpse singing?
Maybe you heard a corpse.
Fuck you, bitch!
Cracker, chill out.
He's not dead, he's not.
No, Cracker,
Tupac was shot dead for real.
What's all this bullshit in my house?
Go suck your dick, with your TV,
with your car and all your shit!
How comes your wife
is not working for you?
Cause she's not a fucking whore!
Mother-fucker.
She's not a hooker? Look at your
baby girl, the blue-eyed blonde!
Get out of my house!
Told ya, out!
- Shorty, let's go!
Out! You, too!
Dickheads!
Wanna hear something awesome?
In Moscow cops
freed a girl from slavery.
All her teeth were pulled out!
- Again you and your creepy shit.
Wait, you'll never guess
why she didn't have any teeth.
Ok, so what's so funny?
She was the most popular hooker
among the golden boys.
Her blow-job cost 400 euros!
Would Ilona agree to give head
for 500 euros, but live without teeth?
Just shut up!
Shorty, shut up!
Like some Parisian, in that coat.
Looks like he's found a job.
Like a Parisian...
Can you just shut up!
Shouldn't you be going now
to show your naked ass?
Unlike you, I'm working
and not sleeping with anyone.
Working... Watch out, so I don't
see you even getting close to Yan.
Gotta go.
Did you get what I said?
What I don't understand is
why you still give a flying fuck about him.
Go, your pimp's calling you.
- Fuck you!
Excuse me, can you tell me
which apartment Sabina lives in?
What do you need her for?
You see, we are classmates.
She invited me for dinner and forgot
to tell me the apartment number.
I'm listening!
I came to see Sabina.
Sabina!
Yes, dad!
Do you know this young man?
No, I'm see him for the first time.
Do you know her?
No.
Then what did you come for?
Come here.
This is for your act today on the stage.
I want you never show up here again.
I don't ever wanna see you again here.
Otherwise I might want
to get my camera back.
Get lost!
Where were you?
- What are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
I want to talk to you.
Yan, what's wrong with you?
Just leave!
What has happened to you?
Can you hear?
Leave me, bitch, get lost!
You are just like a child,
you need a mother.
Are you insane?
Fuck off!
Have you lost your fucking brains?
Are you fucking insane?
Pour it in a cup, it's not nice
to drink from the bottle.
Why do you steal my money?
Look at yourself, a grown-up man.
Ok, no head on your shoulders
but you've got arms and legs.
Instead of looking for a job,
you steal money from your grandpa.
That's why your own mother left you.
What?
You told me she died.
You, old fucking fart!
Why did you bullshit me my whole life?
You are not the one to blame.
I'm an old man, I don't need a thing.
You, like me, have only desire.
I just wanted someone to be close to me-
a grandson, to take care of,
to wash his shitty diapers,
to play with and make up with,
and listen to his stories
that don't make any sense.
To my sorrow, you didn't give me
any reason to be proud of you.
You even crapped more than regular kids.
Your mother was so young
and stuck with you on her arms.
I thought that fate has given hope
both to me and to her.
But as soon as we got married,
she ran away to Belarus,
so she could keep drinking
and be angry at the whole world.
I'm a stranger to you.
You'll die the same way you were born.
Bye,Victor, I'll be back late.
Freeze!
Listen, buddy, I warned you,
never show up here again.
You can thank me
that I haven't called the police.
I had a good reason for that.
But you told me,
you really want to help me.
Do you understand,
you stole money meant for orphans?
I stole nothing,
I just came to pick it up.
What the fuck you are doing
hanging out next to my house?
What do you need?
What do you need?!
Hey, it's him!
Stop!
Let him go,
or I'll cut his throat open!
Let's go!
- Told ya- run!
Enough!
Let him go!
Listen, we can pull off the last deal.
We can get a shitload of money.
I'm not really sure...
We're gonna get the cash, and you can
leave for England, for your London.
And what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna look for my mother.
Tomorrow there's gonna be
some out of town party for the rich kids.
They'll have all their crap to flaunt it-
cellphones, cameras, gold maybe, cash...
We're gonna have enough shit to jack.
We just need to get a gun.
A gun?
That's a bit more complicated.
Where you gonna get it?
Let's think.
Maybe from Chocolate?
He's got a huge stash.
From Chocolate...
We're gonna need the wheels, too.
This one seems to have no alarm.
C'mon... break the window!
Let's break a window.
- Shush, shush...
Break, are you fucking nuts?!
We still have to drive it.
We're gonna try to crack it open.
Wanna smoke?
- Sure, let's smoke.
Are they leaving soon?
- Should be leaving by now...
Maybe call them?
Just hold on, we made a deal.
Which window?
- The second one, over there.
Look, he took a different car.
C'mon! What are you waiting for?
Go, go!
Wait, a car.
No or yes?
Go on, work.
Check the ignition.
Did you open it?
Wait, wait...
Fuck, c'mon!
See the green one, try that!
- Fuck, I know!
No, the green one, not the red.
- Hold on!
Wait!
It's gonna start now!
Try the green one, I'm telling you.
Fuck, Cracker, you piss me off!
Wanna get in and do it yourself?
What to do? Dunno.
- What the fuck!
Get in. I'm shutting up.
Gimme some light.
Shit, just shake it!
Fuck knows...
How the fuck did you get here?
Just scram!
Let me in!
Back door, told ya, fast!
Drive away, faster!
Come closer!
You asshole, we almost got caught.
Enough, Cracker, chill out.
I'm gonna pull over now
and you are getting out.
Guys, I really wanna go with you.
Just tell me what to do.
You know where we are going?
- No.
Then, let's pull over, you get out.
Is that clear?
Or do you not understand?
Fine, but listen, Shorty,
can you get a gun?
I can, my papa's got a pistol,
a small caliber
Can you get it for tonight?
Dunno, not easy to pull it off.
My papa's paranoid.
Listen, calm down.
Get a couple of winter hats, too.
Go.
Don't forget the beanies!
And grab a bag, too,
so that we won't get caught.
Yan, why is he there for so long?
Why the hell do we need a pistol?
We are not gonna kill anyone!
Hey, he's coming.
Ok, we done?
- Here's everything. A gun and the hats.
Sure? Your folks didn't catch you?
- Nope, nobody saw a thing.
Shorty, come...
Go home now, your parents will worry.
I'm coming with you!
Yan, you promised! I'm with you, dudes!
Cracker, wake up! It's them.
What the...?
- Get ready.
I said, gimme the cash!
Let's wait till they are wasted.
Yan, the water is warm.
Are you fucked up?
It's so cold!
No, I'm telling you -water's great!
Fuck, it's so cool! Let's go!
Ok, everyone, shut the fuck up!
Stay put, otherwise
I'll shoot you in the head!
Everybody looks aside!
Cast down your eyes!
Where you think you're going, cunt?
Don't move!
Lights on, bitch!
Nobody moves.
Where the fuck are you going?!
I'm gonna explain this only once:
take all your fucking money and phones,
and throw it in the bag.
Or I'll fucking stab you!
Is it clear?
Guys, just calm down, we can solve it.
Sure, we can!
What are you waiting for?
Faster!
And you, bitch,
why are you still sitting?
You too, fucking cunt!
Come on! What are you staring at?
Get everything out!
I told you, everything!
Hold the gun!
Yan, what the hell?
So you recognized me, right?
Downstairs, when I was still in the mask.
This is the first time I see you.
That's what you said to your father.
Are you ashamed of me?
Don't...
What do you want?
I want to be loved.
You are so pretty.
Hush, hush, you...
Enough!
Take off your shoes!
Take the fucking shoes off! Faster!
This is great, right?
Enough, I told you!
I'll cut your throat, got it?
Enough, shut your mouth.
Just shut it up!
I said, enough, bitch!
Didn't you get it? Shut up!