-I'm sick of it.
-Yeah. So am I.
-Best will be getting ready to go.
-I know. Absolutely.
I can predict totally
what's going to happen.
-Yeah, I'll end up taking Geoff home.
-Dire.
-And you'll go home with Bill.
-No, I won't.
-Yes, you will.
Because he farts in bed
and his feet stink.
-So there's no truth to the rumour?
-Absolutely not...
-Can I borrow your orange jersey?
-No.
Sauce.
Thanks.
Next.
-How are you?
-Fine.
Can you tell me please...
what is paua?
Shellfish. And wouldn't like it. I'd
have the fish and chips if was you.
-Have a nice day.
-Same to you with knobs on.
Was ist das nobs?
Are you asleaze or tease
the quiz he wants you to take.
Come on, Mel. You could
be doing that at home.
He doesn't want to stay over on the
first date, but he does with you.
Do you a) believe him
and take him straight to bed?
b) smile wisely and
take him to bed anyway?
Or c) know he's lying and
steer ahead with caution?
C.
A.
B...I'd smile wisely.
I'm giving it up.
Isn't that the band Adrian was in?
Ahhh... nah.
-Who was he?
-Her ex.
-Yeah, ages ago.
-When she was young and stupid.
ike you.
I like this one.
-Gidday, Melsie. How's it going?
-Pete! How's your wife?
-Hey, Mel.
-Adrien.
What's the story?
I'll see you round, eh?
See ya.
-I like the look of that drummer.
-Got bad habits written over him.
You wish.
Hi. Just the usual, thanks.
-A drummer without girlfriend?
-I dunno. What?
Homeless.
What about them?
They don't look too bad.
-Anyone know'em?
-Nah.
Well, that's a start.
-You've been in the bush, have ya?
-Yeah.
-Oh yeah. How was that?
-All right.
Were you there for long?
What were you doing?
I was killing stuff.
Like what?
Pigs. Deer.
-Yeah, it was all right.
-I hate the bush.
People wander in there, you know,
and they never come out again.
You can't... yeah. You can't
escape into the bush. You can't..
Can't stand it.
Have we met before?
No.
They're nice shoes.
Where did you get those from?
Italy.
Let's go.
Your place or mine?
Yours.
I've been to mine.
Suppose you live in a luxury
yacht down here, do you?
You got that right.
I love that smell.
Seaweed, old rope, plastic bags?
Fish'n...
-I could carry you, if you want.
-No, you couldn't.
Oh I could. I used to be a fireman.
No, you didn't.
-I did.
-No, you didn't.
No, I didn't.
-So where is it?
-Close your eyes.
And I will lead you there.
Straight ahead.
Nice.
Sit down.
So who's your girlfriend?
It's for you.
Oh, you've got avery big heart.
And you see the way those
two lines cross there?
That mean's someone who is very
close to you is very dangerous.
And this hand...
This hand...
that's what you're born with and
this is what you make of your life.
A big mess.
Are you Taurus?
I'll bet you've got Taurus
in your rising sign.
I'm a Leo.
Is that good?
Well, Leo and Aries are
really good together.
-Right.
-You know like...
Right.
Do you know what else I can do?
I can read minds.
So what am I thinking?
Oh well, I'm not going to
tell you what you're thinking...
'cos you're thinking
what I'm thinking...
Hey...
Let me out!
You jerk.
Help! Let me out!
Let me out!
Good-morning.
What are you? Deaf or something?
Sleep well?
Where am l?
Exhilarating, isn't it?
For your hangover.
I've got work today.
Where are we going?
To my place.
You said you wanted to.
You're going to love it.
Well, what's the time now?
And when will we get back?
We can't go back now.
We're almost there.
Relax.
To you.
You know the best thing
about going away?
Coming home again.
You all right?
No, I'm not.
Silly billy.
Did I tell you, l, you know, really
don't go for all this nature shit?
Don't worry. I'll look after you.
There is nothing I wouldn't
do for you, you know.
Why are you so jumpy?
I'm not jumpy.
I just don't know you very
well, you know, and l...
I didn't realise
we were coming here.
Look, I'm sorry.
Look, I know it's silly...
-I just want to go home.
-Yes, it is silly.
But don't worry.
I'll get you back.
Not now. The tides
are wrong, but ah...
First thing in the morning.
I promise.
Just chuck up your wet stuff.
I'll dig you out something dry.
I suppose you provide these
for all your guests, do you?
I will always remember
you like this.
So, why don't you tell
me about yourself?
If I wasn't in love with you,
I wouldn't be so boring.
But I just want to say'l love you'
all the time - it's all I think of.
But you don't even know me.
Let me tell you astory.
Once upon a time
there was a lovely girl...
Let's call her Melanie,
Princess Melanie...
whose mother, the queen,
the wicked queen...
was so absent-minded she forgot
that she had a daughter...
and went away on long
journeys with nary a backward glance.
Her father, the king,
took many courtesans...
and the lonely girl
grew up wild and wanton.
Many princes were her suitors...
and she pleased herself
with all of them.
A troubadour stole her heart, but
he rode off into various sunsets...
Ieaving her slaving in the kitchen,
dumped there.
Poor, lovely girl.
But then...
one dark and stormy night...
a man who wasn't a prince,
just a man...
blew in and took her across
the seas to his castle...
where they fell in love...
and got married...
and lived happily ever after.
How did you know my name?
Well, you told me last night.
Right.
-What else forgotten about last night?
-Nothing to be ashamed of.
This place is going to
do you a lot of good.
How do you know so much about me?
I know everything about you...
because I love you.
You can't love me.
Oh, but I do.
So there it is.
But ummm...
I don't know anything about you.
Oh, don't worry about that.
Here I am.
Do you want me?
-What are you doing?
-Nothing, I just thought I'd...
-What are you...
-Nothing, I just thought...
-What are you thinking?
-Oh, come on. You know you want...
Not like this. This is... different.
I need to know
do you love me?
You have to love me.
All right. I love you.
-No, no, no, l...
-Don't say it like that.
You make it sound cheap.
Make it cheap.
I want to marry you.
You understand?
Oh, that's funny...
-Oh, that's funny, is it?
-No.
You think that's funny?
You're insulting, you know.
Never, never laugh at me.
You are not kind.
You want to get some
kindness into you!
I'm too kind.
...too kind.
Oh no you don't.
I wanna talk to you.
Open the door.
Open the door!
Are you listening?
Just open the door.
I just wanna talk to you.
Come on out.
I just want to talk to you.
God.
Good-morning.
Hello?
Hello, can you hear me because...
because I can't hear you.
Um... There's a, there's a,
there's a man that l...
He's... he's hurt and I think
he's going to hurt me.
There's a... a a jetty,
and there's and there's rocks...
and there is water...
and and and I l think
I've been kidnapped.
Um...'K' for...
kippers and'l' for idiot
and'D' for desperate...
and'N' for nothing.
I think I'm in danger.
Please don't do this to me.
Don't leave me.
Fat chance of that, isn't there?
You bastard!
Wipe that smile off your face.
You're not going to do this to me.
I'm not staying! You wake up!
I'm not staying here.
You friggin' help me,
for God's sake.
Come on.
That's it.
Get up.
Come on. Get up.
Get up!
Thank-you.
Which way is it to the
nearest neighbour?
You tell me - which way is it?
Is there anyone else on the island?
I could murder you for doing
this to me. You know that?
I know that. I do.
This isn't working.
Stitch it.
I'm not stitching. I'm not.
I'm not stitching that.
Okay...
Oh God!
You know what?
You should try reciting
your times table backwards.
It'll take your mind off the pain if
you concentrate on something else.
8O...
72, 64...
No, no you need something harder
than this...
Poetry, poetry.
Wait, wait, wait...
"What is true love, who can tell.
What causes such a..."
magic spell..."
that fills the veins
with liquid fire..."
and fills the heart
with warm desire."
God. Do it quickly for God's sake.
You nearly finished?
"To make the loved
one all your own..."
Jesus...
"And place her on
a loving throne..."
"... but change she earth and change
still I will love her till I die"
which might be quite soon.
Look, I'm I'm nearly finished.
I'm just tying the knots.
Don't die. Please don't die.
"l am bright with
the wonder of you..."
despite the dark
waiting I endure..."
"l am bright..."
with the wonder of you."
I'm so sorry.
Hello.
-Did you think I was dead?
-I'm glad you're not.
"Yesterday has gone.
Bring on the sensible day."
Who said that?
I don't know.
Me.
Open the flue. That's the thing at
the bottom of the chimney, see?
Should be vertical.
-Good.
-Good...
and now the second door down.
Open that.
And put the lid on.
All right. I've done that.
Now what?
Now you have to give it
a good talking to, you have to...
tell her how much better she'll feel
with a good fire in her belly.
-I'm not doing that. That's stupid.
-You talk to her firmly but clearly.
Right. Well...
I don't know you very well, but
I'm sure we're going to get along.
Good.
Now you listen to the fire.
The fire will tell you all...
that it needs.
There you go.
Eat it...
Eat.
Look.
Here comes the choo choo train.
Choo choo.
-lf you don't eat, you'll die.
-And go to Heaven.
Doubt it.
Hello.
Don't fall asleep, okay?
Stay awake and talk to
me please. I get lonely.
I'm not asleep.
Yeah, you are.
I've got my eyes closed
so I can see you better.
I'm manifesting you.
You're much nicer in here.
Actually, I know what you mean.
I went out with a guy like that.
Whenever I left his company,
he came with me inside my head.
That got your attention, didn't it?
-I'm jealous.
-God, don't be.
He took off with someone else.
Bastard.
-Good.
-No, it wasn't. It was awful...
Adrian.
You'd think I've known with a name
like that, don't you? Adrian.
Bloody Adrian.
This particular day,
I was standing in the kitchen...
staring out the window...
don't you reckon it's weird what you
remember when bad things happen...
Iike he says he's leaving...
really quietly like...
that he didn't love me.
Didn't think he ever did.
And then he runs outside...
and a car pulls up,
like magic or something...
And he gets into it, drives away.
Gone. Just like that.
I wouldn't ever do that to you.
It's rather unlikely
under the circumstances.
No, seriously, I would
never do that to you.
-You don't even remember me, do you?
-When?
I ordered oysters.
And you had a little bead of
sweat in the middle of your...
forehead and
I wanted to brush it off.
You needed rescuing.
Was it that obvious?
This can't go on.
Come on, come on.
Wake up. Please.
We're gonna go back. And you're
going to help get us there.
-No.
-Yes, you have to. Come on.
You'll leave me.
Love equals trust.
Please.
I'm so happy here with you.
We'll work everything out
when you're better.
But we've gotta go.
Please come on. Let's just go.
If you love me...
you prove it.
In the shed.
Wheelbarrow.
There you go.
Ready?
-You're being very brave.
-Stupid.
Yip. Well they go hand in hand, eh?
-Yeah, probably.
-I only do stupidity.
Oh, you can say that again.
Don't worry.
Your secret is safe with me.
What secret?
That you're afraid.
Yeah. Only of you.
Nah. Of commitment.
Yeah, right.
But love will find away.
Will it?
You know, I've gotten used
to you a little bit.
It wasn't easy though, was it?
No.
This is gonna hurt you more than
it's going to hurt me.
Okay.
When you get your breath back...
do I have to talk to
this to make it go?
You have to sing.
-Anything in particular?
-No, you choose.
""What shallqwe do qwith
the drunken sailor?
What shallqwe do qwith the
drunken sailor?
Early in the morning?
Hoo-ray and up she rises
Hoo-ray and up she rises""
How much further is it?
We're there...
We're there!
No!
Thank you, darling.
Haven't even touched your tea and
I went to all the bother to make it.
Sorry.
I don't expect you to like this...
but you'll get used to it.
And it's foryour oqwn good. Because
I m goingto have to shut the lid...
but at the coldest
hour, the one before daqwn...
...Illopen the lid and
qwe can do qwhateveryou qwant.
Within reason.
Stay there.
Everyday in everyqway
I m getting better and better
Everyday in every qway
You've got to feel god about
yourself though, haven't you?
You have been so generous...
you're kind, you're good...
And I don't just mean
last night either.
You know, because at the risk of
sounding just a little bit crude...
you were brilliant.
I mean, you were the best.
Bar none.
I'm so grateful to you,
my beautiful thing because...
you helped me break
through my own resistance.
You know and you loved me
no matter what I did to you.
Do you know, for the first
time in my life, I'm happy?
And I don't even know
your name, do l?
God, you're cold.
No that's okay. That's good.
That's good.
I'll love you forever.
You and me...
born again.
You've got to feel good about
yourself though, haven't you?
God, it's so quiet.
Am I talking too much?
'Cos that's what men complain about,
that women talk too much.
But I reckon men talk just as
much, even more some of them...
and they're often not
very good listeners, are they?
Oh, I don't mean you, my darling.
You know, you're in
a class of your own.
You're a good listener.
No secrets.
We must be honest.
Don't worry. I'll get rid of them.
Bill?
So what's been going on?
It's a delicate matter.
It's our honeymoon.
Who got who?
It's not funny, Bill.
I'll say...
So was it you or him?
-What?
-Smashed up my hut.
He's supposed to maintain it,
not demolish it.
-So where is he?
-He's fishing.
-On his honeymoon?
-Yeah.
-That's not very nice.
-Well, it's fine with me.
-Hiding in the dunny.
-I didn't know it was you, did l?
Hope you're not going to stay long.
Visitors are like fish.
After two days, they stink.
Does he know?
-What?
-About this mess.
This pisses me right... off.
Ionly slept qwith him once.
And he qwasn't even very good.
He's usually aggressively tidy.
I don't think you're
very good for him.
You dig up the carrots too?
-I like digging.
-Strange.
You're not very good at it...
I mean, what awaste, you know...
Complete bloody waste.
Dust to dust.
I'm having a learning curve.
Think the bullet...
right to the target...
-Can you feel your heart beat?
-Yeah.
Now, breath out.
Slowly, squeeze the trigger and...
I am so...
so proud of you.
-I love you.
-And I love you right back.
I'm going to do it myself
now, okay? Okay?
Do you think I could shoot you?
Bet you couldn't.
I might kill you. Do you think
you can kill someone twice?
I don't know. We'll just do it.
Oh, look.
It's perfectly all right, you know.
There's no harm done.
Do you forgive me?
There's nothing to forgive.
So I'm forgiven?
Totally.
I totally,
totally forgive you, too.
Come on.
Wake up!
What happened?
Nothing.
What did you do?
-What happened to him?
-Nothing has happened to him.
-He's dead!
-No, he's not.
-What did you do?
-I haven't done anything.
-He's all right.
-He's dead!
-He's not!
No, he's not! He's got his eyes
shut so he can see me better.
-That's all, he likes it out there.
-He's dead!
He's not... dead!
-There's nothing wrong with him.
-Come here!
-He's fine!
-Shut up!
Look, look!
Open your eyes!
What have you done to him?
-What?
-What have you done to him?
Where did you make him go?
You've done something to him...
-What are you talking about?
-You've made him dead!
You, you, you made
him dead... murderer!
Murderer!
Let go of me!
Calm down. Calm down.
-Where is he?
-Calm down!
Get off me.
I don't want to be held by you!
-Calm down!
-Get off me!
How you want your eggs?
Runny. Ta.
Come on, m'girlie.
They let you keep your babies
in jail, don't they?
Are you pregnant?
A little bit.
Well, how much is that?
He'd have wanted you
to be godfather.
-Hey, Bill?
-What?
If you let me stay here...
I'd love you forever.
No, you wouldn't.
You don't even like me.
Yes, I do.
So what was the big idea?
There's no big idea.
"See you round, Bill."
Oh, right...
Oh, right. That.
A bloke wakes up with a hangover...
and thinks he's scored himself a
nice warm back to snuggle up to...
and then you know...
Well you know...
I had a lot on my mind.
Like now?
No. You know now,
now there's nothing.
Nah, nah, don't you do it...
So what'd he do to you?
Freaked me out.
Remind me not to, eh?
You're such a smart arse.
Know any hymns?
""Allthings bright and beautiful
Allcreatures great and small
Allthings bright and qwonderful
the Lord God made them all
He gave us eyes to see them
And lips that qwe may tell
Hoqw great is God Almighty
He made all things qwell.""
Something smells good.
I could scrub
your back if you like.
Just there. Yip.
No, thanks.
-When did you say the baby was due?
-Soon.
Lovely.
I don't get it.
Bloody old Barnacle Bill, eh?
-Maybe he's good in bed.
-No, he's not.
-He's obviously been practicing.
-Why don't you give a speech?
Ah, thanks love...
Thank you all for coming today.
It's been a great day and...
As you can tell,
I'm avery happy man.
Thank you to Burt and Nance...
for putting on this fine spread
that you see. It's pretty yummy.
Been off the scene lately, but we'd
like to welcome to you all.
Feel free to visit us over there.
The door's always open.
Thanks to Mum and Dad. Unfortunately
they can't be here today.
But if they hadn't done
a certain act a few years ago...
I wouldn't be here either.
Drink up and have a good night.
And thanks to the
lovely bridesmaids.
When I saw them all dressed
up in their finery...
hard decision to make: "Which
one do I marry, you know??"'
Think I've chosen the right one.
>> Napisy pobrane z http://napisy.org <<
>>>>>>>> nowa wizja napisów <<<<<<<<