OFF BALANCE
(Un Delitto Poco Comune)
Sorry...
Can I talk to you in particular?
Not that I'm not happy
with your success...
I fear only that will separate us.
Susanna, your mother is right...
You are very regular... Want
draw them all...
The
say this because I think our future?
Leaves for London,
I do not know how and you say now!
What does the future hold for you?
To marry and to have children?
The all like it's a bad thing!
Is it bad if the only
target of our bond.
This is absurd, Robert.
But suddenly
I start to feel uncomfortable...
As if talking to a stranger...
Dad, come and see.
Play a concert Dominici.
Amazing!
Dad was worried about you.
I had your new all day.
Why do not you come to the concert?
Shortly before the
concerto became a murder...
- Murder?
- The victim was a woman. Terrible crime!
Please, Dad, my non
ruin the evening!
Pour always the same scent...
Do I fit...
This toast was
me or my music?
For you were!
Well, I thought I hated.
I did not know it was so obvious
...
Maybe it's a kind of defense...
- Defense?
- You know very well what I mean.
It was so easy to fall in love...
Something usual...
And what has changed?
- Your music influenced me!
- Maybe the champagne!
Maybe! And the impact continues...
Maybe start a flirt...
I know... One night soon,
would invite me for dinner...
How are you so sure?
It is written!
Do not tell me how you
predict the future!
Sometimes, yes.
Okay... I give up...
I'm sorry... I can not concentrate today...
According to the autopsy, the
death was instantaneous...
The blade cut the carotid artery.
Fingerprints found many.
- And the gun too?
- Neither the gun.
I knew!
I'm afraid I only left the deposit
candy from the first floor...
He says he saw a 30 year old new
coming from the building...
But, this can be any
...
I know, but the only clue we have
heinous crime in Perugia
They killed young doctor
with Napoleonic sword
Huge success
Robert Dominici
Okay! We're done for today.
Leaving already?
Both got this
we wanted, right?
What say?
You proved that you can
get me from Robert.
And I think I can do without him.
Not true. From my own
perspective at least.
From mine, it is!
You go to his house?
Is it right to play
so with my feelings?
Hurts!
I do not like...
I did not understand how you felt...
Forget it... Go now...
Get...
Sorry...
= = Do you want to go to the station?
No thanks.
No, your promised. No more
ultimatums. Not a word about marriage.
Only when
if you so wish...
I just am
near you, Robert.
Where are you?
I come there...
I love you!
This is yours.
I went out... I do not know why...
As if I had a premonition...
Current many mad at
streets nowadays...
When I found the...
eyes were open...
But I knew he was already dead...
I do not know what to do!
And what makes
me feel worse...
... is that we had a fight last
silly...
Only tonight we realized how
really love!
Only find this
murders, police!
Stop before
kill and others!
- Loves Susanna;
- Maybe... And what with that?
Slept with her, even though it was
mistress of your best friend.
You take what you want, and
your heartbreak for others!
Listen! To recline together
both have to want...
The Susanna came only
in my home...
There raped
in the middle of the road, of course!
Okay, okay...
I take it back.
You're a gentleman.
You can go now.
- David, how old are you?
- Twenty-four.
Did you, by chance, the doctor knew
Carla Pesenti;
You ask if I
alibi for the night that killed her?
- You have an alibi?
- No, I have not!
But the killer certainly has!
will capture the killer
I can spend?
Now I understand...
On your days calling...
I did not want to see nor
to talk to anyone.
I can not stand the persons
look at me with sympathy.
Maybe I show myself so.
The grief of others
helps your own!
Not let you reactions
and forget.
How do you manage?
The coax...
You were very much in love with Susanna;
I do not remember anymore...
When I think about it, I see before me
dead...
Her death is the most lively
picture of me now!
Tormenting yourself!
I came to help you.
I'm alive.
Without obligation, of course.
It is a pity, Helene...
What is shame?
You said the right thing
at the wrong time.
How would like to hear these words
another time!
I love you, Robert...
And no hurry...
Hi, Dad! What's new
Do not answer! The
Your face says it all!
Sit down to your
prepare something now...
Thank you, dear.
I have not eaten anything today.
You know Dad...
often think the
mom angry...
... Because you never
regular working hours.
Well, now
I understand perfectly.
This is the right
job for you!
Hello?
What?
Dad?
Hello?
You'd think that you can catch me?
A month passed and you're still there
you started!
Do you hear me?
Are you still there?
Yes, here I am.
Good! I will say something
will you like...
We will never catch me!
I can kill whoever I want!
Yes! I'll go crazy!
By the way...
Your daughter was that
picked up the phone?
Cute... Cute...
What did she say?
Someone was crazy... No
I made no sense...
Current many such!
Is the right job for me...
... but come moments
who abhor.
You are very smart and
confident about yourself...
But with an opponent who is not
falls on your traps...
... you have no hope!
Honor to lose by
an opponent like you!
What are you doing here?
Sorry...
I'm a little drunk.
I was returning here and there for hours.
Not even know how
finally got here!
Tell me where you got the whiskey.
Will be served myself.
You will not find ever!
The hide lest thy
drink your guests?
No, just
is a beautiful piece of furniture.
Robert;
Thanks for everything... For
kindness you showed...
I have to leave for a while, but I will
have you with me, in my heart.
Robert, what a pleasant surprise!
Not believe it when the
dwarf said he will come!
A joy you are! Shortly
unshaven perhaps...
Newbie are you?
Did you stay a few days?
- I'll stay a few days.
- Very glad, Robert.
Great! Great, my son!
And they also...
Not exactly what
I was hoping to find...
... but better than nothing!
- How about you?
- If I knew what you looking for...
Why would someone
kill a doctor?
Perhaps because he wants to hide something.
You're two months here and
not even touched the piano!
And I do not want to see anyone!
I understand... you claimed
death of Susanna...
But, we should not resign from life!
You lose your freshness...
You look like mature man...
And it makes me feel more
old...
What can I do
to help you?
There is nothing, mother.
Will pass, you see...
I'll leave tomorrow.
I know... It's hard when
start to lose...
You'll get used to it... I
I started very young...
At forty, my
youth was lost!
To see the bulletins.
You, Robert; We await you!
Come in, come in.
He means.
Seats.
I come immediately.
I will not tell lies, Robert.
When you want the truth...
is what we fear.
There is no doubt.
You're very unlucky, Robert.
Your case is very rare.
It is a disease that usually
occurs in childhood.
Anyway. In
conference will go in Paris...
... I will discuss your case
.
I'll be honest.
I do not think there are hopes.
The disease certainly
initially manifested in childhood.
Stayed in a latent form,
and revealed just now.
It's a shame...
A rare virus, with very
long incubation period.
And now that the disease
activated...
... definitely will
rapid evolution.
Warned. Maybe
affected brain cells.
And this will result
someone abnormal psyche.
There were a few similar cases.
You must enter
clinic for monitoring.
To see me die?
Front?
Helene, I'm...
Robert! And once
in thinking!
It is no coincidence... All
time to think...
This is wonderful...
How are you?
I want to tell you something that has
make me happy...
Waiting child, Robert...
- Really?
- Yes!
Your own child, Robert!
My own child?
These though are good news!
You can begin with this tomorrow...
- Goodnight.
- Okay, goodnight.
Hey, Helene.
Will you tomorrow.
- Good night, sir.
- Goodnight, Luciano.
Dr. Vanni, from the criminals
ture laboratory...
will examine for signs of
the murderer...
Some hair, a fiber
below the nails...
should be done immediately?
I want it too! Traces,
if there are natural...
... not lost!
Sorry...
Good morning, sir.
Can I ask what you say?
I asked the doctor if there
risk to the baby.
- The baby?
- Me sorry...
Do you know who the father is?
It's not
hid the Helene...
It's so happy!
Father is the
Robert Dominici.
The Robert Dominici...
pianist...
Very unfortunate as women
of Robert Dominici.
I knew once...
And this killing...
The great talent...
genius...
All women
him fall in love...
By laughed once, Robert
Dominici. You were very convincing.
But now I will not save you!
The Vanni was...
They found pieces of skin on the nails of the girl...
Call him and tell
to go to sleep...
I want the results of the examinations
tomorrow morning...
Go now!
Break the door!
You sure, Captain?
You will find trouble!
When it comes to such a
killer, no one speaks.
- And if not that?
- Of course he is!
All the evidence lead at him!
I do not think longer lives here.
If so... I'll find him!
I want to have a constant
surveillance of this house.
24 hours per 24-hour period!
- You look so happy?
- I have every reason to be.
- How is the girl?
- Better than I expected.
Is bouncing agency.
You can view.
Is one ours through...
They make the sketch.
- Who is this?
- The sketch of the killer.
Kidding?
It was dark... I
terrified...
For a moment I saw him...
Only they remember...
But the killer is 30 years.
We know this for sure!
He went on to kill
was elderly...
had wrinkles
and very little hair...
Do not weary now.
See you next time.
Explained it.
Saw the face of Robert.
Subconsciously, replaced
image to another...
A psychologist will explain better...
Your reference should be
ready before two hours.
'm Late because something strange happens
...
The killer is not new ..
is around sixty...
- It is not possible!
- I checked three times.
Then, you were wrong
all three times.
How is this possible?
Continue the investigations for the killer...
Already margins have narrowed
...
The killer
is between 50 and 60 years...
He demonstrated by our laboratory...
I want the policeman Nteti...
It is very urgent...
We ask the phone...
- Excuse me.
- Thank you.
Hello?
Handsome show on TV.
There you say well though...
For months asking a
killer 30 years...
... And suddenly, as if it
is over 50...
Think twice before you speak...
Otherwise, everyone will understand how
fool you...
Okay .. .
Let's start from the beginning.
With the murder of Carla Pesenti.
Already interrogate all
patients doctor.
Even this
American doctor...
... that would meet
medical conference.
In Paris... In Robert
Hutchison Gklifornt...
I requested information from
the conference secretariat.
Maybe tell us what
why would meet.
Welcome.
I do not know to help
it, but anyway...
I was afraid that they would not
were here, Laura...
Only friends say Laura!
You're my friend?
You're the first woman to
which I love!
I was 20 years old then...
Let me see if I remember
who you are...
You were twenty...
And I, how was I?
Nineteen.
Help me, please.
And of course I remember you! Even
and now you're handsome!
In your twenties you were a doll!
Many say this...
I'm starting to believe it myself...
Girls...
Even friends of my mother!
But, preferably
come to me first!
Good!
I want to kiss me...
You want to say something to you like you were a child
...
So you want and
kiss on the mouth!
I don't like your type!
Why do you want to ask
forgiveness from the Lord?
Father...
Killed...
killed?
Killed... and
kill again...
Listen to me!
You have to hear me!
I do not know,
Father Giuliano?
I'm Robert... The
Robert Dominici...
Are you the Robert;
The Robert Dominici;
It is possible!
How is it possible?
Because you look bigger?
Seems like yesterday that we did
friends in the evenings...
I was talking about music
and women...
... and you to God...
Nice game played
thy God!
Look at me!
Playing with my desperation...
God you make me and rot...
Inside and out...
My mind rot...
I can not help myself .. .
Nobody can
to hold...
Nobody... except the time...
Every day is like one month...
Each month as ten years!
Time is running out, and
I'm not ready...
We will not forsake God is merciful...
...
This is the mercy?
Give me absolution!
At least you,
give me absolution!
If not as a priest, as a friend!
Adrea! I feel!
I feel very impatient!
Get ready!
We have many things to buy!
Two months left... The
little pretentious!
- His father knows?
- That is demanding?
Not... That left
only two months!
What is your name?
You at least not talk...
I hope that is...
course not talk...
You dog...
Well if it begins
and you can talk...
With all those idiots
you date...
In ever loved?
Boss you ever had?
Sure you had!
Must
were very nice dog...
Only
is difficult to imagine now...
After Jerash and your
boss drove in...
And I'm sure
forgive him...
I did not forgive...
I hate them all...
young and old. ..
Them young because they have
front their lifetime...
old men because they had
a lifetime...
We will kill them all!
Sir police, the phone!
Lower the music!
That's it!
What you become, Datti;
He long time...
Come... Tell me the truth...
I am sure that with pethymises.
You know... all complain
for your failure...
And it saddens me very much!
I regret very much!
So I decided to give you a chance.
I want to help.
But this time
I want you to grab!
I'm going to take a look...
All...
You stay here!
It's all ready.
Do not shake anyone,
if I do not signal!
In my opinion, the guy
us make fun.
I do not know what to think...
Come to see how
things... Go!
I did not bring the dog today?
Not...
Do you like dogs?
Well, I will bring him tomorrow.
All is quiet here! Yes!
Tell him not to worry!
The police want to make sure
I have the gun ready.
Is right... Is
your first business.
I'll take a look around.
Go?
Nothing happens here. The
Antzelis looking around.
See you tomorrow.
Do not forget the dog!
Sorry... Do you have time?
Yes, five.
Then, it's time!
For what?
For this!
No, no... Do not yell! And
looking to find him... Gone!
I want my friend Datti.
Come on, call him!
Give me the police! Hurry!
Hello?
Hey, Datti...
I am again...
Are you ready?
Now is a great
your chance!
Get in the car!
For Us!
What we want us? In
killer to go to catch!
Leave quiet their law-abiding citizens!
We are here for over an hour.
Is a shame!
- Is everyone here?
- Yes, about thirty.
The crippled and
two old men to leave!
And the kids too!
Okay... You! Thou!
You!
You and you!
You can leave! For Us!
Follow me!
Okay. From here please.
Come!
Sorry about this, Helene.
Must be transparent as possible.
What is?
I do not know...
looked at them again.
What is?
I do not really know!
Helene, I know I'm asking
many of you.
But, you must help me.
One of them is the killer.
The woman who killed
today was a little younger than you.
And wanted to live...
Sir, you ask the phone.
- Who is it?
- It is very urgent!
Do you really want to arrest me, right?
However, stop torturing
the Helene now...
As for Helene, be warned:
Do not leave unfinished business!
Go home.
Will be glad your daughter.
Sleep tonight, and
tomorrow you again...
How is the Gloria;
Time I see her!
What are you doing, Datti;
You ask if they record the call?
If you want to know where
call, I'll say so myself!
Down here I am, in the cafe.
Get down to drink a coffee together.
You came to the window...
I like your shirt!
Yes! You go
blues, Datu!
- Where is he who was calling?
- I do not know!
Where are you, paliompastarde?
I know you're here, bitch son!
Revealed, you bastard!
I will kill you!
'll Kill you! Where are you?
How did he escape from the park?
We caught of them.
I do not know! He said that
would drive me crazy...
And it does...
A, here are you? At the funeral
disappeared suddenly...
Yes I know... When it came time to
condolences...
... I did not have the courage to face
her mom.
I do not know if you understand me.
Of course, the police.
'll Take them with me these.
Send legal
books in my house.
They have no value.
But I have since I was a student
.
- Not in drives one!
- I know!
I leave myself... Is
a matter of good taste...
First time brew
my suitcases...
But, many times you
travel with me!
In fact, I was preparing
our suitcases.
Do not make me cry...
I know... You're hard...
I know someone who will
laugh if listened to you.
I hate him, even
for this, Dad!
Why should I leave you
and go to Rome.
Probably you are not in danger drom
him, but I want to be sure.
Dad, why do not you come with me
? I will miss very...
I must arrange
few things. Then I will come.
Thy promise.
Do not go out, I'm
passer.
Once I took
Gloria at the Station.
- So now you're alone.
- Yes, but not for long.
I will leave for Rome.
I think that would shift there.
You know, Rome is
room for everyone.
Do not you think we should proceed
slightly ahead?
So you see the whole
home Helene!
Yes, yes... You're right!
Sorry for peremvasi.
Can not
overcome the poor guy!
So you went your daughter
at Station!
The train of 4:42 for Rome!
By the way... The
Gloria smokes too!
I saw two packs of cigarettes
in the bag!
Bad for health!
I had to see me!
I had a crisis...
I thought I would die...
It's the end...
You're lucky! You know why?
Why do not you know that you will die...
But the man never thinks
death?
When he is old and scared...
I, never thought the
death all these years...
All these years...
And I'm only 35 years old!
Hello?
I am the Robert.
Robert, my love! It is not possible!
Like Magic!
I hear your voice and see
the same time!
Good!
As if you're beside me!
But, what your voice is?
Nothing... I'm just a cold...
I forgot to tell you. He will
come get me the Adrea...
You're going on a journey for a few days...
not to mind, right?
Yes, Helene, mind!
We have to leave!
Well, why not?
Why turn back...
Tomorrow!
I thought to tell you before
write the official report.
Thanks.
There is something strange, which
I can not understand...
What?
Recognize the voice?
Is the voice of the killer?
Yes!
Are you sure you always
he telephoned?
Yes, I believe so.
It is the voice of a very old man
man.
No, do not do wrong!
We sometimes test.
The result was the same.
How?
The first witness said
that was 30 years old...
Histology...
...
pieces of skin from the clutches of the victim...
... showed she was 50.
Now tell me that the voice
corresponds to a very old man man!
And all these
a few months!
One case only...
is a rare disease...
Her name
early age, or progireia.
A few things I know about this disease.
Usually affects children.
But it is very rare.
Sometimes contest
and adults...
... but at least
visible forms.
Years ago I met a man who had
infected...
He was 40 and looked 70!
We only show! The body of
actually was 70 years old!
See! Here are...
"Progireia..."
"... or Syndrome Hutchison
and Gilford."
Are the two scientists who discovered
!
I read these names hundreds
times in calendar Pesenti...
Robert Hutchinson Gilford...
Medical Conference in Paris...
We felt that was the name
a scientist...
... You epeirne
part in the conference...
and not dealt another.
Well, the Hutchison
not say the Robert!
I know!
The Robert was the name of someone
patient in the calendar...
Someone called Robert
had contracted the disease...
Robert Ntoministi!
Robert!
Can I get in?
Robert sent me.
I know yesterday called from New York.
He said he would come tonight...
Well...
- Today coming.
- Robert came.
Well, I came here because
I have to tell you something.
Nothing happened?
No, no...
Nothing will separate you
by Robert anymore!
Why take long then?
Excuse me a moment.
Please, sit.
I'll bring something to drink.
How did you know where I hide the whiskey?
, Robert has
secrets from me!
I see it!
Who are you?
You captured this photo...
It was the party of a mutual friend
...
How telling him?
About two years ago...
Before
know well and love...
Already I was in love with Robert then!
And from the way he
looks at the lens...
... I would say that he too had
in love ever since.
You have almost the same
voice of Robert!
And the same eyes...
The same look...
"The eyes have
a special glow!"
So you say...
There have changed my eyes...
The same is!
Well, what are you talking about?
I am, Helene!
I'm Robert!
No, you are not the Robert...
You're old...
Difficult to understand...
I know...
Well, I... I have this weird
illness.
Within months...
... ended up with that!
Illness?
I would like to explain to you, but...
Is there anything I need to do...
baby...
My Baby?
Our baby!
I can not allow
be born...
I do not understand?
It has the same blood as me!
Look at me!
You may be like me!
Unable
talking seriously!
My baby!
Nightmare is!
You can not be the Robert!
I can not wait, Helene...
A month is a long time!
It's too much
for me now...
I...
I can not wait any longer...
Even
one months is a long time!
Dying...
I can not wait to
born our child...
And then will be to convince
to kill...
I do not have time!
I have to do this!
Helene!
Are you okay?
In mattered?
Datti, finally!
I did everything to
make me stop...
But, how to understand?
Finished now...
is the most cruel joke
God...
... and He did it to me...