(Grinding)
(slow piano music)
- [Voiceover] I've come to
realize that my whole existence
from the age of 13 on has been
about crisis. A crisis
of metamorphosis.
I've always been aware that I've
been in the process of changing,
I just never know until why.
Now with the cancer
sucking the life out of me,
doesn't seem likely
that I'll ever find
the final form my life
is supposed to take.
(fire crackles)
I wash in the noise of
memory and morphine.
I find myself unable
to project myself into
a future that is
increasingly finite.
Now with the funding for
my movie having collapsed,
along with the rest
of the economy,
all that's left for me to do is
reflect on a project and a
life I'll never complete.
I've come to the
conclusion that my
childhood memories are not real.
Though manufactured for
me is a kind of fiction
framed by the adults who were
present when I was young.
And these good natured people,
friends, relatives, all,
continually repeated the same
stories and anecdotes about me.
Often reinforcing
their tales with
photographic and video evidence.
And because consciousness
is malleable
and memory a clever
liar, the substance,
the true reality of who
I was had been lost.
The time in maturity
I've come to think of
my past selves as distant others
with their own needs
and motivations,
not like characters
in a novel or a movie.
How fitting then that I
spent an entire career
exploring my own existence
in the creation of fiction.
My first film "Disquiet" was a
dramatic investigation into
the very nature of character.
How it's defined and observed.
Now, as I struggle
with the unfortunate
reality of my
terminal condition,
I wonder about the
young man I once
was twenty some odd years ago.
Not as a memory but as a, as a
character completely
separate from myself.
My thoughts focus not so much on
on past events, but on attitudes
and motivations,
needs and desires.
All in an effort to find how
much of him is still within me.
But is this a hollow pursuit?
Can one ever truly know
the man he once was?
(groans)
Oh, fuck! Oh God!
(heaving)
Interior. Theater. Day.
Scene 13. An acting
class in progress.
(Latin percussion music)
The sound of Latin
percussions fill the space
as a capoeirista
performs on stage
before twenty young students
sitting in the audience.
- The rhythmic movement
back and forth.
Got to keep your hands
in front of your face
in case you get a
foot coming at you.
If you do it from this side
you might come down here
and back up, and
strike with your foot.
The whole time you float
back into the Ginga.
This is the basis of capoeira.
Then you start getting
into movements like this.
And you might try to fake
them and then kick high.
The whole time you're
making it look like a dance.
You see the slaves in
Brazil weren't allowed
to train in fighting,
so they had to make
this look like a ritualistic
dance and they had
chains on their hands
so i'm blocking my face
like that but you see
the hands stay together.
(music stops)
You know each time Sam
came home from Iraq
something about him changed.
I could barely put
my finger on it
and neither could our friends.
It was something...
subtle. Barely perceptible.
We used to play capoeira
together in Central Park
and had plans to do so the
last time he came home.
But then he called
me the night before
and told me he
wouldn't be coming.
And he wouldn't tell me why.
I pressed him and
he finally said
he was afraid he
might hurt somebody.
Now as you just saw, capoeira
really isn't even combat.
There isn't even
much contact, it's
more dance than anything else.
So when he said
that, I realized that
it wasn't just us who
knew he had changed.
But deep down, Sam
knew it himself.
He no longer trusted himself
not to hurt his friends.
It pains me to say
this, but I'm afraid
the next time he
comes home on leave,
he'll have changed so much I
won't even know him anymore.
I'll have lost my best friend.
(applause)
- Well done, Sergio.
Seth, you're up.
(piano music)
♪♪
- This is my father's
favorite piece.
I learned it in high school
for the sake of pleasing him.
I was never the son
my father wanted.
That, is my brother Andrew.
He was the athletic one.
The popular kid
with charm to spare.
I was too much the mama's boy,
the piano player,
the singer and actor.
But dad loved this piece.
And sometimes I think
this piece of music
was the only real connection
we had as father and son.
(music stops)
When the war in Iraq began, my
parents thought it
was a just fight.
They thought toppling
Saddam Hussein would
be good for America
and good for Israel.
I disagreed loudly.
Andrew, on the other hand,
sided with my parents.
And he even joined
the marines so he
could get in the
war on terrorism.
I thought to
myself, at least one
of us would make
our father proud.
(piano plays) I remember
when he came home on leave.
They finally shipped
him off to Iraq.
Our family and
neighbors beamed at
Private Wiseman who
proudly wore his uniform
on the front porch
for everybody to see.
That was the last
time I saw him.
Nearly four months
later, he was dead.
(music stops)
That's when the music stopped.
A son that is followed
at home like a shroud,
my father no asked me to
play Mendelssohn for him.
We no longer watched
television at dinner time.
Gone are the politics
or the discussions.
Sometimes I think he can't
even bare to look at me.
I've come to realize that
I'm no longer his son.
I'm merely the
child who remains.
(applause)
- [Darwin] One summer,
a few years ago,
I observed this boy playing
guitar in Central Park.
Shirtless and bare
foot on the grass,
singing songs of
doomed hopeless love.
I only saw him for a moment
but I fell completely in love.
For years his body and
face fueled fantasies
from which whole
narratives evolved about
the life we would share,
and the love we would make.
I imagined it was a
Seth character when
I wrote the script to
"American Personae"
the movie I'll never get
the opportunity to make.
Can I tell you about him?
I'd like to tell you.
Not about the story which
is substantively about
the production of a
graduate student stage play,
instead, I want to talk to
you about what I'm most proud.
The characters. The first,
as I said, was named Seth.
And like me, at that age,
he be a thin Jewish kid
with artistic aspirations, as
well as a self-hating closet
case who chases after women
far too beautiful for him.
But it was after the first
draft began to circulate
and I started
getting feedback that
I realized how
badly Seth's story
needed to fit into modern times.
And my way of thinking
about being gay
and coming out was
terribly dated.
As I was talking
to this pen rod,
our culture had
changed so much that
it became difficult
for me to imagine
the character in the world
of the white middle class.
At the tender age of
43, I felt like a relic.
A museum piece from a bygone
era of act up and queer nation.
There was a time when, uh,
gay men's social calendar
was replete with
funerals, of all things.
My how times have changed.
Clearly, I needed
a new paradigm.
In African American
men, I found the
perfect models geared
for this precise purpose.
The characters would
still be fragments,
splinters of the
young man I once
was but refitted culturally.
And while "American Personae"
would still be about
several generations of
gay men and the different
worlds they inhabit, it
will now also be a tale of
young men for whom
Stonewall never happened.
This life on the down low is a
culture war waged from within.
- Okay, look. Are
you gonna be on
my ass all night again tonight?
I'm really tired
and I'd rather be on
your ass, if you
know what I mean.
- I'm sorry. Forget it.
- Okay. What is this for?
- A class.
- I can see that. It's a text
book. What kind of class?
- Literary and cultural studies.
- That's too bad.
Why'd you stop?
- You're not taking
this seriously.
- I'm sorry, Celia, but
you know I'd never be cast
for this sort of bad boy
part in a million years.
- Why not?
- Celia!
The branding character
belongs to one
of those wildlife
shorts on Animal Planet.
- That is so elitist.
- It's not elitist, it's
just this type of guy is
so outside my experience I
mean, I'm not from this world.
- Oh what, there are no
mechanics and plumbers
in daddy's little world
of doctors and engineers?
- Well I'm sure
that there were but
I don't know how they talk to
their wives or girlfriends.
And what I don't get
is how all these girls,
you know even, even the smart
ones go for guys like him.
- Well, bad boys are strong and
assertive, and women like that.
- Even when strong and assertive
means they treat
women like shit?
- I didn't say
they weren't jerks.
(phone ringing)
- Oh God.
- What?
Oh, speaking of your world.
- She stresses me out.
- You know if you
don't answer it
she's just going
to keep on calling.
- Hi mom. Yes. I'm on my
way home from the library.
Wait, why are you so worried?
You called for Deek?
Why would you do that?
Yeah well he's at the
apartment and I'm not.
I'm on my way there now, okay?
What, I'm fine!
Okay, I'm getting into the
subway, I'm going to lose you.
I'll call you tomorrow.
I love you too. Bye.
She's too much.
- I wonder what Brandon the bad
boy would have to
say about that?
- He'd probably
say I'm a bookish
little nerd who's terrorized
by his own mother.
- Oh, come on!
- I'd laugh too
if it weren't me.
- Aw, poor Isaiah. Don't worry.
I think bookish
little nerds are hot!
- [Celia] Oh, mmm! Okay!
A little softer, yeah!
Hmm, mm hmm! Yeah, like that.
That's really nice. Mm!
Don't stop, don't stop.
Mm, yeah! Slower,
slower, mm hmm.
Don't stop, don't
stop, don't stop.
Okay, now a little
faster, just a little bit.
- Okay.
- Oh, don't cum okay? Don't cum.
Just like that.
(pages turning)
- [Darwin] These are
some characters notes
I made while I was
revising the script.
The portrayal of Celia should
be approached cautiously.
It would be too easy
to play the part
as a one-dimensional
manipulative harpy.
This is a young lady who has
had a lot of bad luck with men.
In Isaiah, she sees
a lot of potential,
possibilities that he
could not see himself.
She merely wants to bring out
the best in him. And so on.
The conflict here is not that
Isaiah's attracted to men,
a dirty little secret that he
can't admit to himself, no.
The problem is his desire for
an ordinary middle class life.
Where Celia wants, more
than anything else,
a bohemian existence with
creative fulfillment.
- [Celia] Here's one for you.
Eric. Lead role.
Male. Early twenties.
Self-righteous, sharp
witted, intellectual.
Skinny hipster music geek with
a dark side. Oh,
I like it already!
This role requires a
broad emotional range,
character's deeply insecure and
prone to turns of
extreme aggression.
Student film, three
to four day shoot
plus two days of
intensive rehearsal.
Must be New York City based.
- I'm so done with
student films.
- They could be a great
networking opportunity.
- They're not worth
the humiliation,
or the cost of the head shot.
Besides, I'm going to be
too busy this semester.
- You drive me nuts.
- What?
- You get every role
you audition for,
but you don't take it seriously.
- I take it seriously
enough to know
when I can give it
a hundred percent.
And right now, I
don't think I can.
- Let me ask you a question.
Where do you see
yourself in ten years?
- Celia, you're starting
to sound like my parents.
- It's a simple question,
where do you see yourself?
- Realistically,
I guess teaching
English in some high school.
- And acting?
- I suppose I'll be
involved with the theater
department, maybe
community theater.
- You're not even gonna try
to make acting a career?
- Celia, the odds
of making it or even
just making a living as
an actor are pretty slim.
- That's so defeatist.
- It's not defeatist,
it's a fact.
They want runway
models with big pecs,
I mean, look at me. I'm
not exactly Ashton Kutcher.
- You're not even gonna try,
Isaiah, that's my point!
- Are you getting angry with me?
- No, I'm just frustrated.
- I can see that, why?
- Because you have more
talent than anyone I know.
It's so easy for
you and you don't
take it seriously.
You don't care.
- Come on, Celia.
- It just pisses me off.
- Don't be like that. I hate
it when you get angry with me.
- I'm sorry. Three months
in, I'm already nagging.
- Oh, you want me to go on
a few auditions don't you?
- I want you to
have more ambition.
- Uh, two auditions!
I'll go on two auditions.
- Three! And I get
to choose them.
- [Isaiah] Don't stop!
- So, the question
remains how can theater be
both entertaining
and instructive?
How can it be divorced
from a place of illusion
and transformed into a
place of active experience?
Non-melodramatic theater
is one kind of theater
that has very
specific social goals.
It forces the spectator into a
place of inquiry and criticism,
by perching the
theater of anything
magical and completely
stripping it
of its so called
hypnotic tensions.
The actor no longer pretends
that there's a fourth wall
and the audience
is no longer swept
away by what he sees on stage.
I can already see a lot of you
looking at each
other rolling your
eyes saying who
is this nut case.
Well, I'm your director,
and the first thing I
want to say to you as
your director is you will
all need to want to be here.
This is going to be a
very challenging and
growing experience
for all of us, but
you're gonna have to trust me.
Rasheeq has written
an epic play here,
and we're going to
perform it accordingly
to some very basic
Burkting principles.
(leaves wrestling)
(lighter striking)
- Celia.
- You missed her.
- Damn. You scared the shit
out of me. Who'd I miss?
- Celia and Rasheeq. I told
them I ran out of weed,
so they left. I'm sure
they'll be back soon.
Do you partake?
- Sure.
- [Isaiah] Don't you correction
guys have to take drug tests?
- Medical staff works for
a separate contractor.
Plus my one year
probation's over
so I have a window
for indulgence.
So you misplaced
your girlfriend?
- Guess so.
I saw the way she
and Rasheeq were all
over each other and vice versa.
- They were a little blatant.
- So you were expecting
to come in here
and find them having
a little rendezvous?
- Maybe.
(laughs)
- You theater people are
a humpy bunch aren't you?
I was just wondering
if the idea of Rasheeq
and Celia upset you
or turned you on.
- What do you mean?
- Rasheeq's a good looking guy!
- Yeah. Well he may be good
looking but I don't go that way.
- In the army, it's pretty
tricky. Sometimes dangerous.
You have to have a
fully operational
gay-dar like really,
really sharp.
- Is that so?
- Yup. Most in the time
other black dudes are
hard for me to read so I
get the false positives.
Except for you Isaiah.
- You're way off. Really.
- I can see you
getting off on the idea
of Rasheeq sticking it in her.
And you wondering
what it would be like.
- Why are you saying this?
- I have fantasies too.
- Obviously.
- I started making the costumes
for the show, you know.
- Edward mentioned it.
- Been thinking a lot about your
final fitting, you want
to know how it goes?
- Not particularly.
- You're trying on
the pants, and while
I'm making a few
alterations my hand gently
glides over your
ass, your crotch.
You told me to stop but
your dick's already stiff.
A few minutes later and
I'm going down on you.
I bet you're hard just
thinking about it.
(water running)
- I'm not my image.
- [Voiceover] Hello!
Is anybody home?
- Hello Stephen, if that
is in fact your real name.
- You're recycling lines
from your old scripts.
Venturing into Dennis
Potter territory, isn't it?
- Oh, in more ways that
you could possibly imagine.
- Video camera batteries.
- Ah, thank you!
So does this, uh, bring
you back a few years?
- "The Disquiet"
rehearsals? Yeah.
It seems like it
was just yesterday.
Hey, where's your
cast? Shouldn't you
guys be rehearsing?
They are most
likely still in bed.
I postponed it till one o'clock,
most of them are either
tend bar or wait tables.
- Of course.
- Figured I'd let them
sleep in on their first day.
- Well, that's nice of you.
- Keeps me from having
to pay for lunch.
- That's not so
nice but at least
I don't have to pretend anymore.
- [Darwin] What?
- Come, Nico told me you
lost funding a week ago.
- Yes.
- So you found
alternative funding?
- No.
- You're funding it yourself?
- Like I ever had any money.
- Okay, so what
am I missing here?
- Look, the project is
finished, Stephen. Okay?
Kaput. It's just dead
as a coffin nail.
- But you're going
through with it anyway?
- The theater rental's paid
and the fee's nonrefundable.
- Have you told your cast?
- No.
- Christ, Darwin!
- No lectures okay, please!
- Ugh!
Look, jerking yourself off is
one thing, this is just rotten.
- It is just a few days
out of their lives.
- These people are counting
on you and your non-film.
They're counting on a product,
a premiere, a wrap party.
You know all that shit!
- You're right!
You're absolutely right. My
actions are indefensible.
What do you want me to say?
Life's a bitch ain't it?
- Why are you doing this?
- Need.
- What need?
- I don't know. I don't know.
I guess it's because
I want to know
that the story has taken
place as a real event.
To know that these
characters existed.
- You have dozens of
unpublished scripts.
Many better than this one.
- Yeah, well this
one is the truth.
- You are so arrogant.
- Well it's the
truth as I see it.
- The truth is you
see it as ugly.
Why can't you write
about the positive
things in the gay community?
- Oh I see! The community
demands positive images!
I guess the community
and certain actors
don't want to look
in the mirror.
- I turned down that
part because it was ugly.
Edward was mean, he was twisted.
- Not he's not.
- Seriously, is
that how you see me?
- Half the lines I wrote for
him are direct quotes from you.
Alright, will you
just wait a second.
Here we go.
- Darwin.
- Here we go!
Listen to this.
"I've already had love
and it's long gone.
Now I just tie up
boys in my bed."
Does that sound familiar?
- We're through.
- What, is the mirror
too harsh for you?
- You're such a fucking asshole.
- What, do you deny you said it
or are you ashamed?
Are you embarrassed?
- Look, just return the
batteries when you're done
jerking yourself and
everybody else off!
- Better hurry up or you'll
be late for your GLAD meeting.
- It's bad faith, Darwin.
It's bad faith and it's wrong.
- I love you, Stephen!
- Go fuck yourself!
(laughs)
- [Darwin Voiceover] Even
before he left the theater,
I regretted goating my friend
into a pointless argument.
Since the doctors discovered
the cancer in my pancreas I,
I become aware of certain
shifts in my personality.
I feel less like
myself and more like a
bad copy of the man I once was.
All distorted and
blurred at the edges.
The character of Rasheeq
was to be a reflection
of my mid-twenties
when as a graduate
student I fancied
myself as a writer,
having dropped
acting in a strange
fit of internalized homophobia.
Wearing makeup is
undignified and
hardly masculine after all.
But I didn't just want to write,
I craved relevance most of all.
I also began to understand the
power my youth had over others.
Specifically, older gay men.
- [Voiceover] He
was my lover, Jorge,
we were together for five years.
- But most of us knew
him for nearly twenty.
- I'm not in
competition with you.
- I know you're not,
I'm sure the last
couple years have
been rough on you.
But it's been rough
on a lot of people.
Getting old is a bitch!
Getting old in the
age of AIDs? Oh, shit.
- Lonely, but it's better
than the alternative.
- True.
You know one of the
reasons I never called you
I wanted to give it enough
time after Carlito's death,
just to make sure of how I felt.
- [Kenneth] I don't want
to hear this, Jorge.
- [Jorge] I've always had
feelings for you, Kenneth.
- [Kenneth] Jesus,
you have been watching
too many of those
sappy telenovelas.
- [Jorge] Kenneth!
- [Kenneth] I
can't believe lines
like that still
work in Manhattan.
Or do you just see
all those first
Long Island guys in the sticks?
- [Jorge] Please!
Keep your voice down.
- [Kenneth] My voice is down, is
that why you invited me here?
- I just wanted to spend
some time with you.
- What, a twofer?
Use your loneliness
and get laid at the same time?
- [Jorge] Well get laid, anyway.
- You piece of shit!
- You're aging too, author boy!
If you don't sell
something big or
hook up with a nice
rich daddy quick,
well hell fourty's
just around the corner!
Then it's gonna get real tough!
Bagging groceries at the AMPM
might be closer than you think!
- Well done. Well
done! Any questions?
- I kind of like how
the scene had the men
talking directly to each
other, touching on nerves.
But the scene
itself isn't direct.
- Yeah, it was like a
strange awkward dance.
Even when you think
the Jorge character is
letting his guard down, it
turns out to be a gambit.
- So it wasn't soap?
- No! Not at all.
- This is the least soapy
thing we've workshopped so far.
- Good. Any questions, Arthur?
- Yeah. Um, without having
read the rest of the play,
were you able to
get a feel of the
characters just by
reading the lines?
- Sure.
- Totally.
- Even as a straight
guy that's never been
in a situation like
this, I mean I don't know
if it showed but
I was right there.
Just saying the words put
me where I needed to be.
- [Arthur] Interesting.
Trust me, it showed.
- Anyone else?
- Uh, when was this
supposed to take place?
- Yeah, I was wondering
the same thing myself.
- [Arthur] In the late
80's, early 90's when
a term "AIDs widow"
sort of took hold.
- Gentlemen, good
job. Good job, Arthur.
Okay, up next we have Rasheeq's
one act play "Corpis".
David, you've been game
for everything already.
- This is volunteer, right?
- [Stephen] Yes.
- I don't want to be
involved in this one.
- [Stephen] May I ask why?
- [David] I'd rather
not get into it.
- Well, you don't
owe me an explanation
but I think you do
owe the author one.
- [David] Look man,
I'm sure you mean well.
But if you want to do a piece on
the prisoners of
Guantanamo Bay, fine.
If you want to do a piece on
the Holocaust, you know, great.
But don't think
you can put those
two side by and in comparison.
- Why do you object
to the Auschwitz
reference and not to Manzanar?
- [David] That's personal.
- So it's your
history? As a Jew?
- Yeah, so?
- Manzanar is your history as an
American isn't it?
As a human being?
- Look, like I said, I
don't want to get into it.
- But you want to take
ownership of certain
histories and not others?
- Leave it alone, Rasheeq.
- [David] Look, show me
evidence that the prisoners of
Guantanamo Bay worked to
death, starved to death...
- Sadism isn't the
only parameter.
- Show me that, and I'll perform
in your shitty little play!
- This is inappropriate
in the class room.
- You know what, Rasheeq, maybe
I don't own the Holocaust
but I can lay claim to it.
My grandmother
survived Bergen Belsen.
You want to tell her how
GTMO compares to that?
- [Rasheeq] GTMO,
Manzanar, Genene,
I'm sure your grandmother would
be the first to see it my way.
- Great. So now you're an
expert on my grandmother.
- [Rasheeq] She'd
seen it all before,
or do you own your
grandmother's history too?
- You I love how
everybody in your world
denies the Holocaust
ever happened until
they can use it
to their own end!
- David, stop right there!
- And you think all
Holocaust denials
from my world? What is that?
- What about fuck you
and your quality of
suffering bull shit.
- [Stephen] Stop it!
- Don't you mean compassion,
mister arrogant Jew!
- Oh Christ!
- [Stephen] What was that?
- What the hell
he'd just call me?
- Out now! Out!
- [Sergio] Take it
easy, it's not worth it!
You're such an ass hole!
- [Rasheeq] Nothing to
say? I can't believe you
made me apologize to
him. It was humiliating!
- I can't believe you said it!
"Mister arrogant Jew"!
What are you thinking?
- He claimed he owned history.
- You claimed he owned history!
Do you have any idea the
position you put me in?
- I never said anything
even remotely Antisemitic.
- Don't be so naive, this isn't
about religion.
It's about politics.
Why can't you respect
my position for once?
- You covet yourself
well enough.
- Look, people can believe
that they own history.
It's normal, it's healthy.
Have you heard the
name Pierre Seel?
- No.
- Seel was a man, a
gay man, captured by
the Nazis and put in a
concentration camp by being gay.
The Nazis took a metal
bucket Seel's lover's
head, and they set
the dogs on him.
Tore him to pieces
before his very eyes.
- [Rasheeq] Your point?
- My point is that's gay
history. It's my history.
And as bad and rotten
as Guantanamo Bay is,
it's nothing compared to that.
- The United States of America
not as bad as Nazi Germany.
Don't you think you're
setting the bar a little low?
- [Darwin] Edward
is an amalgam of
several refugees from the 1980's
I've known over the years.
And like most of those man the
character's capacity to love
had been irreparably damaged
by loss. A tragic, empty husk.
(record plays piano music)
My poor friend Stephen couldn't
help but see
himself in the role.
(phone rings)
- Hello! Well, Mr.
Flood, how are you?
Right. I know your name's Kevin.
(laughs)
Uh huh. Listen,
I've got a career
opportunity for you in academia.
It would require you to dust off
your skills as a drama curch.
(phone rings)
- Hello?
Mama! Hello!
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Buh bye.
- [Stephen] No
that'd be fine. Okay.
Okay, so I'll fax
you the play tonight
and send him over in
the morning. Okay.
Oh, and I've set
up a meeting for
you with the department chair.
No, just be your
usual charming self.
(laughs)
Yeah. Alright,
alright. Bye, Kevin.
Ah! Thought you were gonna
let me die of thirst.
Was that your phone ringing?
- It was nothing, just a
little family business.
- Rash, Rash!
- Gin, Edward. I splashed
a little gin in my eyes.
- Ow.
I set up a meeting for you with
a friend on mine in Manhattan.
He wants to go over your play.
- Another teacher?
- No, this one's like you.
A little thick
headed for academia.
You will meet with
him, won't you?
- Yeah sure.
- Good.
On your belly.
Kevin Flood's the real deal and
the theater fest deadline looms.
- [Rasheeq] I'll go!
- Good, but I have some new toys
I want to use on you tonight.
- Can this be the
last time for a while?
I'd like to be able to go
to the beach this summer.
- Oh, you should let them
see the wounds of art.
- Edward.
- Alright, but that
means tonight is going
to have to be something
extra special.
- Tomorrow's your big day!
You must be very excited.
- I guess. I'm more
nervous than anything else.
It's out of my hands now.
What's wrong?
- I don't know.
On my drive home from
work I was really
looking forward to our play
time. Now i'm just bored.
- With me, or with the toys?
- I don't know.
- We could just try having sex.
You know, without
the accessories.
- Would you like that?
I thought you'd rather be
doing Isaiah's girlfriend.
- I almost did, but
then I realized she
doesn't interest me.
- So what interests
Rasheeq these days?
- You!
- Me?
- Pleasing you.
- Don't say that.
- Why not?
- Because I know where this is
going and I'll just ruin it.
- I owe you so much.
- You don't owe me anything.
- But, the giving and
the wanting together,
isn't that love?
- Fuck!
- Why are you
reacting like this?
- 'Cause that's not
part of the deal.
No wonder I've lost interest.
I should have seen this coming.
- I don't understand.
- I help you with your academic
career, and you surrender
your body to me,
that's the arrangement.
- We never had an arrangement.
- And then you leave.
Find a nice girl.
- And if I don't want that?
- You know damn
well you want that!
- Even if I want you?
- That's the deal breaker.
- Edward.
- You don't need me anymore.
When the production's
done I suggest
you find somewhere else to live.
- Please. Don't.
- You need to get
on with your life.
I'll get clean linens
for the guest room.
- You know, when I was younger
we used to rehearse
everything barefoot.
Don't bother asking me
why, I have no idea.
But as we soon as
climbed the thrust,
the shoes and the
socks came off.
I've come to think of the
stage floor as kind of a
third rail, connecting all
of us to it and each other.
The things one imagines.
I spoke earlier of the
crisis of metamorphosis,
but in 1988 and the
age of 27, I found
myself at a crossroads
of identity.
It was a time
filled with longing.
A longing to fill a void both
spiritual and intellectual.
Freshly home from
serving in Iraq and
nearing his 30th birthday,
the character of Wesley
was about to find himself
at a similar crossroads.
- I thought after a
time I would tire of
painting you but
you've become perfect.
Perfect age, right
on the cusp of 30,
a fit man's body
but with that boyish
mischievous spark
still in the eye.
I don't think
anybody could do it
justice in New Orleans,
certainly not in words.
And then it passes so quickly.
I think you know
what I'm about to say
and trust me, it isn't
any easier for me
to say than it is
for you to hear.
There are those of us
who have what it takes to
be an artist and those that
don't. It's as simple as that.
And God, I saw so much
potential in your earlier work,
so much possibility but
you just don't have it.
I mean whatever it was I saw
in those earlier paintings
that you brought to me, I mean,
what is it now? Three years ago?
Well whatever it was, I
don't see it and it's just,
it's just not there. I
mean, maybe it never was.
But you've known this for a
while, haven't you Wesley?
Of course you have, you're too
smart, you're too self aware.
Must be horribly
frustrating for you
but you'll just have to
settle for a lesser career.
Maybe like a senator or
president of something.
Wesley?
- [Darwin Voiceover] Wesley was
relieved to be told
he had no talent.
He felt liberated
from the tyranny
of his artistic potential,
free to pursue the
stability that be
desperately craved.
- [Voiceover] So
you said something
about the probability of
being stretched to the limit.
- Did I?
- I watched the tape.
- Oh, then I guess I did.
Well if you want me to
peel that particular onion
then I guess I should start
with the 1980's when any gay man
who was sexually active at
the beginning of the decade
was astonished that he was
alive at its conclusion.
Especially if everyone he knew
or slept with had perished.
- So it's just that you find
odd that you didn't get HIV?
- Odd? Odd and evens.
- What's that?
- Well, if you flip
a coin twelve times,
half the time it will land on
heads the other half, tails.
Two choices. Fifty percent
chance of either outcome.
Now, what if I told you it
landed on heads twelve times?
- That's impossible.
- It's not impossible but
it's probably improbable.
We call the universe improbable.
- But there are too
many variables in
something like
contracting a disease,
you can't compare it
to flipping a coin.
- Well, of course not.
But I thought of that too.
So I, one day, many
years ago, I dug
up my father's Colt
Python 6, a revolver.
I loaded a single round in the
chamber and I gave
it a good spin.
Then I put the barrel in my
mouth and I pulled the trigger.
Obviously I didn't
die, but there was
a one in six chance that
I'd blow my head off.
- Hey! You turned it
off at the best part.
You should have heard him go
on about the fabric of reality.
- Chances are I've
heard it all before.
- Oh I thought you'd be curious.
- Nope.
- Well, whatever.
Unless you told him,
he doesn't even know about us.
- Careful, Rene. He may seem
nutty but he's very perceptive.
Always sniffing for
blood in the water.
- How dramatic. God,
you're as bad as he is.
- Just do yourself
a favor and keep
it cool and
professional with him.
We're having fun and
he'd just ruin it.
These are new.
- I just printed them
for my entropy show.
If anybody would do it, I
can't even interest a gallery.
- They're fantastic,
like pictures of memory.
- Any particular memory?
- An old bus graveyard near the
train station when I was a kid.
Buses from like
the 40's and 50's.
I wanted more than anything to
explore them, find treasure.
- Sounds like a painting.
- Don't start.
Right now my interests
lie elsewhere.
- Ah! So this is a booty call.
Ah! I don't think so,
I'm sweaty and gross.
- Sweaty and gross is sexy!
- My shift in the restaurant
starts in an hour.
- I'll skip the appetizer and
go right for the main course.
- No, no, no, no!
I can't do that.
I gotta go, no. I gotta go!
- [Wesley] Want
to come out to the
island with me on Saturday?
- [Rene] Fire Island?
- [Wesley] Long Island.
- [Rene] Why?
- [Wesley] Look at houses.
- [Rene] No, I got a
wedding to shoot at two.
- [Wesley] And on Sunday?
- [Rene] A bar mitzvah.
- [Wesley] Oh. I
didn't realize your
videography business
was doing so well.
- [Rene] Why do you want
to live on Long Island?
- Why not? It's
the American dream.
Own a home, invest
in the future.
- ♪ Domestic bushes
shelter from failing♪
- That's a bit harsh.
- Tim Rice never lies. The
suburbs are about giving up.
- People get married
and have bar mitzvahs
out on the Island too, you know.
there's nothing stopping
you from working there.
- Well, I'm not just
interested in paying the bills.
That's not my world and
you're not that man.
- How do you know
what kind of man I am?
- You're ready to plunge
into this other life
just because one miserable
old has been thinks
that you're not an artist.
- Okay, I got it.
- Don't become that
other man Wesley.
I mean, what are you,
how old are you again?
- I'll be 30 next month.
- 30? Oh fuck! Forget what I
said, do whatever you like.
Ouch!
- Smart ass!
- You love my ass.
Ah! You made me late!
- Fuck.
- [Darwin Voiceover]
That scene between Wesley
and Rene is the
crux of the story.
The entire reason for bringing
these characters together.
Yeah, it's a conversation
I think gay men
should be having but can't. Why?
Because somewhere along the line
we got it into our heads that we
should want to be
like the straights.
That we could pretend
to be like them
You know, just as the
liberation came out
of the 70's and
death from the 80's,
the 1990's sewed the
seeds of assimilation
and conformity that
have taken root today.
The total hijacking of
the gay movement came
when we chose emulation
over invention.
- The only thing these
little gay boys want
today is from that insidious
institution of marriage.
- Imagine that!
- Don't laugh.
It barely works
for the straights.
God, the horror of our society
is that everybody works
so hard just to be normal.
- And end up voting Republican.
- Sad, but true. I mean this
is such a strange generation.
They're either out of the
closet the day they pop out
of the womb...
- Rene.
- Or, they're
walking a tight rope.
- Isaiah.
- Lovely, isn't he?
- Mm! He is! Funny
how everyone else
know he's gay except
him and his girlfriend.
- Well I don't know about that
last part but he is adorable.
- Stay away from him, Kevin.
Seriously, you have
nothing to offer that kid.
- Go fuck yourself.
- Don't delude yourself
into thinking that you
can save Isaiah, he isn't
going to reenlist like Wesley.
And come to think of it, I think
what you did with
him was really cruel.
- Well if he had gone back
to Iraq he might be dead now.
- You really think you can
save these kids, don't you?
Did it ever occur
to you that Wesley
knew who he was in the Army?
- No character's more fluid
than that and you know it.
- He wasn't a good
painter, Kevin.
Seriously, you made
him think he was
something that he wasn't,
and then burst his dreams.
And now that he's trying
to build his life back up
again what do you do?
Belittle his choices.
- Oh, he just wants to
live with his boyfriend
in some gingerbread
house in the burbs.
I'd hoped he'd be
stronger, you know invent.
- See that's what
I'm talking about.
That liberation shit doesn't
exist in their world.
They grew up on "Will &
Grace" for God's sake.
That's a big shift.
- None of it's real. I mean
a life cannot be purchased.
- Yes, it can! A life
today is a life style.
Citizenship is out,
consumerism is in.
Or have you been dead
too long to realize that?
- Or perhaps alive too
long to truly believe it.
Well, I'm not dead yet.
- I know. I realized that when
I was watching you talk
to your cast tonight.
- You mean my old
shpeel, my shtick.
- You were the old
Kevin. Strong, confident.
Inspiring others
with your ideas.
Look, just do your
job. Be their teacher,
and stay the hell
out of their lives.
- Well you're one to talk.
- I'm not like you
Kevin. I just play with
their bodies, not
fuck with their souls.
- Such a bitch.
- I haven't spoken about
the Kevin character
mostly because I find him
to be the most troubling.
Now if I had the possibility
of celebrating my 60th birthday
he's the man I fear
I would become.
An anguished, impotent
artist who has
survived long passed
his creative half life.
Bitterly spending his
autumn years teaching
talentless rich kids at
some private college.
Well, dying of cancer
is a bitch but I,
I prefer my fate to
that of this character.
The outliving of
one's creative self.
I'll let you guys
decide for yourself
whether or not that last
statement is true or not.
I'm not sure myself.
(video camera beeps)
I started making this
video to talk about
the characters and how they
relate to their author.
I mean, who knows,
maybe this will
be playing at my
memorial service.
That said, the
movie's conclusion,
seeing between Wesley and Isaiah
is one that speaks
of the horror of
having one's terrible
desires fulfilled.
(knocking)
- [Wesley] Come in.
- Hi.
- Hey. I thought I
was done but then
I saw something that
needed fixing, so.
(sewing machine working)
- Is this where your
fantasy takes place?
- Not exactly. Not in
Kevin's studio at any rate.
It was different.
Look about that.
I was drunk and high that night.
I shouldn't have said
those things to you.
- How did you imagine it?
- [Wesley] What?
- The room. You said you
imagined it differently.
- A dark grimy
room with bolts of
fabric everywhere
like in El Paso.
- [Isaiah] You did
theater in El Paso?
- Community theater,
just costume
and stage hand stuff, you know.
I was stationed at Fort Bliss.
(Sewing machine working)
There. Done.
- You're not going
to watch my undress?
- You can go in the
other room if you want.
- Uh uh. I want you to watch me.
- Nice underwear.
- Celia bought 'em for me.
- [Wesley] Figures.
- I'm like whatever,
never really thought of
underwear as being
all that important.
- Neither did I.
I always wore the
Sears brand growing
up, still do.
I always thought they
made me a third rate homo.
- I, uh, had a boyfriend
in high school.
- Oh yeah?
- Jacob and I, we were
supposed to go to NYU together,
after he finished his tam
ritz studies in Israel.
- Didn't turn out
that way did it?
- I think his parents
suspected him, or us.
They ended up
sending him to a real
conservative
yeshivah in Tel Aviv.
- Damn.
- I heard the rabbi there
is like a cult leader.
Jacob never came back.
Not to stay or anything.
I was afraid it would happen,
but I knew that it would.
Deep down I think
that he knew it too.
- That's crazy.
- About a year later
we came to visit
his family during one
of their holidays.
He hadn't written
to me in months.
Thought, you know,
hey maybe he couldn't.
I was so excited,
so happy to see him.
- But what happened?
- His eyes were distant, he
wouldn't even shake my hand.
He refused it right there in
front of his whole family.
I mean, before he left
I'd been with him.
I held him and I
kissed him, then
at the airport he just
looked right through me.
- Shit. That's horrible.
- Well aren't you
gonna check the fit?
- Yeah, I know it
needs to be done up.
Take it up a few inches.
- Check it, please.
I was so pissed off
that night at Edward's.
- 'Cause of Celia and Rasheeq?
- 'Cause I felt like a fraud.
You have no idea how close I
was to fooling around with you.
I mean, I wouldn't have pursued
it or initiated anything but...
- You just would
have let it happen?
- [Isaiah] Yeah.
- You like me touching you?
- Yes.
- So you're going to just
let something happen now?
- Mm hmm.
- If we do this now
it makes you a trick,
I want you to be more than
that do you understand?
- Mm hmm.
- Drinks after
rehearsal? Maybe dinner?
- I'd like that.
- Better get out of here before
certain imaginations
go into overdrive.
Don't stand me up, Isaiah. Okay?
I'm really looking forward to
getting to know you better.
- Exterior. Theater.
Night. Scene 73.
Busy east village street
on a hot summer's evening.
Wesley exits the theater and
looks around quickly spotting
the circle of actors
assembled near the box office,
watching as they smoke and
chat amongst themselves.
He catches sight of Isaiah and
for a moment their eyes lock.
But the circle unwinds
and Celia appears at
its center just before the
other actors begin to disperse.
In a display that
Wesley understands is
meant for him alone,
Isaiah puts his arm around Celia
and gives her a kiss
on the forehead.
Wesley cracks a pained
ironic smile as he
watches them walk
into the distance.
Although it's
tragically obvious,
Wesley and Isaiah
will never meet
even though that's
what they both desire.
A chasm at once social, sexual,
and political that
cannot be filled.
(knocking)
- Darwin!
- Maybe he's not in there.
- [Wesley] He's in there.
- [Isaiah] How'd you know?
- [Wesley] I heard him talking.
- Stephen was right.
It is bad faith.
- Darwin. Darwin!
- Dear God who slipped
Pirandello into my morphine?
(knocking)
- Darwin! Come on
man, let us in!
- Darwin, let them in.
Let them bring us to life.
- The project's finished.
- Maybe he's having a seizure.
(knocking)
- [Rasheeq] Darwin!
- We deserve to exist
beyond your imagination.
- How could I become this?
Maybe I have outlived myself.
(knocking)
- Darwin!