(Women laughing,
chattering)
oooh-whoo!
(laughing, chattering
continue)
woman:
uh-huh.
there you go, baby.
mmm!
- go for it, benny.
- yeah, benny! go get it!
go for it!
- you mind if i join you?
- if you think you can keep up.
c'est votre monde.
- go for it!
- yeah, go ahead! go ahead!
(women hooting,
cheering)
yeah, benny!
(women shouting,
hooting continues)
go, benny, go!
i've got something
for you.
don't hold it back
now.
girl:
benny! benny!
- benny! benny!
- what?
get out of that
damn shower already!
damn it, tasha!
get out!
mama said
you gotta get out.
tasha, i'll be right out.
all right? i'll be right out.
- mama said now!
- tasha, leave me alone!
mama said she don't know what you could
be doing in here for an hour and a half!
kiss my ass, all right?
now go tell her that!
mama, benny just told me
to kiss his big black butt!
what's going on
in here?
ma, i am trying
to take a shower!
i told you not to
pick on your sister.
okay, mom,
i'm very sorry.
benny, come downstairs
and help me wash the car.
all right, i'll be right out, dad.
one second.
don't take that tone
with me, boy!
you've been up here
an hour and a half.
you think water
grows on trees?
don't take that long
to wash your big, wide ass.
what is there,
a drought around here or something?
i heard that.
there's gonna be a drought on food,
you keep talkin' back.
(chuckles)
- so i see you're not stickin' to your diet, huh?
- this is low-fat.
put it down.
get that off of there!
so, first day
on the new job, huh?
- excited?
- no, dad, i--
you know,
i remember my first job back in college-- milking cows.
not very glamorous,
but taught me to respect the dollar.
i thought this summer i'd just take a poetry class.
no, you're gonna have plenty of time
for poetry back in school next fall.
- this summer it's work. physical, manual work.
- but, dad--
nothing like physical work,
especially for a boy in your shape.
get you moving a little bit.
but, dad, only 10 people
got accepted to this class.
benjamin, writin' didn't buy this car.
hard work did.
every time i sit behind the wheel,
i feel like i can conquer the world.
i want you to know
that feeling, son.
- yeah?
- yeah.
so i could drive
the car now?
get that "conquering the world" feeling going.
i can even drive it to work,
'cause my bike is broke.
you ain't gonna conquer nothin' in my car.
take your sister's bike.
- but, dad, that's a girl's bike!
- who'll know?
- jesus, durrel! turn that shit down!
- sorry, mr. king.
hey, what's up, benny?
- so, what are your plans for the summer, durrel?
- oh, you know me.
hang out.
listen to some tunes.
sleep.
terrific.
hey.
come up here, baby.
- me and trisha was thinkin' about--
- theresa! it's theresa!
baby, i know
it's theresa.
trisha's just like my little pet name for you,
that's all.
anyway, benny, me
and tr-- uh, theresa--
was thinkin' about
going to that carnival.
- you want in?
- no, man, i gotta go to work.
work? what about
that poetry nonsense?
- oh, my father didn't think it was a good idea.
- you pussy!
- come on, durrel!
- you never stick up for what you want.
- oh, man.
- all right then, man. we outta here.
(engine starts)
bye-bye, fat boy!
fuck you, durrel.
he's teaching me
about responsibility,
getting me prepared
for my future!
welcome to
the house of burgers,
where the burger's
the king.
can i take
your order, please?
i'll have a burg-- ap--
and a-- lar--
i'm sorry,
i-i couldn't hear you.
would you mind
repeating that?
i said i'll have a large--
ur-- ah-- meno--
- what?
- come on, man!
get your shit together!
"get my shit together"?
benny, remember,
the customer is always correct.
do you mind
repeating that?
- i can't really hear you that clearly.
- okay, man.
i said i'll have a burg--
ap-- and a-- lar--
- what?
- what seems to be the problem, man?
the problem is you don't know how to fucking speak!
look, jerk-off, just get me
a burg-- app-- and a larg--
or i'm gonna come
in there and kick your ass!
- oh, yeah?
- actually, i'm gonna blow your head off.
somebody pass me
them bullets.
i'm gonna kill
this fool.
i need a quick break.
durrel!
what, you tryin' to
get me fired?
no, man, just tryin' to add a little
excitement to your miserable summer.
- this here's dana. right?
- yes, it is.
dana, this is my boy benny.
uh, cool outfit, man.
fuck you, durrel!
gimme a minute,
would you, baby?
gimme a minute.
gimme a minute. gimme a minute.
what happened
to theresa?
oh, man. lost and found
at the carnival.
lost her, found dana.
maybe you could score us a
burger and fries or something.
- durrel, i only been working here for an hour!
- chill, man. i hear you.
- that ain't why i'm here anyway.
- why are you here then?
two words, baby:
the fuckin' beach.
quit your job.
let's mob to the beach today!
are you stupid?
you know damn well i can't go nowhere.
my father got me this job.
lookee here. lookee here.
tell me what you see.
so what?
a box of sunglasses.
- i got 'em for 10¢ apiece!
- fuck you, durrel.
- what do you mean, fuck me?
- i know what you're thinking.
i'm not getting caught up in no
more of your stupid-ass schemes.
we sell 'em for five bucks apiece,
we make about five grand.
- you can take that class.
- no, man.
i'm not with it, man.
- plus the beach bitches.
- "beach bitches"?
beach bitches!
the hottest in the world, man.
we go down there
and we just fuck 'em all,
'cause in l. a. that's all
they wanna do is fuck.
their parents encourage
that type of behavior.
for real?
i don't know, man.
i gotta work here during the day and write at night.
- van gogh, man, you a virgin.
- shh!
what the hell you doin'?
you tellin' the whole city.
how you gonna be a great writer like
van gogh if you don't fuck somebody?
see how stupid you are?
van gogh was a painter.
you think van gogh
don't get laid?
benny! we got
mouths to feed, huh?
and tell your little
ugly friend
if he ain't buyin' nothin',
he's gotta leave.
all right.
i'm comin' in.
- (whispers) fuckin' asshole.
- did you say somethin'?
- no, sir. no, sir.
- see what i'm sayin'?
you gonna be like that
the rest of your life?
we leave at 1:00,
we on the beach makin' money by 3:00, guaranteed.
your parents are goin' out
of town anyway, man.
here. take these
sunglasses, man.
as soon as you put them on,
women will begin flockin' to you.
manager:
big ben. my boy.
you can't be serving my customers with sunglasses on.
people gonna think
you on drugs or somethin'.
i think they're hot.
leave 'em on.
- benny, take 'em off now.
- they're sexy.
- leave 'em on.
- the customer's always right.
why don't we go
somewhere romantic?
why don't you just give me
a big kiss?
aaah! what the hell
are you doin'?
- benny, what's goin' on?
- i'm trying to order something
when he jumps the counter like
he's tryin' to attack me!
i thought there was a-a-a bee
or somethin' on her shoulder.
he was gonna attack me with
that look of lust in his eyes.
don't look at me like that,
you sinner.
manager: benny, what's wrong?
you seem to be distracted.
i'm talking to you,
benjamin!
don't call me benjamin.
benny, if you walk
out that door,
i'm afraid you will not have a home
here at the house of hamburgers.
benjamin, i'm calling
your father!
girl, you look like
a pot o' chitlins!
mm-hmm.
raise on up and let me see them candied yams.
okay, baby.
(imitates engine revving)
- yo, durrel, let's go get some beach bitches!
- (gasps)
ohh!
damn you, durrel!
come back here, baby!
don't leave me hangin'!
shit, benny!
you wanna watch me fuck,
i'll put you in the closet
or some shit like that!
- but ask first!
- my fault, durrel.
come back here, baby.
durrel still loves you.
benjamin!
what are you doing home from work?
- uh--
- (whispers) ran outta meat.
they ran outta meat.
"they ran outta meat"?
yo, come inside
and help your mother pack.
man, if he calls my dad,
i'm dead.
man, relax.
ain't nobody gonna call nobody.
- (rings)
- hello?
benny, let me speak
to your father.
i'm sorry, i can't let
you do that right now.
benny, put your father
on the phone now!
i'm sorry.
you have the wrong number.
damn, durrel.
- (rings)
- (sighs) hello?
benny, you fat
little chubby weasel!
put your father on the phone
right now!
i'm sorry, there's no one
home right now,
but if you call back we can all talk to you at one time.
bye-bye.
yo, durrel, i'm dead, man.
what am i gonna do?
- want me to cut the phone wires? i'll do it.
- no.
- i'll smooth cut them motherfuckers.
- (phone rings)
destructive motherfucker.
what to do?
- leave the phone off the hook.
- yeah. you're right.
father:
benny, who's on the phone?
uh, nobody.
it was for me. i got it.
yo, get your head out the
fridge and help pack the car!
- come on, durrel.
- i ain't liftin' shit, man. i got a bad back.
- take out the garbage. mow the lawn.
- easy on the door, benjamin.
- keep your room clean and stay off the phone.
okay, baby? - i'm not a baby.
ohh! baby, get up.
can i help you?
pull yourself together.
are you all right?
- do you have the map?
- i told you i don't need-- easy!
- i don't want to get lost on this trip again.
- what "again"?
- just get the map.
- look, we're going up and down the coast.
as long as the ocean's
next to us, we'll be fine.
will you please go in
the house and get the map?
i'll go get the map.
no, you stay here
and let your father get it.
you say goodbye
to your sister.
fat ass.
midget.
"find the map."
i don't need a map.
i got a compass
in my mind.
- (buzzing)
- who left the damn phone off the hook?
(rings)
my fault, pop.
hello?
oh, uh, hold on,
okay?
- who is it?
- it's for durrel.
durrel? what's that boy gettin' calls for here?
don't he have a home?
i don't know.
i'll talk to him, though.
durrel!
the phone!
well, did you find
the map?
- we'll stop and get a map.
- woman, enough about the damn map.
(engine starts)
benjamin, check on my car
every night, okay?
it's benny.
- yo, who you talkin' to?
- it's your old boss. he's got me on hold.
- yo, man, gimme the phone.
- chill, man!
i'm tryin' to get you
outta trouble.
uh, yeah, yeah.
how you doin'?
mr. washington,
your son gave me nothing but insubordination.
insubordination?
- gimme the phone.
- he what?
- what are you doin'?
- just walked out?
benjamin! get your ass
down here right now!
- come down here, fatty!
- what are you doin'?
gettin' you outta trouble.
i'm gonna beat your ass bad!
i don't think hittin' a child's gonna do any good,
but if you gotta
beat him--
durrel:
you fat, lazy...
- waste of space!
- gimme the phone.
use the left.
durrel:
it's for your own good, son.
daddy, no!
daddy! daddy!
please, daddy, not the hot wax!
daddy, you're burning me!
gimme the phone!
i got you outta trouble.
- yeah, right.
- got you outta trouble.
you see? that's what happens when
you leave the house of hamburgers.
you get your ass whipped!
now y'all remember that.
come on. we got a big
lunch crowd coming in.
whoo-whee!
this a cool-ass box, bro.
- i got it for my birthday.
- man, we gots to take it to the beach.
nah, it'd get ruined.
it won't get ruined.
it'll get ya laid.
i'll carry it.
i can't wait 'til we get down there, man.
boy, i'm gon' have a ball.
look like i done
took off a few pounds.
i got a little thinner here.
what you think?
thinner than an elephant.
- fuck you, durrel.
- i'm just fuckin' with you, man.
actually, i was gonna ask you what your secret was.
we can bottle this shit
and make a fortune.
we could, huh?
(snickers)
- so, when's dana gonna be here?
- dana who?
you know. dana.
you was just--
oh, that.
she ain't comin'.
i thought she was gonna
drive us down.
benny, man, you don't take
seashells to the beach.
they already
got 'em there!
- so how we gonna get there?
- that's a good question.
no way, durrel!
first you make me quit
the job my dad got me--
- i didn't make you quit your job.
- you made me quit the job.
all that talk about those beach bitches.
now you wanna take his car?
- he love this car more than my mother!
- benny.
- no way, man. no way!
- benny, man.
- look at this car.
- i'm not allowed!
remember what you told me your
dad said about conquering the world?
he said you could do anything
behind the wheel of this car, man.
feel it. feel its power!
(imitates engine rumbling)
oh. is that your daddy?
you hear your daddy?
"benjamin, you can have anything in this car, son.
all the pussy you want."
daddy was talkin' about pussy, man.
all you can handle.
benny:
durrel, my boy.
ready to take a ride
on the phat side?
- whoo!
- (tires screeching)
how'd you like to read me
some poetry?
- get out, durrel.
- what?
out.
i'll get the keys.
(rap music playing)
pick up the pace,
biggie smalls,
or we ain't gonna get
there till next summer.
(bicycle horn honks)
- i got a problem, man.
- what's that?
i think i'm addicted
to pussy.
it's like it controls my mind,
like crack or something.
no offense, benny, but in
order to be addicted to crack,
first you gotta try the shit.
now let's get to the bank.
- how much should i get?
- how much you got?
- $300.
- cool. take it.
- all of it?
- yeah.
what? are you crazy, durrel?
that's my life savings!
man, you gotta have money
to make money.
- we entrepreneurs!
- we are?
trust me, man.
durrel gonna handle the partnership.
well, mr. entrepreneur,
how much you got for the partnership?
- how much what?
- money. how much you got?
- on me?
- yeah! how much you got?
- or in the bank?
- either one.
- on me?
- yeah. how much money you got on you?
uh, nothin'.
i ain't got nothin' on me.
- and in the bank?
- shit in the bank neither.
(music playing)
(engine starts)
hey, durrel!
don't do it! durrel!
that's my dad's car! durrel, wait!
♪ i thought a lot
about us ♪
♪ and so i made up
my mind about it ♪
♪ and it's your love
that i'm after ♪
♪ got to make it happen
then you'll see ♪
♪ baby, then you'll see ♪
♪ it's not about
a big old one-night stand ♪
- ♪ i'm tryin' to show you i'm the only man... ♪
- (horn honking)
♪ for ya ♪
♪ i'm glad to treat you
like no other man can ♪
♪ 'cause i'm here with you,
it's somethin' 'bout me ♪
♪ and it's somethin'
about you ♪
♪ so, baby,
let me know... ♪
you the only one
for me, baby.
the only one.
(snaps fingers)
next.
you the only
one for me, baby.
- (snoring)
- (truck horn blaring)
- (horn blaring)
- benny!
- (continues snoring)
- what?
- benny, you fat, stupid motherfucker!
aaaah!
whoo, boy!
you almost crashed your daddy's car!
hee-hee! whoo!
♪ why can't you see i'm only
here to treat you right? ♪
did that sign say
arizona?
uh, n-no, baby.
(chuckles)
you're just dreaming.
go back to sleep.
i think it did say
arizona, daddy.
no, you're too young
to read, sweetheart.
take a nap.
- you called me fat.
- no, i didn't. when?
- when i was drivin'.
- you mean, when you was sleepin'.
it was just
an expression, man.
"you stupid,
fat motherfucker"?
in all the books i've read,
i've never read that expression.
i'm sorry.
i can't help it
'cause i like to eat.
you could eat
a little less, man.
girls won't like me
at the beach.
what are you
talking crazy for?
they like them big
bodybuilder-type guys.
bullshit, man.
i ain't got no
bodybuilder's-type body,
but i gets crazy pussy
at the beach.
i get crazy pussy
everywhere, though.
christ!
it's all attitude, man.
look at the fat boys.
them guys get
the hottest ladies around.
not 'cause of their bodies,
i'll tell you right the fuck now.
it's attitude.
you get 'tude,
like the fat boys,
you'll be scoring all over.
- think so?
- know so.
look.
them honeys over there.
watch. attitude.
ladies!
what's up?
they don't
speak no english.
they swedish or swishish
or some shit like that.
- how you know?
- i don't. don't care either.
it's like those
penthouse forums, man.
the only word they understood was "mercedes."
- (women giggling)
- (honks horn)
look, man,
forget all that.
if i give you the keys
and let you drive the car,
you gotta promise
to drive slow.
- i'm gonna drive slow!
- not too fast.
who's to say what
too fast is, anyway?
whoo!
get out of the way!
hey! move it, move it!
whoo-hoo-hoo!
(tires screeching)
oww! oww!
owww-ooooh!
(siren wailing)
i told you to slow down.
- this is gonna cost us money.
- chill, man.
- i saved us money on a motel room.
- how you do that?
the girls said if we drive 'em to l.
a., they'd pay for the motel.
if they don't speak english,
how you know they said that?
i translated.
if you fellas are drivin'
to l. a., i'd go a lot slower.
yes, sir.
no, no.
one room is fine.
you know who that is
over there?
that's coolio
over there, man.
there's no way we're gonna
be able to pay for this room.
man, i said i'm gonna
handle it.
the girls are gonna
pay for the room.
- our biggest problem is how we're gonna
ditch 'em after. - now you wanna ditch 'em.
what are you tryin' to do?
why you wanna ditch 'em?
i ain't tryin' to be
posted all weekend.
gonna drop them off at the
room and go do our own thing.
man.
no, no, no, no.
you stay.
we go. okay?
we go. okay.
(laughs)
free motel, baby.
let's walk it to the beach.
whoo-whee!
this beach
is phat!
it's like heaven, man.
what you think?
it's all right.
i think i'm starvin', though.
let's go somewhere
and get something to eat,
sell some sunglasses
and be outta here.
oh, man, it's too late to start sellin' sunglasses.
see, everybody bonin' out.
well, let's just go get
somethin' to eat.
man, we just got
to l. a., man!
all you can think about
is food?
man, let's go
get some women!
durrel, let's go somewhere
where there's both.
women and food.
how 'bout that?
♪ oh, yeah ♪
♪ chester in the house ♪
♪ hide your kids ♪
♪ here we go now ♪
♪ bop your head ♪
♪ bop, bop your head... ♪
good lord!
you're beautiful, baby!
(imitates engine revving)
she's beautiful.
ain't she, benny?
- mm-mmm.
- man, what's more important to you, food or pussy?
yo, look, don't even ask me
no hard question like that.
i'm figurin' to go
walkin' around.
- give me some money.
- what?
what do you need
money for?
what you think, man?
in case of emergency.
shit.
all right, go ahead.
spend the money.
take the money. you always do.
$3?
hi, i'm angel.
what's your name?
um, benny-- benny.
excuse me.
how you doing, benny?
i'm all right.
so, uh, you go to school
around here or somethin'?
(blubbering)
so that's when i decided that, um,
i wanted to be a writer.
let me dance
for you.
- why me?
- why not you?
well, i just never figured
a girl like you would be
interested in a guy like--
- let me dance for you.
- okay.
(slow music playing)
♪ do you want me?
do you want me, baby? ♪
(upbeat music playing)
(whimpers)
whoo!
(laughs)
did you like that?
yeah.
actually, i wish
you wouldn't have stopped.
want me to dance
for you again?
- uh-huh.
- okay.
good lord.
heavens to murgatroyd!
what, my money
not good enough for you?
d. j: okay, guys,
let's hear it for the sinister shaniqua!
shit, man, hold up
some real money.
was somebody
talkin' to you?
i'm the only one in this place who's gonna talk to you
when you got a measly dollar
hangin' out your mouth.
your teeth gonna be hangin' out your
mouth if you don't get outta my face.
i just thought you were a happenin' brother like myself.
brother?
man, you ain't no brother.
- you're just a sucka, man!
- see, now i'm gonna fight you.
what's that,
six dances already?
actually, i think it's seven,
but let's shoot for eight.
you want another dance?
- hell, yeah!
- okay.
all right!
benny, benny!
i see you done found
yourself a little hotty.
- shake that thang!
- durrel, don't talk to her like that.
relax, g.
she really
likes me, man.
- hee-hee!
- what's so funny, man?
she been dancin' for me
like this all night.
- benny, man, you gotta pay her.
- what?
you think i'm that desperate,
i'm gonna be payin' for this?
- sweetheart.
- what are you doing, durrel?
you just doin'
your thang,
shakin' your pretty,
round, brown butt,
- but you got my boy here confused.
- (sighs)
benny, my shift's almost over anyway.
why don't we settle up?
settle up?
eight dances.
that's $200.
i thought
you really liked me.
i do like you.
fellas, is there
a problem here?
cheap
motherfuckers!
oh, you real tough when you got
all them strippers around you!
shit, benny!
$200, man!
how could you be
so stupid?
now we only got
50 left.
- 20.
- 20?
i spent the rest
on food.
look, man, you drive.
i'm too depressed.
i don't have
no luck with women.
what's happenin',
"brutha"?
- who is this?
- you wanna race?
- against that? please.
- what? who is this guy?
benny, get in.
get in.
durrel, you're not racin'
my dad's car.
that's it!
you're not racin'!
- race you to the beach.
- don't race him.
you're not racin'
my dad's car!
durrel, are you crazy?
i'll die.
80 miles an hour.
you boys got any drugs on you?
no, sir, officer.
just a video camera.
yeah, yeah.
real good one too.
yeah, just a real good
video camera.
i told you
to slow down, man.
you trying to get us
locked up out here?
- my dad's gonna kill me.
- your daddy never gonna find out.
shit, man, i'm fucked.
my father finds out everything.
"stay next to the ocean,
and we'll be fine."
where is the damn ocean?
yah-dah-dah-dah!
it's just nonstop complaining with you.
look at your daughter.
she's just a little girl
and she hasn't eaten all day.
you're okay,
aren't you, baby?
i think i'm gonna
die, daddy.
(dance music playing)
(laughing)
(imitates
engine revving)
ladies, ladies.
party, party!
- (giggling)
- benny, man, go get the box.
benny,
go get the box!
man, i don't want
any of that stuff.
come on, man.
don't embarrass me.
these girls
are really into us.
man,
how can you tell?
duh, i don't know.
come on, man, take a hit.
(coughing)
hey.
- which one you want?
- what?
- pick one. i'll take the other.
- (coughs)
i don't even know
those girls.
- what are you, a butt pirate?
- fuck you, durrel.
at least my first time is gonna be with somebody i know.
(speaking swedish)
(coughs)
you motherfuckers
keep that shit down!
what are you
doing here, casper?
i thought this was
a high-class joint.
what do you got in here,
a little party?
whoa, ladies!
what's up?
yo, mikey z's in the house.
and you guys are?
they don't speak english,
asshole.
they don't know what
i'm talkin' about.
fuck! this is like
a penthouse forum.
sound like somebody
you know?
who?
(slow music playing)
♪ it's been too long ♪
(woman vocalizing)
- you know what your girl's thinkin'?
- how lucky she is?
wrong.
she's wishing someone would call switch
so she could see
what a real man's like.
(sighs)
woman:
you like poetry?
'cause i love poetry.
boy, what is you doin'?
playin' golf.
what you doin'?
i was gonna go get
some more ice.
some crazy shit happenin' in there, man.
you know what i'm sayin'?
no, not really.
girl's into crazy sex.
you wanna try?
- try what?
- stabbin' that!
- she wouldn't be into me.
- she told me she would.
- yeah, right.
- she told me!
- what'd she say?
- she said she likes 'em big.
- real big.
- bullshit.
no, man. no offense,
but my ass was a little too narrow for her.
you fuckin'
with me, durrel.
man, you gonna
hit them skins or not?
i just want my first time
to be special.
you see
the titties on her?
they plenty
motherfuckin' special.
- i don't know what to do.
- you don't need to know nothin', man.
old girl's
like an instructor.
now go in there
and tame that ass.
- yeah.
- yeah! whip that booty!
whip that booty.
tame that ass.
- but leave the lights off.
- all right.
and don't talk.
- see, man! don't talk?
- no need for talk.
i thought maybe i'd read her
a little poetry to get her goin'.
she don't need
to get goin'.
- you're fucking with me. you're bullshitting.
- no!
did she say
she wants me or not?
- not exactly.
- oh.
what exactly did she say?
i don't know.
she don't speak no english.
oh, you asshole,
durrel!
benny, it don't matter
what she said.
the girl's into crazy sex,
and she don't care who it's with.
she was all over me
and that beastie boys reject.
- she was all over him?
- all over both of us.
- vanilla ice?
- yes.
- i know i can get it.
- my boy.
yeah.
(grunts)
shh.
(loud cracking,
crash)
oh, benny.
(chuckles)
nice goin',
lightweight.
- chubby, you done broke the bed.
- (giggling)
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist and wind and-a check-a,
check-a check-a check-a ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist and wind and-a shake
and a little bit of ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist it once and then wind,
don't never give it up now ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist and wind and-a shake
and a little bit of ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist it once and then wind,
don't never give it up now ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist it once and then wind,
don't never give it up now ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ twist it once and then wind,
don't never give it up now ♪
♪ shake it up, shake it up,
shake it up now ♪
♪ it's time to get ill
on this track... ♪
that's it, man.
we ain't got no more money.
you didn't have to get no
whole damn dozen doughnuts.
durrel, i'm not gonna change my eatin'
habits 'cause you didn't bring enough money.
whoooooo-whee!
(imitates engine revving)
baby!
we'll worry about money later.
lock the trunk.
hold the glasses, baby.
later?
what do you mean, later?
we don't have no money,
no future, no job.
how we gonna get lunch?
durrel: hey, carol! carol!
- it is carol, isn't it?
- no. corey.
aw, shit.
i'm so embarrassed.
i told you this
wasn't carol, man.
she's way too pretty
to be carol, anyway.
whoo!
this is my friend
glori.
how you doin'?
i'm durrel.
um, i was just gonna go for a little swim.
you wanna join me?
sure. why not?
do you mind?
- no. go ahead.
- cool. let's go.
meet me back
at the car in an hour.
we gonna
sell some sunglasses.
durrel!
(sighs)
i'm one of
the fat boys.
- really?
- yeah.
which one?
uh, the fat one.
that's original.
hmph!
(sighs)
♪ must be how it works ♪
♪ land of wanna-bes,
gotta-bes and soon-to-bes ♪
(chuckles)
♪ yeah ♪
♪ searchin' ♪
♪ across a world
so full of misery ♪
♪ and games ♪
for someone ♪
♪ who said that she'd show me
the way to love again ♪
♪ you told me ♪
♪ that i'd never need
to search for love again ♪
♪ but i wonder ♪
♪ if you are in it for the love
and not just games ♪
♪ you just keep talkin' 'bout
how it is in the world ♪
♪ she got the fake furs and
desiring things that ain't hers ♪
- ♪ hollywood ♪
- ♪ yeah ♪
♪ a beautiful star
in a fancy rent-a-car ♪
♪ you know what
i'm talkin' about? ♪
- ♪ hollywood ♪
- ♪ right on ♪
♪ she's a model, singer
entertainer ♪
- ♪ that's hollywood. ♪
- (hawk screeches)
- it's all your fault!
- look at all this doggone smoke!
- did you put water in the radiator?
- yes!
well, why is it
smoking like this?
all right, you ready to
make some chips, baby boy?
yeah, we'd better
make some chips,
'cause if i don't,
i'm gonna die of starvation.
big as you is,
you can live on your stomach for two or three weeks.
- camels do it.
- do i look like a motherfuckin' camel?
oh, shit!
it's kenny fuckin' rogers!
man, that ain't
no kenny rogers!
that's kenny rogers.
come on. i got a plan.
you're gonna make a fool out yourself.
you know that ain't kenny rogers.
- that's kenny rogers!
- that's not kenny rogers.
yo, kenny.
here's some sunglasses for you and your celeb friends.
oh, come on, man.
i don't need these damn glasses.
man, what
are you crazy?
- you just gave away $25!
- no, i didn't!
five sunglasses!
$5 apiece!
that's $25.
you draw it up.
- what are you, stupid?
- am i stupid?
what i said--
are you stupid?
i didn't give away the money!
you did! you the stupid one.
what you think people
gonna do when they see
kenny rogers
wearin' our sunglasses?
they gonna go crazy
for this shit.
durrel, that is not
fuckin' kenny rogers!
- hey, man the booth.
- what?
- i need a little break.
- we ain't been here five minutes!
well, go get somethin' to eat or something, man.
got no money
to get nothing to eat.
well, go watch
other people eat, man.
there's a little pool party back at the motel in a little bit.
i'll check you there.
♪ i woke up in the morning,
sunny day on the beach ♪
- ♪ you wouldn't believe what's not in my reach ♪
- ♪ i believe ♪
♪ i mean some people got
hobbies like models and kites ♪
♪ but mine are the things that i can chew and bite,
that's right ♪
- ♪ a foodaholic of the worst kind ♪
- ♪ feed me ♪
♪ if i don't get somethin' to eat
i'm gonna go out of my mind... ♪
- (screams)
- (seal barks)
are you crazy?
i would've eaten that!
♪ i'm gettin' paranoid
and seein' mirages ♪
♪ everything look like
hamburgers and sausages ♪
♪ but right about now
i gotta take a pull ♪
- ♪ i'm goin' crazy... ♪
- (man whistles)
heavy d.
the line forms at the rear.
- what?
- maybe you didn't hear me correctly.
i said, "heavy d,
the line forms at the rear."
if i was you,
i wouldn't be makin' those fat jokes.
i ain't makin' any jokes.
just statin' the obvious.
fuck.
mmm. hot box.
hot box.
uh...
your box.
it's, um, real hot.
woman:
yeah. real hot.
got any luther?
i just go crazy for luther.
i think i'll do
just about anything
for some luther.
uh...
hey!
your radio!
i think you
made him nervous.
why do you have to
tease them like that?
denise, why not?
come on, you guys.
let's go get some luther.
fuck luther!
let's go find some real men.
let's go to that party and find
some men with some money.
i'm down.
yo, what's up,
homeboys and homegirls?
welcome to the 1995
summertime
fly-ass phat beach
bikini contest, baby!
- (cheering, whistling)
- coolio: yeah!
we about to have some fun
under the sun.
let's welcome our seven beautiful
contestants to the stage.
number seven make a brother
like me wanna go to heaven.
number six make me wanna
do a karate kick.
oh, number five
is all the way live.
number four,
i wanna close the door!
number three,
you can be down with me.
number two, i'll let you
kick it with the crew.
and number one, you got it goin' on!
you know what i'm sayin'?
(cheering continues)
man: i love you!
i love your ass!
i love everything
about you!
hey, baby.
so how you doin'?
man, what is your--
- that's my girl.
- that's your girl?
why don't you be like houdini-- do a magic act...
- put me down.
- and disappear.
- aaaah!
- (thuds)
so kick back, relax,
have a drink.
we'll be back as we introduce
our ladies to you one-by-one.
- (cheering continues)
- i respect you! i love you!
(hooting)
whoooo-whee!
hot damn, boy!
god! ohh! whoo-hoo!
what's up, man?
- amazing things.
- what, you sell some sunglasses?
no. i'm in love.
whooo-whee! look!
it's an ass contest.
now, how can you reduce
a woman to an ass?
- it's easy.
- anyway, i'm in love.
- coolio: give it up for number one!
- (applause, cheering)
me, too, my brother.
ha ha!
all right, let's hear it
for number two!
(applause, cheering)
- whoo! baby!
- i'm gonna get laid!
put your hands together
for number three!
(applause,
cheering continues)
i love women
by the pound!
oh, yeah, let's hear it
for number four! yeah!
number four!
i love number four!
whooo!
whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo!
- this is my dream girl.
- and she's mine.
all right, let's kick it
live for number five!
(applause,
cheering continues)
number five.
i'd love to bounce
that on my dick!
- bounce it! bounce it! bounce it!
- durrel.
- durrel!
- what's up?
asshole!
yo, i'm sorry, benny, man.
but the booty, man!
it's the booty!
it's been callin' me, man.
- hello.
- ooh.
she might be
the finest of them all.
excuse me.
you are one fine black woman.
the finest.
what do you say,
a little walk on the beach?
little candlelight
dinner for two?
pardon me!
no offense, guys,
but neither one of you are really my type.
what? i'm every
woman's type, baby!
oh, man.
i had that all wrapped up if it wasn't for you.
she was givin' me the blow-off
for your benefit.
if you weren't droolin'
all over,
she'd be back in my room
screamin' by now.
the only way she'd be in your room is screamin' for help.
- please.
- you think you could score with that ahead of me?
- you ain't even a threat.
- bet on that.
what do you got,
one of your famous dollars?
- i got that box from last night.
- yeah?
tunes kick real nice.
$300 against it.
- bet.
- hi.
- hey. what's up?
i seen you talkin'
to my friend candace.
i don't think
she's really your type.
- oh, really? and what's my type?
- me.
(hawk screeches)
(rap music playing)
sell sunglasses.
buy food. get dream girl.
buy food.
get dream girl.
sell sunglasses--
hey!
hey! hey!
(tires screeching)
- (rap music playing)
- (car squeaking)
durrel, get out here.
get out here!
what's goin' on, baby?
oh, nothin', baby.
it's just a twitch.
- what's goin' on out there?
- get out.
nothin'. it's some
crazy homeless guy.
- go on!
- fuck you, durrel!
know that guy.
he gave us his radio.
he what?
makes me quit my job,
steals my dad's car,
fucks in my dad's car.
it's all my fault, man.
and i'm dead hungry,
no food, no money.
(sighs)
followin' behind durrel.
hey, you!
i got your radio!
- oh, uh, thanks.
- you left it with my friend.
i thought you might
want it back.
yeah, thanks.
i got it for my birthday.
it's nice.
i guess i look
kinda stupid, huh,
leavin' it with your
girlfriend and stuff.
you like her, huh?
- she has a boyfriend?
- usually.
shhh--
i feel so alone.
like a seashell
washed up on the seashore,
waiting for the tide to
wash me back
so i can find my one
and only true love.
that was nice.
where did you hear it?
- actually, i wrote it.
- really?
- yeah.
- it's beautiful.
i'm denise.
what's your name?
i'm benny.
me and my friend durrel
came down to make some money.
- have you made any?
- no.
it's durrel!
all he wants to do is
pick up women on the beach,
and i'm tired of this.
i don't understand.
all i need is one girl.
candace?
everybody
likes candace.
well, it's nice
seeing you, benny.
hopefully i'll see
you again.
and maybe you can read
some of my stuff--
- i mean, your stuff.
- yeah, i'd like that.
(voices echoing) mr. lifeguard,
save me! please! save me!
i need you
more than she does.
can you give me
mouth-to-mouth?
pump my chest.
i'm not breathing.
actually, um, i'm not finished
with my training course yet,
but, uh,
i would practice on her.
ohh! ohh!
aaah! my radio!
ohh!
look at it!
man! ohh!
hey, fatso, can you
throw the ball back?
- what?
- you heard me, chubby. throw the ball back.
- you want this?
- yeah!
boy:
mom!
that was a crazy serve.
we were gonna go play some volleyball over there.
you wanna join us?
no, i'll just go
back home to the room.
come on, man.
we need that.
hey, uh, did you hear about that big
volleyball tournament tomorrow?
mm-mmm.
shit.
so we can win $10,000
just like that.
- are you any good?
- please.
see ya.
well, all right.
but this is
just business,
not social.
who's thinkin'
about social, baby?
sir, sir, sir,
sir, sir, sir!
hey!
what's up, bro?
- what's goin' on?
- my car over there just won't start.
i think something's
broke or something.
- can you help a brother out?
- yeah, i think i can help a brother out.
can i just rub a little lotion on
your back so you don't burn?
no. i don't burn,
and i don't want your hands on my ass.
yo, mikey!
they're towing your jeep!
- oh, look, it's your shadow.
- i tried to stop him,
- but old boy wouldn't listen.
- thought you had a porsche.
it's in the shop. shit!
get your friends for tomorrow.
damn, that's a nice
jeep you used to have.
alone at last.
mmm.
you're about to be.
ugh.
uh...
yeah, um,
i'll call you later.
♪ it's a good day ♪
♪ and this weather's
got me feelin' high ♪
♪ another fuss
is goin' on ♪
♪ we're comin' deep
at five ♪
♪ i can't run,
i gotta come clean ♪
♪ let's hit
the car wash scene ♪
♪ oh, no-o-o-o ♪
♪ so many brothers
jock'n me ♪
- ♪ because my crew was fly... ♪
- (grunts)
♪ they bustin' new jeeps
tires burnin' ♪
♪ hey, it's only right ♪
♪ it's gettin' crazy ♪
♪ shake this bottom
on my way ♪
♪ to another place ♪
- ♪ do you want me? ♪
- ♪ is he jock'n you ♪
♪ or is he jock'n me? ♪
- ♪ is he jock'n you? ♪
- damn!
♪ or is he jock'n me? ♪
♪ is he jock'n you
or is he jock'n me? ♪
(grunts)
damn!
look like y'all
done lost another one.
those serves were
the craziest, benny!
goddamn, big boy!
you just served the hell out that ball!
thanks for the food, man.
where you goin'?
bakersfield.
you can't go home.
we ain't made a sale yet.
and we not.
never!
what are you
talkin' about?
while you was back there
stinkin' up my dad's car,
- the sunglasses got stolen.
- stolen?
i'm leavin'. you can stay if you want,
but i'm goin' home.
benny, i'm sorry, man.
what you gonna do?
i'm gonna go home,
ask for my job back.
and just so you don't spoil
my whole weekend,
i'm gonna tell the girl of my dreams that i love her.
well, who is she?
what's your little plan? what's up?
don't even
worry about that.
just know i got a plan.
foolproof.
♪ yes, one, two,
one, two ♪
♪ i want you, i need you,
i lust you, i dream you ♪
♪ baby. ♪
here, i wrote
this for you.
- what's up, denise?
- hi, benny.
ugh!
how do you know him?
what did he
give you?
"love to be in love,
to dream,
"to understand your dreams
and shout from the rooftops
that you have found
the one you love."
- (laughing)
- wow.
i think that's
really eloquent.
well, if that means
stupid, i agree.
you guys are coldhearted.
he's a really nice guy.
- not like his friend durrel.
- both: durrel?
benny says he's scamming
all the time.
yeah, i'm leavin' for the army tomorrow.
goin' off to war.
who knows if
i'll ever make it back.
really?
which one?
uh, you know,
that saddam hussein?
vietnam.
yeah. yeah.
- tanya, don't get jealous now.
- please.
this morning i went for
a ride in his mercedes.
- he got a mercedes?
- yeah.
- candace: hi. durrel?
- call you if i make it back.
i've been looking
for you all day.
- oh, really?
- uh-huh.
- who was that?
- oh-- phhh!
(laughs)
no one.
so, um, i thought
i wasn't your type.
oh, come on.
that was just talk.
i didn't think you'd give up so easily.
so, um, what are you
doing tonight?
- whatever you are, baby.
- (giggles)
well, then,
what do you say
we go for a nice,
long ride along the coast?
i'd do anything for just a nice,
relaxing ride.
top down.
wind in my hair.
you know, i just
quiver all over
just thinking
about it.
benny! benny, man.
i've been lookin' all over for you!
- where the hell you been?
- i'm just thinkin', man.
i needs to borrow
the car tonight.
- what?
- i need to borrow the car. it's life or death!
- no.
- don't make me beg, man.
get out of my face, durrel.
i'll get on my knees and beg
like a little baby dog.
durrel, read my lips.
you're not touching my dad's car!
but it's this girl, man.
- i think i really like her.
- yeah, you like her, huh?
like her enough to bounce
her on your dick?
no, man, i'm talkin' serious.
and i can get her if i--
- lie to her and tell her you got a nice car?
- no, it's not like that.
- she don't care if i drive a bicycle.
- is that right?
well, you'd better get yourself a schwinn,
'cause i can't help you.
remember love, man?
you told me you were in love today.
i'd do anything to help you get that girl.
so help me.
you know how you don't like me abusing women.
this'll stop me.
i got a problem, man.
help me, benny. save me.
you don't like this girl.
i think this could be the only
girl i'm ever with again, ever.
- you're lying.
- i'm serious!
- who is she then?
- met her at the beach.
this shit is amazing.
we both come down here
and fall in love
in the same day.
what happened
with your girl?
i just gave her this poem
that i wrote for her.
ah! aggressive.
what'd she say?
i don't know.
i ran away.
- you ran away?
- isn't it amazing?
she's gonna be sitting there
wondering for the rest of her life
what her life
could've been like
with this mysterious poet
she met on the beach, man.
don't take much
to please you, does it?
(sighs)
all right, durrel.
one of us might
as well get the girl.
but don't be fuckin'
in it!
- here.
- i owe you big-time.
yeah, you do. we're leaving first thing in the morning,
come hell or high water.
hey. here.
- where you get this from?
- set aside a little emergency fund.
you been holdin' out on me!
you probably got some more.
food.
hey!
you get your car back?
why?
you do that?
nope, but i tell you what.
you can take it out of the money you owe me.
owe you?
the bet's over tomorrow.
ah, tomorrow's too late.
i'm going to pick up candace right now.
i'll wake you when it's time for the show.
see ya!
(giggling)
(women speaking swedish)
(moaning,
giggling continues)
what's up?
yo, what you got,
slimmy-slim?
what do i got?
yeah, you know,
how you doin'? what's goin' on?
i'm tryin' to eat.
hey, you know where
your boy is?
i don't know.
he's out with some girl or something.
do you know
where they went?
- they in a hotel bar right down there.
- this hotel?
- what do you need with him?
- relax, my man.
i'm not looking for him.
i'm lookin' for that girl that he's with.
i don't know about her,
but durrel's pretty much into her.
hopefully not before
i'm into her,
if you know what
i'm sayin'.
- no.
- me and your boy put a bet down.
who could, you know,
wax that ass first.
a bet?
durrel doesn't even have anything to bet.
he put up his box
against my $300.
his box?
that's my box!
easy, big guy.
there's people tryin' to sleep around here.
man, to hell with you.
- where you goin'?
- to kill durrel.
durrel, that car
handles real nice.
oh, yeah?
how do you handle?
slow down, baby.
so, how long have you had it?
- what?
- the car.
oh, the car.
about two years.
ever since i bought
the beach house.
oh, really.
is it right on the beach?
- right on the atlantic.
- you mean the pacific.
that too.
why don't we go back
to your beach house?
now you're talkin'.
well, i'm just gonna go freshen up a little bit, okay?
baby, durrel give you all
the freshings you need.
- can i drive?
- drive?
wreck that motherfucker
if you want to.
whoo!
well, ain't we just
the smooth talker?
- what's up, baby?
- i ain't your baby.
whatever.
- (man hoots)
- shit!
that's a $12 t-shirt
you just ruined!
yeah, uh,
hi, officer.
i'm a handicapped man,
and this goddamn car
is just taking up
all them handicapped spots.
yes, it's, um,
it's a convertible mercedes.
- hey, benny.
- how you doin'?
hi.
where you going?
i gotta find durrel.
- what's up, cuz?
- don't "what's up, cuz?" me. this was a bet?
you fucked around with my
dad's car and this was all a bet?
- relax, man.
- and you betted my box?
- benny, chill.
- man, give me the keys. i'm leaving.
man, you way too uptight.
all weekend you fucked around with the glasses,
and you treated
every girl like shit.
don't any of 'em mean
anything to you?
nope.
does this one even know
she's a bet?
what are you?
the leader of the women's movement or something?
you act like
you know this girl.
durrel, i don't have
to know her.
i just don't treat
people like that.
i don't care who
they are.
hi, durrel.
you ready to go?
you. hi.
thanks for that poem today.
it was so sweet.
he gave you
a poem today?
yeah.
mm-hmm.
benny, i'm sorry, man!
benny, i'm sorry, man.
i didn't know.
- how could you?
- i didn't know it was your girl, man.
it shouldn't make a difference whose girl it was, durrel.
you're right.
- you're a lowlife.
- i know.
- a scumbag.
- i agree.
lower than the animal.
garbage!
someone who just don't care
about nobody but theyself.
what can i say except
i can't help it.
hey, wait, wait,
wait a minute.
i just saw my car.
car?
does the word "obsession" mean anything to you?
this is the fifth time in two days
we've seen your one-in-a-million car.
no, baby.
i'm sure this time.
no, i'm sure you tired from driving all
over the world trying to find a hotel.
now, can we just go in here
and get a good night's sleep?
more than any animal.
garbage, trash.
a person who has no feelings
for anybody but himself.
we leaving tonight, man.
that's it.
cool. all right.
tonight.
that's right.
i just wanna forget this weekend ever happened.
i called
mr. johnson back.
he said i can come back to work
as soon as i'm physically ready.
then we do it.
all right.
let's just get our bags and go.
- okay.
- all right.
- there's just one small problem.
- what?
it's a yellow mercedes,
license plate "doctor t."
- $150!
- damn!
- do i get a blow with that?
- durrel, we'll never get the car back!
nothing, nothing, nothing.
just a minute.
give me all the money you got, man.
i'll handle this.
that's all i got.
how 'bout $7
and some change?
- (dial tone)
- hello? hello?
damn it!
they hung up on you!
we didn't have
enough money.
here we are,
alone at last.
- mm-hmm.
- this nice, warm bed...
- and this nice, warm room...
- mm-hmm.
- next to that nice, warm ocean.
- how 'bout some lovin' for mr. peppy?
mr. peppy's
had a long, hard day.
mr. peppy's day wouldn't have been so long and hard
if mr. peppy
hadn't forgot the map.
let's just go to sleep,
wake up in the morning and
forget this trip ever happened.
oh, but, baby,
it hasn't been that bad.
it's been real bad.
benny: how could you be so stupid
to park in a handicapped zone?
- don't yell at me.
- well, why did you park there then?
man, i didn't know handicapped people go dancing.
you think it's all a joke.
well, now you know they go dancing!
- benny: and--
- durrel: and?
benny: and we ain't got no money for food
and i'm hungry and we ain't
got no money to get the car.
jesus christ!
what else could you do to fuck up my life?
huh, durrel?
- what else could possibly go wrong?
- (knocking)
father: hey, hold that shit down!
it's 3:00 in the morning!
- sounds like my father.
- hey, open up.
(whispering)
that is my father.
get the door.
- durrel?
- hey, mr. king. what's up?
what you doing
here?
uh, just kickin' it.
too bad benny ain't here
kickin' it with you,
but he's bein' responsible this summer,
earning a living for himself.
yeah, that benjamin is one
responsible kid you got there.
durrel,
hold it down.
yes, sir, mr. king.
- good night.
- i'm outta here.
- where you goin'?
to go tell my dad.
yo, yo, yo. what's up?
you get your car back?
- you think it's funny?
- take it easy! take it easy!
- you think it's funny.
- it's not my fault genius over here
doesn't know the difference between
handicapped and mentally handicapped.
i'll let him
at you again!
i just came by to make sure that show
you promised tonight wasn't going off.
- bet's off.
- bet's off? wrong!
the bet
is just beginning.
guess who's gonna be playin' in the
$10,000 tournament tomorrow? me.
maybe you and mr. fitness over
here should put a team together.
ohh, that is
so funny!
here's the best part:
sweet little candace is on my team.
- i'm gonna get laid.
- you gonna get what?
- what's his problem, man?
- he gets crazy sometimes, man.
see you guys tomorrow.
peace.
and i'm gonna get laid!
(laughs)
how we gonna get
my dad's car back?
man, wake up! shit.
- what?
- $10,000. volleyball.
with that crazy serve of yours and my skills,
we can't lose.
but, durell,
i got to get back home tomorrow so i can go to work.
with $10,000,
you won't need to work.
and when candace sees
that crazy serve of yours,
she gonna go crazy
for your shit.
mmm.
candace
watching you
in that little itty
bitty bikini of hers?
well, where we gonna
get the players from?
sorry, partners.
yeah, i'm sorry. that's right.
- you girls play volleyball?
- (giggling)
we're here to sign up for
that volleyball tournament.
- $25 sign-up fee, please.
- say what, partner?
i said $25.
durrel.
come here, man.
where we gonna get $25 from
to play this game, man?
chill, don't get your panties in a wad.
i'll handle this.
um, since i'm so damn fine... (laughs)
how 'bout $7
and some change?
how about $25?
from now on,
i'm handling things.
- hi, benny!
- hey, denise.
- this here's my friend durrel.
- hi, durrel.
you look upset.
is something wrong?
no. it's just that we can't
enter the tournament
because we don't have
the $25 entry fee.
i've got 20.
- give it up!
- shut up, durrel!
we can't take
your money, denise.
i want you to have it.
candace and tanya didn't even
ask me to play on their team,
so maybe i can help you
beat them.
if you win,
you can take me to dinner or something.
- okay. all right, cool.
- tanya: we've got to go!
- oh, thanks.
- oh, i've gotta go.
- hope to see you later.
- all right. bye, denise.
hey, yo, man.
old girl got it goin' for you.
yo, man, it ain't even like that with me and her.
me and her are just friends.
man, friends are just girls
that you haven't fucked yet.
- durrel, do me a favor.
- what's up?
just shut the fuck up.
let's go get the girls.
25!
now where that court at?
yo, yo, check it out!
welcome to the first annual
hip-hop volleyball tournament!
(cheering)
word up.
yo, what's up?
this is tre black from 92.3 the beat coming to you live.
today's winner is going
to receive $10,000!
so kick the beat,
big baby!
(cheering continues)
- damn!
- oooh!
tre: pretty athletic for a fat boy!
- (grunting)
- (crowd gasps)
- (applause)
- tre: yeah, the crowd is hyped!
woman:
beautiful!
benny:
aces all day!
tre:
hey, yo, that's a shutout.
phat serves by the fat man
means a big fat-ass zero
for the green team.
even the ladies are gettin' into this fat boy.
- yeah! yes!
- (crowd cheering)
tanya:
hit it, baby!
(cheering)
unbelievable!
yo, let's break for lunch.
hey, yo, fat man, don't
fill up on the free hot dogs.
this food alone
is worth stayin'.
never mind the $10,000.
- hey, nice servin'.
- yeah, i know.
hey, durrel,
i'll be over there.
you ain't seen
nothin' yet.
inga and ulga, or whatever
the hell their name is,
was on the '88 olympic team.
- tournament's all wrapped up.
- we'll see, baby.
we got a little
secret weapon of our own.
hey, benny.
good foot-long?
mm-hmm.
uh, so, i just
wanted to tell you,
that poem you wrote me--
it was so romantic.
and i didn't know
how to approach you,
but...
good luck.
(chuckles)
ohh. whoo.
good luck to you too!
uh, i-i hope you win!
daddy, look.
it's benny.
benny?
benny. benny!
what?
- oh, shit!
- what the hell you doin' here?
uh, i got a volleyball
tournament over there.
volleyball?
you're supposed to be working!
they gave me
the weekend off.
- i bet he got fired.
- let your father handle this.
- wish you'd shut up.
- how'd you get here?
- i walked.
- from bakersfield?
no, from the hotel.
hotel? benny, get your shit.
you're going home.
- but, dad, this is for money.
- you can't play volleyball.
- how would you know?
- oh, look at you! your condition!
you never let me
do anything!
all you say is, "you're too fat,
you're too clumsy."
- all i wanted to do this summer was write.
- i got you a job.
yeah, flippin' burgers.
how far is that gonna get me?
at least if i win,
i can pay for my poetry class.
yeah, and if you lose,
how you gonna eat?
benny, get your shit.
you're going home!
i'll diet.
dad, i love you,
but this is somethin' i gotta do.
and if i lose,
i'll deal with it my way.
bye, ma.
see you later.
the boy's got some fight.
takes after me.
hey, yo, yo, yo!
we're down to the final two teams
in the volleyball
tournament today.
- (cheering)
- give it up
for the grand prize
of $10,000! $10,000!
yo, the blue team
has been awarded the serve.
they been spankin'
that ass all day.
the fat man's been on it.
i think the red team's in trouble.
- what y'all think?
- (cheering)
yo, let's get
this party started right.
it's on!
cowards!
- (grunts)
- (crowd cheers)
- (crowd laughing)
- (laughing)
(cheering continues)
- (grunts)
- hell, yeah!
(cheering continues)
- chase it!
- tanya!
- it was in your corner!
- did you see that serve?
here comes another!
- and another!
- (groans)
and another!
(groans)
come on! right here, right here,
right here, right here!
- (groans)
- (crowd groans)
come on.
what was that?
ohh! oh.
almost. almost.
about this much more
and it would've been over.
(groans)
- oooh!
- yeah! yeah-hah-hah!
- come on.
- yeah.
why didn't you
get it?
- come on, sweetheart.
- nah, nah. see? you can't play.
you're boring me!
you're boring me.
come on.
hit the ball!
aaah!
- hey, what you doin'?
- back up! back up!
no, no, no,
no, no, benny!
oh, that serve was just
a little too hard for me.
maybe you could hit it
just a little bit lighter?
sure. okay.
- benny, don't go for that bullshit!
- listen.
if you lose, we could go
for a nice walk, me and you.
- we're gonna have to continue this game now.
- benny, come on, man!
and if i win?
(sighs) probably won't feel like doing anything
except going home
by myself to cry.
let that bitch cry.
the server must serve
or forfeit the game.
come on, fatso!
- come on, benny! you can do it!
- wanna kiss me?
skip that shit!
come on, man!
yeah, i wanna kiss you.
- no. don't kiss her.
- yeah. go ahead.
first,
you have to lose.
shit!
damn, benny!
come on!
(crowd chanting) benny!
benny! benny! benny!
- come on, benny!
- on your feet, benny!
come on, benny!
c'est votre monde!
(gasps)
- what did you say?
- c'est votre monde.
it means, "it's your world."
(echoing)
so, if i lose,
you'll kiss me, huh?
uh-huh.
let's do it.
uhh!
that's it. that's it.
hey! what about us?
we're over, baby.
(cheering continues)
(chanting continues)
benny! benny! benny!
benny! benny!
(chanting fades)
(cheering)
(whistling)
♪ you are my kind of guy ♪
♪ and i want you
to know it, oooh ♪
♪ you are my kind of guy ♪
♪ even though
i don't show it ♪
♪ oooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ i know you used to party
all night with the girls ♪
♪ but in this case
that ain't cool ♪
♪ up here you can be
someone else's type ♪
♪ but when you're with me
your time is all mine ♪
♪ you are my kind of guy ♪
♪ and i want you
to know it. ♪
yo, what's up,
everybody in the house?
give it up for tre black
and the blackness party!
- ♪ come on ♪
- ♪ put your back into it ♪
♪ this for my people
on the positive ♪
♪ drum and a bass for the booty
here to move your mind, cutie ♪
♪ you can move a mountain
separatin' us east to west... ♪
dad.
i'm really sorry about, you know,
quittin' that job you got for me.
don't be, benj--
benny.
i'm proud of you,
boy.
you saw somethin',
you went after it and you got it.
oh, and that
poetry class?
- your mom'll pay for it.
- no, no, ah-ah--
i'll pay for it.
(laughing)
but, dad,
i won the money.
spend it on this beautiful
young lady right here.
- spend some money on me too, benny.
- (laughing)
- ♪ come on ♪
- ♪ put your back into it ♪
♪ here we go ♪
♪ back to your roots with the herbs and
the fruits and the big black gator boots ♪
♪ ladies on the dance floor
second that nature ♪
♪ east to the west side
down for the ride ♪
♪ if you wanna come
just roll with the flavor ♪
♪ treat the brothers from the east
and the west like your neighbor ♪
♪ and like a good neighbor
i'll be there ♪
♪ hold on, y'all,
answer this question here ♪
- ♪ do the east side run this mutha? ♪
- hell, yeah!
- ♪ do the west side run this mutha? ♪
- ♪ do my people run this mutha? ♪
- hell, yeah!
- ♪ so do we all run this mutha? ♪
♪ 'nuff respect
to the east and the west... ♪
you gonna be able
to get home okay?
i got the car
back, massa.
durrel.
yeah, pop, we'll, uh--
we'll be all right.
we'll, uh, take the bus
in the morning.
all right.
i'll see you tomorrow.
me and your mama gonna
turn in early tonight.
we didn't get lost tonight,
did we, baby? mmm!
what are you, stupid?
yo, man, here are the keys.
i'm out.
yo, ho, ho, ho.
slow your roll.
(laughs) uh,
i got a surprise for you.
what?
- candace is up in the room.
- in the room?
- in the bed.
- under the covers.
- with the lights off.
- damn!
looks like i would've won
that betty-bet after all.
yeah,
you would have.
but, uh,
go and get it anyway.
oh, you know that
mando.
oh, but, uh, be sure
to leave the lights off.
oh, you done found yourself
a little somethin' somethin',
now you're teachin' me?
durrel! shut up.
- sorry, denise.
- she loves the dark.
the "do not disturb" sign
will be on the door.
ho, ho, ho.
before you go, look, uh--
take this.
she likes ice.
(laughs)
- ♪ put your back into it ♪
- ♪ atlanta ♪
- ♪ miami ♪
- ♪ put your back into it ♪
- ♪ l. a. ♪
- ♪ new york... ♪
(music continues faint)
where's your titty at?
(both screaming)
(sobbing)
♪ even when you sleep ♪
♪ even as you breathe ♪
♪ you'll be thinkin'
about my face... ♪
why don't we go ride
down this coast?
- what about durrel?
- catch the bus.
♪ you'll be thinkin'
'bout my face ♪
♪ visit us in your sleep
you without me ♪
♪ everyone's asleep so we
definitely have to creep up ♪
♪ takin' over inside
out through your lungs ♪
♪ i kept on a-talkin' there was one
guy a-comin' back to get some ♪
♪ i gotta swing it to
the left of my g-string ♪
♪ and now we swing it to the
right and it's the same thing... ♪
(music fades)
one, two, three, four!
bucwee boiz,
we in the house!
(echoing)
♪ let's dance ♪
♪ uhh-uhh-uhh
uhh-uhh-uhh ♪
♪ get it on down
get it on down ♪
♪ i gotcha, baby ♪
♪ i gotcha, baby,
i gotcha, baby ♪
♪ you gots to go,
you know you gots to go ♪
♪ so hit the door 'cause
♪ get your big butt high,
get your big butt high ♪
♪ you gots to go,
you know you gots to go ♪
♪ so hit the door 'cause
♪ get your big butt high,
get your big butt high ♪
- ♪ let's dance ♪
- ♪ here we go here we go, yo ♪
♪ hubba-bubba-baby
with the bucwee boiz ♪
♪ we said we in the house
and we making noise ♪
♪ yo, gettin'
this party started ♪
♪ big butt girl
start actin' retarded ♪
♪ tweakin' it,
gettin' some ♪
♪ kickin' that hey-bop-a-lu-bo-whoa i told you before ♪
♪ if you ain't on the dance
floor you gots to go ♪
♪ get to steppin', baby, baby
let's make it happen ♪
♪ get off the wall,
let's take a chance ♪
♪ say what, you don't wanna
dance uhh, you gots to go ♪
♪ hit the door
and don't come back no more ♪
♪ hell yeah, don't know
where you're goin' ♪
♪ but you're gettin' up
outta here ♪
♪ puddy tat's comin',
puddy tat's comin' ♪
♪ puddy tat's comin' ♪
- ♪ puddy tat's comin' ♪
- big time!
♪ i can't hear you,
what'd you say, buddy l ♪
♪ uh-uh-uhh,
uh-uh-uhh ♪
♪ get it on down,
get it on down ♪
♪ i gotcha, baby,
i gotcha, baby ♪
♪ you gots to go,
you know you gots to go ♪
♪ so hit the door 'cause
♪ get your big butt high,
get your big butt high ♪
♪ you gots to go,
you know you gots to go ♪
♪ so hit the door 'cause
♪ get your big butt high,
get your big butt high ♪
- ♪ what's that number-one zodiac sign? ♪
- aries!
♪ i said, what's that
number-one zodiac sign? ♪
aries!
♪ won't be no ladies present
for the f-- ♪
♪ i said, fellas,
let's burn this mother-- ♪
♪ ooh, lord,
what's goin' on? ♪
♪ ain't no ladies
for this mutha ♪
♪ yeah, yeah!
but we fun! ♪
♪ somebody scream! ♪
♪ break out ♪
♪ uhh-uhh-uhh,
uhh-uhh-uhh ♪
♪ get it on down,
get it on down ♪
- ♪ what you got? ♪
- ♪ i gotcha, baby ♪
♪ i gotcha, baby,
i gotcha, baby ♪
♪ i gotcha, baby ♪
♪ you gots to go,
you know you gots to go ♪
♪ so hit the door 'cause
♪ get your big butt high,
get your big butt high ♪
♪ let's dance. ♪
get to steppin'!
and don't you ever
come back!
♪ baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ ain't nothin'
but that s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ so get into the groove ♪
♪ lay back to the "smoov" ♪
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ ain't nothin'
but that s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ so get into the groove ♪
♪ lay back to the "smoov" ♪
♪ have a fly booty like a cutie
off the pages of a mag type ♪
♪ i got the fever for the
flavor what your love like ♪
♪ i may be strong but i ain't
trippin' up my manhood ♪
♪ 69 for the ways
i make you damn good ♪
♪ and never give a hoo'
'bout what the next say ♪
♪ i got your back
thirty-six-five all day ♪
♪ i'm givin' what you need
what you please be ♪
♪ beg and plead, never need
keep it real, see ♪
♪ i'll take you on a trip
around the atmos ♪
♪ tip or tokes put it down
to the utmost ♪
♪ 'cause when i need
a friend you's a friend ♪
♪ when i needed bread
you was steady kickin' in ♪
♪ so now we live and lay
like a fat cat ♪
♪ drop top in the breeze
lay your head back ♪
♪ and get into the groove
with me ♪
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v, "smoov" ♪
s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ ain't nothin'
but that s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ so get into the groove ♪
♪ that's right, lay back to
the "smoov", lay on back ♪
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ ain't nothin'
but that s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ so get into the groove ♪
♪ that's right, lay back
to the "smoov" ♪
♪ now throw your hands,
in the air, in the air ♪
♪ and wave 'em 'round like you just don't care,
you don't care ♪
♪ you got to get your groove
on with the "smoov" jones ♪
♪ let me know 'cause b-m-dub's
gonna take you there ♪
♪ now throw your hands
in the air, in the air ♪
♪ and wave 'em 'round like you just don't care,
you don't care ♪
♪ you got to get your groove
on to the "smoov" jones ♪
♪ let me know 'cause b-m-dub's
gonna take you there ♪
♪ now can i get paid
or can i get laid? ♪
♪ how you do? i'll do ya,
how you want me to ♪
♪ been keepin' game
since the third grade ♪
♪ i'm tryin' to put it down
like a "playa" ♪
♪ i walk like a "playa",
wanna talk like a "playa" ♪
♪ the situation, conversation
good vibration ♪
♪ it's singin' for
the green god i'm chasin' ♪
♪ the price of fame and gain tell me how to maintain,
it's the same ol' game ♪
♪ baby, i can see that you
in need of somethin' ♪
♪ could it be the money? ♪
♪ 'cause if it is you ain't
got nothin' comin' ♪
♪ i heard you got a grip
from tom slick cool ♪
♪ how'd it feel to take
a little boy to school? ♪
♪ did you hit him
with the candy? ♪
♪ yeah, that shit'll
come in handy ♪
♪ i had you livin'
like little orphan annie ♪
♪ at best i stand to lose
a stack of my cheese ♪
♪ in the land where
the scammers deceive ♪
♪ i believe to this day
steady as we go, b ♪
♪ and let's groove
to that s-m-o-o-v ♪
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v, yeah ♪
s-m-o-o-v, "smoov" ♪
♪ so get into the groove,
that's right ♪
♪ lay back to the "smoov",
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v, "smoov" ♪
s-m-o-o-v, groove ♪
♪ so get into the groove,
that's right ♪
♪ lay back to the "smoov",
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v ♪
s-m-o-o-v, yeah ♪
♪ so get into the groove,
that's right ♪
♪ lay back to the "smoov",
lay on back ♪
♪ ain't nothin' but that
s-m-o-o-v, "g" ♪
s-m-o-o-v, "smoov" ♪
♪ so get into the groove,
groove ♪
♪ lay back to the "smoov" ♪
♪ yeah, b-m-dub, baby,
b-m-dub, baby ♪