PIAGOL
Cinematography Kang Young-hwa
Screenplay Kim Jong-hwan
Music Jeong Hyoi-Gap
Sound/Recording Lee Kyeong-sun
Edit Yang Ju-nam
Effect Lee Sang-man
Developing Choi Kye-soon
Assistant Director Kwak Keun
Procedure Lee Yik-jae
Cast
Captain Agari: Lee Ye-chun
Secretary Ae-ran: Roh Kyung-hee
Charge of Culture, Chul-soo: Kim Jin-kyu
Man-soo: Heo, Jang-kang
Yoo-chul: Yoon Wang-guk
Partisan Dong-shik: Song Kwak-sang
Dal-suk: Lee Won-chul
Soju: Kim Young-hee
Partisan ll-dong: Cho Nam-suk
Injured Partisan: Kwak Gun
Chief Captain: Kim Ik-hwan
Producer Kim Byung-ki
Adapted Screenplay and
Director Lee Kang-cheon
Stand at ease!
Chul-soo.
Form the ranks,
2 deaths, 1 injured, 1 lost Carbine.
What? A carbine?
Did you bring the carbine
from the dead?
Yes, sir.
Who's the one that lost it?
Step forward.
Are you prepared to be shot dead?
Captain, I climbed onto the wall
of the police office.
I got shot on my arm, and lost it.
I got converging fires at that time.
So I couldn't climb over
the wall and lost it,
captain...
You gave them your carbine
instead of taking their ammunition?
Comrades, we failed this time
due to wrong information.
There left only our revenge
on the Namsanli villagers, got that?
Start!
Ah, it's far away.
What?
Our fates to be chased like this.
It is far away to have good days...
Never having a situation to live
in a steady place anywhere.
The supply fight is a trouble
these days, too.
Chinese troops aren't coming,
our soldiers are decreasing,
so the liberation day is far away.
Now I can't even trust
what the officials say.
Shish...
how dare you say that?
Just between you and me,
Armistice has already been concluded.
Who would come?
Comrade Soju,
captain is calling you.
Go to see him.
Soju, what's so funny?
I'm busy.
I'm going to see the captain.
Our republic intends to abandon us?
Why do you say that again?
They seem to cut the line
after the truce.
Probably.
Was Soviet Union hurry
to conclude the truce?
Why do you keep saying that?
It could be harsh to the leaders' ears.
Who live in Namsanli?
My mother and uncle.
I see.
It's Soju again. Barely 2 measures
of barley rice and women's clothes...
Soju didn't complete her duty
and she's only proud of her skill.
Ae-ran is much better than her.
I'm different in my background..
Right, you are from North Union Party.
There you are.
Come in.
Captain is waiting for you.
You care for the laundry and diary.
Chul-soo must be deaf.
Huh! The laundry smells much like Soju.
Comrade
be careful with your words.
Why? You don't like it?
Soju must be busy with
doing laundry and
being warned by captain.
She must be overworking.
You don't need to be bothered by Soju?
Huh, you neglect your duty, Soju, and
you still don't throw out the female temper.
Thus, you have weak spirit
for our communist party.
I see. I'll never do that again.
For us, a grain of rice is
more precious than this.
Comrade, Soju.
Let go,
let go.
Anyways, our captain is the best!
Did you see it yesterday, didn't you?
Once captain doesn't like, it's over.
Not to mention it, do you recall
the purge in Baemsa village last fall?
Ah, you mean the reactionary
who tried to surrender himself to us?
Yes. Captain said the guts
of the reactionary were plain,
and that cut and chewed them
with his shitty face.
It's disgusting.
That's warning from his conduct.
You learned it in class.
Captain,
Captain!
What is it?
A messenger came.
Then, you go and talk with him.
Code!
Cloud!
Half Moon.
Captain,
Comrade Seo is coming.
Chief Captain Seo?
Let them, hurry...
I didn't expect you come suddenly.
You are working hard.
I came here to praise our
brave comrades to encourage.
It's the honor of Agari troop.
Attention!
Today, it is my honor
to have this time with you partisans.
You... for our nation, the Soviet Union,
during our revolution, with strong spirit...
fought ruthlessly, and it was
our partisans' brilliant results in war
that you've completed the attack
of the enemy territory
and demolished the bridge
on the fight of May Day.
Today I confer this decoration on Agari
always fighting bravely
and praise his service.
Service medal.
Captain of Agari unit, Chu Bong-hyuk.
This person is granted this medal
for showing the heroic spirit
in partisan fighting
during National Liberation War.
November 10th, 1953,
North Leader Dept.
of National Provincial Party,
Partisan Headquarters,
Commander Cho, Byung-ha
This decoration is given only
with certificate under revolution,
but you will see the honor and privilege
will always shine on his chest.
We decide to
grant a pig to other soldiers.
Attention.
Comrade Oh Soju, step forward.
And, I give an order to Oh Soju
to call back to main office,
according to the agreement
at the last military committee.
Ae-ran, don't forget to watch
all the staffs at the village.
Our Great Leader Kim ll-sung suggested
we stage a purge against reactionaries
before destroy the enemies.
The reactionaries like defaulters,
sneakers and romanticists
in troop should be cleaned up.
Line up!
Comrades, we should develop
our fight today.
We should reserve as much as we can
we could recall
the serious hunger from last winter,
so our departure of today's fight
is Namsanli village.
Namsanli village,
a nursery of the reactionary
a nursery of the reactionary.
We will punish the entire reactionary
and fight for our supply.
Though some of us are
from Namsanli,
we should risk our necks for this great
and imminent revolutionary struggle.
We should show our
strong spirit for the Party,
execrating the reactionary
parents, brothers like enemies.
Complete each of your duty.
Then go!
What's wrong?
I fell down.
Bastard.
How did it go?
Nothing.
Mother,
Mother.
Yeah, who is it?
It's me, mom.
You! You shot your mom?
No... mom.
Mom..
You.. you...
Who shot the old lady?
I did.
You didn't know whose house it was?
No, I didn't. I just killed a reactionary.
People would become serious,
after killing that old lady.
It's weird.
Isn't it right we praise his decision
for cleaning up the reactionary?
Comrades, good job.
We should clean up
the reactionary sooner.
Ae-ran, take him forward.
You should do this tonight.
Execute the reactionary
in People and Party's name in haste.
I'll execute you reactionaries
with honor of our party.
Step forward, you serious
reactionary headman.
Your Namsanli village is
a hangout of the reactionary.
We have the evidence from
this undercover man in the village,
you aren't supportive
for our partisan's task,
which we fight for
people's victory in edge.
We punish you reactionaries
in People and Party's name
for your interruption the day before.
That's right.
We'll punish a foe of our brave
comrades who died that night.
Agree!
These sons of bitches informed them
of our mobilization.
You could survive if you help us.
Now you know the guilt of
this bad reactionary.
If you're not guilty and reactionary,
you should kill them
with your own hands
to prove your faith to out party.
Would you survive killing him
with this spear?
Would you die with this gun?
Choose your way.
Well...
What do you hesitate for?
If you don't kill him quickly,
I'll shoot you first.
Hey!
All right! Kill me! Kill me.
You red bastards! Cruel sons of bitches.
Is that communism
that kills the innocent?
Kill me, you bastards.
I'll inform your sins
to the world after death.
You, reds!
What are you doing? Hurry!
You're brave.
This strengthens your spirits
like iron.
Your future task is to report
all the detailed information
of village for our party.
Your duty should be continued
and passionate.
Otherwise,
we'll disclose to the villagers
that you killed the headman.
Understand?
Now go back to your home.
When you go back to the village,
inform that you escaped after captured.
If you betray us, you'll be dead.
Ae-ran, good job.
You have steely strong spirit
for the party.
Now, we expanded our cell
to Namsanli.
it will soon become democratic
without the reactionary.
Let's move.
Follow without breaking up your ranks.
Were you well acquainted
with the headman?
He's my uncle in my mother side.
What? Is he your uncle?
You shouldn't say that in front.
Why did you lag behind?
Don't break up your ranks.
It's inevitable
because he was reactionary.
Captain, he's not my uncle.
I've already disowned him.
ldeologies are different.
The headman's not related to me.
Son of bitch,
what's this frantic all about?
I am a real partisan.
Please forgive me this time, Captain.
You just said you sympathized
with the reactionary,
and what're you trying to do?
I did it for old memories.
My uncle paid my tuition.
But he's nothing to me now.
Obviously, he's an enemy.
Captain, please watch
my deeds afterwards.
I'll complete all the tasks upon my life.
Son of bitch, your last moment
is such shabby.
Once you're decided to be eliminated,
die quietly with no one to care.
If we keep this kind of
guy with reactionary spirits,
we will end up in a disaster.
It's a precaution for him surrendering.
He said he disowned his uncle,
but he can't disconnect his blood.
He seemed to be disturbed ideologically
before killing the headman.
What? Why didn't you point that
at the critical meeting?
I didn't have a chance to speak...
You were mostly close to ll-dong.
So were you negligent in your duty
for solemn party's judgement
with your cheap friendship?
No, no sir. Absolutely not.
Then, you didn't trust the Party's resolution?
I swear. It wasn't on purpose at all.
I'm not good at speaking by nature.
You are old, so you don't tell a lie.
Yes, sir.
Comrade, Ae-ran. Give him a special
lecture for this old fool comrade, huh!
Yes, I will.
Comrades!
I told you that
we keep fighting intensely
even though the truce was made and
our republic can't send reinforcements.
As our staffs are decreasing,
don't forget that our direction
for our nation Soviet Union
is staging a purge,
breaking through the enemy's offense,
destroying rear bases,
and perturbing the people
with our strong military spirit.
I want you to arm yourself
with your iron-like ideology.
What are you watching?
Clouds.
Floating continuously and slowly.
They go anywhere, don't they?
We don't need to care for the clouds.
Anyways, Comrade Ae-ran,
guess what I'm thinking of now?
Do you have a moment to think?
What're you talking about?
Well,
about how to outlive with lasting life
and without being attacked.
And about how to eat beef ribs
after a great supply fight.
No
that's not what I'm thinking of.
I think of you.
Me?
About how to keep my nose
to the grindstone?
Uh? No, that's not it.
Ae-ran, you know what...
Of course you do.
Why did you punish the young couple
in Nogodan, Captain?
That's because of their love affair.
You put their affairs onto Party's judgment,
but you are fine with that?
That's why there's a secret.
My work is absolute secret.
You should know the secret relationship
can't be conflicted with Party's rules.
Is that so? Huh!
I don't understand.
I can absolutely obey the order
from the party.
Ae-ran! Ae-ran is my secretary.
Of course you should
be connected with captain.
Why are you doing this?
Let go...
I can't.
I, a partisan only work for the Party.
Hey Ae-ran... what a bitch!
You seem like a poet in a fairyland.
What?
You don't need to be mad.
What're you thinking?
You're just looking at the mountain.
You must miss someone.
You must miss a woman!
What's that for?
You don't need to hide your nature.
It's dangerous a partisan has a thought.
That would be a fatigue of an intelligent.
What?
What did you just say?
Chul-soo, are you upset?
I didn't mean that seriously.
Stop it.
I became a partisan cursing my social class
and working hard for the party for 3 years.
Forgive me.
I raked up unpleasant old stories.
By the way,
what were you thinking?
Is it a secret you can't tell?
It must be a secret.
Don't... why are you
so cautious of me?
Ah, how free those clouds are!
Comrade
you were lucky today.
You should be careful with your words.
I was close to ll-dong,
and scared to get an attention for that.
Many go out for Wool
and come home shorn.
I didn't know that.
I'm still shuddering
let's not talk about it.
Ah, Comrade Chul-soo also...
Huh? Why?
No, well he might be...
Did he do something with Ae-ran?
We'll see how Captain treats him.
Comrade, Soju,
what're you doing here?
It's terrible!
The enemy starts to attack.
Chief Captain has already died...
What? The main office
has been defeated?
Yes, Piagol is now destroyed.
Piagol is now over.
Comrade Soju, let's go to the base.
You should report to Captain.
Captain, comrade Soju has...died.
What?
What happened to Soju?
Yes, yes...beside the stream down
there...who...did...some
Speak straightly.
She's d...ead.
How did you find Soju was dead?
I was doing laundry and
woman's underwear was drifted.
Underwear?
Yes, yes, this is...
Did you see Soju coming, did you?
No... not at all.
It's strange.
A dead body couldn'tjust come here.
Yes.
Let's go find the truth.
Who would've done this to Soju?
How should I know?
She's shot and walked here...
that was terrible.
Dal-suk should know it.
Do you really think so?
There's no evidence,
but it's Dal-suk who found Soju first.
I don't think so...
What?
Then?
Comrade!
I can keep your secret.
Huhu... that's why I like you...
You're choking me!
Let go!
You'll regret this.
Comrade, what is it?
Dal-suk cut his throat.
Dal-suk did?
Right, it's him who killed Soju.
Yes.
Man-soo! Leave it here
and hurry to get him...
Yes, sir.
What're you doing here alone?
Yoo-chul told me to come with you.
Let's hurry.
Yoo-chul? Why?
A pheasant...
right, he's got a pheasant...
he's baking it now alone.
Is that so?
How did he catch it?
Did he shoot?
He knocked it with a gun stock.
With a gun stock?
Like this...
Captain,
well... Dal-suk tried to rebel
even against me, his friend
What did he do?
Why isn't he coming?
ln fact, I told him to come to Captain,
but suddenly he tried to
shoot me on the chest.
So I tried to beat him
but I curved and put it forth.
Forgive me. He was a nice buddy.
All right! He was mad to death.
Otherwise,
he could've been dead by me.
Man-soo, you took the trouble.
It's a pity our number's decreasing
but he was a reactionary.
You are right, sir.
Today's destination is Osanli village?
Well.
Namsanli and Osanli, we always go to 'li'.
There's no other way for people
to live and die in mountains
and they'll go to hell.
To hell?
Why, of course!
Do you think they're going to the heaven?
Have you seen hell?
The foresight you mentioned
before just came into being to me.
To see the light from the dark.
Comrade Chul-soo,
I don't want to go on
supply fight today.
Please tell Captain for me.
I am not well.
I don't know.
You'd rather tell Captain instead of me.
You're his secretary.
Secretary?
Do you think I am connected
with Captain for that?
Why are you so cautious of me?
You're always cold to me,
but does it prove your innocence?
I don't know what you're saying.
Blaming my deeds?
You're afraid of me.
You don't need to hate me.
What do you mean I hate you?
I've already lost my humanity.
Not to speak of me now
Dong-cho, Dong-cho...
Yes, sir.
Why don't they come?
Yes. Ae-ran went to the waterfall
with Chul-soo a while ago.
Call them now!
I'm concerned about you.
Your lonely face weighs on my mind.
I don't want sympathy of woman.
Anyhow, I resent myself,
and your words worsen my situation.
Comrades, Captain's calling you.
Would you not go down to the village, comrade?
I know it well.
They'll save your life upon surrendering.
I didn't know you would say that.
I'm a human being,
Ae-ran,
thank you.
Ae-ran, have you ever
thought of our destiny?
ln this harsh mountain,
in this valley like hell,
cursing this situation,
is it only me who is dying in here?
Ae-ran, so are you?
I'm sick and tired with this life in the mountains.
Let's get out of this hell.
I'm an old and sinned girl,
and there's no hometown,
even if I leave this mountain.
I'd be dead after being chased,
escaping from Piagol.
But, there's one thing...
it's nothing,
but my life of youth still cuts to the heart.
The certificate of Service Medal.
The end