"Your turn!"
(Soundtrack: finger-guessing game from TV)
"Here goes ..."
"Straight six!"
"We have deep feelings for each other"
"That's five wins! Don't let go"
"Loneliness is hard to bear"
"Four happinesses, two couples"
"Let me give you all my love"
"Two good brothers, eight highways"
"Three toasts to the revolution!"
"Drunk every day, drink with every meal"
"Drink like an Asian hero"
"There's a cow up the mountain"
"Dancing with rigid hips"
"Eyes like green peas on a turtle's head"
"My hands are on your hips ..."
Get on
Where to?
- Downtown
- Get on!
Get the guy to pay his fare
Mister, can you pay your fare?
Your ticket?
I'm a policeman
Fenyang Public Security Bureau...
Fenyang People's Procuratorate...
Fenyang People's Court...
and Fenyang Justice Bureau...
urge criminals to turn themselves in
To advance the rectification policy
and the fight against crime...
the county party committee
and the government...
have launched a 100-day
public security campaign
This campaign is county-wide
The relevant national laws
and regulations...
There's one thing...
My supplier from Xiaoyi came yesterday
Someone stole his wallet on the way
The money is no big deal...
but he needs to get his ID back
As you know, it's a hassle to get a new ID
When was it stolen?
Around dusk, yesterday
Where?
By the bus terminal
I'll ask around
Try your best, will you?
That damn Xiaoyong is going great guns
They say he's been to South Korea
No way, it was North Korea!
Whatever, he got to go abroad
He's smart
Dear viewers,
our famous local entrepreneur...
Mr. Jin Xiaoyong will
get married tomorrow
On behalf of Fenyang
TV's call-in program...
I'd like to give Mr. Jin
our most sincere congratulations!
Thank you
Mr. Jin, tomorrow is your wedding day
Many friends have called in to us...
to request songs for your wedding
Do you have a few words for
our viewers and friends?
People of Fenyang, old friends...
First, I want to thank you for all
the support and help over the years
On this special occasion...
in gratitude to supporters
of our company in Fenyang...
I'd like to give something back
to the community
Our company has decided
to donate 30,000 yuan...
to Fenyang's 'Project Hope'
Hang on, there's no rush! Er Bao...
There's no need...
Don't go just yet
A gift from Xiaoyong. Take it, take it
- Come on
- Okay
- See you tomorrow
- Take care
Bye
What a schedule!
Hey, your mother was asking
if you've invited Xiao Wu
Huh? Why is she worrying about Xiao Wu?
I'm just saying she asked
Forget it
What should we do? Shall I tell him?
Are you kidding? Too late for that
- Where's Dong Dong?
- He hasn't shown up yet
- Is he okay?
- Yeah, I was at his place yesterday
Who lifted from a Xiaoyi guy yesterday?
- Near the bus terminal
- I did
- Where's the ID?
- I threw it away
Go find it
What's up?
He's Gengsheng's friend
This is from yesterday
Liubao...
Thanks for the tip
- Lousy weather these days, stay dry
- Does it matter?
You're asking me?
Let's eat
Go ahead
Do you know what this
provincial campaign is all about?
Then do you know what 'crack-down' means?
The purpose of this campaign is...
to promote the newly
promulgated criminal laws
In order to implement the new measures...
we must raise public awareness...
and promote the study of the new laws
Such as the code of criminal procedure
and the criminal law
Both have come into force this year
We promote...
Give your uncle a hug
Be a good girl, will you?
Give me a hug
Who bought you this mango?
Who bought this mango?
- It was your daddy, wasn't it?
- Tell uncle
I'll take her, she's a shy kid
Seems nice to have a kid
Yeah, means a lot
Did you find that thing?
That ID card, the Xiaoyi guy's
- Is this the one?
- Here, let me see...
Yes, it is
You guys know what you're doing
I'll buy you lunch
Sure
As you wish
You need to lie low for a bit
They're turning up the heat
If you get yourself caught...
you'll be in real trouble
I've stopped
Yeah, go easy
Why don't you learn to do business?
Look at Xiaoyong
He's doing great
I hear he's putting up another building
by the West Gate
I don't think like him
Who does? It's all about gut feeling
Think big, grab your chances
Do nothing, get nowhere,
that's what I'm seeing
Excuse me, boss...
What do you want?
We're here with the police,
about the demolition and relocation
We don't see you for ages and when you
come you want to demolish the place
- We'll take measurements
- Okay
- Got it?
- Yes
Liang Xiao Wu,
what are you doing here?
Chief...
Not even a hello?
Pretending you don't know me?
I didn't see you
What are you up to?
I'm doing business
Business?
You've heard the announcements?
Yes, I have
You... You need to shape up
Learn to be a good person
Look at your buddies from the old days
Most of them have changed
Look at Jin Xiaoyong
He runs his own company
They even named him "Model Entrepreneur"
And you? Still up to your old tricks?
I stopped, long since
Oh yes, it's his wedding tomorrow
His bride is as pretty
as Ni Ping (a TV star)
What about you? Are you engaged yet?
He's getting married tomorrow?
Of course, why would I lie to you?
Here, he gave me an invitation
An invite to the wedding, here
Chief, I've got to go
Sure
Give it back! What are you doing?
Come over here
- What's up?
- Come
Don't fool around!
What's wrong with you?
What do you want?
Did Jin Xiaoyong invite you
to his wedding?
He didn't tell you?
No, did he tell you?
It's his wedding, not mine...
Did he invite you or not?
He did
Maybe he was too busy to tell you
At least you won't have to
shell out for a gift!
Shut up!
You just sit there smoking!
Get a move on!
Don't you see what time is it?
Time's getting on! And you?
You want to smoke all 20 boxes
before you move your ass?
It'll take forever to get it all done
Chef, what are you doing?
Filling prescriptions?
Look at the time!
Can you get it done?
Just got your jobs done!
Hello? What is it?
Of course! What's happening?
I still think you should invite Xiao Wu
A wedding is a big deal
At least do it as a courtesy
I know it's not really my business
but I just had to say it
Everyone who comes tomorrow
knows what he does
What do you want me to do?
Remind everyone that Jin Xiaoyong...
was once a pickpocket too?
Is that it?
Is that what you want?
Let it go! The army is holding
up a load of my cigarettes
I need to sort that out
Talk later
And fifthly...
Those who fail to report cases,
shelter criminals...
destroy criminal evidence
or traffic in stolen goods...
shall be investigated and prosecuted
Those who threaten
reporters and witnesses...
will be punished in
accordance with the law
Those who persist in
flouting national laws...
will be severely punished
"I stand in the mighty wind"
"Wishing it could blow
away my endless heartache"
"I watch the clouds which span the skies"
"With sword in hand,
wondering who's the hero in this world"
This is cheaper, but the other one's better
Sounds good, doesn't it
- Can we have another listen?
- It's not that expensive
You won't find anything
with better sound quality
Even it's not too pricey,
but we want one with better sound
Let's hear something else on it
It's the best you can get at this price
See for yourself, have another listen
The bass isn't great
- You think the bass isn't good?
- Hmm...
It has the best sound of
any domestic-made product
Great quality absolutely
There was one in the mailbox at 8am
And then more came at 6pm
Hey, you
What's up?
Change these to big notes for me
Are you tired of living?
I told you this morning,
can't you see what's going on?
Are you asking to be caught?
Why do it?
I need the money
If it's urgent, I can lend you some
It makes no sense if I borrow it
Why? Is your ma sick?
No
You need to hide out for a couple of days?
Then what's it for?
Xiaoyong is getting married tomorrow,
it's for him
As a gift?
Was it worth the risk?
What notes do you want?
Hundreds
Here you are
What is it for?
Give me some red paper, to wrap it
Red paper?
Why are you weighing it?
It's paper money, not gold
One year when Xiaoyong and I
had only 41 cents between us...
we went on foot all the way
from Fenyang to Beijing
We were in a motel when I told him...
that when he got married...
I'd give him six kilos of money
There weren't 100-yuan notes back then
The biggest was a 10
You think he still needs your money?
He's much better off than you now
It's not about the money
We are different
Here...
- Is it done?
- Yes
Go on then
You're here...
- Been busy?
- So-so
Let's talk inside, come on
Can you take a look at this, boss?
- You go in first
- Do what you have to
- What is it?
- How's this deep-fried meat ball?
It's okay, as long as it is deep-fried
Try some, it's freshly made
I just ate
Try it
What's this all about?
I'm getting married tomorrow
You didn't invite me?
It won't be a big party, just family,
haven't told many others
Don't tell me you were
too busy or just forgot...
to invite me to your wedding
Not many people knew
It's not what you think,
just a few people, mostly family
You're doing it on the cheap?
Mostly family
Family?
Since when is the police chief family?
And Fatty Wu? He's family, too?
You've fucking changed...
Fucking changed...
Stop fucking this, fucking that...
Okay, okay
Are you pissed-off?
I pissed you off?
No
I'm not pissed off with you
Don't say you forgot
You fucking did forget
I did forget
It's true
What's this?
A gift
Money?
Take it back
What's it for?
I have to go
Look at your tattoo, you fucker
Dear viewers...
Our famous local entrepreneur...
Mr. Jin Xiaoyong will
get married tomorrow
On behalf of Fenyang
TV's call-in program...
I'd like to give Mr. Jin
our most sincere congratulations
Mr. Jin, tomorrow is your wedding day
Many friends have called in to us...
to request songs for your wedding
Do you have a few words for
our viewers and friends?
People of Fenyang, old friends...
First, I want to thank you
for all the support and help over the years
On this special occasion...
In sincere gratitude...
to supporters of our
company in Fenyang...
I'd like to give something back
to the community
Now, it's time for your calls
Our first request comes from Erhu
and others in the Fenyang Grain Bureau
The song they've chosen
for Mr. Jin is 'Raining Heart'
"The lady is pretty, the lady is charming"
"The lady walks in the green fields"
"The ears of corn have grown"
What's so funny?
Nothing, go on singing
I won't
How come?
I spent big money to hear you sing
Go on
No, I won't
Karaoke isn't fun if you don't join in
I want you to sing
Big sister, play some duets
This song is for two people
"My feelings are like an untouchable net"
"My feelings are no
longer a streaming ocean"
Your turn
You go on
Come on!
Go on, sing!
Grow up! You're as shy as a girl!
Take the mic
It's only a song, it won't kill you
Come on
Why aren't you singing?
I can't sing
- You can't do 'Raining Heart'?
- No
'I Heard You Singing Once'?
When was that?
It's the name of a song
How about...
'Tow-men in Love'?
No
'Neither Rainy Nor Windy'?
Are you kidding me?
I really can't
Boss...
Your girl is no good
What's wrong?
I spent 50 just to sit around?
How come?
In our "Great Shanghai Karaoke"...
everyone has fun dancing and drinking
She refuses to sing or dance
That can't be right! Meimei!
Our guest Xiao Wu isn't satisfied
with your service
I asked him to join in
a song and he wouldn't
I asked him to dance and he wouldn't
What did I tell you?
Our guest Xiao Wu is like my brother
If he doesn't want to
sing, you do it for him
If he doesn't dance, you do it for him
- How can you be so dumb?
- Never mind
Brother, this won't do
You're my brother,
I can't accept your money
It's too embarrassing
You don't have a smaller bill?
No
How about this...
Meimei, take a stroll
outside with your brother
Cheer him up, you hear me? Go on
Here's your jacket, get going, all right?
Brother, get her back here before dawn
What am I saying? Dawn?
Get her back here before nightfall
All right?
Get going! Hurry up!
You silly girl, get going! Go on!
What a nuisance!
Where are we going?
I shouldn't have worn my high heels today
You could go up there,
that'd be even higher!
You're quite stubborn, aren't you?
Let's go back
Okay, I can go by myself
That's all I get for my 50 yuan?
You're boring
Didn't you tell me to go?
You're the fucking boring one
What isn't boring?
How about this...
Come with me,
I need to make a phonecall
Is that the paper mill?
Can I speak to Chen Gailian?
I'm her daughter
It's a long distance call from Beijing,
so please hurry
From Beijing, thank you
Noisy, isn't it?
Ma, it's Meimei
No, I'm not at school
I'm with a film director
Don't know yet
I know
How's everyone at home?
Is my brother still getting into fights?
After all, he's a worker now,
he needs to grow up
How's dad?
Is he getting better?
Tell him not to lose his temper
Don't you worry
Take care of yourself
I know
Don't worry, I'm fine
No need to worry about me
Okay
Okay, I'll call you when I'm free
Bye
So this is Beijing?
Who am I?
I'm the film director?
Miss, what would you like
to do with your hair?
Just a shampoo and oil treatment
Miss, you have great hair
Do you fancy trying a 30s look?
It's called "Red Dust in the Wind"
- What's that?
- It's the latest thing!
Forget it, just the oil treatment is fine
Oil treatment it is
Shit, you southerners know all the tricks
Have a cigarette
Everyone's into mood and taste these days
- No shampoo for you, mister?
- Me? No
Let's put on some music to enhance the mood
- Have you ever been to a salon with a girl before?
- Never
But you know how to please a girl
What do you mean?
You unplugged the guy's
electricity, just like that
That's easy
Deep-fried dough sticks
are called 'Youtiao' in Fenyang
In Tianjin, they call them 'Guozi'
So 'Guozi' are 'Youtiao'
but they taste better
Really?
Pretty?
Not bad
Actually, you're more
interesting than I thought
I'm ordinary
It's getting dark
I must go back
So that's all?
Time's up, no more entertainment
So I spent 50 on your
phone call and hair-do?
You had nowhere else to
go, that's not my fault
I'm going back to the karaoke bar
Come and see me there sometime
What are you doing here?
Nothing, officer, just passing the time
Passing the time? Show me what's in the bag
Come on, open it
Fuck! Did you betray me?
Aren't you going to check the guns?
I trust you
"Each day, I wander"
"Wander with no regard for day or night"
"How I long for some companionship"
"To keep my heart from drifting"
Give it back!
Come here
Are you fucking crazy?
Just having fun, no meaning
Let's go play mahjong
Not interested
What's wrong? I can' fool around with you?
No, fuck it, you can't
You bloody idiot!
Fine!
I want to stand on the seashore,
I'd like to see the sky again
The sound of the waves is so wonderful
Okay, pack your things first
I'll be back soon
I'll wait for you
You had the chance to leave
Why didn't you go?
Why?
"My feelings are like an untouchable net"
"My feelings are no
longer a streaming ocean"
"In these long, rainy days ..."
"why do I keep thinking about you?"
Boss?
Who is it?
You're too early, we're not open yet
- Spending my money here is no good?
- Not at all
Hurry up! Get ready!
Who'd you like to see today?
A Sichuan girl or a Guizhou girl?
Today, I want a Beijing girl
- Beijing? So you want me to keep you company?
- Sure!
Come on, be serious
Where's Hu Meimei?
Meimei?
You have a thing for her
That's right
She's sick, not in today
- Sick?
- Uh-huh
She must've been dancing too much
Listen...
We have other girls here
I'll get you another one
You're playing me
Don't just stand there
You have work to do, clean up this mess
She really is sick?
Yes, I wouldn't lie to you
Where does she live? I'll go see her
Why not, if you want to...
Meimei, you're lucky to have a day off work
Lucky? I feel like I'm dying
Can you stay with me?
It's nothing serious
Drink some hot water and you'll be fine
- Is there any hot water?
- We haven't boiled it yet
Meimei, we're going now
Bye-bye
I'm off. Bye-bye
I'm going, too. Bye-bye
Did you find it?
Yes, I did
Good
Santu!
Over here
Fuck, you're smart!
Learning to socialize...
and pick up girls!
And you're not even shaving yet!
Give me some face, okay?
You'll do
Run along
Who is it?
Me
Why are you here?
To see if your boss lied to me
You shouldn't be here,
the landlady doesn't allow visitors
You said to come when I had time,
and I'm free today
You're crazy
So you really are sick?
Why would I pretend?
What's the problem?
Stomachache
That's no big deal
Have a smoke, that'll help
No
You want to see a doctor?
Can I get you some medicine?
No, but you could pour me some hot water
What's your name?
Seriously?
Liang Xiao Wu
I was just kidding
How could I forget?
You went to the hair salon with me
Are you all right?
Yeah
I wish I had a hot-water bag
Stay right there
What's up?
I need a hot-water bag
It's on the house, take it
- I won't stay, then
- Bye
- Are they really demolishing it?
- Yes
I'll come and lend a hand
Don't worry about it
Thank you, I'm much better now
You're welcome
Take a seat
Your family must own a coalmine
You seem to be rolling in money
I'm just a craftsman...
living on my skills
You don't look like one
I earn my living with my hands
It's not easy to be a craftsman
Some run karaoke bars
Some wholesale cigarettes
This is all I can do
You really can't sing?
No, I can't
Then why do you keep coming?
- Do you like hearing me sing?
- Yes, I do
I do like singing
You know...
People often say that I look like a star
But I know very well...
that I'll never be a star
Sing me a song
What do you like to listen to?
Your favorite song
- I like Faye Wang's songs
- Okay
Then I'll sing one
Go ahead
Don't laugh at me
I won't
"Why is my sky always weeping?"
"Why is my sky always so gray?"
"Drifting on the other side of the world"
"Letting loneliness invade me"
"Over and over again"
"The sky, filled with longing"
"Is your sky hung with clouds?"
"Does your sky have a cold moon?"
"Exiled to the other side of the world"
"Letting loneliness invade me"
"Night by night"
"Sky... filled with ..."
How about you sing me a song, too?
- I really can't
- Just one song
Close your eyes, then
"My feelings are like an untouchable net"
"My feelings are no
longer a streaming ocean"
"In these long, rainy days ..."
"Why do I keep thinking about you?"
"I miss you ..."
"I'll miss you one last time"
"My feelings are like an untouchable net"
"My feelings are no
longer a streaming ocean"
"In these long, rainy days ..."
"Why do I keep thinking about you?"
"My feelings are like the rain in June ..."
Xiao Wu...
- Why didn't you knock?
- In a joint like this?
Why are you here?
Xiaoyong wants me to give this back to you
What did he say?
He says your money isn't
clean, he can't accept it
We're all friends, hope you understand
Go back and tell him these exact words...
He gets money by smuggling tobacco
and ripping off bar girls
That's not clean, either
Sure, I'll pass that on
I'll be going
Get out!
On my way
It's okay
Sing your song
Be nice to me, will you?
All right
- I'll be counting on you
- Fine
Will you be my man?
- Sure
- Really?
Yeah
Promise?
Promise
Xiao Wu!
You again!
Xiaoyong says to tell you...
He's not smuggling cigarettes,
that's regular trade
And he's not ripping off the singers
in the karaoke bars
That's just the entertainment business.
That's it
Get lost!
Sure, I'm off... Bye-bye
What's wrong?
It's okay
I'm fine
From now on I'll come
by to see you every day
No need for that, just buy a pager
I'll page you whenever I'm free, okay?
Okay
"Can't shake my thoughts
about being in love"
"Can't stop thinking about anger and hate"
"All generations are fated"
"We shed the same blood"
"We drink the same water"
"It's a long road, stretching far"
"Each red flower has its own green leaf"
"But who will be my life's companion?"
"So distantly remote, coming and going"
"Days gone by return to haunt me"
"A lotus root may snap,
but its thread holds"
"The world keeps changing,
and I can only sigh"
Is it for your fiancée?
No need to check,
it beeps when someone pages you
Your play, come on
Well, brother, look at you today!
I look okay?
Better than that, you look great!
As if you're just back from America
You must be doing well!
Not bad
Thanks for the smoke
Big sister, how's business?
We get by
Not like you!
Always making easy money, aren't you?
You've made all this money...
But you still smoke Hong Ta Shan?
You should switch to imported ones
You can afford it, brother
Is Meimei here?
Not here today
Where is she?
She's out on a job
I'll wait for her then
Sorry, no
Not today, not possible
See, she won't be back soon
Where has she gone?
There were some clients from outside
From where?
They picked her up by car
Where are they from?
Taiyuan
From Taiyuan?
Yes, from Taiyuan
Why did you let her go?
You knew I was coming today
You should have come earlier
It's not my job to watch her for you
You're so fucking ungrateful
Watch what you say, you
You don't own her
What are you to her?
What is she to you?
You swagger in with your dirty money,
like you own the place!
Hu Meimei
Who's looking for Hu Meimei?
Oh, it's you
Is she back yet?
She moved out
She really did move out
Someone came in a car this morning...
and helped with her stuff
Where the hell did she go?
No idea
She didn't even tell the boss
It must be somewhere great
Ma, I have something for you
You brought me a gift?
It's a ring
You must be tricking me
Let me see it
I got it for Ma, not you
Your old man can look at whatever he wants
We've been peasants for three generations
I can't tell if it's gold or copper
It's gold,
I wouldn't give my ma a copper ring
What's the occasion? Why do a pig's head?
Our sister-in-law is coming tomorrow
You call her that even though
they aren't married yet
- Don't be an idiot
- Like you're any better, loser
I am a loser
"Oh, papa"
"My sweet papa"
"Oh, mama"
"My beloved mama"
"Poison!"
"You... What do you think you're doing?"
- Dad, are my brother and his fiancée back?
- Yes, they are
And Cui Xian and the kid?
They'll be here in a minute
Xiao Wu, when did you get here?
Last night
Did you hear that Zheng
Gangtie was arrested?
No, I didn't
That's what I heard
Nonsense, I played mahjong
with him a couple of days ago
Since you're all here,
there's something I want to discuss
Your brother's fiancée...
is a city girl
Her family is well off
Ours is not
I've talked with your ma about the money
And I want to talk with you about this too
I want each of you boys
to make a contribution of 5,000 yuan
What do you think?
Let's discuss it later
Xiao Wu, I hear that Xiaoyong got married?
Yes
Who's the bride?
I don't know
I'm waiting to hear what you think
Let's discuss it later
Xiao Wu, when did you get a pager?
Let me see it
You're the eldest, say something
Where will I find 5,000?
I haven't paid the road
tax on my tractor yet
Xiao Wu, what do you say?
I'm broke, I'll do what brother does
So what do you think?
Let's come back to it
later, there's no rush
Sister...
- You're back
- Yes
Sanduo, you don't need your ma to carry you
Come here, greet your uncle
There you go, greet your uncle
Say 'uncle'
You don't want to?
You forgot your uncle?
I gotta go
Is your brother here?
Yes, he's inside
Uncle, you're here
Would you like some water?
No, I've had some
I was looking for Erbao
Dad, I saw the fields have been ploughed
I did it twice,
yesterday and the day before
It's done
I thought you must've been busy
I wanted to come and help
I planned to come yesterday
But my tractor was held up in Xiaoyi
I know you're quite busy
So I thought I'd do it myself...
rather than to wait for you
when it's getting so hot
Did you plough all the fields?
Yes, they're all done
What are you going to plant this year?
We're planting maize and sorghum
There's been plenty of rain this year
How about millet?
Sure
We'll grow more millet, for sure
Millet fetches a good price
There's been plenty of rain this year
I do plan to grow more millet
Right, this area is great for millet
What else can we grow here?
It's harder to husk sorghum and corn
The market for millet is strong
And there's hay, good for feeding livestock
Get up! Give us a hand
We only just came back
Had a good snooze
Dad, have a smoke
Brother, here you are
Xiao Wu, try one
What kind of cigarette is this?
- It's Marlboro
- Marlboro?
How much is one pack?
- 12 yuan, they're American
- 12?
That's as much as a whole
carton of Princess brand!
How can it be worth that much?
Is it some special tobacco?
No, this is the cheapest brand in America
That's how much it costs
Erbao and his wife work for the state
They drink coffee and
eat cakes all the time
Imported cigarettes are
no big deal for them
Sister, you're wrong,
money's hard to come by in the city too
- I didn't mean it, sorry
- Never mind
Enough talk, is the food ready? Let's eat
Wait, it's still cooking
It'll be done very soon
Erbao, when did you buy the ring?
How could I afford it?
It was a gift from her ma
Can I take a look?
How much did it cost?
It's an imitation, 18k gold-plated
Ma, where's your ring?
I've put it away
Show me
Wasn't it a gift to me?
Yes, I gave it to you
But not so you could
give it to someone else
I haven't given it to anyone
Then what ring is my
brother's fiancée wearing?
I've been in here, how should I know?
Show me the ring anyway
Are you forcing me?
- No, I'm not - I should have
never raised a black sheep like you
Do you know how I earned the money?
Show me the ring
You want it back? I don't have it
Show it to me
You want to destroy this family?
Both family and state have rules
How did I raise such a disobedient kid?
I should've drowned you in urine at birth!
I'll kill you with a rolling pin
Do you know who you are?
You're the son of Liang Changyou!
If you're not my son,
get the hell out and stay out!
You unfilial son...
I won't come back!
Don't!
I'll never come back!
Never ever!
Zhang Wenhuai reporting for Shanxi Radio
With a brand new look to welcome
the return of Hong Kong...
the 15th Party Congress
has concluded successfully
Xinzhou Prefectural Administrative Office has
decided to prioritize the building of urban culture
The policy will be promoted widely
Anyone who wants a slice of pork,
please come to my house
Demolish
You're moving out?
Moving out?
Been here for ten years,
but now they say it has to go
What the hell!
If the old doesn't go, the new won't come
One thing's for sure
The old is going... but where is the new?
Come help!
Stop the thief!
Dandan...
Where's your granddad?
Stand up
Properly!
Why are causing trouble again?
Empty your pockets! Quick!
Quick!
Stand still!
What is this?
Look at yourself! Sit!
Is this yours? Where did you get it?
Bought it
You'd better tell me
Stay there!
All your things are in here
We'll come back to it later
I'll count your money
Watch!
110 yuan
Sign here
Dandan, play with your
aunt, Granddad is busy
You're like a one-man crime wave
We've caught you so many times!
You're incorrigible!
I think we need to throw
the book at you this time
Think about it!
Let me check my pager
No, you can't. Sit back down
Zhao, here's that information
Good, give me a moment
Get up!
Stand straight!
Over here
Stand here and think it all through
Stand properly
Watch TV if you like
But think about your problems
You're a repeat offender
Watch TV, I'll be back to deal with you
Promote corporate culture
Showcase the Hongxing spirit
Hongxing State-owned
Commercial Trading Company...
extends its sincerest
greetings to all our friends
Looking for refreshment?
Golden Monkey is here to help
Golden Monkey's leather shoes
for men and women...
will always be loyal
friends to your feet
In tonight's news...
Our city has held a party-building workshop
The construction-site meeting for Fenyang
Township Justice Office was held in Chengzi Town
Please stay tuned for more details
Come on, the car is waiting outside
How did you end up here again?
You idiot
Have you been dropping
IDs into our mailbox?
Yes
Sit down
When were you last arrested?
I think it was 1993
94, 95, 96, 97, so it's been 4 years
Chief, can I have a look at my pager?
Pager? You got yourself a pager?
It's locked in that drawer
What does it say?
It's the weather forecast,
"Sunny, turning cloudy"
Thanks to the crack-down campaign...
a number of offenders have been arrested
Yesterday, the police arrested
the recidivist Liang Xiao Wu
This news has been welcomed by the public
Our reporter is on site
Yesterday, the police arrested
the recidivist Liang Xiao Wu
What do you think about the arrest?
It's a good thing, he's a law-breaker
Everyone thinks his arrest is a good thing
The recidivist Liang Xiao Wu was caught
yesterday How do you feel about it?
A black sheep like him
deserves to be caught
Chief, I didn't see you yesterday
A friend had his 40th birthday,
I drank a bit too much
You should drink less,
alcohol is bad for you
What does it say?
A Miss Hu paged
Wishing you all the best
"I stand in the mighty wind"
"Wishing it could blow away
my endless heartache"
"I watch the clouds which span the skies"
"With sword in hand,
wondering who's the hero in this world"
Stop here
Wait for me, I'll be back