the wind can be really fierce ah
this is your first time, isn't it
yes
today you'll man the winch
if you fell, nothing but death...
pick that up, help me over here
Ok
had a "crane faint" on your first time
sorry
now we also need more crane time
and then, we take a break
too much wind today... let's forget it
sorry
help me pick up the crane and stow it
Ok
Pieta
in
the
Toilet
starting the blood samples
let's label it neh
please hold your breath
what do you intend for the future
what do you mean
you have been working so much
ah
to our company, with full-time employees
we always feel like worms
insects
on the wall, attached to the building by a cable
like insects, like...
insects
insects neh
yes, insects
together that makes us insects
do not rub the innermost
dry next to it and then rub
Long time no see
you still on the cable ah
ah
you still painting
no, I've given up painting
why
I want to get married so I'm not doing it
you're getting married
no, I'm lying
tomorrow I'm doing my solo exhibition
right
"Fascinated Times"
good name
got to go
just who was that
she is my ex-college classmate
and ex-girlfriend
beautiful one neh
also, she's realy well to do
so she's also perfect
yes ah
what are you doing
don't do this
it's alright, I won't show it to others
that's not the problem
that is the problem
you, come here
no
you come here right now
I'm painting
which is more important, me or painting
people who ask this question are really low
you are the low one here
don't hide
oi
you know what Tanaka has on his wiper's handle
it says KILL
I didn't know, what the hell for
kill
last time, before going to work a building, Tanaka watched it and said
today I'll kill you
then wrote the word on it
he definitely has a mental problem
probably thinks of himself as a terrorist
and us, we are cable men
a real basket case
is Ozaki-san in now
no, she isn't
how long for her to come today
on that I'm not very sure
she won't come today
oh, is that so... thank you
thanks
hello... here I am at your personal exhibition
so you got busy today
Ok, good
listen, can I have some of your time next Tuesday
why should I have to pretend to be your sister ah
they asked me to bring relatives to the hospital
what did you think of my personal exhibition
good ah
so
so, I mean to say it's not only good
whatever that means
a while ago I won the Okura Art Award
it's the you've wanted some time ago
right... congratulations
oi
what
why this
anyway, you didn't take my paintings seriously
I didn't mean it
Hiro-chan, you got talent
I don't have any, I'm just a cable man
at the least, you were better than I am
even my paintings have recognition
maybe I just have to keep going farther than you
honestly, I do not care for that anymore
well, I do... goodbye
are you kidding
you've torn my school uniform
I have to wear this uniform to graduate school
you're really bad bad person, well done
I'll contact your parents
tell me their phone numbers
this doesn't concern my parents
their numbers, tell me
what are you watching
how much money for a uniform
ten thousand
this is one thousand
you're free to go
see you
this is one thousand
now you're my sister
I'm telling you, this is one thousand
next time I'll give you more
tell me your phone number
quickly
calling Sonoda Hiroshi-san
what you got is a stomach tumor
tomorrow you'll begin treatment in the hospital
that won't work
why
let your parents come together to talk about it
I won't do it
why ah
you be quiet
if it is so, then by doing nothing
you'll live only about three more months
frequently blurred vision, loss of appetite, fever, anemia
are the main symptoms
for this cancer, there's no specific treatment
it's writen
we still can go back
the hell with getting better
you can live easier now and die later
please hurry
get off
not there yet
off
hurry
spineless
how about going to my house, now
no
why
what for
I want to draw your portrait
so are you an artist
I don't think so, but I'm very good at drawing
really, just to paint me
yes
no, no, next time
then tell me your number
next time we meet I'll tell you
alright
I just got off work
ah, what people - really well done
why have you two come
because...
I'm saying I'm all right
we can have a good meal
and we go home
have you painted anything good
not one canvas
so there is no sense to stay in Tokyo, right
I, ah
I was your age and already in a very serious...
I don't need to cause trouble to others
actually I say it's no trouble
here we are, Sonoda-san
starting tonight with the anti-cancer therapy
each day you take these three times, two with breakfast, lunch and dinner
oh, without fail
you didn't eat that
not yet
yes
may I
ah the amount of meals here is really small, is it not
not enough to eat in full
may I have this too
dessert
right
I'm Yokota
I'm called Sonoda
Hiroshi
yes
I was hospitalized for esophageal cancer
How about you
stomach
stomach ah
stomach neh
hope to usher adulthood
formidable
good to me
hope to return to my life
ah disgusting
doctors
ah, ah, hello minister
today I come with a new patient
oh
can you help me to see how he is doing
good
sit
please sit
good
how is your health today
well, it isn't good right now
don't worry, with efforts the disease can be brought down
good
please, could you show us one of your hands
doctor, drawing blood in this place seems quite easy
Ok, blood from this place, right
good, let's start
starting
please, clench your fist
first wipe
disinfection
wow, nervous
finished
good, you can relax your hand
that was the first one
ah wait a...
it's not over yet...
that is the side effects of anticancer drugs
yes, their side effects
after that it will be diarrhea
yes, next they'll cause diarrhea
Ok
you heard about the side effects of anticancer drugs, like vomiting in pregnancy, as women do
morning sickness ah
Ok
you're not really ready
here, for you
hold it
to change your mood
this is my favorite thing
giving gifts to friends
night
good morning
hey, you all right already
why do you ask
I thought you were still in the hospital
ah I'm Ok, thank you
when I saw you coming up I was really surprised
then let's get going
good
it looks like this seems a bit too heavy
sorry
well, I'll start cleaning the exterior wall
No, no do not force yourself
I have absolutely no problem
so today you can go rub the windows together with Noda, she's new
good
you go ahead, I got to go to the toilet first
Ok
hi
how was that
a broken toilet faucet
I got caught accidentally
oh pity, you'll get cold
Hashida, you can work some overtime with me
oh, you're really mean
someone complained about leaks in the second floor toilets
why did this happen now
we did not use the other side of the toilet
Tanaka, I can help
no, don't worry
it's nothing
you'd better go back and rest
hey, don't just casually go rubbing shop windows
the proper thing to say to a helping hand is thank you
I told you not to rub
don't worry, I'm about finished
I'm telling you not to rub
why why why eh
it's my right, my job
what're you doing
you Ok
as good as it can be
escape can give a lot of breathing space
you know, it's said you can tell a dying person's time right away
I don't believe that
I don't believe it either
are you very busy now
not so busy
life in a hospital is generally not very busy
come with me to the lounge
come on, come on, just for a bit
starting tomorrow!
a great nighttime
outing!
finally able to go
out since the start of
a bout of straight
fighting
body swelling subsided
look at this, she didn't even blush
she looks like figs teacher, isn't it
"figs teacher"
with Tomoko Sasaki
she looks serious in over half of them, though
but there are funny ones
such as this, and this
why, look at that
very interesting
it doen't look funny
you sure
it looks very painful
painful, why
why
normally, it's generally not amusing
all the same, generally it's not funny
enough
brother
this for you, eat
this is also for you
do you know Hero Rescue Team
no, I don't know
you don't know...
you do not know it
but, it's a lot of fun to try painting it
see you later
I made a mistake
sorry, I gave you the one meant to Miho
this is his brother
sorry, I got to take the other back
it got dirty with the cake
I didn't mean to throw it away
I only had this one
sorry
mother, have some beer
I'll save it for a big event
What is it
eat it
ah I've waited since morning for dinner, at least let's enjoy it
Masato is not here today
he hasn't come back
if he had come back, it'd be just fine
could you help your grandmother to bathe
brother, how are you feeling today
this is for you
this is for the gods, so they can hear our prayers
don't be bothered with what happened before
I gave you the wrong drawing and the cake together, it wasn't your fault
see you later
civilization originated in places with water
that is because moisture is essential to the growth of crops
and large cargos can travel through river channels
thus the use of river transport
so, water was essential for the development of civilization
but then
60 percent of our own body is water
that only emphasizes the importance of water
this is very important, please copy down the blackboard carefully
I need to go to the toilet
you're being a stalker, a lolicon
and while you idle in the hospital, I'm busy
here
what
plus errands fee
looks easy
what
hospital life
it is not
carefree adult's life
is this what you eat every day
yes
unedible
what
nothing
at my age, it's a crime
I'm not interested in children
got to go
who's the child
my sister
don't lie
her lips, she has just such lips
she kissed you in the lips
there were sister kisses for you
there was no kissing, so wipe your mouth
me, I won't wipe mine... your mouth is the one she kissed
bye bye, folks
bye bye - goodbye
so... this is for you
wow, it's amazing
my own drawings
amazing, can I keep it
yes
nice
a great gift
I'm his mother, we appreciate your gift
nice to meet you
do you draw often
not now, I don't
this is so
look at this, amazing
amazing, very nice
thank you very much
handsome
excuse me, can I have one
sure
so many days of rest
and the company won't keep him longer
I often say
it's not fun working in this company
Yokota-san showed some nerve saying that there's a lot of people
but he didn't get nervous hearing he might be fired
that's not it
you don't know that
don't I know
that's not it
really
looks like it
hey, want to eat some
it was just brought by my younger colleagues
no, thanks
it seems I have to hurry back to my company
as if the company is a mess without me there
on second thoughts, I could eat one
no, I won't let you
I beg you, be a good grandmother now
as if this'd give back my stolen clothes
nothing of the sort
we're your family, in our own home now
we won't steal
it's not nice to steal
I'm tired
stop
really, give me a little candy, Oita
stop ah
you're going to meet your boyfriend, right
kiss fiend
not yet kissing
what, I envied you that
nice
nice ah, I also want to have a boyfriend
the game is the game
you aren't also a virgin, right
why aren't you at school
it's not fun
so you are more unfortunate than others
yes... and I wanted to look if you got better
stand up and look at me
and now show how to properly kiss
really, the man should lead
maybe
try to do something
do something
still shy
still silly
come here
what do you like
this
excuse me, I want to buy this fish
what'll you do with them
confidential
ah Hiro-chan
let's introduce you
how are you doing
Ok
ah
he is my college classmate Sonoda
Nice to meet you
this is the writer, Sakai-san
my personal exhibition was possible thanks to Sakai-san's recommendation
right, because her work is not very good
as if that could be true
we think you are very talented neh
next time let me see your work
if you let me, I'll help you
that doesn't interest me
doesn't it
I hate people like you
you can just make such good work
but thinking it cannot be recognized, that it does not matter
no matter what you do, we don't need people with such attitude
let's go
excuse me
that dress you're wearing, deliberately looking soiled
that's a rustic chic look
bring them over
good
come ah
I'm tired, I'll stay here
those really boring people
why they despise the sick man
hey look, look
do you want to see my underwear
come dive into the water and you can see them, oh
you'll see
come on
satyr
or not
I'll be discharged tomorrow
although our time together wasn't long, thank you for your attention
going to work tomorrow
of course, going to the company
I wasn't away from the company that much, but enough to risk dismissal
saying how people should or shouldn't live
that doesn't make sense
nor does this rat race we live in
also, the food chain frowns on fraternization
so Yokota-san, why are we alive
for me, it is because
I don't want to die now
are you all right
thank you, I'm fine
be careful
sorry to have dragged you here
Takuto's the one who wanted us to pray together
it's nothing, anyway I was idle
this statue, you know what it is, right
it is the Pieta
I learned as a student
holding a dead son
how can she look so serene
well, the doctor said his life expectancy was only six months
but because of the treatment efforts
now he may get through the year
he has a major surgery soon ahead
and if the surgery goes well
maybe he'll be able to leave the hospital
that child has been sick so much
I think a lot about it
why does my child have to bear such pain
but if you can overcome the disease
you'll be more cherished than others
for the rest of your life
so it's necessary to stay strong
what's this ah
it's not practice
oi, wait
oi
why don't you paint anymore
that girl is so fast
yes ah
Hey wait
running away
that's wicked
terrific ah
Takuto
what
I also have a surgery soon
we can make it
ah restarting
ah
restarting
so wicked ah
I got 11 points
where's Takuto
Takuto
he was discharged from the hospital
the "gada gada"
into the red
the wrong ones snap and fall
how are you feeling
Ok
good
test results will take a while to get right to my office
Ok
hello
I got to go
sit
Takuto was discharged, nice ah
you heard it from somebody
in the hospital, they told me
so ah
is Takuto alright
Takuto...
is gone
there are some hospital rules
they cannot say that a child has died
so, when Takuto left us, they said it was a discharge
about that
help me painting some of Takuto's drawings
paint anything you choose
I'll keep them with me always, Sonoda-san
you can paint from Takuto's videos
please
no
paint anything you want
sorry
I just dabble
I see
I embarrassed you, I'm really sorry
thank you very much to have taken care of us
how I wish I could skip living here and now
can't you come and play now
no, not so near dinnertime
why eat so unedible stuff
go out and eat good food, that should do it
I have to eat here, now
then you come see me eat
it's Ok if you go cycling
why
you can treat me ah
no can do
please
then go to the nearby cafe
no can do
don't be capricious
no, no, don't
I'm sorry, I have to go back
why this now, I don't like it
you keep refusing reasonable requests
and also plead sickness as an excuse
so cunning
cunning, when
every time
you do it too
I wasn't born with twisted thinking
I have to say
cool your temper
I have a right to my temper
there are many people more miserable than you
I don't care if there are
I became real real sick
I'm also sick ah
go... figure your wrongs
just drop dead
you just drop dead
I tell you
don't get stuck in a dead end, mopping the floor
don't look like tere's no one you love alive
the inspection found that the cancer has metastasized into the peritoneum
so you want to discuss options, Sonoda-san
on guidelines for future treatments
it's feasible to continue chemotherapy
but then
side effects become a great burden to the body
the alternative is to stop chemotherapy
not having to care about the side effects
resting at your home or a nursing home
of course, this way it's impossible to inhibit cancer cell proliferation
why did you hang old butterfly painting in the room
your father found the painting decorative so he put it in a frame
after you got hospitalized
how is your physical condition
so so
then, take good care
about that
I'm considering whether or not to go to a nearby hospital
they turn dirty soon, anyway
it doesn't pay to rub the windows
you are grown, now
28, ah
oh yes
where are you keeping your paintings
in Tokyo
you can make some money, you can sell me one now
you don't have to give me money, I'll send you one for free
well, well, I want to buy it
no
don't mention it
I don't need it
I have been, in fact, a great fan of yours
but I couldn't speak about it openly, sorry
what, I'm busy
sorry
what is it ah
I want to finally say hello to you
what does it mean
I'm going to a hospital in the countryside
you're not there yet
eh
you're not going to die yet
goodbye
eh
are you free right now
killing time
don't splash me
recently neh
I ran very hard
I thought I could run near to dying, so I tried to run
and get really really close to it
but I didn't die
it's not so easy to die
where are you going
to get medication
I forgot to eat
about this, it won't matter, right
what won't matter
you don't have to die
you take the pills, you don't die
it doesn't matter any longer, right
it doen't matter any longer
you have not really accepted the fact that we're all going to die ah
I know that
I'm reconciled though it pains me
also, it's hopeless
so quit this kid act saying I don't know how it is
it was my first time
you have to take responsibility
and no
you cannot die
I'm still alive, you have to live with me ah
come on, ride
I'm sick
but you're a man, right
neh
what do you do to prolong your life
I want to spend the rest of my time at home
where is it that you want to live, in your parents' home...
no, in my flat here
you do
yes
so, that's it
I understand
and another one
right right right
so
right right
face to the side
good
completely back to me the following
hand stays here
like this
hello
you came back ah
still the same issue
I also came back
are you free right now
what are you doing
what
pick up that chair
get it up here
what do you want to repair
the step stool could get handy
also, get my the pot of paint
which pot
thre're two - both
here you go
brushes
thank you
what do you want to do
painting
but why painting in the toilet
because it represents purification and ascension
ah you don't say
I guess it does
coming true ah
hey, is this Ok
good
also, the change for these
I'll put it here
thank you
good good
it looks weightless, like...
a really scary jump
the weightlessness, the weightlessness
besides the girls I usually shoot, ah
it's the first I shoot something else
my pleasure
you got a good ass there
you help me shoot mine
why
you have to help me shoot it
do I
let me give you this
I'll show I have a good one, too
good good
not ready to film yet, not yet
now, ready to film
this isn't your ass
get off, you
you peeling off and no one to look
how about this
a really good looking butt ah
you see, you see
you come back one o'clock
what
over one o'clock
I ah...
for decades I've been desperately trying
to win this cancer
I thought I had been healed, a remission
now every Monday to Friday I'm doing radiotherapy
I can be discharged for one month after two months doing this
then it's back to the hospital
two more months of radiotherapy before being discharged for a month
and so on, repeatedly
this said world, it hardly changes
it's all exactly the same
and so, it can be very cruel
you know it
it changes only by itself
I have nowhere to go from here on
congratulations
where did he go from the hospital, tell me now
apart from the patient's family, it's not...
you can tell me where he went to
I am sorry, due to the privacy of all concerned we cannot disclose this information
I don't see how this can work
you have to tell me ah
I am sorry, we have to comply with the rules
that doesn't wash with me
sorry
hurry, tell me
that...
you are Sonoda's sister, right
who are you
I'd have suffered a lot without the care of your brother
very, very much
you have to reconcile
really well done
really well done, that guy
even if you painted this thing
it's useless for you now ah
you didn't deliberately paint to die eh
he didn't paint to die
he didn't
what are you doing
how do you make yourself want to die
I don't know
sorry
look
don't look
your friends say you're shy ah
just some panties, why you so shy ah
you got a good ass there
you got a really good ass
enough of that
saying that, I've seen plenty of bare asses
Yokota-san
ah what
it's that
what
I always feel
what do you feel
I'm alive
ah
...
??
?????
stood before dying Summer is the entrance
knife mention in blue neck edge soul
big eyes gazed This is where the world is quiet blue
not to say Relationship But for this very good "every day"
suddenly say Goodbye
beside you laugh for you do not like the dumped me
in the desired category We met in the farthest place
as in who also No new snow on the tread
silver side of the pond Two blue lonely
\h\h\h\h\h\h\hoverlapping method lips do not know the end of the
is a miracle we are Unable to spread light
\h\h\h\heven so much the better for you tonight to think of overlooking
Life beginners completely naked little warrior
will be flying skirt Wings also put in place alive today
to occasionally flies Good day secretly smile
looked up at the stars Laughing say sorry and thank Hao Hao
Not once do we've
\h\h\h\h\hEven the moon will not know that we won this world
today's sky Blue tirelessly with
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\hyesterday also helped thunderstorms
"too ugly again have a degree, "someone in the distance saying
\h\hthen find who teach good? This is my first born
cosmic wink that a sudden I'm in love
silver side of the pond two blue heart beat
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\hoverlapping lips quietly remembered
you really are That day I was born
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\hspilled from my hand out of my pieces
first tight tight embrace this world sleeve
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\heven throw off too tightly back
is a miracle we are Unable spread of light
Now that we have altogether on