Take your top off.
Nobody can see you here.
You know I don't like that.
Anna, the dog!
- Schumann! Schumann!
Paul!
You hitchhiked here?
I couldn't afford the train.
Does my sister know you're here?
I got money from Mom,
but it wasn't enough.
I don't understand how you decided
to spend your vacaion here.
Why?
At the funeral, you told me
I could come any time
when home got too much.
Robert!
Robert needs a break
and something to drink.
He doesn't drink enough.
Hi.
How are you?
- What are you doing here?
Vacation. Here...
You're supposed to drink more.
Tell me. What are you doing here?
I didn't feel like hanging out
a home the whole summer.
You could have called.
How long you staying?
- Don't know. Till I get bored.
Robert, why not come outside
since you're taking a break?
I didn't want a break.
What?
Sorry about Frank.
Thanks.
- It must have been tough.
You weren't at the funeral.
I couldn't.
You changed everything around.
- Not everything.
But a lot.
What's grandma say?
What can she say?
She doesn't notice anymore.
Frank planted that cherry tree.
We left it there...
sort of a memorial.
- Robert!
- What? It's true.
Anna, where should Paul sleep?
The guest-room's no good.
It's too damp and dreary.
Not with me. My room's too small.
I...
I can sleep in the kids' room.
It's mine now, but we can
put you in there for now.
You smoke?
This is a sleeper.
We can turn it into a bed.
Make yourself comfortable.
Paul, how long do you want to stay?
Don't know.
I'll call your mother.
She won't be home.
Susanne, Stefan here, your brother.
Paul is at our house.
Give me a call
when you're back. Bye. Ok.
Paul, I'd appreciate it
if you wouldn't smoke in here.
No problem.
- Fine.
He takes after Frank, doesn't he?
We should set a limit.
- We can't do that.
Of course we can. Your sister could
have asked if it's alright with us.
Maybe it's a peace offering.
You know she doesn't talk much.
You think she knows he's here?
She'll call.
Don't you use it anymore?
No.
What's up?
The Berg Sonata is giving me problems.
The middle section is really hard.
Now idea how I'll have it ready
for Saturday.
What's on Saturday?
I have an audition.
Exciting.
The Leipzig Conservatory's
young students class.
Young students...
Still play table tennis?
Tha wasn't much, huh?
You won't get it.
Robert!
Seen the grill tongs?
Why didn't you say so?
Let me play! Give me the paddle.
You think I'm not up to it.
Hey!
Schumann! Come here!
Yes!
Hey!
Robert, turn the sausages.
You do it, Paul.
I don't have a free hand.
Robert.
Alright. Fine.
Well then...
Cheers.
Dear Paul,
welcome to our house,
that is also your house.
We are very happy
that you and your mother...
That you have decided to set aside
the old conflicts,
that were material in nature...
and that you've come to see us.
I know things haven't been
easy for you laely.
The financial difficulties...
- You know what? Let's just toast.
Yes.
To a nice couple of days.
What do you think when you hear
"Aspirin?" - Why do you ask?
Rendske wants to develop
a new slogan for Aspirin.
He started a naional campaign...
- How did Frank kill himself?
His current favorite is,
"Aspirin - Wellness afterwards."
I can't take anymore "Wellness."
They even created a new position,
" Wellness Coach."
He wants to subject all managers
to a "wellness check-up."
I've had enough.
They waste money on that
while cutting the training department.
A wellness check-up would do you good.
- Over my dead body.
Paul, no! Not from the table.
Not from the table.
Good night.
Night.
Why didn't you open it up?
- I like to sleep on the floor.
Ready.
Good morning.
Morning.
Sleep well?
- I slept... okay
- The room really stank.
- Paul, not at breakfast, I don't like it.
Robert, don't forget
we need to trim the cherry tree.
I'd like you and your father
to take care of it.
I can do that.
Give me a bread roll? - That's nice
of you, but my men can handle it.
I can take care of your pool.
Aha.
Somebody should fix it up.
Then we could swim here.
We?
It'd be nice in this weather.
- Somebody's sucking up.
Can you do that?
I learned a thing or two from my faher.
Is it true that Frank was broke?
- What?
Was he broke?
- Who told you that?
Mom.
And?
It's not your business.
Just asking.
What the...
What are you doing?
- Measuring the pool.
Yes, boy...
What are you doing?
I'm measuring the pool
to figure out how many tiles we need.
Must be...
...about 15 square meters.
You can really do this?
Sure.
I have time.
Hi, Paul.
- Stefan? - Hi.
I have to go to Madrid.
I have no choice. Tregomain is sick.
Tomorrow?
Tonight. My plane leaves at 1 0:1 5
For how long?
Awhole week. - Tregomain calls in
sickwhenever he wants. You never do!
Rubbish!
- But your family is coming to visit!
I didn't know and I can't change it!
Paul offered to tile the pool.
That's great. Very good.
It might be asking too much of him.
If he offered it himself...
- I can do it. No problem.
The time...
Paul, how long would tha take?
Aweek to do a good job.
We could pay you. Wha do you think?
- Good idea.
Then you won't have to hitchhike.
You can even go first class!
Playing the good Samaritan today?
Man...
That's great.
- What?
Paul's going to fix up the pool.
I would also like to travel again.
Nobody's stopping you.
Take a trip.
Wouldn't you like to see Vienna again?
With Schumann in my suitcase or wha?
The boy is totally uncomplicated.
And Robert's here, too.
They get along well.
Robert has better things to do.
- I'll be back Monday.
I promise I'll do something
with the boys when I'm back.
Smell.
What is it?
White rum. Want some?
Maybe laer.
Don't they know?
How? It looks like waer.
Robert! Come say goodbye.
Go say goodbye.
Please get changed.
- Paul!
Ciao!
You giving up already?
What's up? Come on! Let's go!
Here's your leash. Come on.
Paul! Are you crazy?
What? You don't want to swim?
- Yes, but not here.
The pond is dead.
Nitrate contamination.
You're not going in there, no!
You're not going in there!
That go any louder?
Where did you find that?
Brought itwith me.
Hold on, the cops are on my tail.
Bloody helicopter...
Feel like playing?
I have another controller here.
No thanks, I don't like shooters.
This isn't a shooter!
Turn it down. I'm going to sleep.
Okay.
Do you like that? Yeah?
Do you really like that?
Yes, you like it!
Nice!
Oh yes, I like that, too!
- Good morning.
Morning.
Would you like some fresh orange juice?
- Yes, please.
Saturday is Schumann's birthday.
Guess how old he'll be.
Ten?
- Ten!
Four! Four years old. Come here.
So... Yes, he likes that.
Yes.
Crisp-bread?
Will you manage all the Berg today?
- I did yesterday.
Play it like that and
we don't need to go to the audition.
Come! Sit. Sit. Sit.
I said sit!
I thought what he played yesterday
sounded really good.
There you go.
That's good.
Jerk!
Stop it now! Don't play with
your food, children!
I was going to wash anyway.
Put that here, please.
I'll do the rest.
Yes?
Robert, way too much!
First piano, then crescendo!
But that's what I did!
Paul!
Table tennis!
Okay.
What's wrong?
- Her and her authority-complex.
Robert!
Robert, come inside!
Paul, what about the pool?
I suggest you get on with that
and we'll work on the Berg sonata.
Serve!
It's okay.
Are you coming?
I'm taking Schumann for a walk.
Hello?
Want to come?
Okay.
Do you get along with your mother?
Well...
Is she doing better now?
Don't know. We don't talk much.
Would you like her
to talk with you more?
You know she talks a lot,
but she's always complaining.
You have to understand her.
It's a difficult time. - Yes, I know.
You do?
- Sure.
You must miss Frank a lot.
Oh, shit!
What is it?
Oh, it's red. Must have been a wasp.
Are you crazy?
Come home, I'll put an onion on it.
What is it, boy?
We're going home now, yes! Come!
It stinks! - It's supposed to stink
so it can help. Let me through.
Yes, sweetie! Now you get yum-yum.
Come on! Let me through.
Come on! Let me through. Come! Yes!
Yes, now it's time!
You're playing badminton!
Nowwatch out! Watch out!
Paul!
Let's do the tree.
Okay.
Watch it, Schumann!
- Schumann, get away.
I'm going shopping. Be right back.
- Okay. Schumann, no!
This one?
- No, not tha one. That one.
And do the small one, too.
- Okay.
Fire it up!
- You know. It's not so simple. Say...
I'll be right back.
- Hey!
Dad?
No, everything's fine.
She went into town.
He's okay.
Mom's gotten to like him.
Like him a lot, actually.
A lot! Hello?
Yes, I'll tell her.
Yes, it's nice here, too.
See you! Yes, bye.
Yes, bye.
Paul?
Are you alright?
Aren't you supposed to use iodine?
- Alcohol is better.
Oh, man!
Careful!
Jesus Maria!
What have you done? Are you crazy?
What?
- Where's Paul?
What's going on?
- I hurt myself.
Why didn't you call me?
- We were fine.
Robert, get me the washing soap!
You didn't bring me any chewing gum?
- Sorry, I forgot.
I met Professor Kubler.
You'll be third.
This is terrible.
Look at that! Wha did you two do?
Anna?
- Yes?
You have sweat on your lip.
Gone.
Paul, don't forget
to write down your hours for the pool.
The paints are in my car.
Washing soap!
You have to pick up
the boss's wife at the brothel. Drive!
Man, why won't it go straight?
- You have to drive in the middle.
Oops, I ran someone over.
- Doesn't matter.
What're you doing?
- Man, Mom! Now I'm dead.
You have one more.
I thought we could wach a movie.
I'm explaining him the game, but...
- Do I go left or right here?
Um... Left and then right again.
Do you want to play?
- No, you go ahead.
Right here or the next one?
Straight ahead.
Thank you, good-bye!
Yes, sweetie!
How are they?
Oh, wonderful colors!
Very nice.
I hope they're enough.
We have mortar and glue.
You can plan your own time.
The sound needs time to develop.
Accelerando does mean get faster,
but not take off like a greyhound.
You always exaggerate.
I've told you a million times. Stand up.
That's lame.
Lame?
Paul? Paul, come here. Come here.
Robert will play you something
two different ways
and you say
which version you like better, yes?
First yours, then mine, okay?
They both sounded good.
- And...
what makes the two versions
different in your opinion?
The first one had more power.
The second was...
somehow...
Don't be shy. Just your feeling.
Which did you like better?
Maybe the first. But I don't
know how it's supposed to go.
Forget him. There's no point.
- It's only a game. Keep playing!
If I have to choose, the second.
Bullshit!
Something to drink?
Yes, please.
Come in.
- Coming.
Smell.
Good.
Didn't you put sugar in it?
- No, no. No sugar.
So...
- Thank you.
Sorry...
Cheers!
Good.
- You have...
You, too.
- Yes?
Gone?
You want some? It's delicious!
- I can't drink milk.
Lactose intolerant.
What do you think
about sleeping out tonight?
Us three?
- No! Us two.
At the pond.
Yes, you should, while the weather...
I'm happy to have
you two out of my hair.
But you have to be here
at 9 tomorrow like we agreed.
Yes. Sure.
Wha's happening at 9?
- Dress rehearsal for the audition.
No thanks.
You're going to have
a big alcoholic's nose.
And you'll die of lung cancer.
Unless you kill yourself first.
How did he do it?
Who?
- Who do you think?
What did they tell you?
They only said that...
tha Frank killed himself
'cause he had problems.
Aha.
And?
I think I'd rather sleep at home.
What are you doing? - I don't
feel like answering stupid questions.
Okay, Paul.
I promise, no more questions.
Promise!
Cross my heart.
He hanged himself.
In the garage.
Damn.
For real, with a noose?
No questions!
- Sorry.
With a cable.
From the ceiling lights.
I found him there.
Do you know what that looks like?
What it looks like...
His face all blue!
His tongue hanging out!
His pants all stained!
You know howthat looks?
He was so ugly!
Yeah, I mean...
Why did he do it?
Why did he...
I don't know! I don't know!
Let's call him!
Let's call him and ask.
"Hello, Frank!"
Hello, Frank,
why did you kill yourself?
Why did you kill yourself
and not leave us a note?
Maybe he'll tell us.
It's okay.
Forgive me. I'm sorry.
Hey!
Ow! Watch out! My bandage!
Watch out!
Something wrong?
No, why?
Are you crazy?
- What?
The water!
Shit!
Give me tha.
What time is it?
Quarter to ten.
Wasn't dress rehearsal at nine?
So what?
Morning.
- Morning.
C'mon, table tennis!
Okay.
Man!
Well?
- No dinner today.
Why?
- Just take what you want.
Salami?
- No thanks.
Paul, how are you getting on?
- Bit by bit.
Where's the frozen pizza?
- When it's finished, it's finished.
Do you have enough tiles?
Yes.
Who do we have here?
Good boy. Time for a walk!
Can I come with you?
Look wha yummy stuff you get!
You like that, don't you?
To Schumann!
To Paul!
To...
To the audition.
The Berg sonata. Robert,
it's turned out really well.
Don't forget you have to drive me.
Paul, could you do us a favor
and look after Schumann?
Robert!
Good luck!
Yes, hello?
Yes, going fine.
How's Madrid?
No they're out.
No idea. They didn't say.
She left it here, yes.
I will. Bye.
Schumann!
Shit!
Hello.
- Hello. Where is my dog?
He was here.
There's my good boy!
Hello!
Where's Robert?
- No idea. He sent me away.
He didn't want me to come in.
Let's change that.
Almost there.
So.
Robert behaved so badly,
you can't imagine.
Hold this?
He's so aggressive sometimes.
Hold it.
I don't know where he gets it.
He is at a difficult age.
And his father's never there
when he needs him.
Yes...
- Hold this?
Yes, it's hard.
I'm so sorry, Paul.
I think...
It's great how strong you're being.
Why?
You're so brave.
But you don't always have to be.
No one's asking you to.
Don't get it dirty.
I won't.
Howwas your audition?
Good.
Successful?
Of course. What do you think?
Where's Anna?
Don't know. You should know.
She went to pick you up.
I don't know either.
Weird. I'm in my room.
I looked everywhere for you!
I'm talking to you!
Let me check on your breath!
How stupid do you think I am?
Did you think I wouldn't notice?
Darling, I'm sorry!
I'm sorry! Put cold
water on it. Robert, I'm sorry.
Did your mother call?
No.
I put some chicken in the oven.
- Anna...
Come here.
Shit.
Yeah, yeah.
Here.
You don't want it?
Come here. Come. Come here.
Come, come, come.
Is Robert sleeping?
I think so.
- You should go to bed, too.
Where were you?
You smoke too much.
Occupied!
I'll call you laer. Bye-bye.
Does it hurt a lot?
Yes.
I'm so sorry.
But I don't understand why
you drink alcohol before the audition.
No?
Explain it to me.
Mom, take care of Paul
and leave me alone.
Hey!
- Stefan! You're already here?
I thought you were coming tomorrow!
How long has it been
since I saw you at the piano?
She was a real talent.
- Long time ago.
Anna, are you going to tell him?
Tell him what?
Wha do you have to tell me?
Oh, that! We've had so much fun!
I knew you would.
Paul is totally uncomplicaed,
not like your son, the diva.
Anna...
And he's very skillful...
in the pool. - What's that?
Nothing. - Chic bandage.
- Anna did itfor me.
Aha! Playing doctor! I see!
We like those games!
I leave for a couple of days and...
Where is Robert?
I don't knowwhat's wrong with him.
He is out of control.
Played the audition stinking drunk.
Of course he didn't get in.
Tha can't be true!
- It is! But I thought of something.
I spoke with Mom
and she said I was right. It...
The piano has to go.
How is it on the front?
Front? What front?
I don't know.
Bad weather front,
battlefront, marriage front...
How is your hand?
Stupid thing to happen.
In the US, you could sue your mother
and you'd be pretty sure to win.
Wouldn't I need witnesses?
- Yes, probably.
I didn't see anything.
Then case closed. There is no case.
If you say so.
What are you doing here?
That doesn't look good.
Good night.
Are you mental?
Could be...
Have you been drinking again?
Was it fun?
What?
You know what I mean.
Shit!
I saw you.
What?
- I did!
Don't yell!
You fucking asshole!
Shit.
I love her.
- Wha? You gotta be crazy.
I do. And she loves me.
- She loves you?
Don't make me laugh.
Careful, it can get infected.
Here.
No wholegrain left.
Robert,
some cheese?
You?
- No, thanks.
Paul, don't you want any breakfast?
Let him be.
Listen, Robert.
Your mother and I spoke about
your stunt in the conservatory.
You must understand
that it's not fair to her.
You know how much she invested in you.
- That's not the point.
What's not the point?
That stupid audition.
You see?
That's the totally wrong attitude.
It wasn't a "stupid audition."
It would have been
an important step forward for you.
You lost a huge chance.
Some never get that chance
even though they're talented.
I hope you understand.
Anna's reputaion at the conservatory!
This will spread like wildfire.
I honestly thought tha you
were more mature and responsible.
Why won't you tell me
what happened here when I was away?
Well...
Anna and Paul...
Anna got on my nerves. That's all.
He's not hungry.
Alright.
Never mind.
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
Robert!
Wow, great! It looks really great!
If you fill it tonight,
we can all swim tomorrow
and christen it.
Stefan and I are going into town.
Food's in the fridge.
I think Robert will be back soon.
Have a nice evening.
Do me a favor and take
Schumann for a walk? - Yes.
Anna!
Be right there!
Tell me what I should do.
I was just swimming.
Congratulations.
Now you have your fucking pool again.
Then Anna will be happy.
Come on.
I gotta go.
Bye, Robert.
Bye?
I'm outta here. My train's
in a half an hour. - So soon?
Lie on the bed, it's more comfortable.
I prefer to sleep on the floor.
Paul?