["Nocturne op.9 n°2"
by Florence Robineau]
♪
[alarm ringing]
[alarm rings continuously,
music cuts out]
[alarm stops]
[clock thudding]
[sighs]
[low, unsettling music]
[birds chirping]
[heels clacking]
♪
[Mr. Brown]
Martha, you're late again.
Hurry up.
[dramatic thud]
[eerie music building]
[music fades out]
[pen scratching]
[footsteps approaching]
[Mr. Brown]
This is for the 2:00 PM meeting.
Don't be late.
Um, I actually haven't
seen my son since days,
and I want to go home.
[Mr. Brown] Enough.
We can't afford any more delays.
Do you understand, Martha?
Okay, Mr. Brown.
[footsteps leaving]
Great.
[telephone ringing]
SCO, Finance and Consulting,
Martha O'Hare.
How can I help you?
Hey, sweetie.
How are you doing?
Been a while since I saw you
and I was wondering
if you might come over tonight.
[Martha chuckles]
Oh, sweetheart,
you know that Mr. Brown
doesn't like
when you call the office number.
Mr. Brown can go fu...
Love himself.
- Oh!
- Your mobile is off
- and we miss you so much.
- [Yanush] Mommy, Mommy!
- I want to talk to Mommy.
- I bought some liver and wine
for a romantic
candlelight dinner.
Doesn't that sound
better than office work?
Ooh, liver and wine.
You know what I like.
[clicks tongue]
[giggling]
- [Yanush] Mommy! Mommy!
- Yeah, wait.
I'm passing you over
to our little beast.
- Oh!
- Talk to you later, love.
[Martha chuckles]
Bye. Bye. [kisses]
Mama, I miss you so much.
Can you bring me to bed today?
Oh, pumpkin Yanush.
I'll see what I can do, okay?
Mama, you have to promise,
Mommy.
Mommy?
Okay.
I promise.
Say, "It's a promise.
A big, fat promise."
Okay, this is a promise.
A big, fat promise.
I have heard that.
I love you, Mama.
- Cheers.
- Bye.
I love you, too.
[muttering indistinctly]
[sighing]
[soft, ambient music]
[keys jangling]
[eerie chord]
[sinister giggling]
[gravel crunching]
[upbeat rock music
playing on radio]
[sinister music]
[Martha gasping]
[dog barks]
[crickets chirping]
[dog barks in distance]
[Martha gasps]
[dog barking]
[Caleb sniffing]
[Caleb growls]
Sweet smell of fear.
[dog barking]
Calm down. Good boy.
You're a really good boy.
[whistles]
Oh, my God. Mister?
Thanks, God. Mister?
Hi. My name is Martha O'Hare.
I was on my way home.
Mister?
[eerie music]
[Martha screams]
[rats squeaking]
[Martha inhales deeply]
[bricks clattering]
Father.
Did you hear the bricks?
No.
No. She's asleep still.
[Kain laughs]
[rat squeaks]
[Martha gasps]
[chuckles softly]
[soft, mysterious music]
[brick slides, clatters]
Caleb, my son,
did you wet thine hatchet?
Your tools are your sustenance.
Without your tools,
you cannot hunt.
You cannot eat.
You cannot create
and you cannot survive.
Oh, father!
But Caleb loves food.
[hatchet thuds]
Then wet thine hatchet!
[inhales deeply]
[bricks sliding]
[metal scratching]
Father, look.
Well done, Caleb. Well done.
[rat squeaking]
[unsettling music]
[clanging]
[clicking tongue]
[door opens, Kain clicks tongue]
[dog barking]
[solemn piano music]
[chuckles]
[debris crumbling]
Fuck!
[groans in pain]
[screams]
[dramatic music]
Father! Father,
she's trying to flee, Father.
A strong will to survive.
[screaming]
Seize her.
[whimpering]
[bricks clattering]
[screaming]
[Martha gasping and screaming]
Can I?
No, no, the moon has not yet
reached its zenith.
It's 12:00, son.
Let our guest join us and share
with us good wine and liver.
What says thee?
- Bindeth her to the chair.
- Oh, okay.
[Martha crying]
Thou says liver.
- May I partake some liver?
- [Kain] Certainly.
And bring me some wine, my son.
What strange [indistinct]
does thee wear?
Thou art not from here?
Tell me, woman.
[breathing heavily]
Where cometh you?
Uh, I'm from Dark Lake, sir.
Dark Lake?
I know not of such a place.
[cutlery clatters]
I... I think
it's not far from you.
I wasn't passed out
for too long.
I don't know how I came here,
but, sir...
I just want to go home.
Can you please let me go home?
Thou wanteth some liver?
[shrieks]
This liver
of Mr. Jenkins.
The swineherd.
He was known
for his pork liver with onions.
Friendly man.
[chuckles]
[sinister chord]
How impolite.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm Kain, the butcher.
And this is Caleb Shamen,
my young son.
Please excuse his behaviour.
His brain was seriously damaged
20 years ago
during the big famine.
Twenty years?
[gasps]
Big famine?
What year is now?
[Kain] Her head must be
seriously injured.
Poor little thing.
Reminds me of Snowflake somehow.
Snowflake was our little lamb.
A wolf once came in the yard
and had Snowflake's
neck in his jaws.
I went out with the musket
and dropped the wolf
but it was too late.
Snowflake was injured.
Blood was pouring out
of his neck.
He lay on the ground
in his own blood,
twitching and yelling,
as if yelling
could save its life.
It is the 13th day
of October, 1866.
And the day of oblation.
[clapping]
1866?
The day of oblation? Sure.
What does that mean?
Mister, I'm sure
you're good guys
and you understand
that I just want to go home.
Can you please let me go home?
[sniffles
I send you $10,000 immediately.
Do you have PayPal?
You don't look like
you have $10,000, ma'am.
And what is this Paypal?
Anyway, we are not thieves.
We don't need your money.
But we could use some money,
Father, couldn't we?
Shut up, Caleb.
What do you think
we are doing here?
I have never stolen, never.
Son, keep in mind.
Hunting in order to survive
is something every animal does.
The lion, the wolf,
even the frog.
But stealing is man-made.
Man-made like money itself
in order to enslave nature
and subjugate all beings.
We don't steal, son.
Keep that always in mind.
We hunt. We eat.
We survive.
[cellphone ringing]
[chuckling awkwardly]
[suspenseful music]
What is that?
Where does it come from?
Caleb, calm down.
Calm down and take the hatchet.
[breathing shakily]
[Kain screams]
♪
[distorted yelling]
[Martha yelps]
[Caleb grunting]
[shutter clicking]
I dare you, motherfuckers.
I double dare you.
Father, have you seen?
She's made lightening strike.
Father, she's be the witch.
Good God! Good God!
I've got your soul in this.
And if you dare to don't
get out of my way,
I swear,
I'm going to fucking kill you.
We doth be in this box, Father.
- She's put us into this box.
- Caleb, calm down, my son.
I have no fear
of your witchcraft.
If my time has come,
I will die as it is written.
[Kain breathing heavily]
[suspenseful music]
[fire crackling]
Caleb, son,
if she doth tell the truth,
why beeth she still here?
Caleb Shamen,
have no belief in this woman.
She does lie.
Taketh her.
[Caleb screaming]
[Martha screaming
and whimpering]
[both screaming]
[Caleb chuckling]
[Martha whimpering]
[ominous drumming music playing]
♪ Hail to nature
and all its creatures ♪
[Martha crying]
♪ Thank you, dear Mother Nature,
for feeding us ♪
♪ With the beautiful
fruits you give ♪
♪
No. [crying]
No, please.
See her stretch marks.
She beeth a mother.
[Martha squealing]
Cry not, mother,
we'll beeth your child.
[cellphone ringing]
[crying]
Thou art here and not with him.
Oh, mother!
I lost my wife
and my other son
to the hunger death.
Her name was Karen,
and she was proud
and her skin
was white like milk.
I thought to nourish them
with my own flesh.
But 20 years. I saved him.
[crying]
Their flesh gave us the strength
to survive the famine.
In remembrance of that,
your body...
will be our present
to the mother of mothers.
The kindest
and the cruellest,
Mother Nature.
[ominous drumming music playing]
♪ Dear Mother Nature,
mother of all ♪
♪ Take this woman's blood
as our gift ♪
♪ Excuse our weakness
and forgive our souls ♪
♪ We bow to your wide power ♪
[Martha screaming]
[gurgling]
[groaning]
[crying]
[screaming]
[suspenseful music]
[eerie chord]
[Kain and Caleb yelping]
[clapping]
[whistling]
Bring the hatchet.
Ah!
Knife, fork, scissor, flames
have no place
in children's games.
[Caleb groans]
[Pink Rabbit exclaiming]
Go forth, Devil.
We must [indistinct].
I shan't let you conquer me.
[Pink Rabbit] Devil!
[cackling]
Devil! I am the devil
in a pink jumpsuit.
I am the devil,
coming for you.
[exclaiming]
No, no, no. Didn't you see
what happened to Caleb?
[hissing]
[hatchet clattering]
[Rabbit growling]
Can I borrow this?
[Kain groaning]
Psycho!
Kicks himself in the face.
Gorgeous.
Martha!
It's me, I'm your joker.
[Martha muttering faintly]
[growling]
The smart phone thing wasn't bad,
but you have to try a little
bit harder to come home.
[eerie electronic music]
I am giving you
this special extra life
because you went away
off the rules.
And I am no unfair player.
And no cheater. No.
That's not me.
I am a fair player.
Rule number one.
[bell ringing]
Put trust in the strength
of your mind.
Your will
and the power of your thoughts
will bring you further.
[snickering]
I won! I won! Yeah!
[blabbering]
Back to you, Martha.
[snickering,
then chuckling goofily]
Oh, let me help you with that.
[giggling]
Better! Better!
Rule number two.
[bell ringing]
Each level is over
when every enemy is dead.
Finito!
Muerto! Tot!
[making choking sound]
Totally gone!
Got it?
What? Kill them?
I can sneak out.
They're knocked out already.
Why should I kill them?
[growling]
[screaming] Why? Why? Why?
Do you think I make the rules?
It is the way it is.
The rules are the rules.
Don't ask stupid questions.
Okay, and rule number three?
And rule number three.
[bell ringing]
[clicking tongue]
Never.
Never ever say my name.
[giggling]
So late already.
Tick-tock, tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick-tock.
Good luck, have fun.
I'm out.
Great.
[door thudding]
[breathes deeply]
[dramatic music]
[Martha gasps]
[bell ringing]
[Caleb screaming]
[Martha groans]
[Martha screaming]
Ah! [coughing]
- [Caleb speaking indistinctly]
- [Kain groaning]
[Caleb] My father
is [indistinct].
[Caleb continues speaking
indistinctly]
[crying]
[slicing, blood splattering]
[bell ringing,
audience cheering]
[footsteps approaching]
I hope you go to hell,
motherfuckers.
[Martha yelps]
[giggling]
[evil laughter]
[Martha gasps]
[snickering]
[eerie music]
[giggling]
[Martha screaming]
[Yanush giggling]
[Yanush] Mommy!
[mobile playing lullaby]
[deep voice] Mommy!
[Martha panting]
[gasps]
[evil laughter]
[monkey chattering, cat meowing]
[mysterious music]
[purring]
Humph.
[cat meowing]
Is that your ball?
[laughs]
You're a really good boy.
You know what?
My son would love you.
From the fair.
[kissing]
[Yanush] Mommy? Mommy, I'm here.
Mommy? I'm here.
Mommy?
Pumpkin?
[Yanush] Mommy?
[giggles]
Pumpkin Yanush!
[Yanush]
Mommy, get me out of here.
- [horn honking]
- Ah!
[screaming]
[car crashing, glass shattering]
[panting]
A bad conscience
is worse than any curse, right?
Come over, Martha.
Take a seat.
[mysterious music]
[breathes deeply]
Ma'am.
Please.
I just want to go home.
Choose one.
Ma'am.
I just want to go to my son.
[laughing]
Go home to your son? Martha!
Oh!
You are serious, right?
Sure I am.
I just killed two guys
trying to win this game.
And you...
Please, ma'am.
Please.
Let me go home.
No.
I am so sorry, Martha.
I am just a token in this game.
Same as you are.
Same as we are all.
[cat meowing]
[purring]
Not my game,
not my rules.
But if you let me,
I'll help you a bit.
Do you know...
where your son is?
He's waiting in his bed at home.
[scoffs]
At home?
Martha, you can't follow, right?
Look inside the ball.
Okay, you know what?
I'm leaving.
Look inside the ball!
[sighs]
[cellphone ringing,
Yanush humming]
[babbling]
[horn honking]
[Martha screams]
[car crashing, glass shattering]
[cellphone ringing]
No.
This ain't true.
What are you trying to suggest?
To identify the truth,
inner place,
where there is no reality
to prove.
It's impossible.
I don't know what you
and the Pink Rab...
[dramatic music]
And the pink fucker in the suit
are trying to tell me,
but my son is at home.
I've just talked to him.
He's waiting.
In his bed.
Hell is an empty place.
But future is in your hands.
If you want,
you can win.
I don't want to play games.
I'm leaving.
I don't want to play your games.
Fuck!
Where is the door?
Where is the door?!
"Put trust in the power
of your mind."
Oh!
[Martha] Ah!
Power of mind
can't remove walls.
[wincing]
[Martha crying]
Martha, listen.
There is no way out of here.
Except of death.
Why me?
Why me?!
Because you have a reason.
[Yanush] Mommy!
- Mommy!
- [Martha screams]
Mommy, come home. I'm waiting.
- [Martha screaming]
- Mommy!
Mommy!
- [voice distorting] Mommy!
- Stop that.
- Mommy, I'm waiting.
- Stop it!
Mommy!
I'm waiting!
[distorted screaming]
[Martha shrieking]
Okay.
What the f...
You have to win
against yourself.
Your inner obstacles,
your fears,
your anger,
and your guilt.
[gasps, Martha yelps]
[grunts]
Take this.
Yeah, goal!
[groaning]
You're weak.
'Cause you're insecure.
[whimpered groaning]
Martha!
You have to listen
to your heart.
No.
[grunting]
[laughing]
[Yanush] Mommy? Mommy, please.
Mommy! Mommy, I love you.
Please don't give up.
I miss you so much.
Fight, okay?
[laughing]
[Yanush] I miss you, Mommy.
Mommy!
- Mommy!
- Pssh... Baby!
Don't worry.
Mommy won't let you down.
I am coming home.
Rule number two:
put trust in the strength
of your mind.
[groaning]
What?
And now fuck you, asshole.
No, wait.
You're supposed to be dead.
[yelling]
No. Ah!
Go to hell!
Beware...
of the deadly...
clause.
[distorted moaning]
[grunts]
She's dead. Come on.
Where is the confetti?
Let me go home.
[robotic voice] Rule number two.
Each level is over
when all your enemies are dead.
Who's there?
Pink Rabbi...
You almost got me.
Rule number three.
Pink jumpsuit asshole?
[robotic voice]
Rabbit! Ha! Rabbit.
You should have paid more
attention in biology class.
There are unmistakable
differences
between cats and rabbits.
Look at my wonderful paws
and my lovely face.
Nothing like those
overbite bitches,
- ugly carrot-munchers.
- [scoffing]
[giggling]
A talking cat!
[chuckling]
Let me introduce myself.
I'm Mr. Denise,
the Puppet Player.
[scoffs]
I'm supposed to kill
a talking cat?
[giggling]
[gasps]
Who wrote that shit?
[scratches, Martha winces]
[sighs in pain]
Do you still think
this is a ridiculous challenge?
Ah!
[hissing]
[Martha groaning]
[cats meowing]
[gasps]
[meowing continues]
[chuckles softly]
Mits, mits, mits,
mits, mits, mits, mits.
Put, put. [clicks tongue]
- Put, put, put, put, put, put.
- [cat snarls]
Mits, mits, mits,
mits, mits, mits, mits.
Put, put, put,
put, put, put, put.
[cat hissing, Martha chuckling]
[cat purring]
Got you, motherfucker.
[cat meowing]
[groaning]
[cats meowing]
[meowing]
In another world,
we could have been friends.
[cat screams]
[bell ringing,
audience cheering]
[birds chirping]
[Martha gasps]
[laughing]
Hey, folks, I'm happy you
appeared in such large numbers.
I hope you enjoy the show.
[coughing]
What a sorrow in my head,
a little rabbit's head.
I'm dead.
A lot of blood on this dress,
in my pants and on the grass.
Oh, what a mess!
I can't believe.
Stop the rabbit.
He's a thief.
He took my life
just for his joy.
And gave it all his little boy.
[Yanush laughing]
[Martha and Yanush giggling]
[Yanush] I'm back.
Yeah.
Wonderful! How wonderful!
[giggling]
[Martha] Go away,
let me alone with my son.
With son?
[screams]
Where is he?
[giggling]
[Martha shouting]
[Pink Rabbit grunting]
Oh, Martha!
What a violent behaviour
in front of your son.
[giggling]
Yanush!
[giggles] It's me.
[grunting]
Martha, what are you doing
with Mr. Zeit?
Oh!
Martha, you killed Mr. Zeit.
You killed Mr. Zeit.
Tick-tock, tick-tock, tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick-tock.
Tick.
Tock.
[water splattering]
[tense percussive music]
[guns cocking]
Hands up.
Don't move or we shoot.
Turn around
and get on your knees.
[rock music playing
on headphones]
[banging on table]
[music stops]
Hey, Mr. Fox.
I dare you, boy.
I double dare you.
[door opens]
[door shuts]
Hello.
My name is Officer Fox.
Miss...
O'Hare.
You know why you're here?
[Martha] To be honest,
fuck no.
I have no idea.
When I was on my way home,
then I got stopped
by that Pink Rab...
The guy wearing a pink
jumpsuit and a rabbit beanie.
A pink jumpsuit
and a rabbit beanie.
Well...
do you mean this beanie?
Yes, exactly.
So you believe me?
Did you get him?
Did we get him?
Well, miss,
O-H-A-R-E.
[footsteps approaching]
[Officer Fox exhaling,
Martha coughing]
[sinister music]
Wait.
Let me help you with this.
Thank you, Officer.
I don't know
what's going on here,
but believe me,
I had a very shitty night,
and I just want
to go home to my son.
How old is your son, Martha?
He's four.
I know all that sounds crazy,
and maybe it's just a prank
by this pink one-suit guy.
He's somehow...
managed to put me
into all these quests.
Anyway, I'm sure you guys
will figure out what happened.
Can I go now?
Take a seat, Martha.
I'm not sure what you're up to,
but don't even dare
to play games.
Officer,
let me go home.
My son is waiting.
Your son is dead, Martha,
and you know that.
No.
You're wrong.
I've just talked to him.
Come on, Officer.
There must be a mistake.
Martha.
Your son is dead.
He got hit by this woman.
She was hunting around
for a mobile phone
on the car floor while driving,
instead of looking at the road.
Her name was Miss Brown.
No.
No, no, no.
Mr. Brown is my boss.
And my son is alive.
I've just talked to him.
Just before I met the Pink Rab...
The guy wearing
a pink rabbit beanie.
I know there are a lot of people
named Brown in this world.
It must be hard for you
seeing this name every day.
But nevertheless,
your son is dead, Martha.
You're divorced, living in
a one flat room in Dark Lake.
And that night after,
you killed four people.
Four people and a black cat.
[laughing]
I killed four people?
Stop playing.
Stop playing, Martha.
I know you're trying to play
the legal insane card,
but it won't work with me.
You killed four people, not to
speak of the poor little cat.
This little black kitty
looked like Mr. Jenkins.
Mr. Jenkins.
[Martha] Mr. Jenkins?
Mr. Jenkins was the name
of the swineherd
Caleb and Kain killed.
Caleb and Kain?
And a swineherd
called Mr. Jenkins?
Are you kidding me?
Yes. They ate his liver.
Do you mean these two guys?
Yes.
They are cannibals.
Caleb and Kain.
They pretended to live in 1866.
They tried to eat me.
I didn't want to kill them.
It was not my fault.
The rabbit guy made me do it.
He said,
it's the only way out.
Cannibals? The rabbit?
Come on.
Kain was a hardworking farmer.
Everybody in this area
knew them.
They were good guys.
His son is...
How do you say it?
Mentally challenged.
[Martha] Yes, because
of the great famine.
What famine?
That's why Kain
had a wooden leg.
He fed it to Caleb
and his younger son,
and his wife, Karen,
to try to save them.
But he couldn't.
After they died, they ate them.
What the...
His wife and younger son died
in a fire a couple of years ago.
He lost his leg and Caleb
had a rare genetic defect,
and there were all alternative
weekend farmers.
Look at them.
Look what you did.
No.
It was the rabbit guy.
The guy with the pink beanie.
Oh, the pink beanie.
[door opens]
[cart rolling]
[door shuts]
This is Madam Martita.
She's travelling around
with the Boston fair.
Now, watch what happens to her.
[Madam Martita screaming]
[Martha] Get that. Get down.
Where's my son? Where is he?
Where's my son?
[Madam Martita screaming,
gunshot firing]
[Martha exhaling]
The pink rabbit guy pretty
much looks like you, Martha.
What do you think?
Officer.
I know that sounds weird,
but something wrong
is going on here.
I've had a fight with
two cannibal trying to eat me.
I've confronted
the fortune teller
with telekinetic powers,
and a huge mutant brain
under her head scarf
owned by a black cat,
both trying to kill me.
And then,
there was this old dude
under the pergola.
Is he dead?
The janitor of the Fourth Street
Elementary School, Mr. Zeit?
He was such a good guy.
Oh, my God, Officer.
I...
I thought he made
my son disappear.
This crazy one-piece guy
is playing an evil game.
He puts up all these
monsters against me.
They're all on his side.
Martha,
you a graduate of
the Boston School of Law,
and a lawyer at a big legal firm
and if we believe your
medical records,
you're suffering from nothing
than depression,
and you're taking nothing
but anti-depressants.
So, you're an average
American citizen.
Stop playing and confess.
[Martha] No, officer.
I swear, I am not a killer.
I see. This is going
to be a long night.
Todd? Todd? Todd!
I have to do everything
by my own.
[rock music playing
on headphones]
Just what you attention-craving
wannabe rock-stars
are getting paid to do?
Eating donuts and listening to
subversive punk rock bands,
dreaming of a radical new world,
while your dad to whom you have
a questionable relationship
forces you to join the enemy?
You should either
grow yourself a pair of balls
and tell your beloved daddy
that you hate this job
and the police and join
an un... underground movement
to play revolution with a couple
of reckless boys like yourself.
Or you should grow up and do
your job like a responsible men.
Fuck!
You wait.
[door closes]
As if I have another chance.
[rock music continues to play]
[suspenseful music]
No, Pumpkin Yanush.
I know you're waiting.
Waiting at home.
Waiting in your little bed.
Waiting for mommy
to come to tuck you in.
And give you a little kiss
onto your forehead.
So you can ease your pain,
and all the worries
in your head,
knowing
that you're safe.
Knowing that mommy is around,
and you are not alone.
I'll be around, my love.
I will be there.
[cellphone ringing,
Yanush humming]
[babbling]
[horn honking]
[Martha screaming]
[car crashing, glass shattering]
[cellphone ringing]
No.
No, no.
I am not
going to lose my mind.
No.
[crying]
I am Martha O'Hare.
I am not a mass killer.
I am married to my best friend.
And my son is alive,
waiting at home,
because I promised
to be there on time.
And there is no way
I am going to disappoint him!
I am not
going to lose my mind.
I know
you are watching.
And this game is very hard.
But I ain't going
to lose my mind.
Listen, Rabbit.
I ain't going to lose my mind.
Wow, Martha, you gave
an amazing performance.
I'm sure
if this would be a movie,
the critics would acknowledge
this beautiful performance.
Heart-gripping.
But you know what?
This is no movie,
and I'm not a goddamn
national brown-nosed critic.
I don't buy it.
[Martha laughs dryly]
I knew it. [chuckling]
What?
I knew.
I am not insane.
So, you will confess?
Confess?
Confess what,
Officer... Fox?
Or should I say,
quest number three?
Stop acting.
[Pink Rabbit laughing]
What the fuck is he doing?
Oh, man. Is this even legal?
What will we tell
Internal Affairs?
It's your first day, right?
[chuckles]
Welcome to the sheep.
Let's get ready to rumble
with the wolves.
Oh, look.
The sleepy heads from booking
forgot to note your broken nose.
But my nose is o...
[Martha screams]
[crying]
[water splattering]
[Pink Rabbit shrieks]
[Martha sobbing]
- [Martha whimpers]
- What?
He is here.
What is?
Behind you.
Under the desk.
[chuckling]
Oh, you think that is funny?
No, no. No.
Ouch!
That was bad.
[Martha crying]
Look, you ruined
this beautiful table.
[snoring]
Oh, fine.
Show me your nose.
[grimacing]
That looks bad.
The officer's senseless
police brutality.
You know what?
You should kill that pig.
Remember rule number two.
[exclaiming]
Rule number two.
[bell ringing]
Each level is over
when every enemy is dead.
Finito.
Muerto! Tot!
[choking sound]
Totally gone.
Got it?
Kill him?
With what should I kill him?
With my bare hands?
[laughing]
[door opens]
Mr. Fox.
Is everything okay?
I'm trying to conduct
a serious interrogation
with a cold blooded mass killer.
How can you fucking dare
to interrupt me?
I... I couldn't see
the screen anymore,
so I thought...
I'm going to excuse
this behaviour because
this is your first week,
and I like your father.
He's indeed a fucking
awesome golfer.
But if you dare to enter this
room again without permission,
I swear I will fire your ass,
and you will never, ever
find a job as a cop again.
Do you fucking understand?
So, get the fuck out
and let me do my job.
Your tits.
A little tip, just because
I can't stand cops.
[laughing]
[dramatic music]
[coughing]
[laughing]
What the fuck is wrong with you?
What does a butcher
say to a pig?
What?
Nice to meat you.
Meat you!
[laughing]
[Martha grunting,
blood splattering]
[bell ringing,
audience cheering]
Ooh! Yay!
Slaughtering day. Oink-oink!
[suspenseful music]
[sighing]
[soft ambient music]
♪
Officer Todd,
one thing he said was right.
You should quit this job
and start something useful
with your life.
I don't know what,
but if I was in your age
and had the chance
to start something new,
I would choose this underground
revolution thing.
That sounds pretty dope. Cheers.
[crickets chirping]
[sighing]
[metal clanking]
[gasps, then laughs]
[laughing]
Shit, fucking bastard, cop.
Fucking asshole.
Fucking fucker rabbit.
Oh, no.
Pumpkin Yanush is waiting
and I want to go home
and this fucking
bastard cop has...
Shit, rabbit.
Fuck!
[sobbing]
What the fuck?
My car.
Martha, your son
is still waiting.
I'll drive you. Come in.
Good choice.
Fasten the seat belt, please.
We're ready for takeoff.
[car speeding]
[tires screeching]
Hey, your keys.
A small present
so that you don't forget me.
[chuckling]
It will bring you luck.
[both laughing]
I hope you go to hell.
Fuck you.
It's your choice, Martha.
[snickering]
Good luck.
[laughing] Have good luck.
[Martha chuckling]
Pumpkin!
[kisses]
I love you, Pumpkin.
I love you.
You know what?
I won't let you alone again.
I promise.
Yeah, I promise.
Pooh, you smell.
[Martha sniffing]
Ooh. Ugh, you're right.
I'll take a shower.
Over there.
You wait, okay?
Don't fall asleep.
[door shuts]
Do you want to read?
This here.
Oh.
[sinister music]
Where did you get that?
From papa?
Okay.
[Yanush] Read. Read.
"The Homecoming
of the Pink Rabbit."
[Martha gasping]
No! Pumpkin!
Pumpkin!
Oh. [screaming]
- You lose.
- Why?
And rule number three.
[bell ringing]
[clicking tongue]
Never!
Never, ever say my name.
[giggling]
[thudding]
[telephone ringing]
[ringing continues]
SCO, Finance and Consulting.
Martha O'Hare.
How can I help you?
[Martha's husband] Hey, sweetie.
How are you doing?
Been a while since I saw you,
and I was wondering if you
might come over tonight.
Wow.
Hey, um...
It was just a dream.
I'm coming, okay? Wait.
I'm coming home.
[sinister music]
[electronic beeping]
♪