( gunshots )
THIS IS WHERE I TOLD
DEPUTY JACKSON TO MEET US.
HEY, LOOK.
THERE'S A STRAY HORSE OVER THERE
WITH A SADDLE ON.
LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
FUZZY, TAKE A LOOK
DOWN THERE.
IS THAT HIM?
IT'S JACKSON, ALL RIGHT.
HE MUST HAVE KNOWN
HE WAS MEETING US
WITH THE INFORMATION.
THAT MAKES THE THIRD DEPUTY
IN A MONTH.
WELL, WE GOTTA
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
EVERYTHING
COME OFF
ALL RIGHT, JUDD?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU KNOW,
THAT DEPUTY--JACKSON.
YOU'RE NOT HERE
TO ASK QUESTIONS.
ALL RIGHT.
HEY, JUDD.
GRAYSON'S GOT YOUNG WALTERS
IN A GAME OVER THERE.
WELL, THAT WASHES ME UP.
WOULD YOU MIND
IF I SIT IN?
PLEASED TO HAVE YOU--
HOW ABOUT YOU, WALTERS?
SURE.
THANK YOU.
HEY, BEN,
DRINKS FOR
THE GENTLEMEN.
COMIN' RIGHT UP.
SHERIFF, DID YOU SEE
MY BROTHER AL?
I WOULDN'T SWEAR TO IT,
MISS WALTERS,
BUT I THINK HE'S OVER
IN THE SALOON.
I BEGGED HIM NOT TO
GO IN THERE.
I'LL HOLD.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, WALTERS?
FORTY BUCKS.
IT'LL COST YOU
TWENTY MORE.
THAT BEATS ME.
I'M RIDIN' RIGHT ALONG
WITH YOU.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
FULL HOUSE.
JUST A MINUTE.
FOUR DEUCES.
YOU COULDN'T HAVE
WHY NOT?
I DISCARDED ONE.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING--
YOU STAY OUT OF THIS!
IT'S CROOKED AND MAYBE
YOU'RE A CROOK, TOO.
KEEP TALKING LIKE THAT
AND YOU'LL BE SORRY.
YOU'RE BOTH CROOKS--
I'M GONNA CALL THE LAW ON YOU.
YOU ASKED FOR THIS.
AL!
HE'S DEAD.
YOU MURDERER.
IT WAS SELF-DEFENSE,
ASK ANYBODY.
IT WAS COLD-BLOODED MURDER,
JUST LIKE ALL
THE OTHER KILLINGS
AROUND HERE,
AND I'M GOING TO
DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
JUST WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GONNA DO ABOUT IT?
I'M GOING TO WRITE A LETTER
TO THE UNITED STATES MARSHAL.
I'LL TELL HIM WHAT'S HAPPENING
IN THIS TOWN,
AND I'LL NAME NAMES.
I WOULDN'T IF I WERE YOU,
AND I'D GET OUT OF TOWN
WHILE YOU'RE STILL HEALTHY.
IT'LL TAKE MORE THAN
YOUR THREATS TO MAKE ME
LEAVE TOWN, BILL JUDD.
YEAH? WE'LL SEE ABOUT THAT.
I DON'T MIND
A MAN-AGAINST-MAN FIGHT,
BUT A MAN-AGAINST-WOMAN FIGHT
CALLS FOR SOME INTERFERENCE.
THIS'LL TEACH YA
TO MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS!
NOW REACH!
LET'S KEEP THIS
A CLEAN FIGHT.
NOW, MISS, TELL ME
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
THAT MAN JUST
KILLED MY BROTHER.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE HERE?
ARREST THAT MAN, SHERIFF.
FOR WHAT?
FOR MURDER.
HE KILLED AL.
THE MAN WAS GOIN' FOR ME,
I SHOT IN SELF-DEFENSE.
IF IT WAS SELF-DEFENSE,
I'M NOT GONNA ARREST HIM.
A MAN'S GOT A RIGHT
TO DEFEND HIMSELF.
WHAT KIND OF A LAWMAN
ARE YOU?
HE SHOULD BE ARRESTED
AND HELD FOR TRIAL.
I DON'T MAKE ARRESTS
ON THE SAY-SO
OF ANY STRANGER
THAT RIDES INTO TOWN.
THEN WE'LL ROUND UP
SOME WITNESSES.
WHICH OF YOU SAW HIM
SHOOT DOWN THAT YOUNG MAN?
ALL DEAF, DUMB, BLIND.
WELL, THE BOYS
GAVE YOU THEIR ANSWER.
NOW GET.
I THINK I'LL STICK AROUND--
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG HERE.
COME ON, FUZZY,
LET'S HELP THE LADY
WITH HER BROTHER.
I JUST KILLED AL WALTERS.
GOOD, ANOTHER ONE
OUT OF THE WAY.
BUT THERE'S STILL TROUBLE.
WHAT KIND?
HIS SISTER--SAID SHE WAS
WRITING TO THE MARSHAL.
GET HER OUT OF
THIS TERRITORY.
ALL RIGHT, BOSS.
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE.
WHAT IS IT?
A STRANGER IN TOWN,
ASKING A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
WHO IS HE?
NOBODY KNOWS--HE WANTED
THE SHERIFF TO ARREST ME.
GET RID OF HIM, TOO.
BUT HOW?
YOU KNOW HOW.
YEAH, I KNOW--
AND HE'S GOT IT
COMING TO HIM.
HE WAS A WONDERFUL BROTHER.
A LITTLE WILD,
BUT GOOD.
HE NEVER HURT ANYBODY.
WHY DID THIS HAVE TO
HAPPEN TO US NOW,
JUST WHEN EVERYTHING
WAS BEGINNING TO WORK OUT.
WHY, UNCLE BOB?
I DON'T KNOW, BETTY.
WE JUST GOTTA MAKE
THE BEST OF THINGS
WITHOUT HIM.
COME ON, MISS BETTY.
OUR JOB IS TO SEE
THAT IT DOESN'T HAPPEN
TO ANY MORE FOLKS AROUND HERE.
THIS IS MIGHTY RICH COUNTRY.
HOW COME THERE
AREN'T MORE SETTLERS AROUND?
THERE WERE, LOTS OF THEM,
TILL BILL JUDD AND HIS GANG
SHOWED UP.
THIS GAMBLER, GRAYSON--
HOW LONG HAS HE BEEN IN TOWN?
OH, ABOUT TWO MONTHS.
WHAT NOBODY CAN FIGURE OUT
IS WHAT A SLICK GAMBLER WANTS
IN A SMALL PLACE LIKE THIS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO
NOW THAT YOU'RE ALL ALONE?
SHE WON'T BE ALONE--
I'M STAYIN' ON.
THANKS, UNCLE BOB.
WITH YOU AROUND,
I CAN STICK IT OUT.
I LIKE YOUR SPIRIT,
YOUNG LADY.
I'LL GO PUT UP
THE HORSES.
ALL RIGHT,
I'LL GET SUPPER TOGETHER.
I BET YOUR UNCLE'S
A BIG HELP TO YOU.
HE'S NOT REALLY MY UNCLE.
HE'S JUST AN OLD FRIEND
OF THE FAMILY'S.
HE WAS WIPED OUT IN THE DROUGHT
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO
AND CAME TO WORK FOR US.
HE'S A LITTLE TOUCHED
ON SOME SUBJECTS,
BUT HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
VERY LOYAL.
YOU'LL BE SHORTHANDED
WITHOUT YOUR BROTHER, WON'T YOU?
YES, I WILL.
WOULD IT HELP ANY
IF WE STAYED ON?
THAT WOULD BE WONDERFUL--
WOULD YOU?
WOULD YOU LIKE TO STAY PUT
FOR A FEW WEEKS, FUZZY?
FINE--WE CAN BOTH
USE A LITTLE REST.
YEP, IT WAS ME THAT
SETTLED THIS TERRITORY--
FIRST MAN IN THE VALLEY.
TOO BAD YOU LOST
YOUR HOMESTEAD, UNCLE BOB,
WHY DIDN'T YOU
START UP AGAIN?
A LOT OF RIFF-RAFF MOVED IN,
TOOK UP EVERYTHING.
SURE WAS A FINE MEAL,
MISS BETTY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I DON'T WANT ANY MORE COFFEE.
COME ON,
HAVE ANOTHER CUP.
IT KEEPS ME AWAKE.
YOU DON'T WANT TO
HURT BETTY'S FEELINGS, DO YOU?
( grumbling: )
ALL RIGHT.
SOON AS YOU'RE FINISHED,
I'LL SHOW YOU BOYS
WHERE TO BUNK.
IT'LL SURE BE FINE
TO STRETCH OUT
IN A NICE,
COMFORTABLE BUNK AGAIN.
AH, IF IT AIN'T ONE THING,
IT'S ANOTHER.
I'M GONNA GET ME
A NEW PARTNER, THAT'S ALL.
OKAY, SO LONG.
YOU TRYIN' TO
GET RID OF ME?
WELL, YOU'RE COMPLAINING ABOUT
THE LIFE YOU LEAD.
I DON'T SEE WHY WE
STAY OUT HERE ALL NIGHT
WHEN WE COULD HAVE SLEPT IN
A NICE, COMFORTABLE BUNK.
'CAUSE I GOT A HUNCH
SOMETHING'S GONNA HAPPEN.
YOU MEAN WE'RE GONNA
SIT HERE ALL DAY?
IF IT'S NECESSARY.
I CAN'T DO IT,
I'LL FALL ASLEEP.
NOT AFTER ALL THE COFFEE
YOU DRANK LAST NIGHT.
NO, THAT WORE OFF
HOURS AGO.
THERE'S THE RANCH.
WE'LL LEAVE OUR HORSES HERE
AND SNEAK UP ON FOOT.
JOE, YOU AND CROWDER
BRING THE STUFF WITH YOU.
WE GOT ENOUGH TO
BRING DOWN TEN RANCHES.
NOW, REMEMBER INSTRUCTIONS.
EACH OF YOU TAKE
ONE SIDE OF THE HOUSE.
I'LL COVER THE FRONT DOOR
SO I CAN PLUG THAT STRANGER
WHEN HE RUNS OUT.
WHY, THEM DIRTY RATS.
COME ON, WE'LL GIVE 'EM
A RECEPTION.
YOU READY?
LET 'EM COME.
( gunshot )
I WONDER WHAT'S HAPPENED?
HELLO, TOUGH GUY.
FIND BUNCH OF CUTTHROATS,
TRYING TO BURN DOWN
A GIRL'S RANCH.
YOU WON'T GET AWAY WITH THIS,
MY MEN WILL--
YOUR MEN ARE ALL ASLEEP,
JUDD, TAKE A LOOK.
WE JUST HEARD A SHOT--
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE?
THIS HOMBRE
AND HIS THREE PALS
WERE GOING TO BURN DOWN
YOUR RANCH, MISS BETTY.
NO!
THERE'S THE PROOF--
KEROSENE AND RAGS.
WE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
BURNED ALIVE,
IF IT HADN'T BEEN
FOR YOUR FORESIGHT.
WE DON'T KNOW
HOW TO THANK YOU, SON.
THAT'S NOT IMPORTANT.
WHY ARE THEY SO ANXIOUS
TO GET RID OF US?
I'LL HAVE THE ANSWER TO THAT
WHEN I FIND OUT WHO'S
GIVING THEM THEIR ORDERS.
JUDD'S NOT SMART ENOUGH
TO BE THE BIG BOSS.
WE'LL HOLD THEM HERE
UNTIL AFTER DARK,
AND THEN WE'LL
TAKE THEM INTO TOWN.
THAT WAY, IT WON'T ATTRACT
SO MUCH ATTENTION.
( knocking )
KINDA LATE, SHERIFF,
BUT I DON'T THINK YOU'LL MIND.
GOT A LITTLE BUSINESS FOR YOU.
WHAT'S THE MEANING OF THIS?
THESE TWO JUMPED US
AS WE WERE RIDING
PAST THE WALTER'S PLACE.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING THERE
WITH KEROSENE AND RAGS?
LOCK 'EM UP, SHERIFF,
UNTIL WE CAN ARRANGE A TRIAL.
BY WHAT AUTHORITY ARE YOU
TELLING ME WHAT TO DO?
THIS GUN--YOU WANT TO
ARGUE WITH ME?
WELL, SINCE YOU
PUT IT THAT WAY.
OPEN UP THAT CELL.
NOW, I EXPECT THESE MEN
TO BE HERE IN THE MORNING.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
JUST WHAT I SAID.
ARE YOU INSINUATING
I MIGHT BETRAY MY OFFICE?
THAT'S WHAT I'M INSINUATING.
YOU KNOW, THAT STAR
YOU WEAR ON YOUR VEST
IS REMOVABLE.
WHO'S GOING TO
REMOVE IT?
MAYBE THE PEOPLE
OF THIS COUNTY
WILL HAVE SOMETHING
TO SAY ABOUT THAT.
GOOD NIGHT, SHERIFF.
PLEASANT DREAMS.
THAT WAS A GOOD NIGHT'S WORK--
NOW WE CAN GET SOME SLEEP.
NOT SO FAST, FUZZ.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WE'VE STILL GOT WORK TO DO.
OH, CHEY, I--
COME ON.
WELL, THIS GIVES US
A GOOD VIEW.
GOOD VIEW OF WHAT?
THE STREET--
THE JAIL, IN PARTICULAR.
WE'LL JUST WAIT HERE
A WHILE.
WHAT FOR?
BECAUSE I DON'T TRUST
THAT SHERIFF,
AND I WANT TO BE AROUND
IF MY HUNCH IS RIGHT.
IF I'D A KNOWED THIS WAS
GONNA BE AN ALL-NIGHT PICNIC,
I'D A BROUGHT
MY BLANKET ROLL.
RELAX. WE MIGHT HAVE
A LONG WAIT.
WAIT?
NOTHIN' MORE CAN HAPPEN NOW--
AH-CHOO!
NOTHIN' MORE,
EXCEPT ME CATCHIN' A COLD.
SORRY, FUZZY,
BUT THERE ARE SOME THINGS
WE'VE GOT TO DO,
AND WATCHING THE JAIL
IS ONE OF THEM.
( mumbling )
WAKE UP, FUZZY,
IT'S DAYLIGHT.
OH--MY ACHING BACK.
ARE YOU SATISFIED?
NO, I'M NOT.
WE'LL WAIT A LITTLE LONGER.
DOGGONE IT, CHEY, WE COULDA HAD
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
HOLD IT--
TAKE A LOOK.
WHY, THAT DIRTY,
DOUBLE-DEALIN' SHERIFF,
LETTIN' THEM CROOKS
GET AWAY!
COME ON, CHEY,
LET'S GET 'EM!
WAIT.
THEY'LL GET AWAY!
THAT'S WHAT
I WANT 'EM TO DO.
COME ON,
WE'LL FOLLOW 'EM.
( knocks in code )
Boss:
GET IN HERE--
I GOT A FEW THINGS
TO SAY TO YOU FOOLS.
THIS IS WHAT
I FIGURED WE'D FIND.
LET'S LEAVE THE HORSES HERE
AND GET CLOSER.
BUT HOW WOULD WE KNOW
THEY'D BE LAYIN' FOR US?
I PAY YOU TO THINK
AS WELL AS SHOOT.
YOU KNEW THAT STRANGER
WAS AROUND,
YOU SHOULD HAVE BEEN
PREPARED FOR HIM.
WE GOT EVERYBODY OUT
BUT THE WALTERS GIRL
AND A COUPLE OF OTHERS,
AND I AIN'T GONNA
BE STOPPED NOW.
Let's jump 'em before
they can pull their guns.
Let's wait and see
if they mention Grayson.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
GET THAT MAN IN BLACK.
WHAT'S THE MATTER? SCARED?
I AIN'T SCARED, BUT HE'S
A SLIPPERY CUSTOMER.
NOW, DON'T GET ME WRONG--
I'M NOT BACKING OUT.
YOU BETTER NOT BACK OUT.
AH-AH--
( muffled sneeze )
You want to have
the whole bunch
out on us?
I can't help it--
got cold, stayin' up all night.
MY ORDERS TO YOU ARE TO
GET THE MAN IN BLACK,
HIS PARTNER,
AND THE WALTERS GIRL.
I WANT IT DONE
IN THE NEXT 24 HOURS.
RIGHT.
AH-CHOO!!
I THINK I KNOW
WHO THAT IS.
ALL RIGHT, BOYS.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN FIND
OVER THERE.
COME ON, BOYS.
( gunshot )
LET'S GET TO THE HORSES!
WE'LL HEAD AROUND
SUNSET ROCK.
WELL, LET'S DO SOMETHING--
IT'S GETTING WARM AROUND HERE.
WHEW! THAT WAS A CLOSE ONE.
YEAH, NOW WE CAN GO LOOK
THAT SHACK OVER WITHOUT
BEING DISTURBED.
MAYBE WE CAN
GRAB THE LEADER.
NO, HE'S TOO SMART
TO HANG AROUND THERE,
BUT I'M HOPING
HE LEFT SOME CLUES.
HEY, UH,
THERE'S UNCLE BOB.
SO IT IS.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
ALL OVER FOR YOU FELLAS.
I JUST BEEN TO TOWN,
AND THEY TELL ME
JUDD AND HIS GANG
BROKE OUT OF JAIL.
WE KNOW--WE'RE ON OUR WAY
TO TAKE A LOOK AT THEIR HIDEOUT.
THE FELLA THAT GIVES 'EM ORDERS
WAS THERE A COUPLE MINUTES AGO.
I'M GOIN' WITH YOU.
NO, GET BACK TO BETTY--
I DON'T WANT HER TO BE ALONE.
RIGHT.
I DON'T THINK
THERE'S ANYBODY HOME.
I'M NOT TAKING
ANY CHANCES.
LOOKS LIKE THE BIRD
FLEW THE COOP.
I DON'T THINK WE'LL
FIND ANYTHING HERE.
I'M NOT SO SURE--
DO YOU SEE WHAT I SEE?
THAT'S NOTHIN' BUT
A BUNCH OF OLD SPUR MARKS.
WHEN WE FIND THE MAN
WHOSE SPURS FIT THESE MARKS,
WE'VE GOT
THE LEADER OF THE GANG.
MAYBE YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING.
FIND ANYTHING
IN THAT SHACK?
NOT A THING.
THEN WE STILL DON'T KNOW
WHO'S GIVING JUDD HIS ORDERS.
I'VE BEEN THINKING,
AND I'VE GOT A SUSPICION.
WHAT IS IT?
GRAYSON--WHAT'S
THE ATTRACTION
IN BUFFALO GAP
FOR A BIG-TIME GAMBLER
LIKE HIM?
HE'S HERE
FOR SOME REASON.
MAYBE YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING.
I HEARD HE GOT TO TOWN
JUST ABOUT THE TIME
THIS DIRTY BUSINESS STARTED.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
UNCLE BOB?
WELL, IT COULD BE.
FUZZY, I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
IF IT'S GONNA
GET ME IN TROUBLE,
I DON'T WANT
NOTHIN' TO DO WITH IT.
YOU'RE GONNA DO
A LITTLE GAMBLING.
NO SIR--NOT ME.
COME ON,
QUIT STALLING.
DON'T RUSH ME--
I GOTTA THINK.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR YOUR PARTNER,
HE'S NOT COMING.
WHY NOT?
HE MET WITH A LITTLE ACCIDENT
JUST OUTSIDE OF TOWN.
LET'S PLAY CARDS.
I-I GOTTA HAVE
A DRINK FIRST.
HEY, BEN.
GIVE THIS OLD GEEZER
A DRINK.
OLD GEEZER?
I'LL HAVE YOU KNOW--
WHAT DO YOU
WANNA DRINK?
GIVE ME A DRINK OF WATER.
WATER?! WE AIN'T GOT ANY.
IF YOU'RE CALLIN' ME,
PUT IN YOUR CHIPS.
LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU GOT.
FULL HOUSE.
HA! NOW I'M GONNA
LOOK FOR MY PARTNER.
NOT SO FAST.
I'M TOPPING YOU.
HEY!
THAT'S THE SIXTH TIME
THIS HAS HAPPENED--
YOU'RE CHEATING!
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I SAID, YOU MUST BE CHEATING.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU ACCUSE PEOPLE.
WELL, I STILL MEAN IT.
PROVE IT OR FACE
THE CONSEQUENCES--
HE'S MY PAL.
MAYBE I CAN PROVE THEM, JUDD.
HEY, CHEY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEP. YOUR MEN NEED
SHOOTING LESSONS, CROWDER.
PUT UP YOUR HANDS, EVERYBODY.
JUDD, DROP YOUR GUN.
FIRST POKER DECK I EVER SAW
WITH ALL TOP CARDS.
YOU'RE PRETTY HANDY'
WITH THOSE CARDS, GRAYSON.
WHAT OF IT?
WHAT'S YOUR CUT
ON THIS RACKET?
ALL RIGHT,
YOU'LL TALK LATER.
I'M ARRESTING YOU
ONCE AGAIN, JUDD,
FOR TRYING TO BURN DOWN
THE WALTERS' RANCH.
YOU TOO, GRAYSON, FOR--
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO WITH ME?
YOU'LL FIND OUT--
GET ON YOUR FEET.
WHAT HAPPENED TO JUDD?
HE GOT OUT THE BACK DOOR--
SHOULD I GO AFTER HIM?
NEVER MIND,
WE'LL GET HIM LATER.
COME ON, GRAYSON.
( gunshot )
TAKE COVER, FUZZY!
WHERE'D IT COME FROM?
NEVER MIND THAT,
I WANT GRAYSON TO TALK
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
GRAYSON--
GET HIM INTO THE HOUSE.
I'LL GO FOR A DOCTOR.
IT'S TOO LATE--
I'M FINISHED.
WHO SHOT YOU?
MUST HAVE BEEN JUDD.
WHY?
THEY WERE AFRAID
I'D TALK.
I GUESS THE BOSS
DIDN'T TRUST ME.
I TOLD HIM YESTERDAY
I WAS FED UP WITH
ALL THESE KILLINGS...
I DIDN'T MIND THE GAMBLING.
WHY DID THEY BRING YOU
TO BUFFALO GAP?
TO HELP CLEAR OUT
THE SETTLERS,
PUT 'EM IN DEBT
SO THEY'D LEAVE.
WHAT WAS YOUR CUT?
HE PROMISED ME
A SECTION OF LAND,
SAID HE WAS GONNA BE KING--
KING OF THE WEST.
WHO IS HE?
I THINK HE'S CRAZY.
HIS NAME IS--
HE'S FINISHED.
CHEY, I'M WORRIED
ABOUT UNCLE BOB.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW HIM?
YESTERDAY, AFTER YOU LEFT.
SAID HE WAS GOING DOWN
TO THE SOUTH LINE
TO FIX A RAIL,
I HAVEN'T SEEN
OR HEARD FROM HIS SINCE.
HAS JUDD OR HIS MEN
BEEN AROUND?
NO, DO YOU EXPECT
THEY WILL BE?
YOU NEVER CAN TELL
WHEN A RATTLESNAKE'S
GONNA STRIKE.
I'M AWFULLY WORRIED
ABOUT UNCLE BOB.
DON'T WORRY, BETTY,
WE'LL FIND HIM.
( horse approaching )
UNCLE BOB,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, BUT ONLY
BY GOOD LUCK.
THE GANG JUMPED ME
AND TOOK ME TO THE SHACK.
THEY WENT LOOKIN' FOR YOU--
THAT'S WHEN I MADE MY GETAWAY.
GRAYSON HAS JUST BEEN KILLED
BY THE GANG.
GRAYSON! WHEN?
RIGHT HERE,
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
DID YOU GET ANYTHING
OUT OF HIM?
NOT MUCH--HE DIED BEFORE
HE COULD NAME THE LEADER.
WHAT ARE WE DOING TO DO?
IF WE HEAD FOR THE SHACK,
I THINK WE CAN TRAP THE BOSS--
HE SAID HE WAS COMING BACK.
DID YOU SEE HIM?
NO, HE KEPT OUT OF SIGHT.
IT'S TIME FOR A SHOWDOWN.
WE'VE GOT TO CAPTURE
THIS MADMAN BEFORE HE
DOES ANY MORE DAMAGE.
WE'LL TAKE GRAYSON'S BODY
TO TOWN AND HEAD FOR THE SHACK.
I'M GOING WITH YOU.
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS, BETTY.
THEY KILLED MY BROTHER--
THIS IS MY FIGHT, TOO.
LOOKS LIKE
THE PLACE
IS DESERTED.
WE'LL GO IN
AND HAVE
A LOOK AROUND.
I BETTER STAY OUTSIDE
TO KEEP GUARD.
FUZZY WILL GUARD OUTSIDE--
YOU COME WITH US.
THE BOSS WAS RIGHT--
HE SAID HE'D GET THEM
TO THE SHACK.
NOTHIN' WE CAN DO
TILL THE BOSS SHOWS UP.
MAYBE THERE IS--
COME OVER HERE.
SEE THOSE?
SPUR MARKS.
I NOTICED A VERY FUNNY THING.
SPUR MARKS CAN BE
LIKE FINGERPRINTS
WHEN IT COMES TO
TRAPPING A KILLER.
I'M WEARING ONE TYPE OF SPUR,
BETTY'S WEARING ANOTHER,
AND YOU'RE WEARING
STILL ANOTHER.
I THINK YOU'RE WEARING THE ONES
THAT FIT THOSE MARKS!
CHEYENNE!
YOU'RE CRAZY!
THERE'S ONE WAY
WE CAN BE SURE.
SUPPOSE YOU SIT DOWN
AND PUT YOUR FEET UP,
SO WE CAN COMPARE THE MARKS.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
AFRAID THEY'LL MATCH?
NO...I AIN'T AFRAID.
( hears commotion )
YOU'RE A SMART MAN--
IT'S ME.
UNCLE BOB,
HOW COULD YOU?
YOU HEAR THAT?
I HAD NOTHIN'--
ME, THE FIRST MAN OUT HERE,
ME, WHO SETTLED THIS TERRITORY.
IT BELONGS TO ME,
NOT ALL THE LANDJUMPERS
THAT MOVED IN.
IT'S MY LAND,
AND YOU NOR NOBODY ELSE IS GONNA
KEEP ME FROM GETTIN' IT--
( gunshot )
I KINDA FIGURED IT WAS YOU
ALL THE TIME.
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
THE BOSS MUST BE HAVING TROUBLE.
LET'S GO,
WE'LL SURROUND
THE PLACE.
I'M SURE GLAD YOU WERE
ON YOUR TOES, FUZZY.
I'M TAKING YOU IN.
WE GOT COMPANY!
COVER THIS MADMAN,
BETTY--
THEY'RE SURROUNDING
THE SHACK.
YOU AIN'T
GETTIN' AWAY ALIVE.
NEITHER ARE YOU.
FUZZY, TAKE A WINDOW.
KEEP LOW AND DON'T LET HIM
TRY ANY TRICKS.
AH HA!
THAT PUTS ONE OF 'EM
OUT OF THE WAY.
YOU GOT AN IDEA?
YEAH.
WE'LL STOP FIRING,
AND THEY'LL GET CURIOUS
AND COME IN TO SEE
WHAT HAPPENED.
WE CAN TRY IT.
BETTY, STRETCH OUT
ON THE FLOOR AND DON'T MOVE.
FUZZY, GET BEHIND THAT DOOR
AND KEEP YOUR GUN READY.
YOU--GET IN THAT CHAIR
OVER THERE.
GO ON, MOVE.
NOW REMEMBER, YOU'RE COVERED--
ONE WRONG MOVE AND YOU GET IT.
HERE'S THE DEAL--WE PLAY POSSUM
TILL THEY GET INSIDE.
THEN FUZZY, YOU TAKE 'EM
FROM THE BACK.
IT WON'T WORK.
IF IT DON'T, YOU'LL BE
THE FIRST TO GO.
THEY'VE BEEN QUITE
FOR NEARLY FIVE MINUTES.
THEY'RE EITHER DEAD
OR PLAYIN' TRICKS--
WE'LL FIND OUT WHICH.
IT'S THE WALTERS GIRL,
SHE'S DEAD.
( knocking in code )
HEY, BOSS,
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
Say yes, have 'em come in.
ALL RIGHT, BOYS,
COME ON IN.
DROP THOSE GUNS AND REACH!
I'M COMIN' AFTER YOU, JUDD.
YOU'RE FINISHED, JUDD,
DROP THAT GUN.
HERE I COME, JUDD.
I GUESS PETER NEVER THOUGHT
HE'D BE A PRISONER
IN HIS OWN JAIL.
THAT'S JUST WHERE HE BELONGS.
BESIDES, WE'VE GOT
A MUCH BETTER SHERIFF NOW.
HEY, FUZZY.
HEY, WHERE YOU ALL GOIN'?
WE'RE GOIN' UP TO SUNSET ROCK
TO WATCH THE MOON COME UP.
BY THE WAY,
HERE'S A PRESENT FOR YOU.
WHAT'S THIS FOR?
TO KEEP YOU AWAKE, SO YOU WON'T
GO TO SLEEP ON THE JOB.
( alarm rings )
AAH!
( ringing )
Captioned by
CAPTIONEERING
Your Closed Captioning Resource