This is a district of Sao Paulo.
A large latin American industrial city...
...responsible for 60 to 70%...
...of this country's gross national product.
Brazil has 120 million inhabitants...
...of which, 50% are under 21 years of age.
Of these, almost 28 million...
...live in conditions below the standards set forth...
...in the International Childrens Rights prescribed by the U.N.
There are also approximately 3 million homeless children...
...who have no one and no defined family of origin.
The situation of these children is more chaotic...
...when one is aware that they can't be prosecuted...
...which permits the exploitation of these minors by some adults.
Forcing them to commit crimes or acts of delinquency...
...knowing they won't be prosecuted.
At most they'll be sent to reformatories...
...where they will spend several months; where the pressure...
...and lack of space will cause their immediate release.
This district here, is one, wherein live...
...the families of workers from large neighboring factories...
...mom and dad who both work and children who remain at home...
...with care provided by an older sibling or a paid neighbor.
Fernando, who plays the main character of "Pixote"...
...Iives with his mom and 9 other siblings in this house.
This film is acted by children who belong to this social class.
The Survival of the Weakest
O. K. Iove, that's crazy!
-I've been waiting an hour. Want me to give up the job?
-Just a minute longer, please.
I'll give you a call later on, okay? Bye.
My son has been missing for over a month.
That's another matter.
Just give me his name for now.
José Maria.
-José Maria, what? -José Maria Da Silva.
Get moving, all of you!
-What's up? -They're rounding everyone up.
Some old guy was killed, they're pinning it on us.
Pedro Socrates, 15 years old : father, Julio; mother, Ambrosia.
Diego Emanuel, 13, Marcelino dos Anjos, Father; unknown.
Joao Henrique, 10, Mother: Maria Da Costa, 35; Father: unknown.
-My father's dead! -Father: unknown!
Anastasio Pereira, 17 years old...
...Father, Roberval; Mother, Severina.
José Altacilho: 16 years old. Father, Fortunato; mother, Julia.
Edmundo Pires, alias Marilyn, Parents: Luis, Esmeralda...17.
Raimundo de Souza: Father, Pedro...
What a mess. Everyone up.
Get in line.
Back again, eh? You know all about what's going on.
You don't get hit for no reason here.
Let's have some order here!
Inside you're a man, see?
Any trouble, and you'll answer to me.
-Any questions? -No questions.
Sunday is visiting day.
No whores. Only family.
Get them to the dormitory.
Come on, quickly! Quick!
Quiet!
Keep quiet!
It'll be O. K. if you keep quiet.
What the...?
I won't ask who's responsible!
No one will own up!
But hear this, I'm nobody's father!
I don't put up with any bullshit!
You want to kill each other, do it outside!
Not here or I take the rap
This is a respectable house.
You tell me everything, or, I'll smash your heads in!
-Pixote, did you see who did it? -Not me. I was asleep.
Fucking hell! Get him to sick bay.
You're gonna look pretty.
Watch out for Lilica.
Keep still! Got ants in your pants?
Hey! You're afraid.
Take a drag.
Breathe in and hold it.
Right on!
The smoke that satisfies.
Go again.
Shit, man, I'm so hungry.
I'm spaced out.
It doesn't get to an old hand like me so easily.
Let's split.
Pixote!
Fucking sexy chick!
My ass, she's a fag.
Lilica.
But I'd fuck it.
How's your memory?
That guy's Almir.
Son of a bitch cop.
You pushed an old guy under a car the other day. He's dead!
Did you need to do this...
...just to rob his wallet!
The guy was some judge. Know what that means?
We sure fucked up.
How could we know he was important?
The Commissioner's got the screws on me.
The Chief Commissioner put the screws on the commissioner.
I want the names of who did it.
Nothing will happen to you.
Here, the law protects minors.
You're untouchable.
But I'm not taken in by this minors' business.
If you won't collaborate...
I'll just finger one of you, then where will you be?
The old man died in lpiranga and 24th, the 24th of May.
Who hangs out there?
The guy doesn't know anything.
He died at the block, not at the corner...
...Iike this jerk just said.
Talk faggot! Tell us! Speak up, you whore!
Your lips are sealed, eh?
One good turn deserves another.
When we get out of here no one will stop us.
-Got it, pal? -Got it.
Start scrubbing, you pigs. Let's get this dirt off you.
Get rid of the lice.
And you, darling...
...get your pussy nice and clean.
What are you staring at?
You like it?
You want to touch it?
Sit here.
Are you new here?
Boy, I coughed all night!
Drink up, before it gets cold.
You'd better.
You'll only have to drink it tomorrow.
You're gonna be nice and strong when you grow up.
The...
...world...
..is...
...round...
...Iike...
...an...
...orange.
Have you written that? Why aren't you writing?
Open your book. Too tired to do it?
Well, you must learn to write, to know things.
Come on, wake up, will you!
Start writing.
Fess up!
I know nothing.
Come clean, you son of a bitch!
How can I tell you what I don't know, shit?
No swearing allowed here, asshole!
You'd better talk.
I can wait all day. I'm in no hurry.
You'll tell us in the end, anyway. So talk!
Okay, okay, I'll talk. It's like this...
...I met two guys on the street.
They asked me for a cigarette, and I gave 'em one.
-Marijuana, right? -No, just a plain cigarette.
Then they asked me if I 'd ever been involved in a hold-up.
I said, yes, and they gave me a gun, and we went to the bank.
There were two guys there...
...taking money out.
I'd like a loan.
-How much do you want -800.
-Hand over the money! -We need it.
There isn't much. It's early.
What do you care? It isn't yours, hand it over.
-Quick, before someone comes! -Please, don't kill me!
I'll blow you away!
In the bag, quick!
Stop, Dito!
Shit I quit playing!
Pixote screwed it all up. He blurted out my name!
Piss off!
Cut it out. I've got something more interesting for you.
Naked women!
Imagine taking down her panties and putting it in her.
Pixote's blushing.
-Enough, that's not for kids. -Shit, Lilica!
It's already hard.
There it is you jerk offs.
You act like big men but you have tiny weenies.
You, who are still on mother's milk, can do me a favor.
Stop it, only big boys can do that.
I need a little favor from you.
On Sunday your folks might bring me some...
-Don't want much, do you? -I don't want any trouble.
It's easy for you, isn't it?
-Don't ask me! -I know I could bring it.
But what's in it for me?
No one will rape you, nor beat you up.
We'll make sure of that.
Could you want more?
There's just one other thing.
-I want cash. -Bug off, fairy.
Let's play soccer.
Think about it, eh?
I just told you I don't want trouble.
If you want a copy of today's message...
...ask for number 1,720 and for the theme...
...Jesus, the king who bestows happiness.
Go talk to the judge, mom.
I will son, but I'm sure he won't let you out.
What for? So you can go back on the streets again?
If anything happens to me in this hell hole...
...it'll be your fault.
What could happen?
If your Grandpa turns up, will you talk to him?
-I sure hope he doesn't! -Why?
He pisses me off!
Come here, Roberto.
Today's my big day.
See Fumaca's mother?
Never misses a visit, you'd think she likes it here.
That's right. Ugly old bat.
Looks like she brought him something.
Maybe it's coconut pie.
The last one she brought was great.
Dito, your mom wants to see you, c'mon.
I don't wanna see her!
-She came all this way to see you. -I didn't ask her to!
C'mon, Sapato told me to get you.
Tell that cow I want nothing to do with her!
You won't talk to your mom? Ingrate.
She sacrifices for you. Now go see her.
-Can I go? -Yeah, go on, Dito.
When did he arrive?
About 2 months ago, I guess.
-Almost kicked him to death. -Why don't you ever come home?
-You don't turn me on anymore. -I don't?
Ever since I was a kid...
...I did nothing but listen to you...
...I followed your story...
...I knew your glory...
...I knew by heart...
He's good. He really sounds like Roberto Carlos.
When he gets out he'll be a star.
And what about you?
Because I read...
...in those star magazines...
...that you had been...
...a poor kid like me.
But you know...
...I didn't need to be told that...
...because it was written all over your face...
...what you suffered, what you went through...
...and what you lost.
Look, I'm in a jam. Can't you help me?
What sort of jam?
I need to get hold of a few joints.
What do you mean "joints"?
Just a few.
I won't get you anything. Don't make trouble.
You watch out for yourself, son.
I am...
...the Roberto Carlos of the poor.
I'm the boy who loved you and grew up...
...I sing where you no longer can.
That's the destiny life has given me.
Why can't you be like him?
I can't sing.
Besides, you'd have to get me out of here!
It's even worse out there. Now, let's watch the singer.
Since you won't get me joints, I'll look for my mom.
If you find her before I do, let me know.
In your footsteps...
...where you passed by.
-Keep still. -Any other questions?
-Why did you leave home? -Granny nagged me, so I left.
Look, I'm only trying to help you.
But you have to trust me. Tell me everything.
If I do, you'll turn me over to the cops.
I'm not a cop. I'm a doctor.
Promise you won't tell the judge?
I told you, I want you with the others.
-What is it? -Transfer.
We don't have his evaluation yet.
Not my problem. Let's go.
I still haven't told her everything.
If she doesn't know, how will the judge let me out?
There's another lady there.
Everything you said is kept confidential.
Go. Obey, Mr. Sapato.
Almir, I don't want any trouble.
I want those kids back in 3 days.
Relax, I always bring them back.
Sure, but some of your colleagues haven't.
-And I take the rap. -Don't panic.
If anyone asks, they're on vacation.
What are you looking at? Get a move on.
Hurry!
Help!
No! Help!
I don't know. Could be any of them.
I only remember he was a blond.
They all look the same. How can I be sure?
You say he looked like that blond one?
He's already committed a homicide.
Could be, but I only saw him for a second.
I can't be certain.
It's him all right. He's a wild one.
You seem certain. I cannot be sure.
Let's go. It won't bring father back.
I know it's painful, but it's still part of our job.
What's your name, kid?
I like it.
Have you seen my son? You know him?
Fumaca
Do you know where he is?
Is he sick?
Has something happened to him?
They took away a bunch of guys...
...and Fumaca hasn't returned yet.
You'd better inquire further.
Lady, better make yourself another son...
...Cause that one's had it!
The bodies of 2 boys, of about 14 to 15, have been found.
The victims were riddled with bulletholes.
The authorities are at this moment...
...going around to all city reform schools...
...the only clue was the drill uniforms they are wearing.
Let's go! Quick!
Get dressed and out!
We have visitors. Keep your traps shut, or you're back here!
This is the dormitory wing.
We work miracles with our small budget.
That explains the conditions.
-Are the children locked up? -No, it's not like that anymore.
This is our chief supervisor, he is dedicated to his boys.
Excuse the mess, it is difficult to clean all day long.
And that boy?
-Shouldn't he be in school? -No, he is sick.
Infectious Hepatitis.
Son, how are you getting along here?
The doctor comes twice a week.
Did the mother see the boy in the infirmary, or not?
Sure she did
She said she'd been here Sunday.
She was told the boy had run away.
She doesn't know what she's talking about.
I took her to the infirmary myself.
She was shocked, naturally...
...considering the state he was in.
She knew the police had been here and had taken the boy away.
But the police never returned.
When boys fight, they are worse than adults.
Could one boy attack another with such violence?
Only if he was King Kong.
When he's better, you can talk to him.
We'd like the press to spend some time here...
...to acknowledge the valuable work we do.
Pixote, you're here! Where's Fumaca?
They took us away somewhere and worked him over.
-They said, he'd killed that old man. -His mother was here on Sunday.
She blew up when she found out they'd taken Fumaca away.
She said she'd tell the papers.
It's gonna get rough.
So, Pixote, tell us everything.
Almir, that son of a bitch, drove off with some of the kids.
Carlinhos and Mirandinha, he killed them both.
Then he took us to the police station...
...and stuck us in solitary.
We were there for a long time. Sapato came and took me out...
...and put me in fatigues.
-I gotta get out of here. -Me too.
I saved a bit of glue for you.
When you're through, get rid of the can.
-Thanks. -Let's split.
Hang in there, O. K.?
The boy is in fine shape.
If he doesn't eat well, he's gonna "kick it. "
-lsn't that how they talk? -lt is.
Internal hemorrhage. It's what I feared.
Weren't you caring for him? How did this happen?
As if...you give me this boy all busted up.
I did everything I could.
Don't try to pin this on me!
Cad! This will cost you your job, I swear.
Did you have to turn the boy over?
I didn't turn him over. The police came for him.
Scream at them. I had no part in it.
You accepted the boy in this condition?
It was on my day off.
-You accepted him, then? -What should I have done?
Nothing!
What I want is for all of you to go to hell!
The press will come down on us like a ton of bricks!
God, this is the last thing we needed!
-What's the kid doing here? -He's out of it.
He won't remember a thing.
I won't be blamed!
I will put the blame on you!
Make your own bed. Everybody has to pull together.
Come on, get dressed.
The doctor says you can go. Snap to it.
Where's Fumaca? He was in that bed.
That's nonsense, kid. I don't know any Fumaca.
Swallow this.
...drawn up by President Figueiredo...
In São Paulo, violence on the streets increases daily...
...at dawn the body of LCB was found.
The Director of the lnstitute explained to our reporters:
Fights are frequent between the children...
...mostly due to their social background...
...as for the case of the minor who was found dead.
I have informed, that he had been brutally beaten up...
...by one of his colleagues...
...and that the attacker has been identified.
His assailant, A.C., 17, has a police record...
...of armed robbery, assault, and 1 homicide.
A typical juvenile delinquent.
I really don't know. I went and he wasn't there.
Then they told me he had run away.
Then when I went to visit him...
...they told me he was in the infirmary.
Then a boy told me it was a lie; that the police had got him.
I don't know. I just want my son.
I think this institution is pretty mysterious.
This reporter saw him in the infirmary in a terrible state.
He couldn't have taken a step. So how could he have run away?
Everyone get to bed.
Shit, you want to destroy me?!
But it won't be like that.!
You scum, you think you can get rid of me?!
But you're wrong, you hear?!
That's quite enough for today!
Sapato, you son of a bitch, I want to talk to you!
Everyone to the dormitory!
Everyone stay put!
Come on, I 'm gonna bust your gut!
I 'll cut you in pieces!
Sapato, you swine, get your ass here!
I didn't hurt Fumaca! He was my friend!
It was you and your gang of friends!
You are stoned.
You want my hide!
Don't get carried away.
Even if you had done it, nothing will happen to you.
You'll be 18 soon and everything will be fine.
No one will bother you. You don't even exist.
There will be nothing on your record.
I wasn't even on duty yesterday.
Keep cool, and everything will work out.
Now, everybody get to bed!
-Why the rush? -Let me go! You want my hide!
What's going on? Who's there?
What have they done to you?
They got me, Lilica.
They finished me off.
They took me to the box.
They let me have it.
Really worked me over.
Where are you hurt? Tell me, tell me.
Tell me, where did they hit you?
Everywhere.
Help me, Lilica.
I'll help you, I'm here beside you.
I promise no one will lay a hand on you again.
No one will harm you.
-He's dying. -No he's not!
You're my man. You're my love. You're my life.
I promise I'll always stay by your side.
-He's dying! -He's NOT dying!
You're not dying. You're gonna stay with me.
I love you. I do.
You'll pay for this you fucking swine!
I'll kill all of you!
I'll be the next one. Dito, let's split.
Open this door!
Let's destroy this shit hole.
They want to kill me!
Mr. Mario, I'm really very worried.
How so?
It was a kids rumble?
-What was the dead kid into? -Deviates.
If there is no suspect, find one.
This will blow the whole thing wide open.
The 2nd death in less than 2 weeks.
You can ask Almir about the first one.
You know why, this country doesn't budge?
Because it's full of idiots.
The judge has just arrived.
Well let's get it over with.
Tonight, a boy was killed.
Tell me everything you know, as if telling your father.
I'm here to help you.
Why all the destruction?
Isn't this your home?
A home we all ought to take care of.
Why all this crazy fighting, even killing each other.
You're here to reintegrate into society as useful citizens.
You're missing the chance of a lifetime.
Why?
Can anyone tell me?
Can you?
I'll only leave here when I know the truth.
Only God can give or take life away.
They're all blind, deaf, and dumb.
They're covering up because they all feel guilty.
You're almost 18, aren't you?
You were a friend of the victim?
I knew him.
-Tell me about him. -I have nothing to say.
I know nothing.
-Want to talk in private? -What?
You can talk. The judge will protect you.
Why'd you do it? Did he betray you?
Where you jealous?
Go on, tell us!
It's a lie! You're trying to frame me!
Did you start it? Queer stuff, right or wrong?
He hit you and that's how it happened, right?
You animals!
You killed him, you disgusting fairy!
Stop!
Leave!
Get out!
Go!
You can tell me, son. Don't be afraid.
My God!
That's the window!
Freedom's outside.
Let's go.
C'mon, let's go, man!
It's worse out there for me.
Idiot!
Stop, thief!
I love lying here in the sun.
When I am with you, I feel so calm.
And you?
Imagine us in Copacabana.
Beautiful beach, beautiful sun.
Take all of us, Dito. Take us.
I promise. When I make the big time...
...all four of us will go. - Awesome!
I want to ask you something.
Anything.
- Do you like me? - Of course I do.
Then say...
...Lilica, I love you.
- Cut it out, Lilica! - Say it, Dito.
Don't fuck with me.
Fuck with you, I will.
Lilica.
Awesome. Long time, no see.
What a surprise, get in.
I thought you had forgotten me!
Forgotten you? How could I forget you.
You took your time! We've been here since 9.
Go on, Lilica. Take it in.
The peace pipe.
- It's all yours, Dito. - No, I don't do grass.
Don't do grass?
You only took a small hit. I don't care for non-smokers.
If you think you're gonna sit here looking on...
- I just don't feel like it. - Don't feel like it, my ass.
Show this crumb what it's all about.
Suck in, man.
Cristal, your car is really great.
It is for me and my friends.
But only my close ones.
What do you think this is, man? Lemon pledge time?
- Leave the kid alone, Cristal. - What are you thinking, queen?
What are you thinking, eh?
Sorry.
Sorry my ass! You ain't gonna watch anything!
You come here, drink my whiskey...
...mess the place up...
...watch this shitty film...
What do you think I am, a hostess?
You've got it all wrong.
Dito is just a kid.
He doesn't know anything about this sort of thing.
- Give him a break. - I won't even wish him luck.
I'm wasting my time with these crumbs.
You want to know something? I won't make no deal.
So you can't get out, now!
You can't do this. Dito worked his ass off to get the dough!
That's not my problem. It's yours! Out!
Just this favor.
No, I won't.
Let me talk to him for a while.
Assholes!
Some is missing. There's 5,000 or so.
I soon as I sell the stuff, lt'll be O.K.
And where are you going to deal it?
In Rio. I know the spots.
I'm gonna save you some time.
I don't do this for anyone, but I like you.
When you get there, see my friend Debora.
A fine chick with a large clientele.
Take the stuff to her. Rio's a pretty bad place.
If you can't find her look for Raulzinho at the cowboy club.
- You know the place, don't you? - I know it.
Get going then.
And don't forget.
You owe me 5 more grand.
And no double-crossing.
If you mess things up it'll cost double.
This is your break. Either you deal...
...or you'll get dealt!
Boy, am I hungry!
Just pretend you are eating and you'll be O.K.
Do you think we are on the wrong train?
If we are, we'll get the right one.
We'll get there sooner or later.
When I get my share, I'm gonna get a board like that.
I'm not into that.
I'd like a stream where I can see the bottom.
I spoke to the lady. She's nearby.
Me and Lilica will go. You two stay here.
Hey man, we're together. Why can't we go too?
Yeah, Dito. I want to see the lady, if she's sexy.
- O.K. Let's go. - C'mon Pixote.
It's good. I'll take it.
- How did you get here? - By train?
What are you staring at? Think I'm pretty?
I think.
Cristal is still kicking? I thought he'd vanished.
- Is this your first trip here? - Yeah, the first.
Okay, that'll be 1 3,000.
Did she say she lived here?
Where does she sleep?
No telephone; no nothing. It's empty.
- Why? You don't trust me? - No, it's not that.
Let's be friends.
I'll take you home. I've got a son about your age.
Wouldn't you like to play with him?
This is for food, and the rest will come later.
What? Don't you trust me? You've got my number.
It's very simple.
I'll take the stuff, take it to my friend...
...he pays me, and I'll pay you.
Or do you think I'd walk around with all that money?
We won't leave without the dough!
- I'm the boss, Lilica! - You're gonna get dealt.
- Debora seems all right. - Keep out of this, Pixote!
Okay, you know best.
This is the way I work, if you don't want it, fine.
How long would we have to wait?
Jesus, I'll be back as soon as I can.
But leave half the stuff for good faith.
The water is great, Lilica.
Don't splash, Chico.
Didn't they teach you any manners at home?
What home, Lilica? The brothel?
Watch your mouth. My home was no brothel!
Will you two quit fighting!
Shouldn't Debora be back by now?
Maybe we'd better go back. Dito will be pissed.
We just got here. Why do we have to go now?
I want to know if Dito's got the dough.
I saw some great threads today, all embroidered.
When I get my share, no one will mess with me.
- I won't die like Big Boy. - Nobody knows the future.
When I get my share of the take, Lilica...
...l'm gonna buy a nice black.38 and you know what I'll do?
This is a hold up! Get 'em up, you bastard.
That's how I'll treat those ass kickers.
Everyone will respect me. Chico, the Trigger King.
And know who'll be the first?
The big-shot cop who beat me up at the station...
...and I didn't even know why he was hitting me.
But his day will come.
That son of a bitch will pay.
Roberto should be here with us.
It'd be great if he were here.
But he couldn't go in the water; his leg would rust.
- I'll be 1 8 next month. - Getting old, eh? Lilica?
Then the going will get rough. I'll have to cool it.
If I'm caught, I'll be beaten and locked up forever.
When I'm 18, I'll split.
I'll see if Roberto will let me join his band.
For me, things will be the same.
They'll always be on my back.
They'll always find a way of messing me up.
What can a queen expect from life?
Nothing, Lilica.
I knew that whore was double-crossing us.
Fuck!
Son of a bitch!
How did we ever get into this?
You got us into this.
Did I give her the stuff?
Wake up, will you?
Aren't you the lay of that bastard, Cristal?
How does Cristal come into this?
Well, all you wanted was to make it with him.
You took us along to show off.
Baby's jealous, isn't he?
I didn't do it to show off.
I did it for you.
One thing I hate is people cheating me.
Business is business.
- Yes, or no? - That depends.
Some business requires a little cheating.
Kiss off, Lilica! I never wanna see your face again!
What's wrong with you? What's done is done.
Just go!
Really want me to go, Dito.
Just repeat that and you won't see me again.
Go on, say it! Repeat it!
Come here.
It's okay. Raulzinho's waiting.
Not me, I wouldn't feel safe.
If they're caught they can say they're begging, or something.
I'll do it.
Don't hand over the stuff without getting the cash.
No "laters."
No, I must go to Sao Paulo, on business.
I'll be back in two days.
Who are you? What do you want?
We called you up. Cristal sent us.
Yes, I know.
No, no, I'm here.
Come in.
No, I'll be back soon.
Let me see the stuff.
Put the shit over here!
No, it's a private matter. I'll tell you later.
Hang on.
- How much? - 8,000 in cash.
What the fu...?
Okay, okay, hang on.
Why the hell did you give it to him?
Didn't you hear what Lilica said?
What could I do?
He asked for it.
Just because he asked, you gave it?
Hi there!
See who's there? That cow Debora.
Let's go call Dito.
No way, well take care of her ourselves.
- What about the stuff? - We'll get it later.
C'mon.
Everything O.K. - Hi, boys.
We came to get our money.
We waited all day.
I was held up in traffic.
Glad you came. I've got the cash.
You wait outside and after the show I'll pay you.
No way!
We're not gonna fall for that twice.
We want it now, okay.
Piss off! Leave, or I'll call the police!
Then your bag goes with us!
Speak to me!
Speak to me, for God's sake!
This is Dito, this is Pixote, all real nice people.
Hey, take a look at that dark one over there.
- What do you think? - I like it.
She's a love machine, man.
1,000 a day, at least.
I'll hand her over to you, because I'm going away.
It's a bargain.
Let's get to the point.
Turn it off!
We gotta talk.
Close your eyes.
You think I'm stupid?
I was good to you, wasn't I?
Sure, but you know I've got to cut out.
Only for a while.
They're O.K., What's more, you said you'd agree with it.
What am I gonna do with these kids?
It's only for a while. I'll come straight back.
Don't want to make trouble, do you, Sueli?
Okay, forget it. Just let me rest.
Hand over the 1,000, then...
Easy, brother!
This gun is great. It's brand new.
You only need some bullets.
Another 1,000 and it's yours, you'll need it.
I've got one.
- Like it? Do you want it? - Of course, I do.
I'll take it for Pixote.
What are you peeking at?
You hurt?
You sick?
I may be.
Why are you staring?
- Should I have kept the baby? - What baby?
That one!
What do you think that is? A steak?
Didn't your mom tell you the facts of life? Even looks like you.
Look at him!
Stop staring at me!
Get out, or I'll stick you like I stuck him! Go!
This goddamned fever...
...won't it ever go away?
There's blood in the bathroom, I think she's hurt.
No, she's not hurt. She's menstruating.
Didn't they ever tell you?
Every woman has it.
Quiet, Lilica. I don't want fighting here.
Why are you people so quiet?
It's like a funeral.
I'm sorry, but I'm not myself today.
Anyone want some?
I'll just give it to Lilica.
You're of age now, right?
Now I can see you better.
If you know how, everything will be swell.
We'll divide the money in half.
- In half! - Shut up, will you?!
You've got a deal!
- This could put you in jail. - Don't worry, we're minors.
There won't be any trouble.
Of course.
So sure of yourself.
eh, darling?
Who are you trying to fool?
The macho number doesn't add up with me.
My last left a souvenir in the bathroom.
You saw it, didn't you?
- What did you say your name was? - Pixote.
Pretty name.
Don't be angry with me.
I'm on the edge today.
They told me you are nice people.
Pixote could be the man for me. How about it?
Here we are.
- Isn't it nice? - What a flea bag!
I didn't expect a place like this!
It's cheap.
Anyway, for making love, it's the company that counts.
What are you waiting for, pops?
I thought you couldn't wait?
Lean back. Let me help you with your pants.
Shall I put some talc on it?
Gimme your whole repertoire.
- You're terrific. - So are you.
Never seen anything nicer than you.
I'm crazy about you.
Okay, you motherfucker...
- Hand over the money! - Take the money...
...but don't kill me, I have a family!
See if this makes you cum!
Take everything, but don't kill me.
What did you think of our performance?
It was really great.
Give me your meat, if you don't want it.
You're like pigs! Take it!
She's pissed off?
- They're queers, aren't they? - Lilica likes cock...
...but Dito doesn't. I know him. I can assure you.
Now, I'll have a big chocolate ice cream.
What about you?
Cognac and marshmallow.
Enjoying it?
Well worth the money, eh?
How much is a car like this?
You're rich, eh?
I want one.
I want a car like this.
I want a car like this one.
Easy now, or I'll blow your brains out!
Quiet, or I'll cut your balls off!
Nice and quiet.
Go on, get in there!
I think he shit in his pants.
- Everything okay? - Better and better.
He beat me so hard, I ended up in the hospital.
I told him, "Shove your money up your ass."
"I'll have a house and a car all my own."
Then I went to Sao Paulo, on my own.
I worked in a nightclub.
It was great. I felt like a queen.
I would dance all night.
Change the music.
Hey, I was enjoying that!
Sueli told me too. She's great, eh?
That's all I needed.
Like it?
What did you do there?
I was a go-go girl. I had a bikini like this...
...all covered with glitter.
Smashing! Sort of heart shaped.
I love dancing.
I used to dance all night on a stool like this.
- Why did they throw you out? - That's a long story.
This car is much nicer than Cristal's.
Think the guy in back is hungry?
Just leave me alone!
What's up with you today? You're being so difficult.
Nothing's the matter.
I hate drunks!
Look, she's drunk.
No big deal.
So what!
- And stop talking trash! - I just don't like it.
So, give me some money, and I'll go.
Drop dead, you silly fag!
Don't treat me this way.
I'm gonna split.
No one's leaving.
Don't you like it here? What's wrong?
Something upset you?
Don't break up the party.
Ever give anyone a French kiss?
God, she's gross!
Anyone like to dance?
Did he have to do that to me?
Bar me from the door of the club...
...with everyone looking.
Whenever I recall that, I can't control myself.
Wake up.
Where's Lilica?
She split.
Just as well, she was pissing me off.
Don't talk about her that way.
- She was nice. - Go after her, then.
- You'd make a lovely couple. - She was cool.
You're the son of a bitch!
Look, if you don't like it, just get out!
The fewer we are, the better.
You can't say that This isn't your house!
You're asking for it!
We saw your mother giving her ass to Sapato.
You screwy bastard!
- That goddamned whore! - Think I didn't know?!
I told you she'd be first on my list.
So keep your nose out of other people's business!
Did you hear, you asshole?!
What time is it?
Up we go!
Let's go make babies.
Sit there gringo, We'll
soon finish you off.
Let me kiss you.
Fuckin' gringo, don't push me!
Don't push me.
Let me kiss you there, you scumbag!
Keep still, creep, or you're dead!
Get him, Dito! Get him!
I told you never to say my name!
Stop that! Look out, Dito!
Shoot!
I'm leaving, Sueli.
Dito was a nice guy.
I know, don't talk about him anymore.
Dito's dead.
I was falling for Dito.
Lilica was right to fall for him.
All of my family is from Minas.
We could go there.
Come with me?
Don't go away.
I can't live all alone.
What's wrong?
It's over.
Come with me, will you? What's wrong?
Don't be like that.
Calm down. Everything's okay. Sueli's here.
It's over now.
Better now?
Baby, suck it.
Mommy's with you.
Get off me, Pixote!
Get off, Pixote! I don't want this!
Take your dirty mouth off me!
I'm not your mother! Do you hear?!
I don't want a child!
I hate children!
Go live your own life! We'll each get by on our own!
Scram!
Go.