PROLOGUE
followed by
TRAP
Vermin
I'd like to ask you something.
It's quite difficult.
What have you got of...
Really dangerous traps?
The most dangerous you have.
We have all kinds of things here.
Why d'you want? For...
For the devil?
For animals? For...
For large animals, yes,
but not that either.
For really big animals,
you've something?
I don't know what you mean
by 'really big'. If...
This trap is a mousetrap
in all its innocence.
You could perhaps build
a bigger trap on the same model.
We have a little bigger.
A trap for the imagination.
The DEVIL'S GRAIN
for the destruction of RATS
- The Egg Trap.
- Yes.
Paul.
We must meet someone
who likes eggs too,
to take someone with an egg trap.
No, no, no.
Someone who hates eggs.
For when we give it a good kick.
- Ah, yes.
- You see.
In all innocence.
There.
Now, you please.
We must hit the egg?
Yes...
- But it's still small.
- You want something dangerous.
- The most dangerous you have.
- The most dangerous, I said, it's...
For flies. Flies are the devil.
It's, very dangerous.
I advise you rarely...
Really, you are someone special.
There's this.
- It wouldn't hurt a fly.
- Or even a tiger trap.
With this you could...
Hunt for everything.
A tiger trap.
The way to set it
isn't complicated, you see.
But, you still have to be very careful.
Because it's still
a very dangerous trap.
It could completely crush a bone?
Ah! Yes. Pulverize a bone
completely, no problem.
- It can cut a leg?
- Yes, yes.
If you want for tigers and lions..
As bait...
You can put a cow.
You hang a cow from a pole
Should I have a cow at my disposal.
There!
There you have to be
very careful because, there...
- I remove the safety catch.
- Yes.
And now...
If you can back off a little bit
because it is very, very dangerous
- And remove your foot too.
- Yes.
- It's not broken?
- No.
The bone is broken forever.
In the beast the nerves will remain...
- Yes.
- Which are there.
This is what holds the beast,
holds...
The animal.
The animal, if you want.
I'll take it.
You're afraid of being robbed?
It's difficult to answer...
Yes.
To be stolen, but...
Stolen... But what can be stolen?
Things.
Not material things anyway.
Not necessarily.
So if it's not material things,
then it's spiritual things.
Perhaps, perhaps.
Because you'll have noticed,
here we have all kinds of traps.
But we don't have...
Hog traps.
- Right.
- Is...
I'm afraid there isn't...
something... pig like
in this fear of theft.
Are you a virgin?
No.
Why that question?
What sign are you then?
- Taurus.
We're in a world of animals.
I think that...
in the world of animals
anything is possible.
So I think that
when you are afraid of stealing,
of being stolen,
it's the same thing.
It's that you want
to become an animal.
D'you think?
I'm looking to see which animal.
Because if there are men
who come to attack you...
These men...
against whom you defend yourself,
For as long as you defend yourself,
they will attack you.
You will be attacked.
And I see, you will be attacked.
With a straw.
Make a hole in your head.
And then drink.
They will absorb...
your thoughts, your dreams.
You're afraid of that?
And as you're afraid someone
will steal your spiritual force,
you protect yourself.
And you protect yourself
against animal forces.
What you call in your language,
a very mediocre language,
Thieves.
They don't exist, thieves.
Property doesn't exist.
From the last century, we know
that property, and theft too,
So society...
Property doesn't exist.
So you protect yourself from what?
If I might ask?
From myself perhaps.
I think...
You make a delirious interpretation.
I apologize for
being so frank with you.
And there is something in you,
let me say...
I apologize for being so frank with you.
But there is a pig, a pink one,
inside of you.
I've set a trap for you.
I told you:
Take the machine to kill flies,
because the fly is the devil.
But it was the devil of another era.
Now the devil is a pig.
A pink pig.
Who will look like David Niven.
Who will be...
Very elegant.
Who will be very...
Very chic.
And that.
It is inside of you.
I have high hopes
about the girl.
She's an angel who has too often
been possessed by the devil.
She's always
mixed up in dirty business.
There's never the impression,
nor the truth besides,
that she's told the truth.
Yes.
And what's even stranger,
is that she's found among thieves.
And troublesome elements
who aren't even thieves.
The underworld who emerge more numerous
each day, from the slums of Paris.
And who are enraged.
She prevents, they say,
the students from studying.
The workers from working.
And they steal.
Prison
Here, Bulle!
Bulle, listen to me.
We have much to say to you.
We think it is normal
and even desirable
that a girl as intelligent as you are
interests herself in the problems...
We would even be interested in your
opinion on the possible consequences.
Because, reform, yes.
Chaos, no.
Our approach rests on the extreme
sympathy we have for young girls.
Momentarily gone bad.
Listen to me, please.
You must come to my place.
You really must.
I've loads of precious things.
Jewels, stones,
animals, lots of things.
There are no guards there.
I don't need, don't like them.
You must come to my place because...
Because I want.
It's urgent. You must both come.
I don't like single women.
Here is my card.
Anyway, you won't find it.
No one does.
- What can I do?
- Can you hear me? - It hurts.
Can you hear me?
What can I do?
You've dropped
all the dishes on the floor.
Hurts!
Shit!
You've dropped
all the dishes on the floor.
- Where does it hurt?
- That hurts!
- Where?
Where?
Where does it hurt?
- What can I do?
- Can you, with the axe...
Smash the door?
The axe. Smash the door.
Smash!
With the axe, the door.
Can you hear?
No!
- With the axe, smash!
- Can't!
Kick in the glass.
Gloves.
The worst is,
we can't see anything.
Yes.
Do you remember...
- D'you think?
- Yes, yes, you are beautiful.
In your shitty thing there
with the nuns.
- You've always had beautiful eyes.
- D'you like them? - I love them.
And you've always
had beautiful eyes.
I'm less important then you.
- You must always be beautiful.
- Yes, it's important, don't you think?
Because...
Like a little shepherdess.
- They are marvelous.
- Really?
You have fine, silky hair.
You have long, silky hair...
Don't have to poo.
And you still have skin like a peach.
And with the money one can make.
Everywhere.
needed to vomit.
Vomit on the pillow.
Then she vomited and then...
More.
I would put...
the fur down.
- Fox.
- I've got one.
Make me one. You sew
so well, with your fairy fingers.
Absolutely.
And la Rivière wasn't worth a penny.
It's because you're so pure.
You have purity.
- D'you think we can poo here?
- I don't know. On the commode.
My proposals can do
no wrong in their place
They were real, useful, honest,
in the sense that I gave them.
How often have vilified authors
and the indignant public
protested against this way
of shredding a work,
defacing all parts,
judging from the scraps
removed here and there
in the choice of an infidel accuser
who produced the evil himself,
by detaching the whole
that corrects it and explains it,
in twisting everywhere
the true sense?
Let one judge the isolated maxims
of La Bruyere and La Rochefoucauld.
Would they still be just?
You dropped all the dishes on the floor.
D'you see evil?
It's hell.
He knew that nothing could resist
the lucidity of his gaze.
The desire to...
...that would scare... Death...
My accumulated violence
fills me with silence.
Impenetrable.
Its story.
you would think it ended badly.
He tried to know
and he was burned alive.
It reminds us of Sodom
imprisoned in the castle
like Kafka.
And the fire arrives.
Whereas, he believed it was water,
He thought he could
fight the fire.
It has not been possible.
The pig that was in him died.
With... the acolytes
who had women's heads.
Me, I consider this story
as a premonitory dream.
Although I know nothing of it.
since I never saw it.
nor filmed, nor told it.
Subtitles:
Corvusalbus and Limbo