Chess is generally known
as a royal game.
But sometimes people overlook the fact
that a few pawns
can seriously kick ass.
Shit, they're all over the place.
Now what?
Plan B.
- What?
- What is Plan B?
This is Plan B.
That's Plan B?
You could have cleaned up.
Let's go, then.
Yeah!
Can't you carry anymore?
A bit too much, huh?
Yeah, okay.
Come on, you jerk!
- Shit, I'm out of ammo.
- Give me a go.
- I'm empty too.
- Great!
Watch out!
What's wrong?
The boss is in there.
He called us wankers!
Shit!
I see you, you wankers!
What do we do?
- Come on, cocksuckers!
- Do you have a pen?
A pen?
I'll shoot you another asshole!
Huh?
FUCK YOU
Fuck!
That's how it's gotta be, right?
With some shooting, fight action.
It'll be awesome!
Cha, react!
Okay...
- You know what I mean, right?
- No.
Like... fight action...
Phong, react!
Ah.
Yeah.
- Ah!
- Yeah!
That's good, that's good!
That's really good.
Did you bring these guys?
Great.
You're fired.
But... the way you want to do it
isn't going to work.
It's either that way or not at all.
Interesting.
Listen to me, George Michael,
it's going to be exciting.
Take Jackie Chan and Jet Li and piss off
from my set before I kick your ass.
Got it?
Idiots.
These boys were about to become
my best friends.
PLAN B
Subrip and re-edited by: phntalytee
Why can't I be at the funeral?
Aleksey was my brother-in-law.
And this gentleman
is my worst nightmare...
My biggest enemy.
Two days' work for nothing again!
- He knows nothing about action.
- I do the action here.
I work my ass off
to get you big jobs, big money...
The only big thing on this job
was the make-up girl.
As big as the other jobs before that?
Bullshit.
This is U-Gin, by the way.
The four have been inseparable
since childhood.
U-Gin isn't a gifted stuntman
like the others,
so he declared himself their manager.
And that despite the fact
that he really sucks at numbers.
Are you serious?
If Can keeps playing the diva,
there'll be no more jobs!
- "Diva"? We're the best!
- But you're not professionals!
If you were, you'd put your asses on the line
and wait for it!
- So we're whores?
- Do I look like a pimp?
- At least they get money.
- As a beginner you get paid less.
We've been starting up
for six years now!
Guys, we can't go on like this.
By the way,
I have something to tell you.
Hi, baby.
I'm coming home right now.
I'll cook.
Sorry, guys.
- Phong, I'll help you look.
- For what?
Your balls, jackass!
Funny!
Come on, it wasn't bad.
- What did you want to tell us?
- Fuck it.
- What's wrong with him lately?
- No idea, man.
Oh fuck, that late?
I have to get to the office.
Shit.
The queen is the piece
with the most freedom to move.
She can move straight
or diagonally.
But she has to decide on one move.
If she leaves the chosen path,
she gets unpredictable...
and the king will deem her... useless.
The car is here.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey, sweetie.
INVITATION TO JOB INTERVIEW
Yes!
How are you two?
Great.
- I think I hear a heartbeat.
- That's mine, you dope.
- Really? / That loud?
- Yeah.
You're the sickness, I'm the cure!
- You're the sickness, I'm the...
- Can!
Can! Did you take out the garbage?
Yes.
- Don't forget to get the garbage out.
- Okay, mum.
- Then come and eat.
- Okay!
Are you posing infront of the mirror?
Of course not!
Yes, we have time for you.
Trust me, you're getting
the best for this job.
Yep.
Shall we say tomorrow at 2pm?
Of course. All right.
The hallway's got to be cleaned...
No problem.
Remember... We clean up. Ciao!
Fisher's Isle, tomorrow at 2pm.
- Do a good job.
- Am I supposed to do it alone?
Great.
Reel Deal Action Design,
U-Gin speaking, how can I help?
Yes, that's right.
Yes.
I have the best stuntmen in town.
For the lowest price,
if you get me.
Yes... Today?
Okay.
One moment, I'll write it down.
No, we'll be there.
Yes. Thanks, bye!
Nice!
Private calls on work time...
- That's a pay cut
- What?
If I take a breather, it's pay cut.
If I have to pee, it's pay cut!
Can I do something without a pay cut?
If you don't like it...
I can find some new idiot anytime.
- Yo! Bro?
- Yo, chilla, what's up?
- Yo.
- Yes, I'll be there in a sec!
- Everything okay?
- Yes. I got a great casting call.
- Really?
- Yeah, let's meet up later.
- See you later.
- See ya!
Cool!
Help...
Congratulations, you got lucky.
Babysitting Kopp.
Babysitting? He's an old hand.
- He had some bad luck.
- Bad luck? Kopp is a loser.
He's been chasing
this Gabriel for years.
Some important files are missing
and the case has to be closed.
A lot of bad-mouthing
from you guys over there.
You know why
he's been transferred here, right?
He shot his partner.
He was between him and a suspect.
Three bullets into the leg,
without blinking!
- You know his nickname?
- RoboKopp. So?
So? He may have caught
the suspect, but...
his partner is on the disability pension.
He's crazy. Take care he doesn't
get you into the same shit.
See you.
So...
since we're forced to work
with each other...
we should talk straight.
If you want to know something...
just ask me.
And this guy, who is about
to ask my favourite question,
was to be my new partner:
Is what Plöger says true?
That you shot your partner?
If we two ever get
into the same situation,
I'll show you how it happened.
Guys, at 4pm,
your lives are gonna change.
Can, you and your kebabs!
Next time we get Asian food.
- You know I don't like noodles.
- But they're healthier.
Vegetables, fish, lean meat...
I've got vegetables in here.
It's healthy too.
Okay time out! Are we here
to swap recipes?
- Should I get you onto a cooking show?
- What's so urgent?
Guys...
I got you into
a top casting!
- Shit. It's going to be a "top casting".
Why don't you listen first?
- It's for a German movie.
- Do we get paid?
- It's a low-budget thing.
- Shit.
Do you think I can pull the best jobs
out of my ass?
Is he being serious?
Is he texting his lady?
- Man, I have to do some shopping.
- Shit, who's eating all that?
You're playing housewife now?
Ulla earns the money,
I can at least do the shopping.
What are you laughing at?
Who's still living with Mummy
and gets his undies ironed?
Fair.
Okay guys, what about the casting?
If it's as good as you say, I'm in.
- Cool!
- Nice.
Guys, I'm out.
I can't go on like this.
What do you mean?
How many castings do you want to do?
How many have we had
and what have we acheived?
It's over for me.
It ain't over till it's over!
Your Stallone quotes
will be over too.
I understand you.
Let's just do it this one time!
- Just one more time.
- Come on.
Yeah, come on.
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Stop it!
Okay, Okay.
But I'm telling you...
just this one time.
- Aye! Meet in an hour?
- I'm in.
- Nice.
- And you know what?
I've got a great idea.
Sounds good!
Wow.
Are you serious!
Going to a fancy-dress ball?
Fancy-dress ball?
-Bruce Lee.
-Marty McFly.
Cobretti.
- Right
- We've got something for you, too.
- I'm not wearing that.
- We're all in the same boat.
- Forget it.
- U-Gin, you're one of us, right?
Just shut up and put on the jacket.
Nice. Cool location.
Hell of a job again.
Hey.
Don't give up just yet, blondie.
We're not done yet.
I've already told you everything I know.
If you're lying, you dirty little bitch...
Gabriel's gonna get you
back in little slices
like a fucking Serrano ham.
Cool!
Guys, we really gotta
leave an impression.
- Crap.
- Chill, man. Trust me.
No solos this time.
Okay, what do you want to do?
We are the sickness, you are...
Shit. Sorry.
One moment.
Fuck.
Didn't I say "no solos this time?
Are you ready?
- You're the sickness, we are the cure!
- Yeah!
Yo! We're Reel Deal Action Design.
We have an appointment at 4pm.
Cool location, huh?
Shit! Guys!
Shit!
Oh shit!
That's Eddie.
What can be said about him?
Small-time crook, megalomaniac,
and really crazy
And pretty ruthless.
- Hey.
- Shut up!
- Did Gabriel send you?
- Who?
We... are here for the casting.
Congratulations. You're about to play corpses.
Seems like you idiots
have turned up in the wrong movie.
Roll credits.
Kill them.
No, wait.
Eddie, come here...
Great. The address is Neues Ufer 96
69, a very alluring number.
It has almost nothing
to do with 96, except...
Well... U-Gin and numbers.
- U-Gin, what did you do?
- I'm sorry, guys.
They seem tough. Why not use that?
Why get our hands dirty?
And what if this bitch lied to us?
Gabriel will come and kill us all.
Let's be smart.
Good.
Listen up, you clowns.
This chick here...
who's sobbing so sweetly...
is Gabriel's wife.
She told us something very interesting.
- Gabriel who?
- Shut up.
Don't you read the papers?
He's in all the headlines...
He thinks he is the
Tony Montana of Berlin.
This Gabriel has a safe full of cool shit.
And we want this cool shit.
Yes, Gabriel and his cool shit.
For 20 years I'd been trying
to put this guy behind bars.
For 20 years this cool shit
has prevented that.
In his safe was a whole archive
of compromising documents
that he used to control
his "business partners".
Bankers, businessmen,
politicians, prosecutors, etc.
Whether he bought them
or blackmailed them,
everything went into that safe.
And those who weren't willing
to play along... well
One thing was clear...
The safe would give
anyone great power.
But even though nobody knew about it,
Gabriel didn't just hide it
in his bedroom,
but at a secret location
somewhere in the city.
But his wife Victoria
or his brother Aleksey...
had to help him if he was arrested.
For that, they needed access
to the archive.
Because the paranoid bastard
didn't even want to tell them...
he created a system.
He spread the coordinates
and the safe combinations...
over several secret locations
that he controlled.
To find the safe, you had to go
from one clue to the next.
He only told his wife and brother
the first location.
That way he was prepared
for emergencies...
and he made sure
nobody could get near it...
without him knowing immediately.
Want to know where you come in?
- Not really.
- Shut up.
You will get me this cool shit.
- We won't do shit for you.
- I said shut up.
Is he gonna be a daddy?
So sweet.
A real daddy?
- You're gonna be a father?
- I've been trying to tell you.
Fuck.
To add drama,
we'll keep him here.
You do the job,
then you'll get your daddy back.
Cool deal, huh?
If our sweet little bitch
hasn't lied to us
there are four locations in the city.
At each location,
part of the combination is hidden...
as well as a clue to the next location.
Like some fucking treasure hunt.
On that paper are some numbers.
They're called coordinates.
Fascinating things.
This is location no.1.
How do we know
you're not having us on?
Sweetie...
you will have to take that risk.
- Man, we won't...
- Shut your fucking mouth!
You've got until 8am tomorrow.
If you don't make it by then...
he eats a bullet.
If you talk to the police...
And if you ask one more stupid question...
he eats a bullet.
Go.
- I wouldn't do that, big guy.
- What you gonna do about it?
You don't wanna know.
Stop that shit.
Piss off already.
Okay.
"Come on, Cha, this one last time."
Nice casting!
I hope you're satisfied.
- What do we do?
- Go to the cops, of course.
Didn't you listen?
Then Phong is fucked.
Got a better idea, Cobretti?
We do what we gotta do
and get it over with.
Hello, McFly, anybody home?
They're gangsters, don't trust them.
- Do we have a choice?
- I'm not risking Phong's life...
so you can play Rambo.
- It's not a movie!
- What movie?
Where is that loser Boris?
Do something useful for a change.
Keep an eye on those guys.
Can is right.
They'll be watching us.
If we don't comply,
they'll find out and kill Phong.
- That's what I'm saying.
- Boys, believe me, we're making a huge mistake.
We need a car.
That way we'll go faster.
Where do we get one?
Want to steal one?
U-Gin, nice work.
Easy, wasn't it?
Come on, bro.
Great.
U-Gin, if you want to get going,
now is the perfect time.
My car!
That went well.
He'll call the cops.
We're collecting those clues
and that's all.
- We're running an errand.
- Delivering pizza?
- Did I reverse the number?
- Guys, chill.
Where do we go first?
- It's a cafe in Kreuzberg.
- Anything else?
The info is engraved
on the handle of a...
dagger?
1. BIG TROUBLE IN LITTLE ISTANBUL
WE CLEAN UP
CLÜB for Members Only
- What's a "clüb"?
- It's meant to say "club".
They want to be left alone.
I'm gonna go in there,
play brother and that's it.
Trust me.
You don't get along
with your brothers that well, huh?
- Leave it to your manager.
- You want to go in?
You could try and play sister.
Watch and learn.
Yo.
What do you want, doofus?
Seems to be working.
- He hasn't copped it yet.
- That guy who was just in here...
says you're all fat, ugly sons of bitches.
Wait, wait.
That's not all. The best is coming.
The chink that's with him
said he fucked all your mothers.
Yours...
Maybe he's not such a bad manager.
yours...
My words exactly
Not yours,
but yours twice.
You know what, Cha?
I've always believed in him.
You're dead, you bastards!
- Shit!
- Fuck!
Sons of donkeys?
Fuck it.
It worked!
Shit!
- He's a crap manager!
- Shut up and run.
That way!
- What's up?
- Why are we running away?
Don't make trouble, man.
Come back.
Boys, get lost.
You better watch yourself.
Son of a dog. Get him.
Fuck!
- Move over, I'm driving.
- What's wrong? Chill man.
- What the hell did you tell them?
- Me? Not a thing.
Kopp.
Got it.
What's going on?
Work to do. Kreuzberg.
Hey, wait for me!
Yeah, what?
All right.
You're lucky.
Your boys are making progress.
POLICE
Thanks for calling.
- I thought it might interest you.
- What does he mean?
That's Gabriel's cafe.
A neighbour reported a brawl
with the guys from the cafe.
The witnesses didn't see much.
The guys in there aren't very talkative.
Why wasn't Gabriel up on that?
He had other things on his mind.
His brother Aleksey recently died
under mysterious circumstances.
Gabriel treated him
to a nice new home six feet under.
Since women are as welcom at gangster
funerals as they are at a papal election...
Gabriel had not yet noticed
the kidnapping of his wife Victoria.
Yes?
Three guys, you say?
You got beaten up by three guys,
you losers?
What did they want?
You don't know?
Let me tell you what I know...
If Gabriel hears about it...
he'll beat the shit out of you.
And without knowing it,
Lionid made a very dumb decision.
You're lucky he doesn't
have time for your shit today.
Losers...
Three guys, you say?
Interesting.
Somebody is in excellent form.
And has unfinished business
with Gabriel.
They'll give you hell if you
don't forget this Gabriel thing.
And me too, by the way.
What I don't understand...
What kind of idiots
want to mess with Gabriel?
That went well, huh?
Well? Now we have to pick street fights.
Live for something or die for something .
You decide, Cha.
Are you nuts?
Couldn't you just take a picture?
We're carrying a clue to Gabriel safe.
Better safe than sorry.
Besides, be glad we're doing so well.
HEATER
Piece of crap!
Everything all right, boys?
Need a hand?
- Good with cars?
- Well he is.
- Let me see.
- It won't start.
Let's see. I think it's the alternator.
Let's push-start it.
Put some effort into it.
Okay, guys.
A bit faster.
Faster.
Little more still.
Hang in there. More.
Yeah!
Mum's Food Joint
I've always thought
I'd die on duty.
Looks like the cholesterol
will get me first.
- When did you join?
- 20 years ago.
Lousy pay, no time for family...
my dream job.
I know.
At some point you're not even surprised
that you've slept at the office again.
What does Mrs Kopp say to that?
Mrs Kopp...
She's been called Dombrowski again
for five years.
Didn't she want a three-way with Gabriel?
- Toilet?
- Out of order.
2. RED HEAT
Wait.
You're not getting in like that.
- Why not?
- This is a place with style.
- What?
- Can, you'd better wait outside then.
Tie is compulsory.
Give me yours.
Your shades are fucking annoying.
It's like a dick on your face.
Better a dick on the face
than no dick at all, Minnie Mouse.
Guys, the next clue is a heater.
Let's check.
Hey guys, how about
a nice bottle of Petrus?
We're sticking to beer.
It's pretty boring here.
- We should head.
- Right.
- Stay for a while.
- No, we're hitting it.
Ciao.
Guys.
This place has no fucking heater.
Great. What now?
Let's check that door.
Shit!
Let's go
Can and I go in.
You go to the bar and keep watch.
Enjoy it. Have one for me.
Not bad.
Want to have a contest?
Looks like I won.
You're a natural...
I can do alot of things
with my mouth...
Champagne.
Got anything?
Nothing.
Fuck, that's hot.
Can you help me?
You're the sickness, I'm...
Yo!
Damn it.
Okay, I've got it.
Nice stuff.
- Can you dance?
- Can I dance?
- Looks good.
- Yeah.
I told you there's no toilet here.
Sorry.
What's your name?
And one to the right, and...
Did you have to ask her name?
Don't you see how hot she looks?
What's going on?
We're getting thrashed by a woman.
- I haven't got serious yet. You?
- Not yet.
Want some more, you wannabes?
She looks angry.
She's beautiful when she's angry
What kinda group sex is that?!
Okay, you wanted it this way.
Three, two, one.
The bill, please.
Come back, you...
That's mine.
Bastards.
Mind your step.
It's okay.
Taxi.
Get out.
- Well, cuties, where do you want to go?
- Just drive.
At least give back the ties, you jerks.
You bastards.
Fucking hell, we're out of beer.
- You morons forgot to stock up.
- We can go to the gas station.
I'll do it myself.
You always buy that mixed shit.
- Hey, I've got to piss.
- Tie a knot in it.
- I can piss right here if you want.
- You're pissing me off.
Take that sissy to the loo.
Great.
How can I do it like this?
Or do you want to hold it?
You'll need both hands.
I can't when someone's watching.
- What?
- I can't when someone's watching.
Are you shitting me?
Think I want to see your dick?
Don't try to fuck with me, idiot.
You wanker, I'll get you.
Don't think you'll get away
with fucking me over.
Look!
Stop! Whoa!
Stop! Stop!
Cool!
Thanks.
You won't belive this...
I already know this story.
And the ending is pretty shitty.
Fuck!
To Aleksey!
If you would come with me now, please.
Oh shit.
I hate these dogs.
What? That's good luck.
- Maybe you're heading for good times.
- Funny.
That's also one of Gabriel's joints, isn't it?
- Coincidence?
- I don't think so.
Somebody is systematically
trying to piss Gabriel off.
A rival?
I can't imagine
anyone being so dumb.
Plus...
Plus what?
Gabriel has a lot of enemies,
everywhere.
Despite that, the bastard
seems to be untouchable.
So he has a lot of them
by the balls, or he bought them.
And these assholes are sitting around
watching his back.
They're sitting around here, too.
You mean Gabriel's meddling
in our stuff?
Why do you think my case
went down the drain?
Why did it even go to trial, then?
When they arrested Gabriel's brother...
for a minor offence, I nabbed him.
Pathetic wimp.
Not at all like Gabriel.
I told him what they do
to handsome boys like him in prison.
And then I had him.
I had him ready to testify
against his own brother.
Gabriel's brother? Really?
Well... A chance like that
comes up once in a lifetime.
Yes?
To fuck up. Verb, transitive.
Definition: to conclude something without success;
to execute a task extremely badly...
Not telling Gabriel in time
that three guys are trashing his joints.
I'm glad we've been able
to reach an agreement.
In the Middle Ages,
the bearer of bad news was often beheaded.
Pretty excessive.
I wonder what they did if,
in addition,
the bad news was delivered too late?
Remind me
to look that up sometime.
I'd really like to know.
You're sure it's the same three guys?
Yes... and that pig
is snooping around again.
Kopp?
The guy is a real bloodhound.
Let him do the dirty work,
so he's busy.
Okay.
And? What now?
Well...
It looks like only two guys
can keep up with Gabriel.
God and Superman.
So you don't have a clue.
No, Schulz.
I don't have a goddamn fucking clue.
- Have you ever thought about quitting?
- Yeah.
As soon as Gabriel is thrown into
the deepest shithole on the planet.
And that shithole
into an even deeper shithole.
Yes?
The three guys you're looking for...
I know where they'll turn up next.
But you won't tell me who you are?
Someone wants to serve us
our three guys on a platter.
Let's go, then.
3. THRILLER NIGHT
- Keep the change.
- Thanks. Isn't it too late for a visit?
Take my card and give me a call
if you need me later.
What visit?
Okay, the next hint is
"Frederick Krueger".
Who the hell is that?
No idea.
But he must be
somewhere beyond this wall.
How do we get him over?
- Cha, Cha.
- Lift it up.
Cha. Cha, I love you.
Where is Can?
Be quiet.
You're my bros.
I know, but you stay here
and shut your mouth, okay?
I'm sorry, guys.
I've been a shitty manager.
Yeah, that's true.
From now on I'll get you
the best jobs, okay?
If you shut your trap now,
you still get to be our manager.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- You guys are the best.
- Thanks.
You do this kung fu stuff and all...
Bruce Lee, I can do nothing
against you.
Lick my tiny yellow balls.
Fuck, man. I hate cemeteries.
Stop feeling me up.
Are you scared?
What? Never.
I gotta piss.
Ever heard those ghost stories?
What ghost stories?
The one about the White woman
at the cemetery.
She drags people
into the graves at night.
You're shitting me.
When have I ever done that?
She's real, man.
Shit. Back there.
- What, where?
- Over there.
I can't see anything.
Ha, ha, very funny.
You fell for it. Ah shit.
- Look, the gravestone.
- Shit.
Search it.
The clue should be around here.
Are you done? Can we go now?
19 BUDDHA STATUE
Got it.
Where's U-Gin?
Wasn't he here?
- How will we find him in the dark?
- No idea.
Maybe if he smiles.
Fuck, what was that?
No idea, man.
But it came from back there.
- Go and look.
- Go look for yourself.
Untie him, you goddamn freaks.
Those are my bros coming for me.
Are you done?
Cha and Can. My bros.
I love you, guys.
Shit. What the hell is that?
I think he wants you.
Shit!
Holy shit.
- Man, kick his ass.
- If he wants some, I'll give him some.
Hey Cha!
You can't do shit.
- Come on, Cha!
- Come on.
Give'em hell.
I thought this guy was hardcore.
You're the last pussy.
Yeah, let's get
the black bloc anarchists back.
No. If you want the hardcore guys
we have to get the Young Conservatives.
I told you the stories
about the white woman were true.
Wasn't that a guy?
What the hell, man?
Can we get outta here, please?
I think he liked you.
You're so damn funny.
You've got a nice butt, though.
Pull yourself together
or someone will call the cops.
Well, guys...
having fun?
Listen up, you clowns.
This tour de fuck-up of yours...
might have won you some fans.
But you've broken some laws.
24 cases of assault and battery.
Property damage. Car theft.
And your mummies
won't like this one...
You didn't pay
for the bubbly at the strip club.
So let's be clear.
We can put your asses in jail.
So how about you start singing?
# Two is not alone. #
Okay.
Separate interrogations.
Spit it out. What was
your business at the cemetery?
- What about the strip club?
- And those thugs at the cafe?
Are there just three of you?
Who are you working for?
What do you know about Gabriel?
Hello.
Hi, brother. You look mean.
Your arms are... good.
Do you work out?
Solly, me no speak German.
Me no from here.
That's a good-looking beard.
Trimmed. Sweet.
Me get up from bed,
call Can in telephone.
And your partner
totally looks like Al Pacino.
Me no fight. No like hurt.
Do you know those guys
"Starsky & Hutch"?
Know them?
Not from here.
Hey... did I tell you
I'm having trouble sleeping?
That's why I stay up all night now.
I'm having trouble with the old lady.
I'll be staying here.
We've got all night.
But you don't, right?
Your crusade against Gabriel
started today, whatever the reason.
Mine has been going for 20 years.
You and I,
we want the same thing, don't we?
All right, I'll tell you everything.
Okay, let's not waste anytime.
Send the SWAT team.
- God, my head.
- Shit!
What do we do now?
Hey, Cha.
Did you tell them anything?
- I told them where the casting office is.
- You what?
Did you think
you could fuck me over?
Yeah, what?
Where are you?
The cops?
And why didn't you call earlier?
You wanted to wait till the boys
left the station, you fuckwit?
If you come here again,
I'll thrash you...
you filthy son of a bitch!
- Guys, we've got to get outta here.
- What about these two?
- Shit!
- Shoot them then go.
- Hey, boss.
- I'll take care of it.
- Even better.
Hands up!
Chill out. I told them
where the casting was...
- not where Phong is.
- Huh?
What the hell is this? Huh?
Who called you?
Get out of here, you morons!
You're messing up the floor!
I just mopped it!
Idiots! You're morons!
Why?
The cops might've saved Phong.
I don't think so.
When I told those two about Gabriel,
I knew they got all antsy.
They didn't care about Phong.
Everybody just wants that safe.
Oh, Eddie.
Didn't you ever wonder who might have
heard about Gabriel's safe?
Think it was by chance
that my new partner...
suggested kidnapping me...
on the one day that Gabriel
would be at the funeral?
You've been lying to me
the whole time, you jerk!
But when you found some suckers
you could blackmail into doing your work.
I was surprised, to put it mildly.
Maybe even impressed.
But you see... Eddie...
you are my sucker.
Then again, it's not your fault.
Your brain seems to be
even smaller than your dick.
I swear to you, you bitch...
if I ever lay my hands on you...
I'll slice off your tits...
and feed them to the troll
that shat out your grandma!
Shut up.
What about this one?
How can they get the codes
if we have the dagger?
Okay.
They need Phong alive.
We might still need him.
So what now?
I haven't thought about that yet.
Guys...
This whole time we were chasing
the hottest jobs and the big money.
I know what you can do.
This time it's not about money or fame.
It's about helping our brother,
getting together again.
But we don't have
the fourth part of the combination yet.
Guys, we're family, right?
Besides...
problems are there to be solved.
- For Phong.
For Phong.
Yeah?
Thanks for the heads-up.
They tricked us.
Those boys are not as dumb as they look.
4. LITTLE BUDDHA
- Dude, I've got to puke.
- Again?
Yeah, I'm fucked.
- Okay, we'll go on ahead.
- I'll catch up.
Fuck!
Hello?
All right.
We're on our way.
Sorry.
My wife always worries
when I'm gone for the night.
We'll get to the bottom of this now.
Let's take the back entrance.
How do we find a Buddha statue here?
No idea. Start looking.
Let me handle this.
You want to play the brother now?
Thank you for your welcome.
We wouldn't bother you
if it wasn't really important.
We're Archaeology students...
and we'd like to see your Buddha statue.
We're writing a thesis
on the Imperial period,
when the emperors were alive, etc.
Anyway,
we're very interested in your culture...
as it's more than 100 years old.
What's she saying?
No idea.
I'm Korean.
You should know that by now.
- What kind of Asian are you?
- Don't know.
Okay. Plan B?
What?
- You can't do this.
- Sure I can.
88 GARDEN ALLOTMENT
Quick work, eh?
Archaeology students?
Really?
- Oh!
- Shit!
Come on.
Shit.
Hey, I've got something for you.
You got it going on.
Here, I didn't even need them.
Not any more maybe.
Phong?
You guys have got something I want.
Huh?
She's after the goddamn safe too.
Your decision.
You still don't get it,
you're way out of your depth.
- Cha!
- Cha! Cha!
- Fuck!
- Now hand over the coordinates.
Bravo.
A grand move.
I see you've learned to write
the rules to your own game.
You really thought I was a pawn...
that you could move around
your chessboard...
Like you did with your brother?
We have to do something
or the boys are fucked.
Kopp, there are too many of them.
We're responsible for them.
You know...
I've always expected...
some scumbag
to go after my archive.
That it turned out to be you...
is almost interesting.
But to be honest, you bore me.
Call for backup.
I'll try to hold them up.
This is suici...
Police!
Everybody stay calm.
Now it's getting interesting.
Did you tell her how your brother died?
What does he mean?
Sweetie,
are you really that naive?
Like I said, lousy pay.
Did I ever tell you how the story
with my old partner ended?
He was a corrupt asshole,
just like you.
If you have something to say, say it.
Did you really think Gabriel would
let my key witness...
against him and his life?
I guess you've lost sight of one thing.
This is still my game.
You've lost sight of one thing too.
Your brother
wasn't only a better person than you...
he was also a better fuck.
Take care of them!
Phong! Get her.
Fuck!
Kick his ass, Can!
Shit!
I told you it was a bad idea.
- Well? Still alive?
- I'm all right.
- Go and help Phong.
- Sure?
- You're okay? They went that way.
- Yeah.
Enough!
You look beat.
Come on, doll.
Phong.
What are you doing here?
You're all so stupid.
Over there!
Playtime is over.
My game, my rules.
Fuck.
Live for nothing or die for something.
You decide.
Can!
Your move.
Dead or alive,
you're coming with me.
Yippie-ki-ay, motherfucker.
Are you okay, lad?
I've been better.
The bullet went right through
don't worry.
We've got something for you.
Phong, in her pocket.
- Cha, you all right?
- I'm fine. You?
Yeah.
About time we got rid of this shit.
These are the coordinates.
That's garden allotments near the airport.
There's additional info. C13.
That will be the plot number.
Guys, there's something else
for me to do.
I'll send someone.
And...
good work, guys.
Think about it...
All this time I couldn't get hold
of this pig and his minions...
and then I got a hold of Gabriel's archive.
And with this archive...
I would bust the rest
of the corrupt slimebags.
If you want to know
what a happy bastard looks like...
just look at me.
I guess that's about it.
What can I say?
After 20 years of rowing up
shit creek without a paddle...
within a day these boys showed
what it all comes down to.
They stuck together...
listened to their hearts
and stayed true to themselves.
To the end.
You didn't expect me
to quote "Die Hard", did you?
Here, you deserve to have them back.
Shit. Those bastards.
I'm so fucking hungry.
I'd even eat kebab.
Hey, Phong,
were you crying earlier on?
What?
He's right.
You really had watery eyes.
Guys, never!
He didn't think we'd get him out.
- Honestly, did you cry?
- Yeah, sure.
Fuck. My battery's dead.
So what?
This story is our chance to get rich.
I have to find us
a production company real quick.
Over my dead body, man.
What?
It can't get any worse than this.
Yeah, man, come on.
- I'm done with this, boys
- Come on, man.
Come on! Come on!
Subrip and re-edited: Phntalytee
Lick my tiny yellow balls.
Cut.
- Look at me.
- Oh shit!
Cut.
Your shades are pissing me off a...
fuck you!
Sorry.
A little louder, please.
Hey guys, take it easy.
Where do we...
have to go?
Where do we have to go?
Why did you laugh?
- That's my line, Can.
- Oh, sorry.
Can's right.
- Can we start again?
- It's rolling.
Good.
I mean... he's gotta chill.
If Can keeps playing the diva...
Again please.
- Think I want to see your dick?
- What?
Don't try to fuck with me. Come on.
121-11, take 1.
Sorry, sorry.
If Gabriel hears about it,
he's going to...
beat the shit out of you.
He's going to give...
He's going...
He'll cut you...
Fuck!
If I ever get my hands on you,
I'm going to slice off your grandma's tits.
On two conditions..
The first...
I forgot.
Cut!
Shit.
What happened?
Fuck.
- Shit.
- Cut.
Action!
Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
"You're the sickness, I'm the cure".
Yeah.