Wake up,
we're at Bar Street
25 RMB
You're exhausted and still drinking
What a warrior!
Thanks
By the way
Want to sleep in my car? I'm in no rush
Where is Wu Bar, please?
You're going to Wu Bar?
Turn right
at the intersection
Where are you?
I'm here
Why don't I see you?
I'm at Bar Street
I warn you, don't be late again
Can't you be nice?
Today's meeting is important
Why can't we talk at home?
You haven't been home in six months
I've booked Room 7.
Wait there
Ridiculous
Sir, do you have an invitation?
To what?
Our Third Anniversary Party
Must I have one?
One moment
Welcome, Mr. Zhong
You know me?
Greetings
Pardon the foreigner's Chinese
This way, please
Sir, please check your coat there
Out of the way! What invitation!
Third anniversary. That's why I'm here!
Don't touch me
No invitation
Captain Zhong
Do you remember me?
I'm TV host Zhu Nan
My partner, Quanzi, interviewed you
Are you working on a case here?
Personal stuff
I understand. Police are people, too
It's just so hard getting any news
I just interviewed a drunk driver. That scum —
We'll talk later
Where is Room 7?
What?
Room 7
There's a guy looking for Miao
Hang on, Handsome
Life is like a cocktail
to be savored
This drink can be had any way you want
This is our Boss, Wu
Hello, I'm Wu Jiang
Call me Zhong Wen
How do you feel here?
Like a prison
Yes, once you're in there's no getting out
I'm joking. Miao isn't here yet
I'll show you around. Come on
This was a factory,
shut down for environmental reasons
Guess how long it took to redecorate
Brother Wu
This is Brother Zhong
It took me two years
The other bars demolished all these pipes
Such wonderful stuff. I kept them all
The piranhas were your idea?
They're illegal
I don't know the law
In local waters
they'd be alien invaders
"Survival of the fittest" is a rule of nature
You know Miao well?
She says your business keeps you busy
What a storyteller
Freeze!
That's my favorite room
Have a drink
Let's talk after the clients leave
Welcome to Wu Bar's Third Anniversary Party!
Room 7 is ahead. Turn right
You didn't tell me about the celebration
Zhong, please wait for me inside
My bar is full! I lose money by coming here
It's been a while. You're prettier now
Did you "renovate"?
Don't touch! It'll fall off
Which bottle would you like?
I'm not drinking today
Please, my boss expects me to sell these
Don't trouble him
You'll never change his mind. Put down here
Let's start with this
Please wait
I'm here. No rush
What's with the tattoo?
I've got more where you can't see them
You got smarter these six months
But your temper seems better
You told Wu I'm a businessman
Should I have said you're a cop?
It's a hard, shameful,
low-paying job
Your drink, sir
How's your hospital internship?
Don't worry about me
Did you get that scratch today?
Did you disinfect it? How did you get it?
Don't ask
You want to tell me
Someone reported a case this morning
A cook stabbed someone with meat skewers,
got cornered, and threatened suicide
Are you jumping or not!
Calm down
Three things: One, give me back my stove
Fine
Two, I'm not paying a fine. Three…
Hurry, it's freezing
I'm not going to prison
What are you yelling about?
I didn't yell
See, this is minor
It's major, a life was at stake
Have you jumped before?
It's my first time
How's your aim?
Good enough
Brother, let's talk
Stop. I'm not talking to you. Go.
Who will you talk to?
I'll talk to her. Bring her here
I'll talk to her. You, get out
This went on all day. We were all exhausted
I was worried he'd lose it
So you started to talk to him
I didn't
Let go
Stay still
Help!
He's not hurt. Said he'd treat me to lamb skewers
It's not worth it
to risk your life for strangers
What's so important we need to talk here?
You'll see
Everyone's a victim of gossip these days
Don't admit anything. Goodbye
Hello, Boss Niu
I'm Zhu Nan, host of TV's Life Channel
I've seen you on TV
May I interview you?
What a mess! You can't film here
He looks familiar
He owns a property company, a regular
He's rich. Comes for the girls
Boss Niu, let me introduce
this beauty. Do you know her?
Looks familiar
Some flirt
Boss Niu
She looks so familiar.
It's been a long time
He's my ex
How did you meet Boss Wu?
He came to the hospital with an old injury
What do you think of him?
I don't know, so I shouldn't say
Sorry, Brother Zhong
There are so many clients I neglected you
Why did you change your look?
You know full well
To introduce
This is my boyfriend
Now you know why we're meeting here
You two chat, I'll make my rounds
I don't like him
I'm telling you, not asking
How old is he?
It doesn't matter
He's almost my age
So what?
Look at the company he keeps
He's stringing you along
Why should he?
Why should I obey you?
What is it about him? What can he give you?
I feel safe
I'm a cop, and you feel safe with him?
He's got time for me. Do you?
He's my shoulder to cry on. Are you?
Some cop
Let me see what the racket is about
Stop it
Get out
Invitation. See, I have one
I know you've been angry with me
I feel like an orphan
Tomorrow marks your mom's death. Don't say that
Don't you talk about her
When she was here,
you were never home.
I was sick in the winter,
and she carried me to hospital by herself.
I finally got you
Give me back my money
You only started to care after she left
I don't need you
Come out here
Excuse me
What are you doing?
How dare you make trouble here?
It's only right to pay what is owed
Let the scumbag pay me and I'll go
Shut up and get out
I want the pay owed to me and my crew
You have a death wish
Today I do
You won't get away now
Take it easy. I'll pay you tomorrow
No, not tomorrow
Take some cash, I'll get my men to handle it
Today, I said
This won't work
I'll talk to him
Who are you?
I'm just having a drink
Please put out the fire first
I thought it's a major incident
It is, to me —
Turn it off
How many years have you been working?
I've been a laborer for ten years
Did you know there's a song
It was written for me
Turn it off
Let's talk openly here
Get the scumbag into the open for once
Don't go
What are you doing?
One last time: will you pay today?
You've seen it all
I can't pay you today
You're lying again, scumbag
Scumbag
Great move!
My front tooth
This bomb is too amateurish
I've called the police
Did you film that?
I forgot
Get the waiters to help. Call an ambulance
Stop! Out of the way!
You're fine
Where are you going?
To find Wu Jiang
Come, sit
Captain Zhong,
I'll interview you after Boss Niu
The show is about to start
I must go. My clients are waiting
You think everyone here is weird, right?
Drunks tend to make trouble here
All sorts of people show up
Welcome
Two words: traffic jam
You worry too much
I hope that's the case
You're suspicious of everyone
Tonight's show begins now!
Dad
Who are you?
Get into the cage! Don't think of getting out
There are so many of us. Let's attack them
Did you hear that? The men are going to help!
Inside!
How long had I been out? Wu?
Hours. You must have been exhausted
Why did you do this?
Ask why the police took so long, instead
No one called them
Everyone thought, I don't want to be involved
Do you know what you're doing?
Kidnapping's a felony. At least ten years in jail
Where is my daughter?
Miao? Waiting in the hall. She's a good girl
Don't talk about her
She never said her dad's a cop
That makes you a bad dad, and a bad cop
Am I your real target?
Sir, the police are at the door
Ignore them. Wait downstairs
So you called the police
Sorry, I used your phone
I answered a call from your lieutenant
I described the situation. He'll be here soon
You were military, over 20 accomplished years
with local, regional, casework, and SWAT
Penalized once, which you applied for yourself
You've done your homework
Too bad you couldn't handle your family
After all these years, your pay is so low
A year's pay for a tiny house. Was it worth it?
You don't get it. Some things are priceless
Lieutenant is still on his way
No hurry. We'll talk when he arrives.
Tell me your demands now
Don't tell me what to do
Hostages are hurt. The police won't be patient
I'm patient enough
Say what you need to say
Fine. You're my target
Guess why?
I've made many enemies
Last year, car thieves sold their loot nearby
We're short-staffed today,
so let's stick to the plan
There's one outside, five inside
The white-haired one is the leader
Do you know White Hair?
Yue. Everyone here knows him
Freeze! Police!
Stop! Watch them
Yue is known to be vicious
You'll suffer if you try to
capture him by yourself
Please let me go
I'll capture you myself
Just you wait. Your time will come
I'll wait for you
You did this for him, right?
I've heard of those guys
They're ranked too low
Most people use threats to boost egos
I agree
Lieutenant, you're here
I'm chatting with Capt. Zhong. He's fine
I want $80 - 90 million in non-sequential bills
Don't threaten me and talk about difficulty
Wu, I don't know what you want
Make a reasonable demand
Lieutenant has a bad temper
Don't get your hopes up. If we can do it, we will
Take it easy on him
You don't want money
Fine, I'll be frank
I want to see someone
It's easy for you to find people
But my friend lives far away
I haven't seen him in a while
You want to know why? You'll see
Not your call? Why are you wasting my time?
Calm down, let's talk it out
Talk it out?
You're trying to bluff? Don't bother
I forgot you'd been shot
I'm curious. What's it like?
It's like taking a vicious hit with a stick
I couldn't find my shoulder
or this side
Then, this pain that sears through your heart
I've felt that searing pain
What happened to your leg?
It was long ago
The dark green pickup ahead
Pull over
Two suspects are in the truck-
the leader's a cripple.
Should be the one in the back seat
Have you ever kidnapped anyone?
The hostage is in there. Don't shoot
Captain Zhong, we're going
Stay safe
Take care of them
Don't worry
I'll chase them
Call dispatch. We need backup
That's a better attitude
Are you really bad at small talk, or just acting?
Fine. My only demand is to see that person
Not "we'll try." It's a "must."
Confirm in five minutes
We're in no hurry. Let's chat
How are they?
Chao is fine. Hai broke his arm
The backup cars will catch up soon
Don't be afraid. I'm a policeman
Be brave. Mr. Policeman will come soon
Stay put
Where's the other guy?
Too bad we couldn't save the driver
The main perpetrator is still on the loose
Not a bad story, but you guessed wrong
I despise people who kidnap children
The trip shouldn't take more than three hours
Traffic's smooth at this hour
The hostage? Emotionally stable, pragmatic
Sure. I'll be on lookout
Taozi, come up. Keep your eyes on him
Calm down. Play some relaxing music
Let me have a taste
Why? For courage?
Take it easy, this stuff is strong
What's going on?
What's wrong, Niu?
Heart attack
Is there a doctor here?
Do you know how?
Hospital
I'll go with you to the hospital
We must get to a hospital. He can't die
Shut up
I'm a doctor. I must go with him to hospital!
Out of the way!
I'm fine. It comes and goes.
What a phony!
25 YEARS POLICE SERVICE WITH
22 MERITORIOUS AWARDS
HOSTAGE INCIDENT — A KIDNAPPED WOMAN
WAS THREATENED BY KNIFE
Where are they?
Honestly, I'm anxious to see him
I warn you, if my friend isn't here
All the cops you bring will be useless
Procedure isn't my concern
What, you want to come in? No need
I'm a man of my word
Wu Jiang
When my guy arrives,
Wu Jiang,
the hostages will be fine
come here
Except Captain Zhong
Wu Jiang
Listen! You won't get out
but you can make other requests
Open up
What do you want?
I need the restroom
Anything else?
Boss Wu, may I interview you?
Sure
Get out
Dad, you're here!
Are you okay?
Sorry, Dad, forgive me
I dressed up like that to upset you
I didn't show I cared. You're much prettier now
Put this away for me
Be careful, Dad
Where can I get a phone?
They took all our phones
They're on the table in the hall
But…
Hurry up!
I'm Zhu Nan, host of the Life Channel
I risked my life for this Exclusive
at a kidnapping
Here's the mastermind behind this case
Can I say that?
You must have a great story,
Boss Wu. Say hello
Hands off. I want a drink. So what?
Let's continue
Do you feel that
I'm insane for doing this?
No. Why are you committing this crime?
I just did what no one else dares
Let me go
I'm not done with the interview. Look —
Are you done?
You were nice to me to get my dad here
If you must say that
You're using me
I'm not a good guy,
your dad's not a good cop.
Neither of us
can make you feel safe.
This is Zhong Wen. I stole a cell phone
Are you safe now?
I'm fine. I'm hiding
What's going on?
There are over a dozen hostages
There were four suspects. I got rid of one
The boss, Wu, is the leader.
He has a knockoff 64
What are his demands?
He wants to see a prison detainee
What's the name?
Wei Xiaofu
Chief has agreed and is making arrangements
We've made a plan with snipers and SWAT
Are conditions suited for a SWAT assault?
The bar is two stories tall. The hostages are
in a cage, watched by the three suspects
If we attack now
It'll be too dangerous for the hostages
They may have other weapons
Understood
We may attack at any time
Boss, that guy escaped
I have to go
Find him! Useless fool
He's here
Is that all you've got?
I bet you still can't handle him
Brother Zhong, you're amazing
But aren't you worried about your daughter?
Miao said, you used to be her hero
How'd you become a deserter?
Let's talk
In your own words, let's talk openly
Dad, don't worry about me
I wanted her in my "law of the jungle" experiment
Don't come out, Dad
Sure, you must think in your dark corner
but fingertips
don't grow back
Stop
Dad, don't come
Don't come
Let her go. Target me
Now you're like a good father, but it's too late
Stop
I'm fine
Give him room. So, you're here on a case
Where were you? Were we in any danger?
Lady! Stop saying stupid things
What did I say?
You don't stop talking! So annoying!
With this scoop, she'll be promoted tomorrow
None of your business
I'm fine
Let me go. Do you think I can escape?
I'm sure you will. You'll be fine
From my experience, he'll release us soon
In all kidnappings —
They'd be killing the hostages now
It's usually about money
I know Wu well. He's rich.
It's more than that
Is there a back door here?
- There's just this door
- Boss designed the bar.
He sealed the back door
What does your father do?
He's a policeman
Such hatred, beating him so badly.
Must be over a girl
Don't worry. We don't know him
I know you
The drug store
The thief- he stole from me
That's right
I didn't recognize you without your uniform
She was there that day, too
That's Lan, now a manager at the nightclub
And the famous Boss Niu.
We were all there
Something happened inside
Captain Zhong is in there. What happened?
We're together again. That's destiny
Cut the nonsense
Comrade Policeman, what's your issue with Wu?
Talk it out with him. Why involve us?
Destiny, my foot
Chief Zhang, a high official
I'm so honored. They're all fine
You want to see them, right?
Look. They're lively and well-fed
I am Police Chief Zhang Guomin. Don't worry
I'll do my best to help you
Go ahead, Boss Wu. We'll wait
Film this area and the people
My friend isn't here. You're unreliable
Give us more time. Several reasons —
I don't care. You have five minutes
Show some respect. Five more minutes
If he's not here in ten minutes, I'll get violent
Please come, Boss Wu
I want to talk to you
Go ahead
Alone
Our usual place
Zhong, what more is there to say?
You just want us.
Why involve innocents?
I need more chips
And how do you know they're innocent?
What do want to say?
You created an elaborate plot
Yes
But you can't win with your way
We'll see
You need a middleman.
I can help
A cop helping a criminal. What a joke
What do you want to know from that case?
I don't want to discuss that now
Then we'll wait for Wei Xiaofu
You ask lots of questions. My turn
You cops don't see much of this, do you?
We see all kinds
How many cases have you been on?
Lots. Over 100 a year
How many cops die in a year?
About 400 die in the line of duty in China
And how many hostages?
Accidents happen
Will there be an accident today?
I don't want casualties today
Including me?
Yes. Every life is precious
I stopped believing that long ago
Although you've done your homework
Zhong, you sneaked into my secret chamber
So you know some of my secrets
You can see this is beyond negotiation
So we have nothing to talk about
I see you're a boxer
I've got some time. Let me tell you a story
You asked what happened to my leg
As a boy, I went overseas with my father
He killed himself due to gambling debts.
I had to repay them
The only skill I had there
was fighting
I had always fought
on others' behalf
Fighting over who's more vicious
I never had a worthy opponent
You risk your life for money
but life is so worthless and fleeting
I swore to stop once I repaid the debts
So during that time I was like a crazy man
I finally repaid all the debts
but I didn't want to do anything else
It was all about
money, life and death
So I continued
You may be killed by your opponent at any time
My nickname was Spider. I never lost,
but a spider is an insignificant bug
Illegal boxers are the same
I knew your men from boxing
The foreigners were the best in their countries
The shorter one, Pichon, is a regular champion
Everyone wanted us to fight
I know it's inevitable
Before the fight, I felt the bets were too big
The better fighter you are, the more you're worth
and the closer to death you are
What happened at that fight?
In the beginning we were even
Then he got the upper hand
Next round, he'll let you win
The two bosses arranged everything
I found out just before the final round
It was a fight to the death
Next round, kill him
Boss didn't know my heart was soft that day
I'd decided to return to China after that fight
and bring some fighters to help me
Poor Pichon
only knew he was to lose
I told him he had been fixed to die
Disobeying the boss meant death
So several of us escaped and hid for a time
We're lucky to be here, alive
Why did you suddenly go soft?
As you say, you don't get it
You've lived quite a life
But one can't treat another's life lightly
Everyone has the right to live
To live well
You know why I'm still alive?
You came back to China five years ago
just for the drugstore robbery
For the truth
The world is full of lies
Is this the only way to find the truth?
I should say, it's my way
Don't sit
Amazing! You almost succeeded
This bulletproof glass is worth every penny
It's a police rescue effort, you'd do the same
Your plan was good, snipers and SWAT together
but I'm no amateur thief
Why didn't you let me sit?
I wanted to save you
You want to help me and save me
He's on screen
- There were gunshots
- Chief Zhang, I'm still alive
Your Captain Zhong? He also lives
Cut the nonsense. Let me see Wei Xiaofu
Why did you get me here so late at night?
Get him in here to see me
You're kidding! I don't want to go in
It's against the rules to bring a prisoner here
Please know we must guarantee his safety
You're tricking me
You must see Wei Xiaofu, right?
Let me break it down for you
You're armed, took hostages and are at a stalemate
I can kill some hostages
And I'll make sure you'll never see Wei
The police will find another way to attack
What are you saying?
Only I can help you to see him
He trusts me. I can try to bring him in
I'll talk to him, and you free the hostages.
Think on it
Life is like a cocktail
What might the next sip taste like?
I've filmed everything you told me to
Trust my skills
And if you don't come back?
Trust me, I will
But you must guarantee Wei's safety
You dare to trust my guarantee?
Trust is mutual
Take two people. Your daughter stays
I said, all the hostages
Impossible. I must keep some
I know which ones. Let the rest go
No
No deal
Three
You can only bring three hostages
Put down your gun
You two have hot tempers
Here. You two fight.
You win, I promise you can bring people out
You lose, go alone
Dad, you're hurt
You can't defeat him. Don't fight
You're not young anymore
It's embarrassing to lose. Never mind
Why? Fight! You're a cop!
Good prevails over evil
Take us out
Fine
Agreed
Comrade Police, it's all on you! Go, go!
Be careful, Dad
In a few seconds, you won't be able to get up
This fight is too hard
We can't benefit from his loss. Pray for him
Captain Zhong, there's no shame in giving up
Stop playing the hero, Dad
Zhong, give up if you can't handle it
Dad, stop! You can't beat them
Get up, Cop
Go, Mr. Policeman!
Beat him
How suspenseful
He is good
Stop, Dad
Stay down or you'll die
Stop fighting
We don't want to go out anymore
Cop, we're moved. You tried your best
Mr. Policeman, we don't want to go anymore
Stop, don't get up
Please stop fighting, I'm begging you
Don't let go! Hang on tight!
He can't last! Harder!
Careful, Cop
Cop, let go! Watch out
Let go. You won
You won
Give me your scarf
Don't lock up again! Aren't we all going?
Here's an idea
I'll take my daughter out first
When Wei Xiaofu comes in, she may go
I'm not going anywhere
I'm staying with my dad till the end
Don't regret it
As agreed, I'll give you the man you want
Bring three people with you first
Why change now? This is too much
It's leverage in case you don't come back
I'll release them just before Wei comes in
That's not a change. Choose the hostages
Wu, I really can't go on.
I'll forfeit the money
My health is poor. May I be one of them?
Wu, if you think I'm useful to you I'll stay
I'll go out to film, okay?
Have you decided?
The two injured hostages,
and him
You
Me? Just me?
No, I'm staying with my girlfriend
Only you dared make a move.
We need more men like you
I'll make an exception. Go together
Hurry
You're a casualty: you lost a tooth
Just me?
We're inseparable
I owe him money, I need to pay him outside
You'd have enough to pay if you'd drink less
Captain Zhong, you must return
Zhong,
You have ten minutes. I'm very punctual
Hostages are coming! We need a stretcher
There are four more
This is a suspect- cuff him
You saved my life
Cheers for the Policeman!
There are more people back here
Are you badly hurt
I'm okay. It's minor,
Chief Zhang
Check out these suspects
Three suspects and three guns
Where are they located?
In the main hall, with 16 hostages
Physical conditions of the hostages?
All right
But they can't last much longer mentally
Lieutenant
I felt you took action too soon just now
Captain Zhong, the suspect wants to talk to you
I'll tell you everything I know
Speak
I did this for money
I never imagined he'd make such a big deal
Please don't go in. You'll never get back out
They told me they
don't expect to get out alive
That's all I know
Thank you, sir
These are from the building's management
We have eight more minutes
It differs from the blueprint-
the windows are sealed
This door
is made with 25cm-thick steel panels
The walls are 50cm thick
There was a back door but it's been sealed
He's from building management
How could you allow all these changes?
It's private property, out of our jurisdiction
Fine. I'll call if I need you
He's really built himself a fortress
Over here?
You can go in from the roof here and be hidden
Seven more minutes
This is a homemade bomb with a timer
The wiring is complex, with multiple detonators
He means to blow up everyone, including himself
There are so many hostages
The best way to save them
is for me to bring Wei in
Trading two people for 12.
Has he agreed to go in?
I was on the phone with my mother
She wants me to behave, to try for early release
Please help us
It's too risky
Your safety is a concern
It may be dangerous, but we'll try our best
Help us. We'll apply to reduce your sentence
I still feel unsafe. Forget it
We can't force you to take a risk like this
Thanks for taking care of my mom all these years
I promised years ago that I would
Everyone on our team donated to your family
I'm touched
Here's the information on the suspects
Bin, a Thai
Pichon, a Filipino
Wu Jiang returned five years ago, as a Thai
The victim Mei's parents were divorced
The mother died,
a brother went overseas with the father
I think Wu Jiang is Mei's brother
He's not asking for Wei Xiaofu's release
Three of the hostages were witnesses back then
I think he wants to know what happened
Cops, criminals, witnesses: all here
It's been five years
You have four more minutes
Let's talk method
We'll dress as Zhong and Wei. SWAT stands by
First, cut open the roof by laser
The door opens, we attack from above and below
It's hard to attack through the crack in the door
This way, we get their attention
Roof-cutting time varies.
We'll endanger the hostages
Hostage safety comes first
Let me negotiate again
You can't-
lives are at stake. Talk is useless
This is too major.
It calls for a hard-core assault
Assaults are most risky now
And you're not taking a risk by going back in?
Keeping my promise will build trust.
There's still a chance to talk
You've been talking for six hours
Some negotiations last months, you know
No
We got injured hostages out with talking
Lieutenant was looking out for you
Trading two for 12, good deal
See? As Lieutenant, I should go in,
not you
It's my case, the same one as five years ago
I'm most suited to go in
Besides, my daughter's inside
Shouldn't he stay away for that reason?
Stop arguing
Zhong should go back in
But get a substitute for Wei
Wu will know
at a glance
Chief Zhang, please come here
Repeat what I say. "Three more minutes."
The thug says —
What?
Boss Wu says, three more minutes
"If he doesn't come, you will die"
"If he doesn't come,
I will die"
"No joke"
"No joke." He's really not joking, please help!
Less than three minutes now
Chief Zhang, Wei Xiaofu has agreed to go in
Reason?
One, to repay our favor
Two, he doesn't want to be evil
He's a real man
Make a small opening to save time. Go!
Yes, sir! Run
Bomb Squad, give Wei a suit
The Lieutenant is in charge.
It's on you
Guoqiang, this is your sniper operation
Yes, sir
As you say, your own safety is key
The sniper needs to set up.
Talk and buy more time
On my orders. It's already loaded
Don't be angry.
I didn't want you to bear this alone
If possible, let me talk a bit more
If I can control the scene,
don't let the sniper shoot
You win
You can still smile?
These clothes are safe and warm
But it weighs over 35kgs
Does this count as a merit?
I might get a reduced sentence for this?
I can still care for my mom in this lifetime
The roof-cutting team is in place
Hurry
Say something, Captain Zhong
Are you being brave for your daughter?
How is it your daughter's here?
If she wasn't here, would you be going back in?
What's wrong with her?
When the hostages come out we'll go in
Once we go in, will we get out alive?
I promise to keep you alive as long as I live
What if you die first?
Just kidding. I'm a nervous wreck
Once inside, stay next to me and don't move
May I speak?
Speak the truth, not nonsense
What did you stuff into my clothes just now?
That's nonsense
Arms
You should get a job at Airport Security
Again, bullshit
Go
Police
Police! Hurry, help! What's going on?
Talk, don't hit.
We're in positions of power
These sons of bitches
Where's my daughter?
Dad, I'm here
I'm fine.
You take care
Help! Police! I'm afraid of heights
Your outfit is awesome. Can you get us out?
What is all this?
What's tied around our necks?
Can you tell me what's going on?
It looks like a bomb. Is it real?
It's real
We're missing one person
Maybe there's a still a hostage inside
Good job, Captain Zhong
You really brought him in here
I'm a man of my word.
I want to evacuate the hostages
Your crimes are not serious
We can explain everything away
I can prove you stopped voluntarily
You can't help me. It's my time now
18 more minutes
What's he wearing? What a ridiculous getup
We must do our best to protect him
This is my turf. You can't protect him
You guaranteed his safety
His temporary safety
In this getup, I don't recognize him
Remove his helmet
Helmet off
Stay back
Don't play this game with me.
They despise me
I'm not afraid. He thinks I'll cause evil
Stay back
I don't want to wear this
It's stuffy. I'm dizzy
I'm not afraid.
Wei Xiaofu
Isn't that what's-his-name?
How come it's him?
Put on your helmet
Relax, Captain Zhong. I'll be with you now
The police forced you to come, right?
You're wrong. I came willingly
You've rounded everyone up.
The truth will come out
I've been waiting for this day
Big brother, when will you be back?
Everyone knows this girl, right?
Now you know
she's my baby sister
We were separated. I found her five years ago
She's the meaning of my life
I came back,
but didn't see her
I finally found a way to meet with you
I don't know what happened
five years ago
But you were all there.
Let's talk
It's been so long. What if I can't remember?
The bomb is remote-controlled.
It may help you think
Let me think. I should remember
Let's begin
When we're done I can go back out, right?
Someone won't make it out today
Then what can I do to make sure I will?
Don't mess with me, but that's hard for you
Say your piece. Hurry
Who should speak first?
Cutting the roof takes time
The team is worried about disturbing those below
You're right. My first idea won't work
Just play for time
Let me start
Wait, Zhong
Remove your communication devices
so I won't have to
We're trying other ways to get in
We can launch the assault in 15 minutes
Till then, you're in charge of the inside
Wei Xiaofu, you start
It all started with me
That night, almost at this time
A few customers were at the drugstore. I went in
I want to do something for my mom
She's in poor health.
But I can't afford tonics
My mistake was being too nosy
I'll give you 20 extra
I wanted to ask whose wallet that was
No way-
who're you trying to kid?
You were drunk, what do you know?
I was drinking, but my mind was clear
Hand it over
What is this?
I just picked it up from the floor
You stole it
I just picked it up
Do you know who I am?
You dare to steal my stuff? Go to hell
I really did pick it up
Wait.
Don't move.
And then?
Then…
Quickly
I'm clearest on what happened next
Go to hell!
I really picked it up
Wait.
Don't move
This is mine. Did you pick it up, too?
Does he have any more?
Two boxes
I'm a man of principles. I convince with reason
Were you being reasonable?
I call it as I see it
That's called hitting me when I'm down
What?
I remember every word you said that night
This box costs tens of thousands
You have good taste
Shall we handle it ourselves
or call the police?
Handle it or call police
You can't tell? He's poor
Call the police
Sure. I'll call them now
Don't call the police
I was afraid it'd turn into a big deal
That's how it became a big deal
Who dares to call the police? Don't!
Stop, if you want to live
What do you mean? What do you want?
Give it to me
Give it over. Now
Hello, Police?
Thinking back I really was confused
I should have run. They wouldn't have stopped me
But I —
Give me the phone
We're being robbed!
The drug store by Gu Lou
Give it to me! Let go!
When my sister was thrown to the ground
You just watched
He was closest, and he ran.
What could I have done?
Of course I wanted to approach, but they left
I'm not experienced with one-on-one
I wasn't scared, but he dragged me away
And then?
I'll tell the story for you
I was off-duty and passed by
Comrade Police, something's happening there
Don't move. Stay away
He stole something. She called the police
The thief, he —
Step out
Stop. Don't come over
Call dispatch, notify local police
I was thinking then —
I'll tell it for you
The criminals may kill the hostages
Don't move! Back off
Captain Zhong has the power to —
One more step and I'll kill her
- easily and decisively kill you
You're being ridiculous
If that were true, it wouldn't be a problem
All life is precious.
Without understanding —
Captain Zhong is used to talking it out
There's no rush. Let's talk it out
But Zhong was distracted.
His wife was
run over by a car
and being treated in hospital
The hospital and his daughter kept calling him
I get it
Why are you on the phone?
I'll be right there
Hang up
Wei Xiaofu gets out of control
Are you tricking me? What do you want?
Do you think I'm bluffing?
And the rest is history
LIVE
Captain Zhong, tell us what's going on inside
You tell great stories.
How can you be sure?
Were you there? How do you know everything?
Are you done speaking?
It's my turn
Miao will tell you, but she doesn't know much
That night, my wife was running a high fever
I was working and couldn't take her to hospital
She forbidden her to go
She took a cab alone, and the accident happened
I ignored my phone,
but felt something was wrong
I felt rushed that day
Captain Zhong was so patient that day
Take your time, we'll talk everything out
When I called back I found out what happened
By the time I rushed to the hospital
it was too late
I wanted to explain to my daughter, but
she wouldn't listen or forgive me
I tried to convince him to stop
I took the drugs for my mom
Let's clarify everything and do what must be done
Let the girl go.
It would be bad if she got hurt
We'll think of a way to help your mother
Will that do?
So can't you let me go?
Please!
Wei was agitated.
Your sister was quite calm
I didn't know what to do. Suddenly —
Accidents always happen suddenly
Fine. Let me continue
It was chaos outside. Your sister said, softly,
"Kill me."
What did she say?
She spoke very softly. I thought I'd misheard
What did you say?
You heard it, too
I heard her cry out, once
That was her second cry
What did you say?
"Kill me"
What are you doing?
It wasn't me, I didn't move
Ambulance
She injured her carotid artery and bled to death
This is the truth you wanted
So, my sister killed herself
Of course. I used my knife as a bluff
I never guessed she'd grab it,
it scared me
Why should I believe you?
I believe him
You weren't even there
She was troubled.
See what drug she bought
What drug?
What drug did she buy?
Manager, I'm afraid you must tell us
What are you doing?
Testing for leaks
You're paying for this
Sleeping pills
Prescription?
100 pills
By law, it's sold by prescription only
I'm a man of principle
And then?
I'll take over from here
The law is dead. People are alive
A warning:
to pull a bluff, just take a few
Can I buy them or not?
Sure,
but it doesn't cost this much
I'll give you a few more pills, then
Coming! One moment, please
Are you done?
Yes
Continue-
What? They're all the same
You broke up?
It's always that
I've taken them before. It's horrible
I had my stomach pumped. Vomited like mad
What else did you say?
Nothing
You're no angel.
I remember what you said next
What true love?
I don't trust anyone any more
There are so many men
We're not the same kind of people
What do you mean?
Playing innocent
You're so blind!
Just go and die
When did I say all that?
You said it
Wu, I never did.
I tried to talk her out of it
Your sister died because of what she said
You sold her the drug knowing she was depressed
I can prove he sold her the drug
They're working together
Shut up!
Calm down.
They did find sleeping pills on her
Does buying sleeping pills equal suicide?
Extreme agitation may cause dire actions
I know why
Watch what you say
Half of female suicides are for a man
The other half are for several men
Boss Wu
I say so because I've done it
I realize now it's not worth it, but many don't
Listen to me
I completely understand how you feel
It's hard to live alone abroad for so many years
Your sister was your only family,
the light of your life
She died, so you came here to investigate
or take it out on someone. That's natural
Go on. You have five more minutes
You planned this
to punish her killer, right?
Regardless of method,
you have the wrong target
You mean, you're all innocent
What Lan said makes sense
Explain yourself
There's something you should know
Your sister was pregnant at the time
She sees you as a parent
she must have told you
Stop
When the M.E. discovered her pregnancy,
we investigated
She had no marriage record,
and the father never came
See? Men are not worth it!
No one here is who you're looking for
Even if you find him, it could become a story
You're trying to confuse me
I want to clear your mind
Even so, you're out of time
Look, you've made it like a trial today
Each one of you is guilty
The law has already —
You just watched as my sister died?
You, a cop,
I admit I made mistakes
It was your knife.
Does ten years in jail pay for her life?
What do you want from me?
Niu, Lan, you stood by while she died.
You're killers
What did I do?
No one minds others' business any more
At least let me know why I have to die
I helped her. I tried to talk her out of it
She didn't trust anyone. It's not my fault
Manager
Put on your helmet
For a small profit, you let my sister die
I'm not the only one.
And she didn't die from the drugs
No one shoots!
Tell them to put down their guns
Don't force me to shoot
Stop, Wu.
You can still live if you surrender now
No shooting
Fine. Stop shouting or I'll shoot you
This is a great outfit
Drop your guns.
Behind you, Dad
Life's like a cocktail-
Gotta drink it to know
if it was bitter or sweet
You're hard to handle
Meet Kun,
bartender and bomb maker
My leg
What do you want?
Don't worry. This is fake.
The real ones come later
- None of you can hide from them
- Please! Spare us!
Why didn't you just kill me?
Glad you understand.
I'm saving you
But it's over
Not yet
You're my sister's boyfriend, right?
What kind of joke is this?
I found half a picture among her things
I remember your tattoo
You've changed it,
but I still know it
Really?
Since Zhong has said so, I'll tell you
Yes,
I am he
Interesting. I thought you escaped long ago
Yet you work and make bombs for me
Why are you pointing your gun at me?
I want to see how you avenge Mei's death
Good for you. We're really all here
I was a coward then
But now I know I'll be last to go,
I fear nothing
Talk fast. You have two minutes to live
Wu, you had a part in her death, too
What?
She told me
you didn't want her to be with me
But I genuinely fell in love
with her
She got pregnant and told you
But you said you'd come to kill me.
She was so hurt
There was no hope for me,
so I broke up with her
That night, we had a big fight
She stormed out, crying.
I ran after her
Even that last time we looked at each other
we never knew how fragile life would be
I lived for revenge.
Now I know how much she hated me
What one didn't treasure, one may not salvage
Right, Wu?
Come on, you've got the gun
Wu
I wronged her the most
I most deserve to die
Get down
Miao!
Dad, I'm here
Dad I'm here
You missed the first train
I could have gotten on, but there's no point
You destroyed my plan
Your plan? Why must you harm my daughter?
Everyone's lives are worthless except Mei's
No one has the right to
take others' lives in anger
Stay away
My sister didn't deserve to die
So you have to hurt more people?
If she were alive, would she want this?
But she's dead.
She's not coming back
Then you should treasure life even more
Dad
Let my daughter go
This is the same scene as five years ago
Shoot. You get a merit. I get to die.
Win-win
Of course, there may be accidents
I beg you, let my daughter go
If I do, will it be over?
You must pay for your actions
Throw the gun over
Don't obey. Don't let him have the gun
Wu Jiang
You're right. Someone must pay
I'll do anything for my sister
Sadly, now I know I'll never escape
One last game, Zhong. You and me.
There's one bullet left.
Shoot before the next train
Shoot me and I'll stab her in the neck
Shoot yourself and she lives
Dad, don't believe him
Shoot me and I'll stab her neck
Shoot yourself and she lives
Don't shoot, I'll kill her anyway
Who lives? Who dies? It's up to you
I was late then because I was saving someone else
I was wrong to blame you
Unfortunately, I failed there, too
Zhong, the train's coming
I'll take responsibility for your sister's death
My daughter
has nothing to do with this
Please don't hurt her, no matter what
I want to see you be that kind of father
I'll give you ten seconds before I shoot
No, Dad
Child,
I've been a bad father.
I had no time for you,
and made you feel vulnerable.
Sorry
But… for you
I'll do anything
One…
Sorry. I removed the bullet just now
I would do anything for my sister
A small trick
Zhong, I admire you.
Go wait for me on the platform
Dad, I can't go
Go, get someone! This is an order! Now!
Run
Is there anything else, Zhong?
I have to arrest you
Say I disappeared.
I'd do anything for my sister
I'd die for her
Wu Jiang!
Get out of my way
It's not worth it
I'll take the blame
Ignore me, as if I were a bug
Don't worry about me
Give up. You can still live
Goodbye
Down the well-lit street
A cold spell suddenly attacks
Distant warmth cannot
Relieve nearby sorrows
Am I just going with the flow?
As long as the story continues
I must remain on defense
Loyal to my own battle
Hurry, get a doctor!
Hang in there
You threw the switch?
Yes. Perfect timing, right?
What can I use for my rescue
When love has drained away
Who can keep whom
Who will my heart wait for
What can I use for my rescue
Love is like a poison arrow
Who can protect whom
Who can make love last forever
Wait
Good one, brother
That hurt
All the hostages are safe,
no penalty for you
How's Wei Xiaofu?
He's a tough kid
Take care of your father
Dad, you're great
I'm very ordinary
Stop being humble, cop
Take it easy on me from now on
Wu Jiang says, you win this round
This is for you. He says goodbye
Double slate
You gonna clap it on my nose?
Watch his foot!
Why didn't we use a fake knife?
Sorry, Jackie
Go again
Fake it-
we're shooting a movie, Bro
Then go and fight
Stop
Jackie
Your ear
It looks funny again
Your nose
Let's do another take
Go again
Again
Wait
This is no good
It's so hard
Can we do this?
This won't work
So you want this
This way, then
It's so difficult!
He's just not a good choice
Look at the… $%… %&!@&…
I'm speaking Portuguese
Just look at the company you keep —
Look at the people he's with
Slap me
Please slap me
I beg you, slap me
Jackie
You're just not good company —
the company… (garbled)
You're not in good company —
Who is good company —
You shouldn't be in company —
He's with different people every day —
I quit
I'll refund my pay
Stand still
Hello
Say it boldly
He's afraid
then he &%&…!!
He's on screen
What have you done?
Jackie
Don't
I didn't
Go
Now you're talking like a good father
I have another line, go again
Sorry
I'll punch you later
Damn
It won't break
That really hurts
Go again
Yes!
Jackie broke it
I've proven I can break it
You said it's unbreakable,
So I had to break it
Especially with Jaycee Fang here
I must prove it to him
Why won't it open?
What's going on?