Is anyone outside?
Please help!
Security!
Police!
Is anyone outside?
Sameerana!
Sameerana, wake up!
A boy suffering looking
at the helpless girl..
Looking at his efforts to save her..
A girl is fighting for her life back.
These two look like they
are related for years..
..but that isn't true.
These two were strangers
till 18 hours ago.
Yes, you heard it right.
Not just accidents, but sometimes people
meeting for the first time can be so dramatic.
That begs the question, who are these two?
How,
why and where did they meet each other?
What lead them to this accident?
This may seem unclear to you.
To make it clear, lets go into the story.
Wahh!
You look like beauty looking at a mirror.
Even if the guy is a Mr.Universe.
It will be difficult to please me.
After recent weight loss,
even I can't take my beauty.
I should get my aura cleansed immediately.
Hey Sammi!
What happened?
Only you can compete me with my beauty.
You looked like a heroine when
you were young. Didn't you?
Madam!
I placed all the saplings here.
Saplings?
What are all these saplings for Mom?
I thought if I can give
pure air to the world,
you would be a blessed
with happy and long life.
So, starting from tomorrow,
till your next birthday
I am going to plant ten thousand saplings.
Sammi! Oh my god.
Go get a net.
Get it fast.
Go fast!
Take this.
Can't you be little careful dear.
It almost lost its life.
I was also the same in the morning.
Struggled to breathe like this fish.
You are savior of both our lives,
Wonder Woman!
Stop with the silly banter.
Don't forget your inhaler refills.
I worry a lot about you than you do.
You never care about yourself.
I will be careful Mom.
Okay.
Get a friend for this fish.
Okay. Bye!
Auto!
Where to drop?
DSL Mall
Get in.
- Bye sir.
- Bye!
Hello Grandpa.
- I'm here sis.
- Hi bro
How many rounds today Granpa?
He finished five.
How many rounds did you finish?
Me? Just two.
Just two?
You are Young and energetic
should finish minimum 10 rounds.
I will finish by end of the day.
Tell me this Pavan,
Heard you got an chance to
record a music album in Spain.
Why should you leave such
an opportunity for me?
I am not at all happy with your decision.
There's a lot of life for you
to explore and experience.
Listen to me.
Email them mentioning that
you are accepting the offer
Don't worry. I will take care of myself.
Grandpa, I can let go of anything for you.
This matter ends here.
I can't let anything happen to you.
You are my Hero. That's it.
We have better things to do.
Tomorrow is your birthday.
It will be a grand celebration.
I have few shopping plans for that.
So don't disturb me asking to
send mails and check files.
Bro. messaged list of items required.
Get them on your way home.
I got it sis.
Grandpa. Are you okay?
Why are you roaming on
roads when you are blind.
Grandpa, are you okay?
Sis, take him home safely.
I will be back in a while.
Who are you? What do you want?
Where's the girl sitting here?
That girl?
She got down because of traffic.
Why are you driving so rashly?
Its common aggression
being a Mahesh babu fan.
Even Mahesh babu doesn't
encourage such rash driving.
She will also pay the price
for her rash behaviour.
Chill bro!
Happy green day brother.
- Happy Green day.
- Thank you.
Let me fly away, like a streak of colours.
Listen to the tune, like a breeze of song.
New dreams are revealed like full moon.
Caressed heart, melts like melody.
A colourful sky welcomes me.
Overwhelmed with music..
..my heart is elated.
My Heart is elated.
A Parrot, overflowing with colours..
Pollinates the garden and makes it heaven.
A twist in the tune,
rings a bell in your heart.
When a tune takes off,
walk turns to dance.
Its all over the place, stay in my lap.
My heart is like you are, little crazy.
A word in epic and a tune in heart..
..mix these two and its amazing.
Wanting to cross the skies..
..whatever unfolds is our way to freedom.
Every tune born, becomes a song..
..creating new life,
this is the truth of life.
My Heart is elated.
Let me fly away, like a streak of colours.
Listen what the tune has to say,
like a breeze of song.
New dreams are revealed like full moon.
Caressed heart, melts like melody.
A colourful sky welcomes me.
Overwhelmed with music..
My Heart is elated.
My Heart is elated!
Oh heck! How did I forget that?
Can you open the doors please?
I need to go out.
Hello? I need to go out.
Why did you press for basement?
Press stop. I will get off next.
Guess he can't hear.
Just one slap on your face.
Everything seems to go wrong.
What does it really mean huh?
Are you head strong? or Is my hand strong?
You a psycho?
Who the heck are you? Why did you slap me?
Hey, why are you whining?
Is it paining?
Won't you think of other person's pain?
You have a reason when you feel pain.
But you can't understand when
others feel the pain. Am I right?
Hello. I think you are
taking me for someone else.
Seems you are drunk in the
morning and babbling non sense.
You got slapped for your rash behaviour
and you go on praising your beauty.
Does your peanut brain know
anything called common sense?
You are not even qualified
to talk about beauty.
If there's anyone who
can talk about beauty.
Its her.
Noobs should be aware of legends.
Shut up you mental.
Look at you, Chocolate on your face,
fish in your hand..
You are the mental one of us.
Oh god, did I call you mental?
So sorry for undermining you.
You deserve godly curses.
Don't feel bad.
God, such a drama queen.
Are you getting angry?
You slapped me taking me for someone else.
I don't even know who you are?
Hmm,
do stray dogs need a reason to bite people?
Yeah, stray dogs don't need
a reason to bark as well.
Heyy! Where are you going?
- To check the lift sir.
- We can take care of it. Don't go there.
Its nerve wracking not knowing
which corner another bomb is planted.
- Listen to me sir.
- Don't interfere. Go to your duty.
- Sir, please..
- Just leave.
- Gangadhar where are you?
You have to be at the spot with seniors.
- I am checking the elevator sir.
Mall security will take care of the lift.
You need to be here to evacuate the place.
We need you here. Come soon.
Okay sir. I'll be there.
Hello. Is anybody there? Hello!
Please! Security! Open the doors.
Security.
- Oh lord.
Hello. Anybody here?
- Oh Princess is crying for help.
Stewards are waiting outside
for your orders to respond.
Just shut up.
You'll be behind bars after I go outside.
Hello. First you get out of here vampire.
You are such a stress buster Sunny.
If not for you, my brain would get fried.
Very difficult to handle.
Hello. Is anyone outside.
- Is anyone outside?
- Is anyone outside.?
Try crying in local language first,
then try national languages.
That might help us better.
Are you annoyed?
Helloo. Anyone there?
REPORTER - Today at uppal mall,
a bomb blast took place.
There were no casualities since
the bomb blasted in a corner.
But there was some collateral damage.
Security has evacuated the entire mall
safely. Mall is temporarily shutdown.
Investigation is on track.
Heck.
Oh lord.
It feels like begging for
money by distributing pamplets.
HELP!
Can someone please help.
Mom, why do you like bangles so much?
- Not liking, I was mad crazy about them.
Bangles and Flowers were always
my company when I was with your dad.
This time around,
I will get bangles for you.
Wah. Audience might've lost their
mind seeing your bangles idea.
Bro, did you ever imagine
what would a lady Einstein do?
This is all because of you.
Can't you do something to get out of
here rather than doing commentary.
Uh huh!
Thanks for the beat.
Hey! Honeybee eyed, Fishy thorned lady..
why the agitation..
Hey! Don't explode around
when I speak the truth..
Your beauty doesn't make you special..
come down a few steps.
Your beauty is miniscule,
compared to entire universe.
Hey! Honeybee eyed, Fishy thorned lady..
why the agitation.
Hey! Don't explode around
when I speak the truth..
Lord of creation didn't do a mistake..
He took a lot away for your beauty.
Mask called Face is not of much value.
Listen to me, don't go by it.
Whoever marries you,
goes from fry pan to fire.
Real beauty is on the inside.
Have a look inside.
You wouldn't forgive a mirror,
if it goes heavy when you look at it.
You go in search of
praise in the morning..
..otherwise you can't wake up.
I wouldn't bargain when
I am speaking the truth.
Love with beauty is an ailment,
better don't go there.
Hey! Honeybee eyed, Fishy thorned lady..
why the agitation.
Hey! Don't explode around
when I speak the truth..
Your beauty doesn't make you special..
come down a few steps.
Your beauty is miniscule,
compared to entire universe.
What is it now?
Go bang the door until
what you ate is digested.
I should bang the hell out of you.
Do you recall why you slapped
me in the first place.
Recall?
I was fully aware of what I was doing.
I intentionally followed you
and consciously slapped you.
But why?
What the heck have I done to you?
- Didn't you come here by a auto?
- So?
- Will you slap me for coming by an auto?
You moron.
This Fish has better brains than you.
- Is it true?
While coming here,
you almost hit an old man.
What did you yell at him?
You didn't have a minimum courtesy
of letting an old man cross the road.
Instead you were shouting at him.
- Grandpa. Are you okay?
Why are you roaming on
roads when you are blind.
He is my Grandpa.
He brought us up like a Mother.
How can I tolerate such an act upon him.
- Did you slap me for that?
- What do you mean?
If that's your reason,
I will have to slap you twice.
At whom do you think I was shouting at?
Sorry.
Why are you roaming on
roads when you are blind.
- Why are you driving rashly?
- Jai Mahesha.
Auto guy took off quickly,
so I couldn't come and apologise.
Story, narration and performance.
You pulled it off well.
Hello. Excuse me. I am not so cheap.
I would never disrespect elders.
My mom raised me well.
I said sorry then and there.
You can confirm it with the lady with you.
I don't know the relation of that lady
with you. But she will vouch for me.
To sis?
Forgive me for what happened.
Its already too late.
My mom would be worried about me.
I feel some lift fuse must have gone off.
They should've solved the issue by now.
If we bang the doors hard,
security guard might come our way.
Please help.
You are talking as if you've
come to your friends place.
I don't think you
understood what's going on.
If a fuse goes off,
lift will not behave like this.
You've been banging the door for an hr.
Not a single person has come for rescue.
From the moment we came, Police are
roaming around with sniffer dogs.
I guess, it could be a bomb blast.
We don't know the blast intensity,
since we are in basement.
Bomb!
A bomb blast?
Don't be so analytical.
You are speaking dangerously.
Come on.
Fearing will not make facts false.
I think my guess is right.
I've seen news about this
report from Intelligence report.
I don't think you are right.
You know what. You really look beautiful.
Tell me something about
myself that I don't know.
You really have peanut brains.
You are such a jerk.
It is said that beauty with
brains is a rare thing.
OH GOD!
Do you really realize where and in
what kind of condition we are stuck.
Relax!
We didn't do much sitting
at home during lockdown.
Same applies here. We can't do a thing apart
from sitting here and munching popcorn.
You and I are locked in a lift.
BOOM!
And here goes off a Bomb.
Men can't help but exploit a situation
when they are stuck with a beautiful girl.
Women can't help but speak off their beauty
irrespective of the situation they are in.
You said its a blast, lift is off.
Aren't you scared a bit?
Not a bit.
Otherwise are you showing off?
Is she is in vibration mode?
What's happening?
Help!
Security!
HELP!
- Hey!
- Anybody there?
Hello Madam.
Oh Miss India.
What are you trying to do?
Get out of your act.
You think you will be saved
if you just shout loud.
Control yourself.
I drank 5 glasses of cane juice.
How can I control it?
I know its difficult.
An hour or two is controllable.
A Day or two is impossible.
Being stressed will increase pressure.
Peace is the only way. Just relax.
So be cool.
Why can't I control cane juice.
Its all my fate.
God! Please save me.
See.
Agitation will only increase the pressure.
Like I said.
Just sit on this stool and relax.
Just feel the pleasure. Not the pressure.
Wah!
What a rhythm?
Manforce Condoms.
Just feel the pleasure. Not the pressure.
Wohoo. Punchline fits here also.
So crazy no!
Sorry!
Want this?
Now open and relish it.
Your plight is also the same
as this Coke tin. Right?
Lucky tin.
I am laughing out of helplessness.
You don't know how it is for a girl when her
bladder is full and stuck with a stranger.
If you don't mind. I have an idea.
I don't mind. Please tell me.
If you agree, I can pee in my pants.
I'm sorry. What the heck am I talking?
That's okay. I can understand.
Adult diapers. Bought 'em for my grandpa.
If you are okay. You can use them..
What?
Here?
Do you have any other option?
- Feeling better?
- Thank you so much!
Solutions come along with problems.
I guess that's the divine plan.
So, the solution to get outta
here is somewhere here only.
- Maybe.
Your grandpa? Diapers?
He has BPH issues.
Actually,
my entire life is surrounded by him.
Its very clear for me.
Its his birthday tomorrow.
This shopping is all for that.
Tomorrow its my birthday also.
Is it?
- What a coincidence.
So, you had to present me his gift.
Come on. Who gifts diapers.
I was just kidding. I'm sorry.
This is his gift.
I got a watch when I got
distinction in boards.
I sold that watch and bought him a guitar.
I don't mind getting injured.
I can't take if anything happens to this.
- Is he a guitar player?
Maestro Illayaraja..
Is Illayaraja your grandpa?
You can't stop yourself. Do you?
Sorry.
Illayaraja and my grandpa
got trained with same master.
My grandpa couldn't become a composer
becuase his father didn't support him.
- Its the genes I guess.
- I got the same madness for music.
Now my grandpa supports me.
You got lucky.
How about you?
Are you entering Ms. World competition?
Its enough already.
I wanna be a playback singer.
- Nice
But enemy that stops me from
becoming a singer is always with me.
- I didn't get you.
I have Asthma.
Everytime I show up for an audition,
my asthma comes along and ruins it.
It wouldn't let me sing at all.
It completely shattered my dreams.
All I want is to record a
single and send to music labels.
But it seems impossible for me.
Oh. So that's why you
are taking this fish.
- What do you mean?
There's a treatment. You stuff the fish with
medicine and you stuff yourself with the fish.
- You idiot. Stop it.
No way. Its a pet.
Oh ok.
There's a Heroine at home,
waiting for this Hero.
I wonder who's waiting for me.
Tamanna or Tapsee.
Oh shit.
I forgot.
This needs to be in aquarium within 4 hrs.
There won't be much oxygen after 4hrs.
What do we do now?
Oh my god! Will I be gone after 30 mins.
Please do something and save me.
I completely forgot about this.
You are such a beauty.
Why do you have to worry about everything.
Its your words.
Problem and Solution go along together.
Wait.
Voila!
- Ashtray?
- Wohoo. An ashtray saved my life.
- Kudos guys.
- Thank you.
Enough with the Thanks.
Do you intend to say your name now.
- I'm sorry.
- My name is Sameerana.
- Saa mee raa na.
- That's a lovely name.
- Thank you.
- I am Pavan.
- My name is Gabbar Singh.
Sameerana translates to Breath.
Pavan translates to Wind.
That means for you to breath,
I am necessary.
But in my dictionary,
Pavan translates to Power.
Time seems to be 8.
Can't we get outta here?
Mobile reception is completely dead.
My mom would be worried about me.
Relax!
Lets hope some security guy shows up.
We might get out of here.
So, Just chill.
Chill?
You can chill drinking beer
at a beach on full moon night.
Can you chill eating pepper
fritters on a sunny day.
Woah! You seem to have too many fantasies.
Can you share your fantasies for fun.
Oh!
Just for fun.
We have all the time in the world.
You seem to get a kick out off
knowing about girl's fantasies.
You seem to make me
agree about your beauty.
Sorry?
- Nothing.
- Yes it thrills me.
So.
- Roll. Camera. Action.
Okay.
This is a long wishing fantasy.
- Sitting on a stylish bike.
- Enjoying a nice ghat ride.
- Uh huh.
Get down at a less crowded
road side tea shop.
A boy comes from the shop
comes and asks what I need.
- Bro, get me a cutting chai.
- Why did you come into my fantasy?
Where am I in it?
I can hear guitar sound in the background.
- Oh is it.
- Okay. I'll get out of your fantasy.
- Its okay. You can stay.
- Vibes are good. You can stay.
After the boy goes to get Tea,
I'll take out a cigar from the pockets.
- I'll light up a matchstick.. NO
- I'll light up with a lighter..
..drag a puff. Meanwhile, hot tea is
being made with Elaichi and Ginger.
I take the chai... one sip of
chai and one puff of cigarette...
..enjoying the nature view along.
After the last puff..
..then drop the filter on
ground and stamp on it.
I am at my utmost relaxed mode.
Here's the tray.
Then sit on my bike,
and start my ride again.
Wah!
- What a fantasy!
Its just out of the world.
Bike, Cigar.. Wah!
A Fantasy can be what you want to do
or something you can't do but want to.
- What kind is yours?
- Something I want to but can't.
- Why so?
- Smoke and Asthma don't go well at all.
Let it be.
- What about your fantasies?
Let's avoid my fantasies.
- What happened?
Nothing.
Better get rid of those stupid acts.
What?
Lets end it here and
come back to reality.
I am famished.
Looks like you have bought a lot.
Can you give me something to eat.
- Yeah. Thanks for reminding.
I completely forgot.
Poor fish.
- Haha. Pavan must be burning of hunger.
- What is it Pavan? You seem to be off.
What happened?
- Nothing.
Hey Pavan.
I know you are hungry.
Only you can prank me all the time.
Isn't it?
Come on. I have enough for a full dinner.
Actually, I have a trip planned
with my friends this evening.
All this shopping is for that.
I am supposed to be on a flight now.
- But here I am, stuck in a lift.
Oh s***!
- What happened?
- Power is gone I guess.
- Its been a battery light all this while.
- How do we do now?
Mobile light it is.
Mobilee.
Oh god.
One second.
Nice job.
- Isn't it?
- Its really good.
Here we go. Do you like some wine?
Uh Ohh. You guys seem to
have planned it really well.
- Why should only boys have all the fun.
Are you ok with vital brand?
- Haha. Brand doesn't bother me.
- Only content.
WoW!
Mobile light turned to Moon light.
And what a lovely and romantic night.
Our guy seems like a bachelor.
Am I risking anything by offering
him wine in this situation.
Hello. Is offering me wine concerning you?
Your face is very evident.
These kind of things
shouldn't bother you at all.
A single glass will make earth look
like merry-go-round for ladies.
Even if I bottoms up this entire bottle,
its like a few drops.
So, don't worry.
Whatever we do now will not
make you repent in the morning.
I'm good. I understood.
Lets enjoy!
Now we are on track.
I'll tweak your idea a bit,
it will be a game changer.
You aced it.
You settle here buddy.
So what's next?
- Wine.
- Our guy is in a haste.
Can you please pass on my guitar?
Sparkling pearls, shining laughs.
To which melody is my heart listening.
Looks like a dream,
but feels like reality..
Verbal chaos is out of my lips.
Procession bore by darkness..
Fireflies are chatting..
Beads of fancies strung together..
My heart can't recall the name.
Now and then there are
shining presents in my eyes.
Not knowing the dizziness
my feet are dancing.
Oh my heart!
you are a firefly.
You are a firefly.
To know where Raindrop is created..
..lets go to the laps of clouds.
To know where a wave starts..
lets read the story in breeze.
Before I know its me..
My thoughts steal the moment.
The world is upside down,
asking for help..
I wouldn't leave you, says shining moon.
Pavan.
You said earth will be go merry-go-round.
But you've taken me to another planet.
Battery is about to die.
I will switch off the mobile.
You look sleepy. Sleep well.
Ahh!
Hey.. what are you doing?
- No.
- Sameerana..
- You Idiot.
- Pavan take your hands off me.
Get away. Take off your hands.
- I am really sorry Pavan.
I'm so sorry.
Just when I was sleeping,I was worried
there was something on my chest.
I thought it was you.
How can we expect a rat here suddenly.
I can understand its embarrasing for you.
But I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
Pavan, please don't be serious.
Relationships mean a lot to me.
They are both my strength and weakness.
I would never misbehave with a girl.
I am not that cheap.
It doesn't hurt me for
slapping me by mistake.
I can't be hurt for this
especially with you.
I also misunderstood you in the morning.
So, no hard feelings.
You seem to be angry outside,but on the
inside you are ego less and clean hearted.
You are not a stranger to me anymore.
I trust you with all my heart.
I completely trust you Pavan.
Good night!
Oh my god!
WoW.
Happy Birthday Sameerana!
Thank you so much!
This is totally unexpected.
So far in my life,
there's been only 2 big surprises.
Both happened today itself.
At 12 afternoon, you slapped me.
Now at 12, you are celebrating
my birthday here in this lift.
I wouldn't be this thrilled if I
were with my friends in Kerala.
If I were featured on Femina cover page.
If I got 1 mil. likes on Facebook.
I wouldn't be this excited.
My Grace!
Thank you.
Its all good. Go ahead.
Happy Birthday to you.
Sameerana.
Can you give me your phone.
You said you didn't have a
single recording of yours.
This is your first and best recording.
I wish and know that you will
achieve your dream this year.
You got gift that are worth my life time.
I will remember this birthday forever.
This cake was for your grandpa. Right?
Why did you use it for me.
I can't celebrate his birthday anyway.
Atleast your birthday is on the same day.
I am happy.
Still, Cakes bought for our
kin has our emotions in it.
We have our love and care invested in it.
Ohh
- Ohh
Looks like this Rat too has
its delight in this cake.
Bloody..
What are you doing? Why did you cage it?
I am shit scared of Rats.
See these goosebumps.
- Are you scared of rats?
- Haha. Why?
Because of a grievous moment in my life.
What happened?
My grandpa got chocolates from
abroad when I was younger.
My sister ate all of them except one
by the time I came back from school.
I ate half of it and kept the rest
in my pant pocket and slept off.
A Rat ate the rest of the chocolate.
Its fine if it just ate the chocolate,
but it also ate a little of me.
Still,
it doesn't justify you caging it like that.
- Sad for it.
- What? Sad?
You can cage Fish in a bag.
Can't we cage rats in boxes?
- Hey, it will be a Pet.
- I want to get rid of it.
I can't take chances letting it free.
Not sure where else it will creep in.
Safety measures.
Mom would be so tensed about me.
I am worried about it.
What about your dad?
They got divorced when I was 5.
From then, it was just Me and Mom at home.
Mom raised me bold since
there was no men at home.
I get a lot of freedom.
She taught me how to live independently.
All she does is for me and my well being.
Then call her..
Tell her you are safe and
a guy named Pavan is along.
Tring Tring Tring Tring
Samee.. Where are you?
Where have you gone?
You didn't even call.
You phone are unreachable.
I'm stressed out because of you.
Mom. I am safe. How are you?
I am in shopping mall. Stuck in a lift.
Don't worry.
I have company, a guy named Pavan.
He's a good guy.
What do you mean stuck in a lift?
That too alone with a guy?
Be careful.
You know you can't trust these stupid men.
No Mom, its all good here.
He looked like Romeo intially,
turns out he is a bit of Lord Rama.
How did you get stuck in a lift?
Tell me this first..
That guy is the reason for that.
He cornered me in a lift
and slapped me hard.
After a Bomb blast and Power cut.
, we got stuck here.
Oh god! What's wrong with that guy?
How could he slap such a
cute and innocent face.
Take care my dear.
We'll send him behind bars
after you get outta there.
Its ok Mom. He is a good guy.
There's no need to send him behind bars.
Ohh.. you are taking sides already.
What's going on?
Hope you guys are not doing
anything impish already.. Right?
Shut up!
You know a guy needs to be all
time charmer to impress me.
Enough with that.
You never know, you might get a guy
with bald head or stomach pouch.
Such people keep their wall
sized photos all over the home.
Pavan.
- Yeah.
Its worrying me,
imagining Mom alone at home.
We have to somehow get outta here.
We don't know how long we
have to sit here like this.
Now it would be very silent outside.
If we can shout harder and bang doors..
someone might hear us.
Shall we try? Please..
Practically speaking these
things doesn't work out.
From how I see,
there won't be a single bird in the mall.
Even I didn't want to
miss Grandpa's birthday.
Still I had no option,
I had to sit quite all this while.
Anyway, why should we not try it..
This could be our way out.
Lets give it a shot..
Okay.
- Lets go.
Ready?
- Ready.
1..2..3..Go
HELPPP!
Is anyone around?
HELPPPPP!
- HELP
- HELP!
Come on Pavan. Put some force.
Which force?
- Manforce!
Uff..kick these damn doors hard.
You know..
our noise should reach the city.
Got it.. its like you did in the morning?
All languages?
Uhh.. one is enough.
Ok.. our shouting should reach the city.
Right?
Yes.
- Now see.. it starts now.
HELP.
- HELLLLLPPPP
- Is anyone outside.
- HELLLLLPPPPPP
- Help please.
- HELPPP.
HELP.. HELP
HELP!
HELP
- Help please.
- Is anyone outside?
Let it go., we'll be tired.
We don't even have water.
Hey, come stand this way.
Why?
will you take a runup and kick the door.
That Manforce logo and
you are going so well.
Wait!
You look like a brand
ambassador for Manforce.
Ohh.. then you finally agree
that Samee can beat Sunny..
WHAT?
Are you happy about this? Moron.
Hey Pavan. shall we play Truth or Dare?
But with a small twist.
We'll write down,
T for Truth and D for Dare.
We'll turn the bottle,
Bottle will decide what to do for us.
Did you understand?
If a Dare comes.. Do you the have
to dare to do whatever I ask.
Of course!
No conditions apply.
Oh god..
Looks like the Wine started working.
Don't overthink it.
Just to pass the time.
Come on, lets start.
Ladies first always.
Okay.
T D T D.
Here we go.
Dare it is.
Fish is in the net.
You moron. Wait for it.
A Rat will come for rescue.
This lady is different species..
So, are you ready for any kind of dare.
Yes.
Think twice before you answer..
You look like the guy in a reality show.
I already said, I am all up for it.
No conditions apply.
I want to do it now.. here.. with you.
Yes, that only.. Starts with S.
What?
Can you dare?
Of course.
I love doing it.
Time and again.. Again and again..
Till I am sweaty and tired.
Lets do it.
S..
I..
N G.
SING.
She pulled it off real smooth.
Let's sing.
Nice.
Now your turn.
Hey, its truth.
Come on.
Like they pledge on the Gita and start..
You should speak only the truth.
I Love You.
What? Are you surprised..
This is true Sameerana.
I mean.,
proposals aren't new to me to be surprised.
Obviously, given my beauty..
Proposals aren't a big deal.
But this is first time,
someone made a sincere proposal so fast.
But I have seen you before 3 months.
Indian biggest Swara music
was founded by my grandpa.
You were there for an audition once.
To all the legends and mentors..
I pay my respects..
Bless me to do well and be in one
of these photographs like you.
Okay sir.
Madam, you can go in.
Ok Sameerana. You can go for the take.
- What happened? huh..
- What could've happened.
I'm sorry sir.
My asthma is not letting me sing
though you gave me an opportunity.
All you need is Self
belief to overcome asthma.
Your have a good voice miss.
Don't lose your trust.
Don't lose your goal also.
Constant efforts is the key.
Better luck next time..
..and take care.
Thank you sir.
What., are you laughing at me?
My self belief would be great,
if you blessed me.
I will be a great singer one day.
My young photo will find
its way here among you.
The voice of passion.
Oh.. 10th grade is a
younger for the age you are.
Good Morning sir.
- Morning
Why did that girl leave in tears?
She couldn't perform upto
mark due to some issue sir.
But she seems to be talented.
I couldn't even see her face.
- Shit
- Yeah its mine.
I stuck this photo that day.
- Yes, its the same photo.
That day I saw this tattoo on your hand.
When you were giving the bottle,
I saw the same tattoo again.
The voice of passion.
- I liked that stranger lady that day.
I didn't wait for a sec,
when I realized both ladies are same.
That's why.. I couldn't stop my proposal.
From "I hate this guy"
to "I like this guy"..
You made it happen in one day.
Whatever be the situation..
I changed my diaper infront of a man..
I couldn't even imagine a stranger
celebrating my birthday this grandly..
My only motivation to lead my life.
, is to become a singer.
When I almost lost hope,
you made me sing a song.
You are truly an impressive guy Pavan.
But, I don't know..
how you got emotionally connected to me.
That's why you couldn't stop
yourself from proposing.
There's nothing wrong with it.
But I should also feel the same for you..
To be impressed and to
connect emotionally..
are two different things.
There will be a moment..
when I can say "He is the one"..
..that I will come and hug
you tight to express my love.
Just like how you did now.
I believe in that kind of moment.
I'll be waiting for such moment.
I believe such moment will
decide my life partner.
I hope you understand.
Given my beauty,
I can't fall in love that easily.
I will wait for that moment.
Ahaa.. didn't you mock me
by singing in the morning.
Your beauty is miniscule
compared to world's beauty.
- You had a few lines of rap also.
Whoever marries you,
his life goes from frying pan to fire.
You may become ash.
Change your mind.
Shit
Pavan
We should've stopped the candles.
Its over. Relax.
Thank god!
Hey
Sameerana, are you okay?
No Pavan.. I can't breath.
Asthma is kicking in.
Its getting difficult.
Hey Sameerana.
You'll be fine.
It will be okay, but where is that thing..
what's that?
- Inhale..
- Yes Inhaler.
Do you have it on you?
I asked you to open the
doors to get inhalers.
So sorry. Come on
Forgive me for this.
Do you have any other medicines.
We can't do anything..
Its like leaving that fish on floor..
Look at me. You'll be fine.
Sameerana.. you will be fine.
With all this beauty,
how come I have asthma.
Arghh..
Hey, is anybody outside?
Try breathing.. you'll be fine.
Keep looking at me.
Look up.. Everything will be fine.
You're breath. I am air. Do you remember?
Heyy
I guess your Einstein mind will
throws coins instead of bangles..
Bro, you have any idea what
a lady einstein could do?
I'm so sorry.
I put you in this situation.
Nothing should happen because of me.
Please stay.
Try taking longer breaths.
There's a lot to see in life..
Swara music will put a
big picture of yours..
You should become that big.
More than anything,
you should come hug me..
..and express your love.
Sameerana.. Sameerana?
Take longer breaths.
Everything will be fine.
With tearing eyes and bleeding heart..
stranded lost at the
shore of passing time..
Every breath you leave,
becomes a final word..
Every breath is confronting my silence.
Conflict is me, fight is with myself.
How is it justified if
you become a statuette.
If the heart stops and
you become motionless..
I can't find your
existence in imagination.
I've lost it all.
I've lost it all.. with you.
I've lost it all..
In darkness of heart, I've lost it all.
I've lost it all.
In the waves at end of sight.
, I jumped and lost it all.
In the laps of sea and swings of waves,
entertaining you by falling and raising.
A fish following your essence..
..swimming all the way.
Time is merciless and asked
me to throw the bait..
Neglecting your heart, I let it go.
Overwhelming sadness is drowning me..
To appease now is like going upstream.
This curse will hunt me to death..
My heart is wordless, soul is lifeless.
Coming times looks like vaccum..
I am drowning in my own tears.
I've lost it all.
I've lost it all..
Maybe God puts problems
and solutions together.
Hey Guys.
Me and this girl got stuck in a lift,
after the bomb blast in the mall.
She has severe asthma,
right now she is not able to breath.
Not sure if she can make it alive or not.
Not sure what to do and
how to get out of here.
Please save us from here.
Please!
Please inform to Police or rescue team.
Please save us.
I'm recording this on 24 January,
its around 4:30 in the morning.
One second.
Please get a similar
inhaler when you reach here.
Please don't forget.
Please save her.
Sameerana.
Sameerana. Wake up!
Sir!
Is this my daughter?
Its her.
Don't worry. Please sit.
Don't worry. I will take care of this.
Control Room.
Do you have an inhaler?
Bro, do you have inhaler?
Bro, make it fast.
Is anyone inside?
Yes.
We are inside. Please help.
Sameerana.
Samee. Samee.
Samee
Samee. What is all this?
Mom is here. You'll be fine.
Open your eyes.
Samee.
Samee, try to breath.
Open your eyes. Open your eyes.
Wake up.
Try to breath.
You'll be safe.
Though I gave life to you..
..I feel breathless whenever
you have trouble breathing.
Nothing will happen to you.
- Let it go.
- No Sis.
I couldn't forgive myself if
something happened to her.
Its beyond my belief,
If this life is mine.
My breath's address,
Shows the way to you.
Recalling your struggle,
I was ignorant all this while.
Never for a second in this turmoil,
Did I stop searching for you.
You should become such a famous singer..
..swara music will host your photo.
You should come running towards me..
hug me and say "I Love You".
I Love You Pavan.
You didn't feel love for me,
until you almost lost your life.
I don't know.
I could see your love in that moment.
But I couldn't hug you then.
Mom struggles whenever I feel breathless..
I could see the same with you then.
Which girl can refuse someone who
loves her like her mother does.
But for you to be impressed
shouldn't he be Mr. Universe.
I don't think there's such a man yet.
Even for him to exist,
he should be born to a beauty like me.
98.. eight 8s.
Got it. I'll Whatsapp you.
Bye!
I'll call you.
Yeah!