My name is Turkish.
Funny name for an Englishman, I know.
My parents were on an airplane together
when it crashed. That's how they met.
And then they named me like that airplane
that was Turkish.
And this is Tommy.
He tells everyone he was named
after the tommy gun.
But it was actually named after
of a famous 19th-century ballet dancer.
For as long as I can remember, I've always known Tommy.
He's my partner.
That doesn't mean
we're walking around holding hands.
It means I'm always trying to get him out
out of the messes he gets me into.
I keep him strict.
So he doesn't lose his sense of smell.
But really, he's like a brother to me.
What do I know about diamonds?
I do fist fights.
Just a week ago, I was throwing fist fights.
and enjoying life, and then suddenly.
What do I know about diamonds?
I think they come from Antwerp, don't you?
-Khayyam, are you going to listen to me?
-Do we have a choice?
You didn't have to take it literally.
Well, that beautiful story of Adam and Eve.
There's a deep moral in it.
...but to demand that a grown man,
to believe that?
What's the matter?
Well, what's the matter?
What do you want me to do,
to drop my pants already?
All right, come on in.
It's a beautiful story.
That's all. Just a story.
The Catholic religion is based
on mistranslation.
That's enough. Reuben, say something.
Listen to me. Are you busy?
I'll tell you the whole story, the whole thing.
The point is that in the translation of the Septuagint.
of the Septuagint,
which in Hebrew means
"young woman,"
translated into Greek as "virgin."
It was easy to make a mistake,
...because there's a very slight
difference in pronunciation.
Out of this error grew a prophecy:
"A virgin shall bear and bear us a son."
Do you understand? People's attention
the word "virgin" has caught people's attention.
It's not every day a virgin
gets pregnant and gives birth.
But let that prophecy
for a couple hundred years.
and the result will be
a holy catholic church.
Oh, hey, what are you trying to say now?
What I'm trying to say is,
that even if something is written,
it doesn't mean
that that's the way it really is.
But that's their hope.
And who cares if it's true or fiction?
-People like to believe.
-I don't want to hear it anymore.
Anyway, who are we here to see?
-Michaela.
-Hello?
Mutti.
Rudy! Rood!
Rood, Rood, let them in, please.
Rood, it's all right, run them.
-Michael. -Mutti.
You kept us waiting for half an hour.
What are you trying to do, give me a heart attack?
Get down on the floor!
On the floor!
Get down!
On the fucking floor!
Get down! Get the fuck down!
On the floor! Get down! Get down!
Get down, I said!
-Time.
-Seven minutes.
Where's the rock?
Michael, where's the rock?
Feature film
LISTENED
Cousin Avi.
Saul
Miki
Vinnie
Frankie Four Fingers
Turkish
Gorgeous George
Tommy
Tony Bullet in the Tooth
Boris Razor
Doug Head
Brick
When does your plane leave?
In 20 minutes.
Give me your gun.
If in London.
you're gonna need a gun,
call this number.
-Boris.
He'll get you everything you need.
Is it okay to hit like that?
It's an underground fist fight, Tommy.
It's not a tickle contest.
What these guys are doing
hurting each other.
What's up with the sausage, Charlie?
Two minutes, Turkish.
Look at that. Well, how am I supposed
I'm supposed to do business sitting in this?
Okay, we need the right office.
I need a new motor home.
And you're gonna get it for me.
Why me?
Well, you know about motor homes.
Why would I do that?
You spent the whole summer in one of these. Which means
you know more about them than I do.
And the price has to be right,
so you don't have to sell your pants.
What's wrong with this one?
There's nothing wrong with that, Tommy.
It's all good.
I'm just not quite sure about the color choice.
I've already made all the arrangements.
All you have to do is go and pick him up.
Here's the address.
But it's a campground.
Here's 10 tons, and it would be really nice
to get some change.
-What's up with the sausage, Charlie? -What's up with the sausage?
-Five minutes, Turkish.
Five minutes ago, you said
that it would be ready in two minutes.
What are they, gypsies or something?
I fucking hate gypsies.
What a sensitive boy you are, Tommy.
Fuck me. Hold me tight.
-What's that?
-It's my belt, Turkish.
No, Tommy. You got a gun in your pants.
-What's a gun doing in your pants? -What's a gun doing in your pants?
-It's for protection.
To protect me from who?
From the Nazis?
Aren't you afraid you're gonna shoot your balls off
when you sit down?
-Where'd you get it?
-Boris Razor.
Boris is the fucking
tricky-ass Russian?
It's a little heavy, don't you think?
Toughness is a good thing.
Severity is reliable.
Even if it doesn't go off,
you can always take one in the head.
Boris the Razor,
or Boris the Dick.
Sharp as a sickle to the balls and hard as a hammer,
like a hammer blow. A living Soviet emblem.
They say this bastard is impossible to kill.
Back to my partner, Tommy.
Tommy is in our other business -
...slot machines.
We're living off it, and we were even able
to hire Gorgeous George.
However, at the moment.
Tommy is tight on defense.
All right, I'll take it.
Tommy's enthusiasm
for firearms has a reason.
Sooner or later in an underground fist fight.
you have to deal with this:
with Brick.
If this one isn't worth it,
to bet on him, then I don't even
I don't know who to bet on.
-He looks pretty good, doesn't he? -No.
-No, he looks great.
You'll be proud of him.
You think that's what people should be doing
to do for me? Make you proud of yourself?
You deserve it.
Get your tongue out of my ass, Gary.
That's usually how dogs lick.
You're not a dog, are you, Gary?
No. No, I'm not a dog.
Nevertheless...
for all intents and purposes, you're a real dog.
On everything but loyalty.
Rumor has it that Brick likes to get rid of people
of people with a stun gun,
a plastic bag, duct tape.
and a bunch of hungry pigs.
Liam, you're a completely ruthless cunt,
I'll tell you that.
But now is not the time to complain.
Errol, feed him to the pigs.
What the fuck are you two hatching?
If you want to do business with Brick,
the most important thing is to stay out of debt.
If you hit it, you're screwed.
That means you're in his pocket now.
And once you're in his pocket,
there's no going back.
I hear he's a good fighter.
That's why I'm using him.
I'm gonna do you a favor, boy.
What he's really saying is,
that I'm doing him a favor.
Because everyone knows that in my fights.
nobody goes down. Unlike his fights.
Hey, Errol, I don't think he likes me.
You don't like me, do you?
I don't know what you're talking about.
But I'm well aware of the fact that I want to get out of here
to get out of here. Fuck, it stinks in here.
All my fights are fast and clear,
so we can get out of here before we get
as soon as it's reported to the authorities.
Play by the rules and everything will be just right.
By what other rules?
It's very hard to make a living in boxing,
...and so, from time to time.
to compromise my principles.
And in general, it's best to forget about principles altogether.
Are they Lancashire pigs?
Who the fuck is talking to you,
talking to you, boy?
Oh, yeah, Tommy. Brick loves Tommy.
Don't let me down.
You don't want to let me down,
do you, boy?
I'll meet you at the ring.
Boris, this Frankie is Four,
fuck him in the mouth, Fingers,
...carries a diamond the size of my fist.
I've already told you that the diamond is in a briefcase
in a briefcase strapped to his arm.
I sent him to you to buy weapons.
What else do you want me to do for you.
to kill him for you or something?
But you don't kill him yourself.
Americans can't know
that the Russians are involved.
Otherwise they'll come to me.
Boris, you're my brother,
so try to act smart like I do.
Find someone who can
to steal the fucking rock.
I don't want this to backfire on me.
And I don't want you to kill him, Boris.
It would raise suspicion.
So don't hire idiots on the case.
Before he leaves for New York,
he'll be in London for a couple days,
...so act fast. Okay?
And here's the other thing.
It might help you.
He likes to gamble.
86 carats?
Great cut, great shape.
It's an excellent stone.
You're a good guy, Frankie.
And you did a really good job.
So, when are you coming back?
I'm gonna have to move
a couple of smaller rocks,
to get a good price.
This one will take a couple days.
-Talk to my cousin Dougie.
-Dougie the head?
And here's the other thing, Frankie.
-What?
-Stay away from the casino.
You did a great job, son.
-Don't screw this whole thing up. Okay?
-I hear you, Avi.
I'll see you later, Avi.
86 carats.
-Where?
-London.
-London?
-Yes. -London.
Well, that's where the fish and chips and tea are,
...bad food, bad weather,
Mary fucking Poppins. London.
No, it's not for me.
That's Doug the Head. Everyone knows Doug the Head.
If there are stones and those stones
are stolen, that's him.
Doug is pretending to be Jewish.
He wants to be a Jew.
He even tells his family
that they're Jews.
Only he's as much of a Jew
as I am a fucking hamadryl.
He thinks being Jewish
is good for business.
And in the diamond business.
...it really helps.
-Avi!
He's coming today. Take care of him.
Avi, you know I don't buy rhinestones.
He doesn't sell rhinestones. Make it smaller.
Who do you think I am? This is England.
We play by the rules here.
Listen to me.
If the stones are kosher, I'll buy them.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have lunch. Uh, bye.
What are you standing here for?
It's a free country, isn't it?
Well, this is a private store, isn't it?
Get the fuck outta here.
Girls, I want to see you in my office.
I just got a call from Avi's cousin.
-You'll meet him soon enough.
-Yes, Dad. You told us.
-He's a serious man in New York.
Girls, I'd like to see you in my
office.
Yes, Dad. You told us.
Weight is about reliability.
For me, reliability is the most important thing.
I'll take it.
How much do you want for it?
Not at all.
Okay, then what do you want for it?
I want you to do something for me.
There's a fight in a couple days.
What's the fight?
Underground boxing.
I know a bookie
who will be taking bets.
If you bet for me,
...consider us even.
-Why can't you do it yourself?
-Well...
...there aren't many bookmakers around here
that take that kind of bet.
And I owe this one a lot.
Besides, I know something
that other people don't.
So?
What do you know?
It's a campground. Gypsy campground.
-Right on the money.
-What are we doing here?
-Buying a mobile home.
-Who are we buying from, the fucking gypsies?
Are you out of your mind? This is gonna end in shit.
You'll be fine.
You're such an asshole.
I fucking hate gypsies.
Nice car, mister.
Well, not as cool as your bike.
How's it going?
Who are you looking for?
Mr. O'Neill.
-Would you like me to bring him in?
-That'd be nice.
Get out of here.
-So you'll find him?
-Yeah.
-What are you waiting for? -What are you waiting for?
-Waiting for you to pay me five pounds.
Fuck you, I can find him myself.
-Two fifty.
-I can give you a pound.
You're a fucking asshole.
There's one problem with gypsies.
What are you doing? Back off, man.
It's impossible to understand what they're saying.
You Tommy? You here about the motor home?
-Mr. O'Neill.
-Fuck that. Call me Mickey.
They don't speak Irish,
and they don't speak English.
-How's it going?
-The weather's not bad.
He's just a gypsy.
Holy shit! Look how big he is!
How tall are you?
-Guys, how much is in him?
-Healthy, yeah.
Mom, come look at this big guy here.
I bet you're a little bit
of boxing, sir? You look like a boxer.
Come on, Micky.
Ask them if they want a drink.
Yeah, I'd kill someone for a drink.
You don't have to kill anyone here,
I'm telling you.
Get your hands off me, now.
How about a cuppa, big guy?
Don't play dumb, Micky.
Offer the man a proper drink.
Ooh, dandy.
-Wouldn't the big guy come with us?
-He'll watch the car.
-Does he think we're thieves?
-No, nothing like that.
He just likes
looking after cars
Nice dogs.
You like dogs?
-Dogs?
-What?
-Yes, dogs.
-Dogs. Do you like dogs?
Ah, dogs.
Yeah, I like dogs.
-But I like motorhomes better.
-Welcome.
If anyone knows how to bargain, it's gypsies.
That's probably why
they talk like that--
...so it's impossible to understand.
But if Tommy can buy cheaper
than we bargained for,
there's ice cream waiting for him when he gets back.
Good doggy, from a good family.
He'll be a little homesick,
but then he'll get used to it.
See you, guys. See you, boss.
All right, Micky. I'll see you later.
I don't know what all the fuss is about.
They're not such bad guys.
Hey, you looked at it when you bought it.
And I helped you as much as I could.
See your car? Come on, go for a drive.
Get the fuck out of here while you can still walk.
No one's doing anything to you,
...until you get yourself in trouble.
All right, give us our money back
and take back your cabin.
What the fuck am I gonna do with this fucking cabin
if it doesn't have fucking wheels?
-What, you want to fight?
-Over my dead body.
Go away, go away!
I won't let you fight! You know what happens
what happens when you fight!
Get her out of here.
Fucking hell.
You want money? Well, then no fucking around.
You and me.
So this is the kind of fight it's going to be.
Better not get up.
You better not get up!
Lie the fuck down and stay down.
I promise you, you won't want to get up.
...You have a death blow, you fat faggot,
you know that?
Watch it, motherfucker.
All right, guys. Get me on my feet.
Get down,
...or you'll never get up again.
You're a badass.
Sick, I see. I'm leaving.
You're not going anywhere, fat ass.
You're gonna stay here until we're done.
Turns out this chatty,
tattooed gypsy--
...Roma underground boxing champion.
Which means it's harder
than a coffin nail.
But that's not what Tommy's thinking about right now.
Tommy knows that if in a few minutes
gorgeous George doesn't come to his senses,
...then he, Tommy, will be buried with him.
Why the gypsies need to explain to anyone,
...why and why did a stranger in their tabor
a stranger died?
It's easier to bury them both
and move on to another place.
They don't have social security numbers
they don't have, do they?
And now Tommy, nicknamed "Titty".
...praying...
And if he doesn't pray,
...then he should fucking do it.
Hey, Bad Boy.
Sol.
Take it easy. No, it's mossonite.
Mosso's what?
Mossonite, man-made diamond, Lincoln.
Toy.
Glass.
It's cheap.
And he's standing...
...he's not worth a fucking thing.
Bad boy, how many times do I have to tell you:
go gangbusters.
Save that game for me and Saul.
All right. Uh-huh.
What is it, Vince?
It's a dog, Saul.
Don't bring her here.
What's the problem? It's just a fucking dog.
-Where did you get it?
-From the gypsies.
Here you go.
They slipped it to me along with some left-handed gold.
You know gypsies, Saul. They're always
they're always throwing their dogs in the mix.
She better not bite.
Look, what are you doing?
I want the dog to get used to the store
to the store, why?
Get the dog!
Hey, come back!
It's okay, Boris.
-Don't worry about the dog.
-I'm not.
What can I do for you, Boris?
I have a job for you.
I already have a job.
Fifty tons for half a day's work.
Go on.
I want you to put up one bookie.
From Russia with love, huh?
I have some pebbles for sale,
...have someone to drop them off to,
...but I came to you.
Easy, Frankie, my son.
In another man's monastery.
I'm not in a convent, Doug.
I'm in a hurry.
I've got to stop by the bookie's.
To the bookie?
-Who are you betting on?
-Harris Bomber. -Harris Bomber.
A fist fighter?
Maybe you know something
that I don't?
Look, there's probably a lot of things I know
that you don't even know about.
Tyrone's tough as nails,
aren't you, Tyrone?
That's exactly who I am.
Tyrone's going to drive.
He took an extreme driving course.
Yes, I did.
And I don't want that dog
drooling all over my seats.
What are your seats like?
Tyrone, buddy, it's a stolen car.
When I'm behind the wheel, it's my car.
So make sure the dog
doesn't drool on my seats. You got it?
I can't believe you found her.
Where was she?
Ran back to the gypsies.
You go. How did she find them?
I don't know. I'm not a dog, Saul.
Ask the dog.
Maybe it's fucking homing.
or something.
Watch your brakes.
Saul, I'm fucking imagining it,
you said he could drive.
Don't worry about me. You better worry
about my seats and my dog.
All right?
What?
I heard you say he's a great driver.
Well, what the fuck is he gonna do
can take us away from?
Don't worry about Tyrone.
When you need him, he knows what he's doing.
-Worry about the guns, huh? -Yeah.
-Yeah.
What's that?
It's a shotgun, Saul.
It's a fucking anti-aircraft gun, Vincent.
-I want to cause a panic, okay?
-You're gonna cause a massacre, not a panic.
Doesn't look like a bookie's office.
Why are we standing here?
How about we stand over there?
It's too crowded.
Is it too tight?
You could land a fucking Boeing in there.
Leave him alone. That's just the way he is.
Right, Tyrone?
Yeah, that's the one.
He's such a fucking idiot.
Tyrone, what did you do?
Yeah, Tyrone, what did you do?
Look, you're yanking my chain,
so enjoy it.
It's okay. Don't pull away.
Otherwise people will see the damage.
Why did you do that?
I haven't seen her.
It's a four-ton truck, Tyrone.
It's not a fucking bag of peanuts.
She's standing at a stupid angle.
She's behind you, Tyrone.
Remember, if you're backing up,
everything comes at you from behind.
You better teach your dog.
-Get the dog away from him.
-Get the dog away from me.
Give me that squeaker.
Last time he chewed on it and didn't say a word.
Hey, don't swallow that.
He won't be able to swallow it.
Yes.
Why the fuck...
...you put up Luxury George.....
...for the fight...
...two days before the Bomber fight?
The enemy was half his size.
I didn't expect this to happen.
You put a man
in a banned boxing fight--
...what the fuck else did you expect?
Rubbing ointments and shiatsu massages?
What's your problem?
Who messed you up?
You fucking pissed me off, Tommy.
You.
But you're the one who said
that it was a good deal.
Yeah, but I don't see any connection.....
between losing 10 tons of money,
Luxury George's hospitalization...
...and a good deal.
What do we tell Brick now?
That the fight isn't going to happen?
We'll replace the fighter.
Is there any hope that Brick won't notice?
Who the fuck are we going to put in place?
John Pistol will do?
Or is Willie the Crazy Fist?
I see you're out of the loop, huh?
The crazy fist has gone crazy,
...and Pistol shot himself.
Oh, my God.
What?
Let's hire this fucking gypsy.
-How much will you pay us?
-10 tons.
Holy shit. It's not a lot of money, so we need to talk.
All right. Uh-huh.
I'm signing up for the motorhome.
For what?
To the motor home.
Understood, only for the best.
It's kind of like we
wanted to get a motor home.
Why don't you like this one?
It's not for me. It's for Ma.
For whom?
For his ma.
Brick holds and illegal bookmakers.
They take bets on anything
that's mixed with blood and gore.
And here I am replacing a fighter,
...and Brick is sure
to take advantage of the situation.
He's gonna pull down my pants,
put Vaseline on my ass,
...and take good aim
before he shoots.
And if I hadn't found a gypsy to replace him,
...he'd just rip me in half.
They're so adorable,
the paint on the walls is curdling.
Come on, get angry, you woolly-haired faggot!
As soon as he gets in the ring,
he shits his pants in fear.
You poke him with a stick.
he's a beast in front of your eyes.
You like dogfighting, Turkish?
We lost Gorgeous George.
Say that again.
Where did you say you lost him?
This isn't some fucking
bunch of car keys, is it?
And that's not why we lost him,
because he's fucking unconscious, huh?
We're not giving up the fight.
I bet your balls
you don't say no.
We're changing the fighter.
Oh, for fuck's sake, can your girl
can talk?
And who did you trade him for, sweetheart?
You don't know him, but he's cool.
Cool?
I don't care if he's
I-Mohammed-Better-than-Bruce-Lee,
...you can't change fighters.
-No. -The fight's still on. -No.
As soon as I announce a replacement,
all bets will be called off.
You can't change fighters at the last minute.
And that's why there's not gonna be a fight,
you understand that well, you fucking asshole?
You can take your own bets on this fight.
Put your goat on a leash, Turetsky,
before she gets whipped.
Or do you want to get fucked, sweetheart?
Make sure your man goes down
in the fourth round.
Do you understand me well, Turkish?
I really didn't want to get into it.....
...in debt.
But now I'm in his pocket.
You're walking on fucking thin ice,
my pedigree-pal friends.
And when it cracks,
I'll be waiting for you underneath.
Now get the fuck outta here.
Doug, where's Frankie Four Fingers?
How would I know? I'm not his mom.
But I'll see him soon.
-When's soon?
-He said he needed cash.
Said he'd be back right after the fight.
After the fight?
What fight?
You mean after the boxing fight?
-Is betting allowed in there?
-It's a boxing match, Avi.
-Does he have the diplomat with him?
-Yes, he has the diplomat with him.
And this asshole's a betting man?
You're talking about Frankie,
who's always got a gambling problem.
Avi, I'm not a telepath.
I think you're just stupid,
I'll tell you that.
Do you have any idea
why they call him Frankie Four Fingers?
I have no idea.
He's called that because he makes
idiotic bets with dangerous people.
And when he loses,
they circumcise him.
Don't think it's on the dick.
I'm sure he can pay.
Not with my money.
Got your toothbrush? We're going to London.
Did you hear that? I'm going to London!
-Avi!
-Shut up and sit down, you bald faggot!
I really don't like
leaving my country,
...especially not on a warm, sandy beach.
not on a warm, sandy beach,
...where everybody wears straw hats...
and they bring you cocktails.
We have sandy beaches here.
Who the fuck needs them, these beaches of yours?
I hope you can understand that concern,
that I feel
for my friend Frankie.
I'm gonna find him, and you're gonna help me find him.
And we're gonna start at the place
where the fist fight takes place.
Now how am I supposed to get this toy?
He'll probably cough it up.
Is he gonna be okay?
I hope not.
-Are we gonna rob a bookie?
-Yeah, you're the big one.
What are we waiting for?
We're waiting for a man who has
four fingers and a briefcase in his hand.
Why?
Because we agreed that the Russian
the Russian gets the diplomat, and we take the money.
What's in the briefcase?
Fucking hell, Tyrone,
concentrate on the steering wheel.
Oh, my God.
-It's a private party tonight, guys. -Yeah.
-We're well aware of that, son.
That's why we're here.
All right, then. Go through the back.
Back door? I thought it was the front.
-It's a private party tonight, guys. -We know.
-We know. That's why we're here.
Tickets.
Are we ever going to get in at all?
Avi, Avi, you have to understand.
It's not exactly Las Vegas,
and the fight isn't exactly legal.
I don't care about Vegas or the law.
I'm looking for Frankie.
I know, and he said he'd be here.
If this is the place to place your bets,
he'll be here.
Let's cut the bullshit.
To get it right.
Don't worry, he'll lie down in the fourth.
Is that him?
I don't know. How many fingers does he have?
I'm sorry, please, I don't have binoculars today.
All right, without further ado.
Let the show begin.
Do you know who owns this office?
Even if you know that, it's no use to you.
it's no use to you, so get everything you've got in here.
Vince, what are you doing in there?
What do you think I'm doing? Solomon,
...I'm already in pain!
Lower the flap now.
What's up, Vince?
It would be a lot better if you would stop
calling me by my first name.
-Money in the bag.
-The bets are in.
I don't give a fuck about your bets.
I understand.
But everyone...
...Bets...
...done.
And if all the bets are in,
there can't be any money in the till.
I don't fucking believe it!
I'm not fucking convincing you. It's a fact.
What have you got?
Nothing, actually.
There is change and no bills.
Show me your hands.
Okay, you have five fingers.
The coins are copper.
What the fuck do you mean, brass?
It won't open because
because it's a bulletproof door.
Hold this.
My leg.
What are you whining about?
I haven't touched you at all.
We're fucked.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Get us out of here.
Tyrone, what are you doing? Get us out of here!
Tyrone, who the fuck is this man?
It's a man with four fingers
and a briefcase, Vinnie.
In the red corner of the ring.
a young, promising boxer.
Micky, the short of it is, in the fourth round.
you go down. Is that understood?
You just make sure
that he doesn't kill me before he does.
Let's salute the bonehead....
...with a cannon blast--
...Micky!
In the other corner of the ring...
He just looks like a fat faggot.
He is a fat faggot,
only a very dangerous one.
Bomber Crazy Harris!
Try to look like a boxer.
And let's, uh.
...let's get started!
Do you realize that I've been fucking
down forty tons?
What the fuck?
-I'll pay you back all the money.
-I don't like it.
I will return all the money, I answer. I answer.
That fucking gypsy, he's the one who set me up.
Thanks for the tip, Brick.
Listen, you pus-faced faggot,
if I throw a bone to a dog,
...I'm not interested in whether the dog likes it
or not.
You stop me again,
and I'll fuck your balls clean off.
-He's here.
-Come on, you explain it to him.
-What are you doing?
-The diplomat was strapped to his arm.
And why didn't you cut it off?
We're not fucking butchers, Boris.
But the briefcase is strapped to his arm.....
Look, we're... Anyway, you have a problem.
There was no money in the office at all.
Id.
Here's ten tons for you.
No. Keep them. We want these.
Well, or at least half of it.
What was in the briefcase--
was agreed to belong to me.
What was in the office is yours.
Right?
There wasn't much money in it,
so here's 10 tons to help you out.
I'm afraid it's too late.
We want half, and that's only because
because we're very generous.
Because if we wanted to,
we'd take the fucking rock for ourselves, Boris.
Careful.
Drop the gun, fatty.
Stupid motherfuckers.
He shouldn't have heard my name.
Give me the rock.
-He's in the briefcase.
-What?
It's in the briefcase.
Did you put the rock in the briefcase?
Open it and give me the stone.
The only person who knew
the lock code, you just shot him.
Anyway, it wasn't smart to chill out
after Mickey's performance.
Brick was looking for us, looking for us to kill Tommy,
to kill Tommy, Mickey and me.
I know he's looking for us,
but I don't have a choice.
I'd be happy to get out of the country,
but that would take money.
But all my money is in the safe,
and the safe is in the office.
Once I get them, then, uh.
Oink, oink, oink.
Shit.
So this is where you keep your money.
What do you two want here?
You're jumping out of your pants
just to sniff something out.
That sounds hostile to me, John.
And we don't like hostility,
do we, Errol?
No, John, I don't.
I just shined my shoes.
Come on, put the kettle on.
-Will you have sugar?
-No, Turkish, thanks.
I'm sweet enough as it is.
He's your problem now.
Okay?
10 tons you can keep--
along with the corpse.
But if I see one of you faggots.
Look at him.
I have a fist fight in a couple days.
And I need a gypsy.
Uh, okay. Uh, sure.
Sure? Dickish.
I didn't ask you, I told you.
And this time.
...I really want him to lay down in the fourth.
This time, seriously.
I know you came here
to open your safe.
You can open it.
Turkish is a tricky bastard.
I thought he was gone with the money.
Don't think too much, Errol - there'll be trouble.
Okay, one little piggy has been taken care of.
Now find me the dumbasses
who attacked the bookie.
Find them today.
Good morning to you, Mrs. O'Neill.
Tommy.
You're as sly as a snake.
Where'd you get the flowers?
You're looking for my boy, aren't you?
-Do you know where I can find him?
-Yes.
Can you tell me where?
I don't want you dragging my son
into any kind of trouble.
He's my only son.
And he's a good boy.
He hunts.
Hunting? Hunting who?
Hunts hares.
They exhibit two dogs - hounds.
On a hare.
And the hare has to get away from the dogs.
What if he doesn't?
Well, then the hare is fucked.
Real fucked up?
Yeah, Tommy.
Even though the Nazis
had not yet landed.
You know these assholes, Errol?
I know a lot of assholes.
But I've never seen anyone as fucking stupid as these two,
I've never seen before.
John?
No, I don't know.
Tyrone.
Fat, stupid bastard.
-So what?
-It depends.
From what?
From whether you buy a motorhome or not.
Not the red one. We should go with pink.
-But that's a whole other cabin.
-And this is a different fight.
This cabin is twice the size of the previous one.
Turkish, you'll get twice as much
you'll get twice as much for this fight.
And my mom needs a house.
I like looking after her.
It's a fair deal. Take it.
Micky, you're lucky you're still alive after
after your performance, we're still alive.
What the fuck would it take
buying a palace on wheels?
I'm not saying your mom doesn't deserve him,
I'm just saying.
Okay, all right [speaks very slurred].
Okay.
And this one - she really likes the color blue.
Did I make myself clear?
Yeah, very accessible, Micky.
Give me a moment to consult
with my colleague.
Do you understand a word I'm saying?
I'll tell you what.
Fuck you.
Let's get hammered.
What?
He wants to bet on a hare.
What, like Tommy last time?
Look, do me a favor.
I'm doing you a favor.
Here's the deal.
If I win, I get the cabin.
And all the guys got a pair of these shoes,
like yours.
If I lose.
...so fuck it, then,
I'll fight for free.
If there's one thing I didn't want to do,
it was arguing with a gypsy.
But I had no other choice.
I had to do something to get him
to get him to come forward. But if I lose.
...I don't even want to think about losing.
All right. My money's on the hare being fucked.
What the fuck? Complete?
You got it, London.
Here we go!
I'll fucking tell you everything! Get them off me!
I'll tell you who robbed the bookie!
The color blue. Bye, guys.
So who's totally fucked now?
Something's not right here.
I mean, we're the ones who were gonna buy the cabin from him.
So why didn't you shoot him, huh, Tommy?
Although if you'd thrown a gun at him,
it would have made more sense.
What? What, are you trying to tell me
I can't shoot?
No, Tommy. I didn't say
you can't shoot.
I know you can't shoot.
What I'm trying to say is that that piece of shit
piece of shit you're wearing in your pants,
...it's no use.
Are you saying it's not working?
Did you fire it?
Oops.
I'd like to meet this
fucking tricky-ass Russian.
Why does he have a teapot warmer on his head?
To keep your head warm.
-What happened to him?
-He was shot in the face, Lincoln.
I thought it was obvious.
What are you putting that on him for?
Did you mistake it for a teapot?
-What do you want from me?
-Guess.
-I'm not a sorcerer, I don't bring the dead back to life.
-But you're so bad,
...and the bad guys know
how to dispose of bodies.
I only make corpses.
I don't know how to dispose of corpses.
Done, sir.
Oh, that's great.
Errol, make me a cup of tea.
Hold his legs.
What the fuck else am I supposed to hold him by.
by his fucking ears?
I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
Do you know who I am?
I know.
Good. That'll save time.
Well, I don't know.
If you carry a corpse in one piece,
you're always gonna have a problem.
The best thing you can do with him
...is to cut it into six pieces
and stack them up.
Will someone tell me who you are?
And when you've broken it down into six pieces,
that's when you can get rid of him.
Just don't hide the pieces in the fridge,
so you don't scare your mom.
In fact, I've heard that the best way
is to feed the corpse to the pigs.
Hogs need to go without food for a few days,
...and after that, they're gonna eat
the dismembered corpse for all it's worth.
But in order for the meat to digest well,
you have to shave the corpse's head first.
and pull out all the teeth.
Of course, that can be taken care of later,
...but who wants to pick out
the victim's teeth out of pig shit?
And they'll eat the bones no problem.
It takes at least 16 pigs at a time
it takes at least 16 pigs to get rid of one corpse at a time,
...so beware
of hog farms.
A 200-pound body will be eaten by pigs....
...in about 8 minutes.
That means that one pig....
...eats two pounds of raw meat.....
...per minute.
This is where the proverb comes from...
... "greedy as a pig."
Well, thanks for the tip.
It's all clear what's what.
Now, if you don't mind explaining,
who the fuck you are and what you are.
I don't have to tell you about feeding human meat to pigs,
I don't need to tell you anymore.
Do you know what the word retribution means?
Retribution is an act of avenging, it is vengeance,
...carried out by any means necessary.
In this particular case.
it's going to be done by a fucking asshole.
.
Gentlemen.
Why can't you find me Frankie, Doug?
Avi, what do you want from me?
I'm not a detective.
What about Tony?
Tony - A bullet in your teeth?
What's a Bullet in your teeth?
-Tony!
-You fucker.
He's reliable.
He'll get anyone from under the ground.
You're gonna die, Tony!
He was hit six times in a row, but they couldn't kill him.
but couldn't kill him. He took the bullets out and melted them down.
I shot you, fall down!
His father made his teeth out of two bullets,
so he loves his father.
Why don't you fucking die?
-He's the best one to find Frankie. -Six times.
-Six times?
At a time.
Well, you're in trouble now.
Sounds promising.
What are we waiting for?
Bonjour.
Well, what was it you wanted to tell me
so fucking important?
Mister, how do you think
why we have a dead body in our office
-with a briefcase strapped to your arm?
-Well, tell me soon.
Give us four days,
...and I'll bring you a fucking diamond,
the size of a house. I'm not kidding.
What do you think of that, Errol?
I think it's imperative that we drain the blood
to drain the blood while the time is right.
It was a rhetorical question, Errol.
Do you remember what I told you about, uh,
what you think?
-Give you 48 hours.
-Yes.
You can keep that fat faggot
you can keep it to yourself.
Anyway, the guys
can't get him off the floor.
After all, it's your family, fatty.
And if anything, the pigs will finish what the dogs can't,
what the dogs can't eat.
What should I call you? Bullet or Tooth?
Call me Suzanne if you like.
Tony, there's someone I need to find.
It depends on
how many elements are in the equation. How many are there?
40,000.
Where was he last seen?
Bookie's.
At the bookie's?
Give me the pipe, Susie.
-The bookie was put up last night. -Yes.
-They did? Tony, make yourself clear.
I thought you guys invented the fucking English language.
was invented here,
and you make it sound like
you can't understand a damn thing.
Kicked out, I mean robbed.
We're gonna meet someone
who might know something about this.
I need a gun.
You don't need no gun.
You need me.
So I fucked him up with black ink.
from head to toe.
Now he's gonna be dead before he dies.
And I took the gold, of course.
Fucking great.
Hey, Hammer.
Hey, Tony, how you doing?
You all right, buddy?
Nice tie.
I heard you retired.
No, the blood in my veins hasn't turned sour yet.
That's unlike you, Hammer.
Who put up the bookie Brick?
-Do me a favor, Tony.
-I'll do you a favor, Hammer.
I'm not gonna fuck you up
in front of your girls.
What good is that gonna do, buddy?
Jesus, I don't know anything.
Are you comfortable, Hammer?
What a sad irony:
your fancy tie will ruin you.
Well, now you can think about my question
on my question.
What the fuck are you doing, Tony?
Driving down the street with the glass over your head.
-What do you think I'm doing?
-Don't, Tony.
Hey, are you brushing your teeth with dog shit
instead of toothpaste?
Pull over, Tony.
Pull over, Tony!
I'm not gonna slow down.
I think I'm going to step on the gas.
Here, listen to the music.
I love this song.
Okay, I want to know who put out
Brick's bookmaking firm.
What, Hammer?
I think it was two black men,
who work at a pawn shop on Smith Street.
Did you think it through?
I'm telling you, it was two black men,
who work at the pawn shop on Smith Street.
Very effective, Tony.
Yes, it's not very gentle,
but very effective.
Are we taking him with us?
It's Russian.
Russian?
To be precise, he's an Uzbekistani.
Uzbek? I've dealt with those
sneaky-ass Russian dogs.
-First name.
-Yurinov.
Boris.
-Boris Razor?
-Yes.
Is that the Boris who's Boris the Dickens?
And why is his name Dick Dick?
Because you can't hit it, Avi.
He's not gonna fight
unless we buy his mom a motor home,
...and you took all our money.
Mother of God, can you say that again?
He's a stubborn bastard.
He says he has to take care of his mom.
-And then what?
-What can I do?
I can't make him fight.
Yes, Turkish,
you're not much use to me alive.
Useless asshole.
Punish that gypsy, Errol.
I want Gypsy to fight.
Brick decided that
if we smashed our slot machines,
it'll help me convince Mickey.
And as if that wasn't enough,
...He decided it would also be a good idea to ....
burn down Mickey's mom's cabin.
Burn it when she slept in it.
Turkish, come here.
You'll follow us--
...shoot the fuck out of you.
Calm down, son. Take it easy.
I got a gun, son.
So don't you mess around.
What?
You want to make sure my hand doesn't waver?
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry, Mickey.
Did you do it?
What are you sorry for then?
-You two, what are you doing here? -What are you doing here?
-Back.
-I'm going to give you a good one.
-Fuck off, Darren.
Get the fuck outta here!
What a fool I feel.
His mother is fuming beside us,
...and I ask him to fight in the ring.
All right, I'm gonna fight
before he kills anyone else.
If he had said no,
things would have been a lot worse.
Russians.
I should have known.
Cossack whores, you damn anti-Semites.
What do you know about this goy?
Former KGB officer.
He's had special training as an undercover agent.
He'll be impossible to find.
Yes.
There's a strange man here
wants to sell us an 84-carat diamond.
-Where did he come from?
-I don't know. It's hard to say.
He has a heavy Russian accent.
What was I supposed to do?
He was poisoning me with dogs. Here, look.
Sneaky fucking Russian! No wonder
he didn't want to do it himself.
All right, let's take it from the top.
One of us, uh.
Tyrone, that's you, is going to the Russian.
As soon as you see him, call us.
Let's go.
Look, you got to be careful with him,
with this guy.
I hate Russians. I'll deal with him.
No problem.
Call a doctor.
Shoot the fuck out of him!
And then call me a doctor.
Okay, but first we get the stone.
First the rock. Then the doctor.
And not just any doctor, boy.
A good Jewish doctor.
Find my friend a good Jewish doctor!
Take the keys from him and find the stone.
-I think you have something you want to tell us. -What?
-Calm down, honey.
Do you guys want him
so he can talk or what?
What the fuck is a fake, huh?
They're not combat-ready, but they look like the real thing,
and no one's gonna argue.
And the bullets may be blanks,
but they're extra loud, just in case.
Just in case we decide
to stun him to death or something?
-Yes.
-Boris is here.
-We're on our way. Don't let him out.
-Hey, wait.
He's not alone.
Let's go.
You're a fucking Cossack.
Sneaky fucking Russian.
So, where is he?
He's not alone anymore. Three men came into the house.
-And they locked Boris in the car.
-Why didn't you tell us about this?
How do they - do they look cool?
They look beat up.
-Let's get out of here.
-What about the Russian?
I want you to bury him.
All right. (chuckles)
I think we should get you a new gun.
But for now, try this one.
How much further to the Russian?
One minute left.
-Well, come on, then.
-No, no, not so fast, Winnie.
We can't take them now.
We have to follow them.
You shouldn't drink that stuff.
Why is that? What's wrong?
-She's out of sync with evolution. -She's out of sync with evolution.
-Shut up.
How do we get rid of him?
-Want to shoot me?
-It's too noisy.
-Would you like to stab me?
-That's too cruel.
-So do you want to kill him or what? -You want to kill him or what?
-I'll cut him up. I have a knife.
That's what I like.
Do they even shoot?
Of course they do.
How do you know? They're fakes.
What do you know about dummies?
What the fuck are you doing, Solomon?
You wanted to know if they were shooting or not.
I didn't say try it in the car,
Saul, you asshole!
And what are you gonna do with it.
pick his teeth?
Wipe the butter off of it
and put it back in the table.
It's a normal tool down there.
Cows were domesticated about 8,000 years ago.
Before that, they were like trucks--
running around.
The human digestive system
is not adapted to dairy products.
Fuck you, Tommy. Where'd you read that?
Let me help you.
Oops.
You. Do you need a knife?
No, I don't. I don't know what to do with him.
It's a knife, for Christ's sake.
What have you been doing at the same time
with a fork all these years?
Sharp side, dumb side.
What, you need a lesson?
Isn't that Boris, by any chance?
Tyrone, what have you done?
What are we gonna do about Bouton?
You can take it with you if you want.
Just tell me which part
is your favorite part?
They're coming out.
Lie down and watch them.
Cover yourself, Avi.
Just don't make a scene.
What scenes, Tony.
Shit, you don't have to bring the dog
with you, Vince.
I can't just leave her here, can I?
Pint of black, Warden.
I thought you wanted to wash up. The restroom's back there.
-He left the door open.
-I don't think that's a good idea.
Shall we go in?
I don't want to go in there.
It's a very dangerous animal.
They say Russians are very dangerous.
This one's a freak from every angle.
I don't give a fuck what he is.
All I need is a proper barrel,
and all my questions will be answered at once.
Jesus, Tommy,
you really do have a steady hand.
Well, hurry up, then,
before the Nazis land.
Just show him who's boss.
Boris...
That's quite a show.
Drowning Trout Pub.
Stop by and pick us up.
And Doug...
... make it quick.
I don't want to make a fuss, and I'm not gonna
put a bullet in your head,
...but if you don't give me what I need
what I want,
there's gonna be a fucking murder here.
What's your name?
Shoot him.
Let go of the gun!
Okay, so you're the local dick,
...and these on the sides are your balls.
There are two types of eggs:
...big, brave balls,
and little faggot balls.
Those are your last words, you better pray.
Obviously, every dick is always standing
looking out,
...only he's got no brains.
And as soon as he smells pussy,
he comes alive.
And now you've decided it smells like
of good old-fashioned pussy
and you brought with you
your faggot balls,
...to have fun.
But you're a little confused.
There's no pussy in here.
Now you're gonna wish you were
you weren't born a woman.
Like a brainless dick should,
...You don't understand the situation.....
...now you're starting to shrivel up.
And your little balls
are shriveling up with you.
That's because the side
on the side of your gun says "fake."
... and the .50-caliber Desert Eagle ...
... written on the side of my, uh.
There's nothing for you to catch here.
...along with your balls.
And now.
...get the fuck outta here.
Close the door.
Lock it up!
Give me the briefcase.
Fuck you!
Shoot me.
Of course you are. I'll shoot you.
Give me the briefcase or I'll shoot you.
You know what?
Fuck you, too.
Go ahead, shoot me.
Do me a favor, Russian faggot.
You! Drop your weapons.
Fuck you!
You, drop the gun!
All right. (chuckles)
Avi...
...get down!
-Tyrone?
-Fuck him, let's get the fuck out of here.
Give me the briefcase.
Avi...
-Where's the briefcase?
-Put the gun away
What's Boris doing here?
Fuck you!
Where's the diplomat?
-You piece of shit Boris,
I thought I told you to shut up.
I'll show you.
No hit.
Fucking hell.
Fuck you all.
Lucky bastard.
Look how flawless it is.
Don't get used to it. You should give it to Brick.
Leave the dog here.
-Saul, why can't we just leave? -Because life is short, Vincent.
-Because life is short, Vincent.
And if Brick wants it, it'll get even shorter.
-So, leave the dog here. -Yes.
-Yes, I'm leaving it here. -Yes.
Don't worry.
If that gypsy asshole here
messes anything up, you'll be held accountable.
It's okay.
Sit. Sit.
I don't want to go in there.
I'm never coming out of there.
You're not getting out of here
if you don't go now.
Okay, give me the rock...
...and I'll give it to Brick.
How's that?
All right. Uh-huh. Wait a minute.
I can't get it.
Why did you put it in there?
Well, I hid this in case we got robbed,
in case we got mugged.
Are you out of your mind or something?
Who's gonna rob two black men
who are sitting in a car with guns,
...that costs less than your shirt?
Tony the Bullet in the Teeth and his friend,
a .50-caliber Desert Eagle.
What do they care?
They both look right at me.
Never underestimate
the predictability of stupidity.
We got out of the car.
You can keep your water pistols.
Look, tell him the rock
is in the office.
I'll figure something out.
What's he so afraid of, Luxury?
Don't mind me.
Tommy, why are you sweating?
-Well, actually, I'm a little concerned. -Well, I'm a little concerned.
-Concerned about what?
What happens if the gypsy knocks this one out too?
I mean, it's happened before, you know?
We're going to be killed before we can get
out of the building and then fed to the pigs.
It makes me feel good to see you fucked up
and jumping up and down on the walls.
Pardon my cynicism,
but I don't trust the gypsy.
Don't think I haven't thought about it.
He's burying his mother tonight,
God rest her soul.
You know how gypsies drink at a wake.
I'm not worried
about Micky taking down his opponent.
I'm worried about whether this bitch is gonna make it
to the fourth round.
What if he doesn't make it
to the fourth round?
We're going to be killed
before we can get out of the building,
and I think they'll feed it to the pigs.
Why are you so calm?
-I said...
-I heard what you said, Tommy! -I heard what you said!
You don't have a choice, do you?
Show me how to hold
that fucking gypsy,
...and I'm gonna show you how to handle
of a cold-hearted thug,
who feeds human meat to pigs.
Oh, shit. I'm gonna go for a walk.
Fucking dog!
Hold her.
-Something smells in here.
-Open the window.
You live like animals.
Okay, where's the rock?
-Well, where is he?
-He's here.
-Where? -Where?
-I left it in the box.
It's empty.
I'm gonna have a heart attack.
Tony, do something scary.
No, I'm serious!
A dog. The dog must have eaten him.
Well, let's have a look. Tony.
-What?
-Look in the dog.
-What do you mean, look in the dog? -What do you mean, look in the dog?
-Well, I mean, open it up.
It's not a fucking can of beans.
What do you mean, open it?
You know exactly what I mean.
Well, that's a bit much.
I don't know anymore.
No, don't do that.
She's fucking beeping!
Haven't you ever heard a dog squeak?
Give me the damn gun!
I'll shoot that dog!
Fucking kill her!
You sneaky bastard!
Oh, thank God.
I fucking hate dogs! Come on, Tony!
Tony, let's go.
Tony?
-You want to declare something? -Yes.
-Yes. -Never go to England.
The dog will go back to the campground.
She goes back there all the time.
How will the dog find the campsite?
Saul, have you smelled what it smells like in there?
All right.
But first we'll wait until dawn.
In the meantime, we need to get rid of the bodies.
This one, with the teapot case on his head,
is starting to stink.
Right. Let's get them in the car,
and then we'll go look for a pig farm.
Mickey.
Micky!
Miki, are you feeling okay?
I need a drink.
You can't let him drink!
It's not for him. It's for me.
Ah, guys. Amen.
That Anderson-- Good night--
is a tough bastard.
So be careful.
You got it, Micky?
Micky!
I need a hangover!
If you see a gypsy, Turetsky or his girlfriend
or his girlfriend walking down the street in front of me.
...shoot the bastards.
All right, then. We got a fight to go to.
All right, Tom.
I hope this time we have
a fucking fight this time.
Yeah, I hope so.
Miki will lay down in the fourth.
Terry's over there taking bets.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Forgiveness will be when he lies down.
-Are our guys at the campground yet?
-Uh, yeah.
I hate fucking gypsies.
How long do we have to sit here?
As long as it takes.
Now shut up.
I hate fucking gypsies.
Is he fucking drunk?
He's always like this before a fight.
Do you know when you're supposed to go to bed?
Of course he knows when he has to lie down.
Hey, fuckface, who's asking you?
He asked him, all right?
Fucking snout? Well said, Errol.
I'll remember that the next time
when I'm getting off your mom.
-Not now.
-It's not a fight, it's a tragedy.
It's a good one. A real war.
Not yours.
Then there's a whole bunch of gypsies who might not find this
might not find it fucking funny.
Especially when they're
putting out their torched kids.
Get the fuck in the ring.
Three rounds and you'll get your brains blown out, gypsy!
Okay, I'm in charge here. No fucking around,
no pointing fingers in my eyes.
Let's do our best. Let's go!
What the fuck?
You gonna kill him or what?
Do you realize the consequences
if you knock him out?
Don't knock him out, Mickey.
Break.
Is he fucking deaf?
What's he doing?
Go sit down.
What the fuck are you doing, Micky?
Why are you dancing like a fairy?
If they find out you're mucking around,
they're gonna hang us.
Go ahead, hit him.
But just don't fucking knock him out.
All he has to do is not get up.
Well, now we're fucked.
He can't get up.
We gotta get outta here.
The dumb gypsy knew
that Brick's thugs with shotguns.
...sitting outside his campsite.
And once they kill everyone in the campground,
they'll do the same to us.
Have you ever been crossing the street.
and you look the wrong way?
Give me the fucking shotgun!
All of a sudden, there's a car right next to you.
So what are you doing?
Usually some stupid thing.
You freeze. And your life
doesn't pass in front of you at all,
...because you're so fucking scared,
you can't think.
You just freeze with a stupid face.
But gypsies don't. Why not?
Because he knew the cabin could be burned down.
I had an immediate impression,
...that he took the death of his mother
the death of his mother.
And for every action, there is a counteraction.
And the Gypsies' opposition
...fucking thing.
Pete, come in.
If you want your friend to hear you,
speak up.
-Give me the fucking shotgun!
-I'll give it to you, motherfucker.
That's when I thought that the gypsy
was betting all the money on himself all the time.
That's why the bastard wouldn't go to bed
when he had to.
He was shoeing us,
...and he profited.
And now we find ourselves in a position
even worse than when we started.
The next day we headed to the campground.
During the night, the gypsies disappeared.
It was probably for the best,
...considering that somewhere around here.
they buried 12 people.
Where is he?
We're not gonna fucking find him, I'm telling you.
We can't get a man to participate
in a fight if we can't find him, can we?
You can't find a gypsy who doesn't want to be found,
to be found, Tommy.
He and his rabble are fucking nowhere,
somewhere in Kampuchea.
Shit. Let's go.
-What are you doing here?
-What's it to you?
What are you doing here again?
I'm walking the dog. What's the matter?
What's in the car?
Seats and steering wheel.
What do you know about gypsies?
I know they can't be trusted.
All right, take your dog. And get out of here.
Get the dog, Tommy.
Get the dog.
All right, then. Come here. Come here.
Stop. Daisy, Daisy!
Loves the doggie.
He's always playing with her
playing stupid games with her all the time.
Stop fiddling and get in the car. Tommy!
Good, good.
Good doggy, Daisy, good doggy.
Can you give me a hint,
what's in your trunk
a corpse with a severed arm doing in your trunk?
George,
check it out. What's that on his head--
is that a teapot warmer or something?
Oh, you like the doggie, huh, Tommy?
Tommy convinced me to keep the dog.
It took me a while, but I agreed on the condition
he'd take her to the vet first.
Her squeaking is getting to be annoying.
And the vet found a dog in his stomach
a half-digested shoe,
a squeaky toy, and, uh.
...an 84-carat diamond.
It's amazing how many things
can happen in a week.
She still won't shut up.
Well, what's it gonna be?
You go to a man
who knows about these things.
Well, what do you think?
You don't know anyone
who might be interested?
Maybe me.