Parry Sound,
Georgian Bay's biggest variety.
Hey Bea, wake up honey,
we're almost there.
Bea?
Hey.
Hey! We made it.
You did.
How was the drive?
Not too bad, actually.
- Hello, buttercup.
- Hi, Dad.
Hey, you! Come on!
Can I go look inside?
Yeah, go.
Good dog.
Here, I'll take that.
Everybody, this is my daughter, Bea.
- Hi.
- Hi, Bea.
- My wife, Ally.
- Hi.
Pipe, can you watch the place a minute?
Sure.
Can I have an ice cream?
Yup!
Oh, you want to stack them.
No, not in there. Eric, no.
Stop!
- Hi.
- This summer's a trial,
Scotty.
Not promising anything.
- I know.
I know.
- Scotty,
I need my special milkshake
with extra vanilla.
- Coming up.
Hey, what would you say to
a hot tub in the backyard?
- That'd be cool.
- Mm-hm? You think your
mom would like that?
- I don't know,
because there's germs.
- Yes, germs.
Do you remember this place
when your grandfather had it?
- Sort of.
- Well, he's left it to me now.
Been working hard to fix it up.
- I like it.
- What?
- I can't hear you.
- I like it!
- I love this place.
I love that Scotty's
keeping it in the family.
That's good.
- No, it's for sale.
Joe up the road was yakking
about buying it, remember that?
- Yup.
- That would be a
disaster, though.
- I think a swimming pool
would be better than a hot tub.
- All right.
Let's build a swimming pool,
then.
- Hi.
- Hey.
What'cha reading?
- Catching the Big Fish.
- Do you like it?
- Yeah. Dad gave it to me.
- There's lots of great kids up
here, Bea.
- I know.
- You just need to take
some initiative.
- I wish I was older so I
could drink special milkshakes.
- You don't want
to be old.
- There's a spider up there.
- Where?
- In the corner, up there.
What if it crawls in my
mouth when I'm sleeping?
- It won't crawl in your mouth.
- Kitchen's closed for
the night!
- No, no, no, no.
- Good night bunny, love you.
- Love you, too.
- I'm a mechanic, right?
I'm a good one, but I
could be a great stripper
and there's money to it.
Could travel,
make love every night.
But you, you have a family.
That's the best, I'm jealous of
you, man.
He's not playing anymore.
- Callum, come on.
Good dog.
- Whoa!
- Was it dark enough for you
last night?
- Yes.
- Morning, Pipe. Western?
- Uh, sure.
- I hear you're thinking
about buying this place.
- I was, but the wife
says no, so that's that.
- That's right.
- Three cones, please.
- Sure. What kind can I get you?
- The orange.
- I'll have the
butterscotch one.
- And I'll take chocolate mint?
- Okay.
- I love those candies.
- Me too!
- They're the best.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- You didn't eat it.
- Not hungry.
- Hey Bea, I know you're a
little old for a lemonade stand.
- Yeah.
- But I did uncover a box
of gack up in the attic that
if you wanted to
put a table out?
- Okay, sure.
- Make some spending money,
good.
- Did you hear
about Gillian and Rachel?
- Oh my gosh,
I don't even know why.
He's such a fruit.
- I kind of like
him, he's pretty cool.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
- No, just don't.
- Sue, don't say that.
Guys, my ice cream's
really melting.
- Yeah.
- Oh, stop!
- Callum!
Come on, Callum!
Ready? Ready?
Ready to get the stick?
Get the stick?
Get the stick!
Go get it. Go on.
Come on, Callum, go get it.
- Dollar is spelled wrong.
It should be with an A.
D-O-L-L-A-R?
Want me to fix it?
- Okay.
- There, have you sold any yet?
- No.
- People around here are cheap.
Is that your dog?
- Yeah.
His name's Callum.
- His eyes are so cool.
My mom's allergic, so I can't
have one.
Let's put them in rows.
Hey, Pipe, want to buy
something?
- What are you selling?
- Tipis and canoes, and these
red jewels.
- The jewels aren't for sale.
- Oh.
- Um, all right, I'll
take a canoe.
- You sure you don't
want a tipi?
They look really good together.
- No.
- Sold!
Have a good day.
- All right, you too.
- See? Easy.
You here for the summer?
- Maybe, my mom doesn't
want to make any promises.
- What's her job?
- She's a teacher.
- Cool.
- But she's not my teacher.
- Yeah, that'd be weird.
- Yeah.
- Want to come to my house?
- I'd have to ask.
- Why?
Well, go ask, then.
- Just the bill.
- Okay, hey bunny.
- My friend wants to know
if I can go to her house.
- Who does?
- That girl.
She's helping with the gift
shop, and we just made a dollar.
- You good, Betty?
- Mm-hmm.
- She's the one who bought
that ice cream, remember?
You told me to take initiative.
- I know, I just thought
that maybe--
- Please, Mom? Can I go, please?
- Let her go. It's summertime.
- Okay, well, call me when you
get there.
- Okay, thanks.
- Scotty, please do not butt in,
okay?
- Okay.
- I just wanted to do something
fun today.
- I'll do something
fun with you.
- Where's your brother?
- How should I know?
- This smells moldy.
- Well, it's not.
- Hey, tell Romeo Nick's
having a party tonight.
- Maybe I will, maybe I won't.
They think they're so cool.
I'm Kate.
- I'm Bea.
- Good to meet you.
I think walkovers are
pretty easy.
I'm working on a back flip.
- I know some tap.
- Oh, you've got to
teach me to tap, promise?
- Okay.
Yeah, I've been taking
lessons for a long time now,
and it actually takes a
lot of ankle strength.
- What's your favorite
Popsicle flavor?
- Banana.
- Banana?
- Is that bad?
- Well, it's, like, the worst
flavor ever,
but it won't kill you
or anything.
- Well I also
like chocolate.
- Yeah, chocolate's much better.
Mountains or ocean?
- Ocean, I think.
- Paris or Hawaii?
- Hawaii, Hawaii, yeah.
- Um, hot chocolate or coffee?
- Hot chocolate.
- Walking or swimming?
- Walking.
- Hey, guys!
- Don't look at them don't
talk to them, keep walking.
- What's her problem?
- Why aren't they your
friends anymore?
- Because they squealed.
They made up stupid stuff
about Romeo.
Never, ever squeal that's a
rule, promise?
- I promise.
- That's just my brother.
He shoots stuff for fun.
Don't be scared. Come on.
Anybody home?
Hi-ya!
Romeo taught me karate for
self-defense.
Want a sip?
- No, thanks.
- I know what we can do.
I'm thinking of being a
hairdresser or a pilot.
Don't worry, I cut
Romeo's hair all the time.
- You're not cutting it,
are you?
- No, I'm just giving it a
little style.
Do you want to go to the party
or not?
- No.
Do we have to go?
- Yeah, of course what
else are we gonna do?
- Whoo, warm!
- Feisty man, feisty.
- All right! It's time.
Who's coming swimming?
- Sorry, Nick.
- Ah Billy?
- It's too early, man.
- You said you were coming in
for sure!
- Pass.
- I'll come.
- Really?
Billy, you're, uh one lucky
bastard to have this girl.
- Oh no! No!
- Let's go! Let's go!
- This way.
- Oh my God!
- You're so beautiful, Cheryl.
-  - No, I'm not.
- Yeah, you are.
Oh, god, yes.
- That's Romeo.
- We should do it.
- I don't know.
- Come on, trust me.
It'll be great.
- Romeo, I don't think, no.
No!
- What is wrong with you?
- What?
- You're a cock-tease!
This is bullshit. Forget it.
- I wanna go home.
- Cheryl is such a cock-tease!
- Why?
- Because she makes it seem
like she wants it all the time,
but then when he wants it,
she doesn't!
- What does he want?
- Jesus, Bea, don't you
know anything?
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
You can't help it that
you're from Toronto.
- What are you doing?
- Kissing. Was that okay?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
Wait here.
You sleep with your head
at this end,
and I'll sleep this way.
- I should call my mom.
- No, you already called
her twice.
Lie down.
- I have to go to the bathroom.
- Okay, hurry up.
Do you ever think that
maybe you're adopted?
- No.
- Sometimes I think I am.
Like I don't really fit
with my family.
- Well, I've seen pictures
of when I was a baby with
my mom and dad,
so I'm pretty sure.
- Did you cry a lot?
- I don't know.
- I feel like we could be
sisters, do you feel that?
- Yeah.
- Kiss me.
You taste minty.
Night.
- Good night.
- Oh, and try not to put
your foot in my face, whoops!
Turn the light off.
- Jesus Christ!
Who are you?
- I'm Bea. I'm Kate's friend.
- Go back to sleep.
Katie? Kate!
- Mom?
- You left the door
unlocked again don't be stupid.
- I left it open for Romeo.
- I want you to clean that
pool today, no more excuses.
- Hmm-mm, yeah.
- Live from
the Parry Sound newsroom!
- You sure you're not hungry?
- No.
- This is Moose News.
- Yeah, I miss you too.
So what time do you think
you're going to be here?
Luke, can you come have some
breakfast, please, Luke!
- Hey, you still owe me 50
cents.
- So are you okay for dinner?
- No, I don't!
- Yes, you do!
- No!
- Yeah, I loaned it to you
for your stupid pinball!
- No, 11 is too late.
Hey!
- Oh, yeah!
- Come here.
- Of course I'm disappointed.
Yeah, I'm disappointed.
This is bullshit.
You're just not going to
see your daughter this week?
- Make me a mix.
- Bea's dad runs the
Snack Shack.
- Cool.
- We started a gift shop
for money.
- What are you selling?
- Tipis and canoes
and stuff, they're handmade.
- Who made them?
- Friend of my dad's.
- Can you give me
a ride to Jesse's house?
- When?
- Now.
- Don't do it, he owes me
50 cents.
- I can't. I'm working
with Billy.
- Can I come?
- No.
- I need coffee!
- I'll get it for you, Mom!
- Thank you, love.
- What's your name again?
- Bea.
- Let's go outside.
Mom's making us clean the pool.
Come on, let's get in.
- It might have germs.
- Oh, my God.
Grab that net over there.
You think Romeo's cute?
- I don't know.
- Everybody falls in love
with him.
- What happened to his
head?
- Oh, last year, he got
into a motorcycle accident.
He had to have a
brain operation.
He almost died.
My mom was freaking out
'cause she loves him the most.
Why are you so serious
all the time?
You should see your face!
- What did you say to Mom?
- Nothing!
- Well, she knows something.
She was just screaming
her head off.
What did you tell her?
- I didn't!
- You don't know anything.
Okay? Nothing.
You hear me?
- I know.
- Don't stare at me.
- I didn't squeal.
He can't help it when
he gets mad.
It's just because of his head.
It's like there's a switch in
his brain, and it just flips.
It's like, he's okay, he's
okay, he's okay, and then bam!
Bam, bam, bam!
- I, I need to, I...
- Are you okay? What's wrong?
¶ Planning your escape
days away ¶
- Here, drink some juice, you
sleep okay?
- Yeah.
- What happened, did something
scare you?
- Nothing.
- Bea faints easily.
It's really common,
but if you feel
stressed or nervous, then--
- Mom. Mom!
- What? It's nothing to be
ashamed of.
Okay, if you feel dizzy,
you just lay down.
Stay close to the ground.
- I know.
- I think my mom might
have the same thing.
She's stressed all the time.
- Specials, on the house.
- I want you to take it easy,
okay?
- Okay.
- I can keep her company,
I've nothing else to do.
- That's great.
- I don't know.
- What?
- Your nose.
- How'd that get there?
Eat.
- I'd like a special.
- Give me a second.
- Thank you.
- She's a kid.
She's making friends. It's good.
- Am I doing something wrong?
- No.
- Thanks.
- It was delicious.
- Next time, you do the dishes.
Hey why don't we have a
family night tonight, okay?
- Okay.
- Get some rest!
- We will!
- Family night, pfft!
- Hi, Emile.
- Hey, Kate.
- What're you doing?
- I'm trying to get the battery
to work.
- That's cool.
Um, my mom was wondering
if you could fix her car.
- Well, depends what's wrong
with it.
- That's okay, thanks bye!
You did it! Come on!
You think she's hot?
- Yeah, she's really pretty.
Oh, I really like her--
- Her butt?
- No, her hair.
- God, Luke,
what are you doing here?
- What are you doing here?
- Something.
Ah, you want to see it, you've
got to show Bea your pee-pee.
- No way. You're crazy!
- Fine. Forget it.
- I don't want him to show me.
- You coming, or what?
Bea, stand here.
Luke, pull down your
pants for three seconds.
- No.
- Come on, what's the
big deal, it's nothing.
Pull down your pants, and you
get this whole sexy calendar.
- No way!
- This is Miss May, and
that's only a taste.
Pull them down now!
What no way,
you're such a chicken!
- Why'd you do that?
- I have to teach you stuff,
Bea.
You can't go through your whole
life without seeing a penis.
I'll show you.
This is how big it gets, and it
gets hard.
Romeo walks around with
a boner all the time.
- What's a boner?
- Oh, my god, Bea!
Do you wish I had a penis?
- No, I'm glad you
don't have a penis.
- You're my best friend.
Let's hide a secret
in this tree,
something you've never told
anybody in your whole life.
Ready?
- Ready.
- Parry Sound.
- Go.
- Thank you!
- Oh, sorry.
- I'm ready.
His opening shot, whoa!
And it goes in, oh, yeah!
Want to play some tennis?
- Sure.
- If you had to live
in a world of only movies
or only books,
which would you choose?
- I don't know.
That's a hard question.
- Yes.
I'd go with books.
- Really?
- Definitely.
- Think I'd have to go
with movies.
Couldn't live without movies.
- Holy
mackerel.
- Think I missed a
big chunk of the movie there.
- Watching them?
- Good night.
- Night, bunny!
- Night, love.
- It still changes everything.
- What?
- Well, you said you
were selling,
and now you're talking
about renovating,
and those are two
different things.
- I don't wanna
fight tonight.
- Okay, you know what?
I think you should sleep
on the couch.
- No.
- I'm serious.
- I'm serious too, no.
- Go on.
- No. Close the door.
- Wake up!
What do you think?
They're called French Midnight.
Lola put them on.
- Nice!
- I have to brush my teeth.
- Did you dream about me
last night?
I dreamt about you, here.
A present.
Put 'em on.
- Breakfast time.
You coming down?
- In a minute!
- Is Kate in there with
you, I'm making omelets.
- Ooh, omelets,
omelets sexy, sexy omelets.
- Bea?
- I'm coming!
- I wanna teach you something.
Pay attention.
Open your mouth.
Open your mouth!
Wider. Okay.
Stick your tongue out.
- Whoa.
- No, it's called
French kissing.
Okay, I put my tongue
in your mouth,
and you put your tongue
in my mouth, all right?
And we kiss, okay ready,
do it again.
- Okay.
- Open your mouth.
All right.
Maybe Cheryl had her period,
and that's why she didn't
want to have sex with Romeo.
Do you have your period yet?
- No.
- Oh, my God.
It's the curse.
Every month, a bucket of blood
comes out.
I can teach you how to wear a
tampon, or you can wear a pad,
but they're gross and mostly,
you can't get pregnant while
you're on your period, but
sometimes you still can,
like my sister, Lola,
sometimes freaky things happen.
Did you like it when I French
kissed you?
- Yes did you like it
when I did it to you?
- It's pretty good for your
first time,
but you'll get better at it.
- How come you spit like that?
- For moisture.
Breakfast?
- All right.
- You guys good?
- Yep.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
- More coffee
when you get a chance?
- Sure.
Did you have breakfast?
- I can pay
for the ice creams.
- I want you to eat.
- It's summer holidays, Mom.
- Well, tell your dad you
don't want his omelet,
and if you faint, don't come
crying to me.
- Your mom was way more mad than
your dad.
- He was sad, though.
- Does he ever make spaghetti?
- Yeah, sometimes.
- I would be so fat if I had
your dad.
My dad's a loser.
Do you think he's possessed?
- No.
- His eyes are freaky,
I think he's possessed.
- I don't think so.
- Then why is he so happy all
the time?
- Well, my mom rescued him.
- Well, he's not normal.
I want to go to my house
and make halter tops.
He can't come,
my mom hates dogs.
They just get everything dirty.
- Stay, Callum, you can't come.
- You start.
- I start?
- Yeah, you start.
- I'm going.
- Why does it have to be
Nick's dog?
- Because he didn't pay,
shut up.
Hey, not for you, runt,
put them back.
- Can I have a beer?
- You only get one if you
play, how 'bout it, Bea?
- Hey don't be a jerk,
leave her alone.
- Okay, , it's your
turn, go.
- 'Kay.
- Okay, oh oh,
my god, 'kay.
So yesterday,
when I was at work,
this guy came in and
completely spazzed out--
- I like dogs.
- Shut up, Billy.
- Anyway, and then he
got back up,
and oh, look at that.
- Really? I lose, great.
- Nice.
- Sure you don't want to play?
- No, we don't want to play.
This is my room.
Lola's learning how to
make clothes for fashion.
It's like a can-can skirt.
- This is the same kind
we have at the Shack.
- Oh, yeah I took that from
you before we were friends.
Look, she made this too.
It's like a halter top.
You should try it on.
Take off your shirt.
- Hey!
Out, now!
- It's my room too.
- Don't touch my stuff.
Seriously, you guys,
if Lisa starts to cry,
I'm gonna kill you.
- Bitch!
- Kate, you are
such an idiot.
- Hello?
Yeah.
Okay.
Shit.
- I feel dizzy.
- It's okay just lie
down, like your mom said.
Have a chip.
- Okay, salt is good.
- Hey, you know what
I've been thinking?
I've been thinking that I can
come back to Toronto with you.
We don't really fit here.
- My mom says she doesn't fit
here either.
- Are they gonna divorce?
- I don't know.
I think I should go home now.
- No.
Hey, do you wanna borrow this?
I can loan it to you, and
you can get here faster.
The brakes don't really work
that good, but that's okay.
Never slam on the brakes.
Otherwise, you'll go flying
over the handlebars and die.
- Kate? It's dinner.
Tell your girlfriend to go home,
okay?
- She acts mad, it's just
because she's lonely, see ya!
Hey! They're my favorite.
Put them in your pocket.
- Thanks.
- Come on. I know.
Bea, can you help me a second?
- What happened?
- Just hold him still.
- Do you think he's possessed?
- No, I don't think
he's possessed.
He's got a thorn in his paw.
- You're so brave, I love you.
- You're a lucky boy,
eh?
You're a lucky dog to
be loved by this one.
There you go, hey,
who's a good dog?
- I'm sorry for what I
said to you this morning.
Of course I never want
you to faint, I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- There's lots of other
girls up here, you know?
You could make more friends.
I don't wanna make more friends.
- I just think you and
Kate have been spending
a lot of time together
- She's my best friend.
- I know.
If something's on my mind, I
want to feel like I can talk to
you about it, and you should
feel like you can talk to me.
We're a team, right?
- Yeah.
- Well, is there anything
you want to talk to me about?
- Could Kate come back with us
to Toronto?
- What?
- She feels like she's adopted
and she doesn't fit here.
- No.
- Why couldn't she just come
with us at
the end of the summer?
- No!
- Why?
- Because she's not adopted.
Her family is here,
and she has school.
- She can change schools.
- No, Bea.
- Then what if I stayed here?
- We're not staying here.
- Apple pie is ready!
- Are you and Dad
getting a divorce?
- No.
- Promise?
- Yes, I'll bring you some pie.
- Maybe could Kate come live
with us?
- We'll see.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Can I have some?
Thank you.
- Hey, Ally, what time
do you want us back?
- Six o'clock.
- Sounds good.
- Are we going swimming?
- No menus,
fries to go, please.
- Sure.
- Mom?
Are we still going swimming?
- Yes.
- When?
- Soon.
- You can have one,
I'm not having any.
- Oh, thank you, we're
going to keep going.
- Want to buy one?
- No.
- Mommy, you can have one,
go, go, okay!
- Hey, Bea.
Oh, that's nice.
I'll have three three tipis
and two canoes, please.
- Really?
- Yeah, I'm going to
make a mobile with them.
My sister just had a baby.
I'm an uncle.
That's cool, right?
- Yeah, that's cool.
- Was born blue.
The cord was wrapped around
her neck three times,
but her fists were like this.
Gonna be a fighter.
My sister had to be knocked out,
though.
I could never be a parent,
goodbye!
- Thanks, Emile!
I made $5.00!
- Fantastic.
- I wanna go.
- I asked my mom about
moving to Toronto with you.
- What did she say?
- She said go ahead,
but she said there's
no way your mom
would say yes,
did you ask your mom?
- Yeah.
- What did she say?
- She said, "We'll see."
- She said, "We'll see?"
That's like a yes!
- I don't think she meant yes.
- I'm so coming to
Toronto with you!
Could we share a room?
- We could share my room.
It's not that big, but--
- We can go to the same school!
- Yeah! We'll have Mr. Grey.
He picks his nose and hides
it in his beard all the time,
but he's nice.
- This is my favorite place.
You're the first person
I've ever brought here.
- Oh, it's so slimy
on the bottom.
- Don't touch
the bottom.
Gotcha!
- Oh my God, ah!
Are there any poisonous
snakes around here?
- Yeah, probably.
- Oh.
Well, once, I went hiking
with my dad when I was little,
and one was that close.
You could hear the rattle
and Callum tried to save me.
He was just a puppy, and he
was going to bite it, but then
my dad picked up a rock and
smashed it on the snake's head.
- Did it die?
- Yeah.
- That's a really sad story.
Hey, I know a secret hideout.
- My dad says we
shouldn't go off the path.
- Do you always do what
your dad says?
Come on!
- Kate!
- I wanna show you!
- Wait up!
Got you!
- Ssshht!
- Okay, Billy, let's do this.
- Okay.
Oh, shit, hold on.
You got it?
- Yeah, hurry up.
- What are they doing?
- We need to go.
- No, we have to stay.
- Pull it up.
- Please.
- Ssshht!
- Okay, tie it down to
that tree or something.
- I'm scared.
- You're always scared!
Don't be such a chicken!
- Hello, who's there?
- Hey!
Hey, what are you doing!
- Kate, Jesus Christ!
- Is that Nick's dog?
- Get the hell outta here!
- What did you do to his dog?
- It's none of your business!
- Hey, shut up!
We have to do this, Kate.
It's none of your business.
- Romeo stop!
You're hurting me!
- You shouldn't be here!
- Bea help me!
- No!
- Get outta here, okay?
Go home, now! Run!
- Dude, we gotta bounce.
- Ah shit!
Billy, help me.
Kate, come on.
- My head...
- We've gotta
get out of here, man.
- Lift her up.
- Hey!
Never squeal.
Kate!
Kate, where are you?
Don't faint.
Please do not faint.
Stop being scared.
- Come on, Pipe,
it's not that hard.
You can do this.
Bea, there you are.
Can you help Joy
blow some balloons?
- I can't blow balloons right
now, Mom.
- What? Of course
you can.
Eric, go check on Scotty.
- I'll check on him.
- Okay.
Thanks.
- Come over here, baby.
Over here, buddy.
Can Mommy see your balloon?
We can compare.
- Dad?
- Hey, look at these.
Emile did most of the work,
but I'm the finishing
touches guy.
How's my buttercup?
- I'm not a buttercup...Dad.
- I know. Okay.
I'm never calling you
that again.
How's Forsythia?
Forsythias are cool.
- Hey, Ally!
- Hey, come on in, guys!
- Do you need any help
with anything?
- No, I think we're
just finishing up here.
- Awesome!
- Grab yourself some beer!
- What is it?
- It looks great.
- Hey!
- Hi!
- Did you go swimming?
- Yeah.
- Okay, well, put your
wet stuff in the sink.
Grab a cake.
- Scotty, get in here!
- Coming.
- They're coming,
they're coming.
Ssshht, okay, okay they're
coming, go, go, go.
The birthday girls!
- Happy birthday!
- Party time.
- And there's cake!
- Look at that.
- Nice.
- All right.
- Beautiful.
- Happy birthday,
I wanna be part of this.
- It's not your birthday.
- I know, it's their birthday.
- Thank you.
- Thank you!
- Hey.
- I wanted to bring back
Kate's bike and her clothes.
- Okay, thanks.
- I really need to see her.
- Well, she's at the hospital
with my mom.
- Is she okay?
- Yeah, she's fine.
She just had a bit of a fall.
- Is she mad at me?
- Why would she be mad at you?
Look, I think you should
just stay away from
my sister for a while.
- Why?
- Because you're
causing trouble for her.
- How am I causing trouble?
I brought her some candy
they're her favorites.
- Okay. Go home now.
- I can think of something
you haven't done before.
- Oh yeah?
- Okay.
First, there's seven cards
all together.
The first one is turned over.
- Tell me, are you one?
- Are you two?
Are you three?
Are you four?
Are you five?
Are you six?
Are you seven?
Are you eight?
Are you nine?
Are you 10?
Are you 11?
- Okay, that's enough.
- Are you 12?
Are you 13?
Are you 14?
Are you 15?
Are you 16?
Are you 17?
Are you 18?
Are you 19?
- So she couldn't
hold it anymore.
- Are you 20?
Are you 21?
- Mom?
- Bea, where have you been?
- I had to return Kate's bike.
- Aw, you missed
the cake.
- It was some really good cake.
You can use this one.
- Are you 27?
Are you 28?
- Thanks.
- So what happened?
- Are you 29?
- So she just pissed
on the floor,
right there, in the restaurant.
- Oh, that's something I've
never done.
- Exactly see,
I told you!
- I'm going to bed.
- Are you 36?
- Oh, no, honey come on,
stay with us.
Oh lord, what is going on out
here, whoa.
- I'm okay! I'm okay.
No broken bones.
I think we should slow it
down a little bit, though,
if you don't mind.
- Where did Bea go?
- She just left.
- You want some?
- How are you so happy
all the time?
Mom?
Mom, what happened?
- Tonight was good, I think.
I was happy.
Were you happy?
You seemed happy.
- Is Dad okay?
- Wait a minute.
What's going on here?
- Well, what do you think is
going on, Bea can see you.
- Hmm, not an idiot.
- Really?
- Do you think I'm an idiot?
- That's enough.
- Leave
me alone.
- Can I help you?
- I'm fine, honey.
Please, just go back to sleep,
okay?
- I just need to give me
a little bit of credit.
- What about me, what
kind of credit do I get?
- Well, it would depend on how
much credit
you think you need, 'cause it
doesn't ever really seem to
be enough.
Thank you so much for
taking the orders, Ally.
Thank you so much for doing
this other thing, Ally.
Bea, I'm sorry,
can you help me, please?
No, Bea, I'll tell you, she gets it.
Gets what?
No, please stop!
Don't do that.
I'm so sorry, darling, I'm sorry.
It's this place, Scotty.
It is not this place.
I love this place, and Bea
loves this place, right?
Bea gets it.
She cares unlike you.
That is not fair! That's not fair!
So why don't we just
let this whole place burn?
- All right, Bea, go back to
your bed.
- We should probably just...
If you hate this place so
much, just let it burn!
- Shut up!
I'm done.
- No, you're not.
- Bea.
Wake up.
We need to go.
- Where?
- We're leaving now.
- What?
- Get up, get dressed.
Come on.
- Where's Dad?
- Let's go.
- Why don't you ever
listen to me?
- Ssshht, not now!
- What about Callum?
- Dad needs Callum
to stay here.
- I have to see Kate.
- Get in the car.
- You promised.
- I didn't promise
anything.
- You did.
- I've been trying, Bea.
Your dad's been trying too.
It doesn't work.
He doesn't listen, and it's
been building and building.
I don't know what else to do.
Bea!
Bea, oh, my God!
Oh, my god, hold on.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
It's gonna be okay, hold on.
Scotty!
Scotty, help!
It's Bea, she jumped out
of the car.
- What?
Bea, don't move.
- Hey, honey.
- Hi, beautiful.
- Do you need anything?
- Is Kate here?
- I don't know.
- Daddy?
- I'm here.
- How's everybody doing?
- We're all right.
- I'm Dr. Roe.
Do you remember me from earlier?
- Yeah.
- Do you still have
your headache?
- No.
- Okay.
I'm just gonna have
you sit up for a moment
so I can have a listen
to your chest.
That's it.
And big breath and out
and again and out.
Great.
And just look over here
with your eyes only,
and the other way.
Great, and you can lay
back again.
So I've reviewed the
CAT scan and the x-rays,
and thankfully,
everything looks good.
That was quite a tumble you
took, though.
Were you trying to
hurt yourself?
- No.
- Why did you jump out of
the car?
- So I could be with Kate.
- Kate is your friend?
- She thinks I'm chicken,
but I'm not.
- You're not a chicken?
- No.
And I don't want my mom
and dad to fight anymore.
- All right.
I'm going to talk to your
mom and dad for a minute.
Is that okay?
- Okay.
- Be right back.
Ssshht, it's okay, okay.
- Well, we've been separated
for about three months
me living up here, them
living in the city.
- She's never talked about
hurting herself before?
Did she show any signs of
depression over
the last few months or
the past year in school?
- No so we're good to
take her home?
- Kate?
- You look worse than me.
Did they bring you any Jell-O?
- Not yet.
- They said I could go
home today.
- That's so great,
I'm sorry I ran away.
- It's okay.
- But I didn't squeal.
I didn't tell on Romeo.
It was really hard.
- Is it true you jumped
out of a car?
- Yeah.
- You're even crazier than I am.
I got seven stitches,
right across.
- Wow.
- Romeo confessed about the dog.
The cops came and everything.
- Really?
- He's gonna get some help now.
My mom says I'm a tough cookie.
- I wish I was a tough cookie.
- You are.
- Hey.
- Kate?
- Bea!
- Kate!
- Wait up!
- Kate can't go to Toronto with
you, Bea.
- Mom?
- I'm sorry.
- Can you unlock the door for
me, please?
Thank you.
- If you're leaving,
I wanna come with you.
- What about your family?
- Jesus, Bea! I was just
kidding.
You should see your face,
so serious.
I mean, I can't actually
come to Toronto.
I know we said it
and everything.
- What's in the suitcase?
- Oh, it's just Lola's stuff.
She said I could sell it, so...
You could come visit,
I want you to.
Maybe, but I think my mom
really needs me right now...
...to help with baby Lisa and
my brother Luke and stuff.
I think my parents
really need me, too.
The halter top,
it'll look really good on you.
You're more than my best friend.
I know.