Present a Jan Jakub Kolski film
PORNOGRAPHY
Screenplay
Based on the novel by Witold Gombrowicz
Starring
Set Designers
Interior Design
Costume Designer
Makeup
Edited by
Sound
Production Managers
Executive Producer
Producers
Music
Cinematography
Directed by
That spring 1 kilo potatoes
cost 0.6 zloty in Warsaw...
1 litre milk 0.54 zloty,
1 litre kerosene 1.20,
Parsley, 0.15.
It was Warsaw 1943
in the wartime Poland...
... deep in the teeth
of German occupation.
With my friends from the Rity cafe
before the war...
... we'd now meet in an apartment...
... only to drink and still try to be
artists. writers. and thinkers.
What brings you here,
Frederick?
A cold arctic wind...
or maybe a warm one... I forget.
Is that so?
Earnest as can be,
I've got four hare pelts
and leather soles to sell.
Anyone interested?
Thank you.
Counsellor Lipszyc.
Baron von Ordo's daughter.
Mr. Leleniewski, composer,
deep into the esoteric East.
Painters,writers
and poets who survived.
The best blue blood in town.
What more can you want?
Just a match, please.
- Where have you been?
- Stop it.
- Stop it!
The cloying smells there...
the shamelessly bandied
words,
"God, art, theatre, nation,
proletariat..."
as if the war was of no
concern to us.
We chatted while Europe
was in flames.
Then Frederick arrived,
sat down and said little.
Hardly could I realise that
he'd get me involved
in the strangest story
of my life.
Am I handsome?
You look young.
But am I handsome?
You have a striking face.
But we don't
call it handsome.
You’ve got carried away, huh?
But I like you anyway,
my dear Witold.
I'm not handsome
but you know what?
I'm beautiful.
Let's go.
In the next months.
as we got close...
... he turned out to be
quite refined...
... experienced in theatre,
film, and circus art.
One day my old friend
Hippo S. from the Sandomierz region...
... wrote asking me over
with my new friend.
"It's peaceful here but for
some bands of marauders."
"The countryside isn't safe."
"Come, both of you.
The more the merrier."
What's in there?
- Something.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Meaning?
Everything.
Everything?
Will you take the boy
to the manor...
... with a heavy bag of onions?
Sure.
Karol!
There they are.
Thank God, you've arrived.
This must be Mr. Frederick.
- Welcome.
I know... you wrote...
theatre, wrestling bouts...
... romancing all those
chorus girls, right?
Right.
I won’t ask anything.
- Let me take your case.
- No, thank you...
I’ve grown fat.
Devil only knows why.
Because of everything.
And you're following in my footsteps.
And that's Mary.
My wife... my dear Mary.
They burned Sieniechów. In Rudniki.
they broke the overseer's legs.
I had refugees
from Poznan.
No news from Ostrowiec or
Bodzechów whatsoever.
Everybody's waiting, all ears...
It's peaceful for the time being.
But wait till it bursts
when the front line gets closer.
It'll be a bloodbath...
an explosion, a riot...
Like I say...But the worst thing is
there's nowhere to run.
...pray for us now. and
in the hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary. full of grace,
The Lord is with thee...
... blessed art thou among women
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb.
- Hello, Iie-abed!
- What time is it?
- Oh, it's late.
- I promise to improve.
And here's Henia.
my beautiful one...
... the most beautiful
in the whole world.
Mum is ready
and the horses are too.
It's Sunday, we’re off to Mass.
You may join us if you like,
but we won't force you.
Truth is the church burned down
and Mass is in the coach house.
You may find it quite interesting,
gentlemen.
... Your crown woven of
stars on your head...
I didn't understand
what moved Frederick so much...
Must've been someone
he saw or remembered?
- What's your name?
- Veronika.
Are you sure?
And that's Henia...
My little Henia...
Karol, son of the
overseer of Ikana.
Now. A handyman
in Hippolit's care...
A flaxen-haired god,
daring partisan...
and a reckless whipper-snapper.
His appearance tipped
the delicate balance...
... between us and them.
There was too much youth now.
Something pert about Henia
lording it over us. unawares.
Her youth wasn't meant for us...
Karol's youth was for Henia,
and hers was for him...
But the whipper-snapper
and the silly goose didn't know it.
Siemian and his men.
Must've shot someone.
Let's go to sleep.
I saw.
A nice couple.
God willing, she'll get
engaged one of these days.
Someone local?
Yes. a neighbour,
Vaclav Paszkowski of Ruda...
a very decent man indeed.
His mother runs the estate,
a saintly woman, but... a widow.
Henia's young...
No better suitors around, though.
Attorney-at-law, responsible,
talented, and very well-read.
I see,
Why so sad?
There's something cheeky
about youth, don't you think?
What?
Everything.
I haven't thought about it.
Didn't you see they're
made for each other?
I didn't spy on them.
No mutual attraction at all.
What's lacking
is the chemistry of love.
- What?
- The chemistry of love!
No power can join them.
Rather than power,
it only takes a few tricks...
Like housebreaking a dog.
- Give them a push.
- What?
- Right away?
Now.
Do you know
what you're abetting?
You really don't.
You want it?
I do.
Want to make a bet?
- What's at stake?
- Exactly...
- I don't know.
How. about... everything?
Meaning?
You'll see.
Wait.
12 cigarettes...
rolled specially for you.
Brown-nosing, huh?
Are we intruding?
No. I've had it with
these potatoes.
Would Miss...
care for a... stroll?
I sure would.
Closer to the socket.
Karol!
The trouser leg!
Roll it up.
Wait!
Let her do it
Why me?
Do it for him.
So... Let’s go.
The suitcase.
Vaclav...
the captivating lawyer...
Henia's fiancé... and yes...
Frederick's future victim.
I got it instantly and felt
my sympathy for him grow.
Welcome onboard, friend.
Mr. Frederick, it's terribly sad.
Sad?
Away with it!
Gone!
Play a happy tune, please.
Happy?
Please.
Bravo!
So talented... Is there
anything you can't do?
Many things.
Like what?
Well, I can't take you away
from Vaclav. try as I might.
No one can do that...
in the whole world.
No thank you.
Hans...
Berta keeps writing me...
Good girl.
... to beware of
those dangerous Poles.
Hans!
But they're such nice folks.
Eggs! Eggs, for fuck's sake!
Eggs! Capish?
Eggs!
Mr. Myszynski!
- Should I give them eggs?
- Yes. And fuck them!
Good morning!
Good morning! They don't
understand a fucking word.
Lock the horses in.
With the cows.
- Eggs.
- Yes, eggs.
Wait a minute.
Here are your eggs
My pleasure.
A gift from
our chickens and cows.
Zoska, the milk!
Here you are.
Here.
- Thank you.
- Good day.
Andres... eggs!
- Here.
- No, thank you.
Good bye.
Good fucking riddance!
Don't ever come back again.
I get drunk...
... when I'm afraid.
I stash bottles away everywhere,
in case I get scared.
Do you ever get scared?
Never.
Never?
Sometimes.
- Got scared?
- And how!
So have a drink.
I will.
Hello!
Where to?
To the village
to get kerosene.
- May I come along?
- Please do.
- And Mr. Frederick?
- No, thank you.
I have to tend the flowerbeds.
The King came and sprinkled...
... silver poppy seeds on the eyes
of the mouse and the red pony.
The Poppy King's knights
wandered for years.
The mouse got very tired.
"Peep. peep. when do we get home?"
The King asked,
"Who's been sleeping in my bed?"
"Who's been drinking from my bowl?"
Peep, peep, peep...
We're playing.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
What a beautiful dolly!
It's not a dolly.
What is it?
The Poppy Seed Princess.
May I see her?
What will I do without her?
I may die...
I'll spank you!
Little mermaid...
I have a daughter your age.
Delicious...
Got any more?
- It's paid already.
- For the book.
It may be your most expensive one.
What?
Having the time of your life, huh?
I'm working hard.
I see.
What's wrong?
Something happened?
Nothing's happened whatsoever.
- Why so nervous then?
- Because I like it.
I can't do without it.
Take a sip, come on.
Smell the flowers...
See how beautiful it is?
The man on high
is watching over us.
The children are playing...
... and we’re playing with them.
Remember?
What's the matter?
- The cork's inside.
- I'll pull it out.
- I'll get another one.
- I'll do it...
Leave it!
See what you've done?
Karol!
Why are you shouting
at the woman?
Don't be scared. It's dead.
Want it?
Why worry?
We have enough to eat.
- What're you doing?
- Shining my shoes.
Yes? Here!
I'll shine them for you.
I'll drive the horses. Dad. OK?
Witulin's not far, dear.
- Barely 5 km.
- Please, Mum...
All right, but with an adult.
- Mr. Witold?
- Excellent choice.
Witold's a born teamster.
Karol! You'll come
with us in a taxi!
- You like Karol?
- Of course...
- He's a childhood friend.
- I know.
But do you fancy him?
- I?
- Yes.
- I like him very much.
- Is that all?
He's a beautiful boy
and in love with you.
Not with me or any other girl.
He just wants to get laid.
He's just a child!
Hurry up!
All right. I'll tell you.
I'm no shrinking violet.
I laid a Home Army man
who stayed with us one night.
Do your parents know?
They caught us red-handed.
But they didn't catch on.
- Why not Karol?
- Because.
But you won't tell Vaclav, right?
He believes in your
spiritual communion...
He's a true Catholic.
Do you think
I have no morality?
I'm Catholic too!
You believe in God?
Would I confess or take
Communion if I didn't?
My future man's principles
suit me to a T.
His mother is almost mine.
I'm honoured to join
a family like his.
Ah, here they are!
No more flings
once I marry him.
Dear Mrs. Amelia.
This is Mr. Frederick, mother.
And Mr. Witold, his friend...
... a man of letters.
With her arrival, a new aura
filled Hippolit's house...
... superior, absolute,
dispelling any doubts.
Frederick cast away his
two live toys, Henia and Karol.
Engrossed in talk with Amelia,
he was dead to the world.
They flew over our heads
of ordinary humans...
... mostly about God
and the beauty of the world.
Just look how beautiful
it is here.
Absolutely... beautiful.
But take a really good look
and admit if it's not.
Really very beautiful indeed.
Just magnificent!
- You're an atheist, right?
- Right.
- Say it, please.
- I am...
I'm an atheist.
- I knew it.
- Bravo.
I'm bored without you,
bored to madness...
Along with my dog
and my squirrel...
I write, read, and smoke
and my eyes are still blue.
But all this is just
the force of habit...
The dawn is still grey
and the dusk gold-blue...
Day crosses to one.
night to the other side...
... and the roses bloom
seemingly unwilling...
... as they can't do otherwise.
Yet the world has ended.
can you understand?
It is no more
and I won't bring it to life.
The time is hard and quiet,
but wait a minute... I...
... may be already
on the other side.
'Without You' by
Maria Pawlikowska-Jasnorzewska.
Are you all right, Mrs. Amelia?
- What're you doing. mother?
- Mrs. Amelia!
- Oh Jesus!
- Watch out!
Water! Mr. Myszynski!
Put it out!
Shoot at everything.
Karol!
She's bleeding copiously.
What do we do?
I don't know.
Come close to me, please.
Closer.
Don't leave, please.
You'll see.
I want you to see...
... everything till the end.
Jesus!
Sir, we caught the bastard
near Rokiciny...
Silence.
He had the knife on him.
My mother couldn't
have died just like that.
No, please!
- How then?
- I don't know.
Not that way.
We don't know what happened...
... not you, me, or even that boy.
Perhaps, as he says...
... he took a knife to cut the cake...
- No! No. no.
She couldn't have died like that.
- It wasn't like that.
- It could’ve been!
It could have been.
Imagine it.
Even a majestic lady
like your mother...
... could have died under
the silliest circumstances...
... for a piece of cake.
Understand?
I don't know.
Let's go... please.
Thanks to Hippolit's connections,
the death was recorded
as 'due to natural causes.'
The killer was back on Hippolit's
estate, locked up in the Belfry...
... waiting for God knows what
by the decision of no one knew who.
Stop! Listen
You ride too fast
but sow the grain correctly.
- And the raspberry?
- OK.
You can get dressed.
- The next rehearsal?
- I'll let you know.
Well, what do you think,
dear Witold?
- Do they act well?
- It's going to be a film.
- A film?
- Uh-huh.
I have an idea of a screenplay.
But some scenes require
experimenting with live actors.
Writing a script with no actors
in mind is sheer nonsense, right?
First get them to strut their stuff.
And the script should
bring out what's in them.
You were great.
Wait till I tell you.
- Goodbye.
Aren't you ashamed?
Of what?
Shame doesn't belong in art.
Boor! Murderer!
What murderer?
It's not true!
I won't let you.
He's a prisoner
and cannot be beaten.
Don't be afraid.
It's that death...
I can't come to terms with it.
Look, your mother always
got down to essentials, right?
And you?
But I can't.
What should I do?
Do what you will,
but wear your dignity intact.
Tell me what I should do.
Live through it till the end!
Drink every drop of her death
to the bottom!... Got that?
Shitass!
I've lost my voice.
Come!
What's this?
I'm writing as I've lost my voice.
Judge by this if I've gone crazy,
as I'm not sure myself.
When you finish reading this letter.
burn it and pretend...
... that nothing happened.
Vaclav must see our show.
Tell him you’ve found out
about their trysts...
... and find it your duty
to let him know.
We’ll put the heat on them
till the appearance of betrayal is out.
Then we'll see what happens.
Don't reply. I'll leave instructions
under the brick by the gate.
We're running out of eggs, Andreas.
Let's visit the funny Pole.
What's his name?
The fatso playing the chicken?
Hippolit or something.
Oh, the last eggs.
Karol!
We've taken the right path.
We’ll turn Vaclav into a bed
on which Karol lays Henia.
Be gentle and considerate and
Vaclav will believe the hoax.
P.S. Did you recognise the man?
Colonel Siemian of the
local Home Army unit...
... who stopped us on the road.
Why did you bring me here?
I found it my duty.
Thank you very much.
I don't think it matters much.
Thank you for bringing it
to my attention.
They want to liquidate Siemian.
Yesterday they came from Warsaw
about a planned action...
... but what followed was
a pathetic scene.
The colonel said
he was going home...
... that he'd lost his courage
and was full of fear.
Really pathetic.
Too much tension.
It's a... disaster!
You should've seen it.
All those secrets he knows.
In his present condition,
he's likely to squeal.
He will.
What now?
They'll send some hatchet men
with his death sentence...
- What do you think?
- I? It must be done.
I see it like a soldier!
And we?
You what?!.
From now on, you too
are soldiers. Wait.
Wait for your orders!
Mother!
We have a problem with Siemian.
This has messed our plans.
Let's wait it out
and see what happens.
We'll have to act in sync now.
You must burn this letter.
Yes?
- May I have a word with you?
- Come on in.
- Would you rather rest?
- No. no.
You know why I'm here?.
That show... on the trolley there.
I wonder how I could help you?
I just want your opinion.
Tell me, like man to man.
what you think of it.
- I? What's there to think?
- I can't make light of it, see?
They're childhood friends.
It was just... child's stuff...
a kind of game.
Game?
- Yes, but...
- What?
How should I put it...
Rather peculiar...
- Odd...
- Calm down!
- I shouldn't have taken you there.
- You couldn't have done better.
But I have to say one thing...
Loud and clear.
I wonder how Henia
can feel anything for me.
See the way I am?
I have no illusions.
I'm not fond of myself really.
I don't understand what
she could see in me.
This puts me off. believe me.
What I hold against her...
... is the way she welcomes
my advances.
What're going to do?
My friends...
I'd like to hearten you.
I have good news...
This war will soon be over.
This war...
You look funny.
Funny? I?
Yes, you.
- Me?
- You turned pale... a bit.
But the colours are
coming back now.
The saucer got stuck to the cup.
That's all.
Good God!
He's a changed man.
All he wants is to run away.
I had to lock him up
like a thief.
"Just give me the horses and look
the other way"... This is for you.
I can't give him the horses.
He wants you to be
his accomplice.
In getting scared shitless?
If the Germans catch him...
- You spoke of hatchet men.
- I did.
But they're not here.
What if they don't come?
What do you think?
Excuse me... could you?
Come in.
I've got something.
I had it stashed away
in the forest.
It's strong.
You're seeing a man
who badly needs help.
How could I help you?
I've cracked up, you know.
It's this fear.
You know what it means...
... when a brave man turns chicken?
- It's nerves.
- No sir, not nerves.
It's a transformation.
Daring turns into cowardice.
Understand?
Only three weeks ago
I had my goal, task, struggle...
Now I have nothing.
Everything's gone, like...
I'm with my pants down.
Worse still I'm right!
I'm right at last!
Why don't you calm down, Colonel?
You want to get rid of me, huh?
- Who?
- All of you.
You want to do me in, right?
Admit it.
- I?
- I'm no fool.
As long as I feared nothing.
they feared me.
Now I'm scared, so I'm dangerous.
What can I do?
Just tell them to let me go.
Or help me escape.
Give me a hand.
Colonel, there's a war on,
the country's occupied.
- To desert now....
- Uh-huh...
Ever been scared shitless?
I am now.
- I've lost it. Got that?
- Listen to me, Colonel.
First, calm down. Tell them it's
a passing nervous breakdown.
And I'll talk with Hippolit.
Maybe I'll be able
to arrange your leave.
No way out. We must cooperate
in this underground action.
And not a peep about ours.
Act as if you were...
... with the Home Army struggle,
the Poland versus Germany dilemma...
... not Henia and Karol's coupling.
We must see our plan through.
They’ve sent an order.
They're not coming.
- So they leave it to us?
- Your voice is back?
- By ourselves?
- Yes, fuck it!
- Who then?
- What?
Who'll do it?
First we must decide how...
So. how?
Quietly.
No pistol... a knife.
We could enter
through the wardrobe.
That's no good,
the man hardly sleeps.
Get him to open the door himself.
You're right.
Now the hardest part.
To kill him?
I couldn't.
Neither could you.
- Why not?
- Can you?
And you?
No.
Enough! I'll do it
without your help.
- You?
- I?
Out of the question!
It's an order!
We've received an order!
I can't be a swine.
Some sense of duty at least.
I know... duty, responsibility...
- But you can't slaughter him!
- Bugger! How then?
How?
- Have Karol do it.
- Karol?
Who else?
Karol... Could be...
the simplest way indeed.
- Hello!
- Hello. hello.
Siemian's turned traitor.
We have proof.
You'll slit his throat tonight.
I?
Scared?
With what?
A knife.
What if he doesn't open the door?
We’ll find a way
to make him open it.
- Little sparrow...
- What're you up to?
Smoking a cigarette...
one of the twelve.
- Let's say... Saint Peter...
- I mean about Karol.
As far as I know...
he doesn't smoke.
I shouldn't have brought you here.
It was me who brought you.
I almost forgot.
I was looking for you.
No one's minding the store.
The caretaker... is asleep.
Come in please.
What do I do with this?
Who's been drinking from my cup?
Who's been eating from my bowl?
What's this tune?
Just a tune.
Strange... both happy and sad.
Hela did say the same.
- Who?
- Hela...
... my friend's daughter.
What's this story?
A sad one.
I admire sad stories.
- You won’t like this one.
- How do you know?
I had a friend...
... a Pole married to a Jew.
She was lucky to have died
before all this.
We'd tell that bon vivant.
"No booze or women."
"Your daughter's Jewish."
He wouldn't listen.
He'd hide her in the closet
and come back at dawn.
She'd say,
"Don't leave me. dad."
To make up,
he'd whistle this tune.
"Don't be angry", he'd say.
"I'll dance with you.
Like with a real lady."
In his arms, her legs dangling
over the floor... they'd dance.
It was her favourite pastime.
What was next?
One night he was too late.
She couldn't wait so she went
out onto the stairs... the street.
- With her black eyes and hair...
- Don't finish.
- I know what comes next.
- You don't...
You can't even guess.
He bribed everyone,
Poles, Jews, Germans...
... and went off on
the same transport with her.
When she saw him.
at the entrance to the camp,
she stretched out her hands,
"Tateleh! Tateleh!"
You know what happened?
He hid.
He hid from her... his own child.
A couple of days in a cattle car
amidst corpses and shit...
... turned him into an animal.
And then... they gave him
a pretty serial number.
You know what? 123000.
And a triangle with the letter P.
I'm sorry, madam.
You know why I’ve come.
No idea.
Karol can't kill.
He's still a child.
This is war.
Vaclav, talk to me.
Say something. please.
- Karol told you about Siemian?
- A little.
You'll go with him, you hear?
You'll knock. He'll open for you.
He won't suspect anything.
- Will you?
- I will.
He's a traitor. He must die.
What're you doing here?
I'm wondering...
At what?
The chemistry of love.
Knife and blood...
... will unite them all.
As the youngster kills
an adult up there...
... here another adult will sacrifice
the youngster. Full circle.
A bloody communion.
- What?
- Nothing.
I'm checking if you think
I still have all my marbles.
I’ve more important things
than your boozing, you hear?
Colonel, it's me, Henia.
I have important news for you.
Colonel?
Jesus Mary, have you seen this?
- Vaclav.
- Let me alone!
See?
I told you so.
I'll leave it for you on the road.
Don't spy on me.
My mother would slap me
on the wrist for being indiscreet.
And that's all.
CAST OF CHARACTERS