www.titlovi.com
Nike, a goddess of
Greek mythology
When originally discovered
the arms and head were missing
Later, the right arm was found
but the head remains lost
The unreconstructed statue is
on display at the Louvre Museum
Portrait of the Wind
Murase Photo Studio
How do I look?
Strange?
Very beautiful.
You're at marriageable age now,
aren't you?
What do you say, Tamio?
Too young,
but fine feathers make fine birds.
Don't be so rude.
You're so beautiful,
he's shy.
I still remember you
as a little girl.
Now you're at university.
Soon you'll be a granny.
Watch out.
You'll soon be an old fart.
Don't be cheeky.
Are you ready?
Okay, change position.
Like this?
Look at the camera.
Ready to shoot.
Now.
Won't you get some photos?
Me?
No, thanks.
He may be sarcastic,
but he's a good photographer.
I don't like taking photos.
Watch my hand.
Are you ready?
Now.
How did the job interview go?
Terrible.
How about you?
No luck, either.
Is that right?
No one wants art school
graduates.
Maybe not.
But let's keep trying, anyway.
How many interviews to go?
Just one.
And what happens if they
reject you, too?
I'll join the
long-term unemployed.
Look.
That's Shinmachi over that way.
I don't remember much.
It's all changed since
we grew up there.
But one thing's for sure.
That's the town I was born in.
"Fine feathers make fine birds. "
Don't you dare say that to Mari.
Why not?
Girls are easily hurt.
Is she that thin-skinned?
Silly!
She's your kid sister.
Let me see.
Tamio.
Someone to see you.
Great photo.
Did you take it?
Yes, three years ago.
When I was in Palestine.
Such beautiful eyes.
A lot like your eyes.
What?
You think so?
Her father was a suicide bomber.
He died the day before I took it.
She looks so strong and powerful.
Yes, but there's also the sadness
of losing a loved one.
But she didn't cry at all.
People don't always cry
when they're sad.
So what can I do for you?
I have something to ask you.
What do you do
with your negatives?
We file them away.
Even the old ones?
They're a photographer's
treasure.
Are you after some?
Yes, from about 20 years ago.
Taken here?
We dispose of them after
10 years with no orders for prints.
I see.
Sure.
Thanks.
But hang on.
My father kept the ones
he particularly liked.
Want to look through them?
Sure.
They're filed by surname.
Suzuki... Suzuki...
This one?
That's not it.
That's a great clock.
Grandpa got it when
he opened the studio.
Not working?
It'd cost more to fix it
than to buy a new one.
But I can't just throw it away.
This one?
That's not it.
When I was a boy,
it still worked.
It has such a beautiful chime.
Here's another.
How about this?
Is this it?
Who's the girl?
That's me.
You lived around here?
When I was 5 my parents
divorced and moved away.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Thank you.
He always wanted to be
the Japanese Capa.
Don't start.
But his dad died on his feet
of a heart attack.
So he got stuck with the studio.
That was bad luck.
That's enough.
Before that,
he flew all over the world.
But now he's stuck in a
local photo studio.
I think it's great.
What is?
Working at an old photo studio.
Everyone's got digital
cameras now.
Photo studios are being
replaced by apartments.
They're out of fashion.
But studios are a record of the
local people's precious moments.
I think that's wonderful.
They're just like time capsules,
aren't they?
All the happiness of
the local people.
Did you ever play here
when you were little?
You don't remember?
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Hey, give me a ride.
On the bicycle?
Sure.
Hey.
Take your hands off.
Make like wings.
Close your eyes.
What?
That hurt.
Are you okay?
Hey?
I was worried.
- Are you sure?
- It hurt.
Naturally.
That was dangerous.
I got a real shock.
Thank you for the photo.
Come again any time.
Take care.
See you.
Listen.
What?
Anything between you
and Tamio?
What do you mean?
I thought maybe you
were in love with him.
What?
With Tamio?
You must be joking.
So you don't love him?
He's just an old friend.
A friend of my brother
and a good customer, that's all.
Nothing more.
Really?
Sure.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
You're so full of beans.
Beer.
And green peppers.
Grilled green peppers, please.
You were like a man
reborn today.
How's that?
You behaved differently.
No, I didn't.
You big liar.
I bet you have a sore shoulder
tomorrow.
I'll be fine.
Beer, please.
For me, too.
What a doll!
Does she live near here?
She's Mari's classmate.
From art school?
Got a boyfriend?
Someone you love?
What's that?
Don't be so rude.
Leave them alone.
Don't get too ambitious.
Know your place.
He's right.
But she's really beautiful.
I hope he's alright.
I guess so,
he could walk by himself.
But he lost so much blood.
I was too scared to move.
That's natural.
As a photographer,
I've seen far worse than that.
Blood doesn't scare me
any more.
When you see so much death
around you,
it's as if your heart is
like a bomb.
Laws and morals
lose all their meaning.
Death no longer scares you.
It becomes the only way to
keep your dignity as a human.
It's like being dead,
even when you're alive.
Will you go back to Palestine?
Not any more.
I thought you would.
You keep that picture
of the girl on your wall.
I won't go back.
Why not?
Just being there made me
way too callous.
I'd take pictures of people
dying before my eyes.
I'm too scared of
losing all emotion.
I'm burned out as a
news cameraman.
I can't get the shots.
But photographs express someone s
joy or grief to others, don't they?
And I really sensed her grief
from your photograph.
Because you took that picture,
I was able to share that
little girl's grief.
You're just being nice.
No, I mean it.
I wonder what Nike looked like.
That's the point.
What was her face like and
what was she looking at.
I like not knowing.
You're forced to use your
imagination.
Doesn't that make it
truly wonderful?
Once I tried to draw her face in
one of my classes.
No matter how hard I tried,
I didn't like any of them.
I have no happy memories
of my family.
Father used to beat Mother
when he was drunk.
Once he lost control,
there was no stopping him.
Mom was always
battered and bruised.
One of my relatives told me.
But, when I first met you,
I couldn't get you out of
my mind.
Now I know why.
It's because we're the same
kind of person.
Private Party
When's the baby due?
What are you on about?
They're having a baby.
You did it, handsome.
When's it due?
Next January.
Less than 9 months?
When it comes to love,
he's a fast mover.
Let's get drunk.
Congratulations
to the happy couple
May they live long
Until they're both
old and gray
Good morning.
I was dreaming.
What about?
There was this little girl.
A tiny little girl.
She was looking at the sea.
She spread her arms as the
sea breeze blew on her.
Where was it?
No idea.
But it was very beautiful.
Maybe it was our little girl?
I guess it was.
Then let's have a baby girl.
Let's take her photo every day.
Good idea.
Let's do that.
No need to memorize
everything at once.
Thank you.
Look, right now
your first priority is the baby.
I know.
I'm being very careful.
Three months is the most
dangerous time.
You must be very careful.
Especially with your first.
Aren't you due at the hospital?
Hospital?
Right.
I'd better hurry.
Now you take care.
Mom.
Did you think I was your Mom?
No need to worry.
We'll find her.
Hello?
Is this child's mother about?
Are you there?
I'm sorry.
Thank you so much.
Say thank you.
Thank you.
That was very kind of you.
Delivery for you.
Yes?
The neighbors all envy me.
How come?
I'm lucky to have such a
dear daughter-in-law.
Is that right?
If only your father
were still alive.
He'd love to see his
first grandchild.
This is your wife's watch?
According to the autopsy,
she was strangled to death.
What did he have to say?
Apparently, he'd never
set eyes on her before.
Then why did he
have to kill her?
I'm afraid that will take
some time to resolve.
You mean through a trial?
Yes, but a closed trial.
What do you mean?
All criminals under
the age of 20,
are tried in a closed,
juvenile court.
What?
The entire proceedings
are carried out in secrecy.
Match them up
and run them through here.
Turn off the light.
This red button next to it,
turn it on.
Then switch this on.
And it comes out here.
Can you tell us something
about the victim?
Any comments about Ayako?
Anything at all.
Please.
You have to eat,
or you'll get ill.
It's the best I can do,
but try it.
Thank you.
I never knew Ayako was
taking pictures.
May I?
I wonder what that was?
Closed
Why are the victim's relatives
excluded from the process?
With an adult,
the courts are designed to punish.
But with juveniles,
the aim is to rehabilitate.
And he is to be tried
in juvenile court.
I'm not interested in
his rehabilitation.
Why is he so protected?
We're the victims, not him!
Of course.
But it's different for juveniles.
Who cares about
who or what he is?
We want to know
why he did it.
I have to know.
You can get to see
the transcript.
This is ridiculous.
Did you plan to kill her?
No, not at all.
I never wanted to kill her.
Then why did you
choke her to death?
She resisted,
I wanted to stop her screaming.
Before I realized it,
I was choking her.
What did you think
when she stopped moving?
I never imagined she was dead.
I'll change the question.
Your mother abandoned you
when you were ten?
Yes, she ran off
leaving Father and me behind.
How did you feel then?
I was disappointed
and very angry.
Why did she have to leave me?
How do you feel about the
victim and her family?
I feel sorry for them.
What will you do after you
return to society?
I'll work at my father's business
and work towards something.
That's all I have.
Did you know the victim
was pregnant?
No, I didn't.
- Did you know she was pregnant?
- No, I didn't.
A pack of lies.
What the fuck?
Cut it out.
He's sorry.
Thank you.
- See you.
- Come again.
I cut up all her father's photos
when I got divorced.
So Ayako didn't know
what he looked like.
But now I regret not leaving
any pictures of him.
A hopeless man,
but her father, after all.
She should've known what
he looked like.
She did.
She found the negative for
this photo at my studio.
She asked me to print
another copy.
I thought she wanted a childhood
shot of herself.
But that wasn't the case.
So she did see him?
I just can't do it.
Remember the three of us
used to skip stones?
You were both so
good at it.
Tamio, why don't you
re-open the studio?
I can help out,
like before.
Ayako would be sad
to see you like this.
She'd be much happier if
you were yourself again.
Cherish her memories,
then you won't be lonely.
I envy her.
You still love her deeply,
even when she's gone.
Let me try.
Wow, that's great.
I'll try again.
Alright, get ready.
Be perfectly still.
Look here.
A big smile.
Fix her Kimono.
Smile.
Turn to the right, please.
The right?
That's too far.
Like this?
Hey, look over here!
Good boy.
Excuse me,
you're Murase, aren't you?
Mr. Tamio Murase?
I'm Ihara,
a magazine reporter.
It's about your wife's case.
This is the criminal who
killed her.
They called him Boy A,
his name is Tatsuya Yamagishi.
He lived in the next town.
His father owns
Yamagishi Motors.
Expensive, imported cars.
Even though he murdered her,
he still doesn't acknowledge it.
According to the police report,
his first words were
"When can I go home?"
He was a dropout,
but he will matriculate.
He'll take college
entrance exams next year.
He's a murderer who will not
admit to his crime.
He'll be released very soon.
An adult would get
the death penalty.
I can't allow that.
I intend to write about him.
I need you to tell me
how you feel
about your murdered wife
and your unborn child.
How dare you.
Leave me alone.
Get lost.
I'm compiling a story
about this boy, Yamagishi.
I want an interview,
if possible.
Go get lost.
Leave me alone.
Stop it.
That's enough.
If you change your mind,
call me here.
Not bad at all,
for you.
Have some, Aunty.
Please.
My husband loved these pickles.
- Did he?
- He did.
Not too green?
No, I like them crunchy.
He also preferred them like this.
I wish he could share
Mari's pickles with us.
Listen, Tamio.
Forget about Ayako.
Find someone and be happy.
I can't do that.
It's been a year now.
Only a year.
No qualms.
After all,
a man needs a woman.
How dare you say that?
Ayako was stolen from me.
How can I ever forget?
If there is someone else,
tell me.
Of course there's no one.
I talked to her,
then we agreed to ask you first.
That's ridiculous.
Tamio has no
special feelings for me.
If he agreed,
would you marry him?
Answer me.
You would, right?
You can't stay single forever.
I'm her brother,
I know it's strange,
but she would make
a good wife.
It's rare for him to get
this drunk.
He reckons that you'd make
a good wife for me.
He's a great guy, but...
He's a big mouthed drunk.
He reckons I'm insensitive
not to notice
you've loved me since
we were kids.
I had to laugh.
He's so stupid.
Exactly, he's stupid,
and you're insensitive.
If I can make it skip 3 times,
take me out
on our next day off.
I blew it...
Let's go out anyway.
What is it?
Nothing.
I won't have the baby.
How come?
Because...
Wait a minute.
Do I mean nothing to you?
I'll never be happy
with any man.
It's not just your decision.
It concerns us both.
Explain yourself.
Come back.
All families
soon break up.
- That's not true.
- You don't understand.
You were brought up in
a happy family.
I have no confidence.
I never even knew my father.
Lots of people don't,
but they still lead happy lives.
How can I be happy?
I've never known happiness.
You said it was better
not knowing.
Just wait.
You said I have to
find what's important.
We can work this out.
We'll be together.
That's what I want.
What do you want now?
My investigation found out he
had a deprived childhood.
Abandoned by his mother.
A brutal, violent father.
Perhaps he saw your wife
as a mother image.
So he kills her?
Give me a break.
Of course not.
Leave me alone.
I don't need this.
He's been released,
you know.
He served his time,
so they let him go.
He killed your wife and child.
Don't you think it's too soon?
He hasn't once expressed
any regret for doing it.
I'm concerned
he might do it again.
I've heard enough.
Get lost.
Just leave now.
I'll be back.
Don't bother.
May I help you?
Take a look around.
I'll come back later.
What's that for?
Nothing.
You're not planning
anything foolish?
Answer me.
I just can't let it go.
Her killer got out, he's living the good life.
I can't forgive him.
He deserves to die,
or worse.
Even if that happened,
nothing would change.
An eye for an eye,
that's the only way.
So you plan to take revenge?
Her soul can't rest until I do.
But that's exactly what he did.
Kill him and his family will
suffer like you have.
He stole her future.
But you have no right to
take his.
Don't be so stupid.
You just don't understand,
do you?
No, you don't understand.
Do you know what Ayako
would say?
Of course I do.
Perfectly well.
No, you don't!
You don't know her feelings,
nor mine.
Be more constructive.
Forget about revenge.
Promise me you will.
Please.
Okay.
I promise.
You mean it?
Looking for a car?
I'll leave it to you.
What's the mileage?
I'll check it out.
Just over 30,000km.
Where's your toilet?
That door there.
It's an old model, but low mileage.
It's a good buy.
Want a test drive?
No, maybe next time.
Ayako's Landscapes
Ayako's Wind
Every single shot
has an element of wind.
She always shot the wind.
My hometown, by the sea.
A tiny little town.
I had her in the hospital there.
It was cold and stormy night.
There was a big fire that night.
I heard the sirens all night long.
At the long, stormy night
she was born.
The town is known
for the wind.
She knew the place?
Yes, we used to go back there
once a year.
Then my father went bankrupt,
he just disappeared.
I haven't been back for
over 20 years.
I wonder what she
thought of me.
I've struggled alone to
make a living.
I was sometimes
cold to her.
She never said anything.
Once, when I broke up
with a man,
she pushed herself up against me
while I was crying.
She started crying with me.
I was so glad that she did.
She had a very kind heart.
But the poor girl...
...she was so lonely.
I was surprised when she
said she was getting married.
She was afraid of men.
I never thought she'd marry.
Thank you, Tamio.
Her time was short,
but she had you.
That made her very happy.
Forget about her murder.
You have Mari now...
...concentrate on her.
I'm sure that's what
Ayako would want.
She was like that.
I remember her well.
We called her Aya-chan.
Her mother was beautiful,
and she was very pretty, too.
She was always out back,
looking at the sea.
I warned her it was dangerous.
But she'd just laugh
and stay there until it got dark.
We found it here.
Ayako's wind.
Yes, I'm free, why?
Just come tomorrow night.
All the local guys will be there,
It rarely happens.
Yeah, sure.
Mari, you come, too.
Me, too?
Yes, be sure to come.
Okay.
You think it'll work?
I'm sure it will be fine.
Don't worry.
He's good at such things.
It will all work out.
After all,
they do love each other.
Really?
But don't let on
to Tamio and Mari.
I won t.
We take photos for
the real estate agency.
Do we have to?
Sure, we need to find
new avenues of business.
There's no money in it.
If we do a good job,
it'll be steady work.
It's not as if we're busy.
Let's do it.
Watch out!
Here.
Thanks.
A fine looking gentleman.
Yes, he passed away last year.
Really?
He wanted that for
his funeral.
He did it for his family,
before he died.
Did your father take it?
He used to say
the photographer was in every picture.
What does it mean?
His feelings reflect
on every picture he takes.
Like a mirror,
he said.
Not in body,
but in spirit, he meant?
Sit over there.
Why?
I'll take your photo.
What's the occasion?
Our wedding photo.
With this hair?
I like it that way.
But...
You look great.
It'll make a great picture.
Here we go.
Can I take a look inside?
Sure.
Does the navigation system work?
It just needs the key.
Just give me a minute.
There you are.
Hey.
What is it now?
It's not working.
No problem.
Is this the place?
Starring
Tadanobu Asano
Music
Akiko Yano
Conceived & Directed by
Taro Hyugaji
English Subtitles by
Stuart J Walton (Sprout)
Preuzeto sa www.titlovi.com