Mosfilm
Third Creative
Association
Irina Kupchenko
Oleg Yankovsky
in
THE TURNING POINT
- Mmm... Quite an edible shish kebab.
- Yes.
This, however, cannot
be said of the perch.
Yeah?
I've noticed you order the perch
every single time.
How do you explain that?
- Well, we're on the high seas.
- You’re right.
This is the second time
we've been at this table,
and we haven't gotten
to know each other yet.
Viktor... Vedeneev.
Nikitin. At your service!
- Albina.
- Nice to meet you.
Well! Now introduce
your lover.
What makes you think
I'm his lover?
Well, you can see it
with the naked eye.
Indeed?
- You're observant.
- I'm sorry, what's your name?
Natasha.
So, to the question
of observation, Natasha.
Your engagement ring,
it's shiny.
It’s new.
It hasn't had time to fade yet
from the laundry and the dishes.
Bravo!
You are newlyweds and I propose a toast:
"To newlyweds!"
- To Sherlock Holmes
- Well, here we are. Hooray!
- Muscovites.
- Muscovites!
- Help yourself.
- Thank you.
- Are you going to Moscow?
You got it again!
Thank you.
And we are also
going to visit the Crimea!
- Going to work on Monday?!
- Yes.
Going to work on Monday.
Do you actually work as...
Sherlock Holmes?
In a way. A lawyer, generally speaking.
But that's not the point, if you want,
I can give you
some lessons in deduction and you
too will impress some
neighbors at the table.
It's not hard at all.
- One last dance.
- Yes!
- That’s right, let's go dance.
- Let's go.
Natasha!
Hello!
Ouch! Listen, let's get out of here.
- This is awkward.
- It's okay.
You take the stern; I'll take the bar.
Let's go!
Look, they won't leave us alone.
They like us,
what's the problem?
They want to be friends.
And you, selfish girl!
- Me?
- Yes.
- Is it bad?
- So...
- I don't need anyone but you.
- Don’t you?
Let’s just tell them... to get lost.
Great idea!
I think they're gone.
Listen! It's not gonna work.
They're in love with us.
More than enough!
We certainly overestimated
their feelings.
To Moscow! To Moscow!
Natasha!
- Natasha!
- Mmm...
That's it, we're here!
Vacation's over.
Natasha!
How? Really?
No, no.
Natashka, don't sleep!
We'll be home in a minute,
you can sleep like a human being.
All right, all right.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
Okay, what's up?
Have you had enough?
I've had enough, I'm telling you.
I see, you're a racer!
So, you got it?
Got it?
You come over here, they're
going to give you a prize. Go on!
We should call an ambulance.
- So?
- Yes, they've been called.
- Get that dog out of here.
- Rex!
- She’s got a pulse. That's right.
- It's not the pulse, it's a finish!
- Don't you know?
- What?
She came out of the bushes
out of nowhere...
At least pretend in public.
- What do you mean?
- "What do you mean?"
- If you close your eyes – hold on!
- I do!
- I see how you do it.
- What's the matter?
He's not sober. His
legs aren't holding him up.
He's walking, wobbly.
- Who's wobbling?
- Can't you see who?
That’s silly!
Keep your nonsense to yourself.
- Wobbly.
- Can't you see I'm okay?
- What's wrong with you? You're wobbly.
- Really?
- You guys come over here.
- Yeah, okay. Well, what do you want?
- Come over here!
- Yeah, okay.
Well, what?
What are you doing? Let me go!
Let me go! That's enough!
Yes. In the tube,
breathe into the tube.
I'll bring you a tube.
and then you can breathe.
- Let me go!
- You talk too much!
Yeah, get him out of here!
Get him out of here!
Get it off! Let me go!
Now you'll get a Section 206, too.
- Leave him alone.
- Don't hurt his hands!
Relax your arm.
Please.
You didn't seem to relax it.
And now?
Yeah, yeah. Got it.
Okay.
- All right!
- Well, Vitya...
It's sad enough,
but it's not that bad.
- Mild concussion, two fractures.
- Yeah?
Here, Comrade Captain,
did me a favor and called me.
You can go now.
Did you take a blood test?
- Yes, I did.
- Go home, take it easy.
You'll be called.
The main thing is
that it's not a big deal.
That's the main thing,
isn't it, Comrade Captain?
Pray to God.
Symposium. See?
Estonians invited us for four days.
Well, what are you up to
at night, Natasha?
Now.
That's the way it's been since March.
I’ve already asked you,
can't you do it in the morning?
Let's have a decent dinner.
Natasha! Natasha!
Really? Well, well, well!
What happened?
So, what to do? Natasha.
Stop it!
Don’t do it. What are you doing?
Stop... That's enough! Come on!
That's all right.
It could have been worse.
Come on, stop it! Come on, stop it!
Natasha!
That's it! Stop it! That's it!
- That's it?
- That's it!
So!
[Victor laughed]
Hello, young lady!
Please take this.
Anna Egorovna Koroleva.
- May I come in?
- Sure.
Hello.
I don't feel comfortable
bothering you over nothing.
What do you mean?
Have a seat.
- Thank you, I won't be long.
- Okay, sit down.
The thing is...
It's hard for me to
tell you this, but...
Your care package is no longer needed.
Not needed?
How should that be understood?
You care package is not needed.
So.
Are you the son?
We've done everything we can.
Even more.
I see.
It's because of age.
The injury had nothing to do with it,
although it did play a part.
Age...
Everybody loses their
parents at some point.
Yes.
I need you to go to the head doctor's
office and review the report.
Now.
- You don't feel good?
- It's okay, I'll be fine.
Zina!
It's ammonia, it's okay.
- I think you'd better lie down.
- That's all right, thank you.
No, let's lie down.
Let's go.
- Okay.
- Victor Andreyevich!
I wanted to remind you
about the publication.
You promised to check it
before the vacation.
- Did you read it?
- Yes, I did.
Well, what do you want me to write?
Give me a hint.
Well... any of your thoughts
or...
What thoughts? Give me a hint.
- How old are you?
- Thirty.
Thirty...
Look, it's very simple.
If you decide to cheat,
to collect publications,
If you're 30 years old
and you decide to give up
on yourself, that's up to you.
Why should I deal with it? Why should
I have think of it?
You shouldn’t, and I
do.
- Viktor Andreyevich, you’re called!
- Now.
Listen, go and see Sementsev,
he'll write it down. Okay?
- Viktor Andreyevich!
- Yes.
- Is that the 17th??
- 17th.
I'll be right there.
Hello!
Hi.
Everything's fine.
I didn't.
I did.
What can I say? Nothing.
All right, neighbors, are you ready?
Okay, eight o'clock.
Oh, look who's here!
Why didn't the neighbors tell?
It's not good, it's not good to hide
your superiors.
- Come here, come here. Hi!
- Hey!
- So, how did you get your vacation?
- It was okay.
- Natasha, how is she doing?
- She's fine.
- Victor Andreyevich, hello.
- Hello, Anechka.
- Got a tan!
- Thanks.
Showing up among the workers...
like that...
- So, Misha, are you still writing?
- I am.
- Victor Andreyevich, welcome!
- Hello, Slavochka.
- Your bosses were interested in you.
- Yes?
- When's the defense?
- I don’t know.
- Got any cigarettes?
- Look in your briefcase.
- Here, take a look. Tanya, show me.
- Slava!
- What's the occasion?
- I think it's about the business trip.
Uh...
What's up, guys?
I don't understand about the 28th.
Ooh! We got gifts from the south!
- Good for you. He doesn’t forget us.
- Thank you, I don't want.
- Here you go!
- My pleasure.
Well, neighbours,
it's not working again, is it?
Here,
take a look around the perimeter.
Thank you.
Vitya!
It's you, right?
Ah... Hi.
It’s been a while.
- Hi, Svetka.
- Hello!
- What are you doing here?
- What about you?
I'm, uh...
going to a funeral.
- Was this person close to you?
Yes. Someone I know.
My mom's buried here.
I'm talking about the monument.
Troubles.
Have you seen the one in the cap
and a turtleneck?
Cap?
No.
How have you been?
You're a talented scientist, aren't you?
Yeah, kind of.
Where's your moustache?
Did you get married,
or did you get a promotion?
Both.
Look...
And who is your wife?
- Her name is Natasha.
- Do I know her?
I don't think so.
Why so serious?
I'm at a funeral.
- Do you see any of ours?
- No.
Did you hear about Volodya?
Volodya? Yes, I heard something.
You have new friends.
- Why do you think so?
- Well, it's inevitable.
You, as a biologist should know.
Cells are renewed, so are
people.
Too bad! Yes?
There he is! I'm sorry,
for God's sake! I'm sorry.
Bye.
Listen up! Wait, please.
Wait!
Comrade!
Let's have a drink!
What should we drink to?
To the rest of her soul.
- Whose?
- Hers!
Anna Egorovna Koroleva,
whom I sent to the afterlife.
- When did this happen? Why?
- That night.
She didn't even get a chance to... read
our note and taste the apples.
I... don't understand.
- Did you know that?
- Yeah.
Why didn't you say anything?
- Well, what's gonna happen now?
- I don't know.
A trial?
Well, yes a trial.
You're out of your mind. Stop eating!
Do you realize what could be happening?
I mean, that changes everything.
From this very minute.
What minute?
Well, I don't know...
Should we do something? Any steps...
Prison! Do you understand?
- Coffee for you?
- Yes. Coffee.
- But what to do?
- I don't know.
Did you talk at the institute?
No. Why?
But it's all going to hell.
Do you realize that?
Let's get a drink.
He's out of his mind.
You're crazy!
It's not me. It's you.
Cheers!
Give me a kiss.
- Now?
- Yes! Now.
- And this is Sukhumi.
- Mm-hmm.
Yes! We had a good time after all,
not bad.
Well, at least the weather.
is good.
What's true is true.
Well, you guys did
a great job calling.
Of course you did!
Listen, Victor,
as long as the weather is good,
let's get the motor running somewhere
in the woods or in the country.
Do you have a country cottage?
- No way.
- Okay, you're still young.
What do you do for a living?
- Biology.
- It’s interesting!
I used to dream about it
when I was a kid.
Didn't you?
- Genetic engineering.
- That's totally cool! So, how was it?
Any luck constructing anything?
Some kind of artificial genius?
It's just that
young people are getting into
and the whole thing's getting younger.
Even old age is getting younger!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
How long have you been in law?
- I've been practicing law all my life.
- And who are you?
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Lawyer, investigator, how you...
correctly noted - Sherlock
Holmes.
And now I'm a prosecutor.
- Who? You?
- What, don't I look like one?
I've just never seen
a prosecutor.
Well, come on in. Admission's free.
- Have you ever been to court?
- No, God forbid.
- Never?
- No.
Well, aren't you scared
when you...
I don't know, what are you guys
doing?
I second the accusation.
No, that's okay.
I understand you,
Natasha, but you know...
criminals are mostly bad
people. Honestly!
And those who suffer from them
are mostly good people. There!
You and I suffer.
Hm... Now, if...
Well... how do you say?
You want to talk about my
profession?
No, not necessarily.
Well, with my buddy.
Well, I told you.
He was just driving along
and he was right under the wheels...
Oh, come on,
let's talk about something else.
Just curious.
Here's a case like this.
The man...
just went under the wheels himself.
The driver was absolutely not at fault,
He didn't do anything wrong.
Who suffers?
Oh, honey! You can't solve these things
so easily.
He did, he didn't,
there's all sorts of reasons.
Details of the investigation.
The serviceability of the car.
Yeah, a thousand things.
And... what do you care so much about?
You should advise your buddy
to get a lawyer.
No, of course not.
Excuse me if I'm being intrusive,
but is this like an accident?
The driver is completely sober.
Wasn't speeding.
What about the victim?
- Dead.
- Right here?
No, not there.
Yeah...
Again...
A lot of tough questions.
Everything matters here.
And the victim's vision?
- The victim.
Yes, of course.
If, as you say, the old lady.
- Walked without looking.
- Without looking!
From behind the bushes. It was like..,
she was blind.
Well, there's data on that
in the polyclinic.
But these are important points.
Yes, of course.
Well, I don't... I don't envy
of your buddy.
- The tea is cold. Can I warm it up?
- Thank you.
No! Well,
why isn't anybody eating the cake?
Well, you're welcome.
- Oh, no.
- Thank you.
Yes...
Really, let's talk
about something more interesting.
It's a pity to waste time on this.
Cheers.
Thank you.
And Igor can't help you.
He's in a position
where he can't interfere
in matters where he knows someone.
That's you, isn't it?
Did it happen to you?
Well, there you go.
That's what I thought.
You know what?
I'm gonna give you the number
of a very good lawyer.
The best thing is to call him.
But Igor won't be able to.
We didn't count on it.
We just came for no particular reason.
- To reminisce about our good days.
- Well, that's fine.
Let's have some tea.
Cakes, please.
- Thank you. Ow!
- You're welcome.
Thank you.
Have you been called yet?
No.
Uh... what? Should they call?
Yeah, they should. They have to!
They can... imprison?
I don't know.
Albina!
Put on some music or something.
Before she stepped off the curb,
did she look in my direction?
She turned her head, she looked,
and walked away.
Looked and went.
It's all on the record.
I want to bring this to your attention.
I think it's a too important point.
Certainly important.
I was looking, I could have seen it.
but I didn't.
Oh, well... Looked and didn't see.
It's quite possible.
Do you agree?
And I think you're excluding
that possibility.
Or you just underestimate it.
Look, don't you think
that we're having a little bit of a...
one-sided conversation.
Who's interrogating who, you or me?
You're right. I'm sorry.
And you don't have to worry so much.
I'll try, but my position...
makes it natural.
Well, I guess so. All right!
And so we'll go on.
- How fast were you going anyway?
- Average speed.
Answer, please, in detail.
- What do you mean by average? Up to 60?
- Yes.
Are you stating that categorically?
Categorically.
Okay.
Read it and sign it.
- So, that's it for today?
- Almost done.
Now as for the victim.
Whether she saw it or not.
- Let me have a smoke.
- Please.
It's quite possible that she
...didn't see your car.
Because of low vision, lost
even maybe to a considerable degree.
But it's not confirmed yet.
We've made inquiries to the clinic,
and there's no record.
- There's nothing?
- No.
But no one's going to
stop that.
We call as witnesses relatives,
loved ones, those who lived nearby.
Okay, I see, I see. Thank you
But you do realize that it's like a bolt
from the blue.
I'm in misery.
In misfortune.
But why me? I mean,
it could have happened to anybody.
You know what I mean?
Sidorov, Petrov, Ivanov.
- Your husband after all.
- My husband?
- But nobody's safe.
- Oh, no!
God forbid!
He's a motorist, too.
We drive, too.
You say you've been on the "Azerbaijan"?
No, on the "Russia".
We were sailing on the "Abkhaz"
two years ago.
- But... Really...
- There, you see!
Swimmed, sunbathed,
and rode in a carriage in Batumi.
We were making plans,
and then all of a sudden.
it's all gone, it's all gone to hell!
But in human terms, why?
Well, wait a minute.
Everything is not lost.
- Am I? You're reassuring me.
- Well, I don't know.
But at least it feels good,
that the sword is in your hands.
What sword?
The one hanging over my head.
Damocles.
- Can I go now?
- Just a minute.
Kobozev, come in!
Sit down.
- Hi.
- How do you do?
All right! Witness Kobozev.
As you have already shown, on April 26,
at approximately 7:10 p.m,
...you were traveling on the highway...
...in a Volga automobile.
As you passed the intersection.
Close to the lawn,
you bumped into a car...
Well, how'd it go?
I thought we were...
we got an early start.
Well, kind of a... competition.
First I got him, then he got me.
I have to say I got around him.
Caught him at the light.
All right! And what can you tell me
about the speed,
of the car in front of you -
"Zhiguli"?
What can I say?
- The speed… was quite low.
- Yeah.
Well, it was... it was
about 70, at the most.
Mm-hmm.
So it's about 70.
Approximately or exactly?
Exactly.
I followed him... ...in the lane,
I thought I'd go around.
I'm looking at
the speedometer -- 65... 70.
Yes... 65-70. Exactly!
Well, got carried away...
Look, I don't know
and I don't want to know
how they got carried away
and how they beat me.
That's right! And I forgot you.
And please speak
in your own name - "got carried away."
You, Vedeneevs sit down and
don't interrupt.
And stop smoking!
This is a confrontation,
not a youth cafe.
Sorry.
Was it 65-70 at the
time of the accident, too?
Of course.
Also...
I was like a shadow behind him.
And when he slowed down,
I almost ran into him.
I barely made it.
Okay. Do you have
any questions for the witness?
No questions. I think we need to check
if the Volga's speedometer is correct.
You check yours!
- Yeah, okay.
- It's already been checked.
The Volga's speedometer
and yours.
- Yes?
- Yes.
You are dismissed, Kobozev.
Read and sign.
You too, Vedenev.
- Goodbye.
- Am I free?
- Just a minute.
Sign right here.
- I signed.
- No, not on the record.
Please read this.
This is a no-exit pledge.
- What?
- Here.
- Well, all right. Go ahead.
- Signed.
Go.
I'll give you a ride.
Are you listening? Call me in about
ten minutes. Can I take a message?
Please.
Valera!
- Do you need a review?
- I do.
Well, come on in, I wrote it.
- Okay. Look at me.
- What?
Nothing, let's go.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Hello.
Could you please tell me if this is the
apartment of Anna Egorovna Koroleva?
- Yes.
- May I come in?
Sure.
Hang it right there.
Guests are here!
Come on in, come on in.
Don't just stand there.
- Hi, there.
- How do you do?
- There! Mother’s friends.
- Good evening.
You're welcome. Have a seat.
Be seated.
Thank you.
Please be seated.
Thank you, no.
The thing is...
we're not acquaintances
of Anna Yegorovna.
I thought you were acquaintances.
So... who are you, then?
We are...
how can I tell you...
This is my wife Natasha.
Well, I'm basically...
Well, the one...
Well, the driver of the Zhiguli.
The driver of the Zhiguli?
Well, yeah. The one who hit her.
We're here to tell you...
to express our feelings.
It wasn't easy for us to cross
the threshold of your house, but...
- We felt it necessary...
- Hello.
Hello.
We were wondering...
whether or not to go.
We know the wound is still fresh and...
any other person...
in our place...
Well, you know what I mean?
We understand...
we understand that...
you can't have
any good feelings for us,
Still, it seemed to us that...
better if we....
together with you... try to resolve...
this situation.
- Situation?
- Yes. The situation.
But I don't see any situation.
There was a woman and she's gone.
That's the situation.
But it's not that simple.
You may be aware that there's an
investigation.
And not all the matters are clear yet.
Not all matters?
- Yeah, not all of them.
- Which ones aren't clear, for example?
Well, it has to do with
Anna Yegorovna.
I see.
Interesting!
You know, it's very difficult
to talk...
you could’ve understood us.
But... this is primarily about...
about establishing the truth.
And... you have to
understand us.
There are questions that no one
can answer except...
you, who knew her.
Well, well, well.
- How was her vision?
- Uh...
Got it.
You're interested in vision.
I mean, wasn't she blind?
No, she wasn't.
But nobody's
talking about total blindness.
I wonder where they're going with this,
these guests of ours?
Oh, well, there you go.
She wasn't blind.
Is that okay with you?
Well, of course it isn't!
They want a blind one. Don't you get it?
I'm sorry, we didn't come here
to argue.
or to listen to your accusations.
Although, I'm willing
to listen to anything,
that I deserve from your side,
please, if you must.
Well, brothers,
you have nerves of steel.
What makes you think that?
Well, of course! A woman was murdered,
and you go to find out
what kind of vision she had.
And maybe you're also hoping to somehow
get out of it with our help.
Is that it?
I didn’t murder.
I'm not going to get out of it.
Why are you here?
What exactly is your purpose?
Don’t do it!
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
Go that way.
What's there to say, anyway?
Her eyesight was bad.
She didn't like to
go outside.
- Just like that she felt.
- Ha-ha... felt!
That he's sitting in his Zhiguli,
is this gorgeous young man right here,
who one day,
you see,
will fail to slow down in time.
You don't see a lot of old ladies
roaming the streets,
much less those with bad eyesight.
They're just walking right up to him.
in front of his wheels.
- Do you have a car?
- We do! We have a car.
It's a good one! It's big!
It's called the Black Crow.
You've never ridden one?
- You're very aggressive.
- Yes?
Maybe...
I'm gonna put your husband away!
You can count on it.
What was that for?
That's for this!
That you're getting too far apart.
- Now, walk off with your feet.
- You shouldn't do that, Victor.
See, the man's worried.
Why are you doing to him so much?
Because I have a Zhiguli.
No, that's not it.
It's because you don't know how
to drive a car,
for the fact that you took
a woman's life,
and now here you are,
trying you're making it up to me.
He'll get out of it.
You'll get out of it, don't worry.
Just don't come here again,
You won't get anything here.
You're gonna get yourself in trouble
for trying to apply pressure.
See how many witnesses
are here.
I see.
Well, if you do,
get the hell out of here.
Roll away, roll away!
Goodbye.
- Well?
- Let's get out of here.
You're right.
But I'm listening to
you. What's the news?
No news.
Well, that's news.
Apparently they weren't
very hospitable.
It's only natural,
I warned you.
Well, what's the point?
As a lawyer, I need to know
if she was wearing glasses.
I need her glasses right now,
during the indictment phase.
No glasses.
No way.
Reading glasses, outdoor glasses.
Well, at least some glass.
- This is your only chance.
- I understand.
- What did they say?
- They didn't say anything.
Where should I drop you off?
- No, we'll be fine. Thank you.
- Call.
- Aren't we going home?
- No.
Have a good time!
What's up? Where are we going?
Home.
Are you smoking?
Well, okay.
What do you intend to do next?
I'm scared, Vitya.
Really?
- Yes?
- I'm suddenly scared now.
We're lying here - you're with me.
And you're not with me anymore!
- You left me and you're running away.
- What kind of nonsense is that?
Alone, without me.
That's running away!
Yes, what nonsense.
- It's silly, isn't it?
- Of course it is.
Go to sleep!
Okay.
Close your eyes and go to sleep.
- You sleep, too.
- Uh-huh.
"I'll be late tonight.
Don't worry. Kisses, V."
Hold on. Hold on.
Marusya! It's me, sorry.
There's a fellow here asking for you.
- He says it's an urgent matter.
- Vitya!
Vitya!
- Hello, Vitya.
- Hello.
Well, show yourself.
- How was your rest?
- I didn't get much rest.
- Paul, did you feed him?
- I'm not hungry.
I offered.
- So, mom?
- Well, how did you two meet?
And I called
Pavel Dmitrievich at work.
I wasn't expecting you at all.
Yes?
Where? Where do you want to go?
Mom, I'm going for a long trip.
Well, anyway...
Think of it as going abroad.
I don't even know how often
I can write to you.
Well, uh... anyway, I want you
to be ready.
I understand.
You're a family man.
I can tell it to you.
Only when there was Anya,
maybe she wasn't so good,
but you weren't eager to make money.
It's not about the money, Mom.
How can I tell you?
It's a different kind of trip.
You can't make much money there.
Well, anyway... you'll eventually...
you'll figure it out.
I don't want to get into your business,
but you've changed, Vitya.
You don't come here that often.
and Pavel Dmitrievich and I can see that
You must have grown up early,
that's what I think.
Maybe it would have been better if
your successes came to you later.
- Fifty years from now.
It's okay, Mom.
It's all right.
And Natasha...
You don't know her very well,
but she's not
the kind of wife who rushes.
Yeah, I don't know you much either.
- Hello.
You don't ask where I've been?
I never ask,
if you can tell.
Yep.
- I went to see my mother.
- That's what I thought.
Listen,
I'll probably postpone the defense.
Is that her advice, your mother’s?
What’s she got to do with it?
These are my thoughts.
I can see you're just so attracted
to prison bars.
Well, what do you think?
I've got to payback.
Or shouldn't I?
Pay up?
For what?
For the death of a woman.
Um...
That's where you're going.
Well, really, what she was like -
lame or blind,
she still lived.
Right?
That's right!
And now you want to sacrifice
your life and my life too.
Why yours?
That's right!
You're not counting me.
Natasha, really?
All right, let's drink tea.
It's probably all boiled out by now.
Vitya!
There's one piece of news that
that changes everything.
One more?
We're going to have a baby.
- Repeat.
- We're going to have a baby.
When?
I don't know, you can count.
Natasha!
Natasha, why are we walking?
Let me get the elevator.
- Come on, silly, we're here.
- Oh, yeah.
- Hello there.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
- That's us.
There's no one in the apartment,
I'm waiting for the housing authority.
- Come on in.
No, you did the right thing,
for coming in.
Especially now in this
position.
- Yes.
- All roads lead to you.
Yes, of course.
Then it's a little awkward for us,
but you can understand us, too.
And that's her, our
Anna Yegorovna.
What a nice face. Isn't it?
Is that...
I'm going to show you
some other pictures.
You see, that's her and her father.
And this... That's the nurse of mercy.
- Is that her?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. In the middle there.
And that's her and her friend.
- Is that before the war?
- Yes, yes, with a friend.
- Give it to him.
- What?
- A lighter? What does he need it for?
- Give it to him, give it to him.
- You think?
- Yes.
- It's a Ronson!
- That's okay, you'll get over it.
Zina.
You know what we mean.
Do you understand why we have to
to come to you?
To visit Anna Egorovna's relatives...?
But here you have confirmed that she
couldn't see well. She wore glasses.
- Is that right? Confirmed?
- Yes, yes.
Here, but unfortunately in the clinic
that's not registered in any way.
And here, if they could
help the investigation.
The whole thing would have been
repeated at the trial.
- In court...
- Yes, in court.
Zinochka,
understand me,
woman to woman.
Oh... I understand, of course,
what you're thinking.
I mean, that's not good at all,
but it has nothing to do with the baby.
Oh, if you'd just come right out
just admit that you were pregnant.
Oh, I don't know how to help you.
Uh...
Why don't you talk to Kostik?
I have his address.
Kostik?
Do you think it makes sense?
Well, he was the closest to her somehow.
Anything happens,
she immediately calls Kostik.
So I'll go get the address now, shall I?
- Thank you, Zinochka.
- Uh-huh.
You are very kind.
And... we won't forget you, no.
And... I hope that you
come and see us with your boy.
- Yes.
- Good evening.
- Hello.
- Are you Kostantin Mikhalych Korolev?
- Yes, I am.
My last name is Vedeneev.
We're here to talk to you
about something...
Don't I get it?
Her right eye was dead.
She kept turning sideways,
like a chicken.
She's got a left eye,
and she barely even looks at it.
You should put her glasses on...
Scary stuff!
I tried it once
and almost went blind myself.
- Cheers.
- Cheers. Cheers!
Uh... Vitya!
That's not the way to do it.
What?
- You leave something in the shot glass.
- Vitya!
That's it!
Cheers!
Why aren't we dancing, huh?
Vitya! May I invite your
spouse? Do I have the right?
- Sure, what are we talking about.
- Well, absolutely... later.
Have something to eat now.
Here, let me get you a salad.
- Have some fish then.
- Go ahead.
Konstantin Mikhalych,
you don't eat.
Me?
I'm eating.
- You're the one who's watching.
- Well, of course.
We eat.
Would you be so kind
as to have one more?
I'm the one who's going to burst.
I'm gonna eat it all up and burst!
Konstantin... Mikhalych...
Feed, feed...
I'll do it the other way around... huh?
What do you mean?
But that doesn't sound like you,
Konstantin Mikhalych.
You know...
Looks like it, doesn't look like it...
No glasses there.
Vision is bad.
So?
And you're gonna have to, Vitya,
gnaw into the permafrost.
It’s impossible, can't stop you.
Steam is blowing,
salty icicles are hanging.
It's beautiful!
It’s a joke! Joke!
What are you afraid of?
Look at his face,
it's all stretched out.
Yeah, don't be afraid, Vitya.
Don't be afraid!
Let's do it! What are you talking about!
Uh...
If only... my lover...
was here
- Do you mind?
- Do you mind? Of course!
Well, of course,
what are you talking about.
Or you'll come home:
"Who have you been with?
Where have you been?"
This seems like a good time.
We'll call you in a minute.
Just like that, you in your voice.
Well, it's more civilized that way!
- You're on your own!
- Oh, for God's sake.
- Two pennies...
- Here! Go ahead.
Vitya!
- Where are you going?
- That way.
And the phone?
261-35-34
261-35-34 now.
So...white dance?
- Well, you're good!
- What's wrong with you?
You made that up really well.
What are you laughing about?
Isn't it bad for you to dance?
Yeah, don't be jealous! Because I...
Don't be jealous!
No, I said, isn't it bad for you?
What?
Well, to jump?
Isn't it bad in your state?
Not really.
- That's what I'm talking about!
- Come on, Kostik!
Come on!
Vitek...
That's sad.
Ride! Everything! Chief, that's it!
Did you go to bed yet?
This is a nightmare.
I think...
I'm sorry, but it's better if you
were put in jail.
That would have been better
for both of us.
That's right.
Ouch... You need to see a doctor.
Or else you'll have a baby
with a handicap.
Some kind of a flawed child.
What?
Nothing.
Go to sleep.
Turn off the light.
Well, all right! You have a reason
to hate me, let's say.
Well, you tell me. Well, how could I
make you feel better
I lied about a baby.
It's embarrassing, I know.
Well, there's got to be a way
to get out of this dead state.
Well, what'd you do? You're going to
jail? Yes.
Well, say something!
Come on, don't be silent!
All right!
What's good?
I love you so much.
I love you so much, silly.
This is all because of you!
Don't just lie there like a stone.
Give me a hug.
No.
Sleep, sleep.
- Well, I'm asking you.
- No promises, I'm a superstitious man.
- Well, I'll be counting.
- We'll count together.
- Still waiting?
- It's okay.
You promised at 4:00,
but... I came earlier.
I promised at 4:00,
I'll meet you at 4:00.
I have some serious news
for you. Do you know?
- You're not listening to me.
- Yes, I am.
I'm listening, it's just that
every day is news.
The victim's glasses
are being disclosed.
- What?
- I said, the victim's glasses.
that's exactly what it says
about her eyesight. Let's go.
- Do you understand me?
- Yes.
Please be seated.
- I don't see a reaction on your face.
- Yes, there is a reaction.
Where can I take you?
Straight ahead, please.
To the Kievsky railway station.
My father was a chauffeur.
Died in the fiftieth.
He was badly wounded.
Well, what about your grandfather?
Well, grandfather.
A Kuban Cossack, an Ataman.
A nasty piece of work.
Scar across his face.
Yes, interesting, interesting.
Well, well, Victor, I'm glad you've
come to see me.
Congratulations again!
- Your thesis is wonderful.
- Thank you, Andrey Vasilich.
We’ll move it, print it and so on.
Thank you.
You've got there,
honestly, some stupid expressions
I underlined it. Check and correct.
- OK.
By the way, there are much
fewer smart people than we imagine.
And even more independent and brave.
Well, now that's it!
Now my granddaughter Katya
will give you tea.
Godspeed, and let me rest.
- Katya!
- Andrey Vasilich!
I would like to ask you to
postpone my legal defense.
Postpone it? Why?
- Has something happened?
- Yes.
I'm going to jail.
- What's this nonsense?
- Truly nonsense.
I hit a woman. The woman died.
Old woman died, I exceeded
speed, I will be trialed...
Well, in general...
So...
Well, we must do something, right?
After all, something is done
in such cases?
We did everything that is...
is usually done in such cases.
And... What?
Of course, I understand
this is a serious matter,
but don't go to jail now
because of this.
- It's funny and sad.
- Funny and sad.
But that's how it turned out.
Turned out...
And it seems to me,
that there is no need
to run away from this.
It is better to not try to escape.
What's this nonsense?
Are you tired, Victor?
What's wrong with you?
I’m tired.
And are you...
really going to prison?
Well, maybe I could do
something for you? Tell me.
No! No, no, no.
No.
Look how desperate he is.
Your Cossack Ataman
has spoken within you.
Yes, except that...
And how long are you going to leave?
I don't know, I think... no...
Not really.
I have nothing to tell you, Victor.
- And yet, I wish you...
- Thank you.
And who plays this, you?
My granddaughter Katya.
Can we invite her here,
your granddaughter Katya?
For what?
Do you want to play?
Well, if you don't mind,
instead of tea.
Please come here. Katya!
Natasha, we don't need so many things.
Oh. OK!
A lot, Natashka.
They're handkerchiefs, or do
you think you don't need them there?
OK, well.
I'll put the old ones in.
Well.
And why did you take this? Calzones!
Where did you find it?
- But these are yours.
- I've never worn them in my life.
Well, that won't do.
Shirt?
Too colourful!
I wore it on vacation.
Vitya, but they are all colourful.
Natasha, maybe a sweater?
Which one is this?
The old one with the deers on it?
Well, with deers,
probably not necessary?
But however, maybe
a sweater with deers will just fit.
Are you having fun?
Is it really
«weight off your mind» for you?
As established by the court, the
citizen Koroleva...
violated articles 16, 18 and 20
of the traffic laws,
in result he caused an
emergency situation.
The defendant Vedeneev,
was driving at a speed of 65 kilometers
per hour, that is,
he exceeded the established article 74
speed rules of the road.
However, at the hearing,
the expert came to the conclusion that
if Vedeneev was driving
at a speed of even less
than 60 kilometers per hour
he still would not have had
the technical ability to prevent
a collision with the citizen Koroleva.
In this connection,
the court does not find
a causal connection between
his actions
and the severe
consequences that have occurred.
Therefore, the court considers Vedeneyev
Innocent
of the act incriminated to him.
On the basis of the above and
guided by Articles
303 and 316 of the Criminal Procedure
Code of the RSFSR, the court sentenced
Viktor Andreevich Vedeneyev
under Article 211
of Part 2 of
the Criminal Code of the RSFSR
to be acquitted
for lack of corpus delicti.
The verdict can be appealed
within 10 days.
Hello! Is this Andrey Vasilich?
Hello, this is
Natasha Vedeneeva.
No! It's all good.
Yes. Everything is fine.
No, everything remains in force.
Protection and everything else.
Yes.
- 21st at 14:30
- at 4:30
- Huh?
- 4:30
Oh, sorry, Andrey Vasilich, at 4:30
Yes. He's right next to me.
I'll pass him the phone now
Hello, Andrey Vasilich!
It's all right!
Good!
Corrections? As promised, I will do it!
Huh?
To the printing house? Okay.
No, no, no! It's okay!
Okay.
Andrey Vasilich, well, goodbye.
OK! Bye!