Retreat! Quickly!
Good.
Turn around! Turn around!
Turn right!
Perfect! Perfect!
Okay.
Good. Do it again, again, and again.
A weak kick like this?
Is this Thai boxing?
Do a strong kick. Do a strong kick.
Use your waist and your body.
Master.
Again. Again.
Strong kick. Strong kick.
Master.
A weak kick like this?
Is this Thai boxing?
Strong kick!
Master.
What the hell is it?
My dad sent me a thousand baht.
You only gave me five hundred baht.
You will spend it all.
Just take five hundred for now.
Yes sir.
Wow!
It's my dad.
You think he's handsome?
My dad worked with Michael Jackson.
He dances the same.
Let me look.
I will tell you one thing.
Your mum never had a affair for sure.
Look! He looks like his dad.
The square face is very popular right now.
You don't understand?
Your dad's not just a famous country singer.
He's also a famous joker.
He takes all the showbiz jobs
so others have none.
Did you know he was going to send
you to study in another country.
But still you come to be with me.
You say it like you make fun of me.
Was that fun?
Damn you! That hurt!
Wow! Is this your car Jib?
It's pretty.
It's the latest one.
This car has a camera too.
Clear picture and shockproof.
Oh! This one! Cat. Look at this one!
This is the one I want. This one.
Let me look.
Is it powerful?
Jib, can I play with it?
Sure. This car is the best.
I just modified it to go a bit quicker.
lf you boxed as well as you talk,
you'd be a Junior Champion.
Phong! Get with the times!
Look at Jib's car! Isn't it cool!
Do you like this one?
No, I like the other one.
Don't you remember?
Yes, I remember.
Cat, I want one of those.
Can you buy one for me?
I want this one.
This one? It's twenty baht.
Can you sell it for ten baht?
- I can't. I would lose money.
- Can you get a different one, Wun?
Okay.
Do you have a cheaper one?
Yes. This one is fifteen baht.
Can you sell it for eight baht?
Take this one then. It's five baht.
What is this?
It is a ''damn shit''.
Tsk.
Damn you.
It's locked.
Come this way.
Where's my ladder?
Where's it gone?
I only used it yesterday.
lf I find out who took my ladder,
I will kill them.
It was me.
- Master.
Uncle.
Richard!
Good work!
Beer in the morning!
- My friend.
- Okay, okay, okay.
Drink coffee?
- You!
- Cat! Cat! It doesn't matter.
- Uncle!
- Okay, okay.
- Hey!
- Hey, Cat!
Were you scared yesterday?
Okay, okay. Sorry.
What are you looking at runt?
Get out of the way!
Go, go, go!
Master.
Master, yesterday l...
They said I couldn't,
but I wanted to.
I want to go outside sometimes.
I'm telling you.
lf I hit you like I hit them...
...you will die.
Why are you crying?
What were you doing?
You know he has a heart problem.
Do you want to see him die
before me?
I'm sorry.
Save it and say it to your parents'
spirits at the temple.
Sorry.
Hey, Wun! can you just stay still?
I have both good news and bad news.
Tell us everything.
What will happen will happen.
Wun's cardiovascular system
is now very weak.
His heart rate is less than
30% of the normal rate.
lf it drops more,
it will be very dangerous.
We must monitor him closely.
He must take stimulants and
diuretics to improve his lung efficiency.
This must continue until
he has his operation.
Relax.
We do have some better news.
Siam lnter Hospital in Ratburee
tell me they have a
twelve year old patient.
He has a head injury who has
been in a coma for many months.
The doctors have just confirmed
he is brain dead.
His blood group and the size of
his heart are suitable for Wun
Now we wait for his parents' decision.
It does seem to be good news,
though really it is bad news.
Because...
Still a child loses their life.
You going to stare at it until a car
comes out from the book?
Phong. Can I borrow the money
that your dad sent?
Do you want it?
It's a lot of money.
I'll give it all to you.
What? You only have about
a hundred baht.
Oh! I pay for stuff sometimes.
What about your savings?
Still not up to two hundred.
Will it be enough?
Don't worry.
I will ask for money from the master.
Are you stealing uncle's money?
I want to take money to give to Wut.
He wants to buy a present for Wun.
I'm only taking one hundred,
and it's my money too.
One hundred is not enough.
Did you really get money from the master?
Sorry.
Who is master Lek?
I want to learn Thai boxing
- I'm a tourist, I don't know.
- Right.
Hey, Excuse me.
Excuse me. Where is master Lek?
I've come to learn Thai boxing.
To wear a band on my head
and do like this.
Can you speak English?
Yes. I want to learn Thai boxing
with Kroo Lek.
Can you speak Thai?
Where is master Lek?
I want to learn Thai boxing.
I know a way to get more money.
Hum... This is my friend.
He will teach you about Thai boxing and...
Go, go! Kick, kick, kick, kick!
He will kick.
Quickly.
Cool!
Kick, kick, kick.
Again, again.
- Again, again, again
- Okay, okay, okay.
Powerful! Powerful!
Sorry!
Don't butt with him.
Look out little missy.
Out of the way runts.
Hey! Hey!
Fuck you!
Thai boxing.
Wut. Remember uncle said:
Don't pick on someone bigger than you.
You little son of a...
Wut! Help me!
Oh shit!
He's coming! He's coming!
Okay, Phong.
Muay Thai!
Cool!
Go!
Do I teach you boxing to hurt people?
It's for...for harmony.
It's for protecting yourself.
Not to hurt people.
Go!
Are you good?
Will you use Thai boxing to
rob and kill people one day?
Do I teach you to behave like this?
No! Be still! Be good!
Today I will hit all of you.
What are you doing here?
Go home!
Master Lek! Master Lek!
You're bad friends.
You don't take the beating.
And let me be the only
one who is hurt.
Because you are stupid.
Wun. You're making fun of me?
He's only young. He's only young.
- Master. Phong is teasing me.
- No, no! What? No,no!
Hey! Who's teasing him again?
You know he is sick.
You only just make trouble,
and now you do it again.
And Wun has a heart problem.
How can you scare him?
I must punish you. I will hit your butt
to get you to remember it.
- Sir. I'm so wrong.
- Are you wrong?
Yes. I'm wrong. So very wrong.
I will hit your butt, but maybe your butt
already hurts. I will hit your leg instead.
Oh! No,no!
Remember do not scare him.
- Do not scare him.
- No, no.
Two thousand five hundred baht.
Oh! Too fucking expensive.
Are you cheating us?
- You little fucking dog-mouth!
- Don't listen to him, sir.
Can you give a discount?
Two thousand two hundred baht.
Any cheaper and it would be free.
You know this car has very few extras.
Can you give more discount please?
No. Enough!
You again, damn it, Phong.
It happens every time and it happened again.
What can we do?
We only have one thousand six hundred baht.
I don't know either.
Can you just think?
At times like these your
damn brain doesn't work.
Wut. Here's the car that Wun wanted.
Oh! Jib my dear friend! You are like
an angel who makes everything good.
Hey! Damn Phong!
We are sharing the cost.
Oh! You are not cool!
Thank you Jib.
Hey, Jib. Now you are friends
with the temple boxers?
No! I just meet them by chance.
Being with them will drag you down.
You need to go to the temple and
wash the bad luck out from your life.
Why did you say a stupid thing like that?
Why? You got a problem?
Jack. Do we have a race tomorrow?
Yes. There is one tomorrow,
You can bring your car to join in too.
Wut, Phong. Go home.
Don't follow us. Two-faced bitch.
You coming with us?
I don't like to wait.
I'm going now.
Is this your new car?
The same as the one I want.
Can I play?
You don't need to ask me, it's yours.
Happy birthday Wun.
My car.
#Happy birthday to you...#
Where's my money gone?
Hey! Hey!
Ho! You're good! Like a professional.
Really! Good enough for other
people to see?
Oh! You're ready to race!
Really!
Take it, take it. Come, come.
Thank you.
- You don't need to thank me. It's Wun's.
- lf it belongs to Wun,
it's the same as if it's mine.
It's not the same.
How dare you say that, Phong?
Happy birthday Wun. Happy birthday.
After you finish don't
go to bed too late. Okay?
Tomorrow you can take Wun to meet
your gang leader at the race course.
Not a good idea.
Don't get involved with them.
Do they have car racing tomorrow Jib?
Can I go with you?
Don't go! Wun. Trust me.
Otherwise you will get sick again.
But I really want to go.
Master has told me I must go
to stay at the hospital soon.
I don't know when I will be back.
Wut. Please let me go. Please,
Wut?
Please let me go. Please Wut?
Wait and see. I will get
first place for you all.
You're boasting!
What time does the racing start?
What racing?
The car racing.
Who's racing?
Me.
Oh! Little boy! You're
gonna be in the race.
Where is your car?
Let me look.
You will see.
You think my racecourse is for fools?
I already told you not to come.
He just want to try to
race on a real course.
You didn't need to say a thing like that.
Yes. You didn't. And I've
modified this car for him.
You have?
Wun. Today can you just watch?
Oh! Cat! We left the master
to come here today.
Let me enter the competition.
Please Cat? Wut, please?
Hey! Take him away.
He's a fucking pest. So annoying.
Hey! Don't.
lf he want to race,
then let him race.
I will arrange it.
Don't let your tears
drop on my racecourse.
I feel a thrill of excitement!
I'm going to buy a drink.
Wun! Go Wun!
Quick Wun! Quick!
My car!
Hey! Wun!
Wun! Don't go in there Wun!
My car!
You die!
Wun!
Hey! Follow them! Quickly!
You!
Wun! Get out! Get out!
Let him go please!
Keep your nose out of it.
You!
I have to be the hero again.
Quickly! Quickly!
Wun!
Go quickly!
Wun! Wun! Wun!
You cannot come in here.
Master. I could not get there in time.
Then he ran away.
Suddenly he fell down.
I could not help him master.
I have good news.
At ten o'clock today, US ambassador
Mr. Peter Ana arrives for a check-up.
Good morning your excellency.
- Welcome here.
- Thank you.
This is our medical team.
Hello. How are you
- Hello. How are you.
- Thank you.
- Please come with us
- Thank you
I saw just now that you had
trouble walking up the stairs.
Quick! Get out quickly!
Go!
On behalf of the Tealaw people.
The minority who try to get compassion.
Who try to get territory from Thailand.
But never get any attention
from the Thai government.
Today it is time to make the
whole world look at us.
As we speak, a terrorist attack
has occurred in Thailand.
As yet, none of the renowned terrorist groups
has claimed responsibility for this act.
...now no group has taken responsibility....
...for now the request from terrorists...
...lately we get a report that terrorists...
Ha! Come on.
- What you're not sure.
- No. Try again.
No, again.
Don't cheat me.
- Damn Phong! Don't cheat.
- Okay.
- I just hit you softly.
- Why?
- Again.
Hey! Hey! Loud noises.
Not in the hospital.
Don't you listen?
Haven't you heard the news yet?
What news doctor?
The terrorists have attacked
Siam lnter Hospital and taken
the US ambassador Mr Peter Ana
and everyone inside as hostages.
All five hundred people in the hospital...
Uncle, this is....
What about the heart they're
transferring to here?
I've sent my staff to
coordinate with them.
The most important thing is time.
Because the heart has been
taken out from the body already.
And the heart can only be out
from a body for four hours.
Four hours.
I'm not sure how long they
will parley with the terrorists.
...now the police have closed all
routes to Siam lnter Hospital,
but there is no progress as the terrorists
still refuse to communicate.
We will continue to report on
these events as they happen...
- Wut wait!
- Wut.
Phong what happened? I will take...
What?
I can take....
This is all your fault!
Wut! I'm going too. Wut!
Can you drive quicker?
This is as slow as a tortoise.
lf you didn't have me, how would
you get to Ratburee?
Hurry up Ood! Get a move on!
This car is old.
It can only go this fast.
You argue with me?
Now you dare to argue?
Sir. They want a reporter.
No. Don't follow us.
You're no use to us now.
Excuse me...excuse me...
There's a lot of people.
We can't get in. Believe me.
Huh! Where are you going?
Just coming through.
Nothing to worry about.
On behalf of the Tealaw Army, we want
our human rights and equality
With no tribes, no racism
and no discrimination.
We want equity.
Enough!
Take them out!
Go! Get out! Go!
Quick! Get out!
Go! Go! Go!
What we gonna do?
We have less than four hours.
Believe me.
I watch a lot of Hollywood films.
Everytime they get in a sewer, they
end up where they need to.
It's damn dirty.
Smells dirty too.
Phong! Take it off!
Which way?
l think this way.
You don't believe me!
I'm the one who got us into here.
Why did you come this way?
It smells bad.
We shouldn't go this way.
It stinks.
I think this way.
Oh! You never fucking believe me!
Walk quickly!
Go!
Quick!
Go quick!
Go!
My cigar's finished.
How's that?
Okay.
I can't. I can't.
I'm allergic to tobacco.
I'm out of here!
Where are you? Damn boy.
You look in that room.
I'll look in this room.
He won't escape.
Phong. Go quick!
Phong. Quick!
Phong. Take the rope.
Cat! Why didn't you ask me
before if I wanted to do this?
Hey! Wait!
They're not here!
Hey! Stop!
He's getting close to me.
Shut the fuck up.
Jib. How did you get in here?
- I go first.
- Wait for me!
Bad luck has come to me now.
Be quiet, damn Phong.
How can I be quiet? You look.
Where are you going?
Don't come.
Death is the best thing of life.
I wish only one thing...
that I am the last person who dies here.
No!
I'm not a terrorist.
Where are you going?
Don't go out there.
They are really dangerous.
I know the way out.
I will take you out of here.
I have friends with me too.
You wait here.
I will be back, I promise.
Excuse me.
Where is the doctor
responsible for Mawin?
- I will check for you.
- He's been gone for long time. Can you call?
Now we have an interesting video
from a member of the public.
The video seems to show some of
the hostages trying to escape.
How you let this happen?
...we will try to report the progress
as soon as we can...
They're little kids and you cannot stop them?
Go catch them!
Catch them alive.
What?
I don't want to make more
trouble with anybody.
We just want what we are due.
It's better to just follow my order.
Do what I said.
What? Too fucking scared?
Enough, enough. Don't do any more.
The kids won't be in here. Let's go.
I go now.
Ghosts! Ghosts!
Cat! Here!
Don't worry. Believe me.
I'm here. Don't be scared.
- Let's go quick.
- I don't believe this is a real man!
You're still scared of me?
What are you complaining about?
Doctor. Doctor.
Wake up, doctor.
Hey. You don't need to.
I can do it myself.
What are you doing?
Doctor. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry doctor.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I'm really sorry.
You didn't mean to hurt him,
but you put your feet in his face?
Look! Your footprint!
Can you find where they keep the heart?
Where is it?
- Are you sure it's this way?
- Sure.
There's only one walkway in this hospital.
How can I get it wrong.
Are you just guessing?
Organ Donation Center!
Quickly! Quickly!
Where is it? The room is full of boxes.
Yes. Full of boxes.
What's that? Can you turn back?
It's upside down. I can't read it.
Come here. I can do it.
Oh! You're damn stupid.
This is Wun's name.
It must be the heart for Wun.
Are you sure?
It's at the door.
Hey! Stop!
Go now!
Quick!
Don't move!
Catch them, quick!
Jib! Help me! Help me!
Phong! Take the rope!
I'm gonna pull now.
How are you Phong?
Are you trying to kill me?
I'm going to die!
Hey! I survived!
Phong hold it tight.
Why Jib?
That hurt! Damn it, Jib!
I should either thank you or curse you,
huh?!
Ouch.
I think better to thank you.
Take a picture quickly!
Go! Go!
I'm in front of the room
of Mawin Boonrubsrab
younger brother of
Nattawut Boonrubsrab
the boy who is in the Siam lnter
Hospital in Ratburee.
He has something to say to
his brave, bold brother.
Wut.
I know you are the
best in the world.
But I want you to come back.
I don't want the heart.
lf I don't have you,
I don't want anything.
Wut please come back.
I don't want the heart.
lf I don't have you,
I don't want anything.
So now we know who they are
and why they needed to
get into that hospital.
We know these children are brave people.
And we hope that they escape
with the heart that they need.
Quick!
Go!
Go! Quick!
Go! Go!
Just little kids that make
our plan go wrong.
And make the ambassador
less important.
And all this is not in our plan.
No!
Now it might be easier.
This way sir.
Quickly sir.
Wut. We still have another heart.
Yes.
There is another heart.
Doctor! Doctor! Doctor!
Doctor! Help! please!
Can your brother use a woman's heart?
I give it to him.
lf we want her heart,
we must do the operation now.
The attack on the Siam lnter Hospital
by the Tealaw Army
ended with efficient arrests
by the military.
The Thai military has successfully
gained control of the hospital...
...the Thai military have arrested
them safely...
...arrested safely....
Police captain Jeerapong Kripong was
hurt while disguised as a doctor.
The four children who were in the
hospital to get the heart for
their brother are all safe.
They are now on their way to take
a new heart to their brother.
It's close to exams and you all
have a lot of homework to do.
After you finished school,
why didn't you come home?
Where have you been?
To get back here to train Thai
boxing like you used to.
I really want to know who had this idea.
Do not blame him!
You're all older than him.
You cannot just do what he wants.
Is this wrong?
Jib. You must know you are wrong.
Go. Stand over there.
Because of your dad I will forgive you.
Cat. Boxing is for harmony
and to protect yourself,
not to hurt people. Understand?
I told you. It's for harmony.
Who's still not been punished?
Why do you hide from me? Why?
Why?
Softly please.
I cannot.
Again, again.
I'm your dad's best friend.
Go!
Wun, come here.
This is all your fault.
Why do I get punished?
It's all because of you making
trouble all of the time.
I will not forgive you.
Turn around.
I don't want to do it.
But it will be an example to them.