- Let me go. She needs me.
Let me go.
- Well look who it is.
A man smart enough
to end up in cuffs.
- How do you keep
it all together?
Hm.
Everything falling
apart in your life and
still you believe.
- Nice shot.
Composure, you gotta
keep that composure.
Come on, Rob, what
are you gonna do?
What are you gonna do?
Come on guys.
You have to know when to
take it hard to the hole,
or when to pull up and shoot.
A player that doesn't know
that is not gonna play
this game long.
When you leave the court
at that final buzzer,
you better be able to look
me in the eye and say
that you give it all.
All you had, is
left on the floor.
Give us strength to fight,
to the last man to the
last play to the last bell
we fight.
- We fight.
- Amen.
- I'll catch up with you.
- Bye.
- Hey coach.
- What's up man?
What's going on?
What, you want me to
walk you to class?
What's on your mind?
- It's my dad.
He's a punk.
Sometimes,
sometimes I just want
to punch him, you know?
He's just...
He's so sick.
- Sick how, man.
- Kurt.
Sit down.
I'm just thinking to myself,
when was the last time
that we had a father son chat?
- I can't recall, sir.
- Neither can I.
So, how's school?
- It's good I guess.
- Girlfriend?
- No.
- No?
Boyfriend?
- What? No.
Any other questions, sir.
- Kurt, relax.
I'm just making sure
that I know my son.
You know they say that
teenagers change, so I'm just
determining the level
of your adjustment.
- What do you even
know about us?
- You can stop with
the histrionics.
- Do you know your wife
calls her friends cry...
- That's enough.
- Stop it Jim.
- He did that to you?
- I didn't say that. I just...
- Well what did you say?
You better say something, what?
- Never mind. Just...
I tripped whatever, you know.
He was yelling, I got scared.
- Um.
Listen, listen man.
Relationships with our
parents can be very
complicated, okay?
They can be very
very complicated.
We want to protect them a
lot of the time because
they protected us right?
But there comes a time when
a parent can do something
that's gonna cause you to,
to not see them for
over 20 years.
That's, you know, tragedy.
It hurts, a lot, but
it does happen.
All I'm saying is
that you know, there
can be a time when
you shouldn't protect them.
- Coach, he's a judge,
what am I supposed to do,
call the cops?
- I would suggest that you
pray to know what to do.
- I don't know how to pray.
Can you help me get the
conversation started or something?
- Mr. Paul, this is Judge
Rogers, Kurt's father.
- Pleasure to meet you, sir.
What happened, Kurt, you been...
- Judge Rogers was
in my office today
before I finished lunch.
- You pervert.
If I find out you laid
a hand on my son.
- Dude, are you
serious right now?
- You do understand that praying
is against school policy?
- I know the policy.
- You people use religious
coercion and propaganda to
brainwash kids like my boy.
I presided over three cases
where so called Preachers
were praying.
- Dad, you're tripping.
- Shut up!
Don't use that kind
of language with me.
I never should have brought
you to this school.
God does not exist.
And no so called coach is
gonna change that fact.
- Well maybe he doesn't exist,
because if he did exist,
he wouldn't have made
you such a jerk.
- Aiden, stop!
Stop!
Clean out your office,
get out of here.
Get out of here, Aiden,
- What are you talking about?
What are you doing?
- You're fired!
You're fired. - I'm fired?
For what? - Go!
Get out of my school.
- I didn't do anything, Mr.
Patterson.
- You did. Go.
- Mr. Patterson, those are
my boys that I coach.
- Those were your boys.
- Mr...
- It's done.
I'm sorry, go.
- Mr...
- Go, go home.
It's time, go home.
Go home.
- Alright, listen up.
I've got some bad news.
Coach Paul's been terminated
and he's not gonna coach tonight
nor any further.
I'll have my starting
five at tip off.
Everybody be ready.
- Are you serious?
- Hey lawyer, who doesn't
answer the phone.
Calling to let you know
that we're not doing
business with you anymore.
Your line's closed,
and you need to get out of
this thing before you end
up getting hurt.
- Everybody's sweating bullets.
Weaves going back and oh...
One girl's had separated,
it looked like two
different people.
I'm telling you, I would've
been so embarrassed.
- Oh my God.
- Miss Lilly, on
a church Sunday,
fell out with a heat stroke.
Roll it went up over her head.
It was so embarrassing.
Oh, Lord, I mean,
it is so hot and we can't
get a drop from the sky.
- It hasn't been
this bad for years.
- It really hasn't.
I mean, I can't remember when
we had a drought like this.
It was...
Oh...
- What?
- You know when it was?
That summer I found
out I had a twin.
And I would sit under that
big old live oak tree.
I said, "God you just saving
your tears until I find"
my baby brother and then
you going rain down those
cool tears of joy.
Baby brother, shoot.
Dog gone it.
- Well you are five
minutes older than me.
- Well how do you know?
I'm gonna check the records.
You better stop talking
that older sister stuff,
thank you, Bill.
- We found out we liked the
same flavor ice cream.
- I know, it's crazy.
Both hate okra.
- Oh you know it's true.
Can't stand it.
- Hm mm mm.
Hmm.
So how's the practice going?
- It's good, doing very good.
- And my case?
- Good.
You know, I filed
all the papers.
I just keep waiting and
waiting for the trial date.
- Well it's filed and that's
good, that's progress.
That's really good.
Yeah.
So how you doing for money?
- I'm good.
Well I could use a little
loan if you've got it.
Just until the next
settlement comes in.
- Michael,
you know I don't put
icing on cornbread.
No, I cannot.
You know I invested
all my savings
on the case for son and all those
experts you said I needed.
I don't know if you know
but all of that came
out of my house.
- And you will get it back.
- When?
- Off the top.
- When? It's been
two years Michael.
- Laurel, some of these
things take time.
- Well I don't have time.
Because now the bank is
making rumblings about
taking my house.
- How much does the bank say
they want to save your house?
- $10,400, can you find that?
- I'm not gonna let anybody
take that house from you.
Okay?
Nobody.
- Promise?
- I promise.
- In Jesus name.
I believe in you.
I don't want this
ice cream to melt.
- You know they can't
keep a good man down.
Tonight.
Princeton, Memphis, Oregon,
FSU, those will be easy.
Thanks for that, hope you
still got the touch.
- Excuse me?
You that lawyer, with
all the ads everywhere?
- That would be me.
Michael Brown.
- Do you like
throwing money away?
- Excuse me?
- All those games you
picked, they're all wrong.
Princeton is, Charmin soft.
Oregon is fast, they
can't shoot the ball.
Memphis just got a new
coach, what are you doing?
Florida State, they need to
stick to playing football.
- Aiden Paul.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
- Hey, thanks.
In case you need a good lawyer.
- Water, coffee, or juice?
- Water and
I'll have the light menu.
- Can you cover this?
- Thank you.
- Any time brother.
- Thanks for taking care
of the boys today, Ray.
- We missed you.
We got outscored by 20
in the second half.
- This thing's got me
thrown, I mean, really.
I got no idea how he could've
found out about that
on the same day, I mean it
doesn't make any sense.
- I know.
- You did?
- Yeah.
Look man,
I feel bad.
I was hoping,
this might help you
get on your feet.
Just read it.
The lady's a good lady,
and it's a private school
and all, but I mean,
it's a gig.
- Then they started to
concentrate, but they
didn't have to concentrate
under pressure.
This is a big deal
right here for this...
- Kansas just used
its last time out.
- Oh.
- He backed off as well. Wow.
- He's got one more,
Kansas at the very least
will have a shot to tie
with 10.8 seconds.
- Kansas has made only
two three on the night.
They must make one here
to extend the game.
Thomson driving, almost
lost the handle.
Chambers for the tie,
Unbelievable.
Dosier at mid court, for
the championship no, we're
going into overtime
in San Antonio.
Jim the free throws did it.
It put Memphis in this position.
- In Heaven.
Beyond my understanding.
My faith is in you.
- What's up, Coach?
- What's up, man?
- Come on, man. Stop acting
like you ain't happy to see
us or something.
I know you miss getting
down with us, huh?
I know you miss that.
What's up, Coach?
- Coach!
- What's up, Coach?
- What's up?
- Hey Coach.
- What's up, man?
Look guys, the important
thing is is that
you stay together,
right, because you're a team.
That's what a team does,
a team stays together,
no matter what. So,
no excuses.
- Look, this Coach Clemmins.
I have no idea what he's doing,
and I don't think he does.
- Hey coach, for real.
They did you wrong.
They did you real wrong.
I don't know if we can
do this without you on
the sidelines, man.
- Yeah you can, man.
Yeah you can.
Well, you know man,
there's no place I'd rather be,
you know that.
You believe that when
I say that right?
But,
it's out of my control.
- Coach, you can sue them.
- No, man, everybody
wants to file a lawsuit.
That's not me. I'm not
filing a lawsuit.
- So you're just gonna
sit back and accept it?
Just gonna sit back
and do nothing?
- No I'm actually
looking for a job, man.
- How's that job,
get you back on the
sidelines with us coach?
- I guess it doesn't Ron.
- You told us to never give up.
Go for our goals, our
dreams, everything.
And now look at you.
What are you gonna do?
- All that,
all that talk about us
being part of a team,
being like your sons,
just talk right?
Just tough, talk.
- Seeing as life is
really complicated okay?
You don't know that
because you're
16, 17 years old
but, it really is.
Tried everything I could.
- I think it's pretty
simple, coach.
You always taught us,
to fight.
You always taught
us to play hard.
And now that it's time for
you to fight and play hard,
you just punk out.
- Punk out?
I love all you guys, but
you gotta go alright?
I'm...
I'm not your coach
anymore, okay?
- You kicking us out now?
- Come on.
- I knew you were nothing
but a fake,
white boy pretender.
- Man, get out of my house.
My house.
- Hey.
You're the swami.
You were right about
those games, you know?
- Yeah, you were right too,
I think I might need a lawyer.
- Let's talk.
- I saw your sign out there,
on the road,
and in the diner,
and then I found your card here.
Three times, do you know
the significance of that?
- I can't say that I do.
- Oh, it's the Holy Trinity,
Jesus died and then
rose on the third day,
there's 27 books of the Bible
which is three to the third
power...
- 66 books in the Bible.
- Right.
- 27 in the New Testament.
- Alright, well 66 is still
a multiple of three and
Jesus prayed three times in
the Garden of Gethsemane.
Before his arrest. - Okay.
- After that...
- Okay, okay
I get it. Three's a sign.
- Right.
- Look.
I don't even know if I
believe there is a God.
But I sure know you can't
pray with kids in schools.
- You ever try that?
- Praying?
Who hasn't?
- What'd you ask for?
- For what?
- That I wouldn't have
a wife that cheated.
- And?
- I'm divorced.
- Because she cheated?
- No.
- You did.
- I don't think I can help you.
- Counselor, what do
you want most in life?
- Make money, be happy.
- Well, all I want to do,
is help kids.
I want to help boys become men.
To coach them and help them,
it's the only thing I know
how to do.
That's what I'm good
at, that's my calling
is to do that and
that's why I'm here right
now, is because a kid came
to me for help and
and I gave it to him,
the best way I know how, the
only way I knew how to help him
and they took everything
away from me for that.
So I'm here now asking
for your help,
and yeah, you would be putting
your neck out on the line,
but that's what I did for
somebody who needed help
and that's why I'm here so...
Come on, let's
make some history.
- I need a retainer.
Up front in case you
have a crisis of faith.
I'll do the rest on contingency.
- How much do you need?
- $10,500.
- Mr. Brown, I'm unemployed,
I don't have access to
that kind of money.
- I can't do it for free, swami.
- Would you take $5000, Mr.
Brown?
- Michael?
- What are you doing here?
How did you know where I was?
- Do you realize
what you are doing?
I just want to pay my score.
They're gonna make me
tell them everything.
Everything I know.
You should check your office.
- Why?
- They left a message.
- You know you give
a person a chance
and they just take advantage
of you, today you just
can't be nice, didn't want
to listen to the pretty face
that you got involved,
after you knew your
line was closed.
I want my money.
And whatever happens to
the people you love,
that's all you.
- We should go, get out of here.
- Go?
Go where?
- Anywhere, just not here.
A vacation, hm?
I mean you spend all your
time around these old things
nobody wants.
- Oh, so I guess
I'm nobody, huh?
- Well I didn't mean nobody.
I just meant we should
be, more spontaneous.
Leave.
- I have to work.
- You own the shop.
- And I need $10,400 remember?
- I remember.
But a few days won't hurt.
I mean the case is gonna
be settled real soon.
- It will?
- It will.
- Michael look at me.
In my eyes and tell me you
think this case is gonna
be settled soon.
- It will.
- We're the same.
Exactly same DNA.
- It will.
- Michael...
- This is a...
- I've known about
it for a while.
I just wanted to see how
long it was gonna take
for you to tell me about it.
- Why didn't you...
- Why?
Because with people you love,
you tend to be more forgiving.
But I just kept hoping that
you would do something,
do something to make it right.
- Laurel...
- And you want me to leave,
my life.
You look around here and
you see old stuff,
but I see treasures.
The people who made
all this stuff,
they've long since passed,
but what they put their
hands to
is treasure.
That's their legacy and I
used to have one of my own.
That died in that car
accident, so right now.
I just want to make
their legacy live on
right here.
So no, I don't need a vacation.
I am where I need to be.
- I'll pay you back.
Every cent.
- I have to work.
- Laurel, I'll pay you back.
I promise.
- Oh God.
- That's my sister, my heart.
I did this to her,
I got to fix it.
I'm gonna fix it.
Watch me.
- I pledge allegiance
to the flag of the United
States of America,
and to the republic
for which it stands
one nation indivisible with
liberty and justice for all.
Have a nice day.
- Under God.
- Do I know you?
One nation under God.
Approved by Congress in 1954,
is there a specific reason
you excluded that phrase?
Oh, you've been served,
by Michael Brown,
attorney at law.
Mr. Paul will see you in court.
- And the plaintiff should
be allowed a hearing
for immediate reinstatement.
My client's season will be
nearly over in 60 days,
your Honor.
- My client needs more
time for discovery.
We need more time.
Six months is what
we're thinking.
- Six...
Your Honor, this hearing
should take place this week.
- That's not feasible and
besides that's absurd.
- That is not absurd...
- I have heard from both
of you upwards of an hour,
you want to forever try the
case to make the plaintiff
suffer, and you
want to catch them with their
pants down so they can't
prepare properly.
Both positions strategically
valid, both positions
logically flawed.
Gentlemen, you have 30 days
to complete discovery.
Trial begins in another 30 days,
I'm sorry if you're client
has to miss his basketball
season but my docket does not
revolve around basketball.
And I'm sorry if you're
client has to work to
prepare for trial but
sometimes counselor,
that's the way it goes.
Thank you, gentlemen.
- Thank you your Honor.
- You're welcome.
- I had hoped you'd be a
little more sympathetic
to my client's case your Honor.
- I am a man of both fact
and faith Mr. Brown,
and I would suggest you
find a strong dose of both
before this trial begins.
- I'm Joseph T.
Herrington, trial lawyer,
Judge Rogers asked that I,
that we intervene and bring
our two hundred years
of collective
experience to bare.
Now who is this lawyer who is
shaking a stick in the beehive.
Smart, filed a
claim for retaliation.
Doesn't depend on the success
of the underlying claim.
Nevertheless.
Michael Brown, Yale Law in 1985,
three disciplinary complaints,
suspended for six months,
last chance reinstatement.
Misses deadlines.
Last five years filed
65 cases, 58 settle,
three lost at trial,
two dismissed due to
lack of prosecution and
one little victory for a
rear end car accident,
verdict, uh,
$2,500
We will not simply
scorch the earth,
they'll be no settlement,
they'll be no compromise,
they'll be no way out.
Still,
you go get me a
settlement conference with Mr.
Michael Brown.
- Aiden Paul?
Aiden?
- The first amendment does
not give coaches the right
to impose their religion
on their students either.
Coaches are
government employees,
when they are coaching, they
are bound by the establishment
clause of the first amendment.
This means that they cannot
encourage, organize,
or participate in prayer.
When they get home,
they can pray,
but whenever they coach,
they coach and not preach.
- You know, you've managed
to divide the community
in a way I haven't
seen I a while.
Your resume is impressive
but I must say,
and I'm not one to
beat around the bush,
there is no one in the
state who will hire you.
- Aiden Paul?
- Good afternoon.
- How may I help you?
- This is my first time here,
so I don't really know what
to do but I have to apply
for unemployment benefits.
- Fill out these forms and
wait over there. Next.
- Ma'am, I'm sorry I'm not
trying to violate any thing,
but I've just been waiting
in line for three hours.
- Denied.
- You lost Michael.
Don't let this escalate.
It won't be good
for either of us.
- I'll have the money.
Long before it's due.
Guaranteed.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I've been looking for
you for over a week.
Trial's around the corner,
I'm meeting with the defense
in less than 24 hours.
- I've been busy.
- Your phones off.
- I'm staying at a
friend's house right now.
And I don't need
that extra bill.
- Well good news and
bad, which first?
- Um,
I don't know why don't we
let the good news drown out
the bad news?
- Alright bad.
The firm of Herrington Smith
and Hail took over the case.
We drew the partner Joseph
Herrington, he's tough.
Hasn't lost a trial in 20 years.
- So we can't win?
- Oh yeah, yeah we can beat him.
But we may not have to.
That's the good news.
They called, wanted
to talk settlement.
- Well that's...
That's a good thing, right?
- Good? That's very good.
- See I pushed for this
trial to come up fast,
that put pressure on them,
they don't want to put their
resources in this and
know that it's bad PR so,
they want me to
come by tomorrow.
- Like a get my job back,
like very soon, good thing?
- I told them if getting your
job back wasn't on the table
we wouldn't talk.
They said let's talk.
It'll all be over tomorrow.
- Sorry, after conferring
with my client we decline to
make an offer.
- You never had any
plans to settle.
That's considered deception,
deceit, old fashioned lying.
- I did no such thing, there's
always a possibility,
albeit a lower than
slight chance, but
anything's possible.
- Well.
If that's the way you
want to play it.
- You're really not gonna
dismiss this suit are you?
- I don't quit.
- After you learn a few
things about your client,
I'm sure that withdrawing
might be a smart move.
- Patience prevents me
from folding prematurely.
- I got to give you
a little credit.
Realizing that if you argue
the merits that the actual
constitutionality, the
prayer, you lose so instead,
you plead retaliation.
That may get you an A in
my common law class but
in the end, these are
little consequence here.
- That's presumptuous.
- Provatic maybe.
Reality is
if you argue prayer,
you lose.
- I'll take that
under consideration.
- You realize this trial
starts in two weeks?
Per your request?
- That's fine counselor.
I wouldn't mind
hastening the headline,
Joseph Herrington loses.
Now that headline,
I'd toiler for.
- T.
Joseph T. Herrington.
Not Joseph Herrington
the plumber,
Joseph Herrington
sanitary worker,
Joseph T Herrington, litigator,
that's something you
seem to forget.
There will be no settlement.
- Very well.
Joseph Herrington. T.
- With your client and his
lawyer, I would expect this
to be the shortest
deliberation in history.
We're done.
- $5,000.
One hand.
I wasn't sure if I
should run or slug you.
- You said that you wanted
to talk so I hope you got
some good news for me.
- You should've made
an appointment.
My life doesn't revolve
around this case.
- I never seen another soul
anywhere near this office.
Hopefully we'll just be
back to normal living,
you know as soon as we
get the settlement.
Thank God for that.
- You lost your job,
your house, your team,
your record,
still you thank God.
You lost your job for praying.
If prayer was so powerful,
wouldn't you still be working?
- What am I supposed to do?
Just be faithful when I am
rolling in the riches,
balling,
on top.
- They're not settling.
- They're not settling?
- That's funny because I
thought that you told me
they called you
and said that they
wanted to settle.
- They called,
but they snuck me.
- Snuck you?
Oh I see so they outsmarted
you is what you're saying.
- Say it any way you want.
But that's not the worst part.
- That's not the worst part?
What's the worst part?
- No matter what happens,
just keep praying right?
- Why don't you go ahead and
tell me the worst part?
- Look,
you see that stack of
motions they filed.
That's 50 grand in fees
sitting on that desk.
- Where's your stack of motions?
- You didn't pay me 50 grand.
- Well what is five
grand stack look like?
That's really it?
- And there's more.
- More?
Oh there's more?
- More.
- There's even more. Wow.
- You should've told me.
- This is supposed to be sealed.
Why are you handing me this?
This is sealed.
This is sealed record.
- If that gets in.
You can't win.
- What do you mean
if it gets in?
It's not supposed to be in,
it's not supposed to be here,
you're not supposed, no one is
ever supposed to be able to
look at this.
Because it's supposed
to be sealed.
We're dropping this lawsuit
right now, do you understand?
- Drop it?
- Yeah. I can't go to trial
with a lawyer... - They have it!
- Who can't keep something
that was sealed as
a minor record.
- Their money unsealed it.
- There's no way this
should be here right now,
do you understand?
There's no way.
- So you just want to drop it?
- Yeah, that's right.
- All my time.
The kids are important.
Et cetera and so forth.
You know I don't get you, swami.
I don't get you.
One minute you're all about
prayer and the next minute
you're ready to quit.
- Ready to quit?
- I'm not quitting anything,
I'm getting out of suicide
right now, that's
what I'm doing.
I lost my job, I lost my
bike, I lost my house,
I lost my living, I
lost everything.
And all I keep... I'm
waiting for answers,
all I keep getting is you,
sitting here telling me
it gets worse.
Oh they outsmarted me. Oh.
You're sealed record from
when you were 10 years old
is now public because they
have money and we don't.
- That's right.
I tell you this so you know
what we're up against.
I tell you this so that
you can understand,
they're playing for keeps.
You get it?
And all you got is me.
Hm, me.
The only person crazy
enough or desperate enough
to take your case.
The only person who's willing
to stick their neck out
for you.
The only person who...
You can't quit.
We can't quit.
I didn't tell you this to quit.
I told you this to fight!
Now you asked me
something the other day.
You asked me did I
want to make history,
well I'm telling you now.
Let's make history.
- What are we gonna do
about this, Mr. Brown?
- Mr. Brown?
- Ladies and gentlemen,
our legal system trust the
community to enforce the law.
Today, you are that community,
your job is important.
And relatively simple.
You have to decide if Aiden
Paul violated a rule,
and whether any violation
deserved termination.
Now,
they will tell you that Mr.
Paul was terminated for
praying with a player,
and that that prayer constituted
a violation of policy,
and for that,
termination was proper.
And then you'll hear the truth.
The truth is,
that Mr. Paul threatened
to report the school's
principal's violations
to the Board,
and later, that same
day, he was fired.
Those are the facts
ladies and gentlemen.
At the end,
actually,
the reason we're here
is prayer.
And where you believe
it's greatest value lies.
Thank you.
- Oh.
The truth.
You know, when
someone tells you,
they declare that they rely
on the truth all too often,
in actuality, the truth,
it evades them.
Because they're so
blinded by their
passionate stand
of their position.
Now I have no doubt that Mr.
Brown believes his client's
position carries the
shield of the truth.
But reality is far
from that barometer.
You see in 1962, our
Supreme Court held
that teacher led prayer
is unconstitutional.
I'm gonna say it again,
listen very carefully.
The Supreme Court held
that teacher led prayer
is unconstitutional.
Opening up prayer in school
is akin to opening up.
Pandora's box, why,
because we don't want
our children indoctrinated
with whatever religion,
whatever religion, just
happens to be popular
at the moment.
So we say no.
You want to discuss those things,
you want to ask questions
you do it inside your own home.
The separation of
church and state
is an enforceable,
constitutional
principle.
Mr. Paul very simply,
violated that principle,
and the school,
they terminated him
for doing such.
That termination, you know
what that termination does?
It protects our children
from the undue influence of
people who happen to be popular.
People that our children
look up to like Mr. Paul
who will do anything to win.
Influence.
People who influence
our children.
Ladies and gentlemen of the
jury, with that verdict.
I want you to inform
the plaintiff,
I want you to inform Mr.
Paul that we as a community
we respect and we
uphold the law.
No matter how many
athletic events
you may coach to victory.
We respect,
and we uphold the law.
Thank you.
- Your Honor,
plaintiff calls Kurt
Rogers to the stand.
- It has been brought to the
court's attention that.
Mr. Kurt Rodgers was never
properly served a subpoena
to testify in court today.
- Judge I was informed by the
witness that he would testify
today,
but I would move to admit
his deposition testimony.
- Your Honor we object to the
admission of this deposition,
we were not informed of
the deposition because.
Mr. Brown deprived the
defense the opportunity to
cross examine the witness, the
deposition is inadmissible
hearsay under rule 801.
- Mr. Brown?
- I anticipated the witness
would be here to testify
your Honor.
- Not good enough.
If the defense did not have
the opportunity to cross
examine the witness,
the testimony,
it's not admissible.
- Your Honor, these witnesses
are inappropriate.
The facts of this case
turn on whether Mr. Paul's
termination was a violation
of school policy.
- Your Honor, is counsel
gonna allow us to put on our
case or continue these jack
in the box objections?
- Is opposing counsel gonna
adhere to one single rule?
- I agree with Mr. Herrington,
this case is not about.
Mr. Paul's character, it
is only about whether he
was terminated for
violating a rule,
or for pretexual reason.
Next witness.
- Mr. Patterson, you
claimed that Coach Paul
was terminated for
praying with a student?
- That's correct, yes.
- Isn't it true that on the
same day he was terminated,
he informed you that he was
going to report you to the.
Board for the misallocation of
funds assigned to the team?
- Not in that way, no.
- In what way then Mr.
Patterson?
- I recall he
mentioned some kind
of a complaint, but
I don't recall him
threatening me to
threatening to report
me to my superiors, no.
- But if he was to do so on
the same day that he was
terminated,
it would look pretty bad
for you wouldn't it?
- Yeah, if you say so.
- Well did you?
- Did I what?
- Did you miss allocate funds?
- Absolutely not, sir,
and I'm insulted.
- Oh I'm so sorry
to insult you, sir.
Do you need a moment
to gather yourself?
- Objection your Honor.
Argumentative.
- Sustained. That statement
will be stricken.
- Mr. Patterson praying
with a student
is not a terminable
offense is it?
- Yes it is.
- According to your policies,
conviction of a felony,
forgery, falsifying records,
stealing, fighting, immoral
or indecent conduct,
these are listed as
terminable offenses,
and funny thing is, there's
no mention of prayer.
- It's not specifically
stated, I'll give you that,
it's assumed under
indecent conduct.
- I'm sorry.
Are you saying that your
school district categorizes
prayer as indecent conduct?
- Yes, but not in the way
you may think however.
- Well pray tell
how do you do so?
- Indecent defined as
not being the norm,
not fitting, not
indecent as obscene.
- The definition that
you're relying upon,
this definition is written
in your policies?
- No I don't think...
- No it is not.
You would agree, Mr. Patterson,
that being transgender
is not the norm?
- Honor, objection.
- A little grace your Honor.
- Very little.
- Yes I would agree.
- And there is a transgender
teacher working at your
school, and a parent complained
because this teacher
discussed it with a student.
- I believe that's true, yes.
- And according to
your definition,
not being the norm
is indecent, right?
- According to that
logic, I guess.
- And that teacher
still teaches, yes?
- Mr. Brown, precisely
what is your point?
- My point is that you chose
to terminate Coach Paul
for praying with a student
but you chose not to
terminate a transgender
teacher who discussed
their sexual identity
with students.
Mr. Patterson.
Tolerance and
understanding is a river,
that flows both up
stream and down.
Does it not?
- Guard said it's about
that time, he's locking up.
- My mentor was never allowed
to enter the room down there.
He and everyone that looked
like him were forced to
sit up here.
Argue from the balcony.
Separate.
- Shackled by stupidity, huh?
- Shackled by stupidity.
- So I'm up tomorrow?
- It comes down to you.
- They can't bring up the
things about the past?
- No I don't think so, but
don't open the door.
I thought you said at the
beginning of this thing that
if we argue prayer's
okay at any time,
then we're gonna lose?
100%.
- We might.
But what are we
really fighting for?
Just a job.
- History, right?
- History remembers those who
win in a spectacular fashion.
Or lose in the same way.
Either way, you and I
will be remembered.
- Coach?
Hey old man.
- We know you gotta
take the stand.
- And we know you've kind of
always had our backs and...
- We wanted to have your back.
- Just don't let them
shake you coach.
You know they say a solid
d wins championships.
- Hey man, I
appreciate it, guys.
What we in a huddle now?
What we gonna do? Do we fight?
We fight.
- We fight.
- Amen.
- You guys, thank
you for coming.
- What? They followed me.
What can I say?
You were terminated, for praying
with one of the students
and that that
violated the rules.
Did you or did you not
pray with Kurt Rodgers?
- I did.
- And why?
- I did it because I
recognized pain in his eyes.
I knew it.
And
so then I made a choice to
help one of my players.
That was all.
- You do understand that
not everyone believes
prayer helps?
- I'm not concerned with
what everyone believes,
or what everyone thinks.
I just know that I'm the
only person who's walked
a mile in my own shoes,
and I know
the hopelessness of a
life without any faith,
know what that can be like.
Everything I do, and
everything I did
was to
help my players, and help
them become better men.
- Your witness.
- You understood that prayer in
school is against the rules?
- No I didn't.
The constitution guarantees
my right to free speech.
Period.
- Strain lay interpretation
be that as it may,
is it your claim that
prayer helps,
helps.
That prayer has helped you.
- Yeah.
- Helped you as a child?
- Uh huh.
- Prayer's helped you as far
back as you can remember?
- I've been praying
all my life and
it has always helped me
through troubles yes.
- In 1991, when you
were 10 did you...
- Objection, your Honor.
This is case is not about Mr.
Paul's character,
as a child or an adult.
The facts of this case
turn on whether Mr. Paul's
termination was a violation
of school policy and
I quote Mr. Herrington.
- He has you there Mr.
Herrington...
- Counselor's just a tad
late with that objection,
Mr. Paul is the one who opened
up the door to his past,
on a principle that prayer
has always helped him.
In 1991,
were you arrested for murder?
Don't look at your counsel,
he can't answer that for you,
you're up there all on your own.
In 1991, were you
arrested for murder?
- I was.
- And did pray help you then?
- It did.
- Did prayer help you when you
pushed a man through
a glass window?
- Yeah.
- Did prayer help you when
you punched the man and you
broke his nose?
Did prayer help you when you
shot and killed the man?
Your very own father?
- Thank you Lord that you
will redeem my soul in peace
from the battle
that is against me.
- I'm sorry I can't,
I'm standing right
here, I can't hear it,
could you speak up?
- Thank you Lord that you
will redeem my soul in peace,
from the battle
that is against me.
- Your Honor, please
instruct the witness
to answer the questions before?
- Please, sir, answer the
counsel's questions.
- His questions, yeah I did.
It did help me then.
- That's the same help,
that you were giving Kurt
regarding his father.
No further questions.
- Counsel?
- The plaintiff calls Nona Paul.
- What are you doing?
- She called, said
it's her last chance.
- You should've
told me about this.
I don't like this at all.
- Just trust me.
- It's time.
It's my turn.
- Did Aiden shoot his father?
- No. No he didn't.
- Did he say he did?
- Objection.
- Overruled.
- Yes, yes he did.
- Ms. Paul, in your own words,
tell us what
happened that night.
- I was a drug addict.
I had two strikes.
His father,
was a horrible,
violent man.
He and his friends would
do terrible things to me.
Things a child should
never have to see.
Aiden was always my protector.
Until that night.
That night, his
father went after,
Aiden,
and I decided in a split
second, I would do,
what I knew I had to do.
- What did you mean by
coming after Aiden?
No need to answer that.
- Your mother has cancer.
Small cell carcinoma, it's a
very invasive type of cancer.
I'm sorry.
- Come together
they asked of him,
saying Lord we'll doubt
this time restore again
in the kingdom to Israel.
And he said unto them,
it's not for you to know
the times or the seasons
which the Father hath
put in his own power,
but you shall receive power.
- Can you forgive me?
- I was just a little kid.
And you left me in the system.
I grew up in foster homes.
You never even came to visit me.
- I was a coward.
Simple as that.
Facing you everyday, I,
it was facing my failure.
My fear.
You are everything I
wish I could have been.
I don't deserve
your forgiveness,
I don't deserve your love.
- Yeah you do, I
want you to have it.
You do deserve it,
you already have it.
You're forgiven okay?
I forgive you.
I don't even care, I just want
I just want you to be here.
- Well Mr. Brown, we
find ourselves in
a precarious position.
Here's the promise, don't have
my money by the end of the
day, that email
becomes a reality.
- Counsel?
Are you ready for
closing arguments?
- He's pointing to you.
- Mr. Brown is the
plaintiff ready?
- Your Honor,
I need a recess for a day.
- Objection.
- This jury has been patient
and I will not make them
wait another day.
- Your Honor, I have to
attend to a personal matter,
of extreme urgency
and I have to do it,
right now.
- Your Honor if he had a matter
of such grave importance
he should've addressed
it before today.
- Mr. Brown, I find this last
minute request to be both
unprofessional and discourteous,
Mr. Herrington, are you ready
for closing arguments?
- Prepared your Honor.
- It is time for your closing Mr.
Brown, now.
- With all due respect your
Honor, to you and to the jury.
I will not be doing my
closing argument today.
There are some things
even more important than
our convenience,
or even the rule of law.
Today I'm faced with
one of those things.
Please forgive me.
I'll be ready tomorrow.
- Mr. Brown.
Mr. Brown! If you step
into that gallery,
I'll order you arrest
and held in contempt
of court, this is my courtroom.
And you will be
held accountable.
In my court, in my book,
do you understand?
- Let me go.
She needs me.
Let me go.
No.
- There he is.
Man too smart to
end up in cuffs.
- How do you keep
it all together?
Hm?
Everything falling
apart in your life and
still you believe.
- Don't think I don't get tired.
Don't think I don't
ask for answers.
I do, but I keep the faith.
- I'm a gambler.
I gamble.
You don't know what it feels
like to grow up a gambler.
You feel empty,
unwanted.
The only place I've...
The only place I actually
felt like someone,
was sitting at a table.
- Well Michael, you know
there's one family that I know
that I'm always a part
of no matter what.
- No matter what.
- I stand here, my hands and
feet shackled like a slave.
My freedom is restricted.
Freedom.
Freedom is why we're here today.
The defendant has shackled
my client's freedom to share
his faith with someone who
simply asked for help.
And when my client responded
yes I'll help you,
and decided to break
his shackles,
they fired him.
They say that
prayer in schools is
constitutional prohibited.
I say it's constitutionally
protected.
Freedom of speech protects
our right to speak freely,
and a plain text reading of
the amendment says no law,
no law shall be made to impede
free exercise of religion.
So they say separation
of church and state,
I say there would be no
state without the church.
But ladies and gentlemen,
I'm helpless,
I've taken him as far as
my abilities have allowed.
And now it's up to you.
I'm helpless bound
in these shackles.
I can't break them, I
can't unlock them.
I can't do anything on my own.
- Has the jury
reached a verdict?
- We have your Honor.
We find
for the plaintiff, Aiden Paul.
- And for damages?
- We award the plaintiff
$700,000 reinstatement
with full pay and for the
defendant to pay attorney
fees in the amount of $250,000.
And the jury collectively
wants to say that
as a community,
we wish more teachers
would take the time to
pray with the students
in our schools.
- Defense moves for a
directive verdict your Honor.
- Denied.
- Request to the state of
the order pending appealed.
- Denied.
Coach Paul,
you are ordered reinstated
as of immediately.
Congratulations, counselor.
But my order of
contempt still stands,
you still have to show more
respect for the institution
of the law,
now you may conclude your
celebration in custody.
Bailiff.
- Five minutes older than me.
- Stop it.
I am the baby and
I always will be.
- Never understood, I always
wondered how a man could
survive in quarters
fit for a rat, huh?
Well, the reason for my visit.
- You read my mind.
- Thomas Hill.
- Who?
- He sat unseen for nearly
30 years but a name who
who still haunts me
to this very day.
Third year, law school I was
an intern in the district
attorney's office and I
tried my first case.
I was arrogant and
he beat me down.
The walk of shame when I got
back to the office, whoa.
I promise I'd never allow
myself to get beat again.
When things got difficult,
those two words,
they motivated me,
Thomas Hill.
Now replaced by Michael Brown,
the only man to have
ever beaten me,
replaced by the only other
man to have ever beat me
who's name will drive
me to my twilight
to never feel this way again.
- Was that a long
winded congratulations?
- That's what it sounded
like to me, yeah.
- Seeing that a jury's
ordered my client to pay
nearly one million dollars
combined with the fact that
we do not wish to upset the
Supreme Court's precedent's
in the unlikely event that
you should win an appeal.
I have been authorized to
make you a one time offer.
- $300,000.
- $200,000 Mr Paul,
$100,000 to counsel.
- This check is dated
four days ago.
- I had the authority to
issue it anytime I felt that
you actually had a chance
to make your case.
Which didn't arise until your
moving
closing.
I don't want to stand
around here all day so,
what's it gonna be?
- My job?
- Court's order stands.
I did ask the judge
for one little favor.
- You can go ahead and
roll your things up,
I'll be back to get
you in 10 minutes.
- Still don't think there's
anything greater going
on in here Michael?
- What are you doing?
- What does it look
like I'm doing, man.
- Here and now?
- Don't you understand,
don't you see?