Fuck.
ROSENHOLM UPPER SECONDARY SCHOOL
Are you just going to leave?
-I'm in a terrible hurry.
That's my bike.
-Okay. Sorry.
Do you need help?
-You don't have to.
I will stick to this.
-Jep. Good.
Excellent.
Yes, well, I'm busy.
Do you always get slippery when you tip the bike over?
-Only if no one sees.
I thought you weren't coming.
Frida, now the first year begins.
Now let's drink and party
and drink and party.
And let's fuck all the third graders.
You slut.
-Thank you.
Here.
-Welcome.
Welcome to. Testing, one, two.
Those are the tutors.
The redhead on the right is Pelle Ratz.
He runs the school's Instagram.
He is involved in everything
with those two next to him.
Mathias Kofoed and Emil Hartman.
Pelle has a younger sister Nadja.
Over there. In the velour case.
He's very popular.
So is her friend Amalie.
You have to join them.
-Calm down, Selma.
No. It is important to spin
right from the start with the right guys.
I will not be a wallflower.
-You'll never be a wall rose.
Here we go.
Welcome to Rosenholm High School.
It's great to see so much
happy and hopeful young faces.
It goes by quickly.
Before the tutors have the floor,
I would like to emphasize... This applies to you as well.
...that school does not tolerate
bugs of any kind.
It is not allowed,
and will result in expulsion from school.
That's just how boring it is.
Emil, you can continue.
-Thank you.
Testing. Not at all.
I'm glad you're listening quietly,
when the headmaster speaks.
Surely you're making some noise?
Welcome to Rosenholm!
Let's go.
-Me?
Hello.
-Hey.
I'm Selma, and this is Frida.
-Hi.
Nadja.
-Hey. Amalie.
What category are you in?
-1Q.
Kind of nice. We're in the same class.
-Oh yeah, well nice.
It will be fun.
What secondary school did you go to?
-Tofteskolen.
Wouldn't Enemark High School be closer?
-Yes.
Yes, but in Rosenholm
has better maths teaching.
That's Mathias from 3Z.
He's really good looking.
He can make me his leather jacket.
He was with Natalia in 2Q.
He wrote there with his tongue Natalia
Natalia's name. Natalia loved it.
I want him too. Now.
Our projects include
probability calculus -
calculus of proportionality, exponentiation
and symbol manipulation.
Can you explain,
what symbol manipulation means?
Nadja.
I can't.
Do I look like I know?
Could be. What about the others?
Yes?
Doesn't it mean different
rules about -
how the symbols are used
based on certain basic assumptions?
That's right.
Cool.
Hello. Will you come to the audition?
For which audition?
-To audition for the Skylark Festival.
To those where the sons of three
humiliate the girls of number one?
It's going to be a pigsty.
We'll fix them at this address.
Parents or teachers must not be told.
This is a secret.
Read the address and burn the note.
Let's say hello properly.
Emil Hartman, 3Y.
Frida Frimodt Hansen, 1Q.
Pelle Ratz, 3Y.
-Mathias Kofoed, 3Z.
Hello.
-I need to talk to you.
Like what?
When a third grader
greets number one, number one has to say hello.
According to whom?
-Our third graders.
You can do that, can't you?
-I can.
When mowing, you have to go all the way down.
-Really deep, that is.
We want to see,
whether you are a submissive.
I can certainly tell you,
as long as you bow to me first.
Ahaa. Well, that's all right.
Right, guys?
After you.
Wow.
-Your turn.
No need to imagine.
Tough chick.
-Are you coming to the audition?
Very unlikely.
Here's some tea.
Wonderful, Birgitte.
-Thank you.
Did you have a good first day of school?
-Oli. Everyone was really nice.
It was really fun,
but we've got a bit to do.
The maths task must be returned in two
in two weeks. Can we do it over the weekend?
You get the picture,
that high school is a real buffet?
What do you think of Pelle?
-Nadja's big brother?
Yes.
He seems to have it under control.
Let's have a look at that maths assignment
this weekend?
I'll get Pelle.
-You don't have to.
No, but I would love to be a leather cat.
The whole leather thing is really degrading.
-How so?
The boys in number three just want to
hitting on pretty freshmen.
Just as much as I want to hit
a handsome third grader.
Frida, a woman has the right to have a dick.
If you want to get an egg,
you have to find an egg.
For example, from that audition.
-I don't understand why you want to go there.
Don't you have any limits?
-No.
That's why you're coming along.
-Unquote.
Yes, because they're at Pelle's.
They came to see me today.
-Who?
Pelle and others.
-See what?
And you're just now telling us. Let's hear it.
What did they say and do?
They asked if I would come
to their stupid audition.
Frida, you're out of your mind.
It's insane.
They've looked you over.
You have to come with us.
-Whatever they're looking at.
Not me.
You're coming with us. You don't have to do anything,
if you're afraid of embarrassing yourself.
I'm not afraid of embarrassing myself.
-Then send me along.
I'm in the mood for a kebab.
Could either of you pick one up?
It's not true.
You still owe me a cigarette.
Emil?
-I called last time.
Don't bother me.
Now look what happened. It's not funny.
Fuck you.
That Frida is quite pretty.
-Really pretty.
What do you think, Emil?
He presents the elusive.
-Just fine.
That's what it's like to be cheap.
-I only have one leather coat.
Oh, today?
-Heko heko.
I'll book Frida.
-You can't book them all.
I'll just book Frida then.
-Why would he take care of you?
Emil! Look at me now.
Look at this physical miracle.
The perfect piece of meat. And a pork butt.
Who could resist this?
Me, and I think Frida too.
Why don't you believe in Mathias' abilities?
You don't think he can hit on Frida?
Emil.
-Tietty.
Thank you.
Stop that.
-Let's smash the mattress room.
If the girls in three have one,
so do we.
It is our turn to be worshipped.
-I have always adored you, my love.
I know the weekend is coming.
Tracks 19 - 21 for Monday.
Frida, do you have a moment?
-Yes.
I let some students
make presentations for the lesson.
Could you elaborate on some basic concepts?
-I don't really know...
That counts as a task, of course.
Okay, but how will it be done?
A pair of third-grade maths students
will help you.
Smart students like you will be supported.
What do you say?
Yes, it's fine.
-Nice.
Hi, maths lovers.
Hello.
-I'll help you with the task.
We could agree on something more specific.
-Okay. What should we agree on?
Will you come to the audition?
-No.
If you come, we can work something out.
-It's a party.
You can still talk about statistical
hypotheses and probability calculations.
Let's agree on something right now.
-Now is not the time.
I need to save my bike,
before some psycho knocks it over.
See you tonight?
Okay, I'll be there tonight, but that's all,
to work something out in more detail.
Of course. See you later.
Come on.
I'm glad you left.
-I'll just be here to watch you.
Yeah, right.
What are you doing?
-We have started to smoke.
It shows you that you need to be watched.
Do they live here?
-They live above Dad's restaurant
Aren't you going to try?
-What?
What's wrong with you?
-You're weird.
Frida, I'm glad you came.
Welcome to. Hello. Mathias.
-Selma.
Hello. Welcome to.
-Thank you.
I am the father of Pelle and Nadja.
Have some rice porridge.
You'll get a little bit of pomp and circumstance.
Then there'll be shots and drinks.
Here.
A mouthwash is enough,
so you should eat some porridge.
Have a fun evening.
Take care of everything. I'm out of here.
You're behind.
-We must be careful not to get stuck.
Do you know where the toilet is?
-No.
Hold this.
You'll have to take care of me then.
Moi.
-Hi. You have a nice dad.
Let's go find the remoulade sauce.
-Jep.
Hi, maths lovers.
Glad you could make it.
I thought we had to agree on something.
-Right.
Would I come to you one afternoon?
-Okay.
It is then agreed.
Shall we go and celebrate?
No thanks. I was going to the bathroom.
-It's down the hall.
What is it?
-French 75. It goes in the head.
Do you get drunk on skins,
so they'll do what you ask?
Yep.
Okay. Give me one.
Cheers.
Shall we dance too?
It was a joke.
This is perfect.
They know how to make good drinks.
Emil, now I...
At least better than yours.
Are they together?
-They are. Didn't you know?
En.
I think Emil is the real player.
-I guess so.
Hello! Can you hear me?
-Now it starts.
Hello!
Welcome to
to the audition for the skunk festival.
Let's get things moving.
-The girls come on stage one by one.
Let's see how brave you are.
-And hot.
And how sexy you are. Cheers!
Cheers!
-Cheers!
Please get down on your knees.
Bring on the remoulade sauce.
Come closer.
-I don't like remoulade sauce.
Everybody likes it.
-I don't.
Clown, leave it,
if he doesn't like it.
Maybe you just don't have the courage.
I dare,
but I don't like remoulade sauce.
Two at the same time?
The sauce is not enough.
Okay, spoilsport. I thought that
let's have some fun, but you're boring.
Okay.
A bit harsh.
Give him a round of applause.
Frida! Let's take your picture.
-Why?
It is needed for selection.
-Not now.
Yes, Frida?
-Not now, I said.
Frida Frimodt Hansen, 1Q.
Thank you.
-You're so fucking pretty.
Are you leaving already?
-Yes.
Why?
It annoys me that someone is taking pictures,
when I've said no.
It was just a flap.
-Ai?
Sorry. Sorry,
if you didn't find it funny.
May I be excused?
Et.
-Can I walk you home?
-Can I even walk across the road?
Et.
Wait a minute.
Surely you can forgive me?
-Your behaviour is completely ridiculous.
We thought you were in on it.
I'd like you to join us.
Okay. That's a strange way to show it.
I didn't think you were that shallow.
-Do you think I'm shallow?
You're in on that.
-Is that superficial?
I see right through you.
Me no piss.
-Am I trying to fuck you over?
Yep. And I really don't want to
you to be my math partner.
What happened?
Leave me alone.
-I guess there's nothing else to do.
Then go.
-I'll go.
Go to your girlfriend.
-I will.
Why don't you go inside?
-Why don't you go?
I was here first.
-This is a common way.
You're really annoying.
-You're really lovely.
Did you have a nice evening?
Yes.
-Frida Frimodt, hello? Did you have fun?
It's nice.
Did you drink a lot?
-A fair amount.
Was it just a party?
-What do you mean?
Did anything exciting happen?
-No.
Okay.
What are you going to do today?
-Go for a run?
Hungover? Do you have to?
-Yes.
Hello.
-Hey.
Why did you leave yesterday?
I felt bad about the shots.
Wasn't it the remoulade sauce?
-Something like that.
Why did you come on stage?
-How come?
Then it was my turn.
-I saw you didn't like it.
It was just a game.
-Was it?
Yes. I liked it, though.
I would have said it myself, by the way.
You made me look like an idiot.
You ruined my moment with Pelle.
Excuse me. I just wanted to help.
-You did?
You seemed to enjoy the attention.
-What do you mean by that?
Why can't you just admit it?
-Because it wasn't like that.
Okay.
-I'm sorry if I spoiled your story.
It's OK.
What happened after I left?
-It was a crazy party.
Dancing with Pelle.
Or we were on the dance floor at the same time.
He was looking at me. Right.
Access to the skunk festival
only eight girls.
Something has been posted to Rosenholm's account.
-What?
Photos of those who make it to the party.
Are you involved?
-No.
But you are.
You've already gotten so many likes.
Like what? Show me.
It's true.
Pretty wild, isn't it?
What is it? You're quiet.
-Weekend just makes me tired.
Friday was a lot of fun.
-It was.
Frida! Frida.
Frida!
Hello.
-Hey.
You were chosen for the skunk party.
Congratulations.
Thank you. And thank you as well.
-You did a great job auditioning.
Rispekts.
-Thank you.
I have to go to class.
-Me too.
Shall we go one way?
-Yes.
See you later.
Amalie also received an invitation.
-But Selma didn't.
No, but that's the spirit of the game.
Will you come to my snails,
Amalie and the other girls?
I don't know yet if I will come at all.
-Come on.
Are you serious?
Do you realize how many people would want your job?
Should have red lips, tight skirt
and high heels. I don't have those.
Let's get it then.
It's a bit like being on show.
-Frida...
Think of it this way. Guys think,
they can make us do anything.
In reality, we have the power.
They are so easy.
All they need is a pair of heels and a miniskirt.
Let's take advantage of it.
We run the dogs.
It's going to be a pigsty.
Otherwise, you're really gorgeous. Let's go.
The comparability calculation has now started,
and you will solve the problem.
You can solve the task here
or go to the corridor.
What are you doing?
-I'm probably going to the hallway.
What about you?
-I'll stay here.
Hello.
-Hey.
Thank you for the last one.
You're a good kisser.
Forgive me.
I don't know what got into me.
Shall we forget the whole thing?
-Yes.
Thank you.
-Only one candidate.
I do not negotiate with terrorists.
-I do negotiate.
I want to help you with your maths assignment.
Okay, but then let's forget it,
what happened on Friday.
Absolutely.
-This is totally professional.
Indeed.
Hi, honey. According to this young man.
you have a math assignment together.
Yes, it is.
So go ahead and get started. Nice to meet you.
-Samoi.
It was hard to decide whether to bring a pizza
or remoulade sauce.
I chose a pizza.
I hope it's OK.
Okay. This is good.
You have a beautiful place.
Near the forest.
I love the forest.
-Samoi. I often go to the forest.
I run there often.
The hill is my favourite place.
-Me too. I almost always run there.
It's really great there.
Should you?
-Yes.
"You have to understand the rules and justify,
why they apply."
"You have to think abstractly."
You have an insane LP collection.
It's insane.
The sound sounds more authentic.
-Same opinion.
A really good album.
-It's really good.
That was also cool when you sang.
-Learn. Seriously.
What do you think about what I have read?
Was it badly worded?
-No. It was good.
Frida...
-Yes?
That Friday kiss...
-We were supposed to forget about it.
Yes, but I've thought about it a lot.
A lot.
Are you too?
-I was really drunk.
That's just what happened.
You're with Nadja.
It's a complicated thing.
-How so?
He's more vulnerable than you think.
-Okay.
Let's stop talking about it until
everything becomes even more complicated.
Let's call it a day.
-I just...
I didn't expect to meet you.
I know I'm dating.
But I think about you all the time.
-Learn.
Nadja and I have to get a divorce.
-I don't want to hurt Nadja.
I'm the one who insults him.
-Stop this.
I don't want to stop this.
-We don't even have anything.
It would be stupid to leave Nadja,
because I don't want you.
Okay. Are you sure?
I am. You could leave now.
I just want to say,
this is not complicated for me.
All that I feel,
when I'm with you is real.
But...
-There's nothing but for me.
But it is, Emil.
I don't understand how you can sit there
and I stand here...
...and I feel something between us
and you don't.
What do you think?
-Sounds nice.
Would you be interested?
-Yes. Like on Monday.
Let's agree then.
-Yes.
I can think of something. There's nothing new,
if I say I'm staying over.
I'm angry that I didn't say that.
I tried.
I'm not going to give up.
See you at the hill in the woods at 18:00.
Frida?
I understand. It sucks for you.
Okay. What's going on?
Why?
-What's going on with Emil?
Nothing. I...
-Don't talk shit.
That's what I did. I'm your best friend.
Do you think I'm stupid?
No, but we have nothing.
Fuck!
-Are you together?
What has happened?
We kissed.
I know it sucks,
but I can't stop.
Think of Nadja.
That has to stop.
I think about Nadja all the time, but...
-No buts.
You will be blacklisted,
if people find out about this.
You pull me with you.
-You have done nothing.
No, but we were rolling together.
And I don't want to fight with Nadja.
So could you put an end to it? Right now.
Yes.
Emil asked me to meet him at six...
-You're not going.
Of course not.
-Good.
I'm going to Selma. Bye.
You came.
-You waited.
In our year, I think we have
more girls than others.
Hello.
-Hey.
You said you were going to Selma.
-No, I'm going to Nadja.
You said Selma.
-Said Nadja. You just don't get it.
I'm going too.
Sorry, I didn't know,
that you had said that.
I didn't know either,
that you were coming.
Where were you?
I just...
Were you with Emil?
Olin.
-Oh, hell, Frida.
Where were you?
In the forest.
-In the forest?
Just now?
-No. He...
Were you...?
Yes.
No shit.
-Yes.
Bloody hell.
Was it fun?
-Fucking great. Really fucking nice.
Naughty girl.
I thought you liked boy stuff.
too complicated.
It's bloody complicated.
-I know. I just can't help it.
Emil is so sick of...
-Sick of what?
Sickly lovely?
-Yes.
He knows,
how to make girls think that way.
What do you mean?
-Emil is a player.
He brags that he has made a guarantee
you're his own leather jacket.
No. Emil wouldn't do that.
I think he will leave Nadja.
Do you really believe?
Have you seen how popular Nadja is?
Emil will not leave Nadja
and risks everything.
I don't want to talk to you anymore.
-You don't understand what's going on.
What is it about?
-Emil is taking advantage of you.
And you let them.
-What do you mean?
That's obvious.
A skinner's feast is a competition.
You are the prize. Emil just wanted to be
with you before Mathias does.
You're drooling over Pelle.
He'd just be using you.
I'm sure you will.
The only difference is that Emil is dating.
I do it of my own choice.
You are being used.
Emil may well be...
-Be what? Loved you?
Do you know who he's in love with?
Himself.
The Frida I know is so smart,
she'd figure it out.
Selma I know
would not be so jealous.
I am not jealous.
The attention seems to go to your head.
Or you just can't stand that all
is happening to me and not to you.
What's wrong with you?
Or don't you just not know me anymore?
Vai...
-You really don't know me anymore.
Let's take a break.
Suitable for.
It was wonderful
I think about you all the time...
Emil, do you want a beating?
He's lousy
at everything except FIFA.
Emil, your turn.
Hello. What's that on your mobile phone?
so interested in?
Nothing.
-Come on and play.
I smell blood. Come on.
-Yeah yeah. Calm down.
Here goes.
What a good start.
I miss you
You're a complete shit too.
What is it now?
-What the hell are you doing?
Why?
-with Frida.
Nothing.
Were you fooling around behind my little sister's back?
-No.
You are lying. You're texting.
-Did you check my cell phone?
Oh shit.
So you haven't thought about leaving Nadja?
-I don't know.
I'm going to stop playing around with Frida,
or whoever it is.
I'll make sure you don't screw Nadja.
-I won't, I promise.
Otherwise you're screwing me too.
You are my best friend
and I love you very much.
But if you screw Nadja,
I can't be your friend.
You know how important Nadja is to me.
She is my little sister.
I can't bear to see him betrayed
and I can't guarantee what I'll do if you betray him.
It's going to be a great evening.
-Sickly good.
You can borrow clothes for a leather party.
Got enough booze for tomorrow?
-Yes, dad will arrange it.
Quite a luxury.
Shall we go?
-Yes.
Is something wrong?
Can we talk?
What has happened?
Nothing special.
There's just no time now.
I don't understand what this is about...?
Are you ready?
-Yes.
READ
This is good.
-Chilean.
See you later.
-When are you coming home?
I don't know.
-Are you going to town?
I don't know. Could be.
Have a nice girls' night out.
Take care of yourself.
-Yes.
Frida, you want a shot?
Yes.
You are absolutely wonderful. Cheers.
-Cheers.
I've been watching you for a long time.
I don't know if you've noticed.
En.
-Yes, I am.
You're in a class of your own.
-Do you think so?
I would like to kiss you.
What?
What is it now?
-Shall we go?
I'm quite serious.
You're really pretty. Sorry, I...
You're handsome too.
-Do you think so?
Emil and Nadja are gone.
They were so terribly fucked.
That's not possible.
It sucks, we have a mattress room.
Shall we list it?
-Yes.
Cheers.
This is getting empty.
You and I are going to dance now.
-Yes, ma'am.
YOU'RE GORGEOUS
MATHIAS WAS HERE
Damn, how lovely you are.
Can you really not march
into my room like that?
Did you have a nice party?
-I want to be alone.
Mom's shoes?
-I borrowed them.
They're completely ruined.
May I be alone?
Is everything OK? Were you drunk?
-Go on.
What is it?
-Can you go? Go on.
Okay.
You know where we are if anything comes up.
Close the door.
I've never danced so much.
Frida.
Hello. Thanks for the last one.
Thank you to yourself.
Is everything OK?
-Yes, it is.
I'm just busy. See you later.
-I'll see you.
Not eating?
-I'm not hungry.
I've been feeling miserable for a couple of days too.
Do you know why Nadja is not in school?
En.
-No word from him since the party.
I'm glad you came. Dinner will be here in a minute.
-I'm not hungry.
Is something wrong?
-No.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm just tired.
Selma has not been seen for a long time.
Are you in a fight?
-I don't know.
Let me know if something is wrong.
You can tell us everything.
Everything.
I know. It's just a lot of things now.
Hello.
-Hey.
I'm sorry for all the things I said.
-It's okay.
How are you doing?
Did you have a good party?
-You didn't miss anything.
I heard that it was crazy there.
And you were with Mathias, right?
En. I mean...
-Or you were.
Okay. What about Emil?
I hardly saw him.
I'm sorry for what happened between us.
happened between us. I thought we could...
You're not the one who's lazy.
-What do you mean?
First Emil, who is with Nadja.
Then Mathias, whom Amalie has a crush on.
Who's next?
Pelle perhaps?
Frida, wait. Excuse me.
-There's no need to apologise.
I think that's who you really are.
Go find your new best friend Nadja.
No, you can't,
because you stabbed him in the back.
I'm so full of you.
Are you ready?
Did something happen at the party?
Was there a hiss?
-You'd like to know.
What about you?
-No one is pretty enough for me.
What about you and Frida?
-What about us?
You were in the mattress room for a long time.
-Yes.
No?
-Yes, we were.
Did you just sleep in a spoon?
Maybe you told him an innocent fairy tale.
-No, we did it.
Really or just in your imagination?
I guess so.
-Yes.
Oh, you had sex?
I don't think so.
You are unbelievable.
-Frida is a treat.
Indeed.
Does he want you,
or is he just playing with your feelings?
What are you explaining?
-Will you become a couple?
One thing at a time. Calm down.
If you want Frida, do something,
before she moves on to the next one.
Good advice. Thank you.
Did you notice that Emil is back?
-I noticed.
Leave him alone.
Okay. Your turn.
I want you to see how wonderful you are.
Mathias.
-Hey.
Did you delete the picture?
-Yes.
Did you show it to anyone?
-No.
Why did you take the picture?
-Because I think you're pretty.
Remove the image.
Hello.
Sorry I was so cold
and just left the party.
There was just a lot of everything...
-Don't think about me.
Don't run away now.
Nadja's case is a difficult one.
-I don't want to hear.
He has been really sad for his mother
since she died six months ago from cancer.
I don't want to cause more grief.
-Of course not.
I've been all over the place.
When I saw how you and Mathias
flirting at the party...
I got really jealous.
That's when I knew I had to.
Forced to what?
Leave it to Nadja.
But I didn't tell you,
that I have a crush on someone else.
Are you?
Okay. Who do you have a crush on?
Frida fucking Frimodt Hansen.
I'm crazy about you.
Emil, I'm crazy about you too.
I know we can't because of Nadja.
to be together right now.
But I hope so,
that at some point we can.
Yes.
Hello.
Are you all right, Nadja?
-Emil went ballistic on Friday.
I'm really sorry to hear that.
Life sucks.
-I'm going to get some food.
Will you be OK?
-Of course.
I asked Emil if he was in love
with someone else.
Okay.
Do you know something?
-Me?
I have suspected that
Frida and Emil have something going on.
I don't know anything about it.
Frida and I don't talk anymore.
You know something.
And I don't know.
-Selma...
Help me, please.
I think they have communicated.
You think?
-Yes.
Has Frida shown you any messages?
We need access to
his messages.
You probably know Frida's password.
-I know, but we can't do that.
Frida doesn't notice.
No.
If you help me,
I can help you.
In relation to what?
-Bell.
The clown?
-Yes. It's pretty obvious.
What do you mean?
-That you like him.
Pelle said to me,
he thinks you're really pretty.
No. Really?
Let's use my mobile phone.
Here.
I knew it. They're together.
With whom else
Frida has written?
Mathiaksen.
Like what?
Give it to me.
Hello. Bun, please.
FUCKGIRL OF THE YEAR!
Yes.
I thought you were with Nadja.
That you went home together.
That all you wanted from me was sex.
Do you think that's what I am?
I thought you were different too.
Emil.
Hello.
Selma, I'm having a party tonight. You can come, can't you?
-I need to talk to you.
What is this all about? The picture...
-Yes. It's ridiculous.
What were you thinking?
-I didn't do it.
You took a picture of Frida's profile.
-I haven't done anything.
Mathias also has the picture,
Maybe he shared it with someone.
Pelle will manage the account.
I'm sure you know the password.
Selma. Many people know the password.
Anyone could have done it.
Remove the image.
-I have nothing to do with the picture.
Okay?
Okay. Can you write the name of the author?
Nadja, wait a minute.
-What now?
I want to talk to you.
I understand that there are
a revealing picture of a student.
Have you heard of it or seen it?
They all are.
-Right.
It is illegal to share
sexual or explicit images.
What does it have to do with me?
Suppose you had something
to do with the publication of the photo -
you must remove it immediately.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't care.
I don't think so.
I don't think you care at all.
I think you posted a picture,
because you're upset.
Shall we have a chat?
Sweetheart. Come here.
About.
Mathias?
-You shouldn't come here now.
I know I'm not welcome.
-I'd like to kick your ass.
I want to talk to Mathias.
What have you gone to do?
-I didn't publish the picture.
Anyone can have a password.
-Delete photo.
I have done nothing.
Just the fact that you took the picture,
tells me what a jerk you are.
You should have taken a picture yourself.
What are you freaking out about?
-What the hell are you freaking out about?
All this shit is your fault.
-Our fault? It's your fault.
You could have said it directly,
that you have a crush on Frida.
Games with Pelle, Nadja and me
my feelings. Fuck you, Emil.
I did not publish the picture.
What do you think of me?
Thank you.
Hello.
-Hey.
I'm really sorry,
that I took that picture.
I deleted it when you told me to.
I didn't publish it.
If you need anything, a friend, for example,
I'm here.
Thank you.
-I just want to say that...
I think you are absolutely wonderful.
If I had known that you and Emil
were in love, I wouldn't have...
Emil is not in love with me.
Yes, it is. Frida.
He really is.
I have to say one thing.
I know very well,
it's all very complicated now.
But it was all because of that,
I'm really into you.
I had a crush on you too.
-But?
What else? Was that it?
Does it all make no difference now?
-No, but everything is ruined.
Everything is in pieces.
Before there was no but now there is.
Hello.
Isn't he in the picture?
-Yes.
Nadja published the picture.
What? Are you sure?
I am.
We visited your Instagram account
to read your posts.
Why?
Nadja got me into it.
I had no idea there would be that picture.
I understand if you don't want to talk anymore
to me, but I really regret what I did.
I don't understand how you could do that.
I understand very well,
if you can't forgive.
It's difficult, though.
But...
But?
I've done all kinds of shit myself.
So...
Maybe one day.
-But one day.
Okay, see you in the morning.
I'm here for the last day.
After the autumn break, I'm changing high schools.
Switching?
-Yes.
Frida,
I'm really sorry about everything.
So do I.
-Excuse me.
See you later.
-I'll see you.
Hello.
Are you still seeing each other?
No, that's the end.
-All of it?
Completely.
-If so, I can forgive you.
Are you serious?
-I've missed you.
Likewise.
Shall we play?
Will you come tonight?
-Tietty.
No way!
Hi, Jette.
-Hi, Frida.
Is the task already completed?
-No.
I just came to say that it's not going to be finished.
After the autumn break, I'm changing high schools,
so there's no point in doing an assignment.
Thank you for everything, though.
-Frida, come here.
Now it feels difficult,
but don't forget how amazing you are.
Internalize the fact that you are gorgeous.
I don't feel very great.
-You are, though.
If someone makes a mistake about your relationship,
show them who you really are.
It's no more complicated than that.
It's just maths.
Sorry to interrupt.
Can I borrow your mike?
Now?
-He's had enough attention already.
I will be brief.
-All right.
Thank you.
Hello.
Most of you probably know me from years ago
the year girl, but my name is Frida.
I know,
that I have hurt some of you.
I know I've made a mess of things.
I'm really sorry about that.
But is it fair to label me
as fuck girl of the year just because...
that I was with a boy,
who took a picture of me...
that you decided to share?
I don't think it is.
But you're a real fuck girl.
Yes.
Some things really are real, Pelle.
That's what one of you has taught me.
When we are together,
there's something real.
I can still feel it,
even though I'm standing here alone.
I am happy,
that I got to experience something so real.
That's hard to find.
That's all I have. Thank you.
It's not real.
-Who does he think he is?
I'm a real fuck girl too.
So do I.
Likewise.
I'm a fuck girl too.
Silence, please.
Thank you.
I want to stress that in this school
no one is called names like that.
Academic year for all year groups
has got off to a good start.
I want to tell you,
what happens after the autumn holidays.
Frida!
Excuse me.
Transcript: Pivi Ahlqvist