["Big Surprise" playing]
♪ Yo yo yo, yo yo yo Yo yo ♪
♪ Yo yo yo, yo yo yo Yo ♪
♪ Won't you come be my lover?♪
[man laughing]
[men speaking in foreign language]
♪ Yo yo yo, yo yo yo Yo yo ♪
♪ Yo yo yo, yo yo yo Yo ♪
♪ I can even show you What you want♪
♪ Don't you want To find out? ♪
♪ There's going to be ♪
♪ Big surprise ♪
♪ Yo yo yo, yo yo yo Yo yo♪
♪ Yo yo yo, yo yo yo Yo♪
♪ Open your eyes Tell me what do you see ♪
[Simon] I guess this is it, huh?
Where are we?
Where's the closest town?
Huh? Hey!
Hey, wait a minute, you've got my case!
♪ There's going to be ♪
♪ Big surprise ♪
[sighing]
Ah, shit.
♪ There's going to be ♪
[indistinct conversation]
♪ Big surprise ♪
♪ I love you, I love you ♪
♪ You don't want to find out ♪
♪ And I love you, I love you ♪
♪ Looking for my... ♪
♪ There's going to be ♪
♪ Big surprise ♪
[sighs]
[indistinct chatter]
[pop music playing on speakers]
[tires screeching]
[women laughing]
Hi.
[indistinct conversations]
[music continues playing on speakers]
I'm just looking for a beer, that's all I want. [grunts]
[indistinct conversations]
[indistinct chatter]
Can I get a beer, please.
Make that two, will you?
Now this girlfriend of mine...
is jealous because I'm now sleeping with my wife!
[indistinct conversation]
[Simon] Well, yeah, it's a long story...
Then when the rebels took over,
they cut all lines of communication.
I couldn't even phone my newspaper.
I lost my camera, my passport.
Most of my money.
The only thing I could do was grab a few things and head for the border.
You know, you're the first person in three days
I've been able to communicate with.
By the way, how far is town from here?
I'd like to phone my editor
to get him to cable me some more money.
There is no town.
[Simon] Pow!
It's this bar and a dirt airstrip.
[both chuckles]
This bar caters for the locals,
and an occasional hunting trip like ours.
There is a phone, though.
Oh, great!
But it hasn't worked in the month I've been here.
Oh, shit!
Well...
That's me.
Mr. Broke, cheers!
Cheers.
Look... the people I'm here with...
they're planning to fly out in a week or so,
I'll talk them, I'm sure we can help you.
Oh, God, that's great.
I appreciate it.
-Come with me. -All right.
Can you just watch my stuff?
Sure.
[Bob] I always found the mercury tip would stop anything in its tracks.
[Eric] Yeah, but you gotta' hit it first
[laughter]
Hello, Yvonne, you got something to drink?
[Yvonne] Yes, thanks, Bob.
I'd like you to meet Simon Rush.
-Bob Jenkins. -[Simon] Hi.
Hi, hello.
You wanna join us?
-Yeah, I'd love to. -Here.
Do you want to grab a seat?
[indistinct conversations]
You see, these are my hunting partners,
that's, uh Alex,
that's Jay,
and this is, uh, Eric Du Pont.
The last of the great white hunters.
So, you're American. Where you from?
Originally from California, but I've relocated to New York.
Great. Alex and I are from Berkeley.
Small world, eh?
[chuckles] Yeah, very.
Short glass. Ah. Hilton!
Drinks all around.
Yes, sir.
So, uh, what brings you to paradise?
[Yvonne] Simon's a correspondent for an American news network.
He's just been over the border reporting on the war.
Barely escaped alive.
Really? Is it that bad?
Well, the border areas are now totally in the hands of the rebels.
Who's supplying the rebel forces with arms?
Is the Soviet Union involved?
Hey, Jason, why don't you take the war games shit a give it a rest.
You think the Russians are everywhere.
Hell, yeah. Those Commies never let up.
You can't afford to relax. You ask Simon.
Are the superpowers involved?
Yeah, indirectly, as usual.
[Jason] What did I tell you?
Man, we are going to kick their asses all the way back to Siberia.
Just wait and see.
We are going to win, right? I mean, don't we always?
Thank you.
Simon lost everything when he left the capital.
I was hoping you guys could help me out.
I mean my paper would gladly pay you back once I got home.
Well, we'd be glad to have you.
Maybe you could do a spot of hunting, eh?
Great, thanks a lot.
Ah, it's our pleasure.
Here... mud in your eye!
[Simon] He says...
"I'm shot."
[laughing]
Just like that, he says, "I'm shot."
[all laughing]
We looked around at each other,
and we just started cracking up.
And, well, Lifeson was laughing with us, too...
when they carried him away.
I mean, here you are...
playing a game of poker with your buddies...
and you get shot!
And you get shot right in the ass...
in some nowhere dust hole in Africa.
Hilton, let's have another one of these.
[clacking]
[screams]
[laughter]
[gun clicking]
[Simon] What are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
[groans]
[laughter in distance]
[laughing] Right!
Hey, watch out, here he comes.
The Omega marking gun.
It shoots a ten millimeter paint pellet.
Accurately up to about, oh...
-One hundred fifty yards. -[firing]
Gotcha! [laughing]
Yeah, it's used extensively in your country for marking animals.
[laughs]
And, uh... Also, it's used for tactical war games.
Yeah, I brought a few of these along,
I thought we might have some fun with them, you know.
Oh!
You didn't find my little joke too disturbing?
No, no problem.
Ah.
Just remind me not to turn my back on you.
[chuckles nervously]
Hey, Eric, why don't you wake Yvonne up, eh?
We'll have some breakfast.
I'll get it.
Yeah, you, uh...
[paint gun cocking]
You must be hungry, Mr. Rush.
[firing]
Yeah, I'm starving.
Thanks, Yvonne, that was great.
Glad you liked it. We live well in the wild.
Yvonne, can we have some more coffee, please?
[Simon] Come on, I'll give you a hand.
Mr. Rush and I have some business to discuss.
-We do? -Oh, yeah.
Well...
Coffee!
Now, uh, Mr. Rush...
Look, if this is about the money
I told you my paper will cover all my expenses, all right?
Everything's about money.
But you're welcome to stay here as a guest.
As I understand it, you, uh... You got no money,
you... got no passport, no visa.
And no way of contacting your office, am I right?
Yeah, you're right.
Now, as I said, you're welcome to stay here as a guest
and I'll try... and pull some strings
for you to fly out with us when we leave, is that acceptable?
Oh, yeah, that's perfect, thank you.
No, it's our pleasure.
We've got a proposition we'd like to make you.
You know, we got a... [chuckles]
An idea for a little entertainment, and we'd like your help.
Yeah!
Might even be a story in it.
To make up for your untimely departure from the war zone.
[Jason] Simon...
Look, we're all pretty pissed off with this hunting shit.
Kind of soft targets, you know.
Kinda like Eric.
Hey, only kidding. Joke!
Yeah, right, after a while, dumb animals are no fun.
Like playing Pac-Man after flying an F-16 simulator.
What we're saying is that hunting is no longer a challenge for us.
We're looking for something
with a little bit more... subtlety.
Well I, uh...
I don't understand what that has to do with me.
We want to hunt you.
[chuckles] What?
With these.
Ouch!
Fuck, give me a break, man. I'm trying to take a shit here, man.
-[laughing] Gotcha, you asshole. -Asshole?
Man, I'll give you another asshole between your eyes.
Hi Yvonne!
Hey, Jay, kiss my microchip.
Shit.
[squawking]
We'll give you food and water and an ample supply of pellets.
And a 15 minute start.
Now, the idea here is to get a clean body shot for a kill.
So, we hunt you, and you hunt us.
It's the ultimate, man on man.
Of course you don't have to play.
As Bob pointed out, you may find good material for a story.
And even if you don't, well,
I think, you must admit that being hunted has a certain appeal.
A real challenge, eh?
Yeah, four against one.
A real challenge.
So, are we going to play or what?
[paint gun fires]
You try, Mr. Rush. There you go.
How accurate are these things?
Well, fucking awful, aren't they?
[both chuckles]
No.
[laughing]
[clears throat]
[gasps]
[laughing]
Fucking hell.
Looks like you got yourself a target, boys.
All right, then. We start tomorrow morning at eight o'clock.
Fires a little high and to the right.
Coffee?
Tea, I think.
I promised you a new asshole, and I always deliver.
You're such a geek you'd probably miss and shoot yourself.
[laughing]
You know, Alex, you're so cool, man.
If I stay here, I'll freeze up.
Fuck you, Jason.
Not me, man.
Her.
What are you hot for?
Little Miss Iceberg?
What, are you kidding? I'd love a piece of that ass.
You'd need to take Tom Cruise along just to get close to her.
Screw you, man. A lot of women find me attractive.
They like me for my mind.
Yeah, right.
Like the time back in college when you took Lisa Pinelli
back to your room to show her your RAM pack?
You had a black eye for a week.
Mr. Sex Appeal, right.
Fuck you!
You'd have more chance with me than with her.
Oh, yeah?
Don't be so sure.
Oh, I'm sure.
[Eric chuckles] So, the Swedish shopkeeper says to the man,
"Ball or aerosol?"
And the man says, "No, I want it for under my arms."
Well, um, I think I've said enough.
I think after that last joke, you've said too much.
[chuckles]
Well, we've got a long day tomorrow.
So, I'll wish you both a pleasant good evening.
Good night.
He's a good man.
He is.
I love him dearly.
[sighing]
How long have, uh, Bob and Eric known each other?
They were in the army together.
With my father.
Your father?
He died in '62.
I'm sorry.
I never knew him. I was born three months after he died.
And Bob and Eric?
They've always been Uncle Bob and Uncle Eric.
They were soldiers together with my father in the army.
They were there when he died.
And so they've always looked after Mum and me.
So, when Mum died, naturally I went to work for Bob.
-I, uh... -Oh, it's okay.
They're happy, they're together again.
Life goes on.
And you?
Me?
With Bob.
Bob's a good man. Really, he is.
He's... He's just been under a little pressure lately.
I know he can be pushy and temperamental and...
But he's a good man. Really.
He is. He's...
[sighing] He's Uncle Bob.
Well... [clears throat] it's getting late.
-I think we should turn in. -Yes.
All right.
Good night, Simon.
Good night.
-[footsteps] -[wolf howling]
Hello, Jason.
What?
I was kind of hoping we might...
toast some marshmallows?
[Yvonne chuckles]
I don't think so.
It's been a long day.
[mimicking violin] I noticed.
Good night, Jason.
We begin in one hour.
Have fun.
I will.
It's only a game.
It's gonna be fun.
Besides, these guys have bitten off more than they can chew.
Just be careful.
You got it.
Hey, Rush, you'll need these.
Food and water in the bag.
Put the camo on, and we start soon.
-Thanks, Alex. -No problem. I'll see you.
Not if I see you first, pilgrim.
Bang bang, you're dead.
[paint gun firing]
[Jason] That's bloody marvelous.
I think I'm gonna join Mr. Rush.
Gentlemen.
Hello, Mr. Rush.
Come here, I've got something for you.
-[Simon] Really? -[Bob] Yeah.
Here, take these. They might be good for your nerves.
Why thank you... Mr. Jenkins.
Are we all ready then?
Right.
Okay, Mr. Rush. You have 15 minutes.
Off you go.
Good luck.
[paint gun firing]
Oh, bloody good shot, Eric. Bloody good, yeah.
[Simon grunts]
Right.
Gentlemen.
Shall we?
I'll take point. Let's go.
[indistinct conversations]
Jenkins.
There's no way he'd come up here.
Why don't you give your mouth a chance, pinhead?
Hey, Bob!
What do you think he's going to do now?
I think you guys should shut up and keep your eyes open.
No need to get so tense, Bob. It's only a game.
It was never a fucking game!
Keep an eye open on the trees.
Now... let's see who hunts who.
[laughter]
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
Too bad, Eric. We'll see you back at the camp, hey?
Okay, lads, good hunting.
Get ready to move out.
Go!
Do either of you see the bastard?
I can't see shit to spit at, man.
Same here.
[Bob] All right. Alex, go right.
Jason, cut left.
Head out about 100 yards and then over the hill.
I'm going to lay down covering fire
and I'm gonna follow you.
Well, move it, come on!
[chuckling] Nice try, buddy boy!
I'll see you around!
[inaudible]
Shit!
Smart son of a bitch, huh?
All right, don't write a book about it!
He's gone over the ridge. Come on, after him!
-[paint gun firing] -Shit!
-[Simon] I thought you'd wanna get your money's worth, pal! -Shit!
All right. You two go around the ridge. You go down there.
I'm gonna go over the top. I'm gonna try and flush him out.
We'll meet at the plane crash.
If you hear shooting, you make for the sound. Now move out!
Sounds good to me.
If Bob said, "Napalm the guy," you'd think it was okay.
Fuck, yeah.
Keep your eyes open. The next time, it'll be Rush painting your ass blue.
I wonder what Bruce would advise.
That computer of yours would tell us to nuke the fucker.
[chuckling] Agent Orange, huh?
The great American way!
Hey, what do you say we like, uh, you know, just...
Hey, Jay.
Don't try to walk, talk, and think all at the same time.
Your brain can't handle that kind of input.
Erase yourself, dip shit.
Yeah, I reckon we pick up the pace a little,
try and beat the man back to the wreck.
Yeah, just don't forget that Rush is still out there.
Oh, he got lucky with Eric.
But we'll nail him and be home before dark.
[Jason] Fuckin' A, bro.
[footsteps]
[Bob] So, nothing?
[Alex] Not a sign.
My guess, he's high-tailing into the bush.
Don't be so sure.
Shit.
He's been making fools out of us the whole fucking day.
I mean, I don't know who's hunting who anymore.
[heavy thud]
Ha-ha, buddy boy!
I could have shot any one of you!
I thought I'd give you your money's worth, pal!
-[paint gun firing] -Oh!
Shit!
Ha-ha, Bobby!
I'll let you boys off this time.
I'll catch you later, guys.
Shit!
I've had it with this clown. Here.
[clicking]
You can't be serious, man. We can't go after this guy for real.
It's murder!
I don't see any problem.
You came out here to hunt, I'm saying let's hunt.
Yeah, but, Bob, we're talking about a fucking human being here,
not an animal.
What he is, is a sly bastard
whose been making fools out of us for the entire fucking day!
Yeah, but that's no reason to kill a guy.
Why not?
-I mean, who'd know? -We'd know!
So?
-What about the authorities? -What about them?
Rush crossed the border illegally.
I'm saying let's hunt him, not fuck around with these pop guns!
It's not right!
Right? Out here?
We decide what's right.
Yeah, but what are we gonna tell Yvonne and Eric?
Well...
We'll say he shot at us.
We had to shoot back.
You know, I'll say one of my guns is missing.
So what'll it be, lads?
All right.
[sighing]
Follow the river.
[gunshot]
It's not like you to miss.
Let him run a little.
See if he likes it.
Shit.
[Bob chuckling]
He's headed for higher ground.
Trying to stay out of our way.
What if he decides to cut out?
Where to?
The Leopard Lounge is 40 miles from here.
The nearest town is twice as much. No, no.
No, no. He's going nowhere.
Look. You and Jay go back to the camp. Follow the river.
I'll try and flush him out.
You tell Yvonne and Eric what I told you.
And then keep quiet.
I'll deal with them later.
All right, lads, off you go.
All right, Mr. Rush.
It's you and me now.
We're in deep shit, Alex. Bob's lost it.
Tell me about it.
Look, I'm going to tell Eric.
You fucking crazy?
How the hell else are we going to stop this?
You cross him, he'll kill you. You saw his eyes.
Yeah, but he's gonna do Rush.
Rather him than us.
Without Bob, the Pentagon deal is right down the toilet.
I don't give a fuck about the deal, man. This is first-degree murder.
Look. Just play along.
When he calms down...
we'll get him to call off this shit.
Then...
All right. I'll play along, okay?
But I'm not gonna shoot to kill for nobody.
Agreed.
We'll get into camp.
Just play it cool.
Yeah.
Just like the man told us, huh?
[gunshot]
[grunts, panting]
Why the hell did I get into this shit?
Should have stayed in the fucking war zone.
[Bob] Are you having fun, Mr. Rush?
What the hell are you doing, Jenkins?
[chuckles]
Well, I'm playing the game, eh, as agreed.
[Simon] You crazy son of a bitch, this is no game.
That depends on how you look at it, eh?
Yeah, real funny, you bastard.
-Why, huh? -Why not?
I'll come looking for you in the morning.
[in American accent] I'll come a-looking for you, you hear?
[laughs]
Hey, Jenkins!
-Jenkins! -[Jenkins laughing]
A game.
That piece of shit.
[Yvonne] I still say this is absurd.
Simon's no killer.
[Eric] Yvonne's right,
and, besides, he had no gun.
I must say, I don't understand this.
I told you...
Bob thinks Rush might have stolen one of his guns.
He said nothing to me.
I don't know.
I... guess he doesn't want you to worry.
This is all crazy.
-That's exactly what it is. -Bob, you scared me.
You all right, old son?
[scoffs] Yeah, I'm fine.
No thanks to our friend out there.
Well, you've, uh...
heard about the turn of events, have you?
Yes, I must say it baffles me.
Yeah.
He fired at me when I was up at the ridge.
I fired back...
I think I, uh, scared him off...
into the bush.
Yeah.
Crazy bastard, isn't he?
Is that whiskey?
-Yeah. -Yeah, cheers.
Mmm.
Yeah, well, I...
I think I'll go wash up.
[dogs barking in distance]
[Alex] I'm taking my pump action when we go out tomorrow.
No sense in screwing around.
[Eric] Well, I think we should head for the bar
and contact the authorities.
[Alex] No need for that, we can handle it.
[Eric] But somebody may get hurt.
[Alex] No problem.
[Alex] I know who's going to get hurt.
Not one of us.
[Jason] Alex, will you pass me that whiskey, please?
[Yvonne] Yeah, Eric's right, we should go to the authorities.
No police.
Bob... please.
[groans]
I suggest we all turn in.
We have a busy day tomorrow.
Alex, you take the first watch.
I'll do the last one.
Then you two can split the rest.
Good night.
[Alex] What the fuck's the matter with you?
You lost your tongue?
You really would shoot him, wouldn't you?
Don't be an idiot, Jason,
I'm doing it to get Jenkins off our backs.
Now, go get some sleep.
Everything is gonna be all right.
[sighs] Well...
I suppose I should get this shit over with.
[blowing]
[Eric] Bob... do you mind?
[Bob] No, come in.
-Sit down. -[Eric] Yeah.
-You want a drink? -Yes. Thanks, old son.
-Here, cheers. -Cheers.
Hmm.
Tents, campfire...
it's like old times.
[Bob] Hmm.
Khaki gods, eh?
-We were the best. -[gun cocks]
Ah, that's a long time ago.
A lot of water's flown under the bridge since then.
We've come a long way, though.
This deal will make us.
Oh, we've come far.
Too far to destroy it all.
Bob... we should go for help.
Bob, this Rush business is turning...
Eric.
He's mine.
Mine!
Don't get in my way!
[Simon] Eric. Give me the gun.
Give me the gun.
Slowly.
-What the hell do you think-- -Shut up.
Shut up and let me think.
Don't you think you should have done that
before you started shooting today?
Before I started shooting?
Eric, I just held you up with this splat gun.
Do you really think I started this thing?
Well, I'd like to believe you, but...
[both grunt]
-[thuds] -[Eric grunts]
That was stupid, man.
That was fucking stupid.
Hey, Yvonne?
Why, Simon? Why?
Listen to me. I didn't do anything.
One minute I'm in the bush, playing this game,
and the next, bullets are whizzing past me.
But why?
Why should they start shooting for real?
I don't know, I can't figure it out.
All I know is that I've got to get the hell out of here.
I'm gonna take the Land Rover.
You can't.
Bob removed the rotor arm.
Oh, shit.
All right.
Then I'm just gonna hide out until you guys leave.
I don't want to fight, not like this.
I want to come with you.
-No, no way. -Please, Simon.
-Uh-uh. -Bob's been drinking heavily, and...
He hit me tonight.
All right.
Take this bag...
and keep your gun.
-Let's go. -What about the guard? He's--
No, I took care of him on the way in.
I wanted to leave Bob a little message,
so that he'd know I was here.
Let's get out of this place.
[Simon] I found this place just before sundown.
-Whoa! -[crashing]
Whoa, be careful.
Other than loose rocks, I think it's pretty safe.
There's an overhang down here
that should conceal the light and the smoke from the fire.
So we'll just hole up here until they move out.
I hope we don't sleep walk.
[chuckles] So do I.
And when we got divorced...
she won custody of the kid.
[grunts] There wasn't much left for me in New York, so, uh...
I took the overseas assignment and I've war hopped ever since.
I send my ex-wife money for our daughter, but, uh, well...
She seems to like it that way.
And you?
When there's a war going on...
and you're face down in the dirt...
trying to keep your head on its shoulders...
you tend not to think of your wife's lover...
driving your little girl to school.
I'm glad I came with you.
Bob really scares me.
And I don't?
No.
Good morning.
-It's beautiful country. -Hmm.
It certainly is.
[Alex] Take a look at this.
[Jason] I think I'm gonna be sick.
[Bob] Bastard.
Bastard!
[Simon clears throat]
What are you looking at, Mr. Rush?
This really is beautiful country.
[men grunting]
Put him on his bed, we'll bury him tonight.
Hey, where's Yvonne?
Well, she's not in her tent, so she's with Rush, right?
Why'd she go with Rush? He killed Eric, man.
They were getting pretty cute.
What are we gonna do, Bob? Eric's dead!
Don't be a dick all your life.
Get your stuff together, we move now!
[Simon] Hopefully, they'll take the hint
and get the hell out of here.
The way I ran rings around those guys yesterday,
it shouldn't be too difficult to persuade them to give it up.
And then you and I...
will live happily ever after.
I hope to God you're right.
Bob can be stubborn when he wants to.
Hey...
I'm sure it'll be okay.
Look, I'm gonna head out to camp
and see what they're doing.
I'll be back in a minute.
Mmm. Good stuff.
I'll improve, I promise.
Bye.
Hey.
Be careful.
And ruin a great track record?
I'll see you soon.
[chuckles]
What's that?
What do you think it is?
No fucking around with you, right?
Oh, no.
I thought I'd give Mr. Rush some special treatment.
You're right, let's get him.
All right, we'll split up.
I'm gonna go down to the river near where we saw him yesterday.
I want you to go south, below the ridge,
and you to go north, above it.
Right!
Oh, and, lads...
no more games.
You shoot to kill.
[birds cawing in distance]
[screaming]
I've got you, you mother...
Hey, you don't have to do this, man.
Shut your mouth!
I wouldn't let you go,
not after what you did to Eric.
-What? What are you talking about? -Shut up!
[grunting]
[both grunting]
[groans] My back!
[grunts]
[Alex] Jason.
Jason. [panting]
-It's Rush! -[gunshot]
Alex! Jesus!
[screams] Ah! Oh, God. Alex!
Don't die, man! Just fight it, man!
-[Alex groans] -Let me get help.
Don't talk. Don't talk. Just fight it, man!
Stay alive, Alex.
Just stay alive, I need you, man.
Bob? Bob!
What happened? I heard shots.
Rush shot him in the back, man.
Oh, my God, he's dead!
[crying]
My God, what happened?
[groans] I tripped on the way down here.
What happened?
Alex and I had a little disagreement.
Disagreement? Where are they?
[sighs] Come on, Vonnie,
I just want to get this cleaned up.
[sighs]
Okay, let's get you down to the river.
All right.
[inaudible]
[sobbing]
[Bob] We commit their bodies to the ground.
Ashes to ashes...
dust to dust.
[clears throat]
Come on, son.
[Bob] Getting late.
Wait.
Look.
Let's get that motherfucker.
Now, wait, wait, wait.
We'll take him in the morning.
-Let him feel safe. -No, Bob. Come on!
[grunts]
Take it easy.
Okay.
[sighs]
In the morning, Rush.
[Jason] Hey, buddy.
[crying] Oh, man.
What can I say?
How am I gonna make it without you, Alex?
I'm going to get him, Alex.
Rush is gonna pay!
I promise you that if it's the last thing I do.
I promise you, man.
I promise!
[Bob] Here.
You're too drunk to stand guard.
-Go to bed. -Bob, I...
Go to bed!
Well, Mr. Rush, here's to you.
-[gun cocks] -Rush?
It's me, Bob.
Vonnie...
where have you been?
I've been worried about you.
That would be a first in a long time.
Yeah, that's not fair.
-What happened to us? -You happened!
You don't care about anyone anymore, Bob.
You just walk over everyone.
-Look-- -That's far enough!
Yvonne...
Call off this crazy game, Bob.
I don't know why you're doing it.
Call it off before somebody gets hurt.
It's too late for that.
Alex and Eric are dead.
Your friend killed them.
Uncle Eric?
He's dead, Yvonne.
Dead!
Now... I don't know why Rush started this...
but I intend to finish it.
-Oh, Yvonne-- -Stay where you are!
I've got to... I've got to think.
I can't believe you!
Vonnie!
I buried them today!
I'll show you their bloody graves!
Look...
Rush is a sick man!
We can take him alive if you help us.
We can...
We can get him to medical care.
But I can't do it without you.
What can I do?
That's my girl.
Empty his gun.
We'll come for you in the morning.
We know where you are.
You do?
Yes.
You won't hurt him, Bob?
No.
Please.
I've got to think.
I'll talk to Simon.
No, don't do that, he's a nutter!
He'll hurt you.
I'll, uh, see you in the morning, then.
They're on the other side of those rocks.
Now, go around that way and be quiet.
Now, wait for me to fire.
At Yvonne?
I don't know.
What do you think?
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[groans]
-Simon-- -Shh!
-Is it Bob? -It's not the Easter bunny, honey.
Stay here, I'll be back in a minute.
No, wait! We should talk to him, try and reason with him.
Yvonne, the man has a machine gun with my name on it.
I'm not about to ask the son of a bitch to dance.
-Simon... -What?
I love you.
[grunts]
-Where's Jenkins? -Fuck you!
-[sighs] Jason... -[groans]
I'll find him myself.
[groans]
[gun clicks]
At last, Mr. Rush...
we meet again.
I see Yvonne did her job well.
What?
She and I, uh...
She and I came to a little agreement last night.
-Yvonne? -Yeah.
I imagined to persuade her that you are a violent man in need of help.
Listen, I don't understand. I, uh...
No, of course you don't.
[cocks gun]
Goodbye, Mr. Rush!
Bob! You said you wouldn't hurt him!
[chuckles] Hello, Vonnie.
Here, put the gun down before someone gets hurt.
Yvonne, come on, huh?
[sighs]
-I said put the gun down! -[gasps]
[Yvonne] Bob, you said you wouldn't!
[stuttering] Why are you doing this?
Why am I doing this?
You killed my partners!
-What? -I didn't kill anybody!
Relax, Mr. Rush.
I know you didn't.
How could you?
What?
I did.
[stutters] Wait a minute, who's dead?
Eric and Alex are dead, Simon.
You killed Alex?
And Uncle Eric?
Why?
Well, I had to.
It's all a question of mathematics.
It's the defense contract.
Oh, very good, Mr. Rush.
You see, with those guys dead,
he stands to make a fortune off that contract.
[Yvonne] You killed them!
You killed Uncle Eric for money?
It's not just money, Yvonne.
It's like he says, it's a bloody fortune.
[grunts] You see, I planned a little...
hunting accident.
You know, some sort of crash...
[chuckles]
A very, uh, distraught Yvonne and I
would return to civilization grieving,
grieving... for lost friends.
But then you came along
and offered me a wonderful alternative.
[chuckles]
Yeah, of course, you had to go and spoil it all.
Didn't you, darling?
By falling for Simon here.
Oh, well... that's history.
Now I'll have to take that idiot Jason
back with me to corroborate my story.
He will, of course, meet with a little accident.
Problem solved.
That's enough for now.
So, Mr. Rush...
Yeah, I think I can honestly say it's been, uh...
[smacks lips] It's been fun.
-[gunshots] -[Yvonne grunts]
[Simon screaming]
Simon!
Sorry, Yvonne, but I've got to rush!
[Yvonne screaming]
-[water splashing] -Mmm.
Now... where is that idiot?
[in sing-song voice] ♪ Oh, Jason! ♪
[chuckles]
[footsteps approaching]
-Good morning, Mr. Jenkins. -Good morning.
-Your newspaper, sir. -Thank you, Smyth.
Hello, Bob.
Hiya, Bobby boy.
Listen, I want to talk to you about this neat idea
I've got for a new game.
Hold on.
["Prey For The Hunter" playing]
[engine revving]
♪ Don't be la-looking ♪
♪ For an early break ♪
♪ I know I will find you ♪
♪ Somewhere Somewhere ♪
♪ To be safe ♪
♪ You gotta run ♪
♪ Or be prey ♪
♪ Prey for the hunter ♪
♪ Looking for adventure ♪
♪ Somewhere on the road ♪
♪ This is not game we playin' ♪
♪ 'Cause I know ♪
♪ I know this is The end of the road ♪
♪ You gotta run ♪
♪ Or be prey ♪
♪ Prey for the hunter ♪
♪ You gotta run ♪
♪ Or be prey ♪
♪ Prey for the hunter ♪
♪ You gotta run ♪