Official Selection in competition 66th Venice Film Festival
Far Sun Film Co Ltd. Hong Kong and
Peony5 Film Co Ltd. Taiwan
Present
PRINCE OF TEARS
National Athem. Please rise.
These visuals are
from the only 1 950's surviving copy of
the Republic of China's National Anthem
which was screened in every cinema
before every film in Taiwan.
The audio is a medley of sound
from that era including
speeches by Generalismo Chiang Kai Shek,
news broadcasts,
radio commercials and talk shows.
After the 1 949 revolution in China,
Chiang Kai Shek took his army and people
from Mainland China to Taiwan
with the dream that one day they would
defeat the Communists and return home.
The government proceeded to imposed
martial law on the island.
But for the children of the Mainlanders,
life remained a paradise.
Please sit
Taiwan 1954
At that time,
"Communist" is the other name for Terror.
Crystal Rock Primary School,
near an air force base in Central Taiwan
What are you looking at?
That is my father's jet.
No, that's my father's jet.
My dad said your dad is just a co-pilot.
My father said,
your dad is a drunkard.
Forget it, our dads are small potatoes.
Rainbow's father is the General.
He is the The Godfather.
That is my father's jet.
No, that is my father's jet.
Where is it?
The prince...
dropped his first tear.
He felt he didn't know his people.
Rainbow, what are you reading?
"Prince of Tears"
Starring : Fan Chih-Wei Terri Kwan
Joseph Chang
Zhu Xuan
Kenneth Tsang Chiao Chiao
Kao Jie Li Lie Lin Yeo-Wei
Yan Xin-Rou Cai Pei-Han
Lee Bo-Shiuan
Cinematographer Chin Ting-Chang
Sound Tu Du-Che Music Yu Yat-Yiu
Theme Song George Lam
Art Director Yonfan
Editors Kong Chi-Leung Derek Hui
Line Producer Wade Yao Aileen Li
Producer Fruit Chan
Written & Directed by Yonfan
The story begins
The handsome prince and his princess...
They finally live happily ever after.
They bring their lovely daughters
to this beautiful island named Formosa.
They intended to build a happy family,
seeking a fairy...
tale-like life,
However...
"Story of the children"
"Master Qiu"
This statue David is...
by a very famous ltalian artist.
When we draw this picture,
other than his handsome face,
you must notice his curly hair, too.
I think Mr.Qiu looks better than David.
Rainbow Liu,
what are you laughing at?
Nothing
She said you more handsome than David.
Sun Xiao-Zhou
Show me your drawing.
This is the statue of David in her mind.
Drawing is important to express oneself.
It doesn't have to be real nor unreal.
Drawing is to express our thinking.
To liberate our thoughts on paper
and by colors.
Do you get it?
Yes.
Ok, class is finished.
When do you think...
you can return home?
I don't know.
I have been here for many years.
How is your home town?
I hope we can return soon.
How is your novel coming along?
So-so; I haven't found the heroine.
- Mr. Qiu... - Hi, come in.
Come on, sit on the bed.
What are you going to tell me?
Sir, I want to marry you when I grow up.
Silly kid, don't say that.
I am old enough to be your father
you're like my father.
Since I can't marry my father,
I want to marry you.
Do you also want to marry me?
I don't want to marry you.
Sir, where are you going to?
I am going to the cliff to paint.
I want to go too.
Ok, but you have to tell your family.
I can just tell my sister before I go.
Sir...
It's so windy, how can we draw here?
If you stay calm, you can draw anywhere.
It's so beautiful here,
why hasn't anyone taken me before?
This is a restricted zone,
no one is allowed to come here.
But why can we come here today?
Because...we are artists.
Wow, artists are great!
That's right.
Zhou, look!
How beautiful is the ocean!
You can put it in the painting.
Ok!
Zhou!
Where are you? Zhou!
- Zhou!
- Mom, come here, I am right here!
Zhou, how can you come here?
Mr Qiu, you've gone too far!
This is a restricted zone!
I know,
I just want her to see the ocean.
Let's go!
I'll stay a bit longer.
I am inspired.
Why did you come here with Mr. Qiu?
You can get killed by coming here.
- Freeze! - Wait...
Wait...
Wait!
This is the military zone.
I suspect you're...
spying on naval defence.
I want to arrest you as "Communist Spy".
I am an artist, not a spy.
Nonsense artist, Take him away!
- Go. - Let me go!
Take him away...
- Move on! Move! - Let me go!
Good morning, Miss Xie.
Good morning, class.
Painting is a kind of human behavior,
we must seek truth from facts.
Today, the subject is watermelon.
Don't look down on this watermelon...
Thus Mr Qiu
disappeared from the School forever...
In Zhou's memory,
this is the beginning of missing...
the coolness of the wind,
the beauty of the sunset...
the melancholy of the man...
the vanishing innocence of her childhood.
Sis, what is 8 times 22?
How come you're so good at Math?
Because I like our Math teacher.
I like master Qiu. But he left us.
Li
I made 1 00 dumplings for Mrs Zhang.
Can you bring them to her later?
Sure.
Tell her not to let them overnight.
Have you finished your homework?
Yes.
So, let's go to pick up Dad.
All right
Mom, I'lll go first.
Zhou, slow down.
All right.
Good Afternoon.
- Mrs Sun - How are you?
Hi, Li.
Li, greet your auntie.
What do you have for dinner?
Dumplings!
Oh, that's what you're good at.
I must learn it from you.
Little ball on the floor,
flowers count twenty one,
256, 257
28, 29, 31
I feel nervous every day at this time.
I just worry that Han-Sun is not coming.
Nonsense! Why think this way?
Han-Sun is a pilot, he is great!
Dad is back! Dad is back!
Dad, I want to see the sunset.
All right.
I made a special fish dish...
for tonight.
Isn't Ke-Qiang coming with you?
I almost forgot him!
Ke-Qiang is Uncle Ding to the kids.
He has a scar on his face
because of a fire.
It was scary to the children
when they were little.
Dad said never judge anyone
by his appearance.
Ding's scar was a result of saving someone
from the fire.
You made so many dishes in no time.
Come on,
try this dumpling with turnip.
There is a party next week at the camp.
We are short of one musical item.
I'd like Ding to play violin.
Ping, what would you say?
Good!
Haven't heard Ding's violin for a while.
Uncle Ding plays violin?
Dad and Uncle Ding are great musicians.
One plays accordion & one plays violin.
With their handsome uniforms,
they charmed so many girls.
You girls of the Qing-ling School choir,
in those days,
you enchanted many of us.
You boys...
only paid attention to Ou-Yang.
You never notice me.
Come on! In the end,
I married you, right.
- What'd you say, Ding? - That's right.
Well, from now on, Zhou and Li,
you follow your dad and Uncle Ding.
One plays violin...
& the other accordion.
Ok,
I like Dad's...
"Lonely Accordion Player"
That is the first song I learned.
Come on, Ding, have some more.
Thank you.
Don't be shy, this is your home as well!
How are the dumplings?
Han-Sun,
your music is too Eastern European.
Better change your style.
I like...
the Slavic romanticism.
I don't think that is a problem.
Is your violin still with you?
Yes, it is.
So, better get more practice.
All right.
Have some noodles?
See you.
Take care.
Be careful!
Why did you mention Ou-Yang?
You did it yourself.
Now I regret telling you that we met.
Come on, it's history.
"Two months ago,
Parents' Day at Crystal Rock Primary."
You brought all your furnitures...
from Shanghai?
Can we visit...
your house sometime?
Mrs Sun, what do you think?
Oh, yes...
You stay here for a while.
Sorry. Can you take care of Rainbow?
- Sure! - Thank you.
You're back!
You're cleaning up, huh?
Where have you been?
Let me roll you a cigarette, ok?
All right.
What's up?
I'll cook Lion's Head meat balls tonight.
I bought Five Flower Pork.
Let's go inside.
Baiguan will sing in the Air Force Club.
Let's go to Taipei, next week.
Sounds great!
We haven't been there for a long time.
We can do some shopping.
Today at Parents Day.
I bumped into Ou-Yang.
So, she also lives here!
No wonder you are lost.
You're so bad!
As first, I thought you were after her.
And I thought you felt for Ding.
That is not possible!
I love only you.
Ou-Yang married General Liu.
Her daughter is the classmate of Zhou.
Perhaps,
we can get together sometime.
I think it's quite difficult.
We are home now.
It smells great!
Hurry up, line up, kids...
Good morning class.
Good morning, Miss.
Lin Xiao-Bi,
why are you standing here?
I am being punished.
Why?
Because I refuse to drink skim milk.
Why don't you drink skim milk?
It's horrible, only poor people drink it.
I only take high class things.
Kids,
you know the story behind skim milk?
It is a sign of the friendship
between American & us.
You must know that other than us
only those who go to Sunday school
can drink it.
Ordinary people hardly get the chance.
Since you're children of the Air Force.
You can drink it daily,
get it?
Yes, Miss.
So, drink it without hesitation.
If not, Uncle Sam will say...
the China kids are not behaving.
Yes.
Come on, be quick.
It's almost finished.
Finished by you?
I mean the whole bucket of milk.
Does it taste good?
I... I really wonder.
See, put in a piece of Black Sugar,
Stir it, it tastes sweet.
It looks like chocolate.
Wow, chocolate! It's classy!
Rainbow Liu is so generous.
Shake it, then the taste comes out.
And the color is changing!
That's right.
Look,
they all want Black Sugar from Rainbow.
Big deal!
Sun Xiao-Zhou
Do you want a piece of Black Sugar?
No.
Put the filling inside. Right,
then fold it.
Fold it.
Look, it's like this.
Zhou, watch carefully.
That's right, let mom teach you.
Coming.
Hi, Ding, come in please.
No, thanks.
Sorry to trouble you with my laundry.
Don't mention it;
Li should be glad to do it.
Thank you.
Don't you want to come in?
No, I must leave now.
Take care.
See you later.
Li, some laundry from Uncle Ding.
How come it is like this?
Coming...
- Ding. - Ping, I am sorry.
Uncle Ding.
Li, have you seen a paper note?
You mean this one?
Have you read it?
Did your mother read it?
Ding, what's the matter?
I am sorry, Ping.
Dad, charge up!
Go... Hurry up!
Why don't you go in?
It's not so convenient.
This isn't your first time! Don't be shy?
Thank you.
It doesn't matter, it's ok.
I will go home now.
Take care, Mrs Hu.
What's up?
Mr Hu was arrested.
They suspect he is a spy.
He is now under investigation.
Don't worry.
As long as he is innocent,
he will be fine.
But you never know what will happen!
Ding, you are from the Bureau
of Political Security.
Can you give Mr Hu a hand?
Ping,
don't get involved in this matter.
Let's go in first.
Let's talk inside.
How's dad's accordion?
Do you want to learn?
No!
Do you want to know...
how he wooed me?
Your father took me to his plane.
It was a beautiful morning.
We went to the airport.
I said "How can it be?
You're breaking the rules."
He said "Never mind,"
Each pilot can break the rules 3 times.
So, the first time was with me.
On that day,
he flew very slow,
we saw all the houses,
the people and the animals.
They are all under our feet.
I could even...
see your grandparents.
How can I not help falling in love?
How about the second time?
Oh, it was for your sister Li.
How come I don't remember?
I want the third time?
If there is a third,
your father will never be allowed to fly!
Never be allowed to fly again...
Line up, one by one.
Kid, you should line up.
Time for skim milk!
How come you have such a big piece
of Black Sugar!
Father gave that to me.
Zhou, do you have Black Sugar too?
Keep yours,
try mine first.
Take a seat.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Hurry up!
Is Sun Han-Sun here?
Yes.
We'll take you to the Commander's office.
You are now under arrest for spying.
Have you got it wrong?
This is the warrant.
Ping, I am fine.
I have been loyal to the country,
I did nothing wrong.
I will be fine.
I will follow you.
Take him away.
Han-Sun!
Are you Jin Wen-Ping?
Yes.
You're accused of being pro-Communist.
We'll take you into custody.
Take her away.
Search the house.
Yes.
The sun will rise tomorrow.
The flowers will bloom next year, too.
But the beautiful bird flies
and never returns.
Zhou, Li, come on, follow me.
My little bird of youth will never return.
Zhou, Li,
something happened to your family.
Give way...
Search again!
Search every inch of it.
Ding.
Yes.
Little girl, look
We didn't take away anything.
Remember that.
Ding,
Iet them sign on the warrant.
Then, tell the girls that...
their parents will be gone for a while.
And this place...
it will be sealed tomorrow.
Ask the neighbors to take care of them.
Yes, sir.
All right, let's go.
I'll take you...
to Uncle Kou's home.
They'll take care both of you.
I want daddy's accordion.
Don't take anything useless.
You will stop going to school
for the time being.
Help Auntie Kou to do some chores.
Come with me now.
You'll be back.
Li,
are the lunch boxes ready yet?
Yes, they are ready.
- Wake Ah-Lun up. - He is dressing.
Take care of the baby while I am out.
Yes.
Come on, be a good girl.
Take care.
Ah-Lun, get up for breakfast.
Girls,
- did you sleep well? - All right.
Everyday is the same, dressing up...
and eating breakfast.
You're lazy!
Why don't you eat breakfast?
It will help you grow tall...
- and strong. - I am tall enough.
You are not!
Come on, eating more...
will help you become smart.
Come on, eat your breakfast now.
Mom, I want Lion's Head meat balls
tonight.
- Lion's Head again?
- You naughty boy!
Li is not your maid.
Lion's Head is delicious
but you can't have it everyday.
This is a difficult time.
We should be thrifty.
Just let him eat what he likes,
what a nag!
Come on, let's have breakfast.
You look beautiful!
Because of their help.
So I will have a break,
I am going to play mahjong.
Who is coming this early?
Who is it?
Are the Sun sisters...
Iiving here?
Yes, they are.
I am the driver of General Liu.
Ms Liu would like to bring them a gift.
Stay where you are. Wait right here.
Sign this.
The meeting begins.
Dad, I miss you,
are you going to abandon us?
Don't be silly! I will never abandon you.
Are you taking good care of your sister?
Yes!
Good! How is your grade in Math?
I haven't got it yet.
Haven't got it...
Wait here for me,
I have to talk to Uncle Ding.
I was accused of flying to
the Communist Zone during the war.
You knew my purpose is going there.
I just wanted to bring back Li with me.
They are accusing me of treason.
But the people I saw,
the things I did,
you were with me all that time.
You knew what I said, what I did.
You witness it all.
Help me!
"General Liu"
Why was he arrested?
Treason, Sir.
He is unyielding.
Who are these girls?
His daughters.
Pity!
Mom.
Zhou.
Mom...
Ding.
Why did you take her along?
Hasn't she dragged us down enough?
Mom...
I am not your mom.
Because of you,
your dad snuck into the Communist zone
he is now being accused of spying.
You're not born by me,
I do not deserve to be your mother.
And you do not deserve to be my daughter.
Mom...
Sis...
Li,
I am sorry...
Forgive mom.
Li then remembered...
she loved sitting under the big tree
at school...
always had the feeling that...
why mother always treated her
better than her sister?
The reason is she was not born by her.
But, so what?
She has only one family, one sister.
Zhou...
Let me take you to see your dad.
No, I am taking care of the baby girl.
Hurry up,
or you may never see your father again.
Kids, don't touch the car.
Are you Zhou and Li?
Auntie.
Let me take you to see your father.
Madam, they were
just sent to the Dry River.
So, let's hurry there.
Madam, that's a forbidden place.
Move on, I know what I am doing.
Yes, Madam.
Madam, here we are.
Zhang,
take them to see their father.
Promise me,
don't tell anyone that you've been here.
Zhang, be careful,
don't let others see them.
Don't let the kids make a sound.
Yes, Madam.
Come on, hurry up.
Don't make any sound!
Move faster,
hurry up...Come out and line up...
Hurry up! Move faster.
Hurry up! One by one!
The verdict.
The accused, Wang Sheng-He,
male, aged 30, Cantonese.
Tutor at the Taiwan Cadet School,
follow Communists...
order to spy on Taiwan.
You're accused of recruiting adherents,
in the name of
the "New Democracy Youth League"
to tempt trouble minded youths.
Sentenced to death.
The accused Sun Han-Sun, male, aged 32.
A Captain of the 9th squadron
of the Air Force.
The verdict is...
the accused sent out intelligence...
to the Communists.
In 1 947,
he entered the Communist zone
in North China.
He intended to rebel the government
with the Communist.
Sentenced to death.
Hurry up...
Escort the prisoners forward.
Give them wine.
Ready for execution!
Execute!
4 x1 = 4, 4 x 2 = to 8,
4 x 3 = 1 2,
a total of 1 2 people.
4 x1 = 4, 4 x 2 = to 8,
4 x 3 = 1 2,
a total of 1 2 people.
Here are your favorites -
Lion's Head meat ball.
It is delicious!
You should get more!
I want to buy a pair of new shoes.
You just bought one pair last year.
Why do you want a new one this year?
I want them for the Speech Competition.
Who told you to join the competition?
They say I can join,
only if I wear new shoes.
You're so stupid!
Don't shout at him!
Zhou,
this is my home, not your home!
You'll eat me out of my home.
This is your home, not my home.
I don't like it here,
I want my dad to shoot you to death.
What's up with you? You want to go home?
I'll let Ding take you back home.
Don't eat it...
if you don't want to!
- You cheese-eating mouse!
- She is ridiculous,
how dare you break my bowl?
Go get Ding here!
Zhou finally saw the place
where Ding lives.
It is a mechanic warehouse
near the airport.
He lives alone.
All his secrets are kept in
that little room.
A giant Dr. Sun Yat-Sun painting...
Iook over them.
Zhou.
I'll take you back to school tomorrow.
Thank you, Uncle Ding.
However,
Zhou liked the changes.
Because, it gave her the chance.
To return to the school
where Master Qiu once taught.
Uncle Ding will take care of you.
Try this piece of Black Sugar.
Why are you so nice to me?
Because you didn't like me,
so I must be nice to you.
But I like you now.
So you don't have to be nice.
Then I must be even nicer to you.
Let's meet at the statue everyday...
before school.
Sure!
Miss, you are home!
Hi!
Let me show you around.
Let's read.
Long time ago in a far away kingdom.
A celebrating for the birth of Prince.
The newborn prince was really cute
Why are you so cheerful?
What are you reading?
We are reading "Prince of Tears."
"Prince of Tears"?
Zhou, do you like it?
Yes.
She reads and she cries.
Do you know...
why the prince got frozen.
And, why did he went blind?
I don't know.
Because he saw the injustice
and corruption of the world.
He wanted to change.
But he had no way out.
So, he finally sacrificed himself.
Let me read you...
the part I like most.
Ok.
Come on, sit closer.
Rainbow knows which part I like most,
right?
Yes.
"Your Highness, please forgive us."
The poor people said to the prince.
"Why?"
"Because we are poor, we are dirty,
we are an embarrassment to you."
"lt is not your choice to be in poverty,
it's the society that made you so."
Rainbow's lives in
an old Japanese house.
It was full of...
beautiful European furniture
and paintings.
General Liu is frugal
and conservative.
He believes the army could return
to China soon.
So he insists on letting
the garden go unattended.
But Madam Ou-Yang Liu...
is an elegant Shanghai lady.
When she came to Taiwan,
Iike other high society people,
she took everything she loved with her.
General Liu married late.
However, their Shanghai wedding...
was the talk of the town.
- Good morning. - Good morning.
- Good morning, Zhou. - Good morning.
Zhou, why are you standing here?
I am waiting for Rainbow.
- I've been waiting for a long time.
- Let's go.
This is fun!
What a big picture of Dr. Sun Yat-Sun!
Not like ours,
only a small one on the wall.
But Mom says Dr. Sun autographed it
for father.
Rainbow, let's have a treasure hunt.
Ok.
This is Uncle Ding's violin.
It's wonderful!
But I haven't heard him playing.
This is yours.
No!
Look, this is Uncle Ding's picture.
Wow, very handsome.
No way, my dad is more handsome.
I like your mother,
telling me stories.
Which story do you like most?
The story of Qiu Jin.
Me too.
But those progressive women...
usually act like men.
Your mom is progressive too.
But she isn't like a man.
She wears trousers.
Your mom seems to know my mom.
No way, your mom is so high class!
Last time...
they met at Parent's Day.
Your mom seemed avoiding my mom.
No way, everyone likes your mom.
It's like everyone likes me, except you.
Don't be silly! I like you, too.
Let's be the best friends.
Sure.
Uncle Ding,
whom are you writing a report on?
Silly kid, mind your tongue.
I am not writing a report.
Madam.
General.
I'd like to reframe this picture...
of you with Generalismo Chiang.
Don't bother.
It's just all a facade.
I looked in on the gardens.
They seem to be so desolate.
Shall we do some gardening?
Why waste the time and effort?
We'll be back to China very soon.
Actually, I don't quite approve...
that you moved everything from Shanghai.
Alright, let me just change the photo.
She looked at this lonely soldier.
Does he understand her lonely youth?
Sometimes,
even she feels
she does not understand herself.
She is from a...
family of wealth.
Yet she feels that she has nothing.
She wants to share,
but she wants to possess too.
The accused Chang, female, aged 31,
a clerk at the Taipei Stationery Company,
a member of "Patriotic Youth Association".
Among Taipei students,
she tried to recruit young people.
to spy for the Communists.
Sentenced to the death.
She is a revolutionary,
but can't help being Bourgeois.
She appreciates the simplicity
of lndanthrene,
but she can't stop loving the softness
of fine silk.
The decadence of beautiful things
& the pain of the truth,
she wants them all.
She desires too much. She started
to blame herself.
Zhang.
Please give this letter...
to Mr. Li of the Dongfeng Bookstore.
And please tell him that...
I can't attend...
the literature meeting this Thursday.
Yes, Madam.
Zhang...
That's all.
How's everything? Bro Chiang
I have it.
Please keep it.
Thanks.
This is very urgent.
Please sent it as soon as possible.
Sure, no problem.
Thanks.
Yesterday Zhou...
was here with Rainbow.
I cannot complain,
because she is with General's daughter.
Poor Mr. Sun and his family!
Sun has a pretty wife.
But it caused his buddy's betrayal.
Ding filed a charge against Sun
in the Commander's office.
Spying is such a serious crime.
Sun is dead for sure.
But why was the woman arrested too?
It was to make the show perfect.
You know what kind of person Ding is.
I think, the woman...she will be fine,
and she will be his woman later.
Zhang.
Yes, General.
Where did Madam go yesterday?
She went for a movie in the afternoon.
Then she went to shop for some fabric.
Didn't she go to the Women's Association?
No, General.
Not very much a General's wife.
Is Zhou always here for fun?
Yes, General.
Is Rainbow very fond of her?
Tell Madam not to read "Free China".
This garden seems to be desolate.
Madam is right.
I think it is time to do some gardening.
Yes, General.
Sis, are you doing well here?
I am fine.
Let me tell you a secret.
Uncle Ding turned in dad.
Dad was executed because of Uncle Ding.
It's because Uncle Ding fell for mom.
Never tell the others.
Why are you so quiet?
You're a spy,
you filed a report that sent my dad
to his death.
How do you know your father is dead?
I saw the execution at the Dry River.
Who took you there?
Auntie Liu and her driver.
Now I will file a report on Auntie Liu
and her driver.
How was your test today?
Not bad.
Miss, excuse me, I have to go now.
Mom, I am back.
Good evening, Auntie Liu.
Good girl.
Is that for me?
Yes,
I made some sandwiches for you.
After the snack,
you can go for a movie.
Bravo!
So, let's hurry up
and finish our homework.
Sure!
Try this dress first.
Ok!
Auntie Liu, you are beautiful!
Zhou, I have a present for you too.
See if you like it or not.
Open it now.
"Prince of Tears"
This is our little secret,
only you and I know.
Thank you, Auntie Liu.
What a beautiful sunset.
Will your mom take you see the sunset?
No, but Daddy did.
Rainbow, how do you like it?
Mom, it looks nice! I love pink.
I know.
What did you put in the schoolbag?
Nothing.
Mom, can I wear this to the movie?
Sure, but take care of it.
This girl is Zhang Xiao-Yan.
She won prizes at the Film Festivals.
She acts very well.
Hello!
Yes...
Yang...
Phoenix, come here.
Auntie, I didn't do anything wrong.
Come here,
I want to check your temperature.
Do you have a fever?
No, I do not.
General.
I am sorry...
I've broken your vase.
That night she knew her time had come.
She left her daughter the necklace.
It has 266 pearls,
a family treasure.
Come back...
Hurry up!
Is it silly that I cry like this?
Nonsense!
Zhou, let me take you home.
No, thanks, I can go home alone.
Rainbow, see you tomorrow at the statue.
All right, see you.
- Miss, let's go. - See you!
That night,
Madam Liu finally made her exit.
She left behind her beauty and beliefs
in a blurring ambiguity.
Zhou, why are you still standing here?
Go to class.
Why isn't Rainbow here today?
Mom won't allow me to talk.
Rainbow then disappeared in Zhou's life.
People said Madame Ou-Yang Liu
was a Communist spy.
General Liu
was sent to the military court too.
Rainbow was sent to
the "Woman's Association for custody."
They want to check
if she was influenced by her mother.
People said,
the Communists are powerful...
at brain-washing kids.
Zhou thought it was all her fault.
She felt that she was a sinner.
Not unworthy of Rainbow's friendship,
Mom!
Zhou.
Let me take a good look at you!
Oh, you look thin.
Did you drink skim milk at school?
Has Uncle Ding taken good care of you?
Have you missed Mom?
You grew bigger & taller.
- Ping! - Uncle Ding!
We will have extra dish tonight.
Mom, I am back.
You're home!
Did you pay attention well in class?
Yes.
Li come here,
Iet me take a good look at you.
You're going to high school,
are you prepared?
I am ready.
I just made 1 00 dumplings.
Deliver them to Auntie Zhang's.
Remember to let her sign the bill,
they are on credit.
All right.
Yes, coming.
Hi, Ding.
Ping.
Look, you are too generous
Are you busy making money?
How many dumplings can you sell a day?
About seven to eight hundred a day.
Give me the laundry,
I'll ask Li to do for you.
Li, come over. The laundry first,
the dumplings later.
Please go inside.
Where is Zhou?
I just saw her.
Li is a big girl now.
I'd like to send her study in the city.
What do you think?
This is a good idea.
Would you go inside?
Mom, I am back.
You're home
We are discussing...
Li's schooling.
Have you greeted Uncle Ding yet?
Uncle Ding.
Uncle Ding has a friend in the city.
Li can...
stay with them.
Li come here.
Take this.
Go and have some noodles.
You can go to a movie later.
Don't be too late.
We'll get changed.
I just want to let you know,
Ding and I are getting married.
Li, is Uncle Ding's shirt ready?
Why are you still wearing pajamas?
Go get changed,
we're going to take photos.
Move now.
Mom, it's always Uncle Ding's laundry.
Have you got anything else to say?
They are right,
you're finally going to marry Ding.
I just want you to iron the shirt.
Why did you say such a thing to me?
Mom, everbody...
is talking behind us?
They are laughing at us!
Because of you,
Uncle Ding sent dad to jail.
And Dad was shot dead.
He killed Dad,
now he wants to sleep in Dad's bed.
I just can't stand it.
What happened to you?
Li, come here.
You know why I do this.
I just want you girls to live better.
You think I know nothing...
of the gossip?
So what if this is true?
It's history.
We have to survive anyway.
That time you came to see me in custody.
I scolded you,
your father returned
to the Communist zone,
all because of you.
That's why he was charged with spying.
I never said a harsh word to you before,
because you were not born by me.
That was the first time I scolded you
and I regretted.
Mom is just an ordinary woman.
I just want you girls to live better.
Mom, I am sorry...
Do you understand, Li?
Are you ready?
Yes, we are ready.
Let's go.
"Story of lost lovers"
Li, take good care of your sister.
Yes.
Ding.
Are you ready?
Coming.
Send them to school now, don't be late.
Let's go to school now.
Take care.
- Goodbye, Mom. - See you, Mom.
Don't make supper, let's eat out.
Come back early.
You're back! I missed you.
Where have you been?
How have you been?
Since our seperation,
I was imprisoned on Green lsland.
I always thought I would see you again.
But then one day,
my heart broke.
And that was the day you were executed.
I almost gave up my desire to live.
Until I received Ding's first letter,
I could...
never forgive myself
for Han-Sun's death.
He urged me to prove his innocence.
Such a simple request,
but I refused to do so.
When I found out the verdict.
It was too late to reverse the judgment.
On that day, I accompanied him
to the execution ground.
I gave him a last drink of wine.
I didn't see hatred in his eyes.
Bearing an unforgivable guilt.
I tidied everything for him.
I know Li has always disliked me.
But how can I tell her that...
I was burnt because of saving her?
That fire...
Burnt my ambition and made me what I am.
Do you remember Ou-Yang?
When Han-Sun and I met you.
You two were best friends.
Now, your children too.
One night I found "Prince of Tears."
Zhou said it was a gift from Ou-Yang.
I flipped through the pages.
It was a comic book from our youth.
It survived the Japanese invasion.
It went through the Communists.
Now, it appears in our remote village.
"Prince of Tears"
It sounds so long ago.
Because of this book,
Ou-Yang guided me to the
"Progressive Reading Society".
She wanted me to be progressive.
And I was so attached to her.
Long time no see!
I never thought we meet again.
You loved her.
I love only you.
My daughter told me that...
Zhou is her classmate,
she likes her very much.
Do you remember...
how we met?
That time,
you picked up my book "Prince of Tears."
You asked me
why is it named "Prince of Tears."
I said,
because the Prince saw
and hated the injustices of the society,
so tears filled his eyes.
You said, just so simple?
I said...
tears are the beginning of the story.
Afterwards...
everything will be changed.
On that day,
we leaned on to each other.
She turned the pages one by one
and explained the meaning...
of each picture to me
the hidden meaning behind the words...
and the pictures.
Do you recall her name?
Ou-Yang Qian-Jun.
I betrayed her, and betrayed you.
When people look at me,
Their eyes are telling me...
you betrayed the man who loved you,
and the friend who trusted you,
Then, married a man
who brought down your family.
Once again Ping hears
that familiar accordion.
There is a nameless sorrow in her heart.
She knows Han-Sun will never return
after this visit.
And she misses him so.
In a trance,
she returns to the day they were arrested.
She sits in the kitchen.
Listens to the music.
Rolls some cigarettes for Han-Sun.
I love your music.
I love your simplicity.
I love your honesty.
I love you...
till the end of the world.
Why do you make so many cigarettes?
You'll leave on a mission soon.
So better bring more with you.
Why is it so noisy out there?
Let's take a look.
And she will never forget
his last glance before parting.
The story...
floats away.
One still clings to it.
And one can only rely on hope now.
Han-Sun returned today.
From 1 950 to 1 954 during
the martial law era in Taiwan
Over 3000 people were sentenced to death,
and more than 8000 were jailed.
Their aggregate prison terms
exceeded 1 0,000 years.
This movie is based on a true story.
The father was executed in 1 954 accused
of treason & re-established in 2005.
His remains are yet to be found.
The mother remarried in 1 956
and had two more children.
She is 86 and still lives in Taiwan.
Ding married Ping and spent
his life quietly in Taichung
and died in 1992 at the age of 79.
Li has had a happy family life in Taipei
with two children.
Zhou became an actress
and was a top star in the 1960s.
It's all by-gones.