The long memory is the most
radical idea in America
– Claire Spark Loeb
I am mashing the berries,
I am mashing the berries.
They say travelers are coming on the march,
They say travelers are coming on the march.
I stir (the berries)
around, I stir them around;
I take them up with a
spoon of buffalo horn,
spoon of buffalo horn.
And I carry them,
I carry them (to the strangers),
I carry them (to the strangers).
PROFIT MOTIVE AND THE WHISPERING WIND
In memory of Anne Marbury Hutchinson
Baptized at Alford, Lincolnshire, England 20 - July - 1591
Killed by the Indians
at East Chester New York 1643
A courageous exponent
of civil liberty and religious toleration
Mary Dyer, Quaker,
Witness for religious freedom
Hanged on Boston Common 1660
"My life not availeth me in comparison
to the liberty of the truth"
The Great Swamp Fight
Three-quarters of a mile to the
southward on an island in the great swamp,
the Narragansett Indians were decisively defeated
by the United Forces of the Massachusetts Bay,
Connecticut and Plymouth colonies,
Sunday, December 19, 1675.
The Narragansett Indians were decisively MASSACRED
by the United Forces of the Massachusetts Bay,
Connecticut and Plymouth colonies.
Erected by the state of Rhode Island, 1933
After the Pilgrims' arrival,
Native Americans in New England
grew increasingly frustrated
with the English settlers'
abuse and treachery.
Metacomet (King Philip),
a son of the Wampanoag sachem
known as the
Massasoit (Ouamequin),
called upon all Native people
to unite to defend
their homelands against
encroachment.
The resulting "King Philip's War"
lasted from 1675-1676.
Metacomet was murdered in Rhode
Island in August 1676,
and his body was mutilated. His
head was impaled on a pike
and was displayed near this
site for more than 20 years.
One hand was sent to
Boston, the other to England.
Metacomet's wife and
son, along with the families
of many of the Native
American combatants,
were sold into slavery in the
West Indies
by the English victors.
In the "Miery Swamp"
100 feet W.S.W. from this
spring, according to tradition,
King Philip fell
August 12, 1670, O.S
This stone placed by
the R. I. Historical Society
December, 1877.
Unidentified site of
1770 Boston Massacre
Victims of the Boston Massacre,
March 5th 1770
were here interred by order
of the Town of Boston.
Here also lies buried the body
of Christopher Snider
Aged 12 years,
Killed February 22nd, 1770
The innocent, first victim of
the struggles between
the Colonists and the Crown,
which resulted in independence.
The Stono Rebellion, the largest
slave insurrection
in British North America, began
nearby on September 9. 1739.
About 20 Africans raided a
store near Wallace Creek,
a branch of the Stono River.
Taking guns and other weapons,
they killed two shop-keepers.
The rebels marched south
toward promised freedom in
Spanish Florida, waving flags,
beating drums, and
shouting "Liberty!"
The rebels were joined by 40
to 60 more during their
15-mile march.
They killed at least 20 whites,
but spared others.
The rebellion ended
late that afternoon when the
militia caught the rebels,
killing at least 34 of them.
Most who escaped were
captured and executed;
any forced to
join the rebels were released.
The S.C. assembly soon enacted
a harsh slave code,
in force until 1885.
Near here is the early site for
the Richmond gallows
and "Burial Ground
for Negroes."
On 10 Oct. 1800, Gabriel,
an enslaved blacksmith
from Brookfield plantation in
Henrico County, was executed
there for attempting to lead
a mass uprising
against slavery on 30 Aug. 1800.
A fierce rainstorm
delayed the insurrection, which
then was betrayed by two slaves.
Gabriel escaped and eluded
capture until 23 Sept.,
when he was arrested in Norfolk.
He was returned
to Richmond on 27 Sept.
And incarcerated in
the Virginia State Penitentiary.
On 6 Oct. he stood trial
and was condemned. At least 25
of his supporters
were also put to death there or
in other jurisdictions.
Thomas Paine 1737 - 1809
Author of 'Common Sense'
The pamphlet that stirred
the American Colonies
to independence
John Adams said:
"Without the pen of Paine
the sword of Washington would
have been wielded in vain."
Captain Shays served with the
Continental Army, and was
the leader of Shays'
Rebellion in Massachusetts.
Shays' Rebellion had a lasting
effect on the framing
of our Country's Constitution,
and history of the United States
Captain Shays was a true
patriot, who in 1814,
came to live in Scottsburg,
New York until his death.
"When I am gone
and my warnings are no longer
heeded, the graft and avarice
of the white man will prevail.
My heart fails me when I think
of my people, so soon to be
scattered and forgotten."
Patriot and Warrior
Died at Fort Moultrie
January 30, 1838
Frances Wright
Phiouepal D'Arusmont
Born Dundee Scotland
September 6, 1795,
Died in Cincinatti, Ohio
December 13, 1852
I have wedded the cause
of human improvement,
staked on it my fortune,
my reputation and my life.
Man kind is but one family
In Memory of Thomas Wilson Dorr
Son of Sullivan and Lydia Dorr
Born in Providence, Nov. 5, 1805.
Died Dec. 27, 1834.
He died in the Faith
In memoriam George Lippard
Born April 10 1822
Died Feb 5 1854
Erected to the founder
of the order
by the Brotherhood of
the Union October 12, 1885
Memory of Gen. John Brown
Who Died at
New York, Sept Yr 3 1776
in the 48 year of his Age
John Brown Born May 9, 1800,
was Executed at Charle-ton
Dec. 2. 1859
Here lies buried John Brown
Here lie buried with him
twelve of his followers
The following men of
John Brown's band escaped
but were captured and
hanged December 16, 1860
The following men of
John Brown's band escaped
Henry D. Thoreau
B. July 12, 1817, D. May 6 1882
Emma Willard 1787 - 1870
Author of the system for
the higher education of women
Edmonia G. Highgate 1844 - 1870
Teacher, Orater, Freedom Worker
She devoted the labors of her
brief life to educating
the freed slaves in the South,
and her eloquence
enlightened the North
to their plight.
"Oh how inspiring the thought
that these dear souls
are 'forever free.'"
Jermin W. Loguen
1809 - 1872
Sacred to the memory of
Sarah Moore Crimke
Born at Charleston, S.C.
20 Nov. 1792
Died at Hyde Park, Mass.
23 Dec. 1873
On this spot
Crazy Horse Ogallala Chief
was killed
Sept. 5 1877
William Lloyd Garrison
1805 - 1879
Helen Eliza Garrison 1811 - 1876
Lucretia Mott
Born 1st Mot. 3rd 1793
Died [8th?] Mo. 11th 1880
In memoriam Sojourner Truth
Ann and Wendell Phillips
D. April 24, 1885 - Feb. 2, 1884
These seven flowering pear
trees are in memory of the
seven Milwaukee citizens
killed during the struggle
for the Eight-Hour Day,
May 5, 1886
Wisconsin Labor History Society
August Spies
Adolph Fischer.
Albert R. Parsons.
Louis Lingo.
George Engel.
The day will come when
our silence will be more
powerful than the voices
you are throttling today.
This monument represents
the labor movement's
struggle for workers' right
and possesses national
significance in commemorating
the history of
the United States of America
1997 - National Park Service
United States Department
of the Interior
John Beeson
Born in England, Sept. 15, 1803,
Died Apr. 21, 1889
A Pioneer and man of Peace.
Morewood Massacre
On April 2, 1891, at the
nearby Morewood
Mines of the H.C. Frick
Coke Co., sheriff's
deputies killed seven strikers;
two more died later.
These were among
some 16,000 workers
striking for higher wages
in the coke region.
Thousands of mourners
attended the funeral
of the original seven victims
who were buried
in a mass grave in St. John's
Cemetery, Scottdale.
By late May
the strike had collapsed,
& the organising of coke workers
suffered a severe blow.
Pennsylvania Historical and
Museum Commission 2000
Those who died at Morewood on
April 2 1891 are as follows:
Paul Dohannis
Single shot in the head.
Valentine Zeidel
Single shot through the neck.
James Josef Brochto
Shot through the breast.
Jacob Shucaskey
Shot through the head.
Left a wife and five children.
John Fudora
Shot above the left eye.
Antonio Anda Rist
Shot through the head.
Crsezo Cresigner
Single shot through the breast.
Joseph Klassman of Doonnelly.
Married.
Paul Galinsky of Spring Garde.
Married, six children.
Homestead Strike
On the morning of July
6, 1892, on orders of
the Carnegie Steel Co.,
200 Pinkerton agents
attempted to land near
here; strikers, citizens
repulsed them. Seven
workers, three Pinkertons
were killed.
8,000 state militia arrived
July 12; by November
the strike was broken.
Homestead Strike Victims
In these two adjoining
cemeteries are buried
six of the seven Carnegie
Steel Company workers
killed during the "Battle of
Homestead" on July 6, 1892.
The graves of Peter Ferris,
Henry Striegel
and Thomas Weldon
are here in St. Mary's Cemetery.
The remains of John Morris,
Joseph Sotak,
and Silas Wain lie in
Homestead Cemetery.
The seventh victim, George
Rutter, is buried in Verona.
Lucy Stone
Born West Brookfield, Mass.
Theodore D. Weld
1803-1895
Frederick Douglass 1818 - 1895
Harriett Jacobs
February 11 1815 - March 7, 1897
Lattimer Massacre
Near here at Harwood,
on Sept 10. 1897,
immigrant coal miners
on strike began
a march for higher wages
and equal rights.
Unarmed, they were fired upon at
Lattimer by sheriff's deputies.
Nineteen marchers...
Polish, Slovak and
Lithuanian... were killed.
The majority of the dead
were buried in St. Stanislaus
Cemetery, Hazleton.
Others were interred in St.
Joseph's & Vine Street
Cemeteries, Hazleton, and
in St. Patrick Cemetery, McAdoo.
Here on September 10, 1897,
nearly 400
immigrant coal miners
on strike were
met and fired upon by
sheriff's deputies.
Unarmed, they were marching
from Harwood to
Lattimer in support of
higher wages
and more equitable
working conditions.
Nineteen of the march-
ers were killed,
and 38 were wounded.
This was one of the most
serious acts of violence
in American labor history.
Henry George 1839-1897
The truth that I have
tried to make
clear will not find
easy acceptance.
If that could be,
it would have been
accepted long ago.
If that could be,
it would never
have been obscured.
But it will find friends -
those who
will toil for it;
suffer for it;
if need be, die for it.
This is the power of truth.
Henry George,
Progress and Poverty
Joseph Gitterle
Died in the Virden Massacre,
October 12, 1898
"Life to him was sweet,
and fair as the autumn sky,
but duty called, and, bravely,
he answered, "Aye"
E. Kaemmerer
Died in the Verden Massacre,
October 12, 1898
"He thought it better to be dead,
to die for liberty and
his friends, than to live in
bondage or just for bread."
E.W. Smith
Died in the Verden Massacre,
October 12, 1898
It was not because he loved
life less, but because he loved
his friends and freedom more,
that he gave his all.
Elizabeth Cady Stanton
Mother - Author - Orator
Woman Suffrage Leader
Called woman's rights convention
First in history.
Susan B. Anthony
B. February 15, 1820
"Don't iron while
the strike is hot!"
Kate Mullaney Founder of the
first all-female labor union
in the U.S.A. 1864
Frances E.W. Harper
1824 - 1911
Safe in the arms of Jesus.
Safe on his gentle breast.
Anna Lopizzo
Killed during Bread and Roses
Strike January 29, 1912
Voltairine de Cleyre 1868 - 1912
Harriet Tubman Davis
In memory of
the men, women and children
who lost their lives
in freedom's cause
at Ludlow, Colorado
April 20, 1914.
Erected by the
United Mine Workers of America
Victims of
Ludlow Massacre April 20, 1914
H. Cerlat F. Baran J. Loomey
Killed in Everett Nov. 5, 1916
Erected by the Russian Colony
Frank Little 1879 - 1917
Slain by capitalist interests
for organizing and inspiring
his fellow men
In memory of Fannie Sellins
and Joe Starzeleski
killed by the enemies
of organized labor near the
Allegheny Steel & Coal Co.
At West Natrona PA.
Erected by the United
Mine Workers of Dist. No. 5
They fell a victim to
the lust of greed;
they whose blood ran hot
with labors need
they foully murdered.
Aug, 26, 1919.
F. Sellins
1872 - 1919
J. Starzeleski
1865 - 1919
In memory of Wesley Everest
Killed Nov. 11, 1919
Age 32
Matewan Massacre
In 1920 area miners went on
strike to gain recognition
of UMWA. On May 19 of the
same year, twelve Baldwin-Felts
Agency guards came from
Bluefield to evict the miners
from company houses.
As guards left town,
they argued with town
police chief Sid Hatfield and
Mayor Testerman. Shooting of
undetermined origins resulted in
the deaths of two coal miners,
seven agents and the mayor.
None of the 19 men
indicted were convicted.
Terence Vincent Powderly
1849 - 1924
"That is the most perfect
government in which an injury
to one is the concern of all"
Eugene V. Debs
1855 - 1926
COPY OF RECORD
OF DEATH
Bartolomeo Vanzetti
Date of Death:
Aug. 28, 1927
Immediate Cause of Death:
Electric Shock
Judicial Homicide
Ashes of Sacco and Vanzetti
Lest we forget
At dawn on November 21, 1927,
six union miners were killed
at the Columbine mine
fighting for a living wage
and a measure of human dignity.
Five are buried here:
Mary "Mother" Jones
Born May 1, 1830
Died November 30, 1930
"She gave her life to the world
of labor, her blessed soul
to Heaven. God's finger touched
her and now she sleeps."
Barnett
Ida B. Wells
July 16, 1862 - Mar. 25, 1931
Ferdinand L.
Feb. 18, 1852 - Mar. 11, 1936
Crusaders for Justice
Curtis Williams
His life for a union
Ford Hunger March - 1932
Joe York
Joseph Bussell
Kalman J. Leny
Joe DeBlasio
His life for a union
Ford Hunger March - 1932
Martyrs - Heroes - Unionists
Shot down May 30, 1937,
Memorial Day,
at the gates of Republic
Steel Co.
While parading for the right
to organize a union,
promote industrial democracy and
to secure justice and
equality for
working men and women
everywhere.
Erected May 30, 1967
by The United Steelworkers
of America Committee
to commemorate
the 1937 Memorial Day Massacre.
Emma Goldman
June 29, 1869 - May 14, 1939
Liberty will not descend
to a people,
a people must
raise themselves to liberty.
Lucy Parsons 1859 - 1942
Anna Sosnovsky Winokour
1900-1949
Mother & Comrade
Ralph H. Chaplin - Husband
1887 - 1961
Medgar W Evers Mississippi
Tec 5 - OMC - World War II
Jul 2 1925 - Jun 12 1963
Carson
Maria McL. - 1869-1958
Rachel L. - 1907-1964
Elizabeth G. Flynn
1890-1964
"The Rebel Girl"
Fighter for working class emancipation
Lorraine Hansberry Nemiroff
1930 - 1965
I care. I care about it all. It takes
too much energy not to care...
The why of why we are here is
an intrigue for adolescents:
the how is what must command
the living.
Which is why I have lately
become an insurgent again.
Lorraine Hansberry
Hajj-Malik el Shabazz
Malcolm X.
1925 - 1965
Betty S.
1936 - 1997
There is no speech nor language,
where their voice is not heard, Ps. 19:3
A evening the dove came back
with a branch of
olive in her beak and peace after
these storms.
Paul Robeson
April 9, 1898 - Jan. 23, 1976
"The artist must elect to fight
for freedom or slavery.
I have made my choice. I had
no alternative."
Fannie Lou Hamer
October 6, 1917 - March 14, 1977
"I am sick and tired of being
sick and tired"
William L. Patterson
1890 - 1980
Eternal fighter for
civil rights and socialism
Dorothy Day
November 8. 1897 - November 29, 1980
Deo Gratias
I.F. Stone
1907 - 1989
Esther M. Stone
1908 - 2000
It is my deepest belief that
only by giving our lives
do we find life.
- Cesar Estrada Chavez
"They shall beat their
swords' into plowshares
and their spears into
pruning hooks.
One nation shall not raise the
sword against another,
nor shall they train for war again."
Isaiah 2:4
and all the others
English subtitles: Mark Rance