Good evening.
No time to chat today, Tarak.
Very busy.
A cup of tea for me.
Won't take too much of your time.
What's it this time?
Is it a story or an essay?
Neither.
What is this?
- It's a diary.
- Diary?
Give it a read.
Gold mine!
Professor T. Shanku.
2016... 2?
Maybe, this was his second diary
of that year.
But does the name sound familiar?
T. Shanku?
Meaning?
Trilokeshwar Shanku.
Scientist and inventor.
He used to live in Giridih.
He's been missing for a few years now.
But this is a recent diary. 2016.
The initial rumours were that he lost his life
during a very dangerous experiment.
But I've also heard...
he's hiding in an undisclosed location
in India...
and continuing his work
in secret.
He'll reveal himself at the right time.
The diary's date makes
the second option seem correct.
But where did you find this?
Remember the meteorite
that hit the Suderbans?
Meteorite...the Sunderbans...
Oh ho!
A meteorite crashed in the Mathariya area
about three months back.
How can you forget already?
Oh, yes! Correct!
I remember now.
The media went crazy.
Of course, they did.
It was a huge stone.
- But how is this diary--
- Related?
I'll tell you, brother...
So, I had gone to the place...
To Mathariya?
First, I found an monitor lizard's skin.
I thought, since so many animals have died,
I might find some tiger skins too.
You get really good price for it.
But I was too late.
Didn't even find a deer.
- Then what happened?
- Then...
You found the diary in the meteorite crater?
Does that mean...
You won't find the answer
to that mystery in there.
You can read it
if you want.
You people are used to making up stories.
I write too.
This is much more interesting
and adventurous.
Not just that...
The ink that has been used
to write in this diary...
It's a strange ink.
How?
You've seen the diary.
What's the colour of the ink?
Why? It's black.
Open it and see.
Take another look.
What?
This is...
But it was just...
Didn't I tell you...
An ageless inventor!
Now stare at the writing for some time.
I would have never parted with it,
you know.
I'm under a lot of financial stress,
that's why.
Thank you.
May God bless you.
Goodbye.
Yeah, tell me.
Is the proof ready, Samaresh?
What?
The proof?
Oh, yes...
Meet me in an hour.
Okay.
May, 1st.
Today, I finally received the new issue
of the "Cosmos" magazine.
This famous Swedish journal
has printed one of my essays.
I had discussed all my inventions
in the essay.
I had never done this before.
Although, I've received many requests
from various publications from all over the world.
I had to reject them all
due to lack of time.
I have cut down a lot
on my research work nowadays.
I have realised that in a place like Giridih...
with the limited resources of my laboratory...
it's not like nothing can be achieved today...
but there's no need.
However, I had the opportunity
to explain something in this essay.
The reason I did not make my inventions
public to the world.
There's just one reason.
My most important inventions...
like the Annihilin Pistol or the Miracurall medicine...
or the Omniscope or the Microsonograph...
or the memory revival machine, Remembrane...
None of these can be built in a factory.
These are all human handiwork.
And there is only man who can do it.
And that's Trilokeshwar Shanku.
Congratulations!
Your article in the "Cosmos" magazine
has caused quite a stir in the world of science.
Is that so?
Yeah, yeah!
And the people that know you...
They are all saying
what you've done is incredible!
Considering the little resources
you've down there at Giridih.
Take for example, the very means by which
we're presently communicating.
This is also your invention.
Holocon: holographic conference.
Now, let's cut to the chase.
You've heard of Sao Paolo's famous Ratantan Institute,
I presume.
Of course, I have.
It's president, Professor Emilia Rodriguez...
is a good friend to both of us.
And we've talked to her
earlier this morning.
And she told us she has read your article.
And obviously she is fascinated.
Now, let me tell you
about the decision she has taken.
Coming August, a science conference
is being organised in Sao Paolo.
From the 25th to the 28th.
It'll be the usual seminars
and panel discussions.
And besides all that,
on the last day of the conference...
the institute will present you
with a doctorate.
What?
And wait!
It doesn't end there.
An exhibition is being planned
to showcase some of your favourite inventions
alongwith their
necessary research papers.
And you two are invited
to the conference, I hope.
Of course. Emilia will be sending the official invitations
by email as well as by post.
I've never been to Brazil.
Yes, we know.
And when we told her that...
she said that our stay won't end
in just three days.
They're organising a week's tour of Brazil
after the conference is over.
Oh, that's wonderful!
I couldn't have asked for anything better.
Alright. Let us know
when you get the invitation.
And we'll contact you
with any additional information.
Great! Thank you. Thank you.
Bye, Shanku. Take care.
- 'Auf wiedersehen'. Bye, Jeremy.
- Bye, Will.
A gentleman is here to meet you.
Which nationality?
I didn't ask.
But he is wearing a dhoti and cotton kurta.
And he spoke in Bengali.
What did he say?
Tell your master to stop reading the article
in "kishmish".
And spare ten minutes of his time.
He wants to tell you something.
- Ask him to sit in the verandah.
- Okay, sir.
Hello, Tilu.
I apologize for interrupting
your reading of "Cosmos".
I've come here with the deep desire
to discuss certain things with you.
I'm sure you'll listen to my request.
- Sit.
- Yes.
You must be a little surprised.
The fact that I've written in "Cosmos"...
No one here knows about that.
And only my father called me Tilu.
After he passed away,
the nickname had no use.
My name is Nakur Chandra Biswas.
I live in Makardah.
I could see you in front of me
for the last few days.
But that and this is not the same thing.
You could see me?
What do you mean?
It's been like this
for the last one and half months.
People from different places,
events from different places...
I can suddenly see these things.
Although, it's not very clear.
But I can still see.
I've heard your name.
I've seen your photo in the newspapers too.
The moment I tried to remember what you looked like
you were right there in front of me.
Hmm.
And this has been going on
for a month and a half?
Almost a month and a half.
It was raining very heavily that day.
It was afternoon.
My brother was at the school.
He teaches in Makardah Primary School.
Our mother has passed away.
My father was at Noni Ghosh's house
playing chess.
I was having some tamarind chutney
in my room.
Suddenly, I see.
In all probablity...
you are talking about ball lightning.
Ball lightning?
It's a very rare event.
But it does happen.
But if that electricity passes
very close to a person...
and if certain changes are seen in the person
because of that...
then nothing else could be said.
On that note, would you like some coffee?
Would hate to disturb Prahlad...
It's no bother at all.
I'll give you company.
Prahlad! Prahlad!
Coming, sir.
Please bring us two coffees.
3-8-8-8-9-1-7-1...
Nakur?
3-8-8-8-9-1-7-1.
The news of death in the paper.
The wall on the right
of the victim's table...
There's a painting.
Hidden behind it is a safe.
And the number you mentioned?
That's the passkey
to open the safe.
If you enter the number
the safe will open.
It's stuffed with legal documents...
important papers
and bundles of dollar notes.
Please don't mind me, Tilu.
I don't want to waste your precious time
by talking about all this...
Not at all!
You have a rare gift.
Any scientist would be fortunate
to meet you.
I just want to know...
What are the other traits that developed in me
after I came in contact with the ball lightning?
- Am I right?
- Absolutely!
Problem is I don't consider
these special abilities.
It's as normal as breathing.
I'm not thinking about it as special ability
while I'm doing it.
For example, on the table in front of you...
What? What can you see?
A brass Budhha statue...
It's not very clear...
just an illusion.
Like I said...
I'm still not very good at it.
The statue is in Makardah.
It's in our lawyer,
Shibratan Mallik's chamber.
I've seen it only once.
I imagined it on your table.
But it didn't completely show up.
I could see you often...
that's why I thought
I'll visit you in Giridih.
I'll have chat with you...
- Here you go.
- Yes...
I wanted to warn you about something.
- Warning!
- Pardon my insolence.
I know you don't just belong to this country.
You're respected through out the world.
You're invited all over the world
and you must respond to those invitations.
But if you attend the Sao Paulo conference,
I'd request you to be especially careful.
What about Sao Paulo?
I can't tell you that.
It's still not very clear to me yet.
And to tell you the truth,
I don't even know where Sao Paulo is.
Sao Paulo is the biggest city
in South America's biggest country, Brazil.
Oh, I suddenly saw...
My heart shuddered.
And the very next moment I saw...
- What did you see?
- A garden...
And a beautiful restaurant in it...
That man didn't have a good aura.
- Where are you putting up?
- Huh?
Where are you staying?
Hotel Manorama.
How long will you stay?
My work here is done.
So...
How can I get in touch with you?
Well, I have a mobile phone.
- You do?
- Yes.
Then give me your number.
Let me give you a call instead.
I have your number saved.
How do you have my number?
Oh!
I should have guessed.
Please go ahead.
I've saved your number as well.
Tell me something.
What?
Would you go abroad
if you get the opportunity?
Abroad? Me?
It means a lot
that you've even considered me.
I don't need anything else.
Please accept my salutations!
And my blessings for Newton.
It's unbelieveable!
Mr. Biswas seems to have been blessed
with the power of hypnotism...
telepathy and clairvoyance.
Tell me, do you believe in his theory
about ball lightning?
What other explaination can there be?
To be honest...
I've read about instances
where by being close to a lightning strike
the deaf could hear again...
The blind could see again but...
Anyway, I've got the email
from Sao Paulo.
Oh, I'm glad to hear it!
Listen, Shanku...
Why don't you take Mr. Biswas along with you
to Sao Paulo as your secretary?
God, Wil! Instead of being a scientist
you should have been...
Oh, no, no, sorry, Jeremy.
But I have an open mind.
I'm not joking, Shanku.
If you take him along with you
we can see a demonstration of his powers.
And above that, he can participate
on some TV talk shows...
And he will return to his place
with some money in his pocket.
Come on. Think about it.
Let's see.
If I find him excited at the prospect,
I'll let you know.
Okay, that's that!
- Keep us posted. Bye.
- Bye.
Bye.
Tell me, Nakur.
The invitation is already here
from Sao Paulo.
Oh, yes.
Actually...
I was feeling a little awkward at the prospect
of going abroad with you at first.
But now gradually
I've come to realise...
that if I'm not there with you
at Sao Paulo, you'll be...
in great danger. That's why...
Well then, I'll let them know.
That my secretary, NC Biswas
will be travelling with me.
And a separate invitation
should be sent for him.
SREEGURU LIBRARY
One more thing...
At least, three days before leaving
that is August 22nd...
It would be great
if you could come to Giridih.
We must evaluate your sensibilities.
Welcome! Welcome!
Good morning, Tilu!
Good morning.
You are looking great.
Result of praticising yoga.
Take a seat.
Two coffees, please.
Yes, sir.
What else have you been doing?
My English is more fluent now.
And I've learnt Pitman's short hand method.
And I've read a few books on etiquettes
to get used to the culture abroad.
Your letter of recommendation
helped me get the passport.
And see this.
Apart from the suit
I got from Kolkata...
I also got shirts, tie, handkerchief,
shoes and socks.
I've made you spend a lot of money.
Don't worry about it.
My father, his friend Noni Ghosh,
lawyer Shibratan Mallik...
Everyone has heard of you.
They were so happy
that I was going abroad with you...
that they lent me some money.
And my brother lent me this suitcase.
Did you have to buy this too?
What to do?
I normally use neem stems.
Nakur...
Yes?
You might want to read it.
Might find it helpful.
- I won't need it.
- What do you mean?
I found an old book with pictures
in my local library about Brazil.
I have read it cover to cover.
There's only one problem.
And what might that be?
I can still speak a little bit of English.
The book said the official language
of Brazil is Portuguese. That is...
You don't have to worry about that.
I'm here.
You know Portuguese too?
Considering the deep impact
of the Portuguese culture on Indian history...
When I was 11 years old...
I had learned the language from Portuguese Pastor,
Father Rebello.
Which is why I consider you such a genius.
Will we travel to the forests of Brazil?
They have promised to take us around.
Will forests be excluded?
I have read about the forests there.
It talks about a species of snake
that is double the size of a python.
- Anaconda.
- Correct. Exactly that.
- Welcome to Brazil.
- Jeremy, it's been a long time.
Oh yes!
- Shanku!
- Wilhelm!
- You look good... Thank you.
- And you too.
This is Mr. Lobo.
He's Emilia's secretary.
- 'Olá'!
- Hi!
It's an honour, sir.
Thank you.
He has been given the burden
of looking after us.
Really?
And this is the great NC Biswas.
- Hi!
- Hello.
Yes.
They are my closest and oldest friends.
They can't speak Bengali
but they understand it quite well.
A little bit.
Jeremy Saunders.
- Hello.
Wilhelm Kroll.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hello--
What's wrong?
Alps...
Bavarian Alps...
You and two young men...
The year 1972...
Climbing...
Then slipping...slipping...slipping...
Then...oh...
Bad...
Very bad.
My foot slipped.
(in German)
Trying to save my life...
Hermann and Karl lost theirs.
He's saying...
Two of his friends in an attempt to save him...
The entire incident played out
in front of my eyes.
I didn't want to say anything.
It's a very tragic incident.
Excuse me. The car is waiting for us.
Come... Let's go.
Come, Wil.
Did you know about this event of Wil's youth?
No.
Mr. Biswas.
Thank you.
- Mr. Shanku.
- Thank you.
Professor Rodriguez.
You're very kind to me.
Yes.
I have to go.
I'll call you back.
Sao Paulo welcomes you.
Thank you.
So happy.
- And I see you've met up with your old friends.
- Yes, I have.
Wonderful! Wonderful!
We're so deeply honoured
to have you here.
This is my secretary, NC Biswas.
Ah!
- Hello.
- Pleasure... Pleasure.
And has Professor Shanku
received his itinerary?
It's in his room, yes.
Wonderful. Alright and...
All of your research materials
have arrived safely.
And we've set up and organised the exhibition
according to your instructions.
- That's excellent.
- Great!
So, I hope you'll be happy with it.
Yes, I'm sure I will.
Alright then.
I should let you get a bit of rest
after this long journey.
Jetlag doesn't affect Shanku.
It doesn't?
Absolutely not.
Didn't you read about the Nervigour
in the "Cosmos" article?
But, of course, your nerve invigorating pill.
Right?
This is the place I saw where...
Where?
Where the foreigner is going to sit with you.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
Sir.
The conference will be inaugrated
with the seminar...
involving the three of you today at five p.m.
Oh!
- Your itinerary.
- Hmm.
Excuse me.
Wonderful.
We're right beside you.
I'm in 3421 and Wil is in...
3423.
Two, one... Two, three...
Will you be requiring anything else, sir?
No, I don't think so.
Not at the moment.
After the conference is over though...
I think we'd all like a tour of the rainforest.
Good idea!
Of course.
Okay...
Ladies and gentlemen...
our discussion must end here for tonight.
The next event will take place
in the adjacent room.
And it'll be an exhibition of a select few...
of the world famous Indian scientist
Trilokeshwar Shanku's most amazing inventions.
Alongwith their supporting research papers.
And for this the Ratantan Institute
is forever grateful to him.
Not only is Prof. Shanku here to take part
in these talks and discussions...
He is also our chief guest.
This is because on the final day of our conference...
we'll present a doctorate to him.
And it's Prof. Shanku's wish
that today's exhibition...
be inaugarated by his two closest friends.
Yes.
We're deeply touched, Shanku.
Indeed, we are.
After you... Come.
Professor Trilokeshwar Shanku
was born in Giridih…
This way.
...a border town of the state of Jharkhand, India
in the year 1945.
(narration in Portuguese)
It's been a while since I have seen
anyone write in shorthand.
Oh, my secretary, Biswas.
He's been learning Pitman.
You know something...
All these documents and blueprints
have been lying locked up...
in my cabinets in Giridih
all this time away from prying eyes.
Suddenly, to see them exhibited
for the public...
here in Brazil is...
But what Professor Shanku is famous worldwide
for is as an inventor.
He has been recognised as the greatest inventor
since Thomas Alva Edison…
by scientists from five continents.
Shanku is single.
His family includes his beloved cat, Newton…
and his faithful manservant, Prahlad.
The two of us were initially
having second thoughts
about whether bringing
all your precious research papers here...
so far from home was a wise decision.
But after seeing the level of security...
that was levied for the safekeeping...
made me much more at ease.
Me too.
- More coffee?
- Yes, please.
You know they produce very good coffee
in this country.
Yes!
I can see that.
I definitely want to take some back
when I go back home.
Good morning!
- Professor T. Shanku?
- Yes.
- Solomon Bloomgarten.
- Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Can we have a talk in private?
A talk?
About what?
I won't take up too much of your time.
Maybe, we can sit at my table.
Alright.
Excuse me.
Excuse us, gentlemen.
Have a seat.
So, Mr. Garden...
Bloom... Bloomgarten.
- Mr. Bloomgarten.
- Call me Sol.
And I'll call you Shank
if you don't mind.
- You'll call me Shank?
- Shank.
Alright, Sol. Let's talk.
After reading your article
in the "Cosmos" magazine...
I've had this desire
to meet with you in person.
When I heard that you're coming here...
I couldn't contain myself anymore.
First thing I did on arriving
was to go and see your exhibition.
Impressive!
- Very impressive!
- Thank you.
- But I have some questions.
- Go ahead.
Can your Annihilin pistol really wipe
every living thing out of existence?
It can.
Oh!
And your Omniscope glasses,
can they function as a microscope?
- A telescope...and
- X-ray device...yes it can.
X-ray device...brilliant.
And your Miracurall pill?
Can it cure any and all diseases?
Well, a couple of pills a day can cure
any disease in two days.
Amongst all the diseases,
can it cure cancer too?
It depends on the stage the cancer is at.
What about the Miracurall ointment?
It can be used to cure snake bites,
injuries, scratches...
you know that kind of thing.
This is the result of a minor car accident I had
about two months ago.
And it still bothers me.
There's a burning pain.
Is that the famous ointment?
Well, I like to carry some of my inventions
with me all the time.
Holy smoke! This is amazing!
Now I know everything I need to know.
Shank, I'm willing to buy the patents
of all four of your inventions immediately.
And I'm willing to pay you
one million dollars for them.
- Sorry, Sol. Not interested.
- Wait, Shank... Please sit...
What are you getting from keeping
all this incredible inventions so secret?
Why are you being so selfish?
Are you really interested in...
Are you really interested
in the public welfare?
Your interest is in the commercial side
of things...
and how you can use my inventions in those.
Isn't it?
Shank, I'm a businessman.
So I'll look at anything
from a business perspective.
What's so surprising about that?
But I am not going to leave you hanging.
I have a cheque book with me right now.
Or if you prefer cash,
that can be managed.
Let me tell you something, Sol.
None of my inventions,
especially the four you mentioned...
can be manufactured in a factory
using machines.
Do you understand that?
I don't believe you.
Then there's nothing I can do about that.
Shank, I'll double my price.
Sol, Sol, Sol...
Even if you offered me 20 million instead of one
my answer would still be the same.
- Shank!
- Tilu...
- Tilu, you are in...
- What's the matter, Nakur?
El... El Dorado...
El Dorado.
Who was that man?
My secretary.
Why did he all of a sudden bring up
El Dorado of all things?
He's done a lot of research on South America,
you see.
So, the fact that he should know
about El Dorado is not surprising.
My ancestors as well as I
on two different occasions in my youth...
have come here to look for El Dorado.
I didn't leave one single country
out of the search, you know.
Finally, I contracted a severe disease...
and I had to quit the search
for my beloved golden city.
And went home soon after.
Coming to Brazil after so long...
I was frequently reminded
of El Dorado yesterday.
And today.
Look Sol, nowadays, everybody knows
that El Dorado is a myth.
- So, there's absolutely no point--
- No, Shank.
I still believe El Dorado exists.
Anyway, I'm staying in this hotel in room 4422.
If you change your mind,
please let me know.
I don't see that happening,
Mr. Bloomgarten.
The nerve of him!
That rascal wants to buy patents
from you?
We also saw that you gave him
some demonstration.
What can I say?
We, scientists, can never resist the temptation
of showing off once in a while.
No, Shanku. You're too soft.
Which is why you have to deal with people
like him.
If he bothers you again, let us know.
We'll put him in his place.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
I've finalised the tour of the rainforest
for you, sir.
- Really?
- Yes.
The day after tomorrow
after breakfast...
we'll be flying out north to Brasilia,
the capital of Brazil.
From there we're going to take a small plane
to a city called Posto Diauarum.
Located just north of the Xingu national forest.
The remainder of the journey will be by boat.
In Brasilia, we're going to be meeting up
a guide called Hyter.
He's quite a unique fellow.
We locally refer to him as a "sertanista"...
Sa-sa-satanista?
The word literally means forest specialist.
He has already been informed
about our arrival.
He'll give us more details of our trip
as soon as we arrive.
So you'll be coming with us?
How can I not?
Professor Rodriguez insisted.
Only when you're on a plane back home
will my task be complete.
What's the matter?
Please don't be offended,
but I couldn't stop myself.
When did this happen?
I fell down in a hurry.
Some water please.
The deed has been done.
What?
It's been done.
What are you talking about?
The research papers of your inventions...
The formulae of my inventions?
What nonsense are you talking about?
Did you dream about it?
It wasn't a dream!
The security guards were bribed...
He entered the exhibition...
- He has copied...
- He?
Who is he, Nakur?
Lobo?
Our very own.
Actually, I couldn't put my thoughts together
in a new place.
That's why Lobo...
Wait... I'll get something for you.
After you get back to your room,
put this ointment on your forehead.
And take this pill now.
What is this?
Cerebrillant pill.
This will keep your head clear
and your emotions too.
But don't be scared.
I'll try my best so that no harm comes to you.
Is it possible for Lobo
to do this on his own?
I'm sure someone is behind this.
Of course.
A very rich man.
Very well done.
Thank you.
One sip is all you need to take, right?
So...
To Dr. Shanku!
- Doctor Shanku!
Good evening!
- Good evening.
- Solomon Bloomgarten. And you are?
NC Biswas--
- You're Prof. Shanku's secretary.
- Yes.
Well Bis, the other day, I heard
you mention El Dorado.
What do you know about the city?
I'm not very educated.
Very ordinary man.
Yesterday, reading a Bengali book
on El Dorado.
Reading... Reading...
Then seeing the city.
In front of my eyes.
That is why...
Seeing the city?
El Dorado?
What a day!
But tell me where is your secretary?
He was somewhere inside
the last time I saw him.
You mean me, here, before, I?
No, no, no...
No...
- I was just talking to them...
- Come on... Scram.
Hi, congratulations!
Please, sit. Please.
Who is this secretary that you've brought?
Why?
This gentleman has got several talents.
He looked me in the eye
and told me everything about myself.
And I've told him I'll hand him over
to Myron.
He'll be rolling in riches overnight.
Your man will be owning a Tesla
in three months time.
Who's Myron?
Holy smoke!
You haven't heard of Myron?
Myron Enterprises. He's the best promoter
and manager there is.
His team of managers have established the careers
of musicians, dancers, singers, even magicians.
And he's already an exceptional man.
But most importantly,
he knows where El Dorado is!
What, sir?
Go on, Bis.
Tell them.
Have you told them that
you know where El Dorado is?
I've told them what I know.
Go, tell them man.
El Dorado is in Brazil.
Definite.
Inside very deep jungle...
Only I know...
Nobody knows.
Nobody stays.
Empty city.
But...
when Sun falls...
the city shines...
Golden gate...
Golden pillar...
Golden pyramid...
Door, window... All gold.
Then...
One time, 1000 years ago...
Heavy rain... very heavy...
Then...
deadly insects...
invade the jungle.
resulting in a cholera epidemic.
All people dead.
Believe me, Tilu, I saw everything play
in front of my eyes just like a movie.
Well! That's it then.
What remains now is for you to organise
an expedition to the Amazon.
For now we're very tired
and would like to leave.
Nakur...
Look, I'm telling you for your own good.
Please don't reveal your abilities
in front of random people.
What do you think?
Do you want to become a stage performer?
You're inexperienced
and you still don't know people.
But if you get stuck with Solomon
you'll be in great danger.
This is my request. Please don't jump
into things without speaking to me.
Please forgive me.
I've made a big mistake.
This is my first time in a foreign country.
I'm from a small town.
That's why I lost my mind.
You've done me a great favour
by warning me.
Okay, I'll take your leave.
We're leaving at 8 a.m.
Hope you remember.
Of course, yes.
I'll be at the lobby.
Did you understand anything?
Understood... A little.
Well, if El Dorado really exists...
Why don't we try to find it?
Incredible!
Even after its existence has clearly been proven
to be a myth.
Are you telling me that Biswas' words
have turned you into a believer?
But leaving all this...
If that rascal Solomon
wants to travel through the forest...
and become dinner to a tribe of cannibals,
I have no problem with that whatsoever.
But I'm not getting involved in all this.
I agree completely with that.
Let's stick to the plan.
Oh, thank heavens!
I'm so disappointed with you.
With me?
Why?
Because you seem not to realise
the potential of your ally...
Your secretary's eyes can see
beyond the mundane.
Ten minutes ago when he was telling us
about his vision of El Dorado...
I got so enraptured
that I couldn't take my eyes off him.
Good morning!
(in Portuguese)
Morning!
Good morning!
I trust you're aware that Mr. Biswas
checked out earlier this morning and left.
Right?
What did you just say?
Due to some apparently urgent work,
he had to leave the city for three days.
And this is for you.
Excuse me.
All check out formalities are done with.
I'll get the car.
- Okay.
Dear Tilu.
Please forgive me.
Couldn't control my urge
to get 20000 dollars.
We are leaving
on the gentleman's private plane.
Our destination is a forest area
350 miles north-west of Sao Paolo.
That's where El Dorado is located.
The foreigner will not be able to reach
the golden city without my help.
I have been forced to give him the directions.
I'll join you once my work here is done.
I am aware your route.
May God bless you.
Yours faithfully,
Nakur Chandra Biswas.
Post script.
Thanks a lot of the Miracurall ointment.
Letter from Biswas?
He's fled, hasn't he?
Yes, he has fled
with that Bloomgarten fellow.
I know that he did it for the money.
He's also said that
he's going to meet up with us
after dropping the foreigners at El Dorado.
Amazing!
Does the man have no self-respect whatsoever?
He dares to show his face amongst our company
even after doing something so base.
Damn it! It's all my fault.
I'm the one who insisted you
to bring him along with us.
Dr. Shanku!
We're all set.
Anyway, don't let this bother you too much.
But from now on, we must stay away from anything
that's paranormal, unnatural and spiritual.
For our own good.
Lobo!
- Hello!
- Hyter.
- Hello.
- Saunders.
- Hyter. Nice to meet you. Kroll
- Kroll.
Our plane is parked out
in another small airport.
Right.
It's a 10-minute drive from here.
- Come on.
- Okay.
How was Sao Paulo?
Very nice.
We'll discuss the plans for the upcoming days
aboard the plane.
If you want to see anything in particular
now is the time to tell me.
Okay but what's your opinion
about El Dorado?
Wow!
In today's modern world,
you're still asking me about El Dorado.
The place has been proven a myth
years ago.
El Dorado isn't even a city.
It is actually a person.
The word "Dorado" can refer to both golden city
or golden person in Portuguese.
Exactly!
The tribal folks started worshipping
a certain individual...
believing him to be the avatar of the Sun God.
And giving him the name El Dorado.
Our present destination is the city
of Posto Diauarum.
From there we'll take a launch
down the Xingu river until we reach Porori.
- Porori...
- Porori.
At Porori, we'll meet the last members
of the Txukahameis tribe.
- Right.
- Oh really!
Who until recently had lived
in their own traditional style.
It's a fascinating tribe!
Fascinating!
I know their language.
So communication is easy.
Yeah.
After leaving Porori...
we'll travel a short distance downriver
and see von Martius Falls.
After which we'll return to Brasilia.
Oh jolly good!
Look to your right!
That the carcass of a cayman alligator.
No matter what you do,
don't put your hands in the water.
This river is rife with voracious piranhas.
What was that?
There's a highway under construction nearby.
They are cutting sections of the forest.
And using dynamite
to break apart the mountains.
How much further?
Soon... Soon...
El Dorado!
My beautiful El Dorado!
It's breathtaking!
Joe, land this thing.
I can't land in such dense overgrowth.
Just find a clearing somewhere.
We should reach the Porori village
by dawn tomorrow.
Good.
I know we're quite deep inside the forest...
but we haven't seen one thing yet.
And what's that?
Anaconda.
It's best we don't run across one of those.
Quite dangerous creatures.
Have you ever seen one of them?
Yes, twice.
We've seen them too.
Well, at the zoo.
Excuse me.
I've read some traveller's articles...
that say this kind of snake
can grow upto 50 metres maybe.
Come on, Wil.
Anyway, I have no regrets
that I haven't seen one of those.
But you'd have to agree what we've seen
of Brazil's rainforest is just simply--
It's a jaguar...
What's that?
I'll tell you later.
But first Lobo...
It's alright, Lobo.
The danger's gone.
You're safe now.
You're safe.
I went behind the bushes to relieve myself.
I saw in front of me...
What happened?
Forgive me, professor.
I've wronged you.
How have you wronged me?
I night before the presentation, I...
I bribed the security guards and...
And entered the exhibition hall.
And scanned my research papers...
Gave them to Solomon.
Is that right?
He offered me money, professor.
A huge sum of money.
What's going to happen to me now?
Okay.
- Once I get back to the city...
- We can think about that later.
We can think about that later.
For now, just rest.
Just rest.
Please forgive me.
Yes.
Go to sleep.
(praying)
Yes.
But how did you even know about this?
Oh, you know, my secretary.
And even after knowing about this,
you didn't think of telling us.
Damn it, Shanku!
What would be the point?
There's no proof.
Because your loss is incalculable.
You're going to be ruined.
If I could just get my hands on Solomon,
right now.
I would boil him and invite
local cannibal tribes to feast on him.
But if Mr. Biswas knew about Lobo's treachery
does that mean that El Dorado is also...
That wasn't dynamite.
Is there a volcano nearby?
- Coffee.
- Thank you.
It smells good.
Coffee?
Thanks.
Porori is just a mile and a half.
Jeremy, the wheel!
The arrow was dipped in curare poison.
Curare poison.
Just keep calm.
Should I take the next bend?
Yes, yes.
Hyter?
It seems we're out of danger for now.
Don't you think?
Yes.
He's got a pulse
but it's very faint.
Curare is a very potent poison.
It'll take him some time to...
In that case, let's get some distance
between us and the tribals.
And stop the boat.
There's no point in going
forward without Hyter.
Professor...
Did you have any idea
that you're travelling with...
one of the world's most celebrated
and genius inventors?
I suspected something like that yesterday.
And today...
But tell me...
What could have caused the Txukahameis tribe
to be so riled up?
I think this might be related to the explosion
we heard last evening.
They still believe these large scale
natural disasters to be acts of God...
showing his divine displeasure.
And they start panicking.
Shanku! Shanku!
That's not going to work, Tilu.
Hey, are you happy now?
This is incredible!
Thank you.
Tell me, Tilu.
Has my ability improved?
Did you find the image blurry or unclear?
Close to real life, isn't it?
All thanks to you.
I wouldn't be able to do it
if it wasn't for you.
What do you mean?
Your medicine.
All thanks to Cerebrillant!
Your pill has made be doubly capable.
- Really?
- Yes.
Let me introduce you.
Joe, come.
This is pilot, Joe Hopgood.
He brought me here in Solomon's plane.
We had to use the small boat
for the last few miles.
Nice to meet you Mr. Hopgood.
And El Dorado?
I made him see it from the plane.
The way I showed you the snake.
Exactly like that.
Wait. Here.
SOUTH AMERICAN EXPEDITION
BRAZIL
This is the book on Brazil.
Look at this.
This is the photo of the snake.
And see this.
This is a fictional drawing of El Dorado.
Where will I find a photo?
This looks very amateurish.
Of course, it is.
And this is what you showed Solomon?
He was elated!
Then what happened?
First let me tell you what happened
on the last day of the conference.
Last day?
What happened?
You already know.
Whatever is going to happen...
if we already know about it...
it can be of a great advantage.
That's what happened to me too.
To Dr. Shanku!
Doctor Shanku!
(singing in foreign language)
Just say we actually end up finding El Dorado
with Bis' help. What then?
I'll make him my ace in the hole.
And take him back to the United States.
Not exploiting his remarkable talents
would be a huge mistake.
But I don't trust our pilot, Joe.
Once he finds out the location of El Dorado.
What guarantee do we have
that he's not going to backstab us?
No, he must be taken care of.
The credit of finding El Dorado should be mine.
I, Solomon Bloomgarten and no one else.
Fine, I'll handle Joe after we get back here.
Make it look like an accident.
An accident.
Absolutely!
And what about Professor Shanku's inventions?
We'll take care of that when we return.
We have the goods.
Why worry?
Now my priority is El Dorado.
What a dangerous man!
That's when I decided
I had to tell him about El Dorado!
Otherwise, the next part of my vision
won't take place.
Although, it didn't take much effort to find him.
- Good evening.
Solomon Bloomgarten.
And you are?
I told Sol everything about himself.
And I told him about El Dorado.
Sol was very happy.
The next day's plans were charted out.
And you already know
what happened after that.
I was just speaking to them.
Hi, congratulations!
Please, sit. Please.
Now let me tell you what happened
after I showed him El Dorado.
The city is hidden in dense forest.
How will the plane land there?
We landed it.
In a relatively empty area.
Bis, I was forgetting something.
There you are.
As promised.
Bis, Joe come.
Come.
Come...
We don't have time. Come...
This was on the plane.
In Solomon's luggage.
All the scanned copies of the formulae is here.
It's still here.
But what will happen when Solomon finds
that El Dorado doesn't exist.
Solomon?
Where is Solomon?
He is not there in this world anymore.
When we entered the forest
it was 5:30 p.m.
And when we fled them...
it was quarter to six.
Stop!
Where did they go?
Bis! Joe!
Go find them.
Maybe they've fallen behind.
That double crossing...
What the... Meteorite!
Run!
Yesterday's explosion.
I already knew about this incident
because of you.
A man like you...
I'm honoured to be in your company.
How can I let go of your enemy so easily?
- How long back to Brasilia, Joe?
- A couple of hours.
- Lovely weather. It must be nice to fly here.
- Yes.
- See you on the plane.
- Alright.
Sorry, Lobo.
If there was room on the plane
I would have taken you.
- But...
- No problem.
I'll put him on a plane to Sao Paulo
once we get back to Brasilia.
Thank you.
Hey, guys!
We're ready to leave.
But... But...
What's going to happen to me now?
Since all my research has been recovered
safe and sound...
I don't think we'll need
to lodge a complaint against you.
I've taken many a group
on a tour of the forest before.
But I'll never forget this trip
with you folks ever.
And professor...
I owe you my life.
My pleasure.
Joe!
I couldn't show them the falls...
(in Portuguese)
Could you take a detour and...
So, that's it.
It's done then.
We've seen everything we set out to see.
Everything but one thing.
And what's that?
As he is already with us...
I wonder if we could see El Dorado
through his eyes.
- Bad drawing. Very bad.
- Come on. Even so...
Then why see El Dorado through Biswas' eyes?
You can see it through my eyes.
Through your eyes?
What do you mean?
Don't forget that the medicine I gave Biswas
that night was my invention.
Cerebrillant.
Unbelievable!