-Now what you've just
seen is a reenactment
of a successful
interdiction operation
that took place six years ago.
Interdiction and
protective reaction.
Those will be your
areas of duty.
This unit, which are also
hot to become members of,
came about because of the events
that occurred in the early 60s,
that is the only effective
means of combating
political assassination
by the interception
and the destruction of
the assassin himself.
Now you might have
been carefully selected
for this program, because
of a high level performance
in the battlefield
and your high level
performance in
physical endurance.
But as your training
progresses, you will gradually
reach a point of acceptance
where you will begin to surpass
everything that you
have ever done before.
You will reach goals that
you never dreamed possible.
And to accomplish this,
you will be given vitamins
to increase your stamina,
chemical injections to expand
your mental capabilities,
injections to assist you
in both physical
and mental control.
You will be
programmed to respond
instantaneously to
any given stimulus.
You will become a reflex
but highly directive unit.
Of course, you
will be taught how
to use everyday
objects as weapons.
Everything from a toenail
clipping to a briefcase.
Control, control
will be emphasized
throughout your training.
Control, control is the key.
When you're finished here, you
will be assigned to safeguard
specific individuals
and institutions.
And because of your
training here, it
will be set apart
from other security
agencies and military
establishments.
In other words, you will
operate independently.
I am your commanding officer.
You will refer to me
only as Mr. Trevor.
Your second in command,
you will address
him only as Mr. Lassiter.
-Stand.
What's your project?
- Kill.
-Again.
-What's your priority?
-Dossiers on the new men.
-Just leave them on the desk.
-One of them had a
couple of tours in Nam.
Looks like a top prospect
for a VIP bodyguard.
I'd say reaction to the film
was excellent, didn't you?
-Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I wonder what the
star of that film
looks like today.
-John, the original
concept of the project is--
-I've had the project
for six years, Frank.
I've had enough.
-OK.
Now you're the head of it.
Doesn't that mean something?
-The program has changed.
Can't you see that?
The project is different.
It's more drugs now,
more mind control.
-Well, it's necessary--
-The whole thing
is wrong, Frank.
-Have you had your
injections today, John?
-Want some water?
-Nope.
What about the injections?
-No, I had no injections today.
-What you're thinking
is dangerous.
-What are you talking about,
the drugs or the project?
-Both.
Withdrawal has
got to be gradual.
You need to be deprogrammed.
If you're not deprogrammed,
you'll be a menace to society,
to yourself, and you know that.
-Deprogramming takes months.
-Nobody gets out of here.
Not you, especially not you.
-I've been training
robots here for six years,
for offensive purposes,
that's what I've been told.
That's what I tell them.
Now two weeks ago,
got three teams
of graduate trainees
sent on missions abroad.
You know, I've sensed
this for two years now.
I think it's true.
We're being used for
offensive missions.
-That's necessary, John.
-Oh, don't give me that crap.
Wasn't born yesterday,
didn't get here on a mule,
and neither did you.
We're being trained as hit men.
We can be used as
political, corporate,
and commercial weapons.
And you know damn well that's
exactly what's happening.
-So what the hell are
you going to do about it?
-What can I do?
I know what I can do.
I can hold a press
conference, blow the whistle
on this Pandora's box, and put
the whole thing down the toilet
where it belongs.
-You can't do that,
and you won't do that.
-Frank, I'm going out.
-Lassiter 712.
Yeah.
Get me a medical survey team
over here as soon as possible.
Yeah.
-I'm sorry, Frank.
-Mr. Trevor, please
step out of the car.
-Anything wrong?
-I'll have to see
your identification.
-You should never go into
action without a recon
in the area, friend.
-Our old friend,
Hook, ambushed me.
-You son of a bitch.
One of these years
when you've managed
to drag your ass to Manila,
without any advance planning,
I'm going to put
another hole in it
for you, whether I
know who you are not.
-I have to see an
old friend, Carl.
You all right, Hook?
-Never mind about that, you two.
Let's have a drink.
Hook, break open the
good booze, will you?
As for you, you S.O.B.,
you've got about two minutes
before the bourbon
hits the glass.
And I want a complete
rundown of your activities
for the last four years.
Now let's make it.
Underwater detonations
were always more dangerous.
The VC put two shells
into my destroyer.
I know.
-You were always meant
for sea command, Carl.
That's why Polish had never
even listed you in that project.
-Hit him again.
He's getting behind.
Project.
I should have quit that after
that training film we made.
What the hell ever
happened to that anyway?
-It's around.
-All that training.
Me and Hook, we were the best.
Oh, we drew-- we drew
a rough assignment,
but I tell you when
that ship's magazine
when out, it was a sight to see.
-No, Carl, I'll never
forgive the project
for what it did to you.
To you both.
And it's happening to us all.
Mentally.
-You mean, they
went on with that?
After the war, all of it?
That's not right for you.
-Why do you say that?
-I can see it in
your face, John.
Cut them loose.
Let them sink in
their own swill.
-Maybe I've done that.
-Hey.
You OK?
-Yeah, no, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
-Look then, why don't you
come out here with us?
We can have a crew
again, just the three of us.
Huh?
-Thing's can't be the
way they were, Carl.
-Just remember, John, you
can't forget the past.
-I know that.
That's the trouble.
And I've got to keep moving.
-Come on, hit him again.
He's fallen behind.
All right, a toast.
Here's to the sweet
ladies
and their silk dresses.
-Trevor was part of
the top secret vote
of the United States.
There are many other
that are
willing to pay any
price for what he knows.
We will comb the entire
island resort if we have to.
But I want him alive.
-Yes, sir.
-We will find the man, sir.
-Yes, sir, Mr. Lee.
-Is he asleep?
Well, we were damn good
sailors once, Hook,
in all kinds of water.
You think I need that?
The way I figure it, we got
$300,000 in the kitty, right?
I'm going to take half.
You keep half.
When's the last time you
took him to the doctor?
Two, what, weeks?
When he wrote to me, and
said there was a chance
that the deterioration
could be arrested.
They still feel that way?
All right, when I get
to wherever I-- wherever
I'm going, I'll
refill the kitty.
You tell him I won't
be back for a while,
so some kind of
military insurance,
or change in the law,
or something
handle that.
At least we could
buy back his legs,
or give him a day on a
destroyer.
You go on to bed.
I know where my bunk is.
And the
of the shore shall
pluck the eagle of the sea.
-Got time for coffee?
Didn't mean to upset you.
-You don't sleep
very late, do you?
-Time enough for that
when I'm old and infirmed.
I poured one for you.
You know, you're about
as sneaky as an elephant.
-Thank you.
I'll remember that the next
time I'm in a tight spot.
-You better remember
it before then
if you want to get your
butt out of that tight spot.
-I'm going to take the old car.
Head out to the countryside.
-Just avoid crowds.
I checked this morning.
Things are going around.
-I need a boat, Carl.
-Give me a couple days,
then call that number.
His name's Kitolis.
-When's the last
time you saw me?
- in 1970.
-What'd I look like?
-Like hell.
-What will you do
when you see me again?
-Lay you on your butt for
the $20 you still owe me.
-If anybody comes
by, I wasn't here.
-Friends?
-Who's got friends, Carl?
-OK.
There's your man.
-Mr. Lassiter.
I'm Lynn Walker.
I'm the US Officer.
Is there any cover story for
the press on this situation?
-No.
There's not going to be.
-Well, we'll have to
tell them something.
-Well, that's fine.
do the telling.
You see, Mr. Trevor's
a very dangerous man.
I think it's best we keep
it from the local press.
-Well, I have my job to
do, too, Mr. Lassiter,
and I intend to do it.
-Mr. Lassiter.
I'm Inspector Cruz.
Yours, please?
This is my associate,
Inspector Ortiz.
-How do you do, Mr. Lassiter.
-Please follow us.
- You see, we thought
he might be here in Manila.
He mentioned a few
people, no one by name,
so we suggest you
begin by screening
the American community,
discreetly, of course.
-You spent some
time in Hong Kong.
You must know there
are others interested
in Mr. Trevor's whereabouts.
Mr. Ortiz.
-A private plane just arrived
at the Manila International
carrying seven
undesirable passengers
by an indirect route
through
or from Hong Kong.
-You know them?
-Uh-hmm.
A man called Alok Lee,
an international trader.
-In what?
Anything of value.
-Of course, they are
under observation, but--
-But what?
-We were ordered to stand off.
Mr. Lassiter.
What do you know?
-How should I know?
-Of course, how should you know?
Obviously, there's
something of great value
involved to bring
Alok himself here.
- He had the.
- The.
Such things could be handled
through intermediaries
and usually are.
-Uh, Inspector, I have no other
information I can give you.
-I see.
Well, then, perhaps before
you retire to your hotel
you might ease my
apprehension in another area.
-Sure, if I can.
-What was Trevor's
motive for all this?
-OK.
He has an illness.
About three weeks ago, he went
through his annual physical
at Walter Reed.
It's a malignancy.
It's terminal.
And it's inoperable.
You see, Inspector,
he's a man who
worked for government
agencies all of his life.
He lived in a sterile apartment
with sterile people around him.
-He wasn't paid well?
-Oh, yeah, quite well, but let's
say not well enough to cover
a lifetime of
experiences he never had.
A man like that wants the
best, and it takes money.
The plates are worth
millions, and, uh, with them
he can buy himself a new
life regardless of how short
it might be.
At least that's how we
look at it.
-I see.
-Oh, Ortiz, when you
get back, talk to Cruz.
I didn't get Miss Walker back
to her desk at the embassy.
-The big one is Lassiter.
-Why so quiet?
I thought you were an
accomplished conversationalist.
-They told me about the man
you killed in the garage.
It was an accident, Miss
Walker, just an accident.
-That accident was
on foreign soil.
It may not concern
you, but I'm the one
who has to make the explanation.
-Well, you're the
picture of efficiency.
It shouldn't be too
difficult for you.
Hey, look, as long as we're
stuck with one another,
let's try to get along, OK?
-The man you're after is
a man like you, isn't he?
-He's not like me.
He's a lot better at
his job than I am.
Excuse me.
Lassiter, I have a reservation.
-Mr. Lassiter?
-Yes.
-We expected you last night.
If you don't mind,
registration, sir?
Oh, by the way, a friend of
yours waiting at the bar.
-A friend of mine?
-Yes, sir, that's what he said.
-Did you tell
anyone I was coming?
-No.
-Uh, where's this bar of yours?
-Straight ahead, sir.
-Thank you.
-Can I help you, sir?
-Yes, I was wondering if you
could get me a room next to Mr.
Lassiter's?
We are going to be conducting
some business here,
and we need to
confer frequently.
-See anyone you know?
-No.
-Mr. Lassiter.
Well, Mr. Lassiter,
it's been a long time.
How have you been?
-Do I know you?
-In a way.
You and your friend tried to
wreck our car in the garage
this morning.
-Oh, yeah.
Excuse me a minute, boys.
Miss Walker, go
look at the fish.
Pretty fish.
Anyway, Pancho, you said
something about the garage?
-I just want you to know that
we don't hold any grudge.
-I do.
-You're joking.
-See you, boys.
-Hey, wait a minute.
You and your lady friend
Have a drink with us.
-OK.
- Me and my.
Right, Ramon?
-Careful, Mr. Lassiter, don't
have any more accidents.
-How are the pretty fish?
-Lassiter here.
- I
- have a coded message for you.
Can you take it?
-Yeah.
Security one code.
-OK, ready.
It's
one, eight, windfall, 63--
043 your location.
Copy?
-OK.
Proceed immediately on this.
-I have it, sir.
Is this the only contact here?
Yes, act fast,
or he'll
the whole program.
-No, I know that, sir.
He's dangerous.
-Yeah, I know he's dangerous.
Find him.
Get it finished.
-Right away, sir.
-Are you all right?
-What?
I saw you from over there.
-No, I'm fine.
I'm just fine, thank you.
Just a minute.
What, uh, what's your name?
Where do you come from?
-My name's Lee Su
from the lodge.
-Uh, Lee Su, stay with me.
-All right.
Walk with me.
What's your name?
-Ryder, uh, Bill Ryder.
-Mr. Ryder.
-You're staying
here at the lodge?
-Uh-huh.
-Have you been here long?
-A few days.
-I just came in myself.
I'm glad you're here.
I, uh, hope that we'll
see each other again.
-I hope so, too.
The lonely
world is a lonely place
where a lonely time
is shared by all.
Summer, winter,
springtime and fall.
It never rains, but
it always pours.
And the lonely streets
are filled with tears.
From crying eyes that
wasted the years.
I reached out--
-Good evening, sir.
Table for one, sir?
-Uh, no, thank you.
I see somebody I know.
Hello.
-Hello.
-May I join you?
-Please.
-Have you ordered?
-No.
I was hoping someone
might join me.
-Hmm.
-Mr. Ryder.
Are you all right?
-Oh, yea, I'm fine.
Just too much night
life, I guess.
Well, cheers.
-Cheers.
-Is today the day?
Found his mothership, did they?
How many?
And it's not the law?
Have a drink Mr. Hook.
Prepare to do battle.
Answer to a prayer.
Open up the door, Mr. Wagner.
We know
you're in there.
if you cooperate,
there will be no trouble.
You are talking to the
, Mr. Wagner.
Open this door.
-Mr. Wagner, let me commend you.
A formidable bit of resistance.
But now that this
is all over, I want
you to tell me what
your friend Trevor is.
-You go to hell.
-Mr. Wagner, I do not want
you to endure more pain.
Trevor has something
I'm interested in,
and for which I have a customer.
You cannot win now, Mr. Wagner.
The spade will pierce
your mask of thought.
When I get out of here, I
will get what I want from you.
Foolish, Mr. Wagner.
Foolish and--
- It's.
Beautiful.
- Beautiful.
-No, it's a word I haven't
used for a long time.
-Why?
-Well, I just traveled
in the wrong circles.
-You're a strange
man, Mr. Ryder.
But I think I like you.
Shall we walk?
-May I see your ID, please?
Well, Mr. Lassiter.
Strange meeting you here.
Coincidence no doubt.
-What happened?
-A battle, obviously.
-Oh.
Miss Walker, if this is a
bit much for your stomach,
you can, uh, wait in the car.
OK, Cruz, how'd you
find out about--
-Routine investigation.
A dossier on Trevor
was most interesting.
It will be in the
name of history.
We cross check that
with a list of Americans
who live here in Manila.
And we came up with one
man who served with him.
Carl Wagner.
A winner of the Navy Cross
for gallantry in action.
Gallantry, Mr. Lassiter.
You know what the word means?
-Who can afford gallantry
these days, Cruz?
-You may be right, of
course it is an old word,
but not everyone
has forgotten it.
-Where is he?
-Outside.
-Oh, my god.
-What are you going
to do about this?
--his
associates from Hong Kong.
At the moment, nothing.
-How'd he find out about Wagner?
-How did you find
out about Wagner?
-Operator, I've been
trying for a half an hour.
Wagner.
Wagner, W-A-G-N-E-R.
That's right.
That's the number.
Disconnected when?
All right, fine.
Thank you.
-Is something wrong?
-I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to wake you.
No, there's nothing wrong.
Just trying to
contact an old friend.
It's OK.
-Don't you sleep?
-Old habits hard to break.
-You've seen much trouble
haven't you, Mr. Ryder?
-A little.
-You have no monopoly on that.
-On what?
-Trouble.
-I know that, too, but I'm a
little concerned about my own,
though.
-Yes, because you
know them best.
You want much in life.
I mean, of life.
-Not much.
All I know is I don't want
what I've had anymore.
And I don't know
what's up front,
because I'm used to that.
I'm feeling like a--
like a kid, weak inside.
If I cashed out tomorrow,
not a single person
would ever know I existed.
And really, I'd just be
another dead soldier.
And I think that what
I want is someone
who really cares
that I've been alive.
You know, someone I can trust.
And someone who would trust me.
A woman.
-It's not a want, same as I.
-Oh, who the hell
knows what they want
or who the hell knows anything?
-I am but one, and
you want many things.
-Well, you see how foolish I am.
-No.
Dreaming is not foolish.
I will dream with you.
And if you also want,
I will love you.
-That was Trevor.
Hurry.
Let's go.
-Hold on.
I think we've got company.
-You idiot.
-Mr. Cruz asked me to
join him this morning.
-Now, first things first,
a letter from your agency.
-I already won Mr. Lassiter.
-Excuse me.
Pardon me, Chief Inspector Cruz.
-Yes.
-You have a telephone
call on our private phone.
Urgent, please.
-Thank you.
Excuse me.
-Have you been in counselor
service long, Miss Walker?
-Four years.
-Dedicated?
-Well, of course.
-This is a secret priority
one message I read
and I understand it.
-What shou I do?
What would you do with it?
-Well, shred it and burn it.
-I can't do that here.
-I don't understand
what you're getting at.
-Oh, if you're really dedicated,
you'd grab it and eat it.
Then you wouldn't use a
public toilet for two weeks.
-We just got some
information of your friend.
-What?
- Mr. Cruz.
-Go ahead.
We have just confirmed a
report that Mr. Trevor was seen
this morning accompanied
by a Chinese woman
along the vicinity of
Lake Lodge.
There is also a report
from the highway patrol
that this same vehicle was
involved in a high speed
racing along the Lake Highway.
-Where is he?
-There is no further report,
sir, except that the vehicle
was not apprehended and
has not been sighted since.
Well, how far is this
Lake.
-Just a short trip by rail.
-Why don't we get up
there, like, right away?
-Everything has been
arranged for, Mr. Lassiter.
- You have 45 minutes
to.
-Give me a few minutes.
I'll throw a few things in my
bag, and I'll be right down.
-So you have 45 minutes.
If
you had taken proper security
measures to begin with,
that phone conversation
never would have happened.
Time is getting short.
-I'm aware of the time element.
Nine days is all we can expect.
-What?
Well, he's already gone 10 days.
-He's beyond normal restraints.
-Sir, I have another
hot tip for you.
Somebody took my medication.
-And your last injection?
-About 30 hours.
I assume
it was in your attache case.
Did they steal that, too?
-Yeah.
You Trevor.
-But what happens if I
don't get to him in time?
What happens if he goes
completely off the deep end?
If you're still capable of
handling the operation quietly
with no publicity,
we can alleviate--
-But personally,
sir, I don't give
a damn about the publicity.
What about the man?
What do I do?
-This is a priority
one situation,
which with serious
international implications.
You may have no choice.
Bring him back or
I'll eliminate him.
-I just wanted to
hear you say it, sir.
Miss Walker, who authorized
this trip anyway?
-I told you before.
I can take care of myself.
I authorize my own trips, and
I go where I feel I have to go.
And let me give you a
bit of advice, Mister.
Pull any more of your
superiority gimmicks,
and this is one
Ratclife girl who
can have you deported
in nothing flat.
-Oh, really?
-That's right.
And I mean it.
-All right, by all means,
be my guest, Miss Walker.
-I'd like to remind
you, gentlemen, we
have no way of finding
out how many, if any,
of the Hong Kong
are still
in the vicinity.
So this trip is primarily
one of investigation.
Sergeant, please
see to our seats.
-Yes, sir.
-Lassiter, are you ready?
-Not really, Cruz, I can't
get used to the heat out here.
-Something you'll have to bear.
Let's go.
-Everybody, get down.
Get an ambulance.
How's Ortiz?
-It's not serious.
No major organs damaged.
In fact, he'll be released
in a couple of weeks.
You reacted very quickly.
It could have been worse.
-OK, OK.
So I'm a terrific person.
What about Trevor?
-Well, since the attack was
made before we left the depot,
I assume that Alok
is still in Manila.
Which leads me to conclude
that Trevor is also here.
He'll be located.
-Hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
What if your
assumption is wrong?
What if he doesn't
have the time,
and what if he bumps
the car in the meantime?
- There are only so many
people on who
could or would help
him off the island.
And we know all of them.
-And Alok doesn't know
those people, too?
Look, we're not
dealing with a moron.
Alok
business is abroad.
Listen, it would be
of great help to us
if you were to cooperate fully.
And stop withholding
information intentionally.
-Oh, gee.
Come on.
We're back to that one, huh?
-We never left
there Mr. Lassiter.
Look, if I were to accept your
excuse for wanting
Trevor, I'd have to ask
many more questions.
I don't think that's necessary.
If Alok wanted those things,
he'd have bought them.
But what he wants is
the man, and that's
quite a different thing.
-What's different?
Hmm?
Mr. Lassiter, the difference
is that if you want
to play game, you
can go do it somewhere else.
Not in my country.
-I think you forget.
I am here by accident,
not choice or design.
-That's precisely my point.
Look, the stupidity,
the stupidity of which
this operation has
been handled has
been nothing but a complicated
situation from the start.
-I agree.
Because I'm not directing it.
-I know.
But when you're in the
Philippine's, I am.
And Mr. Lassiter.
you will cooperate, or
you can get the hell out.
What
are you doing for him?
, that is all.
That is not all.
You tell us what arrangements
did you make with him?
None.
He boat
to contact me again.
What
does he want from you?
A boat.
Did
he ask for that?
No, no.
Wagner called.
He said that, uh--
So, ah-ah,
you lied about Wagner.
Please,
please, I just sell service
and that is all.
You are going to
tell us everything about this.
Do you hear me?
Everything.
Do you understand?
No, no, I--
-You have a friend named Wagner?
-Yes.
-So do I. What can I do for you?
-I have a business
proposition for you.
-You might come in
and talk about it.
-Yes, that's exactly
what I have in mind.
-They work for Alok Lee
and international dealer
from Hong Kong.
-Who's this?
-My secretary.
They killed the poor man.
He couldn't tell them
what he didn't know.
-And you?
-They mentioned Wagner.
And a man named Trevor.
You?
-What about Wagner?
-He's dead.
-What?
-He is dead.
-You have any liquor here?
-Yes.
-Then pour two drinks, and
pour them where I can see you.
I need a boat.
-I know.
-Tonight.
-Out of the
question, impossible.
It would take at least a week.
I'll give you $50,000, two days.
-$75,000, three days.
The best I can do.
-All right, it's a deal.
There's $50,000, and
I'll call you tomorrow.
There'll be two of us.
-Two?
In that case the
price will be $25,000.
-Well, Mr. Wagner
and I have done
much business over the years.
Profitable business I might add.
-Yeah, I know all about it.
Here's to fools and sailors.
-Well, well, Miss Walker, if
you don't stop following me,
I'm going to call the police.
-I'm working with the police.
-Oh, yeah, I forgot.
I'm sorry.
-You've been drinking.
-Damn, I wish I could.
Hey, could I offer you one?
We can't be machines
all the time, you know.
-I don't drink on duty.
-It won't rust your gears.
-No thank you.
-Miss Walker, for someone who's
done so much for their country,
you deserve a little enjoyment.
-Well, there is one
little bit of enjoyment
I will allow myself.
-OK.
-Before I left for
the train today,
I received a message
from my director
asking me to call
off this thing.
You arranged that, didn't you?
-No, I didn't.
But it's cool, because
you don't belong here,
and I don't want you here.
-Oh, man's work, is that it?
-Golly, you guessed it.
-It was all right
a few seconds ago
when you wanted a few
creature comforts.
-You guessed it again.
-Oh, you are a son of a bitch.
-Lee Su.
Forgive me.
-Why?
Why did you--
-Please, believe me.
I can't help it.
-I don't understand.
-I take drugs.
drugs.
I mean it that I'm part
of a military program,
and I train men to kill.
I train them, and
I am one of them.
And we use drugs
in the programs.
I've taken myself off the drugs,
but they're part of my control.
Without them, my response
is I wake up dangerous.
I thought I could handle it.
And I need.
- The.
I brought it.
-Where?
Give it to me.
Get some water.
It's not the same
anymore for me.
I don't know where
it's different,
but it is different for me now.
And when all of
this is out of me--
-Shh.
The pills.
-Yeah, pills.
That's something different.
That's never happened before.
Interesting.
He said, I'm not
programmed for love.
-Remember what I said.
Tell him no more, no
less, but get him here.
-Yes.
Yes, it is.
I have it all arranged.
This afternoon.
At the old wharf
near the dry dock
and bring the rest of the money.
Very well.
I'll be waiting for you.
-Excellent.
Excellent.
Very well done.
-Now may I-- aaah.
-A most interesting analysis.
The attache case we found
in Mr. Lassiter's room
was quite interesting.
,
manipulative, mind drugs,
and yet in Mr.
Lassiter's attache
case-- tell me, old friend.
Did Trevor appear
pale when you saw him?
-No.
-Did his hand shake?
-I don't know.
-His eyes, how
did his eyes look?
-I don't know.
I don't know.
-You are not very
observant, old friend.
I was so certain you would
have much to tell me.
I told you I would pay you
for your services, didn't I?
-No, wait.
I helped you.
I did as you asked.
-We'll burn some incense
for you, dear friend.
-No, no.
You promised me.
We had a deal.
No, no, please.
-Yes, you are being
paid to have no fear.
I leave you in very
experienced hands.
It will be a beautiful thing.
He's an artiste.
-Well, good morning Miss Walker.
-Headache, Mr. Lassiter?
You know, Kitolis who
lives here specializes
in procurements of all kinds.
Either he or Trevor left
two bodies here yesterday.
And, uh, William.
-You going to tell
me where Trevor is?
-Stop it.
Stop that.
We can use him.
-Inspector, I didn't
throw one killing punch.
-Well, it's a good thing you
didn't, because he knows a lot.
We'll make him talk.
He'll talk.
I promise you, you can
finish him off if he doesn't.
-Well, Cruz, I hope that
dude was telling the truth.
How far is it to this wharf?
-Just a few minutes.
Our surface unit should
be closing in now
quietly, no sirens.
-I'm against this.
You know, if we go
in there like
a squad of marines,
Trevor might, might break.
-Thank you Mr. Lassiter.
It's unfortunate
that your superiors
didn't give you another option.
-Frank.
I know what you're going to do.
You're going to try to
take him alone, aren't you?
-The only thing I can do.
-But what if he
doesn't listen to you?
What if he resists?
-All right.
No matter what happens,
you stay here in the car.
It's going to be all
right, but don't you
move until I get back.
-Mr. Ryder.
Will you kiss me?
-Mr. Trevor.
We are about to meet at last.
There is no need
to hide from me.
You are completely surrounded.
Cut off.
And we have the girl.
-Who are you?
-That doesn't matter, does it?
You have something I want,
and I have something you want.
-All right.
What do you want?
-Come out without your weapon.
And I'll come out without mine.
We can settle this with
no further trouble.
Come, Mr. Trevor Here is
Mr. Lassiter's attache case.
We'll leave for you.
-Frank Lassiter's here?
-Come closer.
I do not want to shout.
-This is what you get.
Now what?
-Very well.
Project Kill is what I want.
I want to know
everything about it.
I will trade you
the girl's life.
That and a considerable sum of
money in any currency you name.
-Where's my boat?
-Your contact had an accident.
You can have this boat if
you agree to my request.
The girl will be
returned to you.
You have my word.
-Who are you?
Just a businessman.
-Let the girl go now.
-I cannot do that Mr. Trevor.
I have invested a
large sum in you.
If I want to do one more
to get what I want, I will.
-You've been following me for
some time now, haven't you?
-Do not use the word following.
Investigate is a better word.
It started from Mr.
Wagner, and, uh--
- I want to get on that wharf
is wasting.
-All right.
For the first time, men, keep
your fire above their heads.
, you
tell the chopper
to stop that boat at
the end of the wharf.
OK, Lassiter, it's your show.
-Aah, ah.
Mr. Trevor, please.
I did not do anything.
I left her back there.
Mr. Trevor, please, please.
I keep.
Please.
Aah.
-And this is for an old friend.
And this is for the sailor.
-John, you've got to
come back with me.
-I'm not going back, Frank.
-I'll have to take ya.
-I'm going around you.
If you think you can take
me, go ahead and try.
Otherwise, step aside.
-You know what I have to do.
You taught me.
Priority one and all that.
-Well, that's your
problem, isn't it, Frank?
-John.
-What's wrong, Frank?
-Come back, John.
-What's the matter?
Need some help?
-Ye-aagh.
-Now they're going
to come after you.
-Your briefcase, Mr. Lassiter.
Now they're
going to come after you.