Where the hell's that doctor?
She's 10 minutes late.
Relax, she'll be here.
We're wasting time.
I should've kept that blood
and done this myself.
Why is it that every
time you take matters
into your own hands, you screw things up?
You've made enough enemies around here.
People don't trust you.
Why?
Because of Greg's death?
I didn't have any time.
Stop.
You know, you can't go
around taking people out,
just because you feel threatened.
Who are you kiddin', Miller?
You'd have done the same thing yourself.
It's about time you got here.
Have you finished with your tests?
Where did you get this blood?
Never mind where we got it.
What's the problem?
This.
It's an extra chromosome.
That means it's not human.
Who cares?
Is it diseased?
You know there's been
a lot of speculation
about the origin of this blood.
Well, you know better than to, um,
believe these kinds of rumors.
Don't you, Doctor?
We'll find out eventually.
It's your job to tell us
if the blood is diseased,
nothing more.
Is this all that's left of the blood?
Where the hell's the rest of it?
That's all we have.
There's nothing left for us.
I have to warn you.
If you should use it on anyone,
the body's immune system will treat it
like an infection.
The subject's blood will putrefy
into a puss-like fluid.
The body will swell up like a balloon.
There'll be vomiting and fever.
And the result will be a horrifying death.
Well, now, that's not
a very pretty picture.
Is it, Doctor?
I assure you we are doing
nothing out of line.
You dragged your feet on
this long enough, Doctor.
How long's it take to get an answer?
I can't tell you that.
I'm going as fast as I can.
You'll have to excuse us, Doctor,
but we're all under a
lot of pressure here.
We need an answer.
I'll try to get it done by next week.
But I can't promise.
I'm not waiting another week.
Why don't I just take the blood?
Because I'm not gonna let you.
Your hands are tied until she signs off.
Nobody ties my hands.
I spent most of my life
lookin' for this blood.
I'm not waiting.
Now you're gonna follow our game plan,
because if you don't, they're
gonna take a hard look
at what we're doing here,
and I don't want anyone reviewing us yet.
It'd drag both of our careers down.
And just so's you know,
I'm not gonna let that happen.
Are you very clear on that?
You worry too much, Miller.
Butler!
You okay?
What are you lookin' at?
Get outta here!
Yes, sir.
What is this
shape-changing crap?
Forget the way and
could have gotten dark power
that descend from werewolves.
Butler!
What the hell's going on here?
Leave it off.
The light hurts my eyes.
What did you do with the blood?
You took it, didn't you?
Of course, I did.
There's nothing left.
You took the last of it.
Now we'll have lots
of blood to work with,
right here,
in me.
Wow, you idiot, you could've died.
But I didn't.
Did I?
Have the doctors look at that.
I don't need anybody looking at it.
It's working.
The blood's changing me.
My senses are so keen I can hear Dr Taylor
and Dr Barnes making fun
about our trip to Budapest.
Get to the infirmary now.
Damn you, Miller, you're
not even listening to me.
I can hear your heartbeat.
It's going a little fast, isn't it?
Pitter-pat.
Getting nervous?
I don't scare that easily.
You stink of fear.
I can smell it.
Look at you.
All your muscles wound up tight,
ready to save your ass.
You know what I feel like?
Like killing.
You're being very stupid, Butler.
We still don't understand
what we're dealing with here,
and you just...
I'm taking back what was lost
through millions of years of evolution.
I'll be a new kind of warrior,
changing shape at will.
I'll have the instincts of an animal
and the brain of a man.
I'm terminating this, right now!
You'll never terminate this project.
Watch me.
I'm gonna live forever, Miller.
Jeez!
Mr Butler, you startled me.
Are you okay?
Oh what happened?
I just...
What are you doing?
Michelle!
Oh my God!
What happened?
Butler.
That's all right, come here, come here.
Calm down.
Come and sit down.
It's all right, come on.
Everything's gonna be
just fine, I promise.
What the hell's going on?
Michelle, what happened?
Butler.
That son of a bitch.
Butler, you son of a bitch.
This thing's out of control, Butler.
Butler?
Wash the bodies carefully
and take them to cryonics.
I want them in freezers immediately.
We have to do an autopsy, sir.
That's standard procedure.
No.
Yes, sir.
They should be incinerated.
That way, there won't be any evidence.
No, I can't do that.
I think we're just gonna put everything
on hold for a while.
We need to find a way
to control the process,
maybe even enhance it.
Okay, then we need to do a full prep.
Do you want to replace
the blood with glycol
before they're frozen?
No, it's too dangerous.
If the bullets get dislodged,
all hell will break loose.
Mr Miller?
Ah, how's the girl?
Uh, she's still sleeping.
Good, I'll send a medevac unit down
to get her out of here.
How are you doing?
I'll survive.
I'm sorry you had to see
all of this, Dr Barnes.
It's created a lot of problems for us.
Unfortunately, you're gonna have
to surrender all of your records.
Everything associated
with this program has
to be destroyed.
But you can't destroy all this.
We need our records to...
I don't have time to
argue with you, Dr Barnes.
Please show Agent Berger to your office.
When you're through,
send her body down to
cryonics with the others.
Hmm, well,
this little experiment just gets more
and more interesting, doesn't it?
I'm sorry, my friend,
but you were getting a little out of hand.
And this intermission
will give us both time
to work out the wrinkles,
so to speak.
Oh while you're in there,
work on that attitude of yours, buddy.
- Yeah?
- Where are you?
You said you'd be here over an hour ago.
Oh, you know, I'm right
in the middle of something.
Have Roger sit in for me.
Roger always loses.
I do not.
I'm playing.
Besides, I need you here for good luck.
Oh come on, Anna!
Take a break and have some fun.
Anna, I need you down here.
It's high stakes.
I need your money.
Guys, I have to go.
Count me out, all right.
I'll talk to you later.
She's not comin'.
Stop chasin' that girl
and concentrate on the game.
Get the message.
Deep down, I know she really likes me.
She sure has a
funny way of showin' it,
like tellin' you to take a hike.
The only thing that matters
to her is that substitute skin.
Five Card Stud, suicide kings wild.
Hi.
We missed you last night.
It was a great game.
I lost track of the time.
Larry won $15 from General Hammond.
Oh, what did Hammond say?
He didn't take it too well.
You know how he gets
when he loses to an NCO.
Yeah, especially Larry.
- Here.
- Thank you.
So how's it going?
Oh I started electroplating
at two this morning.
The metal ions fused to the tissue.
I increased the oxygen by 3/10%.
These first specimens hardened again.
This one, I'm still waiting on.
What do you think?
It's still hard to believe it's made
of metal and synthetic tissue.
It's been stable
for about three hours now.
Well, if you
can keep it that way,
a lot of cancer victims
will be very grateful.
I don't know what else to do.
Think maybe I'm just to close to it.
Well, to add to our
problems, we've got to deal
with a new so-called expert
Washington is sending.
- Hmm.
- I've never heard of him.
There's nothing about him
in any reference manual.
- That's good.
- And on top of that,
I don't know a thing about his research.
All the right reasons for them
to send for them to him to work with us.
Well, if he can help,
then we can move on to animal testing.
Think of the burn victims,
people with skin cancer.
We'd be able to graft
whole areas of the body.
So Washington has put me
in charge of the program,
and I am personally responsible
for keeping it funded.
Ah.
- Sorry.
Uh-huh.
- Roger?
- Oh, sorry, sir.
I feel it's time we start human testing.
Excuse me, Colonel,
that doesn't make sense.
We're still having a lot of problems.
I know.
I've monitored your work
for the past five years.
I know all of your successes
and all of your failures.
And I feel you're ready to move on.
We still can't control
the hardening process.
We've never been able to keep it stable.
Sometimes, it works, but sometimes,
we end up with skin as hard as steel.
I'm well aware of that.
If that were to happen,
it would kill the subject,
which brings up the
question of volunteers.
Well, we won't be using volunteers,
not in the usual sense.
What are you planning on using?
Frozen cadavers.
Cadavers?
Are you nuts?
The cryonics team
at Fort Meade has rehydrated
outer skin tissue.
They have kept it alive for months
on a grid of polylactic acid.
Their work fits perfectly into yours.
But how's that gonna advance our work?
Synthetic tissue is not the same
as rehydrated frozen tissue.
Mm-hmm?
What we're doing here
is creating living skin
from metal and tissue.
I am merging the two programs,
all the support that is
in those folders there,
along with your new orders.
What if we say no?
Oh I don't think you want to do that.
Why not?
Well, because I'll cut your funding.
That's outrageous, Colonel.
Where do you get off coming down here
and disrupting our work?
Hmm, that's very nice.
Look, either you cooperate,
or I will just simply take your research,
give it to all those
nice folks at Fort Meade,
and they can take all the credit.
Well, do I have your cooperation?
Yes.
Your full cooperation, General?
You'll have it.
I'll deliver the first
cadaver some time next week.
Why are you all so glum?
You're scientists.
Isn't this how you people have fun?
Well, Donald, it's time for
you to rise from the dead.
There have been some unusual developments,
these past 20 years.
These so-called scientists
don't even know it,
but they're gonna give
you a skin of steel.
You'll be indestructible
and under my control.
What's he saying?
He's a little upset.
- Do you understand me?
- Si.
I will not work here
until it is sprinkled with holy water.
Okay.
Wait a minute, holy water?
How are we gonna get that?
- Hey, don't...
How do I know?
Call a priest, a bishop,
have the Pope send it FedEx.
I don't cook!
- Ramon!
- I go on strike.
Ramon,.
That means we're gonna
be eating peanut butter
and jelly sandwiches again.
I don't blame him.
I'd be upset, too.
This is ridiculous.
- Thank you.
Okay.
I have feeling we're
getting off to a bad start.
I think you've
been out of practice
with medicine for too long.
All right, have Debbie run
a complete pathology test
on the tissue and a molecular
model of the hair, okay?
Okay.
Thanks.
I don't know
where that body came from.
What if it was used for
germ warfare experiments, hmm?
I mean, the last thing we need is
to contract some kind of exotic disease.
It has a clean bill of health.
It came from the cryonics
lab in Langley, Virginia.
Germ warfare is done at
Plum Island in New York.
I'm not lifting a finger
until I have all the paperwork.
Ah, well, then you're in luck,
because here it is.
Come on, Colonel,
you're gonna have to do better than this.
This file is inadequate.
This cadaver has VIP written all over it.
There isn't a clue as to who he is
or where he came from.
Ah, well, medically, it's clean.
For all I know, it could
be somebody else's records.
I don't want to work on him.
No problem here, Doctor,
except for the one you're creating.
I don't like it.
It makes me feel uneasy.
What are you afraid of?
I said I was uneasy.
There's a difference.
You're putting us under a lot of pressure.
Well, you're the expert
in freeze-dried tissue.
You could do this with your eyes closed.
Why don't you start on this
one, and I'll see what I can do
about getting you a fresher specimen?
Please.
There's adrenaline in the cells.
He died violently.
- Mm-hmm.
It looks like a heart attack.
Take a look at this.
I analyzed six samples.
All of them were consistent.
Your subject consumed
high amounts of raw meat.
The striations show high
levels of saturated fats,
cholesterol, tannin and sulfites.
It looks like he was a
very self-indulgent person.
What happened to the hair follicles?
It went through some
sort of molecular disarray,
just before the subject died.
I haven't a clue.
Its whole structure was reformed.
But I did find something
that was interesting.
I found a piece of dirt
embedded in the hair platelet.
I traced this down to salt deposits
along the Danube River.
Which part?
Somewhere near Budapest.
And if you think that's interesting,
I tried cross-referencing
the numbers on his file.
I was denied access.
That means they do know
who he is.
- Exactly.
We can still find out.
All you need to do is
bring me his fingerprints.
I'll run them through the FBI computer.
Great.
I'll get them right to you.
Decision time, Deb.
You know, personally,
I think this Miller guy
is doing us a favor.
I'm getting a little tired
of the same old stuff.
Boo-yah!
Ah, I don't really
care what we use it on.
Come on, it's $4 to you.
Ugh, I fold.
Well, Miller's results are impressive,
and I can't find an error in his theories,
but I still don't like the guy.
It's too rich for my blood.
Well, I'm up for review.
Get me another star and a raise.
So don't start with him.
I'll see you and raise you.
Hmm?
It could be exciting.
Are you trying to
bluff me with that hand?
Put your cards on the table.
Full house, jacks and 10s.
Ooh.
Royal flush.
I knew it.
She beat you.
What do you got to do
to win a hand around here?
- Mine, baby.
- Yes!
I guess that somebody's cheating here.
Somebody's cheating here.
This is...
- Thank you for playing.
- What do you got
to do to win a hand?
Beginning the resection.
- Steady.
- Take it slow.
Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Take it easy, good.
- Mm-hmm, got it.
Okay.
There.
Skin tissue removed.
Philip, you set?
Just a second.
Ready with the next section of bio-ferrin.
Dipping in the acid bath.
On site.
In position.
Roger, what's the body temperature?
54, 54 degrees.
Hand me the positive plate, please.
94 volts.
Readjust it to 90, so it
doesn't harden, hopefully.
What's the difference?
He's a stiff.
That's very good, Larry.
You're set at 90.
Surgery laser up.
Laser's up.
I have a positive charge
over the graft site.
Cauterizing one.
Cauterizing two.
Roger.
Laser's down.
Resection complete.
If the colonel's plan works,
you will cut two years off the program.
We'll know in four hours.
I can't believe we got peanut
butter and jelly for lunch.
You know, I don't know about you three,
but this food situation
has gotten way out of hand.
I didn't think he was serious, but...
Why don't we just put some water
into a bottle and give it to him?
I tried that.
He busted me.
- Oh.
He busted you?
But I did try.
It's bad enough having
Colonel Miller hanging
over our shoulder.
Yeah, I can't handle that either,
that and trying to eat leftovers.
Maybe these cadavers aren't a bad idea.
At least, we don't have to feed 'em.
There you go, again,
always thinkin' about food.
Will you two please stop it?
We are trying to concentrate.
Calipers.
I think you better check this out.
What's the matter?
I'm reading inorganic
material on the sternum.
That doesn't make any sense.
Come take a look.
Enhance it.
Why didn't you tell me about this before?
I just noticed it.
This is mortician's wax.
Get some gauze.
These are bullet wounds.
Hand me the forceps.
Right here.
This man was shot, folks.
This man was executed.
What the hell?
These bullets look like silver.
Yeah.
I'm terminating the experiment.
Come on now.
Oh no, we got another problem.
The body temperature's rising.
It's up seven degrees.
With a metabolic process.
It's above room level.
Anna, he's starting to bleed.
84 degrees!
Shut the pumps.
He's still bleeding.
I can't feel a muscle.
I'm not touchin' it.
There's heat.
I'm readin' 90 degrees here.
Roger, don't just stand there!
Get something to tie him down.
What?
- I don't care, anything!
- Get something!
Get him!
Get the oxygen!
- What?
Give him oxygen!
He's alive.
Do we have any glucose?
Oh my God.
He's alive.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
What the hell are you doin',
sending us a body with bullets in it,
silver bullets?
I haven't the slightest idea
what you're talking about.
Don't bullshit me, Colonel.
That cadaver didn't just
fall out of the sky.
Well, let's hope not.
You know what I mean.
Leslie, you know everything that I know
about this program.
Don't call me Leslie.
How can you act so cool about this?
The question is,
where do we go from here?
We are trying to
understand what happened.
What if he regains consciousness?
That's impossible.
His brain's been dead for years.
Okay, fine, fine, but what if?
Then we have no right
to experiment on him.
It's too late.
He's already covered in bio-ferrin.
What do we do, take it off?
People may I remind you
that technically it doesn't exist.
But he does exist.
Well, it has no
memory and no identity.
Oh, it's an it.
No, he is a human being,
and you're telling us
to work on him against his will.
What will?
Doctor, isn't this what you always wanted,
a living subject?
That's immoral, Colonel.
Morality has nothing to do with this.
Well, then what about these?
What about them?
The man was shot.
Send 'em to Washington.
See what they can come up with.
What good is that going to do?
Have 'em traced.
And then what?
So we'll know what happened.
How it died has nothing to do with this.
Human being, Colonel,
we're talking about a
human being in there.
Deal with it
and get on with the experiment.
Anything else?
No, sir.
He's a lyin' son of a bitch.
What happened?
Yeah?
- Hi.
- Hey.
I stopped by your apartment,
but you weren't there.
I just thought you might
like to have company.
Thanks.
It's the only place I feel
comfortable right now.
Are you okay?
Not really.
I'm questioning everything I believe in.
It just, it upsets me
that they're treating this so lightly.
You know, maybe everyone's just scared.
And they don't want to deal with it.
Hey, don't worry.
I've brought you something
to take the edge off.
That's not gonna help.
Hey, it'll help you unwind.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Remember when I told you about
that little girl they brought
into emergency, the burn victim?
You were interning at Lansing General.
She was seven years old.
90% of her body was scorched away.
It was horrible.
And there was no way we could save her.
I can still see those pretty blue eyes
and the way she looked at me,
just before she died.
Why are you thinking about that now?
When I watched her die, I, I thought,
what is it that left her body?
Something left when she died.
And now I have to think of the other,
the other possibility.
I don't get it.
What if nothing
leaves, if life is there,
locked in our cells forever,
and it can reassert
itself like it did today?
Something momentous happened.
But I don't know why.
Now that you've had time to
think things through a bit,
I'm sure there's been
an attitude adjustment.
Things have changed in the last 20 years.
Yes, you've been on ice for 20 years.
But now, I have things a
little more under control.
Oh.
I thought you might like to see this.
Huh?
Get away!
Hopefully, it will
help defrost your memory.
Unfortunately, you have
to go through all of this,
but as they say, no pain, no gain.
This new development will
give us the opportunity
to reach beyond even our original plan.
Good to see you again, Donald.
Son of a bitch!
The skin is growing way too fast,
and it's getting hard.
I mean, I can't even get my needle in.
Let me try.
Isn't there another
place you could put that?
I don't have time to
think about it right now.
I don't know.
Colonel Miller has
something to do with this.
Now I know I did not hear you say that.
It was a fluke.
Even you said so.
Yes, I did.
But after watching him trying
to communicate with him, I'm not so sure.
I don't want to hear this.
Why didn't you go in
and ask him what he was doing?
I was alone.
Well, could you hear what he was saying?
Mm-mm, he was showing
him cards or pictures.
It looked like he was quizzing him,
like he was trying to jog his memory.
I...
- What about his memory?
Colonel Miller, good morning.
Good morning.
What's going on?
The pins are ready
to jump off the chart.
That's what's going on.
There's brain activity.
Are you sure?
Our machines don't lie, sir.
Colonel, this man belongs in a hospital.
The bio-ferrin is hardening.
Now there's a chance he'll
regain the use of his brain.
If that happens,
this whole thing turns into a nightmare.
We can't afford to
expose the program, Doctor.
What if he regains his memory?
I thought you said that wouldn't happen.
None of this was supposed to happen.
Damn!
We're not equipped for this.
Can't you do something about that?
Like what?
Larry, do we have
enough surgical tubing
to make a catheter?
No.
Oh no, no, no, no, no.
I'll quit before I touch him down there.
Let him piss all over the bed.
Larry, we have to control the water.
Mr Porter, I suggest
you get that tubing.
Please.
Is he feeling any pain?
If the baselines are correct,
yes, yes, he is in pain.
Well, can't you give him a painkiller?
I just gave him some Demerol.
It'll just take a little
bit of time to work.
Where are we, Roger?
We're on two.
What are you doing?
Come here.
Get this for me.
Do I have to?
- Roger.
- Okay, okay.
Hold that.
The FBI has blocked
the fingerprint scan.
They know who he is.
This is what I get when
enter Colonel Miller's name,
in effect, nothing.
It's the same thing.
There's too much secrecy
surrounding all this.
Will you make me a copy
of Miller's security key?
What? You're crazy.
Do you know what you're asking?
I need to find out who he is.
I could be involved in
something I shouldn't be doing.
I could lose my job.
I have to get into that
office, Debbie, please.
Please.
Okay.
But can we do it later?
You know, someone might walk in.
What about tonight?
- Fine.
- Thank you.
Meet me here at seven.
See you at seven.
Yes.
It's the lab.
No, don't touch that phone.
It's monitored with a time code.
I'll be through, in a minute.
Here you go.
What the hell?
You're kidding me.
Well, he can't just have disappeared.
I've got security turning
this place upside down.
As soon as I find out where he is,
you'll know about it.
Hope you know what you're doing.
So do I.
Get everyone into
the rec room immediately.
I've been paging Dr de Carlo.
I can't find her.
Where is she?
She shouldn't be out there running around
with this thing loose.
Here.
She isn't answering.
I don't know what's goin' on.
Well, try her again.
Now either your agency is up to something,
or you're not dealing with a full deck.
May I suggest that you
clean up in here first?
And then review your security procedures.
Roger, Jesus, you scared me.
Thank God you're all right.
Why didn't you answer your pager?
I've been looking all over for you.
This section is quarantined.
For what?
What is going on?
He broke loose and killed Larry.
What?
Larry's dead.
General Hammond wants you
to come with me right away.
He's dead?
Wait, where's, where's Larry?
I have to see him.
See him, later, Doctor.
There's nothing you can do.
We have to get out of here.
It's much too dangerous.
But if he hits the fence,
he'll be electrocuted.
I don't care about the son of a bitch.
My priority is the safety of my people,
and if I find that bastard
first, I will kill him.
May I remind you, Leslie,
you have neither the
right nor the authority
to do that.
Bullshit!
We cleaned up the lab
and placed the body in the freezer room.
Good.
Colonel Miller has agreed to accompany you
on a tour of the grounds.
I want you to start here, go around,
and I will join you out front.
- Yes, sir.
- Gentlemen.
Corporal Turner, I
want you to start here,
conduct a search of the
building, sector by sector.
And when you're through,
we will meet you out here.
Yes, sir.
I want you to go to the metal shop,
see if you can put together something
to knock this thing out of commission.
And if he gets loose, I want him dead.
No problem.
Sector five, sector five.
Sector five clear.
Turner, are you there?
Nothin' out
here but a full moon.
Did you check the south gate?
What about across the lake?
Over here.
It's Corporal Turner, sir.
Oh my God.
God!
- He's over here, General!
- Get him!
- Don't hurt it!
You bastard!
Hit him with the CO2!
This is absolutely disgusting.
Everything is out of control.
Colonel, why don't you pack up and go back
to Langley with the rest of your spooks
and take this zombie with you?
Calm down, General.
This bio-ferrin was your invention.
All I did was merge the two.
What are you doing?
It's the same problem we had before.
The skin is too hard.
It's the only way we
can get the needle in.
As soon as he's sedated,
I want him out of here.
I've made arrangements
with the regional command.
They'll have him out of here,
first thing in the morning.
Good.
It's, it's not working.
It's, it's, we've got
to try something else.
Connect him to the rectifier.
Come on.
I'll be in my office.
Come on, Roger.
Standby.
Here you go.
Try to sedate
him, Doctor, not kill him.
We've tried everything else.
We have to take this risk right now.
Where are you going?
To see Larry.
We need you here.
I'm going with you.
You sure you want to see him.
I mean, he's really messed up.
He's my friend.
Anna, if you need
me, I'll be in the lab.
Sorry.
Philip, what are you doing here?
I don't think you should see this.
I need to find out how he died.
All right, then I'll go with you.
No, I...
If you don't mind, I'd like
to do this alone, okay?
Okay?
- Okay.
- Thanks.
God!
Roger, what are you doing out here?
Waiting for you.
I don't think you should go in there.
What's he doing?
Sleeping, but I don't know for how long.
I better just make
sure he doesn't wake up.
The bio-ferrin is covering him so fast
you can see it grow.
I got to think.
I just got to think.
I've got to think.
Don't do that.
I just came from Hammond's office.
He's fighting with Miller to
get that thing out of here.
I should've listened to my instincts.
None of this would've happened.
Anna, it is nobody's fault.
We did what we were told.
Not one of us thought
it would come to this.
This isn't supposed to happen.
Yeah, well, you look in there,
and you tell me what
you see isn't happening.
He's turning into a wolf
or some kind of monster.
We have to kill him.
What are you talking about?
Moral responsibilities.
Do you realize what you're saying?
If he gets loose, he'll kill all of us.
Look at him.
In an hour, he's gonna be indestructible.
Now I need you to knock him out.
Where do we put the needle?
Stick it in his eye.
It's not gonna kill him.
When I get back, I'll finish, okay?
Wait, wait, wait a
second, wait a second.
You're not gonna leave
me here alone, are you?
- Roger.
- Roger, just do it
and meet us back at my lab.
I'm just as frightened
as you are, all right?
Now inject the son of a bitch.
Where are you going?
I'm going to Miller's office
to get the silver bullets and a gun.
I'll be right back.
Silver won't penetrate the bio-ferrin.
We don't have a lot
of choices, right now.
That's our only chance.
I got another idea.
You stay cool.
I'm getting more silver.
Oh my God.
Are you sure this is going to work?
No.
But melting silver with the metal
from the bio-ferrin is our only chance.
If this sucker doesn't
kill him, nothing will.
General Hammond isn't
answering any of his pages.
Well, we've got to find him
before Colonel Miller gets to him.
If that thing breaks loose,
it'll destroy the entire community.
We're gonna have to shut this base down.
But then we'll be
trapped in here with him.
He'll kill all of us.
We don't have a choice.
Debbie.
What's the code?
Come on!
Look, I don't want to die, okay?
We're running out of time.
Now punch in that code
while we still have a
chance to blow him away.
All right.
Grab those shells and
let's go kill this bastard
before he kills us.
Easy, easy, easy.
Not so rough.
Sorry.
You people in Washington
have absolutely no regard, not any.
What the hell do you
think you are, General?
Aren't you a trained killer?
Oh my God!
He's ripped his throat out.
I'm trained to defend my country.
I don't know how the system
produces scum like you.
What system?
Ah, the old ways don't
exist anymore, General.
Here I am trying to make your job easier,
and all you do is resent me for it.
It's just so confusing, isn't it?
Bullshit!
What about this poor man?
What am I supposed to say to his family?
What a waste!
Well, I don't think you're gonna have
to worry about that,
General, because you're
not going anywhere.
Stand up!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, don't even think of it.
Toss it over here.
And your walkie-talkie.
Ah, at my feet.
You're not gonna get
away with this, Colonel.
Why don't you hang around
here for a while, Leslie.
I've got some work to do.
Oh, don't wander too far.
I hear it's dangerous out there.
You son of a bitch!
Hold it right there.
Where's General Hammond?
Well, let's just say
he's not jumping for joy.
Oh, what are you going to do with that?
These shells are the
only way we can stop him.
Oh, I see.
Forget it.
No one's going to kill him.
Now put the shells down
and give me the launcher, hmm?
Go, go!
Get out of the way.
Over my dead body.
Maybe he got Miller.
What do we do now?
We've got to get out of here.
We've got to get help.
This leads to the old institute.
This door hasn't been opened in years.
Where does it go?
I haven't the slightest idea.
Can you open it?
I might be able to
bypass the encryption code.
Oh shot, remember, remember.
I'll try this.
Hold on.
Think, think, think, think, think.
That's it.
We got to get back to Philip.
We can't leave him there like that.
That's what he wants.
You knows he'll do anything for you.
Besides, he could still be alive.
Yeah, if we get to him in time.
Come on.
Wait, wait.
Just in case we run into that thing.
Very clever, girls.
They said this
was destroyed by the fire.
These chambers are so old,
I can't believe they're still working.
We've been
lied to, all these years.
Those bastards have been using us.
What are you doing?
- Getting rid of them.
- You can't do that.
We need that to protect ourselves with.
She's right.
You know, you surprise me, Doctor.
After all of your clinically
incisive, brilliant work,
to see you so emotionally out of control,
why, it just shatters
my whole image of you.
It's unfortunate you had to stumble
upon my little dormitory here.
Where's Captain Ferraro?
What men will do for love.
You know I've never fully understood
the concept of sacrifice.
No, Donald, it's okay.
It's me.
No!
Donald!
See if you can find a door down there.
I'll look over here.
Jesus, okay.
Anna!
Anna, I found a door that's open!
Shit.
Debbie!
Get down!
Debbie.
Come on!
Anna, get out of the way!
It's empty.
Hey, I have a shell, hurry!
Go!
Let's see that.
Let me see.
I'm all right.
What about you?
Shaky.
I'm sorry I couldn't get there sooner,
but, I couldn't find you.
Thank God you did.
We thought you were dead.
Oh there's bio-ferrin all over you.
You're covered with it.
Let's get out of here and get some help.
Can you make it?
Will you keep the beast away?
I can do that.
Let's go.
Resynced to fit CG-release by K13!!