Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
We all agree that this
gold stays in the ground
until I get word that
it's time to go to Mexico.
What about the folks
who live here, Zeb?
The owner of this
manure pit was killed
in General Sibley's
actions last year.
No one will be back
here for any reason.
This place gives me
the heebie jeebies.
We bury it, we split
up until I give the word
and we all three come back
here together, agreed?
- Agreed.
My regiment leaves
in the morning.
Words cannot
express my gratitude
for what you have done
for my little family.
This year was so hard on us.
Without you, we may
never have survived
as this conflict raged.
Thanks to you, we may
return to St. Louis
and my little one has a
chance at a real education,
and this nightmare
will be left behind us.
I love you, the both of you,
and I will come back for you.
When you come for us,
you swear you'll
never leave us again?
With all my heart.
I believe you.
We deserve a place of peace.
For all time.
I know you cherish this.
Spencer, you're
leaving us again.
You've changed our lives.
I can only repay you with
my eternal and undying love.
That is all I wish.
Zeb, if there ain't nobody
living on this spread,
why do I see people
moving in the house?
There's a woman's face
there in the window.
Oh hell, you two
stay here with the gold.
I'm gonna have me a looksie.
Promise, run, run!
Oh hell, lady, you
gotta be kidding!
Ouch, oh, Jesus Christ!
Run, Promise, run!
Well, look what we have here.
You ignate wretch.
This isn't a pleasure palace.
Well, what about her?
Let's just leave the little
darling to her memories.
I thought I told you jacking
ape to stay with the gold.
Zeb, my legs are hurting,
I need to go see a saw bone.
You shut your mouth,
I was shot four times
in Lawrence, Kansas, and
didn't complain about it
half as much as
that little scratch.
You tie that off,
and let's get the
hell out of here.
You sure do take your
time with them damn cards.
I picked up the habit
of exercising caution,
almost a lifetime ago.
Yeah? Well, to hell with
your caution, I'm down $50.
Don't play if you
can't afford it.
Saloon-keeper.
What will it be?
Well, it's after
nine in the morning,
I believe I'll have a tequila.
Oh, and my friend
here looks hungry,
bring him the house
special, and maybe a beer.
Right, kind of you.
What did you pitch
your name as again?
I didn't.
Oh, Christ, I needed that.
I've been riding since
Yuma, no time for a meal.
I know, you'd be one Zebediah
Scurlock, from Missouri.
There's a territorial warrant
out of Yuma for your arrest.
The warrant stipulates choice
of delivery to authorities.
And the choices are?
Alive or dead.
You got some nerve, shit heel.
I'm giving you a choice,
you can make this easy,
or you can make this hard.
Why the hell would
I surrender to you?
Well, I just bought
your sustenance.
Fiddly, I don't care
much for your deal,
you son of a bitch.
You know who the hell you're
fucking with, jack ass?
I do.
You shouldn't have done that.
You witness that?
I don't get it, you knew
you were gonna kill him,
why did you buy him a meal?
I didn't want the son
of a bitch to go to hell
on an empty stomach.
Sheriff, are these all the
bills for the past six months?
Every one of them.
You looking for
anyone in particular?
Indeed, I am.
It seems to me
a little peculiar,
a young lady perusing handbills.
I'm not what you'd
expect, Sheriff. Thank you.
Okay.
I don't understand it.
Of course, he aint
been in the right mind
since the surrender
12... No, 13 years ago.
What the hell are you
talking about, Wild Eye?
My brother, Zebediah.
I was in Tucumcari last night,
I read in the Tribune
Express that he got himself
all shot to hell by a
bushwhacking shootist.
Poor son of a bitch got
slung over his own saddle.
Man, all down to Yuma
for a territorial reward.
A goddamn shame.
Yeah, a goddamn shame.
You know, he rode
the Cowan trail.
Who's Cowan trail, Wild Eye?
Brick, your brains are like
a gelding's balls, missing.
Forget it.
You know lots of folks
thought him shameful,
for riding with
all those vermin.
Hmm, but they suited him.
And after all the
scrapes he been through,
all that killing, all
the women and children
they sent to their maker
and he never got a scratch
and now he comes to
an end like this.
You know, I served my
time in the regiments,
and look at me, goddamn
battle of Chickamauga,
goddamn Johnny Reb, took my eye,
and gave me this throw, nothing!
Nothing,
is ever even in this world.
Well, I guess that's just
the way the Lord intended,
I reckon.
Well, I intend to even
things out to a fair degree.
How so?
When I was reading
the Tribune Express,
it said personal
effects may be collected
by the next of kin at the
Grissom Brothers Undertakers.
So I paid that
establishment a visit,
you know what I found?
He's Cold Navy and hide
away smith, $2.43, and this.
Seems that mother Scurlock's
dearest oldest golden boy
kept himself a personal
record of his exploits in 61.
Now that opportunistic
son of a bitch,
he probably thought he
could sell all these
to the penny dreadfuls.
Whatever,
most of it is a load of shit.
But one story intrigued me,
about a certain cash box.
Dear, stupid, older brother,
you just may have made
one thing successful
out of your wretched life.
Brick, forget about them two
smithy jobs down in El Paso,
how would you like to
make some real money.
I've missed you,
something terrible.
How long's your stay
gonna be this time?
I hadn't really
thought about it,
I'm too busy enjoying
the scenery right now.
Oh, come on, bastard,
you can't fool me.
You always know your next move.
You know me too well.
If I were you,
I'd never leave me.
And I never argue
with logic, Francesca.
Then how come you do leave?
And how come you ask
so many fool questions?
Hmm, goddamn Ransom, honey.
There's two compelling
reasons why you should stay.
You know in your heart
that you bring to me
all the joy in my life.
It does a woman good
to hear things like that.
Tell me, what is that
void in your soul?
What do you mean?
We've been together,
a good long time now,
when you're here.
And I know all of you, your
strength, your loyalty,
your passions.
And I know about that
canyon in your soul,
that place no one can enter.
Don't make with
fancy words, Francesca.
There is a sadness
inside of you
and you won't even admit it.
You certainly
weren't confronted.
You're wrong about that.
I confront it every day, some
days I wish I didn't have to.
Well, lover, tell me.
What do you know about loss?
A little bit.
I miss my daddy,
now and again.
There was someone in my past,
when I should have
been there, I wasn't.
It was many years ago.
She hurt you.
No, nothing like that.
But if I had been there, I
could have made a difference.
Is she dead?
Yes, every day I think
what could have been.
You can't blame yourself
for a turn of fate.
I don't know if
I blame myself,
but I still should
have been there.
I don't even know
exactly what happened,
only partial details.
What is in your heart?
In the years since,
I've learned that a man
can be responsible for someone,
and if he abdicates that
responsibility, he's no good.
It's like he's dead.
Come on, you,
you gloomy bastard.
You are the finest
man I've ever known.
I've lived with
this for too long.
So is this the-
- The reason I can't
give myself completely?
But I am learning.
Confront your past.
You may be right about that.
What was it you taught me?
Hello.
Hello?
Afternoon, how can I help you?
Just came by to check
out the old place,
I used to know the people here.
Been over 10 years.
Would you fancy some
coffee? I got fresh water too.
That's all right, but thanks.
Sir, listen, can you tell
me what happened here?
Well, I just picked up this
property at County auction.
Oh no, you mean
that bad business
that happened here at
the end of the war.
Yes.
Well, I lived in town then,
but that Sawyer woman and that
little girl, they were here.
And what happened after that?
One day, the
Marshal came into town
delivering an escaped
Indian and he saw them.
And?
There was a woman,
she was half stripped,
and she was shot
right in the chest.
And the little girl,
she was just wandering
around in a daze.
Tell me more.
The story was,
that these fellows,
they buried a cash box
somewhere around here,
and the woman came in and
saw them digging it up.
There was a lot of that
thievery after the war,
with Johnny Reb on the run,
those that hadn't surrendered
to the blue coats officially,
they picked up whatever
they could find
and they took off to Mexico.
Some of them even joined
up with the oysters.
What happened to the girl?
Some say she
went to St. Louis,
well, that's where
the mother was from.
I know.
The County filed a
lien on the property,
and I picked it up
at County auction.
Do you fancy some coffee?
It's colder than I expected.
Name is Zacharias.
If I remember my
Bible schooling,
he was the father
of John The Baptist.
Yes sir.
A fine name, mine's Ransom.
Pleasure.
How long did you know the
people that I spoke of?
The woman and the little
girl, they were my life.
You were not there
during that bad business
that happened, were you?
I was a trail scout
for the union back then,
my regiment had shipped out.
You see, this woman had a
husband who had abandoned her.
He served with General Sibley,
he was reported as dead long
before I came into the picture.
Why didn't you return to her?
We were taking
the last surrender,
of the last of
Johnny Reb's outfits.
I heard that the husband
may have been alive,
so I set out for this
place to find out.
En route I came upon an
official casualty list,
turns out I was wrong, there
was his name right there.
I continued on, met up with
a newspaper man I knew,
he knew about this woman and me.
He showed me a
newspaper clipping,
it reported her death,
no real details, no
mention of the little girl.
Well, what did you do?
I don't remember,
I was in a daze.
I drifted, where? I
don't even recall.
All I know is I was set
out to come back here
and then we ran into that
last regimen of gray coats,
but I was bound and
determined to come back here.
It sounds like you're
blaming yourself.
I should have delivered
those sons of bitches to Satan.
Mister, a lot has
happened in my life.
I remember when I was serving
with General Franklin Pierce,
he was a New Hampshire militia,
and we were down
in Churrobusco, Mexico.
Those days there was no
way to get word to us
because we were so
far down into Mexico
that nobody could
get in touch with us.
And?
Well, let's just say
I had a big surprise
when I returned home, and find
that my pretty little wife
had skidaddled off
with my best friend
who had a Cooper train.
What are you saying?
That you cannot control
life, life controls you.
I don't know if I've
ever believed that.
Do you have someone now?
My second wife
was my great love.
She's not here now in person,
but she's always here by
my side and in my heart.
Should a man be
allowed to grieve?
For as long as he wishes.
You have a woman now?
Yes, she's beautiful,
fiery, loving.
Don't you waste that.
Thank you for the coffee,
gave me something to ponder.
Sometimes it's a long
journey to get home.
That coffee hit the
spot, warmed me up some.
Mister, I sure hope you find
what you're looking for.
Howdie, gentlemen.
Would you care for a little
coffee and fresh water?
Not interested, gramps.
We're looking for some
information, though.
How long has this shit
hole been abandoned?
It ain't no more, I own it,
I intend to spend my
twilight years here.
You know, I've been most
things in this life,
I've worked on the
Mississippi river,
I sold farm implements-
- We're not interested in
your life story, old toad.
Now what happened to them people
here before you, years ago?
It's funny you should ask
that, there was a fellow
who went through here
a couple of days ago
who was asking what
happened to the people
who were here back
in those days.
If you ask me, he knew the
widow in the biblical sense.
Who was this man?
He was a professional man,
a shootist, probably military.
He carried a Mason
Richards Conversion,
rare measure type of fellow,
the collector type, you
know, he had it all together.
And where did he run off to?
Las Cruces,
maybe, I don't know
And, uh, he didn't take
nothing? He just rode away?
What would he take from here?
It's not here.
And what's it
say in that book?
Well that's the problem,
my ever loving brother
was more dedicated to
penning his war exploits
than simple bit of
thievery, goddamn him.
All right, hey, um...
Hell, let's get out
of this cow pie.
Look here you mixed sparrow,
I've had enough of you thumbing
your nose at my spread.
Now, get the hell
off of my land.
Oh, easy there, old spider.
Do you want me to take care
of this old man, Wild Eye?
Take that pecker pawn
you got there with you,
and get a wiggle on.
We're going.
Now!
We're due elsewhere,
on business.
You loathsome sodomites.
Well, tell me what this
avenger of justice looks like?
This son of a bitch who
shot Zebediah Scurlock down.
Tall, dark hair,
professional demeanor.
Is he a Pinkerton?
No sir. He carries a
Richard Mason Conversion,
he seemed like
ex-military maybe.
That's him,
that's the rounder.
That old man, the one
I just told you about,
that's the one he spoke to.
Well, he can flat
shoot, I'll give him that.
Meet Bill Gristy,
he hails from Abilene.
Occasionally I come here
and help Sheriff Meldin
with a problem or two.
So you saw the whole thing.
I did, I was sitting
at a corner, way back,
I don't think anybody
saw me in the saloon.
Fact is I was looking
for old Zeb myself,
saw the same handbill
down in Yuma,
I suspect that's what brought
the other gentlemen up here.
Well, he got him
fair and square,
you can't get them all,
not in this business.
So this Mason
Richard sucker, he
killed my brother.
I only knew
when he brought him we knew
something about that box.
Now, don't get anything
started here, boys.
Oh no, not to worry law man.
I mean, I'm just tracking
down a family heirloom.
Well, good day gentlemen.
So what's the
low down, Wild Eye?
I figure that man hunter
must be about a week's ride
ahead of us, in any direction.
And that old man, now he said
he was headed to Las Cruces.
Zeb was always a flapjack,
so maybe he let loose
with the location
to this bastard,
to where that cash box was,
you know, in a
plead for his life.
Well, that there dandy
might cause us some despair.
Despair?
Now why the hell do
you always look down
the dark side of the road?
You illiterate bastard.
Let's go get the horses.
My God, it really is you.
I'm sorry, young lady, you
have me at a disadvantage.
I never thought
I'd see you again.
Have we met?
The little ranch
outside of Santa Fe,
12 or more years ago?
It was the happiest time of
my life, brief as it was.
The Sawyer place?
Are you-
- I am Promise Sawyer.
I was just out at the
old place a few weeks ago.
Tell me, where have you
been all these years?
We have much to discuss,
meet me in the parlor of the
Elysium hotel in an hour.
That day you left, I asked
mama when you would return,
she said you were a man
who lived on his own terms.
Why did you leave us?
I don't, I don't know what
was in my heart at that time.
I'll never forget the beautiful
cross you gave to mama.
Yeah, it was in
my family for years,
it was all that was
left of a life long ago.
I was a contract
scout for the union
before I met your mother.
The war was at its
end, we were mopping up
the final remnants of the Rebs
that had not yet surrendered.
I was looking forward to a
life of peace and tranquility,
I found it on that
little place of yours.
Then I drifted,
like a damned fool,
I've known very little
peace since then.
It was as if God had
sent you to watch over us.
I believed you truly
cared about us.
I did, and I do now.
You read to me, from
Sutonia's, as I recall.
Well, I was always interested
in historical subjects.
Your mother had one of
the finest libraries
I have ever seen.
So what happened to you in
the years leading up till now?
I stayed on for
about two years,
mama had a stash of gold coins
which had belonged to Papa.
The ruffians never found
them when they tore
through the house.
I had some help from some
of the folks in town,
but when the money ran out and
the debts could not be paid,
I abandoned the property.
To make my way in this world
I had to make
certain compromises,
which young ladies of moral
conscience would never accept,
but I made them, and I survived.
I thrived.
Do you understand?
Due to the world I inhabited,
I've learned salient facts
about the underbelly of society.
I catalogued this information
and used it to find
these men who scarred my
soul.
They left a trail of
slime like wet snails
from here to New Orleans,
and spent the years
dedicated to treachery,
and double crossing each other.
None of them ever made it to
Mexico as was their intent,
eventually two of them
were hanged in San Antonio
for horse rustling.
You wish to know
the final irony?
Yes.
I was in Tucumcari recently,
and there was a news
periodical report about you.
The man you shot,
was the leader of that
gutter trash that night,
Zebediah Scurlock.
I never forgot their faces.
I have spent too long
chasing this, living this,
it appears you're still
my guardian and protector,
whether you know it or not.
This man had a
reward on his head,
and $50 I took from
him in a poker game.
No gold, no fortune, nothing,
your journey is at an end.
Not quite, there's
the cash box.
Why flirt with danger?
Those three vermins
have been sent to hell,
you've made a good
life for yourself.
There's nothing to be
gained by chasing the past,
you'll only find heartbreak.
There is something in that
cash box that I must have.
And there's nothing wrong
with chasing the past,
so long as the past holds
the key to one's freedom.
Maybe.
I just may have a
scrap of information
which may prove valuable.
Come with me and help
me complete my journey.
Tell me,
why must we ever give
up our innocence?
You know,
I've been thinking.
No shit.
I've been thinking
that maybe we really don't need
to be doing all this.
Oh, there you go.
You wanna spend a lifetime
chewing stock or selling nails?
There's a fortune
sitting in that cash box,
and all we gotta do is find it.
And that little girl
might still be alive,
that man on her probably
knows where she's at,
we'll follow them.
In some ways I think, you
not being able to read,
gets in the way
of your brain pan
from seeing the big picture,
like you is dimwitted.
All right, now you cut
that talk, all right?
I've shot men for
lesser insult.
I'm smart, dammit,
I ain't no fool.
All right, all right,
I forgot you were such a
little panty
All I'm saying-
- It seems like we're chasing
windmills, that's all.
Windmills? Well, aint
you the literary scholar.
Listen, what I'm saying is,
I've had it with being on
the tail end of the draw.
This is my chance to even up
the bad deck I've been dealt.
My dear departed brother,
he went through a life time
with a marauder mean
stream than a kindler one,
but he made...
Well, he didn't make big
coin, but he did all right.
Maybe it's time I
learnt from his ways.
Inn-keeper, two beers.
One other thing,
I need some information.
We be looking for a gentleman
who may have rode
through this way.
Senor, I do not interfere
with matters that
do not concern me.
It can prove to be unhealthy.
What may prove to be
unhealthy is your indifference.
I'm looking for a tall,
dark, quiet son of a bitch,
carrying a Mason Rich.
Perhaps you should try
the Sheriff's office,
or the hotels perhaps?
I do not know him.
All right then.
But I will remember whether
or not you told me the truth.
Inn-keeper, dos mas.
Now, I'm gonna go over
there, you stay here.
Howdie friend, what
brings you to town?
What I mean is that
it sure is good to see
somebody new ride through.
Aint that right, Brick?
We're heading to Tucumcari.
On business, ever
been there, friend?
Listen, I don't mind a little
small talk to pass the time,
but I don't see that my travels
are any concern of yours.
Well, I happen to know
you've been there, friend.
Fact is, you made use
of that fancy hog leg
of yours in Tucumcari.
You fetched yourself
a handsome reward
further down in Yuma, all
for a few minutes work.
I think I understand
why you fellows do it.
Hell, I've man hunted a few
times myself, since the war.
Everything all right
over here, Wild Eye?
Yes sir. Me and this gentleman
are just get an acquainted.
Allow me to venture a guess
as to who you two
gentlemen might be.
You'd be one, Brick Logan,
AKA, the stone mason.
You had a lucrative
business reselling the same
rebranded herd three or four
times back in West, Texas.
Before that, you had
a pretty fair turn
with those traveling,
sporting ladies.
Unfortunately, every customer
got clubbed and picked clean,
not to mention a dose.
The Rangers got close to you,
right after the rape
charge was filed.
When they eventually got
you, you beat a night guard
within an inch of his life,
that's when the judge
issued the warrant
and the price on your head.
Don't worry, I don't fancy
a trip to Texas right now.
I have no clue who you are,
except you must be some relation
to that dead meat
I dropped in Yuma.
Now, if you'll
excuse me, gentlemen,
I think that's all we need
to know about each other.
Adios.
How the hell we know he
ain't gonna come back here
and get me?
How the hell is it you never
told me you was a rapist?
I like rape.
Oh shut your yap.
It's becoming
clear why your face
is pinging on a wanted
poster in.
Come on.
Let's go see where
that fellow go.
This is senseless.
Fugitive?
You coming out?
You are wearing on my patience.
You will only succeed in
arousing my deeper anger,
and when that
occurs, hell follows.
I hold here, a handbill stating
you are wanted for robbery
in Santa Fe, New
Mexico territory,
it concludes you may
be armed and dangerous.
Are you coming out?
All right, I'm coming out.
No tricks.
No tricks, I pride myself
on those I keep alive.
That's right, nice and easy.
Kiss God's creation.
Spread out.
You are wise.
You know, in some parts I am
more feared than the almighty.
All right, get up.
Where's your mount?
Down the street, the
telegraph office.
Well, that don't matter.
Let's take a walk.
It's at moments like this,
where I can truly appreciate
the wonder of God's works.
The sublime nature
of the topography,
the blue overhanging
firmament, makes you wonder.
Makes you wonder.
It makes you happy to draw
his breath, does it not?
What's gonna happen to me?
Well, I suspect, straight
to the territorial prison.
I can't go back there.
I do not believe
you have a say in it.
Listen, friend.
I'm not your friend.
Listen, I have
some information
which may prove more to your
liking than turning me in.
And what would that be?
Well, before you tracked me,
I was making a trail
to a veritable fortune.
See, I rode with this
fellow for a few months,
quite a bit older than
me, ex quantro man.
Well sir, he had the most
goddamn amazing tale to tell.
It seems that there was this
cash box of Confederate gold,
that was heisted in the
last days of the late war.
These fellows buried it
and they dug it up again.
Years went by and no one
knew of its existence,
well, I know the location
of this cash box.
In fact, my late partner
and I were headed to get it
when he got killed in Tucumcari.
I was headed there myself
before you caught up with me.
Why are you telling me this?
How much do you stand to gain
from the bounty on my head?
$250.
What if I could
guarantee you thousands.
For the love of money is
the root of all kinds of evil,
it is through this craving
that many have wandered away
from the faith, pierced
themselves with many pain.
Damn it, man. What I'm saying
is I know the whereabouts
of an untraceable fortune.
All right, well, if you
want to tell me this tale,
it may ensure a more interesting
ride to our destination.
A cash box of unregistered
Confederate gold
waits in a church
not far from here.
No one knows of its existence.
Now for the last six
months, I rode with a man
who spoke up nothing
but this gold
and the efforts to
find it day and night.
Then there were the tales
of those who rode with him,
also promised a
part of this gold
and how he betrayed them.
Damn it man, what I'm
saying is I can lead you
to this cash box.
If I do not turn you in.
Well yeah, that's
the general idea.
Those who desire to be
rich fall into temptation,
into a snare, into many
senseless and harmful desires
that plunge them into
destruction and ruin.
Mr, I can't go
back to that jail.
Believe me, a pot
of gold awaits,
give me the chance
to show it to you.
All right, all right, all
right. Satisfy my curiosity.
But do not insult
my intelligence.
What was the name of this
devil you rode in with?
Zebediah Scurlock.
I know this man you speak of,
I was after him myself, whoa.
Tell me more of what you know.
Whoa, whoa.
Location of this
booty is a certainty?
Absolutely.
You would not be
leading me into a trap?
I know my future, friend.
I'm just trying to buy
off the inevitable.
I'm resigned that
I am hell bound.
You are so right.
Goddammit!
Fact is, partner, you
are only worth $250.
Now, I've been known to be
a gambling man on occasion,
and I've entered a gamble
that what you're
telling me is the truth.
Therefore, I stand to reap a
more sizeable reward this way.
You were not wanted for murder,
so I did not shoot
you through the heart.
Consider this your
debt paid to society,
for your peace with God.
You might get thirsty out here.
You bastard!
♪ Lay down to sleep, child ♪
♪ Lay down with the Lord ♪
♪ If the devil finds you ♪
♪ Send him back to hell ♪
Oh hello, I have told
you some of my life
in the last dozen years.
Yes.
Now, the details.
To survive I was forced to
make certain hard choices,
most of the women my
age in this territory
are married with children.
A reason that no respectable
man would take me
once he knew my true story,
so I never let a man
get that close to me.
As a whore I thrived,
so I never had any reason
for a man in my life
longer than a day, a week.
I grew to accept this.
I would never
cast judgment on-
- I am certain
that you would not,
you know how to read
a person's true soul.
This life brought me money,
and some degree of respect
from the men who knew me.
One of the girls in
the house with me,
she knew a man,
older, tough, ex-army,
he rode through town every
six weeks to see her.
One evening he told
her about a cash box
that had been hidden
during the war,
it was to be his
stake for the future,
and it remained
hidden for years.
He betrayed the men
who rode with him
and he held it for himself.
This man carried a journal
which chronicled his exploits
over the previous 20
years, and in that journal,
there was a page indicating
the location of the cash box.
He tore it out and
gave it to her,
I guess he had planned to run
away with her at some point.
When she described the
man and the cash box,
I knew it could only be him.
She showed me the page.
Where's the page now?
Here,
and here.
This man, had the bad
luck of meeting you
in Tucumcari, six months later.
I knew the others were dead,
I was on the trail
of this Scurlock
when you stepped back
into this story again.
You intend to
find this cash box?
Naturally.
I was hoping I could talk
you into coming along.
I don't have much, but I can
pay you a by the mile fee.
I'll go, and you
owe me nothing.
Besides, I might prove useful
in something like this.
Are you certain this
is what you want?
I know they've been
in there quite a while,
they must be up to something.
Yeah, from now on, we'll
keep a close eye on them,
see whether they've been
splitting up or not.
Go, go, follow him.
I'll see what I can find in
that little woman's hotel room.
Go!
Dumb son of a bitch.
I know you're still here
but it seems like
you already left.
I fear that this is going
to be a good long absence.
However long it takes.
That's what I treasure,
a man who is specific.
Please, Francesca, ever
since I learned the story
of Tess and the little girl-
- But you are with me now.
I wanted to confront
your past, not live in it.
It is important to me.
I once read a book
when I was a school girl,
it was about a man who
descended the circles of hell
to find the truth.
I know it.
I never finished it, so
I don't know how it ends.
Shall I tell you?
No, I'm sure it ends sadly.
But it doesn't.
Promise me one thing.
Yes?
Don't let all
we have end sadly.
That even if you decide
never to come back to me,
that you're gonna let me know
that you are alive and safe.
I once thought you were free,
it seems so irrelevant now.
They might try to jump
us if we get this cash box.
What do you say
we go to the edge
of what's left of this
town, and just observe?
If you think that's best.
I do, let's go.
They stopped again, the
hair might be standing up
on the back of that
stranger's neck.
He'd be the type to
know he's bein' tracked.
Aint no question they're
heading for that cash box.
Since we know their
destination, we gotta...
I'm gonna figure a way
to get there before them.
We approach from the North
side, come on let's git.
Wild Eye, I got an idea, what-
- I gotta take a shit but we
aint got time for neither,
now come on, let's git.
When you
arrive at the church,
go to the crypt named Carson.
Inside it you'll find a
panel below a small panel,
now remove the panel
and you will find
the cash box hidden inside.
Who's there? I heard a noise.
My name is Father Thomas,
I'm the last of our faith
in this house of God,
and as you may have
surmised I'm blind.
I thought the place was
abandoned, seems the town is.
Cholera visited
the town last year,
all those not afflicted
by the plague left.
I decided to stay with
this house of God,
blindness afflicted
me some months ago.
Where are your candles,
your crosses, your relics?
The parish sent
two priests to remove
all the church valuables
after blindness set upon me.
They offered to take
me to a monastery
but I chose to stay
where God chose me to be.
So there's nothing else here?
Myself, a few
robes, one Bible,
all the rest was taken away.
Where did they
take everything?
To the monastery in Santa Rio?
Excuse me, Father.
Do you wish to pray with me?
I am a God-fearing man,
Father,
but right now I
have much business,
maybe next time.
I understand my son, death
is all that is left here.
I knew it, they knew
right where to go.
Something I forgot to mention,
yesterday when we
set off I noticed
the journal page was
missing from my velice.
Perhaps I left it
in the hotel room.
Or perhaps those two have it.
Oh, son of a bitch.
No.
Sweet Jesus!
Shit, that son of a
bitch got here first.
My dear God, what
is happening here?
I heard a crash, is there
more than one of you?
Sorry, padre.
Look, Father, I'm just leaving.
Are you associated with
a man who was here earlier,
ransacking what is
left at my church?
Oh, empty, you've
been here ready?
Si padre, a
with a tiny woman?
It was just one man.
Well, I'm looking for him.
You see he's uh, he's
wanted by the law.
I fear this once noble village
has become a haven for brigands.
It seems they like
its emptiness,
if only these souls would
come here to be saved.
Yeah, this fellow say
where he was headed?
I had the impression he
was headed for Santa Rio.
I don't know this for certain,
but once I relayed to him
that this is where the artifacts
from my church were taken,
he left suddenly.
He didn't exude an evil aura,
but one never truly knows
the nature of a man's soul.
Yeah.
Hey!
Stand and deliver,
you bastard.
Oh hell, you
gotta be kidding me.
We all being in
a tight spot here,
we aim on taking every
last red cent from you.
A ghost town like this,
is a right hide away
from ne'er do wells.
I ain't got time of this.
I was worried about that.
Goddamn, I can't
stand amateurs.
Oh, what's gong on?
My God, have you
finally forsaken me?
Wu!
You see that? Damn!
Dumb bastard, he was a priest.
Oh, hell, that
could've been anybody.
No, you're an
illiterate bastard,
and you're also a half wit
with an itchy trigger finger.
I warned you, Wild Eye,
aint no cause for that talk.
Oh, shut the hell up.
We gotta high tail
it outta here.
Santa Rio, Santa
Rio, tell these men,
to let this town finally die.
What about those fellas?
To hell with them fellas.
Good morning my
son, can I help you?
Oh yes. My family were
some of the plague victims
down in Malsecco last
year, name's Carson.
There was a rather
large family crypt,
in the most sacred church,
been there for some years.
Crypt contained a number
of family heirloom,
and it seems when the town
was beset by the tragedy
your priests retrieved the
precious objects from the church.
Well, it was after Father
Thomas's blindness set in,
the church felt that the
town would be exposed
to any element of
transient wickedness.
As you know, Montesecco
is completely abandoned,
and we asked Father Thomas to
join us here but he refused.
Oh, forgive my rudeness
and my poor manners,
I am Father Raymond.
I've seen Father Thomas,
and he still presides
over his church proudly.
Now, Father, is it possible
that my family's belongings
might have been transferred
to this location?
It's possible, I can
look at the inventory list.
Yes, yes, it appears as though
we have a blocked strong box
with a Confederate
Army seal on it.
Yes, yes. Yes,
that would be it.
One of my family members
served with distinction
in the late war
between the States.
Oh yes, I'm sure.
Well, I will retrieve
your box for you, my son.
Well, my son, is
this what you seek?
Lord in heaven, my family's
legacy has been preserved.
Oh yes, I'm sure.
Ha ha!
For the last two weeks, every
time my leg sings with pain,
I think of you,
you son of a bitch!
I'll refill the canteens,
we better get a damn
early start tomorrow.
You best turn in.
There's a good chance
any one of these characters
could have beaten
us to this thing.
Well, I wonder you may
be chasing up a dead trail,
just as your pursuit of revenge
was ultimately unsatisfying.
Then why do you stay with me?
The Chinese say
that a man or a woman
can sometimes be responsible
for another human being.
Are you responsible for me?
Let's just say I
have a vested interest.
You speak in vagueries.
It's part of my charm.
Ransom?
Get up here.
Go to hell!
I'm already there, lady.
Before I do this and
search all your belongings,
maybe you're gonna
start talking.
As far as I'm concerned.
this whole business has gone far enough.
I never wanted any part of this.
The way I figure, you
gotta know something
that you ain't saying.
So you're gonna move that
sweet little ass of yours,
and you're gonna start talking.
Come on.
What in the hell?
Partner, I got
me this filly here,
'cause I'm tired of you always
be behind the eight ball.
So this little bitch
here is gonna talk,
so we can end this chase.
Tiny woman, what do you know?
I like me a woman
with enthusiasm.
Now why in the hell
did you involve her?
I always figured she
knew more than she let on.
I think she's just leading
on that man hunter.
Wild Eye, trust me, she knows.
You brick!
All right, if you think you
can get something out of her,
you're welcome to try.
I gotta take a piss.
So are you gonna talk? I'm
tired of all this business,
so just talk so we
can put end to this,
so we can be on our way.
What makes you think
I'm gonna give you
two any information.
This has nothing to do with you,
you're just a couple
of crazy greasy gnats,
feeding off what aint yours.
It ain't healthy to
give me sass.
You don't scare me!
You and your half blind
partner are nothing.
You know, I have
never met a lady
who didn't find me appealing.
I'd rather swap
spit with a pig.
Well lady, looks like today.
It's your chance to swap
spit with this pig.
Paper romance little lady.
Get the hell off of her.
I oughta kill you right now.
Sometimes, it's just too much.
I know.
You dumb bastard.
I figured a hunch, the
ladies would be your undoing.
Oh, I wouldn't wiggle
around too much if I were you,
that'll make them ropes
tighter, just relax.
I've got plans for you,
similar to the plans
that you had for me.
You see, friend, I knew
where you was headed.
I rode with Scurlock,
he told me everything,
I just hadn't expected
our little fortunate move.
That's where this
gentleman comes in,
thank God there's still a saw
bone to that hell hole, huh?
Also a good thing, my
friend here overheard
where them priests
moved everything.
Ah, yes, good fortune,
and blessed be our
quick healing paths.
You do realize, now I'm
gonna have to kill you both.
Oh my friend, I do not think
that you will have
that opportunity.
And I told you,
I'm not your friend.
That's a shame.
The world would
be a better place
if everyone was just friends.
Forgive me that I have
such high moral fiber
that I did not kill you
when I had the chance.
Is there something
we can help you with?
Where in the hell are you
boys going in such a hurry
and with such an unusual cargo.
Well, we gotta deliver-
- No, I'm most interested
in the man you have hogtied
back here than your pay load.
I'm Ben Wright, County Marshall
here, and I know this man.
He's a professional,
he occasionally brings me a fugitive.
So just what in the
hell are you boys up to?
He's a wanted man.
The hell you say.
Come on, what in the Sam
Hill is going on here?
I think we wound up with
more than we bargained for.
Right you are, Sheriff
Danburry from Santa Rio,
round them all up, we're
taking them in for questioning.
Throw the bodies in
that.
I never should have
involved you in this,
I thought we'd never
get out of there.
I can't believe that Sheriff
couldn't find anything
to hold that stinker,
he just let him walk.
Well, you can't
blame that Sheriff,
would you wanna be under
the same roof as him?
Again, I never
should've involved you.
I'm here because I want to be.
Spoken with true enthusiasm.
What is it inside
that cash box?
What else, besides the gold?
My past, my future, I hope.
Something I
can't really define.
Well, I reckon.
The sheriff said he'd
be holding that cash box
pending the judge's ruling,
which means he might be
planning on turning it in
to a wartime confiscation.
Oh, and there's one more thing.
Yes?
I've crossed paths with that
dandy of a shootist before.
How many people
know about this?
How many times must I relate
my story before it is true?
I told you, there is a
hearing scheduled for next week,
if your story checks out,
you'll be free to go.
And my property?
Your horses, wagon,
and personal effects
are in safekeeping.
You make no mention
of my strong box!
Yes, well that
will remain here
until I get a decision
from federal authorities.
Why is that?
That's my property!
Listen, Mr. Christie,
I served in the war,
and I recall the
seal of the old CS of A.
I know what that box is
and what it was used for,
this should have been
surrendered to the union in 65.
You should not try my patience
any further in this matter, sir.
Just relax, you have
a week till the hearing.
Hey, old man.
What's the status of this man?
It's really not at
my discretion to opine.
Well, what the
hell does that mean?
It means I have
no jurisdiction
as to the outcome
of this matter.
The judge will oversee
the proceedings next week.
Well how about this
proceeding?
Are you joking?
Do you have any idea
what you're up against?
Yes, I do flannel mouth,
your deputy has left town.
See him leave, now!
Let me have that strong
box, and open up that cell.
You realize this
is a capital offense.
Well, you're absolutely
goddamn right, it is.
Now move it, blatherskite.
Now you let him come
out, you take his place.
And hand him the key,
I'll have you know-
That's for the inconvenience
you two-bit peckerwood.
Grab your rig, and
get whatever else,
I suggest we get ourselves
the hell away from here.
What about the Telegraph?
Oh, tickety
tack, tickety tack.
Now can we get out of here?
I shall offer you my
gratitude on the road.
There'll be time
enough for blabbering,
when we put some
distance between us
and that man huntering
son of a bitch.
Hey!
You'll pay for this.
Not today!
Did you see that?
Where might they go from here?
My guess is West,
fewer settlements,
fewer watering
holes, fewer people.
Then let's go.
You wanna continue?
No question.
You know it's liable to
get fairly dicey here on out.
That dandy is right
dangerous with a pistol.
I'm not worried.
Hmm?
You're with me.
Oh, that's real nice.
I'm big Bully Bryant.
That's wonderful,
you have a very unfriendly
mode of introduction.
You don't remember me, do you?
With a face like that,
I should, but I don't.
I didn't always
look like this.
And?
El Paso, three years ago.
What about it?
Two slugs from this cannon,
carved these creases in my face.
Look at me when I talk to you!
You ran with Salice Cook.
You nailed him coming
out of Hogan, Rhyolite,
a week before you picked me up.
Your face...
As I said, two
cartridges from this iron
Shit, my shooting must
have been off that day.
You know what it's
like to look like this?
People turning their
heads, children scared,
no proper doctor in
that territorial prison.
Shouldn't you still be there?
I'm smart, I got out.
I figured the weakness
and I got out.
Took a guard with me too,
and then I paid a visit to
that petty fogging judge.
He won't sentence
anybody no more.
Now it's my turn.
Yup.
You know, there are a lot
of witnesses around here.
You think these
chinks and Mormons care?
Mormons are too busy looking
after all those wives,
celestials, they know what
happens when you come up
against a white man.
Now, I intend to take
my time with you.
It was years in that hell hole,
what you did to me.
How's the thought
of being a cripple
for the rest of your life?
What if I staked you to
the ground, Injun style,
let the buzzards to
pick out your eyes.
You killers for hire,
you gotta learn,
you ain't the Lord
almighty, more like Judas
'cause it's all about the money.
Ain't it, bounty whore?
I hate verbose people.
Thanks, he was a mic bidder.
I get that from time to time.
Did I do the right thing?
Oh yeah.
What about the sheriff
here? He might not like this.
No sense in bothering him,
those two probably
locked him in his cell.
We don't have time for
this son of a bitch.
Whoa.
What are you doing?
Why are we stopping?
We've gotta make like lightning.
That jail cell was
infested with fleas
and I am a fastidious gentlemen.
Oh for God's grace.
Why did you do
all that back there?
Well, I had a
partner of recent,
not a very smart fellow,
but he stuck with me.
I figured if I can work
this up with a dimwit,
I might as well
make my new partner
a smart professional
like yourself.
At least the way I look at it,
there's enough in that
box for the both of us,
Being as such I'm not gonna
contest, we'll go 50%.
Think of it this way,
it's a new partnership
with money for two.
There's one thing
you're not considering.
What's that?
I did not set out for
this thing with a partner.
Well, all right, I went
to a lot of trouble for you.
And I'm grateful for that.
Fact is, I may not be welcome
in that peckerwoods
jurisdiction for some time.
Say on that note
for safety sake,
why don't we divide
the booty now?
No, we need to put
some distance first
between ourselves and that
man hunter and his tiny bitch.
Well besides, that Sheriff
has probably got himself
sprung from that cage by now.
Well, get a move on!
Oh for God's sake, any day now.
Ya!
You know, those two
are going to assume
that we will follow them,
and this could turn dangerous.
I am not frightened,
and I certainly do
not wish to turn back.
You remind me of your mother.
Tell me, why do you
men have such trouble
committing to people or things?
That's a rather
broad condemnation.
Actually, I've committed to
a number of ideals and causes
over the years.
It's with people that
I have a problem.
That is obvious.
Haven't you had
enough of wandering?
Well, sometimes I believe so,
but it's difficult
to accept something
that you know nothing about.
What would that be?
Peace.
You could have it.
Can we ever
actually have peace?
I intend to.
There you go, sounding
like your mother again.
What is this?
Oh, it's a remembrance
of an old wound.
Whoa.
You know how to use this?
Good, you'll find
it more convenient
than that cannon you carry.
I have a hunch, they have to
be on this trail somewhere.
You maybe right,
look over there.
I figured you two would
catch up sooner or later.
You know why we're here.
Well, possession
is 90% of the law,
besides I got myself
a new partner.
And, where is he?
Well he's tied
up at the moment,
so he won't cause us trouble.
Go on and get off your mounts.
Why don't you go to hell?
No.
I figured you for
a wise ass bitch.
Get off your mounts.
Do as he says.
Guns, please.
I do not want any accidents.
I said, guns please!
You know, it's not wise
to surrender one's weapon.
You get the picture
now, jack ass?
Move the fuck along.
Ya! Go!
This will be a
life-changing moment
that you will live to regret.
Well, sure.
Careful now, there's quicksand
all around these parts.
He's gonna betray us all.
Here's how we play this;
I'll leave the
three of you here,
and take your guns
and the wagon.
At some point due
west, I'll leave,
said guns in the
ground, and I disappear.
Where I will never look upon
the likes of all you again.
Kill him!
I've been too far
to let this bush wacker
get the best of me.
You, sir, are a twitchy,
nervous wild card,
which is why you're tied.
Now is the jack of diamonds
and the queen of hearts,
gonna give me any trouble?
Good, you two have more sense.
Is this your man?
I said, is this your man!
You just signed
your death warrant.
Well, no matter who this
whore shares her bed with,
little sister you're
coming with me.
I'm taking you as
an insurance policy,
but you might find
me interesting.
I'll get you,
bastard, I promise.
I just saved you
from the wages of sin.
Money is the root of
all kinds of evil!
Know that you go forth in this
life with untarnished souls.
Now I bid you adieu, you'll
find your weapons
a mile or so down the road,
after all I am a Christian,
and a man of my word.
Yeah, right.
Well, don't just
stand there, untie me.
My hunch is to leave you tied.
Oh, listen, I know we've
been on the opposite sides
of this thing all along.
Well, now's the time
to forget all that,
if we don't, we'll never see
the contents of that box,
and you'll never see
your woman again.
She's not my woman.
Okay, but do you still
wanna see her go off
with that depraved bastard?
All right, I will
untie you, but no tricks.
You are a wild card.
Aint we all.
Much obliged.
We need a plan.
Fine, what do you figure?
Do you intend to release me?
Whoa.
As I said, do yo
intend to release me?
I have not yet
decided, pretty flower.
Will you release me
when you drop the guns?
I'm a man who has needs,
except my needs are quite
different from other men.
My tastes run to adventurous
sport with the ladies,
that is when I allow myself
to consort with your sex.
You see, I find most women
to be filthy creatures,
little brains, not much to offer
but carnal comforts.
After partaking in a woman,
I have little use for her.
Most of them don't live long
after the act is completed.
You may be in for a surprise.
Well, I welcome the challenge.
You may have misjudged me.
Did I, pretty flower?
I think he's dead.
Yeah.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Now it's the time to see
what all the fuss is about.
Thank you.
All right, let me in there.
Whoa!
Damn!
No one touches anything!
Little sister, you
have my.
That derringer may have
knocked the wind out of me,
but it did not penetrate deep
enough, I've been shot before.
You'd been better
off to kill me.
See, after I murder
your man here,
and possibly Mr One Eye,
you and I are
gonna have a party.
There's a great deal
of money in there.
You are so right.
It was in here all along.
Maybe your journey
is at an end.
Maybe.
Maybe you found that
peace we talked about.
What about the rest of it?
I don't care about it,
whatever's left in here
came from an evil place.
I am glad of one thing though.
Yes?
That I saw you on your
way to that place of peace.
They say there's wonderful
country in Montana,
we could go together.
After all, we make a good team.
You should start a new
life on your own terms.
Forget the past,
find a good man,
settle down, raise a family.
Well now, aint this touching.
Now this is little drawing
room romance is over,
let's get to it.
I almost forgot about you.
And what's the
story with my gun.
I removed all the
percussion caps.
Are you deaf? I could've
been killed, you bastard.
You think I trust
you with a loaded gun?
Well, forget about that.
What are we gonna do about that?
Well, I'm glad you asked me.
What the hell?
I've had about
enough of the chaos
this damn box has created.
You're taking it
for yourself, you pig!
Nope, I'm letting you
have the whole damn thing.
No!
Untie me you bastard.
Only thing is,
I'd figure out a way
to get out from
under those ropes
before the damn thing sinks.
Untie me!
I never could stand
quicksand, dirty stuff.
I swear if you
don't cut these ropes,
I'll kill you if I ever see you.
What would life be without
a little challenge, adios.
I'll be back to see you,
wherever you settle,
and I will be there
for you forever.
I almost believe it this time.
I mean it.
Despite your wandering
ways, I know that you will be.
You are the most decent
man I have ever known,
I love you with all my heart.
You know something?
What?
I think I may be ready
for that place of peace now.
I may not be far behind you.
Be strong, young lady.
I will be back someday.
I know you will.
I know you will be.
I swear to Christ
if I ever find you,
I'll cut you from ear to
ear you son of a bitch!
Nobody does this to me, you
double dealing wrangler.
Nothing in this
world is ever even!
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull