Prometheus
Produced by "Ukrainfilm" studio.
Kiev, 1936.
Written and directed
by: Ivan Kavaleridze
Operator: Nikolai Topchij Production
design: Vasili Krichevsky & Yu. Mayer
Composed by: Andria Balanchivadze & Paul
Tolstyakov Sound Editor: A. Prakhov
Cast: Ivas - P. Tverdokhleb
Katherina - Polina Nyatko
Svichka, colonel - Aleksandr Serdyuk
Zhukov, merchant - Ivan Shtraukh
Sidorenko, manager - G. Jura
Nastasia Markovna - N. Uzhviy
Ladansky, general - I. Marianenko
Russian gendarme - I. Nekrutenko
Nikolai I - V. Ershov
Princess Dadiani - E. Eristova-Zhgenti
Gavrilov, revolutionary -
Daniil Antonovich Captured Georgian
Sh. Nozadze T. Shevchenko - N. Nademsky
Episodes: V. Chistiakova,
E. Osmialovskaya, V.
Lisovsky, Z. Tereshvili,
P. Morgulia, S. Panikovsky,
D. Vvedensky and others
Katherina, I can see what's going on.
Pan*, I can see what's going on.
Here is my bride
You are our Pan
You declared us (your
people) free, but...
Katherina, when I have
finished my working duties
I'll cover the roof with reed
and mother will [unintelligible] it.
You would help me.
In the autumn we can move in.
Our house will be warm
We'll buy a horse from
the gypsies, graze it
Our child will graze it
It didn't go as expected, the Pan sent
Ivas away as a conscript soldier.
Panichi*, steward, what will we do now?
My litte dove, "Moscow
doesn't listen to tears." *
If only you Panichi knew
how the people are weeping!
Then you wouldn't do such things!
It's all in vain, mother,
the Pani are deaf
Even God has only ears made of tin.
A travelling agent of the Rogozhsky
church-trade union, Piotr Zhukov.
Your Nobleness, the Rogozhsky
church-trade union...
is like a Makariev brotherhood.
For you, a landowner with
such a paradisical plumage...
it means the Kingdom of Heaven and the
straightest way to the
Nizhegorodskaya province.
For my sales, the Ilyinskaya
province is enough.
Your nobleness, didn't God,
who was born in a crib,
in a simple sheep-fold,
stretch out his hand to
embrace the whole world?
We're fighting for the Caucasus,
stretching our hand as far as Persia,
closing the circle:
Caucasus, Persia, Astrakhan, Nizhny,
the Ukraine, and again the Caucasus.
Steamboats puff, trains rattle,
people turn over their roubles fast...
You, Piotr Zhukov, ought to
be not a traveller, but...
I'm a traveller because I'm walking
on my own land with my own feet.
I'd like to be free in my business,
and have enough rights
to help our country's
industry with cloth, leather,
supply soldiers for example
with bread crust, bandages.
It'll be such a business,
such a business...
for you and for us.
I'm in love with this business.
H-mmm, yes.
This girl you have here, Your
nobleness, she's so good.
I'd take her and turn her into
a performing artist at the Nizhny fair.
What a girl, I'm in love with this girl!
Simply in love.
I'm leaving today. It's war.
I'll be in Moscow.
In Moscow...
Good luck in the war against
Shamil, Your nobleness.
See you in Moskow - we'll make a deal.
My kind regards to the brotherhood.
When passing through,
take a look at the crops.
Be careful, Georgy Pavlovich,
this katsap* has "very round eyes."
We are people of the
same Czar, Sidorenko.
It's good, Georgy Pavlovich,
to have a Czar in common,
But as to money, it's
better to have it separate.
Georgy Pavlovich, olives...
Bring some olives. Olives.
Olives?
Olives from the Caucasus. Olives.
Two deadly enemies, two powers:
The revolution and Russia.
What means life for one -
means death for the other...
Farewell, Sigismund!
Farewell, Gavrilov!
We shall meet yet.
Feklusha... Farewell, Feklusha!
I'm Maria.
Well, Maria. Farewell, Maria.
Gavriov - to the army.
Michailov - to the army.
And you - to Siberia.
"In the depths of the Siberian ores,
preserve your proud and noble patience."
"Your sorrowful toil
will not be lost, Nor
will be your lofty aspirations." [A.
Pushkin]
Oh, it's so hot.
Did you march all the
way in the uniforms?
I'm not taking it off.
The old people say:
While I'm wearing it, it's mine.
Maybe later they will
give us better uniforms
Sure.
A samovar to put on your head,
and bottles to cover your feet.
The old people say:
It's better to remove the tree stump.
Such a grea man, but...
so maybe it will get easier for us?
What do you mean?
Better
a completely different person
That's right.
One thing is a dog
without a collar, and...
- ...what's your name?
- Ivas.
And another thing is
a dog with a collar.
"The Rogozhsky church-trade union."
The war is coming to an end.
Somebody is getting rich.
Only it isn't you and me.
I certainly need money.
Buy my girl. A very good girl.
I'm an Old Believer.
We don't trade in people.
Your uncle is a general. He's in the
good graces of the Prince-Governor.
Your Nobleness,
if you get him to support us
we'd make such business together...
provide clothes for our army,
sell wares to the mountain dwellers,
buy goods from them,
plant cotton on their land,
build our own factory like in Tver,
all profits, all profits!
Very well. I can see
you're a businessman.
A factory is profitable.
Serve our fatherland. And
I'm giving you the girl.
She will love you.
I'm a liberal. My uncle
was a Decembrist.
The girl was freed long ago,
and now I offer her to
you for a wife, but...
in the Eastern custom: for a ransom.
My sincere thanks, Your Nobleness.
I shall love her so...
What a beauty, like a fruit-candy.
Oh, aunt.
Today we expect visitors!
And what visitors!
Ah, what people!
Oh, aunt.
Brother...
Nastasia, this is a newcomer.
What?
You will also be like my own sister.
I was frightened,
I thought it was the police.
No!
We have no license for the
institution, Piotr Ilyich.
Here is your license:
From the threshold - to the table,
lead them to the decanter,
make them sit down next to the pies.
Serve them as much drink and food
until everybody drops down in a stupor.
Rights...
♪ Carriages were standing by the church
♪ there was a sumptuous wedding
♪ All the guests were
dressed luxuriously
♪ The bride was blooming like a rose
bride...
♪ All the guests were
dressed luxuriously
♪ The bride was blooming like a rose
Her own fiancé will not recognize her.
♪ A bride in a white dress
♪ with a bunch of roses pinned to it
♪ she was looking at the crucifix
♪ so sadly that she made everybody cry
Observe the rules of the
business*, Nastasia.
You need to keep these people fat,
feed them properly.
A businessman gets rich by good
calculation, not by miserliness.
I'll do my best, Piotr Ilyich
Don't worry, we'll make an effort.
One cannot make any special business
with "Dunkas" and Khokhol girls. *
Now if we had a Persian
princess in our business...
Soon the road to Persia will be opened,
the war of the Caucasus will end.
There will be also new
goods: olives, rice...
Nastasia, olives! Rice, Nastasia!
What a merchandise - olives...
I'm thinking about the Persian princess.
How could Stenka Razin* throw
such a priceless girl into the river...
The Savage!
I'm making a low bow before the Boyar.
Let your "smerd" * kiss
your hand, Master.
Your feet, benefactor
You were a beloved and nice man,
when I first knew you.
Let me kiss your lips...
your nose... your navel
Dunka, don't be a fool!
Go to the devil!
The devil? But this is where
I've come to, from the devil!
You Herod! You Judas Iscariot!
For 30 pieces of silver you sold Jesus!
Antichrist!
Dunka, come to your senses!
I can't, I can't, I
can't stand it anymore!
I can't, I can't, I can't
What the hell is the
matter with you, Dunka?
Dunka!
Anathema! Here! Here!
Demon! Demon! Demon!
Dunka!
What a harmful girl. A
bad loss for the house.
You're a... good girl...
Here, take it, you'd better
hang yourself first.
This is a grave.
This is death.
What nonsense!
[Taras Shevchenko "Kavkaz"
(Caucasus) 1845] (transl. John Weir)
Mighty mountains, row on row,
blanketed with cloud,
Planted thick with human woe,
laved with human blood.
Chained to a rock, age after age,
Prometheus there bears
Eternal punishment - each day
his breast the eagle tears.
It rends the heart but cannot drain
the life-blood from his veins
Each day the heart revives again
and once again is gay.
The superstition of these people
may resist any enlightenment...
but they can't be insensible
to the benefits of improvement...
A host of soldiers on those
hills gave up their lives.
And as for blood!? All emperors could
drink their fill. (T.Shevchenko)
A riddle I cannot solve.
It pains my soul.
A great pity, that our plans
were not successful.
So much priceless blood wasted.
But through the overall
strength of the army...
Russia will always be stronger
than all her enemies.
Your Majesty, new army
equipment is necessary:
The new rifles can fire from 2000 steps.
Conic bullets which dig deep into
the body, making a deadly wound.
This is why the Chechen are
beating us, Your Majesty.
"The bullet is a fool,
the bayonet is a fine chap". Nikolai
We need to speak to the Princess.
We were sent here for this.
The Princess cannot see you.
Then inform her...
- in writing?
- No, verbally.
Never mind.
Over there, on the other
side of the river,
many discontent people are gathering.
These are peaceful highlanders.
Horava* himself is going down the river.
10.000 highlanders, Mingrels,
Imeretins* are with him...
Why are they coming here,
those "peaceful highlanders"?
When they're here - they'll tell.
The princess will see you.
Just wipe your feet here,
and go to the upper gardens.
What do you want, my good men?
[unintelligible] [Georgian]
[unintelligible]
We'd better talk inside.
[unintelligible] [Georgian]
[unintelligible]
Our people's leader - our "Danton"
He says he's a blacksmith.
Each is forging his own fortune.
My good man,
we have the same God, the same Czar.
Englishmen - predators, would be very
pleased if there were quarrels among us
to get their claws and beaks
into our young body.
What do they want from us?
To them, this is a foreign land,
a foreign religious faith.
They just have the lust to destroy.
Shamil was bought by the English.
And now instead of good peaceful life...
English gunpowder burns out our eyes.
The English are ephemeral,
we are real.
We will bring you a good life.
Taking the trousers from
Christian soldiers?
It's for you, wounded brothers,
for lint and bandage.
They took off our trousers,
burned incense over us.
The funeral has been properly performed.
There will be a final judgment.
An angel will blow the silver trumpet.
Christian soldiers who gave their
life for Czar and fatherland
will be judged,
blank-arsed,
before the Highest Throne.
St. John the Warrior will
avert his eyes from such a host.
The Czar, who only sees us on parades,
will not raise his cup to such victors.
And the main thing is: how do I return
to my aul* without my trousers?
The dogs will snap at me
We are the Russian army.
We repelled the enemy.
Friendly forces were ahead, but...
We are serfs.
[Georgian]
You'll be given some trousers now.
Let me hold your baby.
I won't drop him.
I could have had my own baby,
if it weren't for...
The serfs, Your Highness.
Yes, the serfs. I know.
The whole aul, Your Highness.
Yes, the whole aul, my good men.
Go!
Your Excellency, allow
me to take command.
You are so wonderful, so nice.
The Lord knows, Your Highness,
how devotedly I love you.
Why are those men coming here?
What a rotten people!
This shooting is no
good, Your Nobleness.
What are we shooting for?
To cripple the people?
Also, it frightens the live stock.
The cattle are nervous animals,
and their fright affects the milk.
War is not a market, Piotr Zhukov.
It's a fair, Your nobleness, a fair!
Buy and sell!
How strange! Our regiment!
They're our men! Ours!
Ours indeed! They're shooting at us,
this means they are Russians.
Gavrilov, ours!
This is the 4th platoon!
Maybe I... should go...
Ours!
Ours! Ours!
Gavrilov, ours!
Surrender!
We'll show mercy on you.
Your nobles will do the same.
You're scumbags. Graveworms. Even worse!
Worms eat the dead, but
you're eating us alive.
Soldiers, muzhiks!
There was such man, Prometheus,
chained to a rock over the abyss,
a mighty eagle picking at his heart.
And our muzhik's heart
is picked at by a mean two-headed crow
who is plucked to last
feather in wars of conquest.
Strangle the bastard!
Fire!
Forward!
Follow the leader, don't fall out!
Neither fire nor water will help.
Riots in the villages, riots on the
Volga, riots in the factories.
The dawn of freedom is breaking.
Take him alive!
Forward!
Hurrah!
Hurrah! Hurrah! Hurrah!
I order each soldier of the company
to hit him in the face.
Hit him hard, so that he and
the others will understand...
that revolution in Russia is impossible.
Attention!
Company!
Fire!
A court-martial shall be prepared
for Private Gavrilov and the others.
Report the court's decision
to His Excellency.
Line up the captives!
Her Highness, Princess
Elena Konstantinovna
wants to give them as a
present to the victors.
Their belongings will be
sent as a war trophies
to Nizhny via Derbent with
Piotr Zhukov's treck of carts.
What strong men...
What Apollos...
20 strokes each, and
then march them off...
Godspeed!
They were given 20 strokes,
and with Piotr Zhukov's treck
sent by the long road:
Via Derbent, Temir-Khan-Shura,
Astrahan, by the Volga -
to the fair at Nizhny...
♪ [trad. Cossack song "Volga"] The
daughter of steep banks, lower banks,
♪ Caspian winds and the legends of Tver
♪ suddenly arose from the steep banks
♪ the warrior Corporal
Yemelyan Pugachev.
♪ The steppe wind howls
over the Zhiguli mountains,
♪ the free Cossack Stenka
answers from afar.
A drunken merchant is bad for business.
A merchant must use his brains.
Hey, you there!
Why are those empty barges hanging
about the river banks like whores?
And the men are looking weak.
Who picked them?
Dragging their feet...
Hey, make haste!
I told the general:
Building a rail road with our people
- You'll be flooded with riots.
You must find workers somewhere else.
Ivan Ivanich, you're a chief of police.
What's wrong with you?
You've been given ranks, medals,
Embroidered with gold, not only on
your chest, even somewhere else.
You're totally useless!
Riots everywhere!
Where's the major? Where
are the gendarmes?
Don't you love "capital" anymore?
Fear God, honour the Czar,
but love "capital", Ivan Ivanich.
[song, unintelligible]
"Manufactory (textile mill).
Armand and sons."
[unintelligible]
"Carriages & harnesses
- M.I. Michailovs"
Hello, sister, has been
God been merciful to you?
We live and we work, we believe
in God, and we honour the Czar.
Talented bitches! Excellent.
We're doing our best...
to follow the example of our betters.
I see.
[song in some Caucasian language]
[unintelligible]
Arrest me, arrest me!
Indeed... alas... how awkward...
Write down: the prisoner
tried to escape.
♪ Who can foretell my fortune?
♪ Tomorrow, my falcon,
♪ who shall untie the knot on my bosom?
♪ Tied up by you?
♪ Who shall untie the knot on my bosom?
Ivan Tverdokhleb
This is colonel Svechka's
serf, he's "polimkovy"...
it means "by mistake"...*
You can talk as you like,
I'm from the Kobelyansky (phon.
[Unintelligible])
region myself, I can
understand your language.
He's been taken for a rebel by mistake.
Believe my word, let him
return to the Ukraine.
Give him 50 strokes, so that the evil
spirit will part from him forever.
Yes. Yes-yes-yes
Why, you brute, you devil's spawn,
poking your nose into the revolution?
Trying to squeeze with your pork stall
into our bread lines!
In the morning the carts are going home.
They aren't oiled,
horses aren't scrubbed.
To the carts with you, you mug!
Ivas!
Look who's here!
How odd!
You're not the first, and not the last.
It's in the order of things.
The dawn of freedom is breaking.
I plan to...
I won't say.
I must go to the carts.
Why so early?
The best hour for work
is in the morning.
This room is not properly prepared:
No lamps.
Red lights are needed,
flowers, curtains.
A wider flight of stairs,
a cash register displayed
prominently, a bar,
and a bunch of suitable men, strong
enough and with brutal faces.
A good master must give every business
it's own physiognomy.
But Piotr Ilich...
Piotr Ilich, what about
our "rights" (license)?
Rights...
The Czar grants freedom
to all businessmen.
This means our business
will also have rights.
Girls... The sun is shining...
and flowers here.
We have happy news today!
We are legalized!
The master had his way.
Now we'll do our job legally.
Girls, tomorrow we're going to Moscow.
There's music in Moscow, red lights...
And the police can go to hell now!
Father...
father, father... father
- A prayer of thanks?
- A prayer of thanks, father.
You've got much money I guess?
Praise the Lord, we've earned it.
And it wasn't a loss
to our master either.
God loves the people's labour.
To which saint?
Which one...
Panteleiman. Young, beautiful,
serious, strict.
You fool. Panteleiman is for toothache.
He's no concern to our business.
Forty saints.
Antony! He's always painted
with a naked woman.
A shameless saint, nothing more.
Let's perform the service to the Blessed
Virgin, this will be best of all.
♪ Glory to the Father
both now and forever...
♪ and until the ages of ages. Amen.
♪ O Heavenly King, the
comfortor, the spirit of Truth,
♪ Who art present everywhere
and fillest all things
♪ Treasury of Blessings
and Giver of Life
♪ come and abide in us and
cleanse us from every stain,
Why did Dunka leave? Call her.
♪ And save our souls, O Gracious One.
You Herod's dancing daughter!
Nastasia asks you to join the prayer.
"Princess"! I'll tell her. She will
not hesitate to come here herself.
What an evil spirit.
Dunka! You nasty shameless girl.
You need to pray more
than all the others.
The master will get angry
when I tell him about it.
Gunib taken. Shamil crushed.
Trophies. Captives.
The victors returned to their estates...
Today we celebrate three things:
The end of great and victorious war,
an amicable union with a
very brave Caucasian nation,
and the first anniversary
of the marriage
of Her Highness the Princess
Elena Konstantinovna
with my nephew Georgy Pavlovich.
The Caucasian nations which
were free since the old times,
only began to delight in freedom
after the Russians conquered them.
If you could feel only
half of my "delight",
then I'd really be delighted.
[unintelligible] [Caucasian language]
[unintelligible]
I say: one day she'll
get what she deserves.
Enough!
Whip them! Whip them!
If only you knew what
kind of devils they are!
And what vengeance they deserve!
Whip them! Flay them alive!
What are you doing, little father?
Scaring the toads, so they won't croak
when the Panichi are asleep.
That's good.
We need a whip to lash,
but not for toads.
The toads are not guilty towards us.
Let them croak.
Why are you here?
Prokofy.
Gregory. Piotr. Eudokim.
Sidorenko! Call Sidorenko!
What do you want?
Today is the first anniversary
after we defeated Private Gavrilov,
and got medals and crosses
for our victory over him.
That's why I'm here.
And they want to watch.
You rats!
Dirty rats!
I'm Sidorenko, pan Svichka's manager.
A riot!
A riot? In a village? This cannot be.
What's going on... what's going on...
They sing forbidden songs,
that crazy soldier hit the Pan right in
his face, in front of all the others.
A man don't consist of only a face.
His own Pan! And what a Pan he is!
[unintelligible] [Ukrainian]
[unintelligible]
I've come to build a
factory in your region.
We shall raise the people with capital.
Young and old will start
thinking about their own interests.
Get in, I'm going your way.
Ivas, what's gonna happen next?
Next, we'll fight.
If we can't overcome... in vain...
At least something...
The dawn of freedom is breaking.
Why sheepskin?
There will be a winter,
and maybe not only one.
The end.
Subtitles: IBoris & serdar202