I promise to take care of your heart...
until the end of my life.
I want to see you adorned.
Let me go, Thom.
You and Omar are my life.
I will return.
Ahmad!
Take it easy, Grandma.
I'm here. Easy, easy.
Grandma, we should go to the hospital.
No.
If I go,
I will never come back to this house.
There isn't much time.
I won't be here much longer.
Please don't say that.
I want to know, Ahmad.
Before I die,
I want to know
what really happened.
Listen to the story I kept
all these years,
from beginning to end.
I never believed in love at first sight...
but it happens
when you least expect it.
Have a look, then choose.
All fresh from the sea.
All the fishes are fresh.
Come. Take a look at the fresh fish.
There's mackerel, sardines, threadfish...
-Come and take a look.
-Miss.
-Have a look first.
-These are fresh fishes.
Thom, if you want the good ones,
go there.
Come. There are lots of fresh fishes.
Somehow they always end up at Othman's.
You're right.
Salmah.
Mackerel, Man. Like always.
Give me the big ones.
-The usual right, Salmah?
-Yes, like always.
This is my friend, Thom.
Che Puteh's grandniece.
Che Puteh is unwell.
She's here to look after her.
-Salmah.
-What do you want, Karim?
Thank you, Man.
What?
I'll have the same.
All items are RM1.
That's too much.
It's okay. Take it.
For Che Puteh.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Che Thom.
Are you done?
We'll take our leave now.
-Che Thom.
Your basket looks awfully heavy.
Fresh fish, come and choose!
Brother, that looks heavy. Be careful.
Those hips might just give out.
Salmah.
Taib, I'm going to get more fish.
Man.
Don't stare too long at that house.
What if the walls break?
To Che Thom who...
Dear...
For...
Othman.
Oh, God.
Thank you.
You haven't been here in a while.
Che Puteh hasn't been well.
I can't leave her for long.
Salmah is with her now.
Have you ever been out to the sea?
I'm actually afraid of the deep sea.
I'm scared of drowning.
But the sea is calmer than the shore.
How is that possible?
Close your eyes.
Close them.
Imagine you're alone
in the middle of the ocean.
Look at the sky.
Blue.
Bathed in sunlight.
As far as the eye can see.
Picture the ocean.
As green...
as it is deep...
with no end in sight.
All is quiet.
There is no other sound
except for your heartbeat.
That's calm to me, Che Thom.
But the sea is never calm. Right, Othman?
Otherwise...
that boat wouldn't be like that.
Washed up...
and abandoned.
At least the boat had been to sea.
What good is a boat
if it's just anchored by the shore?
Che Puteh.
Oh, my God.
Grandma!
-Che Puteh. Thom.
-Grandma!
-Che Puteh. Oh, my God. I warned her.
-Grandma.
Grandma.
How did you fall? Grandma. Grandma Puteh.
Grandma's death
left me lost and alone.
I lost a shoulder to cry on
and someone to love.
Che Thom.
How much longer will you be here?
Che Thom, don't go.
Che Thom, you don't have to leave.
Just stay here.
If I...
Che Thom, how long...
-When do you have to go?
-What is it, Othman?
When is Che Puteh leaving?
How much longer will you be here?
A day or two.
There's no reason for me to stay on.
I have no one to stay for.
Before you go...
I know that
I have no riches
nor a family.
I am too ordinary.
And yet I am unashamed to dream of...
having you as my wife.
I will work hard.
I will try.
As long as there's strength in my body,
I'll work hard to give you--
You do have no shame, Othman.
Why would you think
I'd place riches before heart?
We are just the same.
I, too, have nothing, Othman...
except for a heart.
A heart that loves.
I promise...
I promise to take care of your heart...
until the end of my life.
We married soon after.
I have never been as happy, Ahmad.
But two years later,
Japan invaded Malaya.
Hurry up, keep walking!
Japan soon occupied the whole country.
Day after day,
our lives became even more difficult.
Move! Hurry up and go!
Move!
Move now!
Freedom from the British!
Hurry up.
Friends turned to enemies.
Traitors were everywhere.
Calm down, everyone. They are here
to free us from British occupation.
All the men have to help the Japanese.
Malays, Indians, here.
Chinese, over there. Hurry up!
Asia for Asians!
Japan is our ally,
and they want to help us.
Move.
I have to go, Thom.
Man. Don't go, Man. Don't go.
Don't worry.
I'll find a way home.
No need to be afraid.
Just follow him.
That was the first time Othman left me.
Move! Hurry up and go!
The Chinese-Japanese war that started
in mainland China spilled over here.
The Japanese continued their revenge
on the Chinese in Malaya.
Thank you.
We stop here. Exchange the control.
We'll move after an hour.
Everyone, listen up.
An hour from now, we move on from here.
We are going behind that mountain
to build an airport.
Hurry up and cook.
Hey.
Say "Peace be upon you, Omar." Quick.
Peace be upon you, Omar.
-Peace be upon you, Omar.
-Peace be upon you, too.
Didn't expect to see you here.
What are the odds?
Damn Japanese.
The Chinese were hunted
and murdered viciously.
You've been made.
That man is Chinese.
Better make a run for it now.
Why are you telling me this?
It's okay. Relax.
Go deal with it and do it now.
Relax.
Get him! Capture him!
Find them!
I know where you are hiding.
There is no place to hide here.
Search there!
You will not escape.
Come out!
Hurry, find them.
They could be hiding amongst the bodies.
Do you understand my instructions?
This place is terrible
and smells very bad.
Come out!
Make sure the dead are really dead.
Hold it!
Enough.
They are not here. Let's go.
We are wasting time.
It's getting dark.
We'll look for them again tomorrow.
Let's go!
Hey.
Is this big enough?
Let's stay here.
The Japanese are everywhere.
Does it hurt?
Let me see.
How is it?
We can stitch this up when we get home.
You?
Yours.
Oh, this? It's nothing.
Just like what the cowboys say
in the movies.
Lum Kah Weng.
Come again?
My name.
I don't look like an Omar, right?
The Japanese can't tell the difference.
What do they know?
Long live the Emperor!
That's all they know.
Othman.
Othman, I'm going to take care of you.
Don't worry.
I will bring you back safely to Serkam.
If it weren't for you,
we wouldn't be in trouble.
You're right.
In the name of God,
most gracious, most merciful.
Thank God everything went well, Thom.
Do you have a name yet?
We'll wait for his father to come home.
There is somebody there. Hurry.
Hurry.
The Japanese were still around.
Those who managed to escape
hid in other villages
for months.
Othman?
Man.
God is great.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-I'll go now.
-Thank you.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you, too.
Man.
Peace be upon you.
Have you named him?
I was waiting for you.
Omar.
The first time he left me,
he came back.
He almost lost his life,
but he came home.
Peace be upon you.
Grandma.
Mom is here.
Mom.
Mother, what's wrong?
After the war,
we thought
our suffering would finally end.
But life was still very hard.
So much had been destroyed.
Othman says
nothing good ever comes easy.
You have to chase after it.
That's why he goes out
further than anyone else.
He works harder than everyone else.
-Taib!
-Thom.
Have you seen Man?
He was in the sea just now.
I asked him to come back, but he wouldn't.
He's alone out there.
Take me out there.
We can't go now.
-I'll go after the rain stops.
-I'm coming with you.
-You can't.
-I'm coming with you!
Okay.
But not now.
I'll look for him when it clears up.
You're up early today.
Thom?
Didn't you go home?
Let's go. The weather's clear.
Don't worry, Thom.
We'll find him.
God willing, he'll be safe.
-Man! Taib, that's Othman. Man!
-Man!
Taib, hurry.
Man!
Careful with your hands, Thom.
Don't you do this again, Man.
Don't you ever leave me again.
Man, you sure are stubborn.
That was the second time
Othman left me and returned to me.
I thought twice was enough.
After this,
our family would live in peace.
The wind blows
The branch falls on the rock...
You're heavy, Omar.
One.
Two.
Birds chirping in fright
Peace be upon you.
Dark cloudy sky...
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you, too.
You're back. What took you so long?
-It's been a while.
-You're looking good now.
You're all grown up now.
They've had it good after the war.
Lots of ships...
lots of work.
I'll head back now, Man.
-Peace be upon you.
-Who's that, Dad?
Sailors, Omar.
What are sailors?
They work on big ships...
and go around the world.
The whole world?
That's fun.
Thank God.
I'm starving.
-Thom, I'm going to see Karim.
-Can I come with you?
-Finally, I'm home.
-Did you run into any storm?
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you, too.
-How are you, Karim?
-What's this?
Kid, look here.
-Omar, look straight ahead.
-One, two, three.
Omar didn't know what was about to happen.
But I knew.
He was leaving us both again.
Our memories together
Oh, how I missed you
O, moon!
Where are the stars?
On top of...
The ficus tree
Come, sir
Come, love
Let's go
For a stroll
Many stars
Befriending the moon
Come.
Where to?
For a stroll.
It's a clear night.
Many stars befriending the moon.
Come.
-Don't cry.
-Don't go, Man.
I don't want us to be poor
for the rest of our lives.
But we...
We'll make it work here.
I can sew a lot more. You can--
What else can I do, Thom?
I am of the sea, Thom.
The sea is all I know.
I want to see you adorned.
If not in diamonds...
then in gold, even just a tiny piece.
I once promised you...
if you accept me as your husband...
I will strive for riches for you.
But I don't want that, Man.
We have enough.
Let me go, Thom.
You won't forget me?
-Never.
-Promise.
Promise me you'll come back to me, Man.
Thom, you and Omar are my life.
I will come home.
Like a ship with no direction
Love, to be loved
Thank you.
It's all done, Taib.
Wait!
I almost missed it.
Peace be upon you, Omar.
-Man.
-Lum.
Never mind.
Look at you.
I'm more used to your
"I want to go home" face.
Thom.
You're Che Thom?
No wonder you forced me
to bring you back to Serkam.
Thom, this is Lum.
Omar. This is Omar, my son.
-Omar?
-Omar.
He's handsome like me.
Hey.
-Are you working on the ships, too?
-Yes. I'll be on the Swyre.
Me too.
Swyre?
Good, I have a friend.
Che Thom, don't worry.
I will take good care of your husband.
If he misbehaves, I'll...
Hey.
Omar, study hard.
Take care of the chickens.
Take care of my boat.
I want to see them all cared for
when I come back.
Yes, Father.
Take care of your mom.
Write to me, Man.
Thom, you know
I'm not good at writing letters.
Try.
Move over.
And that was the last time I saw him.
I want to know
why he never came home, Ahmad.
Is he still alive or is he dead?
And if he has passed, how did he die?
Where is his grave?
I want you to find
where your grandfather is today.
I need to know...
before I die.
It's been many years, Grandma.
How do I look for him?
Where do I even start?
Try and ask your father.
Mother, Omar--
Jaybah, I know.
Grandma.
Even if I start looking,
-I don't think I can get any answers.
-Try, Ahmad.
-Peace be upon you, Dad.
-Peace be upon you, too.
You just arrived, Ahmad?
-Yes, Dad.
-Have you eaten?
Yes, I have.
Dad.
Can I ask you something?
I want to ask about Grandad.
The wind blows
The branch falls on the rock
Dad.
Dad?
You just arrived, Ahmad.
Have you eaten?
Yes.
Those are mine.
Can I have a look?
This was when your mom and I
went on our very first date.
What about this one?
This was when I was doing my masters
in London.
I received a scholarship that time.
This one? What map is this?
My father's map.
TO OMAR
Dad. This...
You just arrived, Ahmad?
Have you eaten?
THOM & OMAR, LAMA ROAD,
SERKAM VILLAGE, MALACCA, MALAYSIA
Unload quickly! Don't be lazy!
After leaving Serkam,
Father boarded a ship from Singapore.
He was the only Malay
amongst other seasoned sailors.
The work was hard.
But he never felt it. All that mattered
was a better life for his family.
Don't be lazy! Hurry up!
Move faster!
Working again? What is he doing?
-Strong wind, heavy rain.
-Again?
Eat pork. You'll be fine.
Are you an idiot?
He's Muslim. He doesn't eat pork.
Actually, I don't know what they eat.
Maybe he eats the wind.
That's why he's always outside.
Right.
He doesn't eat much,
but he's still stronger than you both.
What did you say?
Well?
Don't you understand?
Lum.
Hey.
Go do your work.
Let's go.
What's the point of fighting them?
They piss me off.
If I don't care, why should you?
You picked up Chinese real fast.
It's all right.
Give me your "best in the world"
cabbage soup.
It's so delicious
it makes ducks mate out of season.
Give me a taste.
I want to know if that's true.
This brother of mine
Sails around the world
He is missing his wife
And he is miserable
-Mail!
-Thank you.
Mail!
-Have you done all the work I gave you?
-Yes, teacher.
Good.
Go to your mother.
Mother, did the postman come?
Are you hungry?
Tomorrow, maybe.
Maybe tomorrow Dad's letter will arrive.
I'll come home early from school.
I want to wait for the postman.
Mom, you have to try
so when Dad's letter comes,
you can read it.
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you, too.
-Omar.
Your book, Omar.
You left it at school.
Thank you, teacher.
-I'll make a move then.
-Thank you.
If Omar
or whoever needs me to teach...
I mean, it's good to learn.
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
Mail!
Postman, wait!
Mail! Wait!
Anything else?
No.
Mom, look at this.
"With love and affection
from Othman Haji Alias."
Didn't I tell you it would arrive today?
Didn't I?
What are you doing?
This is not the first time
you're stealing food!
You call this stealing?
I took so little. It wasn't so much.
If I don't take it, it will rot,
and you throw it out anyway.
Nobody gets special privileges here.
Including you!
-Chef.
-Don't get involved.
Just hold on.
It's not his fault.
It's my fault.
This is both your faults.
Look what you've done.
But it isn't your fault.
I can't eat the things he cooks.
Let me tell the captain.
Man.
Man. Why are you being so stupid?
Then you'll also be fired.
I don't care, Lum.
If you go, I go.
-It's not even your fault.
-Man, don't.
-You want to be a snitch?
-What the hell is your problem?
Hold him!
Hey. Now that I won't be around,
take good care of yourself.
When will I see you again, Lum?
That, we don't know.
But you and me, we are fated.
Just wait and see.
Japan.
I want to go home, Thom.
Lower the cargo.
Okay. Go there. Move a bit.
Move a bit. Okay.
Put it down. Move a bit.
Okay.
Done.
Hey.
Are you okay? Quick, help him.
It's too dangerous.
He's on fire. Hurry!
He's on fire! Save him, quick!
-Hurry!
-Come here!
-Fight the fire!
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
I'm hanging on to
What's left of love
That's still left
In your heart
Even though
You're a world away
If there's love for me
Get home to me
Mom!
Mom, don't!
Even if he doesn't want to write letters,
why doesn't he write anything
on those postcards?
Mom.
-Does he remember us, Omar?
-Of course he does.
He's never asked how we are,
if we are having difficulties or not.
-He's never told us how he is!
-It's hard on a ship.
There's so much work. There's no time.
Please don't be angry.
I'm not angry!
He will write, eventually.
I know he will.
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you, too.
This is the money I borrowed from Othman
some time ago.
Use it.
I'll take my leave.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Mom?
-Can you manage?
-Mom?
Why is that man getting on Dad's boat?
I sold the boat.
Mom, Dad wouldn't let anyone else...
Mom.
I sold the boat. It's sold!
But it's Dad's boat. He'll be upset.
Omar.
I'm going to look for your father.
I'll find him.
Bring him home.
But if he comes back...
and his boat is gone, what then?
What if we keep the boat
and he never comes home?
He's not here.
It's better to have Dad than his boat.
Right, Omar?
Omar.
Where will you look for him?
His last postcard was from Hong Kong.
And if he's not there?
I have to try.
What is it, teacher?
The money from the boat isn't enough
to take you to Hong Kong.
Please take this money.
I insist.
No, teacher.
I'm afraid I will not be able
to pay you back.
I'm sincere.
You can pay me little by little,
whenever you can.
I just want to help Omar.
Teacher.
God willing...
you will be abundantly rewarded.
God willing.
Keep praying for me, Che Thom.
Follow me. Don't worry.
Don't let her get away.
-Help!
-Get out of my way!
-This way!
-Help!
Get in! Be quiet!
-Get in.
-Thom?
-Thom!
-Who's that annoying guy?
Who are you?
I am...
It's me.
You look like a nobody.
-Get him out!
-No, listen here. Listen to me.
You just plucked her off the street.
Do you know who she is?
I don't care who she is.
All I know is she is going to make me
a lot of money.
Okay, sure, no worries.
No worries.
-Get her in.
-Lum!
Lum!
Okay, then why don't I tell Boss Kuan?
You're using his people for your business.
Let's see what Boss Kuan has to say.
Wait!
What did you say?
Boss Kuan?
She is Kuan's property?
Why don't we go see Boss Kuan?
Ah Ngau, let her go.
Come on!
Come!
These newcomers.
She needs to learn the rules.
Take it yourself!
-Thank you, Lum.
-Keep walking.
What are you doing in Hong Kong?
Where's Man?
I came here to look for him.
What are you looking at? Get back to work!
You're stubborn like Othman.
Coming here alone.
It's dangerous.
I had to come look for Othman.
Do you know where he is?
I wasn't with him for long on the ship.
Then I didn't see him again.
I thought it'd be easy to look for him.
I thought that when I arrived...
there would be people who know him...
know where he is.
Like in the village.
Things are different here.
Okay, I have many friends at the port.
Some have worked on the Swyre.
I'll go ask around.
For now, you stay here.
I'll stay with a friend.
I've troubled you, Lum.
Othman's like a brother to me.
So, we're family.
Does he have a mistress?
It's best if we close the windows.
-Did you meet Man?
-He got a promotion and a raise.
But I didn't see him after that.
Othman has boarded the P&O ship.
The ship is in Russia now.
But they're not sure
when the ship will return.
That is Yusop.
He once met Othman here.
And he said Man got a promotion
and a raise on the P&O ship.
He got a promotion and a raise...
but he can't come home.
Lum, can you do me a favor?
Can you pass this letter to Othman?
I know it's not easy.
But I don't know who else to ask, Lum.
I'll try.
I don't care how long it'll take.
As long as it reaches him in person.
I'll make sure he gets this letter.
Thank you, Lum.
Xiao Bo.
This letter must be handed to Othman
on the P&O ship.
It must reach him.
Qing.
Help me pass this letter to Othman.
There's an empty space
Inhibited
-Mail!
-Hey.
Mail!
Help me carry this.
In this lonely heart of mine
There's no cure
For this broken heart
All I need is you back with me again
I'm hanging on
To what's left of love
That's still left
In your heart
Even though you're a world away...
He is not coming back, Omar.
You have to accept that.
I've accepted it.
I know he'll come home.
If he doesn't...
I'll go and find him.
Any news from Othman?
Not even a postcard.
His letters...
nothing at all.
Lum hasn't sent any news either.
These sailors are all the same.
But I'm a landlubber, Thom.
The wind blows
The branch falls on the rock
He pulls the thread, and then he asks...
"Is that a mermaid?"
"No, it's a stingray!"
Then he asks me, "Is it a male or female?"
"The stingray is pregnant!"
Pregnant, he says.
Peace be upon you, Omar.
Man.
Lum.
-Man!
-Lum.
Can't wait.
In the name of God,
most gracious, most merciful.
-It tastes the same, Lum.
-How did it taste?
Horrible.
Did you go back to Malaya, Man?
Did you see Thom?
After you sailed for three years,
she came to look for you in Hong Kong.
At that time,
you had just sailed to Russia.
Good thing she bumped into me.
Did she really come looking for me, Lum?
It was dangerous for her...
but she's brave...
like you.
She said she had to look for you.
Because there was no word from you
and you didn't come home.
You didn't go home at all?
Go home.
Why are you growing old here all alone?
Wouldn't it be better at home?
If I had a wife and kid,
I'd be home by now.
Coffee or tea, Lum?
Coffee, of course.
Don't you know me?
Here, take this.
-No need.
-There are better ones where I'm going.
Take it.
Lum.
I want to thank you for always helping me.
-If you--
-What?
Why are you talking like this?
We have more of life to live.
I'll send you a postcard.
Hey. Hurry up.
If I miss the ship,
I won't make it to America.
Take good care of yourself.
I'm looking for Othman Haji Alias.
Othman Haji Alias?
Over there.
Move.
Dad.
Omar?
Omar, my son.
How did you find me, Omar?
Uncle Lum sent a letter...
with your address.
Sit down.
Have a drink first.
I don't have much, Omar.
Sailed for years...
but nothing to show for.
Dad, our house in the village
is still there.
Your boat, though, Mom sold it.
That's fine.
That's your mom's property, not mine.
Don't you want to go home?
There's no place
for me there anymore, Omar.
Don't you want to see Mom?
Don't you feel sorry for Mom?
Why don't you come home?
The chicken coop
at the back of the house...
it's bigger now.
Do you remember when the chicken escaped?
We chased it around the house.
We chased it until it came into our house.
You still remember that, Omar?
I do, Dad.
A few days after that...
you went to Singapore.
And then you never returned.
Do you know Mom's still waiting for you
after all these years?
Do you know why I never went back?
I wanted to go home...
but I am not the master of my fate.
My money.
How is he?
Man?
Oh, my God, Othman!
Where is this ship going, Karim?
To Manila.
Then Goa,
Cape Town, and straight back to London.
Will it pass by Singapore?
You're thinking of going home?
But how can I go home like this?
With just clothes on my back.
I'd be embarrassed to face everyone.
Especially Thom.
What are you talking about?
Your ship sank. How is that your fault?
And I happen to know your wife.
Do you really think she cares
if you return with money?
As long as you're safe.
All she wants to know
is that you're safe, Man.
After listening to Dad's story...
I understood him better.
Though I know
he was still keeping something inside.
Regardless...
I still want him to go home to Mom.
Dad?
Yes, Omar.
I'd better head back to London.
I'll come back, okay?
Okay.
I won't be staying in London long.
After I complete my studies...
if you want to go home...
we can go back together.
Sure.
I'll be back.
Yes.
Christmas break.
We'll eat together, okay?
Yes.
I'll call you.
In the evening.
I work during the day.
Does your mom know I'm here?
No.
Okay.
I'll take my leave now.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you, too.
Yeah.
Peace be upon you, Mom. How's Grandma?
I've just arrived.
I'll call later if there's anything.
Okay, peace be upon you.
Omar.
I've missed you.
I've missed you, too, Mom.
Dad told me to look after the boat...
but you sold it.
Because you needed to go to Hong Kong.
You'll be back soon.
Mom?
Mom? Mom? Mom.
Wait for Ahmad, okay? I'll call him.
You can speak to...
Omar is here, Mom. He's right here.
Who is it you're looking for?
Which friend of mine?
I was wondering if you knew my granddad?
Othman Haji Alias?
He was from Serkam. He stayed at...
Othman Serkam? Sure.
Of course I know him. We were best mates.
We used to be at the club all the time...
those days.
Do you know where he is now?
Othman's dead.
We belong to God,
and to him we shall return.
Was it a long time ago, Uncle?
A long time ago.
I don't remember what year it was.
At that time, his son was here.
All of us buried Othman together.
That hat belonged to his best friend.
His name was Lum.
Othman always got a good laugh
from telling stories about Lum.
Do you know where he was buried?
Granddad, are you all right?
Would you like some water?
Alia.
How did you know about Granddad?
-Peace be upon you, Mom.
-Ahmad.
How's Grandma?
We're running out of time. She's dying.
Grandma's dying.
Now...
Grandma said if he's dead,
look for his grave.
They might keep records.
There was this one professor
who did research on Malay sailors
in Liverpool a while ago.
Professor Bunnell.
Everton!
Tim says that Muslims are buried
at Everton Cemetery.
Tim says the Muslim cemetery
is at Everton.
But before 1970,
it was at Anfield Cemetery.
How are we going to find him?
Tim told us to go
to the registry office first.
Why didn't your grandpa go home?
He must've saved enough money
after the shipwreck.
If not a lot, at least enough to go home.
Why did he settle down in Liverpool
-and not--
-Alia, can you listen?
"Othman Haji Alias."
"Khan."
"Shihaniz."
-"Harith Sulaiman."
-"Shirajudin."
"Othman...
Bin Haji Alias."
Grandma.
I found it, Grandma.
I seek refuge in God
from the accursed Satan.
In the name of God,
most gracious, most merciful.
Oh, God, forgive him.
Bestow mercy upon him. Pardon him.
Grandma.
It's me.
I'm back.
I found him, Grandma.
He's passed away.
We belong to God.
This is his grave.
In Liverpool.
Othman Bin Haji Alias.
He died in December 1966, Grandma.
He died before me.
How did he die, Ahmad?
Was he loved?
Did he have family there?
No, Grandma.
But...
Dad was there when he died.
Dad buried him.
All this time,
Omar knew his father had died.
I don't know.
I don't know, Mom.
Did Dad ever give a letter to you?
From Grandpa?
Mom, please read Dad's letter.
It's too late, Omar.
This letter is meaningless.
Mom.
Don't you want to know about him?
Did he ever ask about us, Omar?
Ever?
Eighteen years, Omar.
It has always just been you and me.
He's not here.
Now, he sends a letter. For what?
To come back to us?
Mom!
Mom?
Mom, what are you doing?
-Calm down, Mom.
-Move, Omar!
Mom.
Mom. Calm down, Mom.
Move aside, Omar!
Don't disobey me!
This is all your fault!
Because of you...
I waited for him.
Don't you ever mention his name again.
Dad.
Where is Grandpa's letter, Dad?
Push!
-Push more!
-Pull!
I'm sorry, Mom.
I don't listen to you.
I didn't throw away Dad's letter.
I kept it all this time.
Mom.
You want me to read it, Grandma?
-"Thom..."
-Thom...
when this letter reaches you...
I am no longer in this world.
But... I never forgot my promise.
Man!
What are you doing, Man?
Othman!
Hey!
Stop!
Stop! Wait!
Othman!
Stop!
Wait! Come!
Let it go, Taib.
Don't sulk.
It's a good thing.
I just feel sorry for Othman.
What if he comes back?
What about Thom?
And Omar?
You don't feel sorry?
Teacher Hassan is a nice man.
He is well-to-do.
Thom's and Omar's future
will be taken care of.
God willing, Taib.
Thom.
I want to see you adorned...
if not in diamonds, then in gold...
even just a tiny piece.
But you never remarried.
I wanted to move on with my life...
but my heart was set.
It only wanted him.
I'm sorry. I can't.
He probably came home to Serkam
that night.
He came home, Ahmad.
Dad came home, Omar.
Forgive me, Thom.
For thinking that you could be happier...
with someone wealthy...
rather than someone you loved.
Forgive me for not trusting your words.
Forgive me for keeping us apart
all these years.
I used to think...
a ship that doesn't sail is useless.
But now I know, Thom...
a ship permanently at sea,
without a harbor to come home to,
that is truly a wasted life.
I have never forgotten you, Thom.
I still love you...
to this very day.
We belong to God,
and to him we shall return.
If we don't get to meet again
in this life...
may he reunite us...
in the hereafter.
There is an empty space
Inhibited
In this lonely heart of mine
There's no cure
For this broken heart
All I need is you
Back with me again