HYOGENSHA presents
a NISSEI GEKIJO production
What are you thinking about?
Nothing.
Liar! Come on, what?
About you.
Really?
Are you really thinking about me?
When can we really...
Wait.
I've got something to do first.
What?
It doesn't matter.
It just concerns me.
What? What is it?
What are you thinking about?
SHOKEI NO SHIMA
PUNISHMENT ISLAND
Screenplay by
SHINTARO ISHIHARA
Original Story by
TAIJUN TAKEDA
Photography by
TATSUO SUZUKI
Music by
TORU TAKEMITSU
Film Editor
MASAHIRO SHINODA
Starring
AKIRA NITTA
KEI SATO
KINZO SHIN
TAIJI TONOYAMA
HOSEI KOMATSU
NAKAJIRO TOMITA
TOSHIE KIMURA
YOSHIMI HIRAMATSU
SHIMA IWASHITA
RENTARO MIKUNI
Directed by
MASAHIRO SHINODA
You here on business?
For the new weather station?
Seafood?
No. I'm looking.
Looking for someone?
Hey!
Got somewhere to stay?
No.
My sister and her husband
run an inn. How about there?
It's convenient. Right in town.
It's good to see a new face.
A typhoon wrecked the pier,
and who knows when they'll fix it.
We're back to boats again.
This island never changes.
No. It's changed a lot.
So you've been here before?
Yeah. A long time ago.
I run boats for a living.
What do you do?
I sell sewing machines.
Yeah?
You've come a long way.
You said you were looking
for someone...
Yes. I am.
A friend?
His name's Otake.
What does he do?
I don't know.
Is he from around here?
I came from Niijima Island
after the war... 15 or 16 years ago.
He was here before that.
So you're looking for him?
Yeah. For him.
And one other man.
Another one?
What's this?
Oh, Mr Nomoto...
What's going on?
Him and his friends...
...jumped a guard and escaped
from the reform school.
How many of them?
There's three more.
He's the only one we got.
Why would you do that?
You can't get off this island
in winter.
There's nowhere to hide
on this island, either.
They'll come out when
they get hungry...
...but we can't just wait for the police,
so everyone's helping out.
And you're a Public Safety Officer.
You help, too.
This concerns all of us.
I wonder where they're hiding...
I'm too busy to be out hunting
right now!
Is that man's name Matsui?
Yes. Do you know him?
From years ago?
Yeah. Years ago.
Go on, eat it! It's good!
No!
You're not scared, are you?
Go on!
You little bastard!
Are you going to try selling
over on Kojima. too?
I suppose if they're manual
and don't need electricity...
But who'd sew pretty clothes
and wear them on that island?
Has it changed there, too?
No. A little bit of wind,
and it's still completely cut off.
They used to send boys over there.
They did?
The ones who were too much
for the reform school here to handle.
They won't send those runaways
over there, will they?
I doubt it.
There's a grade school there,
but that's all I know.
Hello!
I brought you a guest.
You've got room, don't you?
Thank you.
We've got a room, but the floor mats
are being changed. Could he wait?
Welcome.
How about a bath first?
Well! Mr Kuroki!
What brings you here?
Something came up, and now
with this storm I can't get back.
Staying the night?
Yeah, I thought I'd drink
with the landlord.
Join us.
You're with someone?
He's a guest I brought.
I was at Niijima.
I hear some kids have run away?
Yeah. Everyone's all worked up.
They've got guns and everything!
They're nothing but trouble!
They should send the lot to Kojima.
Don't make jokes! We don't want
kids like that on Kojima!
But didn't they used to send
boys over there?
Did they?
That's what he says.
He says he's been there.
I'll get the bath ready.
You can sit here.
Mr Kuroki's principal
of the Kojima school.
He's from Tokyo... I think...
He sells sewing machines.
I'm Nishihara.
Kuroki. Glad to meet you.
You used to live here?
For a little while.
I see.
As a matter of fact, I have
the feeling I've seen you before.
Oh yeah?
There's so few people on Kojima
we feel like that about everyone.
You're a teacher?
I run the combined
primary and middle school.
Come and see us
if you come to Kojima.
You said you're looking for someone,
didn't you.
What was the name?
'Ota' something... 'Otake', was it?
There's an 'Otake' who lives
on Kojima.
I'd have to see him.
He used to live on this island.
He's lived on Kojima
for years and years.
I don't know him.
You might not.
He hardly ever comes here.
He avoids people.
A real eccentric.
He is?
Yeah.
A madman, but a genius, maybe.
A genius?
Well, yeah, in some ways.
He's a man of foresight,
like a prophet.
But he's headstrong.
He hates interference.
so he keeps away from everyone.
But he's got a head for business.
He succeeds where everyone else fails.
When camellia oil was cheap,
he planted trees.
Two years later. he made money.
He made the first kayak around here.
When fishing was bad,
he made money on lobsters with it.
He makes butter, grows tea...
He makes them his own way,
but he won't tell anyone how.
Butter?
He's got the only cattle on Kojima.
Cows? On Kojima?
Yeah!
Cattle... I herded cattle there...
I wonder what he's like... he sounds
too smart to be an islander.
Yeah... he came from Tokyo
during the war.
Are you a friend of his?
Me? Why?
He's a gloomy man, who hardly
even speaks when you meet him.
Does anyone work for him?
No, he's all alone.
His daughter comes over here
to buy provisions.
She's the only thing in the world
he cares for.
She's very pretty.
But only her.
He won't even keep a cat.
I came over here with her.
She can't go back in this wind.
I'm sure he'll be worried.
But as you were saying...
Or was it this gentleman?
During the war, Otake worked boys
the reform school here couldn't handle.
He treated them more like cattle
than farm labor.
Sure, they were bad kids,
but they were still kids.
He's a brute, that Otake.
There was a notorious killer named
Kinjiro exiled there in feudal times.
When the men were away, he killed
all the women and burned the village.
But now they worship him as one of
the island gods. That's Kojima for you.
Otake was exiled there, too?
He might have been.
What happened to the boys sent there?
I don't know. I wasn't there long
that time.
You were teaching then?
I was still a probationary teacher.
Did any of the boys ever die there?
Die?
I remember there was a rumor...
...that a boy had been killed.
or maybe 'spirited away'.
It was during the war.
so it would have been hushed up.
'Hushed up'?
And you didn't check...
Why would I?
This boy who was 'spirited away'...
hadn't he been enslaved there?
No!... well, I don't know.
The bath is ready.
I'll have your room prepared.
The workmen are done.
Take a bath. It'll refresh you.
I'll take your things.
I've seen that man before.
He says he was on the island...
This one?
Could you take his bag
to the Pine Room?
Something wrong?
Can I take a bath when he's done?
Mr Kuroki, are you sure
you remember him?
I thought so at first,
but I can't place him.
Listen...
Is there a boat tonight?
Tonight? Impossible.
Even if it clears up, how could you
land on Kojima in this wind?
I'm used to wind.
I can't even get the boat out
in these waves!
So when?
Another day or two.
What's your hurry?
Your boyfriend waiting?
Will you try it tomorrow?
It depends on the weather.
Come back and see. but I doubt it.
For the mainland I'd risk it,
but not Kojima.
Hey, Aya!
Where are you off to?
None of your business!
There's no boat.
Your dad'll be worried.
So I'm going.
How?
Hop in.
We'll drive you to town.
No!
Why not? I'll bet your old man
didn't give you much money.
You can stay at my place.
Forget it!
Stubborn as her old man!
Anyway, get in. I can't leave you
alone out here.
What's wrong?
Did you think over what I said?
It's not such a bad deal.
I won't be here forever.
Do you want to rot on Kojima
with your dad?
Who'd ever want to be with you?
Where do you think you are?
This isn't Kojima.
I could do anything I wanted
with you right now.
There's only Tsuneki here.
Stop!
Shoot.
Do anything to me and my father
tells the world your secret.
That's what he said.
But your father...
What about my father? Tell me!
When you get home you tell him...
...I give as good as I get.
Don't move!
She's a lot of trouble.
You want me to grab her for you?
Shut up!
She's too pretty to leave on Kojima!
She used to be so meek and mild...
But she's gorgeous!
Thanks. The bath was great.
Your room's to the right
at the end of the hall.
It can't be!
What?
Nothing.
Do you remember?
No.
It can't be!
Please! I'm asking you to go back!
I know I'm a teacher,
but I can't let you stay.
You've got to go back
and apologize to Otake!
Sabo, wait!
Where are you going?!
The poor boy!
We can't hide him here.
Otake'd find him for sure.
They'll beat him to death!
What can I do about it?!
He came here because
you were good to him!
What can I do?!
Nothing!
I don't want to get involved.
Then why did you?
Has Sabo been here?
No, he hasn't.
There's no point in hiding him.
He's not worth a dog's life.
He's not here. Search if you like.
You're sure you're not hiding him,
Teacher?
No.
What did he do?!
He ran away again.
Mr Otake!
He dropped this!
He's going to take the kayak!
Fine! One boy can't handle that.
Wait!
What?
What will you do?
Whatever I like.
He was in your car?
I guess I didn't notice him.
He knows you, all right.
He said your name.
My name?
As if he knew you years ago.
Mr Nomoto...
...you're sure about the knife?
Yeah. I saw it when
his bag fell open.
Sounds like fun!
'Fun'?
What's he want here?
He sells sewing machines.
Mr Kuroki, the principal at Kojima.
says he's seen him before.
He just can't quite place him.
The guy made him nervous.
Does it have anything to do with
those runaways?
Impossible!
It's not strange for a man
to have a knife.
What else did he say?
Just that he's looking for someone.
Oh, yeah... a man named Otake.
That was the name.
Mr Kuroki says there's a strange man
by that name on Kojima.
He's not 'strange'. He's crazy.
Is this guy looking for Otake?
I don't know. He said
he was going over there.
Hmm...
Should I go see him?
Maybe he's after
the Weather Bureau contract.
I don't like it.
Is he staying at your sister's place?
Yeah. I didn't like the sight of
that knife one bit.
Thanks.
Go see if the guy's in his room.
Missus! More sake!
You've had more than enough
Mr Kuroki. You're drunk!
Don't worry. This wind
won't go down tomorrow.
It's been a while
since I could take things easy.
Surely you're not too busy
on a little island like Kojima...
It's easy work. but I've got
an invalid for a wife!
Is your wife still sick?
'Still'? She'll never get better now.
It's palsy. She'll be bedridden
till she dies.
But she's so young!
All the children loved her
when she was teaching here.
She was always so nice,
and kind to everyone...
Sabo!
It can't be... it just can't be!
What are you doing?! Stop it!
What are you going to do with him?!
He's just a boy!
Boy or not, he's mine!
You would've killed him
if I hadn't passed by!
You're a father, too!
Think of his parents!
Move.
Out of the way!
Brute! You stop that, or I'll go
to the big island and report you!
He can't work like this.
He stays here till he's well.
All right. Keep him for me. then.
I'll come back when he's better.
Let's go home.
Have some tea.
Why won't you sit here?
Akie!
How long is he staying?
How much older is he
than the children you teach?
There's lots more to eat.
It's me.
He hasn't been out at all?
You're sure?
Yeah. The woman from the inn
says he's stayed shut up in his room.
Shut up in his room?
Who is he, anyway?
Is there something wrong?
No.
If he's got a knife,
we should do something.
We should strike first.
I'll hit his room.
No, I'll go. You get out of there.
Matsui?
Mr Kuroki! Are you staying here?
Yeah.
Have you seen...
Did you see the guy?
Who?
It's Sabo. He's back.
Sabo, from Kojima!
Saburo? Impossible!
It's true. He's alive!
It's Saburo. I saw him.
It can't be!
It's hard to believe. but it's Saburo,
all right. He didn't die.
Saburo's come back? The bastard!
Mr Kuroki... he's got a knife.
Nomoto says he's coming
to see me with it.
He's after Otake. too.
Why, after all this time?
'Why'?
He's got good reason.
So he's alive. is he...
Don't tell him you saw me, all right?
I haven't called him by name.
That's wise. He might have
a score to settle with you, too.
Is this where the Kojima boat leaves?
Yes.
Are you going there?
There's nothing to see but the graves
of people exiled there.
Otake's there. isn't he?
What do you want with him?
If you've got business with him,
that's his daughter over there.
That's Aya?
Do you know her?
You wouldn't happen to be...
I'm Sabo.
You knew that, and you still kept quiet.
You haven't changed a bit.
Why do you have to ask?
Shut up and watch.
Are you here after Otake and Matsui?
How's your wife?
She's bedridden with palsy.
I see... I've never forgotten
the taste of her rice...
But why are you here?
Thank you.
It's a good view of Kojima,
but it's dangerous here.
Didn't you know about
the runaways?
So why are you here?
To look at Kojima.
This is the closest place to it.
I used to stand over there.
On a calm day, it looked as if
I could walk across.
Were you on Kojima?
Yeah.
When?
When you were about this high.
Do you know me? Or my father?
Mr Otake.
You know him?
Yes. I do.
Why did you leave?
You don't live around here now.
No.
Are you so anxious to get back?
Is it such a good place?
My father's there.
I see.
Why did you come back?
Are you going to Kojima, too?
Yeah. I've got something to do.
What?
You'll find out.
I see... well, come to our house.
My father will thank you
for helping me.
That doesn't concern him.
But if he'd been here just now...
He would have killed them.
Your father dotes on you,
doesn't he.
You're all grown up.
When did you know me?
When you were about this high.
He took you in a basket
everywhere he went.
Did you play with me?
Yes. I did.
You'd better go.
They went the other way.
The way you came is safe.
Thank you. I'll see you on Kojima.
Yes.
We just missed them!
I was sure we had them!
Now we know where they are.
We'll get them tomorrow.
I thought I'd hit one of them...
Where's the jeep?
Over here.
Get anything?
So you've graduated
to hunting people now...
So it's you, Saburo...
You're alive...
Yeah.
Son of a bitch!
What do you want?
Am I fair game, too?
Don't just stand there. Hop in.
It's been a long time.
Let's have a chat somewhere.
OK. if you say so.
What's the idea?!
Throw the gun away!
I'll drive us right off the cliff!
Get rid of it!
Get out. Let's talk about old times.
I decided when I came
we'd have our talk here.
Talk about what?
Things.
Let's start with why they think
I'm dead over on that island.
Then I'll tell you why I'm not.
I didn't do it! It was Otake!
Yeah, but you watched it.
Who made him want to kill me?
It may have been
just a game to you...
...but I remember it every time
I look down at the sea.
Who's this?
Sabo...
Come here.
Come here!
So you've been stealing my butter,
have you?
No! Matsui pushed a moray eel
into my mouth!
Let's see you run!
You're an exile, too!
You've been left here to rot!
Are you talking back to me?!
Get out!
I'll do anything you want!
I was a bastard, I know!
I try to forget
all about that island!
Oh yeah? I never want to forget!
Forgive me! Please!
I'll give you half my business!
Please!
You just stood there and watched!
You were all having a great time!
It was you who said to run,
then went and told Otake!
What do you want me to do?!
Feel my pain.
Forgive me, Sabo!
Where on the island are you going?
Ashura-ga-hara.
Ashura-ga-hara?
There's nothing there but cows!
Are they still there?
You're going to see cows?
No. A certain man.
Then come to our house. too.
You can stay at the school.
In the staff room.
Or even at my house.
He's your guest. Mr Kuroki?
Goodbye. I live on the other side
of the island.
She and her father live alone in
the most isolated place on the island.
Over the mountain?
Yeah, but it's a hard road.
About two hours' walk.
It's real steep.
She was only this high...
The exiles used to try and swim
from there... they all drowned.
It's over two miles,
and the current's strong.
It's changed... all thatls the same
are the sea and...
It's Sabo!
He's alive, and he's come back!
To do what?
Why did you come back?
You were very good to me,
Mrs Kuroki.
What did you come back to do
here on Kojima?
You can't let him go. you know.
I understand why he hates Otake
enough to kill him. but...
...you can't let him go!
You can't let him do it!
What can I do about it?
There's nothing I can do.
Don't let him go!
You mustn't!
What's wrong?
You're up early.
An old habits come back. When I was
here, I had to get up before dawn.
I'd look across at the big island,
but it never got any closer.
Look. The sun's coming up.
The same sun over the same sea...
it's a strange feeling.
Twenty years... it feels like yesterday.
No... as if I've never been away.
So you're going to Ashura-ga-hara
to see Otake today?
So what?
You're better off not to.
He's changed.
The sun and the sea haven't.
Sabo!
Don't call me that! Sabo is dead!
I'm no concern of yours now.
Anyway. there's someone else
I want to see besides Otake.
Someone else? Who?
It doesn't matter.
Sabo wasn't your problem, anyway.
Isn't that right?
Just stand by and watch,
the way you always did.
There's nothing you can do!
Sab... mister!
The path's still the same?
Sabo!
Hey!
I saw you coming.
I brought the goats out to graze.
Are you coming to our place?
Yeah... so this is Ashura-ga-hara...
Yes.
Have you been here before?
Yeah.
Why?
I tended cattle. Goats, too.
Is your dad home?
Yes. I told him about you.
Me?
About how you saved me.
Oh.
Well, since you're here...
Don't be surprised by my father.
Dad!
He'll be right back.
He left his work out.
What?
Nothing.
There's no one else here?
Who?
Workers, tenants...
No.
Who tends the animals?
Dad and me.
Who said you could come in?!
I won't have it!
I told you, Dad!
This is the man who helped me!
Hello.
My damn daughter...
You want something?
Y es. I'd like to buy some land here...
to grow camellias.
I don't sell land.
If that's all, you can go.
Dad!
What's this?
An exile carved it.
It's very well made.
No! I'm not selling any land!
Get out!
Mr Otake, I wanted to ask you
about something other than land.
You had hired men working for you
during the war, didn't you?
Go away!
I say 'hired men', but they were kids...
...sent over from the reform school
on the big island.
Were they?
Have you forgotten?
One named Matsui? He runs a business
on the big island.
That Matsui?
And a boy named Nishihara
who was here with him?
Saburo Nishihara...
they called him 'Sabo'.
You don't remember him?
No.
You forget?
No. I'm not a man who forgets names.
There might have been a Matsui...
You've forgotten. He died here
while he was working for you.
Some even said he was 'spirited away'.
What's he to you?
He was my brother.
Brother?
I've got to go. Go away, will you?
Dad!
Don't mind him. He hates people.
No. I shouldn't have dropped in on him.
Aya, can I ask a favor?
What?
Will you lend me this?
It's very unusual.
I'd like to copy it.
That?
I'll return it tomorrow.
I'm staying at Mr Kuroki's school.
Sure. I'll come and get it.
No, I'll bring it. I want to talk to
your father again.
All right?
Kozo Kenuma
Nishihara!
This is divine retribution!
Wait!
I passed you in the forest
above the cemetery.
What is it?
What do you want with my father?
Nothing.
You're lying!
Mr Kuroki told me!
What?
You're after revenge for something!
Dad's been strange since yesterday.
Oh.
What are you going to do?
You don't remember Saburo.
who was here twenty years ago.
Ask your father what he did to him!
What did he do?!
He killed him!
Beat him to death!
You're lying!
Ask him, then. He remembers now.
Murderer!
Come with me and see!
Here.
Let's talk more.
I won't sell my land.
No... about the late Saburo.
Don't know him.
It's strange you'd forget.
A boy you killed.
A slave, worth less than a cow
or a goat.
You threw him in the sea.
Never heard of him.
Oh yes, you do.
He sees you and he remembers.
He does?
Yes. I'm Saburo.
Take a good look, old man.
It's me!
Impossible.
You're right. It is impossible.
But it's true. I'm Saburo.
I'm the boy you killed
and threw in the sea.
Then tell me...
...how a dead boy comes back to life
and talks to me.
So I didn't kill you.
Some fishermen from Miyake Island
found me floating.
Take a good look. It's me. Saburo.
I don't know any Saburo.
I'm Sabo!
I've changed, haven't I.
So have you.
But some things don't change.
I never changed in wanting to
see you alive again.
That's why I stayed alive!
That's what kept me going
after I almost died here!
What do you want with me?
Aya... it was a monster that raised you.
What do you want?
Oh, I'm not finished yet.
There's another man I came to see.
Otake... you're Kozo Kenuma,
aren't you.
Aya, that's your father's real name.
You're Kenuma!
No!
I'Il make it simple.
I took your fingerprints
from that Buddha's statue.
They match.
You'd know better than anyone about
no two fingerprints being the same.
It's a wonder your file was still intact.
And a wonder I found it.
It was a lot of work.
Someone told me you were Kenuma,
so I started looking for proof...
...that the Otake who killed me...
...was the same military policeman
who killed my family!
My father was Genichiro Nishihara.
Genichiro Nishihara?
Yes.
The anarchist you killed
for the sake of your country.
You burst in and murdered my family.
Do I resemble the man you left
covered in blood in his library?
To keep it quiet, the Army
and the Government sent you here.
I was left an orphan.
How does a small boy
fend for himself?
I got into trouble. I went from
reform school to reform school...
...and ended up on the big island.
All the time I was trying
to escape from there...
...never guessing
you were right here!
And now at last we meet again!
I'm delighted to find you alive!
Mr Kenuma... I mean, Mr Otake...
...I have to thank you.
I wouldn't be who I am
if it hadn't been for you.
Dad! No!
Stop it!
You don't know what it's like
to spend your life in exile!
No, I guess I don't.
But do you understand how I feel?
You can't erase your fingerprints.
Move... stand aside.
You'll have to kill me first.
I'll kill you!
Stop that.
If you'd been older, you'd have
defended your father with your life!
Move!
Move, I said!
I won't kill him.
Otake... Kenuma...
I'll take the finger.
The one whose print I took.
Cut off your thumb. That'll do.
Cut it off!
THE END