Synced by Anomix33
200 years ago Bijapur Sultanate
was ruled by Raja Hari Man Singh.
In those days the fear of ghosts and
spirits prevailed in the hearts of people.
The most feared demon of all
was called Saamri.
One day Raja Man Singh was travelling
with his daughter Rupali towards Bijapur...
...when his royal
chariot broke down.
How long will it take?
Only a little while, sire.
- Where has Rupali gone?
- She was just here.
Rupali, Rupali!
Princess!
She shouldn't have left alone so late
in the night. This is Saamri's land!
Don't just look at me!
Go and find her! Go!
Saamri!!
Cut him down!
Kill him!!
Find him, find him!
That demon came this way.
Quickly!
This royal proclamation
of Mughal King Hari Man Singh...
...states that Saamri
using his satanic powers...
...has created terror
in the state of Bijapur.
The accusation is that you unrobed
young married women...
...and violated their honor.
You are accused that
to slake your satanic thirst...
...you mercilessly killed
young and innocent children...
...and sucked their blood.
You have fallen so low
from the human level...
...that even Satan
would shun you.
To strengthen your evil powers
you opened graves...
...took out corpses...
...and...
...and ate them.
O, King, destroy
this creature now!
No! Entomb him in the wall.
King...
I believe that this monster
should be purged in pure fire...
...and thus be turned
forever into ashes.
No, holy man.
This demon's head
will be separated from his body.
The body will be buried
in the ruins behind this temple.
And his head...
...will remain under guard
in my palace, far from here.
That way, his head and his body
will never be joined together.
I beg you, my lord, guard the head
with this holy trident of Shiva.
Thus will all this demon's powers
be rendered ineffective.
'The old temple.'
Hari Man Singh...
...I curse you!
As long as my head and body
remain apart...
...all your female heirs
will die horribly..
...as soon as they give birth
to their first child!
And the day my head and body
are joined again...
...will be the end
of your dynasty!
And so Hari Man Singh cut off
the head of that demon...
...and kept it
apart from the body.
The body was buried in the ruins
behind Shankar's Palighat temple.
The demon's head was put
in a trunk fastened with chains.
Raja Hari Singh secured that trunk
in the dungeon of his palace.
God Shiva's holy trident
was put on top of the trunk.
A wall was built across the door
of the dungeon...
...and the severed head was hidden
from the eyes of the world.
A painting of Hari Man Singh
was hung on the door.
And so the stories
of Saamri's evil faded...
...into the darkness
of the dungeon.
The river of time carried off
the main players.
The faces of Sher Khan,
Rajguru Balbir Singh and all the rest...
...became lost
in the mists of time.
The flame of Hari Singh's life
was extinguished.
After him the reins of the state
fell to Prithipal Singh
and then in the course of time,
Raja Ajit Singh.
After him, Thakur Ranbhir Singh
sat on the throne.
The dusts of time settled
over the ancient palace...
...and it became
forgotten about.
The pulse of life left
the palace area and moved to the city.
This is the last remaining heir
of Hari Man Singh - Ranbir Singh.
A grand and important man,
even today.
But the fear of Saamri still
prevails in his heart and mind.
Sir, these papers need
your signature.
Give me a pen.
Have you sent the payment
to Gawahar Saw Mills?
Brother, dear.
Dayawanti,
has Suman left for college?
Really papa,
what kind of talk is that?
Does your daughter ever go to
college without meeting you?
And that is why I have been
rushing home.
I knew my little doll
would be waiting for me.
You call me your little doll!
But see how tall I've grown!
I reach your shoulders.
Brother, the child
has grown up.
Grown up!
Papa what's the matter?
What are you thinking?
Nothing, my dear.
I was just thinking...
aren't you getting late for college?
OK, papa. Bye Papa.
Bye, auntie.
I know the sorrow
in your heart.
If only I could share it.
In this world, every father prays
for his children to grow up.
But I...
I am an unlucky
father who wishes that..
..there shouldn't be any
marriage ceremony in this house.
Because of that
accursed palace!
So finally you come,
your lordship!
And I've only been
waiting an hour.
What are you staring at?
Just one close up.
You're getting obsessed
about your close-ups!
Naughty boy! Let me go...
I don't blame you.
I wouldn't mind some
of that myself.
Hey, dude!
You're cruising for a bruising.
But why are you still
just taking pics?
What's your problem?
Her father.
Doesn't he know about you two?
Not yet.
So you're still only dreaming?
Get a move on, chum.
Or you'll wake up
and find yourself alone in bed.
Here's the dream girl.
How's Sapna?
What are you gossiping about?
He was telling me
about his bed.
Bed? I don't get it...
I'll explain later.
Hey Anand, coming to
the club this evening?
Yes Anand, and bring Sapna.
- I don't know...
- Why not?
I'll have a show
of my own to watch.
I am already 45 minutes late.
The first question will be:
Where've you been?
What were you doing?
Who with?
I'm young and lonely.
You don't know
how lost I am.
Thousands fawn on me
but even so I'm lonely.
Yes me, yes me.
The moon and
stars in my eyes
who knows who
they call today?
Somebody please
read their signs
and come and bring
me joy and more.
Become my...
oh, become my lover, lover.
The business of the heart,
only the heart understands.
What can you or
I do about it?
What is a dream and what is the truth?
Who will know that here?
Live for the moment,
oh live for the moment, lover.
Papa, I'm back.
Sorry I'm late again.
I met my old girlfriend Nikki
and she insisted I go back with her.
And her parents asked
me to stay for a while.
They insisted that I have
dinner with them.
Papa, have you eaten?
Who is this boy?
It's Sanjay, papa.
He's a really nice boy.
- If you met him...
- You'll not see him again.
Please meet him just once.
He's from a respectable family.
Please
meet him once.
Ranbir Singh's family blood
has not become so thin...
...that it can flow away
in the gutters.
I knew it, Suman...
I knew that your father's money
would be a wall between us.
Even so Sanjay, why won't you
meet Papa one day?
I'm sure if he met you,
all these problems would be solved.
No, Suman.
He'd just reject me
because I'm poor.
So now I see how my own blood
wants to shame me.
And how this man is now
my mortal enemy.
You fool...
If you burn palace lamps
in a hovel...
...you won't get light,
you'll burn the hovel down.
But if there's a fire,
the must be some light.
Not for long.
In a poor man's life,
even a brief light is worth much.
Today's love is not love,
it's just the fever of youth.
How much?
How much money do you want,
to leave my daughter alone?
Sorry, sir...
...true love
can't be bought and sold.
You blacken
our good family name...
...and now you argue with me!
Teach him respect!
Let him go, papa.
Please!
Stay off my friend!
Come you bastard dogs,
where are you running off to?
We showed 'em.
I don't understand.
If Suman wants you,
what's his problem?
The problem's always been there,
and it always will be.
I cannot ignore the heritage
of this family.
But what about
your daughter's wishes?
This child's tears
are not something that I want...
...but that vagabond will
take her away from me forever.
But I won't let that happen.
I won't even let his shadow
fall on her again.
Why can't you make
this girl understand, Dayawanti.
Make her understand,
or I dread the consequences.
Who... Who are you?
I am asking you, who are you...
...that has for centuries cast
a shadow of death on this family?
How much more blood must flow?
How many more will you kill?
How many more lives?
You can't kill her. You can't ever
take my child away from me.
Papa what happened?
Nothing, just go back
to your room.
After today you will
never meet Sanjay again.
And if he tries to see you,
I will have him killed.
Don't just stand there,
get out of here.
Those gone days I remember.
Those stolen moments I recall.
The ones I spent with you,
warm in your embrace.
That smile of yours, your blushes,
the time of December, the wet cold.
What happened to those days,
where did they all go?
Only the memories remain.
Those talks I remember,
the nights I remember.
Spent with you,
holding you close.
Wrapping yourself around me,
lowering your eyelids.
Still in my heart remains
the softness of your lips.
Now you've started a fire.
I wonder where you've gone.
Only the memories remain.
Suman, I love you.
Driver, let's go.
Something is
happening to me...
I don't want to die...!
Save me!
Please, save me...!
Come, Suman.
I return your family's
honor to you, sir.
If I wanted I could have made
your lamp the light of my hut...
But I feared that this flame might
have burnt down your palace.
I'm going.
Wait!
You may as well take this gun...
...and shoot both her and me.
What?
I am not upset about my defeat,
I am upset at your victory.
Because you will run from her
once you know the truth.
The truth?
What truth, papa?
It's... It's a secret.
What kind of secret?
One I can't reveal.
But you must reveal it.
No, I can't tell you!
I can't tell you...
This secret is a curse that has
cast the shadow of death on our family.
What kind of curse is it,
to become a wall between our love?
You have to reveal it Papa,
my happiness depends on it.
Please tell us.
All right...
Alright, if you really
want to know...
So be it.
Do you see that palace?
That building is such a cursed
stain on our family...
...that we could
not wash it away...
...even with our own blood.
Every mother, every woman
connected with this building...
...on the birth of her first baby
becomes the immediate prey of death.
Papa, this is just
a superstition.
It is not a superstition,
it's the truth.
But, sir...
Can you really believe such things,
in this day and age?
Look...
I don't believe in things
that people tell me.
But I've seen this
with my own eyes!
The day Suman was born...
...this curse... took away
her mother Bharti from us.
Something's happening to me!
- Are you okay?
Something is happening to me!
I don't want to die...!
What's wrong?
I don't know, sir...
- I can't understand...
- What's happened to Bharti?
Go and look!
What's wrong?
If, after knowing all this,
you don't leave Suman alone...
...then I know that you don't
love her but are her mortal enemy.
So you walked out on her?
You loser.
What'll she think of you now?
You don't understand Anand.
I really do love Suman.
I can't live without her.
Do you hear me? I can't live without her.
- But if you'd heard that story...
- It's nonsense...
Just a made up story.
Suman...
What are you doing here?
Sanjay...
We must go to Bijapur.
Yes, to the old temple
that's the root of all our problems.
No, Suman...
It's better that
you forget all about me.
For the sake of my love, I'm not
prepared to sacrifice your life.
While I'm alive,
nothing will happen to Suman.
I am here for you.
And if it comes to it,
my life is yours.
You'll come with us?
Not only me,
but Sapna as well.
She'll be company
for Suman.
- Does your father know...?
- No...
I didn't tell him...
But I left a letter for him.
Brother...!
Terrible news...
- Suman is not in her room!
- What...?
But I found this letter there.
Father, I cannot live
without Sanjay.
If this family curse is
the barrier to our love...
...then we will return
only after destroying it.
We are going to Bijapur.
To the old palace.
Suman.
I still say you should go back, Anand.
This is our problem.
Why risk your life for us?
You're asking for a thump,
my old mate.
A friend is one who gives
his own life if need be.
If there's a shadow on our family,
why should we allow it to fall on you?
It's no shadow...
It's in your father's mind,
now it's got into your head too.
Hey, why did you stop the car?
What is it?
The tyre is punctured.
See mate,
you need me after all!
If we start getting
troubles so soon..
...we might reach Bijapur
in the next life!
Why did this problem
have to arise now?
We're dead.
Why's that?
I forgot the jack.
I don't believe it!
Don't worry my king!
What do you think I'm here for?
You just deal with the tire,
and I'll be the jack.
Ranbir Singh!
Now it's your daughter's time!
She will suffer the same fate
as your wife.
No! You can't do that...!
Dayawanti!
Take it away.
I'm afraid he's had
a heart attack.
He needs a lot of rest.
In his condition he can't make
the long trip to Bijapur.
This temple looks pretty old.
Indeed.
I don't feel like driving any more.
Why don't we stay here?
Alright, Suman?
Yes Sanjay,
I agree with Anand.
Besides, we're all dead tired.
Looks like there's no priest
staying at this temple.
How would he, Anand?
Is it a joke to climb up and
down 200 steps every day?
It may be for you,
but not for me.
Hail to the Lord!
Look, Anand, this is odd.
What?
This Shiva has
no trident in his hand.
Right!
Who would look after this temple
if there's no priest here?
Right mate, now we've met God,
lets go and meet the saint.
What saint?
Saint Food!
I'm starving.
Mice are doing a dance
in my stomach.
Suman...!
What are you doing here?
Why don't you speak?
What happened?
It was...
I saw...
What did you see?
I saw a corpse, Sanjay...
With no head...!
It was coming at me.
Sanjay it wanted to kill me.
You're talking crazy.
Sanjay...
I heard strange noises.
Strange noises.
A walking corpse,
and without a head too!
There's nothing here.
You're tired and
had a bad dream.
That man seems to be
belonging to this place....
He must know the old palace.
- I'll be right back.
- I'm coming. - Come back soon.
Excuse me...
Do you know
the way to Bijapur?
The palace at Bijapur.
Thakur Man Singh's palace.
Do you know the way, sir?
What happened?
Strange man.
He was waving that axe
like he wanted to cut my throat!
Looks deserted to me.
There must be a watchman about.
- You two stay here.
- OK.
We'll be back.
Watchman! Gardener!
Anyone here?
I just saw a light over there.
- Where?
- Over there.
Can't see anyone.
Let's go.
What is it?
There's someone by the car.
Anand, ask her who she is.
Who are you?
Why don't you answer?
She is dumb.
My mother...
Mangli.
So who are you?
Where is the watchman?
I am Durjan,
the watchman of this place.
Who are you?
We're from Bombay.
She's Suman,
daughter of Ranbir Singh.
We are honored.
After many years, someone
from the family has returned.
Come, come inside.
This is the palace of your
grandfather, Raja Pratap Singh.
This is your grandfather's
picture, Raja Pratap Singh.
And this is your great grandfather's
picture, Raja Ajit Singh...
This is all very fascinating...
But I really need sleep.
I'm sleepy too.
And here is Hari Man Singh,
your grandfather's, grandfather.
What's up?
I feel drawn towards
that painting...
Like he's trying
to tell me something.
Really?
Come.
Come on, Suman.
Have a good night?
Great fun.
Lying on the royal bed
I dreamt royal dreams all night long.
Me king of kings and Sapna
my queen of beauty.
Suman! What is it?
You!
Why are you here?
Food!
It must be cooked.
Oven must be lit.
Durjan called me, so I came.
What's wrong, boss?
Did you ask that man to come?
Why?
Without wood how will we cook?
And only Sangha brings
wood for the village.
Don't ask him here again,
understand?
Let's go.
6... 7... 8...
What a beautiful lake!
What a lovely place!
And in such a place...
...instead of talking love,
the fool is working out!
Do you have to do that?
Take a break.
Now stop it or I'm going.
I'm coming, miss.
So, what's up?
Nothing at all.
If you come any closer...
...I might melt
like candle wax.
Until only the wick is left.
You just don't understand.
These days it's really important
to keep the body fit.
Always thinking of your body,
never of me!
If I think about you,
the Indian population might explode.
What kind of talk's that?!
- I'm off.
- Where?
To Hell.
This is a jungle, not hell,
some bear will eat you.
Big deal.
More fun than watching you
do press-ups.
OK, go then, go on...
Just remember to
call if you need me.
Synced by Anomix33
Let me go!
Sons of mice!!
How many men were they?
I am asking you -
how many were they?
Just one, sire.
Him, one man!
And six of you!
Yet you return
without the girl!
Shame on you!
Sons of pigs...!!
So tell me, how much reward...
...has the Sardar
put on my head?
15,000 rupees...!
15,000!
Now you've made my name mud!
But punishment will come...
It will certainly come.
People are killed by bullets.
But I am going to kill you
by making you eat bullets!
Give me a hand.
You fell down yourself.
Come on, get up.
I am going to kill you
by feeding you bullets.
What will I do?
Feed you bullets!
But these are laxative pills.
Last year, we gave two pills
to twelve people each.
They are still wandering
the jungle with their pots!
Clever, very clever.
That is all very well sir,
but what will come of Murtar Singh?
Murtar Singh?
You have grown old,
but still you sway.
A lot of strength in your legs,
a lot of strength in the legs.
Give me Murtar's Singh's legs!
Bring me his legs!!
Sardar why are you having studs
put in your shoes?
To squash Machar Singh.
He cut off my arms.
My name is Murtar Singh.
He has woken the
flame of revenge in me.
I will beat him
with my studded shoes.
Machar!
Give me those hands!
Your hands!
Sardar, I have been
robbed, destroyed.
What's wrong, Basanti?
How can I tell you?
I'm too ashamed to tell you.
If you're too ashamed to tell me,
I won't be able to do justice.
That scoundrel,
he dishonoured me.
You mean rape!
And this is the second time.
Who was it this time?
Who else in this village
except that rogue Machar?
Stung by Machar a second time!
Sardar if he does it again,
we'll have a malaria epidemic!
There'll be no epidemic.
We'll spray DDT.
We will kill Machar
with insecticide.
Increase the
reward by one rupee!
Shall I lay the table?
Please.
Durjan... What do you
know about this palace?
It's a mysterious place, sire.
I've heard stories about it
from my father and grandfather.
In the time of Hari Man Singh
there was a dreadful incident...
...which still casts a
shadow over this palace.
The tribals believe...
there's a link between this palace
and the ancient temple of Palighat.
You...?
Here...?
Put it down and go.
Those town folk were asking
questions about the palace.
What do you think
they're looking for?
I know everything.
Everything...!
They have come to find the treasure
that's buried here somewhere.
Whenever I mention the treasure,
your mother goes crazy.
My mother knows a lot
about this old palace.
But she can't tell us,
because she is dumb.
But I have told you many times,
there's treasure in this palace, there is.
What makes you so certain
there's anything here?
If there was no treasure...
...why would they come
to this lonely, desolate place?
Let's take a photo of you two.
It's not a passport type photo.
Give a romantic pose.
Like this?
I'm too embarrassed
to look in the camera.
Mate, have you hooked one yet?
The fish here are too clever,
they don't want to bite.
What's she saying?
I think she's saying,
she'll catch the fish for you.
- How'll she do that?
- She's gone.
Now you're for it.
Let's go.
We don't need these fish,
we can go to the market.
- "I am hungry, bring me food,
food, FOOD..." - Shut up!
Is this a fish or a crocodile?
Suman has brought this crocodile
from the market...
...to put you off going
fishing for yourself!
Anand, the female race
are always suspicious.
Rightly so.
Suman come down,
the food is getting cold.
Take those photos later.
Coming...!
That was the last photo.
What's wrong?
The picture...
What's wrong with it?
Nothing at all.
Suman, the food's getting cold.
What is it?
That painting...
I saw a horrible face.
His head was cut off
and blood dripping from his neck.
You're amazing, Suman!
In the temple
you saw a body with no head.
And here you see a head
with no body.
A pretty good tale!
Don't you believe me?
Come on, let's go and eat.
Who's sitting on this donkey?
It's not a donkey,
it's a race horse.
There's a 15,000 rupee reward
on his head.
And you'll catch him?
Of course.
After coming all this way,
might as well make some dough.
Watch, in two days I will grab
this ass from his donkey.
On the river bank,
Nandlal teases me.
It's Basanti...!
Oh, God!
The pot is broken!
Broken!
Let me go.
I beg you, let me go.
Do you beg of me,
or wink at me?
I won't do anything to you today.
I won't even touch you.
See, I have let you go.
But I will watch you dance.
Dance?
I don't know how to dance.
Listen doll, don't try to be
clever with me. Come on, dance!
What is this? Is this an arm
or an elephant's trunk?
Let me breathe!
I can breathe! I can breathe now!
Come with me. - Where?
I'm taking you
to Sardar, Machar Singh.
I will turn you in
and get the 15,000 reward.
But what will I get?
A rope around your neck.
Bring the bastard here.
I have come of
my own free will...
Machar Singh!
- Yes, cripple...?
- You've committed terrible crimes.
But some fun ones too!
Isn't that true, Basanti?
You abandoned the young
and nubile village girls.
Broke their hearts.
Turned your face from them.
And formed a relationship
with 70 year old Basanti!
Whether Basanti is 70 or 16...
...in the country where Ganges flows
she'll always be moist.
You're about to be hung,
so stop beating about the bush.
I am beating about the bush,
but I'm not beating anything else, am I?
I will beat you so much
that your love engine will shut down.
Take him off
to the gallows now!
Who are you to force me
up the gallows?
I'll go by myself.
There's no gallows in the world
strong enough to hang me!
Stop, baldie!
I was having a conversation,
how did you get in the middle?
Wait for me, Basanti!
He's run away!
And so should you.
When I catch him again...
...I'll stamp on both your bodies
with my studded shoes.
Who are you?
Think you're Sunny Deol?
I was really angry with that man.
I was going to wring his neck.
Who are you, my saviour?
Please remove your hood.
Show me your face.
You! You arrested me
and now you...
And now I freed you.
Why?
It's a business, mate.
What kind of business?
Let me hear it as well.
Look, I capture you
and get the reward...
...free you, capture you again,
get another reward and so on.
And what about my share
of this reward?
25 per cent is my best offer.
And 75 percent to you?
Shall I take you to Sardar?
Who'll save you then?
You drive a hard bargain.
Agree or not?
75 percent...
That seems very fair.
I mean, 25 percent.
Alright. I agree, I agree...
Now you're being sensible.
Here's your share.
What happened?
Open the door.
That demon wants to kill me...!
Get me away from here...!!
No, Suman. No.
We came to Bijapur
to prove something.
There is no evil curse.
It's just a trick
to scare us off.
Who's responsible for this?
Answer me.
Answer me, Durjan!
You can't deny what
your own eyes see, master.
This is not a trick by a human
but a manifestation of a demon.
If you really want
to understand this...
...you must ask
the villagers to help.
Bijli, I need to talk to you...
But you must put some clothes on.
I understand Hindi,
these ARE my clothes.
Come and get me.
Will you stay with me?
I want to keep you.
Keep...? But first you...
Is this what you came
all the way from Bombay for?
It's very important
that I talk with Bijli.
At least now I know
what's important to you.
Are you coming with me
or staying with this jungle slut?
Suman, I told you,
it's important that I talk to Bijli.
Then she's obviously
much more important to you...
...than me!
Let's go, Bijli.
Enough Bijli...
I can't drink any more.
I was already drunk
from your lovely eyes.
You have only drunk
from my eyes...
When your lips
are pressed against my lips...
...then your body will
really catch fire.
I remember
those bygone days.
Those stolen moments...
...spent with you,
hugged against my body.
In your arms I cuddled,
you wrapped up in my hair.
Time has taken all but memories.
Why have the dreams shattered?
That past life, our happiness,
romantic places, time of desires.
Our tormented hearts,
the pounding heart beats.
The songs we hummed.
They are lost, gone with the wind.
Why have the dreams shattered?
Come along.
Stop right there!
If you don't, then I swear by Kali
this knife will go through you.
Don't, it's my brother.
How do you dare touch the hand
of Raka's sister?
Bijli? Who is this boy?
This is Sanjay.
He wants to ask us
about the palace and old temple.
Stay away from that palace
and the old temple...
...or be lost forever
in the darkness of death.
Death's darkness can't stop me
from reaching my goal.
What goal?
Your goal means the destruction
of our village and our tribe.
200 years ago an abomination
was buried in that ground.
You want to raise it!
To destroy it!
No...
City boy...
Go back to your city
and never come here again.
Or I swear by the goddess Kali,
I will slit your throat.
You don't scare me.
But keep your knife sharp...
...it might be handy
for cutting vegetables.
Oh Suman, did you really think
that I had left you for that wild girl?
Why don't you understand?
It was to find out
the secrets of the palace.
It was just
a show for the tribals.
Honestly?
I swear...
Now do I get a smile?
Just a little one...?
Just for me...?
I was getting some enjoyment,
now even that has gone.
You dried up old fruit, are you
giving a massage or polishing me?
- Am I some shoe?
- No.
I am Machar Singh, my back
is built like a brick wall.
So give me a hard slap.
A clap, was it a clap?
No, it was a gunshot. I'm off!
You guys got afraid for nothing.
He's one of ours.
Hey friend! What news?
The news is good.
The reward's been doubled.
Really?
But this time
you won't be hung.
What will they do?
Your punishment's been changed.
To what?
This time you will be put
in a live bear's cage.
That's great news, I haven't seen
a live bear for ages.
A live bear!
I'll be torn
to shreds in that cage.
You'd better come up
with a good plan.
Why, are you scared?
It won't be a real bear.
Inside the bear skin will be
your very good friend.
You're a true magician,
just like a sheep in wolf's clothing.
And I will stand in front of you,
puff out my chest and say...
Murtar Singh, you are
a dead man, for sure.
Surrounding me with spears.
Putting me in the bear cage,
you're trying to kill me.
Hey Blackie, you open your ears
and listen to me too.
You think you're safe
inside that cage.
But as soon as you come out,
I'll make kebabs of you...
...and sell them
at the train station.
Idiot, it's Anand.
So, you're Anand.
And this is a real bear.
I'm real too.
I couldn't find a bear skin.
Couldn't find a skin?
Sardar, he's run off again.
You'd better run off too!
Injustice has been done to me.
Machar Singh has run away.
I belong neither
there nor here.
Don't worry.
I will do Emperor Jehangir
type of justice.
Even Jehangir will come
to seek my forgiveness.
I will marry you.
Marriage? With you?
- Both your hands
have been cut off. - So?
It's only the hands.
Who needs hands to marry?
After marriage, we will fly
to London for the honeymoon...
Air India.
I'll get new hands made there.
That's very funny!
My teeth are false too,
I will get new ones made there.
And one more thing, I'm bald,
so I'll get a new wig there too.
Who's there?
Who is it?
I'll kill you...
Kill you!...KILL YOU!
Let me go! I'll kill him!
Who will you kill?
That painting.
I keep telling you,
there's nothing in that painting.
Have you gone mad?
Come with me.
Oh my foot.
Come on, Anand.
Have you gone nuts like Suman?
How can a painting bleed?
You saw the blood
on Suman's hand?
She had no cuts.
- Some sort of trick.
- And that crack behind the picture?
Another trick?
A crack?
I saw it with my own eyes.
There's an opening
behind the painting.
And it must lead to somewhere
or something.
You check that side...
and I'll look over here.
There's nothing here.
Find anything?
No.
A strange place.
No-one's been here for years.
Over there.
A trident?
Anand...
What could be in that box?
Open it.
I told you there
was treasure here.
It's a... severed head!
Maybe some brave soldier's.
The king must have kept
it securely in memoriam.
Tomorrow we'll get Durjan
to have this area bricked up again.
They'll be back
to take the treasure.
- Let's take it now.
- Not yet.
Why?
Tonight...
...when they're asleep
I will get my cart...
...and wait behind
the back door of the palace.
And you can bring
the treasure there.
Right... Right...
Let's go and wait
for the lights to go out.
Do it gently! It hurts.
It's a sprain.
She'll have to stay in bed
for at least 2-3 days.
No walking or moving at all.
Look here.
Now Suman will be able
to get around.
I found this
wheelchair downstairs.
It's getting late.
We should try to get some rest.
No! No, Sangha. No!!
Stop!
No...
Bastard...! Stop!!
You've killed my mother!
I won't let you live...!
I won't let you open the box,
I won't let you have the treasure!
Master...! It's a calamity!
A calamity, master...!! Master!!
What's up, Durjan?
Why are you shouting so much?
Master, you must stop Sangha!
He has taken the head and run off
towards the old temple.
Stop him master, come quickly.
But, Durjan, why did Sangha
take the head to the temple?
If that demon Saamri's head
was found in this palace...
...then his body must have been
buried near the old temple.
If the head and body are joined
then the demon will come alive again.
Master, go and stop Sangha. Go!
Faster! Faster!
Stop, Sangha!
Where's she gone?
Durjan, where is Sapna?
She was here.
What's that noise?
Don't be afraid.
I'll be right back.
But first I'd better go and close
the main palace gates.
Anand, let's check the ruins.
Anand - coffin.
What happened?
Yes I am Anand,
what happened?
- Anand, he was here...
- Who was here?
- Anand he wants to kill me.
- Who wants to kill you?
What happened here?
Where's Sapna?
Sapna's, gone.
I don't know where she is.
What happened?
Stop Sapna!
Don't take another step.
Don't go near
the demon, Sapna!
Saamri!!
I'm not afraid of dying!
Show yourself, damn you!
You won't get away from me!
Sapna...
What's going on, Sapna?
What is it?
What's wrong?
You seem terrified...
I've just had a terrible dream!
A dreadful nightmare...
Dayawanti,
Suman's life is in danger!
I can't stay here.
I must go to Bijapur, today.
Now you've woken the demon
from his sleep of centuries.
There will be such a flood of death,
that all be washed away in it.
And you people
are responsible for it.
I swear by Goddess Bhadarkali, there's
only one way to escape this fate.
A blood sacrifice of you two
to Bhadarkali.
Hail Bhadarkali!
The one that I was dying for,
he has to die today.
The faithless in love we must
settle their account today.
The one that I was dying for,
he has to die today.
The faithless in love,
we must settle their account today.
My love your life
it soon will end.
Death is going to fulfill
its revenge today.
The world changed with the fire
of rage. The moth is still alive.
It has to get burnt
while swaying.
This game is from births.
There are many dangers in
the path of love. Be careful.
Understand the gestures and
listen to me. Win or lose.
Run away, mister!
Let him go.
I swear by Bhadarkali,
Raka will cut this girl into pieces.
With these hands I will sacrifice
her blood to the goddess.
If you want to save her,
then you must fight me.
Listen! I want
that city dog, dead or alive.
Let's search the jungle.
Come on!
Let's not stay here anymore.
Let's get out of here now.
Come on, let's go.
Yes, Suman but we have
to find Anand first.
He must be at the temple
looking for the demon.
Let's go.
Where is your friend?
Where have you hidden him?
Where is my sister's killer?
Speak!
Let me go.
I don't know.
Speak bastard,
or I will skin you alive.
I said I don't know.
Now let me go,
I have a mission to kill.
And so do I,
as you'll find out.
Let go of me.
I said, let me go.
I said, LET ME GO!!
Hail Bhadarkali!
Before you can get to them,
you have to get past me!
Sanjay, get Suman out of here.
I'll deal with this.
Have you gone mad, Anand?
I can't leave you here.
Don't argue Sanjay!
This demon feeds off
the blood of Suman's family.
He'll kill her.
No! I can't leave you
to face this alone.
We live together
and die together.
Go! Go!
Suman's life is at stake!
Take her and get out of here!
Go! Go!
Get Suman out of here!
A friend is someone
who gives his own life if need be.
Papa, look what's happened.
Anand sacrificed his life
to save us.
And the demon
killed Sapna too.
No man has the power to
combat this demon.
Only one mighty power can
destroy him and that is Lord Shiva.
Let's go and beg for our lives
from him.
Shiv Shankar.
Shiv Shankar, simple one.
You are the one who gives life to all.
You are the mighty preserver.
In the middle of the river,
you are the bank.
Your strength
created the two worlds.
Oh creator of all, Shiv Shankar,
Shambo, Bholenath.
You are the giver, you are
the mother and father of all.
Your glory shines.
Strong one, the strength of all,
your devotee calls you.
Open your eyes Lord,
give us your divine protection.
This is an old temple of yours,
we have surrounded it.
Where have you
lost your trident?
How can you have lost it
in front of the demon?
Speak mighty one,
speak God, speak.
Suman, we need that trident.
- Trident?
- Yes, God Shankar's trident.
We can kill
this monster with it.
And I've seen it
in the palace.
Come.
It was here!
Suman, that trident was here!
Look there.
Suman, this coffin
was in the old temple.
The old temple?
Yes, but how did it get here?
That trident must be here.
Somewhere in this palace.
Don't look in his eyes, Suman!
Suman! Don't look in his eyes!
Suman, no!!
What's that noise?
We'll see.
But the demon...?
While God Shiva's trident is on it,
the demon can't leave the coffin.
Let's go.
Burn it!
Turn this palace into ashes!
Let the demon burn
together with this evil palace!
People of Bijapur,
stop right there!
You can't burn
down this palace!
Give me...
just half an hour's grace.
And within that half hour,
in front of this palace...
...I myself will burn that demon
to ashes in front of your eyes.
And if you can't subdue the demon
within that time, then what?
Then go ahead
and burn it down.
Come villagers...
Come and burn this demon
in the village square!
Open it.
Open it!
Start the fire!
Let this demon burn.
Burn him!
Son, I am proud of you.
You have destroyed the curse
that has haunted our family...
...for 200 years!
God bless you. God bless you.
Synced by Anomix33