"SKINNY SKINNY"
What's wrong, Giacomino?
You are not in the usual mood.
Of course, I don't want to spend
another day on an empty stomach.
Okay, we'll purvey for. We will.
"We'll purvey for"...You always say so,
but I feel weak, weak!
It's a matter of vitamin!
Phosphates! Phosphates!
Not phosphates...steaks!
You're right! You're right!
You were always a bit anemic.
But tonight we'll work,
and we'll get paid, God willing.
But who can get until tonight!
I have too much arrear appetite!
I got her! I got her!
The hen belongs to me!
She belongs to us!...To us!
Yes, she belongs to us. How's she?
She is a false lean!
How do we cook her?
Roasted!
- Bravo, I'm crazy for roasted chicken!
Love, love!
- And the fire?
Right, the fire!
We'll put her at the sun!
Bravo! Twenty days at the beach!
- Don't joke!
I'm not kidding!
- Meanwhile, let's kill her.
Ouch!
- What happens? Did she bite?
No!
We're not experienced.
Let's call the concierge!
Shall I go down?
- No, I'll call her in the courtyard.
Mrs. Rosa!
Mrs. Rosa !
What do you want?
Be patient, come up a moment.
Is it urgent?
Quite. Come up, Mrs. Rosa, come up!
Are you hurt?
Much? I think the nail will fall.
But, it is fine!
That's the one! - And why give me this?
- 'Cause, I had it in my mouth!
Here's the Executioner!
Mrs. Rosa.
Come in.
Here is our Mrs. Rosa!
Here is the chair.
Mrs. Rosa, you must do us a big favor.
Let me be, don't speak of favors!
Just today I'm very nervous!
What happened? - Someone stole
a white chicken that was a beauty!
But this is the voice of my chicken!
- No...
But, there's my chicken here?
- No. .. no!
It's my companion,
he's practicing for a great variety act.
He imitates animal sounds.
Let us hear the chicken sound.
Forget it! Don't let him do the
chicken sound. - Yeah, it's nostalgic.
Well, tell me, what did you call me for?
Ah ... us?
- Yes, you called me, right?
So?
- Well...
We wanted to know the time.
- What?
And, to know the time, you made me do
five flights of stairs? - Sorry.
Are you crazy? I've always said it,
the artists are all idiots!
Sorry, Mrs. Rosa.
This has to die!
- It's a sin, poor beast!
By the way, professor...
No, you have to do...
Professor, stop doing the beasts!
- Sit down.
No need, no need. I wanted to tell you,
this morning came the administrator.
He wants the rent!
What manners!
After all, he must only have two months!
And it's 2 months you're here! And never
paid. - Already 2 months have passed?!
You know, months run! - They run?
Well, we cannot run behind the months!
Silence!
Studies later!
Mrs. Rosa,..
tell the landlord
that tonight we debut at the Alcazar.
Come tomorrow and
I'll give you something for him. - Okay.
Think about it, he's a bad guy!
A guy who would throw
your furniture in the street! - What?
And then he kicks you out!
Mrs. Rosa, you are responsible!
These are all antiques!
I'll sue the landlord...
I'll seize the whole building!
The furniture, in the street!
- Oh! Why?
The rent!  - Oh!
- Money!
I would say, eat her alive, poor beast!
Do not be silly, stupid!
Scary, huh!
Mrs. Rosa! - Mrs. Rosa, again!
Put her here!
Pardon!
But Professor Sik Sik, lives here?
It's me, the renowned professor!
Who is she?
Miss!
Sit down, young lady!
Please come in.
Professor, let me introduce Miss Lilì.
She is your partner. I met her
last night at the Cafe of the Artists.
She's jobless
since three months, and I,..
I have engaged her
for three shows a day,..
at 15 lire, and no down payment!
But I came just for the down payment!
A chair for the young lady.
- Sure.
Good! Just what we needed!
- She's cute, right?
What the hell are you doing?
I've said many times, this is the chair
for the landlord! - How should I know?
I am mortified...did you get hurt? Sit.
This is a good chair. - No, thanks,..
I prefer standing.
- Of course! What humiliation!
Can we offer you something?
Certainly you have already eaten.
Actually ... no.
- Us neither!
But of course! As you see,
even abroad they have the same habits.
Artists eat after the show.
Tonight, let's hope that all is well...
so, God willing, we too will eat.
Let's hope He's willing!
Depends on you!
- On me?
Of course.
- And why?
You told the lady what to do?
- Everything!
What I recommend,
is the disappearance of the dove!
The dove?
- Which then should be in your hat.
Remember to sit in the front row.
So that, when I say:
Is there someone of the audience
who wants to come on stage, gentlemen?
You answer immediately: "I WONT!"
Yes.
I WONT!
WONT?
I WENT.
- I WENT.
WONT?
- WENT?
- WONT? But...
Okay, you will just say..
I !
I!
- Bravo!
I wish the show started right now!
You'll have a perfect partner!
- Shall we rehearse?
OK, let's rehearse.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
military and children!
By now, all over the world,
is known my great fame as magician!
The Sik Sik who has amazed the world,..
tonight is finally in your presence.
My life has been almost fabulous!
I was only 7 when, at home,
I already made disappear any thing!
Mademoiselle, please.
Mademoiselle!
Japan welcomed my 12 years of age.
At 13,
kissed me in front the sun of URIENT.
This evening, here, I will perform
experiments the most very famous!
Beginning by that of the glasses.
Mademoiselle! Please Maestro, music!
Excuse me, you have a match?
- No, I don't buy matches.
What do you have in your hat?
A pigeon.
Holy Virgin!
Why?
I'm ruined!
What's with you?
- Miss, you have been my ruin!
You are rude!
- I dislike you!
Hey!
But what are you saying? Imbecile!
Go into the hall, stupid!
You're ruining everything!
Attention, s'il vous plaît!
Maestro, please.
We have two glasses.
You can consult your clocks.
In under a second, the wine
will end up in the glass of water,..
and the water
in the stomach of the young lady.
One!
Two!
Three!
We are now at a second experiment!
A sensational experiment!
Unique in the world!
The disappearance of a pigeon,..
which then
will be found in the hat of a spectator.
Mademoiselle,
thank this esteemed audience!
Come here! Hush!
To perform this experiment,
I need someone from the audience..
who comes on stage to check!
Is there someone of the audience
who wants to come on stage, gentlemen?
I!
- I'll come!
No, I wanted Giacomino...Gia...
One moment!
Before performing the experiment,..
I want you to note
that the pidgeon is without trick!
And that it stays alive for a lifetime!
Mademoiselle, show the pidgeon.
We want to see the dove!
- The pidgeon!
Watch, don't touch!
Oh...why?
Please watch!
Hurry! We're waiting from three hours
to see the experiment!
Is there someone coming on stage?
- I'll come!
Come! Come!
Come!
Were you sleeping?
No, I was looking for!
Please, come on in.
Careful, you will break your head!
Be careful.
You are very clever!
I take this pidgeon...
Chicken.
- Chicken.
I take this pidgeon... - Chicken!
I slam it on your face!
I'm going to put it in a cage...
That is, if you let me do this game!
If you want to understand me! Huh?
One...
Two...
Three!
Maestro, stop the music.
The pigeon that was in that cage,
gentlemen, I made it disappear!
And I made it appear
under the hat of this gentleman!
Show the pigeon!
And I'd say...let's show a chicken!
- And I have done disappear a pigeon!
To each his own!
Chicken !
- Pigeon ! - Chicken !
The pigeon ran away,
this is chicken!
One moment!
The pigeon that was in the cage,
I made find it  in the gentleman's hat..
and I made it become chicken!
Down the curtain!
Go get my hat.
I can't.
- Why?
There's the impresario right there.
Are you happy?
All your fault!
Goodbye contract, goodbye lunch,
farewell all!
But you have it in for me?
- Yes!
But I did tell you it was chicken!
Pigeon!
- It was chicken!
Pigeon! - Chicken!
- Hands off!
Lazybones!
- Lazybones, no!
I realize that intimacy
raises discontent and discord.
And since one does not respect
one's fellow artist,..
it is best to separate. Tomorrow,
you will receive two of my friends.
Mr. Sik, but the contract, the money?
What contract?
The money!
- The money?
The contract is ended, and you saw how.
What money? There is no money!
And..
then, mademoiselle, you're
perfectly right, but it is not my fault!
It's because of this idiot!
Yes, but the idiot gave me the contract.
The idiot gave you the contract?
- Yes, the idiot.
Enough!
I take full responsibility!
Miss,
starting tomorrow you will eat with us.
Where there's enough for two,
there's enough for three!
It is about a real fortune!
A casket full of gold coins!
Gold coins?
- Yes, gold!
In the Villa Belvedere,
near the main gate,..
there is a large oak.
Under this oak
is buried the treasure chest.
Just dig a meter and a half!
The house is unattended,
there are no dogs!
So, there is no danger of being caught,
just dig a meter and a half!
Do you understand? This is what
my grandfather told me in a dream!
But the villa really exists,
I know it well!
What do you do?
We were picking some fresh salad.
- Same as you are doing.
You too?
- Yes, us too.
Then let's go.
- Where? It is here.
Under the oak.
- What? - The Treasure.
The treasure? Not here any more!
Oh, why?
- I have it, the treasure!
You already dug it yourself?
- Yes. I will give it to you.
You to us? - Yes, come with me.
- To us? - Come. - The family gold?
Sir?
Are you hurt?
- No, I'm fine.
Who is this?
- A fellow worker.
I like her.
We'll take her along with us.
Taxi!
We go by taxi!
Please.
Please get in.
But, listen, us too, right?
- Of course, get in.
Get in.
Did you find him?
- No!
Not even at the second floor?
- No.
Professor, the 22 has escaped!
- It isn't possible! He couldn't!
Well, he fled!
- Then look everywhere, and let me know!
You did not expect me, right?
- No!
You did the master until now, huh?
Come in, please. Come in.
Don't make compliments, come forward.
Miss, please.
These are three great friends of mine.
Poor boy!
I beg your pardon, I'll be right back.
I want to fix you
a really delicious dinner.
Outstanding! Please, that way.
There?
- There.
What an amiable fellow! He's amiable!
Me too?
- Of course.
Thank you.
- You are welcome.
Giovanni !
Off you go, in the kitchen!
- Yes.
Come on.
Just a little time!
- For me, any time.
For me too!
Who is that gentleman?
- Who knows!
What a gentleman!
- Great gentleman!
I'm hungry!
You know who doesn't persuade me?
Who?
- The manservant.
He's...strange.
Bravo!
I meant to say it. He's strange.
Please.
Master, it cuts.
I like it!
What a gentleman!
- What a great gentleman!
What manners!
- What kindness!
The real gentleman!
- Yes.
Amiable.
But where is the kitchen?
The kitchen is there.
At table!
- At table!
It's the phone!
- Doesn't concern us.
During my absence...
you treat yourself well!
A small little chicken.
- Small little chicken, huh ?
Let's prepare dinner.
It's stubborn!
I'll answer, it's the same.
We are friends.
Hello?
- I speak with villa Gerbi?
CERVI ? Who's he!?
Mr. Gerbi is at home?
- Oh! Gerbi!
Don't know him either, but I'm going
to call him, let's see if he's here.
No! Do not move,
do not call, God forbid!
This thing is very serious!
You speak with Villa Belvedere!
Belvedere ?
- Belvedere! The villa of the treasure!
Oh, the treasure!
No, I wasn't talking to you.
Say, say...say.
From our private clinic,
a while ago, has escaped a madman.
And you're telling me?
We do not care!
Leave us alone, we must go for dinner!
We think he has taken refuge there,
in his villa. - The villa where we are?
He fled in his pajamas!
He had a monocle?
- What happened?
That gentleman who invited us to dinner,
he's fool!
Oh! That great gentleman?
Yeah!
- But why?
Mr. Gerbi is a dangerous lunatic,
suffering from homicidal mania!
Ma... ma... mania...homicidal?
He kills people?
He kills people!
Hey!
Oh! Dinner ready? Let's go!
No, the cemetery!
All three of us!
Immediately, send the keepers,
well equipped,..
and take him away!
Send for the men in white!
Let's go! Let's go, quick!
Prepare, prepare...
Quick, Giovanni, quick.
And now,
before the food touches your lips,..
I want to tell you a story.
To us?
-To you.
Is it necessary?
- It's necessary. Please sit down.
Please, sit down.
And dinner?
A tale about two bad friends,
who wanted to betray me.
I opened them my house,
and I invited them to my table.
I had treated the food so that
it would be delicious and plentiful.
But the little devil
that is inside the phone...
There's also the little devil?
- An evil little devil, he called them!
It is very bad to listen
to the little devil inside the phone.
I always carry this,
for the little devil inside the phone.
We must cut the throat!
- To the little devil?
To who talks
to the little devil inside the phone!
My poor friends!
What an ugly end!
- Lunch is served.
Great!
Come on, quick, at the table!
Come on, come on!
Sit down. Turn off the light!
- Right away!
What a beautiful tableful!
Did you see Giovanni, my valet?
Poor thing!
That mark, I made it myself.
Like this!
Good.
Now comes the fun.
Ladies first.
Giovanni, take away.
Eat.
Silence!
Eat!
Enjoy your meal.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
No talking...with the little devil!
My friends do not eat?
What is it!
Too much sauce.
Enough!...with spaghetti!
Now, chicken!
Thank goodness!
Giovanni, remove the dishes.
Not those! These!
What a darling!
There.
I adore chicken!
Giovanni, take away!
It is delicious. Delicious.
Eat the chicken!
- Eat!
If the man says eat...eat!
What are you doing?
It will be a boy.
Drink, drink!
My dear, drink!
Drink!
- Ah!
What is it?
It's here! Come on!
Tie him!
The little devil!
Hold him!
- Leave me alone!
Mademoiselle! Mademoiselle!
Ahi! Ahi!
What a beautiful day today!
What day is it?
Thursday.
And when we last ate?
- Who can remember!
Monday, I think...yes, Monday.
We must find a remedy soon.
Otherwise we will end up
like Count Ugolino.
Who is Ugolino?
Ugolino was the one
who ate his children. - Oh! Why?
Why? Because he was hungry!
He was hungry.
And now that our family
has grown by two heads,..
the girl and the hen,..
we are better off than before!
We'll have to work!
Work!
Today we have serious responsibilities.
And then,
remember that work ennobles man.
So, we shall work, pal!
MANUAL WORKERS WANTED
# Alone!
# Alone at the top floor,
all speaks of love
when the sky is clear,
and the heart in turmoil. #
Miss!
Miss, what are you doing?
Miss, you can get hurt!
Wait Miss, I'll go.
Here it is!
You have a hen with suicidal tendencies.
What?
- Oh, French?
Yes, but I understand Italian.
- Well then, let me introduce myself:
Mario Sergi, violinist.
- Lilì, artist.
Artist?
So certainly you live by yourself.
No, I live with mum and dad.
- Oh, Mom and Dad?
And now that we arrived
in the countryside, what do we do?
We'll go back in town.
Imbecile!
- He's ruined our clothes!
Leave him alone!
- You don't mess with clothes!
We are weak.
- Yes, we are weak!
All right!
One mustn't drive like that!
Want to eat?
- And you ask?
Deflate it. - What?
- I'll see to it! Deflate the tire.
And why?
- Why why? Deflate it! Unscrew the cap.
This, this!
- This here? - Yes, good.
May I?
- Quick!
Sir, you have a flat tire.
Possible?
- We deflated it ourselves!
We noticed it.
We were sitting there.
Damn! Another waste of time! - Don't
worry, sir. We'll change it in 2 minutes.
Can you?
- We are mechanics, right? - No!
Yes! Yes! - So, hurry up,
I'll make you a nice gift!
Thanks! - Thanks!
- Where is the tire? - Behind!
Where? - Behind!
- Come, unscrew the tire.
This is the tire!
- No, the spare one first!
But that's the flat one!
- What a brilliant idea, huh?
What a great idea!
At last we can eat!
- Sure!
He'll make us a nice gift,
he's a gentleman! - At least 5 lire!
We've got you!
That will teach you to steal cars!
We are honest men!
- We are innocent!
Come to the Commissioner!
- Ask the owner of the car!
Miss, will seem strange,
but I've seen your parents.
Impossible! - Yes!
Daddy's got long mustache,
and mama's got short ones.
Funny! Have anything else to say?
- Yes.
Then I want to tell you that...
it's a beautiful day today!
Not too bad.
- We could go for a stroll together.
You and me?
- Sure.
Silence I said, silence!
What silence! I'm an artist!
- And I, his gaffer!
We are gentlemen!
- Great gentlemen!
Nothing to say.
You got a great idea!
Wonderful idea! It's you, alright!
Look at that potato, look!
At least we eat!
- Really?!
Here, we eat every day?
- On the clock!
What a gentleman! - Who?
- The King!
Thank you.
See you tomorrow!
You! Let's go to the commissioner!
Now?
- We are at lunch.
Hurry, come!
Tell him to wait 2 minutes,
we eat and we come.
I told you that
the Commissioner wants you, hurry up!
The commissioner
can not wait for your convenience!
We need to eat! - We need to eat!
- Let's go, go!
What arrogance!
- We need to eat!
The two prisoners. - Come in.
Come in!
'Morning!
- Servant, excellency.
Hats away!
Hats off!
The hat!
The real car thief was arrested.
Your innocence is recognized.
You are free.
Oh, why?
- But, right now?
Yes, right now!
Excellency, before taking such
an important decision, say vital,..
wouldn't it be better to wait 10 minutes?
We go in the cell.
If you want us, just call.
No waiting in cell.
You are innocent, so go. Go!
"Go!", "Go!"
"Go!"...and the soup is gone!
- It's gone, all right!
A bit of gaiety!
Be a little cheerful!
I begin to believe you mean bad luck!
- Don't start with this! - That's right!
You're my bad luck.
Don't repeat these things,
no joking!
No, I speak seriously.
- On this subject, you cannot joke!
No joking, really.
- Where did you get that?
A piece of loaf that I managed to save.
Come with me.
- Why?
Put the bread in your pocket, you idiot!
- And why? - Come with me.
Here, some cheese.
Boss!
Wrap it, please.
There.
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
5 lire.
- 5 lire.
And,...sardines cost the same?
- Yes, 5 lire.
Would you like sardines?
- Yes, sardines.
Would you kindly give me the sardines?
- In place of this? - Yes
Here are the sardines. They're delicious.
- I believe it!
Thank you and goodbye.
- Excuse me!
Say.
- You haven't paid.
What?
- The sardines.
But I gave in return a box of cheese.
But you had not paid for the cheese.
- But the cheese, I did not take it.
Right! - Clear?
- Yes. - Goodbye.
The greatest attraction in Europe!
The ride of death...
Excuse me, we're both artists.
- What do you want?
We would like to work.
- A small job, if any.
Here there's no jobs, is fully occupied.
Go to the rides, there are jobs, there.
Got jobs? Seeking staff?
- Yes, porters.
I told you "at the rides", I told you!
- Go! - Thanks. - Thanks!
Excuse me. - Go, that way.
- That way? - Yes
Gentlemen, the last performance
of the death ride...
Around the world for 50 cents! Pay now,
so later there will be no quarrels...
Money in hand!
Take it easy!
But what the...
I'll take your balls away!
Who's there?
But, who is it?
Oh, it's you!
# Pe, pe, pe, pè... !
Za, zam... ! #
Mademoiselle, attention!
One, two...
And three!
- Thank you!
Attention, please!
Mademoiselle ! One...
two...
and three !
Mademoiselle, here, attention!
Attention!
One, two...and three!
Look, mademoiselle, look!
Bread, bananas, cheese!
- Sweets!
All for me?
- For us too. - All three, all three!
# Taratatà ! Taratatà ! #
I'll do it.
- Thanks. - There's him!
And now, mademoiselle, I want to reveal
the secret of your bright future.
Touch a card.
Jack of spades!
You, mademoiselle, will love
a distinguished young man, slender.
With the soul of an artist.
- Artist? - Great artist!
He's not rich... but will become it.
Oh, I hope so!
- Touch another card.
Three of clubs.
This young man has a wonderful mustache.
Eyes of the East!
Imperious character, dynamic, hypnotic!
Voila!
Is that right?
To me! Let me do the prediction, now!
- You? - Yes, me.
I know you!
- And I know you!
Mademoiselle, touch a card.
Six! You, mademoiselle,..
will love a young man
who is a phenomenon of male sympathy.
He's very young, and his celebrity
will exceed that of his alleged master.
He doesn't have a large mustache,
but has a gentle fluff,..
he's somewhat wasted by hunger,
but will recover and then...
Then...You made her fall asleep.
Oh! And why?
- Because you're boring!
Leave it alone!
I take her to bed.
- I, take her to bed!
Away, go away!
Slowly, slowly.
This situation can not continue.
Living together
under the same roof with a woman..
is dangerous.
- Exactly! You're right.
You understood that you're between me
and Lilì, and you're going away, right?
I?
No, you misunderstood!
You are the one going away.
- Oh, and why?
Because I'm older,
and I have the right to stay here.
Oh yeah? - Of course.
- You remain here because you are older..
and Lilì and I will go away.
- You and Lilì?
Nice wedding!
Nice future for that girl!
Remember that,
before I met you, I was a waiter!
I am a great artist!
- I know you!
Waiter!
You're served, sir.
Advanced payment, including the tip.
I say, tip!
- Waiter!
Tamarind, barley water, orange juice?
- Two orange.
- Two orange, with tip!
Waiter! - Yessir!
Waiter! - I'm all yours.
- It's an hour that I call!
Say. - What do you have?
- Me? Nothing!
Something cool!
- Oh! Cool!
Ladies and gentlemen,
back from greatest success in Europe...
Professor, be silent!
Here, you are not allowed to juggle!
For your information,
this is no jugglery. I am performing!
And then, please, keep your place!
There is nothing that binds
an artist like me, and a dish washer!
We know your jugglery by heart!
It needs a digestive!
No, I'm not jesting,
I'll throw this box on your head!
The box on my head?
- Yeah!
I'll be...!
You mind?
Waiter, what the hell are you doing?
- Let go.
When will you bring my coffee?
- Coming now.
Let him speak!
He's a poor wretch!
Bravo! You said it: wretch!
See? Even the gentleman
said that you are a wretch.
Work, work! You make me waste time!
- You better go.
Ladies, Gents...
2 orange coffees, barley water
and an espresso vermouth. - But you say?
Two oranges,
coffee and vermouth espresso...fast.
Please, gentlemen, great attention!
I work for all to see!
No tricks! I work like that...
with what I find.
If there was a bread roll now...
No bread roll?
Then, the experiment continues.
One, two... and three!
The gentleman is served.
At home, we'll get even!
- I won't make me find!
So, they're not your relatives.
- No.
I told you a lie.
But, it is not nice for a girl like you
to live with two men in the same house.
They are two dear friends,
two gentlemen.
I was alone, without money, homeless.
If it weren't for them...
Listen, I'm not rich..
but I work. I have a contract in an
orchestra that will last for a while.
If you want, we will be happy.
"The gentleman is served!"
I'll serve you, as you deserve!
You too!
Right...not your fault.
It's over, for you!
For you it's over!
What's up?
Well...
Look out!
A bit of room gymnastics.
Will do well also to Giacomino!
Of course,
gymnastics is good for everyone!
Bravo! Bravo, Giacomino!
A go-ahead with broken shoes!
Beggar dishwasher!
You are irritable, aren't you?
- What? - Nervous!
A little.
What beautiful flowers!
Hello everyone!
- Good morning, mademoiselle.
Excuse me, miss.
- Please.
Change your way, young man!
Why don't you come in?
Ah!
A floral gift.
- Yes.
I see.
What a nice thought!
As soon as I start working
I'll buy each of you a tie.
And I...
You, when you start working,
will buy me a beautiful dress.
I saw it in the shop below!
It's beautiful, blue
with white polka dots. It costs...
How does it fit me?
- Just fine.
Do you like? - It's so beautiful!
- Are you happy? - So much!
Lilì?
Lilì, huh ? Where is Lilì?
- I don't know.
You don't know? - No.
- So, what are you doing here?
Waiting for a friend!
- On the roof? - Yes!
The fool in love!
Go away, or I'll do to you
what I didn't do at the café!
Oh, speaking about the café, come here.
How did you dare doing me
a raspberry in front of everyone?
And you, how did you
dare calling me dishwasher?
Hands off!
Because you are a dishwasher!
Dishwasher will be you!
- Me, a dishwasher?
Hold on!
- Ah!
Giacomino! - Don't leave me!
Don't leave me!
Hold on fast!
- What's beneath?
The street, Giacomino!
- We are on the fifth floor!
Giacomino! He's dead!
The dogs!
All your fault!
- Shut up, fool!
Hush! We must go away.
If someone comes,
he'll believe that we are thieves.
I'm afraid!
- Afraid... what of?
Why should you be afraid?
They have subsided...they're calm.
Yes, they're calm. - Come on, get out.
After all, they're just dogs.
We'll pass next to them slowly. You'll
see, they'll wag the tail like this.
And why? - Because
they understand that we are not afraid.
See?
Come, come forward.
Let's escape by here!
People coming!
You're so annoying!
Come in.
- Oh God, dogs too!
Be good, dear, now I'm busy.
Go, dear, I'm busy.
Come on, you wanted me to climb up here,
let's hear what you must tell me. Hurry!
No ! Do not start with the same song!
- Pierotta... - I know!
You want to tell me you love me and that
you cannot live without me! I know that!
Pierotta, look at me,
this is not what I wanted to say.
I know that you love someone else.
What a nice discovery!
I told you myself! - It's true.
But it is terrible! Terrible!
- My God!
I wanted to say that in this house,
full of your memories,..
I will take away the life!
You kill yourself?
- Yes!
Why not tell me on the ground floor?
I would have saved stairs and time!
No ! - Go to hell!
- Pierotta, I really do it!
Let's run away!
- No, the dogs!
Right!
Let's face the situation!
- If there is another way out!
Run away, he's coming back!
All right, darling, all right!
I'll show you!
What's he doing?
Come on.
- Come on.
He locked the door!
- Break it, break the door!
No! He's coming back!
You'll see, you'll see!
Laughs best who laughs last!
The fire is there..the door is closed...
Let's arrange to plug all the cracks!
Now the window!
She will see whom she's dealing with!
She will see! She will see!
He's plugging all the slits.
Why?
Who knows!
That's it!
- He's coming back!
So, you're deceiving me with another...
and I commit suicide!
Sorry, I might be too energetic ...
but it takes what it takes.
But what's he doing?
Don't you understand, stupid?
Wants to commit suicide.
- Ooh! And why?
The portrait.
You betray me...and I take revenge!
The flowers!
I was about
to commit suicide without flowers!
Where is my mind today!
Flowers!
- Here we die with due observance!
I don't want to die!
- I'm going away.
Well, well ...
We begin to suffocate.
I feel dizzy.
My stomach aches.
This time, your Gelsomino goes away!
Here we end like the mice!
Oh Gelsomino, what comes to your mind?
Drink, Giacomino. Drink.
Drink, Gelsomino, drink.
Nice, Gelsomino, nice!
Drink!
- Thank you.
Who are you?
What do you want? What's up?
What's up? It's that,
when a person wants to commit suicide,..
he has to see if there is someone
under the bed! If not, how do we do?
But how did you happen in my room?
I would be dead by now!
Let me die. - No!
Let me die! - No!
- Let me die!
Enough!
Hey!
- So, you want to die?
Would you give up life,
and all the good things in life?
Gelsomino...the sky!
Gelsomino...the sea!
The mountains.
- Gelsomino, foodstuffs!
Would you give up on love?
- Ah, love! - Love!
Gelsomino, we too, are unhappy in love.
You too suffer for a woman?
- Yeah!
Then, can I do anything to help you?
Heavens no!
We've already bothered you so much!
We've already prevented you from dying.
- But I can kill myself with leisure.
There's no hurry. And then your case
interests me. If I can be of help...
Shall we tell him?
- Okay.
Gelsomino, we were quarreling.
While quarreling, we fell
on the terrace, where the dogs are.
How ugly they are!
Why keep them?
You hurt yourselves?
- No. - Fortunately, no.
We fought over a woman,
because we both love her.
We don't have the courage to speak,
and we'd like to know who she picks.
I'll see to it! I'll talk to her myself!
In love matters, there's no one like me!
You? - Yes.
- Hooray Gelsomino!
Are you sure you can succeed?
- Oh, sure!
So, we finally found
someone who will help us.
Sure! You're right!
You're very right to leave with
this nice young man you told me about!
What does he do?
- He's a violinist. - Fine!
And then, he loves me so much!
- He loves you!
And then, what good would they be,
those two poor, shabby wretches!
No, not that!
- Enough with the sentimentality!
But, leaving them like that...
- Leave a letter.
Two pretty little words...and go!
Goodbye, miss.
Ah! They told me...
"Tell her
that we want to put at her feet"...
But what feet and feet!
Here!
Here, please.
Thank you.
Will he have spoken to her?
- He promised that he would do it at 3.
It's almost 7 now!
Thanks, man!
Goodbye. - Good evening.
So, we agree:
whatever her decision, we won't argue.
Of course, word of a gentleman!
The chosen will marry her, and
the other goes away! - Agreed? - Yes.
Perfume?
- A must!
Let me do it!
- OK.
A good scent, huh?
Whatever the decision, huh?
The chosen will marry her,
and the other goes away!
Of course!
How do I look?
- Good, good! Very good!
And how do I look?
Behind, how do I look?
Hey!
Hey! How do I look?
Very good, very good.
Good.
- Thanks.
Lilì!
- Lilì!
Where is she?
- Lilì !
Oh! The surprise!
Ties!
- Nice! And dinner!
And the choice!
- Great!
Clearly, the chosen will dine with her.
She's gone!
And why?
- Why! I do not know why!
You're annoying!
She's gone!
Dinner!
Dinner.
Even the dinner!
Ironically!
This is an insult!
You're hungry, huh?
- I? - Confess, confess.
Be careful what you say!
How can you be hungry?
- Good guy.
Right! One cannot eat!
I'm going out, I will wander all night.
- You go out? - Yes!
I'm staying.
- And so do I!
Dinner...
Dinner!
Rice...chicken!
Rice rolls...
Rice rolls...!
Lilì...Rice rolls...!