Barron Industries aim to rule...
...the digital world
Surpass 3D
Do you wonder...
...how data travels...
...from a phone?
How does it travel?
Surrounding us are millions...
...of rays
Everywhere, like the air
This virtual world...
...is ever-present
In shopping malls
In streets and homes,
in this very room
These rays allow digital data...
...to travel
Mr. Barron couldn't be here,
so he has...
...sent us an image
Without the use of any device,
can this image...
...come to life?
Can we see it?
A marvel of our technology
It isn't magic or
back projection, or 3D
The image is made of
countless invisible rays
Thanks to our technology...
...you'll see the image...
...and touch it
We're closing the gap between
the real and virtual worlds
It was a beautiful night
And so was she
"My Desi Girl."
Night waited for dawn
and she was waiting...
Go, Lucifer, go.
...for me...
I. Lucifer.
To save a life, at times,
one must take a life
Ready to die first were...
...Bruce Lee's three friends...
Iski Lee. Uski Lee. Sabki Lee.
Then the face-off
With the challenger of challengers
The only man able to fight me
Not the good guy. The Villain
"Yes, I am a bad man."
"Somewhere up in the
skies is where he lives."
"The moon is where I quest to go."
"It's my request."
"Tonight. Tonight.
Something's going to happen."
What to do? Girls just fall for me
"What to do? Something happens."
My hero.
I hate uninvited guests
Bad times come uninvited
Do you know who I am?
I sprayed Spiderman with a poison
What worm are you?
Cool punch line!
You punch too?
Sure!
They clap at my wit
And wail when I hit
Lucifer. Careful!
Don't worry, desi girl
I'll fix him
Then how about dinner.
- Sure.
Where?
Anywhere. But not Chinese.
I just ate some
Is your flirting done?
Now can we fight?
Lucifer. He's got a big gun
"My name is..."
"The bad man."
"Wow.
What the kick?"
"My name is... My name is...
My name is Lucifer."
Desi Girl.
You've started that again?
Get up!
I said...
Get up.
Prateek Get up.
You were supposed to write
an essay on your father.
What does your father do?
My father.
I am sure he's your hero, isn't he?
Dad? My hero?
Can't chat now
Oh yes, love you very much sweety.
Allow me to quote Navjot Singh Sidhu:
"Flirting turns the head."
"Eyes on the road instead."
Bye, sweety.
Allow me.
Have a good day.
Hey, Walter. Here.
What.
- Excuse me, madam.
Madam. Madam, I...
Hi...
Give me my keys
You speak Tamil?
No, no, no.
Not that kiss. Keys.
You are not understanding.
Okay. I just want the big one.
I don't want small,
small. I have duplicate.
Can you take it out please.
- Pervert.
What happened to you?
It's nothing
- What's up?
- The usual
Akashi. - Someone called him
Jackie Chan again
I am not Jackie Chan.
Not every Chinese is Jackie Chan.
Mr. Jackie Chan. Sit down.
Seeing all of you gives me
no pleasure. I'm here...
...to tell you we have
a new video game contract
Hello.
- For sale in India, too
Your last games flopped
If this game flops...
...the department closes
I will have to shut it down.
I won't fire anyone.
I'll start a restaurant
Where you...
...and you will...
...be waiters
And... Mr. Shekar.
Hello, sir.
- And you shall be the main cook
Making idli, vada, dosa, sambar...
...and chutney
Any problem?
Does anyone else have a problem?
Shekhar?
- What? - Say something.
What?
- Come on.
Sir, excuse me, sir.
I have a problem, sir.
What's your problem?
I can't make idlis
Dosas?
Plain, masala, rava, onion,
veg, non-veg
No idlis
Good. - I hope you don't mind.
- Not at all.
Great.
- Thank you, sir.
Honey, I am home.
Sonia.
Sweety.
You papa pancake
Yummy, thank you.
Brother buttercup
You work too hard
Just "kondom"
Your Tamil is naughty
You mean "a tiny bit"
You never take me seriously
Wait till my book becomes
a bestseller
My thesis on cuss words...
...is important for India.
A must for every Indian woman
You're Sonia Subramaniam.
Not Sonia Gandhi
Why do cuss words pick
on mothers? And sisters?
Why not fathers? Brothers?
I am not responsible for it.
When my thesis is done,
women all over India...
...will puff up their chests...
Too bold
OK. They'll proudly
say: "You papa pancake"
Big buttercup
You uncle undie
- Why is the song so loud?
- I'm talking, not singing
No, no, not you, darling.
One second.
Prateek.
- Why you...
Prateek Prateek
What, father?
- Lower that volume
What?
Of course.
- So...
You are banging the...
Put it down!
I am watching you, little rascal.
I am watching you.
- What is it, Shekhar?
He slams the door on me.
Come here! Its dinner time.
You drive me mad. Just wait
- Come on.
Let's go eat
- Little rascal.
Tell us about your new video game
Of course, of course.
After all it is for kids.
Dude.
- No, dad. Its dude.
Like, dude with attitude.
Dude.
- Okay.
A brand new game
A new hero...
Heroes bore
I hate heroes. Heroes are boring.
Old or new
Don't you like heroes?
Do you prefer villains?
Yes. Villains are awesome.
They have no rules
They just win. Anyone
comes in their way... bam!
You be careful.
- Take my advice.
Make a game with
a villain who never loses
You are speaking absolute nonsense.
The hero always win
Truth and goodness win
Yes right, dad. Just like you.
My father, my hero.
- Prateek.
Don't be a smartypant.
Allow me to quote...
...Late Mr. V. Shantaram.
"Tread the right path"
"Combat evil, so with a smile...
...you die"
Good night, dad. - What goodnight?
The discussion is not over.
One slap. One, one...
- Shekar.
I will give him one.
V. Shantaram?
- Yes, really. Really.
V. Shantaram.
- Right.
Goodnight, honey.
- Okay.
I will have all
the noodles and curd by myself.
The villain never loses
How is it possible? Never loses
"Beloved. Beloved."
I'll show you bad
Mom, what are you doing?
Hurry up. Time for school
Dad will take you today.
- Dad.
We'll be late if Dad drives
Driving Miss Daisy!
Not anymore.
"I'm bad."
"Dance with me."
That is your dad, right?
No.
Okay. Bye, children.
Bye, dad.
- Bye little April. - Bye.
Prateek, come here
Come, come, come.
Dad. You know I don't do that.
Yeah. Okay.
I want to tell you something
You like villains?
I'll make you a villain...
...mightier than the hero
He'll never lose
You like that, don't you?
Give me your hand.
But never forget, Prateek
Evil is wicked and bad
Allow me to quote myself:
"Sell your soul to the Devil and
evil's shadow won't leave you"
Shadow.
- Means "shadow"
Whatever?
- Whatever is good.
World's bad villain.
Today's lesson is on LAN.
Local Area Network.
Who's Lucifer?
When I play video games...
...my gaming name is Lucifer
WLAN. Wireless LAN.
Allows interconnectivity
between computers.
Ms. Boyle can log on
to our computers
Now I will seek connection
to all of your computers.
So then monitor
appears on this projection.
She'll ask for permission.
We say no
Fatso says yes
I've hacked and he is jacked.
And I am sending the invitation now.
Let's see who will be
the first person to accept my request.
Billy. Thank you, Billy,
for accepting my invitation.
Let's see what Billy has to share.
Billy, out.
I have a great idea
for our new video game
We'll create...
...the mightiest...
Hero.
Villain.
- Villain?
Yes, villain. But, why?
Because, Jenny.
Villains are awesome.
What do you say, Akashi.
For Prateek, right?
Yes
Of course.
"Joy will last longer than grief.
Don't lose hope."
"If we are together..."
"...why to feel afraid
during the journey?"
"With wings beneath our feet."
"You and I will fly away."
"Walk along with joy."
"If the path is open,
regardless of where we meet...
...the destination
will begin from there."
"Walk along with joy."
"If the path is open,
regardless of where we meet...
...the destination
will begin from there."
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be right by your side.
I will be right by your side."
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be holding you tight.
I will be holding you tight."
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be right by your side.
I will be right by your side."
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be holding you tight."
Okay, boys and girls.
A name for our villain?
We can't keep calling him
"Random Access Version One?"
We have to think of some good name.
- Dracula.
No, no. You.
- Raaka.
Guys, guys.
It's staring you in the face
Meaning?
- Random Access Version One.
"Ra. One"
- What's that?
- Raavan!
The demon Raavan?
A modern day Raavan
Wild idea!
I like Ra. One it is very dangerous.
What about the hero's name?
Hero's name.
"G. One?"
Good one. G. One means "life"
Ra. One = danger. G. One = life
Hi.
Come on. Come on. Okay.
"If your dreams are
hiding somewhere."
"If you are
hesitating to take a step."
"I will make your dreams
come true in an instant."
"I will again adorn it in
the sky, beyond the stars."
"The sorrows that are in my life,
I will convert it into joy for you."
"Walk along with joy."
"If the path is open,
regardless of where we meet...
...the destination
will begin from there."
"Walk along with joy."
Just like Jackie Chan.
It's working.
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be right by your side.
I will be right by your side."
A birthday gift
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be right by your side.
I will be right by your side."
- What's up?
- The hero must have a face
"I will be holding you tight.
Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be right by your side.
I will be right by your side."
"Don't worry about a thing now.
Because I will be holding you tight."
He's spectacular
Terrific smile
I didn't program a smile
Didn't you?
Why is he smiling?
Is he learning things by himself?
Okay. Now everyone look closely.
The game's main part
The HART
As in "heart?"
Not heart. Always talking romantic.
Not that heart, the HART is Hertz
Amplifying Resonance Transmitter.
It gives the players their power
As the players go
from level to level...
...the HART's power increases,
the colour intensifies
And now... let me come to
the most interesting part.
If the HART is not
connected to G. One and Ra. One...
...you cannot destroy them
If you destroy the HART,
they won't die
No, no, sir.
Destroy their bodies,
they won't die either
Connect them to their
HARTs then destroy them
When does that happen?
Only on level three.
The players get an anti-HART gun
with one bullet
The first to hit the target wins
The player who misses...
So the HART is their strength?
And weakness?
Let me also be... Allow me
to be as romantic as Jenny.
"A hero isn't made of
muscle or metal
"A superhero is made or
undone by his heart alone" Wow.
Great.
See? The movie villain lost,
the hero won. Very good. I like.
That's why the film bombed.
The villain was cool
Not cool. A bloody fool,
a chain-smoker
Smoking kills
This kid is smoking
- Let's go - I must talk to him
Hey little boy. Little boy.
- Let's go.
Your Mom knows you smoke?
Sure!
- I see.
But she doesn't know I kill
With a fork?
- A nail cutter
- A knife
He's flashing a knife.
And he isn't a small child either.
Dad, don't worry.
We can smash his teeth in
Your wallet!
Of course, sir. Of course.
Give him a slap
Sorry, sir. Here's the money,
sir. Plus a tip
A slap, please!
- Slap.
What else do you have?
- That's all I have, sir
I gave you everything I had, sir.
- Don't move
Yes, sir. - You haven't
seen me. Now count to 2000
Good number sir.
That's my lucky number.
Don't slip on the wet road, sir.
Goodnight, sir.
See? I scared him off
But he might return.
Start counting. Good practice
Yeah right, dad.
1000... Prateek.
Prateek, wait
You didn't even fight back.
You coward
No, Prateek. I'm not a coward
I didn't hit him
because he could've hurt you
Allow me to quote the great
Mahatma Gandhi...
..."An eye for an eye makes
the whole world blind"
I'm no coward, Prateek
I am... Hey...
Okay, Akashi. One last time.
I mean one last time.
Let's try.
- One last time.
Alright, guys.
South-India Coffee break.
That means we meet tomorrow. Bye.
Check the system. Somebody
go and check the main system.
Okay, okay, I am going to check it.
- Why is it constantly back...
...sizing inside it?
What happened there?
- Come on, guys.
The launch is in two days.
We can't have a problem
Ladies and Gentlemen.
Barron Industries present...
...a unique and spectacular game
Thank you my darlings.
Thank you all very much.
Akashi's mom
Hello.
- My better.
Now hold your breath!
Barron Industries presents
for the first time ever.
Ra. One.
Relax. Shekhar.
Year 2050
The world lies in ruin
A villain never seen before...
...spreads terror in his wake
An evil villain reigns
Created out of
history's ten most evil men...
...he is undefeatable
An invincible villain
With the power to
invade and control our minds
He is equal to ten
villains rolled in one. Ra. One.
Waging war! My only duty
Wow.
Prateek. Ra. One.
The ultimate villain.
He can change form.
Turn into a man or woman
Wired with artificial intelligence
Ra. One adapts, transforms
New forms, new moves
Never the same threat
Good morning.
To fight Ra. One,
the player has a Superhero
All players get a control suit
Wear it and get connected
Wear it and get
connected to your Superhero
I am on.
Hey Jackie Chan.
He is not Jackie Chan.
Every player can be G. One
A superhero, with a heart.
- Father.
Superhero.
Okay.
- He is looking hot, isn't he?
So hot.
Let's play.
I want to play
No party for me
Akashi. I want to play
the game now. Please.
Shekhar, its okay.
Come on, come on. Come with me.
Prateek liked the game
Thank you, Jenny.
Same name. Lucifer.
- Yes.
Lucifer.
Okay. Ground rule. Game begins.
Level one. Power blast.
Come, Ra. One! Kick-ass time
Welcome, Lucifer
Welcome to the dark world of death
Zip it. Crap face.
I am a gaming champion.
Good move.
Down.
Level two, killer combat.
Yeah!
What?
Cheers
"Look out, look out.
The siren's blaring."
"You drop it down.
I can't stop staring."
"Your smile is so criminal."
"Your eyes are deceiving."
"Yet I fell for you."
"Just like a criminal."
"She's burning like a fever."
"And I am a believer."
"She's enchanting."
"Not just these eyes."
"But your attitude's
full of mischief."
"It's criminal, way that
booty going bop, bop, bop."
"It's criminal, way that party
won't stop, stop, stop."
"Each day your Love...
Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Each day your Love..."
"Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"It's criminal, way that
booty going bop, bop, bop."
"Every eye."
"Stares at me."
"They stop and stare."
"My charisma's radiant."
"My attitude's graceful."
"It's graceful."
"Your attitude steal my slumber."
"And your hair does the rest."
"So you tell us how
do we save ourselves."
"Because your eyes steal my heart."
"It's criminal, way that
booty going bop, bop, bop."
party won't stop, stop, stop."
"Each day your Love...
Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Each day your Love..."
"Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Slyly you stole..."
"My breath."
"Slyly. - She came in my dreams.
She got me losing my mind."
"Slyly.
- Dwelled in my eyes."
- Came in my dreams."
"Slyly.
- Gave me sleepless nights."
"She got me losing my mind."
"Your eyes are deceiving."
"Yet I fell for you."
"Just like a criminal."
- "She's burning like a fever."
"And I am a
believer." "She's enchanting."
"Not just these eyes."
"But your attitude's...
...full of mischief."
"It's criminal, way that
booty going bop, bop, bop."
party won't stop, stop, stop."
"Each day your Love...
Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Each day your Love..."
"Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Each day your Love...
Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Each day your Love..."
"Torments the heart"
"Your sight steals my heart."
"Criminal."
Hey, Lucifer. Let's go.
This stuff rocks. Where is dad?
The game isn't over
He's down, waiting for you.
Come on.
I'm nearly at Level 3
I can whoop his ass.
No one defeats Ra. One and survives
No one in office has
crossed level one yet.
Come back, Lucifer.
Or I'll hunt you in the real world
Go ahead. I'll fix you
Ra. One never loses
When the game ends,
so does your life
You will die.
Lucifer will die.
A problem with the game, I must go
It's okay.
- Let's go.
Bye.
Come on.
Dad
For you and Ra. One.
I will see you, bye.
"You mean everything to me."
Why doesn't Ra. One power down?
Let us have a drink. Celebrate.
I don't want to drink.
Not you. Ra. One and me
Come, come, come.
- You are not taking me seriously.
I will go check the mainframe room.
You go and check
the programming room.
Now.
Ra. One sir, you were terrific today.
Really I tell you. Really, I...
From me to you.
Happy birthday to you.
Today you are born.
I will go and check
the programming room.
But... I will be back.
I will see you.
See you later, alligator.
So?
- So.
Liked the game?
Yeah!
Didn't you want to just hug Dad?
Mom, please.
Cool game. I'll tell him
So why didn't you?
We live in the same house.
I can tell him tomorrow
All right
You felt like hugging him, right?
What did you want to do with him?
Mom, stop. - You wanted to hug him.
- Mom, stop.
Okay, Mr. Ra. One.
Akashi says we can't turn you off
Let us see.
Segmentation full.
Ra. One not stopping?
Hello, Akashi.
- Do you see anything unusual.
Ra. One's not stopping.
I told you so.
Is the main-frame alright?
I am looking.
The log is not
showing anything unusual.
I will bring the GPU and
we will work on this together. Okay?
Okay. I am...
Fatal system error.
Where's Ra. One?
A rose?
Who is there?
Lucifer has to die.
Lucifer must die.
Are you Lucifer?
Lucifer?
I am not Lucifer.
Then you are not use to me.
Akashi, pick up!
Akashi.
Sonia. Prateek. Pick up the phone!
Ra. One.
He's broken out of the game?
I want Lucifer
Lucifer.
I will finish him.
Are you Lucifer?
I am Lucifer
You're lying
Yes, speaking.
"Why won't you talk to me?"
"Why turn your back on me?"
"How do I turn the clock back?"
"Why won't you talk to me?"
"Why turn your back on me?"
"How do I turn the clock back?"
"Without you, nights never end."
"Without you, I know no peace."
"Without you, how can I live?"
"My eyes fill with tears."
"There's a hole in the soul...
...because you take
a little piece of me with you."
"There's a hole in the soul...
...because you take
a little piece of me with you."
"There's a hole in the soul...
...because you take
a little piece of me with you."
Dad...
What is it?
Dad didn't die in an accident
Ra. One killed him
Ra. One.
The game villain
What are you saying?
Do meet me...
Hello.
What?
I'm not going to India
Prateek, listen to me.
I must know how Dad died
It was an accident
We're leaving today
Not me
And that's final.
- Prateek.
You promised me you would return
Why tie me to you,
if you won't come back?
I wait with racing heart
I listen for your step
I look in vain for you
My love
I try and win you back
I try and entice you
The flight...
"My eyes fill with tears."
You were right.
My God! But, how?
Ra. One said he'd break
out of the game and find me
"Prateek, this control suit
is for you
"Ra. One is the villain
you wanted. But remember...
"If Ra. One is from evil,
G. One is from my heart"
Millions of rays surround us
Our technology lets
you see the image...
...and touch it
"If you ever get into trouble,
G. One will look after you"
Play on the good side,
dude. Love, dad.
Akashi, its Prateek.
Hello.
It's Prateek.
Hello, Prateek.
The office.
It's destroyed.
You were here with dad that night.
Did anything happen?
No.
It was pretty quiet.
On the monitor it
says "Lucifer must die"
Who is Lucifer?
It's me, Akashi. That's my
gaming name. Didn't you know?
Lucifer. Prateek. Of course I know.
Akashi.
Who was...
Ra. One has turned into Akashi
I don't like Chinese.
Hello.
- Mom.
Where are you?
I was right. Ra. One killed Dad
He's Akashi now
Where are you?
Dad's office
I'm coming
The mainframe!
Prateek. Just hold this.
Connect the laptop to
the mainframe and try to login.
Now log on
Upload Ra. One's backup program
It's missing
No backup program?
We will have to
intercept this program.
How can we stop him?
Has to be some way to stop Ra. One.
"If you ever get into trouble,
G. One will look after you"
There's only one way
to stop Ra. One... G. One
If Ra. One can break out,
so can G. One
Right.
Ra. One's latest programs
must be in the mainframe.
We'll copy Ra. One's
data and get G. One out
Load this program.
- Okay.
Damn it.
Hello.
- Jenny, I am here.
Akashi is heading to you
What happened?
- Ra. One.
Sonia called. Ra. One is
on his way. Go, Prateek!
No, I will have to try.
I must release G. One now
Ra. One is looking for you.
Not for me. Please, go
Go!
The HART
Prateek, go
Just go.
Hurry
What is happening, Prateek?
What's going on?
- Let's go.
Mom, faster.
Red light
- Let's go.
- Why is Akashi after us?
- It's Ra. One. Not Akashi
Step on it!
What is going on?
- He is after us, mom. Faster.
Mom, faster.
How can Ra. One come out
of the game?
How can he turn into Akashi?
What's going on?
I will tell you later. Drive faster.
- Where is he?
- Don't know
Lost him
He's got a bike
Turn right.
- Where are we?
- Go!
Right turn.
Faster.
Mom.
Prateek.
You okay?
Yes. You?
Prateek.
You missed, G. One.
But, mom...
- Enough about Ra. One and G. One.
We're going to India
There's no Ra. One and no G. One.
Dad?
Come on, Prateek. Hurry
We are late.
- Okay, mom. Let's go.
Okay, mom. Let's go.
- Why is he coming?
- G. One saved us
Mom! G. One saved us
Mom! G. One saved us.
- Okay, bye. Thank you.
Nice shirt, dude.
- Nice shirt, dude.
- You can't come in that
- Can't come at all
We have to cover him
You have to cover me.
Mom's scarf
What are you doing?
Hey you. You can't park there.
I said no parking.
I don't get it
Try and understand
Okay, quiet. Quiet.
OK. How do we get this thing...
...past the metal detector?
Prateek, listen
He can't come with us
There's no way.
- There's always a way.
Will he do?
Yes, of course.
- Yes.
Watch! G. One's cool move
What are you doing?
This.
Be like Ra. One
Act like him
I can't...
...be him
I'm not as powerful
Protection?
Buttercups!
Prateek, language.
- Sorry, mom.
Pants off?
Step aside, sir.
Just go.
I won't go
Some taxi-driver you are
You will take us. That's the rule
I'll take you
Forget his silly taxi. Hop on
Coming?
Rot!
I will take her.
A tight slap for you
We'll take her
Who is it?
Stop that!
He'll die
We'll reset him and press play
He's a man, not a tape recorder
Quiet!
It's no game
If someone dies...
...they don't return
They can
"A man changes outfits
"A soul changes bodies and returns"
Gita. Chapter 2, Verse 22
Page number?
Tell him to let go
Let go!
Yes.
- What a throw.
Tell him
G. One. No touching.
Fan blades under his feet
No touching.
G. One.
G. One. Stop it.
G. One. No touching.
No touching.
G. One.
Good one.
Idiot.
- You OK?
- I'm fine
Idiot.
You can't touch me there
So where?
Nowhere
How to save you?
No need
Buttercups!
Help me!
G. One.
Do something
I must touch you
Then touch me. Touch me.
Please touch me.
- Okay.
Lower!
Punch him
Lower.
Yummy Mummy. Love at first fight
- She's my Mom
- Mine too
Go, mom.
Mom. Main part.
Main part?
What main part?
Main part.
"Robo man. Robo man."
"Chitti."
"Superhero."
- Who is he?
- Our Superhero No. 1
Rajnikanth
I am Chitti. Speed one terahertz.
Memory one zettabyte.
Lord.
"Chitti."
Rajni sir is mind-blowing
Uncle lyer
Surprise visit
Why so shocked?
You're my Dad now.
Say hi to your mate
Hi.
- Hi.
I am pumping while jumping.
I don't like him much.
- You don't like him much.
Bye.
You did that?
No, gravity. Law of attraction.
Hi, Prateek.
Hi.
Bye.
- Bye? Why?
Law of attraction.
How are you?
I don't understand.
- Too deep, you go.
Bye.
"The past is behind us.
The future ahead
"Live in the present,
that's all we have"
What was that?
Shekhar programmed me
to memorise proverbs
Any others?
"Those who say big is best haven't
spent a night with a mosquito"
Any more?
"Smile and win my heart.
Cry and I'll be teary-eyed
"Near or far
"I won't leave your side"
I don't get it. If you don't,
can I delete the folder?
No. No.
Never delete that folder
Never. Decision taken
He's a handsome man.
Bad hair
The electricity needs reconnecting
Bowls!
You scared me
G. One is on stand-by
Stand-by elsewhere
G. One. Go and make yourself useful.
- Okay.
When things settle,
we must do something about him
Why? Can't he live with us?
No. Not at all.
He isn't a TV or toaster
you can leave in a corner
He talks like a human
Looks like Dad, right?
You think G. One was right
about the soul returning?
Dad could be back as G. One,
to protect us
Remember what he'd say
when we were in trouble
Of course I remember.
"When life is dark,
an angel lights a 600-watt bulb"
I've made myself useful.
I charged the inverter.
What to recharge now?
Mom's mood
Changes your mood instantly
Have you no shame? Talking like
that in front of a kid. Sleep now
I don't sleep. I run
Whatever
Bowls!
Goodnight.
- Yes.
I know what to do with him
We'll send him to
the loony bin. He's nuts
Not totally, Mom.
Just "kondom," a teeny bit
What? How do you know
that word? Come here.
Stop it, mom. Please.
Please. You don't
have to say all that.
Stop it.
"When the night has come.
And the land is dark."
"And the moon is the only light."
"Darling. Darling."
"My guiding light."
"You're my world."
"You're all I want."
"Now and forever."
"My guiding light."
"You're my world."
"Nothing compares..."
"...with your name."
"A thousand books told me so."
"My sweet love."
"The world is nothing without you."
"Your generosity melts hearts."
"My sweet love."
"The world is nothing without you."
"Your generosity melts hearts."
"My sweet love."
"I won world but
lost my heart to you."
"My sweet love."
"Darling, darling, stand... by me."
"Stand... by me."
"Just as long as you stay."
"Darling, darling, stand... by me."
"Come on stand by me.
- Stand... by me."
"Just as long as you stay."
"Stand... by me."
It's all my fault
I told Dad to make a villain...
...who never loses
Had I defeated Ra. One,
Dad would be here today
You're a dude, dad.
No nutritional element in this
No smoking. Bad for health.
The pack has a warning
Thousands quit smoking each year
So the warning works?
No. They die
"When the night is long
and the land is dark."
"When the moon is the only light."
"When the night is long
and the land is dark."
"When the moon is the only light."
"My sweet love."
"My prayers are answered."
"You're all I want."
"My sweet love."
"The world is nothing without you."
"Your generosity melts hearts."
"My sweet love."
"The world is nothing without you."
"Your generosity melts hearts."
"My sweet love."
"I won the world
when I lost my heart to you."
My sweet love
"Darling, darling, stand... by me."
"Stand... by me."
"Just as long as you stay."
"Darling, darling, stand... by me."
"Come on stand by me.
- Stand... by me."
"Just as long as you stay."
"Stand... by me."
Just do it.
Good job, babes.
- You're alright. Thanks.
Sometimes I think you're human
G. One. G. One.
Where are you going? G. One.
My photo!
What are you doing?
Idiot
You nuts?
You...
G. One. G. One. Stop.
Prateek. G. One.
My dining table
Get down.
Flying bowls
Ok?
You fool
Prateek.
Stop!
Yes.
What's with him?
G. One.
- G. One?
Shekar.
You hit him?
Power yoga
Power yoga!
Day and night
Carry on. Carry on.
Close your door
Power yoga
Prateek.
Power yoga, American style.
Jailalitha!
Lucifer is controlling me
Off.
Something is sticking out
of your nose
Pull it out, please
"Secrets are revealed."
"That was hidden in the heart."
"It will spread far and wide."
"Now that the Secrets are revealed."
You like it? Keep it.
Thanks.
Sonia.
Good job, babes.
- Why do you pray?
- So God will protect us
Does God drop from the sky?
No. He sends His angels
Do you believe in angels?
Shut up and pray.
There is no God.
We can fix it
So what if an engineer dies?
We have to be the best at
the World Expo
The game will be ready
Match found.
System activated. Welcome.
Do you understand?
Who are...
Who let you in?
Larry. Who is this man?
What?
What's this?
Who are you?
Ra. One? From the game?
Oh my, God.
There is not God.
I want Lucifer
Lucifer
Shekhar's son
He has my HART
Without my HART...
...I am incomplete.
My powers are incomplete.
I want my HART.
Where's Lucifer?
They've gone
I don't know where
But I...
What are you doing?
Electrical impulses.
Jogging your memory
No need to do all this.
I can read...
...your mind, alter your thoughts
Control your thoughts
Shekar Subramaniam, Mumbai. India.
Thank you very much.
Have a good day, Mr. Barry.
You too.
- Sonia, aren't you coming?
- Yes
Sonia, what is Karva Chauth?
When a wife fasts for
her husband's long life
This house is full
of Shekhar's memories
That's why I came back
We can't stay in one place too long
We must leave
Ra. One could come anytime
We have his HART
So he can find Prateek
Meaning?
If we destroy his HART...
...he'd still chase us
We'd be running forever
If we don't destroy it...
...we must fight him
Chances of survival, 0.01%.
This is an emotional decision.
Incompatible with my syntax
The decision is yours
This is all I have left
Prateek, this house...
...Shekhar's memories
I can't leave
I won't run anymore
Shekhar believed in goodness
If we've a small
chance of survival...
...we'll take it
Even if its 0.01%.
Decision taken.
- Decision taken.
Save Prateek from harm
NaclH2o.
Salt and water
NaclH2o?
Tears are confusing
They flow when you're happy.
Or sad
Buttercups!
Flow when you're happy...
Not part of my program
Emotions and me.
We're at loggerheads
Those with emotions...
...would never do...
...what you've done for us
Did I go good?
No.
You did very good.
Hug her, you fool!
Power yoga isn't everything
Go on, hug her
"Darling, darling, stand... by me."
"Stand... by me."
"Just as long as you stay."
"Darling, darling, stand... by me."
Precaution.
Uncertain activity in air.
What is all this?
Hello. Kingfisher 150.
Do you read me?
What the hell is that?
What's this?
They're burning Raavan
Why?
Fool! It's Dussehra
End of Raavan
End of evil
We burn him every year
You burn him every year...
...because he never dies
Hail to Lord Ram!
Come on.
Those who die - don't need
killing again and again
You're cool in Dad's clothes
Thank you.
Shekhar and lyer celebrate
their kids' birthdays together
Fatso lyer?
Everyone knows
Shekhar here. Don't mess up
Prateek, hurry!
Bye, I am going.
Lucifer.
- G. One.
Shekhar made this game...
...for Prateek's birthday
Will you give it to
him on his Dad's behalf?
He'd like that
And you?
I'd like that too
Okay, then. Decision taken.
Lucifer.
Happy birthday, Prateek.
From Dad
No. From you
Okay.
A show for all the kids!
Come, Prateek.
As usual, Shekhar will dance
Dance?
Not today
No excuses. He'll dance for you.
You're looking so...
What's the word in Punjabi?
Firecracker?
Sexy number?
Hot chick?
"Sizzling siren"
Let's start
Prateek.
Shekhar will dance
"Sizzling siren"
"My sizzling siren."
"Where you go, girl,
I am gonna follow."
"What you want,
girl, just let me know."
"My sizzling siren."
"Surely I am gonna get you?"
"You know I am gonna get you."
"You know I even let you...
let you be my Sizzling Siren."
"Let's see you move Don't be shy."
"Look me in the eye."
"Don't say no."
"My sizzling siren."
"I am your hero."
"Give it to me, girl."
"My sizzling siren."
"Surely I am gonna get you?
You know I am gonna get you."
"You know I even let
you... let you be my Sizzling Siren."
"Let's see you move. Don't be shy."
"Come be mine."
"Look me in the eye."
"Don't say no."
"My sizzling siren."
"Let me show you how to dance."
"You'll be mine if say so."
"Look in my eye."
"I won't say no."
"My sizzling siren."
Ra. One is near
Take Prateek and go!
Just go.
Why isn't G. One here?
Ra. One scared him off
Mom, let's go back. We need G. One
We don't need him. He needs us
Where are we going?
To hell!
Don't be scared
Till your hero returns my HART...
...I won't kill you
Sonny!
Honey, I am home.
Boo. Got you.
They aren't part of the game
They weren't...
...but you made them
Where are they?
Sonia
is in my control
Sonia is on a train that
never stops
Lucifer is held hostage...
...at the game launch exhibition
Come, save them
Logic says you'll return my HART...
...and save Lucifer
Emotions say...
...you'll save Sonia
Who will you choose?
Sonia or Lucifer.
Your train has left...
...the station
I won't wait long
Your time starts now.
Tick-tock.
Running about, not allowed
Oh no.
"Wicked Speed. The destination ahead,
the wind at my back."
Oh, God.
- Excuse me.
Toilet trips, not allowed
Missing school, not allowed.
Talking to anyone,
or eating lunch, not allowed.
And hanging from
the train's roof, teacher?
Not allowed.
Oh my, God. Monkey man.
No entry. Children only
Just get out. Please.
Kids. Don't try this at home.
Not allowed.
- Do you wish to die?
"Wicked Speed. The destination ahead,
the wind at my back."
"A chilling gale, crosses
your path, it stops you."
A man is leaping about the train!
The train didn't stop
Contact the station master. Patil.
Contact the motorman.
Move back. The train is coming.
The train isn't stopping anywhere
What now?
- I don't know.
I am sorry.
Leave me. Leave me.
The train isn't stopping
Divert the train's route.
Wait, wait.
The train isn't stopping
"Time has... chosen a moment."
"I will leave a mark in history.
"Wicked Speed."
There's a bomb on the train.
Time-bomb.
Get inside.
- Duck.
"A chilling gale, crosses
your path, it stops you."
There's a bomb.
I think there's been a blast.
"There's no fun when."
"Life isn't on the edge."
"A strong heart."
"Never accepts defeat easily."
"Doing that unimaginable."
"Is the mark of the brave."
"I don't do it for myself."
"I lay my life down for my kin."
"Wicked Speed."
"The destination ahead,
the wind at my back."
Come on. Quick.
"Glory to You."
"Glory to Lord Ganesha."
Prateek.
- He'll be fine
Will you save Prateek?
Of course.
I was created to save your son
"Sweetheart."
Promise me
I promise you
I must go
I have to go alone
G. One.
You once asked me if angels existed
Now I know...
...that they do
"Your generosity melts hearts."
I am here, G. One
You are late, G. One.
Any later and...
I have your HART
So you can't kill Prateek
You have my HART so...
...you can't kill me
Unless our HARTS are connected...
...you can't die...
...nor can I
I must log on
I hope it's connected with the LAN.
Give me display control, come on.
But matters of the
heart... very complicated.
For me it's simple
My only purpose is to destroy you
Keep the HART
Logic says: Your chance of
survival is 0.01%
Why choose death?
Because I gave my word
We're connected
Connected now.
- Ra. One loaded. Game ready to play.
Game begins.
- Welcome, Lucifer.
Let's play.
Hide!
You OK?
Sure, I'm fine
But my head is spinning
Fire.
Done!
Look down!
G. One safe. Level two, killer combat.
Good going, G. One.
- This is good going?
The plan is to get to Level 3
Great plan. That's if Ra. One lets us
Survive two minutes more
- What are you doing?
- Getting whipped
Don't fight. Just try to survive
Watch me
See?
No, G. One. Do it my way.
One minute to go.
Use Ra. One's power
Okay.
Yes.
Oh no.
Duck.
Don't fight. Survive
No, no, no, don't.
Energy levels low.
Run!
Grab his main part!
What are you doing, G. One?
I don't know.
Level 2 clear. G. One survives.
G. One safe.
- Yes.
G. One.
You OK?
Never felt better.
I'm in your world now.
We start where we left off
So come on our Lucifer.
My power has decreased.
Ra. One is stronger now
One gun, one bullet, one chance
You can't hide from me.
Or escape me
How will we destroy Ra. One?
Bullets don't win wars. Hearts do
Now my HART...
"Sweetheart."
...will be my strength,
not my weakness
Let's do this, Prateek.
For your father
"Sweetheart."
Anti-heart gun activated.
G. One.
G. One. HART.
You said it'd work
You can't die
G. One terminated.
Game over, Lucifer.
Get ready to die
I am on.
We're ready
To kick your...
- Language, Prateek.
We are ready, to kick your fat ass.
You forget
If we're not connected to
the HART, neither of us...
...can die
Matters of the heart.
Very complicated.
I didn't forget. Lucifer did
He wanted a villain who never loses
You should be careful
what you wish for, kid.
Instead of one villain,
you have ten
Oh no.
- Shoot me.
Find me
Find the real Ra. One
- Which one?
- Never got to Level 3
One real. Nine fakes
Me!
No, me
Impossible
Dad can't let evil win
He'll help us
I have his folder
Check it
His last proverb:
"Sell your soul to the Devil and
evil's shadow won't leave you"
Shadow?
The real Ra. One...
...casts a shadow
The real Ra. One casts a shadow
Shoot.
G. One.
Game over, Prateek. I must go
No, G. One. That wasn't the plan
It was the plan and always will be
If you want the end of Ra. One...
...I must take him back...
...to the world...
...from where we came
G. One, don't leave me
I can't lose my father again
You'll never lose him
If there's goodness in your heart,
he'll never leave you
Good people die...
...but their goodness lives on
Listen to your heart.
Look. Be a superhero, Prateek.
A superhero. With a heart.
Got to go now.
I will miss you, G. One.
- Yes.
I think I will miss you too.
Tell Sonia...
We made a real
buttercup of brother Ra. One
So glad you're back
You OK?
You know I am very happy
that you two returned.
How's Prateek?
Forever logged on,
trying to revive G. One's HART
Just let him be, Sonia.
Don't dash his hopes
It's his belief.
Where is my Lucifer?
Prateek.
- Coming, mom.
I am on.
Mom, G. One's back.
I told you, Mom! He'd come back
He's right here. He's back.
~~~ Subtitle With No Brain ~~~
"Wicked Speed. The destination ahead,
the wind at my back."
"A chilling gale, crosses
your path, it stops you."
"A desire."
"To serve which doesn't cease."
"The fire of obsession."
"That blinds out the light."
"The dawn pierces
through the dark night."
"A new beginning after
defeating the evil."
"Time has... chosen a moment."
"I will leave a mark in history."
"Wicked Speed. The destination ahead,
the wind at my back."
"A chilling gale."
"Crosses your path, it stops you."
"There's no fun when."
"Life isn't on the edge."
"A strong heart."
"Never accepts defeat easily."
"Doing that unimaginable."
"Is the mark of the brave."
"I don't do it for myself."
"I lay my life down for my kin."
"Wicked Speed."
"The destination ahead,
the wind at my back."
"My sizzling siren"
"Where you go, girl,
I am gonna follow."
"What you want,
girl, just let me know."
"My sizzling siren"
"Surely I am gonna get you?
You know I am gonna get you."
"You know I even let
you... let you be my Sizzling Siren."
"Let's see you move."
"Don't be shy"
"Look me in the eye"
"Don't say no"
"My sizzling siren"
"I am your hero"
"Give it to me, girl."
"My sizzling siren"
"Surely I am gonna get you?
You know I am gonna get you."
"You know I even let you...
let you be my Sizzling Siren."
"Let's see you move. Don't be shy"
"Come be mine."
"Look me in the eye"
"Don't say no"
"My sizzling siren"
"Let me show you how to dance."
"You'll be mine if say so."
"Look in my eye."
"I won't say no."
"My sizzling siren"