RAILS
I'll pay tomorrow...
Were you afraid?...
But... why?
Because I love you...
Where are we going?...
Where the others go...
You won't suffer any more, darling...
Honeymoon?
Up already?
You've no idea how long this sport
has been a passion of mine.
There's your sport!
"My dear friend, allow me to send this small gift
to our very own 'Mascot', who won us so much
money last night! ..."
"... We will be expecting you today at 5 for tea.
Yours, Jacques Mercier"
I'll never play with you, not even over
a glass of water. You're too lucky!
Do you love him dearly?
The lady does not feel very well.
You've left me alone all evening.
We've been here for so long...
Why don't we leave?
Leave? And renounce our luck, now?
I don't expect the ring
will be worth very much.
He's still losing...
There must be a misunderstanding!
The gentleman and I play as partners.
We'll split the winnings.
Were we not playing as partners?
In your situation such
touchiness is out of place.
"Kind friend,
Would you please drop by at 11?
I have something that may interest you.
Yours, Mercier"