[THUDDING]
[FEMALE #1]
Go, Kelly!
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ Yeah yeah
♪ When we're together
it's not hard to fly ♪
♪ And the bar
never seems too high ♪
♪ Whoa whoa
♪ Whoa whoa whoa
whoa hoo whoa ♪
♪ In a league of our own
♪ When it seems our dreams
are out of reach ♪
♪ We chase them down
like gravity ♪
♪ Whoa whoa
♪ Whoa whoa whoa
whoa hoo whoa ♪
♪ In a league of our own...
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
[MALE #1]
Another new perfect routine
from Kelly Johnson on the beam.
[FEMALE #2] Traditionally
not even her best apparatus
but she's on fire tonight.
♪ In a league of our own
♪ We're coming back
[CROWD CHEERING]
♪ No no we're coming back
♪ No one can stop us
♪ We're coming back
no one ♪
♪ No one
[MALE #1]
Now, this could be a huge upset.
Kelly Johnson could take
the entire competition.
♪ No one
we're coming back ♪
♪ In a league of our own
♪ No one can stop us...
[MALE #1] Just the
floor routine to go now.
Kelly's best event.
♪ Ho oh oh oh oh
♪ When it came to losing
we were undefeated ♪
♪ Took our chances
failed to pieces ♪
♪ Whoa whoa
♪ Whoa whoa whoa
whoa hoo whoa ♪
♪ In a league of our own
♪ No one was ever there
to help us out ♪
♪ We were always
our own champions ♪
♪ Whoa whoa
♪ Whoa whoa whoa
whoa hoo whoa ♪
♪ In a league of our own ♪
[SIGHS]
Did I mention Adelaide is one of
the most livable cities in the world?
Yeah, you did
three times on the way
to the airport
and then twice on the plane.
Try and go hard again, huh?
Just a little bit.
The beach where we'll be
living looks amazing.
We learn to surf.
I've always wanted
to try surfing.
It's gonna be great
to spend more time with you...
add all the other pressures.
You okay, honey?
Yeah... just like the last
three times you asked.
- You're doing it again.
- I know, I know.
I'm trying too hard.
It's okay. I love you for it.
I'm fine.
I just really wanna get the bags
and get to the apartment.
[FEMALE #3]
It shouldn't be long now.
[MALE #2]
Good news is, we found them.
Bad news is, they weren't
taken off the flight
during stop over and they're on
their way to Melbourne.
The next flight back isn't due
to arrive for a few hours
but I'll personally make sure
that they deliver
to your residence
first thing in the morning.
Hi, welcome to Adelaide.
- Yeah, finally.
- Thank you.
Oh.
Mom, we're in Australia.
They drive
on the other side of the road.
I knew that.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
- Mom, left-hand side!
- Oh!
[KELLY] Whatever you do,
do not hit the kangaroos.
Hey, you missed me.
I'm down under, not vaulting up
and over anymore, so...
[SIGHS]
This is stupid.
Hey, it's Kelly.
You missed me. I'm down under,
so leave a message.
No likes and no friends
nobody expect...
[FEMALE #3]
Kelly?
[SIGHS]
Well, at least
unpacking was easy.
How about we take in
the local sights?
Why not?
It's been a while since
it was just the two of us.
Let's go party.
We could learn to surf.
[IN UNISON] I've always
wanted to try surfing.
[GIGGLING]
[POP SONG PLAYING OVER TABLET]
♪ No need to worry
♪ 'Cause these are
just moments in time ♪
♪ So don't be
in such a hurry ♪♪
You are gonna tighten
your tie, right?
And make a good impression
on your first day.
Yes, Mrs. Johnson.
It's a good school.
You'll make friends in no time.
I'm sure.
Okay. Come on.
Don't wanna be late.
[TURNS OFF MUSIC]
[FEMALE #3]
Jacket.
[FEMALE #3] Notice anything
different about what they're wearing?
Mom, seriously, on my first day?
[LAUGHING]
So you're sure
you don't want me to come in?
Think I'll stick
with the wrong uniform
and skip the mom escort.
Don't wanna use a public
embarrassment on the first day.
I'll be working late
at the hospital.
- You have the bus pass?
- Mom.
Uh, of course you do.
Have a good day, honey.
Like there's any chance
of that happening.
No. Mom, other, other side.
[CAR HONKING]
[SIGHS]
- You must be Kelly.
- Hi.
I'm Ms. Seranty,
deputy principal.
Let's get you
to your first class
and do a quick tour as well.
Uh, yes, ma'am. Thank you.
You know, dear,
that's the wrong uniform.
That's the winter one,
although you just have
come from winter, haven't you?
Yes.
Jessica,
why aren't you in class?
My mum went back to hospital
and I missed the bus.
And I had to finish
copying these fliers.
[SERANTY] Yes, I heard about
your mum. I'm sorry to hear that.
But if you're late, I need you
to be in class straight away
alright? You can do that later.
Please excuse me.
Girls, why aren't you in class?
That's the wrong uniform.
Thanks, I got the memo now.
American? Hm.
Gymnastics. You're... into that?
Yeah. The elite program here.
- Um, your mom not well?
- She's fine.
- Oh, I-I just...
- You were wrong. She's fine.
[SERANTY]
Jess, this is Kelly.
Could you please escort her
to Ms. Matzel's class?
And that will be enough
of that eye-rolling, thanks.
Yeah, and so I got out
of the car...
I turned to wave...
and then I just,
I tripped on the step
my heel caught my skirt.
Oh, it was so embarrassing,
I went down flat on my face.
So it's like...
watching you vault
minus the sprained wrists?
I told you,
that vault was broken!
[FEMALE #4]
Enough, Nic!
Turn around, face the front.
Get your books out, too,
please, Nic.
Now, Nic.
[SCOFFS]
[MALE #3]
You okay, there?
Yeah, I'm fine, just, uh
hanging out... with my bag.
Just relaxing. Getting comfy.
Okay. There are two things.
Great job of convincing me
that's comfy
but it's probably not
and, second,
that's not your bag...
it's mine.
Hm, are you sure?
I mean...
they all look the same.
Pretty sure.
It's got my name on it. See?
Oh, there.
Guess you really like that spot.
Now I've got a problem.
What? I, I, I didn't
take anything.
Good to know,
but that's not the problem.
The problem is you know my name
but I don't know yours.
Oh.
Uh, it's, it's Kelly.
Kelly Johnson.
Dude, where are you?
We're starting.
'Sup?
Well, I should go.
But it was nice
to meet you, Kelly
Kelly Johnson.
It's, it's nice to meet you, too
Scotty, Scotty...
I... don't know you last name.
[PANTING]
Hey, you're the new girl.
You know,
that's the wrong uniform
for this time of year, right?
Yup, I've heard.
I'm Nicola,
but everyone calls me Nic.
Hi, I'm Kelly.
Wait. Say that again.
What? I-I'm Kelly.
You're American!
Oh, I love your accent!
- Say more things.
- What?
Oh, just say more things
so I can hear you talk.
Uh... apple pie?
- Uh... blizzard...
- Oh...
Pillow fight, banana...
- You're funny!
- Thanks.
- Um, this is my first day here.
- Oh, really?
Well, well, where are you from?
Why, why are you here?
Well, how long
have you been here?
Why, why at the gymnastics...
Do you do gymnastics?
- Uh...
- Oh, it's so exciting.
- I'm from Atlanta.
- Mm-hmm.
[KELLY] Uh, I'm here
with my mom for a year.
She's a surgeon
at the City Hospital.
I, I do...
Well, I-I did gymnastics.
Oh, well, um,
if you don't do gymnastics
then... why be here?
Um, I'm just sorta used
to being in a gymnasium
kinda feels like home.
I don't really have
any friends, so...
Well, now you do.
So if you've done
lots of gymnastics before
maybe you could help me out
a bit then, yeah?
- Help you out?
- Yeah.
I wanna get good enough
to make the elite squad.
Well, you looked pretty good
on the trampoline. I mean...
Yeah, well,
until I fell on my face.
Well, my dad
is a gymnastics coach
so I might be able
to help a little bit.
Really, a coach?
Yeah, but let's not
get into that right now.
Okay. Sure.
[POP MUSIC ON CELL PHONE]
Okay, spread your arms.
Like that? Is it better?
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Okay. Ow! Ow!
Have a great day.
Oh, my... That's great.
Anyway, um, so what's the deal
with the other girls
on the team?
I think I met... Jess.
- Jess?
- Yeah.
Jess is basically a jerk.
You know what I mean?
Jess is on a sports scholarship
to Floruit.
She's a year older than us,
finishes school this year
and easily one of
the best gymnasts around here
and sort of the...
queen of her year.
She lives just with her mother
and grandmother
like, this tiny,
little place up north.
Actually, I think
everybody's a bit scared of her.
I mean, I am.
She's very motivated
to win a US
gymnastics scholarship
'cause I think it's her only
chance to go to university.
She won't be able
to afford to go here.
'Cause you're from the US, you
two might have a lot in common.
Not my first impression.
Uh, I don't think she liked me
within the first five seconds
of meeting me.
Yeah, she can be pretty scary
when she wants to be...
which is always.
She works part time
at a fish and chips shop
and I went there once
with my parents.
My dad made me ask her
for some vinegar.
It was so weird.
Oh, and she has a bit of history
with one of the guy gymnasts
Scotty. You perhaps saw him
training at the gym.
Then there's Ashley.
She envies Jess,
like, huge, like...
And is Jess' right-hand girl.
They've been friends
for years, but
really... their frenemies.
Like, Ashley's a good gymnast
but she just doesn't have
Jess' talent
so she can't quite get
to be the head girl
so she has to settle
for the next best.
There's a bit of jealousy there.
Think I know what that's like.
Sam is and ex-rhythmic gymnast
um, stuck with it for years.
She never really quite got
the rhythmic stuff
she just kept dropping the ball
and getting tangled.
Dropping the ball
and getting tangled?
Yeah, literally.
Like, great lines,
flexible, strong
but she couldn't quite grasp
the extra co-ordination needed.
Her coach said
she should try artistic.
Sam's easy-going,
like, always be nice
but she's in Jess' elite little
group nowadays and...
Oddly enough, she's turned into
a really good net baller,
as well.
Netball? What's that?
Oh, it's a way big hit.
It's like basketball
but you don't run with the ball.
Then what do you do with it?
Score goals, of course!
I'll take you to a game
at some stage.
Then there's the boys.
Justin, really good gymnast
doesn't attempt Floruit.
He was in an elite program,
but quit.
He likes performing and singing.
He's pretty good, too.
He juggles doing gym,
singing and acting lessons
and I think he might even be
part of a band. Not sure.
I call him Biebs.
- Why?
- Biebs.
Justin.
- Beiber.
- Oh, right.
Makes sense. Got it.
Uh, what about the other guy?
Uh... Oh, Scotty?
Plays heaps of sports.
He's a Floruit.
Um, he's a little bit
shy for me.
Rich parents, too,
but he's a really nice guy.
Jess and Scotty
had a thing going for a while.
- What?
- Mm.
[NIC]
Yeah, they broke up last year
but I reckon she's still sort of
keen on him though.
But he doesn't like her
anymore, right?
I'm just asking so that I know
the lay of the land
and everything.
You did hear what I said
about Jess, yeah?
And for the record,
she broke it off.
She didn't want
any distractions.
Then there's Luke. He's cool.
Does attempt Floruit.
Um, Luke's brothers and sisters
have all been in gymnastics.
His sister
was an awesome gymnast
but she's overseas
studying now...
- Hello?
- Hi.
Yeah, sorry, here.
Uh, hey, so what's, what's your
story? What are you all about?
Best part, you see, I was a
trampolinist, but I wanted a change.
See, I always wanted
to do artistic gymnastics
but because
I've come into it late
I don't really have the control
like the others.
That's why
I'm in the seconds gym
trying to get
as much training as I can.
Well, that's what
Jess told me to do.
She keeps describing me as,
like, out of control
which, I mean, I just don't get,
like, what does she mean?
Hm.
I can't imagine.
Hey, Kel. So how was your day?
You mean, besides wearing
the wrong uniform all day?
Was it that bad?
[SIGHS]
No.
I'm sorry.
There's just some posts online.
Do you want me to beat up
somebody for you?
It depends. How quickly can you
get to Atlanta and back?
Well, you've that photo
from back home on there?
It's a nice shot.
You used to have
the other picture
with your father
coaching you at the gym
as your background.
Always used to make me
feel a bit jealous
when I saw that picture.
Really?
Yeah. I, I deleted that.
Not happy memories
at the moment.
Listen, Kel.
I know this trial separation
is hard on you...
but coming here is a circuit
breaker for all of us.
We needed it.
Yeah, I know.
I get it.
Maybe you wanna
go back with your dad.
Mom, no.
I wanna be here
with you. Really.
I made a friend today.
Nic.
She's, she's really great.
She's funny. You'll like her.
That's great, honey. I knew
you would make friends quick.
I, uh...
met Nic at the gym.
I-I told her I would
help her out with gymnastics.
Define help out.
Well, I think, I sorta told her
that I'd done
a little bit of gymnastics
and I might have mentioned that
my dad was a gymnastics coach.
So I told her I could...
probably help her out
a little bit.
Alright.
Wait one second.
My championship leotard?
I thought you might be
needing it again.
Thanks, mom.
Okay, what is going on?
Every time you jump up, you have
a different arm movement.
I just go with the flow.
You know, I wanna
add to the move, you know?
I don't wanna be stuck
with a rod up my back.
I wanna be free.
Women's artistic gymnastics.
Free?
I mean, I mean, this whole sport
is about precision
doing the same move,
the same way, the right way
every single time.
You've gotta get serious.
You seem serious enough
for the both of us
and the rest of Floruit.
- I have to work on that.
- Okay.
How about you just watch me
for one second?
- Okay?
- Okay. Yeah.
Alright.
- Just do exactly what I do.
- Yeah.
Wow, you are good!
Alright, now at the end
of your move
try finishing it off nicely.
Present yourself.
- Oh!
- Oh! I am so sorry.
Well, I should've been watching
for spinning students.
So do you gym?
Uh, yeah, I, I do.
- I mean, I, I used to.
- Her dad's a coach.
Well, I might see you
on the floor, then.
Or maybe you won't see her
and she will
knock you down again.
- Thanks, Nic.
- Shh, don't distract me.
I'm practicing.
♪ Ah ah
♪ Ah-ah ah ah ah
♪ Ah ah...
Guys.
♪ Ah-ah ah ah ah ♪
Hey.
Um, we're gonna have
a little mini comp
against the boys
and Jess isn't in our training.
So how about joining?
- Where's Jess?
- Oh.
Family or work sort of thing.
- Sounds fun?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- Go.
No, not you, just Kelly.
What?
We need one extra. Just you.
I don't think so.
I think I'll pass.
No, no, no. You go, Kelly.
Yeah, you show them.
I mean, you really show them.
Let's go.
Go, Ash.
Whoo! Go, Kelly!
[ALL CHEERING]
Go, Kelly! Oh, my God!
You're amazing! You go, girl.
Okay.
And the scores are
girls, 72.5
thanks to Kelly's 14
on her buzz.
Pretty good for someone
not competing, I might add.
Boys, 76.
- Yeah!
- Come on!
Super impressive, Kelly.
I'd like to have you
on the team. You interested?
Thank you, I really
appreciate the offer
but I'm not looking
to compete right now.
Are you sure?
Y-you have so much talent...
I'm sure.
Nic is really desperate
to join the team, though.
I mean, she would benefit
from the better training
and working
with the other girls.
Well, Nic has improved a lot
but I don't think
she's quite ready
for a competition just yet.
Besides, Jess doesn't
want her in the team.
Jess? What does she have...
- Hey, great moves on the bar.
- Thank you.
I'm a little bit
out of practice, though.
If that's your out of practice,
I'd like to see you in practice.
Come on, man.
Is that your best lines?
Luke, you got
that brown paper bag?
Might need it.
I keep forgetting
I need to get new friends.
- I like you accent.
- It's Canadian, yeah?
No, the mighty US of A.
- Thank you very much.
- Told you, didn't I?
Ah, US. I love the US.
What part of States you from?
- Georgia.
- Hm.
- Hey, mom?
- Mm-hmm?
Do you remember Megan
from the US team?
[SARAH] That girl who laughed
that time the uneven bars collapsed.
Yup, I remember.
She was a tough competitor.
Never got the feeling she was
much of a friend, though.
- Why?
- It doesn't matter.
What about Sophie and Elorie?
[SARAH]
They are great gymnasts.
Really nice girls.
I thought they were friends,
as well, aren't they?
I always liked them.
[KELLY]
Yeah, me, too.
Not so sure.
Mel just messaged.
We're officially entered
into the National Teams comp
in Melbourne!
[CHEERING]
You know, I sort of miss
the high of competing.
Yeah. I'd just like
to try it once and find out.
[KELLY]
Yeah.
So, um...
how are you gonna
pay for the trip?
Well, that's why
I've been working
and missing a few sessions.
I was not gonna miss this.
[POP MUSIC]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Kelly. Did you hear?
We're going
to the team Nationals.
Oh, yeah. Congratulations.
You guys must be really excited.
Well, you know how these
teams events work, right?
With only the top three scores
counted on each apparatus
it would really help
to have a fourth team member
to help drop our lower scores.
I'd really like you
on the team, Kelly.
Look, I, I really
appreciate the offer
but I'm just not looking
to compete right now.
But if you need
an extra team member
I don't see why Nic
can't join the team, right?
Nic is just not up to it.
W-what do you mean?
Have you even seen her lately?
Uh, she's improved
by leaps and bounds
like...
literal leaps and bounds.
No, I've not really
seen her lately
but Jess says she's not really
up to a National Team comp.
We need to strengthen the team,
not add a weak member.
Nic has been working so hard.
I think with just
a little bit of extra training
she could really get
to that next level...
Listen, if you change your mind,
please let me know.
You really shouldn't let
a talent like yours go to waste.
[KELLY]
I just don't get this control
that Jess has over
the rest of the team
and Coach Mel.
You literally can't hurt
the team's scores
and they're still
not letting you in.
I'm just not good enough
for the team yet.
I mean, I get it from Mel's side
because it's a really big do
here to coach to go
who gets
the US gymnastics scholarship.
So she's not gonna get
Jess offside.
Don't stress about it so much!
You need to learn
to relax a little.
Hm.
Hey, remember, when I said
I'd take you to a netball game?
Is that the basketball thing
where you can't
run with the basketball?
The netball.
How about coming
to the girls versus boys?
I don't know.
I'm okay. Thanks.
I guess Scotty would just
have to be disappointed.
- Yeah, now you wanna come.
- Okay, fine.
♪ One two three four...
Here!
♪ Kick it up
♪ Go go go go
♪ Kick it up...
Ah!
I'm over this.
Let's go. Come on.
♪ Go go go go ♪
Yup, yup.
[GROANS]
[SAM]
Oh, my knee!
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[ASHLEY]
Oh, Sam!
[GASPS]
You okay?
What happened?
ACL complete tear.
I'll need a recon.
I'm out for twelve months!
Twelve months? Perfect.
That stuffs us up.
[MEL]
Jess!
I mean,
it's tragic for you and for us.
You'll be back, though.
What about Nationals?
Um, no offence, but...
Well, Nic is ready in cane.
I'll have another look
at how she's going.
Nic? Not a chance.
Psycho girl,
she'll only weaken the team.
What about Kelly?
I mean, she honestly
is an awesome gymnast.
- Kelly?
- Yeah.
Who says she's any good?
[IN UNISON]
We do.
Kelly?
Alright.
I guess we need
a third member...
only if she's better than Nic.
Well, I've already tried
to get Kelly to join us.
It might be better
if one of you girls ask her
a bit of peer pressure.
What? You've already asked her?
Jess, she's good.
Like, really good.
She'd be good for the team.
Might even give you
some competition.
I reckon you ask her, Jess
because she'd respect you
the most.
It would just work.
[GROANS]
Uh!
Alright. Fine.
Looked really bad to me.
ACL, I guess.
- That's terrible for Sam.
- I know.
Those injuries take forever
to recover from.
You know what this might mean?
Um, she'll have to have
a reconstruction?
No! Well...
Yes, but something else.
They're a team member short
for Nationals.
- They'll have to ask you!
- Oh, yeah!
Oh, that'd be awesome
but still, like,
terrible for Sam
but I'd love to make the team!
I think you're about to.
- Hey, Sam, how are you?
- Hey.
Yeah, um, not so good.
I've... done my ACL,
so I need a reconstruction.
That's awful, Sam.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah, me, too. You were doing
amazing in the game.
Yeah, well,
looks like that's over
maybe forever.
Hey, you know, I used to compete
against a girl who blew her ACL.
When she came back,
she kicked my butt on beam.
- Really?
- Really.
Okay, enough with story time.
Obviously, we need another
member for Nationals, so...
Kelly, you can join us.
What? You must be joking.
What about Nic?
No, I'm offering...
We are offering
Sam's spot to you.
No way! Nic is perfect!
She's improved a ton!
Ton. What's a ton?
We aren't even
talking about Nic.
Are you saying
you're not joining?
Look, I really appreciate
the offer
but like I told
Coach Mel already
I'm taking a break.
Nic is perfect.
You need a third team member.
- Don't be so stuck up!
- Me?
No, not having this.
You don't have to
worry about it. It's fine.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
- Hey!
- Are you okay?
I'm fine.
[NIC]
Are you sure?
Because I'm stalking you
online right now
and I just read some posts.
Who are Sophie and Elorie?
I mean...
And who is this Megan
and what's her deal?
Hm. Megan.
Well... nothing really
surprises me from her.
She's my old gym rival...
kind of like the Jess
of the United States
but without the warm charm.
But Sophie and Elorie, I mean
I thought
they were my friends...
especially Sophie,
I just thought she understood.
- Understood what?
- Forget it. It doesn't matter.
[KELLY] I mean, none
of it's true, anyway.
But with Megan
my dad didn't select her
for the State team.
She had too much attitude,
thought she knew it all.
So she moved to another state
and... now she hates
my dad and me.
And then a bunch
of stuff happened
and then I moved to Australia
and apparently all my friends
think I'm terrible.
[NIC] I've seen you in
action. You are awesome!
Okay? Anyway, it doesn't matter.
Sam just told me that Ashley
has some friend of hers
joining the team.
She's tried in some other club
and probably
she's pretty good, too.
It's a pity, I...
I would've liked
to have gone to Nationals.
I might quit I think.
There's no point.
What? No! Don't do that!
We have done so much
and you have come so far!
Nic, you're gonna show everyone.
We both are.
Wha-what?
[KELLY]
Is this National Team comp
the same one
that qualifies teams
for the Australian Invitational?
Yeah, the top four or five teams
stand to compete
in the Invitational
the next day I think.
Okay, don't quit.
Meet me at the gym tomorrow.
I've a plan.
What are you two doing here?
The old [INDISTINCT] gym's
at the back.
And yet here you are.
- What are you...
- Save it, Jess.
I've got an offer for the team.
We're not interested.
Do you wanna
go to Nationals or not?
Oh, haven't you heard?
We are going.
Well, you wanna catch
the judge's attention, right?
Impress to get a US scholarship?
I'll compete with you.
Together, the team will have
a better chance of doing well...
but the only thing is
Nic is in, too, if I join.
- Wait, what?
- Still not interested.
What makes you think
we can do better with you?
Jess, Kelly could score
really well.
It could get us
to the top of the club teams.
How does that help me?
Look, I'm not interested
in a scholarship
but the team going to top ten
or even top five
will get attention for you.
I've been competing in big comps
since I learned how to walk.
The girls say you're the best.
So we'll have a one-on-one
apparatus comp...
you and me.
Any apparatus you choose.
If I win...
Nic and I are in.
And if we lose... we're out.
Go on, Jess. Nothing to lose.
You'll smash her.
What? No way!
Kelly is... in real trouble.
Are you sure
you wanna do this, Kelly?
Yes.
Alright.
You're on!
Buzz.
But if I win
and I decide
you're good enough...
you join the team...
without Nic.
Yes, come on, Jess. Let's go!
Smash it out, Jess.
Kip to the high bar
cast a handstand
giant, giant dismount.
Kelly is doing Jess' routine...
except it's perfect.
Ooh, my God!
Kelly, that was amazing,
amazing!
Why?
[MEL]
Okay, Jess
excellent score as per usual
37.5...
[APPLAUDING]
but, Kelly, 43.
Kelly and Nic,
you're on the team!
Oh, my God! Yay! Yay!
Wow!
Hate to admit it,
but impressive, Kelly.
[KEYBOARD KEYS CLACKING]
No way are you doing that
to me, girl.
Well, what have you been up to?
Just working with Mel
before and after practice.
Haven't been trained
in a while, gotta catch up.
Catch up to who? You're
the best girl on the team.
- Ten more seconds, girls.
- Let's go thirty.
- What?
I'm dying here.
You wanted to be here.
Ah, it burns!
[MEL]
Okay, relax.
Thirty seconds relax
and we go again?
What's with the whip, Kelly?
No pain, no gain.
No, seriously,
you're smashing us, mate.
It's all I know.
Either all in or not at all.
[NIC]
Where did that come from?
[KELLY]
My dad, I guess.
It's either
total commitment or nothing.
Let's go again?
[MEL]
Okay.
Ready...
and go.
Nic, what is with the arms?
We talked about this.
Yeah, well, I just wanna be free
show some of my own style.
This is not freestyle dance
this is a major competition!
- Focus!
- Girls, you are too serious.
[MEL]
Relax.
Start the music!
[POP MUSIC ON STEREO]
Look at her.
She's gonna drag us all down.
Never been to Melbourne
but I think
my luggage went there.
That's about as close I've got
to visiting so far, but...
- What's it like?
- Oh, much bigger than Adelaide.
Um, there's this...
How about we just focus
on winning comps, okay?
Some of us actually
want to do well.
So maybe you could focus
on the competitions
and not on everything else.
Chill, Jess.
We all wanna do well. We're all
focused and working hard.
Well, I hope so
because there's no way
I'm letting any dead weight
anchor us down in competitions.
You know what I mean?
Um, has she read
what I'm thinking she's read?
Their pages are public.
You read them, remember?
Well, who cares?
She's just being mean.
No, don't let her
get you down, Kel.
You're the best gymnast
I've ever seen.
- You're gonna do great!
- We both are.
You know,
you might be disappointed
in your new best friend
once competition starts.
She's not all
she's cracked up to be.
Kelly? She's not my best friend.
Wait, what do you mean?
Just remember
you heard it here first.
We'll see when comps start
who has what it takes.
[NIC] Hey, Ash, you
forgot to mention
it's either raining
or about to rain in Melbourne
all the time.
Expecting to see
Bella and Edward.
Do you wanna see how many chips
I can fit in my mouth?
No, not really.
[SCOTTY] Good, it's
actually not that many.
I would've embarrassed myself.
Now you should be embarrassed.
You made me.
- Well...
- I'll be back.
Come back
when you learn some manners.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Yeah.
Look.
You've managed to worm
your way onto the team
and bring your weirdo,
little friend along, too.
But guess what, I've been doing
a bit of reading about you.
Yeah, I've noticed.
You're a lot of things, Jess,
but subtle isn't one of them.
It's true, isn't it?
You lose it
when it comes to competitions?
Okay, you don't know anything
about what happened.
That stuff you saw online
was just some jealous girl!
Not the first one...
and apparently, not the last.
I don't care what you do
on your own time, Kelly
but you had better not tank this
competition, not this time.
- Jess, it's just a sport!
- No, it's not!
It might be just a sport to you
but I've been working
my whole life
for an opportunity like this.
I haven't had everything
handed to me by my daddy.
I've earned this.
Don't you dare mess it up.
I haven't had anything
handed to me...
Oh, Kelly, I really don't care.
I just don't want my future
being dragged down
by another dead weight
anchor performance by you.
You've got it?
[INTENSE MUSIC]
[SNIFFLES]
Hey, Kel...
She-she was with Jess.
What did you say to her?
Just some home truths.
What are you thinking?
We start our comps
tomorrow, Jess.
It's a team competition,
it's not just all about you.
The team does bad, you do bad.
Just get over yourself!
Hey!
What happened back there?
Nothing.
I just...
What if Jess is right?
Right about what?
This is my first competition
on my own
without my dad.
This is my chance
to show everyone
that I'm good enough
to make it on my own
without any sort
of special treatment
but what if I'm not?
What if I just
drag the team down?
What are you talking about?
You're the best gymnast
on the team.
You're just
saying that because...
Because it's true!
But it doesn't matter
how much I believe in you
you gotta believe in yourself.
I'm sorry, I, I have to go.
Hello and welcome
to day three of the competition
to beautiful Melbourne where...
- Kelly, can I talk to you...
- Not now.
- I just don't want you to...
- Jess.
I'm trying to focus
on the competition.
I don't need you
in my head right now.
- Yeah, but that's...
- Don't worry.
I'll be doing my very best...
regardless of what you think.
[MALE #4] So over the next
few days we'll see who qualifies
for the annual Australian
International Invitational.
The Invitational which always
follows the club competition
where only the best and
in-form
Australian competitors qualify.
[FEMALE #5]
That's right, Dave.
The first international
competition of the year
which always attracts
the up-and-coming gymnasts
from Australia and overseas.
There are strong club teams
again this year
but we haven't had
a club team qualify
in the top five for years!
[CROWD CHEERING]
What were you saying
about the dead weight?
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
[FEMALE #5]
Beautiful routine from Kelly.
Will she try and pull out
a big move in this last part?
[FEMALE #5]
No, it's just a front layout
and she struggled
on the landing base.
[MALE #4] Still having a hard
time with that final pass, Michelle.
But we've seen some great
gymnastics from Kelly today.
And it's great to see her
back in competition.
[MICHELLE]
Will you look at that.
That is amazing.
The Aerial club team...
Wait, we might qualify
for the Invitationals?
[MICHELLE]
A real nail-biter.
And all the more tense because
of that last-minute mistake
from Kelly Johnson
that might be...
Aren't you gonna say,
"I told you so?"
I didn't come here to be right,
I came here to win.
[DAVE] The scores will now
be totaled and we'll see...
Good work, though.
[MICHELLE] The scores
are coming through now.
[DAVE] First to qualify, as
expected, the young Aussie Starlets.
Next is
the New South Wales team.
Victoria are third.
Queensland team are in, too.
Aerial have been brave
in their performance.
That's amazing,
the Aerial club team
have qualified
for the Invitationals.
[MICHELLE] That's the
first time in years, Dave
a club team has qualified.
Congratulations to Aerial
and all the qualifying teams.
Oh, my God!
[DAVE]
That sets up some fantastic
competition
for the Invitational.
We'll see Kelly Johnson
back competing
in a big competition again.
Look forward to that.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
- Um, congratulations.
- Oh, thank you.
- It was nice.
- Thanks.
Good work.
Oh, awesome result,
each of you...
Oh, uh, mom's here.
Sorry, g-gotta go.
Uh, talk later?
Weird.
- Oh, you stink.
- Seriously?
No, man. You're alright.
Hey, what was
with the handshake?
Did she say something?
- I said "awesome result."
- Oh, mate, that would do it.
Maybe you should play
hard to get.
Okay, so I just got
a list of the teams
we will be competing against.
Uh, the Aussie teams
which qualified of course.
Plus... France, UK
Germany, New Zealand
and the United states.
Well... we've done, like,
huge just to get here.
- Yeah.
- So...
It doesn't really matter
what happens.
- Yeah.
- What?
Why do you sound like
you're giving up?
Just because they're
international gymnasts?
They're just like us.
Ashley, I have never seen you
look that amazing
on the beam before
and, Nic,
this is your first competition
and you advanced.
I mean, we're only point two
behind the best Australian team.
We're gonna do
even better tomorrow.
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
Is it just me or did it suddenly
get all inspirational in here?
[CHUCKLES]
Well, you're really determined.
It's more bravado
than confidence, trust me.
I think it worked.
Well, I mean, I guess
I'm still a little nervous about
competing against Megan
and my old team
but this is my chance
to show them
that they're wrong about me.
And that's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
This is a different
story from last night.
What changed?
Well, a little pep talk
with a friend.
He told me to believe in myself
so... I'm trying it out.
Well, this friend of yours
he sounds really... awesome
and, uh, handsome.
- Hm, no, he's not.
- Hey.
Which one is Megan?
You can tell by the dagger
shooting out of her eyes
into the back of my head.
[CHUCKLES]
You taught her well, Kelly.
Megan, you've been warned.
Now, cut it out.
- What?
- Hey.
Wait, what?
I guess she really appreciates
him telling her to cut it out.
W-w-what are you doing here?
I didn't know you were coming.
Well, I could say the same
for you.
Yeah, last minute replacement
for Tara.
She couldn't be here
till Saturday night
so they asked me to step in.
Sorry, I didn't get
a chance to tell you
I-I thought I'd call
and surprise you
while I was down under.
Uh, guys, this is my dad, Pete.
This is Coach Mel, Nic,
Jess and Ashley.
My Aerial gym team.
Delighted to meet you all.
I didn't know
you were competing.
"Aerial."
You guys qualified
for International.
Hey, congrats.
That's my girl.
Well, we're about done.
So the floor and the equipment's
all yours.
Uh, but you must wanna
catch up with Kel.
Uh, you know, actually,
I'll just, uh
I think I'll go back...
with you guys.
Are you sure?
I can drop you off
at the hotel, Kels.
Why don't you stay?
We can catch up.
I-I don't wanna distract
you guys from practice.
Team comes first, yeah.
We can catch up later
after training then.
Okay. You guys ready?
Alright, bye.
Good luck tomorrow, anchor.
Oh, sorry, did I say "Anchor?"
I meant dead weight
daddy's girl.
See you on the floor.
Jess, it's okay.
What is she going on about?
That's Megan.
We used to compete
together back home.
My last two comps
weren't that good
so she always liked to blame me
for the team's poor results.
Even though she always
seems to forget
that if she hadn't
stepped out of bounds so much
we still would've placed.
Sorry to mention it, but...
it looked weird
with your dad back there.
Yeah, I actually didn't tell him
I was doing gymnastics again.
Why?
Um, he always used to push me
to try new things
in competitions
that I wasn't really ready for.
It was a really big issue
between him and my mom.
She thought that he was putting
too much pressure on me.
He thought she wasn't pushing me
to my full potential.
And they fought about it
all the time.
And then, eventually, when I
blew really big tumbling pass
in my last competition,
they had a huge fight.
And... the next week
they told me
they were separating.
[ASHLEY]
Oh, God.
So... I don't know
I just didn't really
wanna open it back up again.
And besides, I wanna prove that
I can do this without him.
And show Megan and everyone
that I deserve
that spot on the team
and that it wasn't
just favoritism.
But I guess,
it's just sort of awkward now.
Well, the good thing is,
you did it.
You showed them.
We wouldn't have even qualified
for the Invitational
without your performance.
Um, and your awesome waltz,
Jess.
I mean, you've got so much air
I thought you were
gonna fly in the stands.
You know what, guys?
I don't even care
what this Megan thinks.
Alright? We're all going
to smash it out tomorrow.
We'll make her regret ever
taking a trip down under.
[CHUCKLES]
I thought she did really well.
- Kelly.
- Yeah, I guess she looked okay.
I mean, she did alright
in that stupid club comp
but she'll freak out like before
and tank it
in the big comp tomorrow.
Trust me, I mean, she just
doesn't have what it takes
and it'll be like last year
all over again.
Well, she was going through
a lot back then.
She's just not tough enough.
I mean, daddy can't
save her this time
and she'll crash and burn.
I'm calling it.
Kelly did confide in me
how hard it was for her
in those final comps
before she quit.
Her parents were fighting
all the time.
She couldn't focus.
With her dad as coach,
the pressure on her
must've been huge.
I mean, I feel really
sorry for her now.
She did awesome yesterday.
Just our luck to get caught
in a cross fight
between Kelly and Megan.
If we lose to a club team,
even if Kelly is in it
we'll be a complete
laughing stock.
[SNIFFLES]
[SOBS]
[SARAH]
Kel?
Kelly, honey, what's wrong?
I don't think this
was a good idea.
What, the competition?
The competition,
competing without dad
Megan, all of it.
Isn't this what you wanted?
To win without your dad?
Mom, dad's here.
Your father's here?
He said he was a last-minute
replacement for Tara.
I saw him today.
I had no idea what to say.
It was so weird.
I just wanted to help Nic
get on the team before she quit
and then,
with Megan pushing my buttons
I just thought I could
prove something to myself
and... to dad, too.
Isn't that what you're doing?
Mom, I just, I just feel
the pressure of it all now.
Especially with dad here,
it's just, it's just so wrong.
Honey, I-I know you're upset.
But what feels so wrong?
I know it was my fault
you and dad separated.
What? What?
Is that what you think?
Dad was mad because
I was messing up.
And then you were mad
because he was mad.
All because...
I couldn't do the moves
that I should've been
able to do.
So I thought if I quit,
you and dad would stop fighting
and now I'm back to competing.
Kelly, Kelly,
honey, listen to me.
What happened between your
father and me is not your fault.
We were fighting
about everything.
Not just you
and the competitions.
Look at me.
With the pressure at my job
and the pressure on your dad
to win the competitions
we just lost sight
of each other.
It was not because of you.
What you've just achieved
here is amazing.
To come back, to compete
after all that time away
and with barely any time
to prepare.
And you did it on your own.
On your own terms.
I'm so proud of you, honey.
And I know your dad
will be, too.
You need to make decisions
that are right for you.
Not for me and not for your dad.
It's right for you.
Honey.
[SNIFFLES]
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
This is Jordyn Wieber,
reporting live
from the Australian
Invitational.
The Australian Invitational
is always scheduled outside
of the main competition season.
To let the young,
up-and-coming gymnasts to have
their first taste
at International competition.
[CHEERING]
I'm here with Lauren Bell,
whose sister Sophie
is competing
with the US team here.
Are you excited to be here
with your sister?
[LAUREN]
I'm so excited.
I can't wait to compete
here one day, too.
He's cute.
Did your daddy
help you get him, too?
You know what, Megan?
I used to think
if I was good enough
if I won enough comps,
you would like me
and we could be friends.
But you know what I realized?
That you're not good enough?
No. That I just don't care.
You might be a good gymnast
but you're not a good person.
At least I'm a good gymnast.
You can't even say that.
We'll see what the scores are
at the end of the day.
Yeah, you can check out my site.
I'll post some photos
of me and my gold medal.
You can touch the screen.
That's the closest
you're gonna get to one.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[IN UNISON]
Three, two, one, Aerial!
[MALE #5]
Welcome the team
from the United States
of America.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Put your hands together
our team,
all the way from France.
[CHEERING]
Please welcome our team
from Germany!
[CHEERING]
Please match
your first apparatus
and present yourselves
to the judges.
[DAVE] That's the
presentation out of the way.
Now the competition.
And this will be
a fascinating competition
to watch.
The small time Aerial team
with ex-American
junior champion Kelly Johnson
on the same rotation
as the American team
with some of her
former teammates.
[MICHELLE] As this is a teams
event, they'll have to put up
three outstanding
gymnastic routines
on each on each apparatus.
We saw Jess Watkins score
very well yesterday.
There are college scouts
out here
and they'll be
watching her today.
We also saw good performances
from both Nicola Mathews
and Ashley Bryant.
[DAVE] Of course, Kelly had
that final floor-routine disaster
with her father coaching her
in the US Junior Nationals
last season.
And with that big stumble
yesterday...
[MICHELLE]
The stakes are high.
All these girls are looking
to impress to be included
to make the final training team
for the Olympics.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Beautiful, alright.
[MICHELLE] An elegant vault
from Megan McCormack.
That's enough to put her
in the lead
with Kelly Johnson up next.
These girls are on fire today.
Just a few moments ago,
we saw Megan edge out
Kelly's score on the beam.
Let's see if Kelly
can get that lead back.
[MICHELLE] Wow, that was
beautiful. Fantastic vault.
[DAVE]
Yeah, that'll do it, Michelle.
Definitely good enough
to outscore Megan in the vault.
[MICHELLE] The competition
here today is intense.
These battle between
Kelly and Megan
is setting the standard
for every gymnast who follows.
They're laying down a benchmark
and everyone is trying
to keep up with them.
It's exhilarating.
No one wants to lose
to the small time club Aerial
but these girls
are so focused on making
every step a winner.
[DAVE] The teams are just making
their last rotational change now
which brings Team USA
and Aerial onto the floor
to finish the competition.
- Whoo!
- Come on.
Ashley Bryant from Aerial
put in a great routine
yesterday.
Her teammates will be hoping
she nails it again today.
[MICHELLE] Oh, no!
Ashley's had a big fall.
She'll struggle
to recover from that.
Some nice moves from Ashley
but another stumble
on the landing.
[SOBBING]
I'm so sorry.
It's not so bad, girls.
Jess's routine and score
was awesome.
That keeps us in touch
with the podium finish
and the Americans.
[DAVE]
Michelle, we've seen the floor
it's not Nicola's best event.
She's gonna have to be
at the top of her game
if she wants to keep Aerial
in contention here.
[SIGHS]
So, no pressure.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Run up and fly away.
[MICHELLE] But remember,
only the top three scores count.
Okay, you know
what your problem is?
No, what? Tell me.
Remember everything I told you
about taking it seriously?
Yeah.
- Forget it.
- What?
You've already done the part,
you've taken it seriously.
You've put in the work.
It's time to relax
and have a little fun.
This is your first
real competition, Nic, enjoy it.
- You'll do great.
- Okay.
[MICHELLE] Aerial can still medal
if Nicola and Kelly do well here.
Come on, Nic!
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
♪ I can feel it
[DAVE]
This is much more consistent
than what we saw
in the club competition.
[MICHELLE] She adding her
own unique twist to the routine.
If she keeps this up
Aerial will be
in a great position.
♪ Feel it feel it
feel it feel it ♪
feel it feel it ♪♪
[CROWD CHEERING]
[DAVE] Outstanding
performance from Nicola.
That's just what Aerial needed.
A great score from her.
Nic, Nic, Nic, Nic.
That was amazing.
I-I-I've never ever ever ever
seen you do some...
Did you have fun or what?
Oh, it was, it was awesome.
I-I can't...
- Good routine, Nic.
- What was that?
I'm... proud of you.
[YELLS]
over and...
All the red flags are up
apart from the floor.
So these two routines will be
the last for the competition.
[DAVE]
The scores close here.
The Americans
are comfortably in front
with just Megan McCormack
perform.
One mistake, though,
could change everything.
[MICHELLE] Dave, I feel
certain Megan will put in a
very conservative routine
here to play it safe
and protect her
and the team's lead.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
[APPLAUSE]
[DAVE] Megan would
recall Kelly's fall on the floor
on their last competition
costing her team gold
or any chance of the medal.
[MICHELLE] Even her final pass
is just a very clean front sault.
The American's definitely
taking no risks here.
[APPLAUSE]
[DAVE] Megan and
her team will feel certain
Kelly won't be
able to come up with anything
to threaten their lead.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[MICHELLE]
Huge pressure on Kelly now.
To try and get Aerial
back in to medal contention.
Whoo!
Come on, Kelly!
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[MICHELLE] A beautiful start
with the compulsories, Dave.
She knows what she has to do
here and she's...
Oh, no.
[DAVE] Oh, that's a
heart-breaker, Michelle.
To lose points
on a simple move like that.
[MICHELLE] I think she just cost her
team any chance of a medal, Dave.
She just has a final
tumbling pass left.
I don't think that will
earn her enough points
to make up for that error.
Come on.
[APPLAUSE]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[DAVE]
Wow, oh, wow!
That was beautiful. Amazing.
[MICHELLE]
A double Arabian!
That skill is worth an extra
half a point on her score.
This wasn't a planned part
of the routine.
A double Arabian,
that's a half twist
with a double front somersault.
[DAVE] She must have
added it to make up
for that error, Michelle.
This was the move that cost
Kelly's team the gold last year.
And this year,
it may be just what wins it
for her and the team.
Michelle, just waiting
on the final places.
Aerial has won silver!
The small Aerial club
have taken the silver.
Silver? We took silver?
It's not gold.
We weren't even supposed
to be good enough
to get into the Invitationals.
We just medaled!
[YELLING]
[MICHELLE] Aerial with
Kelly's stunning performance
have taken the silver
by the smallest of margins.
Incredible!
Hey, what's with that look?
She just took gold.
Look at the individual
leader points.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[YELLING]
Good work, Kel.
Glad we had that pep talk
about being an anchor.
Oh, you call that a pep talk?
It worked, didn't it?
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
Hey, what's going on?
Uh, somebody might have
mentioned to the US coaches
that their star gymnast
was a cyber bully.
I hear there's a pretty strict
policy on that sort of thing.
[CHUCKLING]
[DAVE] That includes
the medal presentation.
Congratulations
to all the girls.
[YELLING]
♪ No one can stop us
♪ ...Uh oh
♪ We're coming back
♪ No no
♪ No one can stop us ♪
Finishing with
a double Arabian, wow.
I know, I convinced
Coach Mel to help me with it
before and after practice,
but I can't believe I did it.
That's so cool.
Oh, I'm super proud
of you, honey.
I think somebody else
wants to talk to you.
Okay, hold this.
Stop.
Girl so can work him out.
It's fine.
You don't have to say it.
Say what?
You were right, Scotty.
I just had to believe
in myself, Scotty.
Go on a date with me, Scotty.
[CHUCKLES]
Okay.
- He's asking her out.
- Wait.
- Okay, what?
- Okay.
I'll go on a date with you.
Saturday night,
dinner and a movie.
- Wear something nice.
- Oh, so cute.
That went well.
[CHUCKLES]
- He's really nice.
- Thank you.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Kelly.
Dad, Tara, hey.
Tara wanted to speak to you
and Jess actually
before she flies out.
Jess... nice to meet you.
I was very impressed
with your performance today.
- You're a senior, right?
- Yeah, yep.
Now I don't know if Kelly
told you or not
but I am the head coach
at California State College.
And I would like to offer you...
a full scholarship
for next year.
[SCREAMING]
Are you interested?
[YELLS]
Oh... Okay.
[LAUGHS]
I think you could
take that as a yes.
Hmm.
Now, Kelly...
Look, I want you
to come back to the States.
And-and join our team training
for the Olympics.
You have a real shot at it.
What do you say? Hm?
[KELLY]
Dad.
Kels, what's up?
Did you get Tara to ask me?
Oh, well, Tara asked me
if I thought
you were up to coming back,
and I said yes.
But it's Tara
who wants you on the team.
With you as assistant coach?
Well, that's the plan.
This has been what you've been
working towards all your life.
This is your dream.
No... it's not.
Dad, I love gymnastics...
and I love you
but... not together.
What do you mean?
I don't want a dad
who is a tutor or a coach.
I just want a dad who's a dad.
But this is the Olympics.
It's your dream.
No, dad, it's not.
But... this is what you said
you've always wanted.
Yeah, and it was,
but it's not... now.
And it hasn't been for a while.
And if you would've have been
my dad and not my coach
you would've noticed that.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Kelly, now, I only want
what's best for you.
So if this isn't what you want,
then that's okay.
I've been concentrating
on being a coach.
You know, chasing the dream.
I think I've forgotten
how to be a dad and a husband.
I don't wanna be
without you or your mom.
So are we okay?
We're better than okay.
What about your mom?
You think she might be up to
talking to me again?
That might take
a little more work.
But if I've learned anything
from my gymnastics coach
it's that if you love something
it's worth the work.
You know, now with Jess gone,
that'd make you head girl.
- It could be alright.
- Yeah.
So what happened?
Um, well, she sort of offered me
a shot at the Olympics
to go back
and train with the team.
That's awesome.
Kel, you're not gonna go,
are you?
Are you mad that I'm not going?
Of course not.
But are you sure
this is what you want?
This is a huge opportunity,
Kelly.
You worked so hard for it.
I just feel like I found myself.
I have nothing to prove.
I just want some time for me.
And I wanna have
a mom and dad again.
Oh, Kelly.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
- Hi, I'm Scotty.
- Okay.
[KELLY]
Good day, you missed me.
Havin' a ball down under.
Leave a message.
♪ When you're out there
and they all stare ♪
♪ Acting like they don't care
♪ If you make it
if you break it ♪
♪ Throw it to the moon
♪ You feel your heart beating
♪ At the speed of light
♪ Ready
♪ Set
♪ Just fall
♪ Just thinking flipping
♪ Go on and double twist it
♪ From the top bring it on
♪ Go for the goal to go home
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪
♪ Never fading
when the lights go out ♪
♪ Out
♪ I feel your thunder
♪ Put it in a jar
hide it somewhere far ♪
♪ So you'll never rediscover
♪ The beat of your own drum
♪ Just remember it's your drum
♪ They can't feel it
so don't roll ♪
♪ Just thinking flipping
♪ Go on and double twist it
♪ From the top bring it on
♪ Go for the goal to go home
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪
♪ Never fading
when the lights go out ♪
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪
♪ Never fading
when the lights go out out ♪
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪
♪ Never fading
when the lights go out out ♪
♪ All that you hear
♪ All the voices telling
you you can't ♪
♪ See you got your wings
♪ Show them while you can
♪ Oh we're unbreakable
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪
♪ Never fading
when the lights go out ♪
♪ Out
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪
♪ Never fading
when the lights go out ♪
♪ Out
♪ We are unbreakable
♪ In it to win it
in it to win it ♪♪