After the disasters,
it was as if life itself, it already stopped.
Everything burned.
Afterwards,
nothing seemed to grow again.
Nothing.
The cities died.
People looted them and ran to the sea.
But the seas had died too.
Empty...
And then, it rained again.
But the land and the people were still barren.
People died of hunger and disease, and hopelessness.
And the strong ones began killing
the weak ones for scraps of food.
Those who could, flocked together in tribes
and hid in caves and secret places.
And others became like wolves,
hunting and killing anything that moved.
They were ravagers.
Falk! Oh!
Miriam. Miriam.
Mmm. I heard a gunshot.
Did you see Ravagers?
Falk?
Well, I heard... I...
Thought I heard something.
But it was in the hills.
Probably some scouts.
Come on.
I really think it's time that we moved on, Miriam.
You get him, she's yours.
What have you done?
I put the bed over there and I put the table over there.
- Do you like it?-Yeah.
I like it.
All right, okay, they're up there somewhere.
Spread out. You two go around the back.
It's good.
Good.
- Falk...-Yeah, Miriam.
I, uh, I found something today.
See? Isn't it beautiful?
Miriam...
Wha... What?
Listen, it's dry.
There's nothing.
- Nothing. -No.
Hey...
It'll be all right.It's all right.
I told you not toprowl around out there.
That's my job. Understand?
Good.
Where will we go?
Well, uh, south.
- Yeah. -Well, won't they be going south, too?
Following the Flocker tribes?
Well, uh, yes, but, uh...
We've always managed to keep ahead of them before.
I was just beginning to feel safe here.
Yeah.
Well, that's when you start going careless.
Falk,
can we go back to that place on the beach?
Beach? Why?
Maybe the fish would come back.
Oh! I told you, please,
it's no use.
The seas are poisoned.
They're poisoned.
There has to be somewhere.
Must be somewhere.
A place where there's children.
Come on!
Falk, hurry.
Get him!
I kill!
Go up the tower.
Hurry.
Come on.
The bridge. Let's go.
Cross the bridge.
Kill him!
Go around there.
Miriam.
Miriam!
Miriam...
Someday it will happen again.
A woman somewhere will have a child.
No, Miriam.
Look what I found.
Look at this, look at this.
Give me a kiss, honey.
Don't get wet now.
Boy fromthe steel mill.
We looked all over.He's long gone.
He's out there somewhere.
There's nobody alive out there.
I'll find him.
Move out!
Can we go back to that place on the beach?
Maybe the fish have come back.
It's a place called Genesis.
A place where things still grow.
It means something, Falk.
All the wayto the Appellate Court.
Don't think you can get away with this.
I'll teach you how the system works.
Don't think you can avoid appeals.
Costs be damned...
I won't lose this.
No, no... I'm onmy way, sir.Just on my way.
I... I'm not going to hurt you
I won't hurt you.
I don'tknow you, sir.
Oh, I'm... I'm just a guylooking for some food.
Uh, where are your tribe?
Oh.
Stand in front of me.
Do you know what a lawyer is?
Well, that's ancient history.
You just take me on them and I'll...
I'll talk to them.
Useless. There isn't enough. They threw me out.
Shh... Go on.
I'll talk to them.
I'll talk to them. I'm not going to hurt you.
Come on.
There's nobody here.
They're here.
Hold it!
Hey! Hold it!
Stop! Please stop!
Listen to me!
Just listen to me for a second!
Now! Stop! Listen, this...
Halt!
Hands on your head.
Don't move!
This is amilitary installation.
You're trespassing.
Oh.
I... I didn't know that.
I'll just be moving along.
Hands!
"Special Order Number 18963.
"Subject: Security.
"Effective immediately.
"Any unauthorized person found
trespassing on this installation
"will be regarded asa looter and a saboteur
"and executed.
"Signed,
"John C. Ogden, Colonel, United States Army,
Installation Commander."
Make yourself a smoke.
Say your prayers...
Looter.
Sixty seconds.
- Now, listen, old man... -Sergeant.
Master Sergeant Cramer.
All right. Master Sergeant Cramer...
Now, shh.You just listen to mefor a second, will ya?
There's no government anymore.
There's noarmy anymore...
There's no law anymore.Just survival.
Ten seconds.
Take your choice.
Turn your back orface the firing squad.
Sergeant.
Food.
You didn't get that belly eating grass.
You're eating food.
Yeah. Yeah.
Where do you hide it?
Follow me, Major.
Major?
Huh. What did you call me?
Follow me, Sir.
After you, Sir.
Watch your step. Watch your step.
Chair, Major.
Listen to me, Master Sergeant Cramer.
I'm not a goddamn Major. I'm a loner.
Now I'm gonna let you continue your little soldier game.
At least you've got a reason for living.
Before I go, I want you to show me...
How to use this thing.
Sergeant!
Now I'm telling you for the last time, Sergeant.
Go back to your soldier game.
Go on, move!
Major,
I know wherethere's people.
And music. Liquor.
- That's a kind of Flocker camp? -Yeah, yeah.
And Major, the women.
You've never seen anything like 'em.
We'll stow ourgear here, Sir.
Good idea not to show 'em what we're carrying.
I'll talk to 'em.
Brought the Major for a little R and R this time. Right?
Come on, Major. Everybody's waiting for you.
Hurry up.
Have no fear, Major.
They're as friendly as you get these days.
Like any other town, Major, near an Army post.
Good and bad.
You know thosecivilian women.
I keep tellingthe boys,"Flies spread disease,
- "keep zipped." -Sergeant, who are those people?
Flockers, Sir.
You give them something, they'll give you something.
- Sergeant!-Ah-ha!
Mmm...
This one's name's Grace, Sir. Amazing, isn't she?
Oh, yeah.
Good luck, Sir.
Mister... You havesomething to trade.
Uh, the bag, maybe.
The bag.
You hungry?
I don't have anything to trade.
I only asked if you were hungry.
Take these.
There's a couple of trees that still bear a little.
They're stubborn.
Go on. Take them.
Take them.
Sir.
Come here.
Take this.
I... I didhave something,
but not to trade. Please.
Stop it!
Oh!
Let go of me.
Stop it!
No!
I'm not going to hurt you.
I wasn't worried.
Who are you?
Nobody. My people, I, uh...
I got separatedfrom my people.
I got tobacco.
- Tobacco. -No.
Yeah.
No.
Uh-uh.
Oh, yeah.
Not all of it.
- Half. -A third?
I don't come cheap.
Oh, okay. Have half.
Some things still grow.
More things grow now than used to.
It means something, Falk.
Genesis. Again?
My God, my God, haven't you seen enough?
You still can't believe that.
Yes. Yes, I do.
No, Miriam.
No. No, Miriam.
For God sake, Miriam.
For God sake, get it out of your head!
What is it?
What's the matter?
You almost hit me.
Oh, I must have been dreaming.
Her name's Miriam, huh?
Yeah.It was. Miriam.
Oh.
You kept saying, "Genesis."
Genesis.
It's like in that Bible.
Is there such a place?
No. No.
It means "in the beginning,"doesn't it?
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know.
It's only a dream.
No, it's only a dream.
It's just a dream.
Just taking your fair share.
I was going to keep it all.
Well, why the hell not?
You're leaving anyway, weren't you?
Yeah.
You're going someplace. Huh?
Genesis.
Take me with you. Please.
I told you. It's nothing.
It's just a dream.
Hey.
Oh!
Major!
Sergeant, you are a hard man to lose.
I want to give you warning, Sir.
Burned.
Could be crawlingwith ravagers.
All around.
Keep an eye out.
Only way to make sure. Only way.
You're raving, Sergeant.
This place is as safe as any other.
If they burned it, it was a long time ago.
So you forget about it.
- Now go back where you belong. -All right.
I'll keep a sharp eye outfor any moving lights.
Sergeant! What the hell you doing?
I heard somebody out there.
Follow me.
Sergeant, get down, get down.
They're out there, Sir. Do you hear 'em?
Sergeant, back!
Get back!
There's one! Take him!
All right.
I've been following you since yesterday.
- What the hell for? -Well, why the helldo you think?
Welcome to the post, ma'am.
Sir.
Here's the watch list for the Major's approval.
We're a little short of personnel,
but I think we can manage, Sir.
Your bath is ready, Sir.
Me first.
Sergeant.
Yes, Sir.
Isn't there, uh...
Isn't there anything you can remember?
I remember many casualties, Sir.
The Major having to operate the bulldozer.
Digging a mass grave.
Sergeant, that wasn't me.
That was a grim task, Major.
Well, maybe it was your Major
that you buried in the grave.
You were very ill, Sir.
Sergeant, I was six years old then.
Don't you understand anything?
Falk...
What?
I can't go back to my people.
Why?
Once you leave, you can't go back.
They kill you.
Now listen to me. I...
I don't want you dead.
I just want you gone.
You understand?
Now...
Tomorrow you're going.
You, him.
Tomorrow, Sir,
drop her off at the nearest Civil Defense Center.
Let me give him one.
Ask him again.
He ain't gonna be doin' much talkin'.
Nobody is following us.
I'll find you some shelter,
then we're splitting up.
Let's go.
All secure, Sir.
All right, let's get us some sleep.
Sergeant...
I'll show youto your quarters, Miss?
Look what I found.
You'll forget her.
Leave me alone, please.
No!
Look, what I've been trying to tell you all along...
Faina.
Say my name.
All right?
Faina.
You don't like to be teased, do you?
I told you I was a loner.
There's no room in my life for another woman.
One was enough.
You couldn't love her that much.
Take that damn dress off.
No.
Take the dress off!
- No! -Take it off!
Take it off!
Look, there's no room in my life for anybody.
Do you understand?
Now please, leave me alone.
No.
Faina, please, please, listen to me.
I'm made all wrong for this.
I'm not what you think I am.
I'm not what I seem to be.
I'm good for you, you'll see.
What makes you so goddamn stubborn?
When my older sister died,
she dug her nailsinto the back of my handuntil I cried.
She said the painwould make me remember.
Remember what?
Never to be afraid.
And never, never to be ashamed.
Leave that up. Hurry.
I'll cover you from the other side.
Looks like there's nobody here.
Candle wax.
Behind you!
Move out, Major. Move out.
Come on.
Sergeant!
Go on,I'll catch up with ya.
You're gonna get it, you lousy bastards!
Come on, you...
What is it?
Nothin'.
I mean...
He was just a crazy old fool, wasn't he?
We couldn't have saved him.
It wasn't your fault, you know.
I guess.
We gotta keep moving.
Come on.
Turn the old man loose.
Falk.
Careful, now.
Ravagers?
No.
Easy...
No, they're not.
Give you a handwith this here.
Easy...
Don't move.
Please.
I don't want to hurt you.
Just want to talk.
Who are you?
You look fed.You've got new clothes.
You look like peopleused to look...
Long ago.
Are you people from Genesis?
Hand over that weapon
and we'll talk.
Come on.
We're going with you. So, come on.
Major!
My God! It's the Sergeant.
Major.
Help him, Faina.
Hold up there.
- A little scratch. -Hold up.
Let's go!
My God!
Heave away.
Hey, steady.
Oh, look at all this.
These ships. How did you people find them?
Find them? No, it wasn't like that.
Rann brought us here with the ships a long time ago.
- Oh, my God.-Yeah.
- Look, they keep bringing more things. -Yeah.
Where's it coming from?
This is just the storeroom.
The other ship is full of supplies.
50 years worth.
We could live like this for 50 years.
In hiding Rann says.
Who, who... Who's Rann?
Rann is Rann.
Oh.
When you change,
I want to show you something.
It's real.
It works.
How?
We have a generator.
Lots of diesel fuel.
Oh.
The last time I saw electric lights I, uh...
Why, I was a kid.
Lots of comforts.
We almost have everything.
Come with me.
Come on, you can see all of this later.
Hey.
Can I talk to you?
Look. Look, you show me marvels.
Food... Uh... Uh, electric lights.
Uh, things that, uh... I mean, you show me things
that nobody else in the world has.
Yet, you're trying to tell me that
something is wrong about it.
Now what is it?
Come on, what is it?
Well...
Yeah.
You and that girl was going someplace.
Where?
Nowhere.
Anywhere.What the hell differencedoes it make?
Genesis.
Oh, God, that Genesis again.
The girl,
we all heard her.
You know where it is.
Look, there's no such place.
And even if there was,
I mean, uh, why would anybodywant to leave all this?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, you're cautious.
Fair enough.
I'll show you now.
Who is it?
Open up. Just be a minute.
Brown!
Tell him we are not going to run.
Tell him it was all a mistake.
Sure. Sure,I'll tell him.
He listens to you, doesn't he?
No.
No?
What are they alldoing in there?
They want to leave the ship.
Rann says no.
Nobody leaves.
Bring up the small boat.
Hey. Watch it.
They're somewhere behind that island.
Over here.
Move!
Come on. Move it!
Is that Rann?
We done it before.
I remember how my dad...
His name is Falk.
- MAN: Ah.
Pass me the bread.
Ever think you'd see anything like this, Falk?
Not ever.
Never.
And I've seen a Flocker's camp before.
We're not Flocker's here.
I guess I spoke out of turn.
Yes, you did.
I'll accept your apology. You did apologize?
Oh, yes.Oh, yes. Sure.
I'm sorry.-
How come you've seen so many Flocker camps, Falk?
Huh?
What does it matter?
I mean, maybe you're not Flockers
and you should think you're better off than them,
and in some respects you are.
You see, what, what I mean is,
there's no real difference.
They hide. And you hide.
They're afraid of strangers,
you're afraid of strangers.
Hold on, Falk. You're getting out of line.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Now let him saywhat he thinks.
Um, if you had todecide for us,
what would you do?
Speak up.
We're interested in your opinion.
Well...
It seems to me that
hiding in fear is not the answer.
There may be something better out there.
But you'll never know it.
Not if you stay here, locked and caged up,
just waitingfor everything to end.
You've, uh, you've got to take a chance.
And gamble awayall our lives,
in the hope that there's something better out there?
Why?
We have everything we need right here.
- MAN: Yeah, we sure do.
Except hope.
Well, now...
Well, look around you, Falk.
Isn't this better than...
Huh.
It can't be.
It... It's real.
Caught this morning.
We get 'em right here.In the channel.
The fish, yeah,
returned.
They're showing upmore and more.
Maybe it's a sign.
Damn it, Hank, that's enough!
Now, once and for all,
I say the land is finished.
Maybe not, Rann!
Now look, maybe not.
If the fishhave come back,
that means the seas are not poisoned.
So why can't the land come back?
Look, when I was in a Flocker's camp,
I met an old man.
He gave me an apple.
He gave me two apples. Two.
New, ripe apples.
Doesn't that mean something to you people?
Well, doesn't it?
Somewhere things are beginning to grow again.
Maybe children.
Children are beginning to... To... To be born once more.
Can't you see that?
Well, can't you?
It's settled.
Nobody leaves this ship.
You mean that I am a prisoner here, too?
Prisoner? Huh.
You can do anything you want.
As long as it doesn't jeopardize the rest of us.
Well, I can live by anything then.
That makes sense.
Good. Good, I'm glad to hear it.
Because our rulesmake a lot of sense.Hmm?
- Right?
Oh, by the way, are you with him?
- No. -Yes.
No.
Yes.-
No, she's not.
She doesn't know.
There seems to be a difference of opinion.
Now you see,
this is where our rules come in very handy.
A good-looking unattached woman
can be a threat to the peaceof the community.
Now, we're not telling youwho to choose,
but you've got to choosesomebody.
Him.
Aha.
Done! You're married.
A toast to the Major and his lady.
Good luck to both of you in married quarters, Sir.
To the Major.
This calls for a celebration.
Bring out the whiskey.
Oh, plug in the jukebox.
Hey, Falk, they're all dancing back there.
Come on. Don't you ever dance?
You're laughing.
See, you like being married.
Admit it.
My God.
- What makes you so damn... -Stubborn?
I told you.
I'm good for you.
Come on.
Let's go back to the music.
Falk!
What do you want?
We want to talk to you.
What?
We want to know about Genesis. Where is it?
I don't know.
I thought this was it.
But I was wrong.
Come on, you can trust us.
You heard what the man said.
He'll never let you leave this ship.
What if he can't stop us?
We've got others.
Will you lead us?
Admiral, it was amazing.
They had me.
I mean, they really had me.
Then the stupidbastards cut meloose up there.
They cut you loose? -
Ravagers! -
Let's go, let's go, come on!
Follow me to the Armory.
Move, come on, move it.
Brown, get some men,
get up topside and see if you can hold 'em off.
Okay.
Come on!
Here you go.
I'm here, Major. I'll cover you, Sir.
We're finished. We gotta get off this thing.
There's a hatchway where they brought water through.
Do you remember?
I remember. How do we find it?
Follow me, Sir.
Go on, Sergeant, get out of here. Take her with you.
Brown, where do we go?
Through the doorway.
Look out!
Genesis?
Well,
I guess we're it.
Come on!