* RED TOMAHAWK *
General George Custer and his
gallant soldiers, of the7th Cavalry,
were massacred, on the morning
of June 25, 1876.
At dawn of the following day,
while thousands of Sioux,
still roamed
the Black Hills of Dakota,
the first to come Upon that
carnage was Captain Tom York,
special agent
of the United States Army.
Hi!
Is anyone there?
Good morning, young soldier
Be welcome!
My name is, Crone.
Ned Crone.
Tell me why you look so scared.
The 7th Cavalry was slaughtered.
You better get out
of here quickly.
Well, I'm sorry for the cavalry,
but...
I will not leave this land.
It is best to let,
the animal rest for a while.
It looks like he's about
to suffocate.
I don't have time,
I have to get to Deadwood
and wire to Fort Bastion.
Are you saying that all
the Cavalry boys were killed?
More soldiers are on the way.
They could be ambushed, like Custer.
So you better get going.
I will stay here.
My partner and I discovered
wealth in this region.
He's in town,
to legalize the land
and if I leave here, someone could
come and take possession.
Listen, friend.
These hills are full of Indians.
Mr. the Indian was not born yet
that will get me out of here now.
Hey, captain! And Custer?
How is he doing?
Has he already wiped
out all the Indians?
Are you the telegraph operator?
Myself
I have a message for Fort
Bastion I can't send,
because the wires must have
been cut by the Indians.
When General Custer is finished with
them, we'll have the cables in order.
Custer is dead.
I don't believe it, Captain!
Dead Custer!
The entire 7th Cavalry was slaughtered,
there was not a man left.
What about the city?
We are going to be slaughtered.
They were slaughtered.
Ten thousand Sioux
must be around.
I have to send a message.
But there are no possibilities,
Deadwood is isolated from
the rest of the world.
Maybe we can send messengers.
If Custer is dead,
there is no way to pass.
Did you hear that?
Custer is dead.
Him and his entire army.
Are you sure about that,
Captain.
I saw the bodies.
The Indians will leave
Deadwood in ash.
Captain...
I have a partner there,
Ned Crone, Sir, did you see him?
You had a partner there.
What do you mean by that?
He is dead.
What did you do?
Did you leave him there to die?
What are you doing?
What do you mean, what are we doing?
I saw you two!
You are completely mistaken.
Fort Bastion...
They were arrested, given amnesty
to accompany General Custer.
Who are they, Captain?
He must have tied himself up,
saw what was going to happen to him.
I never thought of seeing a sniper
as with an arrow to the neck.
Oh!...
My God!
No, please! Not!
It can not be. He is dead.
Sal has been waiting
for him for months.
She used to come and wait.
all due diligence.
I wonder if this will be
the last step to get here.
All the Indians in the region will come
and they will remove our scalps.
Yes!...
they will take off our scalps.
Because?
Because? Because soldiers
like that are in the city,
instead of fighting the Indians.
What happened?
The fight has become so bloody
did you run away to hide?
A coward! Traitor!
People like you caused this!
This captain is, a deserter.
Look at him, without a scratch!
Do you look like you were
fighting the Indians?
Not!
Of course,
I was with General Custer,
but he ran away from
the battlefield, the coward!
Is that so, Captain?
Well, look at him, and the only man,
in uniform in this city.
That's right.
Are deserters! They are lying!
The uniform doesn't lie.
He speaks like this,
to save filthy skin!
Hey!...
Hit hard! Lynch him!
There will be no time for you
o go to court, Captain.
You should have stayed
at Little Big House.
Get your treats out of here!...
You are at an advantage,
don't you think guys?
That's the advantage he gave
Custer, none.
Smith!
It will be like fighting 50 men
at the same time.
Smith! If I attack again
from Tom York,
I'll make five holes in you.
Do you know the captain?
Of course yes.
He abandoned General Custer.
He does not belong
to the 7th regiment.
He is a government agent,
seconded to the US Army.
So, who were the guys who
accused him?
They were defectors,
as I told you.
Excuse me, Captain.
Did you see the deserters well?
Yes, I saw it,
I think I could recognize them.
Some deserters in the city?
They must have been hiding,
after they put the crowd against you,
they set a beautiful trap for me.
We will take care of you.
Captain.
If you see those two again,
tell me who they are.
Rest assured,
I'll be aiming for them a 45.
You look awful.
I didn't get to see you either,
two or three years ago.
You used to give letters, in El Paso.
Yes, for a while.
Then I accepted the position
of Sheriff in Tombstane.
I heard that you "cleaned"
the place in the blink of an eye.
No. They always overreact
to the story, Tom.
You know it.
Knowing him, I don't think so.
And my feet, they itch.
Did you come to Deadwood,
after gold like the others?
I don't,
I'm carrying guns for Wells Fargo.
They got here.
Hmm! Well, unless we can get,
in touch with the army,
we are not going anywhere else.
What you're saying is
that the cavalry has divided
in two by Custer,
on the way to Little Big Hom?
That's right.
They came in two different directions.
They came in a circle to reinforce
the 7th regiment.
And Custer will not be present.
The only thing that will be there,
are the Indians waiting for them.
Therefore,
it is necessary to alert them.
You are very tired!
To help? Let me see!
At least three fast messengers
will be needed.
Three horsemen
in two directions?
One of them has to go
to Fort Bastion to pick up the soldiers.
It's ok. Three horsemen.
I feel better.
Three horsemen without their scalps.
Yes. We will have to try.
Do you have to try?
No not me!
No sir. Listen, Tom,
somewhere in the mountains,
the Indians are waiting,
with bloody red axes
and thirsty for more.
This is not something to be done
and no man in his right
mind should do so.
Do you think they'll attack Deadwood?
I think so, don't you think?
What chances of survival
will we have then?
What are the chances
of people in the city?
You have a chance to die,
in very good company, friend.
If we alert the soldiers,
they would be ambushed by the Indians.
Which is true,
they go straight to the killing.
If they are prepared,
they will defeat the Indians.
The Indians are in great numbers.
But they will face them.
Of course,
they will face them, right
but they will have a chance to defeat
them, which Custer had.
No, Tom. There is no chance, unless
that has a much superior weapon
Hey Tom, didn't you have some Gatling
guns at the Fort? There were four,
but Custer didn't want to bring them.
He said they served to delay him.
He wanted a quick victory
on the field.
Quick win...
I can understand,
President Grant
and the generals just wanted,
a quick victory.
It was a lot of anxiety,
I think.
Why did you ask
for machine guns?
I heard that there are two
of them here in the city.
What?
Don't get excited, Tom.
I don't know where they are or who has
them, or if they really exist.
If that's true,
it would give soldiers a chance, right?
You won't like it, Tom.
Okay, I won't like it.
Your friend, Columbus Smith
That's what this bull is called.
who tried to pull my brains out?
He knows almost everything
is happening in this city.
Where can we find him?
When he had that "date"
with you, he was
taking the dirty laundry
must be at Chinaman.
So, come on.
Get out of here now!
What are you doing?
The city went crazy.
They counted on Custer.
It seems that they will face
the problem with the barriers.
The Indians break the barriers.
Hey you there!
Put it here. Come on.
Hear me out! Wait!
Wait!
You are fighting on the wrong side.
The battle is within you.
We will all die.
Yes, we will die,
but can't we die with dignity?
A doomsday speech.
Yes, the end of the world.
The problem is that
he may be right.
It could be the end of Deadwood.
If we don't get the machine guns,
you can bet life that everything is lost.
Please,
Look at God before it's too late.
Seek God.
Apparently,
he tried to cross the mountains.
See what happens if we try.
We will not try.
If he accuses us of defecting
the way he accuses us
people will slaughter us
and spit us out.
Let's stay hidden.
Perhaps the Captain will not see us.
In a city this big?
There is nowhere to hide.
Sooner or later, we meet.
But you can't find us
if you're dead.
A dead person cannot
see anything.
So, we have no alternative.
We `ll kill him.
Keep working! Keep walking!
Hyah, hyah!...
How can I wash this?
It stinks! Nobody can wash.
Hiu!... It stinks a lot,
smell yourself, okay?
It smells really bad,
but try again, okay?
Try the Lord! You wash!
Hey, Captain!
Problems with staff?
No. He thinks he's still,
in San Francisco.
Colombo won it,
playing cards over there.
I wish I had lost it.
Captain, I'm very sorry.
You already told me that.
It's always like that, Columbus
knocks first and asks questions later.
And as soon as I get into
fights that's how I do
We need a favor.
If you can,
I am at your disposal.
There are rumors that machine
guns, are here in the city
Exactly.
The army needs this. Quickly.
I need volunteers
to carry them, Smith.
They are hidden.
Can you take us to them?
No, I can't, because
I'm going to tell you something.
Lil has them and she will give nothing
in this world.
Smith?
Your skin,
mine and that of men is at stake.
Will she hear the voice
of reason?
Why don't you talk to her!
If she accepts, will I go with you?
At least I have a volunteer.
Two, if she delivers them!
Thank you, Smith.
Lil's bar is over there.
Do you know her well?
No one in this city
knows Dakota Lil well.
Looks like you have
friends everywhere, Tom.
Are you one of the defectors?
Yes he was!
Place your bets, gentlemen.
Please, make your bets.
The bets are over.
Black number 25.
Place your bets, please.
The bets are over.
17 black and advantage.
Hey, why didn't you tell me,
who knew her?
Do not know.
The bets are over, gentlemen's.
Lil, where did you meet?
Do not know!
I think it's time for you two
to get to know each other.
I want to introduce you to a friend
of mine, Captain Tom York.
Tom, I introduce Lil McCoy.
Captain!
Finished bets,
please, gentlemen's
Captain, are you on business,
or for fun?
Business. And I think it's better
to get straight to the point.
Someone could replace you.
Oh no!
Never stop a game of chance.
Place your bets,
please, gentlemen's.
The game of chance I'm here
for could be your life.
13, red and Advantage
Place your bets, gentlemen's.
Lil...
Could mean,
the lives of us all.
Maybe we better die.
Place your bets, please.
Place your bets, gentlemen's!
Perhaps, madam,
but I fear that is not your decision.
And yours?
Can't we speak in private?
This is my private place.
If you want to speak, speak!
I wanted!...
Speak!
The Army is in need
of machine guns.
Double zero.
The game is over! Because?
I started just now.
If you want to lose, your money,
they will accept you there.
And the subject
of machine guns is closed.
You know where they are, don't you?
Two of them.
I don't know anything about it.
Where did you hide them?
Lil, can't we sit and talk?
What else is there to say?
In this city its like that, nobody
get in your business life.
I have to get into this.
Listen, Lil,
the army is in dire need
of machine guns.
If Custer had these weapons,
this story would have been different.
Nobody's going to get their hands
on those weapons.
They can avoid,
a useless massacre of soldiers.
Soldiers who can
fight thousands of Indians.
I'm sorry!
What kind of woman are you?
I'm not the type you judge.
If I knew what I think.
Listen, very carefully,
Captain.
Some time ago,
no one knew me as Dakota Lil.
It was mother, wife...
I don't want the story of your life,
I want the machine guns!
Wait, Tom! Let's hear it.
Thanks!
My husband and I had a ranch,
around Deadwood.
He was guarding,
machine guns for your partner,
when the Indians came.
They killed my husband,
my son and...
they took me with them.
But I didn't tell them where
the weapons were hidden.
I knew they could be used
to kill innocent people.
Listen, understand how you feel,
but the situation is
completely different now!
These weapons cost the life,
to my husband, my son...
and my reputation as a woman.
I swore that no one else
will use them.
And, believe me, Captain...
No one will use them again.
It's useless.
We will achieve nothing.
I don't know, Tom.
I've never seen her like this.
Perhaps it is better
to give him time to think.
We do not have time.
Let's look for them.
Where is the ranch?
Columbus Smith must know.
Come on.
Mr. Elkins.
Soon it will be dark.
Yes!
With each passing hour,
soldiers are closer to Littte Big Hom.
I can't forget
the way she looked at you.
I don't forget the way you
refused to help us.
You also looked at her,
in a strange way.
But there is nothing strange!
Two Pairs!
Three of the same suit.
He was trying to win himself!
Oh yes? Good luck.
Did you do it? Not here!
Smth!
Do you know the lands that Lil
and her husband had?
Of course I know the McCoy land.
They talked a lot,
about the projects they had,
for them and suddenly,
he was killed.
Very strange.
Captain York looks like
Ben McCoy.
It refers to the fact that he is dead,
this is how I feel.
Did you ever see the McCoys' ranch?
The ranch?
It is a small hut outside the city.
They wanted to make the place,
a big ranch.
Is very far?
It is very close to here.
We think McCoy
hid his guns over there.
Maybe you're right!...
Come on, practice playing
cards while I'm gone
It looks like this is from
the salon.
It could be Lil.
Let it go!... Sheriff!
We need the guns in Deadwood.
There are no weapons.
We all heard the Captain!
It will tell us where
the machine guns are.
Did you say machine guns?
He doesn't know what
he's talking about.
Are two.
One for each end of the city.
Because. This will prevent
the Indians from entering.
It will take us to arms,
or will be dead,
when the Indians arrive. Let me!
It's not going anywhere!
All people out!
Thanks.
You were at a disadvantage.
Come on, captain!
Take her out of here.
We need these weapons
and plan to have them.
It looks like
I got you in trouble.
We will meet back at the hotel.
Not!
We stay here.
Listen take it. Come on!
We can take care
of these clowns.
Are you on the side of the army?
The Army is the only thing
that can save our skin.
Yes it's true. How Custer
and his boys saved their skins.
If it is, we will kill
for these machine guns
Even if they kill each other,
you mean.
Captain!
When he entered the hall, it was not
my intention to look at him that way.
I answered the look, didn't I?
For a moment,
I thought I knew him.
There is a Chinese
in the laundry that said,
that I look like
with your husband.
No, I don't think so.
Do I look like someone you know?
Nobody I remember.
Ah! Weird!
Charming!
Two strangers.
Who think they know each other.
Captain.
When, I said I needed,
to of the machine
guns, I was confused,
but when I said I needed them
to fight the Indians,
then I realized that
the Army really needs them.
Will you tell us where they are?
Yes. They are buried near
the house where we lived.
They must be rusty by now.
They are wrapped in oily fabric.
There are even four tripods.
The population is all agitated.
They think that machine guns
will solve all their problems.
They don't care, with the army.
She told me where they are.
Where?
As we were thinking near
the McCoys' house.
We better saddle the horses.
I will get a cart in the meantime.
Listen, you two,
dig up the weapons.
Maybe it's a good idea,
if I'm going to hit the ground so,
to give the Army clues about
the location of the Indians. Wait!
You're not going to walk the hills alone,
are you? It is my obligation.
The machine guns are dismantled.
Do any of you know how
to assemble them?
I can not.
I could try, but that's it.
York, he's an expert, in arms.
Ep, what do you think about the two
of us going to check out the hills?
It seems that there is nothing
more to do in the city.
Stop worrying, we are not going
to get in the middle of the Sioux.
We still want to keep our scalp.
You can see their fires
in the distance.
Okay, but I suggest that you
take different directions.
Ep...
you are going south...
Do not say. I know.
North Right! So!
Hide the horses and the cart when
they return to the city.
By then, I will have
the weapons assembled.
Aren't you going with her
to the ranch?
Hmm...
maybe it's a good idea.
Those hooligans,
out there we better get out the back.
And we better get together first, Tom.
I'll give you some time.
We will meet before nightfall,
God willing for all of us.
Captain,
and Lil are already coming here?
I didn't know they were
at the hotel.
Did you know, Smith?
I didn't know, either.
You leave the key.
Why don't you go and see?
Come on. Elkins?
You were right, they were there.
I saw them going out the back.
If we run,
well get the machine guns.
Come on!
We have company!
If someone follows us
to the machine guns
the whole city will know,
their location.
The door is open
Elkins!
Yes.
Did you get to see them?
Yes, they came out from behind,
when we show up.
Very smart!
We can go after them,
I have no better idea.
They will take us,
to machine guns.
We will follow them.
Make sure they don't
follow us this time.
One less.
The other is already going.
Are you sure you know how
to assemble them?
I'll try to mount.
After all, how was it that your husband,
obtained these weapons?
He and his partner, Red Sawyer,
decided to buy weapons
at very low prices.
They thought.
It is the same as buying
a white elephant at a low price.
They intended to sell them
to the army.
The army does not buy
second-hand equipment.
They realized that.
These weapons are not brand new.
They were made in 1865,
which was the year
that Catling changed the cylinders.
They used to accumulate gases,
in the barrel cylinders
and explode in the sniper's face.
When they were unable
to sell them to the army,
Sawyer made a deal to sell
to the Indians.
My command did not allow him
to carry on this business.
They had a horrible argument.
My husband buried them.
And Sawyer told the Indians,
that if they wanted to
the guns had to get them
at the ranch.
They really left them to us,
didn't they?
Perhaps it would be
better not to kill him?
He has already dug his
grave without the weapons.
Take the machine guns
and leave him alone
It has already
caused many problems.
Weapons are useless
if they don't have ammunition.
Check for ammo.
What kind of projectile is used?
58 caliber, special!
They have to be there.
No, they were not
buried with weapons.
It makes no sense.
Yes it's true.
Because
if the Indians found them,
there would be no ammunition
so they would be useless
She must be right.
There is no ammunition here.
Your husband thought
of everything.
I will make a deal with you.
Leave the Captain alone.
And I will tell you where
the ammunition is.
Will say anyway.
When I'm done with you
will tell me everything
The Indians thought that,
but I didn't say anything to them.
You are quite insensitive.
If you are lying, tell your
Captain that we will be back
and not only will we kill you,
but you will also
Where are the ammunition?
They are buried beside
the Court on East Front Street.
Captain...
Captain.
Tom?
Who is it? Smith.
I had never seen so many Indian
bonfires in my life.
Did you go north?
I don't need a compass
to know where the North is.
I do not know.
I saw many fires in the south.
The city is living hell.
They are looking for riots.
Open the door
Columbus Smith,
I saw him come in.
Who is it? And Kane.
Ep!
Tell me, Kane, were you
the one who fired the shot?
I shot in the air, to scare them.
These guys are looting the city.
You don't seem to have
scared them too much.
If we don't act rigorously, Deadwood
will be adrift, lawless and out of control.
We have to stop them.
The only thing we should stop
is the Indians on the hills.
You have a civic duty
to help the city.
To hell with the city!
I have a greater duty
to the army!
I hope you know
what you're doing.
We expect the same.
I hate to take this cart.
The weapons are heavy, Smith.
Yes, I know it will slow us down.
But let's go.
I will help you load.
It's ok.
Thank God!
I thought I would never
open my eyes again...
Uh, of course.
The way my head is hurting,
I think I was dying.
Elkins and the other men tried
to kill him.
Yes,
it's a shame that they didn't.
Do not say that.
I don't even have to ask about
the machine guns...
They took them.
Ep and Columbus Smith.
Ah!...
Ah!... have they arrived yet?
Not me...
I didn't see them.
They should be here by now.
I told Elkins where
the ammunition is.
Because?
Was necessary.
You told them not, to kill me.
Many people died,
uselessly because of these weapons.
There will be many more deaths
if you do not recover them.
Wait, your friends will
help you find them.
With every minute that passes...
There is no more hurry.
It's raining and the attack,
Deawood is not immediate.
I know the Indians.
I know what you're thinking.
I was thinking.
I still haven't thanked you
for saving my life. Oh no!
Are you wondering
if there is anyone who knows about
the Indians, I am that person.
No, no, Lil.
Do not torment yourself.
You are right, I know them well.
I managed to escape, finally.
But she was someone else,
no longer a wife or a mother.
Or...
the simple Ohio girl who had
been and who had married
my husband.
Your husband...
was a man who had
a dream right?
And when the dream died,
I died...
But now its night,
the inhabitants
of the city have gone mad,
with the idea that the Indians
would massacre them.
I don't think I'm her anymore.
And you are not!
I don't know who
I am or what I am...
not even life, after all.
Life is nothing,
but an endless game.
And I spend all my time making
the wrong combinations.
It may be, but that's over.
Why did you say that?
Is there anyone else who can do it?
Do not.
I'm tired of missing
combinations.
Everybody is.
you are not the only one
I am tired of pretending
that I am insensitive.
It is not insensitive at all.
So who am I? No Lil...
No, no.
If you're thinking about kissing me,
I don't even know what that is anymore.
Lil...
Has the Captain set up
the machine guns yet?
Gone. They were stolen
a few hours ago.
Were they ambushed?
There were four men.
I recognized one of them,
it was Elkins.
What about the captain?
Was he kidnapped or what?
No. He...
he went out a while ago.
She must turn the city
upside down to take up arms.
The ammunition was
buried next to the court.
He said he would go first.
Lil keeps an eye on
the horses, fine.
The best you can do
is stick around.
They blocked the two
entrances to the city.
Damn you who don't realize that there
are many ways to get into the city.
The Sitting Bull knows them all.
I'm sure of it.
I believe so.
They don't know that the Sitting Bull
is going to get around the barriers.
And I'll tell you something, if you're
crazy enough to get back to roulette,
you will enter a bar full of hyenas,
drunk and scared.
I think today,
we're all pretty scared.
Lil told us the story of Elkins
and his friends.
They even have the ammunition.
Elkins has a freight company.
Maybe we can find him there.
Perhaps...
but unless he knows,
what are you doing,
or it will take a long time
to assemble the weapons.
He doesn't know that we know.
This means that he
is waiting for us.
EIkins will regret not killing me.
Because?
We can mount machine guns,
we can't.
What if he has already
assembled them?
So, we have 58 Caliber
for breakfast.
There he is!
Ep!
See if you can get there
and get in the back.
Smith, come over there
and appear from the side.
It's ok!
Hey Elkins!
You better hurry up. Elkins.
Want to try it yourself?
Don't shoot! Do not shot.
We surrender! Let's go out.
Captain!
We need the damn weapons
at Deadwood!
If we take them,
to the Army in time,
the Indians will
not approach Deadwood.
That's what you say.
We don't believe that.
The guns are here, in Deadwood!
Have you ever been in front
of a machine gun before?
This weapon is not complete.
It is mounted enough
to make holes in your body.
As I already said, Captain.
We will not allow to take
Deadwood machine guns lightly!
None of them!
You, Ep Wyatt and Columbus Smith
are going to have to fight the city.
I believe him.
I think you better believe that.
He will return,
with a raging crowd.
Maybe I can make a foul in time.
You mean, its not working?
You should see him bluff
in a poker game.
I'll get the horses.
A weapon will not destroy,
the entire city.
They will not let you out
of town with machine guns.
These weapons will have
no use for them.
One at each end of the city,
the Indians do not attack like
that they will surround the city.
Don't get me wrong,
Captain.
I'm on your side, I agree.
The Army that fights with the Indians.
But can you take
the weapons in time?
We will try, for sure.
Why aren't you running away in fear?
I'm scared to death.
I'm just not running away.
We have to hurry, Captain.
I'll get the cart.
You said that Gatling
had trouble marketing this model.
After he invented it,
the factory was destroyed by fire
and had to start over.
That was in 1862.
Then they produced machine guns,
in time for the war.
It was never used even though Gatling
wrote to Lincoln.
Old Abraham,
never made many mistakes.
Several of his
generals committed.
The Gatling machine gun
appeared in North Carolina.
They feared that he might have
the sympathy of the Confederates.
They assumed that if they hired him,
to manufacture the machine guns,
he would then organize
an attack to steal them.
They would be in the line of fire,
with the weapons they bought and paid for.
We have to get the machine guns back.
If we don't, we will be dead.
Gather the Massev brothers
and evacuate the bars,
we will gather a crowd.
We need to recover the weapons.
Let's get them!...
Captain, the crowd is arriving
at any moment.
Where are they?
Where are the what?
Both weapons are missing
cylinders.
We will reload them and pick
them up, on the way.
It's no use.
Without cylinders,
weapons will not work.
There is no point fighting
for weapons that don't work.
Tom!
I looked for you everywhere.
I heard you were here.
Did you hear that they were after of us?
They are really coming.
Well not only hid it,
the ammunition elsewhere,
but it also hid
the cylinders elsewhere.
Wow! What a beautiful memory.
Well, it's not worth having the guns,
if they don't work.
You're absolutely right.
We are back in action.
Is everything loaded? All ready.
Turn around. That's it.
What a strange way
to say goodbye.
We had a strange arrival,
didn't we?
Ep, if you ever go back,
to Deadwood.
Try your luck at roulette.
Of course yes.
There, in those woods.
This is what the Sitting Bull calls
the first perimeter.
I was there last night.
Warriors watch over the city.
I found the same thing
on the other side.
How did they get through?
There are only a few Indians here.
The main battalion is miles away,
waiting for the army.
I walked between the guard posts,
but it was dark
and I was riding a horse.
This is different.
I'll go ahead and attract them,
on this path.
I think I better go with you.
Wait a minute, they'll be in the middle
of a battle. This is the idea.
Keep them busy so you
can go with the cart.
They will attract many warriors.
If they took the machine guns.
I can't take them on horseback.
So said Custer.
Machine guns are holding us
back from the city.
Besides that...
when they fire they wake up, all the
Indians within a radius of kilometers.
And I'm going to tell you
something, partner,
it's better not to shoot unless
it's necessary.
Good luck, Smith. Thanks!
I don't think I gave Columbus
enough time for him to pass.
In fact, you didn't.
He belonged to Custer's regiment.
It belonged.
I think it's as close as two people
can get in without losing their scalp.
Well, at least we left
the perimeter.
Now,
let's cross the Sioux Nation.
How long does it take,
to put the wheel back?
Depending
on the help you receive
Bring the ammo box.
It's ok.
Are you ready?
Wait a second. We can put it now.
It's all right...
you can go down.
Now turn this over.
You told Kane that whoever
invented this weapon was a rebel.
No. Dick Catling
was totally neutral,
but when the Yankees generals
were convinced the war was over.
Come on.
Come and help me, right?
It's done!... Enough is in place.
Oh well!...
Ep, help me with this gun.
It seems to me
that all fractions,
I would have needed those "girls".
Of course yes.
Older models fired 50 bullets,
per minute.
These are the 1865 models.
They fire more shots.
What about the latest models! The ones
Custer didn't want to take with him?
They're even better.
But the old Yellow Hair was
too busy trying to be a hero.
And perhaps they would have been,
if he had taken the machine guns.
I think everything is in order.
Let's move.
In this type of terrain we will pass,
the time spoiling the wheels.
Let's go as soon as possible!
If you run aground,
it won't be too fast.
This wheel will not take it,
much longer.
Advance!
A war group.
We have reached
the crucial point of the Sioux.
The secret is to go unnoticed.
The secret is in getting,
arriving is a broken wagon
to the Arrow Point Peninsula.
Unless the plans have changed,
Battalions A and H must be
arriving in this Zone.
Do you think you can convince them
to meet there and take a stand?
With the help of a battalion
of soldiers from the fort.
Battalions A and H and soldiers from
the fort don't know about your plans.
After we hid the weapons
at Arrow Point,
Ep and I are going to meet with
the troop commanders to alert them.
You go to Fort Bastion,
pick up soldiers.
I hate to talk about it,
Captain!
But Arrow Point, is in the middle
of Sioux territory.
It is more or less the same
situation that Custer had to face.
You know this is what I like,
you always have something positive
on the tip of your tongue.
It would be a shame to take this,
for a single war.
Yes. We would have
the Sitting Bull, above us.
Hopefully it is not necessary.
Come on.
There is still much?
I'm afraid there are 8 or 9 km to go.
Indians!
Will they come back?
Yes, a million friends with feathers.
Let's get out of here.
I went fishing
at Arrow Point once.
Hopefully thats what
were going to do,
with Gatling machine guns.
Both are ready to act.
The problem is in attracting the Indians.
I hope this plan works.
I would like to try
the machine guns on the Indians.
It's ok. Go to the fort.
Do you know the way?
Yes I know.
You go further.
Take my horse. It's ok.
Battalion H must be very close by.
In the Southwest.
What about battalion A?
South-west,
across the river,
a few hills from here.?
If you can stay high,
you can see them. Tom...
You know, of course,
that there are Indians across the river
and along those hills.
What are you trying to say?
Bye!...
Weve said goodbye before.
Hey. Smith? Say it.
When you return,
from the fort with the soldiers...
Let's go fishing.
It's the first time, that I'm going,
in a fishery where I am the bait.
Hei today... Hei today!
Hei, today!...
Company, loud!
Captain York! Are you, sir?
What the hell are you doing here?
Where's the rest of your battalion?
They camped farther away.
If they are further ahead,
what are they doing here?
We are checking the terrain,
there are Indians everywhere.
We are completely surrounded.
Well, as General Custer once said,
"a man must die with his boots on".
This is exactly what he did.
That was not funny, Captain.
I know it wasn't.
But it is the truth.
The remaining hope is
that the 7th Cavalry
it would be enough to get us
out of this situation.
So we were checking the terrain,
we were looking for General Custer.
Lieutenant,
take your men across
the river at Arrow Point.
Captain, if we go in any direction,
the Indians are falling on us.
We have two Gatling guns
at Arrow Point.
I understand!...
The captain needs a horse,
you two ride
on the same horse,
until we get to the battalion.
Let's get the men together, Captain
and let's go quickly to Arrow Point.
Company, move forward!...
Let's move faster!...
Attack, attack, attack!...
Ahead, march!
Disassemble!
Take cover quickly!
Hey, you two!
Hurry with that gun! Quickly!
Captain, allow a civilian
to fight with us.
And you better ask him,
if he will allow us to fight him.
Hide behind the rocks!
Quickly! Quickly!
Here they come!
Hide, yes? Go there!
Where are the soldiers in the fort?
Do not come.
Colombus did not survive,
we saw his body on the way back
And the most beautiful sight
I have ever seen.
Yes, it is a pity that Custer
was unable to see her.
Or Columbus Smith.
You know, Captain, I just thought,
that you were a dead man.
We all died!
Do you know what I think?
This could be the starting point,
in the war against the Sioux tribe.
I hope you're right.
All right, gentlemen's,
place your bets.
No one else!
Number 17.
Never stop a game of chance.
The game of chance
that can last a lifetime.
I mean, the rest of your life.
Gentlemen's...
this game is over.
You heard the lady,
Come on, I'll buy you a beer.
"FIM"