- Yes, yes, this is Gwen Pluth.
Right.
Right, well, my doctor hasn't gotten paid.
We met the deductible, yes.
I've called four times on this.
Okay, okay.
Alright.
Thank you.
No, no, no, no, no.
Autumn.
- Jen, back to earth.
- Sorry.
Stop, you can't look!
- Yes, I can.
- It's not fair, you can't look.
- Yes, I can, there is no rule against it.
- Todd!
- You can't cover my eyes.
- Yes, I can, there's no rule against it.
I can't concentrate.
- Tough decision?
You're not getting out
of this one that easy.
- What are you talking about?
I'm winning.
Hello, this is Jenny.
Uh huh.
Yeah, okay, I can be there
in 15 minutes, no problem.
I gotta go.
- Seriously?
- Yeah, hopefully I won't be long.
Hey, no peeking.
Hey, how are you?
- Is she in any pain?
I didn't know what to do.
Please, do something for her.
- I don't think she's
in any physical pain,
but I need you to stay calm,
she's very anxious right now.
Can you get the box of medicine
from the fridge for me?
Hey, it's okay Cynthia.
Hey, it's Jenny, your nurse.
I need you to breathe with me, okay?
Good.
- And what if this doesn't work?
- We're gonna take this
one step at a time.
I need you to trust me, okay?
Hey, Cynthia, we're
gonna get through this.
I'm giving her lorazepam, this
is going to help calm her.
Open.
God, give me the strength
to help calm her.
Good, good, good.
Can I pray for you?
Heavenly Father, I pray
for peace and comfort
for Cynthia right now.
Lord, we know her discomfort
is only temporary,
if she trusts in you.
I pray she would feel your presence
and an overwhelming sense of peace.
In Jesus' name I pray, amen.
- So how was work?
- It's going really well.
- Oh my goodness, I
don't know how you do it.
- Well, she was born to do it.
- It takes someone
special to do what you do.
- I just tell people
it's like being a labor
and delivery nurse, just
delivering to the next life.
It's my mom again, I'd
better get this, excuse me.
Hey, mom.
What?
Is dad okay?
Okay.
Mm hmm.
Yeah.
- What happened?
- I can't stop thinking about
where my dad is right now.
- We don't know what was in his heart.
- Why does God place such a burden on us?
- Uncle Ed, you are looking
like a million bucks.
After taxes.
- Funny guy.
How's work?
- Good, keeping busy.
- Good, good.
They did a good job with
his makeup, didn't they?
He looked peaceful.
- I sure hope he is.
Excuse me, I need some fresh air.
- Speak of the devil.
- Autumn!
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- I ran into her mom
the other day at the store.
I'm sorry, I forgot to tell you.
- Are you back in town for a while?
- Yeah, um,
I am so sorry for your loss.
- Thanks.
Thanks for coming.
- Yeah.
- When was the last time
you two saw each other?
- It's been,
a while.
- Yeah.
- Well, come on in, we got plenty of food.
- Uh mom, can you give us a sec?
- Oh, okay, it was good seeing you.
- You too, Gwen.
- It's so good to see you.
I tried calling a few times.
- I know.
- Why didn't you--
- I'm sorry, I,
things have just been a little,
crazy lately.
So, how's Todd?
- He's good.
Work's been a little slow.
He stays busy though, he just finished
a big project at church, so.
- Still doing the church thing, huh?
- Yeah.
- Um, I know you guys were trying
last time we talked, any luck?
- No, not yet.
Hopefully soon, though.
- Yeah.
- How about you, are you seeing anyone?
- No, no.
- Enjoy being single, you've got time.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, no, I'm, I'm good, fine.
I actually have to get going.
- You just got here, come in for a bit.
- I can't, I'm sorry, I,
I have some stuff I gotta take care of.
- There you are.
- Todd, look who's here.
- Autumn, hi, good to see you.
- Yeah, good to see you too, um, so sorry,
I gotta run, but it was
really good to see you guys.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah, not sure.
- Your mom's looking for you, we're ready.
- Thank you, everyone, for coming.
Jenny's going to say grace.
She's the designated saint in the family.
- Heavenly Father,
Lord, we thank you for this time we have
to celebrate dad's life.
We miss him so much.
We thank you for the time
you gave us with him.
I pray for your peace and
comfort on this sad day.
In Jesus' name I pray, amen.
- Amen.
- He's in a better place now.
- Is he?
Based on what, mom?
- Forget it, this isn't the time or place.
- Dad's memorial service
isn't the time or place
to grieve for him or
consider where he went?
- Jen!
- We're here to pay
respect to your father.
This isn't about your religion.
- I'm sick of pretending
everything's okay.
What if he's not in a better place?
- That's enough!
- Jenny, where are you going?
- I can't do this.
- Babe, come on.
You're upset, you both said
things you didn't mean.
- I'm not going back in there.
- Give her a minute to cool down.
- Please give me the keys.
- You're upset, you shouldn't be driving.
- I'm fine, I just need
to take a walk, okay?
I want to start planning for a family.
- We are a family.
- You know what I mean.
I want kids, Todd.
I don't think I can wait any longer.
I really think we should adopt.
- I want to adopt too, but
it's not the right time.
How are we gonna afford it?
We can barely get by as it is.
- Well, we're not getting any younger.
- I don't want our kids growing up
in the same environment like I did.
I want to be financially stable first.
- When's that gonna be?
- I'm doing the best I can, you know.
- I know.
What if I get that promotion?
Can we then?
- We'll see, we have to
run the numbers first.
- I already did, do you wanna see?
I created a detailed budget based off
of my potential raise, my Christmas bonus,
our tax return, and the money
that we have in savings.
And there's some really great grants
that I think we could qualify for.
- I mean, it could work,
if the numbers are right.
- Hey, Jenny, how was your weekend?
Mine was terrible, Mrs.
Epstein's daughter had me there
until three in the morning, on a Saturday!
That woman is driving me nuts.
Everything's an emergency with her.
And on top that, I only
got two hours of sleep.
My husband snores like a bear.
I keep telling him, "You
need to get a CPAP."
But does he listen to me?
Typical guy for you though, huh?
Adoption?
What, you can't get pregnant?
- It's none of your business.
Please don't take things off my desk.
- Well, it ain't cheap to adopt, you know?
- I know, that's why
I need this promotion.
- What promotion?
- I'm sorry, Barbara's waiting on me.
- Okay, um,
uh huh, sure.
Uh huh, three weeks, okay.
Uh huh, got it.
If you get the information,
I can take care of it
by next week, thanks.
Hey, how was your dad's service?
- Uh, okay, I had some family issues.
- I'm sorry to hear it.
You could have taken more
time off, if you wanted.
- No, I'd be thinking about it all day.
Maybe it's better I'm
at work keeping busy.
- I understand, denial is
part of the grieving process.
So what's up?
- I was wondering if you've
given any more thought
to that promotion.
- Corporate wants me to
interview a few more people
before I make my decision.
Standard procedure,
it's a formality really.
You'd be a perfect fit for it.
- That's great, because I really feel
like I would excel at this position.
I have ideas on how to
improve our patient care
and tighten up compliance with the regs.
- Okay, good, I'm hoping
to make my decision
in a couple weeks and I'll let you know.
- Thanks.
- Sorry to hear about your dad.
- How's your mom handling it?
- Okay, they got divorced
a while back, so.
- That's good.
Hey, thanks for letting me
know about that promotion.
Nothing like a little competition, right?
- What?
- The director's position.
I'm interviewing for it tomorrow.
You're not mad, are you?
- No, of course not.
- We're ready to get started.
We have three new patients this week.
Jenny, I want you to take the first one.
Marilyn, why don't you brief us on Autumn.
- Sure, let's see, patient's
name is Autumn Cooper.
She's 28 years old, she
has end stage leukemia,
and she's comfortable at this point.
- I did the initial assessment yesterday.
Patient refused further spiritual care,
but God has His own ways.
- Jenny, it'll be okay.
Take a drink of water, water helps.
Here, here.
Take this, drink, good, good.
Okay, now, please breathe slowly.
Deep breaths.
Are you gonna be okay?
Okay.
You've got nothing to worry about, Jenny.
Obviously, there's a
conflict of interest here,
so you won't be taking the case.
- I'd be happy to take her, Barb.
My case load's pretty low.
- Thanks, Mare.
Why don't you take the
rest of the day off?
Go home, relax.
Your friend's in good hands.
- Yeah.
- I'm so sorry to hear
about your friend, Jenny.
Don't worry, I'll take good care of her.
- Hey.
- What you doing home?
- I left early.
- What happened?
- Autumn's on hospice.
- Your friend Autumn?
What's wrong with her?
- She has leukemia.
- So she's back home now?
- Yeah, I think so.
Why is all this happening to me?
- I don't know why, babe.
Thanks for dinner.
- Yeah, sure.
- What you thinkin' about?
- Autumn.
God's brought her back
into my life for a reason.
I feel like He's giving
me a second chance.
I think I need to go there, now.
- Okay, you sure now's
the right time, though?
- Yeah, I need to help her.
- I've always admired your passion.
It's one of the many
reasons I married you.
But can't we have dessert first?
- Pray for me?
- Of course I will, I love you.
- Love you too.
- Hi Jenny, it's Pastor Greg.
I just wanted to let
you know that I'm here,
if you need to talk.
- Jenny? Jenny Pluth?
- Hi, Mrs. C.
- How are you?
- Hangin' in there.
- It's great to see you.
- I'm sorry to intrude,
were you headed out?
- Oh, it's no problem.
You're always welcome here, any time.
I was just heading to the
store, it can wait, really.
Come on in!
I haven't seen you in so long.
- Where's Mr. C?
- Working late.
What have you been doing
with yourself these days?
Autumn said you were married.
- Yeah, almost five years.
- Good for you, are you working?
- Yeah, I'm a hospice nurse.
- Oh, we just signed
Autumn up for hospice.
- I know, I work for New Hope.
- Are you her nurse?
- No, I couldn't, conflict of interest.
- Oh.
- When was Autumn diagnosed?
- Almost two years ago.
She's had, let's see,
three rounds of chemo,
countless blood transfusions.
Even a clinical trial.
Now we're here.
- How is she holding up?
- She's tired a lot, really weak.
She's not eating much.
- I'm here for you guys.
If you ever have any questions,
or if you just need someone
to talk to, let me know.
- Thanks.
I moved Autumn to my room.
You know where it is.
- And when I got back he was gone.
I can't imagine where he'd gone to.
- He was in here just a minute ago.
- Jenny!
- Hey, how are you?
Um,,
pretty, pretty awful, actually.
Nothing pretty about it, just, just awful.
You can grab a chair, just put
those clothes on the floor.
- Still don't put your laundry away, huh?
- Shut up, I have a legitimate excuse now.
Oh no, no, don't do that.
- It's fine, I don't mind.
- Did my mom call you or something?
- No, I found out
today at a work meeting,
of all places.
- Sorry.
Are you my nurse?
- No.
Why didn't you tell me, Autumn?
- I didn't, I didn't wanna be a burden.
It's not like we've really
been talking lately, so I...
- I'm so sorry.
Hey, you looked good at dad's service.
- Yeah, well, I only bust out the wig
for really important occasions.
- How are you feeling now?
- I'm,
I have some good days.
And bad.
Mostly bad.
- I'm here for you, okay?
Whatever you need.
- Thanks.
- How are you doing spiritually?
- Um, you know me, I'm
more science than religion.
- Are you scared?
- Um,
I don't know.
Not really.
Whatever's next has gotta
be better than this.
- Going to the store, need anything else?
- Pistachio pudding.
I don't, I don't really feel
up to seeing anyone else today,
mom, I'm really tired.
- Okay, hon.
It was great seeing you, Jenny.
- You too, Mrs. C.
You need any water or anything?
- No, no, just waiting on that pudding.
- Okay, well, I didn't want to stay long.
I'll let you rest.
- I get tired so easily now.
It's really frustrating.
- I'll stop by
tomorrow, if you want.
- No, you don't, you
don't have to do that.
- I want to, I can bring
you dinner or something.
What would you like?
- Mashed potatoes and creamed corn.
- You got it.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I got this for you.
I thought it might answer
some questions you may have.
Come on, humor me at least.
You never know, it might help.
- Okay.
Fine.
- I love you, Autumn.
- Love you too.
Thanks, Jenny.
Sorry, I
didn't want to interrupt.
Hi, I'm Marilyn, your hospice nurse.
- I was just leaving, take care.
- Thanks.
- How are you feeling today?
- How's she doing?
- Someone her age doesn't go on hospice
until they've been through
every possible treatment.
She maybe has a month.
- That's it?
- She's gonna decline fast, too.
- She believe in God?
- No, and I don't want
to make the same mistake
I did with my dad, but I
don't wanna regret not doing
or saying something that
could change her eternity.
- Aw.
- Smells good, what are we having?
- Hey, sorry, it's for Autumn.
I'm headed over there in a bit.
- What, but what am I supposed to eat?
- There are leftovers in the fridge.
- Nah.
- I can put a pizza in, if you'd like.
- Thank you.
- Hey, can you do the dishes?
I'm not sure what time
I'm headed back tonight.
- Sure.
- Pizza will be ready in a
few minutes, I set a timer.
- Okay, thanks.
- I don't know if I can do this.
I am so nervous.
I'm not sure what to say to her.
- Why not just be there for her?
She'll experience Jesus
through your actions,
not your words.
- Will she?
My dad didn't.
- Share your story.
Ask her what she believes.
You can't change her, only God can.
And He's got His own plans for her.
- Maybe.
- My appetite does not accurately reflect
the quality of these potatoes.
- I'm glad you liked them.
So, can I ask how your
doctor's appointment went?
- Yeah,
she said I'll probably
be declining pretty quickly.
She thinks two months,
but I think she was being generous.
- Did you get a new book?
- Yeah, yeah, my mom got it for me.
- What's it about?
- It's an analysis of a
bunch of different accounts
of near death experiences from like
all over the world.
And it's still theoretical,
but it's pretty interesting.
- Why did we stop being friends?
- What do you mean?
- Why did you stop calling?
Why didn't you return my calls?
- Ever since you became a Christian,
things have been different.
You really changed.
And I just
didn't think we had
anything in common anymore.
- Really?
I do see things differently,
but that doesn't change our friendship.
You've always been my best friend, Autumn.
- I, I, I know your faith is based
on something real for you but,
I never felt anything like that.
And I've never felt,
I've never found any evidence
that God even exists.
- Well, in the Bible--
- Outside of the Bible, Jenny.
And if there is a God,
I really don't think He cares about me.
- Autumn, He does care about you.
I know that He does, and He loves you
and He wants what's best for you.
- Could have fooled me.
Can we talk about something else?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- Hey, do you remember that time
my dad took us to Glacier Park
and we found those shiny
stones by the swings?
He told us that story about the pirate
and the lost treasure.
- Yeah, didn't we take the stones back
to your parents' house in a plastic baggie
and bury them in the backyard?
- With the treasure map!
- Ah, the treasure map.
- Did I ever tell you that my dad
planned that whole thing?
- What?
- He brought fool's
gold and he scattered it
so we would find it.
- No!
- Yeah!
I wonder, I
wonder if it's still there.
- I have no idea where
we put that treasure map.
- Well, at least the gold is safe, right?
- Of course, it's in a plastic baggie.
- It seems like yesterday.
Everything changes so fast.
- As all of you know,
this is the first time
I've ever held political office,
but I'm gonna do the very best I can.
Mayberry is a fine little town
but I think we can make it even better.
I think the important
thing to remember is this,
what government on any level is--
- Jenny, Jenny.
It's late.
- What time is it?
- Two in the morning.
Thank you so much for everything
you're doing for Autumn.
It's so great to have you around again.
- It's so good to be around again.
- Bye honey, drive safe.
- 200,000 acres.
Some of the richest land in California,
in the hands of two unlikely heirs.
- Hey, what time is it?
Everything okay?
- No, it's not.
I asked you to do the dishes.
- Sorry, I fell asleep watching TV.
- It must be nice.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I can't do everything around here.
- You're the one spending
all the time with Autumn.
It would be nice if you were around here
every once in a while.
- Seriously, you're giving me a guilt trip
about being with my dying friend?
- No, that's not what I meant.
It's late, I'm going to bed.
- Hello?
- Jenny, where have you been?
I've been trying to get a
hold of you all morning.
- What, what time is it?
- It's close to 11.
You've already missed two visits.
- Oh no, I am so sorry.
- I want you to
come right to the office.
We need to talk.
- Okay, I'll be right there.
You wanted to see me?
- Come in.
What's going on with you lately?
- I overslept, I was at Autumn's late.
It won't happen again.
- How are you holding up?
- Okay, I guess.
- This is getting in the way of your work.
Feel free to confide
in me or Chaplain Finn.
That's what we're here for.
You know that Autumn refused
spiritual care from us, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay, Marilyn told me she overheard you
sharing your faith with Autumn,
even after she told you
she didn't want you to.
- What? That's not true.
- Normally this wouldn't
be any of my business,
but since you represent New
Hope, this is a problem.
- I can't believe she
said that, she's lying.
- Were you sharing your faith with Autumn?
- Yeah, but...
So what, you're gonna forbid
me from talking to her?
- I didn't say that, you just have
to be careful what you say.
- So I'm just supposed
to just watch her die
and keep my mouth shut?
- My hands are tied, Jenny.
We can't force our beliefs on anyone,
especially as a company, you know that.
- I wasn't forcing my beliefs
on her, we are old friends.
- This is not open for discussion.
You're putting the company at risk.
This is a liability, do you understand?
If you care at all about the promotion,
you'll follow orders, do you understand?
- Yes.
Can I talk to you outside?
- Why, what's up?
- Can we just go outside, please?
- Whatever you have to say to me,
you can say right here.
- Fine, why did you tell Barbara
I was sharing my faith with
Autumn against her wishes?
- Weren't you?
- No, it wasn't like that and you know it.
Are you sure this has nothing
to do with the promotion?
You're unbelievable,
you've tried undermining me
ever since you found out
about that promotion.
- That's not true, I'm just doing my job.
- Is there a problem here, ladies?
- Not here.
- Jenny?
- No.
- You sure there's no problem?
It was so loud I had to leave my office.
- I don't know what that was about.
You wanted that file on Autumn?
- I did, thank you.
- Hey, honey.
- Hey.
- Where you going?
- I'm gonna go play basketball
with Chris at the gym.
- Oh, okay.
- Going to Autumn's?
- I don't know, why?
- Just wondering.
See you later.
- Oh, hey, before I forget,
we have that adoption meeting tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Bye.
- Have fun!
- Okay, so, before I go
into the specific details
of our program, I wanted
to take just a minute
to talk about adoption in general.
Two of the biggest
questions that I get are,
how long is it going to take,
and how much does it cost?
And though I appreciate those questions,
I really want to encourage
you to think about adoption
differently than anything that
you've ever pursued before.
You definitely need to
think about it differently
than purchasing a car
or purchasing a home.
And though those are important decisions,
adoption is going to profoundly impact you
and so many other people.
It is the absolute furthest
thing from a transaction.
Adoption is so much more than that.
So you and your spouse
need to be on the same page
before you even get started.
And putting in the effort
now will definitely pay off.
It'll be worth the wait.
- So, what'd you think?
- Seems like a good company.
- That's it?
- What else do you want me
to say, we're not ready.
- I don't know.
- This is why I didn't want to go.
- Why?
- Because now you're set
on the idea no matter what.
You heard what they said.
There's a good chance
we make too much money
to qualify for any grants.
How are we gonna pay for the home study?
Don't get mad, you know it's the truth.
- I'm not mad.
- Look.
If this is meant to be, then it'll happen.
God will make a way.
We just need to trust Him.
- How are you?
Jen.
I'm scared.
- About what?
- I think about
what it's gonna be like.
- What do you think happens next?
All evidence points to
decay.
Aren't you gonna say anything?
- Like what?
- I don't know,
something reassuring.
- I can't.
- What do you mean you can't?
- Now you want my advice?
- What?
- Autumn, I'm risking my job to be here.
Everything in my life is falling apart
and I just want to help you.
- Your life is falling apart?
- I didn't mean that.
- I didn't ask you to sit here
and watch me die.
You wanna talk about God?
Tell me how this is part of His plan.
Do you think I deserve this?
Why are you here, Jenny?
Are you here to save me?
Or are you just here to save
yourself from the guilt?
You're just like every
other Christian I know.
You doubt God just as much as I do.
You're just too afraid to admit it.
- Hey, take a deep breath.
You're okay.
Here, here, drink this.
Take a sip.
Do you have any Ativan?
I'm gonna go ask your mom, okay?
Water.
- Are you okay, hon?
- I gave Autumn half
a milligram of Ativan.
She can have one to two
tablets every four hours
as needed for her anxiety.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Are you sure?
- I think Autumn is
struggling, spiritually.
I've seen spiritual distress before.
It's different from physical pain.
It usually manifests itself
as anger and anxiety.
- We've never been a spiritual family.
- I know.
- But ever since Autumn was diagnosed,
things have changed for me.
I do a lot of praying now, Jenny.
- That's good.
I'm telling you this because,
because you and Mr. C should be prepared.
Autumn may only have a week left.
I need you.
Show me the way to help my friend.
Are you even listening?
- In Cash Fast, our
pay day loan is quick and easy.
♫ I can't fight this alone
♫ You're there and always have been
♫ When I was at my low
♫ Your love came crashing in
♫ I'm broken down
♫ Worn out
♫ You made my life new
♫ So let me fall
♫ Into you, fall into you
♫ Let me fall
♫ Into you
♫ Fall into you
♫ Let me fall
♫ Into you
♫ Fall into you
♫ I'm letting go, breaking
free from all my pain
♫ I'm letting go, getting
rid of all my shame
♫ I'm letting go into
the one and only name
- Hey, ma.
- Hi.
- I'm really sorry for
the way that I acted.
- So am I.
- And I'm sorry for not
returning your phone calls.
- I know, you've been
through a lot, come on in.
Thirsty?
- No, thanks.
Look, I'm sorry about
what I said about dad.
- I know.
- I feel like I gave up on him.
- He gave up on us,
a long time ago.
And he's responsible for his choices
and their consequences.
But that's in the past.
We need to focus on what's in front of us.
We still have each other.
I'm seeing a counselor now.
- Good for you!
Do you really think dad's
in a better place, mom?
- I think God could even
forgive your father.
- I think so, too.
Maybe they had a long talk.
- Maybe.
- That's all, folks.
- Thank you for stopping by.
- Do you have a minute?
- Yes, come on in.
Marilyn told me Autumn's
not doing very well.
- No, she's not.
- Jen, I think what you're
doing for Autumn is great,
but it puts the company at risk and--
- I know, that's why I
wanted to talk with you.
I thought about it and you're right.
I'm sorry for the way that I acted.
I'm too close to this case so,
that's why I'm resigning.
So I can be with my friend.
- You're quitting?!
- I'm letting go.
- Are you sure
you want to do this?
- I feel more like I need to do this.
I already lost so much time with Autumn,
and there's only a little time left.
Here's my letter of resignation.
I talked it over with Todd
and he supports my decision.
If I truly believe what I say I do,
then I need to live it.
Autumn means more to me than my job.
I need to be there for her.
- Okay, I hate to see you go,
but I respect your decision.
Don't be a stranger.
- Thank you so much.
Hey, I wanted to let you
know that I gave my notice
so I could be with Autumn.
I wish you the best of luck
in the director's position.
Really, I mean it.
- Can I help you?
- Yes, can we talk about my promotion?
- Your promotion.
- Well, now that Jenny has resigned,
I'm the only choice.
What's the raise like?
Do I get more vacation time?
- Well, you were
interviewed and had a fair
and objective evaluation.
- And?
- And your
leadership skills weren't up
to the standards required by the position.
We've concluded we're not
going to open the position
at this time, I'm sorry.
We can discuss your career
development strategy
at your next review.
- Hey Jenny, come on in.
- Thanks.
- Autumn's been sleeping
all day, but she's up now.
The care your company has
provided has been wonderful.
Marilyn has been great.
I'm so thankful for the work you guys do.
- Hey.
- Can I come in?
I came here to apologize.
I'm really sorry for
the way I treated you.
I can be too overbearing
and controlling sometimes.
- No, not you.
- I'm being serious,
you're ruining the moment.
I quit today.
- Quit what?
- My job.
- What?
Why?
- To be here with you.
- Jenny!
- You are so much more
important to me than my job.
I couldn't let that get in
the way of our friendship.
I'm here for you now, okay?
- You didn't have to do that.
- I wanted to.
I will keep praying for you but,
I didn't come here to preach, okay?
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Todd and I are thinking about adopting.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- That's amazing.
- I want to, Todd's
worried about the money.
It's expensive.
- Can you not have the
kids the old fashioned way?
I'm sorry, I didn't--
- No, don't be, it's okay.
- I didn't know.
- Yeah, I haven't told many people.
- I think it's really wonderful
that you're going to adopt.
You're gonna be a great mom, Jenny.
You deserve it.
- We'll see, I want to.
- You will.
- Thanks.
- I can't believe you're
doing this for me.
I, uh, I read a bit
of the Bible you gave me.
Just a little bit.
- I really didn't come here to preach.
I just wanted to be with
you when we have the time.
There is a passage I think you'd like.
I can mark it in the Bible for you.
It's about how
we need not worry about our lives,
because God takes care of us.
You should read it, if you'd like.
- Okay.
- Now, what I really came here for.
- The treasure map!
- Yeah, next time I come
I'll bearing pirate's booty.
- So, tell me, what's so
good about this God of yours?
- Well, I can tell you
where it started for me.
- You're sure you don't want any help?
- I'm fine, promised
Autumn I would find it.
Thanks for letting me do this.
It really means a lot to me.
- I know.
- Hello?
Okay, yeah, I'll be right there.
Thanks for the call, Mare.
- What are you writing?
- Autumn's eulogy, her mom
asked me to speak at her wake.
- I'm proud of you.
- For what?
- The way you've handled everything
that you've been through.
- Thanks.
I guess I blew our
chances at adopting, huh?
- You did the right thing.
- Hey, mom.
- I'm sorry, Jen.
- Thanks.
- Hey.
- I've got something for you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- I'm gonna...
- Of course.
- You did a lousy job
making that map you know?
I destroyed half my mom's yard
and still couldn't find these stones.
It doesn't seem real.
I can't believe you're gone.
I'm so sorry I wasn't a better friend.
- You were a better
friend to her than you know.
- Hey, Mrs. C.
- Hi, honey.
I want you to know you were wonderful.
Autumn was so happy to
have you by her side.
- I wish I could have done more for her.
- For what it's worth, I
don't think you could have
done anything more.
I was going through
Autumn's things last night
and I found the Bible you gave her.
- You can keep it.
- You don't know how much your prayers
and support have meant to me.
It's hard to explain, but
I felt a sense of peace
in Autumn's passing.
I know God was right there by my side.
- You don't know how much I needed that.
- Oh, honey.
- Hi everyone.
For those of you who don't know me,
I'm Jenny Pluth Paine, Autumn's friend.
When Mrs. Cooper asked
me to do Autumn's eulogy,
I didn't hesitate to say yes,
even though the idea of it terrified me.
Autumn was my best friend growing up.
We have some really
great memories together.
I would do anything for her.
She was,
is, very special to me.
God has taught me a lot
through this journey.
I wasn't as strong in my
faith as I thought I was.
I learned that everyone
has their own journey,
and Autumn let me find my way
and taught me how to
love like a real friend.
So, Autumn and I met at recess.
We were play hopscotching and had to first
draw the little squares.
Autumn's were perfect, and
mine were all squiggly.
And we looked back at them and she,
she said that's because
her fine motor skills
were exceptional, at seven years old.
Well, Autumn, you truly were exceptional.
Hello?
- Hi, is Jenny Paine available?
- This is she.
- Hi, this is Steven Marks
with Trust Community Bank.
I'm the Branch Manager here.
- Hi.
- I'm calling to notify you
that you're the sole
beneficiary of an account
held by the late Allen Pluth.
- Okay.
- If you could come in
at your earliest convenience, we'd like to
go over the account with you
and we have a few documents
we'd like you to sign.
- Oh, okay, sure.
I can be there later today.
- Thank you,
and you have a great day.
- Okay, I just need one more
signature from you right here.
And then this is the total amount
that was left in your name.
- Oh, wow, I'm shocked.
I had no idea my dad had
listed me as a beneficiary.
- Well, you're all set.
You'll see the transfer in your account
within two to three business days.
- Thank you.
- Absolutely.
I feel like I should.
Have a good rest of your day.
- Thanks, you as well.
- Didn't see that coming, huh?
- It still doesn't seem real.
- Yeah.
You know, I bet your dad would want us
to use this money to
help start our family.
What do you say?
- I think we should pray first
about what God wants us to do.
- Sounds like a plan.