This is the wrong house.
This is not the one
I told you about.
I know, but I've had my eye on
this place for a long time.
Yeah, but there's a family here.
I know.
Come on, the one down the
road is loaded with stuff.
Don't worry. We'll get there.
But first we're gonna
take care of this place.
We can't.
Why not?
There's a family here.
Right, well...
We all kind of voted...
We want it.
We're gonna go in.
No occupied homes.
Listen...
We take care of our own.
No occupied homes.
That's the deal.
Not anymore.
And now to show you
the vast and urgent
fight underway
by doctors and states
across this country...
States across this
country tonight.
Center for disease
control prevention
has issued a dire warning
about one of the most
dangerous strains of bacteria
which resists all
known antibiotics.
Let us begin this half hour...
With a call for urgent
action this morning.
To stop the spread...
Of a so-called
"nightmare super bug."
Trying to contain a
new kind of bacteria
normal antibiotics don't reach.
The fear and the challenge
is to keep these bacteria
from reaching the
general population.
The normal issue of giving
someone an antibiotic
and curing them becomes
very difficult.
National guard units
were activated...
The president now declaring
the outbreak a
national emergency.
We are facing a potentially
dangerous problem,
but we do have a
window of opportunity
to contain it.
All the institutions
have failed.
Everyone has gone into hiding.
The sickness spread quickly.
The cities were
hollowed out in weeks.
We tried to set up safe zones.
And quarantines.
But sooner or later,
someone infected would get in.
And wipe everyone out.
All you could do is
isolate yourself
and your family.
We followed the rules.
Stay hidden.
Stay quiet.
Stay alive.
Three times four...
Why don't you teach her
something she can actually use?
Like how to skin a rodent?
All right, try it again.
From the top.
- An improper...
- Improper...
Can I borrow your hands?
I'll set it up.
A real feast.
Mm-hmm.
Think it's okay?
The smoke?
Yeah.
Probably would have been
wise to wait an hour or so.
Hey. No peeking. You'll
ruin the surprise.
Ah, that looks great.
Here, hold on.
The candle...
Okay.
It's a birthday, right?
We gotta make sure it's special.
- Okay.
- Oh yeah.
Make a wish.
Can I eat it now?
Well, yeah. Get in there.
Happy birthday.
Eight years old.
- Mm.
Is it good?
Could this be your
birthday presents?
What is it?
It's an old... An old series
that used to be on the radio.
A long time ago.
Let's get it set up.
Terror.
You will know terror soon.
Our weekly series,
designed to frighten you
and bring you to the
edge of your seat.
And then withhold
the resolution.
This weekly study in terror
is brought to you by
candy toothpaste.
Okay, brush your teeth.
Get... no, get the
back ones too.
There you go.
Go swig and spit.
Now go to the bathroom.
Birdie.
Birdie, come on.
Come on.
I'm hungry.
Well, you had a lot
of food tonight.
Here you go.
But I already brushed my teeth.
Yeah, I'll let you
have a pass this time.
Let's have a little thanks
for what we've got.
Thank you for this day.
And thank you for
keeping us safe.
And for our little girl.
Big girl.
Our big girl. On her
eighth birthday.
Keep her healthy and strong.
Here...
Take it slow.
No, I didn't do it.
That's... this is
fucking bullshit, man.
I didn't do anything. I
didn't take anything.
I didn't steal anything.
I didn't do...
What's going on?
This little fucker
stole crackers
from the pantry.
I didn't. That's bullshit.
I didn't take anything.
Shut the fuck up.
Hey, rez.
What's up, guys?
- I didn't do it, rez.
- We found cracker crumbs
in this little shit's bed.
That's fucking bullshit.
- I didn't do it, rez.
- Okay. Okay.
Okay, we heard you.
What should I do?
They say you took food.
I didn't, rez. I swear...
Do you know what the penalty is
for taking food from our house?
I didn't steal, I
swear to god, rez.
- Come on...
- Shh.
Be quiet.
- I didn't...
- Hey, hey hey.
Hey, I believe you.
I do.
Thank you, rez. Thank you.
Do you know why?
Why?
Because I took the crackers.
Call everyone in.
We're gonna have a show.
Wait! What? No, rez!
No!
What's wrong, man?
Nothing.
You're not gonna try
to leave, are you?
Because you know I'll find you.
I won't be gone that long.
Maybe an hour, hour and a half.
I'd love some scotch.
Single malt. If they have it.
Uh, check the medicine cabinets.
Is anyone here?
Expired.
Mama don't mind.
Hello?
What are you doing, Jack?
We can't take him in.
I couldn't leave him there.
He would die.
We cannot take him in.
I couldn't leave
him there to die.
Do we know where he's from?
Who he's been running with?
That was a stupid move.
And where would you be if
we hadn't taken you in?
Russell?
As soon as my leg recovers,
I'm gonna make a move.
That's fine.
You're under no
obligation to stay.
Where're you going?
I'm gonna meet my brother.
Let me guess, it's a safe house?
Refuge stocked with food?
Well protected?
Doesn't exist.
Pick up something for birdie.
Okay. I will.
Oh, hey...
Take care of my girls.
How did you break it?
I was in an accident.
What kind of accident?
Haven't you ever
asked your father?
Dad never tells me anything.
He's just trying
to keep you safe.
Pass me the scissors.
You used to have
a family, right?
A little girl?
Yeah.
Hey.
You can have a water.
Don't mean to intrude just
looking for some food.
You're not gonna try
to leave are you?
Because you know I'll find you.
Who gave you permission?
Get off the step now!
You know what, asshole?
Did you insult my
kids and family?
I'm tired of being
beat on by people.
You come here all the time.
You have been all
warned not to come.
Off the property now!
Get off now!
- You don't shut up.
- Get off...
Shit.
Motherfucker.
I knew it was bullshit.
God, I remember when all
this shit fell apart.
Ain't nothing left in us.
Nothing at all.
We're just animals.
There's nothing left
here, there's nothing.
We're just fucking animals.
Do it, pussy.
Go ahead, try and
make yourself a man.
Do it.
Do what you came for.
Okay.
Do it!
Can me and Kyle go outside
in the back and run around?
I don't know, sweetie.
Your dad's not here.
I'll be quiet.
Mom, please, mom.
Please.
Shh.
Keep an eye on birdie,
I'm gonna get my coat.
Jack says she's
been doing better.
Well, Jack's in denial.
Get inside. Inside now.
What was she doing outside?
It was for a few minutes.
I don't care. She
doesn't go outside.
What's wrong with you?
I can't trust you?
Birdie, get upstairs.
Now!
Don't look at me
like I'm an asshole.
I heard her from a
thousand yards away.
Anyone else in the area did too.
Calm down.
I'm calm.
When I'm not here,
you're their safety.
When I am gone, you
stick to the rules.
You don't go outside.
Terror.
You will know terror.
He's in the house right now.
I know he's gonna kill me.
Just a moment, please.
Call the police. Call them now.
Now.
Help.
Did you hear that?
He's in the house. He's
in the house right now...
Stay here.
We're sorry.
We can't help you.
We don't have anything for you, pal.
Okay?
So how 'bout you fuck off,
unless you wanna get shot?
Just a guy looking
for some food.
Birdie, did I ever tell you
about the safari I went on?
- Mm-hmm.
- I did?
Did I tell you about
the serengeti one?
I did. Mm.
Do you know where
the serengeti is?
- Tanz...
- Tanzania.
That's right. Very good.
We just tuned in.
Birdie found it.
What do you think it is?
I don't know.
All right, turn it off.
Why?
Batteries.
Are you going to leave?
Yeah.
Where are you gonna go?
I'm gonna go meet my brother.
Where?
He lives in a house
with a bunch of people.
Look, we're almost
out of inhalers.
We have maybe three months left.
There's a bunch of
new subdivisions
on the other side
of the interstate.
I can scout out some new areas.
Jack.
We should go to decatur.
Decatur's bad news.
You don't know that.
I do know that.
There's nothing out there.
Back when everybody was
trying to get away...
Your dad ever explain to you
what was going on?
The plague.
Yeah.
Who are those people?
Birdie's not doing well,
her coughing's getting worse.
I just feel like we're
running out of time here.
Daddy.
There's a man standing outside.
- What are they doing?
- They're watching us.
We need to leave.
We need to get out of here.
- It's time to go.
- Go where?
To his brother's house.
Why are you filling her
head with this shit?
It's not shit.
It's a pipe dream.
It's not a pipe dream.
I told you, I don't want
you filling anyone's head
- with this bullshit.
- It's not bullshit.
You don't know what is outside.
Jack?
Got less than a
quarter of a tank.
You could make it 140.
Maybe 150 miles, if we're lucky.
If we can get it running.
Where are we going?
We're going to canton.
We're gonna have to go around
the perimeter of the city.
Should have enough gas.
Just hope the battery works.
Mom?
Come on, sweetie.
Jack?
Nell, let's get things packed.
Get the canned goods,
birdie's inhalers,
hats, blankets.
All right, let's move.
Let's get our stuff
in the truck.
All right, watch out, sweetie.
Get the garage door.
When this thing starts we're gonna
have to get out of here in a hurry.
Come on.
Please, come on.
Get the other battery.
Where's my radio?
Sweetie, I don't know. It's not
that important right now, we...
No, birdie. Birdie.
Birdie, come back there.
Jack.
What are you...
What are you doing?
Come on, let's go. We
gotta go, we gotta go.
Come on. Come on.
Get down.
Go.
What's the matter?
You're not happy to see me?
Okay, let's go.
Come on.
Come on. God damn it.
Come on. Okay.
Okay!
Door.
- Go Jack. Go.
- He's in. He's in.
Let's go. Let's go.
Fuck.
Son of a bitch.
How bad is it?
Son of a bitch, it's bad.
Fuck.
What's wrong with Kyle?
No, no, no, no, no...
You gotta keep going.
You gotta keep going. Just go.
Fuck.
How bad is it, Kyle?
It doesn't feel bad.
Do you feel like...
I don't know what
we can do, guys.
I mean, really.
We have no clean rags.
We have just...
We need alcohol.
I know. We gotta find something.
God damn it all.
Look, let's just get
some place safe.
We'll figure it out.
How you guys doing?
Just passing through.
About to leave.
Hold on.
Give me all your food
or I'll blow your
fucking face off.
Okay.
You better put that gun down.
Go on, you little shit.
He's lost a lot of blood.
We need to get him some help.
How are we doing on fuel?
The back roads cost us but
we didn't have a choice.
Couldn't go on the main roads.
So not good.
Our best bet, is to go and
meet up with my brother.
We're not going anywhere
until we figure out
what to do about that.
We have to do something
about that light.
I don't want to attract
unwanted visitors.
We can't carry him.
You go.
Take the truck.
Find your brother.
And then you come back for us.
No.
Everyone goes.
I'll wait here.
We stick together.
If we leave at dawn, I'll
send someone back for Kyle.
No one's getting left behind.
You can't wait here.
You can come back for me.
We already know that's
the only option.
Just... keep yourself covered.
We'll be back as soon
as we can, okay?
Hello, birdie.
Let's move.
- Here, two bags.
- Okay.
We'll cut through some of
these neighborhoods up ahead.
Okay?
Got a little hike ahead of us.
Still in the middle
of fucking nowhere.
Mom, can you tell me a story?
Oh, sweetie. I don't have
any good stories in me now.
Please.
The Princess and the
dark knight one.
Once upon a time,
there was a Princess
who was being pursued
by a dark knight.
And he wore big black armor
because he had been in so
many battles and wars,
on his planet.
Was the dark knight a man?
Half man, half machine.
Yeah. Yeah, he's half
man, half machine.
So he had this big,
thick black armor.
And a deep voice.
And he breathed like a...
Eh, kinda like Russell's
breathing right now.
I remember this.
We just turn into the woods.
It's a short hike
for you guys.
It's somewhere here.
The marker.
Come on. Just a little further.
Daddy, I'm tired.
Come on, birdie.
We gotta keep going.
No.
Come on, birdie.
Hey. Does any of this
look familiar to you?
I've never been this far.
Whoa.
Let's make camp for the night.
We should rest.
Come on, right here.
I think we should stop.
We'll make camp here tonight.
Come on. We're close.
It's just over the next pass.
We are lost.
It's the last...
It's the last hill.
Come on.
Here, come on.
There you go.
There you go. Okay.
Where are we going?
- Calm down. Calm down.
- God damn it.
We left Kyle in
the goddamn barn.
All right.
Oh, come on.
Stop here.
Okay.
Come here.
This isn't it.
- We're done.
- Here sweetie.
All right.
All right, come on.
All right. Come on, sweetie.
Sorry.
Don't say that.
We're gonna take it
day by day, okay?
Check that out.
Get down.
Pass me the water bottle.
We need water, right?
Give me the bottles.
I'll backtrack and I'll
catch up with you guys.
I'll get it.
I don't want you
tripping over yourself.
Nell. Nell!
Oh, fuck.
Which way did they go?
Where did they go?
Nell!
There's a cold front
coming through today.
We'll make sure we're parked
as close to the road by sundown.
No, we should make it.
I don't know about
with this baggage.
Don't be scared.
No reason to be scared.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Not like that cripple, see.
He came at me,
okay?
What I did was self-defense.
I believe in looking
after myself.
I wanna look after you, too.
And I wanna keep you safe.
I wanna give you love.
I wanna keep you warm.
Get your fucking hand off her.
I've got something clean
to put in that dirty
mouth of yours.
Step back. Step back!
- Brother...
- Drop it!
- Put it down.
- Brother, brother...
- It's all right, brother.
Brother, it's okay.
Okay? Calm down.
There's no reason we
can't share here.
There's two of them.
This one, she's... She's
big and she's strong.
You can do what you
want with her.
But this one, she's weak.
She's weak.
You don't want her.
Put the gun down.
Put it down, brother.
You can be saved,
if you put the gun down.
Nell, you okay?
Brother, you want
to save yourself,
you can share the feeling.
Daddy!
Now it looks like
you've walked yourself
into a world of
trouble, brother.
But don't you worry.
I wouldn't let you leave
this world alone.
Which one of these females
you wanna take with you?
Huh?
The little one?
- You want the strong one?
- Don't...
- Please. -Or do you
want the weak one?
You want me to make
your mind up for you?
- No.
- Which one?
Cat got your tongue, mister?
Huh?
Maybe I'll make your
mind up for you?
No.
Told you to repent, brother.
Were you with my brother?
Were you with my
brother, Russell?
♪ Somebody take the
keys away from me ♪
♪ No, I don't care who you are ♪
♪ don't let me get
back to my car ♪
♪ how the hell did I
get to abilene? ♪
♪ Two tanks of gasoline ♪
♪ driving two cars a scene ♪
♪ don't blame me
♪ my heartbreak
heals real slow ♪
♪ somebody pick me
up some listerine ♪
♪ but only give me one sip ♪
♪ let it roll off of my lip ♪
♪ somebody keep a
wary eye on me ♪
♪ don't let me get
to that door ♪
♪ though I may
reel, I may roar ♪
♪ don't blame me
♪ my heartbreak
heals real slow ♪
♪ Unless you wanna
take a ride... ♪