Go on then, Miss Dudu,
have a nice working day.
Are you going to the coffee house again,
Nedret?
Where else!
Run, run!
Nobody has been there before you.
The owner of the coffee house
will put up your statue in the square.
With a chair stuck on your ass.
Well, very good,
What else would I want?
Have a nice working day.
Thank you, brother.
Where is Huseyin?
Is it you who’s opening the shop again?
He'll come, he'll come.
He is a little sick today.
As if he really is sick!
Instead of telling me that
he'll wake up in the evening at best.
They drank last night again, right?
What can I do?
Shall I leave the shop closed?
What do you mean by
what can I do?
Is it me instead of you
who is going to do it!? You are a father.
You are going to take him
before you and talk to him.
You are going to pull on his ear.
Isn't it a shame that you are getting up
every morning in this age!?
Don't open it one morning and
let the cuckold hit the panic button.
-Right, goodbye.
-Goodbye.
If you give him cloth,
he'll ask for the lining.
Look at this.
It doesn't matter if there are
dustbins all around.
What one needs is good manners.
Don't put it down,
it'll lose its abundance.
God bless you, Mr. Esref.
You are a johnny-on-the-spot.
If the devil lost his hand in my bag,
he wouldn't be able to find it back.
Good morning.
-Were you coming to me?
-No.
I got a little bored.
I couldn't fall asleep, either.
Is it your head again?
Do you drink water?
-Of course, I do.
-Drink it abundantly.
It is usually caused by thirst.
-Come on, let me make us coffee.
-No, let me go to the seaside.
You can go later on,
the sea will be there forever.
It's been standing there for ages.
Let me make you a bitter coffee
so that you can open your eyes.
Maybe It'll stop your ache.
Well, I'm saying so but you
haven't seen a doctor yet, Mr. Esref.
Why would I?
I am just fine.
You are, you are but...
I don't know.
You have my deceased mother's
stubbornness.
Just like you...
...she would bury her head
like an ostrich...
...when we talked about
seeing a doctor.
Your mother was 100 years' old
when she died, though.
Fair enough.
-May she rest in peace.
See, she wanted grace.
Oh, great Mrs. Mukaddes.
My dear mother.
Are these new?
I bought them from Izmir.
Its linen is nice.
Put sugar in it if you can, please
New tricks to old dogs.
It is so this morning.
A sweet morning.
What a beautiful saying.
Now, let me take a picture
of the two cups side by side.
Then, I will post it on my page.
And I'll write “A sweet morning” under it.
My customers love it.
I have 3572 followers.
Wonderful.
If your son followed me, too...
...at least 1000 people would
come upon me.
He is busy.
He must not have seen it.
I'm only joking.
Why would he deal with me?
He is a busy man.
My son...
Are you up?
Did you wake up?
Are you awake?
Sleep now,
Fatos will be here soon.
Well done, my son.
Right, I'm up.
Why did he cry?
-Hasn't Fatos arrived yet?
-No. Okay, I'm leaving now.
You are late, Fatos.
The metrobus hit the wirey things.
They made us wait a bit.
Quick, Uras has woken up.
I'll be there right now.
Thank you, God bless your hands.
You're doing it again.
Your money is not valid here, Mr. Esref.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
You bring good luck to me, anyway.
When you come,
this shop swarms with people.
Come on, Leman,
what luck are you talking about?
I wish this good luck touched me too.
How can it touch you more?
Not only here, did you not sew the clothes
of the whole of Izmir?
Didn't the villager, the city-dwellers
run to you?
Was there anything better than your art?
Even now, all of those Haute Coutures
can't hold a candle to you.
Come on, Leman,
what remains of my art?
Don't talk like a mad person.
You are not saying that you are lazy
and that you loaf about.
Empty excuses.
Good morning, sister.
Good morning.
Where is my red dress?
You promised.
I was going to wear it
on Safiye's wedding.
The girl got married and
had her second baby.
Anyway, dear.
I'll wear it on her children's wedding.
The red dress would really suit
me well when I am 80.
Sister Leman...
...my mother wants
50 buns with olives.
It is due for this afternoon.
Has your mother opened
a public soup-kitchen?
What's 50?
Are you asking the British royal family
to join you for tea?
Look, tell that mother of yours...
...I heard she was saying she made
the buns to her guests.
That Perihan shouldn't make me
fly into a rage.
I'd let her lie out in the middle of
the downtown.
Dad...
...the harbour is this way.
You are right.
Okay, there is no problem.
They are the script crew, let them wait,
what's their job?
They’re going to get out of here and
rush an episode, following your directives.
They stopped the set.
They are afraid that we’re going
to go empty this week.
What can I do, Ozge?
Shall I wear wings and fly?
The traffic is not moving at all.
Hang up! Don't make me break your
heart in the morning.
What's he waiting for?
Sound the horn for him!
Good morning, Mr. Kaan.
-Good morning Mr. Kaan.
-Good morning.
My notes are zipped on the desktop.
Examine it carefully and then,
send the e-mail.
Don't bring disgrace on me
like the last time, Ozge.
Ozge, I know this look very well.
It's a look that says,...
...“Do I really deserve this cruelty just
because I wrote “their” instead of “they are”?
Get angry, upset with me as much as
you like now...
...but one day,
you will thank me.
In that “they are”...
...lies a big career, a big life.
You will understand it, then.
Are you hungry?
Shall I order a toast?
There's no need.
Right, good morning, friends,
from a horrible and...
...disgusting Istanbul morning.
-Good morning.
-Welcome.
Let me point out that it'll be
a bloody morning.
That's why we're going to
speak clearly and frankly.
You know that this is
for the sake of our job.
Don't take this personally but...
...if we were to shoot
the last episode you wrote...
...we would be killing the series
which is...
...already on shaky ground.
Let me tell you that.
Good luck.
Thank you.
What did you do?
Have you caught anything?
Brother Cemal!
What happened to the man?
Mr. Esref!
Brother Esref!
Something happened to the man.
Mr. Esref!
Get closer, get really closer.
The greatest problem in our series is
the male character.
The boy has no dynamic, friends.
Especially that last episode.
What is that?
He's sending the girl flowers,
feeding the cats on the street.
What did you do?
There is no reason not to have the loser hold
hands with the kids in the park and sing.
Mr. Kaan, stray animals are receiving a
positive feedback from the viewers.
We used the flower because...
...he was a bit firm with the girl
in the previous episode.
Miss Rana, these are lukewarm events.
The viewers do not even care
about these.
The female viewers like things
like that now, Mr. Kaan.
For them, the classical male typing is--
Is that so?
Where is that female viewer
who likes characters like this?
I cannot see them myself.
We are number 6 in total,
the rating is 3.80...
...It says 10.30 share in this list.
Where is that female viewer?
I can't see her.
I wonder where they have gone to!?
Mr. Kaan, when we look at
the viewers' survey...
...we see that women no longer accept men
with macho attitudes.
Miss Rana, they are 3-5 people.
Those women who live in your neighbourhood
and don't watch television.
We have nothing to do
with them anyway.
Look, you're playing
for the cinema viewers again.
I tell you all the time,
they are different.
Miss Rana, are you kidding me?
Are you living in Norway or something?
Or perhaps you are watching BBC
every night.
Have you ever wondered and looked
at the series that are above us?
There is a bloodbath there.
Okay, now I'm not saying
let's give a gun to our guy...
...and have him kill
whomever comes his way.
But you literally portrayed
a sexless character.
I'm sorry I'm going to speak clearly.
Let a few women shout that
they don't want to see a macho man...
...or shout about the women's rights or
the state of being an individual...
...the rest of the women,
when they go across television,...
...they want to see a man.
A man.
And for two hours, they forget about
their sluggish husbands...
...and kiss the man in the series
in their heads.
And that's our job.
To give them a soft porn material.
What happened?
Did you take offense by this sentence?
I'm sorry but that's
the gist of the matter.
I wish it wasn't like this...
...I wish we didn't work
for such an audience.
But unfortunately, we do.
This is our sea, it's shallow.
Shallow.
Don't expect anything deep, please.
How is he?
Good, good.
He's being given serum now.
He just collapsed suddenly as
he was shouting at me.
I didn't understand
what happened.
Thank you so much,
Captain Kemal.
I hope he gets well soon.
I'm here, you can go on your way.
Call his son.
He really abandoned you.
Let him come and take a look.
He is stubborn, you know.
He said not to call him but you
call him secretly, anyway.
-I hope he gets well soon.
-Thank you.
What happened, Mr. Esref?
It's nothing, don't fuss.
I am good.
I blacked out and I fainted.
We can't have this bird here,
though, sister Leman.
Like she is going to break the cage
and eat us, God protect us!
The man wanted it.
She is his faithful friend.
What happened?
What did the doctor say?
Well, what should she say?
Clean air and plenty of food.
Don't do this, Esref.
Is that a serum?
What's happening?
What's his state?
I don't know.
You can ask the doctor.
We were just talking about you now.
How have you been, Mr. Esref?
Good, how have you been?
I'm going to get up once this is over.
I'm taking up space here for nothing.
There are sick patients, doctor.
Doctor, let's go outside
to talk for a bit.
Of course.
Tell me everything without keeping
anything from me.
Tell me so that I can watch my step
with this stubborn goat.
I guess it's not an ordinary faint.
He was having an epileptic seizure
when the captain found him.
What they told me is that his jaw was
locked and he was shivering.
As far as I know,
he's been having severe headaches...
...and he's been forgetting
stuff for a long time.
The same old same old.
We've gone back to the beginning again.
Are we not going to do something
we like in this country?
Never mind. We'll copy and paste
the series from last year.
Shake your head and
get your pay check.
Someone runs away with the girl and
the boy saves her in this episode.
Just write it away.
-Only for the sake of our job.
-For the sake of our job.
-May it be easy.
-Thank you.
I'm telling him right away.
What happened?
Mr. Ilker is expecting you
in his room.
Can you bring my phone?
Hello.
-Is Mr. Ilker available?
-Yes, of course, he's expecting you.
Why have you panicked so much, boy?
Sit down, child, sit down.
If I hadn't seen the reports
that are before me, maybe.
But let our competitors panic, Kaan.
We thought you were abroad.
I was in a meeting.
You asked for me suddenly,
I'm unprepared, Mr. Ilker.
We're not eating men up here.
Well, sometimes we do but...
...you are not one of them
You are the head of the
most successful unit in this channel.
Our dramas are doing really good.
Thank you.
-I want to jump right into the subject.
-Yes.
We have two subjects.
The first one...
...what do you say to being
the head of the team...
...that will go to Los Angeles Festival
next week?
I don't trust this sales unit much.
Because they are inexperienced.
I think you should talk to the customers
one on one...
...as you are selling our series.
I'm sure you'll come back having
sold all of them like a monster.
What do you say?
Great, I mean it would be great.
-I'm glad.
-Great.
The second one is that
this place...
...deserves a new chief editor.
I mean, Mr. Ersoy is a
bit old for this place now.
I want a young and
dynamic person like you...
...to create storms over the viewer.
What do you say?
I mean, oh, God.
Of course, with pleasure.
Thank you.
Of course, these are staying
between us for now.
Of course.
I will tell this to Ersoy
in an appropriate way.
He is my old friend after all.
See? We are not asking the men
we'll eat to come up here.
What is it?
Are you upset about Ersoy?
He's a valuable person.
I learned a lot from him in the past.
5 years ago, I went through
the same scene with him in this room.
He felt nothing about his old boss.
You are a good boy, Kaan.
I'd like to congratulate
those who raised you.
But don't forget...
...the place for sentimentality
in this profession...
...is only in those series you make.
Don't you ever, ever project these
onto your real life.
Because your burden doubles
from this day on.
You are going to work really hard.
Anyway...
...one day we'll talk about all these
over dinner.
About that sentimental matter too.
Don't let the people downstairs
be without you until that day.
Make them work really hard.
Don't worry.
Okay, then.
-Let's hope for the best.
-Thank you.
Hello, Kaan.
I am Leman.
I know, sister Leman.
What happened?
Is it my father?
Don't you bustle now.
Listen to me for a bit.
Kaan...
...he called himself.
As if he felt it in his bones.
-Sister Leman?
-Yes?
What's going on? Where is my father?
Is he with you?
I'm giving the phone to him now,
talk to him yourself.
Hello, dad?
Hello, son.
It's nothing.
They bustled.
I felt dizzy a little bit.
It's my blood pressure, you know.
It's because of the heat.
Kaan, we are in the hospital.
He fainted and he shivered and locked.
The doctor said.
Dad, why are you not calling me
right away?
Why would I call you, son?
I just felt dizzy a little bit.
We can't call you every time I sneeze,
you are busy there.
Is it the blood pressure, dad?
I mean are you sure?
I know you.
I am going to call your doctor
and hear what's going on from her.
It's not going to happen this way.
Dad, can you give the phone
to sister Leman, please?
I am going to talk to her.
Have her send me the number of the doctor.
-Son, there is no need.
-Dad, please.
Don't object. Could you...
...could you give the phone
back to sister Leman?
Hello, Kaan.
Sister Leman...
...could you please send me
the number of the doctor?
Okay, okay.
Let me go and ask for it, then.
I'll text you later on but...
...texting is really hard for me.
Anyway, maybe I'll call you
and say it myself.
Are we on the outs with each other?
Of course, we are.
Aren't you ashamed? A big man like you,
running away from the hospital.
Well, Leman, don't tire me out.
Look at this beauty.
Let us enjoy this a little bit.
Stop talking about the hospital
and such.
Look...
...I hope you and that doctor
didn't make Kaan bustle.
Don't let the kid get away from his job.
I'm saying this but...
...I made you get away
from your job today.
Don't talk crazy. There’s not much
business during the week anyway.
You were going to make 50 buns,
I'm talking about that.
Karma rocks.
It serves that Perihan right.
She's telling people that
she cooked the buns.
She should have made it herself today.
I hope she gave herself away.
I cannot believe this.
Hello.
I was just looking at that now.
Look, don't tell me you've liked it
or we'll be cross.
What is that?
She literally lifted the bag and
shoved it in the camera.
Of course, so that we can
see the brand.
She's so graceless.
Irem, close it down and
go back to your study.
Unbelievable, mom.
The school ends in 10 days,
what study are you talking about?
Okay, you can do it but
in a graceful way.
With that body like a log...
No, girl, they won't learn it.
I hate you.
I heard that. And your father will
hear it too when he comes.
Exactly, exactly.
They'll always be provincial.
Is it so hard to be a little bit graceful?
I'll tell you what.
It is the fault of the person
who brought them among us.
Ceren got cross with them,
and now we have to deal with them.
No, honey, it's too late.
We're going to make them grow distant
from us slowly.
My dad came.
I'm hanging up, kisses.
You are happy because
your saviour came but...
...still, you have to finish your study.
What is it, Kaan?
Is it about work?
What's this?
I don't know.
Fatos brought it.
Yea, we call it beetroot pickle.
They sent it from the village.
It's really good.
What are you doing?
What a shame!
Irem, you are really trying my patience.
Go and look after your brother.
Tell me, what's going on?
My dad fainted today.
Why?
How?
I don't know.
It's not his blood pressure or anything.
It's something else.
I talked to his doctor.
How is he now?
He's fine now.
He was being given serum and all.
The doctor wants to talk to me
face to face.
He couldn't stay there and
he ran away from the hospital.
Typical dad.
Wait, don't worry right away.
Maybe it's not something important.
Hello, Ozge...
You are buying me a ticket to Izmir
in the early hours like 7 o'clock.
From Ataturk airport.
Arrange a car for me...
...from the Izmir airport.
The car will be with me the whole day.
I will try to go and
come back in a day.
The return...
What shall we do about the return?
Arrange it for 6-7 o'clock.
Okay, we'll talk tomorrow anyway.
By the way, you are going to
book the return tickets for two people.
You have my father's ID details, right?
Okay, you are buying for him.
Yes, he'll be in the business class too.
You do all of these and then
send me a screenshot.
I'll tell you later, okay.
What am I doing?
Yes, love, what are you doing really?
We should have sat down
and talked about it.
What can I do?
Shall I not go?
No, go, of course...
Anyway, wash your face,
get comfortable.
We'll talk after dinner.
I hope you become 220 pounds, mom.
-Good evening.
Dad.
The salt is here.
You've already brought it.
Sure.
Are you here?
These weren't eaten.
I thought I'd come here so that
we can eat it together.
-Are you available?
-I'm not.
I'm going to go and ask for a girl's
hand in marriage.
Who would give their daughter to you,
you stubborn goat!
I think you remembered
your deceased father.
Don't open that subject now.
You made mousaka, good.
Let me make a salad right away.
Hello, friends.
Welcome to my channel.
I'm going to play my new song
for you today.
As you all know,
I'm not very good at the guitar but...
...I'm still trying.
I hope you like it.
The lyrics belong to me too.
By the way, girls,
don't forget that...
...we are making a good luck charm
this evening.
I hope one of the great Amazons,
I mean, in music...
...one of the whole women warriors
can hear me.
Tell me the truth.
You and the doctor,
you didn't ask Kaan to come here, right?
Yes, we did.
I am relieved now.
What about it?
You'll get to see your son.
Is that bad?
Didn't you miss your son?
I missed him,
how can one not miss his child?
Look, every cloud has a silver lining.
They've been saying they’re going to come
for these past two summers...
...but they didn't.
Somehow, they managed to go to Bodrum,
Dalyan, though.
They kept putting photos up...
...from the ships and the yachts.
Didn't I see it?
I did.
It's all because of that sinister-looking
bride but I'm not saying it.
I'm sorry but...
...no one should ignore their father
this much.
He has a job, what can he do?
He made his life with great difficulty.
He dealt with so many things.
I am proud of him.
He was this big...
...when his mother passed away.
Now, let's give you your right.
You raised him.
You were a sister to him but...
...it's hard being
without a mother, Leman.
He didn't bend his head for once.
He didn't upset me for once.
While everybody's sons would
break glasses, stone dogs...
...he...
...stayed at this table.
He studied his lessons.
I am proud of him.
You be proud of him, too.
I am, dear.
Why wouldn't I?
Be.
-You count as his mother.
-I do, don't I?
See, this is our destiny.
Some of them are gone...
...it's just us now at this table...
...talking about the dead and the living.
It didn't happen like that,
it happened like this.
Thank God for this, too.
Turns out we have...
...come to help each other
out into this world.
Thank God for this.
Oh, well...
...you made me cry.
I'm going.
Don't drink too much, okay?
Or if you do, I'll scratch your eyes out.
Go to sleep, have some rest.
Kaan is coming tomorrow morning.
We talked, you'll be in my place,
father and son.
He'll be in my place at 9.
Well, I'm going now.
Where are you going?
We were having a nice conversation.
-We'll talk later on, you're tired.
-You know.
-Good night to you.
-Good night to you too.
Hello, Ozge, I've just landed.
How are things there?
Is she coming too?
She was going to send
her assistant?
Let's do it like this,
you gather the group, you start...
...and video call me
two minutes later, okay?
No, tell the truth!
Tell them his father got sick
and that it was urgent.
Exaggerate the situation.
Create a case of victimhood.
Turn the situation to our advantage.
Believe me, it's not so hard, Ozge.
I'll be on the road for one
and a half hours.
You start the talk,
and then call me right away.
Okay?
Okay, bye.
Dad...
...a tie?
A tie, right?
No need, you are not going
to the shop anymore.
Dad...
...the wallet.
Your work cannot be wasted on
a Sunday night.
We have a very good first episode
in our hands.
You know my notes.
There are some filling scenes
we want to add.
If they are shot, too...
...this will be a fantastic episode.
Mr. Kaan, our director is
sending you his greetings.
He is in the set right now.
He is very sure of the scenes
he has shot.
He thinks there is no need
for any additional scenes.
He thinks that it would lower the tempo
in the first episode...
...and that we should trust the
viewers' intelligence a little bit.
Is that so?
Miss Zeynep,
let me put it like this...
...in our profession...
...I've always ignored the
viewers' intelligence completely.
The thing you are telling me doesn't
exist. It's a made up world.
If there was that intelligence,
we'd be doing something else now.
I'm sorry but this is how it is.
He is a young,
enthusiastic friend of ours...
...but I cannot throw away a project
that's worth a billion...
...out of the street, just because of that
enthusiasm on making art.
It'd make you lose money and
it'd make us lose time.
If need be, we can show him the door
and find another friend ...
...who can do the job and
make us get the ratings.
Is it ringing, is it busy?
I don't understand who he's talking to.
Look, maybe he called you.
It says there is a missed call.
See, you never hear it.
Adnan, the cheesemaker.
What is this?
Why would Adnan call me?
He sees me every day.
Turn right and stop on the pavement
on the left.
I'm sorry I have to hang up now.
We'll talk about these face to face
when I come back.
Don't worry,
everything will be great.
They arrived.
Go and welcome them.
Don't forget,
it's all for the sake of our job.
You get on with it now.
May it be easy.
Dad.
Son.
Are you okay, dad?
I am.
Welcome, welcome.
Welcome, my boy.
We have been waiting
for a long time.
Oh, dear, welcome.
Come on, come.
Come on in.
You are hungry, right?
Come in.
We'll have breakfast together.
No, brother, thank you.
I am full.
Have a cup of tea at least.
-I'll deal with it.
-Dad, come.
Salih, bring a chair.
Sister Leman,
can you show me the socket?
-Well, it's normal.
-Excuse me?
I'll deal with it.
You sit down.
Shall I give you a cup of tea?
I'll have coffee, please.
I bought the machine.
I can make those
fashionable things now.
Latte, espresso, cappuccino.
I learned the names
and the machine but...
...it has been too difficult.
I'll have a double espresso, then.
Sister Leman...
...he looks well but how is he?
We'll talk later on.
Has the shop changed?
I don't know.
But it looks really good,
that's for sure.
I'll give him this and come back.
The boy must be hungry.
Young man...
...take this.
Why didn't you come in?
Everything changes in this life...
...except my father.
I know that.
-Uncle?
-Dad!
We can't impose sanction
on the patients, unfortunately.
You father is the sweetest man but...
...he is a bit interesting.
-You know better, of course.
-Well, he is.
I couldn't diagnose neither his character
nor his illness.
We had a hard time giving him the serum
that day.
He just left.
It's a bit your duty too.
Can't you take a few days off from work
and stay here?
No.
It's not possible.
No, son.
What do you mean no?
It's your house too.
You have your order in the house.
You have your wife and your kids.
I'd be a burden to you there.
Dad, why did you say that?
I can't leave this place.
I've got business here.
I've got things to do in the house.
There's Dudu and there's you.
Me?
Dad, I won't be able to stay.
That's why I'm taking you with me.
-I didn't say that.
-What did you say?
Don't worry about Dudu.
I will look after her like she's mine.
She'd be a friend to me in the shop.
You are not going to be there forever.
What's with the gloom?
Surely, you'll come back.
Dad, your grandchildren.
Look, Uras grew up.
The last time you saw him,
he was a baby.
Haven't you missed them at all?
I have.
You were going to bring them
last summer?
I really long for them.
Then?
I'd be an extra there.
I'd give you trouble.
My child, human flesh is heavy to bear.
Dad, I'd carry you on my shoulders
if it came to that.
Okay?
Agreed?
Okay, we're done.
Come on, let's prepare your suitcase.
I'll take these.
-Don't forget the key.
-I've got the key, don't worry.
The car is there, Mr. Kaan,
it can't make it to the street.
Don't feed her with the same thing
every day.
You are going to give her roasted and
salted sunflower seed and red apple.
Put her in a place where
she can see the street.
She likes the spaciousness.
Don't worry.
I'll look up on the internet...
...I'll write parrot care and
learn all of it by heart, don't worry.
She is not like the others.
You are going to talk to her.
You are going to have a heart-to-heart
talk with her. Don't forget.
I won't.
That's it.
Don't you ever forget.
I won't.
Dad, come on.
We're expecting good news from you.
Godspeed.
I entrust him to you.
Come and go with best luck.
Okay, Miss Dudu.
See you later.
Oh, my beautiful Izmir.
It shakes like this from time to time.
You are not afraid, right?
I was a parachute jumper in the military.
Have you forgotten?
Why would I be afraid?
Let the plane be afraid of me.
Right.
A strange uneasiness has come
over me lately.
After the kids were born.
When you have a child,
you think of them, right?
Are you going to read all of this?
Unfortunately.
You do your work.
I am comfortable here.
All is good.
I wish I had taken the front seat.
We both sat in the back,
it'll be a disgrace to the man.
It's a showy car.
Son, was there any need for all
this expenditure?
Dad, it is the car of the company.
They must be the ones giving
the driver his pay check, then.
That's good, then.
Sound the horn like this,
all of you.
As if the road will be cleared
when you sound the horn.
See their line of thinking!
We should go to Kordon,
to Pasaport tomorrow and have some tea.
We haven't been there in ages.
Dad...
...we are in Istanbul, not Izmir.
Of course.
Mrs. Ece, I'm leaving?
Are you saying anything?
I've been out all day,
I couldn't talk to you.
Actually, there is something.
Don't be afraid,
It's nothing important.
Kaan, he's bringing his dad.
He's going to stay here for a while.
I don't know for how long.
He's going to take him
to the doctor and all.
-I hope he gets better soon.
-Thank you.
That's why you’re going to be spending
more time with us.
-Talk to those in your house.
-I will.
I'll tell them, it won't be a problem.
Look, if it's going to be hard for you,
I can arrange an assistant for you.
No.
I can do it myself.
Okay, if you say so.
Then, let me put another plate
on the table.
Okay, I'll do it.
-We're here.
-Welcome.
Thank you.
How was your journey?
It was good, we flew like a bird.
People are like birds.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, my girl, thank you.
There you go.
That's very nice of you. I forgot to put
my slippers because of hurry.
I'm sorry it's not your size
but I'll deal with it.
-You are Fatos, right?
-Yea, I am Fatos.
Thank you, my girl.
Where are my grandchildren?
My girl, look, your grandfather has come.
Uras is sleeping, he'll be waking up soon.
I'll bring him.
And Irem must have her headphones on.
I'll bring her now.
-You go ahead.
-Come, dad.
Let me wash my hands and my face.
Come, take a breath,
you can do it later.
Irem, Irem!
Your grandfather has come.
Come along.
Your grandfather has come, run.
-She has come.
-Welcome, granddad.
Praise be!
She grew up
and became a young girl in two years.
We're talking on the phone but
you can't tell.
And you put pictures on that thing,
Leman is showing me but...
...when I see you like this now,
Look, how beautiful you are.
Really?
And you look very stylish.
Come on, take me to the boy,...
...I'll take a look at him
without waking him up.
Okay.
You are talking funny again.
How is it funny?
You can leave, Fatos.
Let me cook the other fish
and then leave.
Praise be! Look at my grandson.
He sleeps, he wakes up.
That's what he does.
And he thinks he's talking but
he's making ridiculous noises.
Is that a way to talk about your brother?
He's little now, he'll learn.
This is very showy.
Are you playing it?
Well, I'm learning.
If I can find a chance
because of my mother.
I was cross with them for three days,
I didn't talk to both of them.
Then, they had to buy the guitar.
Actually, my mother told me to take
piano lessons but...
...I am into guitars.
I have a free spirit.
I've been obsessed with the flower
children of the 60's, 70's lately.
Janis Joplin and so on.
And we have Sena Sener here.
She wrote her first song
when she was 15.
I want to write my own songs like her.
I have 2-3 years.
And then there is my Nazan.
The way she says
“let's go away from here.”
I know, she says
Truly, granddad,
let's go away from here.
Let's go to a world that is more just.
Let's leave this place.
Praise be, girl,
you know so many things.
Go on, play for me,
Let me have a listen.
Granddad,
you must be loving us truly.
Why wouldn't I, girl?
Why would you say such a thing?
You are really valuable for me.
Take it.
Irem, to dinner, come on.
Take your granddad with you too.
We're coming, we're coming.
Son, my child.
He's very quiet.
Can't he talk yet?
He's going to talk a bit late,
they say it's a sign of intelligence.
I mean he refuses to talk as long as
he can't talk as good as us.
You are talking to him, right?
He can't learn otherwise.
Sure, for example, I have a session
with him every morning for half an hour.
But he only learned to say “yea”.
And that's from Fatos.
You eat your food.
Wait, let me give you some.
We are not strangers, my girl.
I am your father.
Of course, daddy.
Irem, you still haven't touched anything
on your plate. Let's not start again.
Mom, I don't like salmon.
Irem, you're going to eat everything
in that plate, okay?
Dad, I already have an extra four pounds.
Who, you?
My girl, you look like a garpike.
What extra are you talking about?
What's a garpike?
Garpike is a kind of fish.
If you use it to refer to a person,
it means that the person is thin, skinny.
Gars or garpike are members of the
Lepisosteiformes...
...they're found in warm
and hot waters, and--
Irem!
Enough is enough!
You are doing this not to eat your food.
Come on, eat it.
Don't play with your food.
Look how delicious things
your mom has cooked.
She didn't cook them.
Fatos did.
Irem, they are cooking together.
You're just saying so because
you want my granddad to think so.
-I'm not buying it.
-Irem!
Son.
-Irem, come back to the table.
-Son.
Dad, I'm sorry.
She's become so impertinent lately.
She's making me do the things
I wouldn't do.
She is young, of course,
things like this will happen.
You should take the path of
least resistance a little bit.
My girl, take Uras.
My girl, what happened to you?
-Did something make you ill?
-No.
-Please, don't let my mother know.
-We all ate the same thing.
-Don't ever tell my mom about this.
-Okay.
I won't, my girl.
What happened, granddad?
Granddad?
Are you okay?
What happened? What is it?
Irem...
...what are you doing here?
Nothing.
My granddad was consoling me.
She's okay now.
She was a bit angry at her father.
Go on, girl.
Go on, go this way.
I'm managing the whole farm
and the city.
My dad lets me play it
for half an hour every day.
Because it grows
my commercial intelligence.
We put these on the plane and
earn money.
Look, the train has come.
They want tomatoes.
So, this means we are going to sow
the tomatoes in the soil...
...and wait for it to grow
for two hours.
They will be uploaded tomorrow.
My girl, can you grow tomatoes there?
You should plant the tomato in the soil.
I already know the man but
I thought I'd not call at this hour.
Do you know how many days
you have to wait?
It also needs watering and fertilizer.
This is a game of it.
I know it's a game but what use it is
as long as you can't eat it!
You come to me and we'll plant
the real one with you in our garden.
Really?
Dad...
...your appointment is arranged
for tomorrow.
The doctor's appointment.
You make up with your daughter and
I'll see the doctor tomorrow.
Why, what happened?
Okay, you are forgiven.
We are going to get up early
tomorrow morning, dad.
This is a very valuable professor.
He'll do a thorough check up.
What happened, granddad?
Are you sick?
No, it's a general check-up.
Don't worry.
It's nothing, my beautiful girl.
I am as fit as a flea.
Don't you have turnip in that game?
Go on, plant some.
Irem, come on, it's time to go to bed.
You got really tired all day.
Let me show you your room
if you want to rest.
Okay, thank you.
Here it is.
We didn't touch your suitcases
so as not to give you discomfort.
You can settle yourself.
Dad, you have a bathroom here.
It'll make you feel comfortable.
We put some clean towels, as well.
All is good.
You can call out
if you need anything.
No, what would I need?
-Good night.
-Good night, my girl.
It's showy, praise be.
Good.
Dad, your water is here.
-If you get thirsty during the night.
-Okay.
Shall I turn on the television?
Maybe you'll fall asleep with it.
No, there's no need.
I'll fall asleep, don't worry.
I almost forgot.
Sister Leman sent a picture.
-What was the name of your parrot?
-Dudu.
Look, she sent a picture of Dudu.
She put her in a showy spot.
She's enjoying herself.
Dudu girl, why have you
forgotten me so fast?
Thank her.
-Okay, then, I--
-Son...
...don't think about me.
I'll be sleeping tonight,
being proud of you.
It's true, right?
You came here with a suitcase.
Istanbul is a big city.
It could spit one out on the floor when
the occasion arises.
But, look...
...you settled down, your wife,
your children, your job.
You did all of these on your own.
I am proud of you.
Thank you, dad.
Thanks to you.
-Well, then, goodnight.
-Goodnight.
Istanbul is a big city.
It spits one out on the floor.
I'll be worried about you.
Don't go, son.
Why is Izmir not enough?
It's very close.
Dad, like I told you...
...I can't do my job here.
Did I study for four years for nothing?
There are three tiny, local channels.
You can't grow in your job here.
So you insist on drowning
in the big sea.
What can I say?
You know.
She slammed the door and left.
She said she doesn't want to see
them ever again.
She said may you get no benefit from
the bracelet and the money.
I called, it was off.
I sent a message to Kaan.
We've arrived.
You know they make us turn our
phones off in the plane.
You are good, right?
Are you comfortable?
I am good.
Don't worry about me.
How are your grandchildren?
They must have grown up.
That's why I called.
Say it.
I've found Irem a little strange
this time.
What do you mean?
She had a row with her father.
She got angry, left the table.
She went to the bathroom. I saw her
making herself throw up with her finger.
I hope it's not something psychological.
Like she's punishing herself
because of her anger.
She is so thin.
She made me swear so I can't tell her
mother or father.
Really?
Why?
Some girls do you know what these days.
They throw up what they eat to stay thin.
That sickness has a name.
Blum-blom or something like that.
I don't remember now.
I'll look it up and call you.
What can we do about it?
I don't know what to do, either.
It was very hurtful to see that, Leman.
She is a tiny girl.
What happened?
Don't step on it, don't!
Kaan, what's going on?
Irem is here.
My dad?
Dad?
Ece, call the ambulance!
-Call the ambulance!
-Okay.
-Is he breathing?
-Fatos, bring water.
Come on, sit there.
Well...
...there is no need for fear or worry.
Everyone keeps telling me
not to be afraid.
I'm sorry but I owe God one lifetime.
Am I going to be afraid of that?
You tell me.
What did you find in me?
Is it dementia?
What's the rush?
We can't diagnose right away.
Let's see the film first.
Turns out everyone's so eager to
shoot my film.
If I'd known,
I'd be an artist and even get paid for it.
Mr. Kaan, I'm going to guide
you to a centre that is very close.
In fact, it is within walking distance.
They are going to take
a tomography scan and MR.
They'll send me the results.
Today is an extremely busy day.
I have two operations during the day.
I'll get back to you tomorrow at worst.
We are going to really speed up
this process.
Don't worry.
Oh, dad.
Love, we've just walked out,
we are at the door. Where are you?
I've just driven into the street.
-Okay, I've seen you.
-I've seen you.
Dad, Ece will take you home.
I have to go to work from here.
Look, this doctor is an interesting man.
He is the best in his field.
So don't worry about anything, okay?
I'll see you in the evening.
Okay, don't worry.
-Hello.
-Hi, love.
-I hope you get well soon.
-Thank you, my girl.
Love, I entrust him to you.
Okay, don't worry about us.
May it be easy.
-I'll see you in the evening.
-Thank you.
I'm sorry, my girl.
I've given you so much trouble.
Dad, is that a thing to say now?
I'm glad the kids
didn't wake up in the morning.
Anyway, we're all human here.
What did the doctor say?
He can't tell yet.
He's going to call us tomorrow.
As long as you are good.
What are you looking at, what?
Drive on!
Can we stop there for a second?
How can I stop in the middle of the road?
Why? What happened?
Very well, then, it wasn't fated to be.
Pass.
What?
I'm buying a sack of soil!
Am I buying a land?
What is this?
Our prices are standard, sir.
Okay, then.
Give me one of those, then.
I also want a flowerpot but...
...I don't want it to be plastic
like this.
It is for a girl child,
I want something showy.
This will do it.
Take this too.
What are those?
What did you buy?
You leave it, I'll carry it.
-Where can we put them now?
-You leave it, I'll carry it.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, my girl.
Put it here, son, put it here.
We gave you trouble.
Thank you.
-Good day to you.
-Good day to you, thank you.
What are these, Mrs. Ece?
We've brought you some soil in case
you may miss your village.
What's this?
You haven't cleared the table yet.
Mr. Esref hasn't eaten anything yet.
Okay.
My head isn't clear.
You go on and have breakfast, then.
I'll be back right away.
Thank you, my girl.
I gave you trouble.
Don't mention it.
She makes fun of me like that sometimes.
I mean Mrs. Ece.
Don't be troubled because of me.
I've been coming to clean
Mr. Kaan's house since he was a bachelor.
It's been years.
But she doesn't want me here anymore.
She wants to send me.
I know.
Why, my girl?
It is so.
She wants someone
more modern instead of me.
She says she is embarrassed
when guests come.
And I am a bad example to kids.
She says I'm not a good "lore" model.
Whatever that means!
I hear them talking.
Mr. Kaan always shuts her up.
He doesn't send me for the sake
of the old days.
Look, brother Esref,
Let me tell you something.
Your son is a really good person.
I'm dealing with her for his sake.
You raised him so well.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, my girl.
Don't--
One day!
I wasn't here for one day and
it's all turned into a mess.
Where is the script?
Is it this one?
This is not even half of the episode.
Did five people write 50 pages
in two days?
-What kind of a disgrace is this, Ozge?
-We tried to push them, Mr. Kaan.
But they weren't pushed, Ozge! If they’d
been pushed, it wouldn't be like this.
Go out, not now.
You are going to wait on them
with a whip if need be.
These are the writers' group,
these guys are relaxed.
Haven't you still figured it out
in all these years?
Let's give them some bits
from the old episodes this week.
Let's chase away those
who are giving advertisements.
And then close the shop.
You are alive, I'm well.
Great.
Hello.
Are you available?
Yes, is everything okay?
I guess so.
You guess so?
Well, I don't know.
Your dad made me stop the car suddenly.
We bought a sack of soil, a flowerpot and
a seedling on our way back.
Why?
I didn't ask why.
The man wanted it,
and I didn't object.
He needs to be happy after all, right?
Ece, I don't understand
what you are trying to say.
What did I say now, love?
I'm just telling you what went on.
-Well, okay, then.
-Actually, I called for this.
We were going to invite Mr. Ilker and his wife
to dinner, you asked me to remind you.
Oh, God.
I forgot all about that.
Shall we postpone it?
Kaan, we talked about this.
Let's keep it close since
the offer is still fresh.
Let's invite them in,
It would be too formal if it's outside.
And we were going to meet his wife.
You told me all these.
What about my father?
He'd sit with us a little bit
and then go to his room.
I mean if you like.
Don't think about these things now.
I'll arrange it.
By the way, I'm going to invite my mother
and her husband to dinner too.
So that we are crowded.
Your mother and his husband.
Yes. We'll have to put up with them
for a night.
Let's save the appearance.
Love...
...I have no problem with them.
You don't like them.
I wonder why.
Anyway, we'll talk about these later.
Please remind Mr. Ilker.
Okay, I'll ask him when I see him.
Okay, kisses.
It's good.
-My girl, isn't there a newspaper around?
-No.
They read on the...
Tablet.
There's a magazine,
shall I give it to you?
I'll take it.
Don't bother.
I'm sorry I had some things to do.
Oh, God, is my Uras pasha here?
-Come here, come.
-Go to granddad.
-You didn't get bored, did you?
-No, my girl, I am okay.
Fatos, why don't you turn on the
television?
He didn't want it.
I asked him but he said it's giving him
headache.
Shall I give you a painkiller?
No, my girl, I am good.
What are you doing, my pasha?
Are you okay, my pasha?
Oh, he's smiling.
Oh, you, yellow balls, you.
I'm sorry, my girl.
This is how they love a child
in my hometown. It just popped out.
My girl, go and sit down.
Don't stand up.
-My girl, eat your food.
-I am eating, dad.
It just stays there on your plate.
Do you really like Nazan Oncel?
Yes, granddad.
All the female poets represent my spirit.
Their own lyrics, their own songs.
They are the insurgents
in a man's world.
Go girl.
Look, let's make a deal.
If you finish the food on your plate...
...I'm going to tell you a story
about her.
Nobody knows this,
not even your father.
I know her.
She calls me in bairams
and we talk.
Granddad, come on?
How do you know her?
Me is shocked right now.
Girl, why are you talking
like a foreigner?
Ece, wait a second.
Tell us more, dad.
I think it was 1996.
You weren't born then.
Your father was going to university
in those days.
In my hometown, we celebrate the salvation
from the enemy occupation...
...each year on September 11.
Parade in the morning...
...entertainment with music
in the evening.
On the day of the salvation, they set up
a stage in front of the city hall.
Everyone goes to that entertainment.
Anyway, let me spit it out.
They said that Nazan was coming that year.
She was just beginning to be
famous back then.
We would hear her name a lot.
She and her orchestra land
on the Izmir airport...
...and they see that
Nazan's suitcase is lost.
The dress she's going to wear
in the concert is in the suitcase, too.
So she won't be able to wear it.
Because they say the suitcase would only
come the day after.
They tell her “let's buy you a ready-made
dress from Izmir.”
She says no. She says it's better if I go
on stage with what I'm wearing now.
That is exactly a move she would make.
Anyway, do you know
how I know about all of these?
They go downtown in the morning...
...Nazan sees my shop.
It's an old tailor's shop,
so she likes it.
You saw me there too.
You came to the shop and saw it.
I am an old tailor.
Yes, it was quite a retro shop.
Anyway, let me spit it out.
She said so when she was there.
She heard about our art
from the neighbours.
I told her “since you came all this way
for us...
...let me sew you a dress...
...you don't have to wear
it if you don't like it.”
She said she doesn't want it.
I insisted so she said yes.
We left my shop...
...and went to Mehmet's variety shop.
You should have seen us running.
Our feet were hitting our bottom.
We went into the shop,
I asked her to pick a cloth.
“Pick a cloth, Miss Nazan.”
We picked a thin one.
It was a chally and it was purple.
I took her measurements right there.
I guess it was 11 in the morning.
She went to her rehearsal.
She came back in the evening and
her dress was ready.
I sewed her a thin, modern dress.
It was very showy.
She really liked it.
She gave me a hug and said
“God bless your hands, thank you.”
She asked me to want something,
anything from her.
I said “Now that I've seen the light in
your eyes, I don't want money or anything.
But I'll take a benediction from you...
...and that would be more than enough
for me, Miss Nazan.”
And then we went to watch that concert
with Leman in the evening.
It was such a showy concert.
She calls me every bairam
and asks me how I am.
She asks if I'm okay or
if I need anything.
She is a loyal woman.
Granddad, how come?
This is all.
I didn't know this story, either.
I guess it never came up in our
conversation before.
Granddad, so you have Nazan's
phone number, right?
Could we call her if we wanted to?
Is that okay?
We'll talk if she calls herself.
It would be shameful otherwise.
Then, when is the nearest bairam, dad?
The way things are going,
every day is a bairam for us, Irem.
Go on, wash your hands
if you're done.
I promise you that we'll go to
her first concert together.
-You promised.
-Okay, promise.
-Bon appetit.
-Dad, what are you doing?
-Give it to me, I'll take it.
-No, it won't stick to my hands, right?
I'm going to make myself coffee, anyway.
I'll do it.
-How do you like it?
-It doesn't matter.
I talked to Mr. Ilker today.
About dinner.
Okay. And?
They're only available tomorrow evening.
So?
So they're coming tomorrow evening.
Why didn't you tell me before?
Before?
I talked to the man an hour ago,
and I'm telling you now.
By the way...
...we won't talk about this Los Angeles
business at dinner tomorrow.
I'll tell my father
in a more convenient time.
Okay, we'll talk.
Why are you waiting at the door?
I thought I'd wash my hands.
Irem is inside as you hear.
Then let me wash my hands in the room.
Shall we talk a little bit?
Okay but judging from your intonation,
I can tell you are going to bother me.
A girl to girl talk.
I won't bother you, don't worry.
But this conversation will stay
between the two of us.
Promise?
I promise.
First of all, you don't really believe
the things your granddad told you, right?
Why wouldn't I?
He is an old man after all.
His head is not clear sometimes.
He's living in an imaginary world.
Come on, Irem.
My daughter can't be this naïve.
Didn't you hear it?
When you said let's call her...
...he said she called him
in bairams anyway.
He didn't call her,
he slurred over it.
Anyway, never mind these now.
I'm going to ask you something else.
What did your granddad tell you
in the bathroom last night?
You two were...
...he was holding your shoulders.
He was consoling me
because I had a row with my father.
Nothing else happened, right?
Mom...
...I'm getting something but...
...tell me what you're saying clearly.
The news you read,
the state the country is in...
...made you paranoid.
Not my granddad's head but
I think your head is not clear.
Irem, how are you talking to me like that?
How can you think of
such a disgusting thing?
I hate you!
Don't ever let my dad know about this.
Irem, what did I say now?
I hate you!
Get out!
-Okay, I'm leaving.
-Get out or I'll scream.
Okay, okay.
You searched the recipe
for the Peking duck with orange.
Are you looking at my search history?
What's it got to do with it, my love?
I didn't want to order in
when Mr. Ilker and his wife come here.
I wanted to do everything myself.
I wanted everyone to be astonished.
What's wrong with this?
Ece, calm down.
Your beauty is enough, love.
So you're kindly telling me that
I am bad in kitchen.
Ece, what are you talking about?
If you want to have a row,
tell me frankly.
I'm already dealing with a thousand
things, don't you start, as well.
Am I starting it?
You are the one who talks allusively.
On the one hand my dad's trouble
and the job...
...on the other hand, Irem's trouble,
and now you add yourself to the list...
...to make it complete.
Am I troubling you?
I'm showing your father nothing
but respect.
I've been doing everything on my own
for the past two days...
...so that everyone can be happy.
-What? On your own?
-Yes.
It is me who is doing everything alone.
Go to your room,
I'll bring you water.
She'll pass by in anger now,
don't let her see you.
How many people do I need to be?
How many of me do you need?
Go to your room.
If they can clone me, let's go
and have it done tomorrow.
But no, even that wouldn't be enough,
right?
You need an army of me.
I'm staying here tonight.
Mrs. Ece asked me to.
We were going to make a list
for shopping, for dinner.
There's no need.
You can all eat me.
Don't say so.
It's too early.
I was going to sleep more.
Don't whine about it.
It's a surprise, your granddad wanted you.
There he is, go near him.
What happened, granddad?
Come here, squat with me.
Look, this one is called Irem,
this one is called Uras.
Are these flowers?
No, cherry tomatoes.
Remember the game you're playing?
This is the real thing now.
We're going to plant them now.
Take this spoon.
Dig a pit here.
Take this,
may your hand bring luck to it.
Press there, bismillah.
Granddad, you are great.
But why didn't we plant it on the garden?
No, digging up the garden and all.
They would say something, never mind.
This is your garden now.
We're going to put it somewhere
that gets sunlight.
Take Uras, too.
Put it next to it.
Press.
They need sunlight.
Let's give them their first water.
Pour it down slowly now.
I hope you take root like these,
you and your brother.
I hope no one would make you
bend your head.
Always stay green like this.
My dear grandchildren.
Do you want espresso, Mr. Kaan?
I'll bring it,
you go to your father.
Come on...
...go and wash your hands directly
and then go to the breakfast.
I'll tell you all about how to care
for them there.
High five, bro, let it be known that
I am the owner of a farm.
Wow. We'll see.
Good morning.
-Dad...
-Well... I...
...let me go back now.
I'll go to the bus terminal
with a bus...
Dad, what are you talking about?
We've seen the doctor.
They would've called us
if there'd been something.
If there is something important, they can send
the file to the hospital in my hometown.
They are doctors too.
What did Ataturk say?
He said “entrust me to Turkish medics!”
He didn't say one of them,
He meant all of them.
My son, I'm good,
don't think about me.
Dad, stop for God's sake.
Forgive me, please.
About last night.
I didn't want to say so.
Well, you know...
...it was a really bad moment and
I just stormed at Ece.
I really care about you.
You can't go anywhere,
I won't leave you.
My son,
I'm not hungry or homeless.
I am able-bodied, thank God.
I'm only saying I'm going back to my
house, I'm not saying anything else.
Dad, this is your house, too.
Dad, look...
...this is the first time I've seen
Irem happy in ages.
And you are the reason for that.
Please don't go.
Don't leave us.
Please stay with us.
At least stay until these give tomatoes.
Okay, dad?
Go out, you need to do shopping.
Don't wait, I'll clear the table.
-You got the list, right?
-Yes.
Okay, leave then.
We have a guest for dinner this evening.
Kaan's boss, Mr. Ilker, with his wife.
It's a matter of Kaan's promotion.
That's why it's going to be
an important evening for us.
I'll be in the kitchen all day.
I also arranged an assistant.
She'll come soon too.
By the way, I let my mother know.
They'll be with us too.
So we're going to be a bit crowded.
You won't mind it, right?
You can go to your room
if you feel tired.
No one would take it bad.
My dad will do whatever he wants, Ece.
Of course, dear,
that's what I said.
Did I say something different?
A good partner, a good housewife.
Someone who can cook well etc.
It's an old and outdated understanding.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that it is some women again
who deal a blow...
...to the fight of the women
in this country.
Let me summarize, granddad...
...the assistant cook will be paid and
sent away before the guests arrive...
...and plus, my mom is
embarrassed of you...
...among these upstanding people.
Apologize at once.
Is that a thing to say to your mother?
What a shame!
-Irem, apologize.
-I didn't do something to apologize for.
-Sit down!
-The shuttle is waiting at the door.
Please be a little bit more honest
from now on.
By the way, don't worry,
I won't make a scene in the evening.
I'll go to bed early,
like those well-behaved...
...docile girls that are in your series.
What's going on with this girl?
I don't know.
And I don't understand.
Is she big, is she little?
What's this?
I gave birth to a big hatred.
Don't say so, my girl,
don't say so.
Hatred is a big word.
The human body is tiny.
If you took that hatred in,
it wouldn't fit.
If you carried it,
you'd crush under it.
Don't say that.
Fatos, I'll come with you too.
It'd be nice for me to stroll around.
Dad?
Yes?
Okay then, go on.
It'd be a change for you too.
Fatos...
...buy a showy coffee for my dad.
A showy one.
We'll drink it together.
I can't meddle
with their domestic things.
I can't say anything but,
you know, there is also a thing like this.
Uras can't talk.
They say it's because of high intelligence
but of course, he can't talk.
Have you ever gone before him and
talked to him?
And you expect him to talk.
Mr. Kaan couldn't go to Irem's performance
because of his job.
There was this English theatre thing at her
school. You know, they call it an event.
Irem was going to sing too.
And there was a dinner of the channel
that night...
...it was an anniversary dinner.
The celebrities, everyone was there.
They both happened in the same night.
When Mr. Kaan went to
the channel's thing...
...all hell broke loose that night.
Irem felt worthless.
That's what she said.
I can't say anything,
these are domestic matters.
But if you ask them separately,
they are all right in their opinion.
One of them wants her father with her.
The other one has a job.
He is working day and night.
It's hard.
Yes, professor.
He's not with me right now but...
Face to face.
I have two kids myself.
God bless them, my girl.
Thank you.
One of them is called Zeliha.
She's in high school.
I want her to go to university.
And Metin is my son.
So it goes.
If there's work,
he goes with his father from time to time.
Portage etc.
But Zeliha will complete her education,
brother Esref.
You should see her, she's so clever.
She's doing so well at school.
One night, his father said let's marry her
she's a girl child after all...
...and I got so angry.
I punched the door,
It's wood got broken.
He hasn't opened his mouth
since that day.
What I say happens in my house.
Come, Kaan,
Come near me.
I'm going to explain the situation
to your father, as well but...
...now that I caught you here.
Just a minute.
Why did we buy this, brother Esref?
Because there was none in the house.
They don't eat it.
What's this?
Are we buying a car?
It's always like this here.
They don't eat it.
What's this?
A famous vegetable
where ‘m coming from.
The patient will have momentary loss of
memory and complaints...
...such as not being able to find words...
...because the bulk has been growing
in the temporal lobe.
Maybe you have realized.
What your father has is glial tumor.
It's the difficult kind.
I am shocked too. I wouldn't
give it a chance if you asked me yesterday.
Mr. Esref must have a very solid structure.
Professor, now I...
In this case?
Operation.
When?
Right away, I'd say let's not lose time.
I...
...have to go abroad.
I have to.
Isn't there anyone else who can
accompany him?
There is, there is...
Look at her hair.
Is that good now? Like someone put
a watermelon on her head.
Brother Esref?
Brother?
Kaan?
Miss, have you seen an old man
in a blue shirt?
We haven't.
Brother Esref, where are you?
My child, my child...
-...look at me.
-Yes?
Okay, calm down.
I can help you out if you're lost.
What are you saying, my child?
I'm a grown-up man.
Why would I get lost?
I lost my son.
Kaan.
He had his yellow shorts on.
He had brown shoes.
He's about 8 years old.
Is that your grandchild?
What grandchild are you talking about?
My son, Kaan.
He had his yellow shorts on.
And brown shoes.
I sewed him those shorts
so that he can wear it in the bairam.
His name is Kaan, he got lost.
Give.
I didn't die today,
I don't think I'll ever die.
Oh, Fatos, the dogs should bite you!
You should have been more careful, Fatos.
What are you laughing at?
Did you see someone naked?
We're losing our heads here and
she's having fun, laughing.
Get up, brother Esref,
get up, let's go home.
They're calling from the store.
Are you going to pay for the things in the
trolley? Or should they put them back?
Of course, we'll pay for them.
Are we thieves?
Come, brother Esref, come
Mr. Kaan...
...they're asking to confirm...
...you are saying okay to dinner
with Mr. Ilker and his wife, right?
Okay, okay.
Okay, I'm telling them.
And we are ready.
I gave the brief to the group,
they are reading it now.
Okay.
Where have you been, Fatos?
I called you a hundred times.
Why don't you answer your phone?
There was a mix-up.
What kind of a mix-up?
I forgot something from the list and...
...we went back to buy it.
I wish you forgot yourself too!
We won't be able to make it!
It's all because of me.
We'll help you,
we can do it altogether.
There is no need,
the assistant is here.
In the recipe it says to shower
it in hot water.
That's how we'll do it, right?
I think it should boil for 5 minutes.
It's going to stay in boiled water for half an
hour and then we'll check if it's still hard.
Move aside, my girl.
Don't worry,
I'll take it out with that thing.
-Dad, I wish you wouldn't bother.
-No, my girl, no.
I think you're boiling water, take it.
So that you wouldn't fight, right?
Move aside for a minute.
Look, we're going to cut them
in the middle.
And after we boil it, we'll pour olive oil
and lemon juice over it.
-Are we going to put garlic?
-No, it'd make it lose its flavour.
Silence for a minute.
Is my Uras pasha here?
Welcome.
I grated the fresh ginger,
It must be its flavour.
Of course, the amount of honey and
orange juice is important, too.
God bless your hands,
It's really good.
Bon apetit.
God bless your hands,
my beautiful daughter.
I really love this vegetable.
The ones I've eaten in the restaurant
didn't taste like anything...
...but this is splendid.
-Bon apetit.
God bless your hands, mom.
Mrs., ask for this one's recipe.
It would make a really good raki appetizer.
But you're going to do it
exactly like this.
But you don't drink raki.
Why on earth would you say that?
I don't know, I felt like saying it.
When I ate this...
...I wanted to go somewhere by the sea.
Actually,...
...you should pack up your things...
...leave your job...
...and move to a coastal place somewhere
in the Aegean region.
Here we go again...
...his self that wants to run away
from the city.
Is it a lie?
Let's go.
Is there something that's holding
you back here?
This decision is taken
after the second glass of wine.
After the third one...
...he says we're definitely going.
After the bottle is finished,
the suitcases are prepared.
And when he wakes up in the morning...
...he runs back to work...
...like none of this was discussed.
It is the only channel we watch.
If you leave your job, who's going to
shape the media's future?
Thank you.
I think Mr. Esref lives there
somewhere, right?
-Yes.
-I can tell.
Praise be, you look young.
Thank you so much.
If you come that way, be my guest.
I hope so, thank you.
Kaan...
...what a beautiful family you have!
-You are very lucky.
-Thank you.
Are you having a dig at us?
Don't say that, my dear wife.
Kaan, are we playing a game of silence?
You say 10 sentences in a second
in the meetings...
...and look at you now.
My dear, if you were to shut up
a little bit...
...maybe then he can talk a bit.
Don't say that.
Well, it's so joyous that...
...I was swept up in listening.
Mr. Esref...
...how was Kaan when he was little?
Could you tell us?
We have to know everything
about him, right?
We're going to trust him
with a huge channel after all.
It is for sure that he'll be
more successful than you, love.
-Oh, you...
-There's nothing to be angry about here.
Let the young ones take the lead.
Yellow balls.
Did I hear that right?
Praise be, you little thing.
Bon apetit.
God bless him.
Aren't you going to sleep?
I'll stay a bit more.
What's this?
You're celebrating the new words
your son learned?
He said a proper word at least.
Don't worry,
it wasn't embarrassing.
Everyone except you laughed at it anyway.
Is that so?
I didn't find it funny.
Go to bed for God's sake.
I don't have the strength.
-Okay.
-Good night.
-Fatos, has my dad gone to bed?
-Yes.
Dad, are you asleep?
No, son.
Could you come to the living room
with me please?
Okay, I'm coming.
Dad...
...shall we have a glass together?
We've got melon and cheese too.
In the tea glass,
exactly the way you like it.
Son, at this hour?
Is it late?
Is it very late?
To your health.
What? The day after tomorrow?
No, Esref, I'm coming.
Don't object.
Leman, you asked and I told you.
Don't make me regret it.
They have enough trouble here...
...let's not have Kaan
deal with you, too.
I didn't want to say that, of course.
I really care about you.
I'll go to bed, I'll wake up,
I'll go to bed, I'll wake up...
...I'll get better and come.
Don't worry about me.
Are you going to be good?
Tell me the truth.
Leman, when did I lie to you?
You're making me even more upset now.
Pull yourself together.
I'm going to sew a dress for you.
I didn't forget it, don't worry.
Esref...
...promise me.
You are going to be okay
after the operation, right?
Promise, really, I promise.
I have your word.
Or I'll be cross with you later on.
Okay, we'll talk in the morning.
I'll call, it's late now.
-Call me when you wake up.
-Okay.
Okay.
-She didn't wake up, right?
-No.
Let her sleep, let her sleep.
Oh, my beautiful girl.
She tormented saying that...
...she'll go to the hospital too
in the past two days.
Of course, she'll be upset.
How can she not? You are a grandfather.
I wish I hadn't been so stubborn and
had the operation back in Izmir.
I gave trouble to everyone.
What trouble are you talking about,
what are you saying?
Of course, they'll get upset
when they have to get upset.
If you live your life spoiled like that...
...fate would slap you in the face in such a
way you wouldn't be able to get up again.
Everything is for people.
The sorrow and the joy.
They will learn.
Okay, I got this.
We didn't forget anything, right?
No, I put everything.
-Dad, we can leave.
-The girl will wake up.
Don't worry she doesn't wake up
at this hour.
Come on, then, let's go,
get better and come back. Huh, dad?
Of course, it'll be like that.
Fatos, my girl, see you.
I'll be there in the evening anyway.
I'll see you there.
Dad, how did you find it?
It's good, right?
-It sees the garden, as well.
-Thank you, son.
Sir...
-...welcome.
-Hello.
Let's do the necessary examinations
first swiftly...
...then, we can have all have a chat.
Accepted?
Yes.
You'll be a guest here for tonight.
It's classical here, we're going to check
your measurements etc.
We'll have a nice hair cut
in the morning.
And then, we'll make you better swiftly.
-Granddad.
-Irem?
My child.
You forgot to water the tomatoes.
But don't worry, I have.
They'll be showy when they come out.
Live long, girl.
-Move aside, let me sit there too.
-Come, come.
Don't worry.
Your granddad will be fine.
Didn't you get angry because I came?
No, I didn't.
Surprising.
-I'll leave you to school.
-Okay.
Don't sulk now.
There is nothing to be afraid of, son.
Dad, I am not fine.
What happened?
There is no reason to go into
mourning now.
We've come here,
here we are.
Tomorrow will take care of itself.
I don't know how to say it.
I'm in such a place right now that...
...it's as if...
...I'm on a thin bridge.
I am on the top of a vast,
thin wall.
There are cliffs in both sides.
But if I take a right step,
I'll fall down.
Because the bridge itself is wrong.
They made such a bridge that...
...it's always full of others' faults...
...full of cruelty and mercilessness.
It's as if they laid each brick with sin.
To stay on it,
you need to sell your soul to the devil.
There is no other way.
Because when you take a step
as a human...
...someone that is coming behind you
will see that weakness...
...and push you off that cliff.
When I thought I won everything...
...I realized that I lost it, dad.
Son, are you out of your mind?
What did you lose?
You've got your family, your wife,
your kids, your job. You are complete.
I am proud of you.
That's what I'm talking about.
Do we have to pay this price, dad?
I can't stop anymore.
Not even for a second.
The kids must always go to
good schools.
We must have a very good house.
We must never have anything missing.
I must wear a different suit
in every event.
Ece, as well.
People want this from us...
...and we give up on other things
for these.
I always have to run,
I always have to run more.
Because if I stop for a moment,...
...I am afraid that the person coming
behind me will push me.
Did you know?
The chief editor we have now
will be fired next week...
...because I'll take his place.
And the man doesn't have a clue
about this.
And I smile and say...
...good morning to this man
every morning.
What kind of a false pretence is this, dad?
I am your son.
It was you who taught me
how holy duty is.
I know of the times that you didn't get
any sleep so that you can...
...sew clothes for the neighbourhood
residents in bairam.
I saw it, I was there.
I saw everything from you, dad.
I worked...
...I went into everything wholeheartedly.
I tried to make everything fit into
these hands, everything.
But the past...
...my past.
I couldn't make it fit.
So I took it out of my palms
and threw it away.
The strange thing is
I don't remember when I did this.
Or rather, was it me
who did this...
...or did the others take it away
from my hand...
...that's what I couldn't understand.
Dad, I won't be able to be with you
during the operation tomorrow.
I have to go to America tonight.
Everything was planned beforehand.
If I stay with you,
I will lose the trust of my boss.
I know that everyone will act like
they give me right at first.
In fact, they will praise me
for a couple of days.
Saying see he didn't lose
his human side.
See he turned down his job
and stayed with his father.
But this is exactly the trap
they will set up, dad.
Because they will shoot me from
my human side a couple of days later.
Because someone else will take
my place...
...and the power will be transferred
to them.
Look, I'm climbing the stairs now...
...but if I don't go, I will stop and I'll
start going down the stairs suddenly.
Now, please tell me, dad.
What would you do if you were me?
You are right, son.
I would do the same thing.
No, you wouldn't.
You wouldn't go.
I'm going.
I can't go.
I am so desperate, dad.
So desperate.
You are going to drown
in the big sea, right?
Fair enough.
You are right.
This is how it should be anyway.
If you stay, you'll be unhappy
and I'll be the guilty one.
Go and make a life for yourself, son.
How can I say don't go?
I am human,
I got a little selfish at first.
It would be a sin for me to...
...keep you right beside me.
That would be selfish.
If it doesn't work out, you can come back.
You can at least say that you've tried.
This is for your good even
if you lose or win.
This is the rule of life.
Who survived this trouble called life
without getting dirty a little bit...
...and getting wounded?
This is life.
It makes one get dirty.
But I know you.
In your core,
your heart is pure too.
Go and make a life
for yourself there.
-But shall I tell you something?
-Dad.
What are you talking about?
I'm going there for three days.
I won't make a life for myself
there or anything.
Oh, right.
My head was gone and
I didn't know it.
Hello, are you home?
Both of you?
Okay, I'm coming.
We'll talk when I come.
Son, I'm going to tell you something.
If you're going to be this upset
about it...
...we can wait for a bit more.
You go and come back. And I'll go through
with the operation then.
Dad, I thought about this.
Why wouldn't I?
But the doctor...
...the man doesn't have
any other available day.
Only tomorrow.
And dad...
He wants you to get rid of it at once.
I see, son.
I understand.
Ece, what's going on?
You came in a hurry.
You're not telling me
what this is about.
-Why don't you sit down, my girl?
-I won't sit down.
In fact, if it's possible,
I'll go away from this house at once.
Stop, stop, stop.
What's that?
Are you running away
because I've come?
I was 9 years old
when you married this man.
You remember that,
don't you, mom?
Because I do remember it.
Now I don't know if you remember
or if you chose to forget...
...about it knowingly.
I was 9 years old when this man
came to this house...
...and screwed up my childhood...
...and my youth!
It all started with him spying out on me
in the bathroom.
What the hell are you talking about!?
Don't you ever talk!
Or I swear I'll kill you.
-My girl...
-Don't call me my girl!
And then Mrs.Servet...
...he tried to touch me with his filthy
hands even when you were at home.
-It's a lie!
-But he didn't do more than that.
Do you know why?
It's not like it's because
he made himself stop.
It was because he was afraid.
Because one day,
I stabbed him with a pocket knife.
Of course,
you know about all these...
...but do you know
why I'm telling you now?
To shout at these walls the fact that...
...everyone knows everything!
Don't cast aspersions on me!
You know she's never liked me
since she was a child.
And now look at the things
she makes up!
Shut up.
Believe what you want to believe in!
While you were living life without making
a sound because you were...
...afraid you'd lose your husband, I,
your 9 years old daughter...
...started to carry a pocket knife
in my pocket, mom.
I never wore a skirt.
While you were sleeping
in your room, farting,...
...I was having ugly nightmares...
...and I had a table and
chairs behind my locked door.
When you weren't in the house,...
...I waited under the rain,
under the eaves dripping wet...
...so that I wouldn't be alone
in the house with him.
How did you consent to this, mom?
I was your daughter!
How did you keep silent, mom?
I forgot none of these.
I've never stopped hurting.
I doubted everyone, every man.
I broke even the heart of that good
hearted-man, Mr. Esref, because of you.
God damn you both!
Rot away in this house!
I hope you rot away!
I won't come to your graves even
to spit on them.
Know this.
I've come, Fatos, I'm here.
I had something important to do
so I dealt with it.
You can leave for the hospital now,
come on.
I was ready anyway.
Uras.
You have cash for the taxi, right?
Yes.
Mr. Kaan gave me some earlier.
Okay, may it be easy!
Fatos.
Actually, I could have gotten
a different assistant...
...for a couple of days but...
...you never know who someone is.
I can't trust anyone but you.
That's why I tired you out this much.
Don't mention it.
Thank you, Mrs. Ece.
Thank you.
Kaan, could you give the phone to my dad?
Okay.
Dad, it's Ece.
Hello, yes, my girl.
Daddy...
...we couldn't talk properly...
...when Irem raided the hospital.
Fatos is on her way,
she's coming.
I have to stay with the kids.
But I'll come tomorrow,
taking Uras with me too
Don't worry...
...you will get better.
Okay?
Okay, my pretty girl.
Don't worry about me.
I am good.
Be good.
Stand over us...
...like a mountain, okay?
Promise?
Promise.
Okay.
What's she saying?
What did you talk about?
Not here... Granddad is not here.
Granddad is not here.
He'll come, he'll come.
My girl, can you find me
some water, please?
Hello.
How are you?
Good, good. As always.
I'm going to tell you something
if you can excuse me.
Well, I need your help.
He's pretending to act like a macho
towards the girl without shame.
Damn you...
...it's the same old pack of lies
all the time.
Brother Esref, we can watch something
you want to watch.
Turn it off for a bit.
I'm going to talk to you about something.
Let me go out so that you can wear
your pyjamas and get comfortable.
No, sit down.
Listen to me.
I'm going back to my hometown,
to my house.
What!?
Don't worry, my girl,
my head is clear.
Kaan was scattered today.
He was grieved.
Because he wasn't going to be able to
stay with me.
And there's this doctor over us.
So?
I'm going to ask them to send...
...the document to the hospital in Izmir.
I'm going to have the operation
there when Kaan comes back.
Pretend like you were sleeping and
you weren't aware of anything.
When you wake up in the morning,
you can tell Ece that I ran away.
Brother Esref, it was better
if you just stabbed me in the heart.
It's better if I die.
My girl, we're talking about
Kaan's happiness here.
I may end up not surviving
this operation after all.
God forbid.
Do you want the child to regret it
all his life?
He would never forgive himself.
Let him find me alive
when he comes back.
The rest is down to him.
My girl...
...I can't torture my own child like this.
Well, you're talking well but...
...how can you go at this hour?
The plane etc,
how is it going to be?
Don't worry about that,
I arranged it.
Of course, it's ready.
Let me take a look at it
on the plane, please.
Okay.
See you.
Kadir.
Mr. Kaan...
...I can bring something else
if you like.
Have a safe journey.
Hello, welcome.
Mr. Kaan.
Okay, I'm coming.
If Ece calls, you can tell her
that I'm sleeping.
The nurse has just been here,
she wouldn't come again for a while.
I wish you wouldn't bother coming.
The car is waiting downstairs.
No, I won't leave you without seeing
it with my own eyes first.
If someone asks anything, we can say
we're going for a bit of fresh air etc.
Brother, what's this?
Don't worry about me, my girl.
I'm in safe hands.
Am I going to be in the back again?
Give your blessing, my girl.
I give you my blessing, brother.
You give me your blessing too.
I'm giving you my blessing.
Okay, be well and I'm going to make
flaky pastry for you.
We're going to eat it with ayran
until we explode.
I hope so my girl, I hope so.
Come on, child, thank you.
Son, I opened your bag this morning
secretly...
...to put this, I'm sorry.
But I may not be surviving
this operation so...
I didn't want to leave this realm...
...without telling you these
when my head is still clear.
You told me that you'd carry
me on your shoulders.
You have, son.
Don't get upset.
I give you my blessing.
Take good care of your kids
and your wife.
Look after Irem more.
Make sure that she eats...
...and check on her with your eyes
after she's eaten.
Kiss all of them for me one by one.
I'm leaving the house in Foca to them.
And I'm leaving the shop to Fatos.
Let her sell it and
send her daughter to school.
I'm writing this letter at night.
I don't know what state I'll be in
after the operation in the morning.
Well, you know...
...it's not easy.
They'll get inside my head.
You'll be with me
in the morning but...
...maybe I won't be able to talk.
Maybe I'll forget everything.
Then, at that point...
...don't forget us.
Remember.
You have a father here.
All that we've been through is
so precious, son.
Don't you ever forget.
Remember us.
Dudu...
...my girl...
...pray this morning.
So that your father can get well
and come here.
29 missed calls
Calling Leman...
-Hello, Leman...
-Esref, where are you?
-I've been trying to--
-...shut up please.
-I'm in the shop now.
-What?
Did you come here?
I've got a surprise for you.
Come, if you want to see it.
-Come on.
-Okay, I'm coming.
Is he crazy or what!
It looks really good, dad.
It does, doesn't it?
My son
I am sorry for your loss.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Come on, everyone is leaving.
Irem, what are you doing?
I'm going to suffer a seizure
because of the heat.
Mr. Esref.
Stubborn goat.
I'll be ashamed if I wear it...
...you'll get upset if I don't wear it.
You're kidding around with me
from there, right?
I'm sorry for your loss.
Mrs. Nazan, welcome.
Welcome.
I'm sorry for your loss, so sorry.
Nazan, you came for my granddad.
You are Irem.
You know me.
Your granddad mentioned you.
Sing your song, sing.
See what's just happened!?
Oh, God.
From the sound of the city
From my darkest moments
I came to you
Am I late?
Where are you, my showy one?
When I was a child yesterday
And when life was passing me by
You stole my tears
You are gone but don't forget me
Don't be afraid, remember us
Take this, my pretty girl.
For your granddad's soul.
When I was a child yesterday
While I was angry at wars
You stole my tears
You are gone but don't forget me
Don't be afraid, remember us
Granddad, granddad.
Remember us
Don't be afraid