THIS IS WORK OF FICTION. ANY SIMILARITIES
TO ACTUAL EVENTS IS PURELY COINCIDENTAL.
So cool.
What are you waiting for?
Alright, goodbye.
Last week, you're booked by Syafiq.
This week, I am booking you earlier.
If you win, we split 30/70.
Only 30%?
- Only 30%?
- Thirty percent is also money.
There is also something for you tonight.
- As if you don't understand.
- How's my ride?
Front and back tires are TT100.
Single pistering and upgraded carburettor.
Okay. I think, starting next week,
I am going to train him.
How's that? Deal?
It's on!
- So, it will be 30/70.
- It's a deal.
Did you win?
- So noisy.
- Noisy.
What?
You are talking about this bike?
Hey, how much is he giving you?
Thirty-70.
This bike is not in the best condition.
Are you making fun of me?
Rather than bet on that bike,
it's better if you bet on mine.
At least, this bike's pick-up
is good in first and second gear.
Look at the mirror. The front and back
are chromed, for what?
For your girlfriend's reflection?
Hey, mind yourself.
The mirror?
I'll take it off, then.
You are damn noisy.
Hold this. Because of this,
we were made fun of.
- Remember, 30/70.
- Get lost!
- Don't be arrogant.
- Get lost.
Hey, how long do you
want to ride people's bikes?
You can afford this bike.
Just sell your EX5 and you will be able
to afford the down payment.
Bro, they'll pay me if I win.
When I get my new bike, I'll come
to your house and make some noise.
- Really?
- Really.
Okay, let's go!
We race for 1km, freestyle!
Come on!
Quick! Come on!
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
Okay, stand by.
We go toward the Jalan Parlimen.
Quietly.
- Okay, come in quickly.
- Where?
- Here?
- Yes.
Switch on the light.
Okay. Wait here for a while.
You just came back? What time
do you want to check out tomorrow?
What do you mean by "check out", Mom?
Because you treat this house like a hotel.
What were you doing this late at night?
Don't you know when to sleep?
I helped my friend at the burger stall.
What nonsense are you talking about?
I'm just worried that
something bad will happen to you.
Don't worry, Mom. It's not like I'm
doing drugs or flirting with girls.
I'm just helping at the burger stall,
it's not like I'm selling drugs.
- You smell!
- What?
Like cigarettes. Go brush your teeth
and don't forget to wash your feet.
Hey.
MY MAIN GOAL: MOTOR 125Z
Madi! Why are you so inconsiderate?
Playing music so loud at this hour!
- Peace be upon you, baby.
- Peace be upon you too.
Why aren't you asleep yet?
I'm out shopping with my mom.
Baby, tomorrow you're fetching me right?
Yes. Who else will fetch you besides me?
Hmm.
I just wanted to confirm it with you.
Okay, okay.
What are you doing?
Why aren't you asleep yet?
I am sleeping now.
Okay, baby, my mom is here.
Don't forget about tomorrow, okay?
Baby, can I get a kiss?
Okay, thank you.
Goodbye.
OPEN 24 HOUR
This is Dataran Merdeka.
There is a lot of history here,
and we're proud of it.
Let's get a good parking spot
and then we shall go.
What is that?
Crazy. What kind of person
rides a bike like that?
Crazy bunch of people.
Really?
Hot topic? What's that?
Oh my God.
She went out with a rempit?
Does that mean her daughter is a slut?
Praise to God the Almighty.
- Really?
- Miss Maimon.
- She wore sexy clothes?
Praise to God the Almighty.
Miss Maimon, this is the invoice
from Initial-D Company. Please sign.
- Signature only?
- Yes.
Why are you in a hurry?
Seeing your girlfriend?
Thank you, miss.
Just now, I saw your boyfriend over there.
Really?
He didn't call me.
Why don't I know?
How can you possibly know?
You only know how to gossip.
Please take care of my belongings.
I'll collect it tomorrow morning.
Okay, see you.
Why are you late?
You only know how to complain.
Just get on the bike.
Why do you look so tired, baby?
It's because you called me last night,
so I didn't get enough sleep.
Excuses.
So, where are we going?
Are we going back straight
or having lunch first?
Where do you want to go?
I want to go eat. I'm hungry.
I feel like eating fruit.
What kind of fruit
do you want to eat now, baby?
What are you looking at?
Pervert! Move aside.
- You want to ride the bike?
- Yes. Let me. Move aside.
You came late, looking tired even.
Go faster. I'm scared.
Hold on tight.
Move your foot aside.
Hey, what's this? Boyfriend riding behind?
What a shame.
In that case, you're not rempit.
Might as well become a girl.
You have no class.
- It's okay, baby, just go. Just go.
- Just ignore them?
Just go?
What's wrong?
Handsome boy.
- Faster.
Hey, handsome boy.
- Handsome boy. Faster!
- What's wrong with them?
Baby, let's swap places.
Come on, quickly.
- Faster.
Okay, baby. Make sure you go home now.
Don't go anywhere else after this.
- Here.
- Oops, thank you.
After this, I'm going to Macha's house.
If you don't believe me,
you can follow me.
You're crazy. I'm going in.
- What's wrong?
- Where is my fruit?
Pervert!
You're a pervert, baby.
You don't want to come with me
to the shop tomorrow?
I don't want to.
Tomorrow will be the best day ever!
125Z is already out.
Okay, I'm going now. Remember
to wash your feet before bed.
Alright.
- Goodnight, baby.
- Goodnight.
MOTORCYCLE SHOP
That's the bike that I used the other day.
The sprocket broke. I'll buy a new one.
Hi. Where's my bike? Can I take it now?
Okay.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Usually, young people like you
pay the installment first.
But it's good
that you didn't pay the installment.
Then, I could give you a discount.
You only mention
a discount after I've paid?
You said you wanted to pay cash,
so, I didn't tell you
about the installment.
- Is it this the one?
- Yes, it's this one.
Mad, please get the stuff I talked about.
Alright.
The petrol is low.
Can you give me a full tank instead?
I'm already giving you
a free raincoat and helmet.
You even want a full tank?
Hey, if that's the case,
how can I make a profit?
Boss, here's the oil,
raincoat, and helmet.
Your petrol is enough to go fuel up.
If somebody wants to buy my old bike,
can you sell it to an old person?
- I'm scared that the bike will "barai".
- What's "barai"?
- It won't work.
- Oh, so you still care about the bike?
Okay, no problem.
Okay. My key?
- Bro, here's your old helmet.
- I thought of giving it to you.
Hey!
Praise to God the Almighty.
Keep it down! My dad is inside!
You bastard!
125Z!
Why didn't you ask me to come with you?
Right. I'll ask you to come with me
even if I go to the toilet.
Bro.
- Can I use your workshop?
- Sure, but after I pray.
Hey, Cha, even a rocker like you pray?
What do you mean by that?
Just wait till I'm done praying!
Amin.
- Are you done praying?
- Yes, Dad.
Dad, what are you reading?
Dad.
Dad, have you eaten?
What nonsense are you talking about?
We just ate together.
What's your problem?
It's nothing, Dad.
Actually, I want to buy a new bike.
125Z. Like Madi's bike.
- Can I?
- What?
A new bike? 125Z?
No problem, my son!
- Really, Dad?
- Yes.
- Really?
- Yes!
Go to my room, open the cupboard.
Inside the cupboard...
There's no need for that, dad. It will
only be a waste to buy stuff for him.
Brother, you don't even know
how to take care of your stuff.
I'll take it, okay, Dad?
Don't be jealous, sister!
Mom!
- Six. Seven.
- Mom!
Eight. Nine. Ten.
One. Two. Three.
Four. Five. Six.
Seven. Eight. Nine. Ten.
- One. Two.
- So many money.
- I can even get married with this money.
- Three. Four. Five.
Why did you take the money from the safe?
- What are you going to do with the money?
- Dad asked me to.
I just asked for the money from your dad!
Don't you dare use it!
I want to pay the mortgage,
car, kitchen appliances!
Put back the money!
- But dad asked me to take the money.
- Just put it back.
- But dad...
- Put it back!
Put it back. Don't be stubborn.
Dad allowed it, but not mom.
One. Two. Three.
My back.
MACHA'S WORKSHOP
Here's your block. I think
it's good enough. So, how is it?
Here, try to change it.
It came from the best place.
- Cha!
- What?
- It's not good enough.
- What? Not good enough?
Just kidding.
Hey, I did your carburetor as well.
I already borrowed a spanner from Botak.
He lends you his stuff?
I gave him something he wanted,
that's why he lend it to me.
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
Wow.
New paint job.
Orange and silver.
Who's bike is that? He just bought it?
He's one of my boys, doing some jobs.
Jobs?
Nice helmet.
BGH 9234.
Just came out?
You really take care of your bike, hey?
How much was the down payment?
I bought it with cash.
Cash?
Parents' money?
My dad passed away.
Madi?
Joe, come here.
Here.
Since you've bought a super bike,
you really have no time for me.
- How's Lan?
- I just came from Lan's workshop.
I was there for some time.
I changed some of the parts.
The price is high.
Are you up for it?
- Just tell me when.
- Cha, borrow me your lighter.
Hold on.
Give me one cigarette.
Lighter?
When do you want to setup the bike?
Let's do it tomorrow
since I'm working half-day.
- Who's going to assemble this?
- Do it yourself.
Hey! That's my dad's bike!
Madi, keep the bike clean!
You can do it, I assure you.
Come, let's go!
Let's go!
Come on, let's go!
Police! Police! Run! Run!
RM50! Even school kids can pay it.
RM50!
All you did is talk, give me RM50!
Hey, this is only RM20.
Give me another RM50.
That's a lot of money, Cha.
Don't think of go into debt.
Shut up! Do you want to race, or not?
- Yes, of course!
- Then, what are we waiting for?
How much did you get?
Bro, what about my share?
Here, take this.
This is my share.
Come on!
Quick! Quick!
Quick!
Quick! Quick! Get ready!
Let's go!
Alright. Here is the money.
Go!
Come on!
Let's go!
A 125 managed to catch-up with a TZM?
- I know, right?
- This kid is pretty good.
Bro, I think something
is wrong with the sprocket.
I can't go fast with this sprocket.
Can you change it?
Can you massage me, baby?
Are you tired, baby?
Your baby.
Let's go eat after this?
I don't know why, but suddenly,
I feel like eating Kuey Teow.
Are you up for it?
Macha is treating us.
No problem.
You ate just now.
Do you still want to eat?
Let's eat when you're done.
Can I come with you tonight, baby?
- Come with me?
- You have a game tonight, right?
- I'm bored at home alone.
- What about your parents?
They all went back home.
- So, don't worry about it.
- Really?
Then, it's better if I go
to your house instead.
It's much more fun that way, right?
Damn, you guys! Get a room, will you?
Why are you so jealous? Right, baby?
He's jealous.
He doesn't have a girlfriend.
Yes. Mom? Okay, I'm coming.
Baby, do you want to
go there or home first?
It's easier if we go there.
Hey, I want to come too. I can cook.
You guys can race if you guys want to.
- You can bring your Play Station.
- You are totally right.
I can handle the cooking.
Why did you ask him to come?
Hey, it's not even your house.
What here, okay? Let me pray first. Wait!
At least let me win this bet tonight.
- Ride your bike carefully.
- Wait for me at the finishing line.
He will surely win.
- My mom is calling. Just answer it.
- Okay, baby, go, go.
Madi? He's in the toilet.
Why is it so noisy? It's always
like this at the night market.
Later, I'll ask Madi to call you back,
okay? Peace be upon you.
Yes, baby! You've won.
Serve you right!
Go home!
You think you can beat me, Madi?
I'm the champion in this game.
This is my PS. I've been practicing a lot.
Hey.
Unfair play!
Let's eat first. Put it aside.
- I'll eat it later.
- Eat while it's still hot.
- Toilet! Toilet!
- Are you running away?
Why didn't you call me?
Let's go out for a bit.
Okay, I'm back.
Let's get it on.
Start the game, Madi. Are you playing?
- Turn it on first.
- I already did.
Baby.
Baby, are you okay?
Make sure to eat if you're hungry.
Cha, don't you want to eat?
- Cha, wake up. It's already dusk.
- No. It's nothing. It's okay.
Police? Police! Run! Run!
- What's wrong with you?
- Let's not wait until daylight.
Let's go.
How did you get in?
I called you, but you didn't pick up.
I saw the gate was open,
but nobody answered the door.
So, I just let myself in.
- What time is it now?
- It's three o'clock.
Hey.
Do you want to come with me today?
My boys want to go on a trip.
We are going to the waterfall.
Let's go together, okay?
Hey, don't! It's cold.
Guys, stop it!
Do you always come here?
With other girls?
What do you mean by that?
I've never done that.
Yeah, right.
Did I ever bring a girl here?
Never, right?
- No. Never.
- You're jealous for no reason.
Who says I'm jealous?
I already have a boyfriend.
- We are no more than just a scandal.
- Just a scandal.
Stop it.
It's okay, right?
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
Can I use your place?
Sure, but let me do it first.
- What do you think you're doing?
- You can't use my place.
Hey, that's not fair.
I won't allow you to do it for free.
Hey, I've been waiting for this
for so long,
but it's okay for you guys
to do it anytime you want?
Enough.
Get lost. Pity her. Let them be.
She has such fair skin!
That's all you can think about.
That Macha is really greedy.
Let's go.
Come on in.
Let's go in.
Have you eaten?
What about drinks?
I'm thirsty.
I'm not thirsty for drinks.
I'm thirsty for your love.
Can you take off your helmet?
Fuck!
- Is it okay like this, bro?
- Fuck! Fuck you!
Where are you going? Let's do it.
Hurry up, let's do it.
What are you guys doing? Are you peeping?
Shame on you guys!
Let's go.
Eh.
Peace be upon you.
Are you high, bro?
- Toilet?
- It's the door on your right.
Don't disturb me!
Annoying fellow!
Noisy.
- Rizzo.
- Yes.
- Is that your girlfriend?
Yeah right.
Did you forget your friends
because of a girl?
Why would I do that?
- Give me some of that.
- Rizzo.
Bro.
Do you know the guy with the red bike?
Where does he usually hang out?
If I'm not mistaken,
they always play around,
where is it,
the Damansara area.
- Damansara.
- Why do you ask?
Damansara is not that far.
Komeng.
Do you want to go there with me?
You scared?
I think it's better
if you go there first.
I have something to do first.
I have to do it by tonight.
What you waiting for?
What else? Get ready.
Hi.
- Okay.
- Let's go.
Do it slowly.
Alright, bro.
- Hurry!
- Such a loser.
Really?
- Who's that?
- I have no idea.
Don't worry, he'll get up.
Who's that kid?
What a cocky guy.
Excuse me.
Peace be upon you.
Can I ask you something?
Who's bike is registered
under BGH 9234, 125Z model, red?
Why do you ask?
Do you want to buy the bike?
No.
I came to challenge it.
Watch your mouth!
How much do you want to bet on it?
What? Betting is child's play.
I think it's better if we
burn the loser's bike.
So, if you win, you will
set ablaze all the bikes here?
So, what are you saying, stupid?
If BGH 9234 or any of your boys
can beat me, you can take my bike.
But if I win, I want this bike.
Five laps on this track! Okay?
Okay, I want your bike!
Okay! Let's get it on!
- Why did you agree to that, Cha?
- Relax, I know you will win.
Hurry.
Let's go.
Are you sure about this, Cha?
Quick! Quick!
Get ready!
Be careful!
Okay.
Go!
Are you crazy?
- What made you think we can beat a TZM?
- Trust me.
What's up, bro?
Park your bike here
and watch me burn the bike from there.
- Madi, calm down.
- You better watch out.
- Relax.
- Just shut it!
- Where's Macha?
- I'm not sure.
- Hey, where's Macha?
- So, how is it going to be?
I've been waiting for so long.
Can I ride with you?
No. Can't you see that
I'm in the middle of a race here?
Don't you know that I'm a hardcore rempit?
I like "Mat Rempit".
Please let me ride with you.
After I ride with you,
you can "ride" me later.
- Follow me.
- Where are we going?
Just follow me.
- Before I came here, I was...
That's is so rude!
Chase him!
DBKL'S HEADQUARTER
Stand up.
Pick him up!
You really are a fool!
Do you know what you have done?
That is Spark's bike, bro! Spark's bike!
Eat this!
Serve you right!
You made me angry!
Damn you! Show me his leg.
Show me your leg.
Destroy the bike.
Oh, no!
Spark! What happened?
Yeah.
What's going on?
Let's go!
SIX MONTHS LATER
Quick, quick. Bro,
can I ask for your help?
Bro, I want to put this
RX-Z's head on my bicycle.
Why do you want to do that?
You want to join an illegal race?
Don't kid around.
You want to become like me?
It's not what you think.
This is just for fun.
Okay, that's enough. Ask that guy.
Bro, can you fit this
RX-Z's head on my bicycle? Please?
- I'm busy.
- Please?
My friend and I have been
to many other places.
Ah Kieong, Ah Meng, Foo Kieong.
All my friends have already
fit it on their bikes.
Only we haven't done it.
- Isn't that right?
- Yes.
Please, bro.
I'll pay you extra.
Madi.
Let's go.
- Let's fit yours first.
- Here you go, bro.
Peace be upon you. Can you
please take a look at my bike?
- What's wrong with it, miss?
- I'm already late for work.
I don't know what's the problem.
I tried to start the bike,
but it couldn't.
Can you lift that thing?
Mr.
It's useless. I've already tried
so many times, but it kept failing.
I'll come by this evening to pick it up
since I'm already late for work.
- I'm afraid I'll miss the next bus.
- Alright.
Bro. Hey, bro.
It's you.
I thought you were dead.
Come here.
Can you take a look at my bike?
I really pity you.
You can't be a rider anymore,
so, now, you fix bikes?
Take a look down there.
Check my brake disc.
Yes, down there.
Pity you.
After you've checked it,
can you wash my bike?
Alright.
Tell Spark I want a rematch!
RX-Z open match!
You hear me?
Just tell me where and when!
Just you wait.
- What's up?
- I'm really angry now!
Angry, I tell you!
I came across Madi.
My bike needed some repairs,
so I went to a workshop.
I didn't expect him to be there.
You know what happened?
- So, what does he want?
- He beat me!
He's not satisfied. He wants a re-match.
Tell Spark that he wants
to challenge an RX-Z open game.
- Okay. I'll tell him later.
- Alright.
- Goodbye.
- What's up?
- She can go faster if I put on the fiber.
I have to change your exhaust as well.
- Okay.
Spark, Ajak.
Yes, he's with me.
Wait.
Spark, Ajak.
Helo.
Whose bike is that?
Hey.
Macha.
You don't want to give me some of that?
What are you doing with this?
Are you racing?
Racing? This is somebody's bike.
Where can I find a secondhand bike?
- There is a race at 3 a.m. It's RXZ open.
- Is it Spark?
- Yes, it's from Spark.
- Same.
Where can I get a secondhand RXZ?
Body parts workshop. What was that for?
Idiot. Body parts workshop
doesn't have RXZ.
Idiot!
Peace be upon you.
Macha.
There's no one around.
Are you sure this is the house?
Yes, I am sure. He asked me
to come here. Peace be upon you.
That's him. Here he comes.
Take a look at his bike.
-Peace be upon to you, bro
-Peace be upon to you too.
Bro.
- Bro, this is my friend Madi.
- Hi. My name is Madi.
- Do you want to have a look right now?
- Let's go.
Why you didn't tell me
this guy is your relative? Idiot.
Do I have to tell you everything?
They also greatly indebted to me.
Take it.
What are you waiting for?
- What are you going to do with the bike?
- Actually,
this guy borrowed my bike,
so, I have to borrow this bike from you.
- Are you doing an illegal race?
- Bro, who said that?
With this body? How am I going to race?
I love this bike so much.
You have to take good care of it.
The key? Let me start the bike.
- Are you sure you don't want to sell it?
- Nope. This bike has a lot of memories.
Turn on the choke first.
- Did you pray Bismillah, bro?
- Okay. Okay.
It's not that I don't want to beat him up.
If you see him, you'll feel
sorry for him.
What's the point in beating him up?
It's a waste of time.
Don't create drama.
Do you want me to set up
a race for both of you? You have guts?
Do you really want to do it?
Take a look. My tooth is gone.
It's painful, you know.
It's painful? Are you sure?
Or are you scared of him?
- How many confirmed?
- Four.
- Four?
- Yes.
- How about that kid?
- That kid? No reply.
Mat kental.
- I'm taking my leave.
- Goodbye.
Ajak.
Where's Ika?
What are we doing here?
Let's go now.
Faster. What are you doing here?
Let's go.
Hurry up. Don't do this.
Let's leave.
Hurry up.
Zulaika! Are you taking the day off?
Auntie, I thought there was no one inside.
So, you can just walk in?
The reason why I am here is...
You two can chat.
I need to pick up the laundry.
You can get drinks from the fridge.
Okay. Thank you, Auntie.
When did you take off the casing?
I decide whether or not
I want to take it off.
Why are you here?
Are you in trouble?
I just came here to tell you
to forfeit the race because Spark and his
followers are planning to set you up.
With your condition, you should back off.
When was my leg in a cast? Look.
Look here.
I want to repeat that race
because those idiots burnt my bike.
You don't have to lecture me.
Leave, before I kick you out.
He'll be here sooner or later.
Count the money.
- Bro, where's Madi?
- No idea. I'm tired of him.
- We are screwed if he doesn't pitch.
- I have no idea. We just wait.
We haven't seen him since
this morning. It's already late.
I hate to see your face.
That guy just knows how to
set up games, but he doesn't show up.
Relax. He'll be here soon.
There he is. Just arrived.
Hey, you're late. You're so late.
What's the deal?
If I win, I'm gonna beat you up.
If I lose, I still want to do the same.
Deal?
Setting until done.
Madi, come on! You can do it!
- How long ago did the game start?
- Yeah.
Where's Komeng?
He went drifting.
So, you guys are going there?
Madi!
What happen?
Quick! Help him!
Madi!
- Madi!
- Oh God, Madi!
Oh, my god!
- Madi!
- Baby! Baby!
- Baby, wake up.
- Madi.
Madi!
- Madi!
- Wake up, Madi.
- Baby!
- Madi!
Baby?
Baby!