Chiang Tai Dye Mill
Ah Sheng,
the dye has been quite bad of late
The color doesn't stay
That's right, someone must be behind this
Sheng bro, the chief wants to talk to you
Sir, is this OK?
It's all right
Brother Sheng
Chief
Look at this, how come it's like this?
How can this be acceptable?
Our dye is a little...
A little what?
It's the same dye
See, theirs is much darker
Why is our dye lighter?
Maybe we need to concentrate it a little
What's the matter?
They are from Manchuria
Our boss hired them
To mix the colors
Then I...
Don't worry! You can still work here
They have come to assist you
I have no problem in that
But I have to go talk to the others
There's no need; you do your own thing
They have their own jobs
I'm afraid it will delay work
Yes
The colors will be a mess
Relax, we brought our color sticks
Look
What do you need the rods for?
This is the special tool from Manchuria
It's quite special
So it's got to be alright
The boss said, from today onwards...
You will have a pay cut of 20 percent
Why?
Why do we have to bear a pay cut?
You wish to know the reason?
The 20 percent is so we can pay them
That's not right
That's highway robbery
You Manchurians shouldn't be violent
You should be reasonable
Brother Sheng...
This is the most sensible thing
What do you want to do?
Brother Sheng...
You...
Ah Chao, Shih Sheng, stop messing around
Why are you hitting... it's unreasonable
Stop fighting; stop it
Our fabric is getting worse recently
That's why our boss
is hiring the technicians
Yuan Li Hou and Chuan Min are here
To help you
It's because of the Manchurians
We have to take a pay cut
Be quiet
This is the boss' idea
Take it or leave it
Then I'll be the first to leave
Chou Shih Sheng
I'll quit too
Me too
I'm also leaving
So am I
I'll go too
Count me in
I'm not going to stay either
Let's go... l'll go too
Stop
What a nerve, Chou Shih Sheng!
You started a strike
Whoever dares to leave the mill...
I'll break his legs
Move away
Move it...
You want to fight
Stop fighting
I'll break your legs
Don't fight anymore
Chuan Min,
you cant' even beat the women
We'll beat you! Goddamn Manchurian
Cut it out...
All right, chief
We'll follow his orders
And take the pay cut
Now go back to work
Ah Chao
Are you alright?
Chief Ma recruited some Manchurians
And made us take a pay cut
They are violent and looking for fights
They must've planned it before, Shih Seng
Uncle Li, you've been here for a long time
We have been earning a lot for him
You're the color specialist in Chiang Tai
The raw materials are worse than before
I knew it would not work
All right,
we should go to talk to the boss
It's no use fighting against Manchurians
The boss himself hired them
Well... Mr. Li
Can we go to the court?
That's worse; let me tell you why
Boss holds influence in their court
Can't sue him and get beaten up
if we don't work
If we work we receive less money
Who knows how much they'll deduct later!
Why do we even bother coming to work?
How I wish that we knew some Kung Fu
Ah Chao
We'd fight them if we knew how
Don't worry about bruises and injury
Our wonder pills from Shaolin...
heal all bruises
Cures cuts
lmproves circulation
You can eat half and rub the rest on
Better than candy, I'd say
In my opinion we should continue working
Rather not create a scene with them
True, let's avoid getting beaten up
You're all here
Hey, don't rush...
This can cure it...
You're lucky, sir
Take the whole box; go ahead...
What the hell are you doing? Ah Chieh
Our work is different from yours
We have to pretend to be someone
To be a monkey you need to look like one
To be a monk you need to be bald
They always fall for it
How come you're all free tonight?
Our boss hired
a whole bunch of Manchurians
We need to give up pay for them
Your brother got into a fight with them
Ah Chao got hurt too
Let me look at it, Ah Chao
What are you doing?
You dare to sell me fake medicine
What are you talking about?
My medicine is really from Shaolin Temple
Do you really think you're a monk?
Aren't I?
The monks from Shaolin know martial arts
Well, so do I
Good then, go get revenge for Ah Chao
Don't push me into it
I can't use my skills for revenge
It's for peaceful purposes
What the hell is that kind of martial arts?
It's only for a living
Don't lie
Who is lying?
Shut up, let's go Ah Chieh
Thanks, I'm leaving now
Li Se, donate twenty cents
Merciful Buddha,
Shaolin Temple needs fixing
Please donate some money
Move it, I don't have...
Your goodness will be aptly rewarded
He is over there
It's really him! Let's go over to see him
Is that OK?
Don't worry
Gentleman, Lady, Shaolin need repairs
Donate some money to help out?
Chu Jen Chieh
What, it's you
You're really good at this
Of course, otherwise all those...
All those dummies wouldn't fall for it
We'd like you to pretend to be a monk
And take revenge for us with your kung fu
Don't count on me; they will kill me
Are you Chu Shih Seng's brother?
Yes, I am
Are you our friend?
Of course
You see, they took advantage of us
Are you going to help?
I will
What are you waiting for?
Hi, big fellow
I'm not really a Shaolin monk
I'm just pretending to be one
That's it; let's go...
We'll tell you the details
Let's talk about it when we get home
I know this is for stirring yellow
Do you like the other shades of yellow?
What other kinds of yellow?
Are you playing with me?
Hsiao Hung
There are too many people here, hold on
She'll bring out the yellow fabric later
You just follow her
Hsiao Hung
What are you doing here?
And you?
Why are you here? Ah Chuan
I'm... here for a girl
Is that true?
Both of you got a date or what?
Yeah
With who?
The girl with the yellow fabric
You...
That cute one with the yellow fabric
You too?
Is that her?
That's her
Let's go
Goddamn it; you people are too much
Had our salary reduced...
And still you tease the ladies
You jerk! Dare mess with me? Get them
Break it off!
Who the hell are you?
I'm a Shaolin monk, San Te
Monk San Te?!
That's me
Merciful Buddha
Great kung fu! You really from Shaolin?
That's right
No wonder you could do that!
Why are you fighting here?
Is that necessary?
He's great
Good timing. Venerable Monk
We're the workers from Chiang Tai Mill
They are the famous Manchurian technicians
Our boss hired them
And we all got a pay cut
Beat them up
Why are you so reckless?
If I didn't hold myself back...
You would either be dead or injured
All the workers, please listen
Yes...
About your pay cut
I'll try my best to help you
Really?
Thank you...
San Te
You go back to tell your chief
I'll visit him later
Let's go
They left
Chief! A monk has come from Shaolin
Who is he?
Monk San Te
Isn't he the abbot of the 36 chambers?
Yes, he is
Don't get nervous
What can he do to us?
Chu Shih Seng asked him to come over here
Come here; why?
Perhaps he's here for us
Ok, we'll see how tough he is
His martial arts is unbeatable, sir
Is he really that good?
Did you fight against him?
We haven't had a chance
But he did show off a little
His steps and strength are incredible
I don't think we can handle him
So he's coming to help the workers
Where is he now?
He's waiting outside for our reply
He came to our doorstep
Everyone... don't worry
We don't need to sacrifice our pay
We asked a monk to help us
Move it...
Are you looking for trouble? Get to work
C'mon, get to work...
What're you doing? Ah Chao!
They're coming
Move your fat ass
Please come in
You...
Merciful Buddha
This is Monk San Te from Shaolin
He has come here today...
To restore justice
Why the hell did ya
have to blather to him...
about our factory affairs?
Everything is going on so smoothly
Chief Ma
You took part of our pay
for the Manchurians
And you still think we are happy
Yes, he dares to think that
Please listen to me. Let's discuss it over
Chief Ma
It's really unreasonable
I mean, we're all human beings
They don't need to work and they get paid
And though we need to work very hard...
we still bear with a pay cut
The government is controlled by Manchuria
There's a difference
because they are Manchurian
You are relying on
the power of Manchurians
To force us to agree for a pay cut
Who said that?
You don't need to work
if the pay is no good
You'll beat us up if we don't work
Yes...
Please have mercy, chief Ma
Merciful Buddha
San Te Monk
The Government sent them
Please stay away from our business
Don't get involved
I can help you if you need a donation
How much do you want?
Just give me a number
I...
Fifty taels
One, two, three, four, five
This is bribery. Let's beat them up
Stop! Don't be afraid
Violence isn't a solution to problems
What do you think, Chief Ma?
You don't agree with me
No...
Have mercy
You still can change your mind. Sir
Give them their old wages
OK
I'll listen to you. San Te Monk
Merciful Buddha! You're a good man
Yes
Please listen carefully
You'll get the same pay as before
All of you can go back to work
That's great
Thank you for your help
You...
Please
Shih Seng Ge, using Jen Chiehs skill
Plus our great ideas
Those goddamn Manchurians
They couldn't believe it
But they believe it now
Honestly, I can pretend to be anyone
I'm very skillful
I can even feign to be a girl
I'm so eighteen and never had a boyfriend
Let's drink... cheers...
Don't be too confident, Ah Chieh
We were lucky to fool them this time
What if you can't fool them next time,
you'll...
Look at me! Lt'll always work
What are you doing now?
No more pay cut, Shih Sheng
We can finally relax
Come on... Let's have a drink
Go ahead! Let's drink...
The monk should've stayed in Shaolin
Why did he come to Canton?
I saw him in Chiang Tai Dyeing Mill
His martial arts are unbeatable
All of you are afraid of him. So...
I just wanted to calm things down
I agreed to give them
their old pay for a while
Idiot
There are many great fighters in Shaolin
Had I offended him...
All of the workers will be against us
Of course with your contacts...
There shouldn't be a problem
Shaolin Temple
should keep to its own matters
Let's wait a while.
After the monk leaves...
we'll reduce their pay again
Fine then. You can leave
Yes
Let's go...
Hold on! Did you fight against him?
No
So he just showed off a little
But he is really tough
OK...
Please ask San Te Monk to come over here
I want to see how much he can do
Of course
Keep steady
Master...
San Te monk is here, Mr. Wong
You are...
I'm the monk San Te
You are from...
I'm from Shaolin Temple
And why, may I ask are you here?
For donations or to help people
Both
It looks like you missed one reason
I don't think so
Well, to promote Shaolin martial arts
Oh, I practice some time
I really would like to see that
I hope you can show me some moves
That's no problem
Ah Chao
Please let me have the honor, Master
I...
Please
This rock is too big;
might hurt the workers
Wonderful... it's a very unusual step
Your eyesight is great
You can see the pebble from so far away
This is from outside
Your inner strength
should be even stronger
Would you show us?
Please grant us the honor. Master
All right. I'm going to show you something
Come on. We are waiting
I don't want you to hit those workers
You can fight with us
But I'm afraid I'll hurt you
We want to see your great skill
We're willing to take the chance
Go ahead
Monks don't encourage fighting, Mr. Wong
If martial arts is
what you'd like to see...
You can come to Shaolin Temple
That'll be all. I have to go
Please don't leave. Monk San Te
You came down from the top
Can you go up the same way?
I think walking the stairs will be faster
You...
Ah Chieh, you...
Did everyone see it?
You've seen it already
San Te
You don't need to send me out
Don't move
Chief Ma, please don't push me to fight
That's what I want you to do
We can talk about it
This pole is not suitable for me
You can use your internal strength
Show me the best of Shaolin
What is this?
Damn it
You asked a monk to help you
He is a bloody looser
Where is your unbeatable skill? Monk
I...
It's your fault. Stupid bald guy
Let's go
What should we do with him?
He dared to fool you
You can use real Kung Fu to deal with him
You're still playing around
Chief, Chuan Ge
I don't think he can stand it anymore
Please let him go. We'll apologize to you
Apologize
All of us will do it...
No, it's no use
Brother Chuan, we beg of you
Please release him
I beat up the people who cheated me
My goodness
Please help
Go ahead! Everyone
Let's go...
Damn it! Beat him
Look... he is really in bad shape
Uncle Li, what did they do?
Don't be noisy...
How is your wound?
They blew San Te's cover
I told you before. You can fool them once
You can't make it twice
All of our workers were beaten
We are going to lose ourjobs
Big brother
So dear monk, what're you going to do?
God! What was I thinking...
And caused so much trouble for everyone
Shut up
Why don't you try to make a living?
Get some honest work
Don't always opt for the easy way out
Just like you, Big brother?
Look at you! You're punch bags
You deserve it because you cheated others
But not only did you get punished...
All the workers suffered too
That's true. I shouldn't involve everyone
But I made it the first time
No one got a pay cut
It would be fine if we stop then
I shouldn't have continued the act
Do you really think I know Kung Fu?
I can't do anything
You ought to learn some useful skill
All right, I will
Don't expect my help when I succeed
Ah Chieh
Chou Jen Chieh
This time...
Who do you want me to be?
Monastery of Wu Dong or Bai Mei
You want me to be a governor
or an officer?
Tell me. Who do you want me to be?
Aren't I good?
Yes
Look at you
Are you pretending you got beaten up?
Ah Chao was beaten up
Ah Chao's injuries are real
I always try to fool others
Why did I do it?
You don't need to lie
How can I compete with others
without lying?
With real Kung Fu
You're still pulling my leg
You know that I can't do Kung Fu
You can learn it
Where can I go to learn it?
You can go to Shaolin Temple
Shaolin. Why don't you go?
All of us were injured
Will they take sissies like us?
You think Shaolin is that easy to enter?
Not for others; but you can, Ah Chieh
Why me?
You can pretend to be a monk
That's right
You askin' me to do it again?
Ah Chieh
You'd rather see us suffer, Jen Chieh
And let them bully us forever
Yes, after you learn kung fu...
We won't need to lie
All right.
Say, even if I can get in Shaolin,
it'd still require many years to learn
That's all right. No matter what
We'll wait for you to avenge us
I'll learn not only for revenge
But also so that I can teach you
Then we'll be able to protect ourselves
Yes. Merciful Buddha
OK
Don't get close. I'm really a monk
I can't get near women folk
But not me
Don't hit me
What the hell are you talking about?
Go collect the grain. Don't stand here
Collect the grain?
Take it over
Stop hitting me...
There is someone here. Cut it out
I'm not a barrel. Stop it
Oh come off it, please
What are you doing?
I'll make you carry 50 bags of grain each
Master...
Master?
How do you teach these little monks?
It's because I'm not capable
You can all rest today
Please take me to Shaolin Temple first
As you wish
Old monk
How can you treat a master so rudely?
Stop lying!
I'll hang you on the big tree over there
If you dare pretend to be a monk again
Hurry up! Go now!
Continue collecting the grain
Move faster...
Shaolin Monks
are carrying vegetables back
Master. This is not easy to digest
I know
Master, you...
I was a monk since I was little
I was scared of the scarring pain...
So I moved
No wonder!
Please have some tea
Drink some tea
Why don't they drink some tea?
Please drink tea
Go ahead
Good man
You want another one
Such a waste
It hasn't taken effect
Go ahead! It's about time
This monk can really hold it
Better find a place to take a dump
This way
Hurry up...
I don't need any help
Where are you going?
Shaolin Temple
Which Temple?
Which one of the 36 chambers?
The kitchen chamber, of course
The kitchen?
Get out
Hey little one, did you find out anything?
Certainly
Found out every tiny detail. Let's go
Come back! Stop...
What is your problem?
Is this for real?
I have done my homework
To go to Shaolin Temple
You got to have a lot of courage
Did he ask for all of us?
There is the rule San Te Monk sets
After one year, the freshers...
Can go home for a while
Why is that?
For no apparent reason
He needs to ensure your willpower
To see if the person has consistency
and endurance
What will happen otherwise?
You can't go back anymore
And if one comes through all the tests?
He will let them know
He'll tell them which day to return
Which day of which month?
The next day
Really the next day
Two, four, six, eight, ten, twelve
One dozen. Thank you
Excuse me! I didn't see you
It's very difficult to make it, Ah Te
Yes, I found the solution
Just line up with all those monks
Please help me
Thank you. Please help me out...
Let me go...
Please help me
Don't go! Please help me
Do me a favor...
You can get in and out as you wish
lt'd be better if you leave now
Get out. Hurry up...
They walked over the sand
They didn't leave any footprints
Their skill is incredible
Wonderful...
That special Kung Fu of yours
You can walk on the sand
without footprints
It's just amazing. Merciful Buddha
Merciful Buddha
Which chamber do you belong to?
I'm from North Shaolin
I've come to learn
You're too kind... we're the same
What would you like to see?
Kung Fu
We have the same kind of sand pond
But our method is different
Can you tell us the difference?
We're walking very close together
Do you mean right next to each other?
Do you want me to show you?
Please do
Go
Why're you tugging at my clothes?
This is called "Tumbling attachment"
I beg your pardon?
I haven't heard that before
You wouldn't understand it. Move
What is this called?
This is "Priest San Chang
crossing the river"
What does it mean?
The Priest,
when he was crossing the river...
His second apprentice was piggy backing him
Who was his second apprentice?
The General Pig
Are you saying I'm a pig?
Merciful Buddha
Your Kung Fu is incredible
I could hardly follow it
Thank you. What're they practicing inside?
You'll find out if you come in
Abbot, he...
Why can't it open?
Punch it...
Are you crazy?
It's broken. Forget about it
This door is fine
It's not broken
Stop giggling
You're from the North...
Yes, I am
Are there any laymen in North Shaolin?
Not until of late
You have passed the test
I'll take you as my apprentice
Thank you, Abbot
Not yet.
You need enter 36th chamber's gate
The 36th chamber!
You first
Merciful Buddha
Merciful Buddha. Your good name, Abbot?
I'm San Te
San Te?
What brings you here, Sir?
I... um, I've come for you
Is there anything I can do for you?
Hope that you will take me in
I would like to be your pupil
Where are you from?
I'm from North Shaolin Temple
Do they also have freshmen there?
I lived in the village below North Shaolin
How did you get into our chamber?
I fought my way through
And I came in through the Iron Gate
What's wrong with your head?
I... you see, I've got gray hair
I'm still young so I dyed it black
All right. You want to be my apprentice
You'll have to wash your head first
Thank you, Abbot
Abbot San Te
Can I wash my head here?
I'm going right now
Let me go... I need to wash my head
They... won't let me
This water is for washing clothes
Then...
Up here?
We've to keep the water clean.
Take it down
Yes
Take the water down and wash there
Up...
All the water is spilt
Stop it. Everyone
Leave Chin-Long well for him
It's for him to use only
You can use another well for water
Yes
San Te really treats me nice
Does he suspect me? I don't think so...
Can I borrow a bucket? Please
Please lend me this bucket
I can't get water without a bucket
How can I wash my head without water?
Isn't this water?
How can you use a rock to get the water?
There is only a rock
There'd be nothing left if I throw it
Luckily there is no one here
Why is there no water in the evening?
There is no bucket. What should I do?
I can take it off to wash
That wouldn't be so appropriate
Show your face
To fling a letter stuck on knife
is an old trick
The less you think about,
the better you hit
San Te
San Te Abbot. My mind isn't evil
I'll use the rock...
I'm almost done
It's clean now
I didn't remember it's yellow
Why did I bother?
I shouldn't have said I had gray hair
It's yellow
What are you doing?
Man, this time I'm doomed!
Seems okay
Abbot San Te
I've cleaned my hair
Abbot San Te... l've done it
Come and have a look
Abbot San Te... l've washed my hair
Would you come to see it?
I've cleaned my hair very well
You really have gray hair!
Really
Abbot
Please don't touch it
I really have gray hair
Abbot
Please forgive me
It's very difficult
to get water with a rock
I will not try it again
Merciful Buddha
Chou Jen Chieh
You sneaked into Shaolin Temple
I knew it from the start
Did you?
Then it's time to go, I guess
Wait a second!
I thought you wanted me out
No. You can stay
Thank you, Master
You're not going to be my pupil
You've been living here for a long time
You should help Shaolin in return
All right. I'll try my best
We renovate the temple every 10 years
You're in charge of scaffolding
Do you mean all by myself?
That's right
You'll scaffold every single building
You can do it alone
It's a very big temple. Abbot
When will I finish it?
What is your answer anyway?
There's no way I can accomplish it
Absolutely not
All right. I'll do it
Good evening, Master
Don't stop! Go on!
Chou Jen Chieh
Abbot
I told you
unless you're done with the task,
You're not allowed in the chamber
I didn't touch the ground. Abbot
Yeah, that I can see too
I'm standing on the pole
I wasn't in the chamber
Are you doing this on purpose?
No. I'm not messing around
I didn't interrupt them
They can continue
Go on! Hurry up!
Work hard! Keep on going!
Move it! Don't stop!
Please no more... Abbot
I'll fall down if you don't stop
Go do your work
I've finished it, Abbot San Te
You may come to check it out
I've done my job
The whole thing
Yes, I did it all
You've scaffolding at every chamber
Did you know how long it took?
It took a little over than a year
Why did you need such a long time?
I was working hard. Abbot
I climbed up and down
From left to right
Day and night
Sunrise to Sunset
Are you sure?
Well, sometimes I did watch them practice
But please believe me.
I didn't waste time
It's very durable, Abbot San Te
Abbot San Te...
It's very strong
I can tell it's very strong
I want you to tear it down now
I beg your pardon? Tear it down!
Yes, you can leave after you finish
You will be free to go
I have to go after I take it down!
Is that some kind of a prank, Master?
How can you treat others like that?
I thought you'd take me
as your apprentice,
After I finished my task
Now you ask me to tear it down
Isn't that like making fun of me?
You dare talk back to a Shaolin Abbot?
Don't you know you can be punished?
The worse is you'd send me to the Heaven
You...
What did you want to say?
I thought Shaolin Monks were reasonable
How come you aren't?
Shut up. Get out right now
I'm not leaving just because you say so
You're really a cunning monk
At the most I'll need to tie it back again
But I will not leave now
There is no way you're sending me away
I'm going to stay in Shaolin
I want to learn martial arts
Starting from the beginning
So you won't leave, is it?
Nope
You can't make me leave
Never
What happened? I'll tie it up
What's wrong with you?
Are you pushing me?
I'm going to learn Kung Fu
and I ain't leaving
Abbot San Te. Abbot San Te
Abbot San Te...
I...
- San...
- Go!
Do you want to try the Woodmen Lane?
It's a huge incense burner
Get out!
Please take care! Abbot
How is business?
Not too bad
What's wrong?
There is someone here
You're just pouring it down
Look at your palm. You're a lucky person
Lots of people will help you
Please buy some
Give a little...
Come on... it smells good.
I've got peanuts here
Give me some...
Don't go! Ah Chao
Come on. What's just a few peanuts?
Hmm, it ain't stealing
Stealing? Ah Chao
I'll help you
when you're loading the goods
We can off-load a little more
All of you have been changing your career
Not really. We're still coolies
Sometimes there is stuff
We will happen to be there...
What are you talking about?
You're back. Chou Jen Chieh
How are you? Ah Chieh, you're back!
Hey, it's Ah Chieh...
Come on! Everyone
Chou Jen Chieh is back
Ah Chieh
Did you learn a lot of martial arts?
Mr. Li, Hsiao Tsing
Hsiao Li, Mr. Chang
Hsiao Hung
Ah Chieh
You've changed to a new job
Yeah
Where is my brother?
He's still at home
Why is he at home?
It's my fault. I screwed up
Caused you to lose yourjobs
How is business?
We depend on the customers
They are mostly from the Dyeing Mill
Their pay is getting less and less
They can't afford to buy anything
It's all because of those Manchurians
Well, we don't need to fear them anymore
You've learnt Shaolin Kung Fu
What are you saying?
You've learned Kung Fu in Shaolin Temple
There is no need to be afraid of them
Yes, no more fear
I... I didn't learn martial arts
You pretended once before, even though...
you didn't know Kung Fu
Now you've really learnt Kung Fu
I am not lying this once
I couldn't learn martial arts at Shaolin
Why then did you spend
so much time there?
Maybe working your eyes? Ears? Or head?
What did you do there?
Did you learn anything?
I was scaffolding
Hey, are you still making fun of us?
Please be serious
Right. Don't kid around
I feel bad.
I've been in Shaolin for 3 years
Yet I didn't learn anything...
Except scaffolding
Why did you come back?
If you haven't learned martial arts
They sent me away
Ah Chao, have you hurt yourself?
Are you all right?
What happened?
Ah Chieh threw you over
Yes, he did it
Did he throw me over?
It is Kung Fu. He must've learnt it
That's right! He absolutely has
It's fantastic!
But why did he deny it?
Be good! Don't cry!
Don't cry...
Brother
Brother! I'm back
You're back from Shaolin
Yes
Ah Fen, he is back from Shaolin
It's great
Ah Chieh
Brother, your hand...
No big deal. We were waiting forever
You've learned Kung Fu from Shaolin
We've been waiting for a long time
Finally you're back!
Right. We've been anxiously awaiting...
For you to bring justice
Dear sister-in-law
Wong Kao Feng and his staff
They've bullied us for so long
We must pay it back this time. Ah Fen
Teach them a lesson
That's right
Brother, Sister-in-law
I didn't learn anything in Shaolin
I haven't learned Kung Fu there
You're lying
It's true. I haven't
Well, you just don't want to help us
And you've learned it. I'll hit you
I really didn't learn any martial arts
What are you doing?
Let go off me. Let me go...
Please let me go
Did you hear me? Let me go
You're mistaken. You're pulling me
Great Kung Fu
Did I hurt you? Ah Chao
Of course not
I'd throw up if you were really punching
What did you say? That's called Kung Fu
Yes. It is
Please listen carefully
I'll need to try some more
You come out towards me
One by one
Can you move?
Your Kung Fu is fantastic
What's wrong...
Hurry... not so slow
This is yours
Move on... Next...
Is this yours?
It's only that little. They deducted again
What can we do? We need to work
What are you saying?
Nothing
Go to work! Hurry up!
Chief
Move it! Faster
Is this the right color?
Damn you
Get away
Damn it! You're really too much
What are you doing here? We're not hiring
We are here for you
We want to show you something
It's you!
Great eyesight
Show me then! Come on in
Open the door
You can't even open the door
Get out! Go to work
Manchurian pole-man
You...
Do you recognize me?
You remember me, don't ya?
You pretended to be San Te Monk
I'm Chou Jen Chieh from Shaolin
Well, I've never heard of you
I have to show you something
This is Chou Jen Chieh new from Shaolin
Damn it. What are you up to?
Don't move
You're screwing around again
No tricks; I closed the door myself
I'm afraid that you'll run off
Come on
How do you know Kung Fu?
This is nothing!
Watch carefully
Don't worry!
Chou Jen Chieh learnt Kung Fu
He'll avenge us
Hold it! Great move!
Chief Ma is here
Not you again
Excuse me
Right...
Come on
I'll show you the real thing
Using bamboo cord?
What kind of Kung Fu is that?
Scaffolding Kung Fu
Does that count?
Let me show you something new
A little by little
From now on...
You need to give everyone their dues
The pay that you owe them
Stupid
Chief Ma
Now you've seen my real Kung Fu
Please hand them back their money...
If you're wise enough
Never
Mr. Huang Kao-Feng
You were the fake monk last time
Yes. But I've been learning in Shaolin
I'm Chou Jen Chieh from Shaolin
No wonder you're so much better
I'm not here for revenge
I want you to give back the money
To all the workers
for the last three years
Guess, I'll give Shaolin Kung Fu a try
Today I'll have the honor
I'm ready for you
Please...
Guys, the boss is in trouble today
We'll close one day. Everyone
Mr. Huang
It's more convenient to try it here
You can show
whatever you've learnt in Shaolin
Try your best
Sure, I won't feel right
if I don't get it out
Then, please
Great skill
Come on
All right then
Come up and try it yourself, Mr Wong
That's it, Mr. Wong
I will hurt you
If we keep on going
Let's stop, Mr. Wong
You might get hurt or even die
The strength I used
It's like the pay cut
40 percent less
It increased to 70 percent now
Now 80%
Boss Wong, it's 90 percent now!
All right, Chou Jen Chieh... you win
Are you sure of that?
Yes. I indeed am
Good choice, Mr. Wong
Boss seems to be very tired
Please take him back to rest
Let's go
Please remember...
Pay all the workers their full wages
Definitely