Back to those days
Tomuś! 5-10-15!
Hello.
Teeth!
Tomek...
Hang on a minute…
Don’t „Hang on a minute” me here.
I’ve said brush Your teeth.
You watch.
It’ll all be rotten.
Toilet seat!
Load the washing machine.
Later.
There is no later. Now, please.
You don’t have any clean
underwear for tomorrow.
Flush the toilet!
You know, when we go to America,
you’ll have to learn English anyway.
Have you done your homework?
I’ve been assigned no homework.
Are you sure?
I’m sure.
Chicken broth?
You know I don’t like it.
Moskit’s cousin went to the US
and he said kids learn languages fast…
What did he say?
…but adults don’t.
What?
What did he say?
Kids can learn languages quickly.
And you’re an adult.
So, if You don’t know English,
Americans won’t treat You seriously.
You won’t find any good job.
Me and dad are not going to support You.
Oh, really?
Smarty, let’s pretend I support You now.
And You’ll support me later.
Yeah, sure.
What is it?
A carbonite defroster.
I’ll be able to defrost... the captain.
There was one in Jabba’s palace, too.
I love you.
- My little boy.
- Leave me alone.
Hey, You haven’t
brushed Your teeth yet fibber, have You.
- I have.
- No, You haven’t.
I have.
You’ve heard me brushing it.
Put Your new trainers on.
These are cooler.
What was the reason I’ve bought new one?
I don’t know, it was your idea.
Don’t rip Your trousers.
And you stop smoking.
Are you going out?
Mum told me to study, but…
she is in the church anyway.
Open the door, Militia!
Be quiet. Mum is sleeping.
Besides You say "Police".
Pussy! Pussy! Pussy!
Pussy, pussy!
I’ll get you, you dick!
So where do we go, Tomek?
The USA is about to finish the race.
You're a frog.
Hey You there!
Get down the tree now!
Shitheads! Now!
Come on! Follow him.
Get that Polonez! Get him!
Come on! Go!
Geez, you’re so lame.
You’re lame, Moskit. Jesus...
...two, three!
There it goes.
Mom!
Look at this. Mom bought it today.
Is that LEGO?
Yes. The newest set.
Toss me some sandwiches!
I go for the plane.
It’s the latest. Flip it over.
The pirate ship you’ve always wanted.
And a racetrack!
And a car park.
Dibs on that!
Catch!
You asked me how I feel here.
What can I tell you, I work 10,
sometimes 12 hours a day.
This city never sleeps.
It’s completely different.
You’ll like it, you’ll see.
Everything’s huge. There are limos...
I can’t describe it using words.
I work in a huge skyscraper.
I take an elevator to get
to 45th floor every day.
Can you imagine? 45th.
That’s where my radio station is.
It’s cool.
Maybe it’s not the biggest
radio station around, but…
work is keeping me sane.
I miss you, Beetle.
When I look at the sun, I say to myself:
It’s amazing the same
sun shines on my Beetle,
who is asleep now.
Do you still want that LEGO ship?
If so, tell me which one specifically,
I’ll buy it for you.
You know that Malinowski
always keeps his word.
- Repeat.
- Malinowski always keeps his word.
Very good.
Time for your bath.
Come on now.
It’s just a matter of time.
I love you, Beetle.
I love you too.
Listen. That ship is very important.
Write down the model.
6285.
I repeat: 6285.
No!
Have You heard his voice crackling.
He has a mutation.
You are mutation on Your own.
Give it back.
I want to record something for dad.
- May I ask for something, too?
- Like what?
I’d like to have perfume.
- Ooh, perfume.
- Why can’t I?
What? Sure...
What have you done it for?
Well, that’s something new.
According to Malicka,
the capital of Poland is Kluczbork.
Warsaw is the capital.
What are You waiting for, then?
Find it on the map, child.
For Christ’s sake!
That big red one!
I see you, and I hear you.
As usual, Malicka. Dumb as a rock.
Luckily, vocational school
is just round the corner.
along with teenage pregnancy too.
Sit down. F.
Come in, please.
Sit down, sit down.
I’d like...
I’d like you to welcome
your new friend.
She was transferred here
and she’ll need your guidance.
Your support.
Your friendship.
Come in, come in...
Our new acquisition!
- Good bye!
Do you know her?
New girl, you’ll sit with Malicka.
Her name is Marta.
She moved here
from the Kosmonautów estate,
their school was overcrowded,
or something.
Her father is a lawyer.
Or something.
And has a Mercedes.
A Mercedes?
Her dad has one.
Does she have a boyfriend?
She doesn’t.
I mean... she did, but not anymore.
They had an argue, or something,
He wasn’t a good match
for her apprently.
Because he listened to metal...
or something.
And she has a VCR.
A VCR?
You’re a VCR, Moskit.
She wants to trade tapes.
What tapes?
Video tapes.
Video...
So forget about it, Słabiak.
Without a VCR you don’t stand a chance.
Hey, Malicka,
let me touch your boob.
Why?
Have you got boner?
No!
What are you laughing at?
Firstly,
dating a girl is about
just... understanding her.
She must feel understood.
She must feel loved, right?
Secondly,
she must know that you care.
And... you can’t say anything dumb,
or you’ll ruin everything.
Thirdly, Malicka said
you don’t stand a chance.
Thirdly, Malicka is dumb
and doesn’t even know where Warsaw is.
What can she know about women?
Much less a new girl in our class?
I don’t need a stupid VCR to date her.
As long as I get a rental card.
I’ll rent a cool film,
one she likes, and...
We’ll swap videotapes with each other
and not only that.
Hold on, not only that?
What do You mean?
Don’t tell me, Malina, you don’t know
what dating a girl is all about.
Please, enlighten me.
Dating a girl means that
You can eat her face eventually.
You know...
Ew...
Why, ew?
You know nothing about
picking girls up.
Oh yeah? Watch this then.
Hey, Natalia!
What?
You have shit in your hair!
No, I don’t.
The other hair! If you have any!
Get lost.
Piss off, Słabiak.
See? They both talked to me!
Hey, Malina.
What do you think about it?
About what?
About new girl.
Oh, about new one?
She’s interesting.
Pretty.
Very pretty, really.
She has a cool style.
Different than anyone else at school.
She’s very interesting.
I haven’t asked if You like her,
but if I have a shot.
Nobody else has a chance.
Frankfurters!
Handsome devils.
Mom, please.
I can’t help it.
You have handsome friends.
Not on the cards.
Alright, boys.
If you need anything,
I’ll be in my room.
Thank you, Miss Ewa. As always!
I would give anything for mother
like Yours Moskit.
Shmoskit!
Come on. Jeez.
Besides, if I don’t score with
the new girl, I’ll just do your mom.
Go suck a lemon!
Who’s that guy?
I don’t know.
You don’t know?
Have You talked with each other?
I honestly don’t know.
Bugger off, Słabiak.
If you want to know more,
go ask my mom.
Have you heard that?
Game’s over!
But they’ve just started.
We’re leaving.
Come on, Daniel.
Can’t even eat a wiener in peace...
How many times
have you watched Star Wars.
I don’t know, 10?
15? 50?
Oh God.
Something like that.
That’s a lot.
What are you laughing at?
He laughs at everything.
That’s true. Hey, Malina!
Isn’t that your dad? By that gate?
Beetle!
Come on, Beetle.
Go!
Go to daddy.
Dad?
Well hello!
- Hi.
- Hi!
What did you do with my little son?
God, You’ve grown up.
Will you help me with that?
Sure.
I’ll take that. Careful.
What are you doing here?
What do you mean? I came back.
Are You back home?
What are these suitcases?
Come here and look something.
- Alek.
- Hello.
I’ll make something to drink.
I need to wash my hands.
May I wash my hands?
Yes, I’ll get you a towel.
Pass it to Your dad.
Here You go.
Why haven’t You told
us You are coming back?
To avoid the waiting, the nerves.
Surprises are the best.
Actually, I was scared
no one would be happy I was coming.
But we were supposed to visit you, right?
Gosh, you’ve grown.
I thought...
I really miss you a lot.
I love you so much,
I couldn’t take one more day apart.
You look great.
So we’re not going to New York?
Beetle! New York’s come to you!
Look!
Look at this.
What’s in here?
Look inside.
Pull that thing.
It’s stuck.
What do you mean stuck?
Let me try.
What’s inside?
Here!
Look.
Records. Nirvana.
Look, a laser disc.
Oh sugar, it is…
Alright. There’s something for mom, too.
Wait a moment...
Here you go.
You are crazy.
Yes.
Well?
Put it on.
It’s beautiful.
You have to put it on. Go on.
Try it on.
Look, diecast models here.
The most recent Matchbox cars.
Shoes. I had to eyeball it,
I don’t know if they fit You.
Don’t get them dirty.
I’m sure they’ll fit!
This is for me.
“Girl” means girl?
Yes.
This is for mom.
And this?
Is it for Beetle?
No, no. Leave that.
Right, listen...
Look, I’ve thought about Lego set…
And I’ll just buy it for you here, ok?
I just don’t know which
You are up for.
Will You buy me that set?
Sure.
Mum, have you heard that?
Dad’s gonna buy me Lego I want.
Wow! Dad. Look at that.
Well?
Man, You are so beautiful.
Beetle, you have the most beautiful mom
in the world. Do you get it?
It must have been terribly expensive.
You shouldn’t have.
It was Wanda’s idea.
You can put it on for special events,
nights out.
Do you remember this?
I do...
I came back.
You came back.
I couldn’t be without you anymore.
Hi...
You’re not sleeping?
I had to make myself sure it’s not a dream,
that he is really back.
I can’t believe it either.
So, what do we do?
We don’t have to learn English.
What do we do with dad?
You know...
Nothing. Everything will be fine.
Just don’t think about it.
I feel sorry we’re not going to the USA.
Son...
You feel sorry when you are like
a bull in a china shop.
Besides, not everything in America
is as cool as it seems to be.
How is it possible?
Everyone says it’s really cool.
Nah.
Food, for instance,
You would hate it.
Bread tastes like a rubber.
They don’t know what "cream" is actually.
Quark? Forget it!
And mayonnaise?
Their mayo has no taste.
People come off as nice, right?
They’ll ask “how are you?”and stuff,
but actually no one cares.
Money and connections
are the most important.
Let’s leave it here.
Is it working?
No, it’s broken.
But it’s not broken.
Is Your bike OK?
No. It’s all messed up.
Let me look at it.
Oh, there it is.
Gotcha, pinhole.
Alright, we put patch on it now.
Except it’s locked,
and I don’t remember the lock combination.
063.
Hand the towel over to me.
Alright.
Spin them wheels, Beetle.
Great. Thanks.
Everything Ok?
Just don’t get too sweaty, right?
Rajmund! Have You heard Me?
Yes, not too sweaty!
Hello Eve.
Oh, hello Alek.
So You’ve decided to come back?
I wouldn’t.
Well, I wanted to stay,
but I missed you.
Alek, You haven’t grown up yet, have You?
Sometimes it’s good to be childish, Eve.
Alek…
It’s good you’re back,
Boredom’s just begun around here.
- Hello.
Hello.
How can I help you?
Which one is it?
This one.
Could we look at the ship?
The red one?
Yes.
Here you go.
Well, This is the moment.
See?
When Malinowski promises something...
- He always keeps his word.
- That’s right.
Gosh, so many blocks.
Wait till the guys see this,
their potatoes
will turn green with envy.
What is it, Beetle?
What’s up?
Come on. You can tell me.
See, I’d like...
I’d like that VCR.
What about the ship?
I’d rather have the VCR.
Can you show us the VCR?
- Oh, hello.
- Hello.
Long time no see.
Back to your neighborhood.
We’re going to rent some video tapes.
I bought my son a VCR.
Very good.
I bought mine a computer.
Children are the future.
Let Your son to come over one day.
Miłosz will gladly show him
his computer.
Right, Miłosz?
Yes, dad.
Come over to play a computer game.
Well, there you are, then.
Great. Thank you so much. Bye.
Good bye.
A friend from school?
The best student in our class.
But he’s never talked to me before.
See? Didn’t I say
everything would change?
Hi.
Oh, mommy. Hi.
Come with us.
Is that the LEGO?
LEGO, hah.
It’s a VCR.
A VCR?
Alek!
You know, I don’t usually let kids
rent videos on their own.
Something is stolen, right?
And it’s out of my pocket.
But I’ll make an exception for you.
Thank you so much.
Mr. Aleksander Malinowski, right?
Yes.
I tell you something…
I liked listening to you on the radio.
But You are not ‘on the air’ lately.
Oh, my husband was in America.
USA!
Oh, sweet emigration.
You have to be there to understand.
Have You been there?
See this?
Where do You think I have it all from?
Why are You taking five tapes at a clip?
You know what?
Kids these days will rent
even ten at a time.
It’s a good business.
I know what I’m talking about.
Are You going to set some business up?
Money might be here now,
but what about tomorrow?
Clean.
See?
Return it in the same condition.
Right.
Alright. Rewind.
Romek said there’s a fine if You don’t.
Give it here.
So, one more? Before bed? Alright.
What’s in there?
Can we talk?
- Can we talk?
- Sure.
Oh! “Terminator” is good.
What about “Commando”?
What?
- We have “Commando”.
- Ok. pop it on.
What about work?
What are you going to do?
Bags.
Bags?
Yeah, today with Beetle
we saw this woman at the store.
She had a sports bag.
- Right?
- Right.
Very pretty.
The bag, he means.
A sports bag. Colorful.
That’s my idea, I’m going to sell them.
You want to sell them?
Well, not personally,
I’ll just order them.
We’ll buy them in bulk, right?
In America.
Konrad will bring them from New York,
we’ll find someone to sell them here.
Colorful!
I don’t know...
What about radio?
Whenever I have an idea,
you’re the first one to criticize.
As soon as I say something,
you’re against it.
Alek...
I just really like listening to you.
You know what?
You know nothing,
but you pry into my business.
Always the same way.
Just once, for fuck’s sake,
You could listen to me.
Listen what I have to say.
What I think, what my ideas are.
Radio!
Radio, shmadio.
May I?
Yes.
Is that your castle?
Yeah.
I’ve just modified it a bit.
because I thought that...
when you were in the US,
working at the radio,
this was your boss,
He used an elevator to get to the top floor
and can go in here,
you’re sitting here, with a microphone.
An aerial is here
and everyone can hear You.
Look at You. So smart You are.
Is it a set You got from aunt Wanda?
Yes.
I can build anything with it.
Don’t you regret
not getting that ship you wanted?
Well, a little bit.
But the VCR is great, too.
Tell me, when I was away
did mom go out with someone?
Hung out with someone?
Someone?
I don’t know, did you have any guests,
or something?
No.
Just, you know,
auntie, granny.
Mum’s friend.
Lady with three kids.
- From theatre.
- Elwira?
Yes, Elwira.
Mirek.
Uncle Mirek?
No. Mirek.
Mom’s friend.
They had coffee here once.
I don’t like it when you yell at mom.
Beetle, that wasn’t yelling. Come on.
I only had to express myself,
you know dissatisfaction.
Don’t worry about mom, she’s...
Women have their, you know, issues.
Their moods.
You’ll find out yourself,
can guarantee You.
How did you meet mom, anyway?
She was still at university.
I went to see her performance.
It was love at first sight.
And... yeah.
What did you do to get her?
You don’t “get” women, Beetle.
You have to charm them.
Like a knight in shining armor.
I went to her wardrobe.
I didn’t have a plan, right?
I chatted her up.
She turned around, and I said:
“Would you like to go to
the Easter Islands with me?”
- But where is that?
- Far away, Beetle.
As far away as you can imagine.
And that was it?
What did you expect?
I was improvising.
Would you like to go to
the Easter Islands with me?
You’re weird.
I’m not weird. I’m spontaneous.
Like, when?
After classes.
Silence!
Please, go ahead.
Attention. Cheese!
One, two, three.
One more.
Thank you.
I like to come up here.
You can make Your mind up here.
To be on You own.
To stone.
For example.
I haven’t knew the river is so close
to the school.
Well, You know now.
Try. It’s good fun.
Cool...
Have You ever been up there?
You’re entertaining.
Do you like music?
Yes! A lot.
My dad is a radio host.
He knows music from around the world.
For example...
Red Hot Chili Peppers. Faith No More.
Public Enemy.
Do you know them?
Beastie Boys?
Never heard of them.
Then what do you like?
New Kids?
Don’t insult me.
New Kids are for kids!
There’s only one real band. Wanna hear?
Sure!
Oops. Jesus.
Oh, they’re on a cable.
Cool.
Electronic.
Where are they from?
England.
Depeche Mode. It’s French.
And “Violator” is their latest album.
It’s amazing!
Is that why your clothes are so cool?
Hey, you!
Run.
Hi.
Just relax.
Everything’s fine.
There was this gentleman here today.
Alek, tell him!
What?
I’m going back to radio, big whoop.
Dad is going to be the head editor.
The whole country will be listening!
That’s great.
Could you play a song… just for me one day?
On the radio?
What?
What do you think, we can just play
kid songs on the radio?
Why not?
I will, I will.
Maybe I’ll play you one, too...
What are you going to play me?
Stevie Wonder.
“I Just Called to Say I Love You”.
Tomek, go to your room.
Geez, you’re gross.
Oh no.
Quiet.
I’ll check if he’s asleep.
You look beautiful.
I saw one with boobs like these once.
Who?
Polish language teacher.
Yeah, she has huge ones.
But she can’t speak German.
You don’t know what she does
after school.
Neither do I.
Maybe let’s leave it as it is.
Hide it!
How could you do this to me?!
I called dibs on her!
Long before you, you understand?
I called dibs on her, she was mine!
But...
what are you talking about?
We’ve just talked.
Yes You did like hell!
The whole school is saying you’re dating!
You get everything! That LEGO set,
new awesome shoes, the clothes, the VCR!
And what do I have?
Nothing!
All I wanted was to be with her!
Come on, Moskit, let’s go.
We watched the new porn from Minias.
It’s awesome.
We were waiting for something to happen
to jerk off...
But nothing’s happened.
Maybe you have to wait longer
for an erection.
Here, I don’t need it anymore.
Bye, Tomek.
Bye...
For he’s a jolly good fellow,
for he’s a jolly good fellow,
for Alek’s a jolly good fellow,
which nobody can deny!
Thank you, sit down.
Smile!
Well, You make out.
We got it from the head of the station.
Try it if you like.
No, thank you.
I’ll gladly try, if I may, uncle.
Sure.
I’ve never had bourbon.
What does it taste like?
I’ve had it once, but...
Meh, like tea with a kick.
I prefer our vodka.
What did you say the radio was called?
Heart Radio.
My friend got a license.
So we’re broadcasting nationally.
New music.
You won’t hear that on Radio 3.
This democracy thing is opening
the floodgates.
I’ll remember. Heart Radio.
New stores, a new radio, new everything.
Poles are gullible,
they’ll even believe in God.
Danka!
What?
Must be a pity,
in Your opinion, things’ve changed, right?
No more mutual admiration society,
no more party-sponsored getaways.
You know, it sucks.
At least I don’t hear that I owe my life
to Jesus and Wałęsa.
Yeah, because Jaruzelski was so great.
Especially during martial law.
At least he knew what he was doing.
You don’t.
Dad is going to sell bags as well.
What?
Bags?
Son.
Nothing surprises me.
Can You imagine,
Jaruś’s just opened pizza shop.
He’s spent all his life on the couch,
hasn’t done a thing, right,
and now he’ll serve pies up for a riff-raff.
Really? Congratulations.
Oh give me a break.
He is Tech University graduate.
Watch out,
or he’ll get rich and move out...
Uncle...
Come on, let him eat in peace.
Careful, Jarek, it’s always been this way.
First it was mom and dad,
then Włodek, then the party,
and now you’re going to be supportive
for the rest of your life.
Unless she surprises us all
and finds a job.
How about you surprise me
with something, eh?
Big radio host.
You think I don’t know
what had happened at Wanda’s?
Stop it, Danka.
It’s your brother’s birthday, leave him alone.
Do you?
Me? I don’t want to spoil your party.
You don’t know shit.
Uncle...
Stop it, Danka.
It’s your brother’s birthday, leave him alone.
It’s good that he came back home.
Let’s drink to that.
I don't drink a toast to him
being drunk all the time.
Danka!
What do You think, darling?
How many times police were after you?
Wanda always had to bail you out.
Alek was sober! Tell her!
Stop it...
He was jobless.
Wanda barely managed to get him
a cleaning gig.
But no, he’s Mr. Radio.
Alek!
He was on booze constantly.
He fell by the wayside.
He got fired.
Can you stop? Are you done?
- Dad, stay!
- Alek, please.
Leave me!
He battered the shop down!
He was deported after!
- Well, Alek? Am I wrong?
- Fuck off!
Dad...
My apology for an incident.
But you could have told me.
He pisses me off.
I really don’t know why
you’re still with him...
You’re such a smart, pretty woman.
He’s a very good father.
Bah, I know better ones.
Hey, are You a friend Spy-ris?
Why are you eavesdropping on grown-ups?
He’s drinking.
Stop it.
It’s just Mrs. Janeczka.
Why did auntie do that to us?
It’s not auntie’s fault.
Dad got angry and went to the radio.
I wouldn’t worry about it.
What?
Breathe.
Breathe!
Happy?
What are you looking for?
Do we have any Anticol left?
I threw it out, it was expired.
We’ll manage.
It’s not the first time.
1252 days.
What?
That’s how long dad was sober,
not counting USA. If what auntie said is true.
God, you counted?
He can’t go anywhere.
I’ll lock you in here, and then we’ll get
the Anticol together. Like we used to.
Daddy, were you drinking?
Were you?
What are you talking about?
Absolutely not. Come on.
I’m going to school now.
When I come back...
you’ll be lying here, ok?
Don’t be silly, Tomuś.
Helunia...
Yes?
Darling, I have work today.
I’ll have to leave.
Tomek, he really does have to go
to the station.
No.
Dad, you can’t.
You can’t go to the radio.
Alek...
Maybe You should listen to him, right?
He’s right, stay home.
It’s not too late.
There is a school party next three weeks.
I’m saying this now, because I know
you your attitude towards activities,
and someone needs to organize it.
Malinowski...
What I’ve just said?
Malinowski!
That you want to organize it?
We have a birth of a comedian here.
Does anyone have ideas for decorations?
I do!
I have balloons and confetti.
And Purzycki has a party light!
Miss, she’s lying!
Hi.
Sorry, Beetle.
How’s school? How’s class?
It’s good that you’re here.
Alright...
How about “Police Academy” now?
No, son. It’s time to go.
But where? You can’t go.
Where?
I have a show on air, I have to go.
You can’t, call in sick.
Besides, mom locked us in.
You’re kidding.
Where are the keys?
You think I’ve forgotten?
You must take the Anticol.
Call Uszpański and just make an appointment.
Do it for me.
What?
Make an appointment with Uszpański.
What are you talking about?
About disulfiram implant!
You wanted me to work in a radio.
Yes?!
And now I’m supposed to miss my show?
Want me to get fired? Ruin everything?
Mom! Dad doesn’t want the implant.
Alek...
Implant doesn’t work.
- Just do it.
- You know it works.
It’s all a bunch of lies.
Alek...
They can’t make something
that kills people.
You just feel ill, puke, and stuff.
But it’s not like you die.
You can take an implant yourselves
and shove it up your asses!
But...
It’s hard to pick just one song
for my son,
so I thought about my own father.
And I thought
what song could he have played me
to teach me about adult life?
What lies inside us?
I think he’s had a beer.
Hello, Mrs. Słabiak.
Is Daniel home? Can he go out?
Daniel doesn’t want to
play with you anymore.
Hello. Is Moskit home?
Who is Moskit?
Your son, Rajmund.
I don’t think our estate
holds much promise.
It’s dangerous.
I’d rather learn programming.
You should too. Less outdoors,
more focus on your passion.
But I like being outside.
How long does it take?
About twenty revs.
If you want, you can check out
the LEGO collection.
Are you mad?
It’s my dad’s!
It’s locked.
Sometimes, when I behave, he opens it.
But I’m scared to play with it anyway.
If anything breaks, it’d be my fault.
Okay...
Don’t touch it, or it won’t load!
It’s a very sensitive device.
Sometimes it doesn’t load
even if I don’t touch anything.
Alright...
Does it work?
Wait... I’ll check.
So, can I go first?
You’re probably bored with
it playing every day.
I’ll show you how to play,
then it’ll be your turn, ok?
Ok.
Down it pours!
Aim for the head!
It’s just a pisshead.
No.
- Come on, open!
- No!
Aluś...
You’re home.
Alek!
Our sincerest apologies, madam.
Do you want us to take him
to the bedroom?
No. Leave him here, on the floor.
- We’re sorry.
- Goodnight.
We’re very sorry, goodnight.
Thank you.
I saw it on my way home.
I’ll show you.
It seemed strange to me
that he went inside,
so I decided to get You
but there was no one home.
I didn’t want to be mean.
Just thought
You should know where he was.
Help me.
How?
He’s too heavy.
At least take his wallet.
I thought he’d never drink again.
Don’t tell anyone, okay?
Tomek,
everyone knows anyway.
Mom...
Yes?
Dad just peed himself.
It’s time.
May I sleep in your room tonight?
Mhm.
I’ll take the futon,
you take the wall unit.
Alright.
Need help?
Yes, pull out the stand.
So, what now?
Difficult to say,
we haven’t done it for ages.
You were still little.
I was 10.
I remember everything.
How long will this money last for?
I’m still working at the theatre,
we’ll manage, but...
We should say good bye
to the radio though.
I don’t know how much money dad has.
I think he sank all into those bags.
We have to set
treatment facility up over here.
Treatment facility?
Yes. And that takes money.
Ten bottles of vodka,
four cartons of cigarettes.
I’ll double bag it, so it holds.
Hello.
Someone pissed in the elevator again.
ylt’s unbearable.
It’s Holenderowa’s dog.
He always pisses here.
And how’s your daddy?
Mrs. Słabiak saw me.
Don’t worry about it.
No?
Those bags’ve just arrived.
Take his keys, lock all the doors.
And we’ll ration alcohol to him.
How?
He gets a bottle, drinks it, goes to sleep,
and then another one waits.
At least he’ll be home
and won’t get hurt.
We were better off without him.
Every boy should have a father.
One day you’ll understand.
Daniel and Moskit
don’t have one and they're fine.
But dad is sick.
You have to treat this as an illness.
He just as well might have had
a heart attack or a stroke.
Sick people don’t pee themselves,
and they’re nice.
They do, and they’re not.
You’d be surprised.
Turn off the light.
And be quiet.
Helena!
Go.
No.
Helena!
Tomek! Tomek! Tomek!
Tomek! Tomek! Tomek! Tomek!
Tomek!
Go.
Yes, daddy?
I was calling you, where were you?
I didn’t hear.
“I didn’t hear, I didn’t hear.”
“I didn’t hear.”
What even is that voice?
When I go “Tomek, Tomek, TOMEK!”,
then you’re supposed to come, got it?
Now help me up.
Alright, but be quiet.
See? Slowly, slowly.
Jesus. This floor is fucking slippery.
Alright.
Come, let’s walk over here.
Dad...
Give me your hand.
For fuck’s sake!
What is this?!
You know what? Let’s just crawl.
Slowly.
It’s too fucking slippery
to get up here.
See? We’ll just get up here.
There.
Alright.
That fucking thing...
Easy does it. Come on.
Here.
Tomek...
Yes, daddy?
Turn off the light.
Come here, come to me. Come.
Your mom...
She’s a beautiful woman,
you know that, right?
The most beautiful woman in the world.
Exactly.
The most beautiful.
Listen...
When I was...
When I was abroad,
there was this guy
hanging around here, Mirek.
It’s important. You’re a big boy now.
Did you ever see him around the house?
There was no one here.
Don’t lie to me.
I’m not lying.
“I’m not lying.”
“I’m not lying, I’m not lying.”
Peep, peep, what is that fucking voice?
Are you a man or a woman?
“I’m not lying, I’m not lying.”
I’m not lying.
There!
That’s better.
Is she here?
Who?
That mop.
The puppet.
Your mother. Is she here?
That’s good, because...
soon all the...
puppets,
and...
the puppeteers and...
whores
from the puppet theatre...
They have to pass away.
It’s important.
The whores have to pass away.
Repeat after me.
Reapeat it.
- The whores have to pass away.
- Right.
Kulewska, I see you.
Tomek...
Write it down.
internal:
fallopian tubes,
ovaries,
uterus,
vagina.
Tarnowski! Come here, son.
I didn’t expect that from you.
You come from an intelligent family,
you’re bright,
but something...
something’s going on here, Malinowski.
Nothing’s going on, miss.
You can tell me.
I’m watching you.
That’s my job - to see and hear things.
Math:
F.
Physics:
Biology:
Two F’s.
Oh, another F here.
You don’t pay attention.
You are sleeping during classes.
Why did you sleep last time?
You really want to know?
I don’t want to.
I have to know it, Malinowski.
Why do you hate Malicka so much?
What has she done?
That’s a private matter
between me and Malicka.
And what you’re asking me
is my private matter!
I’ll tell you, and then what?
Are you going to help me?
No! You’ll keep giving me F’s.
I’d never tell you anything.
You’re the worst teacher I’ve ever known.
You should quit this job and leave.
Leave?
Why should I?
Because whores have to pass away.
Here you go.
Is that how this Dave Gahan looks like?
I don’t know.
I think so.
You’re quite a man now.
No!
- My little boy!
- Stop it!
- Such a little boy!
Mom...
Hi...
You look beautiful.
Thanks.
May I dance with You?
Let’s get out of here.
What has happened here?
People from the radio came.
He stopped showing up.
They fired him?
They saw him in this condition.
Did they fire him?
I think so.
Thankfully I still have a job.
He got mad at them and broke the window.
I tried to calm him down, but he said...
He called me a puppet and would kill me.
I can’t take this anymore.
I really can’t.
I should take you far away.
I’m a bad mother. I’m sorry.
I’m so sorry.
You’re not a bad mother.
You’re the best mom in the world.
We’ll manage.
Give me!
I know you have it.
I don’t!!!
We’re out until the end of the month,
you must go to grandma.
I’m not going anywhere.
I don’t have any more,
do you understand?
I wanted to borrow from Mrs. Janeczka,
but she said dad... already did.
They know at the theatre, too.
I’m so ashamed.
I’m ashamed to ask anyone.
This is for you.
But...
What do you mean?
They’re great bags.
I have more, so if...
anyone would like to buy one...
cheap...
How cheap?
You decide.
Okay, thanks.
I must talk to you in private!
We are in private.
There is an issue.
This is what you say
when there’s an issue.
They were like this when I came.
When her geezer comes back,
he’ll go ballistic.
You have to take him.
I’m not kidding. ASAP!
For their both sake.
Can you lend me your skateboard?
Yes.
Hello, Mr. Pussy.
Finally got you, you punk.
I’m sorry, I didn’t mean...
Is this your father?
You live on the 8th floor, right?
What’s this?
Dad doesn’t want
to burn the house down.
So he smokes over his chest.
Ah.
How can you run your place this way?
Where’s your mother in all this?
She says this is the best solution.
So she’s no better.
And you are?
A KGB spy.
So you’re well-informed.
Do you know what they say about you?
Pisshead son.
They’re not saying that.
Are You sure?
Remember, you don’t owe anyone anything.
Got it?
My father hit the booze too.
Even worse than yours.
All the time.
My dad doesn’t drink all the time.
Only sometimes.
Then he stops and he’s normal again.
How can you even call this thing
a father?
Look at this.
All what was
good is burned away by alcohol.
Do you have trash bags?
These bottles
must be worth something at least.
Oh!
This is yours, right?
The man in that room
isn’t your father anymore.
He doesn’t even know you exist.
Your father doesn’t love you,
do you get it yet?
What, you thought he’d stop drinking?
He’s lost. It’s over.
Sooner You understand,
easier your life will be.
I’m sorry son,
I’m afraid there’s nothing You can do.
I’m recording now.
I’m recording.
Hi, Beetle!
Look!
Everything’s so big here in America.
Even cars.
I hope you visit me soon.
With mommy.
You’ll see with Your own eyes.
I’ve finished recording.
This is our elevator.
We call it “Windows”.
And it will take us to the 45th floor.
Fucking bith has just arrived.
Stinks of shit here.
Move away dude.
Aluś, show me the mop!
Get the fuck out of here.
Move.
Come on, show me...
“Return to Nowhere”.
I go back through the smoldering embers
of the past
Memories benightedly jutted out
Stripped of the silk
Through the flames of time,
the stumps of those years...
What are You heading for?
What are you doing?
Leave it alone!
Tomek...
No! Leave it alone!
I must take it to the repair shop.
The what...? No!
Leave it alone.
Leave it alone!
- It’s working!
- Tomek!
- No, the head needs cleaning.
- Leave it, dad!
Dad, leave it...
Tomuś, I’m asking nicely!
Give it back!
You’re a liar!
There was NO radio!
What do you mean Juskowiak?
I’m talking about Dejna!
Oh, Tomuś!
Beetle!
Clean.
Give that back!
You little twerp!
Leave him alone!
- Leave him alone!
- This is none of your business!
He has stolen my VCR!
Lies.
Tomuś...
Beetle!
Quipster.
Could you help me out neighbor?
Just a couple of zlotys.
Go away.
Pardon me then.
Hello.
Hello, Szafarowicz.
We need more red bags for tomorrow.
Have You got any?
- Yeah.
- Great.
Here.
Tomek, thanks a milion.
It’s a pleasure doing business with You.
When will I be able to come
to your place?
Soon, I promise.
You said you’ll play something
on the piano. You promised.
I’m going to keep that promise.
What are you doing here, mom?
Tanning, relaxing.
Tomorrow is the first day
of summer break.
Are you happy?
For the bags.
That is your lot.
That’s a lot of money.
You’ll be able to go to grandma’s.
You’ll get a rest.
What about you?
Mrs. Janeczka is going on holiday,
she asked me to look after her dog.
I’ll join you when she gets back.
And dad?
Hard to say.
Maybe he’ll get better by then,
and we’ll come together?
There is a chance to help him yet?
There is. Always is.
But what good would that do?
If he wants to drink, he won’t stop.
What about Mrs. Ala?
Intravenous therapy lady.
I’ll talk to her tomorrow.
But talk to him today.
Could you do it?
Please.
No.
You do it.
Alright.
I’ll talk to him when he wakes up.
Now go to sleep.
Goodnight.
You whore!
- You’re dead!
- Get out of here!
Fucking village actress!
No!
Look what you did to me!
You fucking slut!
You’re done! You’re dead!
Leave her alone!
Help!
Open up!
- Help!
- Mom, get back!
God almighty!
If I were you,
I’d be ashamed to have a child!
What the hell are you doing?!
You should call the cops!
Take yours home!
- Don’t look! Call the cops!
- Mom, are you crazy?
Go back home!
Go to my room.
He’s going to kill me.
I’ll talk to him.
And put something on, please.
You’ll really talk to him?
You’re bleeding! Are you hurt?
It’s nothing.
But talk to him, alright?
Please, honey. Talk to him.
What’s this?!
What’s this?
Leave me alone.
Fuck...
Where is that mop?
Leave her alone.
Where’s that puppet?
Fuck...
Tomek, where the knives are?
There are no knives.
Dad. It’s the middle of the night.
I have to go to school tomorrow.
Mom has a show.
There won’t be any show, son.
Curtain comes down.
Fucking over.
Fucking...
village actress.
I’ll wring her out like a mop.
Today is the mop’s last performance!
Dad, be quiet, please.
You’re still young, you know?
You don’t get it yet.
Look.
See that?
We’ll be better off without her.
Whores have to pass away.
You watch.
Don’t say that.
And stop talking like a woman!
Dad, please, quiet down.
Did that Mirek come here?
There was no Mirek.
Don’t you get it?
We were waiting for you alone.
Just believe me.
Tomek!
Tomek...
Go to the mop
and tell her I’m coming to strangle her.
And then you know what I’ll do?
I’ll climb to that overhead cupboard,
find some rope and hang myself.
Dad...
Don’t worry, Tomuś.
You I won’t hurt. You I love.
Don’t be scared.
Here...
Have a drink. It will make you stronger.
You’re innocent, you know?
Go to the mop, tell her I’m coming.
Whores have got to go. Tell her that.
Is he coming?
Well?
He said you must go.
Go where?
Where am I supposed to go?
Get ready, Helenka!
You little village girl!
Let’s call the police.
No, no, no.
Hide me here.
Here, quickly.
Hide me.
I can’t do it.
You can!
Lift this up.
You can do it!
I can’t...
You can. Push harder!
Harder.
Ready?!
Go to bed.
What?
Where is she?
She has left.
Where has she gone?
I don’t know, she’s just left.
Get up!
I know where she is.
Stop it...
Get up! I know where she is!
Lift it up.
She’s not here.
She’s left.
Are You kidding me?
The mop is gone!
But...
Has he gone?
Have some sleep.
Mom...
Yes, honey?
I love you.
I love you too.
You’re so big and brave now.
This will end, I promise.
I’ll clean everything up tomorrow.
I’ll iron your shirt.
It’ll be like before, you’ll see.
Are you sure?
Yes. I promise.
Our school, our school
Absolutely the best and cherished
Filled with joy and knowledge
Our glorious common cause
Why?
You didn’t even look at me at assembly.
I checked.
You promised to play me something.
I will.
Tomek?
Hi.
This is Marta.
Hello, ma’am.
Hello. I’ve heard a lot about you.
Nice to meet you.
I’ll be right back,
I need to check something.
You probably have
a report with a distinction, right?
And? Is everything ok?
Yes.
Come in.
She’s beautiful.
The door to the living room
stays closed. My dad’s sick, so...
I came to see you, not your dad.
Alright. So…
I’m just saying...
I love summer.
In two days, we’re going to Italy
on holidays.
Abroad?
Yes. How about you?
I don’t know.
Probably going to grandma’s,
or something.
You have two apartments?
No...
Mom is looking after
a neighbor’s apartment.
Oh...
The glass is missing.
The wind broke it.
I’ll bring you a beautiful scarf
from Italy.
It’ll look great here.
Thanks.
Is that you when you were little?
Yes.
You collect crystal dishes?
You could say that...
Who’s this?
A friend.
I don’t hang my friends’ photos
on my wall.
You have so many LEGO blocks.
Yeah. They relax me.
You can build...
all sorts of things.
I relax with Depeche Mode.
Sit down.
Everyone has their own thing, right?
Yeah...
Have you ever kissed anyone?
Of course I have.
What was that?
Don’t be scared, it’s...
I told you, my dad is sick.
You play it so well...
And then you can add some more,
but faster, like...
I see a little girl.
Dad...
This is Marta.
Marta...
This is my dad.
- I'm Alek.
- Hello.
Very pretty.
Close the door.
I apologize for him.
- He’s sick.
- I have to go.
Come here.
Remember not to say anything to grandma.
What if she asks?
Then tell her he doesn’t drink anymore.
By the time you come back,
everything will be fine.
Where is my Walkman?
I think it’s in my room.
I’ll go.
Tomek...
Dad...
Dad, what are you doing here?
Come back home.
I just wanted to tell you that...
I’m leaving.
Tomorrow.
What about school?
It’s the summer break.
Oh, summer.
Come home.
We’ll call Mrs. Ala with the IV drip.
“You’ll stop drinking.”
“Stop drinking,”
that’s all you ever say.
“Stop drinking
and things will be alright.”
For you, maybe.
Maybe things will be alright for You.
But not for me.
Beetle, I always...
really feel like I want to drink.
And I crave more and more
when I don’t drink.
Do it.
What?
It’ll be our secret.
Yeah?
Really?
No one will know?
No one.
You promise?
I promise.
Malinowski always keeps his word.
I was worried.
Did you talk to him?
Is he drunk? Where is he?
Dad has stopped drinking.
What are You heading for? Heaven?
It’s gone.
It has died in flames,
along with my childhood.
To the memory of my father. Beetle.
Aleksander Aksinowicz (1951 - 2017)
In Poland, nearly one million children live in families with alcohol problems.
Help for addicts and their family members should be sought in addiction treatment centers.
You can find a list of them at www.parpa.pl
This story doesn't have to end this way.
Support, intervene, do not be indifferent.