Tulio presents
A Woman of Crime
We got rid of
that uptight type again
What does it matter?
He is rather pleasant...
and earnest
Eeva, you must not tease
Talking about being earnest,
it's me who is really serious
You should know that and...
Look at that and think
You really must decide
which one of us, -
or we think that you've
been playing with us -
all these years
But consider that you
will never get rid of me
My good doctor,
you will soon... discover
I solemnly promise to let
you know in the near future -
and inform you of
the feelings of my heart
All right, I've been cheated
again. - Are you sure of that?
No. I am not sure about
anything concerning you
That's why
I hurried over to see, -
that you get safely home
Otherwise I have no idea, -
whether you like
me better than Kristian
But I do know
This is the most important
question of my life. Answer
Yes, your honour,
I will give you my answer
It is something you
have to find out yourself
Eeva...
Bye, bye.
See you tomorrow
What are you doing here?
Weren't were to meet
in the seaside café?
I'm terribly late. Come on...
No, no. I have no
intention of going there
I am, you see, in the mood
for discovering things
And this time
I will show the direction
(lyyristéi musiikkia viululla)
Eeva... Eeva... Why
didn't I steal you earlier?
That's what I've been
wondering. - You witch
Now you are
mistaken if you think, -
that I will one day let you go
I wonder what Kris
will be saying now?
I'll call him and tell
Kristian... Doctor
We had recently
a serious discussion -
about my heart and so on
I promised
to let you know at once -
if some worrying
symptoms appear
Now I should announce
the big news
Are you coming this afternoon?
- I'll fly, whizz and whirl over there
Don't say anything more
This stupid gadget...
- Hey, listen, Kris. Kris!
These things are
discussed face to face
Take good care
of yourself until then
I have a hundred things
to do before that
Let me just say...
Hello... Hello
Mummy, the person I have
wanted to tell you about, -
but about whom I wasn't
sure, I can tell now
I must appeal
to your good heart
I need a lot of money
You guessed anyway
Thank you for the flowers
Come in, the others are waiting
A toast to the engaged
couple and congratulations
Psst...
Kris dear
Mauri's flower is here.
Would you take it to him?
I'm not meant to see
him before the wedding
It's supposed
to mean bad luck
Gladly
It's nice to see you
one more time... -
before you are a married woman.
Speaking of magic spells -
I wish you all
that's good and bright -
and that your choice
turns out to be the right one
I believe one is
allowed to kiss the bride
Here, dear brother,
sent for the bridegroom
I must also, without grudge,
congratulate you
Thank you. Don't forget us -
although we'll become
a steady married couple -
and then we'll have
a family doctor of our own
Where is your mistress?
- She'll be here soon
She's cooking in
the kitchen to celebrate, -
the rare guest
Welcome, Kris!
Why, this is a lucky elephant
How big and beautiful.
- I thought that if size -
has anything to do with
the amount of happiness
I did try to get
the size of the original
Oh, it's lovely
I wonder
where I should put it?
I was going to serve you
a model dinner, but...
Going to?... What but?
That was supposed
to be a delicious roast
But Eeva, you should
really start learning
Lauri, don't criticize...
I tried my best
Your roast knew my wish
Actually, I had a table
reserved at the Casino -
when Lauri called and invited
me. Now we'll all go there
To make up for the mishap,
I trust you'll let me foot the bill
Thank you.
Perhaps it is for the best, -
as it's difficult
to live on air alone
Let's go, Eeva
I'm sure you'll do
better next time
Eeva, what's the matter?
- Never mind. I'm fine
What an earth is the matter?
Can't you guess,
as a doctor?
Well, what would
bachelors know about that?
Listen, you'll have to go to
the Casino by yourself now
Our little mummy
is not up to it now
Why do you do that?
You'll tire yourself out
Why don't you take a maid?
- Lauri doesn't want to
I'll potter around here
until I get tired
I'll do anything else, -
but I can't
stand washing floors
My head is always
feeling strangely dizzy -
when I have to
bend down like that
I forbid it as a doctor
and talk to Lauri to get help
The tea water is hot
So that now you'll be
a good girl and drink this
What operetta
is being played here?
Oh, dear Lauri
I'll be arranging
an operetta for you soon -
with melodies
and performers
Now I lay me down to sleep,
I pray Thee my soul to keep
If I should die before I wake
I pray Thee my soul to take
Good Lord, bless farther,
mother and son, amen
Judge lsokari. - I must
disturb you this late -
as the acting director.
Pity it should happen just now, -
when the director is away.
They were bringing -
prisoners here by train
and at the station, -
a dangerous woman
prisoner escaped, -
so now we
have to arrange a hunt
She seems quite a slippery
character. - I'll be there
What now? - A dangerous
prisoner has escaped
Why did you
take on such a horrible job?
Now you have to run after
all kinds of criminals
I get angry if I start
thinking about the stupid job
No no, dear Eeva,
don't get worried
It's not dangerous,
and it won't take long
Not long... I must stay
alone all evening again
I hate the whole prison
Why don't you play
a guard as well, -
and see that Boy
doesn't run after me
Well, Boy,
running away again?
Come on, come home
What's that? - My foot.
I stepped on something
Can't see anything in this dark
It hurts terribly
Just a little thorn, that's all
I have always suspected this
Out from this house and fast!
Lauri, let me explain.
- No explanations!
There is the door, and quickly
Remember, you will not
be seen in this house again
No, I won't
You would have heard it
even without this farce
It can be done
also this way
Lauri, there is
a limit to everything
You'll apologize
to Kristian and me, too
Quiet, you... I can't
stand you before my eyes
Is this what you have
learned in your prison?
You're not the right one
to criticize my manners
You yourself are just
like the worst slut in there
If I am what you blame me for, -
it is best that I, too, leave
After your lover?
You don't have
to see me, or Kari
Go to hell
with your lies and threats
Did you lock
the door of Kari's room?
Would I give my child
to a woman like that?
You can never take
Kari from me
I have done nothing of
what you blame me for
I'll travel to to grandmother -
and tomorrow I'll fetch the
boy. You can be sure of that
Hello, lsokari.
- Is it you, Lauri?
Sorry to disturb you so early, -
but it is important
I cannot tell
you over the phone
I am not quite sure yet
You must come here. Come
straight away. - Is it about me?
Is there something...?
I'll come immediately
Shocking,
I wish this would end
Judge lsokari
Hello. - Hello
What has happened?
Your wife... - What about her?
Your wife left home last night.
- So she did. What about it?
That's Eeva's handbag.
- Yes, it is hers
What about that?
- That's hers as well
What has happened?
Where is Eeva? - Here
Eeva!
Eeva... How can
this have happened?
The railway guard
had found her on the rails
She has been
run over by a train
The whole train
must have gone over her
That's why I asked you
to come here to identify her
You know her.
She is your wife? - Yes
It is her.
Her clothes, everything
Here are some of
her letters and things
These were
found in her handbag
Is it true? Is it true?
I heard terrible
things at the station
ls Eeva...?
Is she dead? - Yes
She was run over
by a train last night
Good God, how?
How?
You know as much as I...
about yesterday
Leave me alone
You have already done
enough. - Lauri...
All my life you have hung
on to me, me and her
Look, I loved her, too
It wasn't her fault yesterday
I actually came to tell you
that I'm moving to the city, -
to say good bye.
She never gave any cause
I want you to know
that now, this moment
Eeva loved only you.
She never thought -
about anything else
but being faithful to you
And still she left
me alone. - Yes
We are both alone...
Both of us
Where have the gentlemen been?
- We went to see mother
It's a beautiful stone there
And always together,
Boy and you?
It's hard to watch it. It's
become angry to strangers
Ja-a, poor Kari, -
you must be
lonely here at home
Yes, when all the others
have brothers and sisters -
and everything,
and we have nothing, -
Now that even uncle Kristian
has moved to Helsinki
I guess you are right.
This won't do
I must arrange
something for us
Row, row
What an earth is there?
Mermaid?
Go on rowing, I need
waves around me. Row.
I am rowing, but if I obey,
I want to know the name -
of the mermaid? - Mythical
creatures don't have names
Not even a heart, as they say?
If you tease me
I'll catch you in my net
Try
Hey, hey over there, wake up!
We are at the end station
It's that crazy lifer.
Shall I fetch?
Good morning, director.
- Good morning
They sent 20 prisoners
from the prison
And that Vera Puranen is
one of them. - Who is that?
It's that famous murderer, -
who escaped from
the station on the way here
She got quite a knock on
her head during her escape -
and she's been confused,
but it could be just pretence, -
because they sent her here.
They say she has before -
pretended to be mixed up,
so that we don't have to worry
She won't get away this time?
- No, she is in leg irons
This is where she ended up,
although she didn't want -
to honour this house
with her presence
I wonder if the medical
examination is over?
Shall I bring them to you
after that? - Yes, do that
Well, get undressed!
- She doesn't want to
She comes
from the madhouse
Shall I undress her?
- No, no, leave it
This will do
Children, children, quickly
evening gowns on, -
the director is waiting
You have arrived here
to reconcile your crimes -
against the society.
We have hard discipline here -
but we treat you fairly
Anyone behaving badly
and breaking the rules, -
will have a difficult time here, -
but those who try
their best and behave well, -
they have a chance to shorten -
their time here considerably
Life is not easy,
especially for you -
but do not loose
your hope here
We do not forget
that you are human beings
People who suffer
and struggle with yourselves
Must be playing tricks again
Not this time
She gets those kinds of
attacks... She's a little weird
A little, eh? I would say a lot
Pretends that she doesn't
remember anything
Oh hell, that was
a smart thing to do
The old foxes know the tricks
Pick her up and make
sure she gets treatment
Wild bunch
these newcomers again
Sick in their minds
and sick in their bodies
This is the house
for miserable people
I feel like a prisoner
myself inside these walls
But tomorrow is Sunday
and then this guy -
is going to the forest,
into the sunny nature
That Boy sure
found a beautiful prey
Why don't you call, that
dreadfully angry beast away
Boy, come here and be quiet
The master is happy
to take care of talking
No, but has the mermaid
come onto dry land?
No, but is the big fisherman
on the move again?
Yes, and this time
you won't get away -
like the last time. - Well,
unfortunately it's not possible
I hurt my foot
on the rocks over there -
I limped on for a while,
but then it got so swollen, -
that my journey ended here
Who told you to
go trekking in the forest?
I was looking for good views
Aha, you are an artist.
- Something like it
What will you do to me now?
I'll take you to the civilization
Just get up.
- Not possible
I can't leave you here
in the forest to starve
What do you suggest?
- Take me in your arms
And now, I can't carry
you for kilometers?
You don't have to,
I saw a forest hut nearby
Oh dear, it hurts badly
Perhaps this helps
Wonderful, it helps
I feel good
All right, you can go on with
your hunting. - I don't want to
I will stay with you
until I get you home
Actually... What is your
name? - I am Riitta
What about you?
- Then I am Lauri
Aren't you hungry?
- Terribly hungry
I could eat a whole elk
Roasted grouse will do.
- Wonderful
Can you do it?
- We'll see
This was a wonderful meal.
You must be a restaurant chef
Not quite. Guess again.
- No, I don't want to know
You are Lauri and I am Riitta.
It's enough here in the forest
It would spoil the
atmosphere, if I knew, -
that you are a wholesaler,
doctor, baker or chimney sweep
Isn't it more exciting
that I'm just Riitta, -
and not some seamstress,
sales assistant or something?
You are right, I don't
like to talk about my job
You must be a hangman
or something else dreadful
Almost.
But aren't you sleepy?
Really. I could sleep
even for ten hours
Then eyes closed and
sweet dreams. Good night
What about you,
where will you sleep?
It's warm summer night and
soft moss on the ground
Out of the question.
I'm not afraid of you
You'll sleep here. - But...
But if I'm afraid of you?
- I won't bite
He's not coming.
Let go
Bye bye!
Puranen shall
start the cleaning here
There's no point in
showing off with your amnesia -
nor that you're crazy.
The floor has to be cleaned
On your knees,
you'll get the hang of it
It's best to do as they say, -
otherwise they can send
you to the peat marshes
Look father,
who I brought here
Uncle Kristian didn't
know about your new job
We came, as Uncle Kristian
is here for such a short time
He'll continue his journey
today. - What a coincidence
And now we'll go for
breakfast at our house
I don't like it at all
that Kari stays around here
This is not a suitable place
for children, actually nobody
Must watch out and be careful
Hey, hey...
Damn it, I promised
to make a house call
You go ahead, I'll follow
soon. - All right
Come quickly. Let's go,
Kari. - No, no, father
I want to go with
Uncle Kristian. Can I?
Let the boy come
No walking, it's best to get -
crutches from the hospital
How about a wheelchair?
There is one in
the guest house store
That's fine,
I doubt if the lady -
keeps still
for long otherwise
It's best to show the foot
to a doctor after a while
The wheelchair is fun,
almost like a car
Who are you?
- This is Kari lsokari
Judge lsokari's son
He was supposed
to wait outside in the car, -
but as you are here,
come and say hello
Nice to meet you Mr. lsokari.
But now I have an idea
If you like the water so much, -
it could benefit us both
Would you be my model for
a couple of days? - A model?
Quite naked? - No, not at all
I would only paid your face.
- Well, that's all right then, -
if it's only the face
Goodness, is that you again!
I must say that you choose -
the most extraordinary
ways to appear
Do you know her, father?
- I could almost say so
But where did you find her?
- Well, over there
I was just going to push
these carriages, they are nice
Then she asked
if she could paint my face
Should I ask you?
Does the Judge have
anything against it?
Kari and I are charmed
and I would hope that this time -
you will not disappear as
suddenly as you usually do
and have
a habit of appearing
The painting and that chair
are hopefully keeping you -
here for a long time.
It's very lonely here
And there have been
no women for a long time
Except that Mimmi
Really boring
Who can sit quietly all his life?
I thought that painting
a face would be quick
Listen, how long are you
going to draw the whole body?
What drawing, Riitta?
Now split. - Why?
There are times when
children are not needed
Seems that the boy
is wiser than I thought
He is sometimes
almost precocious
He has been alone so much
When I get
onto my feet again, -
let me start doing
things for you here?
The place really needs
a woman's touch
Let me cook a little and
do some housekeeping -
to pay for this great model
before my holiday is over
Bloody idiot, you'll
burn yourself and others
There you see
the director's washing
I told you that
they must be kept separate
So that they can be
taken care of by someone, -
who knows what to do, not
someone who's asleep
Leena, you start washing them.
Vera can take your job
Hey you,
bring them here quickly
Get on with it, what
are you waiting for?
Are you going
to steal it or what?
Give it here. You won't
get far with it in this house
Gentlemen,
the celebrations start
Well, Kari, what do you think
of yourself? - Yes it's good
But I think
these are even better
Listen, Riitta, you must have
spoiled that boy with your food
But now ends both
the spoiling and the holiday
What? Isn't Aunt Riitta
coming here any more?
It seems not, unless
you and I find a way -
to keep her here for good
Kari, I assume you'd also
like her to stay?
Yes, making things like this
Unless she gets the spirit
again and starts painting
Bye then
What would you say
if I'd ask you to move here -
and become a mother
to two lonely men
I cannot let you go away.
Stay here
Well... I was just going to get
some of these for my friends
Good thing you came.
I have good news for you
Riitta is going to stay, she'll
be a new mother to you
Mother...
Lauri... Kari didn't like that
Perhaps he doesn't want me
to stay after all. - Don't be silly
Of course he wants it.
You are so good friends
The boy must be surprised.
Who knows, maybe he is wiser -
than his father and made a
bunch of flowers for the bride
Quiet, you slut!
Go to hell from this house!
Find out what the screaming
in the church was about
Yes, director, we'll find out
Who knows, maybe they'll
get help in the peat marsh
As long as you find out.
Though it may not be malicious
I have a private
matter for the pastor
I thought about asking
you home, as there is -
simple and
humble wedding
Uncle Kristian,
how come you are here?
I visit here more often
than you realise
Always when I'm around
these parts, I come also here
I also miss
your mother deeply
Uncle Kristian, it's good that
we both still remember, -
and not me alone.
- All right, Kari
You seem to be worried
about something special
Let's talk and
clear things up man to man
Is it about Auntie Riitta?
Don't you like her?
- It's not that
I do like her. She is nice, -
but, oh, Uncle Kristian,
everything is so silly
I didn't understand
that she'll be coming -
to us to live and sleep
Father said that she'll
be a new mother
and now she's there
like a mother
Isn't it wrong that she's
taking my mother's place, -
as if mother never existed
I think it's terrible, -
although Auntie Riitta
is really all right
Poor Kari, I understand you,
but if Riitta -
is good and kind to you,
you must get used to it
It's no fault of hers, either, -
that she met your father,
liked him and you, -
and didn't want to give him up.
And surely it's nicer at home -
much nicer when she's there
taking care of everything
She's no bad stepmother,
like in story books
No, that's true
Tell me, Uncle Kristian,
was my mother beautiful?
Yes, very beautiful
Do you still remember?
- Just a little
Mother smiled a lot
and sang sometimes
She had soft hands
Good God, how
I pity those poor people
So do I, although
nobody would believe it
Luckily I'll soon get away
I only promised to be in
this job for a couple of years
I was so down
that nothing mattered -
but now I'd
like to leave everything -
and start again
it starts to feel better,
although these last days -
have felt twice as difficult
Listen, I have decided to
do the best picture of my life
I have often watched
the face of one prisoner
It reflects unspoken
suffering and pain
She is like a martyr,
with a look like a sleepwalker's
I have always wanted
a model like that
Promise to give her to me
as a model, dear Lauri
Well, I don't know, you can't
paint here. - I'll take her home
She's not dangerous and
the guard can follow her
Dear Lauri, send herhere.
Her number is 311
I can't deny you anything.
I'll try to arrange it
Come in, Vera,
don't be afraid
You can stay here. There
is some coffee for you
We will manage with Vera
Come now, Vera
Well, Vera, there's
nothing to be afraid of here
You poor thing
You must have suffered a lot
Don't be afraid,
I'll be good to you
Wait a moment
How dirty you are...
Per... fume
Perfume. - Yes it is
But, good God,
you are beautiful
Oh Vera,
this is strange
My name is not Vera
What is it then?
I don't know
I don't remember. - It
doesn't matter, take it easy
You'll be all right here
Roses...
They are mine, mine
Try to sit
quietly for a moment
Nothing much
is going to happen
Lucky elephant
The bigger it is
the bigger the happiness
I tried to get one
the size of the original
I know this
What is this? - It's an
elephant, it brings luck
Luck...
Boy, boy...
Beautiful boy
Who's son?
My son. - No. No, no
Come and sit sown again
Have you got a son?
Dog! - Careful, careful!
Boy is angry to strangers
Yes, Boy... Boy...
Come here, nice dog
Did Boy run here?
Listen, Kari,
please go out for a while, -
I'm painting. Please go, Kari
Kari...
Kari... Kari...
This is Kari
No, don't go away!
No, don't go away.
- Let me go, let me go!
No, don't go away
Kari, don't go away.
- Let me go!
No, no, no
Just go quietly
Don't be afraid
any more, Kari
She's just an unhappy,
poor person
Maybe she, too,
has a son
She knew my name
How did she know that?
I mentioned it
But how Boy...?
Listen, Lauri...
- I'm listening, darling
That prisoner was here
She was a strange woman
She got an attack and
frightened even Kari badly
That's what comes from, -
dragging all kinds of weirdoes
here. - You must be right
I feel as if that
person is sick in the head
You should
have her examined
I don't think a prison is
the right place for her kind
Yes, Mrs. Director.
Your word is my command
Well, difficult to
make any sense of that
Indeed
What is her name? - Vera.
They call her Puranen
Why is that?
- No real reason
Well, what are you doing
here? - I came to get father
Go and wait
in the guardhouse
You know you must not
wonder around here?
March, march, march
Don't even think about it.
Now you are coming out
You wait here while I take
this Lyyti into the kitchen
Well, Vera, where
have you been loitering?
But, what the hell
Where is Vera? I locked
her in here an hour ago
Alert, a prisoner has escaped!
Director, a prisoner
has escaped. - Who?
It's that Vera Puranen, who
was modeling for your wife
Why the hell wasn't I told,
that she's dangerous
But the Director himself
said number 311
She's been so quiet recently
that she's hardly said a word
Search the whole prison
and the surrounding area
Don't take it so seriously
You needn't worry about
the fate of a strange prisoner
Leave your work worries
till tomorrow and come to bed
It wouldn't worry me otherwise, -
but because I myself
let her be brought here -
for your silliness and she got
the idea to escape from that
Lauri... Lauri
Kari, what are you doing here
in the middle of the night?
Answer. - Well, there is...
She's hungry.
- Who? Answer now
Who is there?- Look
Good God, I'm going crazy
Eeva, Eeva,
are you really alive?
I have seen
your mutilated body
I have lowered you
into the grave myself
Your are here. You are alive
Can't you talk? What
have they done to you?
Can't you tell me
where you have been?
What has
disturbed your mind?
Can you hear what I'm saying?
Don't you know me?
Eeva, I am Lauri,
your husband
Don't be afraid,
I'm not afraid, either
What? What do
you know about this?
Nothing, I just knew her
There is a scary
secret hidden in this
This isn't happening,
this is impossible
There must
be an explanation
Good God, Riitta!
What has happened?
Who are you bringing in here?
Something
terrible has happened
I don't know how to tell you
But you are brave, always
wanting to know everything
You know that I love you -
more than anything
in this world. Now...
This is impossible
The dead stay in their graves
and don't haunt us as prisoners
She can't be a criminal
Father, father, father,
she's gone, she has left!
lsokari here, the
search must be resumed
She is wondering
somewhere here
Yes, all men to the
search, is that clear?
I'll go with the men
She is coming towards
the city in my car
Yes, she took it from the yard
Can you try and arrange
from there...? - Yes
Yes
I'll do everything I can
Get me the radio police
No, let me go!
Let me go, I don't want
back in the box!
Eeva, don't you know me?
- No, no, I don't want to
Away, away! Not in the box,
not in the box, not in the box!
Operating Theatre
How did it go?
- I don't know for sure yet
She is very weak
She had wound in her head, -
which has been
caused by a hard blow
The bones were fractured and
a splinter pressed the brain -
impairing her functioning
and causing the amnesia
Now that the operation
has been done,-
the brain may
again function normally -
and she
may gain her memory
it may also return
slowly, step by step
I'll follow her progress -
and she should gain
consciousness in the morning
I'll let you know straight away
Water
Kris, you are here?
What has happened?
Where is Lauri?
- He is here
Where am I?
You talk quite...
What has happened?
You have been very ill,
very ill for a long time
You have hurt your head...
- No, but where is Lauri?
Lauri!
What now? - She's
gained consciousness
Does she remember?
Has she explained? - No
She may not remember
anything for a while
She is very weak
and the slightest shock -
could be disasterous.
We must continue as if -
these interim years
never happened, -
until we get
over the worst crisis
She was asking for you, Lauri,
but do remember, Lauri, -
not to tell her yet
Please forgive me
that silly quarrel?
We both got
excited for nothing
I was supposed to go to see ?
Am I still expected?
No, I don't think so
Listen, Eeva, try to remember...
- Remember what?
I can't remember anything
It's like there was a big wall
Everything is completely dark
Why don't I remember?
Kari, my son Kari! - Mother!
Kari... But you have changed
Grown...
But...
For heaven's sake, I have
seen you as you are, grown
Have I been ill for so long?
- Very long, Eeva
Try to remember,
what happened to you then
No...
No!
I can't remember
Don't pester me, I want
to go away from here!
Home, away from here.
Home
Home. She stubbornly
demands to go home
It's only a question of time until
she figures of the whole thing
The best and the only way
would be for her to end up -
back in the same
place where it all started
But she must not yet
be shocked with the fact, -
that you have remarried.
It could spoil everything
But it's impossible. Eeva and
Riitta, what would become of that?
But if it is the only solution?
You should try and endure this
Of course she can come.
- Do you really agree?
Of course
we must do everything
I can be, say,
a housekeeper at home
Riitta, it is not possible.
I can't be done
That's right, and we won't
continue for too long
This thing is also
so near to my heart, -
that I'll be arranging
a locum for myself here
I will come there with you
You must go and rest in bed.
- Already?
You, Kari, will be bringing
my evening tea to me in bed?
Lauri, aren't you coming?
Are you planning to put me
somewhere in this house -
or how are we going to live?
- Of course you'll stay here
Goodness knows
what can happen here?
I have arranged
the upstairs lounge for you
Come here
Well, Lauri...
Come
Eeva dear, I still have
some things to do
All right,
everything is fine so far
But tomorrow is another day
Good morning, Kari.
- Good morning, mother
Where is farther?
Oh, he's left the house
already ages ago
Good morning.
- Good morning
Please come and
have some coffee
Run,Kari, and fetch
Uncle Kristian for coffee
It is nice that you
have coffee with us
Good morning.
- Good morning
So, how are you today?
- Very well
Very pleasant,
don't you think?
Whose things are these?
- Riitta's
Oh, she keeps
her things in here
Well, my son, it's
time you went to bed
Not yet
I must go to the office still
Mother... Don't mind them.
They are married
Uncle Kristian, Uncle Kristian,
I have made a terrible mistake
I blurted out to mother,
that they are married
I don't know, what came over her.
Come quickly, come quickly
Why didn't you tell me?
Why? Why?
We couldnt. I knew
that it would upset you
Dear Eeva... - I want
to leave straight away
I don't want to stay
for another moment
You must take me
somewhere. At once
Mother, mother, I'll come
with you, I'll come with you!
No!
Is that the true story?
It is quite unbelievable
An escaped prisoner, whose
life you had to continue
Subtitles
Timecode Finland Oy