Vodka, straight up.
- My name's Collette.
- Collette?
What is that,
French I guess?
Wow, you sure know
your stuff.
Paris.
I'm Lloyd.
I'm from Fresno.
Pleased to make
your acquaintance, Lloyd.
Collette... a pretty name
for a pretty miss.
It is miss, isn't it?
Cut the cute stuff, Lloyd.
I'm available.
All you got to do is pay.
Another drink for her.
Same for me.
Couldn't help but overhear
your chitchat there.
Not sure Mrs. Lloyd
from Fresno
would appreciate
your dropping this.
Uh, can I help you
in some way?
Pretty sure not.
Excuse me, the gentleman and I are
having a conversation.
- Doesn't look that gentle to me.
- What do you want?
I want to take you home.
Hmm.
It's only my third week
on the job.
The hours are flexible.
The guys are all right.
Conventions folks mostly...
computer software,
that sort of thing.
You don't look like
you sell software.
I don't.
Whoa, are you
a movie star?
This place is great.
Uh, what's in the bag?
Toys.
Wow.
Do you have a butler?
Get undressed.
I want to see you.
Everything.
They're real.
It's a scandal.
This is...
strictly against
the rules.
Are your hands clean?
Excuse me?
I'm a little weird
about that.
Please wash them.
With soap.
It's in the shower.
You did good.
Now leave us.
Aren't you
forgetting something?
I don't forget.
- After I've done with her.
- That wasn't the deal.
Don't be trivial.
It's below you.
Try to relax,
sweetness.
Tension makes the flesh
unpleasantly tough.
Tell me where Bishop is
and I'm gone.
In due time.
Now leave me
with her.
Maybe I'm not
making myself clear.
You forget...
this is just a body.
Inside, I am your superior.
Enough!
That's the spirit.
Feel better now?
1653 Kinney Drive.
That's where he is.
Now go.
Mr. Harrison,
one more thing:
See you in hell.
Now I feel better.
Listen up. You're bruised
and you're scared but you're alive.
That's the important part.
What's your name?
What's your real name?
That man was gonna eat you, and I don't
mean the euphemism for oral sex.
What's your real name?
Franny.
Franny, Franny, Franny.
Franny, you're gonna
get dressed
and you're gonna
walk out of here
and you're never gonna tell a soul
about me, because if you do...
and look me straight in the eye
when I tell you this...
if you do,
I will find out about it
and I will
come after you.
Take this.
Oh my God.
Oh my god...
Find yourself
a real job, okay?
I swear I'll never
do this again.
- I promise. I promise.
- Go.
- Thank you.
- I said go!
Hello?
Hello!
Anybody!
Please help me!
I swear, I'm not gonna
let her drink the water.
Okay, but I may
let her eat the worm.
I'm kidding! Okay.
All right,
she's on the other line.
I've got to go.
Okay, I love you too.
Bye. Sorry,
that was Mom.
She's worried I'm gonna
corrupt you in Mexico.
Yeah. Okay.
Well, I'll see you tonight.
Okay, Miss Valedictorian.
All right.
I love you. Bye.
Hey. You wanted
to see me?
What do you ask for
every week but never get?
A boyfriend who can make
chocolate souffle?
Hot off the press.
You made the cover.
Oh my God!
- I'm so proud of you!
- I can't believe it!
I've got to say, though,
it creeped me out.
You're getting a little too good
at infiltrating these freak shows.
Tell me about it.
This one got under my skin.
Are we celebrating
tonight or what?
I can't. I'm taking
my little sister
and my mom
out to dinner tonight.
Your family's getting in the way
of your social life.
What do you want?
Is Sadie there?
I've really got to show
her something over here.
Remember that shy girl that wouldn't let
herself be interviewed by the others?
Yeah, J.D. 's cousin Tricia.
I called that number she gave me, but...
But it wasn't
a phone number, right?
- I figured she was blowing me off.
- Yeah, it makes sense.
But I typed in the number twice
and I came to a bookmark.
So I followed the bookmark
to some dorky homepage
filled with a bunch
of wacky links...
Ethan, I don't mean
to be a girl about this,
but you lost me
on "bookmark."
Okay, so I followed
the links and they led me
to dead ends and 404s,
but the line kept going.
And then I started
hitting passwords...
most of 'em basic Java
I could hack no sweat...
Ethan, brilliant man
with monklike patience,
tell me what you've found.
That's it?
Three hours I could...
Three hours I could've spent
watching Brazilian porn
or '70s wrestling gone.
But then I realized
that, in fact,
this page is covered
by a transparent image map.
And this invisible map
leads to?
Bam!
An address in Koreatown.
And, lucky you,
a slot just opened up in my hectic
evening schedule.
Maybe I'll meet
some cute Goth chick.
Ethan, that is so sweet,
but the story's finished.
My little sister just
graduated from high school
and I'm taking her
to Mexico for three days
of nothing but sun
and margaritas.
All right, come on.
Aren't you a little curious?
A little, but these kids
are all posers.
It's "Dungeons and Dragons"
with nipple rings.
It's funny at first,
then it's depressing as hell.
I'm done with it.
Okay.
Did you get
that gift for Mom?
Um, I put it
in the luggage.
Oh, okay, good.
Don't worry about it.
Ethan, I know
you're screening.
I'm in Koreatown.
Pick up.
Pick up, pick up, pick up.
Hello?
What are you doing here?
Nothing. Let go of me.
You are not meant to be here.
All right, so let... ow!
Let go of me, please.
Ethan?
Shit, Ethan.
Hello?
Didn't mean
to startle you.
I'm a friend
of Ethan's.
Oh, hi.
I came to drop off his mail.
- I live just down the hallway.
- That's nice.
I guess I'll... I'll just go.
You brought your purse
from down the hallway, huh?
- Excuse me.
- You looking for your pepper spray?
It's not a very
neighborly gesture.
Do I look
like a rapist?
No, I just... well...
Iook, whatever you...
- Look...
- I'm looking. I'm looking.
You can stop
saying that...
Sadie Blake.
What do you want?
I want to take you
for a drive.
- I don't even know who you are.
- A minor detail.
We could do this the easy way,
but where would be
the fun in that?
We're not here.
Didn't mean to startle you.
The Bishop's almost ready.
Sadie Blake in the flesh.
You know,
I loved your article.
That bit about
all the music
the kids are listening to...
the sludge metal...
and the pig's blood
cocktails...
that was great.
So what are you,
an obsessed reader?
You're prettier
than I expected.
Why am I here?
- To answer some questions.
- I don't know anything.
- Really?
- I swear to God.
Okay.
What is that?
Ethan's head.
Don't tell me that.
Take a look.
You're gonna die too, Sadie.
I'm not gonna lie about it,
so you might as well tell me
what you know.
I don't know anything,
you fucking freak!
Now that
was uncalled for.
- I understand you're upset!
- Don't tell me you understand!
Oh my God.
Oh my God. Oh my God.
God is away
doing God errands.
It's just us here.
So stop being a baby
and tell me
what Tricia told you.
Nothing! She didn't
tell me anything.
Ethan found an address
on some website.
That's all
she told me, I swear!
I wouldn't raise your voice at me
if I were you.
Who else did you
share this with?
Nobody.
I didn't take it seriously
until I read about it
in the newspaper.
Do you know who I am?
What we are?
I... I... I swear to you,
I don't.
You did good,
really good.
Hey, you're a brave girl.
You know, I've been around
for a long time,
met a lot of different people,
mostly seen them
do horrible things to each other,
so I'm not so high
on the human race as a whole.
But you're all right.
Time to go.
I'm gonna need
a little longer.
- I don't mind sharing.
- No! No!
No!
Please!
Please don't!
Sex and murder are the only
real pleasures left to man, Sadie.
They fight against them
all their lives and die unfulfilled.
But when you're
one of us,
the two are perfectly
fused into one.
We're lucky that way.
- Please don't do this.
- You don't even know what "this" is.
- I don't want to die.
- Shh.
I've done you no harm.
I'm a good person.
Hippie talk, Sadie. Good and evil
are just imaginary friends.
Wait.
Let's talk about this.
Sexy Sadie,
my sweet and tender prey,
I honestly don't know
what to do first:
fuck you or kill you.
Kill her first.
It's all right.
Oh, please,
get the fuck out of here, will you?
Clyde, what the hell
are you doing here?
- I couldn't sleep.
- You'd better go home.
- Who is she?
- Don't know yet.
No I.D., nothing.
Look, you really should go home.
Why don't I get someone to drive you?
I'm fine.
D.U.I. is the last thing
you need.
Go home to your wife.
Get as far away
from this as you can.
I'll keep you posted.
We need Mrs. Blake
to sign some forms.
Come on, Sadie.
You don't need it that bad.
Oh, thanks a bunch.
God.
- Where are you headed?
- Uh, Santa Barbara.
But, you know, anywhere
north works really.
- I'm Alex.
- Is that where you're from?
Uh, San Diego,
but, you know,
I'm just visiting some
buddies from law school
to do a little... a little partying
before next semester.
You like it toasty.
That's cool.
Are you hungry?
I'm good.
Thanks.
Listen, you're not a cop,
are you?
Do I look like a cop?
They wish.
No no no no no.
I'm just asking
'cause I, um...
I was gonna offer you
some weed.
Oh, you go ahead.
I don't mind.
You don't? Okay.
So, Alex,
you got a wife?
No.
Any kids depending on you?
Not that I know of.
What about a girlfriend?
Nope. Not really.
What're you doing?
You heard that saying
"Gas, grass or ass..."?
I've seen
the bumper sticker.
Well, with me,
you get all three.
Actually, I do
have a girlfriend.
We all have
our problems, Alex.
Okay, look, I'm gonna take
one more hit before...
Okay, don't mind me.
Coming in,
or are you just gonna watch?
I believe the proper term
is "feast my eyes."
"Feast"? Nobody has ever
called me a feast before.
I would forego
all the bribes in heaven
to feast my eyes on you,
throw my arms around you
and take you home.
Well, you've already
got me home,
so why don't you throw
a towel instead?
What time is
the party tonight?
Midnight.
Mmm. And when
in the world do we eat?
Don't you ever
get hungry?
I eat.
So tell me about
your family.
Mmm.
I don't really talk
to my dad much.
My mom's remarried
and she lives in Reno.
And I have
a sister who was born
a minute earlier than me.
She's a real freak, though.
I was always, like,
the goody two shoes
and she was
very adventurous.
She'll never believe me
when I tell her about you.
- How do you mean?
- Come on.
A straight,
single rich guy
with a sense of humor
who's hung like
an Australian alligator.
Come on, Bishop, I've never
met anyone like you before.
She'll think
I made you up.
I bet you were
an adorable virgin.
So random.
What do you
even mean by that?
Did you bleed much...
your first time?
You really want to know?
Jenny, I once had
a friend who said,
"Sex and murder are the only
real pleasures left to man."
You're starting
to freak me out.
I had you going
for a second, didn't I?
I almost gave sweet Jenny
indigestion there, Poe.
You should tell her she can't
be too careful these days.
Rich elegant bachelors
are often psychotic.
- Hmm.
- True.
To Australian alligators.
The blood of Christ...
- You do have a point, though.
- Which one?
About sex and murder being
man's main pleasure.
Well, it certainly seems
that way these days.
Not to sound reactionary.
So which one are you
gonna use me for?
Mmm.
Both.
We've got to stop
meeting like this, Clyde.
I'm getting closer.
Closer to getting me fired.
- Don't be an asshole.
- Too late.
I tell you what: you make yourself
invisible from now on
and I will keep you
up to date on everything.
He may not keep you
up to date.
Who knows how long it would have
taken for your guys to find this John.
Yeah, point taken.
- Look, how much this means to you...
- Don't.
What I meant was,
I can only imagine.
And I wish you could be part of this
officially, but seeing as how you...
It's okay, Joe.
I'll play ball.
But you can't go lifting evidence
from my crime scene.
I sure can.
I'm invisible, remember?
Oh, fuck.
Turn around slow.
Emphasis on slow.
I'll take that phone.
- Where's Bishop?
- He didn't tell me.
You don't need that
with me.
I'm not...
not like you.
World-class
understatement.
As for you being human,
that's purely a technicality.
Humor me here,
how much does Bishop
pay you for this?
I'll make it easy for you.
You just dropped him off
somewhere.
I can't tell you.
He will kill me.
He won't get the chance.
I'm an old man.
Please take mercy.
I'm fresh out just now.
He's running.
He doesn't know
it's you.
He thinks a cop
is after him.
What cop?
All he knows is what
happened to the others.
Where is he going?
Don't take pauses because
it makes me think you're lying.
I am not afraid to die.
Yeah, well,
death is different now.
Daddy.
- Yeah?
- You awake?
Robin Hood's had a busy night.
Two more bodies.
Maybe we have
a blood sample to match to.
It's a she.
Paid a late-night visit
to a local drugstore,
bought supplies
to dress a knife wound.
Any ideas about
her destination?
We've got a parking-lot surveillance
shot of a license plate.
Yeah.
I got it.
Hello, Bishop.
Poe won't be checking
his messages any longer.
We can discuss that
if you like.
I understand you being
a little raw about it.
We should meet.
I figure you should have
the chance to see my face
before I kill you.
Wonton's.
A man made a call from that phone
back there about 20 minutes ago.
I wonder what you can
tell me about him.
It's a public phone.
Lots of people use it.
This guy was in his 30s,
dark hair, the kind
women might go for.
Oh, and my drink's
red wine.
Are you a cop,
his wife, what?
Cop, lover, baby sister...
really, who cares?
You don't want this guy
as a regular.
Anything you noticed might
help me out big time.
Don't get me wrong,
I'd love to take your money,
but the guy came in,
had a drink,
made a phone call,
that's it.
Did he exit
front or back?
Did you see his car?
Did he talk to anyone here?
Nope. I've never
seen him before.
I have to get
tipped, though.
If you ever see him again,
call me at this number
and I'll keep these coming.
"Eve."
Is that your name?
Sorry to bother you,
but I overheard you talking
to the bartender in there.
- You're looking for Bishop, right?
- What do you know about him?
- I know where he's staying.
- He sent you to tell me?
To tell you? No.
- He sent me to take you there.
- I'll get my stuff.
Did I overdo it?
What do you think, dipshit?
Help me.
All right, you take her car
and you meet me there.
What?!
It's a stick.
I can't drive it.
- Learn, man.
- But you're the better driver.
Dwayne, don't become
a problem.
Plus, she has the keys.
What are you doing?
Maybe she's got them
in her breast pocket.
She doesn't have
a breast pocket.
I don't hear
her complaining.
We're sitting ducks here and you're
feeling her up? Come on, man!
Hey, easy, bro.
Can I help it that she's a fox?
Yes?
Hello?
Who is this?
Mom?
Sadie?
Is this you?
Mom, I love you so much.
Where... where are you,
honey?
Is this really you?
You take good care
of yourself and Beth, okay?
Mom, what are you doing?
It's your sister,
sweetheart!
No, Mom.
Sadie's dead, remember?
Welcome to Mexico.
I'm in Mexico?
Well, technically,
you're still
in California,
but who can tell
the difference, huh?
How are you feeling?
Not great.
Yes, physics will
do that to you...
gravity, trucks,
concrete.
You found out the hard way
that you cannot die...
at least not like
regular people.
Who are you?
I am someone who is
very interested
in this... this man
you hate so much... Bishop.
You know him?
You were talking
in your sleep.
There's two kinds of people
that talk in their sleep:
People who can't shut up,
and people who have
something to say.
Get some rest.
Thank you.
What do you want?
I want to be alive again.
You can't.
Ask yourself,
what do you want now?
I want to stop them
from doing this to anyone else.
Open your right hand.
- Then you will do that.
- How?
In English, it's "I'm going
to be your godfather."
I will guide you
in your search,
in your work.
But how will I find them?
It is not hard to find those
who don't know that
you're looking for them.
But...
Rourke, Eve,
Harrison, Poe...
...Bishop.
Those are their names.
How did you know?
I know some people
that can get you over here.
Now it's up to you
to work your way over here.
But you have to start
at the bottom.
You won't make it if you go
straight to Bishop.
Understand?
This will help you survive
for a while.
And when it runs out?
I can't do it.
I won't kill
innocent people.
Every war has
its casualties, Sadie.
And don't fool yourself.
Nobody's innocent...
nadie.
Nadie.
Hello.
How can I help you?
- What room is Rourke in?
- Room number 310.
Hey!
- What do you want?
- You.
- Lady, what the hell did you do?
- Call the cops.
Tell me where
to find Eve.
- Who are you?
- Where is she?
You're that reporter...
who went diggin'...
a little too deep.
If you think I've forgotten my question,
you're sadly mistaken.
- I don't know where she is.
- I'm gonna call the cops!
I thought I already
asked you to.
- You really don't know?
- Try a place called The Red Angel.
- She hangs out there, I think.
- You think?
I can take you to her
if it's this important.
It might come as a shock,
how little you feel
about that first kill...
but it would be
a grave mistake
to think that handling Eve
will be as simple.
Don't let her
get inside your head.
Hey!
You're a beautiful woman.
- Out.
- Whoa!
- Now.
- Whoa, Miss Hot Shit,
who made you God?
Tell me again what you said
on the dance floor.
I said I can never dance with
a hard-on pressed against my leg.
Oh yeah.
Shit, that is so hot!
Sailor, uh...
this is my sister.
What the fuck is she doing
with that harpoon?
Lord Almighty.
Sadie Blake.
You have a million
questions, I bet.
That's your cue to leave.
Here.
It's okay.
Bishop was done
feeding off you
and still
you wouldn't die.
So he gave you to me
to finish off.
- Why didn't you?
- Believe me, I tried.
But I have never seen
anyone put up such a fight.
You didn't have enough blood
left in you for a pulse.
I figured somewhere deep inside
you wanted to stay here.
So you took pity on me,
is that it?
- I owe you?
- You owe it to yourself
to stop hating
what you are
and understand
your fear.
Who says I'm afraid?
Fear is where we go
to learn.
That's where you went
for three days.
- Maybe more.
- What are you talking about?
It takes three days
to turn someone
and it's a very
delicate process.
Only a handful of us
even know how to do it.
I started you, but you finished it
on your own,
alone in that morgue.
You became one of us because
that's what you wanted.
I'm not like you.
And I'm not one of you.
Are you sure?
I'm really gonna have to
ask you to leave now.
One last round, darling.
Sorry, it's already way past closing.
I'll get in trouble.
I'll never ask
for anything again.
Girl Scout's honor.
Can you spare
a cigarette?
How many of you are there?
Not as many as there used to be,
that's for sure.
Nature's way, perhaps.
If so, nature's pretty
damned unmerciful.
Are you merciful?
I draw the line, sure...
no children, no babies...
not like Harrison.
- And you?
- What about me?
Well, you must have gone through some
pretty gruesome self-discoveries.
You must have found
shelter somewhere...
a weapon maker.
Something like that.
So how is Arturo?
He's one of you.
Not just one of us.
He... he ran everything
till Bishop got sick of it.
He really didn't tell you
any of this?
He's always been wise.
You never would have started this
if you knew you were just his pawn.
His pawn for what?
To get rid of Bishop.
Five minutes, guys.
It's full moon tonight.
The best moon of the year
to be with the one you love.
If that's a confession...
you picked the wrong time.
It's a declaration.
We all have our purpose.
I simply forgot what mine was
a long time ago.
I prayed you would come,
Sadie Blake.
If that's what you want.
I can't have what I want.
So do what you
came here to do.
And good luck to you.
Hello?
Fuck!
How'd she do that?
I have a gun!
I don't want
to hurt you.
Oh shit.
I can't move.
I think you broke my leg.
Sure looks like it.
Holy shit,
you fucking maniac, you!
I had a bag...
where is it?
What bag,
you crazy bit... ahh!
Don't change
the subject again.
Do we understand
each other?
My bag, where it is?
Dwayne took it.
- He took your car.
- Where?
It's a place called The Crest.
It's about 20 miles from here.
It's a deserted compound
with a bunch of stables in it.
- That's where Bishop is?
- I guess.
Look, you've gotta
believe me.
I don't know jack
about any of this, okay?
Bishop just told me
to bring you to him.
- He said my name? He knows who I am?
- No no.
I was instructed to go
to the bar
and bring in anyone
who came in asking for him.
Do you know
what Bishop is?
I heard he's the leader
of this cult
and they have
these crazy house orgies,
but I didn't believe
any of the shit
about them feeding on people.
I just...
I thought I'd hook up with some Goth
chicks who are into threesomes.
What is it with you geeky guys and these
Goth chicks anyway?
Please, please,
please don't kill me.
I'm sorry that I hurt you.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so goddamn sorry!
I've never done a bad thing in my life.
I beg you.
When is this party
supposed to be?
Tomorrow at midnight.
These kids that I heard it from
are serious about...
hey, wait!
Wait, hey!
How am I supposed to...
Dear Jesus,
my Savior,
I know
I've neglected you
so bad for so long,
but if you could
help me out of this...
Sadie...
I feel the same way
about you.
- Yes.
- Hello, is this Eve?
Yes.
You told me to call
if I saw that guy again,
- The one we talked about earlier.
- Sure.
Well, he just walked
into the bar.
- Where is he?
- Eve?
- What do you want?
- I want to ask you a few questions.
I'm not in a chatty mood,
Officer.
That obvious, huh?
I think this belongs to you.
Where did you find that?
A redneck named
Dwayne Musgrove
borrowed your car
a little earlier tonight.
The kid can steal cars
but he sure as hell can't drive 'em.
- I know you.
- Do you?
Yeah,
I never forget a face.
Occupational hazard.
What occupation
would that be?
I'm gonna grab that bag
and walk out of here.
I won't hurt you
if you don't try to stop me.
That's one hell of an if.
That's up to you.
- Just a few more questions.
- Maybe some other time.
Here I thought bartenders
were supposed to be like priests.
I'm sorry.
Drop the bag.
Put your hands on the bar. Do it.
- You're under arrest.
- I don't have time for this.
- You have the right to remain silent.
- I need my gear!
I suggest you use
that goddamn right.
Listen to me.
You don't understand!
Oh, sure I do.
Everybody's innocent.
Not me.
Not by a mile.
Did you kill her?
- Was it you?
- Who?
My daughter.
I know you were there.
- Did you touch her?
- Hey, man, take it easy.
Back the fuck off!
Don't you move.
Go. Go!
I'm not who you
think I am.
Really?
You're not a killer?
Tricia's the reason
I'm in this mess to begin with,
but I didn't kill her.
I'm after the man who did.
- Why?
- Because he did the same thing to me.
What are you
talking about?
These people are...
are not...
I'm not one of them.
I'm trying to get rid of them.
And he's the only one left.
His name is Bishop.
I'm gonna kill him.
And the moment that happens
I'm... I'm done.
I'm not a person anymore.
I'll tell you what:
backup's on the way.
You tell them exactly
what you just told me
and we'll see what kind
of deal they cut you.
Look at me.
In the mirror.
You really
don't remember me?
Because I remember you.
My name is Sadie Blake.
I...
I was a reporter.
That's...
that's impossible.
I zipped you
into a body bag.
You can come with me
if you like.
I'll kill your daughter's
killer for you.
And you can return the favor
by killing me.
I can't do that.
Your daughter was raped,
gutted,
and left in a dumpster,
but you can't do that?!
All right...
let's say I believe you.
I still can't help you.
Then this whole conversation's
a waste of time I don't have.
Sorry.
Keys to the cuffs.
Slow.
If you even think about
going for your piece,
I will snap your neck.
Now the bag.
Slow.
Okay, now the tricky part.
Your gun...
toss it out the window.
Please don't give me
a reason.
I'm gonna release you now,
nice and easy.
It takes me 4.3 seconds
to load that crossbow. I've timed it.
You keep that in mind
when you make a run for your life.
Let's try this again.
You're under arrest.
I will fire
if you don't stop!
Last warning.
That fucking hurt.
All right,
Number one's right there
beneath the surface.
I can just barely
make it out.
I'm going to douse the wound
with alcohol.
How many times
have you done this?
You don't wanna know.
Ooh!
Tell me about
your condition.
I'm in pain, I'm exhausted,
I'm angry.
I didn't mean currently.
I meant since...
it happened to you.
What's it like?
Pain, exhaustion, anger.
That's what it's like.
Is it genetic?
I haven't exactly
volunteered for tests.
- What about food?
- What about it?
You can't keep down
regular food?
You have a skillful way
of putting a girl at ease, Rawlins.
Try asking me anything else.
How many guys have
you slept with?
Since my, uh...
what did you call it,
condition?
- None, I guess.
- You guess?
I was taught to never
play with my food.
Number one.
I do apologize.
Hey, you needed proof, right?
I meant I apologize
for what comes next.
That was the easy one.
This one's really gonna hurt.
No shame in passing out.
Water.
Do you mind brushing the hair
out of my eyes?
What time is it?
Late afternoon.
You must have been tired.
Aren't we past all this?
I have to use the bathroom.
You're still
a serial killer.
And I do hate surprises.
All right, stand up
and turn around.
Come on,
what am I gonna do?
You're gonna turn around,
that's what.
Can you at least
cuff me in the front?
It's kind of hard to wipe
with your hands behind your back.
The door stays open.
No arguing.
Cheap thrills.
Were you and Tricia
very close?
Not so much over
the last few years.
Let me guess:
your marriage, your job,
you neglected
your wife and kid,
took them for granted.
If you're aiming
for "perceptive,"
it's coming off
painfully smug.
- Sorry, what I meant was...
- I know what you meant.
Doesn't mean
I don't regret it.
You need help
with that?
In my whole life,
you're the first guy
who's ever offered
to put my pants back on.
I'm not here
to flirt with you.
Oh, I forgot how awkward conversations
get between men and women.
Would you? I can't
twist my wrists properly.
Thank you.
The condition is genetic.
I mean, I'm no doctor, but I've never
seen tissue regenerate like that.
- It's incredible.
- Are we getting personal now?
Well, I did just zip up
your jeans.
You're funny.
Don't assume you know me.
You don't know me.
I know that you drink
a little too much.
I know what you've eaten
in the last 48 hours.
And I know that I'm
turning you on right now.
You have a vivid imagination.
Overdeveloped
sense of smell, actually.
Are we gonna do this,
yes or no?
Long as you remember
our deal.
I kill Bishop,
you kill me.
I remember.
Now let's go.
We have to wait
till sundown.
You are aware
that there are a dozen cops
canvassing the area
looking for two sore thumbs?
We still have to wait
till sundown.
All right.
Tell me everything you know
about this cult,
from the beginning.
Not much of a party.
Look,
we stick together...
no matter what.
Then what's
with the radio?
That's in case
you forget.
I need you to mail this
for me once we're done.
- Your mother?
- I never got to say goodbye.
Rawlins.
Jesus fucking Christ.
You know him?
That's the kid
who stole your car.
He hasn't been dead long.
That blood is still fresh.
Tricia?
Tricia!
Oh my God!
Daddy!
Oh! Oh God!
Oh God!
It's horrible.
They're all dead.
- They're all dead.
- I'm here with you now.
I will never let anything
happen to you again.
Get... get 'em off
before he comes back.
- Hurry!
- Sadie!
- Rawlins...
- Come and help me, quick!
- Rawlins, get up.
- What's the matter?
Get up.
- What's the matter with you?
- She's one of them.
You saw her body
in that dumpster.
- No.
- Bishop turned her. Think it through.
Put the gun down!
Sweetheart?
I'm not your sweetheart.
You make me sick.
I hate everything
you stand for.
But you no longer
have power over me.
I'm free now.
That's not you talking.
They've done this to you.
Bishop predicted you
would act just like this...
blame it all
on brainwashing
because you can't fathom the idea I can
make up my own mind.
- No.
- I finally have a place where I belong.
Tricia...
I'm your father
and I love you.
Bishop is my father
and my brother
and my lover.
It would blow your mind,
the things he makes me do.
He makes me whole.
And you?
You're nothing
to me. Nothing.
Put the gun down now!
And I won't
let you destroy
the one good thing
in my life.
Bye, Daddy.
No!
It's not you
I'm after!
Fuck off!
Suits me.
Why are you
helping him?
He wants to
get rid of us.
He doesn't understand
anything.
You've got five seconds
to tell me where Bishop is.
Five...
- Four...
- Never!
One.
Just when you think life won't ever
surprise you again.
18 next week...
never been to New York.
I promised I'd take her.
Change of plans.
Her father's behavior
I can understand,
but why are you doing this?
- You're one of us.
- Not by choice.
Choice, what is that?
Who has a choice
in anything?
You had a choice in raping me
and leaving me for dead!
You're being childish.
There's an order to things.
Everything happens for a reason.
Maybe revenge is just a story that
you're telling yourself.
Maybe it's just an excuse
to become what you
really are.
I'm not like you.
I see.
Don't you think we were all
scared and confused at first?
I'm not like you.
You keep saying it
to yourself enough times,
maybe you'll
convince yourself.
You're insane.
My definition of insane
is a person who sees
a gift as a curse.
Personally, I think you have
to play the cards you're dealt.
And here's where that word
you like so much... choice... comes in.
I choose to experience
everything
the world has to offer
in exchange for a few
meaningless lives.
These closet pedophiles
and spoiled teenagers
aren't going to be missed
by anyone, Sadie.
So the choice
is all yours:
Sadie Blake
or the dregs of society?
Be honest.
Because you're damned
if you do,
and you're damned
if you don't.
I'd rather be
damned if I don't.
So be it.
You know,
Eve was wrong about you.
You were never anything more
than a beautiful sacrifice.
Don't do this.
Don't.
In which case,
you came a very long way
to die again.
Don't do it, please!
Am I dead?
I don't know
how to answer that.
But you're dead.
I saw you.
I was wearing a Kevlar vest.
Now shut up.
I don't believe you.
How did you find me?
I was tracking you.
I'm sorry
about your daughter.
Can you walk?
This is going to hurt.
What do you think
you're doing?
It's a tourniquet.
It'll stop the bleeding.
You need it.
I called for backup.
Help's on the way.
I didn't come this far
to just walk away.
You can't even fucking
walk, Sadie.
That's my point.
I'm not leaving here
until I kill him.
You don't have
your crossbow.
- Details.
- Jesus!
- Stay with me.
- Frankly, I'm disappointed, Rawlins.
Up!
Are you really
going to save her?
She murdered your daughter
in cold blood.
The very definition of ironic,
I would think.
And yet just like a cop,
always trying to save
their own people.
Shut up.
Get up, Sadie.
Get up.
It's only fair you know
the truth about your daughter.
At first she seemed
just like the rest,
average and dull...
your typical confused teenager.
But the more
I got to know her,
and I mean really know her
inside out,
the more of a revelation
she became.
Oh, she blossomed into
one depraved little girl.
You should know that.
Let him go.
The Alchemist
was right about you.
You'll never
be a true leader.
You don't pay attention
to the details.
Now!
I'm sorry
about your daughter.
I really am.
She was dead already.
So am I.
Come on,
finish this.
Don't think.
- Just do it.
- Sadie...
You owe me this.
I can't live unless I kill
and I can't live that way.
Do it.
Please.
Let's move.
Wait for command.
Secure the rear!
Cover both sides.
Let's go!
Please.
- All right, move!
- Let's go!
Go go go!