To my father...
Couldn't you sleep again?
Count the sheep!
- So what do you want me to do?
- That's it. There is no money.
The truck is lying there.
So?
I couldn't find the money.
You couldn't find it?
So you're telling me,
'If I can't find the
money from somewhere and can'!
make..
...The truck repaired I
will lose the truck'
- Is it right?
- That's right.
Right...
You also have promissory note.
Mortgage.-
You have promissory note?
Did I get it correctly?
Yes, I have.
For how many years
do you know me?
- I don'! know. 10 years, I guess.
- Probably.
Or maybe more.
So...you know me well.
I know you too.
And I know you as
a man with good memory.
Why?
Look, your name is written here.
Do you remember'?
Don't you?
You remember your
debts to other people, though.
The crank is broken.
On the way to Istanbul.
I swear to God,
the crank is broken.
We dragged it here like a corpse.
It awaits to be repaired in the garage.
Brother, he doesn't
repair if I won'! pay 10 thousand.
He wants all in cash.
He wants the money first. Otherwise,
the mechanic doesn't start to repair.
Brother, I know.
I have to pay you, too. I know.
Brother, listen, I know
I delayed the payment.
I have done it before, too.
Truck is full with all goods.
I can'! take my money, either.
I'm begging you.
Mahmut, bro. You don'! listen.
I swear to God.
The crank is broken.
What can I do?
Did I brake it myself or what?!
Bro, I know, I'm late for the payment.
Wait another month, please.
Just a month.
Can'! you postpone just a month?
OK, bro. All right.
Lottery tickets.
Anybody else?
There will be a prolongation.
Portugal is attacking.
Simao hit the ball.
No one is following the ball.
Selam Aleykoum.
ls Selahattin here?
He is dead.
Selam Aleykoum people.
- Selam Aleykoum.
- Well?
- The mechanic asks for 10 thousand.
- Too much. What are you going to do?
The truck is there,
like a corpse.
I don't know what to do, either.
Are you making calculation?
I can'! calculate a shit.
You're right.
You can't.
I'm leaving tomorrow morning.
Find somewhere else to sleep.
I'm going to bed
- What brought you here?
- I just came.
I brought some
goods from Adana.
- You brought some goods?
- Yes, I did.
Why did you come here?
Laundry.
Aren't you going to weigh it?
Are you surprised to see me?
- You have no shame, don't you?
- You're surprised.
I am.
- You haven'! changed a bit. You know?
- Bastard.
You haven'! changed at all.
- Fuck you!
- You haven'! changed at all.
So, I just came into your head.
Is that so? After all this time?
I told you not to
come here in the first place.
- Don't you think it was long before?
- You forgot, of course.
- I didn't forget everything.
- Nor did I.
I told you not to come here.
Never.
What? Your paralyzed husband
got well or what? He comes here now.
Fuck off!
- I never forgot, you know?
- Gel the hell out of here!
I say go! Go to hell!
3 kilos. 4,5 Liras.
- Name?
- Ali.
You're here finally.
I thought you would never come
- Traffic. I was stuck in the traffic.
- Same old story.
I swear I was.
It started at Aksaray.
They came to pick
Kadakal Hotel's laundry up.
Then, the guy called and
said there were two sheets missing.
I'll take care of it.
- What?
- Why? What happened?
- Why are you staring at?
- Who is staring?
Your mother.
- Do I look bad?
- No, why?
You look at me as I look bad.
No, I didn't look like this.
Didn't you quit smoking?
You repeal the same thing every time.
I didn't quit.
- Do it then.
- OK. I will.
- Is there something wrong?
- No. Why did you ask?
I don't know.
It seems so.
No, there is nothing wrong.
Do you need anything? Money?
Something else?
No. I need nothing.
I just came to see you.
- Really?
- I swear, I don't.
Why don't you sell that store?
A launderette among guys.
You are stuck there.
Don't start again
Bekir asks you
if you need anything or not.
- Thank him for me.
I like my brother-in-law.
- He says you should
come to us more often
OK. I will.
- Look. I put my cigarette
out as you asked.
- It's bad for you, not for me.
Bad for your lungs.
I better leave
and you go back to work.
I'm sure foreman
has already started to complain
- The workshop will be closed.
- What?
They are closing it.
Al the end of this month.
Really?
- I'm going to be unemployed again.
Again.
- You find another one.
Don't worry.
When?
Who knows when?
No. Not like this, mom.
Fine, everything is fine. Thank God.
I'm going to send you
some money next week.
Hopefully next week.
OK? I told you, I
will start to work in
the factory, anyway.
They told me to begin in two weeks.
The foreman saw me.
He said OK and also told me to
wail for a little bit.
He said no problem for the job.
They offer insurance
and everything, mom.
Don'! say anything to dad yet.
First, I start to work,
we will inform he, then
No, mom,
I'm not living in the streets.
Don'! worry.
The phone costs too much.
Yes, I'm hanging up, now.
Pass my regards to everyone, mom.
I kiss you and all.
Say hello to everybody.
All right, Hang up, now.
- How much?
- Look what is written on the counter.
4. ..5. ...
- 4,5 Liras.
It's too much.
Outside calling costs 3 Liras maximum.
Don't call, then.
Or call from somewhere else.
Listen.
What's this job in the factory story?
Everyone finds his match, right?
- What? Do you think so?
- Yes, I do.
If you say so, all right then.
- You're a driver, aren't you?
- Yes, I am.
I used to be a driver. I quit.
- Why?
- I crashed someone like you did now.
I can't sleep, you know?
No, I don't know.
My friend, no!
Do you want some tea?
The old man upstairs,
is always watching TV, you know?
- You mean Uncle Muhittin?
- Yes, he is.
When you watch TV,
you forget everything else.
He is wailing for his son to come
and pick him up, you know?
- So, he'll wait for.
- What are you waiting fol'?
Nothing.
There are so many drivers come
and go, you know?
I have been in this hotel
more than anybody else.
Brother?
ls your truck big?
You're cheerful again,
aren't you, Brother Musa?
What?
The ship didn't return yet?
He's a nice guy.
He got the tape and the goggles
in gambling from a Russian.
He travels the seas like this.
He's going to take me
on his ship, you know?
I swear.
He travels the seven seas.
He's going to take me.
- Do you think we will
enter to European Union?
- What?
If we will,
there would be jobs.
There won'! be a shit.
- Brother Riza, come to drink tea.
- Friend. Come.
Come to drink tea.
Selam Aleykoum.
Their tea is different.
Drink it. It's good.
- Chauffeur.
Name?
He's asking your name.
Tell him.
Riza.
His name is Gulam.
He came from Kabul.
He has a store.
He owns a restaurant in Kabul.
His son.
They are illegal immigrants.
He has his daughter-in-law with him.
His son ?ed to Italy.
They came here.
They will go after him
Poor people.
They have a desolate life.
Lottery.
The big day is tomorrow.
- Give me one.
- Good appetite.
- Good luck. Thanks a lot.
- Thanks.
Are you crazy, or what?
Let me go!
Let me go. Are you nuts?
Shout out so the neighbors
can hear you well!
Fuck!
- Didn't you miss me?
- Fuck off!
Fuck you!
I need money.
Money?
My truck...it's broken.
I couldn't find money.
Your truck?!
Yes, my truck...
the crank is broken.
I'll lose it if I can't
find ten thousand.
I went everywhere.
I knocked every door.
I wouldn't have come to you
if it weren't my last hope.
You're talking about your truck!
You're telling me your truck,
without any shame!
I have nothing else.
Selam Aleykoum
Give me the money!
Give it to me! All of it.
You're surprised, aren't you?!
You, motherfucker!
- Selam Aleykoum, my friend.
- Aleykoum selam.
- Selam Aleykoum Gulam.
- Aleykoum selam. Friend.
What's up?
What are you doing?
20...
40, one more 60. It's OK
Good night.
Friend.
Friend?
It's been late and you're still in bed.
Are you sick?
- What time is it?
- Five.
I was worried about you as
I didn't see you up until now.
- Tell again what time it is.
- Five. Five in the afternoon
- I have a terrible headache.
- Do you want me to
bring you some aspirin?
Here.
All right.
- You have fever?
- You don't?
- No, I don't.
Are you hungry?
Do you want to eat something?
Listen, I'm here.
If you need something...
OK, come back in 10 days.
- One week.
- I'll try.
You'll try what?
One week.
I hope so.
You don't need to hope.
One week.
- What? Are you leaving?
- Yes.
Why is this rush?
The truck is repaired.
I'm loading goods tonight.
So, you're loading goods.
Fine.
Give me the bill.
Brother Feyzullah!
Feyzullah!
- What? What happened?
- Come here, brother!
I haven't seen him for a couple of days
But I didn't see it coming.
You haven'! checked them?
You should have worried.
Why should I?
I'm not going to control them, am I?
She doesn't go out anyway.
She is sick.
I have already told you.
Where is this alleged father?
He just got the fuck out
of her and left her to us
- Maybe he is in Italy now.
- He is certainly is.
He didn't seem to be such a guy.
It never came to my mind.
I don't know.
Maybe something else happened.
Maybe the cops caught him.
Aren't they illegal?
All illegal.
The oops might have caught him.
They are illegal immigrants, anyway.
Certainly something else happened
He will come back.
You say so?
Yes, something else should
have happened. Isn't she sick?
What if she will again...
Should we call a doctor'?
What doctor'?
Don'! be silly. Freak!
What if she dies?
Come on.
She is hungry.
Look she is fine.
She is all right.
I warn you anyway.
Fuck!
She peed in it.
Yes, she did.
She didn't go out of her room.
My goodness!
What am I going to do with her now?
Let's call the police.
Right. Let's call them,
so they could close this place.
You nuts!
Don't you know anybody?
An acquaintance or something?
How should I know?
You were chatting with the
bastard all the time.
Nonsense.
There was no chat or anything.
MY goodness!
What am I going to do with it?
Fuck! Are you still here?
Why are you here?
I don't have money.
- I didn't come for the money.
- Why did you come then?
- To see.
- To see what?
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, OK?
I don't want anyone
but Russian broads.
- But how was the broad of last night?
- God bless you.
- Listen, call me, OK?
- Bye.
Isn't the cleaning finished yet?
What's up?
- Why did the cop was here?
- He's my friend.
- Why did you come back?
- It had to be like this.
Do you believe in sin?
What?
Well, I do.
So?
There is a place called hell.
I don't know.
I'm sorry if I bother you, OK?
Do you understand?
I came to say well...
Do you understand me?
I thought you
would go back to your home.
You would, wouldn't you?
Would you want to
go back home? Home.
To Afghanistan?
Would you
want to go to Afghanistan? Home?
Do you understand me?
Would you?
Go home?
Do you understand me?
Home?
Would you go if
I buy your ticket? Home?
Afghanistan?
My name is Riza.
What's yours?
I buy a ticket and...
you go home.
You better go back.
Is that your husband?
Enough!
Aren't you going to stop following me?
- I'm sorry. I came to talk to you.
- About what?
I'm sorry. Al the moment
I'm a bit confused. Well, I'm...
You what?
Bad. I'm really bad.
Shall we drink tea over there?
- I've got things to do.
I have to go home.
- Just for five minutes.
Tell me whatever
you have to say, here.
What can I say to you
in the middle of the street?
Let's sit somewhere.
Just for five minutes.
- Five minutes.
- How is your husband? Is he well?
- What do you care?
- I just wondered.
- You wondered about Necip?
- Is this why you brought me here?
- No. I just wondered.
- How are you?
- And now is it my tum?
I'm fine. OK?
- I'm not, you know?
- It's obvious.
Sometimes, it seems to me, the more I
run, the more I go to opposite side.
- I couldn't escape. I'm not fine.
- Nobody is.
- Are you staying in
this filthy hotel again?
- Yes.
- Feyzullah the bastard is still there?
- Yes he is. Everything is the same.
Faggot. He doesn't give
the linen any more. Asshole!
I told you before
but I want to say it again.
- I'm sorry, OK?
- What the hell are you talking about?
Nothing.
I just wanted to share with you.
To share?
What are you going to share with me?
I asked you to share with you before.
And what happened?
You got the hell
out of here one morning.
Did you care about me
as much as you do about your truck?
Tell me.
Did you? You forgot about me.
You left me and went away.
You are talking about sharing.
Fuck sharing!
- You're right, actually.
- Yes, I am right.
Of course I am So what?
- Nothing.
- Where is your master'?
- He left.
- Where did he go?
- He said he has things to do.
- When will he come back?
- I don't know.
What's going on with my truck?
I don'! know exactly.
But I guess he's waiting for some
spare pieces or something.
Fuck the spare pieces.
When is it going to
finish this bloody truck?
I don't know, I swear.
But I'll ask him when he comes
Stop it! Stop!
- Would you like some tea?
- No, thanks.
The guy here is
making very good tea.
- I give him my own tea to make.
- No, thanks, we won't have any.
That's the one
who will go, right?
Yes, that's her.
- What about you?
- No, she is the only one going.
Sorry to ask but who is she?
Does she understand what we're sharing?
She is someone.
- Is she Afghan?
- Yes. Her husband is in Italy.
- OK. Her husband is in Italy.
- Yes.
Our responsibility
is just to make them disembark.
After that,
it's the responsibility of other people.
- How could she go all alone?
- She won'! be alone.
There will be eighty people.
Half of them are women and children.
She'll take her food with her.
- Well, how much?
- 3,500 dollars.
Really?!
- And when will it be?
- In two days. On the 12th.
Sorry to ask but what is
the relationship between you two?
It's none of your business.
Why do you keep asking?
I'm sorry.
Just wondered.
This is the situation, my brother.
Good.
I wish you had never come here.
Hello?
Just a minute.
Hello.
Brother Riza.
You have a call.
Someone is asking for you.
Hello.
Of course,
I recognized your voice.
Hello.
I'm fine.
What?
Where?
Understood.
OK.
All right.
See you. OK.
Were you surprised
when I called you?
Yes, I wasn't expecting this.
- I just called.
And then, I regretted it.
- Why?
I don't know. I thought 'What
would he think of it, now?
I didn't think of anything.
Didn't you?
No, I didn't
- Necip is dead.
- Necip is dead?
I didn't know.
I'm sorry.
I didn't tell you.
I don't know.
I'm confused.
And then when
you came out of the blue...
I felt weird after he died
I felt relieved from wiping him up.
It's a shame, isn't it?
But I felt like this.
When I went home,
I found him dead.
I went later than usual.
I wandered around for a while.
It's like I fell it, you know?
But I didn't go home.
I didn't want to.
My feel didn't take me home.
Maybe he would be
alive if I went earlier.
He fell from bed,
he died in agony.
I knew it,
I knew at that moment.
I said to myself that he'd died.
That he'd died.
I had enough to wash
and dry his dirty pants
I always wanted to hang
out laundry that...
...I wouldn't be sick of its smell
I wanted to hang clean t-shirts.
...Sheets free from the urine to dry.
I know it's a sin
but that's the way it is.
- Why do you tell me all of this?
- I feel like I killed him.
What?
I killed him...but I don't feel
like it's a sin. I can't feel.
- You have changed.
- Have I?
Yes indeed.
Otherwise, I wouldn't
want to tell.
I couldn't tell anybody.
It's like a secret.
A secret?
I have no one to share with.
You don'! have either.
You don't even have a friend. Do you?
No, I don't...
So did you tell me your secret?
It's difficult to live with a sin
What are you doing now?
- Nothing.
- You look tired.
I don't know. Do I?
'Fired. I'm very tired too,
you know?
I got tired.
I want everything to change.
- Don'! you? Don't you seek for peace?
- What?
Don't you want
everything to be better?
Of course I would
Aren't you tired of driving?
You used to say you were.
I'm very tired.
Then sell this truck.
Do something else.
I can't sell it.
Everything is mortgaged.
This life will never change.
Ever. It won'! change.
Brother Riza, come.
- What happened?
- The Afghan is dead. He was killed.
He was killed in the street. Poor guy.
- How did it happen?
- They killed him.
How should I know?
It's unknown.
You didn't go to work.
They said you are sick.
- You didn't forget my address.
- I didn't.
I was.. .
I was a bit sick today.
That bastard said you were ill.
No, I'm fine now, actually.
- Do you want some tea?
- What? If it's already made.
It's boiling. I'll bring it.
Why did you come?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
I'm scared, I guess.
Are you scared? Why?
I don't know.
- I'm going to ask from you something
if you don'! mind. -What?
- Can I sleep here?
- What?
Here, for a short while.
What's going on with the truck?
It's repaired.
Are you going to leave?
In the morning.
Brother Musa has left.
Good.