STICKUP AT 3 O'CLOCK
- Martínez... put out the forms.
- Yes, sir.
- Good morning, Mr. Director.
- Galindo, what are you doing here?
I finally found the 9 cents that were
missing from Mr. Latienne's balance.
Oh! You made the most of the night.
Let's get back to work then!
Cheerfully, with no remorse.
- Hand me the overtime report.
- Thank you. - With 140%.
I'm sorry, Mr. Director, but
according to the rules that's not right.
The employee lost the 9 cents and stayed
to look for them as is his obligation.
- Yeah, but...
- Did you order him to stay?
I did not.
I prefer employees to sleep.
Then you don't have the right to get paid,
you did it on your own.
Don Prudencio,
you're on top of everything.
Martínez!
A black coffee and an aspirin.
- You know he won the lottery?
- Who?
And they don't want revolutions!
- Have you ever bet on the 113?
- No dear, I haven't.
That could only occur
to Don Prudencio.
- Maybe he's cheating.
- No, he's just a charmed man.
- With that face?
- I mean he's lucky.
As long as luck is not equally shared
there will be no social justice.
Enough, let's get to work!
Work is the only lottery
we workers have.
- Good morning, Mr. Galindo.
- Good morning, Miss Vicenta.
- You woke up early today.
- And I haven't slept a wink...
With 60.000 pesetas at home.
Exposed to thieves.
Because there are too many, sir!
How calm I am now leaving it here.
- 60.000, right? -Yes.
- Sign here, please.
60.000.
- How's the farm business?
- Can't complain...
Getting new customers each day.
And losing cows, but as long
as they continue making swamps...
You devil!
Mr. Galindo, you're always in a good mood.
The mood that the client deserves.
Watch out, vandal!
Holy cow!
Good morning, Mr. GM.
- Good morning.
What a pleasant surprise, Mr. GM!
How's Mr. GM doing?
- You look fine today.
- I'm doing very fine.
And your august mother?
Your beautiful and distinguished wife?
- They are all excellent.
- I always keep them in my prayers.
Allow me.
- Signature, Don Felipe.
- What are you doing, Enriqueta?
- Signature for the head office.
- OK, but...
- The GM.
- The GM? He can wait!
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Mr. GM.
- Please, have a seat. Cigarette?
- I don't smoke.
Smoking is a very silly,
unhealthy and dangerous habit.
Yes, sir.
What nonsense.
- If Mr. GM doesn't need me...
- Stay here, Delgado.
- How come he's here?
- It's obvious.
To tell Don Felipe
to give us extra pay.
Yeah... Such a grim face
can't bring good news.
He's maybe in a good mood
and thought about doing us a favor.
He got a duodenal ulcer, Benítez.
And every time he's in pain,
he loves to be a pain in the ass!
In the last semester you have granted
unsecured loans worth 9 million pesetas,
and who are the beneficiaries?
- Give me the list, Redondo.
- I'll explain, Mr. GM.
There's no need. You have given
that money that is not yours, to...
to a pianola seller,
a truss manufacturer...
a civil servant who wants to put up
a tiger nut milk stand...
They're all good people.
They will return the money.
What if they don't?
Will you replace it?
I think it's time for you
to take some days off.
One year, or maybe two.
With half of your salary, of course.
You need to take care of yourself.
Miss, give me the balances of these gentlemen.
I feel great.
I didn't even get a cold this winter.
I was counting
on my whole salary, thought...
Health comes first.
And during your absence, Mr. Delgado
will take over as director of this bank.
- I want to cash a check!
- Yeah, yeah...
Will they give us any extra pay?
A pay rise?
A change of hours?
A catastrophe.
I want to cash a check!
175 pesetas.
Wait a minute,
don't you see we're busy?
- What's wrong?
- Tell us.
They kicked out Don Felipe.
A two year vacation.
- Sorry, I'm in a hurry...
- Shut up!
- You should've come earlier.
- I told you, the duodenum.
- So many young people dying every day...
- And this man alive and kicking!
If only he'd had a stroke last month!
- Miss, the balances.
- Yes, sir.
Seems like this is the new director.
- The balances, miss!
- Yes, sir.
It was an honor, Mr. GM.
I'm at your distinguished wife's feet...
and my respectful greetings
to your sons and daughters.
Take good care, Mr. GM.
- The balances!
- No need!
- Take good care.
- Have a nice day.
Mr. GM said "have a nice day".
Have a nice day, Mr. GM!
Always at your service, Mr. GM.
Have a nice day.
What's this?
What's wrong with you?
Get to work!
There's too much slacking
in this office,
but soon everyone
will be under my thumb.
- And you, what do you want?
- Nothing...
I'll come back some other day.
It's 4 o'clock.
Didn't you hear?
I'm writing down some reports.
- Castrillo, it's 4 o'clock.
- I know...
But I have to work on some balances.
Do you also have work to do?
- No, but three cents are missing.
- Money is always missing with you, Galindo.
I'm sweeping a little bit.
Apparently today
everyone wants to work.
That's great,
but don't expect any overtime pay.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Don Prudencio.
We know the injustice
that has been done to you.
If they fire you
they will have to fire us all!
- We'll take the same days off as you!
- This your thanks for 40 years service.
Kicking you out when you're old.
What a disgrace!
Don't worry, you can count on us!
- We don't like Don Prudencio!
- The GM neither!
Neither the Board!
And if necessary we'll declare
a sit-down strike!
That's right,
sitting all day doing nothing,
- joking around!
- Easy boys, easy.
Deep down they are right,
I'm old, I'm worthless.
You have always been very good to us.
- Never denied an advance.
- Not even a day off.
Anytime we were late
he always fell for our story.
You'll make me cry.
Now I realize that we have been
a united family.
I'm happy to know that if I lose my job,
I gain six friends and...
Are you having a laugh?
I'm not, Mr. Director,
I'm glad you got fired.
Galindo!
I thought you were a good friend.
- I'm glad because I am a good friend.
- Where is your moral sense, Galindo?
Maybe he wants a promotion.
- He's a scab!
- A pig!
No disrespect, janitor!
There are still classes.
I said I'm glad and I'm glad.
I'm tired of getting up at 7,
of working like a slave,
of having millions in my hands
without giving me time to savor them.
- I'm tired of being poor!
- Come again?!
I want to spend the summer
on the Côte d'Azur...
and spend the winter in Chamonix hanging
out with the female slalom champion!
I was born to live like a duke and
you have stopped me from doing so.
- Me?
- Yes. Galindo, son...
Are you all right?
- He got meningitis!
- Call the shrinks!
I'm using my common sense.
Don Felipe being here
nothing could be done.
But Don Prudencio is another thing...
- It can be done!
- What?
- Sticking-up this bank.
- Wow!
Silly me, you know what I understood?
- "To stick-up this bank".
- That's what I said.
It seems a little strange,
but it's easier than that.
I have everything scientifically studied.
Even with plans,
all I have to do is write them out.
And I can guarantee you
that nobody will find out.
You are not a madman,
you are a scoundrel.
You've got me wrong.
I don't plan to take everything.
I want to share.
Enough! Say no more!
All right. We have time to think about it
until Don Prudencio takes charge.
- Galindo! You'll have to explain yourself!
- Yes sir...
I will keep you informed.
You'll find me at home for any questions.
If you come at night, don't arrive in groups,
the watchman is very distrustful.
Go with him! Put some ice on him,
give him some pills...
- Something's got to be done!
- Poor Mr. Galindo, he's nuts.
Who would've thought?
A man so honest and serious.
- Suggesting that barbarity...
- Well, "barbarity"...
Let's be empathic.
We didn't hear a thing.
Galindo has always been a role model.
Tomorrow he won't even remember.
- Blank check?
- As Mr. Marquis wishes.
This is what I want.
Everything is automatic.
- I was born for this. Open it.
- They'll kick us out.
Don't be a fool.
Open it.
Get in.
- We'll get it dirty, Mr. Galindo.
- You're so meek.
- The Minister saw us.
- What Minister? -That gentleman.
He's the manager.
This button is for the music.
No, it's this one.
Well, no.
This is the real round steering wheel ???
for German dough.
- German dough, the real thing!
- The Minister!
He's not a Minister.
- What are you looking for, sir?
- A Mercedes.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
What color is trendy?
We have the ambassador lacquer black,
the Robespierre red...
- and the navy blue.
- What do you think?
I'd prefer a hard-wearing color.
That would be the cannon grey.
That would be nice.
Do you have a catalog?
- The special or the ordinary one?
- Special.
What currency
do you prefer to be paid in?
- We have no prejudices here.
- Good.
A great life is ahead of us, Martínez.
Having anything you want.
Champagne, caviar...
- This...
- I'm married waiting for another kid!
Who cares?
We'll be rich, Martínez.
- No rules when you're rich.
- The catalogs.
Another for you.
We'll get to visit the whole world...
the exotic Caribbean sea,
Hawaii, Capri, the Swiss lakes...
- I don't think the Minister likes us.
- Where do you want to go?
I'd want to visit Logroño...
- my dad was from there.
- That's a short ride in a Mercedes.
Mine or yours?
- Bye.
- See you tomorrow.
- I saw you!
- What a fright!
I saw you getting out of that car
with a man.
That's my boss, since I left work
so late he offered to give me a ride.
Bye, Lolita.
Last time I saw you getting out of
another car and you told the same story!
He owns three or four cars.
His nickname is "Vehicle fleet".
What?!
- Lolita, you cheat on me.
- You're the one who cheats on me.
You've been promising me
a wedding for 5 years now...
- and nothing.
- Now I'm serious!
We're getting married next month!
And from now on I'll be the only one...
- who gives you a ride.
- Are you gonna rob the Bank of Spain?
- Maybe.
- Then you could buy me lots of things.
I'll buy you th-th...
- Hit him with the vase!
- Shut up, kid!
You missed half the plot.
- Who is the killer?
- I think it's the one with the mustache.
Three pesetas. Won't you give me
a discount for him?
- He and his wheelchair take up
a lot of space - Yes, but he's quiet.
Come on... Business is doing great,
I saw you last night...
Some foreigners.
Since the show has already started,
only 5 pesetas each.
- Finally I find you home.
- I was leaving.
Here you are,
two installments for the TV.
- I don't have any change.
- Don Rogelio told me...
if you don't pay
I have to take the TV with me.
Would you be able to take it away and
leave this house without distraction?
Poor Don José is paralysed, his only exercise
is getting up and down in the wheelchair.
And you know Lupita,
as long she's here, she's not sinning.
Don Rogelio told me
TV is a luxury item.
If you can't afford it,
grin and bear it.
They killed the one with the mustache!
Keep an eye on the lame guy,
I don't trust him.
- He looks like a killer! Come in.
- Don Rogelio told me...
The rubber is here.
Don't miss it!
- Don't worry, I'll pay you.
- When? Otherwise I'll take the TV away.
Soon, maybe in a few days.
Tomorrow's Planners
Share capital 200 million
What a day.
I lost 150 pesetas...
That idiot of Moreno
didn't want to lend me 200 pesetas.
And now here they don't want me
to buy on credit. Unbelievable!
- You're living large.
- I'm a gentleman.
I'm free, baby...
I don't have the money,
but some day I will. And then...
- Then, remember you owe me 100 pesetas.
- Don't worry.
Stick-Up of the Century
- Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
- No, I never think.
- If that Galindo's idea were possible...
- It's crazy.
He seemed very confident
and said they'd never find out.
- They eventually do.
- Some don't.
Come on and get two tickets.
- You owe me 100 pesetas already...
- Shut up and let this honey pass.
I'm free, baby.
I'm not surprised.
- I'm pretty good at this, see?
- I see.
- There.
- And why are we stopping here?
To fool him, you idiot.
- Where's the watchman?
- Sleeping, for sure.
And Galindo too.
We'll wake him up...
- and he'll have a bad scare!
- Didn't he tell us to come and ask him?
I don't want to ask him anything.
I'm just keeping you company!
- Well, here we are.
- This is a crazy idea!
You just watched the movie,
they bust them all!
Because they looked like robbers!
Do we look like robbers?
- Come in.
- Me?
Go ahead, don't be afraid.
Doggie! Ca-calm!
We're... we're just friends.
Good doggie, go inside.
- Go.
- Stop, Rinti.
Come on, Rinti.
We keep him to scare away thieves.
- This is a deserted area.
- Sure.
My brother is waiting for you.
Stop, Rinti.
Come in.
- You watch.
- And I thought we were going to be...
the first to get here.
They almost put us out of business.
- This place is livened up!
- I knew you'd come.
- He came, I didn't.
- Then what are you doing here?
Sit down.
We were sharing out the spoils.
- Already?
- Sure.
Before the stick-up,
we have to know what everyone needs.
That's how you do the accounts,
and then it adds up.
- Have you thought it over?
- Absolutely.
Are you sure they'll never find out?
- Sure.
- And nothing's going to happen to us?
- What could happen to us?
- Do you agree?
- Sure.
- Certainly!
- It's a done deal!
- Count me in then.
Go on, boss.
We're talking about Enriqueta's TV.
Get off, janitor.
Let me do my job.
So, six installments for the TV.
Anything else?
- A mid-season coat.
- For me?
Six pairs of socks.
And a hearing aid for the doorkeeper.
The poor thing doesn't hear anything.
Good. Total: 13.600.
Let's say 15.000.
To round off.
What do you want?
This is so unexpected...
Four or five suits and a coat.
Suede shoes, and shirts...
and a crocodile wallet
with 1.000 pesetas inside.
Good.
- Next.
- It's your turn, sir.
- I don't want anything.
- Some trinket!
Nothing. I'm going home.
You've gone crazy.
I can't believe it!
Mr. Castrillo,
this a business like any other.
A business?
This is a robbery like no other!
We are incapable of robbing anyone,
but a bank is not anyone.
- Who loses money from a bank robbery?
- Clients don't!
Shareholders will deduct it
from undeclared profits.
And they will add it
to the declared losses.
- They'll charge it to the insurance.
- And they won't pay it to the Tax Office!
- They'll even make a profit.
- Understood?
Well.
In that case, I want a villa
in Torremolinos.
- And if possible, a small yacht.
- And he didn't want anything!
No way! Then I want a mink coat!
- I want an apartment in downtown Madrid!
- Order! One at a time!
Cancel my pram,
I want a Mercedes 220.
And I want a furnished apartment
with terrace!
A washing machine
and a lamp for the dining room!
- And flight tickets to Paris!
- And a farmhouse with everything...
Enough! We're reaching 20 million!
- When was there 20 million in the bank?
- There will be.
On the 13th, when Don Prudencio
takes office...
20 million will be sent from
the construction company's account
that must be paid in the afternoon
before a notary.
Just out of curiosity,
how are we going to lift it?
Before the notary gets there,
the brain has everything planned.
This is the plan.
On day X at time D,
three gunmen will enter to the bank.
They'll threaten us with their guns,
they'll force us
to fill a suitcase with money,
they'll hit an employee
and take the money...
in a black car that
will wait for them outside.
That car will disappear!
The robbers
will never be heard from again.
They'll be the perpetrators
and we'll be the victims.
We'll even have a witness...
Don Prudencio.
Wait a moment.
If the robbers take the money,
we don't get paid.
The thing is,
those robbers are here.
- Police!
- And we haven't started yet!
- Everything is planned!
- OK, but I'm leaving!
- Sit down.
- What should I do?
- Open the door.
- It's over!
Sit down!
Listen.
Good evening.
Sorry for the disturbance.
We've run out of water in the radiator,
and we saw a light from your window.
So you just wanted water.
Thank goodness!
Water and everything you want!
For you who serve the citizen...
The citizen must collaborate.
- Somebody's screaming.
- I didn't heard anything. Did you?
I didn't. Why would anyone scream
at this hour?
- Somebody is screaming.
- They're here.
- What's happening to this gentleman?
- Oh, I forgot!
My epileptic cousin. Sometimes
he suffers attacks like this.
The others are also family.
- Where does it hurt?
- Here.
- We have to take him to the hospital.
- No way. Don't bother...
That's our job.
We'll take him in the patrol car.
- It might be serious.
- I'm much better now!
- He's too pale.
- Help me.
Not the hospital!
They'll cut you open at the drop of a hat!
Shut up
and have surgery if you have to!
Careful with the stairs.
The water.
OPERATING ROOM
- Poor man. How he suffered.
- We've gotten out of a mess thanks to him.
- Without him we'd be in jail.
- Thank you, janitor.
See you soon, mate.
Could you give me a light?
Yes, sir. Right away.
You look nervous today.
Me, nervous?
Look at these beautiful mink coats.
- This one, 300.000 pesetas.
- A bargain.
Lupe is an expert and says that
mink coats are not a luxury item anymore!
Beautiful.
Isn't that right?
Is that for you?
Are you inheriting any time soon?
- Who knows.
- Miss, from 8 to 4...
your time belongs to the bank,
which is paying you.
The bank's money is sacred.
He knows something!
Checking accounts?
I beg your pardon?
Here. Checking accounts is here.
Good morning.
- I would like to open up an account.
- Of course.
Come in, please.
Allow me, please.
- Take a seat. You'll be more comfortable.
- You're very kind.
In the meantime I'll write down
your details.
What details?
- Sorry?
- What details?
Oh yes!
- Your name, please.
- Matilde Gómez Smith.
Funny. At first, I thought you were
Katia Durán, the popular star.
You look just like her.
I am Katia Durán.
That's my "nom de guerre".
- A war I wish to enlist in.
- Thanks.
You're full of grace.
- Residence?
- At the moment, the York Club.
- Any inconvenience?
- Not at all!
It's a wonderful place.
And how many legs...?
No! I mean...
How much will your first deposit be?
- 600.000.
- 600...
- Did you say 600.000?
- Yes.
Here you are.
- Won't you count it?
- No. What for?
- Where do I have to sign?
- Oh yes!
Sign here, as the depositor.
I assume that no one but me will be able
to withdraw money from here.
Nobody withdraws anything here.
- Do I have to sign more papers?
- No need.
Thank you very much.
Fernando Galindo,
your fan, friend, slave and servant.
I'll send you some invitations
to see my show.
You can send me whatever you want.
- Good day.
- At your feet!
Could you pay me in advance
500 pesetas?
- What advance?
- From the stick-up.
Do you really think stick-ups
are paid in advance?
- Don't know. It's my first time.
- Go back to your place.
I really need it.
Sit down and shut up!
Amateurs.
You're just a bunch of amateurs.
Come in.
- If you'll excuse me.
- Come in, Galindo.
- What is it.
- A deposit from a new client.
- A really good client!
- You can say that again!
- Do you want a cigarette?
- Thanks.
Tell me, Galindo.
- What did the doctor tell you?
- What doctor?
- Didn't you go to see the doctor?
- What for?
I don't know. The other day,
you were acting so strangely.
I'm sorry, Don Felipe.
It was a minor mood swing.
Happy to hear that.
I was worried.
You've always been such
an honest, sensible and loyal man.
- Forget about it. Won't happen again.
- It takes a weight off my shoulders.
Thank you very much.
Take care of yourself.
You saw that poor guy Martínez.
Thank goodness
he's already on the mend.
- It looks delicious!
- They take good care of you.
They treat me like a Duke,
as Mr. Galindo would say.
What I haven't eaten yet is caviar.
- May I?
- When I ask for it, the little nun says:
"This is not the Hilton, son."
- Doesn't your appendix hurt?
- Not at all!
I've never been so hungry.
Everyday it's a new menu,
so I'm making a pig of myself!
This is delicious!
I was thinking...
while you prepare the stick-up thing...
I could stay here a little longer
to finish recovering.
- How's the patient doing?
- Well, doctor...
- I'm trying to raise my spirits.
- What a nerve!
- Beg your pardon?
- He suffers from nerves.
Are you all right?
This appendix is all right,
but the other one...
- You joker!
- I'm serious, doc.
Why don't you operate on me again?
It's just a cut. So you can practice.
Come on. You're good as gold.
You can go home tomorrow.
- What difference does it make?
- Deep fried.
- They're delicious.
- Good night.
Good night.
Watch the door.
No time to lose.
We'll have a meeting tomorrow night.
- Where?
- My house.
No freaking way!
- I got it.
- What?
Our meeting point.
12 o'clock and no sign from Galindo.
Nice meeting point he chose.
I bet they busted him.
It's bound to go wrong.
Optimistic as always.
I don't like the look of this.
Maybe it's a trap.
And we're next to the cemetery.
The gravedigger in my village
would say that at midnight...
Shut up.
- Did you hear that?
- What?
- It sounded like chains being dragged.
- Wow, Castrillo!
And I was so cozy in the hospital...
Oh Mr. Benítez!
It seems to me that the angel moved.
Yes, Enriquetita, it has moved!
Don't worry.
Hands up!
- Don't move!
- Yes sir, whatever you say.
Didn't recognize me, did you?
I just wanted to show you that
no one will be able
- to recognize the robbers.
- You're right.
- Looks like a totally different man!
- What a trick!
All we need is three silk stockings.
You'll buy them.
Why not Enriqueta? She's the one
who understands such things.
Enriqueta has a more important mission:
rent a car.
- You're going with her.
- Are we going on a trip?
It's a wedding.
That's what you'll say.
We're renting a wedding car
so they don't get suspicious.
And is Mr. Benítez my groom?
- Exactly.
- He's not my type!
Bring her Paul Newman then.
Mr. Benítez,
respects to Paul Newman.
- Being short, I also have my audience.
- Don't let's get personal.
- And you will be the driver.
- Me?
- I can't drive.
- Don't you have a motorcycle? Then learn!
It will all go wrong.
- What about me, boss?
- You're buying the guns.
- Weren't we supposed to carry machine guns?
- That's it, artillery!
Toy guns!
No blood must be spilled.
What about the money
for these first expenses, boss?
Pay it yourselves.
You'll get a refund.
Why doesn't the bank anticipate it?
In a few days, it'll be ours.
- He's right, we want an advance!
- Shut up!
We must choose the robbers.
Come on!
Stop!
Form a line.
Come on!
Me first, boss!
Give me the money! Ta-ta-ta!
- Perfect face of a psychopathic murderer.
- Don't disrespect me, Mr. Galindo.
- This one is small fry.
- Take another look.
Wearing a hat pulled down to his eyebrows
he could be good for the job.
Look this way.
Not you! You'll cough in a minute.
See?
You'll be the third robber.
You're wrong.
I'm a good guy.
- I'll screw it up.
- You'll not!
- They're here!
- The police again!
- What a life!
- Disperse!
- Don't run, that'll make things worse!
- Hit the dirt!
What a job!
It's one thing after another!
When's the wedding?
- What wedding?
- I don't know.
Yours.
Didn't you want to rent a car
for your honeymoon?
Sure, our wedding!
You tell him, lollipop.
- No, you tell him, my little mouse.
- You tell him, my tiger.
- You, my angel!
- Why don't you flip a coin?
- Put any date you like.
- But soon.
Right, my little mouse?
Mr. Benítez,
you're getting a little too frisky.
- No trespassing!
- It's just that you're good for me.
Do you want me to call the priest
and save time?
Pretty hunny bunny.
Don't move, stranger.
You're trapped.
Damn you!
- Give me those guns!
- I'll see you at the Vulture Gorge!
I'll give you vulture...!
- My appendix.
- You're wounded, but not finished off.
Drop that!
Finally you remember
your son's birthday...
- but three guns are too much.
- They're not for him.
- For whom then?
- For the orphans!
Oh Lord, you're going to kill me!
I'm in pain!
Shall we go to the maternity unit?
Bad father!
Spending money on other children...
and we don't have a carriage for
our future baby.
Calm down, Luisa...
And you shut up!
Leave the guns for the boy!
Let's go after the Indians!
Bye.
I'm tired of you spying on me.
That was my boss.
- Got a brand new Chevrolet.
- Lolita!
While we were leaving the office, he said
"Do you want us to try it?"
- I said, why not.
- It's OK.
- Bye!
- No more rides.
No more bosses...
and no more waiting for you
two hours everyday!
- From tomorrow...
- What's this?
- Nothing!
- Give me that.
A pair of tights!
And they're horrible too.
- You've got a double life.
- I've not, Lolita!
- I'll explain to you.
- Tell me now or I'll scratch you.
You know how jealous I am.
Who did you buy them for?
Even if I tell you,
you won't believe me.
Shut up, liar!
Doing this to me after five years.
Get out of my sight!
I won't see you ever again!
Lolita, it's not what you think!
Come on! Faster!
Speed up!
Clutch and shift.
Come on, come on!
- Stop!
- Make up your mind! What do I do?
- Stop, you moron!
- Stop it!
You can't do any stick-up
at this speed!
Police again.
- How are you doing?
- Something wrong?
Not at all!
We're just testing a car.
And it goes smoothly!
What can we do for you?
Nothing, thank you.
Have fun.
Bye, officer.
- Disperse!
- He's gone.
- He looked at us in a bad way.
- Shut up, jinx!
Let's do it again.
See if you find out how to shift.
That's right, someone else can drive.
You don't move
until you reach 80 kmh.
Start the car.
Not that way!
- Clutch.
- He doesn't have a clue.
- Clutch and neutral gear.
- Let's see.
- Start the car.
- Come on!
Come on!
Enriquetita, come here.
Mr. Benítez, you don't have to do
the boyfriend role anymore.
I took it so seriously that I think
I'm on my honeymoon.
Watch out!
- Oh my God!
- Slow down, Castrillo!
Stop, Castrillo!
Hit the brakes!
It's the middle pedal!
- Could you give me a light?
- Yes, sir.
I warned you.
Motorcycles are dangerous.
It wasn't driving a motorcycle,
but a car.
A car?
Well, not driving a car.
I mean, the other vehicle was a car.
I was riding in the countryside...
Not the countryside.
Suddenly, boom!
- A big crash.
- I remind you that accidents...
due to such frivolities do not have
the right to compensation.
Yes.
Wrecked?
It was just a little hit against a tree.
The driver only has a bump
that can't be seen.
No sir!
We don't fix cars here!
This is a bank.
- What a pain in the neck!
- You can't fool me, miss.
You were riding as a pillion with him.
Pillion?
He should be so lucky!
I'm really sorry
because I like that fly swatter business.
It's only 50.000 pesetas, Don Felipe.
- Another credit?
- Yes, but as I told him...
- it can't be done.
- Exactly.
Those days are over. No one
takes a peseta from this bank anymore.
Ha-ha!
Fresh milk.
Now you can't say I'm not thoughtful.
I appreciate it,
but milk disagrees with me.
- It's 9 pesetas a liter! - Doesn't matter,
it doesn't agree with me.
Miss Katia!
Such a nice pleasure.
Your fan, friend, slave and servant.
Come in.
Please, sit down.
- I just came to ask you something.
- Whatever you want.
- Has a transfer arrived for me?
- It hasn't.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
I am the only one
in charge of your account.
- Can I ask you a favor?
- You can count on me.
When that transfer arrives,
will you come to the club to let me know?
- Just me, you know?
- Yes.
If I'm not alone,
don't say anything.
All right. I go to the club,
I come into your dressing room...
and you will be there waiting for me...
Alone?
In case
the transfer hasn't arrived yet,
can I come over anyways?
You can come over anytime.
You'll be always well-received.
Sir, they want to charge us
3500 pesetas to fix our car.
- Don't interrupt.
- They're on the phone.
- Don Pruden isn't around, it has to be now.
- Let them fix it then!
Your fan, friend, slave and servant.
Yes, have it fixed.
But it will look like brand new, right?
Cylinder head? Pinions?
What's that?
Oh well! Have it fixed.
Painted and with new license plates,
no one will recognize it.
- Not so fast. This paint doesn't adhere.
- And there's not enough.
- Add more water.
- Then we're going to wash it.
All you need is two longitudinal stripes
to make it look brand new.
- You're a genius!
- I think there are two million left over.
This money is for Don Felipe.
- It'll be his life annuity.
- That's great. Good for us.
Life annuity for Don Felipe.
It's the least we can do.
Now the accounts balance.
Three million each.
Three million each?
Come on, let's paint!
This car will look brand new even
if we have to paint during working hours.
- Hi. Would you buy me a drink?
- Sure.
- It cost me five bucks to come.
- What have you dressed up as?
Robber.
Ignoramus! One can tell
that you don't go to the movies.
You look very provocative, dear.
Cover yourself up
before you catch cold.
Can't I show off my charms?
Sure you can.
You are made so fine.
I hadn't realized until now.
Perverse...
Stop it! That's enough.
Let's practice.
- The robbers. Make a line.
- Yes, boss!
Let's see the stockings.
The stockings.
- Stockings?
- Mine?
He's the one.
- Didn't you hear? Stockings!
- What stockings?
- The ones you were supposed to buy.
- Well...
I forgot them at home.
- We can't work this way!
- How careless!
- We could put on a scarf.
- Handkerchiefs!
You, the guns.
There were only 9 long ones
and they looked awful,
but the day after tomorrow
you'll have them here
- even though my baby was born with
a birthmark. -This can't be happening!
We can't practice like this.
Calm down, boss.
If we're not going to shoot,
what do we need guns for?
- We point with our fingers.
- Okay whatever! To the car!
Today is the 13th, D day.
Get ready.
It's 3 o'clock.
You stop at the front door.
Does it have to be at the door? We won't be
able to park and there's the street light.
Get out of the car!
- Where are you going?
- You said get out of the car.
Not you!
You have to be in the car, idling!
Again.
Get out of the car!
Didn't I tell you to stay in the car?!
Yes, I'm very nervous though.
It's not happening! I wonder how
Al Capone would deal with this.
Don't be upset, boss.
Everything is going smoothly.
I don't know. Come on!
- With the engine running?
- Idling!
- Where is the suitcase?
- Here.
We are in our positions.
The front door is here!
- What a suitcase!
- The only one I have!
My counter.
No shooting!
Say the words.
- Fa...
- Face against the wall!
Hands up!
- Turn around. That's it.
- This is exciting.
Now Martínez, you come to the window
with the suitcase
- and I'll fill it with bills.
- The money!
- Wait a minute, boss!
- What is it?
We forgot to gag Mr. Cordero.
What for?
You don't need to rehearse that!
We have to rehearse everything!
Put some adhesive tape over his mouth.
- We don't have that.
- Use sticky tape then.
- We don't have that either.
- Don't worry, I'll be fine.
- And what are you going to put on me?
- A big diamond ring on your finger.
- I'm excited!
- Chloroform for her!
- We don't have that.
- It's OK. I'll give it to her.
You have to be at the door!
- What a pity!
- What about Don Prudencio?
- You shoot him!
- No! No blood must be spilled!
He has to see everything.
He'll be the witness.
Can I turn back?
I can't see anything and I'm bored.
Shut up!
I think everything is set.
All you need to do is hit me on the head.
But carefully, gently.
Here on the left side.
- I can't bring myself to do it, boss.
- Hit me.
- What do I hit you with?
- Oh, right.
Here.
Not like that!
Don Prudencio will be watching.
It has to look real.
- You hit me and I get knocked out.
- Now you'll see.
Take this!
That was perfect, right boss?!
What a man!
Your rehearsals are brilliant!
Boss?
Mr. Galindo?!
- What have you done to him?
- He killed him!
Don't play jokes.
He's not reacting.
This is because I fell down the stairs.
Can't I fall down the stairs?
You can fall wherever you want,
but you must know that
leave isn't granted
when suffering accidents
outside office hours.
Did I ask for leave?
I'm tired of you threatening everyone!
Galindo!
You are talking to the branch director.
Until the 13th, you are not
a director of anything.
I will report you to the upper management!
And all of you too!
Do you think I haven't noticed?
Strange things have been happening for days.
I warn you that if you plot anything
against me, it will cost you dearly!
I will be inexorable with the rebels!
Coffee and aspirin.
- How are you doing, boss?
- Badly.
- Does it hurt?
- It does, but I put up with it.
What was inside the sock?
Sand.
You're a brute!
You hit me as hard as you could!
- You told me to hit you hard.
- Galindo.
The transfer of 500.000 from your client
and the check book have arrived.
All right. I'll let her know.
- Such bad luck!
- Why?
- Is it too visible?
- It's because of the adhesive tape.
You were lucky.
A little further down and you're done.
- I fell down the stairs.
- Yes, it's one misfortune after another.
First, Martínez, then, Castrillo
and now you.
Who's next?
Once, I met a very pretty girl
Without knowing,
she was trying to play at love
At her feet, four hearts were sighing
But she mercilessly destroyed them
She has no heart
She has no heart...
Because she mercilessly destroyed them
You will see that this story
is very sad and very silly
because when
she finally wanted to choose,
she found that
there was none at her side
and the girl ended up sad and lonely
And the girl ended up...
sad and lonely.
- Tony.
- Hello, baby.
- Are you surprised to see me?
- I thought you were in Hamburg.
Don't act naive.
You know too well that
I had to get out of there.
Someone told the police.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
Maybe you know the rat.
- I don't know anything.
- It's OK.
I'll find him somehow.
- Where's the money?
- I don't know!
Bullshit! They gave you 600.000
pesetas and then other 500.
That's not true!
Don't make me mad, baby.
Come on.
Am I disturbing you?
Hi, darling!
I was waiting for you.
No, I'm the cashier...
Hey. Hey!
- What's that?
- My boyfriend.
Listen, baby...
Don't play with me.
- Listen!
- Shut your trap!
I need it tonight.
Otherwise...
- Let me alone, Tony. Go away.
- Didn't you hear the lady? Go away...
Tonight.
Don't forget.
Hitting women, you coward.
Why don't you hit me?
- Say that again?
- Nothing. Have fun.
I'd teach him a lesson,
but not in your presence.
Careful! He may be listening.
- Any news about the transfer?
- That's why I'm here.
To bring you the news
and the checkbook.
- I'm getting dressed. Sit down.
- Thanks.
Thank goodness you came.
A helpless woman always needs
a loyal man by her side.
Yes, ma'am.
And a man always needs a woman.
- Mind if I call you by your first name?
- No, ma'am.
Do you have plans for tonight?
We could have dinner together.
We have dinner, a snack, dinner again
and whatever you want.
- To you.
- No. To you.
- To us.
- Right. To us.
It's 3 o'clock. He's not coming.
Something must have happened to him.
- What are we gonna do now?
- Let's get out of here.
- What about the stick-up?
- Let's forget about it.
Why? The rehearsals went very well.
- Without him, we can't do anything.
- He's right. Galindo is the brain.
- I had already chosen my Studebaker!
- Three beautiful suits in my case!
I won't be able to enjoy the caviar!
- And the baby's stroller.
- I'm happy!
Let's go home happily, no remorse.
No, sir! I'll do the stick-up
with or without him.
- Do you think any of this is real?
- What?
All of it.
Your house, the champagne, yourself.
Yes, it is.
It doesn't feel like it's real.
It all seems like a dream...
and I'm going to wake up
in the bank counting cents.
I'm here, with you.
Your checkbook.
- You have to promise me one thing.
- Anything. I'll promise you anything.
If that man asks at the bank if I have
an account, you tell him I don't.
What does that man mean to you?
- It's a long history.
- Tell me right now.
He's my brother. A rascal.
He wants to take my money.
I find myself alone, helpless.
You have me!
Here I am to defend...
My glasses!
- Who cares?
- You're so nice.
- It's a shame we have to separate.
- Now? We just met.
- No way! - I have to leave
before he takes my money.
Yes. We'll leave together,
to a place very far from here.
Where no one knows us.
To Jamaica, Haiti, or Port-au-Prince.
Rocked by the tropical breeze,
and we will get married.
- Right?
- That's not possible.
I'll be rich in a few days.
- You?
- Yes. 20 million.
- Well, I'll have to share it.
- What are you talking about?
I can't hide it from you.
It's an amazing business...
Silence.
I heard footsteps.
Maybe it's him.
Stop!
You go look.
It'll be less suspicious.
Mr. Benítez!
You've been pretty clingy lately.
- You rascal!
- I like the way you are, my robber!
Oh, my!
Who turned the light off?
- The fuses have blown!
- Mr. Benítez, I'll hit you!
- A bus accident. Something wrong?
- Not at all.
- Any news from Galindo?
- He didn't sleep at home.
- This is bad.
- Of course it's bad.
- Maybe he was held and he'll sing...
- Shut up!
Don't worry. If you forget something,
I'll have it sent to your house.
I'll forget something, for sure.
It's been many years here.
It was already like home.
Finally...
Everything ends.
Everything.
On the contrary.
Now is the time to enjoy life.
Yes, right.
- You can keep the flowers.
- The keys.
Oh, the keys! Of course!
And the inventory.
All right.
I'll check it out properly.
Enriqueta, I'll miss you so much.
- Come on, you must be strong.
- I can't help it.
I am very sorry.
You have been like a father to me.
Cordero.
Like a father to all of us.
My dears.
- Benítez.
- We'll never forget you.
- Castrillo.
- We'll come over some time.
- Galindo?
- He's not here.
Say goodbye to him when he comes.
Mr. Director, even if you leave,
I'll always be your janitor.
This is for you,
from my savings.
It's rolling tobacco.
So your little thing doesn't get plugged.
Goodbye everybody.
Enough sentimentality.
Let's get back to work!
Apparently Mr. Galindo thinks
that today is a holiday.
Let him have it. He's done.
He doesn't know who I am.
Good morning everybody!
I've been ambling on my way here,
the trees are already beginning to bloom
and the birds are chirping
in their nests.
- I'll be a bird too and I'll fly.
- Listen to me, Galindo...
Chin up, Don Prudencio,
spring is here. Take a deep breath.
Is this a joke? You're talking
with the branch director.
Already?
Of course. You thought this moment
would never come, right?
- It came!
- Good. Yes, sir.
Birds are not chirping anymore,
no one flies, and nothing at all blooms.
I'll get to work right away,
Mr. Branch Director.
- Where on earth were you last night?
- Where?
I was meditating,
and preparing everything.
Tonight we'll hold an urgent meeting.
All the details must be set.
Come on.
Point A: transformer.
From here the car must leave
at 2:48 p.m. to arrive
at point B at 2:51 p.m.,
then supermarket,
return to the square...
- But the supermarket isn't there.
- Don't interrupt!
Point B, supermarket,
return to the square...
If the supermarket is there,
where is the bank?
The bank is point X,
there's still a long way to go.
- Sorry, boss...
- Shut up!
Let me make myself clear...
Point A, transformer.
From here the car must leave
at 2:48 p.m. to arrive at 2:51 p.m...
Yes, but I think that way leads
to the airport.
- The thing is...
- Keep quiet!
I know what I'm saying,
this is a map with a rigorous scale.
Point B, supermarket, return
to the square, exit through point C...
- No, it cannot be...
- Wait. Try now, boss!
That's it, you put it back to front!
You only complicate things!
When will we split the money?
Later on, when everything
has been forgotten.
What if it's not forgotten?
We must be cautious,
no one should know that we are rich.
I'll keep the money in a safe place.
Wouldn't it be better
to open a checking account?
Do you want us all in prison?
Haste is the downfall of the ambitious.
- Will we have to continue working?
- Of course.
- Why do the stick-up at all then?
- A perfect stick-up is like that,
that's why they never
find out who the robbers are.
Leave it to the boss, he's on the ball.
Can I keep the bus?
Keep quiet!
We can also take all the money
in the box, for the early expenses.
- That's great.
- Let's see...
- Do you remember everything?
- Yes, boss, at a quarter to two...
- I'll pretend to feel sick.
- That's it.
And you two
will take him to the hospital.
- And I will stay.
- No!
You three will go to point A,
the transformer.
You will pass along H Street,
then you reach point F...
before the traffic light turns red
and reaching point G,
you'll back up to pretend...
and at 3 o'clock...
you'll arrive at the bank.
Is it clear?
Let's practice.
It seems to me
that they're taking too long.
They're here.
Looks like his driving skills
are much better.
Careful with the street light!
- Will you ever learn to drive?
- That was close!
- How was it?
- Bad. 20 minutes late.
And thank goodness we've arrived,
because J Street is under construction.
- Forget J Street. Come through K Street.
- K Street?
- The one with the pharmacy.
- It's the wrong direction.
Everything is a problem!
- L Street then.
- No way out.
Why don't we go straight down the main
street instead of taking so many detours?
Sure, so everyone can see you!
- Neither M nor N...
- A churro?
- No thanks. P, K, S...
- You'll run out of the alphabet, boss!
- That's it! S Street.
- Which one is that?
Main Street!
Do I have to explain it all?
- Any questions?
- No, boss.
- Everything is ready?
- Yes, boss.
- When do they pay me the check?
- They're checking the signature.
- Boss. This is a tragedy.
- What's wrong?
We have to delay the stick-up,
my wife is in labor.
- This is a very serious thing.
- And what about having a baby?
You can't have a baby now!
It has to be a mistake.
You don't know my wife.
When she gets down to it, no one can stop her.
Stop her! When life
gives you lemons, make lemonade!
Good morning, Sr. Galindo.
Good morning, Miss Vicenta.
You're a sight for sore eyes!
- How much will you deposit today?
- Today, I'm collecting.
- To collect?
- 400.000.
- Beg your pardon?
- I finally decided to buy the apartment.
Will you spend that money
on an apartment!
A few bricks, some cement,
three partitions, and a 20 year mortgage?
- What a nice terrace!
- You were living so well on the farm!
I'm buying it. It's a whim.
- This signature is not valid.
- You're always joking.
- The T is slightly different.
- That's my handwriting.
The signature that we have registered
has a different style.
What are you talking about?
I want my money.
What about the bank's responsibility?
We're the trustee of our clients' trust.
Who assures me that you signed
this check?
- Me.
- And who are you?
- It's me, Mr. Galindo.
- No, no, no...
Go home, make another check and
when you have the right T, come back.
- Will I get here in time?
- You will...
If not, tomorrow
or the day after or next month.
There are many apartments for sale!
That was impressive,
this is how our money is defended!
No, I can't come now...
Are you in pain?
Hang in there...
When life gives you lemons, make lemonade!
Hold on until at 15:30.
- Martínez.
- Yes, Don Pruden.
- I mean, Mr. Director.
- Tell Mr. Benítez to come upstairs.
- Yes, sir.
- And have those doorbells fixed.
Tomorrow...
What a day today!
- A form, please.
- A deposit or a withdrawal?
- Deposit.
- Oh, fine.
- Here. That counter.
- Thank you.
When will you pay me the check?!
- I've been here for two hours.
- This is a disgrace!
They are checking the signatures,
there are only a few of us.
Hurry up then.
- Number 63.
- Thank goodness.
90.000, right?
No funds, sir.
- No funds?
- Not at all.
- Then why make me wait for two hours?
- Make a claim to the head office.
Of course I will!
Do you know how many advances
you have already collected?
- Oh, many.
- This is a robbery!
As long as I'm here,
no one will rob a cent from this bank!
- Do you know what I'm going to do?
- No, sir.
Until you have paid off the debt,
with its corresponding interest,
you will continue working
without being paid.
- Oh well, just that...
- Not only that!
We will provide you with life insurance
in favor of the bank
in case you die before final repayment,
which will be the most likely.
Number 64.
- The stamp.
- What stamp?
Don't you know about the stamp?
- Never.
- What if an inspector comes?
- Where do I find a stamp now?
- Go to the shop.
- Number 65.
- Me.
Morning.
What a state you're in today.
- Do you want a cigarette?
- Everybody withdrawing and wasting money!
You should make a deposit,
savings must be encouraged.
Saving means security in your old age.
120 pesetas.
Thank you.
- Good morning, miss.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Mr. Galindo.
- Hello, Bermejillo.
Martínez, tell Don Prudencio.
Quick.
- 20 million, right?
- Right.
Don Prudencio,
the money is here.
Do you know that 20 million is very manageable?
All you need is two bags.
What a beauty.
Becoming a millionaire is exciting.
We're getting off on the right foot.
We'll see how it ends.
Don Prudencio, sign here,
here and here and on the back.
- Too early!
- He's having the attack!
- What attack?
- Appendicitis.
- Didn't they remove his appendix?
- Maybe it's grown again.
- Get the coats!
- We're going to the hospital!
Let him have surgery if he needs to,
but you come back ASAP!
What bad timing!
- This goes to the vault.
- The vault?
- Yes, keep it in the vault.
- Don't we count it?
It's your responsibility,
Mr. Director.
- What if something is missing?
- Well, count it.
Let's count it.
- Wake up, Martínez!
- It's over.
Is it a boy or a girl?
Where are the 20 million?!
Did the stick-up go well?
Run, Castrillo!
10.360.000.
I count 9.540.000.
- Impossible. Something is missing.
- That's what I say.
We have to count again.
5, 10, 15, 20...
25, 30, 35...
40, 45... 50, 55...
Wait a moment!
Not so fast!
- We have to start over.
- Well let's do it!
Calm! Calm! Easy!
Let's see...
- 1000.
- 500.
- 2000.
- 3000.
- 500.
- 4000.
- 5000.
- 500.
- Good morning.
- 6000.
- Bad timing again.
- Good morning, Don Felipe.
- What's this?
- 20 million.
It's a pleasure working like this.
The bank is thriving
since I'm not here anymore.
Galindo, son!
Nice to see you.
I couldn't say good bye...
- Mr. Director...
- Ex-Director.
Good morning.
What brings you here?
I forgot my calendar,
I have so many notes on it...
It has to be today?
We are very busy.
It doesn't matter, I'll wait.
There's no hurry, I have nothing to do.
OK, let's go to my office,
take whatever you need, but quickly.
Keep counting.
- 9.000.
- 500.
- 10.000.
- 11.000.
- 500.
- Pesetas.
- 12.000.
13.000.
- If he stays, we're lost!
- 14.000.
- They'll be here any minute.
- 500.
- Pesetas.
- 15.000.
- 500.
- Pesetas.
We have to synchronize our watches.
What time do you have?
- 14:30.
- 14:50.
- 14:20.
- We've gotten off on the wrong foot!
- Could you tell me what time it is?
- 14:45.
Thank you.
14:45.
We're short of time, let's go.
- Are you sure you're doing it right?
- Don't know.
- This is getting ugly. I'm off!
- You stay.
We have to start this car now.
Come on.
What?
What's wrong?
- Don Felipe won't leave!
- How much do you think this is?
- About one million.
- That's great, I get three like this.
Don't touch it, fool!
- Sure you haven't forgotten anything?
- I'm sure.
I have a great memory.
- He's leaving!
- Let's pretend.
- 777.000.
- 500.
- Pesetas.
- 778.000.
- My hat! I almost forgot my hat!
- 779.000.
He won't leave!
- 780.000.
- 500.
- Pesetas.
- 781.000.
- 500.
- Pesetas.
- 782.000.
- 500.
Good morning.
I know it's a bit late...
but I'd like to to cash
this little check.
Yes, father.
Quickly, we have to close.
- Very kind.
- Number 65.
- Here.
Alms from a charitable soul.
There are still
good people in the world.
Blessed are the merciful,
for they shall obtain mercy.
- Do you want everything
in large bills, father? - I do, son.
- I'm missing a thousand!
- This money will bring a little happiness
to those children who have
no other help than this.
Little angels...
Here, father.
Oh, it's so late! If you don't mind,
I'm going to make a call.
- OK, I'm going to...
- Bye.
- How are you doing?
- Good...
We are missing 3 or 4 million,
but we'll have them in a moment.
I could have sworn that I dialed
the right number.
- Why aren't they coming?
- Hush.
Bad if they don't come,
and if they do, that's even worse.
Hello, Fermina?
What are you saying about Cuenca?
No, I'm asking for my maid.
Her name is Fermina.
Cuenca again?
The lines are crossed.
Hello?
- Don't move!
- Nobody moves!
They're here.
Their acting is superb!
Take the money out!
Hands up!
- Come on!
- Yes.
You know, Mr. Benítez,
I kind of like you better as a robber.
Give us the money, quick!
You're a disaster.
You're late and wearing kerchiefs!
What have you done with the stockings?
- The money!
- OK, OK...
If we're lucky
Don Felipe won't even hear.
Why do you insist
on me speaking with Cuenca?
It can't be a wrong number,
when I...
They hung up on me.
No way!
Are you crazy?
You got your way, right Galindo?
As soon as I left...
you start fooling around!
Thank goodness I'm here!
Give me that gun, you fool.
Not me! I'm still!
I'm not putting up any resistance.
You're not Martínez, are you?
- Nor Benítez.
- Give them all of it, Galindo! All!
There's more upstairs!
Watch out, they're for real!
They're robbing our money!
Don't move, I'll shoot you!
The street light.
Don't move, this is a stick-up!
They're shooting bullets!
Don't move, I'll shoot!
One plus one, two.
- Where's the money?
- Inside along with him.
Your fan, friend, slave and servant.
- Martínez.
- Coming!
Mine's dealt with, boss!
- Call the police.
- Yes, sir.
Yes, it's me.
It's a boy... A boy!
Huh? Two more girls?
No way...
BANK BRANCH ROBERY FOILED
The energetic attitude
of the employees prevent crime.
The Bank of Tomorrow's Planners
is proud of you.
In the future you will be an example
to imitate, a standard to follow.
And to reward your heroic performance
you will be rewarded with
an extraordinary payment and
you will be mentioned in our newsletter.
And you, Mr. Director,
will be nominated for a decoration.
- Have a nice day.
- Have a nice day, Mr. GM.
- Have fun.
Bye.
Now he got us all dirty!
I have a plan.
This summer, as soon as
Don Felipe goes to the spa...
Amateurs.
You're just a bunch of amateurs!