♪[Rock Around The Clock
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
♪ 1, 2, 3 o'clock,
4 o'clock, rock, ♪
♪ 5, 6, 7 o'clock,
8 o'clock, rock ♪
♪ 9, 10, 11 o'clock,
12 o'clock, rock,
we're gonna rock ♪
♪ Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ Put your glad rags on
and join me, hon ♪
♪ We'll have some fun
when the clock strikes one ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock,
rock, 'til broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock,
gonna rock,
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When the clock strikes 2,
3 and 4 ♪
♪ If the band slows down
we'll yell for more ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock,
rock, 'til broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock,
gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When the chimes ring
5, 6 and 7 ♪
♪ We'll be right
in 7th heaven ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock,
rock, till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock,
gonna rock,
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When it's
8, 9, 10, 11, too ♪
♪ I'll be goin' strong
and so will you ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock,
rock, 'til broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock,
gonna rock,
around the clock tonight ♪
♪
Well, that's it, Georgie.
The band's through here.
We're canceled out.
That's the 3rd time
on this tour.
What kind
of a manager are you?
How do you expect
to draw crowds
in a town of this size?
This wouldn't have happened
if you'd listened to me
a long time ago.
I tell you,
all the big bands
are breaking up.
People aren't dancing anymore,
they're listening.
Oh, so I'm supposed
to break up my band?
The public's going in
for sounds, Georgie.
They want to hear
small groups, vocalists,
novelty combos.
Sure.
That's right, Steve.
Put the blame on everyone
but yourself.
As the band's manager,
you do a bad job
of selling us--
A bad job of selling?
You listen to me.
The only thing that's
stayed up to date
In this band of yours
is your watch.
Why don't you get wise
to yourself, Georgie?
Take a look at the figures
on record sales
And then look at
the size of the crowds
you've been drawing.
Maybe I should book you
into a schoolhouse
during fire drill.
You might be able
to clear 'em out fast
with the kind of music--
You're fired.
Good.
I wouldn't want you to say
I was disloyal by quitting.
But take my advice,
Georgie.
You wait around long enough
for a proof that the big band
business is dead,
You'll be paying
the funeral expenses.
Good luck to you.
Steve.
Steve's giving you
the right hop, pop.
I don't like funerals,
either.
See you
around the cemetery.
Corny, look,
there's no reason for you
to cut out on the band.
Maybe hiller
can still get some work.
Stevie-boy,
the handwriting's
on the wall.
So I either hock this thing
or turn it into a ferryboat.
Where we goin'?
New York.
I think I can
get a job with one of
the big booking offices.
You thinkin' of
Corinne Talbot?
I wasn't thinkin'
of anybody.
Do we leave
in the morning?
Ready at 8:00.
Soon as I put on
my traveling clothes
and lulubelle here
Puts on her g-string.
All righty?
All righty.
♪
Awful lonesome up here.
You sure you know
where you're goin'?
According to the map,
and it's been right
the past 3 days,
We should hit a little town
called Strawberry Springs
In time to stay over
for the night.
Sort of a shortcut.
Hmm.
Sounds good enough to eat.
What does?
Strawberry shortcut.
Aw, Corny,
go back to sleep,
will you?
Hey, Corny,
wake up.
We made it.
Strawberry Springs,
population 1,472.
This is a cute
little town, wasn't it?
Now, if we can find
a hotel or a motel.
An old barn, anything.
I'm beat.
Hey, man, move the wheels.
You're blockin' the road.
Come on, daddy-o?
We're in a hurry.
Looks like we're
holdin' up the works.
We go for 150 miles
without seeing a car.
The minute we stop,
road hog.
Come on!
Let's go, let's go, come on!
Steve,
The whole 1,472
must be out at once.
Yeah, look at 'em.
Hey,
there's a motel up ahead.
Let's hope
they have a room.
Yeah.
With hot and cold--
hot and cold running,
I know the joke.
Evenin', neighbor.
Evenin'.
Your sign says
you have a vacancy.
Yep.
We don't get many tourists
in this neck of the woods.
Stayin' long?
Nah, just overnight.
Probably pull out
in the morning.
Say, pop,
where's everybody goin'?
Uh, the young 'uns?
This is saturday night,
neighbor.
The young 'uns wouldn't
Miss their dance
at the meetin' hall.
You mean,
they're all going
to a dance?
This is saturday night.
Maybe nobody told them
that dance band music
was dead.
It's probably
a dance for squares.
Square dance?
That's what I said.
They've probably been doin'
that kind of stuff up here
for the last 100 years.
Got a match?
Just the same, they dance,
and i'd like to know why.
You think anybody
would mind if we went?
I reckon your money's
as good as anybody's.
Good. show us to
our cabin, will you?
We'll get cleaned
up a little bit.
It's over there, 12.
She's open. go right in.
Ok, thank you.
"Dance for squares."
Man, them 2 cats
don't dig the most at all.
At all.
♪[see you later, alligator
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
Hey, Steve, we must be out
of our cotton-pickin' minds.
We should be gettin' some
sleep instead of comin' here.
Maybe so.
But something's
getting these people
out of their houses.
I'm gonna find out
what it is.
Ah, what kind of
Cornball music
can they have
In a burg like this?
Probably Joe Grubnic
And his "makes you
want to sit this one out"
orchestra.
They're
slaughtering cattle.
Did you hear that?
All I can say
is square dancing
has sure changed.
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ Can't you see
you're in my way now ♪
♪ Don't you know
you cramp my style ♪
I told you,
slaughtering cattle.
Corny, how long has it been
since you've seen a dance hall
jump like that?
About 3 years ago
at Roseland
When that flea circus act
got loose.
What is that outfit
playin' up there?
I don't know.
It isn't boogie,
it isn't jive,
and it isn't swing.
It's kind of all of 'em.
Hey, sister,
what do you call that
exercise you're gettin'?
It's rock 'n' roll,
brother, and we're rockin'
tonight.
It's rock 'n' roll.
♪ Can't you see
you're in my way now ♪
♪ Don't you know
you cramp my style ♪
♪ When I thought of
what she told me ♪
♪ Nearly made me
lose my head ♪
Say, pardon me, friend,
Would you tell me
what the name
of that band is?
Later, man, later.
I'm gone, now.
I don't dig nothin'.
♪ But the next time
that I saw her ♪
♪ Reminded her of
what she said ♪
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
Miss, pardon me,
do you know the name of
that orchestra that's playing?
Crazy, man, crazy.
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ Can't you see
you're in my way now ♪
♪ Don't you know
you cramp my style ♪
♪ She said,
I'm sorry, pretty daddy ♪
♪ You know my love
is just for you ♪
♪ She said,
I'm sorry, pretty daddy ♪
♪ You know my love
is just for you ♪
♪ Won't you say that
you'll forgive me ♪
♪ And say your love
for me is true ♪
♪ I said,
wait a minute, 'gator ♪
♪ I know you mean it
just for play ♪
♪ I said,
wait a minute, 'gator ♪
♪ I know you mean it
just for play ♪
♪ Don't you know
you really hurt me ♪
♪ And this is what
I have to say ♪
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ Can't you see
you're in my way now ♪
♪ Don't you know
you cramp my style ♪
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ So long
that's all ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
All right!
Say, friend.
Yeah?
Nice guitar
you've got there.
Well,
thank you very much.
And we were just trying
to find out the name
of your band.
The name?
Hey, guys,
we got a couple of foreigners
from the flatlands with us.
Are you serious?
You mean you've never heard
of Bill Haley and The Comets?
Well, i, uh,
I've been kind of sick.
I don't get out much.
Well, stick around, alligator.
Rockin' will cure
anything you have.
Ready, boys?
yeah.
♪[rock-a-beatin' boogie
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
♪ Rock, rock ♪
Say, friend,
you back in this world yet?
Descending, daddy-o.
Comin' in on a cloud.
How come
nobody's dancing?
♪ Rock, rock, rock,
everybody ♪
♪ Rock-a-beatin'
boogie beat ♪
♪ You take a rock,
you take a beat ♪
♪ You take a boogie,
you make it sweet ♪
♪ You take
a rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Rock-a-beatin' boogie beat ♪
♪ Well,
the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ B-o-o-g-i-e! ♪
Dig, man,
When the most
is on the floor,
we give 'em room.
♪ Shakin' to the rhythm
of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Jumpin' to the rhythm
♪ Rompin' to the rhythm
of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ B-o-o-g-i-e! ♪
♪ You gotta jump,
you gotta jive ♪
♪ You gotta dance,
to be alive ♪
Look at that crazy hop.
Hey, those 2 are good.
Square, huh?
You mean,
you didn't know?
♪ Well,
you're rockin' to the rhythm
of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Dancin' to the rhythm
♪ Shakin' to the rhythm
of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Jumpin' to the rhythm
♪ Rompin' to the rhythm
of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ B-o-o-g-i-e! ♪
♪ Rock, rock,
rock, everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll,
roll, everybody ♪
♪ Rock, rock,
rock, everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll,
roll, everybody ♪
♪ Rock, rock,
rock, everybody ♪
♪ Rock-a-beatin'
boogie beat ♪
Say, uh,
that was real keen.
Thank you.
Would you mind telling me
what you fellows were playing?
Well, it's easy,
alligator.
All you do is play
the music upside down.
I suppose for waltzes
you play it sideways?
Waltzes?
Watch your language, man.
There are ladies present.
Haley. Mr. Haley.
Mr. Haley?
That's right, friend.
And I can make them
call you "mister"
from coast to coast.
How'd you like
to make a fortune?
In money?
You kidding?
Of course I ain't kiddin'.
All depends on
how the crops go.
Sometimes we get
paid off in turnips,
sometimes in onions--
Ok, in money.
What do we have to do?
Well, you're musicians,
aren't you?
Just on saturday nights.
The rest of the week
I'm a tractor mechanic,
Billy has a farm,
Johnny sells seeds, al--
ok, listen.
What if every night
was saturday night?
It'd be all right, I guess.
It'd sure mess up
the rest of the week.
What if you fellows
were musicians all the time
and never did anything else?
Something wrong, bill?
Oh, nothing's wrong, Miss.
Incidentally,
you were very good.
Thank you.
You work with the band?
Yes.
Then you're in
on the deal, too.
I beg your pardon?
Who are you?
Well, I'm Steve Hollis.
I manage orchestras.
You're also managing
to be very vague.
Well, maybe I should
start from the beginning.
Perhaps you can
tell me when and where
we can have a little talk?
We can talk here,
I guess.
The dance ends at 12:00.
All right, cinderella.
This is one 12:00
When you won't
turn into a pumpkin.
We'll hang around.
Come on, Corny.
Hey, are these 2 guys
for real?
♪[A.B.C. Boogie
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
Goin' off your rocker,
Steve?
What do you expect to do
with an outfit like that?
Corny, we've been
kiddin' ourselves too long.
If there's
no dance band business,
we don't work, right?
So let's find a high bridge
and jump off.
No, that's what we're gonna do
if my idea doesn't pan out.
You know what
we're gonna do first?
Jump off a low bridge?
We're gonna try to get
the people dancing again.
I figure
if Haley's combo can
do this in Strawberry Springs,
Maybe they can do it
in the rest of the country.
Buster,
is that a long shot.
What have we got to lose?
Well, we got, uh...
Nothing.
I don't know,
Mr. Hollis.
What might be good for us here
might not be the answer
someplace else.
But I'm not asking the boys
to give up their jobs.
Not yet.
Not until I get
them a concrete offer.
But, of course,
once we get started,
They're gonna have
to forget about
tractors and seeds.
It sure is a big step.
Lisa usually does
that kind of thinking
for us.
Well, they have
security here,
Mr. Hollis.
Do you call it security,
being perched up
on a mountaintop?
Why, you kids have talent.
Talent's something
you can sell for big money,
Not just onions and turnips.
I hadn't thought dancing
the rock 'n' roll was talent.
Take my word for it, honey.
Any gal that can make
a guy's eyes pop out
The way you can
has plenty of talent.
And nobody can
demonstrate this dance
Better than you
and your brother.
What do you say?
Do we ride the
gravy train together?
How much gravy do you expect
for your trouble?
Well, we'll--we'll split,
60-40.
Corny and i'll take 40.
40%?
You shouldn't
get more than 10.
Now where did you get
that kind of information?
I've read  variety.
Then you should know,
my dear young lady,
that I'm not an agent.
I'm a manager.
It's a common thing
for managers to get 40%,
sometimes even 50.
We'll have to think about it.
All right.
How long?
Until you come down
from that 40%.
In that case,
we'll both think about it.
My name, incidentally,
is Lisa Johns.
This is my brother, Jimmy.
Hi.
My father owns
the motel.
That's where you can find us
when you've made up your mind.
Let's go, Jimmy.
Don't look at me,
Mr. Hollis.
If Lisa won't go
for the 60-40,
There's nothin'
I can do about it.
Well,
what does she want?
You got me.
All I know
is we always get 100%
of the onions and turnips.
Leave it to a woman
to make all the trouble.
Look, why don't you
forget the whole thing?
How are you gonna get booking
for a new outfit like that
Without going
to Corinne Talbot?
Don't worry.
I'll find a way.
Sure.
Corinne's agency
has every top hotel
And nightclub
tied up for bands
And acts from New York
to California.
You won't get anywhere
selling The Comets
into some broken-down dive.
In that case, i'll just
go to Corinne, that's all.
Definitely.
You know, she won't
even let you in her office
unless you agree to marry her.
Oh, she's probably forgotten
all about that by now.
Besides, what's one thing
got to do with the other?
Business is business.
Corny, I'm so sure
about that Haley bunch
and that girl.
If I could just get 'em
signed to a contract
and promote 'em right,
We got a sensation
on our hands.
You want to take it
from old Cornball?
With the face and the figure
on that Lisa doll,
She's probably been
promoted by experts.
Oh, I'm not talking
about that kind of...
Hey, maybe I am.
Sure.
Sure. romance, Corny.
That way I may be
able to soften her up
into making the deal.
Hey, now wait a minute.
These farmers up here
have shotguns.
Ugh, get off of it.
She's no farmer's daughter.
You heard her say so yourself.
Her father owns the motel.
In that case,
he probably has 2 shotguns.
Eh?
Eh.
Oh, boy.
Ah.
Get a load of that air.
Take it easy, lad.
What do you wanna do?
Frighten your lungs to death?
Ha.
There's your shotgun bait.
Lisa.
Good morning.
You're up and around
kind of early, aren't you?
It's 9:30.
Most folks have
been up since 5:00.
5:00?
I told you.
It's the air.
Nobody can sleep.
Mr. Hollis, this is
my friend Holly Jenkins.
Hi.
Corny Lasalle.
Hello, Mr. Lasalle.
How do you do?
How about
showing me the town?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was just on
my way for a swim.
Oh, you have a swimming pool?
You might call it that.
I'd be glad to
show you the town.
I'll tell you what,
Holly.
You show Corny the town,
And Lisa will show
me the swimming pool.
Uh...
I'll get my trunks, huh?
Does your friend
always do things
on the spur of the moment?
Depends on
who's wearin' the spurs.
That didn't take long,
did it?
No, just long enough.
I was wondering
how you'd look
in a bathing suit.
I bet you were.
I must have my imagination
overhauled.
You, uh, even look better
than what I had dreamed up.
Thanks.
Smell the strawberries?
They grow wild around here.
You come here often?
Often as I can.
That must be
what makes them wild.
You don't waste much time.
It's my imagination.
It's in a hurry.
Men's imaginations
are always faster
than they are.
Oh, what do you
mean by that?
You're leading up to
the point when you think
you can kiss me.
Oh, well,
I don't know about that.
It's all right.
There, it's finished.
Now we can talk
about other things.
Who wants to talk
about other things?
You do.
To you, I'm just
a silly, romantic girl
Who'll want to give you 40%
when you should have 10.
No, wait.
I didn't say anything--
Perhaps you won't mind
starting your argument at 30%?
Oh, now, young lady,
if you think you're gonna...
20%?
You're taking advantage.
Isn't that what
you wanted to do to me?
And you're also
too suspicious.
10%.
Now, look, if you think
I'm a silly, romantic guy
Who's gonna take 10%
when he should have 40...
Ok, you said it.
That's where I heard it.
Do you object to
the way I do business?
I don't know yet.
20%?
Let's be fair
about this. 25.
Then we have a deal?
Mr. Hollis.
Steve.
You are leveling with us?
Honey, managing bands
is my business.
If I don't get them work,
I don't eat.
All right,
it's a deal.
I'll leave for New York
the first thing
in the morning.
Now, Corny will stay here
and work out some more
routines with you, hmm?
I think I'm scared.
There's a lot
of world outside
of Strawberry Springs.
Ah, don't worry, honey.
Why, the public
will dig you the most.
Is that the way you say it?
Yeah.
Remember what
Christopher Columbus
once said:
"The world is no square."
Oh, I'm sorry.
Why, Mr. Hollis.
Hi, Lynn.
It's good
to see you again.
Nice seeing you.
I hope Miss Talbot
feels the same way.
Well, we can find out.
Mr. Hollis to see you.
Send him in.
No earthquake.
Go right in.
Said the spider to the fly.
Thank you.
Hello, Stinker.
You didn't throw it back out,
so I guess it's all right
to come in.
Hi.
I thought you'd be sore.
What about?
Men refuse
to marry me every day.
Only those in
the home for old men.
And you.
Steve, something's
been bothering me.
Why did you lead me
to believe you loved me?
Well, let's put it
this way.
Why did you lead me to believe
you loved all of this
more than you could any man?
What's wrong with it?
It's made me rich.
I offered you
$20,000 a year
And a chance,
if you worked out right,
to become a partner.
Is that bad?
No, it's good.
Except that
I had my own ideas
on how to become a success.
Or failure.
Yes.
Except that I at least
had my choice.
You're stubborn.
You know, talbot enterprises
is the biggest agency
in show business.
I don't go around
offering a deal like that
to every man I meet.
Perhaps you should.
You're a cinch to come up
with something better
than old Steve.
Then why did you come here?
Business.
A favor?
No, i--i think I can
make some money for you.
I never discuss business
during business hours.
That's logical.
How about over dinner?
I have to go to
the chez suzette tonight
To talk to Tony Martinez
about his new booking.
Oh, don't worry about it.
It's on me.
A business expense.
Ok, you've got a deal.
I have a new gown
that shows off my vanity
in the right places.
I know what you mean.
Don't be too stubborn,
Steve.
I'd hate to see you
in the home for old men.
♪[cueros
by Tony Martinez and His Band
playing]
♪
Well, my pet,
I hope you haven't
forgotten your mambo.
No, it's a little
bit like swimming.
You throw a man in the water,
he'll swim.
He doesn't want
to drown, you know?
I'm not sure
I like the comparison.
Steve,
you're trying
to be a crusader
With an unknown band
such as The Comets.
Tony Martinez is going to be
the top novelty outfit
in the country.
That's why
he's doing business.
After he finishes here
he goes to the West River Club
with The Platters vocal group.
It's a hot group.
Martinez gave
the public something new.
That's why they want him.
Now Haley's got
something new, too.
Look, Corinne, i...
I'm not
an amateur in this business,
you know?
I didn't just
get off of the bus.
I've been around
a little while.
I think I can pick a winner
as well as the next guy.
You've picked
a few in your day.
Then why don't you do this?
Book the Haley combo
into the right place.
Give 'em a showcase.
And give Lisa Johns
and her brother a chance
to demonstrate the dance.
This Lisa's a doll, you know?
Looks great,
young, fresh, sparkles.
She can't Miss.
Just how old
is this doll?
Well, she's 20, 21.
What's the difference?
I'm not sure I know.
Suppose we forget
about the dance act
and talk about the band.
But they work together.
Look, it takes
a great dance team
to demonstrate rock 'n' roll.
The young folks
all over the country
want to see how it's done,
So they can do it, too.
Now, if it's
demonstrated right...
And if I don't book
the band and the act?
Then there's other agents.
You know better.
We'll manage.
Shall we leave now?
Still stubborn.
Let me think overnight about
Mr. Haley and The Comets.
We can decide
in the morning, huh?
They're playing our song.
I never heard it before.
Then from now on
it'll be our song.
Come on, darling.
Mike?
Yeah.
Will you come in, please?
Mm-hmm.
That booking for
the Mansfield School
for girls up in Hartford,
2 weeks from today.
A graduation prom.
Tony Martinez plays
the date before he goes
to the West River Club.
We still need
an inexpensive band
to alternate with Martinez.
Yeah,
something high-class.
This Mansfield School
is the most exclusive
in the country.
Calls for a real
sweet combo.
You know,
heavy on the violins,
light on the brass.
The booking mean
much to us?
One shot.
Some of these one-nighters
are more nuisance
than they're worth.
That's what
I was thinking.
I have the alternate band.
Who are they?
A new combination.
They're called Haley's Comets.
Soft music, sweet, refined.
Just the thing for
the dear little girls
of mansfield.
Ok, boss,
if you say so.
You know how they'll
be received as well as I do.
I think I know just
how they'll be received.
You know, these, uh,
these lily-white hands
are working too hard.
So you'd rather
put them in dishwater?
Maybe you'd like
playing housewife.
Look, boss,
we're in the right business.
We could write
beautiful music together.
We could book ourselves
into heaven 52 weeks a year.
Hmm.
Such nice words.
Steve could never think
of something like that to say.
Steve Hollis?
He's in town.
Well, I suppose
I can wait for you
As long as you
can wait for him.
I'm changing my campaign.
I'm going to play rough.
You think
that'll get him?
I don't know.
But i'll know
a lot more when we go
to Hartford in 2 weeks
To hear Haley's Comets.
Lisa.
Steve.
Hi, honey.
Oh, Steve.
Hey, you did that
like you meant it.
We greet all our guests here
like that.
Stevie-boy.
Hi, Corn.
Hi, Steve.
Hi, Jimmy.
Well, are we
big broadway stars,
or aren't we?
Well, let's just say
that, uh, you'll be
close to broadway.
How close?
Hartford, Connecticut.
Hartford?
Yeah, it's a one-night stand.
It's a high school prom.
Tony Martinez and the band
will be there.
No kidding.
Steve, I found somethin' else
while you were gone.
Another outfit. with Lisa
and Jimmy, The Comets,
And this new bunch,
we have our own unit.
What's the name of the act?
Freddie Bell
and the Bellboys.
When they don't work
nights over at the mill,
They come to our
saturday night dances, too.
Are they good?
Oh, yeah.
All right. now look,
this is a solid chance.
The top booking agent
in the country will be
at Hartford to see you.
The top booking agent.
Corinne Talbot.
Yeah, Corinne Talbot.
You sold your soul
to the devil.
You sold out
for a mess of porridge.
Who's Corinne Talbot?
I told you, porridge.
Only she's no mess.
Uh, Corny's crazy.
Look,
this is a great opportunity.
This can be
the start of everything
for you kids and the band.
Steve,
we're in no hurry.
If you don't
want to do business
with this talbot woman,
We can find other ways.
That's what I told her.
No, it's all set.
Now, we're gonna
rehearse every night
until we leave.
Corny, you tell Haley
and the boys.
Yeah.
Come on, Corn. you can use
the phone in the office.
Bully.
You know,
when you get there,
Hartford will be closer
to broadway than ever before.
♪
Steve, I'm worried.
This doesn't look like
a rock 'n' roll crowd to me.
You're right.
Still,
the talbot agency should
know what they're doing.
I wouldn't trust
that Corinne as far as
I could throw lulubelle.
Maybe they just want
a contrast in the music, huh?
Man, is it going to be
a contrast.
When do we go on?
As soon as Martinez
finishes this number.
I'll go get
the boys ready.
Senor, if we keep on
playing music like this
all night,
We'll have much trouble
in staying awake.
Just remember
what we've been told.
There is to be
no exciting music.
Just music.
Si, senor.
It's a living.
Why did you
wait until tonight,
when we get to Hartford
To tell me that Haley's Comets
are a jive outfit?
Those school people
will throw them out bodily.
I own
talbot enterprises, Mike.
I think I'm entitled
to tell you what I please.
This'll make fools
out of us.
Just out of Steve Hollis.
You weren't kidding.
You are playing rough.
I want Steve broken,
in pocketbook
and in spirit.
You think you'll want
a man who has to crawl
to you on his knees?
I'll decide that
when the time comes.
I want that band to fail,
and I want that girl
To go back to wherever
she came from.
A girl you've
never even seen.
I heard Steve
talk about her.
It wasn't what he said.
It was the way he said it.
I wonder if you'd, uh,
go to all of that trouble
for me?
You mean, you'd still want me
after what I just said?
Some people love murderers.
There's the hotel.
Well, that's it.
The Comets go on next.
Steve,
I'm scared stiff.
Ah, relax, honey.
Just imagine you're still
in Strawberry Springs, hmm?
the Bellboys
set to go on?
Soon as we
call 'em.
Ok, The Comets will
warm 'em up first, huh?
Well,
everything looks normal.
Our friend
Mr. Haley is just about
to cross over the bridge.
♪ On your mark ♪
♪ Get set ♪
♪ Now ready ♪
♪ Ready ♪
♪ Go ♪
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long ♪
♪ Now here's a dance ♪
♪ Wack-a doo, wack-a-doo ♪
Infamous.
Barbaric.
♪ It's the hipster's dance ♪
♪ Wack-a doo, wack-a-doo ♪
We're dead.
They're not dancing.
Everybody's afraid
to break the ice.
Come on.
But, Lisa,
they'll crucify you.
♪ Wack-a doo, wack-a-doo ♪
♪ You just take your baby ♪
♪ Don't you leave that spot ♪
♪ Then you dance like crazy ♪
♪ Give it all you've got ♪
♪ That's the razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If you're ready or not ♪
♪ On your mark ♪
♪ Get set ♪
♪ Now ready ♪
♪ Ready ♪
♪ Go ♪
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long ♪
[audience clapping
to the beat]
♪ Let's get together ♪
♪ Get together ♪
♪ 1, 2 and 3 ♪
♪ Jumpin' to the center ♪
♪ To the center ♪
♪ Just you and me ♪
♪ Put your best foot forward ♪
♪ Wack-a doo, wack-a-doo ♪
♪ Baby can't you see ♪
♪ When you hear them holler ♪
♪ And you ain't nowhere ♪
♪ Honey, you just foller ♪
♪ 'cause we're sure
not square ♪
♪ That's the razzle dazzle ♪
♪ Well, it's everywhere ♪
Stop them. stop them.
Mr. gilfillan,
do something.
Just a minute,
Miss dunlop.
My father's going to
donate a new library
to this school.
You stop the dance,
i'll stop the library.
Oh!
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long ♪
Shall we dance, Miss Mullen?
Oh!
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long ♪
So The Comets
are going to be
thrown out bodily, huh?
♪ That's the razzle dazzle ♪
Pardon the expression, boss,
but you goofed.
♪ Razzle dazzle song ♪
Hi, Mike.
Steve.
Thanks for
the big break, Corinne.
Regardless of
what's happening
here tonight,
The--the big hotels and clubs
will never buy The Comets.
Maybe if it was
part of a revue
with real talent.
Are you kidding?
You see what
Lisa and her brother
are doing out there.
Besides,
we have a revue.
I'll get
the Bellboys.
You kids were wonderful.
Thanks, Steve.
It was awful lonely on
that floor for a while.
Excellent.
You succeeded
in making a bunch
of whirling dervishes
Out of girls
who were brought up
to be ladies.
Now wait a minute.
You were fine.
Miss Talbot didn't expect
that sort of reaction.
Would you mind telling me
what she did expect?
I'm sorry we pleased
the audience, Miss Talbot.
I thought that's what
we were supposed to do.
Hey, Lisa. uh,
th-there's the Bellboys.
Oh, let's watch.
♪[I'm gonna teach you to rock
by Freddie Bell
and the Bellboys playing]
♪ Hello, everybody ♪
♪ I mean, everybody ♪
♪ We're gonna
teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, we're gonna
♪ Yeah, so come on
and rock with us ♪
♪ We're gonna
teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, we're gonna
♪ Yeah, so come on
and rock with us ♪
♪ If you can't swing,
get out of the way ♪
♪ Well, we don't want
no squares ♪
♪ Once you learn and
you get in the groove ♪
♪ You'll jump around
and you won't have no cares ♪
♪ We're gonna
teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, we're gonna
♪ Yeah, so come on
and rock with us ♪
♪ I said 1, 2, 3, 4 ♪
♪ 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ We're gonna
teach you to rock ♪
♪ Well, we're gonna
♪ We're gonna
teach you to rock ♪
♪ I'm not Arthur Murray
teach you in a hurry ♪
♪ Teach you mighty slow ♪
♪ Once you learn
and you get in the groove ♪
♪ You'll jump around
and you'll stop the moon ♪
♪ We're gonna
teach you to rock ♪
♪ I said 1, 2, 3, 4 ♪
♪ 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 ♪
♪ Come on and rock with us ♪
Well, you heard the Bellboys,
Miss Talbot.
What do you have
to say now?
There it is, Corinne.
That's our whole unit.
The band, the kids,
and the Bellboys.
You can book all
3 acts together.
Sorry, Steve.
I don't think the agency
can sell your people.
These sort of acts
aren't in our line.
See you back in town.
Good night, Miss Johns.
I think she's dead wrong
about all of you.
I hope you make
it on your own.
Good luck, Steve.
Thank you, Mike.
If the Bill Haleys
and the Bellhops can
make like they make,
Why can't we make
like we make?
Because
the professors have taken
the "cha" out of our cha chas.
So we sneak back a couple
of little cha chas, maybe?
We sneak.
♪[Mambo Capri
by Tony Martinez and His Band
playing]
♪
Steve,
maybe it's my fault.
I shouldn't have
talked to her
the way I did.
Ah, no.
Get one thing
straight, honey.
It's--it's really my fault.
She's out after me,
and all of you are
gonna suffer for it.
We're not
licked yet.
Maybe, maybe not.
I just think
you'd be better off
Without me around,
that's all.
Steve,
that's not fair.
You got us this far,
you can't pull out now.
Sure, we made cats
out of these squares tonight
And you're the one
that proved we could do it.
You gonna admit
that a dame like
Corinne beat you?
Well, look, I'm perfectly
willing to keep trying
if you want it that way.
Crazy, man.
He's stayin'.
Give me some skin.
Yeah.
Yeah, but make no
mistake about it now.
There's gonna be
a lot of tough
sleddin' ahead.
We're headin' for New York
right after this shindig's
over, ok?
♪
♪ Rocking and rolling
the cha cha cha ♪
♪ Rocking and rolling,
rocking and rolling
the cha cha cha ♪
I know that precious
conscience of yours,
Mike,
So I'm not going to ask you
to take care of this.
Must be pretty bad
if you don't entrust
it to my conscience.
I shudder
at myself sometimes
When I think of
the things I do.
It's so nice
to have power.
Ok, ok.
I'll be your straight man.
What are you
cookin' up this time?
The agency has
a lot of friends, Mike.
And you're going
to use them to keep
The Comets from working.
You're going to
blackball Steve.
In impolite circles
it's known as
"lowering the boom."
Corinne, Confucius say:
"Woman who want man
thinks of 1,000 ways
to make him love her
And no ways to
make him hate her."
That's because
Confucius was a man.
When Steve hates me enough,
he'll know that he
can't live without me.
♪
Well, so what's the score?
We've been in
New York about 2 weeks.
We've had about
2 dozen turndowns
And we got
about 2 dozen bucks
left to our name.
You put 2 and 2 together,
and what do you get?
Too, too depressing.
If I were old enough
to believe in fate,
i'd say it was against us.
How do you like that?
Even the radio's
singin' the blues.
They make a fortune
singin' about trouble.
We spend a fortune
getting into it.
In short, we spent our
roll on rock 'n' roll.
This is yours truly,
Alan Freed,
The old king of
the rock 'n' rollers,
Speaking to you directly
from the West River Club.
Alan Freed.
Where we're broadcasting
Our rock 'n' roll party.
Steve, doesn't that
ring a bell with you?
And appearing
here in person...
If it does, I didn't hear it.
I've been counted out, pal.
No, no kidding, Steve.
Alan Freed is
emceeing the show
at the West River Club.
Remember when he was
running the Alamo Theater
down in texas?
The Alamo Theater, yeah.
Well, you loaned him
$1,000 to put on a show.
Corny, you don't think often,
but when you do,
You make up
for lost time.
Honey, run over to your place
and put on something pretty,
we're goin' steppin'.
The West River Club?
Yeah.
There's just one thing I've
got to say to Mr. Alan Freed.
What's that?
Remember Alamo.
Forget it.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
And welcome
to the West River Club.
We're very happy to have you
with us tonight and we're
really gonna rock 'n' roll.
This is yours truly,
Alan Freed,
The old king of
the rock 'n' rollers.
And you're gonna meet 2 of
the most exciting combinations
you've ever met in your life.
And here they are.
The Ernie Freeman combo
With the sensational
recording group, The Platters.
♪[Only You
by The Platters playing]
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make ♪
♪ This world seem right ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make ♪
♪ The darkness bright ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ And you alone ♪
♪ Can thrill me ♪
♪ Like you do ♪
♪ And fill my heart
with love ♪
♪ For only you ♪
♪ Wa, wa, wa, wa ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make ♪
♪ This change in me ♪
♪ For it's true ♪
♪ You are my destiny ♪
♪ When you hold my hand ♪
♪ I understand ♪
♪ The magic that you do ♪
♪ You're my dream come true ♪
♪ My one and only you ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make ♪
♪ This change in me ♪
♪ For it's true ♪
♪ You are my destiny ♪
♪ When you hold my hand ♪
♪ I understand ♪
♪ The magic that you do ♪
♪ You're my dream come true ♪
♪ My one ♪
♪ And only you ♪
♪ One and only you ♪
So that's--that's about it,
Alan.
I don't know
whether Corinne Talbot
Really blackballed
our group or not.
I--i just don't know.
I do know that if you'll
give our unit a chance here,
you'll never regret it.
Well, Steve,
you don't have to sell me
on rock 'n' roll.
I'll tell you
what we'll do.
Uh, Ernie Freeman
and The Platters
Leave for Miami
the end of this week.
There's another
outfit coming in,
But I think
we can push 'em back.
And I think we can
get your guys in here,
And I know they're
gonna do a great job.
You just remember one thing,
that Alan Freed did
remember the Alamo.
All right?
It's a deal.
♪ 1, 2, 3 o'clock,
4 o'clock, rock ♪
♪ 5, 6, 7 o'clock,
8 o'clock, rock ♪
♪ 9, 10, 11 o'clock,
12 o'clock, rock ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ Put your glad rags on
and join me, hon ♪
♪ We'll have some fun
when the clock strikes one ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna
rock, rock, rock,
'til broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock,
gonna rock, around
the clock tonight ♪
More telegrams.
Boss, you can't
go on ignoring this
rock 'n' roll stuff anymore.
Every hotel and club
in the country
is wiring for information.
The only information
you can give them
Is that we don't handle
that kind of music.
Corinne, for Pete's sake.
How far are you gonna carry
this feud with Steve?
An agency has to
keep up with the times,
or fall on its face.
Corinne, listen to me.
Steve's in love
with Lisa Johns.
He's not even
looking at other women.
So you think
it's all decided.
Lisa wants a ring
on her finger.
You want to put a ring
through Steve's nose.
Which do you think
he'd rather have?
The thing to do, dear Mike,
is to see that Mr. Hollis
doesn't have a choice.
Call Steve
and ask him to come
over this afternoon.
Tell him
it's very important.
Still playing rough?
Dear, dear Mike,
just leave those telegrams
on your way out.
Boys, i'll tell you what.
Let's try this.
♪
Ok?
Ok.
All right.
Let's try it.
All right, I think
we've got it now.
Let's do it, huh?
♪[rock
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
♪ R ♪
♪ O ♪
♪ C ♪
♪ K ♪
♪ R-o-c-k rock ♪
♪ Take an "r" from an 8
To the bar 88 ♪
♪ "o" from the tone
of the sax syncopated ♪
♪ "c" from the key of
a 6-string guitar ♪
♪ "k" from the kick
of a rim shot meter ♪
♪ That's how they made it
that's how they played it ♪
♪ R-o-c-k rock ♪
♪ I know my a's
and my b's, and my c'sies ♪
♪ P's and my q's
and my x, y, z'sies ♪
♪ Know how to lose all
the blue, blue, bluesies ♪
♪ Jump in a pair of
my dancin' shoesies ♪
♪ Date with my baby,
rock with my baby ♪
♪ R-o-c-k rock ♪
♪ Oh,
Strauss discovered waltzes ♪
♪ The handy man
found the blues ♪
♪ Then Haley came along
with a rockin' song ♪
♪ Crazy, man, crazy
crazy news ♪
♪ "r" you would hop,
hear the band, it's a movin' ♪
♪ "o" more than that,
it's a go, go, groovin' ♪
♪ "c" what I mean,
it's a honky-tonk action ♪
♪ "k" like a kiss,
it's a cool attraction ♪
♪ Who will getcha
I'm gonna betcha ♪
♪ R-o-c-k rock ♪
♪ R ♪
♪ O ♪
♪ C ♪
♪ K ♪
♪ R-o-c-k rock ♪
♪ Oh,
Strauss discovered waltzes ♪
♪ The handy man
found the blues ♪
♪ Then Haley came along
with a rockin' song ♪
♪ Crazy, man, crazy
crazy news ♪
♪ "r," you would hop,
hear the band, it's a movin' ♪
♪ "o" more than that,
it's a go, go, groovin' ♪
♪ "c" what I mean,
it's a honky-tonk action ♪
♪ "k" like a kiss,
it's a cool attraction ♪
♪ Who will getcha
I'm gonna betcha ♪
♪ R-o-c-k rock ♪
Okay, fellows, that's it.
Take 5, huh?
Hey, Steve,
phone call for you.
Oh, thank you.
You're welcome.
Hello.
Oh, Mike? hiya, Mike.
It's Mike Dodd.
Yeah, boy,
how are you?
Oh, yeah,
it's goin' great.
Yeah, things are really
lookin' up for the kids.
No, no, we haven't
set any engagements
After the West River Club.
No.
We've been holding out
for the right spot.
Yeah.
Oh, Corinne?
Yeah, I could get in
to see her this afternoon,
If it's strictly business.
All right, you tell her
i'll be in this afternoon.
Ok, Mike.
How do you like that?
Corinne's after us now.
What do we
need her for?
For one thing, Jimmy.
She handles class bookings.
I don't want to see you kids
working in dives.
Hey, wait a minute.
Oh, I don't mean here.
I suppose from now on
we won't be able to afford
you guys anymore.
Well, first of all,
we don't even know
what Corinne's deal is yet.
Whatever it is,
we'd work for nothing
if you'd ask us, Mr. Freed.
Thank you, honey.
You kids have all
been just great.
And you made more
money for this place
Than they've ever made
in their history.
And don't forget to
tell Corinne Talbot that.
She'll hear it so many times,
she'll think it's
a broken record.
Wonderful.
Congratulations,
everybody.
Thank you.
♪
All right,
So I was wrong
about The Comets
and your Lisa Johns.
I'll tell you what i'll do.
I'll make you a deal.
Turn your contract
with the unit over
to the agency,
And you come in
as a partner.
Split 50-50 with me
on everything.
Sell my outfit to you,
so you can sell them
down the river?
You'll never get
a deal like that
anywhere else.
Maybe not.
No, Corinne,
I think your idea
of a partnership
Has too many
strings attached.
Then it's no soap?
No soap.
What do you want?
Bookings.
The best you've got.
What if we make a 3-year deal
without a partnership
For The Comets,
the dance team,
and the Bellboys?
With a good chance
that i'll get them on records.
You're startin'
to make a little sense.
I'm prepared to
make such a deal
With the unit opening
in San Francisco.
Tell you what i'll do.
I'll talk to the kids,
and i'll get back to you.
If they're smart,
they'll take it.
It'll guarantee
their future.
Hmm.
It won't do your
future any harm, either, hmm?
See you later, hon.
Ok.
Get me Lisa Johns
on the phone, please.
I'm sure you didn't
ask me to have lunch
For social reasons,
Miss Talbot.
Steve told you about the deal,
of course.
Yes.
You know what
that 3-year contract could
mean to you and the boys?
$100,000 the first year,
$200,000 the 2nd,
And $300,000 the 3rd.
It seems almost
too good to be true.
There's one thing,
however.
You're an investment,
Lisa.
You'll become
an idol of the teenagers,
you'll develop a big public,
Hundreds of fan clubs.
College boys will be
voting you
The girl they'd most want
to get caught in a
compromising situation with.
My agency will be
spending a fortune
On your publicity
and exploitation.
The bigger you
and the boys become,
The more money
we'll all make.
But you're the only
girl with the outfit.
The only one
that means s-e-x.
Like a movie star.
I want my
investment protected.
Of course,
I can understand that.
All right, then.
These are the facts.
If you get married,
you won't be worth a dime
to me or yourself.
The kind of public
you're going to get
Won't want to think
of you as a married woman.
In short, you will
have to sign a clause
That for the life
of the contract, 3 years,
You will not marry.
For the life of the contract,
I'm not to get married.
That's what
the contract will say?
Exactly.
I don't know why
you're worried,
Miss Talbot.
No one's asked
me to marry them.
He hasn't...
I mean, they haven't?
Just the same.
You never know
when some man
Is going to come out
from under a rock
And pop the nasty
question at you.
You'll have to
sign that clause,
or the deal is off.
If I kept all the boys
from making a lot of money
Just because
I wanted to be married,
I'd certainly be
a terrible heel,
wouldn't i?
The heeliest heel
that ever was.
How long will it take
to make up the contracts?
4 days, 5, perhaps.
I'll get on them
right away.
All right, Miss Talbot,
i'll sign the contracts.
Just the way you want them.
I knew you were smart.
Then it's all settled.
You and the boys
leave for San Francisco
at the end of the week.
Fine.
Just one word
of advice, Lisa.
Have fun.
You'd be amazed at
the number of men
around the country
Who don't want
to get married.
♪[Happy Baby
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
♪ Happy baby,
happy, happy baby ♪
♪ Happy, happy baby ♪
♪ I got a baby
and my baby's
happy with me ♪
♪ Happy baby ♪
♪ I got a baby
and my baby's
happy with me ♪
♪ Happy baby ♪
♪ A slick little chick
and she treats me tenderly ♪
♪ Happy baby ♪
Hi, ball of fire.
Morning.
Oh, boy.
Hmm, with all that
hustle in your bustle
You must be
taking your vitamins.
Corinne,
I came up with
an idea last night
that wouldn't let me sleep.
About me, I hope.
About money.
Well, that's 2nd best.
Now, the returns are in.
You and I both know
what rock 'n' roll has done.
It's got people on
their feet again, dancing.
Druggists are selling
more Corn plasters than ever.
So what's your big idea?
A rock 'n' roll jamboree.
Keep goin'.
Now for weeks,
I've had other bands
And vocal groups making up
rock 'n' roll arrangements.
Now as I see it,
we take a bunch
of these good acts,
Put them all
together into
one big show,
And we'll give
them a night of jive
they've never seen before.
Now to get
the movement going
coast to coast,
I think I can talk
one of the big networks
Into televising us
on a national hookup.
Son,
you hit the jackpot.
Now look,
Los Angeles should be
the right spot for this.
They go for these
big jazz concerts
And I think
they'll eat this one up.
Who do you want
to stage it?
Alan Freed.
You know,
he's handled a
lot of big shows.
Sold.
Freed can leave
for Los Angeles immediately
And work with
my coast office.
Now the first week in july
we rent a great big hall.
All the kids
will be out of school
And I think every kid
from 6 to 96 will go
for this in a big way.
July it is.
Freed goes to the coast,
I stay here in New York,
set up the networks.
You're a genius, lad.
Oh, it's nothing, really.
Now that there
are 3,000 miles
And 3 years
between you
and Lisa Johns,
How about thinking over
that offer I made you?
My dear young lady,
one jamboree at a time.
I gotta go.
I got a lot to do.
♪[Mambo Rock
by Bill Haley and His Comets
playing]
♪ Hey, mambo ♪
♪ Mambo rock ♪
♪ Everybody's doin' it,
mambo rock ♪
It's a sellout.
2 more minutes
and the jamboree
goes coast to coast.
We've had some big
deals in the agency,
Steve,
But this puts
the icing on the cupcake.
You know,
I think I'm more nervous
than our kids must be.
Drink.
Numb your reflexes.
You know,
it's a shame that Mike Dodd
isn't here to see this.
Darling, who needs him?
Why don't you marry the guy
so he can forget you?
He works for me.
Let's not talk business.
Hmm.
One minute.
I suppose you think
I'm 7 kinds of a witch
for the things I did to you.
8 kinds.
But considering why
you did what you did,
I suppose
I should be flattered.
Naturally.
Hmm.
You know, Corinne,
you're not really
a bad sort at all
If you would, uh,
not try to run
everyone else's life.
It's the mother instinct.
Mothers always
do the thinking
for their children.
That really puts
the icing on the cupcake.
No, I mean it.
Every time the alarm
goes off in the morning,
I begin to wonder
about this idea of
being a career woman.
Well, you're the boss.
Why set the alarm?
You're being evasive.
Hmm.
5 seconds.
hi, everybody!
Hi!
Yours truly, Alan Freed,
welcoming you all
to our gigantic
Rock and roll jamboree
At famous Hollywood hall
here in Los Angeles,
California.
Welcome to the big new beat
in popular music
and we've got
a tremendous array
of rock 'n' roll talent
here for you tonight.
So here we go
with Freddie Bell
and the Bellboys.
Go, man.
♪[giddyup dingdong by
Freddie Bell and the Bellboys
playing]
♪ I said, giddy up ♪
♪ Giddy up a ding dong ♪
♪ Giddy up,
giddy up a ding dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy up,
giddy up ♪
♪ Well, now I went
ridin' the other night ♪
♪ I picked out a horse,
oh my what a sight ♪
♪ The name of the horse
was ding dong ♪
♪ While I was ridin'
I was singin' a song ♪
♪ I said, giddy up ♪
♪ Giddy up a ding dong ♪
♪ Giddy up,
giddy up a ding dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy up,
giddy up ♪
♪ Now, we rode and we rode
the whole night through ♪
♪ The horse was tired
and I was too ♪
♪ I had a date
with my gal at 8 ♪
♪ Come on ding dong,
we can't be late ♪
♪ I said, giddy up,
giddy up a ding dong ♪
♪ Giddy up,
♪ Giddy up, giddy up,
giddy up ♪
♪ Giddy up,
giddy up a ding dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, a ding dong ♪
♪ Come on, horse,
roll along ♪
Wonderful.
We're gonna really
rock 'n' roll tonight.
And now, america's
number one vocal group,
with 2 great record hits,
Here are The Platters.
♪ Oh-oh, yes ♪
♪ I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Pretending that
I'm doing well ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ My need is such ♪
♪ I pretend too much ♪
♪ I'm lonely
but no one can tell ♪
♪ Oh-oh, yes ♪
♪ I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Adrift in a world
of my own ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ I've played the game ♪
♪ But to my real shame ♪
♪ You've left me
to grieve all alone ♪
♪ Too real is this feeling ♪
♪ Of make-believe ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Too real when I feel ♪
♪ What my heart
can't conceal ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yes,
I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Just laughin'
and gay like a clown ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ I seem to be what I'm not ♪
♪ You see ♪
♪ I'm wearing
my heart like a crown ♪
♪ Pretending that
you're still around ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Too real is this feeling ♪
♪ Of make-believe ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Too real when I feel ♪
♪ What my heart
can't conceal ♪
♪ Yes,
I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ Just laughin'
and gay like a clown ♪
♪ Woo-oo, woo-oo ♪
♪ I seem to be what I'm not ♪
♪ You see ♪
♪ I'm wearing
my heart like a crown ♪
♪ Pretending that you're ♪
♪ Still around ♪
And now,
for the thrill you've
all been waiting for.
Here is one of the most
phenomenal acts in the history
of show business.
Bill Haley and His Comets.
Thank you, Alan.
Thank you, kids.
Let's rock 'n' roll
with a real swingin'
little tune
called Rudy's Rock.
♪[Rudy's Rock
by Bill Haley playing]
It's a hit, Corinne.
It's a big fat hit.
Now, let's talk about us.
Oh, everything's
been said, Corinne.
From now on,
there's nothing
more to talk about.
Why not?
Watch the stage.
Buddy-buddies,
before we go
into our big finale,
I'd like to introduce
that living doll,
That real cool
rock 'n' rollin' chick
who wants to say a few words,
Lisa Johns and
her brother, Jimmy.
Thank you,
rock 'n' rollers.
I just want
to say how thrilled
everybody is backstage
With the way you've
received our show.
And I especially
want to thank
our wonderful emcee,
Alan Freed,
who helped us put
the show together.
And an equally
wonderful man
Without whom,
there would be no
rock 'n' roll at all,
My husband,
Steve Hollis.
What was that
child talking about?
She said "husband."
She ought to know.
Then you are married?
Legally.
I have a contract
with that girl.
I'll sue you, Steve,
for every cent you have.
I'll ruin you
and her and that band.
They'll never make
another appearance
on a stage.
No one breaks a contract
with Corinne Talbot.
Oh, I don't think you'll
sue anyone, Corinne.
If you recall,
it took 5 days to
draw that contract.
And there's a clause
that says Lisa's not
to be married for 3 years.
Well, she won't.
But you just said that--
she can't.
You see, we were married
before the contracts
were signed.
Outsmarted by an amateur
from Strawberry Springs.
I'll tell you one thing,
though.
I think you and Mike
will be very happy together.
You know,
you wouldn't be
such a bad guy
If you didn't try to
run everybody else's life.
Then you're not angry?
No, what good would it do?
Hmm, Mike Dodd, huh?
Well, it's a good
thing I had another man
warming up in the bullpen.
Touche.
Touche yourself.
♪ When the chimes
ring 5, 6 and 7 ♪
♪ We'll be right
in 7th heaven ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
'til broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When it's 8, 9, 10, 11 too
i'll be goin' strong
and so will you ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
'til broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When the clock strikes 12
We'll cool off then ♪
♪ Start a rockin'
round the clock again ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
around the clock tonight ♪