Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Your respective countries have
deemed you the best at what you do.
What I will ask you to do
will test you on every level.
These missions
are off the record.
No one outside this room
will know who you are
or what we're about to do.
We're in this fight
together, do you understand?
We are not soldiers.
Look around me.
Do you think
they will not do this to you?
Plans waiting to be started.
The war is raging.
Get along.
Do your jobs. Understood?
Yes, sir.
Excellent.
Let's get this done.
Man down,
man down! Let's go!
Don't you understand?
This is war!
On me. It's just ahead.
Just over that point.
You sure about this?
I go missing for two months
and you're already doubting me?
No, I'm just saying we're out
in the middle of nowhere
- based on a hunch.
- You don't get it.
This whole team's based
on a fucking hunch.
- Relax.
- I'm not going to relax.
This is my mission
and my goddamn team.
Man the fuck up!
What's up his ass?
Don't worry about it, man.
Contact.
Here!
Where are you,
you son of a bitch?
Ralph, James... guys?
- Guys, what's your 20?
- Contact.
Spread out.
Create some distance between yourselves.
Report. Guys, where are you?
- Your 12.
- Do you copy?
Just over the hill.
Shut up!
We need to finish them off.
Commander Brisco,
Commander Brisco, come in, sir.
I think I lost them.
Fuck.
Commander Brisco, go again?
Do you copy?
Does anyone copy?
Daniel. I'm waiting.
Face me!
Oh, shit! Fuck!
Commander!
Both of our men are down.
We have two down, sir.
Hang on, hang on.
Does anyone copy?
Repeat, does anyone copy?
We got Jacques and Xu both down.
Both KIA.
You're a fighter, Daniel.
I've always
liked that about you.
Show yourself!
Come out of the shadows.
Daniel!
Ralph, I'm right here,
all right.
Look at me, look at me,
look at me.
Hang on, hang on.
You hear me? Hang on.
Fuck! Shit!
Too late.
You were our leader.
We all knew
this would happen.
Just save your breath.
Hold on. I got this, I got this!
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Fuck!
You can't save us!
Listen, I'm gonna get you
out of here.
I'm going to save you,
you understand?
You wanted me, Daniel.
Here I am.
I've been waiting for you.
Don't go.
Don't leave me, brother.
I gotta finish this.
Draw your weapon.
Can you feel it?
The walls around you
are crashing in.
I'm standing here.
I'm here.
Just you, Daniel.
Your team is dead.
Your mission is a failure.
But at last you will
finally get your kill.
Take the shot.
End it all.
The bodies around you
are piled up.
Has my life been worth theirs?
No, no, no!
You see, I'm more than
just a person.
More than flesh.
I'm an idea,
and you can't kill an idea.
Do you understand now,
Daniel?
In three...
Good morning.
I'm Molly Turner,
coming to you live
with breaking news
from an undisclosed location
here in the Middle East.
According to sources,
we have learned
that the United States
is conducting a covert operation
here in the desert
surrounding me.
Now the details of
this operation are top secret,
but we do know
that the United States
along with Russia, China,
France and the UK,
have formed
a special operations task force
to seek out and destroy a new
age terrorist organization.
Now this comes as
a big surprise to us
as I'm sure it does
to all of our viewers.
We can also report that an
American Special Forces soldier
who was captured
has now been freed.
We're still not clear on the details
of the mission to free the soldier,
but we're working hard to obtain
more information on that.
It seems that our world leaders are
setting aside any and all political issues
in order to come together
and fight as a single unit
for all of our nations
at this time.
Again, we will keep you updated on
any new information that we receive.
I'm Molly Turner.
And we are out.
Great job!
Right.
What are you guys up to
out there?
Put it on the table.
The detonator?
Install it under the table.
- Done? Let's go.
- Yes.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go!
Well, you look
like shit.
How you doin' today,
mate?
Shitty.
I can't sleep and I'm stuck in
this bed for a few more days.
Why so long?
Eh, hand's infected and
they want me to take it easy.
How about the leg?
Eh, they ran some tests.
The knife went straight through.
Nothin' too serious.
Shit!
Thank you.
- Love you, brother.
- Love you, too, brother.
- Thanks for comin' back.
- Anytime.
Ladies, you need me
to leave the room?
Fuck off!
Daniel, you think
you should be walkin' around?
If I don't start now...
Five minutes
are not gonna kill me.
Plus, I need to get
outta this fuckin' hellhole.
Fair enough.
How you doin', Daniel?
You know, you're the 12th
person to ask me that.
Good spirits, I see.
I didn't come this far
to sit on the bench.
Well, just take it easy
for now.
I think it's time we...
talk about our next operation.
Daniel, my man.
Back in the saddle.
- How you doing?
- He's fine.
Okay, I got it. I take it
everyone is asking.
I'll be fine.
Thanks, Jacques.
We're just happy
you're back and doing well.
Appreciate it.
These photos were recovered
from your rescue mission.
The tunnels are unique. If you look at the
tunnel walls in each one of these photos,
you can see that the rock
is different.
Our analysts are trying
to find their origin.
Sir, how will
they do that?
We have a database
that our analysts back home
are cross-checking.
We should have the region soon.
That's great news.
Not quite. We still don't
know what their next move is.
Daniel, I was hoping
you could help us with that.
- I'm sure you're all familiar with dirty bombs.
- Familiar?
How many people do you know
have successfully disarmed one?
Their leader spoke a lot
about loyalty
and using powerful chemicals
to get his voice heard.
From what I saw, they're
making compact dirty bombs
that have a much bigger impact.
- Jesus.
- We have to assume
he has multiple compact
dirty bombs being built.
Making a statement is the
centerpiece of his next move.
What does he want?
To be an idea.
- Is it ready?
- Yes.
Good.
They're gonna analyze
the photos I left
and fall into my trap.
A care package
from yours truly.
How long until we leave?
Not much.
Copy that.
Say hello
to my little friends.
Scarface? Al Pacino?
We get it.
We all saw the movie.
- You guys are no fun.
- Lighten up.
So what's new
with Daniel?
He wants back in.
That makes sense.
He's not ready.
He won't take no for an answer.
Supreme Leader?
Yes?
Have you decided?
Yes.
I have the list of targets.
Good.
I want everything to be ready
in 36 hours.
A new world will be born.
Indeed.
How we doin'?
Have it down to three
possible locations.
- Timeline?
- Still working on it, sir.
Keep goin'.
Hold on!
It needs to be loaded
in the right way.
Watch how I do it.
Not like this.
But like this.
But like this!
Calm and careful.
Understood?
Lock it up.
Load it onto the truck.
Be careful.
What you workin' on?
These little beauties
are my lifeline.
Lifeline?
You ever watch
Who Wants to Be a...
No, never mind.
Each one of these bad boys
has a fuse in it.
Just behind the pin...
So you know how
a grenade works, right?
Yes.
Okay. The idea is
to shorten the fuse.
Your typical grenade has a life
span of five to seven seconds.
I like to have a few set
between two and three seconds.
What if you drop it?
Buzzkill.
What'd you say?
You're crazy!
You're crazy.
How you doing today?
Not bad.
Went to the range.
It felt good.
Let me take a look?
Looks like
it's healing nicely.
So, uh, good to go?
Give it another day.
It was seriously infected.
You went through hell.
I know what
I've been through.
But the mind is what
we're most worried about.
I just...
I just can't take it easy
knowing that he's out there.
I understand.
It's more than duty.
Just think about what
everyone's been saying.
Thanks.
How we goin'?
Still haven't found anything.
I've narrowed it down
to three locations,
but the images are still
too similar to be sure.
I see what you mean.
- Damn it!
- Yeah, welcome to my job.
You keep me posted, yes?
- Galina.
- Commander.
She giving you a run
for your money?
- Don't get me started.
- Hmm.
- What'd you find?
- Still nothing, sir.
That leaves us only one way
to find out for sure.
Hey, Galina.
Finally someone
who will appreciate this.
Here, take a look at this.
You know how
a grenade works, right?
Yes.
So I'm taking the fuse
and carefully making
slight modifications.
He's making it blow up faster.
Damn it, Xu!
You work hours and hours,
you spend time...
Nice, keep up the good work.
It's good.
War room, guys.
Ten minutes.
This'll be brief.
We're having trouble locking down
which of the three locations
with a positive match is correct.
Running out of time.
So we'll split up,
cover more ground.
Who's with who?
Galina, Ralph, Xu,
you're together.
James, Jacques,
together.
Daniel?
- I'll stay back with you, sir.
- Good call.
There'll be plenty more
for you, mate.
Be ready for anything.
We go at first light.
- Sir.
- Excellent.
I'm driving.
Hey,
I'm bad with directions.
Oh, God, help us.
Break it off.
Stay on comms.
It should be just ahead.
Nothing out here.
No one's been here
for years.
Heads up. This could
be somethin'.
I don't like this.
Stay cool.
We're just here to look.
All right, here.
This is the spot.
You sure this is it?
I don't know, man.
I think we're lost.
I think you're right.
All right.
It's a bust, man.
Let's move.
You shouldn't be here.
What's he saying?
You shouldn't be here!
Not sure.
Leave now.
You speak English?
Go! Leave now!
I don't understand you.
Go! Leave!
Back off!
Easy, huh.
Hey.
Take it easy.
We just want to
have a look around.
Da?
You come.
Bad thing follow.
Okay.
We don't want to hurt you.
We just want to look around.
The tunnel is
around here somewhere.
Just keep moving.
There!
For fuck's sake!
It's a merchant tent.
What are you doing?
Relax.
You have nice stuff here.
We don't have much time.
A few moments, huh?
Anything?
He's lived in tent
long time.
Tunnel is collapsed.
There's nothing here.
Okay. Let's go.
We're leaving, okay?
Thank you.
You speak Arabic?
A little.
Picked it up on the road.
Impressive.
They are just scared.
Yeah, them and me,
too.
Nice people.
I wouldn't say nice.
Nothing to live on
and a war raging around them.
It's sad.
James,
we're headed back to base.
Copy, en route.
How'd it go?
Ran into some locals.
They were not too happy
we were there.
- You?
- Bust.
No one's been
out there for years.
A total waste of time.
I heard.
Only one location left.
Has to be it.
Syeddy.
We're in the final stages.
It's all coming together.
The West
will see our resolve.
Finally, a mutual understanding
on and off the battlefield.
Sixteen years of war.
To expect an enemy
to lay down his weapon
and cease to fight
is foolish.
As you predicted.
They have been foolish to think
this battle has been won.
After our mission is complete,
the people of these lands
will be able to rise up
and take back what is ours.
All the soldiers in the world
could not stop us now.
Victory is on the horizon.
Have you checked the gas
compounds and their detonators?
Yes. Everything
is coming together.
I will provide you
with a smooth detonation
with a hard-hitting
gas compound.
In a few days' time,
the world will wake up
to a different reality.
- Good.
- We failed you during our tests at the village.
But with additional
research and explosives,
you will not be disappointed.
We cannot have mistakes.
We are too close to victory.
Trucks are being loaded
as we speak.
When you give us
the target list,
nothing will stand in the way
of completing our mission.
You will have your list.
Strike the heart.
The bleed-out across the world
will be a domino effect
that will not be ignored.
Excellent.
A swift and deafening blow.
The dawn of a new balance
around the world is upon us.
Keep on the soldiers.
The clock in this war
is almost out of time.
We stand with you till
the very end, Supreme Leader.
A quiet peace
is on the horizon.
People...
first two tunnels were a bust.
I know what
you're thinking.
We have to
stay aggressive.
We've got him
on the run.
I agree.
Third tunnel is it.
I want a quick
sneak and peek operation.
Any additional intel?
Not as of now.
Fast. In and out.
Exactly.
Get in. Find him.
Eliminate him.
- Sir!
- Excellent!
This shit ever gonna end?
They're like
an infestation of ants.
Squash one,
three more pop up.
We have
a mission to finish.
This is it.
We take 'em all. Go home.
Up ahead.
This has to be it.
Da.
This is it.
- Sat comms are spotty in the mountains.
- Understood.
We're approaching
the tunnel, sir. Going dark.
Exit up ahead.
Look at all this stuff.
Oi, keep it down.
We're sitting ducks out here.
All right.
Let's move out.
Moving out.
Something isn't right.
Yeah, I hear you.
There's nobody here.
Did we miss them?
We must have.
This isn't the place.
Everything Daniel said.
The sarin, his army, his plan.
Doesn't make any sense.
What's the move?
We have to be sure.
You really think
there's a massive army
waiting to pop out
from behind those rocks?
That's not the point.
They must have left
something behind.
Let's go.
They arrive yet?
Approaching now.
I hate waiting,
I hate waiting.
Tents.
Always fucking tents!
On your go.
Clear.
We've got something.
Welcome.
You and your precious followers
have been led astray.
This war is far from over.
Once again, the battle between
two sides of a coin rages.
Which side are you on?
This country was
the birthplace of mankind,
the center of all humanity,
and you stomp on the dirt beneath
your feet as if it were nothing!
These lands have been riddled
with war for thousands of years.
It has become a dead zone
for your capitalist ideas.
I assure you,
our time has come
and we will rise up and
we will take back our lands.
Ralph, it's his
final declaration of war.
There's nothing else here.
Hang on.
What is it?
Move!
Jesus!
This guy is pissing me off!
It's over.
Time to go.
- Let's go.
- This place could be wired.
Commander, do you copy?
- Go.
- We were set up.
He knew we were coming
every step of the way.
Another setup?
Always ahead.
We're fine.
I, for one, am not fine.
He said something about
the dead zone.
That mean
something to you?
I do not know.
I need to get to a computer.
We need to get
the hell out of here.
Movin' out.
On final approach.
Three minutes out.
- You guys good?
- We're good.
Oi, what's up
with her?
We walked right
into a trap.
Galina!
Get to medical. You need a full
evaluation and medical report.
I don't have time
for medical.
He is toying with us.
Whatever he is planning
is happening now!
- Medical first, then the war room.
- But I have to...
I understand, but you need
to get checked out first.
Then tackle other issues.
Go on.
All right.
Slow down. Man!
She's just focused.
When she's onto something,
she's on it.
She's Russian.
Good?
Yes, sir.
Minor scrapes.
They are not playing around
out there.
We're on the frontline
for the world.
Can't fail.
According to the scouts,
the trap has gone off.
Are they dead?
No. There's no evidence
confirming that yet.
Then find out.
I want them dead!
Yes, Supreme Leader!
Come on, go.
Do you have any files
on the dead zone?
A list of all forward operating
bases left behind after the war?
Let me check.
Doesn't look like much.
We dismasted or destroyed
most of our outposts
when we pulled out.
Mmm, but not all of them.
There.
I have a file labeled under
Locations as a dead zone.
That's crazy.
Why would we leave an FBO in place?
Money. It costs more to take
it down than to leave it.
Well, it must have been
a hot extraction point, too,
because it looks like everybody
left that location in a hurry.
Yeah, and we don't have
much on it in the database.
It's perfect.
Wait, what?
Perfect place to hide.
Right in front of our face.
I want everything to be ready
when we receive the order.
Supreme Leader.
- Are we ready?
- Yes. This way.
What'd you find?
The dead zone.
It was a hot zone
during the war.
It's not just a zone.
It is the name of an FBO
used during the war.
- They're using it as operations base.
- How do you know?
In the video,
he mentioned it.
Everything he has said to date has
been incredibly specific and arrogant.
He put it right in front
of our face just because.
Walk me through it.
Middle of nowhere.
A lot of room to move around.
Who would ever think to look
in their own backyard?
It's the perfect place to hide.
- You sure?
- Sir,
this is the place, I'm telling you.
Marino, let's get eyes in
the sky over in that area.
Monitoring from above
will not help.
We've been playing from behind
for too long.
It's time to turn the tables.
We need to move in now.
No, we can't continue
to roam around the desert
hoping to stumble
into something.
- Sir...
- I believe you, trust me, I do,
but I need
a closer look.
Get me Jacques
and Xu.
Yes, sir.
Commander Brisco
wants to see you both. Now.
Great.
What did I do now?
What's going on?
Good, you're here.
Galina found a possible
operations base.
I want you both
to check it out.
- What do you mean, "check it out"?
- Exactly that.
Get as close as you can
and get a positive ID.
- Understood.
- Excellent.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Coming up on the location.
Just over there.
We should be able
to see them.
Remember, quietly.
Contact.
Galina was right.
- Good work.
- Thank you.
Did they find
something?
Do we have overheads yet?
Coming up now,
sir.
This is going off.
Let's get out of here.
Those crates.
They're being loaded
into trucks.
He's moving soon.
- How is it out there?
- Hot. Damn hot.
They're moving.
And fast.
Daniel was right.
Those guys
aren't messing around.
Supreme Leader.
We are ready.
Good.
The list is complete.
The men have their orders.
By sundown tomorrow,
the trucks will be off the base
and on their way.
Excellent.
My leader.
I find myself
thinking back
to the very beginning
of this mission.
How far we have come together.
Two soldiers
left to die in the sand,
both left with
the scars of war.
Together we found
the bravery to stand against
what was forced upon
so many across these lands.
For too long,
they have stood there
barking their orders,
stealing our wealth,
changing our way of life.
Syeddy, the West will never
understand our world.
They look at us
and see a group of terrorists.
They cannot see
beyond the mask.
They fail to see two soldiers
who served their country.
Two fathers...
who lost...
their wives and children.
They look at us and see
a group of men with masks,
with a gun in hand.
History will not
be kind to us.
No, but history
will always have a place
for those who stood up
for what was right,
no matter the cost,
no matter the cause.
You have been loyal to this
cause from the very beginning.
You have led us fiercely.
No matter the outcome
of the upcoming days,
they will know
where we stand.
They will know what
we have been fighting for.
We stand with you
until the very end.
One final address, live.
Syeddy.
Live?
Yes.
I want it to go out
to all the people
all over these lands.
But, uh, the team,
they will...
We are at
the final stages of this war.
The team cannot stop us now.
One final address then.
Our people must know, they must
understand the work we have done.
They will hear and see everything
that we have accomplished.
Your words
will give them strength.
They will rise up
without fear, as we did.
This mission
has taught me many things,
but most importantly,
resilience.
You have fought back
from the forgotten depths
of the desert,
formed a coalition,
and gained faith in your ideas
across these lands.
Our people owe you a great debt
for your leadership.
Debt?
That is not something
I wish to collect.
Our people needed
an idea, a cause.
They needed one unified voice,
one sword.
A sword that you have sharpened
with your own blood and given to us.
Without your leadership,
these lands would have been lost.
Factions of soldiers scattered all over
our lands without a reason to fight back.
You gave them that reason.
You made them believe.
Looking down,
you see them united
under one mask,
under one idea.
Do not believe in me.
Believe in an idea so much stronger
than any man with a weapon.
Or a country with a military.
Yes, we believe in you.
We're all soldiers
fighting on a battlefield
at the end of the day.
We stand with you
until the very end.
At this very moment, the team
is out there hunting us.
They will make
their last stand,
but without true conviction,
they will fail
to bring us to our knees.
It will be too late.
Their mission will be
a complete failure.
We have come too close
for assumptions.
Syeddy, we have come
too far to fail.
They can come,
but they will be met
with more firepower
than they ever
thought possible.
I want soldiers guarding
the base around the clock.
Yes, Supreme Leader.
Good.
The sun is setting on us,
my friend.
It is a beautiful sunset,
indeed.
In time, they will come
to understand our ideas.
In time, syeddy,
in time.
Gather the men.
I want to address our lands one last time
and finish
what we started together.
We will be awaiting your
presence, my Supreme Leader.
No mistakes.
This war ends now.
Of course.
Clear head?
All clear.
Ready to press forward, sir.
Join your team.
We are ready.
We leave at dawn.
Are you getting
irregularities?
I'm getting a lot of
web traffic over here.
He's about to go live.
Get Commander Brisco!
Ready?
- Smith?
- Sir.
- What is it?
- You're gonna wanna see this.
- Get them in here.
- Yes, sir.
What is this?
They're about to go live
with a video feed.
Go ahead.
Western World,
I say this to you
out of my belief
and overwhelming conviction
that I and my people are forever
meant to balance this world.
For too long, you have taken our
wealth, our land and our oil.
You will soon understand
what I stand for.
This ends now!
We have to finish
what we started.
If we don't come out on top,
all of this will be for nothing.
The world's watching.
You know what's at stake.
The ultimate sacrifice
may be required.
Who's in?
I'm in.
I'm with you.
And I will stand with you.
I'm in.
Well, you're all screwed
without me, so I'm in.
Good.
Start prepping.
- Commander Brisco?
- Yes. I need the president.
We're about to move
on the location.
That's great news.
He's coming on now.
Commander, I'm here.
Yes, sir.
I'm hearing good news.
All our intel points to
a forward base of operations
deserted in the dead zone
after the war.
The dead zone?
One of our FOBs was,
um, overrun.
We never reclaimed it,
and they've been using it
as a base of operations
right under our noses.
The tunnels
were just a distraction.
What about the sarin bombs?
I don't have a bomb count,
but I know he has them.
Hmm. Well, I want to
make sure we secure the FBO.
Nothing gets out of there.
I'm confident my men can
contain the situation, sir.
- Failure is not an option here, Commander.
- We won't fail.
Good. I'm ordering Predator
drones into the area now.
If things should get
out of hand,
we're gonna put
a Hellfire missile on his head.
Sir, my men will be
on the ground.
I understand that.
It'll be my call and one
that I have to live with.
The lives of few
for the lives of many,
but let's hope
it doesn't come to that.
We'll get it done.
Godspeed.
Let's get this done.
Yes, sir.
Let's finish this.
She never jams.
Thanks.
- How's it going?
- We'll be ready, sir.
I don't have to tell you
what's at stake out there,
how many lives at risk
if they smuggle those bombs out.
Down in flames
or nothing at all.
Move fast
and get it done out there.
Copy that, sir.
It's a few hours
before sunrise.
Good luck.
- Sir!
- Excellent!
We're inbound.
Happy hunting.
Three klicks,
north-northeast.
This is it.
- All right. We gotta move.
- Weapons tight.
Hit 'em hard and fast.
Make sure your shots count.
Look who's back in full swing.
Sat image is showing
heavy movement.
We're going to have
serious company.
Let's do this!
Okay.
Move out, move out!
A ton of movement down there.
What's the move?
One guard shack,
far-side entrance.
Guard towers
on every corner.
Going to be difficult
for a quiet entrance.
We're gonna need
someone on the inside.
Xu, you're up.
Copy.
I'm at the base.
You're clear.
- How we doin'?
- Good.
They're in position.
Sat feed is strong.
- Drone status?
- Minutes away.
Weapons system will be active
when it reaches the area.
Let's keep that card
in our back pocket.
Understood, sir.
Guard is moving
to the other side.
You're clear. Move.
Xu, on my count.
Three, two, one.
Okay. Change out.
Get to the main entrance.
He's in.
This better work.
It'll work.
Guard tower two.
Tower two clear.
Xu, get to the guard shack
and clear us a path in.
When Xu clears that path,
we move.
Jacques, you're with me.
- Copy.
- Cover the wall.
Ralph, James, we're going in
the front door, boys.
Daniel...
you ready for this?
Let's move.
Here we go!
Why are you so late?
Main gate is clear.
Move in.
Xu, find that bomb.
We're in the tower.
Jacques, eyes on the main gate.
Be ready.
There's dozens
of crates in here.
One by one,
check them all.
We have to make sure
nothing gets out.
Galina, keep steady.
Do not fire.
Holding.
Shit!
They're moving
a transport truck.
Xu, what's your status?
Xu, do you copy? Status!
I got eyes on the bombs.
They're not activated yet.
But they're ready
to move out.
Xu!
Hey, you!
What are you doing there?
They're here!
Arm one of the bombs.
I want them dead!
Do not fail me!
Oh, shit!
We have company.
Weapons free.
Daniel!
Daniel, we have to move!
Daniel, come here.
Snap out of it. Hey, hey.
Daniel! Now get up
and let's fuckin' kill 'em all!
We're fucked!
This was a bad idea.
- Daniel.
- All right, all right.
- You got it!
- Daniel, we have to move!
Ah!
Cover me.
I'm going in.
Buy me some time!
Working on it.
There's too many of them.
Merci.
Where's that bomb?
Clear a path.
Jacques, get to that bomb!
Found it!
Can you disarm it?
I'm working on it.
Okay.
Okay. Red... blue.
- Move!
- Ah!
- It's disarmed. Clear.
- Let's go!
Good work, good work!
Move to the barracks.
Let's go!
Copy that.
On the way.
Coming your way!
Whoa, don't shoot.
It's me!
Xu!
Xu, what the fuck, man?
Lose the mask.
Let's move!
Coming!
- I'm right behind you.
- Go, let's go!
Let's go!
Look out!
Fuck! I'm out.
Changing.
Stop that truck! Let's go.
We need to stop that truck!
Blow the gate!
I'm working on it.
Watch out!
Move! Move!
Supreme Leader,
we have to leave the base.
Shh.
Supreme Leader. Supreme Leader,
we have to leave here ASAP.
Without you,
there is no mission.
Let's go.
There he goes!
Cover me.
Move, move, move!
Shit.
Kill them.
I assure you,
we won't fail.
See you soon, my friend.
Forward.
On me.
Anyone hit?
All good?
I'm fine.
He's not here.
Daniel, he's in the lab.
Copy that.
Let's finish this, son.
Yes, sir.
I got this.
You sure you're good?
Go!
I told you, Daniel,
one way or the other,
this was going to end
my way.
It's not over.
You still
don't understand.
Ideas are much stronger
than any bomb, any war.
Whether I win or you win today,
tomorrow someone else
will pick up where I left off.
How about I stop you today
and we'll deal with tomorrow?
Hold them off!
Incoming!
Let's go!
Let's go.
You cannot be everywhere.
Did I get too close?
I do miss our conversations.
You and I are not
that different.
Devoted to our countries.
And we both have lost somebody.
I'm nothin' like you.
Let's move!
On you.
You have your honor.
I have mine.
You have your loyalty,
You have your mission,
and I have mine.
You're weak.
Spinning out of control.
Toss it.
Rifle too.
Up.
You seem to be
in this situation a lot.
Only with you.
Oh, Daniel,
I'm touched.
Get up!
Move!
Circle up!
You hear that?
Your team is
being overrun.
My weapons
are being moved.
I wouldn't count them out.
Maybe, maybe not.
My men came here today
ready to die.
Did yours?
Roger... Go!
Soon my weapons will be scattered
across Europe, ready to deploy.
I have enough sarin bombs
to wipe out entire cities.
Moments from now,
they will escape
and carry out my mission.
Always remember you and your team have failed.
I'm on him.
No!
This... is for you.
This is not over!
It's not over.
Drive out the truck now!
Go with him!
Get the truck!
Fuck!
- Send the drone in.
- Yes, sir.
Locking target.
Two minutes.
This...
isn't the end.
It is for you.
Target acquired.
You have my go.
- Target locked.
- Fire!
Sir, we're all
accounted for and clear.
Sending your ride to you.
You're comin' home.
Welcome back, brother.
You good, mate?
Yeah.
It's done.
Let's go home.
- Yeah.
- Good work, guys.
The war's far from over.
Only the dead
have seen the end of war.
I'm not gonna miss it here.
What do you think
will happen to this place?
Politicians will take over.
On the matter of the future,
today we found
a little bit of peace.
Peace to the brothers
who gave their lives before us
so we could make this mission
a success.
Amen, brother.
Let's get out of here.
I feel like we're bonding.
It only took us three months.
Hey, Xu, everyone
really likes your new outfit.
- But you dropped this.
- Oh!
Seriously though,
it was the digs.
People...
I have to hand it to you.
Odds were against you,
and you pulled it off.
Thank you, Commander.
These past few months
have been hell on all of us.
And I have to say that you're
some of the toughest,
bravest soldiers I know.
Next time you're lookin'
for a fight,
count me in.
Dismissed.
Sir.
Hey.
Packing up already?
You know how it works.
Back to the States,
look for my next check.
Yeah, I hear you on that.
How about you?
Think I'm gonna
take some time off.
This mission was...
different.
This place
and these people...
Don't go soft on me.
Soft?
Never that, mate.
Hey...
you were good out there.
We were good.
And take care of
those locks of love.
They fit you, man.
That's a good one,
Mr. President.
Well done, Commander.
I never doubted the team
for a second.
All is well.
I think a vacation
might be due.
No, I hate vacations.
Well...
You pass along my regards
to the team and my thanks.
Will do, sir.
What's next
for you two?
- I'm going on tour.
- Again?
I'm gettin' the band
back together.
- Snakeheads.
- Nice!
It's punk rock.
I am going to sit
on a beach...
get a tan...
have a drink.
Stay safe, boys. I can't be on
every mission watching your backs.
It's been a fun ride.
I think
I'll miss you most.
You still crazy.
You all right?
You gonna miss it?
No.
You always had my back.
- Brothers, dude.
- Yeah.
Nah, this mission...
- Yeah, completely fucked.
- Come on.
You know, the world
owes you people a lot.
Now get outta here
before somethin' else happens.
Yes, sir!
Get the hell outta here!
Best damn team ever.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org