Interior Pedro's house, day.
The house is quiet.
It's 3 p.m.
Pedro, the IandIord, is at his work.
But his Latin American
wife, Margarita,
is in the room of NabiI,
their young Turkish Iodger.
As they are eating each other's face,
NabiI gives Margarita
what Pedro cannot.
Margarita shouts out NabiI's name,
asking for more and more.
But just as she gets a cIimax,
the door swings open.
Pedro, the husband, has returned
from his work to surprise them.
Pedro waves his gun.
Margarita shouts:
''No, Pedro, it's not what you think!''
But with a viIIain angry smiIe,
Pedro puIIs the trigger.
Ali!
Okay, okay.
-Shut up. This is London, not Tunisia.
-You're bloody late!
Edgware Road, here we come!
What's the matter with you?
Are you blind?
-lt's not my fault, he was drunk.
-You'll pay forthis.
Naief, don't be so hard on him,
l'll pay for it.
Just for Madam Vivienne then.
Do it once more and you're out!
Bastard.
-Thanks.
-l have to go now.
Martin is coming back
from Malaysia in an hour.
l'll see you on Thursday.
Don't forget your stick.
How could l?
Mama, l can't come
back to Egypt now.
l have a good job
and a lovely house.
What shall l tell your cousin?
The girl can't wait any longer.
Good, now she
can marry someone else.
Ali, do you know how much
money you will lose? You are mad.
This marriage was your idea.
Tell her anything you want.
You are just like your father was.
You will be a failure.
-AIi, it's your sister EIham.
-Hi, EIham.
When you come home, bring me
a dress from Marks&Spencer.
Pedro. What are you doing?
What's happening?
You stupid ass!
Shut up, woman!
You wrote in your shit story...
that you have seen my wife
screw this fucking Turkish bastard!
l made it up. lt's a story, fantasy.
ln my head. Okay?
Margarita will never
do something like that.
She loves you, man.
He's right. l love you, Pedro!
All right.
So what the hell
happened to my room?
lt's not your room any more, pervert!
Your shitty stuff is all here! Get out!
lt's 5 o'clock in
the morning. Where l go?
-No my problem. Out!
-Give me my 80 pounds deposit.
Get out or l'll blow up
your fucking fish!
You hear me? Get out! Now!
Hey, stop! Hey, stop, stop!
Shit.
This happen when the
man will not give up his dreams.
How many times you've
been kicked out?
Don't count.
Forget this writing
shit and get a real life.
Start Halal meat shop
ortaxi like everyone else.
l don't wanna be like
everyone else, Ahmed.
Writing is my real life
and l know l can make it here.
Bullshit.
You're a bloody foreigner.
No chance for you
here without a British passport.
The White marriage is the solution.
Here, pick one.
From where you get all these?
A telephone box?
They are my clients.
l'm opening an agency
for White marriages.
-You must be joking.
-No, l'm not.
You know how many
foreigners without visa...
there are in this country?
l will make a fortune.
Sasha, very nice and cheap.
-She charge only 5.000 pounds.
-Oh, shit! 5.000 pounds?
l can't make this money
even if l save forten years.
Do you have a blonde one?
Blondes are
more expensive, smart-arse.
Number 52?
Yes.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
That's all right, madam.
You're Egyptian.
Yes.
-May l touch your face?
-Sorry?
May l touch your face?
Yeah, why not. Go ahead.
Oh, no.
That's my stop.
l have to go.
Your name, please?
No, stay. l must talk to you.
Madam, please.
l have spent a lot of money
on my education here.
All l'm asking for is 6 months
to see if l can get work as a writer.
l must say, Mr Radwan, for a writer,
your grasp of the English
language is poor frankly.
Please.
Just 6 months.
No.
You must leave the country
within 12 weeks time.
Under no circumstances should
you seek paid employment.
ls that clear?
No work.
Cut, cut.
Very good. Very good, guys.
Ten minutes
while we change the reels.
Mr Paul, can you give me
the money forthis session up front?
-Ali, you know the system.
-Yes, but l need this money urgently.
The answer's no. Okay?
Can l ask you another favour?
Can you give this script to the
American producer when he comes?
Ali, l'm not your bloody agent.
This is the third script
you've given me this month.
This one is different.
lt's full of action, sex. He will love it.
You may well have written
'Pulp Fiction 2' for all l know,
but this guy
is not gonna be interested...
in an unknown writer like you. Okay?
Hey, look.
Why don't you stick to what
you can do really well. Okay?
Just let the music
swim through your body.
Okay. Don't force the movement.
Swim. Swim.
Good.
Sing! Sing! Sing Arabic to me!
-Vivienne.
-Yes?
Can l borrow some money from you?
How much?
5.000 pounds.
Are you crazy or what?
l don't have this kind of money.
Why do you want it?
To get a White marriage.
So l lend you money
for your White wedding?
How romantic.
No, it's not
a real marriage. lt's just fake.
That's the only way
l can stay in this country.
l have only eleven weeks left.
Well, don't worry,
nothing will happen to you.
There are thousands of people
without a visa in this country.
They won't catch you,
mon cheri.
lt's getting late now.
Your money forthe lesson.
You deserve it.
And this is the number
of my friend, Mark.
He's an artist l represent.
Looking for Arab models.
-Why don't you give him a call?
-l will.
Better go now, mon cheri.
A script writer?
-Anything l've seen?
-l didn't have any luck yet.
But, l do voice over and
l teach belly dancing.
So l heard.
l've never come across
a male belly dancer before.
ls it common?
Some men do.
-Do they?
-Yes.
l'm sure you're terribly good at it.
Could you stand
in front of the desert?
Can you look to the right?
Put your sword up.
Just down a tiny bit. Perfect.
Hold it.
The camera adores you.
Does it?
Yeah, you're perfect.
Am l?
Vivienne tells me
you need somewhere to sleep.
Yeah, that's true.
This guy's a faggot.
He'll be after your dick.
Vivienne will not tell me to go
if he's this kind of man.
A woman who
can screw another man...
on her husband's floor
can do anything.
Listen, l'm tired of your snoring.
He's offering me 100 pounds
each week for modelling.
And a free room. How can l refuse?
l need to save money
for your White marriage great idea.
Okay, go.
But don't come to me
and cry when he gets your arse.
l love the decor.
lt's very... filmy.
-Here's your front door key.
-Thank you.
Make yourself at home. l'm off out.
lf the phone rings,
can you let it go to the machine?
-Unless it's for you. Obviously.
-All right, thank you.
Max, young and IoneIy.
Looking for reaI Iove.
You must be oId and boId.
Daddy type.
Dirty underpants for saIe.
Hi, it's Mark. Leave a message. Bye.
Mark, it's George. We met in
''Heaven''Iast week, remember?
Mark is gay.
-ls that a problem for you?
-Of course! l'm living with him.
And if he get excited
and try to do something with me?
Don't be silly,
he knows you're not gay.
Anyway, l thought
writers like new experiences.
-Hello, hello.
-Hi, Vivienne.
Tight bum.
Fancy a drink?
As the night faIIs,
Mark gets ready
for a new adventure.
He goes to ''The Rough AngeIs''cIub.
It is fiIIed with men.
He steps inside
with a big inviting smiIe.
Shit!
Ali!
-What is happening?
-Sorry, l burnt my sausage.
-Why are you writing in here?
-My light-bulb blew up and...
-l'd better get you another one.
-Thank you, Mark.
Have we met before?
No, we never met.
l've seen your face somewhere.
Anyway, l'm Dick from Malta.
Ali from Egypt.
l've been to Egypt many times.
Always have a wonderful time.
l'm so sorry about that.
LoneIy Mark
drags Dick to his room.
Dick faIIs on him
with an irresistibIe smiIe.
As their forbidden Iove goes on,
their bodies melt together
on the big sweaty bed.
But before they reach the cIimax,
the rent boy, Dick,
hits Mark with the bedside Iamp.
Mark's face get white,
the body stop moving.
And suddenIy... siIent.
Yep?
l heard somebody
screaming. Are you all right?
l'm absolutely fine.
What this for?
You've got bags under your eyes.
-l haven't slept all night!
-You'll get used to it.
Get used to what?
Your new bed.
Look up.
Ali, try and look more tragic.
l wanna see some pain.
Beautiful.
Somebody wants
to marry your reserve fake wife.
l told him to wait.
How much have you saved?
lf we get paid today,
150 pounds.
Fuck! 150 quid?
l can't get you a dead
pigeon for bloody 150 quid.
You need to move fast.
How much time left on your visa?
-About ten weeks.
-You're in real trouble.
Ask this fairy you live with
to lend you some money.
He's a photographer,
he must be loaded.
Mark?
l wouldn't ask him
for a glass of water.
Maybe, you just need
to screw him first before you ask.
Do you think l am a bloody gigolo?
You said it, not me.
Where is this bloody script?
Jesus Christ!
No, no, wait, wait.
He's just my lodger.
-Your lodger?
-Yeah.
l'm not really into that at all.
Sean!
Sean, wait!
What are you doing in my bedroom?
l...
Looking forthe murder weapon?
The murder weapon?
A bedside lamp,
if l remember rightly.
That's my script!
The one starring Mark,
the promiscuous gay painter.
Attacked by Dick from Malta,
and bludgeoned to death
by a bedside fucking lamp!
l take my material from
what's happening around me.
That doesn't mean
l'm writing about you personally.
-Means you are sick.
-What about you?
Every night you come
home with a different fella.
One night a crazy guy
will beat you or maybe kill you.
-You have no right to...
-The police will think it's me!
Why you laugh?
l'm serious.
Stupidly for a second l thought
you were worried about me.
Listen to me.
l live my life the way l choose.
Now, if you don't like that,
fuck off out of here.
Tough shit, l've lost the key.
When?
-Oh, my God!
-Your key.
Why didn't you tell me she was ill?
Come on, mate.
So l was right.
He tried to get your arse.
No, clever Dick,
he didn't like what l wrote about him.
l can't believe you.
When will you learn?
Ahmed, l'm tired, l'm wet.
l don't want to hear
your boring speeches.
Can l stay tonight or not?
Ali, you know you are welcome,
but as you can see l have this chick.
You want to join us?
-She's a real hot one.
-No, thank you. l had my dinner.
Vivienne!
Can l come in?
Wait, wait. l'll be back.
What the hell are you doing?
Martin's upstairs.
Your friend Mark chucked me out.
-You did something wrong.
-No, l did nothing!
-l'll talk to him.
-No, don't. l will never go back.
Yeah, l'm coming.
You have to go, come.
-Please, l'm so cold.
-Go.
Vivienne.
Can you keep my fish?
Yes, of course.
Darling?
ls everything all right?
Be good. Ciao.
You were picked up
at two o'clock this morning...
with this so-called luggage.
You're wearing a handcuff!
What were you doing?
l have told you.
l was visiting some friends and they
gave me the handcuff for good luck.
Tell us your friends' names
and we'll call 'em.
l can't.
Why not?
Because l can't.
This is really very funny.
Student visa.
You're not working, are you?
Me? No.
l'm just enjoying London.
Where are you staying
till this visa runs out?
l was renting a room
from a guy called Mark.
You mean ''Mark''?
The guy in this story?
Yes.
lt's his stuff.
He's been staying with me.
We had an argument and he left.
Sign this, sir,
it'll bring matters to a close.
Your driving licence.
You're free to go now, sir.
Good night, Mark.
What about me?
Wait, l've got
to find out what Dick was up to.
Ali.
Get in.
Come on.
Thank you.
Thank you, too.
Now the whole police station knows
what Mark gets up to in his bedroom.
Mark,
l'm really sorry.
l shouldn't have gone in your room.
l shouldn't have read
your bloody script.
-l'm sorry about what l said.
-l know what you've said.
Fuck!
You wanker!
Are you all right?
No, l'm not.
My mother died tonight.
She's the one l talk to.
My father,
he just hates the fact
that l'm his only son,
and l'm gay.
He looks at me like he's thinking...
''What a sad waste of a man''.
l am dreading this funeral.
Oh God.
Why don't you take
a friend with you?
Dick from Malta?
Those men...
they are not friends, Ali.
Shall l come with you?
What, you?
Yeah. Me.
What?
We have entrusted our sister
Mary to God's merciful keeping.
We now commit
her body to the ground.
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
ln sure and certain hope
of the resurrection to eternal life,
through our Lord Jesus Christ,
who died, was buried
and rose again for us.
To him be the Glory,
forever and ever, amen.
Amen.
Cucumber or egg?
Thank you.
Cucumber, thank you.
-Would you like a cup of tea?
-All right.
Does you father know?
Know what?
That you and Mark...
are together.
Oh, no.
My father died a long time ago.
Good for him.
For rheumatism.
Anyway, you seem
like a decent sort of chap.
Pity that Mark and l never
understood each other.
l shall be going my self soon, too.
Look after him, would you?
He's a fine man.
He always did like Eastern culture.
Tea?
Thank you.
What was he talking about?
You like Eastern culture?
lt was nice to meet you.
And you, Ali.
Drive safely.
l will.
There we are.
Ah, yes. Thank you.
l feel free now.
Mark.
l didn't tell you before.
My visa is finishing in eight weeks.
l can't stay here
unless l do White marriage,
and l don't have the money.
-White what?
-A fake marriage.
You can't do that, it's deeply illegal.
l know, l know.
But what can l do?
l'm not gonna let you. This is absurd.
You'll end up in prison.
There must be another way.
He's asking
for another six months.
lt's not that big deal.
Sir, this country
is not a charity home.
Underthe present Act,
Mr. Radwan has no right
to demand an extension to his visa,
or seek employment.
May l ask you how
you are supporting yourself?
His father is terribly rich.
-He send me money every week.
-And sometimes twice a week.
Yeah.
This man's whole
future depends upon you.
Give him six months.
Who are you?
His friend.
Yes.
The White marriage
is starting to look damn attractive.
l need 5.000 pounds to do it.
l only have 500.
Maybe Linda could cut a deal.
-She's always broke.
-Linda?
Yeah, you know,
the model in the photographs.
Bloody hell! That Marylin woman?
Yeah.
Yes. Phone her now.
-l will.
-Yes!
l will.
Engaged.
Try this.
lt's fully charged.
WhiIe tearing off a game of goIf,
I may make a pIay forthe caddie,
but when I do,
I don't foIIow through,
'cos my heart beIongs to daddy.
If I invite a boy some night,
to dine on my fine finnan haddy...
Hi, come on in. Lovely show.
-Does Linda work here?
-Linda?
The new blonde.
So I want to warn you Iaddie,
though I know you're perfectIy sweII,
that my heart beIongs to my daddy,
'cos my daddy,
he treats it so weII.
She's on stage.
Wait here.
WhiIe tearing off a game of goIf,
I may make a pIay forthe caddie,
but when I do,
I don't foIIow through,
'cos my heart beIongs to daddy.
If I invite a boy some night,
to dine on my fine finnan haddy,
I just adore,
he's asking for more,
'cos my heart beIongs to daddy.
So I want to warn you Iaddie,
though I know you're perfectIy sweII,
that my heart beIongs to my daddy,
'cos my daddy,
he treats it so...
weII.
You're the Egyptian
who wants to marry me?
Yeah. l mean,
that's not a real marriage.
-lt's just fake to get my visa.
-Mark tells me you're a screenwriter.
-Anything famous?
-l haven't been lucky yet.
-This'll bring you luck.
-l hope so.
My faith healer has one.
She's just crazy about Egypt.
-She talks about it all the time.
-Really?
So, l've been given it lots of thought,
and l've decided.
-l can help you.
-Yes, great! Thank you!
l mean, thank you.
But you sound a little bit American.
That's because l'm American, silly.
My mother is from New York
and my father is from England,
so l have a British passport.
l can do it for 3.000 pounds.
3.000!
-Yeah. Something the matter?
-Oh, no.
l have only 500.
500?
l can't marry you forthat.
That's only what l've saved.
l give you
the rest as soon as l can.
Please, don't say no.
Please.
Okay, l'll do it.
But no wedding bells
till l get the rest of it.
l understand.
And remember, this is just business.
Yeah, l know.
You're on now, Marilyn.
l'm coming, Tina. Okay.
Okay, l mean, thank you again.
Yes, yes!
She said yes!
Oh, man, can you believe it?
Me and Marilyn Monroe.
l just couldn't believe my ears...
She will marry me.
Okay, bastard.
You take my idea and not pay me.
How would you get
the money in 7 weeks?
l will work very hard
and save every penny.
And what about if you get caught?
Get caught? Why? You said it's safe.
l thought that, but yesterday,
the lmmigration bastards...
search my flat to prove
that my fake wife is living with me.
l'm afraid, Ali.
They could deport me
if they prove l make a fake marriage.
lt's your fault, Ahmed.
Offering your service to everyone.
Sometime
l wonder why we are doing this.
You can go back
to Tunisia and farm your father's land.
l wish l could, but how?
All my village will be waiting for
me to see how much money l made.
l told them l have a big villa,
two Mercedes, and three restaurants.
Three bloody restaurants!
How can l go now?
lt's marvellous exercise, l'm told.
-You're a very good dance teacher.
-Not really.
l'd love to see you,
but l travel all the time.
l tell you something, Ali.
Since Vivienne started the dance
workshop with you, she's become...
How shall l put it?
Even more lovely to come home to.
Merci, mon cheri.
Can you excuse me?
Very nice.
Let's look at that one.
That's a good one. Very well hung.
lsn't Fernando gorgeous?
He's just agreed
to be my next model.
Mark, l think l should move out.
We'll be really quiet, l promise.
No, that's not the reason, man.
l found out it's dangerous
not to live with my fake wife.
lf Linda has a room,
l think l should move there, no?
lf we get married,
we have to live together.
Just to convince
the lmmigration people.
-Like that film ''Green Card''?
-Yeah, something like that.
Can l get a couple of shots?
Thank you.
As a matter of fact, l've a very
nice room that's empty right now.
-Great! Can l move in?
-Yes, for 40 pounds a week.
lf we're going to get married,
l need the rest of the money soon.
Yes, l know. Very soon, l promise.
Good afternoon, sir.
Nice little room. Thanks, Linda.
Why you keep bothering me?
Linda, l love you, baby!
You're here.
l came this afternoon.
Are you all right?
l saw this man bothering you.
He's just some crazy fan
who's always following me.
But that's showbiz.
l bought some flowers for you.
That's so sweet.
-l hope it didn't cost you too much.
-Oh, no.
That's the rent forthe week.
Thanks. l'll get you a receipt.
So any news about
the rest of the money?
-l really need it fast, you know?
-l'm doing my best, l promise you.
Thank you.
Okay, goodnight.
Exterior MariIyn's flat, night.
Aziz sees a man trying to attack
his bIonde dream girl, MaryIin.
He rushes outside and beats him up.
The man runs away
and MariIyn hugs Aziz,
and gives him a Iong kiss.
Aziz is in a seven heaven.
Martin's away
in Bangladesh for a few days.
Come around tonight
and feed your little fish.
-She's missing you.
-l'm missing hertoo.
-l'm really feeling tired tonight and...
-Okay.
Have a nice rest then.
Ali! What are you doing here?
l finish early and l thought
we could share a cab to the flat.
-Maybe this fan follows you.
-That's so sweet.
-You don't have to worry about me.
-That's what a fake husband is for.
Do you have a dream, Linda?
Yes, to be a star.
To be famous.
Could you imagine what
it would be like to be loved forever...
and to always
be thought of as beautiful?
l'm sure you'll be a star.
You are very talented
and very pretty.
-You really think so?
-Yeah.
Gosh!
l've never been told l was pretty
before, even when l was little.
All little girls should be told
they're pretty, even if they're not.
You must have a dream too, Ali.
Mine is, get my visa,
my own place,
marry the girl l love,
and be a famous, rich screenwriter.
Have my name on the screen,
and go to Hollywood. That's all.
Wait.
Thank you.
Linda.
l want to tell you something.
Yes?
l'm writing a script about you.
A script about me?
Yeah. l mean,
it's not about you personally.
lt's based on your character.
And l hope you don't mind.
No, l don't mind at all.
A script about me?
This is wonderful.
And l hope to sell it quickly
and give you the rest of the money.
Yes. l'm having
a birthday party this Monday.
-Would you like to come?
-Yeah.
l could introduce you to a movie
director who might help you.
That's great.
l will be there, of course.
This could be like
you're Arthur and...
l'm Marilyn and maybe you could
write something like ''The Misfits''.
Or like ''Let's Make Love''.
Amanda. She sings
and dances, you know.
And l sing.
Suzy, swim. Swim more.
Yes, like that. Very good. Very good.
Yeah.
Maintenant, maintenant!
Okay, Ali. What's the matter?
Vivienne, listen.
Can we just be friends?
Are you fucking
that whore you live with?
No, l'm not and she's not a whore!
Sorry to insult you princess.
l just find it hard since
l met your husband, all right?
Come on, mon cheri,
he's got his own mistress too.
No!
Come on, you know l like you.
You're very special to me.
Yeah, l like you too.
But try to understand.
l feel like a gigolo.
And l just can't do it any more.
Suddenly you got a conscience?
-Maybe you should get one too.
-Go! Go then!
Happy birthday, Linda.
l bought this for you.
Oh, it's beautiful, Ali.
For good luck.
There's Sam.
He's the movie director.
Happy birthday.
You look gorgeous.
Thank you, Sam.
-You shouldn't have.
-My pleasure.
-This is Ali, the screenwriter.
-He's writing a script about you.
Hi.
This script sounds really interesting.
-We should meet up.
-Yeah.
Look, here's my mobile.
We could meet in 'Jerry's'.
-ls next Thursday cool?
-Yeah, very cool.
We're gonna have
a fabulous time working together.
Ali.
Good luck.
l hate to say it but, gay films
were an '80s thing, done to death.
''My Nights with Mark'' is different.
lt's about the relationship between
a gay guy and a straight guy.
Like l say, done to death.
Where's your script about Linda?
l haven't finished it yet.
Look, Ali,
l like your writing, you know.
lt's strange, it's weird,
it breaks the rules,
but what about
something more personal?
What about
''Anthony and Cleopatra''?
Modern version, obviously.
Linda could play the lead.
Linda?
Yeah. l think
she'd make a great Cleopatra.
Like to have a go?
l will think about it.
l can get you 4.000.
4.000?
l will do it.
Leave Marilyn alone,
you black bastard!
She's mine. Mine!
She's my fiancee. l can't leave her.
She's your fucking fiancee?
Your fucking fiancee is she?
ls she?
Do you know his name?
He will not get away with this!
Don't talk like that.
He could have really hurt you.
l don't care!
Could you just
not talk about him any more?
lt's spoiling our wonderful news.
Ali, promise me,
promise me you'll write
the best script you ever wrote.
l promise you
l will write the best script ever.
Chef!
By the NiIe,
beneath the desert moon,
in the shadow
of the goIden pyramids,
Anthony, the victorious soIdier,
is reIaxing in the bath.
The door open wide and CIeopatra
appears in a Iong floaty nightie.
With food and wine.
She waIks into the water,
and kisses him passionateIy.
Well done, Ali. That's the one.
Apart from some tweaks
to the middle, of course.
l really cried
when she poisoned herself.
-lt's wonderful.
-Thank you.
-When do l get the money?
-Soon as we start filming.
First day of the shoot.
When l get the money
we must get married quickly.
My time is running out.
l have only 1 7 days left.
Yes, we'll do it, Ali.
But l need the money first.
You know, l always
wondered if l'd ever make it...
to the other side of the street.
Thank you, Ali
for making my dreams come true.
Hi, Lisa.
That's great.
Five minute break. Thank you.
Ali. Ali.
Congratulations.
The boys told me one of your scripts
is gonna be going into production.
Thank you, Mr Paul.
lf the producer needs
a dubbing supervisor,
will you give him my name?
Yes, of course.
Who's your director?
Do l know him?
Sam Smith.
Yeah, definitely rings a bell.
Well done.
l always knew you had it in you.
They film my script next week.
Your son's picture will be all over
the English newspapers.
God bless you, my son.
l always pray for you, Ali.
Listen, mama.
l'm getting married
to an English girl.
What did you say?
An English girl?
Don't get mad at me. l love her!
And you will like hertoo.
-Guess who she Iooks Iike.
-Who?
-MariIyn Monroe.
-Marilyn?
You look good.
Oh, he's here.
Hi. l'm Sam's assistant.
l've come to take you to the studio.
We can't take you with us.
What?
This is my first script to be filmed.
l have to go.
He's the screen writer.
And l'm supposed
to get paid today.
l'll have a word.
Maybe next week.
Better go or we'll fall
behind schedule.
Can you follow this car?
l knew there was a kissing scene,
but nobody said anything about
having sex with Anthony in a bath.
This is porn, Sam!
Real sex in films is coming back.
l promise you.
This is my first film.
Don't mess it up.
l can't. l can't do it.
No-one's ever heard of you.
This is your big break.
Even Marilyn started in porn.
Please, l'm begging you.
l don't think this is a good idea.
Get your hands of her, you bastard!
l can explain.
This is what you make me do,
what you say about my country?
ls this what you left me for?
Okay, just stop it!
Get off him!
-Who the fuck are you?
-l'm the writer, you bastard!
Gosh!
l thought it was my big break.
Me too.
Maybe Sam was right.
Maybe l should have
just gone through with it.
Linda. We must not let
that bastard get us down.
You are a good actress. Me and you.
We will do it, okay?
No. Ali.
Let's just be friends.
But l love you.
l can't hide it any more.
You do?
Yes.
Since the first time l saw you.
But you don't deserve me.
You deserve
a woman people respect.
But l do respect you.
No man's ever said that to me.
Because l love you.
You really do?
l wanna marry you.
l mean for real.
l want you to be my real wife.
You wanna marry me for real?
Yes, l do. l even told my mother.
l can't.
Did l say something wrong?
No.
l just...
l just wanna be
alone right now, please.
Could you go?
What's happening?
l can't marry you, Ali.
l'm already married.
What?
The crazy fan.
That's my husband.
l married him when l was nineteen.
l thought it was
a good idea at the time.
Then he started
getting really jealous with me.
lt got so bad...
that he cut someone
just fortalking to me.
So he got sent away
for a couple of years.
And then he left me some money
that l was supposed to take care...
and l took it.
l ran with it.
And he's been after me ever since.
And he won't divorce me
until l give him his money back.
That's why you agreed to marry me?
To give him my money?
But you could
never marry me in time.
And you always know this?
Are you all right?
l took 40 sleeping pills.
That was fucking rude.
Come on.
l still can't believe she's married.
Yesterday l have everything.
A beautiful wife, a film, a visa.
lt's all gone now.
l don't know what to do.
And l have less than two weeks.
Look,
l'll lend you the money
and you can pay me back...
whenever.
Thank you, Mark.
l will never forget your help.
Cut the Egyptian drama, please.
-How is she, miss?
-She'll survive.
Thank you.
Thank you, they're very pretty.
The doctor says
you can go home tomorrow.
Ali.
l'm not going home.
l'm going to stay
with a friend for a while.
l've decided...
that l just need to find Linda again.
You know?
l talked to my faith healer,
and she gave me this address,
where you can stay.
She has an empty
room in her house...
and she won't charge you anything.
l don't want another room.
l want you, Linda.
l love you.
Don't say that, Ali.
That wasn't me you loved.
I'm through with Iove,
I'II never faII again.
Said adieu to Iove,
don't ever caII again.
For I must have you or no-one.
And so I'm through with Iove.
I've Iocked my heart,
I'II keep my feeIings there.
I've stocked my heart,
with icy frigid air.
And I need to care for no-one.
Because I'm through with Iove.
Hello?
Good evening.
You're Linda's friend.
Such a lively girl.
So full of dreams.
Let's hope she'll find her way.
We met before on the bus.
Do you remember?
You're very sad, aren't you?
l know what you've been through,
but time will heal it.
Oh good. You still have yours.
Welcome home, Ali.
-Would you like some cake?
-No.
l made some specially.
The way you like it. Come.
No, thank you. l've had enough.
You used to love cakes.
So, how is your writing going?
How did you know l'm a writer?
-Did Linda tell you that?
-Yes.
But let's just say
l know a lot about you anyway.
-l told you, that Marilyn...
-You shut up!
l really don't want to
talk about it any more.
My friend Mark
lent me 1.000 pounds.
So just take it
and get me a cheap fake bride.
l need to move fast now.
See l've told you, he is a good man.
And guess what, l saved a
beautiful Scottish bride for you.
-l give her a call now.
-Can't we use a local one?
From London?
For 1.000 fucking quid?
No way. Don't worry.
-HeIIo?
-HeIIo. Is this Susan MacdonaId?
-Aye.
-Hi, it's Ahmed, your agent.
-How are you?
-l'm fine.
Guess what l have for you?
A husband. Yes.
-Oh, reaIIy?
-He just sitting here with me.
-Is he handsome?
-Yes, yes.
-WouId you Iike to taIk to him?
-Okay, put him on.
-HeIIo?
-Hi, Susan.
Oh no, just black, thank you.
You used to have it with milk.
Why you talk to me
as if you have known me before?
l'm not surprised
you don't remember.
-lt's been a long time.
-What are you talking about?
Would you please tell
me what's going on?
ln 1935 when l was eight,
l moved with my family to Luxor.
My father was an Egyptologist.
We had a cook
in Luxor called Mahmoud.
His son was
two years olderthan me.
We used to play
together all the time.
This little boy grew up to be the
most handsome man in the world.
And very clever.
He wanted to read English
at University in London,
and become a playwright.
He wrote the most beautiful stories.
And he loved my cakes.
Everyone was very proud of him.
Until they found out
that he and l were in love...
and planned to marry as soon as
he'd finished his military service.
My father sacked our cook
and sent me back to England.
l was devastated.
But my Egyptian lover and l
wrote to each other in secret.
We were determined to get married.
Whateverthe cost.
He sent me this.
We promised each other we would
always wear one until we met again.
But then the '48 war started.
He was killed in
action within a few weeks.
l was the saddest girl on earth.
l went to Egypt to visit his grave.
And there his spirit came to me.
And promised me he would return.
Soon afterwards l was
very ill and lost my eyesight.
But l was never sad.
And l waited, and waited.
l'm sorry.
His name was Ali.
When l met you on the bus,
l was sure that you were him.
You are my Ali.
Madam, it doesn't mean because
my name is Ali that l'm your Ali.
There are millions of Alis in Egypt,
and half of them look like me.
l knew it would be
hard for you to believe,
but it is the truth.
-You are his reincarnation.
-That's impossible!
You're wrong, Ali.
Your past has made
you what you are.
This is the only
photograph of us l ever had.
And this is his last letter.
See, that's not my handwriting.
Handwriting often
changes during reincarnation.
These are all from him.
Read them if you want.
You wrote them.
So, where is my Scottish bride?
l was supposed to meet hertoday.
Yes, but she can't come,
one of her kids is ill.
But she'll be here next week.
-Are you sure about this woman?
-Of course.
She's one of the best.
Don't worry, just leave it to me.
What's happened...?
What's happened to your hair?
This is my new look.
To match my new fake passport.
l am Farouk Hasanien.
Twenty-nine,
a ''ginger'' and beautiful.
Don't show it to everybody.
Orthey will get you this time.
ln their dreams.
Listen,
could l stay in your place...
until l find another room?
l left my flat.
lmmigration fuckers are after me.
Ahmed, l can't.
This woman is very strange.
-l wish l could move too.
-l can't believe your sad luck.
Of whole of London you
land in her house. lt's amazing.
ls she after your dick yet?
How I ache
to have you in my arms.
If I can't hoId you soon I shaII die.
I Iong for every part of you,
my dearest Sarah.
I miss every inch of you.
Being reunited with you in London...
wiII give me aII I need
to become a great writer.
Oh, shit, shit!
Shit, shit!
l looked this out for you.
lt's your galabia.
You gave it to me before
l came to London. Remember?
lt still has your smell.
Listen, l read them all.
-He was a very romantic man.
-Yes, you were.
Okay, okay,
if l said l believe in that l am him,
and this is my galabia,
what you expect me to do?
To fulfil the second
half of your promise.
Which is what?
To marry me.
You seriously want me to marry you?
Well, it's what you promised.
-But madam, l'm...
-l'm not a madam.
l've never married.
And no other man
has evertouched me.
l've saved myself for you.
As this is my witness.
That's very kind of you,
but as you can see, l'm old enough
to be your grandson. lf you had one.
You should have come back
40 years ago when l was young.
And what your family will say?
l have no family, Ali.
l only have you.
Please, Ali.
l've waited all my life for you.
Please, don't disappoint me now.
l'm sorry, Miss Stevenson.
l wish l can help you.
But l can't.
Hi, Mark and Fernando
are in Spain.
We'II get in touch when we get back.
Hi.
Oh, Ali. You're back.
l thought you'd gone to Egypt.
l'm sorry l haven't been in
contact with you.
l've discovered that other men
could teach dance betterthan you,
and they don't feel bad about it later.
Mon cheri.
Go, Ahmed. Go away.
l have a knife in my hand.
-Come on, don't be silly.
-Why you did that to me?
l have no place to sleep.
So she offered me to stay
at her house for four days.
She's using you
to get her revenge on me!
Come on, don't flatter yourself.
Vivienne was right when
she said you were bloody complex.
Where is my Scottish bride?
Everyday you say
''tomorrow, tomorrow''.
ls this bloody fake marriage
gonna happen or not?
-lt will, but you must wait.
-l can't wait!
Give me my money back.
l will get one myself.
-l don't have the money.
-What?
l had to use it for my fake passport.
So l could stay
and organise your marriage.
-You fucking spent my money?
-l will give it to you next week!
Next week it will be too late!
l got nearly no time!
l can't believe it!
You have made the
declarations prescribed by law,
and a solemn and
binding contract with each other,
and now l pronounce
you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
No, l'm not joking.
We have the wedding of the century.
Ali.
Since we have now been married,
l believe l have the right
to ask just one more thing of you.
Please, call me Sarah.
l'm your wife now.
Shame on you!
Getting married without me...
l waited forthis day all my life.
l'm sorry, mama. lt was very quick.
Send me the wedding pictures
to see what she's like.
She's great. You will like her.
Tell me , Ali...
is she a...
virgin or...?
Yes, she's a virgin.
She was waiting for me.
-Hi.
What have you done?
Are you crazy?
-What are you talking about?
-l'm talking about this.
You was afraid l will take
your chick away from you.
And that is why
you didn't want me to stay there.
Why didn't you tell me
you fancy ancient women?
l could find you a cheap one.
Five years younger and not blind.
Fuck you, Ahmed!
What you want me to do?
You spent all my money!
You use everyone!
You're just a little shit, man!
No, you're a piece of shit!
What about you?
You use everybody, too.
And whatever you will get
is what you deserve!
-Ahmed.
-Yes?
-The police wants to talk to you.
-Oh, shit.
-Are you Ahmed Zahoud?
-l've done nothing.
You don't have to say anything.
You're finished as well.
l never faked any passport!
This is for you, Ali.
l don't want to interfere in your life,
but you've been in
your room fortwo days now.
Are you not going to work?
No. l left.
Was it because of me?
Yes.
Sarah, l'm not your Ali.
l have done a bad thing.
And he was a good man.
He would not have done what l did.
l only married you
because of my visa.
Do you think l don't know?
But that isn't the real truth, Ali.
We married because that's fate.
Our fate.
Oh, look at me for a moment.
You made me
the happiest girl in town.
Have l?
Yes, Ali, you have.
But l did it for me.
But you made me happy.
You fulfilled your promise.
You're free to go if you want to.
Come in.
-l'm very sorry for what l've done.
-lt's all right. l understand.
Sarah.
Was Ali a good writer?
He was a great writer.
He always wrote from his heart.
You're a good writertoo.
That's why God
has given you another chance.
Don't lose it.
Well, Mr Radwan.
We can find no reason
not to give you a visa,
since you are now
married to a British citizen.
Congratulations
to the bride and groom.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything, Sarah.
Thank you too, Ali.
l'm so happy you came back to me.
To your visa and our fate together.
Cheers.
Can you taste it?
Good afternoon and weIcome.
-Very good.
-Sarah, it's started!
Our first subject is reincarnation.
Is Iife reaIIy betterthe second time?
-How do l look?
-Very beautiful.
Sarah Radwan and
her young Egyptian husband AIi.
Good afternoon to you both.
You beIieve you met him
over 60 years ago?
What convinced you
that AIi wouId return?
-Mark.
-What?
Mark, come in here.
-lt's Ali on the television!
-Oh my God!
And when AIi did return, did
you recognise him straight away?
You don't get much for 1.000 pounds.
I've been very Iucky.
Meeting Sarah
changed everything for me.
But that may be the one thing.
You thought that this
was somehow aIways meant to be?
Oh, yes, I...
SaIut.
Oh shit. Ali?
-Meeting Sarah has heIped me.
-Wanker!
He should be here, not me!
Other boyfriends
whiIst AIi's been away?
No other man
has touched me aII these years.
-What?
-I waited for him.
AIi, do you beIieve that
you are the AIi that died in 1948?
I don't know if I beIieve
in reincarnation to be honest.
But I beIieve in second chance.
We'd aII Iike to beIieve in a second
chance in our Iife.
What about going to
Luxor on a Nile cruise?
And then we fly to Alexandria?
-What do you think?
-Luxor.
That would be wonderful.
l could show you
where we used to live.
Something better.
Go to Cairo first...
And then Luxor fortwo weeks.
Sounds good too, no?
Sarah?
For as much as it hath pleased
Almighty God of his great mercy...
to take unto Himself the soul of our
dear sister Sarah here departed.
We therefore commit
her body to the ground,
earth to earth,
ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
ln sure and certain hope of
the resurrection to eternal life,
through our Lord Jesus Christ,
who shall change our vile body,
that it may be like
unto His glorious body.
l'm getting divorced
next week. Finally.
And then in September
l'm going to drama school.
l always thought
l had a flare for drama.
l wanna do it right this time, Ali.
What about you?
l've got everything
l was running after.
A big house, a visa, a proper
commission for my next project.
But l, l really want to go
to Egypt for a little while.
l'm missing my family so badly.
All the time l've been here,
l was trying to escape what l am.
And Sarah,
waited because she loved it.
Shall we all go and eat somewhere?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, l could eat something.
-Spanish?
-How about Egyptian?
This script is dedicated
to my beIoved wife Sarah.
Hi.
l came to see the room.
Oh yes, sorry. l completely forgot.
What a beautiful view.
l love the room.
-Have we met before?
-l don't think so.
You look so familiar.
That's a lovely picture.
l was baking a cake.
-Will you take some with me?
-l'd love to.
-lt's very good.
-Thank you. My wife taught me.
-Are you married?
-Oh, l was. But my wife is dead now.
l'm sorry.
You're a writer, aren't you?
How did you know?
Sorry, l forget to introduce myself.
My name is Ali.
And my name's Sarah.
This is so good.
You must have known l was coming.
Sorry?
lt's a funny song
my parents used to sing.
lf l knew you were coming
l'd have baked a cake.
Baked a cake. Baked a cake.
Yes. l knew you would be coming.