A prima ballerina
is a ballet dancer,
the chief ballet dancer,
the most important dancer of all,
who dances all by herself.
The marvellous, mechanical
prima ballerina.
Morning. Morning.
Anybody for Mass this morning?
Mass? No?
Do you want to go to Mass?
The toilet?
Try this.
First line?
A? B? C? C.
First line? Second... CA?
First line? Second line? First line?
Cab?
First line? Second line?
Look at these, aren't they beautiful?
Cable?
Oh, my God.
Jesus. Annie! Annie!
Bagpuss gave a big yawn
and settled down to sleep.
Hello, Rory.
My name is Eileen Sheehy.
I hope you're at home with us
here at Carrigmore.
- Do I get a front-door key?
- We don't give front-door keys out.
It's not home then, is it?
Hello, everybody.
We have Rory O'Shea,
who's come to live with us for a while.
Now, just introduce yourself, Rory.
Rory O'Shea.
Duchenne muscular dystrophy.
Besides the full vocal range,
I have the use of two fingers,
sufficient for self-propulsion
and self-abuse.
Shake my hand or kiss my arse,
but don't expect me to reciprocate.
We don't tolerate
coarse language here, Rory.
Is it always this much fun,
or is today's somebody's birthday?
Was the penthouse not available?
This is the only room.
People are queuing to get in.
And dying to get out.
I suppose it's only
a temporary arrangement.
Would you like
to go to bed now, Michael?
- Well?
- Not at all.
- What?
- Not a whisper.
- Is Dexter ill today?
- Dexter's in school.
I'm afraid he's not, Miss Fishborne.
Dexter's truancy problem
is way out of hand.
The Baltimore County School Board
have decided to expel Dexter
from the entire public school system.
All right.
Rory, you can't play loud music
in the middle of the night.
Have you no respect for the others?
They haven't earned my respect.
That's my music.
That's my fucking music!
I need to listen to that!
If you continue this behaviour
I'll have to take this.
I'm getting my own home soon anyway.
Until you do, you're here, OK?
And there are rules here.
Aggression. Shouting.
Singing in the middle of the night? No!
Have you no consideration
for other people?
If they can hear me, at least
they know they're fucking alive.
If you're alive, shout! Shout if you're
alive! Free the Carrigmore fucking One.
Somebody shout!
She's stolen my stereo! It's robbery!
Are you going to paint something, Rory?
Give us that.
Finished.
What are you looking at, Mary?
My Swahili's a bit off the boil.
Do you speak any English?
Use your card, for Christ's sake!
I'll take that.
It's got the alphabet on it.
He spells out words.
- Does it take long?
- Half the fucking day.
- Language, Tommy.
- Are you worth it?
Are you worth the effort?
Is there a mind in there?
Cerebral palsy. Fucks your brain.
- Don't expect Einstein.
- You'd be Stephen Hawking then?
There's nothing wrong with my brain.
It's the rest of me that's bollocksed.
Ran my bike into a tree.
Is that your most
intelligent act to date?
Fuck off, the pair of you.
You all right?
We've got to take your measurement for
the sleep system we were talking about.
I'm going to try to get you
as straight as possible.
Just relax.
Just try to relax there. OK?
So left side, 40.
- 44.
Yeah.
Right side, 39.
49.
You all right, Michael?
- How are yous?
- Are you looking for something, Rory?
Nah.
Are you enjoying that?
You're all right.
Do you want me to get your card?
I'll get your card.
It's all right,
he just wants me to go away.
He says I'm driving him up the wall.
Love to see you try that one, Mary.
- Did you understand what he said?
- Yeah.
OK, smart boy, guess who this is.
Strict rules of golf, Goldfinger.
- Emperor Hirohito of Japan.
- Emperor...
It's Roger Moore, you dope.
Here, I've a good one for you.
Who am I being now?
Er, don't know, Tommy,
who are you being now?
Michael Connolly.
How are you, Michael?
Er, yeah, I can understand you.
How?
I spent six years in a class
next to a kid
that makes you sound like
Laurence fucking Olivier.
What's he say now?
I think he said you were a prick.
Ah, fuck off, the pair of yous.
Look at you.
Will I tell...
Will I tell people what you say
with my gift?
- My gift.
- Would you like your bath now?
Only if you wash my gift.
My gift.
I'll give you a fucking gift.
Annie, my hair gel's in the bag.
Sorry, Mrs Sheehy says we haven't the
time to tease those spikes every day.
Mary. Look what that bitch Delilah's
done to me.
What are you laughing at?
Not too much.
Are you listening to me?
Start with the back of the head.
You should think about
sprucing your image up a bit, Mary.
It's all about looks these days.
Who buys your clothes for you?
Annie?
Jesus. Have you ever
looked at what she wears?
Do you not go and shop for yourself?
I suppose you don't get out much,
do you?
What's out there?
Out there is out there.
I should be out there.
Don't you want to be like everyone else?
You know, get drunk...
...get arrested, get laid.
Huh?
How long you been living
in places like this?
All your life?
What crime did you commit?
Unarmed robbery?
Bit of a comedian,
are we, Mary?
Bottle of ketchup. An onion.
Eileen.
See you've had your hair done as well.
Fashion's a cruel mistress.
- Very cosy, Son.
- It'll do for now.
Hey, come and meet my friend.
Dad, this is Hugh Grant.
Pleased to meet you, Hugh.
How you doing?
He says he likes your hat.
- It's funny you mention this hat.
- Dad.
This is a fine, big room
you have here, Hugh.
Fair play to you.
Oh, they're lovely.
Did you do them yourself?
Dad, are you coming for a cup of tea?
Right, Son. See you later, Hugh.
Nice fella.
- Did you see them on Wednesday?
- Nah.
They don't have cable here.
- I watched it in Mullins.
- Did you, yeah?
They're very leaky at the back.
And they've no width. None at all.
This is better than the last place.
They're all the same.
- How's your breathing?
- In and out.
- If you wanted to come home...
- I'm all right, Dad.
- It'd be no trouble.
- I'm all right.
Dad.
Couldn't lend us some money,
could you?
I want to buy a suit.
My dad?
Did you have a good look at him?
He can barely look after himself.
What about you?
Where are your parents?
Fergus Connolly.
Is that your dad?
Does he come to see you?
And your mother?
She died and he dumped you?
What a bastard.
Does he know he has a secret fan club?
Go on! Help the poor unfortunates.
Earn your place in heaven.
You buy a cripple a Harley Davidson
you reduce the dependant population.
Hey, how are you, love?
How are you?
Give us some money.
You've got lovely legs.
Hey, get your eyes off her.
I saw her first.
- You filthy mongrel.
- Thanks a lot.
I've had more girlfriends
than you've had speech therapy sessions.
I'm not exactly built
for long-term relationships.
Anyhow, what about you?
Have you ever had your end away?
Saving yourself
for the big wedding night, are you?
Very romantic, Michael.
Thank you.
Follow me.
I'll show you some real romance.
Here, this'll do.
See anyone you fancy?
Over there.
Keep your mouth shut.
I'll do the talking.
Congratulations, you've been chosen
cripple companions of the month.
I'm Rory, this is Michael, and we come
bearing treasure in our laps.
- I've got a badge already.
- Here's the deal.
We buy the drinks, you hold them for us.
How does that sound?
- Sounds all right.
- Excellent. Take it out of this.
No. It's for funding
the needs of the disabled.
I'm disabled and I need a drink.
Life is dishonest, Michael.
There you go.
Thanks.
We're in a show.
He sings, I dance.
- I don't believe you.
- You better.
- What's it about?
- These two guys in wheelchairs.
They're not much to look at.
My character is quite handsome.
And they go to a pub
and meet these two girls.
And they kiss them.
And the girls fall in love with them.
- And they take them home.
- Thanks, lads. We have to go.
I want to hear the end of the story.
- This is the end of the story.
- I'm just getting to the good bit.
I can't go anywhere. I'm blocked.
I can barely stand up.
You can't be as bad as us,
we're legless.
Hey, do you like that?
There's more where that came from.
- You've lovely eyes.
- They're my second-best feature.
Night.
See ya.
What did I tell ya? Eh?
Same again?
- Oh.
- Watch where you're going.
You're all right, none of it went on me.
If I was in a wheelchair,
I wouldn't look for trouble?
You starting?
His mother sucks what?
Come here, you prick.
You bastard.
Picking on a fella in a wheelchair?!
Fuck it.
- He's not worth it. You're right.
- That's not what your girlfriend said.
Stop it. If he'd hit you in the mouth
you'd have nothing that works.
I have a part or two below that might,
given the right stimulus.
He wants to know your name.
- Siobhan.
- He's Michael. I'm Trouble.
- Yeah, I can see that.
- Listen, Siobhan.
Could you help a poor cripple
out of a predicament?
Depends on the predicament.
I need someone to unzip my pants
and direct the hose.
Michael wants to go home.
- That isn't what I had in mind.
- Your mind isn't difficult to read.
Hey. What you doing tomorrow night?
Staying out of trouble.
So should you.
Where's the fun in that?
We'd never have met you.
Beautiful? Yes, she is.
- Hey, girls.
- I love your dress.
How are yous?
Sorry, lads.
McGuvan's, round to the right.
- We've come to boogie.
- Not with them boots, you're not.
Is that the club talking or is that you?
Hey. On this door, I am the club.
Is he all right?
He says you're in breach
of EU Directive 739, Section 6B.
Discrimination against
persons with disability.
In places of public entertainment.
It's a 2,000 euro fine.
Payable by the official denying entry.
That's you, pal.
How are you, Garda?
Look, I don't want
any trouble from the law.
You just bought yourself a load.
My friend is a barrister.
Did you just make that up?
You little legal genius.
Right. Inside. But remember for future
reference, wheelchair night's Monday.
Keep by the fucking wall.
Come on, Michael. Yeah!
Whoo!
Whoo! Whoo!
Come on, come and dance with me.
Sure it's dancing!
What do you think I'm doing inside?
Whoo!
Look who it is.
Come on, Michael! Yes!
Are you OK?
Well, piss faster.
Yeah.
I was wet anyway.
Have we got enough money for a taxi?
I'm sorry, Eileen, I told Michael
we should be getting back here,
that you'd be worried about us,
but he insisted that we stay.
That's what I heard, Michael.
Let's face it, you're not that easy
to understand sometimes.
You have to agree, Eileen.
The collection had to be abandoned
because of you.
And as for you, Michael...
...I am just so disappointed in you.
You have never been any trouble before.
It was my fault, Eileen.
I led him astray,
and I've disgraced myself.
Oh, yes, you have.
So if you just change my underpants,
we'll say no more about it.
So er... I'm going out.
Yeah, of course you can come.
Do you possess a suit?
Rory O'Shea.
Hello again, Rory.
This is Michael Connolly.
He's my lawyer.
Oh, right.
OK, this is your third application
for the independent living allowance.
Your previous applications
were refused on the grounds
that you were unsuited
for self-regulation
and lacking responsibility
for the employment of others.
Would you tell us what's changed
since your last application?
Er, well, I... I'm learning
that I have a lot of energy.
And I'm coming to terms
with learning to control that energy
and use it for...
constructive, productive purposes.
And I think that's progress.
Yeah, I... I think that's progress.
Er, Rory...
you know our funds are very limited.
Yeah.
And er... we have to disperse them
in the wisest way possible.
- Mm-hm.
- OK.
Now I'm afraid that
we've heard a story
concerning the mishandling
of some collection money.
Rory, it's just this scheme demands
a level of maturity and responsibility
from its candidates.
Don't lecture me about maturity.
I'm not a fucking cheese.
We're not sure independent
living is the best choice for you.
Choice?
Is this an application
or has a choice already been made?
Can I suggest we meet again
in six months to review the situation?
Under EU Directive 5096...
...discrimination against...
- I'm not sure I know that directive.
It means you have to do what I say.
Or it's a 2,000 euro fine, isn't it?
Isn't it?
It's a 15,000 euro fine.
All I'm asking for is the chance
to live in my own home.
- Are we agreed on six months?
- Six months!
Six months, Rory, it's not that long.
Some fucking lawyer you are!
Open the door!
Leave me alone.
It's not OK. I have to get out of here!
I'm going to fucking die!
Lovely to see everyone here
enjoying themselves.
Hi, Annie.
One false move and I'm yours.
Sing this one. Here we go.
Have I done something
to make you unhappy here?
No?
Independent living isn't for everyone.
You certainly won't get the
level of care you're used to here.
If anything should happen to you,
God forbid, I won't be there.
I'm appealing
because I am a marked man.
- Slow down.
- I can't. Type faster.
You've rejected my application
three times
on the word of interfering,
dried-up bitches
that wouldn't know responsibility
if it bit their fat arses.
- Do you want to rethink that phrasing?
- Yeah, it needs to be punchier.
Now type it.
Hey, it's Judge Mumbles.
What you after?
- Michael Connolly.
- Ah, Michael, come in.
Rory. Erm...
If you don't mind, it's
Michael's application we're hearing.
You'll hear it. You won't understand it.
Rory, can you wait outside, please?
Between us we've enough experience
of applicants with speech difficulties
to be able to manage without you.
Thanks, Rasheen.
Now, Michael, the purpose of this chat
is to assess what you believe
the philosophy to be
behind independent living.
"Independent living allows me
to grow and mature as a person."
"It helps me fulfil
the potential within myself...
...which is not always realised
by institutional living."
"It opens the way for me
to make a real contribution...
...and to live a fuller life."
Thank you, that's a very good answer.
Michael, you appreciate that
we will pay for a personal assistant,
but you need to find accommodation.
Have you found somewhere?
OK, well, in that case, I think
we can approve your application.
There is just one concern.
Your decision not to use speech aids.
Will that not make things harder
in the long run?
"I don't need speech aids...
...as I will have
a full-time, live-in interpreter."
I'm sorry. Who?
"Rory O'Shea."
Two for the price of one.
I'm out! Can you hear me? I'm out!
You hear that? I'm out!
How did you come up with those answers?
You read their brochure?
You read their brochure back to them?
That's genius!
All we need to do now is get a flat.
How much?
And also, the neighbours are very nice.
- Are they quiet?
- Very quiet.
You're really going to like this.
Hey. Hey!
There's a bit of a problem.
Can you guess what it is?
It's a shame.
You would have loved the view.
400 a month.
Yeah, that's a two-bedroom flat,
city centre, yeah?
Excellent. What's that?
400 a week?
Right, we'll have a think about it
and get back to you.
All right, bye-bye.
Listen, Michael, do you really
want to leave Carrigmore?
Would you be prepared
to do anything you could?
- Fergus Connolly?
- Just in there.
- Can I help you?
- Michael Connolly for Fergus Connolly.
- Do you have an appointment?
- He does, but he's late.
- What time was it for?
- Er... 1981.
- Traffic was murder.
- I'm sorry, Mr Connolly is not here.
Really?
- Fergus Connolly! Fergus Connolly!
- Guard.
I'm sorry, gentlemen,
I'm going to ask you to leave.
They're causing a disturbance.
Fergus, it's lovely to meet you.
I'm Rory O'Shea.
This is Michael Connolly.
We've come to report
a blatant case of criminal neglect.
It's all right, guard, I'll handle this.
Thanks.
Come on in.
George, I'll see you later in Nesbits.
Bye-bye. Seven o'clock.
It's a nice room.
- What do you want?
- Try asking him.
Go on, he's waiting for you.
He thinks you have
nothing in your head.
Tell him.
He's shy.
And he's proud.
Michael didn't even
want to come here today.
For some reason
he thought it was demeaning
to seek out the gobshite
that flushed him at birth.
I had to persuade him.
What do you need from me?
Ground-floor flat, two bedrooms,
wheelchair access.
Michael needs a home.
What then?
You'll get what you had
before we came in.
OK.
It wasn't planned
as a joyful family reunion.
We went there to blackmail
the bastard. Mission accomplished.
We got a home out of it.
Somewhere we can live.
You'd better take it,
or we're both fucked.
Trust me, Michael.
It'll be worth it.
Right, lads, there yous are.
Come on in now till I show you.
Ah. Ah, this is amazing.
- This is amazing.
- Bedroom number one.
This one's mine! This one's mine!
Shower. The whole shebang.
Kitchen.
Lefty.
There you are, all mod cons for you.
A few bits and pieces still to go in.
And the living room.
Lovely colours.
Now, the lighting
can be voice activated.
This switch here if you want to use it.
On!
Off!
Right, well, if there's nothing else,
I'll leave the keys with you, boys.
Right?
Lefty. Lefty!
Is that my paper?
No rules.
No rules, no Delilah.
No interfering old bitches.
Just you and me in cripple heaven.
Freedom!
So after 16 years' military service
I felt a change was required.
I want to do some humanitarian work.
Could you straighten up
while I'm talking to you?
Well now, aren't you great lads
for giving this a bash?
Trying it on your own. Why not?
Jesus loves you, Michael.
Jesus loves you, Rory.
My work with you people
would be an expression of that love.
Will I have to push
you two around all day?
Spaghetti bolognese, that sort
of thing. I've a recipe for that.
...cookies.
We'll have a great laugh.
I'm great fun to be around.
Do yous ever dress up?
I mean, as animals, or whatever.
No.
Not really.
- We could though, if...
- No, I have a real problem with that.
Jesus, there's no way
he's working for us.
You know when something
just makes you feel sick?
What you doing?
Siobhan, have you not done
the Pot Noodles yet? Get a move on.
How are you?
No. I'm not qualified.
You have the best qualifications
we've seen in a long time.
- Really?
- Definitely.
- I already have a job.
- Yeah, you do, stacking shelves.
It's temporary.
- Who would I be working for?
- Me.
Him. Me and him.
Come on, we'd be no trouble.
He can hardly talk
and I'm pretty quiet myself.
Oh, Jesus, I don't know.
- I've never done anything like this.
- Excellent. Neither have we.
We're fucking off.
The pair of us.
With her?
Good man.
See yous.
Hey, Delilah,
we've paid our debt to society,
we've learned our lesson,
you won't be seeing us back.
Michael, a little something for you.
And you know that if things don't work
out for you you're always welcome here.
Goodbye, Michael.
Goodbye, Rory.
I know we haven't always
gotten along, Eileen,
and if I've said anything
to offend you at any time...
...then er... then good.
It'll all end in tears.
Bye, Michael. Bye, Rory.
- Hey, this is all right.
- Yeah. It's bigger than it looks.
- Where'll I put this?
- Stick it in there on my bed.
- They've delivered the telly.
- That's a big bed for a little man.
- Raging Speed Horn?
- Yeah, stick it on and make some tea.
Oh, champagne. Fantastic.
All right. Siobhan, we'll have some
goat's cheese, some Casher Blue,
some St Brendan brie
and some of the holy Swiss stuff.
Is that foie gras? Excuse me,
is that...? We'll have some foie gras.
We'll have some venison paté.
We will have some truffles.
There you are.
That's 415.28 euros, please.
Yeah, definitely,
this spicy one's really good.
Michael, you should try this one.
Who the fuck...?
- OK, you all right?
- Just got to lift it up now.
- Come on.
- OK. You're comfortable?
- Yeah, yeah.
- OK.
- You're doing good.
- Are you being sarcastic? Fuck you.
You all right?
Oh, wait, I'll be back in a minute.
What? Siobhan.
OK, I've got it.
OK?
Oh! Fuck! Shit! Bollocks!
Yes?
Do you have a boyfriend?
Er, I used to.
- Did I what?
- Did you love him?
Yeah.
Did you want to marry him?
I never really thought about it.
Come on, now,
did he break your little heart?
- Do you want to go under a bus?
- Do you want to go under a wheelchair?
Yeah, shut up, Rory.
Here, listen to this.
I really like this song.
- Can I ask you something?
- Mm-hm.
Were you born like this?
- Like what?
- Dodgy hair and shit taste in music.
No. No, that's something
I've had to work long and hard at.
Will I do your hair?
Mister. Are you a goblin?
No, I'm not a fucking goblin.
- Is that an electric chair?
- Yeah.
Bet you it's not as fast as my scooter.
How much money have you got?
It's important there's no cheating.
Nobody go till I say go. All right?
Ready, steady, go.
Get your hands in your pockets.
Come on!
- Come on!
Battery!
- How could you lose that?
- You should have won that.
- You cheated.
- And we still beat you.
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
Next time, babyface.
- Compound.
- Go again.
Hello?
Beast.
Siobhan.
Am I hibernating?
Is this me till spring?
What is that? I'll be there in a minute.
All right. I'll make myself a cup of tea
while I'm waiting.
If you like.
Rory, can you turn it down?
We can't hear ourselves think.
What do you have to think about?
Hey, hey, hey.
This is my room, that's my music and
I want to listen to it. Turn it back on.
This may be your room, but it's
his flat. We need to have some rules.
- Rules? Fuck your rules.
- God, he's a moody bollocks, isn't he?
- I won't have you imposing rules on me.
- What? He's the best?
- Michael, tell her to come back here.
- I better go and sort him out.
Siobhan!
- What?
- It's not your job to make rules.
Your job's to do what we tell you to do.
I do the interpreting. You do the
cleaning, make the tea and cleaning up.
You are our servant, Siobhan.
Our skiwy.
Our slave.
Will you shut up,
or do I have to make you?
I'd like to see you try.
Just remember, you're a servant too.
Mr Interpreter.
OK, where were we?
Will you hold that, Michael?
I'll be back in a minute.
What's the matter with you?
Did you get a hard-on?
Come on. What did she do?
Ho! Did you see that, Michael?
That was life passing you by.
Come on, let's go out.
You're waiting for Siobhan? What for?
What you going to do, sit in here
and have her do everything for you?
Come on, let's go out.
Fine. See you later.
You know what you're doing?
You're building a little Carrigmore
for yourself.
You looking for your friend?
He'll be back in a minute.
- You fuck!
- Out of the car.
- I'm a cripple.
- You'll be a cripple tonight if...
Look, that's my chair.
Careful! It's my fucking chair!
I'll erm...
Who's in charge of you?
Hey, shut...
No fucker's in charge of me!
Put him back in his chair.
Get this car out of here.
- Aren't you going to arrest me?
- No.
That's discrimination. You're only
doing that because I'm disabled.
- It's my civil right to be arrested.
- Look, just...
Name and address.
We'll leave it at that, right?
You'll have to kick it out of me,
you bastard.
Hey.
What?
Rory's a what?
- Hi.
- Yeah?
I'm here for Rory O'Shea.
He's in a wheelchair.
Him? We let him go
about half an hour ago.
Oh, what?
I offered to take him home
but he wouldn't come.
- Did he say where he was going?
- No.
Hey. Hey!
You little fucking shit,
give me my hat back.
- Come and get it.
- Give me my hat or I'll kill you.
Come on or I'll run you over,
you little...
- You have to catch me. Come and get it.
- Fuck! Hey!
Come here!
Thanks for the hat.
This is the midnight news
from Lorne O'Brian.
Six armed nationals
were in custody tonight following...
Do you want some more tea?
Rory O'Shea, in the house.
Where were you?
Michael was worried sick about you.
Were you worried about me, Michael?
Escaping from jail.
I was down to go at 11.30. I'm not
charging you, but I have my own life.
And I haven't?
- That's not what I meant.
- It wasn't her fault?
Your knight in shining pyjamas
says I have to leave you alone.
Five minutes. I can either get you ready
for bed or you can slag the both of us.
- Up to you, but...
- Come back, Delilah, all is forgiven.
Don't you lecture me
about responsibility.
If it wasn't for me you'd be sitting
in your own shite in Carrigmore
spelling out "toilet" on that card.
- Don't say that.
- Don't tell me what to do.
I don't want your help.
I don't want anyone's help.
Rory.
What?
No.
She's not on our side.
She's paid to do what we tell her to do.
Well, I really like her.
A lot.
Oh, Michael, man.
You haven't told her how you feel,
have you?
Help you?
Help you what?
Help you make a prick of yourself?
What have you got to offer
a woman like that?
Cop on to yourself.
Get a tape recorder
and fucking listen to yourself.
Stop for a minute
and take a look at yourself in a mirror.
You boys really need some new clothes.
Thank you.
How are you, Hugh?
Hello there.
- Might be a bit early for this.
- Jesus, never too early, Dad.
In you get.
Fair play to you.
A place of your own.
It's not really mine, Dad.
Happy birthday, Son.
The key to the door.
- What have I told you?
- Listen, Son...
Dad...
Congratulations. Well done.
It's all gone so quickly.
And I wish I could help.
Siobhan. Hey.
You look great. How's it going?
- Great, yeah.
- Great.
This is Michael. Declan.
Great. Look, I'm having a party
on Saturday night.
It's fancy dress. You should come.
I dunno, I've...
You want to go?
Great. I got to go,
but I'll see you around nine.
- And the doorbell's broken.
- I know.
Oh, there's another fella.
Bring him along. The more the merrier.
Hey, a party.
- Ho!
- Hello, Dr Strangelove.
Are you sure that's what
Florence Nightingale wore?
Who cares?
- Ho, ho.
- Hello.
- Doesn't he look handsome?
- He looks great.
Be careful.
Someone might think
tonight's their lucky night.
Siobhan. Great to see you.
Michael, fair play to you.
- This is Rory.
- How you doing? Having a good time?
- Yeah, great party...
- Come on.
Who's the prick?
...this is the war room.
- That's a very good impression.
- I love Peter Sellers.
Michael.
He plays Chauncey Gardener
or something like that.
Come on.
Fancy a go at the karaoke, Michael?
What did he say?
Of course I will.
Don't tread on my feet.
- Who's your man?
- She looks after him.
No, no.
Michael.
Sorry. I'm really sorry.
- I'm fine.
- You sure?
Is your phone charged?
I'll say good night then.
I love you.
I'm sorry, Michael, but...
"Do you have any feelings for me?"
Michael, I'm paid
to do what I do for you.
That's my job.
That isn't love. And what you
feel for me, that isn't love either.
It's gratitude.
I like working for you, but...
...it is just a job.
There isn't anything else going on here,
Michael, do you understand?
There isn't anything else going on.
I'm not hungry.
This is Peter. He's a qualified PA.
He'll be looking after you
until you find someone else.
Really? Well, he won't do.
Michael likes them with bigger tits.
Michael, I made a mistake.
I thought I could do this, but...
I'm leaving.
Don't beg, it's undignified.
Parakeets don't mate with armadillos,
that's the end of it.
- That's a filthy thing to tell him.
- Is it?
- It's the truth.
- Oh, it's the truth you want? OK.
To be equal you must show
the same respect you demand.
If you insult some guy in the pub,
you expect to get hammered.
If you come home late
you don't expect the help to be waiting.
If a woman says no, you accept
you're not the right man for her.
You don't have a right to love
because you're in a wheelchair.
Siobhan. You said you were going,
I think you should go.
- Fuck off. I mean it.
- Your disability is you're an arsehole.
Why does everything
always have to be a fight with you?
I can't help who I love.
I can't help who I don't love.
It's not my fault, Michael.
Let her go.
Michael, let her go.
Where you going?
This is your home, Michael.
Michael.
Are you going back to Carrigmore?
It's suicide. I don't have time
to kill myself that slowly,
so if you're going back I might as well
throw myself in this river.
You didn't fuck it up. We fucked it up.
The pair of us. Nobody did it for us.
I know it hurts.
You're not the only one
with a broken heart.
You have the future, Michael.
That's what I call a gift.
Don't give it up.
You can't give it up.
Shit, you've got the whole world
in your hands.
You're fucking wet as well.
Our home?
Or am I going in the fucking river?
Yeah, it is too high.
Take a letter, Michael.
To Dublin City Council.
Dear sir or madam, as wheelchair users
with suicidal intentions,
I must protest
at the lack of facilities.
None of the bridges are equipped
with easy parapet access.
Thus curtailing the rights
of the disabled to throw themselves in.
Yours in disgust, Rory Gerard O'Shea
and Michael Connolly.
Keep going, tell them.
Do you like to study?
Maybe you ought to
go to college some day.
Part time or something like that.
University? At home? That would be good.
Me, I'd like to study medicine.
Yap, yap, yap.
Guys. You have a nice home here,
you know.
But you shouldn't watch
too much TV, yeah?
It's bad for the mind,
and bad for the eyesight.
Why don't we go for a walk?
It's a beautiful day.
Maybe later.
We're not keeping him, are we?
I'm just going to get some coffee.
You want one?
OK. I'll be back soon.
Are you Michael?
Your friend's very ill.
He has pneumonia.
His heart and lung muscles
are severely affected.
Are you asking me if you can go in?
He's very weak.
Better to let him rest this evening.
I'm sorry, I can't understand you.
How long?
Probably not more than a day or two.
It varies a little bit with Duchenne.
But it's usually around his age.
He'll have known that this was coming.
He's not in any pain. He won't suffer.
He wants to talk to you.
There you are.
I've been worried about you.
Look at all this.
You see.
Rory... O'Shea...
...was here.
Rory O'Shea...
is... here.
Michael...
You need...
...nobody.
You're...
your own... man.
Did you bring...
...my stereo?
I never...
...liked you.
Hi.
We know about Rory's condition. We
appreciate you want to help your friend.
Is now the right time for this?
Why did you come here today?
"I'm his lawyer."
Right, if you want to... erm...
Rory's application for personal
assistance was turned down
on the grounds of
insufficient responsibility.
The grounds for appeal
are given as prejudice.
Would you like to explain why Rory feels
the interviewing panel showed prejudice?
"When I first met Rory...
...I thought he was trouble."
"And I was right."
"He is trouble."
"Yet because he's seen as a rebel...
...you believe he hasn't the
responsibility to live independently."
"But how do you learn
to be responsible?"
"You live in the world."
"You make your own decisions."
"You make your own mistakes."
"So if this panel can offer independent
living to someone like me...
...who until recently
had no concept of what that meant...
...and refuse someone who's very life
is an embodiment of independence...
...then I believe
the panel showed a prejudice."
Michael, I think we're all aware
of Rory's prognosis.
What was your purpose
in coming here today?
"A right must exist
independently of its exercise."
OK. I think you can tell Rory
that in principle...
...he can have the service
he's applied for.
Thank you.
Do not count his deeds
against him.
For in his heart,
he desired to do your work.
As his fate united him
to your people on Earth,
so may your mercy
join him with the angels in heaven.
- We ask this through Christ, our Lord.
- Amen.
Eternal rest grant unto Rory, oh Lord.
- May he rest in peace.
- Amen.
May his soul, and the souls
of all the faithful departed,
through the mercy of God, rest in peace.
You all right?
Can I do anything for you?
Thank you.
Are we going out?
OK.