Presents
a film by
ROSE'S  SONGS
based on a real story
cast
photographed by
Who's Chaliapin?
What was that?
- Did you hear it? - Something got
knocked over in Mr. Rose's flat.
Dad's up there.
Who's Chaliapin?
Mr. Rose's friend.
An opera singer, too.
Russian.
When the war's over, you can fetch
Granny's old mirror. All right?
- All right.
- Come here...
You know he must eat,
or he won't sing.
Come on, put that cricket down.
Come and
try it on...
You'll sew one for Dad, too?
Of course,
I will.
We have to.
- Where's the salt?
- The salt?
Where do you think?
In the kitchen.
- Is that all?
- Why? Isn't that enough?
Ask Mrs. Bödõ then.
What do you think?
- Crap.
- Tomi, you mustn't say
such words.
Dad wants to take
a picture of you before you go.
What, with this?
We're late. I'll just take
the salt up to lmre.
Yes, with this.
- But it's such cra...
- Hush, I don't want to hear.
Now, off you go. The girls can't
wait to see your school report.
- I bet they can't.
- Can't they?
Go on, clever clogs.
Don't keep Dad waiting.
But give me his coat first.
Off you go!
Right a bit.
Stay there.
Come back.
You're too far away.
Come closer. Closer.
Hello.
I'm Mr. Waltz,
this is my family.
Good morning.
How do you do.
I'm Géza Halász.
I'm sorry to disturb you
Mr. Halász.
We're looking for Mr. Rose's villa.
Is this it?
Yes, this is it.
I'm a friend of lmre's.
Pleased to meet you.
Please tell Mr. Rose that
Waltz is here.
He knows about us.
Do come in, please
Mr. Waltz.
Mr. Rose always said
we could turn to him
if we needed help.
I never thought that
one day we'd have to.
We too are only guests -
for a year now. Since
I lost my job.
But, you know,
three kids are three kids. Imre's
gone up to the tower room to avoid them.
Well, children will
always be children.
Since March he hasn't even
come down to eat. Locked himself in.
I take him food and
clean clothes.
- Then I think we'd better go.
- No, no. You misunderstand me.
It'll all be fine.
Only I can't promise
lmre will come out of hiding.
Of course.
One must make allowances for
such a great artist.
Come on. My wife will help you
make yourselves at home.
- Hello.
I had to come, Mr. Halász.
My mistress had to go
to the countryside.
Come in, Maggie.
Can I help?
Don't call me Maggie, please.
It sounds so common.
Of course, you've told me before.
Won't happen again,
Miss Magda.
Oh, come now.
Don't...
Tomi and I are just off
to the school.
Get going then...
Where will I find Gran?
She was in the pantry
a minute ago.
- Thanks.
- Let's go.
Bye, Tomi.
- Good morning, Mr. Halász.
- Julo, your mum's
looking for you.
I'll be off then.
Have you seen my old man?
- No.
- I'll find him somewhere.
You know: "Matter is never lost,
only transformed". Who said that?
- Lavoisier?
- Yes! Lavoisier.
"Matter is never lost,
only transformed."
Let's hurry now, or we'll
never get that school report.
- No. No.
- Let's go!
I know he's a good lad, sweetheart.
But that's how it is these days.
Believe me, both Dad and I,
we only want the best for you.
- But we hardly ever meet.
- Even hardly ever is too much.
- Try to understand...
- What?
That it's best for everyone
if you don't meet for a while.
- But why? Why, mum?
- Because we're Jews,
and he is not.
He'll understand.
He's a bright boy.
I beg your pardon...
Tell your filthy brat to stop it!
Did you address me?
- Well, who else?
- Do we know each other?
I don't know any Jews!
Look! He's still making faces!
He is only seeing
how strong his lungs are.
How long he can hold his breath.
I gave him a watch
for his good school report...
Now he's experimenting...
It's not that bad, is it?
Making his Hungarian jacket dirty!
Pardon?
Take that star off!
But, Madam, it's compulsory
for us from today...
Compulsory?
Like stealing,
I suppose?
That's compulsory for you lot,
too, isn't it?
Hitler'll see to the likes of you.
He knows what to do with you!
These soldiers are not here to see
to us... There's a war on,
Madam.
They'll turn you into soap!
And your filthy Jewish brat, too!
Then that was from
a cake of soap, Madam.
He hit me! Did you see? He hit me!
The filthy Jew!
Do something!
Did you see?
Stop!
You bastard!
Catch him!
Stop him!
You bastard!
I'm very proud of you.
What did you do in town?
Did Dad take you to eat cakes
with that nice Auntie Olga?
I put the Waltzes in the ironing
room. I thought I'd tell lmre.
I knocked, but he didn't
even answer.
He doesn't like to be disturbed,
I've told you.
- I only knocked.
- What are you doing?
I'm trying to make paper the colour
of this Bible's.
It's beautiful.
Whose is it?
Lmre gave it to me - to sell if we
need to. It's worth 1,000 pengõs.
Did you tell Skubala
to come in the morning?
And what shall we say to Father?
The first thing he'll do will be
- to look for lmre. - He'll understand.
Imre doesn't want to see anybody.
Have you been up to him?
Have you been?
He just lies and
looks at the ceiling...
And why does he need the salt?
For the smell of the sea.
But a whole sack?
He lies on it to feel the infinite.
And won't he ever practise again?
King of Rikitiki! He arrive in Europe!
Home of industrious peoples!
Julo a real lady.
Where's Tomi?
I not see.
Sarah! You see this?
Lmre's sworn that he's not coming out
until these rats have been
cleared out of Budapest.
What you telling me?
What you mean?
That you won't meet him, Father.
Bad! I understand!
Bad. Very bad.
I'm not sure yet.
Perhaps for your sake
I may be able to persuade him.
Sarah, you hear?
Rose no sing.
Nu, this is bad.
Very bad.
I bring his favourite tea.
Mr. Halász,
could I have a word with you?
Of course, coming. Have your
breakfast, I'll be back
in a minute.
Good day.
Thank you, my son.
Go home.
Tomi, where are you?
- He's always wandering off.
- You've grown a lot, my boy.
- Grandpa!
- Come, my boy.
Have you spoken to
the child, Mr. Halász?
If you mean Julo, then yes,
I have, Mr. Skubala.
They went cycling again yesterday.
They're fond of each other.
Arpad's a good lad.
Times have changed. Understand?
Don't worry. I understand.
Look, I'm not like that.
We're poor, very poor.
Just don't let the children meet.
Don't worry, they won't.
I give you my word.
- Now, if you'll excuse me.
- That's all I wanted.
All the best, Mr. Halász.
Give my regards to Mr. Rose.
I'll pass them on.
Pass the milk, please.
Here it is.
- All right.
- Just a little.
- Fine.
- Thanks.
Ugh!
That's not mine.
Sorry, I haven't unpacked
yours yet... I thought
this would do...
I'll go and get it.
Pour away, please.
Sloosht.
Nu, you read.
What be written there?
- Segesvár... 1849...
- Sarah's papa fought
in the battle there.
Read on.
- Lemberg, 1811.
- Lemberg.
Sarah's grandpa was there.
Zsuzsõ...
Give me bacon, please.
Mr. Skubala gave it to us.
The best type.
Father, have some bread with it,
you'll be sick.
Oh, Sarah, my dear wife.
Kosher is what's good.
How much longer will it last,
Mr. Halász?
The BBC says a month or two...
A month or two, a year, a century,
a thousand years...
but a single second is
enough to kill someone.
De Gaulle's already in Paris...
Imre heard it on the radio.
Would you tell Mr. Rose that we
miss his voice very much.
If only he would practise sometimes.
He's not even willing to talk.
One can still sing
without saying the words.
It's very important to us.
Please tell him.
I will.
Hello.
I can't believe it!
Girls! Where's the salt?
- I've asked you something.
- I don't know.
- I don't know
- Tomi, what's all this now?
- Nothing.
- He's always doing it.
Where can it be?
I don't understand where it's gone.
Lili, my dear, we've got guests.
Good morning.
I'm Olga Fehér,
Géza's colleague.
Good morning. I'm Lili.
You must have heard of me.
- Of course.
- This is my sister.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Hello. I'm Vera.
Please forgive us. Mr. Halász has
said many times to me, to us,
- that if there's trouble...
- The Arrow Cross broke into
our home at dawn.
They rounded up all the women
from the flats in the courtyard.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hello, Tomi.
We've met already, haven't we.
- Tomi, say hello properly, please.
- If we push this dresser
in the middle,
it will divide the kitchen,
- won't it.
- Of course...
It would divide it, my dear.
Mr. Rose doesn't even come down
any more - just sends messages.
I don't know what will
come of this.
These poor people wouldn't have
any shoes if you didn't
mend them for them.
Well... everything will be alright.
What is it,
did you hear something?
Listen to the other side, quick.
Hands up.
Don't disturb us, Géza.
Take it.
- What?
- Take my gun.
Nu, gun?!
Not broom?
As we practised.
Why he take it?
There not be another?
Ladies and Gentlemen!
See David's fight
with Goliath!
See the real man strike first!
Come on, Tomi!
Grab it!
You give it to him!
Our life depends on this, Father.
Nu, you know!
I no talk!
You do that! Do, do.
Tamás, come on!
As we agreed...
We'll spot the weakest...
- Move.
- Géza!
You can't be such a coward...
Come on, let's show them.
Strike first and win.
What are you?
A coward, a stinking little Jew...
Did you see your mother?
She's got strength!
Did you see her?
That's how to do it, my boy!
To dance, to dance.
If you're ordered to go
to the ghetto, then you've got to
go to the ghetto.
Like cattle to the slaughter house.
- It's not yet the slaughter house.
- Right. Only the entrance to it.
I'm not going to give them my life.
What if they come here?
Oh, Géza, what's this again?
A brace.
It was my father's in the war.
Just tell me what you're going to do?
They'll come here,
say we disobeyed their order and
line us up against the wall.
What happens then?
I'll leave you alone,
only tell me what you'll do
if they want to kill us.
What will you say then?
I'm so scared.
It's all right...
Don't be afraid. I'm here with you.
Leave me alone.
Do you think I don't know?
What don't you know, darling?
- That she's your lover.
- Who?
Olga!
Don't, Géza.
The kids are still awake.
And so is Mrs. Bödõ.
And Magda.
- What about them?
- They, too, are my lovers.
Didn't you know? And Mrs. Waltz.
So? Give me your hand.
I'm serious, Géza.
So am I. Come on.
Give me your hand.
Can't you think of
anything else?
What has that got to
do with things?
A lot. An awful lot.
You can't imagine.
- Ah...
- Good morning, Mrs. Bödõ.
Mr. Halász. You almost
gave me a heart attack.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
Can I help you?
I wanted to say something
to Mr. Rose.
He stayed up late.
He must be still asleep.
But I'm happy to help you
if I can.
Listen, Mrs. Bödõ.
We've got to talk about this.
What about a morning snifter?
I don't expect that, Mr. Halász.
What do you think of me?
Only the best, from what lmre tells me.
That Mrs. Bödõ is like a
mother to him!
- Mr. Rose always exaggerates.
- To your health!
- To Mr. Rose.
- So that he could always sing to us.
May he do so.
I know that nobody knows lmre
as well as you do.
1 August 1904. Forty years,
three months and nineteen days.
That's a lot even in marriage.
Well, that I don't know. I couldn't
even stand a year with my old man.
I gave him his marching orders.
He drank, the wretch.
And that caused his death,
as I heard.
Here I was in Budapest,
all alone, the child in my arms.
Mr. Rose took me in.
Got a heart of gold.
Never met anyone like him.
Imre's very ill. You know
he's an artist, his soul
can't bear these atrocities.
I know, only I thought
I'd ask him if he fancied
a little pigeon soup.
I always made some
when he was poorly.
Mr. Skubala's brought
a brace of pigeons.
Make him some.
I'll take it up to him.
Is there still salt in the larder?
Salt?
Aren't those two whole
sacks enough?
- Tomi, watch out!
- Faster! Even faster!
- Faster, faster!
- Father!
- No faster?
Ah, hello.
How are you?
- Hello.
- Coming for a walk?
- Very kind.
- We've come to say goodbye.
If you'll excuse us...
Goodbye? What goodbye?
What are all those cases?
We're leaving, Mr. Fischbaum.
We're going to the ghetto.
- But why?
- What are you doing, Mr. Waltz?
Oh, Mr. Halász,
I've told her we can't do that.
We're going to town.
Please, don't be angry.
We don't want to be
any trouble to anyone.
We're going to the ghetto.
Now? When the Arrow Cross are
everywhere?
We've made up our minds,
Mr. Halász.
And I? Then what shall I tell lmre?
What shall I tell?
That I let you walk out?
Lmre's a gentleman.
He will understand.
And your daughter?
Have you thought of her?
They won't let her get away,
that's for sure!
Well...
We'll try to be careful.
To be careful?
Look at yourselves,
I beg you.
- Oh, Mummy! Daddy!
- My darling, we simply don't
want to be any trouble to anyone.
Go back to your room, Mr. Waltz.
That'll be the best.
Go on. Please.
- Mrs. Bödõ. Come here, please.
- What's happening here, dear?
Don't ask me.
I don't know.
Mr. Halász must have said
something.
Nothing to me.
Only to open the dumbwaiter.
Four, three, two, one.
Do tell Mr. Rose that
I'm very angry why
he never sang this to me.
Tell him it all went very well.
Please, Mr. Halász,
pass on our gratitude.
For a few minutes he made us
feel like human beings again.
That's not nice.
Look,
like this.
- Shall we put some flowers
in the window? - Yes.
A beautiful flower.
And look what's here.
- A tiny little...
- Pussy.
Much better, isn't it.
Now you draw something.
Come on poppet, it's late.
Let's give Auntie Olga a break.
Here's your tea, Father.
I didn't ask for any.
All right.
Come on, poppet.
Thomas Halász? In person?
Stand in front of me, please.
What's the first law
of the table? Tell me.
Whosoever disturbs through
unjustified tardiness
the family's lunch or dinner,
or does not obey
their mother's instructions
shall for one whole day
be the family's servant.
Until they make amends
for their sins.
Sarah, you see this?
You bore me a Moses!
Dead simple.
In on the bell, out when I knock.
Wonderful.
Have you seen Tomi?
We ought to go for water.
What is it?
- What's the matter, Olga?
- I'm scared.
I can't help feeling that we'll
only live as long as Mr. Rose sings.
Are you his lover?
Tell me!
- That's my business.
- No, you're wrong.
- I'm here, too.
- Why do you hurt me?
- Oh, please. Leave me alone.
- Are you his lover?
Yes, I am.
You brought me here
without telling me.
Think of mother.
What would she say about you
destroying a family's life.
You don't understand.
What is there to understand?
- We're only friends.
- A lover is not a friend.
You're lying.
How could you bring me here?
Where else could
we have gone?
But what about his family?
How could you do that?
- Are you seriously asking me?
- I am.
- His children, his wife?
- And...
what am I supposed to do?
Choose to be alone like you?
Excuse me.
May I come in?
Of course, you can.
Anyway, we're the ones
who're intruding.
Intruding? Come now. We're pleased
we can help, that's all.
But I hardly know Mr. Halász.
So what? It's quite enough
if Olga knows him well,
isn't it?
Exactly.
- Dad!
- Yes?
Will we really only live as long
as that?
- As long as what?
- Well, as long as Mr. Rose sings.
- Who told you that?
- Auntie Olga.
- Is Mr. Rose a Jew, too?
- Yes, he is.
Are Jews not Hungarians?
- It's not that simple.
- Why?
As our religions differ.
Ours is Jewish.
- And the Hungarians'?
- All sorts.
- Protestant...
- Then what makes them Hungarian?
We'll talk about
this in a few years' time...
It isn't easy to understand.
- The woman on the tram?
- What about her?
- She wasn't a Jew, was she?
- No, she wasn't.
- And nobody can meet him?
- Who?
Mr. Rose.
Nobody.
Not even me?
No.
Shame.
- I can't see.
- Read it!
By the rights invested upon me by
the Hungarian nation, I hereby order
every legal and natural entity to
yield assistance, without question
under any circumstance
to the valiant brother
Géza Horányi-Halász, Staff Captain,
Hero of the First Hungarian Army,
bearer of the Grand Silver Medal
of Honour, the Petit Cross
and the Officer's Spear
of the Order of Transylvania, and...
as possessor of these national
decorations,
the defender of the honour
and the repository
of the future of Hungary.
Ferenc Szálasi,
- Leader of the Nation.
- This'll give some chance of survival.
This rabble loves mysterious
documents like this.
They'll hang us all.
I'd add that the seal is original...
or almost original.
Not that I've ever actually
seen one.
You're out of your mind.
We'll crease it a little,
and stain
it here and there.
Even our great arsehole leader
- will not suspect a thing.
- You've got a screw loose.
- Ladies and Gentlemen! Allow me...
- They'll hang us, Géza.
- You said you had nowhere to sleep!
- Please, Gran!
- Where were you last night?
- Nowhere! Here, at home.
- Home! You're a tramp!
- That's not true.
I feel ashamed of you.
Are you going out again?
No.
You're lying again.
It's good that your mother
could not see that.
Why aren't the curtains drawn?
People can see in.
Oh, Gran.
The cricket's keeping me awake.
Have you listened to the radio today?
- Yes.
- And?
- Just the usual things. They're coming.
- Coming, but when?
What?!
Good morning.
Zdrast-vuy-tje.
- What are you up to now?
- Russian conversation, for travellers.
- I can see that.
- So?
But we're not going
anywhere, Géza.
If they find this,
they'll shoot the whole family.
Nonsense, darling.
Why would they find it?
Zdrast-vuy-tje.
And who knows
the eighth rule?
- Julo? Do you?
- What? I don't know. What is it?
Do you know what a
peeping Tom is?
No, I don't!
Don't you? Would you fetch
the dictionary, then?
Oh, it's so Jewish.
- It's so what?
- Jewish.
What do you mean Jewish, Julo?
Running around for dictionaries
and encyclopaedias.
Who says so?
Pászthy... t-h-y.
And who is Pászthy, t-h-y
if I may ask?
A girl in my class.
I see. Well, if you'll allow me,
I'll go and fetch it myself.
I once go to the Orpheum.
There were beautiful girls.
Very beautiful girls.
They dance...
and they no have knickers.
Lift their legs
and nothing underneath.
Mr. Halász. I just wanted to tell you
that I'm going to lock the upper gate.
- As you think best.
- I'm just telling you.
- We come this way when we go to
get water. - I'll lock it.
- All right.
- Would you tell Mr. Rose
to look for somebody else?
I won't be coming any more.
I'll tell him.
Here's something else.
Your daughter wrote this
to my son.
Read it.
Hands up!
Higher!
What's this?
A nest of Jews?
I don't speak German.
She doesn't speak German.
Of course, even if I spoke it,
I would never talk to a German.
- Vera!
- What did she say?
She said why don't we offer
the gallant gentleman a drink.
Stalingrad's a long way away!
You'll work up a real thirst
- before you get there. - I can see
by your nose you're a Jew, too.
Nu, have you got a better offer?
I like you.
At the moment I can't reciprocate
your feelings, mister soldier.
Very good!
Perhaps if we sit down for a little.
I'm sure a drink wouldn't go amiss.
These are difficult times, but we're
all still just people, aren't we?
It's not easy for you, but
neither is it for us.
That's true.
War is war.
It's not easy for anyone.
Budapest is a beautiful city.
Full of beautiful women.
Yes, indeed.
Beautiful women.
"In war a woman is
a real treasure. "
Who knows what tomorrow may
bring. Will we be alive at all?
Yes, indeed.
Will we be alive at all? Would you
tell us what we can do for you?
I get 10,000 pengõs.
- Pardon?
- 10,000 pengõs
and you can stay.
And if we
don't have 10,000 pengõs?
Then I'll requisition this villa
in the name of General von Scheck.
I see.
Prosit!
To the beautiful Jewish women!
Sieg heil!
To women!
Mummy, I really need a pee.
- To the Reich!
To the Führer!
I really need to go...
To life!
- To life!
To Jewish death!
What have you done? Is he dead?
You've killed a German soldier!
- I haven't killed him, he's gone to sleep.
- I knew there would be trouble.
Shall I pistle on the axel?
Do what on the what?
It won't squilch.
Squilch?
Where do you learn such words?
Mr. Skubala always pistles
on the axel when it squilches.
I see.
- Are you sure this works?
- Sure.
We have to wait
a little until it seeps in.
I see.
What did you do with him?
We've put him in a wagon.
- What if he comes back tomorrow?
- Tomorrow?
He won't even know
which country he's in.
- Then the day after!
- Where from?
Szeged? Szabadka?
Or who knows where?
- Anywhere.
- He won't remember.
He'll think the whole thing
was just a bad dream.
Everybody's frightened.
Except, of course, Father.
Imre?
Did he appear?
No.
But the Waltzes have gone.
- Didn't even say goodbye.
- What?
They went without a word.
What a fool I am!
I beg your pardon, Mr. Waltz.
I do apologise.
I forgot about you.
I'm really sorry.
You don't need
to apologise, Mr. Halász.
- Do come out.
- Don't!
- How could you do such a thing?
- I'm sorry.
Shame on you! You swine!
Forgot about us!
What if I'd suffocated?
Eh? What if we'd suffocated?
The Lord moves
in mysterious ways.
Please.
A little decorum, dear.
Please calm down.
I'm very sorry. Very sorry.
How could you forget about us?
How could you do this?
I'm sorry.
I don't know what came over me.
Mr. Halász understands.
The chronic lack of oxygen
- in the brain.
- Mummy, dear.
- I need a pee desperately.
- Come on.
- Wake up, poppet. Do you hear?
- I'm not at home, Mum.
You must wake up.
Quick. Please.
- It's still dark. In the morning.
- Come on, hurry! Get dressed!
Tomi, wake up! Do you hear?
Get dressed! Quick!
- What is it?
- Get dressed. Quick! Hurry!
Zsuzsõ!
What in God's holy name
is going on here, brothers?
Is that how you greet your fellows
in the new motherland?
- Fortitude! Hail Szálasi!
Árpád!
Skubala! Did you bring
this drunken rabble here?
Not so fast...
We'll quieten you down soon.
You come here
disturbing decent citizens!
Why aren't you
in the ghetto, Jew?
Your papers!
What are you waiting for?
I'm sorry, Captain!
Fortitude!
I'm sorry.
Is this a Jew's arm? I sacrificed
this, for our beloved Transylvania!
Once again I apologise,
Captain.
You oaf! Didn't you tell the brothers
that Mr. Rose sang in person
- to the Führer on his birthday?
- Please forgive me, Sir.
The star on the gate misled us.
Scratch it off!
Fortitude!
Is this a Jew's arm?
Skubala, you fucking bastard.
Did you hear?
Scratch it off!
Put this on your forehead.
They can't leave you in peace,
even at night.
The devil take them!
- What will become of us,
Mr. Halász? - Vera, please.
- They've gone. - First the
German, then these people...
Go back to bed.
They were just drunkards...
Please go, Mr. Halász.
Please go.
Imre!
Lili!
Don't do it, Géza.
You can't.
Let's go to the ghetto!
At least we'll be safe there!
I have to talk to lmre about it.
He's alone, but you must think
of your family - your children.
So, talk to him, please.
I'll sell the Bible tomorrow -
we need that 1,000 pengõs.
Will he let you?
He said I could. That's why
he gave it to me.
Dad? Was Árpád with them, too?
Tomi said...
Árpád was here.
Was he?
- Yes, he was.
- Are you sure, Dad?
Yes, I'm sure, sweetheart.
Hey, slow down! Wait!
Careful!
King St. Stephen's Bible - I can
hardly believe it.
Odrola, some tea for
the gentleman,
and give the boy some sweets.
I bet the old hag hasn't
even moved
deaf as a post.
Aren't you cold?
I'm frozen to the bone.
Is this yours?
No, I'm here on behalf of
lmre Rose.
Rose, the famous countertenor?
Yes.
Mr. Halász, you put me
in a difficult position.
This is not just a rare book.
It's like the Holy Crown of Hungary
or the coronation robe.
It's as if I were to sell you one of
the tablets of the Ten Commandments.
Mr. Kalmár, it'd be a great
help to us. Times are hard.
I never thought I'd live to hold
the first Hungarian king's bible.
I never dared to dream of this.
For an old man, like me,
this is the grace of God itself.
Mr. Kalmár, I have Mr. Rose's
permission to sell this very
rare book - if you want it.
Always money!
Nothing else matters, just money.
You're Jews if I'm not mistaken.
That's what's wrong with you -
you live here with us
but you don't understand a thing.
I didn't mean to offend you,
Mr. Kalmár.
I'm not offended.
Are you a lawyer?
No, I was an engineer
in the Ganz Factory
until I had to leave
because of my origin.
It's not easy for anyone today.
Then Mr. Rose offered me a job.
Now I work as a caretaker for him.
At least there's a roof
over our heads.
May I ask how long you
have known him?
Since I was a child.
My father had a little grocer's shop.
He paid for his first singing
lessons.
Believe a blind old man,
those happy years will
never return.
40 pengõs.
Can you change 50?
The congregation is poor.
All right, keep it.
I can see you're a gentleman.
Pay me back later.
You owe me 10 pengõs.
- The fly...!
- Pardon? What did you say?
Nothing.
Where are you going? Get in line,
pigs! Or do you want to die here?
Look, I've got papers.
To wipe my arse with?
Or what?
Please show them to
Sándor Csija.
- He's a childhood friend of mine.
- Anything else?
What are doing? That's an important
document. There'll be trouble.
You may get yourself
into deep water.
- Are you a Yid?
- Who? Me?
- I resent that!
- Your son?
Come here.
Swear on his life.
- Yes, I'm a Jew.
- You see? Fall in!
Chin up.
It'll be all right.
Stop jabbering. Huh!
Csija's buddy!
Move along!
Hurry. Don't stop!
What's happening at the back?
Close up!
Get ready.
Don't be afraid.
I dream my own death.
Where's my tea?
A Jewish seed in my garden grew,
I watered it with vitriol
through and through.
Yet still he grew, arms,
legs and beard -
And a stinking Jewish neck
for the rope he feared!
A Jewish seed in my garden grew,
I watered it with vitriol
through and through.
Yet still he grew, arms,
legs and beard -
And a stinking Jewish neck
for the rope he feared!
- Tomi!
- Dad!
Géza! We've caught
the peeping Tom at last!
Oh, my God!
Something terrible's happened.
- What is it?
- Isn't Julo here?
- No.
- Oh, that poor thing.
The Skubala boy, Árpád,
has hung himself.
He didn't even want to come...
I told him to.
He wrote this to Julo.
Would you give it to her?
I'll never forgive myself,
Mr. Halász.
I wasn't even there.
His mother cut him down.
I'd rather hang myself.
I'm truly sorry.
He was a good lad.
He was.
Would you tell Mr. Rose, please?
I will.
I'll open the upper gate.
If you agree.
Do it.
Mr. Rose will be glad.
I know it hurts terribly now.
- Honey.
- It doesn't.
- How can you say that?
- It doesn't hurt at all.
But I can see it does.
I don't want to be a Jew, Mum.
Don't be silly.
I don't want to be a Jew,
do you understand?
- I do. - I don't want to!
I don't want to be a Jew! I don't!
Stop it.
We are going to die, Tomi!
All of us.
Touch me, please.
Just once in a lifetime.
We are all going to die.
Touch me, please.
What are you doing?
I've had enough.
I'm going to the countryside.
I want to see cows and pigs!
A load of smelly pigs!
Would you tell Mr. Rose?
I knocked but
he didn't answer.
I can't stand this anymore.
You do everything for
him anyway.
Do think it through,
Mrs. Bödõ!
Think it through?
There's nothing to think through.
Mrs. Bödõ!
Stop and think!
Think?
Times have changed.
Take care of yourselves.
If the Russians come or the English,
go down to the cellar.
You may be safe down there.
- What about Magda?
- You've seen her?
- No.
- Me neither!
A fine sort she is!
First she says she's got nowhere to
sleep, then she disappears.
Don't know where to
- just shrugs
her shoulders if I ask.
In my day I'd have got
a good hiding.
Tell her I've gone home.
She'll find me.
- God bless you.
- Let me help.
Don't bother.
You have enough to worry about.
Thank you for everything.
We're going back to town.
- And Olga?
- She's coming, too. Getting ready.
- What's this all about?
- Nothing! We're going!
You're not going anywhere!
You tell your wife what to do,
not me!
What's a matter with you?
That's not what we agreed!
I can't stay any longer.
I've had enough.
- What's happened?
Everything's over, my life, the
world. And you ask
- what's happened?
- I can't let you go!
- You must.
- Olga, please stay.
- We're going.
- What good will it do?
Think it over! It's not
easy for anyone! Stay.
I won't.
And if I ask you?
- Oh, my God.
- It's all right.
Calm down.
Everything's OK.
Can you see it?
You are here.
It's okay.
You can go and get
that mirror very soon.
Géza, how say in Russian
"stinking mess"?
I don't know.
It's not in the dictionary.
I know. Important
words never in dictionary.
Géza, tell Father
to stop this talk, please.
Zdrastvuystje tovarishi.
Here it is.
It's not correct...
Zdrastvuytje tovarishi.
That's correct...
Honestly, this is
driving me crazy.
- What you say?
- Zdrastvuytje tovarishi.
I beg you, Father. They're bombing
because we're under siege.
They want to oust the Germans.
- I know.
- Well, thank God.
I only don't know how to say
"stinking mess".
Zdrastvuytje tovarishi.
Nu. Don't know.
Then I say in German.
That'll be great, Father.
Then they'll certainly shoot us all.
Make your face sooty, Julo.
Do you hear?
I've done it.
- I don't believe you.
Come here. - Yes.
- I thought so!
- Shall I make my face dirty, too?
I'll do it for you, Tomi.
Come over here!
No, thank you.
Death be here.
I can smell it.
Russian no hurt me now.
The war's over.
Aunt Lili!
Mr. Halász!
War is over!
Aunt Lili!
Do you hear, Father?
We've won. Once again.
Don't do a thing, Géza. Let them
take whatever they want! Do you hear?
Here you are. Look here. See?
Read it all. It's written here.
And there's a stamp. Stamp!
You'll be shot in the head
for this. Do you want that?
What are you staring at?
Get out!
I'm Marshal Malinovsky's
interpreter. Clear out! Scram!
- He's some top dog!
- Let's get out of here!
Here is some schnapps.
This will be good for you.
Come away from
the window, Tomi!
Look at the thermometer
and get back into bed, will you?
- I can look at it here, too.
- No, you can't.
- Do you want to get even worse?
- It's not at all cold here.
You just can't feel it...
Come on, now! Dad will be angry.
Don't! Stop it! Don't!
- When will they get back?
- Patience.
- Can I go for the water tomorrow?
- If you're better.
Julo will be happy
if she doesn't have to go.
Tomi! Where are you going?!
Mr. Rose!
Lmre Rose... There's nothing to
be afraid of. He's dead.
When did he die?
He killed himself when
we had to sew on
the yellow star.
Then who sang?
This machine.
You'll hear it in a moment.
Magda's dead.
Cast
written and directed by
Andor Szilágyi
photographed by
Elemér Ragályi
music by
Lászlõ Benkõ
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0363970
A Rózsa Énekei - Rose's Songs (2003) English.srt
FPS: 25.000
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) All DVDs to be subtitled
2) All VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled
3) All videos/DVDs used in lessons at school to be subtitled
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV
____           __            ___   __              ___          __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _     /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /      /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
/                                /                        /