Mr Michaud?
No.
Mr Michaud, we have to talk.
Gilles!
Get me out of here.
What?
Will this one do?
Yeah.
Shall we go together tomorrow?
OK.
Pick you up at 9?
- Lf you want.
- Yeah.
I'll tell them that one's fine.
See you tomorrow.
Don't blame yourself.
It's not yourfault.
It could've happened with me.
Hey, man! Lost your bearings?
Oheck out these novelties.
Gilles Michaud?
- Bob!
- I'll be fucked!
- Hey there.
- Hey.
It's been ages.
You haven't changed a bit!
How are you?
You in a rush?
No.
Oarole, a pitcher please!
Put it there!
Did you or Bisaillon
keep the speakers we stole?
Shit, you were a lousy thief!
I don't remember that.
You dropped the speakers
4 times outside the church!
The priest ran after us
in his slippers!
Bisaillon wasrt too sharp.
Fartman!
He skateboarded
down the ramp on his belly!
I saw that!
- Fuck, did I!
- You were there!
Our old hood's dead.
Summer, you swelter.
Winter, you watch the bricks crack.
I feel like moving to the country,
buying a piece of land, a cabin.
I dunno, raise rabbits for a change.
It's sick, I've never been
outside the city.
The country can be boring too.
It's a change.
You still a professor?
What are you doing here?
Well, today, I...
I felt like remembering.
You are stewed.
Have you been drinking all day?
I came back to see
my old neighborhood.
I'm burying my son tomorrow.
What?
My little boy died.
I'm sorry, Gilles.
Drink.
Drink and shut up.
Takes a thief who doesn't rob often,
but who robs big
so he can stop robbing.
- Who does he rob?
- Fuck!
You put yourfinger on it. Rob who?
What? Where?
Robbing big has become impossible
in Montréal, shit.
Fucking Ohrist!
You feel like you're in a policearium.
- What?
- Apolicearium, shit!
Acop incubator.
No, I mean it.
Every goddamn little peanut vendor
has cameras, security guards,
$10,000 alarm systems,
titanium bars, hell!
Then go to the country.
The country?
Yeah, in the boonies.
All the banks are loaded with cash.
The old folks' savings.
That's where they stuff their cash.
Think so?
Wanna rob? Rob a bank!
Abank!
Jesus!
Gilles, a bank, shit!
Abank's fucking serious.
It's an idea... a crazy one.
But it's an idea.
Tomorrow we split.
You need a change of air.
Follow the 132 down the river.
Yeah.
Tomorrow morning. I'll find a car.
Denis at the shop owes me one.
Gilles, you ready?
I'm blocking the lane.
Yeah.
No suitcase?
No.
The country!
Abig change from Montréal!
What are you doing? Put that away!
Is it loaded?
It's not real.
Think I'm that dumb?
Put it away before somebody sees.
What's it for?
We have a job to do? We need tools.
I don't believe it!
What's wrong?
I'm such a fuckup!
What?
His picture's gone.
That's enough.
What are you doing?
If I hurry, we can still make it.
I don't want to go to the cemetery...
Orwatch him be put in the ground.
Goddamit!
I can't face the funeral.
Today I decided to sing in slang
I'm cool, I'm cool, I'm cool
Today I decided to dress like a bum
Are you alright?
Yeah, sure.
What's wrong?
That's your son?
How old is he?
He was 5.
What was his name?
Gabriel.
I'm sorry.
Shit, nothing's where it should be.
Well!
Is this the solenoid?
Or the water pump, the bendix?
Search me.
Hello?
Anybody home?
Sir?
Our car broke down.
Oould I call for a tow?
Stéphane?
Is that you, Stéphane?
Have you been haying?
No, sorry, I'm not Stéphane.
Did you bring the hay in?
I'm not Stéphane.
Hello.
Mr Orête thinks his son is coming.
Stéphane left long ago, Mr Orête.
You know that.
Yes, yes.
Oan we help you?
Our car broke down. May I call?
Right by the phonebook.
Thanks.
What is it? Italian? German?
Swedish.
They sure do make it complicated.
Fucking lkea... shit!
How are we going to pay?
- You're kidding me.
- What?
You have no money?
No.
A professor with no credit cards?
They're maxed out.
Funeral parlor, cemetery...
You'd be surprised.
I guess. Sorry.
Look, I have a bit of cash
and gifts for cooperative mechanics.
Got the owner's manual?
- The what?
- The handbook.
Glove box.
No, it's not there.
Shit!
Hold on! I'll do it.
There's a trick to opening it.
Here.
You're not wearing a watch?
They always break.
Lemme show you these beauties.
Brand new, all imports.
Anything happens, you just call.
They'll ship you a new one overnight.
Top quality.
You don't have money to pay?
Let's say I have
some of the money, but...
Where you from?
Montréal.
Are you near Ohinatown in Montréal?
Do we look like chop suey freaks?
Montréal chicks are cool.
True.
Ohinatown...
it's full-on Asian.
Are you having a wet dream all dressed?
Damn, the weed is good here!
Hi.
Yeah, hi.
From Montréal.
Nice welcome.
This is like a private club.
Nobody bothers us.
Aman can be alone with his dream.
And he'll finally know it.
Tell us about the bank.
The bank?
Is it busy in the morning?
Yeah... people come through there.
How many?
Nobody.
The bank closed last year.
There's just the ATM.
It's all about method.
It's only plate glass.
No sweat, we'll yank it out.
That thing weighs 21/2 tons.
How can you move it?
With a tractor.
Where do you get it?
In my uncle's shed.
It's all rusty, but it still works.
Your uncle might not like it.
He's dead.
Well, if he's dead...
Oome here!
The glass will make
way too much noise.
Better off going in the side.
Oome see.
Look.
In front we have the street.
On the side, we'd have to angle it...
it's too tight.
It's vinyl siding. It's easy to smash.
And then we can lift it by the side.
I've no grip in front.
O'mere. You didn't see right.
We can lift it,
we just smash the plaster.
They'll hear us 200 miles away.
Looking for a socially responsible
investment?
$9,280...
$9,300...
$9,320. Not a penny more.
Not bad, huh?
Fuckir A!
Tomorrow a hotel room and shower!
Going to Montréal?
Not right away.
Gimme your address.
I'm going soon.
Sure.
But I gotta warn you,
I don't live near Ohinatown.
Yeah, OK.
Gilles!
There's a bed.
Leave him alone.
I think he needs to be alone a bit.
But you...
What's this business with Asians?
Ever slept with an Asian?
It's my dream.
I have the feeling
they're guardians of the temple.
Temple?
What temple?
The temple of living nature.
If you look at Asian chicks, you see
their bodies are like writing.
Their eyes are like letters.
Their vagina... a signature.
Their hair, their smile...
their entire body is made up of signs.
They're like the mystery
and the solution at the same time.
Sleeping with them
is sleeping with the mystery
of living nature.
Not many Ohinese chicks in St Pascal.
Tough luck, Damien.
They block immigration here.
They want us to die off.
So we'll go where the Asians are
and bring'em back to the farm.
Holy shit!
You wear me out.
What hare-brained scheme is that?
You wanna start an Asian colony
in St Pascal of the Boonies?
ASzechuan Sexodrome?
Gilles, you hear that?
He'll be cold this winter.
Say what?
At 5 they don't think.
I've always dressed him.
Hat, scarf, boots.
Pull on his mitts so snow won't get in.
He'll be cold playing outside.
He won't be cold.
The ground will freeze
and he's only wearing a shirt.
He'll be cold for sure.
He's too little.
He'll be OK.
Oome...
That little bastard!
That fucking cock-sucking bastard!
What's wrong?
He took the cash! We were robbed!
Oall the cops.
Get up, we'll make a posse.
You go. I'm sleeping.
Get up, fuck!
I won't let a Mongoloid rob me!
Bob, forget it.
Fuck!
I'll crucify him!
Oalm down. We 'll find something.
How?
Next village.
I'll let the engine run.
Once you're out, we'll take a back road.
Yeah...
Well get going.
Wait. We don't know the layout.
So what?
You shout, Hold up! Get down!
Wait! That's not how you do it.
You choking up?
You're the thief!
I'm a fence, not a thief. Big difference!
Just hold on a sec. Wait.
Gilles, Ohrist!
Wait!
If I don't eat something, I'll faint.
I'm hungry and stinky.
There's a beach down the road.
Oome look.
We're here.
The beach is there.
How come you know this place?
When I was a kid my family came.
You never told me.
You never asked.
Still have family here?
My grars in a nursing home.
We'll visit her.
Not really.
We can eat with her.
They must serve hot meals.
Let's go!
We'll have good mushy food!
Ohillier here than in town!
The water's great!
Sure you won't come in?
It's great! Nippy!
That feels good!
It's saltwater here.
It's salty.
Room 202.
My handsome Gilles.
It's been so long
since you visited me.
Yes, a long time.
I'm sorry, Grandma.
How's life in the city?
It's not too hard?
Grandma,
my little boy died.
I know, my boy.
How?
Your mom called.
You 2 are talking?
Of course, my boy.
When things like that happen,
we can't ignore one another.
I'll leave you a minute.
I lost 2, you know.
I had 11 who lived,
but I lost 2.
A2-year-old
and a 6-month-old.
I didn't know, Grandma.
I didn't know.
You don't forget.
Ever.
You neverforget a child you lost.
How do you go on living?
Tight game.
Real tight.
Ohrist, it stinks of piss!
Sir! Sir! Please!
Yes?
Is there a dog here?
- No, pets aren't allowed.
- No?
Or cleaners. There's piss here.
Oould be.
Oould be?
You think it's normal?
Do you have a problem?
No, you have a problem.
I just said there's piss here.
I don't know who you are,
but mind your business.
Don't you get it?
I said it stinks of piss.
- I'll get the director.
- Smell it, dammit!
There are human beings here,
not pigs!
I hate botched work. Smell it!
Did Alain come back?
Yes.
He runs the motel now.
Why don't you sleep there tonight?
He wouldn't mind?
On the contrary.
He used to love it,
playing with you when you visited.
How is he?
I think
I'll sleep a bit now, Gilles.
Bye, Grandma.
I'll report you! Get off me!
Stop it, Bob!
I've got him.
I'll slaughter you mangy dogs!
We won't slaughter anyone.
Let's go.
A good fight whets my appetite!
If I don't eat I'll keel over.
What about you?
Oome on.
What?
The Levite must be eating supper.
It's Ohristian charity.
Who?
The what?
The Levite. Didrt you go to school?
Not long enough.
These places are never open.
Like banks.
Gentlemen?
May I help you?
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
- Are you the priest?
- Yes.
- The name's Bob.
- Evening, Bob.
- Gilles.
- Hi, Gilles.
It was filthy. It was scary, Ohrist!
Sorry, Father.
- Oall me Jean-Pierre.
- OK, Jean-Pierre. JP.
It was disgusting,
I wouldn't let my dog sleep there.
I called,
the regional office is swamped.
They rely on the private sector.
They don't have the budget to be fussy.
Someone must check the quality of care?
Sure, in the bigger cities...
Riviêre-du-Loup, Matane, Rimouski.
We're too small.
Have you talked to the owner?
I've tried everything.
- He's not interested?
- Wort lift a finger.
I know you're going through
a great loss.
You know?
I see your grandmother often.
If you everwant to talk...
Of course.
The Ohurch is like Oonsolation Inc.
What do you mean?
Gilles teaches sociology.
Religiors a system
for repaying one's ancestors.
Yes, and...?
We all feel a debt to those
who gave us life.
So you think the Ohurch
allows us to pay off our debt
by honoring the dead.
Yes.
But not me.
I have no more debts.
I don't owe anyone anything.
What is it you sell?
Soporifics for the wounded souls?
Spiritual valium?
Abit simplistic, isn't it?
When will you shut the firm?
When the old folks are all buried?
- We 're no ordinary firm.
- Nah!
You deal in the vague and intangible.
Oredo quia absurdum est!
What horseshit!
Relax, Gilles. Relax.
I can deal with criticism of the Ohurch.
You know,
ritual is important
when you lose a loved one.
Whers your sors funeral?
It was 2 days ago.
I wasrt there.
You're not helping yourself.
God may not be in your life,
but there are stages you can't skip.
It catches up with you.
How bout a smoke?
Yeah, good idea.
Ooming, Gilles?
O'mon, Bob.
Your friend needs to be alone.
Yeah, right.
I'm sorry I brought him along.
But he kept insisting.
All you can do is keep an eye on him.
One day he'll ask to go back,
to face his grief.
It's inescapable.
I notice you don't have a watch.
I have these
excellent items. I wondered...
They're very fine watches,
excellent products.
Maybe there's one that interests you?
We're kinda short these days.
It'd help put gas in the car.
Give me one for $40.
I can't go higher.
Thank you, that's great. Thank you!
This one, maybe?
The blue one.
The blue one's more fun, more...
Nice.
Bingo! JP bought a watch!
What's that?
What did you do?
I mean, really!
JP feeds us, he knows your Gran,
and you rob him?
We're here to get rich, no?
Don't we deserve it?
Arert we deserving too?
Deserving, sure.
But he was nice to us.
I can't believe you!
Ohurch property belongs
to the people. Get in.
Thanks.
Go ahead.
No, go on, play.
I just...
I'm like the Russians.
The Russians?
We come here to learn.
I'm a lousy teacher.
Don't sell yourself short.
You're a natural.
You talk with your body.
And hit the white ball low,
you'll never sink it.
- Thanks.
- Well done.
My pleasure.
- So?
- It's interesting.
He says that
this guy Lévesque might buy it.
He works in the town rec department.
We just have to find him.
Oart be hard in a small town.
I bought you a change of clothes.
You OK?
I can't feel my legs.
What?
What do you mean?
I can't feel my legs!
Hold on, I'll help you.
Oan you stand up?
You OK?
Stay here. I'll get the car.
Don't move.
That your cousin?
Yeah.
I'll give you cabin 8.
It's the only decent one.
Anything goes, we're not choosy.
You were a Peacekeeper?
Yeah.
Must've been tough.
You want to talk?
Follow me.
I left the army 2 years after that.
You were bored, fed up?
No.
The army was my life.
Why'd you quit?
I didn't quit, my nerves did.
When I came back I couldn't sleep.
If the kettle whistled, I hit the floor.
Well,
it's been a long day.
Thanks for the beer.
I think...
I served 6 months in Bosnia.
Yeah?
What exactly did you do there?
Good question.
What do you mean?
Our mission changed.
Our job was to escort aid convoys.
Suddenly we were defending a city.
55,000 civilians in a town of 15,000.
We were 200 Oanadian soldiers.
55,000 civilians who couldn't escape?
If they tried,
they were shot like sitting ducks.
No electricity.
No running water.
Ahospital filled to bursting.
No medicine.
You heard the screams all day long.
They did amputations
without anesthesia.
We took over the Fojnica orphanage.
How come?
The staff had fled 3 days before.
They knew Serb troops were coming.
When we entered the orphanage,
it was the smell that...
And the silence.
We collected the dead children.
Others were still alive, semi-conscious.
Every time I smell dry piss
it takes me back.
They killed children?
I saw drunk militiamen, for kicks,
empty their clips into a school bus
full of children.
Jesus Ohrist!
The beer didn't agree with me.
You OK?
I feel better now.
We want to show you something.
It's low tide.
I'm alright.
We made a sea cemetery.
Each cross represents
a child we knew who was killed.
A child who'd come
to the camp every day.
We can't forget what we've seen.
But here at least
we can bearwitness.
At high tide, life goes on.
You can't see the kids.
That one's Ali.
Alittle boy of 9.
He'd come every day for cigarettes.
I gave him 2 each time.
By selling them,
he fed his family for 2 days.
One day he didn't come back.
Oart sleep?
You've hardly slept
since we left Montréal.
I'm not tired.
Thinking about him?
I can't remember anymore.
It happened so fast.
There are just pieces left,
little bits of that night.
As if it happened a century ago.
What happened?
Without warning,
he got meningitis.
Nothing you could do.
It went so fast.
He had a fever.
Lfigured it was anotherflu.
I did the usual.
I gave him Tylenol and put him to bed.
He went straight to sleep.
We'd go to hospital in the morning.
He neverwoke up.
You did what anyone would've done.
I'm not anyone.
I'm his father.
If I'd known, I'd have rushed him in.
But you're not a doctor, Gilles.
What can I do?
I wish I could tell you.
But I...
I don't know.
I'm not good at this stuff.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what you can do.
Try to sleep a bit, OK?
Oan you take this to Aunt Alberta?
Her birthday's coming.
Thanks.
It's all good.
I said we'd pay tomorrow.
Yeah, good luck!
Look, get some rest.
Think of ways to spend the money.
You alright?
Yeah.
Why, hello!
Hi.
How's it going?
- Good, and you?
- Sure.
I'm looking for Mr Lévesque.
Plenty of Lévesques here.
There are Lévesques down every road.
I guess.
The Lévesque I'm looking for works
for the rec department.
- Hold on. Oamille?
- Yeah?
Know a Lévesque who works for the town?
Must be Guy Lévesque,
a real asshole.
He's always at the baseball diamond.
When he's not in the bleachers
peeking under our skirts.
Thanks, girls.
Our pleasure.
Oan I help you?
No, big guy. Everything's chill.
Ohill?
What kind of fag expression is that?
It's a Montréal expression.
Oh, right, Montréal.
That's where they have
the fairy pride parade.
Yeah, that's right.
And Oocksucker Lake, too
on Mount Royal.
I've seen enough of you, tiny.
Beat it.
Jean-Pierre, you started.
You don't belong.
I'd be careful.
Well, thanks again, girls,
for the info. You're sweet.
And real pretty too,
really desirable.
My legs are all tingly.
My back's sweaty.
Lovely area, think I'll stay a bit.
Again, thank you and, it's chill!
Go, go, go!
It's going up!
Keep it up!
That's OK.
- Why hello!
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good, you?
- Your daughter?
- Yup.
She's mine,
not Jean-Pierre's.
The fireman.
Oh yeah.
What's your name, hon?
Momo!
It's Momo?
- Maude.
- Maude's nice.
She's shy.
That's allowed.
Hold on tight.
There you go!
Gee yap!
That's it, hold tight!
Good!
Hold on!
Well,
it could be cheap silver plate.
I can't tell if it's real
before I get it tested.
There's a risk for me,
so it's gonna cost you.
Oost me? I'm selling, not you!
Relax, kid.
I can only give an advance
till I know what I've got.
Real silver has a stamp on the back.
Awhat?
Real silver has a stamp.
Look.
How'd you know that?
My gran was a maid
at the Québec Oitadel.
Look, I'm busy.
Oheck it out. It says "sterling."
It's the real stuff.
Mr Lévesque,
if my partner says it's real silver,
then it's real silver.
Dish out the cash.
It's settled.
Gilles, how are you?
The transaction was a success.
Thanks to...
our business partner,
Miss Mélanie of Oabano.
- Hi.
- Her daughter Maude.
You go on.
I need a minute with Gilles.
I have to get back to the stand.
See you later?
Oome with me, Maude.
Get a load of this.
300 beautiful buckeroos.
You keep'em. I don't trust myself.
Wanna go for a beer?
I'll finish this one and walk a bit.
See you at the motel.
You're white as a sheet. Are you OK?
Yeah. See you later.
I'll be at the hotdog stand.
Where you been?
- With Maude.
- What about me?
- You're with your pals.
- Who'd I come with?
With my pals orwith you?
Why are you here?
Leave him alone!
I was just passing by.
Look, faggot,
beat it or
I'll hang you from our ladder!
For a fireman you're hotheaded.
Another clown!
Don't you get it?
I don't want to see your mug
around here.
Pack your crap,
get in your car and clear out!
Leave him alone!
If you want a beating, wait your tum.
Get the fuck out of here!
Oome on!
It's OK, Gilles.
Shut up, Bob.
Oome on, this'll be fun!
Quite a babe, huh?
Yup.
Don't get carried away.
I won't always be there to defend you.
I think I'm a little bit in love.
It's not love, it's an erection.
It's not the same.
She has a kid. What are you thinking?
To start a family?
She'd like to see me again.
Love, family...
they're not a free game
you win for being nice.
It's fate.
It takes over your life
and doesn't let go.
What have you done in life
besides wiping your ass?
Where are we?
Past Oacouna.
Why'd you stop?
Out of gas.
Didrt you fill'er up?
Out of money.
What? I gave you $300.
I blew it.
Blew it?
You blew $300 last night?
How? Where?
I bought some oblivion in a bar.
Hi, Auntie.
Gilles!
My big boy!
How are you?
Just fine.
Hélêne's little boy!
Goodness, it's been so long!
Oome in, my boy.
Who's this handsome young man?
My friend Bob.
- Hello, Mr Bob.
- Hello.
- Oome in.
- Thanks.
What a lovely surprise.
- Here, a present from Alain.
- Thanks.
Oome in.
We're having a little party.
Let me introduce you.
Look who's here!
Who is it?
- Who is it?
- It's Gilles.
Hélêne's son.
And his friend Bob.
- I'm Madame Déziel.
- Hi.
They've come from Montréal.
Hi, Bob.
That's so sweet.
We're always visiting here.
What a lovely surprise.
Hello. Do you remember me?
Yes.
Madame Amyot?
Hello, Mr Lévesque.
Was it hard to find?
As long as you keep the river
on your left, you're fine.
Don't keep them standing there.
They're hungry.
Hi, Luc.
When evening
descends on the green marsh
We shall listen to
the song of the golden wheat
I haven't sung in ages,
but I could hold that note before.
You still have a lovely voice.
I used to sing with them.
That was my First Oommunion.
Pretty dress.
It was pretty.
Goodness, the whole family.
Look how many we were.
They're almost all gone.
That's your great-uncle Henri.
A big traveller.
- I never knew him.
- No.
But your great-uncle Laflêche, yes.
Of course, Laflêche.
You used to cling to his shirttails.
He took you everywhere.
You'd come with your little bag.
He'd pick you up at the station
in Riviêre-du-Loup.
Always in a new car.
He could repair any engine.
The man was a mechanical genius.
You'd drive off in his big car
and tour the county, like a prince.
You were a little prince.
We'd tour my kingdom.
Yes.
He felt your dad neglected you badly.
He said that summer
was made for dads and sons
to play together.
He was so patient with you.
That's you, my boy.
When you left you'd say
you'd try to bring us back good news.
You again.
You visited often.
What an ugly tree!
We thought it was beautiful.
With all the presents under it.
Times were different.
Ahandsome lad.
Yourfriend seems to like the country.
He never leaves Montréal.
What did you do when you lost one?
We thanked the Lord for the healthy ones
and for calling the sick ones home.
We had to go on.
I had 6 others to feed.
Don't waste strength
on things you can't change.
Expecting anyone else, Alberta?
It's the Maude squad!
Bob the snob!
Mme Alberta,
this is a friend from Oabano.
Hello!
Mélanie.
He's so good!
Your turn, babe.
OK, your turn.
Is that legal?
Want to make it harder?
Like this, with my eyes shut!
You're good!
Where's everybody?
I dunno.
Here, a present.
Thanks.
It's tiny.
Look!
Pieces of old glass.
Beautiful colors.
There are lots there.
What's that?
We hunted for seashells.
It's beautiful! Blue and green...
Where were you?
You don't leave a child alone
nearwater!
It's OK, Maude knows.
What's with you?
I'm sorry for you
but the world won't stop.
I'm sorry for before.
You knew from the start we'd come here.
Maybe, I dunno.
You could've mentioned it then.
Yeah.
Our plan didn't pan out.
We're lousy robbers.
Mélanie wants to buy stuff for burgers.
I can't stand eel.
Want to come?
- Sure.
- Hop in.
Gille's coming along.
What's keeping him?
Want some fireworks for tonight?
- Yes, yes, yes!
- OK.
You're happy, huh?
They have lots.
Listen, but don't look at me.
Look out front.
For us?
Seems like it.
Stay here with the girls.
What'll you do?
Bob who? I don't know you.
That won't work.
Trust me.
You don't have to do this.
Look after the girls.
Oount on me.
Sir!
Suspect fleeing!
Yes, hello?
I'm going to Montréal.
Do what you have to do, my boy.
It's a good idea.
Thanks for everything.
You're welcome anytime.
We can go.
Gilles Michaud?
That's me.
Subtitles: Robert Gray, Kinograph
Subtitling produced with the financial
participation of Telefilm Oanada
for rutracker.org