Papa will drop Teena aunty
at the bus stop and come back.
"Is Teena aunty a small kid
to drop her off?"
Aww!
Aren't you the big boy now?
Isn't Teena aunty still a kid?
Papa will be back soon.
Ok, dear?
- Good night!
- Ok, good night! - Bye!
- Hello?
- Yeah!
You caught the train?
No. I was a bit late
to leave the office.
Deepak will drop me
at the highway now.
I'll get a bus from there.
If you say roughly
by what time you'll reach,
I'll come to pick you up.
No need to come, Roy!
Just keep the keys
by the window, and go to bed.
'I'll be with you
by the time you wake up."
- Ok, good night!
- Good night!
I thought you would
stay awake and wait for me!
You were the one
who asked me to sleep!
You fell from the
bike again?
Oh! It's alright!
Once you finish writing
your current novel,
leave your job then.
You don't need to drive
in the traffic anymore, then!
Even if you feel like
writing something new,
you can be here and write,
full time!
Oh! Is it enough that I simply
sit and write the whole time?
Only 100 rupees, madam?
That's what you said earlier!
A bit more for dropping you off
here, in one piece!
Get going if you wanna leave
in one piece!
Oh!
You didn't keep the keys,
isn't it?
If I keep them,
you wouldn't wake me up!
So?
You fell down
from the bike again?
No! You must've dreamt
about it!
Listen! Let me quickly go
take a bath!
Can you make me
a strong coffee?
Leave it, Roy!
Go make some coffee!
"Someone so close,
without even knowing,"
"Coming to caress,
without even saying,"
"Is it a mere story
in my mind?"
"Or are you the reality
that overwhelms my heart?"
'Regarding the missing case of
Rajagopal, the famous novelist,'
'the hints suggest that
there has been'
'no significant progress
in the investigation.'
'His son, the ex-MLA...'
Hey,
Once I'm here,
I even turn my phone off!
And you're watching TV?
Have you read his novel?
It's superb!
"Someone so close,
without even knowing,"
"Coming to caress,
without even saying,"
"Is it a mere story
in my mind?"
"Or are you the reality
that overwhelms my heart?"
"For us, together,"
"To melt away on this land,"
"A zillion lifetimes will bloom!"
'Can you whisper in my ears,
if this is a dream or reality?"
"Is even the reality
fading away like a dream?"
"When the dusk arrives,"
"Let me be the charming moonlight
on your window shades"
"Within these walls,
as a lit candle,"
"Let me yield you warmth."
"Let me bloom as a dainty melody,"
"With your fingertips,"
"shower the lyrics on it."
"Let me plant a kiss on
the speck of your forehead,"
"Let me gently rest down
on your lap."
"For us, together,"
"To melt away on this land,"
"Will a zillion lifetimes bloom?"
"Am I misreading between
reality and dreams?"
"Is even the reality
fading away like a dream?"
"When the days and nights
extend together, here..."
- "Isn't that Teena's house?"
- "Yeah!" - "Nobody there?"
"They... were there."
"Don't cry, dear!"
"Sir, one moment!"
"Mom!"
We daunt him and feed him
by saying that police will come!
That's why he's crying!
Did they tell you
where they went?
Uhm... She was there.
She had told that
she would leave today.
I don't know if he went
to drop her.
Yeah! There he is!
I'm here to meet Teena.
Couldn't reach her number.
Well... She was on leave.
She keeps the office phone off
when she comes home.
She has gone back today.
You may reach her now.
Ok!
Well... what was it?
You know the novelist,
Rajagopal?
Teena had posted a photo
with him, on Facebook.
It was on the previous day
of his missing.
I came here to enquire
if Teena knows anything about it.
Okay? See you.
'Don't cry! No!'
'Aww! Looks like you're sleepy!'
'Shall we go to sleep?'
'See! A cat!'
'The cat's gone! See!
It'll come back now!'
'Looking for Teena...'
Why are you crying?
It's okay!
- Stop crying!
- Hey!
Yes?
When did the police arrive?
You came, right?
Just 5 minutes before that.
Aww! Let's go! Come!
Let's go to sleep!
He has written only four books.
But all of them are bestsellers.
Have you read any, sir?
I've read one, I think...
My wife follows him
quite well, though.
She is a huge fan of him.
That's what.
Anyone who reads his books
will become his fan!
That day, I met him
at the coffee shop unexpectedly.
So I clicked a selfie,
and posted it on Facebook.
Apart from that,
I don't know him personally.
I'm recording your words
as your statement.
If you have anything more to say,
or pass any information,
- Please call me.
- Sure, sir!
Let's go!
Do you know Rajagopal?
Well! The police asked this
and left just now!
Well, if you could write
a feature about his missing,
it would be of
great demand now.
He's got health issues
due to his age.
The readers wish that
he returns safely.
Yet, you want this!
Well...
Vinu from the library told me that
his books are out of stock,
In that angle, there's a scope
for a feature. That's all!
Are we out of other topics, sir?
Let's just leave this aside!
Of course!
How about your novel?
Will we get to read
it anytime soon?
As if he'll buy and read it
the moment it gets released!
He's simply flattering you!
Such people...
Hey, Deepak!
I just reached my desk.
Yeah!
Continue your work.
Come here in the evening.
I don't think I can, today.
Got some pending work to do.
It's okay. Call me then.
How's your son now?
He's coughing a bit too much.
Gotta take him to a doctor
tomorrow, if it doesn't get better.
Okay!
- 'Alright then. I'll call you later.'
- Yeah. Okay.
'Just add it to the curry.'
'Don't burn the chilly too much.
Turn it off!'
- It isn't burnt, mom!
- Burn it, then!
Mom, Teena is here!
I'll call you after dinner.
Hey, Teena!
Did you eat anything?
Looks like she's gonna
test her food on you!
- Aren't you doing fine, aunty?
- Of course! How's Roy?
He's happy. He's good.
Carry on with your things then.
- Bye! - Bye!
- Bye!
Hey! Let me quickly go
and take a bath! Okay?
Uhm! So you're eating
oats tonight, huh?
No! A nice fish gravy and 'Pathiri'.
Wow! Where did you get them?
Nabeesumma got them for me.
They know that you'd be gloomy
without me, and won't cook anything!
Well, there's something left
in the fridge.
That's why
I didn't make anything.
What did you have?
Nothing yet.
Soumya has prepared
something.
Wow!
I'm having a slight headache.
I may go to bed early.
But... why headache?
Nothing as such!
Don't start worrying about it!
I had my works pending,
as I was on leave.
It's because of looking
at the screen for a long time.
Uhm...
Alright then.
Go to sleep early.
- Okay, sure.
- Call me in the morning, okay?
Oh, sure! Good night!
Bye.
Listen...
I didn't get any appreciation
for cleaning the whole house!
Now if you tell me that
the curry isn't good, I'll kill you!
I sensed it
when I entered the house!
The smell was 'wonderful'!
Really? Don't eat it, then!
Give me!
I was just kidding!
Listen...
Are you planning to sleep early?
I've got an awesome movie!
Shall we watch it?
No, you watch it.
I'm not in a mood.
Oh, I forgot about that.
Once you're back from home,
you're always like this!
Huh? Huh?
I'm getting it!
Stop it!
Shall I tell you
where the missing ones are?
On the way from Vazhikkadavu
to Nadukani,
towards the left is Maruthapuzha.
From there, on the way to
Chinnathodu,
after the checkpost,
there's a big board
with an elephant's picture on it,
There's a route to the forest
from there, towards the right.
On that route,
there's an old house.
The missing ones are there.
Hey, shall I tell you
where the missing ones are?
Yeah?
On the way from Vazhikkadavu
to Nadukani,
towards the left is Maruthapuzha.
'From there, on the way to
Chinnathodu,'
there's a big board
with an elephant's picture on it,
There's a route to the forest
from there, towards the right.
On that route,
there's an old house.
The missing ones are there.
Uhm... Roy must've dreamt
about this.
Take your medicine
and go to sleep.
Okay?
Alright.
Good night.
Hi, chechi!
Good morning!
The police were here yesterday
to see Teena, I heard?
It's about the novelist,
isn't it?
So? Tell me what it is, Tony!
Nothing as such!
A friend of mine,
told me that he saw him
in a bus to Vazhikkadavu.
Which bus?
Vazhikkadavu.
Well... When did he see him,
you said?
Last Sunday, he said.
There are buses to Vazhikkadavu
from everywhere in Kerala.
All he said is that
he saw him on that bus.
I don't know anything else, okay?
Where all can we go
from Vazhikkadavu?
From there, Sulthan Bathery,
And, well...
If you get to Nadukani,
from there, Goodalloor,
Ooty, Mysore...
It's a nice route.
Haven't you gone there?
Hey! Did you reach the office?
Yeah!
Well... I called you
to ask something.
What was your dream
last night?
Why?
Nothing as such.
You woke me up last night
and said something.
Names of some places...
Yeah...
A girl came near our window
and said something.
Well...
Do you remember what she said?
No, dear!
'It was you who asked me
to take my pills and sleep.'
I just woke up.
Okay then. I'll call you later.
Bye.
'Going on a journey, following a dream!'
All credits to my husband!
Hey! Why so early?
Saw a status of yours
in Facebook!
Yeah! I thought of
taking one week's leave.
And the purpose is writing, isn't it?
- Shall I join you?
- No!
I won't disturb you at all!
I'll sit quietly!
Well, did you decide
your destination?
That's a secret!
Something's fishy!
I know!
Think of it that way!
If I tell you now,
you'll say that I'm nuts!
I'd say that
even if you don't tell me!
Hey!
I'm going then.
I'll take you the next time, okay?
And yes. My files and books...
Don't even touch them!
They're important!
Why do I need them anyway?
- Alright! Bye!
- Bye!
Hi!
I saw your status!
Why all of a sudden?
You didn't tell me anything!
Is it an official trip?
No, it's personal.
I thought of telling you.
What's there to think so much?
If I tell you this,
you'll come with me.
I can't join you now
anyway.
My son's fever has worsened.
That's why I didn't tell you.
Well... This is an uncertain trip.
If it works out,
it'll be beneficial for both of us.
Anyway,
I'll talk to you in detail
once I'm back. Okay?
Alright. Bye.
It's your personal number.
Where are you off to?
Hey! Didn't you have a dream
last night?
From that, I got a hint
about the places
where Rajagopal sir
could be at.
I'm gonna carry out
an investigation!
You didn't have this fad
for quite some time!
Yeah! Isn't it been a while, Roy,
that I went on a solo trip?
I... I'm at the bus stop now.
Oh, so you already started, huh?
Well, How's your headache?
That's all gone!
Roy, the bus is about to start.
I'm going. I will call you
once I reach.
Ok? Bye!
But, where are you going?
'Vazhikkadavu'
Were you able to reach her?
No!
She'd be at at some place
with no network.
It isn't that.
Her phone is switched off.
She'll call you!
'By God's will!'
Sir? Remember journalist Teena,
whom we met...
regarding the missing case
of novelist Rajagopal?
Her husband Roy is here,
he says she's also missing.
- Missing?
- Yes!
Suresh told me that he met her
when he went to her office.
Yeah. What should I do, sir?
Do this.
- Ask him to come here.
- Alright, sir.
Hello! Hello!
CI sir is calling you.
Go to that room.
Come. Have a seat.
Your wife is working at
Ernakulam, right?
Why do you think she's missing?
I've not been able to reach
her phone since last evening.
She's gone on a trip.
You have anybody's number
who is with her?
She went alone.
Did you enquire in her office,
or with her friends?
No use asking them.
They don't know anything.
You're just unable to
reach her on phone, right?
And it's not even 24 hours.
Isn't it too early to conclude
that she's missing?
It's not that, sir.
Something...
has happened to her.
I'm sure about that.
Roy, right?
Don't get tensed, Roy.
She might be out of coverage area,
or her phone might be damaged.
That could be why
she's not contacting you.
It's not that, sir!
You don't know.
Whatever happens,
she would contact me!
Something has happened to her.
Anyway, lodge a complaint
with all these details.
We'll enquire.
Sir, look at this.
This is Teena's Facebook post,
from yesterday morning 11:22.
She's let everyone know that
she's going!
Yes, sir!
Well, in that novelist's
missing case,
ask Suresh
what her statement was.
And what about that
land infringement case?
- Haven't you asked Saji to come today?
- We've sent people.
He can't just come and blabber
like the last time!
No, sir! He's a bit snotty!
I'm even snottier then!
'Complaint from Roy Jacob'
I got an urgent meeting.
Will see you after that.
- Haven't you lodged
the complaint? - Yes.
- You gave her number, right?
- Yeah.
Your number too, right?
Yeah.
Then we will investigate
and let you know if there's anything.
Aren't you gonna
investigate now, sir?
Listen...
There's a method of investigation
for each case.
You've given her number,
right?
We'll track her location through
cyber department, and let you know.
You may go now.
Hasn't it been a week
since Rajagopal went missing?
You aren't able to
find him yet!
Will this also be like that?
Teena went to him.
How do you know that?
It's me who told her the route.
So, you know
where Rajagopal is.
Interesting!
Couldn't you have told this first?
We could've found both of them!
Enquire thoroughly about his wife,
and about him too.
Ok, sir!
If you find any link
to the missing novelist,
let me and Suresh know.
Sure, sir.
It's not his wife,
he's the one who's missing!
I gave her leave for a week.
She said she has to complete
her novel.
But didn't she go on leave
recently?
Do you let people
go on leave, so often?
Not for everyone.
Teena's language is good.
Besides, her stories have got
a good number of followers.
So if you don't give her leave,
she'd resign, isn't it?
That's right!
She goes on such trips
quite often!
Still, would she just go
without telling anyone?
You and her shared
a good rapport, isn't it?
Well...
Not so much to mention about.
Is there any problem, sir?
Well, we've received a complaint
that she's missing.
She won't be missing, sir!
She goes and comes
as she wishes!
I wouldn't be surprised
if she comes in right now!
'Going on a journey, following a dream!'
All credits to my husband!
'Yes, Suresh?'
Asif sir!
People here say that
Teena often goes on such trips!
Oh!
Besides, who knows!
She'd have some affair!
Did you check
the mobile tower location?
When the phone got switched off,
it was in Mayyanthani area.
We're checking if she's got
any friends there.
Okay, Suresh. I'll call you
in case of any updates.
Alright.
He'd get tensed
if he can't reach Teena on phone.
He's quite a caring person.
Maybe he lodged the complaint
because of that.
Where's her family?
- Family...
- Well...
Are you Teena's friend,
or relative?
I'm the daughter of
her mom's cousin.
Ever since she
got married to Roy,
she got disconnected
from her family.
Alfred uncle, her dad
is in Germany.
But he got married to someone else,
and is settled there.
- In Germany?
- Yeah!
Sir, Saji is not at home!
Let's come back tomorrow again.
Any update on Teena's case?
Apart from Roy,
nobody thinks that Teena is missing.
Her friends say that
she often goes on solo trips,
and keeps her phone switched off.
But, isn't it the first time
we're receiving such a complaint?
Yes, sir!
Get into the vehicle.
Did you enquire about her husband?
He lives all alone
in that house.
Sometimes his
wife comes on leave.
Only then he gets out
of the house.
I heard that he doesn't have
any close friends or relatives.
Is this his native?
It's his own house.
He's from
an inherently affluent family.
He had a job earlier,
somewhere far away.
Something seems fishy.
The people around say that
he's got some disorder.
Didn't I tell you?
He's the one missing!
Huh? Hasn't he left yet?
Huh? I saw him leaving!
Guess he came back.
We enquired about
your wife.
It's likely that she went
on her own will.
Don't worry.
She'll be back soon.
Even if she doesn't,
you don't care, isn't it?
Why doesn't he believe when I say that
Teena is in danger?
Teena went in search of
Rajagopal.
I'm sure about it.
When we questioned
Teena,
she said she isn't even
acquainted with him.
It's because he's
an infirm person...
Sir, I'll deal with this.
I got you into this, hoping to get
some link to the novelist case...
This is the book
Rajagopal gifted my wife,
whom you said she isn't
even acquainted with!
See!
'To Teena. Thanks for writing
the book I couldn't write.'
It's not us who said that
she isn't acquainted with Rajagopal.
Teena herself said that.
Why would Teena tell such a lie
to the police?
What if she has said many such lies,
which you don't know about?
Come.
The way I see it,
Teena is quite creative,
She's pretty,
and is active in social media,
and she's quite younger
than you, too.
So, she might be having
a lot of kinships.
You two just don't match
each other, as I see it.
You don't have kids, too.
You don't even stay together
regularly.
Right?
What did she post in Facebook?
'All credits to my husband'
What does that mean?
'My husband is responsible
for all these'
So if she left you
on her own will,
we can't do anything about it.
Wasn't that a bit too much, sir?
It was intentional.
Until we find Rajagopal
and that girl,
let his name also be there
in the suspect list.
I felt he is a poor soul.
It's because you are one.
You didn't understand that
'all credits' part then.
Let's see!
It's alright. You're continuing
the tablet for pressure, right?
Doctor, last time we gave
these medicines...
- Did you check his BP?
- Yeah, it's normal.
Ok, continue these medicines then.
One moment!
Take them daily once only.
At night.
- Alright. See you.
- See you.
Let's go! Come!
Did you notice the guy
who was sitting in the corridor?
Who?
The guy reading a book.
I felt something special
about him.
- The guy who was sitting
on the side?- Yeah!
Either I've seen him before.
Or, I might see him again.
Haven't you left his topic yet?
Had you come a bit late,
I would've found out all his details.
Hey, have you heard of 'Déjà vu'?
Isn't it the feeling that
you've already seen something
that's happening
right now?
I've heard about it.
Hurry up with those veggies!
It isn't something happened before.
Something you've dreamt of before.
When we see that in reality,
it's Déjà vu.
There's such an interpretation, too.
Likewise,
We might have met someone
in our dreams,
who is going to be
very important in our lives.
And when you see them
in real life,
you feel an instant connection,
a spark, isn't it?
You're talking about the guy
who was at the hospital, right?
Look! 'll smash your head
with this!
He doesn't look like someone,
who would read
English romantic novels.
He doesn't even look like someone
who would read a book!
Hello?
Hey, can you do me a favor?
What's it?
From your hospital,
can you get me the details
of the guy we saw the other day?
You got nothing better to do?
Can't you focus on your studies?
Why troubling others?
I'm studying to become a journalist,
not a doctor!
Get this clear, first!
Ok, let me see.
- I'll call you.
- Okay, bye. - Bye!
Brother, a strong coffee.
Without sugar.
Hey...
His name is Roy Jacob.
I've got his details.
I got 2 files.
One from
the psychology department.
It says that he's got some dream issues
and he's a lucid dreamer...
As it's from the psychology department,
it is confidential, you know...
I couldn't obtain much details.
Then I got another file.
It's about a treatment he
and his wife had, a few years ago.
His sperm count is low.
He can't have children.
In short,
he's a psycho-messed up case,
whom even his wife left.
Listen...
Leave your 'Déjà vu' stuff aside!
So my expectation wasn't wrong.
No wonder why I felt
a difference when I saw him.
Let me go and do something
that could be of use to someone!
Ok?
Hey...
Did you let go of your 'Déjà vu'?
You don't talk about it anymore!
Can you guess where I spend
all my time in the college?
No need to guess it.
Must be in the library.
You never attend classes, right?
He was working
in the same library for 6 years!
Oh! So you know each other
since then?
How could it be?
He was terminated
a year before I joined.
Now I spend all my time
in the same space he was at!
I heard several stories about him
from the college.
It raised my curiosity.
I got his phone number
and talked to him.
Told that I want to meet him.
- Are you going to meet him?
- Yeah!
He has agreed to meet me
at the park near our college.
Is it?
Awesome plan!
Let me sleep then.
Good night!
The last hour was
Parvathy miss' class, right?
Didn't you attend it?
Isn't it been a while
since you left?
You still remember
the time-table?
Well, you said
you liked her class.
Her class is superb.
But, when did I tell you that?
One tea, uh...
One coffee, strong,
without sugar.
Let's sit there.
The coffee you ordered,
is that for me?
Tell me the truth, Roy!
Do you have any
mind-reading skills?
Didn't you order coffee yesterday?
I thought you're diabetic!
Oh, no! I'm not a diabetic!
I love the bitterness of coffee.
There's a sweetness
even in that bitterness!
Exactly!
A famous writer said it
about coffee.
How did you see me
ordering coffee yesterday?
We're meeting for the first time
today, isn't it?
Isn't this the third time?
Don't confuse me!
How could that be?
- First, hospital.
- Okay.
- Then, canteen.
- Canteen?
Were you at the canteen
yesterday?
I called you yesterday
and planned to meet today, isn't it?
Is that so?
Maybe then,
the meeting at the canteen was...
a dream of mine!
Oh!
So, what else did you see
in your dream?
You were quite talkative.
You didn't let me talk much.
Stop bluffing!
What else did I say?
Well.. about your family,
about your best friend,
About me?
Yeah! He's not a messed-up case
as you said!
He's a very interesting man!
Really!
You know that I've never been
able to do mind-reading,
no matter
how hard I try?
But he tells me all these
with so much ease!
Are you planning to meet him
again and again?
You got nothing else to do?
Of course!
How could I miss
such a special specimen?
Anyway, it's okay
as his 'count' is low!
You're safe!
'Don't close the doors to your eyes,
o' the apple of my eye,'
'when you shine as the beam of my life!'
'like I saw you for ages
with my eyes,'
'and saw your glimpses
in my dreams!'
You closed down
your ancestral home,
and is living here all alone.
What's the reason behind that?
I don't have many friends
in my native place.
So you got friends here?
'Blooming as petals,
spilling as a sea,'
'we painted our days.'
'Searching like fingers,
trembling on nudging,'
'our unspoken desires
soared up.'
'When memories shine
as tears in the eyes,'
'sweetness fills in me,
while sinking into you'
- Hey, shall I ask you something?
- Yeah?
Water...
Air...
Fire...
Earth.
Which one would you select?
Why?
I just wanna know,
how romantic Roy is!
- Water.
- Water?
Yes.
Calm, when you look at it.
But when you approach it,
you realize its depth.
The water is usually cold.
But when heated,
it rises as vapour.
Soar up as clouds.
Shower as rain.
As rivers, waves...
And,
it can even turn into a tsunami!
'Don't close the doors to your eyes,
o' the apple of my eye,'
'when you shine
as the beam of my life!'
'Even before meeting,
we met somewhere,'
'on some fantasy-era'
'I become an island
that no one looked for,'
'are you showering on me
as the mist?'
'We shall cross the dark woods,'
'I shall write myself as a dream
on the book that's you'
'Don't close the doors to your eyes,
o' the apple of my eye,'
'when you shine
as the beam of my life!'
Why are you staring
like this?
It's not a dream!
Nobody else has barged into
my life like you!
People have always left me!
I don't understand,
why someone's wife would leave him,
when he is so romantic!
It's got nothing to do with romance.
She left me when she couldn't
tolerate me anymore.
Are they photos?
Listen...
No need to struggle
and read them all!
I've got a... disorder.
I've consulted several doctors,
and these are those files.
Even they
haven't been able to...
diagnose it correctly.
But I'm clear about it.
My dreams, reality,
imagination, they're all mixed up,
and are stored in a jumbled form,
in my mind.
It's quite difficult
to differentiate between them!
But, isn't that awesome?
Not as awesome as you think!
Suppose what happened
between us last night was a dream,
what'd happen if I behave
with the same freedom,
the next time we meet?
Wouldn't our relation end
that very moment?
Get ready.
I'll get you a coffee.
My condition is not as simple
as you think.
It's very difficult for me
to mingle with others,
in my daily life.
It could get so unbearable
for others.
That's why I decided to live alone.
No matter how hard I try,
sometimes I lose it.
And I become a mentally ill man
in front of others.
One life is all we've got.
What's the point in living it
the way everyone else does?
You two are the strangest people
I've ever met.
I've always felt that
she is even crazier.
You are used to living alone.
You should keep in mind that
she got all alone, only for you.
But these cops don't understand it!
Aren't you ashamed to feel dejected,
listening to some random cops?
Don't let her know about
all these.
You would understand, but...
how do I make others understand?
Roy!
Come out of
your complexes first!
She used to always
tell me there's some truth in,
your dreams and intuitions!
That's the reason why
she went looking for that novelist!
No matter how hard I try,
I'm unable to recollect
the place names
I told Teena that night!
It's your sole responsibility
to find Teena without any harm!
You can challenge those people
who don't understand your relation,
and find Teena
without anybody's help!
Only you can do it, Roy!
The bond that I and Teena share
can't be measured with your police brain!
I'm sure that she won't leave me!
I wanted to come and
tell you this.
That's why I came right now.
Otherwise,
I won't be able to sleep!
You don't believe
what I said, right?
I'll search and find Teena!
I thought she went on a casual trip,
when I commented on the post.
As it is Roy who lodged
the complaint,
don't take it lightly.
I know them personally
for many years.
Their emotional bond is
at a level nobody can guess.
- Inquest Deepak in person.
- Okay, sir.
- Isn't he the guy with a publishing house
and a coffee shop? - Yeah!
Ask Suresh, if Teena and Rajagopal
met in that coffee shop.
Okay. Sure.
Hello! Isn't Deepak here?
No, sir. He's gone out.
Why, sir?
Oh! Okay!
Teena spend more time
in this office, than with me.
It's been 2 days
since Teena went missing.
We will enquire. Relax, Roy.
Teena would call you
anytime from now. I'm sure about it.
Her phone is switched off
since last two days.
The last time she called, she said
that she's going to meet the novelist.
You got any info about it?
Listen... 'SI Suresh, Ernakulam'
called you twice.
Well... Keep it there.
- Okay.
- I'll call him back after this.
Yes, sir.
Sir, as you thought,
that photo was clicked
at Deepak's shop.
I too feel that these
two missing cases are connected.
Once one gets resolved,
the other one too should.
I'll get in touch with
all other friends of Teena.
Let's see if we get
any info.
Rajagopal and Teena
are close friends,
and they are writers, too.
And both of them are missing now.
Is there any connection
between these two?
What do you think, Deepak?
Well... that...
I mean...
Well...
Why did Teena
lie to the cops that
she isn't acquainted with
Rajagopal?
Are you acquainted with Rajagopal?
He is Teena's friend.
I've read his books, too.
That's all I know about him.
One moment.
Hello?
Please hold for a moment.
Yes, tell me.
Hey, listen.
I had told Teena that,
Rajagopal was seen
in a bus to Vazhikadavu.
I think she took it a bit seriously.
She took leave
and left the same day.
What if Teena went looking for
Rajagopal sir?
That's what I feel.
Her husband came here
and made a fuss about it.
He also kept saying
this same thing.
In that case, let me enquire.
He is here with me, now.
Nothing to worry, right?
'No!'
- Alright!
- I'll call you later.
'Selvi by Rajagopal'
'To Deepak, with love. Rajagopal'
Teena introduced me to
Rajagopal sir.
The novel that Teena is writing now,
is based on Rajagopal sir's life.
We were about to
launch her book
through my publishing
company, next month.
It was then that
Rajagopal sir went missing,
and all these problems started...
We had signed a contract
with Rajagopal sir,
that nobody will get to know
about this, until the book releases.
Maybe that's why,
Teena lied to the cops
that she doesn't know him well.
Teena strongly wished to settle down
with you, as early as possible.
And I'm in debt due to the loan
I took for starting this company.
It was the necessity of Teena and I,
to release that book soon.
['Let it be' by The Beatles]
'When I find myself in times of trouble,'
'Mother Mary comes to me,'
'Speaking words of wisdom,
let it be'
'And in my hour of darkness,'
'she is standing right in front of me'
'Speaking words of wisdom,
let it be'
'Let it be, let it be,'
'let it be,'
'let it be'
How do you find it
till now?
Liked it?
It's good!
It's very interesting that
you fictionalized it.
So I was right.
It's a hit!
Why don't you
finish it quickly, then?
Isn't that why
I went in search of him?
You didn't tell me that
this was the purpose.
Well...
I thought of letting it be
a surprise for you.
Surprise!
Why do you keep
your phone switched off?
Isn't that why I get worried?
I had lost my phone.
Someone pushed me from behind,
while at the forest.
I was about to come to you.
I got some info to share.
I have some documents,
related to the life of
Rajagopal.
The school in which he studied,
his friends,
the places he visited,
the awards he received,
all such things.
Here!
So this is how Teena
and Rajagopal are connected.
Teena's been writing a book
based on the life of Rajagopal.
It was about to be published
through Deepak's company, soon.
Why is such a great novelist's
life story
being written so secretly?
As someone who's in touch
with huge publishing houses,
why would he publish it
through Deepak's small company?
So, he's got some secrets
to reveal, through this book.
And when the novel was
almost finished,
both of them went missing.
Somebody who doesn't want
these secrets to be revealed,
is behind this.
Who?
It's not my job to investigate it.
It's the job of the police!
Rather than wandering around
in my backyard,
please investigate this.
The lives of two people
are in danger.
Get out of your dreams,
and turn on the TV.
Rajagopal was found
last evening.
Things are not as you think.
Rajagopal went looking
for some relative.
Somebody informed his family,
when he was found lost and worn out.
He's admitted in the hospital now.
Hasn't it been 3 days
since your wife left?
No info about her yet.
That means, as I said,
she went on her own will.
And if at all there's somebody
behind all these,
I'll get hold of him!
What was the reason for
Rajagopal sir to go like this, now?
He's been facing old age issues
for quite some time,
So we don't let him go
anywhere alone, usually.
Was he trying to write
anything new, lately?
Heard such a news.
He had expressed
such a desire,
But his health issues
are a big factor...
How's his health now?
Is there any hope?
What are you hoping for,
actually?
His life was as mysterious
as his novels.
The last book he wrote was
'Selvi', in 1995.
When asked about if
he'd continue writing,
his answer was that
'one more book will be released.'
Despite his fans waiting
for over 20 years,
he wasn't ready to write, yet.
- Soumya!
- Yeah!
I don't think
you'd be able to see him.
The media and cops
are also not allowed.
He's under the control
of his family now.
If we could meet his relatives,
to get any info.
Even the media with
the same request was asked to leave.
Besides, his condition is
a bit serious.
He might be moved to
the ventilator soon.
Well, if we wait for some time,
would it help?
You may leave now.
I'll call you.
Okay.
I'll call Suresh and get
the investigation report of Rajagopal.
We'll get an idea about
the places Rajagopal visited.
Good.
If Teena went in search of
Rajagopal, she'd be somewhere there.
Yeah. Right!
Hearing the news of his return,
chances are that she may return!
But...
Isn't her phone switched off
since last 3 days?
Looking at it that way,
What if there's some truth
in Roy's words?
Tell me clearly.
What if somebody kidnapped
Rajagopal?
What if they attacked, silenced
and left him there?
I understand your angle.
If so, Teena would be under
the custody of those who harmed him.
Right!
As long as Teena can't come out,
this novel too won't.
Right, sir!
Yeah! How did it go?
Saji is still in Chennai,
his wife says.
Would we have to go to
Chennai now?
No, sir. We will consider this
seriously.
- It's better if you follow up.
- Sure, sir.
- You may get into the vehicle.
- Sir!
But then, couldn't they
just finish them off?
Maybe all they want is
to stop that book's release!
You read a lot of thrillers, right?
I watch such movies, sir!
Well!
Let's go!
Hi! Aren't you Teena's husband?
I'm a relative of writer Rajagopal.
I'm the one who stays with him
in the hospital.
He's been making a fuss
about getting you there, right now!
Wanted to discuss
something important, he said.
In the morning,
the place would be crowded.
Well...
can he speak?
The TV reports said that
he's in the ventilator.
It's all just a sham!
He'll be killed the moment
they know that he can speak!
That's why he lies down
silently.
Why so?
If he starts speaking,
he'll shout out everything!
Whatever they did back then!
As he feels guilty now!
Hey...
Don't go that way.
There's a security guard.
There's an ATM.
Let's go that way,
without anyone noticing.
That way. Get in.
This is my condition now.
I can't speak to anyone.
Please ask Teena to...
finish writing that novel
somehow.
Who's that?
Stay right there.
Hello!
Yes?
I told the police about last night,
and they've gone inside.
What?
Last night...
Sorry, I think you got the wrong person.
He isn't reacting to medicines.
There's multiple organ damage, too.
He wasn't eating or drinking
for more than a week, right?
Yeah.. Okay.
Any chances of him to speak?
No.
We're trying to extend his life
somehow.
Okay! Let's go!
Okay.
Why are you so irresponsible?
- Sir!
- Will call you!
Sir, let me get the vehicle!
Sir!
Teena's phone is ringing, sir.
Please try, sir.
Get into the vehicle, you!
It was ringing, sir!
Okay.
Sir, it was really ringing.
Don't you dare say a word!
You should get admitted
to a hospital, if you're mentally ill!
You should be put behind the bars
for cooking up stories
against such a famous novelist!
We should be blamed for listening to
his words and coming all the way here!
Drive towards that
secluded road.
Yeah.
You can say whatever, sir!
But, hadn't I lodged a complaint?
Did you investigate?
Where is Teena?
What crosses my mind is something else!
I wonder how she managed
to live with you all these days!
Such cases should be closed,
stating that she just left her husband.
Enough, sir!
You've said this before, too.
I went to his house the other night,
and gave a nasty reply.
So, he is a bit annoyed with me
because of that.
You're not able to find Teena
because it's still in his mind.
What are you talking about?
You can't just enter the flat
where he lives.
There are security guards.
Without his permission,
nobody can enter that place.
He's been scolding you
because you babble such things!
Come on. Hop in.
You may take your car
and go home.
I gotta go to the station.
And...
Eventhough sir just keeps saying
whatever he feels,
he's a very capable officer.
I know that
my disorder can cause
difficulties and
confusion to others.
But...
To tell me what's real
and what's not,
all I have is my Teena.
In the eyes of others,
I may be mentally ill.
Do you remember him
hurting my feelings, at the police station?
By mentioning that
Teena just left me?
What if,
I believe it and imagine
or dream about it?
My brain would then tell myself,
that it's the truth!
Luckily I met Teena's friend
Aswathy on the road.
She is the only one who knows
the depth of our relationship.
With the motivation
that she gave me,
I went ahead
and started investigating it.
But now...
No matter whether you
close this case or not,
I gotta find my Teena, right?
Hello, doctor?
I'm Asif, who's investigating
Teena's case.
Yeah. Tell me.
You got any info?
Not yet. Where are you now?
You said you were in Delhi, right?
Did you come here
recently?
No, I'm still in Delhi.
What happened?
Well... Nothing, doctor.
I'll call you later.
Thank you.
Okay. Yeah.
Sir! They had called
from the cyber cell, twice.
Asked you to call them back
urgently.
I'll call them.
Sir, Teena's number was switched on
for some time, this afternoon.
- No calls were made, though.
- Is it? - Yeah.
Did you trace the location?
It's a forest area
near Tamilnadu border.
Chinnathodu.
Whatsapp me the location
immediately.
- Okay?
- Okay, sir!
Yes, sir!
Hello? Brother?
Yes, Deepak.
Don't expect anything
from the police now.
They say that
Teena just left me.
D.. Deepak...
Listen to me carefully,
and trust my words.
I'm sure that Teena is
inside the forest.
She told me that
she lost her phone there.
Even he told me the same,
at the hospital.
Not just that,
It's written in Teena's book that
he and his friends go hiking in the forest.
Well... Brother...
I've reached Vazhikkadavu now.
Tracing
Rajagopal sir's route,
and Teena's last tower location,
I came here.
Now,
as you said, it is a forest area
from here.
Yeah...
Can you tell me your location?
I'll come there.
There's a guesthouse
of a friend of mine.
I'll give you the address.
And,
They don't let the cars in,
after 6PM.
You may come tomorrow morning.
I'll be here.
Hello?
Brother?
'Shall I tell you
where the missing ones are?'
[Indistinct instructions]
Chandran!
Yes, sir!
Have you seen this person?
Who's it?
It's a missing case,
from town.
She... I was about to call you.
Just a moment.
Sir! Chirutha got this
from the forest.
She gave it to me
when I was on rounds.
Thought of giving it to you
when I come to town.
It was switched off
when I got it.
When I woke up,
I turned it on once.
And when a call came, I turned it off
Hello?
Sir! Teena's phone
is in Chinnathodu station.
We'll have to issue a search order for
at least 3km around that tower location.
- I'll get it done.
- Okay, sir!
Pass this info to all stations
on that route.
Sure, sir.
As Roy said,
I sense a threat to her.
Did you call and inform him?
No, sir. As we didn't get
a clear picture...
What if the clear picture
is disastrous?
He's the complainant, too!
Call him and inform this
right now!
Hello?
It's me, SI Asif.
Please come to the station
at 10AM.
Got an info to share.
Wanted to discuss it in person.
Sir, I'm on the way to Chinnathodu.
Chinnathodu?
Yes. Teena is in
some forest nearby there.
How do you know that?
Hello?
Sir, he is on the way
to Chinnathodu, he says!
How did he get to know
that location?
That's what even I'm wondering.
When we got into
the right path,
is he playing
a different trick now?
How did you come here?
In my car.
Let me get ready.
- Let's reach Chinnathodu
as quick as possible. - Okay, sir.
- Isn't this SI Manikandan?
- Yes! - I'm the CI.
Tell me, sir.
We don't know
what the situation would be.
The ambulance and
medical team should be ready.
Sure, sir. We're already here.
Sir, don't we have to
inform the checkpost?
I'll call them.
Yeah.
Yes, sir. What was the color
of the car? A green one?
Yeah. A light green...
- well... Padmini.
- Number?
8585. Right?
Yes, sir.
Yeah.
Shall we block him, sir?
Yeah, stop him for just a while.
- We'll reach by then.
- Alright, sir.
Let him go only when
we ask you to.
Okay, sir.
'Chinnathodu'
Ask SI Manikandan
to come here.
I've shared the live location, sir.
Are SI Manikandan and team here?
Yes, sir. They're here.
Yeah.
Please go search in there.
Okay, sir!
Hey! Look inside
these rooms!
Sir, a room is locked here.
Just force it open!
Check if she's breathing!
Ask them to get the stretcher!
Hey! Where are you going?
Move aside!
Take him away!
- Come here!
- Entering a crime scene and...
T.. there...
Move the hands.
- Sir, it's Teena!
- Move her away from the dirt.
Hasn't the stretcher
arrived yet?
Ask them to hurry up!
Come on! Hurry!
Go! Go!
Place her on it.
Keep the hand properly.
Okay!
Careful! Slowly!
You didn't expect us here,
did you?
When did you
dump her here?
Rajagopal and his friends
killed and buried someone here,
years back!
All these are happening
so that this news doesn't go out!
How many times did I tell you,
that Teena's life is in danger?
- Get the complete history
of this house. - Sir!
Who owned this place,
who is the current owner...
Okay, sir.
And the forest guard
who got her phone,
- Yeah.
- Question him, too.
Ok.
We should know
if anybody used to visit here.
Ok.
Only once we know the details
and history of Rajagopal and his friends,
we can assure if Roy has
a point or not.
Ok.
If any of them are connected
to this forest or house in anyway,
gotta find that, too.
Why did Teena come to this forest?
How did Roy spot it
correctly?
Anyway, get her statement
once she's conscious.
Ok, sir.
- And follow it up correctly.
- Sure.
Okay, thank you!
Teena!
Aren't you okay?
You got any difficulty
in speaking?
The police officers
are here.
They want to meet you.
Okay?
Teena?
On the other day, you said
you didn't know Rajagopal personally.
The book that I'm writing
is based on his life.
I had an agreement that
I'd keep it a secret.
Why did you go inside the forest?
I was hoping to find Rajagopal sir
and complete my book.
What happened inside the forest?
I felt like somebody was
following me.
Somebody pushed me down
from behind.
When I regained consciousness,
I was in that house.
Oh...
Was your book revealing any secrets
related to Rajagopal's life?
As per his words,
such things are there.
But he didn't tell me
what they are.
So I don't know.
These are hard to believe.
Did the doctor say
anything else?
No, sir.
There's been no sign of
physical abuse, or attempt to it.
She's worn out due to
not eating for all these days.
She'll get discharged
today, or tomorrow.
Roy's tower location didn't change,
unlike you suspected.
On those days,
he was at home itself.
The neighbors too confirmed it.
SI Manikandan sir had called.
The forest guard doesn't know
anything in particular.
And he says it's a haunted house!
Did you check the owner
of the house?
The legal papers, history,
such things?
Somebody encroached that land
and built it.
The department
recaptured it later.
Manikandan sir and forest
department are investigating it.
There's another info.
The college in which Rajagopal
studied,
It is just 15KM away from
this forest.
And...
The tales we heard about him
weren't quite decent!
So, you suggest that,
we should take Roy's words
into account, and investigate the case?
Why do we have to
investigate it, sir?
The missing ones are back.
And about the house,
let the police from that area
investigate it.
But yet,
what if Roy's words are true?
There is a villain in this case.
The one who shut
Rajagopal quiet,
and the one
who locked Teena up.
You do this.
Get me all the details
related to both these cases.
Alright.
And Asif,
Get me the phone numbers
of everyone involved in this.
Let me see.
Okay.
Deepak had called.
Rajagopal sir...
There's no hope left
for his recovery, he said.
If you're gonna tell me about
going back to your job immediately,
I don't wanna hear it.
I resigned from my job.
I'm not going back there.
It isn't a dream, Roy!
I've decided to complete
that book.
Deepak has informed the media
about this.
Whatever I wrote till now...
was based on
what Rajagopal sir told me.
I'll continue writing
with what Roy told me.
Until I finish writing it,
can you be with me?
Let me go check.
I'm CI Ajith.
I was there at the location
that day.
How's your health now?
Alright. It's fine.
Heard that your book
is getting released.
So are you done with
writing?
The last portions
are in progress.
We gotta release the book
as early as possible.
Your statement
says that,
Rajagopal didn't tell you anything
about the final portions.
And you went there,
looking for it.
Then, how will you
complete it?
Teena...
you were assaulted,
and Rajagopal was put
in this condition.
There's someone behind this.
Don't you have any desire
to bring them before the law?
I intend to do that also,
by publishing this book.
In that case,
you know what it is!
Why don't you share it
with us then?
See...
Roy is the one
who told me all these.
How can I share them as
authentic statements then?
And then,
as it is my book, I have the freedom
to write whatever I want.
What Roy told me is that,
Rajagopal and his friends killed
and buried someone in that house.
In that case, are the co-convicts
behind all these?
Anyway, it'll all be
in the book, right?
Let the book get released then.
If its contents are true,
whoever's hiding now
will come out!
If not, we will get them out!
You know that the college
where Rajagopal studied
is near that forest,
right?
- Yeah.
- I had inquired about it.
We've got a report of the people
who went missing during those years.
Around 18 missing cases were
registered in that area back then.
In 15 cases,
people either returned,
or convicts were arrested
and the cases closed.
In the remaining 3 cases,
we haven't got any hints yet.
These are the copies
of those case files.
Means,
The one who was killed
and buried by Rajagopal and friends,
is someone from these files.
There is a chance.
What she told me
that day was,
the trail to find herself.
Shall I tell you where
the missing ones are?