Awful weather.
Nobody would want to go outside now.
But...
but just the right weather
to tell stories.
Neither poacher stories,
nor hunter's latin.
No, only...
a story...
of a dog.
One often says: "It's a pity that dogs can't speak"
But that isn't always right.
You just have to able to listen carefully...
and be patient.
Then everything falls into place.
And you know exactly,
how it was.
Yes.
I even know,
where she was found,
the Bella.
Imagine a big factory,
an iron factory.
Bigger than you can imagine.
Thousand of workers...
What am I saying? Many more.
And everybody from the most different countries.
Only I couldn't live there,
without the mountains and the forest.
And just in middle,
a little, stray dog.
Lost, forgotten, gone astray,
How should I know?
It's not that important.
Only among humans, you have to know always,
where somebody is from,
and what's the name.
She didn't even have a name back then,
the puppy.
But she was cheeky,
from early on.
Cheeky and without fear.
Hey...
Bella!
Bella piccolina!
That was her first name.
And she kept it for a long time.
A nice name.
And especially because
it was giving to her without hesitation,
without a thought.
From heart, so to say.
From love at first sight.
Yes it was love at first sight,
between the italian foreign worker and the little dog.
Nobody should say that something like this doesn't exist.
This love is often much stronger...
than the one between humans.
Perhaps because
animals can be grateful.
Grateful for every look,
a nice word, for a petting,
yes and naturally for the daily milk, too.
And concerning loyalty,
well everybody of us can learn
from such a little thing.
From waking till the end of work,
there's only one thought for a dog:
the master.
Finished.
But among humans, oh dear,
who always thinks of the others?
Ciao bella, ciao bella!
Here, Bella, here.
Good girl...
Ciao bella, ciao, ciao bella.
Here, come here.
Scusa mi bella, fine fine...
Fine... Fine...
Well, let me continue telling the story.
There were big chimneys...
and the little dog.
Bella, Bella, come here.
Fine.
No...
No... no...
For our little four legged friend,
life could have continued this way.
Until dog-eternity.
But that's not life.
Nor dog-life.
You don't stay a little dog.
With every bottle of milk you grow a little
and a little.
[unintelligible dialog]
[Italian]
Tina, a mi fidanzata.
Mille grazie, Signorina.
[Italian]
Prego.
Signorina Tina.
Una lettera per te.
Grazie.
[Italian]
Ciao.
Bella, ciao bella...
Come stai, bella bella?
[Italian]
Bloody mutt.
How say?
I said bloody mutt.
Nothing, bloody mutt.
Creatures are not allowed here.
Learn german, then you can read it.
She does nothing, nobody.
Out with the mutt.
Attention Mister.
Out!
Youuu...
Ow!
My dog... my dog...
you kicked her.
Nothing or nobody may dare.
I break you... I break you.
We deliver the steal beams exactly on time.
I just ask myself, if you're ready then.
That depends on the weather, but even more on the workers.
Telephone, Mr. engineer, telephone.
Engineer Witte.
What?
Well, do you have to come to me for everything?
Who?
I see, Scalzi again.
Bring him here.
Always the foreign workers.
Trouble?
Scalzi is a brilliant locksmith.
But again and again we have problems with him.
Women affairs?
No, brawls.
As far as I'm concerned, you can have him.
Consider him.
What's going on with you again?
This guy always has got this mutt,
that's forbidden.
And he sets it on people.
Why did he set the dog on you?
I just said, it's forbidden.
And after all, it's a vicious creature.
No way. Come here.
What's its name?
Bella, Mister.
[Italian]
Nice dog.
You're a fine dog.
Would you like to come with me?
Come? With you?
I need a good locksmith and you need another environment.
Environment?
We build a cable railway.
Into the glaciers.
A spoiled dog.
Sorry.
Why don't you train your dog better?
That's a purebred animal, a hunting dog.
It has to be trained.
I understand something about dogs.
Bella, come!
So, red wins,
black loses.
Here.
This one!
Trick.
But why?
You just have to pay more attention.
You have got damn bad eyes for a hunter.
Don't bully me all the time.
Another one?
Yes, sure.
There,
once again.
Red wins,
black loses.
Thank you, Mr. engineer.
You're welcome.
Well look here.
Our Mr. Engineer plays the elegant gentleman.
Kubesch, come here!
It's a pity.
I had a lucky streak.
Now I would've won for sure.
Yes, sure, sure.
Here.
Well, thanks.
So many love letters?
Ah, thanks.
Well, it's not surprising.
What do I have to do, to write such a letter, too?
That's not so difficult.
Please tell me.
Visit me sometime.
It'd be my pleasure.
Hauptplatz 14.
May I see you soon.
See you soon.
The new assistant forester?
Yes.
Let's go.
There you go.
Mr. engineer?
Transport these things to the material warehouse and give this man a lift.
What? That Macaroni there?
And show him his quarters.
Am I a tourist guide?
Kubesch, you drank again.
That's right Mr. engineer.
But only mineral water.
That's alright.
The private chauffeur is on the spot.
Thanks, but I can't accept that.
Hey,
slowly Macaroni.
Only people, humans drive with me
in the front,
capisce?
Foreign workers and dogs belong in the back.
[Italian]
Tell me, my dear...
Pepi, please.
Name's Pepi.
Josef really, but...
Pepi's shorter.
Why? Joseph has got only 2 syllables, too?
Right,
but it depends on how you say it.
JOSEF!
or...
Pepi.
Well then, my dear Josef..
Pepi, you're a local, aren't you?
Yes, well, a local as I am,
you'll not never ever nowhere find again.
Well great, but then you surely know the house at Hauptplatz number 14.
Well you bet I know that.
That's the Raiffeisen bank.
Thanks, good bye,
bye.
Kissing your hand.
My adoration,
Ms. Angelika. I'd like to apologize a thousand times,
because I haven't shown my face in a long time.
I have been over to Rosenheim.
How was business Mr. Zingerl?
Wonderful.
And that makes you sad?
Yes, because it makes not sense, that I make that much money,
Ms. Angelika. Couldn't you change your mind and...
Don't start with that again.
No.
I'm just here...
I wanted to deposit something and...
Well that...
you can do easily.
The counters are open. Especially for depositors.
But you know exactly Ms. Angelika,
I only do that at yours.
Thanks. Let's go.
Yes, let's go.
Please.
Oh, dear.
That's a hard nut to crack.
She is purportedly a reputable person.
What's that now? Reputable...
That there's nothing on her,
which is not reputable.
Nothing at all.
Nonsense.
How's the fair womanhood in the forester's house?
Well, there's just Katja.
How old?
Past 17.
Oh!?
No Katja, you stay at home today.
That's going to be a long stalk today.
I'll probe the Mr. assistant forster a bit.
Perhaps he leave on his own then.
We don't need anybody there, do we Katja?
So, here I am.
Good day. I'm the new ...
Well I can guess that.
Pepi is not stupid enough to bring the wrong one.
Well...
Had a good trip?
Thanks, very good.
Great. Then we can start with a little stalk.
Fine. Then I get to know everything.
Everything? That can't be done before tomorrow evening.
Oh. Tomorrow evening?
Sure. But if you feel too tired...
No, not at all.
In the meantime, you'll handle the salt...
Yes.
and about Katja, she has to be bathed again.
Yeah yeah.
But don't take her to bed with you again. You know I can't stand that.
She likes it just so much.
Why do you scowl like a courting capercaillie cock?
Nothing...
nothing at all.
What was I going to tell?
About Bella..
that is...
Picco Bella, to be exact,
the way she was called that time.
What she got to know here
was something completely new for her:
Nature.
Bella
What's up?
Outrageous!
Sorry.
Bad dog. Porta, bring!
What did you do?
[Italian]
Bruto.
Hm, ok.
Now hurry up!
Away with the dog!
She always rides along.
I don't care what it always did.
It doesn't drive with me.
She's harmless.
Shut up Macaroni and don't dictate me.
Or I'll make paste schuta out of you.
Ha, pasta schuti with macaroni,
bon appetito.
Where's the bitch now?
Get in, Marcello.
Away!
Away?
Good fortune.
Now,
off you go!
When you come back down, you'll have a unpleasant surprise.
Well, he had it coming.
They had to bring in Macaroni.
Disgusting.
If you don't like macaroni, eat dirt.
Ah, who talks about food.
I mean the italian foreign workers.
I tell you, it comes to...
Stay here when I talk to you.
Ow!
No trouble!
The boss doesn't like that at all.
Your boss,
Your boss lives off my money, which I pay here for the schnapps.
Well Mr. Zingerl, what's eating you?
Me? No Luzie, my heart.
Come on. You've got heartaches.
A man with such a hard padded heart.
Nothing but printed paper.
That's no protection for a heart.
But the best medicine to heal weak hearts.
It will come to that, I tell you.
The Macaroni will snatch away our girls.
You don't have to be afraid for Luzie.
Luzie, it's not about Luzie.
It's a matter of principle.
In principle, the Macaroni will snatch away our girls.
I understand. You want to set up a savings account.
Si, si savings account.
Then, you just need to...
fill this out.
Please,
prego,
Signorina you help me.
I beg you.
Okay then. What's our name?
My name is Marcello Scalzi.
And yours?
Mine? Why mine?
You say what's "our" name.
"our" is "I", "you".
You're a trickster.
You speak german perfectly.
No no no.
I can nothing.
No none nothing german.
Bruta Bestia.
Sorry.
Ah, it's stupid of me to be scared of a dog.
Good dog, good dog.
I show you how good.
Yes yes, I believe you.
Please, you have to let me show.
Bella,
Yes.
good,
fine dog.
Well, well.
Nobody should say,
that a dog doesn't feel it,
if it loses a bit of its master's love.
A animal can be just as jealous
as a human.
Bella! [Italian]
[Italian]
Come here. Very bad dog.
She doesn't like me, only because I am afraid of dogs.
Why?
When I was a little child, I was bitten by a dog.
What is...
"little child"?
Bambino.
Ah no bambino, bambina.
Big difference
and very good difference.
Bella!
[Italian]
Oh...
Fine...
Fear not,
amore, every day [Italian]
Today po da amore, tomorrow po da amore
and tomorrow, tomorrow
grande amore.
Please put your dog on a leash.
We're just going for a walk.
It's forbidden.
Forbidden in the elevator, forbidden in the house, forbidden in the forest.
Always forbidden, forbidden, forbidden.
If you don't it the way it is here, go back to where you came from.
Calm down.
That's alright, isn't it?
Good day, Angelika!
Good day.
Marcello Scalzi, this is Wegrainer Gustl.
I'd wish for a grandfather like him.
Perhaps I am.
If your grandmother was as pretty as you,
why not?
A lovely doggy.
Well why do you stand there like a stag on the shooting range.
Come in, the lady doesn't bite.
Well the new assistant forester you wrote me about.
Only good things, I hope.
To be honest, no. My brother ranted and raved about you.
Yes I know. I'm a thorn in his side.
Nonsense. I would have operated out a thorn long ago.
He's not that bad.
Thanks.
But I still can't do anything.
I might have studied the theory from textbooks.
But in the forest, you stand there like a young rabid at new moon.
You become meaner every year.
He doesn't mean that.
I'm afraid he does.
Luggage is in the room, madam.
Thanks, Pepi.
And you, don't give him a hard time.
I hope there something better for dinner today.
Oh yes...
Well, thank god.
Well,
you like our young lady, don't you?
Yes and how I like her.
I like her more than...
Than who? Than who?
Well, more than everyone I've seen before.
Well, then take care,
that you don't get your fingers burned.
I'm afraid, that's not the right place.
Well, at first you talk big about going out and the like.
And then you back down.
That's not how it is.
I just wanted to spare you the event and
all its consequences.
What consequences?
That's no social gathering for noble daughters.
You think I'm a noble daughter?
Here you express your feelings without any formality.
Do you mean to say by this, that you have feelings?
And how!
Interesting.
And this exhausts your frank utterance of emotions.
Absolutely not. One talks with each other, too.
For example?
"I like you.", or "I'm crazy for you."
And how do I react?
Oh, you know that, certainly.
But you act surprised and ask: "Since when?"
Since when?
Since the first moment.
I was even jealous of your brother.
Why?
He held you in his arms and kissed you.
Brothers are allowed to.
Only brothers?
It depends.
Yes,
it depends.
Yes with love,
it's its own thing.
One falls in love because of defiance
or at least thinks, has fallen in love.
And others,
they don't realize they love each other already.
Every day by poco amore,
today by poco,
and tomorrow by poco,
and tomorrow-tomorrow...
great amore.
I like coming here.
Strange, isn't it?
yeah,
it's so nice to live.
Why visit the dead?
A graveyard is full of stories.
Over there lies a girl and the tombstone reads:
"Engaged with Andreas Weiz"
And this Andreas?
His name is on the war memorial.
Half a year after he fell, she died too.
The people here say: "because of a broken heart".
It's not good, die for love.
It's good, live for love.
I believe you can't choose that.
Come no.
Madonna says:
"love...
the whole world".
But...
because the whole world
is to big for a single person,
one has to...
choose another person
and love him.
For the whole world.
Well I was looking forward to finally see something pretty again.
I wouldn't have to be a herd of monarchs.
A herd of monarchs.
Well, these only exist in Heimatfilms. In the past,
we had our hands full, shooting the game.
Today, we are happy if we get to see anything.
And who's fault is that, Mathias?
Who's at fault when nature perishes? The human.
You mean, it was shot to much?
No, the blessing of the much praised technology. That's it.
The water reservoir for example. It drove off most of the game population.
Different climatic and vegetative conditions.
Sounds of machines, noise of people.
And what did I tell you yesterday?
Look there!
There look, the dog!
These Italians are terribly people, especially if they are in love.
Bella [Italian]
We eat together.
What's wrong?
I don't like the look of it.
Listen, I am sorry, but even over at the Törl, there's no trace of chamois.
They must be have changed over to the Kar.
Well, what did I tell you Petra? No game far and wide.
There you go.
Thanks.
Well, what do your textbooks tell you about the wind?
Well south wind. This means change of weather.
Taking half hourly barometer readings...
Well, do you by chance carry a barometer?
Naturally not.
Well now that's stupid. Were do we take the readings?
Perhaps from the sky? Look up sometime.
What do you think is going on
Well, that means...
That means, we have to return home quickly.
Sooner or later, there will be a great snowstorm.
What was that?
As a hunter you should know how a gunshot sounds.
Yes, but that could only be a poacher.
Yes, with all logical foresight, there's only this possibility.
Mathias, you're just hostile to him.
I can't stand those vain theorists.
But he isn't one.
Oh, I see. You already concerned yourself with this Mister?
And what if it would be so?
I'm old enough actually.
What for?
To form my own opinion.
There's more about Bernd than you think.
Well he has to show that first.
Give me.
Stop! Freeze!
I said, freeze!
I am standing here the whole time.
Where's your rifle?
What rifle?
Don't play-act. You shot just now.
Oh, somebody shot?
Well, who could that be?
You accurately will be told that.
You are under arrest.
I!?
Arrested?
Well,
can't do anything about it.
Watch out, falling rocks!
Come out. It's of no use.
Well that's typical of that old crook.
Yes and I am the disgraced.
Don't worry, Bernd.
No forester ever could stand up to Gustl Wegrainer.
Ah, I was right then. He does poach.
Since he's able to hold a rifle.
You know that and don't do anything against it?
Correct. But he's only shooting with blanks.
Dirty trick.
Well now that doesn't suit you, too.
The Wegrainer Gustl is in principle a much better hunter than most.
He doesn't have to shoot at all costs, like those, who don't care...
and who shoot too, if the game is starved in the winter.
What's the real hunter's passion?
It's the stalking.
And if you get a good look on the buck you're after.
And you are sure to place a good shot.
then you pull the trigger.
What's happening then...
has more in common with butchery...
than with the art of hunting.
Yes, Gustl always takes the best of the hunt.
And he will be grateful for ever,
that you just gave him the feeling today, to be a poacher.
Are there still actual poachers?
Oh yes.
I don't understand that.
Today it's much easier to buy game in a venison store.
Today's poachers are the lords of the hunting grounds,
who shoot the bucks who weren't approved by their own hunters.
M hm,
it's starting now.
What?
You cannot do that!
Hello! Hello!
What's up?
You cannot ride the material elevator.
The storm is too strong.
Not ride?
That doesn't work, else broken.
Better feel cold here, then break your neck.
I have to get down.
That's not going to work, Marcello.
If not going, I go.
Bella!
Man, you're crazy. You can't see your hand in front of your face.
I have to get down. Addio.
Let go of your rendezvous then.
Bella.
If you misstep in the wall, you'll fall to your death.
Awful weather,
it's snowing on the top.
At this season.
This only happens once in a blue moon.
Well look around.
It's a crime how badly this bank is secured against burglary.
Why?
No bars.
The safe is sardine can for nitro blowtorches.
You think?
One really ponders,
to bring your money here.
Tell me about it.
Good day, you still know me. Kubesch is my name. Ferdinand Kubesch.
I'd like some information.
Sure.
Concerning an account for me.
A checking account.
Well I don't know the nicknames of these things.
I think of an account, where I get more
money back then I
payed in.
A savings account.
Yes, I think that's it.
Bella.
For heavens sake.
Marcello's rosary.
Something must have happened.
Mr. Burger, please cover for me at the counter.
Of course.
Come, well come,
Mr. engineer.
Yes.
Something must have happened, to Marcello.
Nothing happened.
He had to stay at mid-station with the other workers.
We couldn't risk using the material elevator.
But look at the dog.
Something has happened.
It brought this. Marcello's rosary.
He wouldn't be that crazy...
Calm yourself down.
We talk to the mid-station.
He's there for sure.
Hm, the line is torn.
We call the mountain rescue service.
Police Department Kaprun.
Ok, I'll go fetch the people.
Soo.
Telephone.
Well and?
Well.
Hello?
Forest administration.
Someone's stuck in the rock face.
Just a moment.
Gimme!
Yes. ...
the climbing iron rope.
My things too.
We will fetch the dog shortly.
You stay here, it's difficult enough to get one person out of the wall.
I bring to your attention, that I am obliged
to participate in every rescue operation.
Well then...
We notify you, as soon as we find him.
Thanks, gentlemen.
Well then.
Look, your rope unfastened. I tuck it in there.
They are coming already.
Thank God!
I can't stand this rain.
Come!
Awful weather.
Let's march.
No, thanks.
Drink.
You don't help anybody, if you torture yourself.
Stupid of me.
Strange.
What?
I planed to talk with you.
And now, we sit together and it doesn't work again.
It doesn't work?
Well,
I can guess already.
Let's leave it.
It doesn't suit some people in the village.
It's not meant this way.
That's nobody's business.
Is an italian a worse person?
These things doesn't have anything to do with nationality.
Then what you're saying is, that Marcello is bad person.
Not that either.
But I want to save you from disappointment.
Love is something different than living your life together.
Only if you are very lucky,
both things come together.
I know, in the beginning you always think,
you belong together because you love.
You only think that because you want it to be.
But why shouldn't we belong together?
I never knew,
a man could be this tender.
This touching and funny.
Do you understand that?
I do, but in every person there are different things, too.
Marcello for example is hot-tempered beyond measure.
I met him as he nearly killed a person.
It's no use to talk him down.
I don't want to.
I just wanted to make clear,
that fitting together is not as easy
as one would like it to be.
You should have seen that.
She became completely pale as the dog came in through the door.
White as the wall.
And why? Because the fears for her dirty Macaroni.
That's a disgrace.
These, these foreigners take away our poshest girls.
Do we need that?
Yes, hear, hear!
Well, if she was yours. Please, whatever.
But Ms. Raiffeisen bank executive,
that's entirely different.
Schnucki, another one.
Another one? That's already the forth.
So what? I do pay.
It's just because of the driving.
After the 8th double, I drive best.
You really have to think about
depositing your money in this bank.
You don't have anything to pay in.
Good one.
That's not funny,
suddenly you money is gone.
Don't talk nonsense.
Ms. Hirt embezzling. That's outrageous.
Not her. But the foreign workers.
There are enough crooks among them.
I wouldn't be surprised,
if he just came on to her,
to access the bank more easily.
In the night.
Here I am,
here!
He's hanging below there.
You can't do anything now.
The wind will blow you out of the wall.
We have to wait until the storm calms down.
Hopefully, he can hold on that long.
Help!
I go get him.
Don't try a bravura performance.
Let's go.
I can't bear it.
We cannot do anything at all.
I go meet him.
Just part of the way.
I'll come along.
Marcello!
Marcello.
I didn't happen much.
He sprained his ankle
and he's a bit frozen.
Bring him in to me.
I call the doctor.
Yes, then everything's fine.
Good bye.
Marcello, don't talk.
He takes her home every night.
But he only leaves in the morning.
Gossip, nothing else but gossip
Well, ask Kubesch.
He saw it with his own eyes.
Alright, Mr. Kubesch?
What's up?
Ms. executive with the Macaroni.
Luzie, don't defame.
Perhaps they only drink coffee at night.
Italians are said to have a thing for drinking coffee.
I put it behind the counter.
I'll come to pick it up later.
What's inside?
You better take an interest in your guests, Schnucki.
Charming as always.
A schnapps.
I don't drink today. Beat it!
Strange,
I have to get it sometime.
Got everything?
Don't yell!
Everything's okay.
You really believe today?
Yes. All funds are in the safe.
I don't know.
But I do.
Let's still wait.
For what?
Until the love of the Macaroni is gone?
Wait.
That's how you do it.
You always have to know when
and where.
Yes,
back then,
there still was game up here.
For the love of --
everything...
has changed now
because of...
the water reservoir.
I think you don't listen to me at all, do you?
Oh, yes, we do, certainly.
Isn't that right, Marcello?
Yes.
Then what did I just tell?
About the monarch stag at Schmiedinger Kees.
That was exactly half an hour ago.
Oh, it's that late,
I have to get home.
I take you.
No, with this foot?
Yes.
Because...
if I walk that way,
it takes longer...
and I stay longer with you.
He knows an answer to everything.
Good night, Gustl.
Good night.
And thank you very much.
A wouldn't know what for.
And if an alarm system is build in after all?
I can tell you, there isn't one in the basement.
Go on.
Don't bustle around that long, start already.
Yeah yeah.
And you really believe we can frame him?
Don't bother.
The people know already that he creeps about at night.
And if she says, that he was with her?
She won't say that. No woman admits such a thing.
Go on already.
No, Marcello.
The people talk already.
Please go home.
People talk. What's difference?
It,
it makes a difference.
What?
I tell you that tomorrow. It's too late today.
Good night.
Good night, Angelina.
[Italian]
What a mess.
The Macaroni's bloody mutt.
The beast will wake the whole neighborhood.
Come!
Bloody, miserable dog.
Bella.
My dog! [Italian]
[Italian]
Somebody broke a window.
What is going on there?
What happened here?
Ah, inspector.
It happened this way,
Rappold Felix and I came along here
and heard something suspicious.
And?
And we then saw, how the guy tinkered with the bars.
That's not true.
He jumps him..
and then "this" happened.
I have to arrest you.
The man is dead.
Come along.
Back you beast.
Ready.
He was charged with manslaughter.
In his trial.
The court retires for deliberation.
Thank God!
Okay, let's go inside...
Two or three years.
You never know.
Good question.
Don't be afraid, he is going to get what he deserves.
It won't take long.
A completely clear case.
I don't know.
It could have been an accident.
An accident.
At two o'clock in the night at the bank.
What was the Macaroni doing there?
You could say the same about Rappold.
Precisely not.
Rappold wasn't the boyfriend...
of Ms. bank executive.
I don't understand at all,
why the court didn't go into the break-in attempt.
That's a mean lie. He didn't break in.
You say that.
You would have said that too, if the break in succeeded.
Perhaps you would have given him an alibi, too.
That he was with you at the time of the offense.
The Mister Heart-breaker.
Ugh.
A cigarette?
Thanks.
Please enter. The hearing continues.
Ah, now the Macaroni gets what he deserves.
Come, so we don't miss anything.
The defendant Marcello Scalzi
is hereby convicted of the crime of manslaughter
according to §140 criminal law...
and will be ...
according to §142 criminal law...
Bella!
What's going on here?
Now we also have mutts in the courtroom.
That's not the dogs fault.
Bella.
How did it come in here?
Bella. Bella.
May I?
[Italian]
Addio Bella.
Quiet Bella.
Nice and quit.
Yes.
Everything is going to be alright.
Stay quiet.
Background: The defendant Marcello Scalzi...
is hereby convicted of the crime of manslaughter...
according to §140 criminal law...
and will be according to §142 criminal law...
with the use of §265a code of criminal procedure...
sentenced to two years in prison.
In life
things never turn out the way
you wish.
Not ever.
And different
for everybody.
That's difficult for a man
who loves freedom.
The sun, the independence.
Angelika moved to Vienna,
to the head office.
She immersed,
a colorless particle
in the office machinery.
And for Bella,
a new life started too.
Bella!
Bella! Come here!
You can't just go hunting.
You're not allowed.
No!
Bad, that's very bad.
Give that to me.
Don't you want to become a good hunting dog?
You still have much to learn.
Our Bella traced the poor animal.
Otherwise it would have perished.
I tell you, Ms. Petra,
she's going to be the best hunting dog,
we ever had.
Many things have changed here in general.
Yes,
yes the assistant forester, too.
He, too.
He's so hardworking.
We didn't expect that of him.
I and Mr. Forester.
Never!
Petra,
you disloyal thing.
Why did you let us down on Christmas?
I was invited, you know.
Ah, doesn't matter. The main thing is that you're here now.
How long do you stay?
I have to leave very soon.
I'm going to go on a skiing vacation in Kitzbühel.
And now I thought you stay a little.
Ah no. Rather not.
If not because of me, then because of Bernd.
I thought you don't think much of him?
One's allowed to mistaken once in a while.
No, no! He's a great guy.
I thought he cares about you.
Yes, that's what I thought, too.
What does that mean?
That means, your observation skills are miserable for a hunter.
He cares about someone completely different.
Nonsense. You stay at least until he comes back.
No.
Where is he?
He is in Vienna.
Yes.
You have a visitor.
I do?
Bella!
To me!
Good girl.
It's not allowed to come to me at all?
It's now.
Go.
Bella!
How happy she is.
And you,
are you happy, too?
Yes,
I am happy.
And that makes me happy.
Please, take a seat.
Thanks.
How I must look...
Pale and sad.
But that's hardly surprising.
You don't belong here.
There's much you have to tell me.
What's new in Kaprun.
I want to know everything,
even the gossip.
No,
there's no gossip about you anymore.
On the contrary,
the people start to feel bad because you're gone.
[Italian]
Grazie.
Recipient unknown.
[Italian]
Tell her
he is in prison
because he murdered someone.
Marcello [Italian]
[Italian]
Cut it short, Dimitri!
Murdered. Done.
[Italian]
Now, tell her how it was, the thing,
with his...
dolce.
Talk already.
Amore,
grande amore,
with Signorina.
bella Signorina.
Capisce?
A visitor.
So early?
It's not... like always...
Signorina Hirt?
Yes?
Signorina [Italian]
[Italian]
Marcello?
Marcello Scalzi.
Who are you?
[Italian]
Marcello's...
I don't even know.
Leave me alone with her.
I'll handle it.
Just calm down.
Per favore si tranquila.
[Italian]
It's very embarrassing for me,
but I have to point out very clearly,
that it's not allowed to keep dogs in my apartment.
I don't keep it. It's just for the visit.
But again and again. That's the fifth time now.
Sorry,
but it doesn't do anything.
The carpets suffer.
And concerning the rest of the foreign traffic in your room...
Please don't get worked up unnecessarily. I quit.
That's just...
She is Marcello's fiancee.
But I told her, that you didn't know that...
What's wrong?
I just canceled my room.
Well done!
You don't need it anymore.
I have to give you the pleasant news,
that Kaprun wants to have its Raiffeisen bank executive back.
... that you're here again.
Attention. Detonation!
Full cover!
[unintelligible dialogue]
Miss Angelika.
Miss Angelika!
Yes?
Please let me tell you again privately
how glad I am, that you returned.
Thank you, Mr. Zingerl,
but you told me that yesterday already.
Yes, this was for the general public.
Oh, sorry.
But today,
Miss Angelika I would like to tell you as...
regular customer...
Yes, too.
But mainly as private person.
And as that,
I mean as such,
I would like to repeat my offer.
Mr. Zingerl,
please excuse me for a moment.
What can I do for you?
It's about...
I want to set up a family savings account.
You want to marry?
Yes.
Then fill out this here please.
First your Name and then your wife's name.
Bernd
Helwig,
Angelika...
Bernd!
It's not that easy.
I didn't mean it this way.
Don't you want to give me some time?
Yes I do.
Then keep it.
As long as you want.
Until that's true,
what's already written in there.
Bernd and Angelika Helwig.
The Macaroni!
Let! Let!
I'll take you to the police myself.
Let go of me!
Mr. assistant forster. Did you read already
that the italian Marcello Scalzi escaped from prison?
Sit there!
And eat!
Not eat.
Angelika.
Don't you have other problems now, you...
you stupid guy.
Angelika. Please bring Angelika.
You better think of yourself now.
Please.
Angelika.
All right then, I bring her here, you fool, (you).
Attention.
The Linz Police Department reports
that the italian foreign worker Marcello Scalzi escaped.
It's suspected
that he proceeds toward Kaprun, his last whereabouts.
Over and out.
Angelina.
You shouldn't have done that.
Not allowed.
Forbidden. Always not allowed.
That makes everything worse.
Och, not worse than locked up.
Always only your letters.
Paper, paper!
You come with me.
Now.
How do you imagine that, Marcello?
Imagine later.
Come now.
You and I belong together.
No.
You only think that, if you love one another, because you want it to be.
Oh, I understand.
You think of me as a murderer.
No, that's not it.
Please try to understand me.
Love...
is something different than living your life together.
I don't understand. You come with me. Now!
No!
Marcello!
Understand me!
I cannot understand.
Marcello, we didn't know enough about each other.
Why didn't you tell me back then about Tina?
Tina?
We both dreamt a beautiful dream.
A romantic fortune. Somewhere on an island.
But this island for two people alone doesn't exist.
You can't live dreams.
You must live reality.
And my reality is here. And yours, Tina.
Visitors, Gustl?
If a had visitors,
I wouldn't sit out here alone.
But the dog smells something.
Well then ask the dog,
if you believe it more then me.
You must go.
Try to get through to Italy.
Home.
[Italian]
Quick.
We may come in for a schnapps, may we not?
What are you looking for anyway?
Perhaps the ram you never hit.
Possible.
And what happens if I won't let you in?
Then we enter without the landlords admission.
Bella.
You?
He sensed me and gave me away.
But that was not very gallant of you.
Visitors after all?
You're still allowed to make fun of a hunter, aren't you?
And furthermore,
a gentleman has to...
keep his mouth shut.
Well then,
because you are here already,
let's have...
a schnapps, eh?
He must have been here.
Yes and has got a weapon now.
Yes, but...
only blanks.
Come Bella.
Bernd?
Where to?
The trace is still fresh. The dog is going to find him.
That's not our business, and yours even less.
An escaped prisoner...
Is this about a prisoner or late revenge?
Come, let's notify the police.
Tow men to the bridge and you with me.
He must have come over the mountains.
In my opinion, he tries to escape across the italian border.
We stay alert, naturally.
But I recommend to close off the passes in the south.
He certainly isn't here anymore.
You were right.
Now I'm almost glad he succeeded.
It's better for everybody. For you, for him and for Angelika.
You!
What the dog smells isn't game.
Marcello.
Be reasonable, Scalzi.
Attention. He is got a weapon.
Away! Away!
Go away.
AWAY!
I shoot you!
Bella!
Bella, come!
Bella, here!
The dog could tell that,
if he talked.
But the tale
is not finished yet.
Yes...
Each bad weather...
clears up sometime.
And then the sun comes out.
Yes, Bella.
Bella Piccolina.
We still have unfinished business, Bella.
Come.
There, go.
There she is,
Bella.