Ten o'clock, my lord.
- Oh, what's that?
- Ten o'clock, my lord.
Anything wrong, my lord?
Everything's wrong.
- Shellfish again for supper, my lord?
- Mm, what of it?
You know what they do to
your digestion, my lord.
They don't do a
thing to my digestion.
- No, my lord?
- No.
If you want to know, I had oysters
and lobsters and sherry and champagne.
Quite, my lord.
I had dinner and spent the
evening with Sr. and Sra. Floud.
- The Americans, my lord?
- Yes.
They taught me their native
game of, um... drawing poker.
- Quite a 'orrible experience, my lord.
- Yes, it was.
I am putting out your
light grey, my lord.
There is something in
the air this morning
- which calls for light grey, I think.
- Mm, possibly.
- What's all this mess?
- I'm packin' up.
We're goin' home, Effie. I can be
pushed just so far and no further.
Egbert, get dressed. I'm sending
you over to fetch Ruggles.
Now look-a-here! I ain't
gonna have no English valet.
- Oh, yes, you are.
- No, I ain't.
I got about as much use for one of
them as a pig has for side pockets.
I'm going to turn you into
a gentleman if it kills me.
Well, you can't do it by hirin' a
man to give me a bath and dress me.
I can button myself up.
I been doin' it for years.
You don't seem to realise what
this would mean to us socially.
- How? How socially?
- Why, in Red Gap.
It will give us, er...
tone, joie de vivre.
What's that?
It... um... er... tone.
To have him there.
Havin' who?
Effie, you ain't aimin' on
taking Ruggles to Red Gap?
I certainly am. Egbert,
get your clothes on.
Now look-a-here, Effie. I can be
pushed just so far and no further.
Egbert. Get your clothes on.
Well, why? Why?
Uh... why?
Ruggles, how are you
about, er... shocks?
- Shocks, my lord?
- Yes, you know, shocks. Upheavals.
Er... you've always stood up under
them pretty well, haven't you?
- I trust I have, my lord.
- Yes, I remember.
You... you were very firm
with that Spanish girl.
- She was a dancer, wasn't she?
- Quite so, my lord.
Yes, unaccountable number
of Spanish dancers in Madrid.
Rather more than in most
places we've been, my lord.
- Ah, yes.
- Rather a pippin, wasn't she?
- Oh, rather, yes.
- Prettier than the typist person.
Oh, much, yes.
Yes, I nearly chucked everything and
went to... went to America with her.
America would never
do for you, my lord.
I don't know. A lot of opportunities
over there, the right kind of fellow.
I... You'll do very well for
yourself there, I think, Ruggles.
Me, my lord?
Oh, yes. Yes, I forgot to tell you.
You're... you're going out to America.
America, my lord?
A country of slavery.
Oh, that's all
finished, I believe.
Some fellow called
Pocahontas or something
did something about
it or... or other.
- Indeed, my lord?
- Mm.
Would it be North or
South America, my lord?
Oh. Oh, North, I think it is.
Somewhere on the West Coast.
Idaho or Omaha, one
of those Indian places.
- The chap's a sort of a millionaire.
- The chap, my lord?
Yes, plenty of money,
you know. Mines, lumber,
domestic animals and
that sort of thing.
His wife took quite a fancy
to you and, er... so they've...
won you.
- Won me, my lord?
- Oh, yes.
Yes, yes. We were playing this
game of drawing poker, you see.
It seems there's a
thing called bluffing
and, though I say it myself,
I'm particularly good at it.
Do I understand...
that I was the
stake, my lord?
Oh, yes, yes. Rather, yes.
Ha-ha. Yes. You see, I didn't
realise that they were bluffing too.
I... I had three of the eights
against a flush of clubs.
So, you really only
lost by one eight.
- Indeed, my lord?
- Oh, yes.
I do hope you don't think I didn't lose
you gamely as a gentleman should, Ruggles.
North America, my lord.
Quite an untamed
country, I understand.
Yes, I expect so, yes.
Oh, yes, that must be Sr. Floud
come to collect you, Ruggles.
Yes.
Yes, thank you, Ruggles.
Come in, sir.
Well, how are
you, Sr. Ruggles?
Well, how do?
Er... good morning, sir.
Won't you be seated, sir?
Yeah, thanks.
Now, er... now
look-a-here, Sr. Ruggles.
I want you to understand that this
wasn't my ideia at all, you know.
- This was Effie's.
- So I understand, sir.
Yes, sir, when she gets
her mind set on something,
she's a wildcat, believe me.
I have no reason
to doubt you, sir.
- Well, well, you old tarantula!
- Oh.
- Well, how... how you coming?
- Hello, hello, hello, hello.
I... I guess you know
what I'm here for.
Yes, I do, yes.
Well, I ain't any more
joyouser about it than you are.
But... but you
know Effie. Hm.
I tell you, when she gets riled
up, she'd fight a rattlesnake
and give it the
first two bites.
I fancy you'll find
Ruggles fairish enough.
Oh, that's all right, Earl.
Your word's good enough for me.
Er... well, I don't want to hurry you
there, Bill, but you'd better pack your grip.
- Pack my grip, sir?
- Yeah.
Oh, hold on. Wait a minute. You
ain't got time. Effie's in a hurry.
You'd better check in first and
then pick up your duds later, see?
Very good, sir.
Is there anything further
I can do for you, my lord?
I fancy not, Ruggles, no.
This is rather
sudden, isn't it?
Well, bound to be sudden, you
know, a thing like this, I mean.
I can't help worrying about
what will happen to you, my lord.
Oh, Ruggles, don't.
I'll be all right.
Be rather fun dressing
myself, I expect.
I hope you will
enjoy it, my lord.
Oh, of course I shall.
- Your digestive tablets.
- Oh, yes.
You ought to take your two.
Yes, well... well,
goodbye, Ruggles.
And look after yourself
and all that sort of thing.
- Yes, my lord. Thank you, my lord.
- Oh, don't thank me.
- I ought to thank you, really.
- No, my lord.
I am ready, sir.
Eh? Oh, yes, yes, sure.
It's kind of sad, ain't it?
Well, so long, Earl.
Keep your head up.
Goodbye, Floud.
Thank you.
Goodbye, my lord.
He has the worst taste
of any man I ever knew.
- To the cleaner, madame?
- To the cleaner?
I want the whole lot
taken out and burned.
- Burned, madame?
- Burned to ashes.
- And then burn the ashes.
- Oui, madame.
My husband is to have
an entirely new outfit.
Er... will you look at that?
He liked that so well,
he bought two of them.
Even the moths
wouldn't eat those.
Come on, Bill, come on,
come on. Stir your stumps.
Hey, hey, hey! Where you
going with my clothes?
Well, maybe... maybe she's
gonna get 'em pressed.
Well, this is the place.
Here we go. Here...
Where are you? Where...
- Well, go ahead in.
- After you, sir.
- Well, go on, go on.
- Oh, no, sir.
Er... you're too
darned polite.
Effie! Effie!
Come on in, Bill. Make
yourself at home. Effie!
Er... we got company.
Well, Ruggles, here you are.
Oh, I'm so
delighted I got you.
I've had my eye on you ever
since I met His Lordship.
I do hope and trust you're going to like
it with us, both here and in Red Gap.
Red Gap, madam?
Er... yes, our home town, you
know, in the state of Washington.
It's a little, er...
bourgeoisie, I'm afraid,
but I think you'll find a few of us who
still really care about what's happening
in the, er... haut monde.
Ah, indubitably, madam.
Oh, what beautiful
French you speak, Ruggles.
- Effie!
- Yes?
Effie, what's that hired
girl gonna do with my clothes?
Never mind.
Now, Ruggles, the first thing we
have to do is take Sr. Floud out
and get him a
whole new outfit.
Now, what for? Now, what's
the matter with my clothes?
They're all right. Bill
said so, didn't you, Bill?
Er... Egbert.
I let him dress himself according
to his own taste today...
and you see what
he looks like.
Do you think we can do
anything about him, Ruggles?
I dare say he could be
smartened up a bit, madam.
Well, I'll dare say more than that.
I can be pushed just so far and...
Egbert, you listen to me.
Look at his tie.
You see what I mean?
His appearance is so disgraceful,
I... I hate to take him any place.
Yeah, you ought to see
some of the places she...
Egbert, you'll do as
you're told. Come along.
Your hat, sir.
Now, you see what I meant about the
wildcat and rattlesnake, don't you?
Look here, now, you go easy
on this clothes business
- and remember I like checks.
- Egbert.
- Go ahead.
- After you, sir.
- No, no. Go on, go on.
- Oh, no, no, sir.
What, are we gonna do
this all over again?
Madame, what, er... what
can I do for you today?
We want a lot of things
for the gentleman.
- Ah, for the gentleman?
- This is the gentleman.
Ah.
Oh, something... something
similar to what he's wearing?
Similar to... What is
this, a second-hand store?
Oh, no, madame!
You see, he got these clothes under
the most peculiar circumstances.
You see, he... Mm.
The gentleman's present condition
is purely the result of an accident.
The gentleman's hotel
burned down during the night.
The gentleman rushed from the burning
building in, er... the altogether.
Wait, wait, wait!
What is all this?
The gentleman was forced to accept
the loan of garments from onlookers.
All circus people!
Now I understand the gentleman's
ridiculous appearance!
Well, you... you ain't
no geranium yourself.
Egbert.
Would you be kind enough to show
us something in morning coats?
Morning coats? Mais
oui, monsieur. Un moment.
Try to walk, Egbert.
What do you think
of him, Ruggles?
In the main, madam,
I am not dissatisfied.
I think he looks
very distingué.
Gay nothing. I look like that bantam
rooster I had before it was run over.
When you came in here,
you looked like that bantam
rooster after he was run over.
Voilà, monsieur, the spats!
Oh, now, look-a-here, Bill! Now, I
don't have to wear them things, do I?
Spats, sir, mark
the difference
between a man well turned
out and a man merely dressed.
Now, Egbert, go over and sit
down and be well turned out.
No, sir, I won't wear
'em. I won't wear 'em.
They'll make me look like
my drawers were hanging down.
- Monsieur!
- No, sir.
I can be pushed just
so far and no further!
- Monsieur! Un moment!
- Egbert! Egbert!
Ruggles, Ruggles,
go... go catch him!
Oh, dear!
Why, Egbert, you look
like a different man!
Yeah, maybe I'd
better change my name.
Here, here, here, here!
What are you gonna do now?
- We're... we're going to trim it.
- Oh, no, you won't!
But, Egbert, it doesn't
go with the spats.
I don't care. That moustache is
gonna stay just the way it is.
What would the
fellows say in Red Gap,
if they saw me come home
with a cut moustache?
No, sir, you
don't go and get...
All right, all right, you can chew
the rag about it as much as you want.
I ain't gonna let you do it.
It took me 20 years to
build up this moustache
and I ain't gonna have
nobody monkey with it now.
Oh, Egbert!
Oh, Effie!
- Hm.
- Oh, madam!
Gah!
Oh, Bill!
Effie, I wouldn't
do that to a dog.
Look, Egbert, isn't it nice?
- How do you like it, monsieur?
- Well, I don't know. Let me see.
How would you like it?
Monsieur!
- Where are you going?
- I'm going home.
I'm gonna find myself a closet
so that I can hide in it.
Oh, no, you're not.
You're going with Ruggles.
Now, come along. Come
on, get out there.
I wish you'd make
up your mind, Effie.
Oh, Ruggles?
While I do some shopping, you might
spend a few hours with Egbert...
I mean Sr. Floud,
in the art galleries.
Art galleries? Yes, madam.
Yes, he's been writing down a few of
his impressions in this little book.
Art, it seems, is
Egbert's emotional outlet.
Get him home early, Ruggles.
We have a few very important
people coming in for dinner.
And see that he acts like a
gentleman, if you have to hog-tie him.
Place Vendôme!
Er... goodbye...
goodbye, Effie. Goodbye.
We have a common sympathy in the
pictorial arts, if I may say so, sir.
- Mm-hm? - Shall we
stroll towards the Louvre?
Wait a minute. She'll be
around the corner in a minute.
Now.
Come on, let's grab a table.
Madam instructed me to conduct
you to the art galleries, sir.
Well... well, you wouldn't know
it, but this is it. Come on.
- Hey, Max! Oh, Max?
- Oui, monsieur.
- Max, bring me my book, you know...
They keep my book
handy here for me.
- I... I got a system.
- Oh!
Oh, monsieur, qu'il est
grand! Quelle surprise!
Yeah, yeah, they tricked me.
- That's it, Max, now, give me a pencil.
- Oui, monsieur.
- And give us a couple of beers.
- Oui, monsieur, oui, oui.
Now, here's what
I do, Bill, see?
I copy out of this here big
book into this here little one,
and then I show Effie how much
I learned at the art galleries.
Yes, sir, but I fail to see how you
are to acquire culture in this way, sir.
Well, I don't know. I been getting
away with it ever since I come to Paris.
Now, look, you write it this time and
that'll make it stronger with Effie, see?
And pick out something good,
something in the middle there,
about, "Here lies the true lovers
of art entranced" or something.
Here is displayed in
its full flower, sir...
Well, sit down, sit down.
You can't write standing up.
- Sit down.
- Oh, no, sir.
Oh. Oh, I know what's
the matter with you.
You think I'm mad at you on account
of these clothes and everything, hein?
Well, I ain't.
I may be a little mad at Effie, but I
ain't mad at you. Now, go on, sit down.
There is a certain difference
in our walks of life, sir,
which makes it impossible for me to sit
at the same table with yourself, sir.
Well, you ain't ashamed
to sit here, are you?
Ashamed? It isn't that, sir.
It just doesn't do for a gentleman's
servant to sit with his superiors, sir.
Superiors, nothing. You're as good as I
am, and I'm as good as you are, ain't I?
- Well, sir...
- Well, ain't I?
Er... yes, sir.
Well, then, what's eatin' you? Sit
down and take the weight off your shoes.
There. There you are, you
see? That didn't hurt, did it?
Mm. Mac, that's just what
we've been waiting for.
Aha!
Well, here you go, Colonel.
Here's, er... spying on you.
Well, ain't you
gonna drink with me?
What's the matter with you?
Don't you ever have no fun?
Ain't you happy?
Well, don't you ever smile?
Well, that ain't much of a
smile. Don't you feel good?
I'm in perfect health, sir,
but it is rather a shock to find oneself
breaking the tradition of generations.
Well, don't let it throw
you, Colonel. Come on.
Excuse me, sir, but you must remember
to address me as Ruggles, sir,
and not as Colonel or as Bill or as
Sr. Ruggles, as you've been doing, sir.
Now, why? Why can't
I call you Colonel?
If we were overheard, sir,
people might take us to be equals.
Well, listen. Where I come
from, everybody is equal, see?
Ah, that may be all very
well for America, sir,
but it would
never do with us.
Well, let's not get into no more
argument about it. We got work to do.
And then we can settle
down to some real drinking.
Where was we in
that book there?
"Here is displayed in its full
flower", sir, "that ruthless realism
"happily alternated by a
superbly subtle delicacy..."
Wait a minute! Hey, Jeff!
- Hey, Jeff!
- Hold her, Newt!
Hey, Jeff Tuttle!
Yee-hoo!
You old Sourdough!
Giddy-up! Now whoa!
Whoa, whoa, you old...
Whoa, my old...
No, wait a minute. I want you
to meet a friend of mine, Bill!
Er... hey, Bill!
Bill, where are you?
Come on down here! I
want you to meet somebody!
Come on, Bill, come on!
You know, I thought maybe you wouldn't
recognise me in my new beadwork here.
Me not know you,
you old Sourdough?
You old longhorn, you!
Oh, Colonel Ruggles, I want
you to meet up with Jeff Tuttle
from Red Gap, State
of Washington, USA.
Pleased to meet
you, Colonel.
I have no military
title whatsoever, sir,
never having served in His Majesty's
forces, not even in the ranks.
Any friend of Sourdough's
is all right with me.
Say, what's the matter
with sitting down?
Why, sure, sure. Pull up a chair
there, Colonel, pull up a chair.
No, pull up one
for yourself.
- Where did you get this?
- Yeah, well, Effie done that to me.
Wait till I show it
to you. Look at that.
Big Chief High Hat!
Here you are, Colonel,
shove those somewhere.
Well, you old stinging lizard,
where did you turn up from?
Europe. We been all
over Europe and Italy.
Cathedrals. Just one
church after another.
And say! How about
a little drink?
Ha! Well, beer's the only thing I know
how to say in these here French joints.
- You leave that to me. Here, boy!
- Oui, monsieur?
Veesky soda.
That's French for highball.
You have to do that... Well,
how did you ever learn that?
Well, it took me some
time to get the accent.
I think we ought to be
getting along home, sir.
Hey, wait a minute! We
just met. Squattéz-vous.
We have important people
coming to dinner, sir,
and we have definite
instructions from Madam.
Yeah, he means Effie.
You know how she is.
- That woman could bite through nails.
- Yes, she chews 'em instead of gum.
Here you go, Maxie, that's
what we been waitin' for.
Now bring three more,
er... veesky soda.
- Look, look, like...
- Oui, monsieur.
Yeah, he got me right away.
Let's make it harder next time.
You old mustang!
You old coyote!
Here's looking at you!
Come on, come on, Colonel. Wrap
your paw around that there glass.
- Yahoo!
- Yippee!
You old horned toad.
- You old maverick.
- Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Yippee!
- What's the matter with a little grub?
- Yeah, a little grub.
Hey, George. Er... Max.
Allé restaurant.
Ask him if he's got
some ham and eggs.
Er... voulez-vous...
er... hammy eggie?
Qu'est-ce que
c'est, monsieur?
The man don't even
know his own language.
Hammy eggie?
Gee, that's beautiful
French, beautiful French.
And after that we'll
take a little drive
to some of the well-known
points of interest.
- Sure, sure, but no art galleries.
- And no churches.
No, and no clothing stores.
And no churches.
And... You said that before.
I wonder what we'll get
instead of ham and eggs.
Yahoo!
Well, by crikey, I didn't
know he had it in him!
You should never let him
get in this condition.
Why, the man's pickled!
Oh, it always affects him
this way. It's terrible.
I beg your pardon, sir.
- Look out, Jeff, grab him!
- I got him, I got him!
He's a tough hombre
when he gets started.
Yippee! Yippee!
You see there? You see?
There he goes again.
We gotta get him out in the fresh
air. It's too hot for him in here.
You go pay the cheque,
Jeff. I'll grab him.
- Oui.
- I'll grab him, I'll grab him.
Come on. Come on there, Bill. Come on,
Colonel. That's it. Now, take it easy.
Here, here, here, here!
Now, don't try no rough
stuff. We got you outnumbered.
Hey, cab!
Er... give us one
with a horse on it.
Come on, now. Come
on, steady there.
Come on, steady now,
steady now, Colonel. Steady.
- After you, sir.
- Here... here we go with this again.
- Go on in there.
- After you, sir.
- Go on in now.
Get in that cab. What do...
Go on, go on, go on, go on.
Yeah. Yeah.
We'II... we'll tell you where in
a minute. We're havin' a meetin'.
Oh, here we... Now,
will you get in that cab?
You won't get in, hein?
Well, there ought to be some
way out of this. Let's see.
- You don't mind waiting, do you?
- No, no.
Er... now, that's not
fair. You ain't thinkin'.
Aw... go on, let
him have his own way.
Oh, all right.
- Voulez-vous,
any place. - Yahoo!
So nice of you to have come. I
only wish you'd met my husband.
I can't imagine what
could have detained him.
- Yahoo!
- Shh!
Oh!
Shh. Quiet, quiet, quiet,
quiet. Keep him quiet.
- Jeff Tuttle from Red Gap!
- Shh! Shh!
Quiet, quiet, quiet!
Quiet, now, quiet!
- We... we gotta sneak in.
- Shh!
- Shh.
- Now, you see? We made it.
- Whoo!
- Shh. Keep him quiet, Jeff, go on.
- Quiet now, quiet.
- Oh!
Well, hello, Effie.
- It's Effie, boys.
- Hello, Effie.
- Egbert, what does this mean?
- Well, you... you...
Effie, you have no ideia the
trouble we had with the Colonel here.
It come on him when we were in the
art galleries. Er... hold him up, Jeff.
- I got him, I got him.
- You see what I mean?
He's a nice fellow too. It's a shame.
You'll excuse him, will you, folks?
Je suis mortifée.
I'm très amazed.
Adieu, Sr. Standfans.
- Bonsoir, madame.
- Adieu!
- We've had such a lovely evening.
- Bonsoir, madame.
Effie?
Erm... Effie?
Er... I...
There... there you are. Now
you see? You see what I mean?
He's a man who should never have
liquor. It brings out the beast in him.
- Whoo!
- Oh.
I suppose you two
haven't been drinking.
- No!
- Yes.
Well, we had to.
He... he made us.
Yes, he pulled a
long knife on us.
- I want to speak to
Ruggles alone. - Uh-oh.
Do you think it's safe to
leave her alone with him?
- Don't worry about me.
- Well, I don't know, Effie.
After all, you know,
you're... you're all I've got.
Now look-a-here,
Ruggles. I'm warning you.
Er... one false move
and, er... you understand?
- Yippee.
- Well, that's better.
- What did he say?
- He said yippee.
Oh, that's all right, then.
Well, Ruggles! And to think I
sent you out to take care of him!
I'm terribly sorry, madam.
Perhaps I should have enquired
of His Lordship about your habits.
Yes.
Er... come, come, Ruggles. You...
you better go to bed. Yeah... yes. Oh!
Oh. Oh!
Oh! Er...
- Good morning, Ruggles.
- Good morning, madam.
Ruggles, I'm horribly
disappointed in you.
Not so disappointed as
I am in myself, madam.
And I'm more
than disappointed
because I thought that Egbert
had... had something in him.
Something in
him? Yes, madam.
And to think of
Egbert and Jeff Tuttle
trailing you around Paris
trying to save you from yourself.
I shall never
forget that, madam.
Of course, er... Jeff Tuttle's
an Indian but Egbert is different.
- One or two lumps, madam?
- Oh, none, none.
Think of your dragging him out of an
art gallery and taking him places that...
Oh! Must have disgusted him.
Making him ride on
a merry-go-round.
I... I don't know where
you got such ideas.
I was not myself, madam.
You don't look like
a periodical souse.
Oh, madam, please.
But to show that I'm broadminded,
you can go and get yourself a drink.
Oh, thank you, madam.
I know how you feel.
- Er... on account of my husband.
- Of course, madam.
But I shall forgive and
forget. That's my nature.
And now, Ruggles, tomorrow
we're sailing for home.
- Home, madam?
- Yes, home, America. Red Gap.
Oh, yes, madam.
Red Gap.
- Is this still Kansas, madam?
- Oh, dear, no!
We're getting into Red Gap. That's
in the state of Washington, you know.
Indeed, madam?
Extraordinary there seem to be none of
the usual signs of an approaching city.
Oh, well, Red Gap ain't
exactly a city, Bill,
but it's the fastest-growin'
town in the West, though.
Yes, sir.
When we get to the station, we'll be
met by my sister and brother-in-law,
Sr. and Sra.
Belknap-Jackson.
I think you'll find Senhor.
Belknap-Jackson quite the gentleman.
Yeah, yeah, he sure is.
When he found out that Ma
Pettinghill... That's Effie's ma.
When he found out that she
made a barrel of dough in oil,
he come all the way from Boston
just to marry into the family.
- Egbert.
- Ouch. Well, didn't he?
Quiet.
Sr. Belknap-Jackson is the
leader of our Red Gap society.
You know, until he came out
here, you'd hardly believe it,
but nobody even thought of
using doilies under finger bowls.
Did they, Egbert?
Nobody even thought
of using finger bowls.
How very extraordinary!
No, sir. Finger bowls.
Here he comes!
I hope Europe
has helped Egbert.
How could anything
help Egbert?
Effie!
Oh, my dear! How sweet of
you to come and meet us!
Why, Egbert, how smart you
look! I'd never known it was you.
Well, I hardly know it
myself. Hello, Knappie.
Bill, where are you?
Oh, Colonel Ruggles.
I want you to meet Senhor.
and Sra. Belknap-Jackson.
Er... this is the Boston
Belknap I was telling you about.
How do you do, Colonel?
The Colonel come all the
way from England with us.
You'll find a few of us
here that really matter.
He's Egbert's manservant.
- His valet?
- Yes. Oh!
Egbert!
Ma!
Well, you durn dude!
Ma Pettingill,
you wild maverick!
You durn horned toad!
What have they done to you,
made you ambassador from Paris?
I do look kind of foreign, don't I? Well,
let me show you something. Come here.
- Effie!
- Mother!
Well, durn me if you
don't look like a lady!
Oh, Ma, here's the
fella that done it to me.
Colonel Ruggles, this
is our Ma Pettingill.
- Hiya, Colonel.
- How do you do?
- Where's your uniform?
- Mother.
- Hein?
- This is Egbert's servant.
No! You look as funny
as Belknap-Jackson!
- Ruggles, bring the luggage.
- Yes, sir.
Hiya, Buck!
- Hello, fellers.
- How do you do, Egbert?
Why, you long drink
of water, I'II...
Say, who's your friend?
Oh, boys, I want you to meet Colonel
Ruggles, a special friend of mine.
Any friend of Egbert's
is a friend of ours.
Well, Colonel, I think
you're going to like it here.
If Egbert likes you,
you must be a regular guy
and if you're a regular
guy, you're OK with Red Gap.
- Thank you, madam.
- Don't keep calling me madam.
Ma's my name. Ma Pettingill.
Any time you can't find Egbert,
just try the old Silver Dollar.
We'll be there.
- Hiya, Ma.
- Hiya, Sam.
The others'll be along in a minute.
Libby, Willy, meet Colonel Ruggles.
- Howdy-do. - How
do you do, Colonel?
- A genuine blackamoor, madam?
- Oh, yeah.
- And a China
person? - Uh-hein.
What do you think
of the place?
It's large.
Belknap-Jackson and my two daughters
put their house-building ideas together
and this is what happened.
The only thing I had to
do with it was pay for it.
But I can't lose. I can sell it
any time to the city for a depot.
And then I go on to say,
"The Flouds were accompanied
by their English manservant,
"secured through the courtesy
of the Earl of Burnstead.
"He will no doubt lend a continental
flavour to the Floud mansion."
- How's that, Belknap?
- I think...
Yeah, some mess of words.
Egbert, I want you to take this over
to Jake Henshaw at the newspaper office
and be sure that
he prints it.
- Ruggles!
- Yes, madam!
- Oh, Ruggles!
- Yes, madam.
- Are you ready?
Er... Ruggles, I want you to accompany
Sr. Floud to the newspaper office.
Yes, madam.
And, er... see that he
makes no stops on the way.
- Oh, Effie, you know me.
- Yes.
Oh, look-a-here, do
I have to carry these?
- Why, certainly.
- Oh...!
- Oh, Ruggles?
- Yes, sir?
Will you see that he
comes straight home?
Remember, we're
holding you responsible.
- ? By the light
- ? By the light, by the light
? Of the silvery moon
? Of the silvery moon...
Listen, listen, Bill. That's Nell
Kenner singing. Ain't that pretty?
- Who, sir?
- This is Nell Kenner's house. Come on.
May I remind you we are instructed to
proceed to the newspaper office, sir?
Yeah, well, we'll get around to that.
We'll head in here first. Come on.
You know, Effie and her circle of cats
is always got their harpoons out for Nell.
But believe me, she's
as right as a church.
But it is highly improper for you to
take your valet about with you, sir.
Aw, they won't know you from the
Duke of Kakiac. Come on in and mix.
Oh, no, sir.
Say, look-a-here, who are
you working for anyway?
You, sir.
- Mix, sir? Yes, sir.
- Yeah.
Uh-oh, look out,
I forgot something.
Come here, come here.
You better take this pool
cue and these mittens, see?
If the gang ever
caught me with those,
they'd run me out of town hitched
to a horse's tail or something.
Go on, go on, take 'em. You can get
away with it. You're a foreigner.
Look out there!
- Well, Sourdough!
- Hello, Eddie.
- When did you get off the trail?
- Just got in, just got in.
- Hello, Sourdough.
- Hello, Doc.
Eddie, I want you to meet my
good friend Colonel Ruggles.
- Colonel, I'm glad to know you, sir.
- How do you do?
Yeah, this is Doc Squires.
Doc Squires, Colonel Ruggles.
- Put her there, Colonel.
- How do you do?
Doc is a feller that'll give
you castor oil for everything.
Wait a minute. I got something
on my mind. Now, what was it?
- That's it. Where's the beer barrel?
- Over there.
Well, let's go to it. We'll
be seeing you around, boys.
- Hello, Harry!
- Hello, boy.
- Shake hands with Colonel Ruggles.
- I'm very glad to know you.
And Stella. Stella, Harry's
wife. Colonel Ruggles.
Get out, get out! Oh, you're
way in over your head there.
Well, Sourdough!
Hello, Hank, my boy.
Hank, I want you to meet my good
friend Colonel Ruggles. This is Hank.
- How are you, Colonel?
- How do you do?
- Egbert!
- Who's calling?
- Why, Nell! Yippee!
- Egbert, come here!
Ha-ha-ha! Pull out your anchor,
Bill. I'll be with you in a minute.
- Have a beer, Colonel.
- Oh, thank you.
Oh, you old darling!
Ha-ha! Nell Kenner, you're
a sight for sore eyes.
Aw, gee, Red Gap hasn't
been the same without you.
Aw, you're joshing me.
- There you are.
- Oh, thank you.
Oh, Jake. Shake hands
with Colonel Ruggles.
- Hein?
- Jake Henshaw, Colonel.
- The best newspaperman in the West.
- How do you do?
- Colonel? What army?
- The truth of the matter is that...
I got it. British
army, of course.
- Now, what's your first name, Colonel?
- It isn't ever used.
- Oh, just for the paper.
- Come on.
Tell him your
first name, Colonel.
Marmaduke.
No foolin'?
Well, anyhow, how do
you like our fair city?
Oh, toppin'.
- Like it, hein?
- I've never seen anything like it.
Well, have you met
any of our fair women?
I've not yet had
that pleasure.
Well, come on and try some
of our fair food, Colonel.
- Oh, thank you.
- Here we are.
Colonel Marmaduke Ruggles.
Oh, now wait a minute.
Let the old horse thief tell
about his trip in his own way.
Horse thief, she called me! You want I
should tell you in English or in French?
French.
Who said that?
You would. It couldn't
have been a little feller.
I say, who is responsible
for this sauce?
Me.
Very excellent it is
indeed, my good woman.
If you're calling me a good woman cos
you don't know my name, it's Judson.
Delighted to make your
acquaintance, I'm sure.
- And who am I...
- Pardon me, Colonel.
I've got it up to "Colonel Marmaduke
Ruggles, British Army retired."
You're staying with
the Flouds, are you not?
- Yes, but only...
- Thank you. That's all I wanted to know.
- I'll see you a little later.
- I say!
Oh. So, you like my
meat sauce, do you?
It's very good.
It's almost perfect.
What do you mean,
almost perfect?
I was just thinking that perhaps a few
drops of this and a little bit of that
might make it into a
really superlative sauce.
So, that's what you're thinking, is
it? Well, let me tell you something.
That I've been making meat sauce
for longer than I can remember,
and nobody's ever found
fault with it before.
I wasn't finding
fault with it.
What do you mean by a few drops
of this and a little bit of that?
Oh, I only meant that perhaps a
little spice and some wine vinegar...
Listen, Colonel.
You'd better stick to something you
know about, like leading a regiment.
Let's not have an
international row about it.
Well...
Shall we dance?
Well, I really shouldn't.
I've got work to do.
Oh? Er... are you
in service here?
If you mean do I
work here, why, yes.
I always help Nell Kenner
out when she gives a party.
- Oh, I...
- I see what you mean.
A man in your position wouldn't
expect the help to dance,
but nobody minds
here, Colonel.
It's funny,
but you're the first one that ever
made me feel different than anyone else.
Might I have the
pleasure of this waltz?
Why, sure.
This is the newspaper
office, isn't it?
And Sr. Floud isn't there?
He's not there. Has
Sr. Floud been there?
Are you sure Sr. Floud
hasn't been there?
What? Why don't I
try Nell Kenner's?
She's giving a beer bust?
What would my husband
be doing at a beer bust?
Drinking?
None of your lip, young man!
He's at the beer bust. Now there'll
be nothing in the paper tomorrow.
I'm surprised at Ruggles.
Well, you'd
better get going.
And hurry. Hurry!
Just between us, Schwartzie,
what do you think?
I don't even like
the buttonholes.
I know just how you feel, Schwartzie.
I tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna get rid of all these here
dude clothes and get me some new ones.
So, I want you to take an
order right now for ten suits.
- Ten suits?
- Yeah, and make 'em all checks.
- Checks?
- Yeah. Here, here, Bill!
That's, er... a little
close even for Red Gap!
He dances with finesse.
Colonel Ruggles, what did Senhor.
Henshaw say your first name is?
Oh, it's never used.
- Oh, what is it?
- You'd laugh at it.
No, I wouldn't. What is it?
- It's Marmaduke.
- Oh, that's nice.
Mine's Prunella.
Oh, er... Ruggles?
- Well, Ruggles, enjoying yourself?
- Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Well, that's fine. What prompted
you to mingle with the guests?
Oh, sir, I had definite instructions
from Sr. Floud, sir, to mix.
I'm sorry to spoil
your pleasure.
But you must come
home with me at once.
I... I feel it
incumbent upon me, sir,
to see if that coincides
with Sr. Floud's wishes, sir.
Never mind Sr. Floud. He can
stay here. You're coming with me.
I think I should speak
to Sr. Floud, sir.
I won't be kicked by a
servant, English or otherwise.
Are you still going
to harbour the ruffian?
- He's an anarchist.
- He's an assassin.
I fail to see anything
funny about it, Mater.
You will! You will!
Quiet, Mother.
Ruggles, how
could you do it?
I coarsely gave way
to the brute in me.
Sr. Belknap-Jackson
is quite right.
Will you be quiet, Mother?
In Paris, you led my
poor husband astray.
And now you've started
assaulting the family.
Ruggles, you
will have to go.
You mean, madam, that I am to be
turned loose in this remote settlement?
Remote settlement?
You see, Effie? The
man's quite impossible.
You'd better pack
your bags immediately.
Just a minute, Bill.
Before you go throwing
Bill out on his ear,
you'd better read this
here piece in the paper.
Oh.
Oh!
Oh! Oh!
- What is it?
- It's terrible.
"Colonel Marmaduke Ruggles,
"late of the British Army,
"and an intimate friend
of the Earl of Burnstead,
"is at present an
honoured house guest..."
Look, look! It
says it right there.
"An honoured house guest of
Sr. and Sra. Egbert Floud!"
Disaster! Complete
social disaster!
"A series of entertainments
"are already being planned by
socially prominent hostesses
"including Sra. Judy...
"Judy Ballard,
"Sra. Ralph Wilton..."
It's continued on page five.
Oh! Oh! Oh! Thank you.
What can happen next?
Oh, how do you do? Why,
this must be Colonel Ruggles.
I'm Sra. Ballard.
Sra. Judy Ballard.
I simply had to make
your acquaintance.
- This is Sra. Myron Carey.
- How do you do?
- And Miss Sarah Grant.
They were just
crazy to meet you!
Hello, Effie darling!
My, how fortunate you are to
have such a distinguished visitor!
Yes. Er... yes.
This is the most eventful thing
that has ever happened to Red Gap.
Or, er... to me.
Yes.
Er... yes.
Oh.
Sra. Wallaby,
our old friend Colonel Marmaduke
Ruggles, late of the British Army.
Oh, I've been dying
to meet you, Colonel.
- How do you do?
- What was your regiment?
- We're all ready for the picture.
- Oh, the picture, Sra. Wallaby, yes.
Right this way.
Just as quickly as you possibly
can, please, and everyone look happy.
Er... smile, Colonel. Er... Senhora.
Floud there in front of the table.
That's it. Now, everyone look
at the Colonel and smile, please.
Now, Colonel, relax just
a bit. No, no, the face.
Now a little
smile. That's it.
Now, Sra. Floud, look at the
Colonel and smile nicely, please.
Oh, a little better smile than
that. Oh, just a little better.
Now, Colonel, look at Sra. Floud.
Sra. Floud, look at the Colonel.
Now a big smile. Big. Big!
Oh, that's it!
I will ask you to drink to the health
of our distinguished guest of honour,
Colonel Marmaduke Ruggles.
I know we would
all like to hear
some of Colonel Ruggles'
experiences in the British Army.
- No. Oh, no. No, no.
- No, no.
- I couldn't talk about my exploits.
- No.
- Oh, Effie, do make him talk.
- Oh, no. No, really.
You see, the Colonel spent many years
with the Black Watch in darkest Africa.
You... you were a Black
Watchman, weren't you, Colonel?
Ha-ha. Hm.
- Whoa.
- Why, Colonel Ruggles.
Good afternoon, Sra. Judson.
Whoa.
Oh, I say, that print
gown suits you no end.
- Oh, do you like it?
- Oh, yes.
What a spiffy little
garden you have!
I suppose it would be expecting
too much to ask you in for tea?
Oh, I should say rather not.
Oh.
Sr. Barker, stop! Come here!
Get out! Sr. Barker!
Sr. Barker! Out!
There. I'm so sorry.
You see, he's never
seen an English cowboy.
Cowboy?
Hm.
I say, what a snug
little home you have.
Well, I just sort of
fixed it up myself.
Did you?
- Oh! Goldfish.
- Oh!
I have always derived
intense satisfaction
from their silent
companionship.
Oh, have you?
Oh, how quaint!
- Who is this?
- Oh, that was Elmo.
Sr. Judson.
He got kicked by his favourite
mule and he never got over it.
Oh, excuse me, Colonel, while I
go and heat the water for the tea.
Oh, can't I help you?
It's hot.
- May I be of any assistance?
- Oh, no.
Men are so helpless
in the kitchen.
Oh, no.
Always bring the pot to the kettle.
Never bring the kettle to the pot.
Listen, Colonel, I've been making tea
for longer than I can remember and...
Don't let's get into
difficulties about this.
But you must listen to
an Englishman about tea.
If it were coffee, I
should be your pupil.
But we're making tea, and when making
tea, always bring the pot to the kettle
and never bring the
kettle to the pot.
Oh, Colonel, your
knowledge is surprising.
I don't see why you should
say surprising, Sra. Judson.
The best cooks have
always been men.
I myself have pronounced views as to
the preparation and serving of food.
- Have you?
- Oh, yes.
Well, do you know something
nice that will go with tea?
Er... yes, yes. The ingredients are
quite simple too. Have you a little flour?
- Oh, would you, Colonel?
- Rather.
It, er... needs flour,
butter, milk, and salt.
Oh, Colonel, you seem so
at home in the kitchen.
Ah, Sra. Judson, it would
be difficult to describe
the intense satisfaction I have
always derived from cooking.
And goldfish.
Er... well, no, no.
Oh, Colonel, you must write
out this recipe for me.
Nothing would give me greater
pleasure, Sra. Judson. Dear me!
- You should open a restaurant.
- Hm.
He's back again!
Down, sir! Down, sir!
- Sr. Barker, out! Out! Out! Sr. Barker!
- Down, sir! Down, sir! Down, sir!
Here. Get!
Oh...!
We're goin' out to the ranch for
a few days to get away from it all.
- Heh-heh! Ain't that right,
Ma? - That's the ideia.
- All right, Nelly?
- This is Henry.
Yeah. Go on, Henry.
Enjoying yourself?
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
I've been taking the
liberty of reading again
the life of your great
American statesman, sir.
Oh?
You seem in a very
good mood yourself.
I am. It's a pleasure to
tell you that you're through.
- Did you say...
- You're fired, Ruggles.
Sra. Floud instructed me to pay
your railroad fare to São Francisco.
Yes, sir.
There's a train leaving at
noon. See that you're on it.
What? Train, sir?
Train, sir? Yes, sir.
Er... train, sir.
Goodbye to you, sir.
Goodbye, sir.
- Oh, it's late.
- Yeah.
Um...
Oh, in that case,
could you tell me
where I could obtain
an inexpensive meal?
Er... try the Silver Dollar.
They've a swell free lunch there.
Oh, thank you. Er... could
I deposit my luggage here?
Er... yeah, leave 'em
there. I'll watch 'em.
Thank you.
- Hello, Colonel.
- How do you do?
- What'll you have?
- A small glass of beer, thank you.
- A small one, hein?
- How are you, Colonel?
- Howdy, Colonel.
- How do you do?
- How have you been?
- In excellent health, thank you.
Er... do you know, I think I
could do with a bite of food.
Oh, we have a fine lunch on
today. Right down here, Colonel.
- How's tricks?
- Oh, jolly.
Ah, them's nice
pig's feet, Colonel.
Yes.
Hi, Bill! Look,
Ma, here's Bill.
Come in here,
you old lone wolf.
Oh, pardon me.
Tryin' to sneak one
over on us, hein?
- Hi, Bill.
- Here, sit down, sit down.
I thought you'd departed
for the ranch, sir.
We just stopped in here first
for a little snort. Sit down.
This is very awkward, sir.
- What's he talking about?
- I don't know.
- Are you drunk, Colonel?
- Ye... Drunk? Heck, no.
I would like you to know that I have only
the kindliest feelings towards you both.
He's tight as a tick.
Ye... No, no, he ain't.
Come on, Bill, loosen up.
Now, what's gnawin' on you?
Yeah, I thought
there was somethin'.
No longer require
your services?
Belknap-Jackson!
Why, the sku... I'll
cut out his windpipe!
- The sneakin' coyote!
- Why, look-a-here, Bill.
We wouldn't fire you even if
you looked like that feller.
I couldn't be happier, sir.
I couldn't be happier, madam.
Oh, yes, you could.
Here, drink that.
Yeah, and follow
it up with this.
I tell you, that Belknap-Jackson
is a Boston cream puff.
You're working
for me, ain't you?
Oh, excuse me. I couldn't help
but hear. But I don't understand.
- Well, tell her, Ma.
- Come on and sit down.
Listen.
- No!
- Yeah, that's right.
Then you're just an ord...
- Oh, this is wonderful news.
- Come have a drink.
No, I just came over
for some cooking sherry.
Well, I'll tell
you what we'll do.
We'll all have one more shot and then
we'll move Bill back into the house.
- What do you say?
- No, sir.
- I'd rather not.
- Why not?
Well, sir, I can't go
on posing as what I'm not
and, er... I don't wish to
remain in service any longer, sir.
I want to make
something of myself.
I would like to stand
on my own two feet.
This is a land, sir, of great
opportunity where all are created equal.
There, that's... that's what
I been... Now you're talkin'.
Like Lincoln said
that day at Gettysburg.
He hit the nail right on
the nose when he said...
Well, what did he say?
That's funny. I was gonna
ask you the same thing.
He, er... What did he say?
- I don't know. Do you?
- I don't know.
Er... he... he said...
- Hey, Sam!
- Yeah?
What did Lincoln say
that day at Gettysburg?
I don't know but
I'll find out.
What did Lincoln
say at Gettysburg?
I don't know.
Harry, what did Lincoln
say at Gettysburg?
I don't know, boss.
Hey, Curly, what did
Lincoln say at Gettysburg?
I don't recollect. Ask Hank.
He reads the newspapers.
- What did he say, Hank?
- I don't know.
- Ask the boys, will you?
- Sure.
- Try and find out for me, will you, Harry?
- Hey.
- Hein?
What did Lincoln
say at Gettysburg?
I don't know.
I wasn't there.
What did Lincoln
say at Gettysburg?
I don't know.
What did he say?
I was asking you.
You wasn't there!
- I couldn't find out.
- That dumb bunch don't know.
There's none of them
there that knows.
What a fine bunch
of Americans!
That's funny.
Four score and
seven years ago
our fathers brought forth, on
this continent, a new nation,
conceived in liberty and dedicated to the
proposition that all men are created equal.
Now we are engaged in
a great civil war...
Why, that's it.
Bill, don't tell
me you know it.
- How does it go, Bill?
- Er...
"Four score and
seven years ago
"our fathers brought forth, on
this continent, a new nation,
"conceived in liberty,
"and dedicated to the proposition
that all men are created equal.
"Now we are engaged
in a great civil war,
"testing whether that nation, or any
nation so conceived, and so dedicated,
"can long endure.
"We are now on a great
battlefield of that war.
"We have come to dedicate
a portion of that field,
"as a final resting place
"for those who here gave their
lives, that that nation might live.
"It is altogether fitting and
proper that we should do this.
"But, in a larger sense, we cannot
dedicate, we cannot consecrate,
"we cannot hallow,
this ground.
"The brave men, living and
dead, who struggled here,
"have consecrated it far beyond
our poor power to add or detract.
"The world will little note, nor
long remember what we say here,
"but it can never forget
what they did here.
"It is for us the living, rather, to
be dedicated here to the unfinished work
"which they who fought here
have thus far so nobly advanced.
"It is rather for us to be here dedicated
to the great task remaining before us,
"that from these honoured dead we
take increased devotion to that cause
"for which they gave the
last full measure of devotion,
"that we here highly resolve that these
dead shall not have died in vain...
"...that this nation, under God,
shall have a new birth of freedom,
"and that government of the people,
by the people, and for the people,
"shall not perish
from the earth."
I'll buy a drink.
Here's to Colonel Ruggles!
Here, here!
Well, I'll tell you, Bill,
we already got a president,
but any time you want to run for mayor
or sheriff or something like that,
you just let me know.
I'm not ambitious for
public office, sir.
Bill, what are you figuring on doing
besides standing on your own two feet?
I keep telling him he
should open a restaurant.
- Great!
- Say, that ain't a bad ideia.
We ain't never had a decent
hash house here in Red Gap.
And I'll stake you to the
best location in town for it.
- I beg your pardon, madam?
- It won't cost you a nickel.
I own the building.
There was a Chinaman tried to run a
chop suey joint there and they shot him.
He couldn't cook ham and eggs. He was
always doin' something Chinese to 'em.
I could help you in the kitchen. I'll
even let you help me with my meat sauce.
How... how much cash you
figure it would take, Bill?
If I might say so,
you're all a bit of OK.
Well, you... you're
more than that.
Doggone it! Let's have a
drink to the new beanery.
Well... well, wait a minute, wait
a minute. What... what'll we call it?
- Er...
- Yes.
- Um...
- Er...
How about calling
it The Busy Bee?
No, no.
- The Mustang Grotto.
- No, no.
I think it should be something
nice like Ye Olde English Tavern.
No, no.
Look, look, look. I got it, I got
it. The Golden Horse Chop House.
No.
Why? Why? Can't you just see a golden
horse squattin' up there on the roof?
No, no, no!
Er... might I suggest
The Anglo-American Grill?
- Um...
- Not bad, hein?
- I like it.
- What do you think, Egbert?
Well, it's all right but I still think
it ought to be called a horse's something.
No, no, no.
- Hello, Belknap.
- Effie.
Here's a letter from Lord
Burnstead. It just arrived this noon.
Oh, dear George.
Dear, dear George. Yes.
Oh! He's coming here. He's
coming here to visit us!
- He's coming here?
- Yes. Yes, yes.
He's going to take
Ruggles back with him.
Oh.
The Earl of Burnstead
our house guest.
My supreme
triumph in Red Gap.
- What's the matter?
- Ruggles is gone.
- What?
- He's on his way to São Francisco.
- What are you talking about?
- I... I discharged him.
You discharged him? You...
Oh, you couldn't. You...
you... How dare you?
- What can we do?
What can we do?
Oh, what can we do?
What can... Oh,
I'm going to faint.
Oh, no. No, I'm not.
I'm going to find Egbert.
It's a mess, isn't it?
It's wonderful.
Well, I don't see anything
wonderful about it.
- You don't?
- No.
You don't?
My father was a gentleman's
gentleman, and his father before him.
And from that heritage of service,
miraculously, there comes a man,
a person of importance,
however small,
a man whose decisions and whose
future are in his own hands.
It's wonderful, isn't it?
Restaurant? Ruggles
opening a restaurant?
Yeah, where the chop
suey joint used to be.
Well, of course he's not going
to do anything of the sort.
Whoever suggested
such a horrible ideia?
Hey, Ma! Old man Schwartz certainly
did a good job on the suit, didn't he?
Oh, hello, Effie.
Ye Gods and little
prairie dogs!
Where in... Where did you
get that horse blanket?
Now, look-a-here, Effie, this is
a man's suit and I aim to wear it!
- Where are your good clothes?
- They're all gone.
Egbert Floud, take
off those clothes.
No, sir, I won't do it.
- Take off those clothes!
- No, sir, I won't do it!
Effie, we might just as well have
a showdown right here and now.
What did Lincoln say at Gettysburg?
Yeah, you don't know. Well, I'll tell you.
He said that all men
are created equal.
He didn't just mean a few men. He
meant all men, and that includes me.
I'm created equal.
- Equal to what?
- Equal... equal to what?
Well, equal to...
She changed the subject on me.
Er... men are created equal to women!
That's why you have no right to
order me around the way you do.
Abe Lincoln said so.
He also said you can fool some
of the people some of the time,
and all of the people
some of the time.
But you can't fool me,
Egbert Floud, any of the time!
You striped bass!
Effie!
Oh, no. I say, you
mustn't do that.
No, no, no, no. No, no.
You mustn't do that. Let me.
- Ruggles!
- Yes, madam?
Lord Burnstead. He's coming.
Here. Here's his letter.
- Coming here, madam?
- Yes, yes. Isn't it glorious?
Of course, I shall be simply frantic
arranging dinners, parties and receptions
but I'm depending
on you, Ruggles.
- What are you doing? Are you busy?
- Yes, rather, madam.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
The... the restaurant.
The chop-suey joint
you were going to open.
Well, of course, that's
out of the question now.
It was a silly ideia to begin
with. Oh, but here I am wasting time
and... and dear George apt
to pop in on us any moment.
Oh, Ruggles, you don't know
what this means to me. Au revoir!
Au revoir!
Well, he's coming to get me.
You're not gonna
let him, are you?
I suppose he needs me.
You mean you're gonna give up all
this just to keep him buttoned up?
What has he ever
done for you?
Well, he did let me down
but I'd be the first member of my
family ever to let his family down.
And I'd have you
know, Sra. Judson,
that it isn't just keeping a man
buttoned up, it's heredity and loyalty,
and I suppose you could call
it habit if you wanted to.
I'd hate to tell
you what I'd call it.
Why don't you practise
what you been preaching?
First I find you're not a colonel
and now I find you're not a man.
Maybe you'd better
find out what you are.
Oh, I feel like
jumping in the river.
Well, go ahead and jump.
And jump in at the
bend. It's deeper there.
Now, let me see. Let me see.
The Earl of Burnstead on my right,
of course. Er... who's next to him?
- Judy Ballard.
- Absolutely not. No, we'll put her...
Way down in the slums
at my end of the table.
Has anybody seen
anything of Ruggles?
Not a sign of him.
- You didn't fire him again, did you?
- I did not.
I looked all over town
for him, everywhere.
Oh, he couldn't desert me
like this in my hour of need.
Do you realise I don't even know
how to introduce my guest of honour?
There's the doorbell.
They're arriving too early.
- I'll tell them.
- You'll do nothing of the sort.
I'll bet a dollar Lord Burnstead
hasn't got his shirt on yet.
Bit of a problem, isn't it?
Yeah, what?
Well, we can't very well go downstairs
without our ties being tied, can we?
- Yeah, no, no, we can't.
- Mm.
Maybe... maybe we can't
go downstairs at all.
Um... no. Beastly bores, receptions,
aren't they? Tedious, I mean.
- I don't like 'em, do you?
- Well, they don't bother me none.
- No?
- No, I never go to 'em.
- Oh, I see.
- I'm... I'm what they call agile.
Agile?
Oh! Oh, you... you
mean agile, hein?
Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
- Admiral, come here a minute.
- Yes.
Now, er... take a look
at this here window.
Looks just like an ordinary
window at first glance, doesn't it?
- You're right.
- Uh-hein.
Did you ever have occasion to,
er... climb out of a window?
Oh, yes. Hm.
- See what you can do with this one.
- Ah.
Oh, I hate to leave that but we
may bump into another later, hein?
- Take her easy, now. Take her easy.
- Yes.
You, er... you'll find a hole in the
wall for your foot. I put it there myself.
Yes. Yes, I found it.
Come right in, girls.
Put your things down here.
All right, thank you.
Is my hair all right?
Yes, that's very good.
Now, how about mine?
- Oh, I'm sorry we were late.
- It... it's quite all right.
If you'll go right in, I...
I'll join you in just a moment.
There seems to be something
the matter with these drapes.
? Cheyenne, Cheyenne,
hop on my pony
?There's room
here for two, dear
? But after the ceremony
We'll both ride back...
I hope that
wasn't the drinks.
- It was.
- Excuse me.
Oh, Miss Kenner, I'm
so sorry this happened,
but I'm so nervous I could
jump right out of my skin.
Well, don't worry
about a few glasses.
Oh, it isn't that.
It's Sr. Ruggles.
I just know something's
happened to him, something fatal.
Oh, nonsense. He'll show up.
But I'm just not myself.
You see what I mean?
- Here I am. Hi, Nell.
- Why, Egbert!
- Where's your coat?
- Effie wanted me to wear it.
But I'll tell you later
how I got out of it.
I want you to meet somebody.
Come on in here, George.
Nell, I want you to meet my
poker-playing friend Earl Burnstead.
- How do you do?
- This is Nell Kenner.
- Yeah, Earl is a lord.
Ain't that right, Lord?
Yeah, but you can call
him George for short.
And I want you two to get acquainted.
You know, Nell, make him feel at home.
Because he ain't quite used to our
ways, and over where he come from...
Er... Oh, heck. I guess
it's the same the world over.
Give me a drink, somebody.
Er... this is a frightful
intrusion, isn't it?
Oh, not at all. Isn't Sra. Floud
giving you a dinner tonight?
Yes. Oh, yes.
Oh, I... I see your point.
Well, you see, I...
Well, you can see for
yourself my tie isn't right.
Oh, isn't that too bad?
Shall I tie it for you?
- Oh, I say, would you really?
- Of course.
Oh, I say, isn't this nice?
Is this your first visit
to America, Lord Burnstead?
Hein? Oh, I'm so sorry. I was
thinking of something else. I...
You're remarkably like a girl I
know. I can't remember her name.
- Hm?
- Yes. You don't know it, I suppose?
- No.
- No, I suppose not.
She's... she's the most
beautiful girl in England.
There.
I'm afraid that's
the best I can do.
Oh, it's first-rate,
really. Thanks awfully.
I say, do... do you believe
in love at first sight?
- No.
- No?
- Do you?
- No.
That's why I'd like to stay
a little while, if I may.
- What?
- Come on in.
Fascinating, your
American rhythm, isn't it?
Yes, isn't it?
It's ready.
Oh. Shall we eat?
Er... no, I'd rather try
this again, if you don't mind.
- All right.
- Yes.
? Everybody loves a baby
That's why I'm in love with you
? Pretty baby, boom...
- Why did you say boom?
- There's a boom there.
- Oh, is there? Oh.
- You don't seem to understand.
- Say it once with me.
- Yes.
Everybody loves a baby, that's
why I'm in love with you.
Pretty baby, boom.
- That's right.
- I see. Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
? Everybody loves a baby
That's why I'm in love with you
- ? Pretty baby
- ? Boom...
No, you do it on the drum.
Hein? Of course.
How stupid of me.
- Yes.
- Hein?
? Everybody loves a baby
?That's why I'm in love
with you Pretty baby...
? Pretty baby...
- I'm sorry.
- What?
- There's another one there.
- Oh. Oh, a ditto?
- Yes, a ditto boom.
- Oh, I like that.
- You like what?
- A ditto boom.
Ditto boom. Ditto boom.
Ditto boom, boom, boom.
Oh, let's eat.
What? No, I'd rather ditto
boom, if you don't mind.
- All right, we'll ditto boom.
- That's fine, that's fine.
? Everybody loves a baby
That's why I'm in love with you
? Pretty baby...
? I'd like to be your sister, brother
Dad and mother too, pretty baby...
Popping in everywhere.
? Pretty baby...
?Won't you come and let me
rock you In my cradle of love...
That was my own ideia.
I know it.
? Oh, I want a lovin' baby
And it might as well be you...
- Oh, would that be asking too much?
- Why, of course not, no.
- I mean two booms.
- Oh, I see. Yes.
? Oh, I want a lovin' baby
And it might as well be you...
Oh.
Oh, was that your drum?
You couldn't sew it
up, I don't suppose?
No. Oh.
Buy a new one, will
you? Buy two, one for me.
I'm sure Lord Burnstead will forgive
us for not waiting for him any longer.
He'll join us, I know,
just as soon as he's finished
his conversation on the telephone,
which I'm sure must
be terribly important.
Possibly a... a
message from the King
or possibly from the,
er... Mayor of Canadá.
Er... possibly.
Well, shall we begin?
Why not?
Go on, pitch in.
You come on in here where you
can't spill drinks all over me.
Oh, I'm so sorry but
I'm just not myself.
Now, you sit down and tell
me what's the matter. Come on.
Oh, I don't see how they
can go on having a good time
when maybe he's...
Oh, you know.
- Who? What are you talking about?
- Colonel Ruggles.
I think he jumped
in the river.
No! Why should he
want to do that?
Oh, on account of a woman. She
treated him something awful.
- Who told you that?
- I was there.
Oh, she said some terrible things
to him and I just know that...
- Why, say, this is serious!
- That's what I say.
Well, we gotta get
busy right away.
- Oh, will you?
- Well, yes, I'll round up the boys.
Hey, fellers,
look-a-here!
Get on your hats and coats.
I got something for you to do.
- It is a ghost! Oh, you didn't do it!
- Colonel Ruggles is missin'!
Follow me. We'll get
going right away. I...
Er... well, the
searching party's off.
Look-a-here, Bill, what's the ideia
of wanderin' around scarin' women?
I thought the Indians had got
you, Ruggles. Glad to see you.
I am glad to
see you, my lord.
I'm sorry I wasn't at the
station to meet you, my lord.
That's all right.
Er... might I have a word
with you alone, my lord?
Why, I should
think so. Why not?
Come on, old timer,
let's leave them alone.
- I don't understand.
- Get them a drink.
She tells me he's in the
river and he ain't even wet.
Something wrong, Ruggles?
I've had a terrible day, my
lord, a... a terrific fight.
- Oh. Were you outnumbered?
- An even match, my lord.
- A woman?
- No, my lord. I was fighting with myself.
- Did you win?
- A decisive victory, my lord.
Oh, stout feller! I didn't
think you had it in you.
Er... you'll find me rather
a changed man, my lord.
I don't know quite
how to tell you
but here in Red Gap I
am considered important.
Quite a personage.
Yes, Colonel
Ruggles, isn't it?
Yes, my lord. Colonel Marmaduke
Ruggles of the Coldstream Guards.
- A horrible mistake, my lord.
- Quite, if there should be a war.
Yes.
Nevertheless, my lord,
when people think you are someone,
you begin to think you are.
That's what I've been fighting
about with myself all day, my lord.
Am I someone or am I not?
Well, I only just got here,
you see, so I wouldn't know.
Oh, I am someone, my lord.
Oh, let me be the first to congratulate
you. How did you ever find it out?
Ah. You recollect an
Abraham Lincoln, my lord?
Oh, yes, fellow
with the cherry tree.
- Er... no, my lord.
- Er... no?
At any rate, my lord, I am
genuinely sorry to have to tell you
that I shall not be returning with you
to London, I am remaining in Red Gap.
Oh, now, wait a
minute, Ruggles.
It's no use, my lord.
My mind is made up.
I am entering trade,
my lord, a restaurant.
Oh, it's no good for you, Ruggles. You
haven't got the background for trade.
Nevertheless, my
lord, I intend to try.
Oh, I never knew you to be
so obstinate before, really.
Still, something tells me
that we'll be back in London.
- Oh, excuse me. Here are your drinks.
- Oh. Hm.
Well, here's to London.
Here is to The
Anglo-American Grill, my lord.
Ha-ha. Yes.
Oh!
Mm, we should be all
right. Ready in ten minutes.
- Oh, they love your meat sauce.
- You mean our meat sauce.
Because I added a few drops of
this and a little bit of that.
Did you?
- Colonel, are we dressed all right?
- Indeed, yes, sir.
Table for four.
Thank you. Hello.
- Hello, Egbert!
- Hello, George!
- You remember Effie, boys.
- Howdy, Effie!
Make way for a lady,
you laughing hyenas!
You're losing
your petticoat, Ma!
Hey, Sourdough, where
did you get the lid?
From Paris, France!
Ain't it terrible?
Hold onto that hat.
It cost me 20 dollars.
Hello, Maude. Hello, Frank.
- Hello... why, hello, Fred!
- Howdy, Sourdough.
- How's everything? Hello, Soph.
- How are you?
Well, Bill, you're kinda
dressed up, ain't you?
Hello, Bill. Where do
you want us to squat?
Heh-heh. Yeah, ain't Bill
movin' around, though, hein?
Oh, Effie, where
is Lord Burnstead?
He must have been delayed.
He's a very busy man, you know.
- Ruggles.
- Yes, madam?
Where's Lord Burnstead?
I understood he was
coming with you, madam.
He was but he didn't.
I can't understand it.
Lord Burnstead probably didn't
care to come to a place like this.
A nice party this is going to
be, without our guest of honour.
You don't know where
George is, do you?
- Who, George?
- Shh.
George? No, I ain't
seen George all day.
No, the left-hand side.
Look-a-here, Effie, you're taking
this thing too much to heart.
Try a little of
our meat sauce, sir.
Haven't you any catsup?
Oh, never mind. I'll
eat when I get home.
What you want is...
what you want is... is...
some more of this imprisoned laughter
of the pleasant maids of France.
- What's wrong now?
- Nothing wrong with the food.
What happened?
I suppose it's wrong to hate anybody,
but I dislike Belknap-Jackson very much.
I'm gonna get you
something for your nerves.
- No, my nerves are quite all right.
- Oh, but I am.
No, I'm all right.
Oh, Effie? Where can
Lord Burnstead be?
I told you he's a very busy
man. He's a man of affairs.
- Have a good time.
- Thanks a lot, old man.
Oh, Effie?
- Hi, Nell!
- Hello, Egbert!
Hello, Nell! Well, Admiral!
Say, where have you been?
- Effie's been looking for you.
- Oh, dear. I'm sorry.
- Dear, oh, dear! I'm so sorry.
- Yeah, sit down, sit down, Bill.
- I have no excuse at all.
- No?
No. It... it must have been
the excitement, probably.
- Excitement?
- Yes.
Do you believe in
love at first sight?
- Oh, no, no.
- No, no.
Neither did we but, er...
Darling, just a minute.
I mean, look. You see?
Well, you old mossback, you.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, old boy.
What's the matter with you,
Nell? You been losing your mind?
- She's going to be my countess.
- She's going to be a countess!
- Sit down, won't you? Come on!
- Yeah, Bill, let's have another chair.
Sit right down here, Admiral. And,
Nell, you sit right next to him there.
This is gonna be my party
on account of my knowing
Nell longer than anybody here.
- Oh, Egbert?
- Yes.
Egbert, I'm going to
be matron of honour
and we're gonna have
the wedding at our house.
- Oh, sure.
- Aren't we?
Oh!
Making a countess
of a cheap dancer!
I wouldn't say that
if I were you, sir.
- You what?
- I wouldn't say that if I were you, sir.
You're insulting, Ruggles.
I beg your pardon, but
you were insulting, sir.
Not only were you insulting
but you were eavesdropping.
- That was quite unintentional, sir.
- You're lying, Ruggles.
- I wouldn't say that if I were you, sir.
- I've stood enough from you.
Aren't you forgetting that you are
nothing but a low, common shiner of boots?
I'm not forgetting that I
am proprietor of this place
and as proprietor of this place I
am politely asking you to leave, sir.
- You what?
- I'm asking you to leave.
If I go, all the real
people will leave with me.
If my success depends upon
catering to people like you, sir,
all I can say is... all I can
say is, Sr. Belknap-Jackson...
all I can say
is words fail me.
- Ruggles! How dare you?
- It's quite all right, sir.
- You can't... you can't do this to me!
- Quite all right, sir.
- This is disgraceful.
- Oh, sit down.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'd
like to say a few words to you
about the proprietor
Sr. Ruggles.
- So, I'm a failure?
- Oh, don't worry about it.
As I always say, it's always
darkest before the dawn
and every cloud has a silver lining
and it never rains but what...
Oh.
- And I'm not worrying about it.
- Oh, yes, you are. Just look at you.
? For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow...
Well, they seem to
love His Lordship.
His Lordship's a very happy man
tonight. He's marrying Nell Kenner. Yeah.
Hey! Hey, Bill! Bill, come on,
get in on this, will you? Come on.
Heh-heh! This is the biggest
show Red Gap ever had.
? He's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
?Which nobody can deny...
?Which nobody can deny
Which nobody can deny...
Why, you old plate of soup,
they're singing it for you!
What?
My friends.
God bless you all.
? For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a
jolly good fellow
?And so say all of us
And so say all of us
? For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a jolly good
fellow Which nobody can deny
?Which nobody can deny
Which nobody can deny
? For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a
jolly good fellow
?Which nobody can deny
? For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a
jolly good fellow
?And so say all of us
And so say all of us
? For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a jolly
good fellow...