- BUT, YOU KNOW, ROSIE,
SHE SAY TO ME,
"LESTER, THIS LADY FROM AMERICA,
SHE’S IN A BIG HURRY,
"AND SHE NEED TO GO PLACES,
AND YOU, LESTER, ARE THE
BEST PERSON TO TAKE THE LADY,"
SO I GIVE UP ALL MY OTHER JOBS,
AND I TAKE YOU TO SEE MR. VARTY.
- HOW FAR IS IT?
- NOT SO FAR.
HEY.
UGH.
- WHAT’S WRONG.
- [muttering]
WHAT A BOMB!
- TELL ME, WHAT IS IT?
- [muttering]
- [groans]
I CAN’T BELIEVE THIS.
boom!
WHAT AM I DOING HERE?
- MISS CHRISTINE!
HEY!
MISS CHRISTINE!
IT’S THAT WAY.
I THINK.
- YOU THINK?
- YEAH.
WE’RE HERE.
- THIS IS IT?
MR. VARTY?
- HEY, I MUST GO NOW.
- OH, OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
YEAH.
HEY, THANKS A LOT, LESTER.
- OH, YEAH.
- THANKS A LOT, REALLY.
- OKAY.
SEE YOU LATER.
OKAY, BYE, MISS CHRISTINE.
- BYE, LESTER.
MR. VARTY!
HELLO!
I COULD HARDLY BELIEVE
I WAS FINALLY HERE,
IN A PLACE BEYOND IMAGINATION,
ITS BEAUTY SO UNTAMED,
IT FILLED ME WITH UNCERTAINTY
BUT ALSO WITH
A WONDERFUL NEW HOPE.
OH!
MR. VARTY.
- OH, MR. JOHN PASSED EARLY.
I’M ELMON.
- OH, HI.
I’M CHRISTINE SHAYE.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
- HI, NICE TO MEET YOU.
- UH, EXCUSE ME.
I SORT OF MADE
MYSELF AT HOME HERE.
I DIDN’T KNOW WHEN YOU WERE
COMING BACK, SO...
- OKAY.
- THANK YOU.
- PLEASURE.
- MR. VARTY.
HI, IT’S A PLEASURE TO MEET YOU.
I’M CHRISTINE SHAYE.
- HI, CALL ME J.V.
- J.V.
YOU DID GET MY FAX, DIDN’T YOU,
THAT I WAS COMING
ABOUT THE PROGRAM?
- AH, YEAH.
DIDN’T REALIZE IT WAS SO SOON.
- OH, WELL...
I HOPE YOU DON’T MIND
I MADE MYSELF AT HOME.
THESE ARE WONDERFUL PICTURES
OF THE LEOPARDS.
- YEAH, THIS IS THE MOTHER WE’VE
BEEN FOLLOWING FOR 12 YEARS.
- OH, THEY’RE GORGEOUS.
- WANT SOME TEA?
- TEA WOULD BE GREAT.
THANK YOU.
UM, STRONG, NO MILK, TWO SUGARS.
- OKAY, WE’LL HAVE A TEA.
- TAKE A SEAT.
MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME.
- THANK YOU.
IT CERTAINLY IS SOME PLACE
YOU’VE GOT HERE.
IT’S NOT EXACTLY WHAT
I’D IMAGINED.
- SO DID YOU HAVE A GOOD TRIP?
- WELL, IT’S BEEN QUITE
AN EXPERIENCE.
TOOK A LITTLE LONGER
THAN I EXPECTED.
YOU KNOW, I’VE SEEN
MANY OF YOUR FILMS.
THEY’RE REALLY GREAT.
REALLY SPECIAL.
- TEA FOR YOU.
- THANK YOU.
- PLEASURE.
MM. SOME KIND OF HERBAL TEA,
HUH?
MR. VARTY--J.V.--
I WOULD LIKE YOU TO HELP ME
MAKE A FILM ABOUT AFRICA.
I FIGURE, WITH YOUR KNOWLEDGE
OF AFRICA,
YOU’D BE THE BEST PERSON
TO HELP.
DID YOU SEEOUT OF AFRICA?
- MM-MM.
- WELL, ANYWAY,
I WANT OUR PROGRAM
TO BE A BIT LIKE THAT.
A ROMANCE WITH AFRICA,
THE MYSTICAL CONTINENT.
- YOU KNOW THEY’RE MAKING
PRETTY PICTURES
ABOUT THE ROMANCE OF AFRICA
ALL THE TIME.
I CAN’T HELP YOU WITH THAT.
YOU WANT TO MAKE
THE REAL ISSUES,
THAT’S ANOTHER STORY.
- [tsking]
J.V.
[speaking African language]
- I DON’T KNOW WHAT--
WHAT’D HE SAY?
- UH, HE SAYS,
"HOW’S THE TEA?"
- ALL THAT TO SAY THAT, HUH?
IT’S GREAT.
THANK YOU.
LOOK, WHY DON’T YOU JUST TAKE
A LOOK AT THE SCRIPT.
I’M SURE YOU’LL HAVE
SOME IDEAS--
[animal roaring]
[both speaking African language]
- COME ON.
WE’VE GOT TO CHECK IT OUT.
- YOU WANT ME TO COME?
WANT ME TO COME?
- YEAH, YEAH!
LET’S GO!
- ALL RIGHT.
- TAKE THIS.
WHITE’S TOO BRIGHT.
- OKAY.
- [speaking African language]
[speaking African language]
[animal roaring]
- WHAT WAS THAT?
- SOUNDS LIKE LEOPARDS FIGHTING.
[speaking African language]
- [speaking African language]
- LET’S GO.
[engine turns over]
- [speaking African language]
- YEAH.
- IT’S THE MOTHER LEOPARD.
[speaking African language]
[leopard rumbling]
- CAN’T WE DO SOMETHING?
- NAH.
CAN’T INTERFERE.
[roaring and snarling]
- WHY ARE THEY FIGHTING?
- THIS LEOPARD HERE HAS INVADED
THE MOTHER’S TERRITORY.
[speaking African language]
SHE’S INJURED.
- J.V.
[speaking African language]
[roaring and snarling]
- IT’S ONE OF THE WORST
TERRITORIAL FIGHTS I’VE SEEN.
- SHE GONNA BE OKAY?
- YEAH, I THINK SO.
I THINK SHE’S OKAY.
[insects buzzing]
- J.V.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT THE FILM.
J.V, ARE YOU AWAKE?
- THIS IS A DEN THAT
SHE’S USED ABOUT FIVE WEEKS AGO.
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE SHE’S LEFT.
[speaks African language]
- [speaking African language]
- J.V.
[speaking African language]
- LION.
WELL, THIS IS ABOUT AS BIG
AS YOU’LL SEE IN AFRICA.
- WOW.
AMAZING.
- THESE ARE THE TWO
DOMINANT MALES OF THE AREA.
- MAGNIFICENT.
- J.V.,
J.V.
[speaking African language]
- HEY, LET’S GO FIND THE CUBS.
[birds twittering]
[Jeep rumbling]
- [speaking African language]
- THEY’RE ADORABLE.
I HAD NO IDEA
THEY WERE THIS BEAUTIFUL.
HOW OLD ARE THEY?
- I COUNT AROUND SIX WEEKS NOW.
- WHERE’S THE MOTHER?
- SHE’D BE OUT HUNTING.
SHE LEAVES THEM
FOR A DAY OR TWO.
DEPENDS HOW SOON
SHE CAN GET SOME FOOD.
- AND THEY DON’T RUN AWAY?
- NO.
STAY HERE IN THE ROCKS.
SEE THE ONE SLIGHTLY BIGGER?
IT’S A LITTLE MALE.
IT’S A BIT BOLDER AS WELL.
WE CAN’T STAY HERE TOO LONG.
I DON’T WANT THE MOTHER
TO CATCH US HERE AT THE DEN.
ANYWAY, I GOT SOMETHING ELSE
TO SHOW YOU.
[projector clatters and hums]
WELL, THIS IS THE MOTHER
THAT WE FOLLOWED FOR 12 YEARS.
WHEN WE FIRST SAW HER,
SHE WAS ELUSIVE, AGGRESSIVE,
AND VERY DIFFICULT TO FOLLOW,
JUST LIKE ANY OTHER
WILD LEOPARD.
THEN GRADUALLY, SHE RELAXED,
ALLOWING US
INTO HER PRIVATE WORLD.
SHE’S A VERY SUCCESSFUL MOTHER,
AND HAS ALLOWED US TO FILM
NO LESS THAN NINE
OF HER LITTERS OF CUBS.
NO OTHER HUMAN BEING HAS HAD
SUCH A CLOSE RELATIONSHIP
WITH A WILD LEOPARD BEFORE.
WELL, THIS IS HER MOVING ONE OF
THE FIFTH LITTER TO ANOTHER DEN,
WHICH SHE DOES EVERY FEW DAYS
TO LESSEN THE CHANCES
OF LION AND HYENA
FINDING AND KILLING THEM.
WELL, HERE YOU SEE
SARCOPTIC MANGE,
WHICH LEOPARDS
SOMETIMES CONTRACT.
IT’S TINY PARASITE WHICH ATTACKS
THE SKIN AND THE FUR
AND MOST OFTEN RESULTS IN DEATH.
ALL PREDATORS ARE COMPETING
FOR FOOD AND SPACE
AND WILL IMMEDIATELY KILL
THE CUBS OF ANOTHER PREDATOR
IF THEY FIND THEM.
THIS IS THE SADDEST MOMENT
WE EVER SHARED WITH HER.
SHE ATTACKED THE LIONS,
SAVED THE ONE CUB,
BUT THE OTHER WAS KILLED.
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
SHE ATE PARTS OF THE DEAD CUB
AND THEN BURIED THE REST
IN THE BRUSH.
EVEN THOUGH WE’D BEEN PART
OF EVERY ASPECT OF HER LIFE,
IT WAS SEVEN YEARS BEFORE
WE’RE ABLE TO FILM HER MATING.
WE’VE REALLY SHARED HER LIFE
IN MANY WAYS.
WE’VE SLEPT OUT
AT KILLS WITH HER.
WE’VE WATCHED HER CUBS GROW UP
AND HAVE CUBS OF THEIR OWN.
AND FOR ALL OF US, IT’S BEEN
A GREAT SPIRITUAL EXPERIENCE,
ALMOST LIKE A LOVE AFFAIR,
JUST TO BE PART OF HER LIFE.
- SHE WAS THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
ANIMAL I HAD EVER SEEN.
I UNDERSTOOD WHY JOHN AND ELMON
WERE SO DEDICATED TO HER.
THE MORE I LEARNED
ABOUT HER LIFE,
THE CLEARER IT BECAME TO ME
THAT IT WAS HER STORY
THAT HAD TO BE TOLD.
NOW IT WAS JUST A MATTER
OF GETTING THE GREEN LIGHT
FROM DAN.
- HI, CHRISTINE.
- HI, PAM.
- HOW WAS YOUR TRIP?
- IT WAS GREAT.
DID ANYTHING COME IN FOR ME?
- THIS JUST CAME.
- OH, GREAT.
HI.
THANK YOU.
HELLO,
- HI.
- OH.
- I’M SO GLAD YOU’RE BACK.
JACK IS DRIVING ME CRAZY.
- THIS’LL SHUT HIM UP.
- LET’S GO TO WORK.
- OKAY.
AND I WANT TO HEAR
ALL ABOUT THIS.
- BLACK RHINO POPULATIONS
OF AFRICA
CONTINUALLY ON THE ROAD
TO OBLIVION.
[gunshot]
A SPECIES WHICH HAS BEEN AROUND
FOR 65 MILLION YEARS
HAS, IN THE LAST DECADE,
BEEN BROUGHT TO THE BRINK
OF EXTINCTION.
MAN’S GREED AND POPULATIONS
CONTINUE UNHARNESSED.
- THIS IS SOME OF THE FOOTAGE
THAT HE’S SHOT OVER THE YEARS.
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE GONNA
COME UP WITH SOMETHING LIGHT,
SOMETHING ENTERTAINING.
WE PUT THIS ON, IT’S DEATH.
IT’S DEPRESSING.
NOBODY WANTS TO SEE IT.
BESIDES, THEY CAN SEE IT
ON THE 6:00 NEWS.
WHAT WE NEED
IS SOMETHING SPECIAL.
- EXACTLY, JACK.
AND THIS IS SPECIAL.
VARTY LIVES IN A TREE
OUT IN THE MIDDLE OF THE BUSH.
HE SPENDS HIS ENTIRE LIFE
FILMING WILDLIFE.
HE’S DEDICATED THE LAST 12 YEARS
TO FOLLOWING
A SINGLE FEMALE LEOPARD
THROUGH EIGHT LITTERS OF CUBS.
HE’S CAPTURED ON FILM
SOME OF THE MOST SPECTACULAR
LEOPARD FOOTAGE EVER SHOT.
TO TOP IT ALL OFF,
SHE NOW HAS TWO NEW CUBS
THAT I’VE HAD
THE PRIVILEGE OF MEETING.
THERE’S A GREAT STORY HERE.
- NOT BAD, CHRIS.
NOT BAD AT ALL.
I WANT TO SEE A BUDGET
AND A FULL PROPOSAL.
THANK YOU.
- [roars]
- [speaks African language]
- GET OUT OF THERE, GIRL.
[snarling and roaring]
GET OUT!
GET OUT OF THERE!
[whispering and muttering]
WATCH OUT!
FOLLOW, ELMON.
[speaks African language]
WATCH THESE TREES.
KEEP GOING.
SHE WENT LEFT, ELMON.
WATCH OUT.
WAIT.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
SHH.
LISTEN.
[snarling and roaring]
I THINK THEY GOT HER, ELMON.
[snarling]
MUST TRY FIRST THING
IN THE MORNING TO FIND HER.
- OKAY.
[purring]
- [speaking African language]
- YEAH.
[both speaking
African language]
- OKAY.
[speaking African language]
[birds twittering]
[mewling]
- FOR ME, SHE HAD ALWAYS BEEN
THE ULTIMATE SURVIVOR.
FOR 12 YEARS, SHE HAD BEEN
MY STRENGTH, MY INSPIRATION.
PERHAPS I’D EVEN BELIEVED
SHE WAS INVINCIBLE.
THE LIONS HAD CORNERED HER
MANY TIMES IN THE PAST,
BUT THE YEARS
HAD SUDDENLY TAKEN THEIR TOLL.
SHE WAS NO LONGER AS AGILE,
AND NATURE ALLOWS
FOR NO WEAKNESS.
FOR SO MANY YEARS, WE HAD SHARED
HER TRIUMPHS, HER SORROWS.
SHE WAS MY SOUL MATE,
AND NOW SHE WAS DYING.
- THE BUDGET.
- UH-OH.
- I KNOW.
I’M TRYING TO BRING IT DOWN.
- DAN, I HAD VALERIE
DO SOME GROUNDWORK
ON THIS VARTY CHARACTER.
HE’S A BIT OF A LOOSE CANNON.
NEVER REALLY BROUGHT ANYTHING
IN ON TIME.
PROBABLY DOESN’T KNOW THE
MEANING OF THE WORD "BUDGET."
- OH, COME ON, JACK.
- CHRIS, DON’T GET ME WRONG.
I’M ON YOUR SIDE.
IT’S JUST I DON’T WANT TO HAVE
TO COME IN AND CLEAN UP WHEN--
EXCUSE ME--
IF THINGS GET OUT OF CONTROL.
- WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT, JACK?
- CAN YOU DELIVER THIS TIME?
- OKAY, JACK.
WE GET THE POINT.
AND EVERYONE KNOWS THAT WHAT
HAPPENED WITH THE LAST PROJECT
WAS NOT ENTIRELY
CHRISTINE’S FAULT.
BUT THIS IS THE KIND
OF PROJECT WE REALLY NEED.
IT’S DIFFERENT.
- DIFFERENT.
- IT’S HIGH-PROFILE.
IT’S THE KIND OF THING
THAT CAN PULL US BACK UP.
- YES, SIR.
- BUT IT’S UP TO YOU, CHRISTINE.
I’M NOT GONNA BABYSIT YOU
ON THIS PROJECT.
YOU’VE BEEN OUT THERE.
YOU KNOW THE TERRITORY.
YOU KNOW THIS GUY VARTY.
YOU KNOW WHAT I NEED.
THIS PROJECT MEANS A LOT TO ME.
I’M COUNTING ON YOU, KID.
- UH, YES, MR. VARTY--WALKER.
- ALL RIGHT.
[both speaking African language]
- WE’VE GOT TO FIND THOSE CUBS,
ELMON.
- [speaks African language]
[cubs purring]
[animal hooting]
[lion snorting]
[birds twittering]
- AH, THEY’RE NOT HERE.
- [speaks African language]
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
[speaking African language]
- [speaking African language]
- [chanting]
- ELMON WENT TO ASK THE SPIRITS
WHERE WE MIGHT FIND THE CUBS
WHILE I PORED OVER MY MAPS
WHICH PLOTTED
HER TERRITORIAL BOUNDARIES
AND FAVORITE DEN SITES.
[both chanting
in African language]
ELMON.
- YEAH?
- COME LOOK HERE.
I THINK I’VE GOT IT.
[speaking African language]
ELMON.
- YEAH?
- [speaking African language]
- OKAY.
[both speaking
African language]
HEH.
[speaking African language]
[both speaking
African language]
- OKAY.
- [speaking African language]
- J.V.!
- HEY, JIMMY.
HOW YOU DOING?
- GOOD.
- LONG TIME, NO SEE.
YEAH, GOOD.
GOOD, GOOD.
- WHAT’S THAT FOR?
- OH, I GOT SOME BABY LEOPARDS.
- OH?
- YEAH, LIONS KILLED THE MOTHER.
- OH, POOR THINGS.
- YEAH, A COUPLE OF WEEKS OLD.
THEY’RE DOING WELL.
- HUH.
- YEAH, THIS IS GOOD STUFF,
THEY TELL ME.
AND YOU?
PROBLEMS WITH THE POACHING?
- OH, YOU KNOW ME.
I’M STILL AS FAST.
- AH, THAT’S GOOD.
AND THE CAMP?
WHERE’S THE CAMP NOW?
- OH, FIVE MILES SOUTH
FROM HERE.
- UH-HUH.
ON THE RIVER, EH?
- YEAH, YOU KNOW ME.
- OKAY.
OKAY.
[speaks African language]
HELLO, IS THAT
"GLOBAL EXPLORER?"
[speaks African language]
YEAH.
IS CHRISTINE SHAYE THERE
BY ANY CHANCE?
- SHE’S NOT IN RIGHT NOW.
CAN I TAKE A MESSAGE?
- YEAH, TELL HER
I HAVE FOUND THE CUBS.
THAT’S LEOPARD CUBS.
- CAN I GIVE HER A NUMBER
SO SHE CAN CALL YOU BACK?
- NO, UNFORTUNATELY,
I’M AT LONDOLOZI
IN A REMOTE PART
OF SOUTH AFRICA.
JUST TELL HER J.V. PHONED.
AND SEE THAT SHE GETS
THAT MESSAGE.
- OH, MR. VARTY.
OH, YEAH, SURE.
I’LL TELL HER YOU CALLED.
HAVE A NICE DAY.
BYE.
- WELL, I’M NOT QUITE SURE
HOW TO PUT IT.
- WHY DON’T YOU JUST SAY IT,
CHRIS?
- UM, I JUST GOT WORD
THAT THE MOTHER LEOPARD IS DEAD.
- THAT’S FOR CHRISTINE.
- I’M HEADED THAT WAY.
[phone rings]
- I’M NOT EVEN SURE
WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT I WAS THINKING THAT
WE STILL HAVE A STRONG STORY
IF WE CAN FIND HER CUBS.
I’VE BEEN TRYING
TO GET AHOLD OF J.V.
TO SEE IF THEY’RE STILL ALIVE.
- YOU KNOW, I REALLY STUCK
MY NECK OUT ON THIS PROJECT.
- I KNOW YOU HAVE, SIR.
[knocking]
- MY SCREENING’S AT 3:30.
HOPE I’M NOT INTERRUPTING.
- NO.
COME IN, JACK.
THE LEOPARD’S DEAD.
- OH, NO.
- AND I DON’T KNOW
IF THIS COMPANY CAN SURVIVE
ANOTHER FAILED PROJECT.
- I REALIZE THAT, UM, BUT,
WHAT THE MOTHER LEOPARD DOES IS,
SHE MOVES HER CUBS
FROM DEN TO DEN.
I’M SURE IT’S A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE J.V. FINDS THEM.
- ALL DUE RESPECT, CHRISTINE,
YOU’VE BEEN SURE
OF A LOT OF THINGS IN THE PAST.
- LOOK, JACK, WE ALREADY HAVE
12 YEARS OF LEOPARD FOOTAGE
THAT WE CAN WORK WITH.
- STOCK FOOTAGE
FOR AN ENTIRE PROGRAM?
YOU MUST BE KIDDING.
CHRISTINE, ALL YOU HAVE
TO OFFER IS ONE DEAD LEOPARD.
ALL WE HAVE IS ONE DEAD PROJECT.
- PLEASE, MR. WALKER,
JUST GIVE ME A FEW WEEKS,
AND I CAN WORK SOMETHING OUT.
- YOU’VE GOT ONE WEEK, CHRIS.
- THANK YOU.
- LOOK WHAT I’VE GOT FOR YOU.
- [speaks African language]
- COME ON, PRETTY BOY.
AH, SISTER.
[speaking African language]
LITTLE TOUGHY, EH?
LITTLE TOUGHY.
YEAH.
DRINK IT.
DON’T BITE THE BOTTLE.
THAT’S MY BOY.
THAT’S MY GIRLY GIRL.
- [speaks African language]
- I SHOULD’VE USED THIS.
- [speaking African language]
- [chuckles]
- COME ON, YOU GUYS.
- OKAY, LET’S GO FOR WALK.
- COME ON.
HAVE A WALK NOW.
[whistles]
COME ON, SISTER.
LET’S WALK.
- HELLO.
IS THIS THE HAZYVIEW HOTEL?
CAN YOU HELP ME, PLEASE?
YEAH, I HAVE TO GET AHOLD
OF J.V., OKAY?
JOHN VARTY.
DOES ANYONE KNOW WHERE HE IS?
HAS HE LEFT ANY MESSAGES?
OH, OKAY.
LOOK, IF YOU DO SPEAK TO HIM,
TELL HIM IT’S VERY IMPORTANT
THAT I TALK TO HIM.
NUH-HUH.
OKAY, BYE.
[sighs]
- "SO I AM LEFT
IN THE DIFFICULT POSITION
"OF HAVING TO HAND-RAISE
HER TWO ORPHAN CUBS
"WITH THE INTENTION
OF REINTRODUCING THEM
INTO THE WILDS."
[leopard mewling and chirping]
HEY, COME ON.
YOU’RE FUNNY, MAN.
"I BELIEVE YOUR OFFICE
IS RESPONSIBLE
"FOR ISSUING SUCH PERMITS,
AND I WOULD APPRECIATE YOUR
COOPERATION IN THIS REGARD."
[engine rumbling]
- MR. VARTY.
- UP HERE.
- VARTY.
- MR. VAN HEERDEN.
- YEAH.
- HI.
- WE RECEIVED YOUR LETTER.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE’RE UNABLE
TO PROCESS YOUR REQUEST.
UNLESS YOU MAKE
A FORMAL APPLICATION.
- UGH.
WHAT’S THE PROBLEM?
TAKE A SEAT.
- THERE HAVE BEEN
SOME COMPLAINTS.
- LIKE, FROM WHO?
- [chuckles]
IT’S NOT OUR POLICY
TO DIVULGE THAT INFORMATION.
THIS ANIMAL SHOULD REALLY
BE KEPT IN A CAGE.
WHAT IF ONE WANDER OFF AND
TAKES SOMEONE’S DOMESTIC CATTLE?
- AH, COME ON.
COME ON.
YOU KNOW THERE’S A PROCLAIMED
GAME RESERVE HERE.
THERE’S NO STOCK FOR MILES.
- OFF THE RECORD,
I AGREE WITH YOU.
BUT THE LAW IS QUITE CLEAR
ON THE ISSUE
OF HAND-RAISING OF WILD ANIMALS.
THEY MUST BE KEPT
SECURELY CONTAINED
IN A CAGE OR ENCLOSURE,
FAILING WHICH,
THEY WILL BE DESTROYED.
- SO UNDER YOUR RULES,
THEY’RE GONNA END UP
IN A FILTHY ZOO,
PACING UP AND DOWN.
WITH ME, THEY’VE GOT A CHANCE
AT RUNNING FREE.
- WE ARE ON THE SAME SIDE,
MR. VARTY,
BUT MY HANDS ARE TIED.
PERHAPS I CAN--
[snarling]
- GIVE IT HERE.
GIVE ME THAT.
COME ON, GIVE ME THE HAT.
DON’T EAT MR. VAN HEERDEN’S HAT.
HOLD ON.
HEY.
GIVE ME THAT.
LITTLE BOY, GIVE ME THE HAT.
- WHAT ABOUT RABIES?
I’M AFRAID THIS WILL HAVE TO GO
IN MY REPORT, MR. VARTY.
- YOUR HAT.
- MR. VARTY, I WOULD RECOMMEND
YOU MAKE A PLAN IN A HURRY.
IT’S FOR THE BEST, YOU KNOW.
HERE IS YOUR APPLICATIONS.
THESE ANIMALS SHOULD NOT BE
RUNNING WILD.
- GREAT P.R. JOB YOU DID.
[speaking African language]
THAT’S A TORTOISE, SISTER.
THAT’S A TORTOISE.
COME ON.
HEY, SISTER.
SISTER.
UGH.
RAN OUT.
- J.V.
- YUP.
- [speaks African language]
- OH, COME ON.
GET ANOTHER ROLL.
- NO MORE FILM STOCK.
- UGH.
COME ON.
LOOK AT THE SHOT WE’RE MISSING.
GOT THE CAP?
- NOT IN THE CAMERA.
- HOW CAN WE WORK LIKE THIS?
- WHY NOT PHONE THE STORE?
- BEAUTIFUL SHOT.
[speaks African language]
- HI, CHRISTINE.
J.V. HERE.
I’M GETTING REALLY WORRIED
BECAUSE THESE CUBS
ARE GETTING BIG NOW,
AND I CAN JUST FEEL THIS PROJECT
STARTING TO SLIP AWAY.
I GOT A FANTASTIC SEQUENCE.
I’VE BEEN TAKING SOME FISH
OUT OF THE--AAGH!
YOU MONSTER!
AH, THAT WAS A CUB.
JUST BIT ME ON THE TOE.
OKAY.
ANYWAY, THEY CAUGHT THESE FISH
IN A DRYING POOL,
AND THEN I LOST--
THE CAMERA BROKE,
AND I HAD TO SEND THAT IN
FOR TWO WEEKS,
BUT PLEASE, LET ME KNOW
ONE WAY OR THE OTHER
BECAUSE THIS IS
A FANTASTIC PROJECT,
AND WE’VE GOT TO GET GOING NOW.
- AND HOW ABOUT
A SWEET DEPOSIT?
HOW DOES THAT SOUND TO YOU, HUH?
OH, YEAH. VERIFY--
- JACK.
WILL YOU EXCUSE US, VALERIE?
PAM SAID SHE GAVE YOU
THE MESSAGE.
- WHAT MESSAGE?
- I JUST GOT THIS FAX.
THE CUBS ARE ALREADY ON MEAT.
J.V. FOUND THEM WEEKS AGO.
- YOU GO TELL DAN
THAT WHAT WE HAVE IS NO LONGER
A DEAD PROJECT.
SO LONG, JACK.
[jet engine whining]
[laughter]
- I REMEMBER YOU.
THANK YOU.
- THANKS A LOT, LESTER.
- OKAY, TAKE CARE,
MISS CHRISTINE.
- WHERE’S J.V.?
- J.V.’S WENT TO HESIVI
THIS MORNING.
TRY SOME GET A PERMIT.
- PERMIT FOR WHAT?
- OH, FOR THE LEOPARDS.
- [gasps]
ARE THEY STILL BABIES?
OH, GOD.
CAN I GO UP TO ’EM?
- YEAH.
CAREFUL.
THEY STILL GOT CLAWS, THOUGH.
- OKAY.
OH, GOD.
SHE’S SO PRETTY.
LOOK AT HER LITTLE FACE.
OH, ELMON,
IT’S SO GOOD TO BE BACK.
- YEAH.
- CAN I TOUCH HER?
- OH, JUST BE CAREFUL
OF THE CLAW DOES NOT HOOK YOU.
- I’M HOOKED ALREADY.
HEY, LITTLE GIRL.
OH.
[laughs]
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
DOING UP THERE, HUH?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
OH, WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
HUH?
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO?
YOU WANT TO TAKE A SHOWER?
HUH?
OH, I GET IT.
YOU’RE GONNA DRINK MY WATER.
- OH, GOOD.
- J.V., I’M REALLY SORRY
ABOUT THE MOTHER.
- YEAH, THAT’S LIFE.
- BUT I CAN’T WAIT TO SEE
WHAT YOU’VE BEEN GETTING.
HEY, LITTLE MAN.
- JUST MIND: IT’S NEGATIVE.
- NEGATIVE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
KEEPING THE NEGATIVE HERE?
- EH, STORAGE AT THE LABS
ARE SO EXPENSIVE.
- WELL, I CAN SEE WE’VE GOT SOME
SORTING OUT TO DO.
HA--HEY, HEY, HEY!
COME HERE!
LEAVE THE FILM ALONE.
- HEY, BRING BACK MY FILM.
MONSTER.
COME, LITTLE BOY.
COME, GIRLY.
YOU WANT TO WATCH
OUR MOVIE STARS.
AH, YOU SEE NOW.
LOOK HOW--
THIS IS JUST PURE INSTINCT.
HOW YOU HOIST THAT HARE
STRAIGHT UP THE TREE.
HE’S NEVER SEEN
HIS MOTHER DO THAT.
THIS IS A GREAT SHOT.
THESE CATFISH WERE TRAPPED
IN THIS MUDDY POOL.
LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIFUL.
- SO ADORABLE!
- AH, YOU SEE, THIS IS ALL
TRAINING FOR LATER LIFE.
- [chuckles]
- THEY DON’T CALL THEM
THE PERFECT PREDATOR
FOR NOTHING, YOU KNOW?
THESE GUYS CAN SURVIVE
ON ANYTHING.
LITTLE CUB, AND HE CATCHES
HIS FISH, NO PROBLEM.
CLAWS, TEETH,
EVERYTHING WORKING.
- [laughs]
- HE’S GOT IT DOWN.
- OH, THAT WAS SO...
WHAT A WAKE-UP CALL.
J.V.!
- STEVENS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I’M HERE FOR THOSE RHINO HORNS
YOU PROMISED ME.
- MAN, YOU SHOULD NOT BE SEEN
IN THIS OFFICE.
- RELAX, MAN.
I’M HERE
FOR AN IMPORT/EXPORT PERMIT.
LISTEN, I’VE GOT
A DEFINITE BUYER FOR--
- NOT HERE.
NOT HERE.
- HEY, I HAVE GOT A BUYER
FOR THOSE TWO CUBS.
- VARTY’S CUBS?
- OH, THIS IS GOOD.
GREAT.
OKAY, MOVE IN
A LITTLE BIT CLOSER.
- THAT’S-A-BOY.
- GREAT.
- OKAY, YOU GET A CLOSE-UP,
AND I’LL GET THE TWO OF YOU
IN FRAME.
WHAT A GREAT SHOT.
OH, THIS IS PERFECT.
GOT BOTH OF YOU.
HE WANTS HIS OWN CLOSE-UP.
- HI, CHRISTINE.
- HI, ELMON.
I BRING MY SON, TIDI.
- OH, GREAT.
HI, TIDI.
- HI.
- GO SAY HI.
GO SAY HI TO THEM.
- HELLO, SISTER.
WHERE’S YOUR BROTHER?
COME, BROTHER.
COME, COME, COME.
[speaks African language]
[leopard hissing]
COME, BROTHER.
COME, COME, COME.
- MR. VARTY?
- HELLO.
- I’M LOOKING FOR MR. VARTY.
- WELL, HE’S NOT HERE RIGHT NOW.
BUT MAYBE I CAN HELP YOU.
I’M CHRISTINE SHAYE.
- VAN HEERDEN.
WILDLIFE MANAGEMENT.
WHERE IS VARTY?
- I’M NOT SURE.
CAN I MAKE YOU SOME TEA?
- EH, NO THANKS.
- YOU KNOW, HE MAY BE A WHILE.
DO YOU WANT ME TO JUST TELL HIM
THAT YOU CAME BY?
- IT’S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
WHERE ARE THE CUBS?
- THE CUBS?
- YEAH, THE LEOPARD CUBS.
- OH, THOSE CUBS.
- WHAT OTHER CUBS?
- ARE YOU SURE I CAN’T HELP YOU?
- IT’S A VERY DELICATE MATTER.
IT’S ABOUT THE PERMIT
APPLICATIONS.
- YOU MEAN A PERMIT
FOR THE CUBS?
- I THINK I BETTER WAIT
FOR MR. VARTY.
THERE IS A BIG PROBLEM.
- OH.
- OH, THEN YOU
MUST HAVE NOT HEARD.
- NOT HEARD WHAT?
- IT WAS AWFUL.
THEY, UH, THEY WERE KILLED.
BY LIONS.
- THE CUBS?
- YEAH, BOTH OF THEM.
OH, IT WAS JUST SO SAD.
TRAGIC, REALLY.
AND J.V.--
OH, J.V.’S BEEN ACTING
SO STRANGE EVER SINCE.
YOU KNOW, HE DISAPPEARS
SOMETIMES FOR DAYS.
THAT’S WHERE HE IS NOW.
JUST GONE.
ELMON WENT TO GO LOOK FOR HIM.
WE’RE BOTH VERY WORRIED
ABOUT HIM.
- YEAH.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
EH.
MEJUFFROUW SHAYE.
I FIND YOUR STORY
VERY DIFFICULT TO BELIEVE.
- OH, MR. HEERDEN--
- VAN.
IT’S VAN HEERDEN
- MR. VAN HEERDEN,
I WOULD NOT JOKE ABOUT THIS.
HERE.
- EH.
WHEN DID YOU SAY THIS WAS?
- UH, LAST WEEK.
- UH.
[tsking]
VERY SAD.
AH, WELL.
I’LL HAVE TO TAKE THIS
AS EVIDENCE, YOU KNOW.
- YEAH, OF COURSE.
- OH, WELL.
SUPPOSE THERE’S NO NEED FOR ME
TO WAIT AROUND NO MORE.
BUT YOU’LL HAVE TO COME IN
TO SIGN SOME FORMS.
- SURE.
OKAY.
- TELL MR. VARTY I WAS HERE.
- I WILL.
- YOU KNOW, I DID TELL HIM
IT WAS FOR THEIR OWN GOOD.
- I KNOW.
WELL, IT WAS NICE MEETING YOU.
- BYE, MISS SHAYE.
- [whispering]
J.V.
J.V.!
- YEAH?
- A GUY WAS JUST HERE
ABOUT A PERMIT.
I THINK HE WANTED
TO TAKE THE CUBS.
- VAN HEERDEN?
- YEAH.
- WHAT DID YOU SAY?
- I SHOWED HIM PICTURES
OF THE DEAD CUBS.
- THINK HE BELIEVED YOU?
- I MAY HAVE STALLED HIM,
BUT I DON’T KNOW
IF HE WAS CONVINCED.
- "DEAR MR. NGLOVO,
"I AM LOOKING FOR A LOCATION
"TO RELEASE
MY TWO HAND-RAISED LEOPARD CUBS,
"AND I BELIEVE THE SIZE
AND REMOTENESS OF YOUR PARK
"WILL MAKE IT
AN IDEAL DESTINATION.
"AS TIME IS OF THE ESSENCE,
PLEASE COULD YOU REPLY
IMMEDIATELY..."
- "DEAR MRS. SAMUELS,
"I’VE BEEN MOST PRIVILEGED
TO BE PART
"OF A VERY SPECIAL PROJECT
OF HAND-RAISING
"TWO OF THE CUTEST ORPHAN
LEOPARD CUBS
"AFTER THEIR MOTHER
WAS KILLED BY LIONS.
"WE NOW NEED TO FIND THEM
A NEW HOME IN A WILDERNESS
"WHERE THEY WILL NOT BE
THREATENED BY POACHERS.
"THEY SIMPLY CANNOT BE PUT
IN A ZOO,
"AND I UNDERSTAND YOU HAVE
A FARM LARGE ENOUGH
TO ALLOW THEM TO ROAM FREE."
- "I UNDERSTAND YOU STILL HAVE
NO MAJOR PREDATORS
"AND WAS HOPING TO INTEREST YOU
IN THE RELEASE..."
- BYE, TIDI.
- BYE!
- "OF TWO YOUNG LEOPARDS
INTO YOUR RESERVE."
- [speaks African language]
[drumming and chanting]
[speaking African language]
- YO.
- MENEER STEVENS.
- SO WHAT’S HAPPENING
WITH THE CUBS?
- UH, THERE IS A PROBLEM.
- I PAY YOU $10,000,
YOU TELL ME YOU GOT A PROBLEM?
- THE CUBS ARE DEAD.
- THE CUBS ARE D--
THE CUBS ARE WHAT?
- THEY WERE KILLED BY LIONS.
HERE, TAKE A LOOK FOR YOURSELF.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO,
DIG UP THEIR BONES
AND BRING THEM TO YOU?
- WHO YOU TRYING TO BULLSHIT,
EH?
LOOK HERE.
THIS CUB DIED OF MANGE.
AND THIS ONE HERE,
THIS IS A SUB-ADULT;
LOOK AT THE CANINES.
THESE AREN’T VARTY’S CUBS.
WHO YOU TRYING TO CON, PAL?
- ACH.
THAT WOMAN...
YEAH, YOU HAVE STILL GOT
YOURSELF A DEAL.
- YOU BETTER BELIEVE IT.
[projector whirring]
- OH, THIS IS GREAT.
WE CAN PUT THIS IN
WITH INSTINCTIVE BEHAVIOR
BECAUSE IT DEALS WITH BALANCE
AND LOWER CENTER OF GRAVITY.
- WE COULD DO A COMPARISON HERE
WITH LION.
- OH, YEAH.
- SHOW THAT THEY ALSO
USED BE A TREE-CLIMBING CAT,
AND THEN
AS THE SAVANNAHS DEVELOPED,
THEY WENT OUT
INTO THE GRASSLANDS.
LOOK AT HIM LAY HIS EARS BACK.
- OH, YES.
LOOK, HE’S A BIG BOY,
ISN’T HE?
OH.
- AH, IS ONE OF YOUR SHOTS.
- SEE?
- SEE, I’M IMPRESSED.
- THANK YOU.
- NOT BAD AT ALL.
- LOOK AT HIM.
YOU LIKE IT TOO, HUH?
WHO IS THAT UP THERE?
WHO IS THAT?
HUH?
YEAH, GO GET HIM.
YOU GO GET HIM.
- AH.
- OH, IT’S GREAT.
OH, THIS IS GONNA CUT TOGETHER
REALLY WELL.
- [shouts]
- OH!
- THROW ME A DUVET!
PULL THAT TABLE BACK!
- GET AWAY FROM THERE!
- PULL THE TABLE BACK.
[leopard yowling]
- LITTLE BOY, MOVE.
THE CUBS.
- CHECK THE COUNTER.
- THEY’RE GONE.
IT’S SPREADING, J.V.
- THROW THAT STUFF OUT THE
WINDOW.
- GET THE NEGATIVE, J.V.
- GO, GO, GO, GO!
- GET THE NEGATIVE!
J.V.!
COME ON!
- I’M GONNA GET SOME MORE NEG.
- J.V., FORGET THE NEGATIVE.
COME ON!
- OKAY, GO TO THE CUB.
- IT’S NO USE, J.V.
COME ON!
[drumming and chanting]
♪ ♪
- YEAH.
[coughing]
YEAH.
[thunder rumbling]
- HI, THERE.
- HI.
ANY LUCK?
- I DON’T KNOW.
I THINK WE’VE LOST MOST
OF THE MOTHER LEOPARD FOOTAGE.
- TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
- "DEAR MR. ’VATY,’
"YOUR LETTER I HAVE BEEN
RECEIVED YESTERDAY.
"ME, I AM TELLING YOU
ABOUT THE MOST TERRIBLE DROUGHT
"AFFECTING MY PEOPLE NOW.
"DANGEROUS LIONS THERE ARE
RAVAGING MY CATTLE.
"SO YOU NOW BELIEVING YOU,
MY FRIEND.
"IT IS QUITE IMPOSSIBLE
TO RELEASE YOUR LEOPARDS
AT THIS TIME."
OH, J.V.
I HAD NO IDEA
IT’D BE SO DIFFICULT.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
- UH, WE GOT TO TRY KENYA.
IT’S OUR ONLY HOPE.
- [speaks African language]
[people murmuring]
[speaks African language]
ARE YOU LESTER?
- HUH?
VARTY?
- DO YOU KNOW WHERE
VARTY’S CAMP IS?
- WHO’S LOOKING?
- DO YOU KNOW WHERE IT IS, MAN?
- UH, MAYBE.
- EH.
WE’LL BE NEEDING A GUIDE.
HERE.
- IT IS FAR.
- YEAH.
- MY JEEP IS OLD.
’63.
- EH.
- TIRES, OIL.
OTHER HALF LATER.
[lion snarling]
- UH-OH.
GO AWAY! GO!
LEAVE ME ALONE!
GO AWAY!
LEAVE THE BIKE ALONE!
LEAVE IT!
DON’T BREAK IT!
PLEASE!
[air hissing]
OH, LOOK WHAT YOU’VE DONE.
LESTER!
COME BACK!
[sniffles]
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
NOT SO FAR.
UH, OTHER HALF.
THIS WAY.
- [speaks African language]
- [speaking African language]
- I CAN ONLY IMAGINE
WHAT YOU TWO ARE TALKING ABOUT.
I DON’T WANT TO HEAR IT.
TONIGHT YOU ARE
EATING VEGETABLES.
[animals calling]
- LESTER!
TAKE ME TO VARTY’S CAMP!
WE’RE GOING TO GET THOSE CATS!
BRING THE CAGES!
CALL THE ZOO!
- ELMON.
[speaking African language]
- [laughs]
- WELL, I’M GONNA GO TO BED.
GOOD NIGHT.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- NIGHT.
- YEAH.
- YEAH, WHERE?
QUIETLY, NOW.
WE MUST FIRST SEE WHERE
HE’S KEEPING THE CUBS.
[animal noises]
[owl hooting]
- [whispers]
WHAT’S THAT, LITTLE BOY?
- [chuckling]
- LESTER.
LESTER!
- HE’S GONE.
- AH!
PUT YOUR TORCH OUT.
ARE YOU READY?
- NO.
GOT A PROBLEM.
- [yowls]
- WHO’S THERE?
HEY, WHO’S THERE?
- SORRY, BOSS.
[speaking African language]
- SOMEONE’S OUT THERE.
COME ON, LET’S GO!
GO, GO, GO!
- HEY, LET’S GO.
RUN!
[gunshots]
- EH, COME BACK!
GET BACK HERE, YOU COWARDS!
- WE’RE GONNA GET CAUGHT!
RUN!
- HOLD YOUR FIRE!
STOP SHOOTING!
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
VAN HEERDEN?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- ANTI-POACHING.
- YEAH.
[chuckles]
"TAKE ME TO VARTY’S CAMP."
[giggles]
- [grunts]
- LESTER,
YOU DOUBLE-CROSSING BASTARD.
[groans]
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- HEY, LESTER.
- HEY, TIDI!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
ALL THE WAY OUT HERE?
- THERE WAS A LION YESTERDAY.
- DOES YOUR MOTHER KNOW
YOU’RE HERE?
- I HAD TO SLEEP
IN THE TREE ALL NIGHT.
AND YOU DRIVE PAST ME.
- "DEAR MR. WALKER..."
- THEY’RE COMING
TO TAKE THE CUBS!
- J.V., VAN HEERDEN’S COMING!
- VAN HEERDEN!
HE’S COMING!
HE’S COMING WITH THE CAGES
TO TAKE THE CUBS.
I SENT HIM THE WRONG WAY,
BUT HE’LL FIND US.
WE MUST GET OUT OF HERE.
HE’S REALLY SERIOUS THIS TIME.
- JUST TAKE WHAT YOU NEED.
- COME.
- THAT WAY!
- OKAY, PRETTY.
- OKAY.
- GOOD BOY, GOOD BOY.
THERE YOU GUYS GO.
- OKAY.
[grunting]
- J.V., WAIT.
WAIT, WAIT, HANG ON.
- THERE.
THAT’S THEIR CAMP.
THEY’RE GONE.
LET’S GO.
THEY COULDN’T HAVE GONE FAR.
FOLLOW THAT ROAD.
- WHAT ARE WE DOING THIS FOR?
- VARTY’S SMUGGLING ANIMALS.
HE MUST BE STOPPED.
B.J., B.J.,
DO YOU COPY?
WHAT IS YOUR LOCATION?
- I’M ON THE ROAD JUST SOUTH,
OVER.
- COPY YOU.
UP!
LET’S GET A BETTER VIEW
OF THE ROADS.
THERE’S VARTY.
VARTY.
FOLLOW HIM.
B.J., B.J.,
I’VE GOT VARTY.
- COPY.
WHAT’S HIS LOCATION?
- FOLLOW THE ROAD TO BIG DAM.
INTERCEPT HIM!
OKAY, WE’VE GOT HIM!
LET’S TAKE ’ER DOWN.
NO LUCK, MR. VARTY.
- HELLO.
- OH, YOU.
WHERE IS VARTY?
- VARTY?
OH, YOU MEAN J.V.
YOU KNOW, I DON’T KNOW.
HE JUST TOOK OFF AGAIN.
BUT DON’T WORRY.
HE’S GOT ELMON WITH HIM.
AND THE CUBS.
- [giggling]
- LESTER.
HEY.
LESTER.
- YEAH?
- YOU THINK YOU’RE CLEVER, EH?
- AH, IT’S A MISTAKE, MAN.
LOOK, NO ONE’S PERFECT, EH?
- DO YOU THINK YOU CAN MAKE
A FOOL OUT OF ME?
- [stammers]
- WHERE?
- [chuckles]
B.J.!
AIRSTRIP!
- OKAY!
LET’S GET HIM!
- SORRY.
- AIRSTRIP.
LET’S GO!
- [speaking African language]
[all speaking African language]
- [speaks African language]
- OKAY.
J.V.!
- YEAH?
- HELICOPTER.
HELICOPTER,
[speaks African language]
- [speaks African language]
LET’S GO!
[engine roars]
FOX NOVEMBER VICTOR,
THIS IS...
[engine rumbling]
- QUICKLY!
DON’T LET THEM GET AWAY!
FASTER, MAN,
GET IN FRONT OF HIM!
IN FRONT OF HIM!
BLOCK HIM OFF!
BLOCK HIM!
- ARE YOU CRAZY?
FORGET IT, VAN HEERDEN.
THIS IS NOT HOW WE OPERATE.
- COME ON!
AFTER HIM!
BLOCK HIM OFF, MAN!
- I’M NOT GONNA BE PART
OF THIS CIRCUS.
- UGH!
- [speaking African language]
[both laugh]
[all cheering]
[African choral music]
♪ ♪
- [speaking African language]
[all speaking African language]
- RUN THAT BY ME AGAIN, PLEASE.
WE’VE LOST 60%
OF THE ORIGINAL NEGATIVE?
- IN A FIRE.
ONE OF THE CUBS KNOCKED OVER
A PARAFFIN LAMP.
- AND PLUS THIS $9,000 INVOICE
FOR THE PLANE?
I THOUGHT THAT WAS FOR AERIALS.
- THERE WAS NO OTHER WAY.
THE CUBS WERE BEING TAKEN OFF
TO A ZOO.
I WAS TRYING TO SAVE THEM
AND THE PROJECT.
- HERE WE GO AGAIN.
- DAN, PLEASE DON’T
SHUT THIS DOWN.
- I’M VERY SORRY, CHRISTINE,
BUT THIS HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
- JUDITH, COME IN HERE, PLEASE.
- I CAN SALVAGE THIS PROJECT.
PLEASE.
I DON’T WANT TO GIVE UP ON IT.
- I TOLD YOU
THIS VARTY CHARACTER
WAS A GODDAMN WALKING DISASTER.
- IT’S MORE THAN JUST A FILM,
JACK.
WE’RE TALKING
ABOUT THEIR SURVIVAL.
- OH, PLEASE.
- DAN, DON’T SHUT ME DOWN.
- YES, JUDITH, I WANT YOU
TO PREPARE AN INSURANCE CLAIM
ON THE LEOPARD FILM.
- INSURANCE CLAIM?
WE’VE GOT ENOUGH GROUNDS
FOR A LAWSUIT AGAINST THIS GUY.
- PLEASE, JACK.
JUST STAY OUT OF THIS.
CHRISTINE WILL GIVE YOU
ALL THE DETAILS.
THANK YOU.
- "DEAR CHRISTINE.
"I’VE SAFELY LANDED
IN THE MASAI MARA,
"WHERE WE HAVE BEEN WELCOMED
WITH OPEN ARMS.
"THIS AREA IS A VAST EXPANSE
OF OPEN SPACES
"TEEMING WITH GAME,
"ONE OF AFRICA’S LAST GREAT
WILDERNESSES.
"YESTERDAY WE FILMED A HERD
OF 10,000 WILDEBEEST
"BRAVING THE CROCODILES
OF THE MARA RIVER.
"WISH YOU COULD HAVE BEEN HERE.
MISSING YOU,
J.V."
"WE’VE BEEN STAYING IN THE
MANIATTA WITH OUR MASAI FRIENDS
"AND ALL THEIR GOATS AND CATTLE.
"NOT EXACTLY THE RITZ,
"BUT THESE PROUD
AND HOSPITABLE PEOPLE
"STILL LIVE IN HARMONY
WITH THE ENVIRONMENT,
"SHARING THE LAND
WITH AFRICA’S WILDLIFE.
"THE CUBS HAVE BEEN
UP TO THEIR USUAL MISCHIEF.
"LITTLE GIRL IS
THE ONLY LEOPARD IN HISTORY
THAT HAS ATTACKED A MASAI GOAT
AND LIVED TO TELL THE TALE."
ELMON, WATCH THE GOAT!
- HEY!
[all shouting
in African language]
LEAVE THE GOAT, LITTLE GIRL!
LEAVE THE GOAT.
[men yelling and muttering
in African language]
- J.V.!
- SUPA.
- [speaks African language]
[both speaking
African language]
- YEAH, IT’S FROM CHRISTINE.
- OH, GOOD.
- YEAH.
[speaking African language]
- J.V., WELL,
I HOPE THIS REACHES YOU.
OH, I WISH YOU COULD HAVE
SEEN VAN HEERDEN’S FACE
WHEN HE CAUGHT UP WITH ME.
I HATE TO DO THIS, BUT I SUPPOSE
I HAVE TO GIVE YOU THE BAD NEWS.
DAN HAS CANCELED THE PROJECT.
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD SAY
TO CHANGE HIS MIND.
HE’S A BUSINESSMAN.
HE’S MAKING A BUSINESS DECISION.
I HAVE TO RESPECT IT.
I TRULY AM SORRY ABOUT HOW
EVERYTHING HAS TURNED OUT.
BUT LISTEN, I DO HAVE
A LITTLE MONEY ON MY OWN,
AND I’M TRYING MY BEST
TO DO SOMETHING
WITH THE MATERIAL WE HAVE LEFT.
I SENT YOU SOME MORE STOCK.
JUST HOPE YOUR OLD CAMERA
HOLDS OUT.
PLEASE LET ME KNOW IF
THERE’S ANYTHING ELSE YOU NEED.
THIS IS GOING TO BE DIFFICULT,
BUT I WILL NOT GIVE UP.
LOVE, CHRISTINE.
[birds chirping]
- [speaking African language]
- "DEAR CHRISTINE,
"I HAVE TRAGIC NEWS
ABOUT LITTLE BOY.
"IT ALL HAPPENED SO FAST.
"THERE WAS NOTHING WE COULD DO.
"HE HAD WANDERED OFF,
AND YOU KNOW
"WHAT AN ADVENTUROUS SPIRIT
HE ALWAYS HAD.
IT IS DIFFICULT FOR ALL OF US."
- [crying]
[speaking African language]
- NO!
PRETTY BOY!
COME BACK, PRETTY BOY!
- [sniffling]
[all singing
in African language]
♪ ♪
- [speaking African language]
- "THE MASAI SAID HOW SORRY
THEY WERE ABOUT LITTLE BOY
"AND HOW THEY HAD RESPECTED
HIS COURAGE.
"BUT STILL, THEY ARE THE MASAI,
"THE GREAT CATTLEMEN
OF THE AFRICAN PLAINS,
"AND THEY MADE IT CLEAR THIS WAS
NO PLACE TO RELEASE LITTLE GIRL
AND THAT WE MUST TAKE HER
SOMEPLACE ELSE."
"THERE ARE SO FEW GREAT
OPEN SPACES LEFT IN AFRICA.
"THESE LAST WILDERNESS AREAS
ARE LIKE SHRINKING ISLANDS
"SURROUNDED BY A SEA
OF HUMANITY,
"AGRICULTURE, AND DEVELOPMENT.
"TO FIND THE REAL AFRICA,
UNDEVELOPED, UNSPOILT AND WILD,
"IS ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE.
"BUT THERE IS ONE PLACE,
"AND I HAVE BEEN GIVEN
PERMISSION TO RELEASE HER THERE.
"ZAMBIA.
"THIS IS OUR LAST CHANCE.
"THIS PLACE IS BETTER
THAN I EVER IMAGINED.
"IT FEELS LIKE WE ARE THE FIRST
PEOPLE TO WALK THIS LAND.
"THE GUARDIANS
OF THIS UNTAMED WILDERNESS
"ARE THE DEADLY TSETSE FLY
AND MALARIAL MOSQUITO.
"PEOPLE AND CATTLE,
"THE BIGGEST THREAT TO WILDLIFE
AND TO LITTLE GIRL,
CANNOT SURVIVE HERE."
[speaking African language]
OH, IT’S A SCORPION.
- [whistles]
[speaking African language]
- IT’S GONNA STING YOU.
- [speaks African language]
[laughs]
[speaking African language]
- "SHE IS NO LONGER
OUR LITTLE GIRL.
"WE CAN FEEL HER RESTLESSNESS.
"HER DESIRE FOR INDEPENDENCE
GROWS STRONGER EVERY DAY.
"SHE OFTEN WANDERS OFF ALONE,
EXPLORING HER NEW TERRITORY
AND SELDOM FOLLOWS US BACK
TO CAMP AFTER OUR LONG WALKS."
[sighs]
- [speaks African language]
- AH, SHE’S NOT
COMING BACK, ELMON.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
- OKAY.
- SLEEP WELL.
- OKAY, SURE.
[birds chirping]
- PRETTY GIRL!
"AND THEN SUDDENLY,
THERE SHE WAS:
"CONFIDENT AND INDEPENDENT.
"I FELT AN ENORMOUS SENSE
OF RELIEF JUST SEEING HER AGAIN.
"SHE ALLOWED US TO FOLLOW HER
BACK TO A WARTHOG KILL
"SHE HAD HOISTED.
"SHE HAS BECOME QUITE
A SKILLED HUNTER.
"A SOLITARY PREDATOR,
EVERY NEW ENCOUNTER
WAS A LEARNING EXPERIENCE."
[snarling]
"LIFE IS NEVER EASY
ON YOUR OWN."
- [sighs]
[audio plays in reverse]
- TELL ME ABOUT INTELLIGENCE.
A SPECIE THAT SPENDS
$1.2 MILLION A MINUTE ON WAR,
DESTRUCTION, DESTROYING
THIS FRAGILE PLANET.
A SPECIE NOW THAT’S POPULATED
THIS ENTIRE WORLD LIKE A CANCER,
CONSUMING 80% OF ITS RESOURCE,
THREATENING
ALL ITS LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
YOU KNOW, WE MAKE
THE ONE CRITICAL ERROR:
WE PRESUME THAT THE EARTH
IS HERE FOR US.
WE ACTUALLY FORGET
THAT WE SHARE THIS PLANET
WITH 30 MILLION OTHER SPECIES.
"I KNEW THIS TIME
SHE WOULD NOT FOLLOW US BACK,
"AND THAT I MIGHT NEVER SEE
HER AGAIN.
"SHE WAS WILD
AND FREE TO CONTINUE
THE LEGACY OF HER MOTHER."
- HEY, J.V.!
[speaks African language]
- UH-HUH.
- YEAH.
[men singing in
an African language]
♪ ♪
[speaking African language]
[both speaking
African language]
- THERE’S THE BOAT OVER THERE.
[both laugh]
- J.V.!
ELMON!
HI!
HELLO!
- [laughs]
J.V., THE FILM WON A PRIZE!
THEY LOVED IT!
- AH, THAT’S GREAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
♪ ♪
[sweeping music]
[somber jazzy music]
♪ ♪
- ♪ ENDLESS DAYS ♪
♪ LOST IN TIME ♪
♪ IN SLOW MOTION ♪
♪ LIVING TO SURVIVE ♪
♪ SPIRITS RACING ♪
♪ VOICES CRY ♪
♪ THESE MAGIC MOMENTS ♪
♪ FILL ME INSIDE ♪
♪ AND I REJOICE ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ HEAVEN’S WATCHING ♪
♪ THROUGH VELVET SKIES ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ VOICE OF FREEDOM ♪
♪ IS RUNNING WILD ♪
♪ THROUGH PARADISE ♪
♪ ♪
♪ FALLING RAINDROPS ♪
♪ ON MY FACE ♪
♪ I FEEL THE JUNGLES ♪
♪ FEEL ITS WARM EMBRACE ♪
♪ AND MOTHER NATURE’S ♪
♪ ETERNAL FLAME ♪
♪ ANCIENT DESIRES ♪
♪ RUNNING THROUGH MY VEINS ♪
♪ AND I REJOICE ♪
♪ OH, TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ HEAVEN’S WATCHING ♪
♪ THROUGH VELVET SKIES ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ VOICE OF FREEDOM ♪
♪ IS RUNNING WILD ♪
♪ THROUGH PARADISE ♪
♪ ♪
♪ FALLING RAINDROPS ♪
♪ ON MY FACE ♪
♪ I FEEL THE JUNGLES ♪
♪ I FEEL ITS WARM EMBRACE ♪
♪ AND MOTHER NATURE’S ♪
♪ ETERNAL FLAME ♪
♪ ANCIENT DESIRES ♪
♪ RUNNING THROUGH MY VEINS ♪
♪ AND I REJOICE ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ HEAVEN’S WATCHING ♪
♪ THROUGH VELVET SKIES ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ THE VOICE OF FREEDOM ♪
♪ IS RUNNING WILD ♪
♪ THROUGH PARADISE ♪
♪ ♪
♪ THE CELEBRATION ♪
♪ FREES MY SOUL ♪
♪ AND I REJOICE ♪
- ♪ I REJOICE ♪
- ♪ I SPREAD MY WINGS AND FLY ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪
♪ ♪
♪ WE’RE RUNNING WILD ♪
♪ TO THE WINDS OF PARADISE ♪