What has turned into a
classic Formula 1 season.
With the weather
conditions so uncertain,
the drivers prepare for...
the track is still
dangerously wet,
but following a drivers' meeting,
a decision has finally been taken.
Three minutes to go.
Everybody off the grid now.
Twenty-five drivers start
every season in Formula 1,
and each year two of us die.
What kind of person
does a job like this?
Not normal men, for sure.
Rebels, lunatics, dreamers.
People who are desperate
to make a mark
and are prepared to die trying.
My name is Niki Lauda,
and racing people know
me for two things.
The first is my rivalry with him.
You want to change?
Photographers, please
clear the grid.
What about Hunt? Has he changed?
No, he's going on wets.
I don't know why it
became such a big thing.
We were just drivers busting
each other's balls.
To me this is perfectly normal,
but other people saw
it differently,
that whatever it was
between us went deeper.
Then we go on wets too.
The other thing I'm remembered for
is what happened on
1st August, 1976,
when I was chasing
him like an asshole.
Trauma trolley, please.
Hello, I think the racetrack
telephoned ahead
that I was coming.
Hunt. James Hunt.
What's the matter? No one ever
seen a spot of blood before?
- Are you all right?
- Absolutely fine.
We all thought you'd
been in an accident.
I have.
If you call a
friendly disagreement
with another driver an accident.
What did you disagree about?
It's none of your business.
Sorry.
His wife.
That's going to need a couple
of stitches. It's a nasty cut.
It was a nasty blow. Done
with a bloody crowbar.
- Why? What did you do?
- Nothing.
Only what she asked me to do.
Which was...
I'd be happy to show
you, if you like.
Oh. Sorry.
I have a theory why women
like racing drivers.
It's not because they
respect what we do,
driving round and
round in circles.
Mostly they think that's pathetic,
and they're probably right.
It's our closeness to death.
You see, the closer you are to
death, the more alive you feel.
The more alive you are. And
they can see that in you.
They feel that in you.
My name is James Hunt.
My father is a stockbroker,
my sister is a barrister and
my brother is an accountant.
And I...
Well, I do this.
It's a wonderful way to live.
It's the only way to drive.
As if each day is your last.
I've never been to a
Grand Prix before.
Oh, you still haven't.
- This is Formula 3.
- What's that?
It's a lower division,
where idiots like me mess about
in the hope of being
talent-spotted
to race in Formula 1.
- You look disappointed.
- No.
Ah. You only slept with me because
you thought I was famous.
That's not true.
Don't worry. I will be one day.
Morning, everyone.
- This is Nursie.
- Gemma.
Nursie, this is Bubbles
Horsley, team manager.
How do you do?
- Bubbles?
- Yeah.
- Doc Postlethwaite, our designer.
- How do you do?
And Alexander, Lord
Hesketh, the team's owner.
How do you do?
Fine, thanks.
Well done, Superstar.
- That's the car?
- Yep, that's her.
Lotus 59.
1,000cc Cosworth MAE engine.
She's no beauty, but
goes like the clappers.
Nothing to be worried about.
Does it before every race.
Good sign, actually.
Means he's stoked.
AH Formula 3 cars to the
assembly area now, please.
Drivers please bring them to
the scrutineering bay now.
All right, Superstar?
Never better, patron.
- Have a gargle with this.
- Thank you.
Quick toke of this.
At Crystal Palace today,
James Hunt's on pole,
with Austrian newcomer
Niki Lauda alongside him
and Dave Walker completing Row 1.
Row 2 is Mike Beuttler
and Dave Morgan,
with Tony Trimmer
and Gerry Birrell.
Who's that?
He's new.
- Some German.
- Austrian.
He's been here since 5:00
am, walking the track.
You might actually have to
concentrate today, James.
You'll need these.
Okay, start her up.
Ah. What music.
They could never have imagined it,
those pioneers who
invented the automobile,
that it would possess
us like this,
in our imaginations,
in our dreams.
Nursie, men love women,
but even more than that,
men love cars.
- Come on, James.
- James. Come on, James.
Go, James.
Hunt's still in the lead,
but Niki Lauda is
right on his tail.
Hunt and Lauda are proving to
be in a class of their own.
They're leaving the
pack far behind.
Herr Red Devil's on his tail.
Lauda takes a look
down the inside...
and he's sold him a dummy.
Lauda is through.
He's in the lead.
Hunt will be determined to
make up for that mistake.
Hunt's in Lauda's slipstream.
Lauda's not leaving any gap.
The Lotus goes for the inside.
It's an aggressive move from Hunt.
Oh. There's contact.
The leaders have spun out.
Lauda's facing the wrong way.
The back marker's gone through.
You can see why
Hunt's fellow drivers
call him Hunt the Shunt.
Asshole.
- Go on, James.
- The Kraut's out of it.
Lauda is clearly furious.
There's every reason to expect
sharp words in the pits.
It's gonna be victory for Hunt.
It's gonna be an ignominious
defeat for Niki Lauda.
So James Hunt scores his third
major Formula 3 win of the season
here at Crystal Palace,
after a desperate
battle with Niki Lauda.
Lauda was unable to restart
after Hunt's aggressive move
caused them both to spin out
in the last lap of the race.
Hard luck. Better luck next time.
Hey, asshole.
That was my line. I
had that corner.
Do you mean the one
that you spun out
of and finished
facing the other way?
I think that corner had you.
That move was total suicide.
What if I hadn't braked?
- We'd have crashed.
- But we didn't, did we?
Thanks to your impeccable
survival instincts.
Fuck you. What's your name?
James Simon Wallis Hunt. Remember
it, my little Jerry friend.
Jawohl. Remember ze name.
And it's very simple.
Hunt. It rhymes with...
cunt.
A word that happens to
describe you perfectly.
Who was that?
I've no idea. He looks
like a rat, doesn't he?
In my home town, Vienna,
my family is famous for
one thing, business.
My grandfather was a businessman,
my father, too.
So when they heard I wanted
to race cars for a living,
they had a few things to say.
Never.
Racing is for playboys
and dilettantes.
Frivolous amateurs with
nothing in their heads.
The name Lauda...
belongs with politicians
and economists,
on the front pages.
What if this is all I can do?
Then you need my money
more than ever,
so do as I say and follow me
into the family business.
Gut.
Keep your money.
Don't invest in me.
But when I'm world champion
and my name is on the
front pages too...
you will regret it.
Get out and never
show your face again.
So if my family wasn't
going to help me,
I decided to risk everything
and take out a loan myself.
I found a Formula 1
team with an okay car
and an owner who had
run out of money
and was willing to
accept my terms.
And so, ladies and gentlemen,
I'm delighted to say
that the winner of the
Guild of Motoring
Writers Award Driver
of the Year...
is James Hunt.
Superb news.
- Well done, James.
- Superstar.
Fantastic.
- Well done. Congratulations.
- Thank you so much.
Yes.
Erm...
You know, my parents always
wanted me to be a doctor...
or a stockbroker or something.
They gave me the
first-class education,
but, well, that all
went terribly wrong
and I ended up with you lot.
Thank you. I need it
more than you do.
I mean, I have a hot head, an
inability to tolerate discipline.
- Yes.
- Very true.
I fall out with people
left and right.
The only creatures
I've ever really
loved or have treated honourably
are budgerigars.
So in any normal area of life I'd
be... or I am, a total liability.
The only thing I've got going
for me is I'm quick in a car.
So, thank you for this and
for acknowledging that.
I'm going to give it to my father
and tell him to put
it on the mantelpiece
and imagine it's a first-class
degree in medicine.
Well done, Superstar.
Another season like that and I'll
move you up to the big time.
Come on, you don't
think I'm ready now?
You are. I'm not. I've got
to find you a car first.
Well, go on, then. Chop-chop.
Don't wait too long.
You don't want
him to do what Lauda just did.
- Why? What did he do?
- Got himself a drive with BRM.
Well, how the hell did he
do that? He's a nobody.
He's never won a bloody thing.
Apparently, took out a
loan and bought his way in
with two million
Austrian schillings.
Jesus.
Niki Lauda. Here for
pre-season testing. BRM?
Sign the release form. I'll
let them know you're here.
- Mr Stanley.
- Good morning.
- Good morning. Clay.
Let me introduce you to
our number-one driver,
Clay Regazzoni.
- How are you?
- Good.
- Pleasure.
- And these are your mechanics.
They're reporting exclusively
to you, as per contract.
Pleasure. Do you
wanna see the car?
Sure.
Hello.
There she is. P160.
- Same as Regazzoni's?
- Identical in every detail.
How much does she weigh?
- 600 kilos.
- But that's crazy.
- Why so heavy?
- It's a V12 engine.
That lump weighs 190K on its own.
Okay.
What horsepower are
you getting? 490?
- No, no, 450.
- Well, it's not enough.
It needs to be 500,
and the engine needs
to be 20 kilo lighter.
We already tried.
- Tried what?
- Everything.
We replaced the entire
exhaust system.
- Barely made a difference.
- Are you using magnesium parts?
Now the engine block.
Any mounting or fixing
plates, strip it out also.
When you've done that, we have
to look at the aerodynamics,
front and rear wing.
Okay, thank you. Good night.
What was Regazzoni's time?
1:53.
Okay, now put him in my car, and
he'll go round two seconds faster.
- Well, that's impossible.
- No chance.
We've been working
on it all night.
Put Regazzoni in the
car. See what happens.
I don't understand. Why
am I supposed to do this?
I don't know, Clay. He just wants
you to take it for a spin.
Gloves, please.
'Fanculo.
- I would say we push it a bit...
- All right.
What did you do to the car?
That's information
I will share with
you under certain conditions only.
Go on.
A guaranteed place in the team,
and a paid contract on equal terms
with Regazzoni for two years.
Are you crazy?
Clay's a senior figure in Formula
1. You're just a rookie.
Well, the only reason we took you
on is because you're paying us.
Well, as of now, if you want me
to stay, we rip up the contract.
- I don't pay you a cent.
- That's outrageous.
Was he quicker in my car?
He was, wasn't he?
Did he go two seconds faster?
2.3.
So, have a think,
work out your priorities
and get back to me.
Hey, Niki.
I know what you're going to say,
that it's none of my business.
What?
If it's the track manager you're
taking on your date tonight...
It's none of your business.
Okay, but if you want my
advice, I'd let this one go.
I'm not questioning your taste.
She is a great girl, but...
Agnes's last boyfriend was
a British Formula 2 driver
who has a reputation
for two things.
For being a little
crazy on the track,
and for going all night and all
day and all night again in bed.
He's a good driver, but an
immortal fuck, apparently.
I don't know about you, but that's
not an act I'd like to follow.
But if that doesn't bother you...
What's his name, the driver?
Hunt. James Hunt.
You see, you share information
and I share information.
That's what team-mates are for.
Where the hell are we going?
I promise it'll be worth it.
Just keep them closed.
Wait for it.
There. What do you say?
She's Formula 1.
Yes, she is, Superstar.
Your brother and I got together
with the bean counters.
And since the economics of F1
are not so significantly different
to the economics of Formula 2,
well, we thought if we were
going to be losing money,
we might as well
be doing it on the
big roulette table in Formula 1.
You fat, little, inbred
beauty. Come here.
Actually, credit where it's
due, we got the idea from Niki.
- Who?
- Lauda.
Bought his way in, rather than
mess about in the lower divisions.
I thought, Bloody
hell, he's right.
No sponsorship, Superstar.
I hope you approve.
No vulgar logos for
cigarettes or condoms.
Just plain white
with the flags. Ooh.
And racing overalls which read,
Sex. Breakfast of champions.
So, when do we start?
- Soon as you're ready.
- Ready?
I've been waiting for
this my whole life.
- Hi, welcome to Watkins Glen.
- Hello.
When the season started,
people wondered
whether Lord Hesketh and his
team of upper-class enthusiasts
were bringing glamour to the
racing community, or just comedy.
Certainly, it was the first
time anyone had seen
a butler serving oysters
and caviar in the pits.
But they have made
quite an impact.
Sixth in France, fourth in
Britain and third in Holland.
AH drivers on the track,
caution flags are out.
A severe crash at the Esses.
Red flag. There is a
car off the track.
And reports are reaching me
that there has been a serious
accident in qualifying.
Er, the identity of the driver we
don't currently
have at the moment,
but, as you can tell
from all the activity
going on behind me
towards the track,
it is clearly a grave
incident indeed.
We will, of course, have
more information for you
as and when we get it,
but it is the sight and sound of
Formula 1 nobody likes to see.
- Get your hands off me.
- Hey, come on.
Drivers of top stature
we've lost just in the
past four seasons
have included Piers
Courage, Jochen Rindt,
Jo Siffert, Roger Williamson
and today, at Watkins Glen,
Formula 1 has claimed
another driver.
The Tyrrell team have
withdrawn from the race.
Their places on the grid
will be left empty.
- Terrible.
- They should cancel the race.
Why?
He made a mistake, went
into the corner too fast.
It's his fault.
- Is that right?
- It's obvious.
Look at the tyre marks.
So says the nobody who had
to pay for his own drive.
How's that working out
for you, by the way?
Fine. How is it at the back?
Not planning on being
there for long.
Ten minutes to the warm-up lap.
Ten minutes.
Asshole.
Arsehole.
Heading into the Grand Hotel
hairpin, second gear.
Turn in hard,
looking for late apex,
gentle with the bar.
Heading into Portier,
second gear, clip the apex,
light brake, stay in second,
looking for a good exit.
Heading through the
tunnel, gradual right,
up through third, fourth, fifth...
Is Alexander round?
Er, yes, he was.
He went back to the
house to take a call.
He'll be back shortly.
He only wanted to show
me his pride and joy.
Rhymes with boy, if you ask me.
And toy.
God, it's so flimsy for
something that costs so much.
There's no comfort, no
protection, nothing.
No, it's just a little
coffin, really.
Surrounded by high-octane
fuel in here.
Being driven round
170 miles per hour.
To all intents and purposes,
this thing's a bomb on wheels.
You're James, aren't you?
Yes.
You fit the description.
Is that right?
Suzy. Friend of Alex's.
Yeah, yeah. I know exactly.
What was the description?
Mostly positive, in
terms of appearance.
Negative only in
terms of character.
I've been told to avoid you.
By whom?
Alexander. He says
you're a bad boy.
Alexander doesn't know
what he's talking about.
I was. I'm not any more.
The new me is very professional.
Early to bed, early to rise.
All very dull.
But according to the team,
the best way to keep
beating the goose-stepper.
Is that what you were
doing when I came in?
Yes, visualisation techniques,
memorising the circuit,
in this case Monaco,
which is up next.
Personally, I've
always been a great
believer in getting
there on the day,
putting my foot down and playing
chicken with everyone else.
But they don't want me
doing that any more.
They want my body like a temple
and my mind like a monk.
And what about your
soul, your heart?
Well, they've got ideas
about that, too.
They want me to stop messing
around, settle down,
get married with the
next nice girl I meet.
They think it would
be good for me.
What do you think?
It sounds fucking awful.
But since they're right
about most things,
they're probably right
about that, too.
You don't fancy getting
married, do you?
Suzy.
Bravo.
Hey, hey, hey.
- What's going on with him?
- Nothing. Nothing.
Didn't want to ruin your day.
It's the Kraut.
What about him?
He's just been signed by Ferrari.
You're kidding me? Jesus.
How did that happen?
Did he buy his way in there, too?
Well, the old man
took Regazzoni back
and he insisted on it, apparently.
He says that Niki's a
genius setting up the cars.
It's terrible. Drives like a pig.
- Oh, you can't say that.
- Why not?
- It's a Ferrari.
- It's a shitbox.
It understeers like crazy and the
weight distribution is a disaster.
It's amazing, all
these facilities and
you make a piece
of crap like this.
We are happy to welcome back
to the Ferrari family...
our good friend Clay Regazzoni,
and to introduce Niki Lauda,
from Austria.
Ferrari family. Our good
friend Clay Regazzoni.
You are family and friend to the
Commendatore as long as you win.
The minute you don't, ciao, ciao.
I totally understand. It's
business. I would do the same.
But it isn't just business,
is it? What we do.
It's passion, love.
Which is why we are prepared
to risk our lives for it.
Not me.
If I had more talent
and could earn
better money with something else,
I would.
How do you know you will make
money here? You haven't yet.
Not yet, but I will.
If you can, I can.
You know, are you
ever not an asshole?
- Why am I an asshole?
- Well...
You know, by now I'm
both quicker than you
and better at setting up the car.
You can't deal with it,
so you're the asshole.
Screw you.
I brought you along today because
you seem like a
lonely kind of guy.
I thought if I introduced
you to some nice people,
that could rub off on you.
Forget it. Make your own friends.
Come on, Clay. I'm sorry.
Are you leaving?
Yes.
Can you give me a lift
to the nearest town,
anywhere with a train station?
Sure. Trento's half
an hour's drive.
Get in.
♪ Been another blue day
without you, girl. ♪
♪ Been another sad summer song. ♪
♪ I been thinking about you,
girl, all night long. ♪
What are you doing?
You hear that noise
when you accelerate?
- No.
- Your fan belt is loose.
My what?
And when you brake, your
foot goes all the way down,
which means there's
air in the system.
- Anything else?
- No.
Apart from the rear
brakes are worn out,
the front right tyre's a bit soft,
which explains why
you're weaving so much.
How can you tell?
- My ass.
- Sorry?
God gave me an okay mind,
but a really good ass, which
can feel everything in a car.
You don't know what you're
talking about. This car is fine.
- I just had a service a week ago.
- Not a good one.
Yes, a very good
one, very expensive.
This car is as good as new. Relax.
Not in a hurry, are you?
No. As long as I'm back
in Maranello Monday morning.
We can speak German. You're
from Vienna, aren't you?
Yes.
- Marlene.
- Niki.
How do you know Curd?
Who's Curd?
Curd Jürgens, the host.
He is, or was, my boyfriend.
There is something very
attractive about an older man.
But when they behave like
a frightened child...
I must have been mad.
Let me do this.
Otherwise we'll never get out of
here. We're in Italy, after all.
Not bad? Three seconds.
Admit it, you're impressed.
My scusi... Tu sei Niki Lauda?
Excuse me, are you Niki Lauda?
Yes.
Do you need a lift?
- Actually, we do, yeah.
- Okay.
It's my honour, Niki, please.
- Thank you.
- My car is your car.
On one condition, though. It's a
piece of shit. It's dog shit.
But if you drive it, you
make my life, Niki?
No one will believe Niki Lauda
is driving my granny's car.
- Niki Lauda.
- Niki Lauda, Niki Lauda.
Will someone please tell
me what's going on?
Who are you? Should I know you?
What, you don't know?
He's Niki Lauda, Formula 1 driver,
and he just signed with Ferrari.
- Him?
- Yes.
- Impossible.
- Why?
Well, you know, Formula 1 drivers,
they have long hair, are sexy,
their shirts are open to here.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
Anyway, look at the way he's
driving, like an old man.
There's no need to drive fast.
It just increases the
percentage of risk.
We're not in a hurry.
I'm not being paid.
Right now, with zero
incentive or reward,
why would I drive fast?
Because I'm asking you to.
And do you always
get what you want?
Yes.
Usually.
This is an incredible battle
between Niki Lauda
in the red Ferrari
and James Hunt in
the white Hesketh.
The challenge of Niki Lauda...
Lauda attacking Hunt.
Lauda gets through on the inside.
Goes wide at the exit.
Hunt is past again.
Once more Lauda tries
to sneak up the inside.
They're absolutely side
by side, wheel to wheel.
So evenly matched.
Fantastic battle
between these two great drivers.
Hunt is now ahead once more.
But Lauda's coming back again now.
Lauda once more
sneaks up the inside.
And again he runs wide.
Again the Hesketh...
- Suzy, we're ready, come on.
- Just... Just one second.
- Can we go, yeah?
- Okay, yeah.
We're in the closing laps of
this race here at Watkins Glen.
They come down the hill.
And Hunt's got a problem.
Hunt pulls across to the left.
Lauda goes ahead on his own.
A sad end to a wonderful battle.
Hunt pushing off the marshal.
The chequered flag is waiting
for Lauda and for Ferrari.
The title going to Niki Lauda,
who wins the race,
who wins the World Championship.
Do I look like a
racing driver now?
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Marlene.
With a car like that,
the rest of us
never really stood
a chance, did we?
Maybe the fact the car is so good
has something to do with me.
Come on, Niki. You're in a
Ferrari. I'm in a Hesketh.
Equal terms, the way
it was in Formula 3,
- I'd beat you and you know it.
- Never.
You might win one race, maybe
two, because you're aggressive.
But in the long run, over the
course of a season, no chance.
Right. Why's that?
Because to be a champion, it takes
more than just being quick.
- It's the whole picture.
- Oh.
You're just a charger
and a party guy.
That's why everybody likes you.
Try saying that and tell
me you're not jealous.
Why would I be jealous?
Think about it.
All that affection,
all those smiles
- is a sign of disrespect.
- Oh.
They don't fear you. Whereas
compare that to me.
Yes, compared to you,
whom no one likes.
- Right.
- Not even his own team-mates.
Right. Because I'm a serious guy.
I go to bed early, I look after
myself, look after my car.
- Yes, you're very well-behaved.
- Go to work, kick ass.
And then, after the race, I go
home instead of going to bars
and talk all this bullshit
with all these assholes.
Arseholes?
You should go home
more often, too.
I heard you got married.
Yes, I did.
So where is she, this
mysterious wife?
- In New York, working.
- Oh.
You know, I've never
seen you with her once.
No?
Well, maybe that's because
you're always at home,
on your own, looking after
yourself, being a good little boy.
Take a drink on me, James.
Thank you, Niki. I
might just have two.
Right, Bubbles,
whatever it takes to beat that
prick next year, just say it.
Your word is my command.
There are no lengths to which
I will not go. I mean it.
What the hell's going on?
Where is everybody?
What's the matter?
Do you know what
the date is today?
Yes, it's November the 14th. Why?
Do you have any idea of the
significance of that date?
I don't know. Time to
start killing pheasants?
Actually, it's the deadline
for securing sponsorship
for the forthcoming
Formula 1 season.
Yes?
Which elapsed at midnight last
night, and we didn't attract any.
Well, so? We aren't
looking for sponsorship.
Like you said, condoms and
cigarettes, vulgar, right?
Right.
Except we are, or were.
I've made something
of a miscalculation.
The economics, Formula
1, realities thereof.
It turns out, not like the
lower divisions at all.
What are you saying?
I'm saying it's over, Superstar.
The banks have stepped in,
started laying everyone off.
Probably have to sell this place.
Oh, Christ.
I need a drive, Pete. I need
you to find me a drive.
I mean, what about Lotus?
You don't wanna know.
- Actually, I do.
- Okay.
They felt your
reputation preceded you.
And what does that mean?
It's my other line. Look,
I'll get back to you.
Peter Hunt.
Fuck.
Don't worry. Something
will turn up.
Doubt that will help
in the meantime.
Why don't we go away
at the weekend?
Skiing. Before I go
back to New York.
Talk to me, James. Don't
make a stranger of me.
You know, Suzy, only a stranger
would invite me skiing
when they know I haven't
got a fucking drive.
I can't watch this.
What were you hoping for anyway?
A well-adjusted knight
in shining armour?
No danger of that.
- Let me give you some advice.
- I'm all ears.
Don't go to men who are willing to
kill themselves driving in circles
- looking for normality.
- I never expected normality.
God knows I walked into
this with my eyes open.
I just hoped I'd married someone
who was half as impressive on the
inside as he is on the outside.
At least there's something
behind the facade.
- Oh, James.
- Fuck off to New York, dear.
There must be a moisturiser
or an eye shadow somewhere
that needs your vapid
mush to flog it.
- Hello?
- Hi, James.
It's Peter. Something's
up at McLaren.
- What have you heard?
- Nothing. Why?
I heard Emerson's off.
He's dumped them in it.
Jesus. Get me in there, Pete.
Say anything, just
get me in that room.
I'll come straight to the point.
- Our esteemed lead driver...
- Fitti-fucking-paldi.
Has ditched us for another
team at the last minute.
- Coper-fucking-sucar.
- And we need a replacement.
ASA-fucking-P.
Fortunately, a few hands have
already gone up, good people.
- Jacky Ickx.
- I'm quicker than Jacky.
- But he's consistent, dependable.
- A grown-up.
Right, and will he go for that
gap when no one else will?
Will he put his life on the line
the day that it really matters?
The sponsors like him.
What do you want, a driver
or a brush salesman?
- We wanna be successful.
- Yes, so do I.
But that means beating Niki Lauda,
not being a show
pony for sponsors.
I heard about this
thing with Niki.
Everyone has.
You really think you can beat him?
I'd beat him in a McLaren.
It's the only car out there
as quick as the Ferrari.
Which is why I'm here, begging.
Look, I'll do whatever you ask.
I'll put on a tie, I'll
smile for sponsors,
say the right things.
I can beat this guy, trust me.
Just give me the drive.
Yeah. Yeah, he can
be a loose cannon.
And, yeah, he will
drive you all mad,
but in terms of raw
talent and right stuff,
there is no better
driver in the world.
He's the real thing, Teddy.
He's what we all
came into this for.
Nine days out of ten you'll
be pulling your hair out,
but on that tenth day,
James will be unbeatable.
And that is the day you will
wish you had him in your car.
You will never win the
championship with Jacky Ickx.
You just might with James.
Welcome to Sao Paulo, Brazil,
and the Interlagos circuit
for the first race in the
1976 Formula 1 season,
where the main news is that James
Hunt has qualified fastest,
beating Niki Lauda's
Ferrari to pole position
by just two hundredths
of a second.
New car.
- I noticed.
- Pole position.
I noticed that, too.
Level playing field now,
my ratty little friend.
Yeah. Let's see where
we are after lap one.
Let's see where we are
in five races' time.
Hunt has the pit
lane pole position,
which should give
him the best chance
of outdragging Lauda's Ferrari.
If ever there was a doubt about
whether Lauda had a serious
challenger to this season,
Hunt and his McLaren have
certainly given us the answer.
Here in South Africa,
James Hunt is determined
to make amends
after that disastrous
retirement in Brazil.
But it's Lauda who takes
the flag here at Kyalami.
James Hunt comes home second
to confirm his championship
challenge at last
and score his first points
of the season.
That wind you can feel is me
breathing down your neck.
Next time I'll have you.
We'll see in Spain.
James Hunt finally takes his
first victory of the season
here in Spain, after
a brilliant drive.
It was only a matter of time.
Luca, don't you think
it's time to tell them?
- It's too wide.
- Disqualified.
- What?
- You're disqualified.
How can we be disqualified?
- 1.5 centimetres.
- It's the same car.
Giustissimo.
You fucking...
McLaren M23 has proved
very controversial here.
Just make it narrower.
I don't care how.
New rear suspension.
New wishbones.
I wanna make sure this
thing is legal, no doubts.
Well, then we'd
better move the oil
coolers back to the old position.
With the oil coolers
back, the wing brackets
- need to be changed, too.
- Fuck.
What the fuck do you
think we're doing?
And with Hunt disqualified
from his Spain win,
his championship year
is not going well.
And now it's all gone
wrong here at Monaco.
His engine is smoking.
Smoke pouring from the
engine of that McLaren.
And James Hunt is out.
- Can you tell us what happened?
- Sure. It's magic.
We've taken a great car, a
great piece of engineering,
and overnight turned it into
a big, huge, stinking turd.
Shit.
What the hell have you
done? The car's evil.
It's fucking undriveable.
James, look, if there's a problem
with the car we'll find it...
The car is a piece of shit.
You should be appealing this.
- We are appealing it.
- We will sort it out.
- They're killing us out there.
- Go and get your dick wet.
- You're a wanker.
- Fuck you.
- You're a fucking wanker.
- I will, arsehole.
But this was a good
race for you, no, Niki?
It's good for everyone
that the quickest car
happens to be a legal car.
James, you're 50 points behind
Lauda in the championship.
You've had another retirement
today. What's going wrong?
Oh, it's dirty politics
and dirty tricks,
that's what's going wrong.
So, as we approach
the halfway point
in this year's Formula 1 season,
Ferrari and Niki Lauda
seem clearly on top,
and James Hunt and
McLaren are struggling.
So, five races in,
how's it going so far?
It's fine. Just got a little
problem with an Austrian rat
and his team of Italian cheats
- who have destroyed my car.
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about the
race in Spain that I won.
Yeah, in a car which is not legal.
Five-eighths of an inch too wide.
You know that doesn't have the
slightest effect on speed.
But you complained
and your team of
lawyers leaned on the authorities.
Now we've had to rebuild the
car, and it's become a monster.
At least it's a legal monster.
You've had to resort to cheating.
You're driving an illegal car and
call me the cheat? It's pathetic.
- Rules are rules.
- Yes, and rats are rats.
Thank you. Thank you.
Do you really think
it upsets me, James,
calling me a rat because
I look like one?
I don't mind it.
Rats are ugly, sure,
and nobody likes them,
but they're very
intelligent and they
have a strong survival instinct.
- Wonderful.
- Marlene, komm.
Leave this jerk alone.
No wonder she left him.
Anyone seen Suzy?
She's supposed to be here today.
We, er... didn't wanna
tell you before the race.
Tell me what?
Jesus.
Is that from him?
Yeah.
So when did all this start?
That weekend I went skiing.
Why have you come here, James?
I've come to get you back.
You don't want me back.
You never wanted to be
married in the first place.
- Yes, I did.
- Oh, come on, James.
You did it because you
hoped it might change you,
settle you down, help
with the racing.
No, I didn't.
And who knows? If it had
been just the drinking
or the dope or the
infidelity or the moods,
it might even have worked.
- But when it's all of them...
- Yes, I know, I'm terrible.
No, you're not terrible.
You're just who you are at
this point in your life.
God help anyone who wants more.
And Richard Burton, will
he able to give you more?
You know, he has quite the
bad boy reputation himself.
What's important is
how it feels to me,
and it feels like he adores me.
- James.
- New York Times.
Are you and Suzy
getting back together?
- James, how do you feel...
- It's all very amicable.
My wife has found
herself a new backer...
I mean, lover, which
makes her happy.
And Mr Burton has found a
way of feeling young again,
which makes him happy.
Let's hope his pockets are
deep. They'll need to be.
And I've found a way to be
single and have an ex-wife
without it costing me a penny,
which has got to go down as
the biggest win of my career.
I have a flight to catch.
We haven't seen this
sort of intensity
from James Hunt all season long.
Reports have been coming out
of the McLaren camp all week
that their car is now fully
legal and faster than ever.
Never mind the bloody
wets. We're still quick.
Hunt has really closed the gap on
Lauda as they head into Druids.
Niki Lauda is under real
pressure from James Hunt
as they go up the hill
into Druids Corner.
And Hunt is in front of Lauda.
So James Hunt gets the plaudits
of the crowd, the
first Briton to win
a British Grand Prix
at Brands Hatch
since Jim Clark in 1964.
James, at the moment
you've got a terrific edge
over the rest of the field. How
have you achieved this advantage?
Big balls.
Would you...
Following an inquiry into
the disqualification
of driver James Hunt from
the Spanish Grand Prix,
it has been decided
to overturn this
disqualification...
Yes.
And to restore his victory
and reinstate his points.
James. James.
James, a few weeks ago you
were out of the running
for the season completely, and
now you're right back in it.
What's changed?
Well, it's a combination
of factors,
not all of which I'm
prepared to discuss here,
but justice being done re the
disqualification in Spain helps,
and having my car back
at its best again.
In theory it's possible for James
Hunt to catch you.
Are you worried?
Not at all.
For him to catch me, he would
have to win a lot of races...
and pigs would have to fly.
Now if you'll excuse me, I have
a family matter to attend to.
James. James.
I should warn you. I'm not
going to be any good at this.
"Bringing flowers"
and "holding hands".
I'll probably forget
your birthday.
But if I'm going to
do this with anyone,
it might as well be you.
My God...
a poet.
What's the matter?
Happiness is the enemy.
It weakens you.
Puts doubts in your mind.
Suddenly you have
something to lose.
When you call happiness an enemy,
then it's too late.
Then you've already lost.
Welcome to the
legendary Nurburgring.
This is a 14.2 miles track,
complete with 185
corners and bends.
An autograph?
With the date, please.
The date? Why?
You never know.
Could be your last.
Welcome to the Nurburgring,
the most dangerous circuit
on the season calendar.
In Formula 1 it is known
as the Graveyard.
The weather conditions
are far from ideal,
and latest reports indicate
there is no relief in sight.
Gentlemen. Well, gentlemen,
please be quiet.
Thank you. Niki Lauda.
Thank you.
I called this meeting because,
as all you drivers know,
the Nurburgring is the most
stupid, barbaric, outdated
and dangerous track in the world.
You've all seen the rain
that has been falling today.
Now, those of you
with experience know
the ring needs perfect conditions
to be even remotely
acceptable in terms of risk.
And today, with the rain,
it's anything but perfect,
so I called this meeting to
take a vote to cancel the race.
Cancel the race?
There would be no
change to the situation
as far as points is concerned.
The race would
simply be cancelled.
This is bullshit.
If the race is cancelled,
none of us get our race fees.
That's true, you leave
without your fee,
but you might leave
with your life.
It also means that you would
effectively win the championship.
So, I can see why this
suits you just fine.
Why? There would be no
points for me either.
No, but there would
be one race less
where I, or anyone else
here, could catch you.
James is right. This
is just tactics.
Maybe he's just frightened.
Which asshole said this?
Yes, of course I'm
frightened, and so are you.
I accept, every time
I get in my car,
there is 20 per cent
chance I could die,
and I can live with it,
but not one per cent more.
And today, with the
rain, the risk is more.
I suppose that all depends on
how good you are in the rain.
I have the track record here.
I am the only person in history to
do the ring in under
seven minutes.
So, actually, it's to my
advantage to race here today.
Because I'm quicker
than all of you.
- Come on.
- Fine. Then let's race.
- Come on, Niki, let's race.
- Gentlemen, please.
Why are we here, Niki? Come on.
Well, all those in favour
of cancelling the race.
All those in favour of racing.
Gentlemen, the race is on.
- Ridiculous.
- What a waste of time.
You know, Niki, every now and
then it helps if people like you.
In places the track is
still dangerously wet,
but following a drivers' meeting,
a decision has finally been taken.
The Grand Prix will go ahead.
Niki.
One minute to go.
Jochen's going on slicks.
You wanna change?
- Is Niki gonna change?
- No.
Then we stay on wets, too.
- Niki, okay?
- I'm good.
All right, fire her up.
This season's fight for the
Formula 1 World Championship
has so far been the
story of two men.
Thus far, it's been going pretty
much the way of Niki Lauda.
But James Hunt has
qualified fastest here.
He is on pole position for
the German Grand Prix,
with Niki Lauda alongside
in the blood-red Ferrari.
It's a long race.
If the track starts to dry out,
the wet-weather tyres will
no longer be as quick.
Niki Lauda and James
Hunt, side by side
on the front row of the grid,
go away absolutely as one.
Lauda very aggressive
on Hunt there,
forcing the McLaren
onto the grass.
Lauda has the lead at the moment.
Lauda leads into the first corner.
Hunt is in second place.
Mass storming past Hunt.
He made the right choice to go
with the dry-weather tyres.
Mass passing Lauda now.
Jochen Mass, in the number
12 McLaren, takes the lead.
Jochen Mass the clear leader,
with everybody else
making the decision
to change tyres after just
one lap of this race.
He's coming in. Come on, let's go.
See? I told you to go on slicks.
You should have taken my advice.
Fuck off. Where's Niki?
Behind you. He made
the same mistake.
Come on.
Come on. What's going on?
The tyre-changing
frenzy has caused
a huge reshuffling of the pack,
with Jochen Mass in the lead now.
You're clear. Go.
Quick.
Lauda urging his
mechanics to hurry.
Quicker, quicker, quicker.
It's a disaster. Come on.
What's going on, you assholes?
This race has gone
wrong for him so far.
His championship rival, James
Hunt, is a long way up the road.
Lauda passing car after car.
He's just going past Mario
Andretti's Lotus there.
Niki.
Get me out. Help me.
We have an accident on the
course. Red flags are out.
Several cars are
involved. Looks like
it might be one of the Ferraris.
- Come this way.
- Come on, come on.
Keep trying.
- Come this way.
- Okay.
News is reaching
us that Niki Lauda
was involved in the accident.
He is being flown by helicopter to
Mannheim hospital
with severe burns.
It's not the burns to his
face that are the danger.
It's the burns to his lungs.
In the intensive care
unit, six doctors and
thirty-four nurses
are on duty for him.
But his condition is far worse
than originally feared.
The flood, which swept down Big
Thompson Canyon in Colorado,
was the worst since records began.
In Formula 1 today, victory
celebrations were muted
after a horrific
accident involving
world champion Niki Lauda.
Due to safety concerns
before the race,
the Austrian had said
he would not take part,
but in the end he did.
He was making up for lost time
when he went off the track,
puncturing the
Ferrari's fuel tank.
Brett Lunger was unable to
avoid the flaming wreck,
but was unhurt and joined with the
other drivers to rescue Lauda,
who was taken to Mannheim
Hospital with severe burns,
the incident reminding us again
of the dangers of Formula 1.
Niki Lauda was trapped
for almost a minute
in a searing inferno
of 800-plus degrees.
Do we have any
change this morning?
No...
Frau Lauda. Frau Lauda?
He's awake and just spoke.
He said, "Tell the priest to
fuck off. I'm still alive."
You can go in.
James Hunt gains on the
absent Niki Lauda.
We need to vacuum the lungs.
I should warn you.
It won't be easy.
Do it again.
Are you sure? The lungs
will already be bruised.
Please, stop.
I know what you're
thinking, but please...
If you love me, you
won't say a word.
- Morning, chaps.
- Hey, here's the man.
Looking good.
- What's going on?
- Jesus. It's Niki.
- What about him?
- He's here.
- What?
- He's racing.
Niki.
It's that bad, huh?
No.
In hospital I asked them
straight, no bullshit,
how bad my appearance would be.
They said with time
it would be fine.
But it won't.
I can tell, seeing your reaction.
I will spend the rest of my life
with a face that frightens people.
You know, Niki, I
tried to write you
a letter at the
time, to apologise.
The drivers' meeting in
Germany, before the race.
- I swayed the room.
- Yes, you did.
That race should never
have gone ahead.
No, it shouldn't.
So, in many ways, I
feel responsible
for what happened, and...
You were.
But, trust me...
watching you win those races while
I was fighting for my life...
you were equally responsible for
getting me back in the car.
- How are you feeling, Niki?
- Fine.
Niki, can you confirm
to us exactly
which procedures you've had
and the expectations
for your recovery?
Sure.
I had a skin graft operation,
where they put half my
right thigh in my face.
Now, it doesn't look too good,
but one unexpected advantage is
it's impossible to perspire
through a skin graft,
so sweat will never
run into my eyes
again, which is good for a driver.
When they heard about
your condition,
Ferrari immediately hired a
replacement driver,
Carlos Reutemann.
Yeah, before even
reaching the hospital.
Is Reutemann driving today, too?
Yes, and keen to
make an impression.
So, let's see where Mr Reutemann
finishes and where I finish today.
James Hunt and McLaren have caught
up a lot while you were away.
Yes.
So is there a question now, or are
you just trying to piss me off?
You still think you can win?
Yes, of course.
I have the better car.
And possibly I'm
the better driver.
But he's a clever guy, and
he's used his time well
while I was lying half-dead in
hospital to win some points.
And what did your wife say
when she saw your face?
She said, Sweetie, you don't
need a face to drive.
You just need a right foot.
I'm being serious.
Do you really think
your marriage can
survive with the way you look now?
And I'm being serious, too.
Fuck you. Press conference over.
- That was hairy.
- Well, you got noticed, Clive.
I'll tell you that.
I thought it went
well, to be honest.
They don't like it when
it's not going their way.
- Clive.
- That's the game.
- See you.
- See you later.
- James, are you all right?
- Good, yeah.
Listen, I think I've
got something for you
on that last question, about Niki.
- You heard about that?
- I did.
James.
Please, James...
Now go home to your wife
and ask her how you look.
Prick.
So Niki Lauda, just
42 days after his
near-fatal accident
at Nurburgring,
will race here today at Monza
against all medical advice and
no doubt in incredible pain.
Niki Lauda.
Photographers, please
clear the grid.
Niki, it's time.
Okay?
Please clear the grid.
One minute to go.
That's a bad start for
Lauda, he's slow away.
The returning Niki Lauda
seems overwhelmed.
He's being overtaken
by car after car.
A terrible start for the Austrian.
It's perhaps too soon for
him to be racing again.
Lauda's off line. He runs
wide onto the grass.
He wrestles it back
onto the track,
but that was a bad
moment for Niki.
Niki Lauda's the
reigning world champion,
but maybe in his current state
he's a danger out there,
to himself and to the
rest of the field.
And Stuck has collided with
Mario Andretti's Lotus.
Niki's boxed in. He's
got nowhere to go.
Niki Lauda is actually making a
move. He's on Brambilla's tail.
He pulls out of the
slipstream to overtake.
Lauda's starting to find the form
that, early in this race,
we believed he'd lost.
Lauda's now lapping faster than
Reutemann and closing
the gap ahead.
Lauda closing on Carlos Reutemann,
the man called in to be his
replacement in the Ferrari team.
And there's James Hunt's McLaren,
smoking stationary by
the side of the road.
This is bad news for
Hunt's championship hopes.
It's Ronnie Peterson
who comes home the
winner here at Monza.
But all eyes are on the man who
finishes a brilliant fourth,
Niki Lauda.
What a race, what a
man, what a season.
With a fourth-place finish
and three priceless points,
it means that Niki Lauda
is a major step closer
to retaining the
World Championship.
So, the long, gruelling and
incredibly dramatic season
comes down to this
final race in Japan
in the shadow of Mount Fuji.
Niki Lauda goes into
this deciding race at Fuji
just three points
ahead of James Hunt.
Hunt knowing he must
beat the Austrian
fair and square to take the title.
James, do you think you can
cope with the pressure?
Well, I've never really understood
what that means. I love my job.
I love competing. I love racing.
Maybe you should ask Niki.
He's the World Champion.
He's got everything to lose.
Mr Lauda, are you
feeling pressure?
Do I look like I'm
I am World Champion,
and on the verge
to become World Champion again.
Hunt now has the
opportunity to win,
but it's not so easy
to become a champion.
You have to really believe
it to make it possible.
James, is there anything
you'd like to add?
If Niki is being
tricky and getting a
kicky out of playing mind games...
then fine, I'm flattered.
But the fact is, momentum is
with me. I've never felt better.
And I fully expect the next
press conference we will have
will be with me as World Champion.
How will you cope with the
weather, bad conditions?
Intermittent heavy rain has been
forecast here at Fuji today,
along with strong winds
and occasional fog
rolling in from the mountain.
And so, with today's
Japanese Grand Prix to come,
Lauda's lead a mere three points.
What a way to finish the season.
Hunt or Lauda?
Well, the final
chapter will unfold
when we bring you
extended coverage...
They've got to cancel the
race. It's lethal out there.
The race is going ahead.
Television rights have been
sold all around the world.
The showdown between you and
Niki is all anyone wants to see.
With heavy rain continuing
to fall here at Fuji,
a decision has finally been made.
The 1976 Japanese Grand
Prix will go ahead.
All drivers to your cars, please.
Five minutes to go.
- All right?
- All right.
- Hold still.
- What the hell are you doing?
To let the condensation out.
- It'll also let the water in.
- Not if you're leading.
Trust me, this race is
all about the start.
- Need a hand here?
- Yeah, hold it, Teddy.
Okay, start the bastard.
Good luck, kid.
Good luck, James.
Thirty seconds to go.
Electric tension here at Fuji.
80,000 bedraggled
race fans and the
racing grudge match of the decade.
And there's Mario Andretti
in pole position,
James Hunt alongside him.
On Row 2 of the grid,
there is Niki Lauda,
and on Row 3 of the grid, Jody
Scheckter from South Africa
in the six-wheel Tyrrell.
Behind him, the rest
of the 25-car field.
There's the flag, and finally the
Japanese Grand Prix is underway.
In these conditions, it must
be almost impossible to drive
a 450-horsepower car.
And it's Andretti who has the
lead, but Hunt is attacking.
Hunt's going round the
outside of Andretti.
Niki Lauda following him through.
Hunt leads into the
first right-hander.
Hunt comes through to
complete his first lap,
leading the field.
At least he has clear
vision in front of him.
Niki Lauda, behind
him, eating his spray.
Lauda is slowing.
Niki Lauda is bringing the
Ferrari number one into the pit.
Some sort of problem, we can't
imagine what, so
early in the race.
What's wrong with the car?
Niki, what's wrong with the car?
Nothing. Car's perfect.
- What are you doing?
- I'm stopping.
His mechanics are asking
what the problem is.
But wait. Niki Lauda's
getting out of the car.
This is sensational.
The reigning World Champion,
Niki Lauda, is out of this race.
It's too dangerous.
Niki, you want me
to say there was a
problem with the
car, for the media?
No.
Tell them the truth.
Now, what is happening?
They're talking to
the team manager.
Lauda explaining something.
With Lauda out, James Hunt knows
he has to finish this race
in third place or higher
to be World Champion.
But the job's not done
yet for James Hunt.
In these dreadful conditions, he
still has to go the distance.
Fifteen laps to go here at Fuji.
James Hunt or Niki Lauda?
This extraordinary
season is not over yet.
In this treacherous final
round, can James Hunt hang on?
And the scoreboard tells a story.
Lap 58. Hunt in the lead.
Oh, God, his tyres,
they're blistering.
Brambilla very close behind now,
closing on him all the time now.
And he's trying to drive
inside James Hunt.
Hunt cuts across the
orange March nose.
Hunt's not having that at
all. And he's spinning.
He missed Hunt there, but almost
took James Hunt out of the race
and out of the world championship.
Now we find Mario Andretti
closing on James Hunt.
Mario Andretti's going past Hunt.
Hunt is slowing. James Hunt
seems to have a problem.
Despite these wet conditions,
these wet-weather tyres
do wear extremely fast.
Hunt's tyres, they've gone.
Hunt nursing his car
back to the pit stop.
That back marker's
going past Hunt.
Look at that left front tyre...
Right front tyre, sorry.
No tread on it at all. And
the other one is flat.
Let's go. Let's go.
Okay? When did you
break your gear lever?
Nine or ten laps ago.
- Alastair, we need to lift it.
- Come on.
- At the front.
- Let's go.
Regazzoni's Ferrari and
Jacques Lafitte in the Ligier
have gone ahead.
Come on, hurry.
You did it. You're going
to be World Champion.
Not yet.
A few laps ago, James Hunt was
looking like champion elect.
Now it looks as though it's
all gone wrong for him.
- James.
- Come on.
- Listen.
- What?
Just go easy out there.
- What are you saying?
- I'm saying look after yourself.
We want you back in one piece.
You're too far back. There's too
many drivers in front of you.
- There's always next year.
- So that's it? It's over?
Clear.
James.
- Clear.
- Fuck it.
James Hunt rejoins the
race in sixth position.
There are four laps left to go.
Surely no way back
for the Brit now.
Concentrate, Superstar.
Just brings it back under control.
Sliding the McLaren
on the very edge there.
Hunt's M23
twitching this way and
that under braking.
And he almost loses
it right there.
Hunt on the tail of Jacques
Lafitte in the blue Ligier.
Oh, don't do it, James.
He's inches away
from the pit wall.
He's inches away from the Ligier.
James Hunt has made
up another place,
but it's not enough,
and this race is running out.
And Watson has spun.
Watson has spun.
Hunt manages to weave his way
between that back marker
and the stationary Penske.
He's catching Regazzoni
but, in these conditions,
it's one thing to catch up,
it's quite another to overtake.
He's alongside Clay
Regazzoni. This
could be the world championship.
He's got him.
The scoreboard still
shows Hunt in 5th place.
Hunt crosses the line.
Now, he needed to
finish third to score
enough points to
be World Champion,
and in the confusion
here, we're being
told that he may
have finished fifth.
He finished fifth?
Our lap charts show
Hunt in third place.
Well, if the scoreboard's right,
it means he's just missed
out on the championship.
Crushing defeat for Hunt
after such a heroic drive.
I can see the race
stewards conferring,
examining the official lap charts.
We're just going to have to
wait for their verdict here.
Let's get you out of there, buddy.
I'm sorry, Teddy. I'm sorry. I
thought I could
make up the ground.
Sorry? What are you talking
about? You did it.
- Did what?
- Jesus. You crazy bastard.
You came third. You
got the points.
You're champion of the world.
James Hunt is now
officially confirmed
as finishing third here in Japan,
and that means he is
champion of the world.
Our new World Champion, James
Hunt, by just one single point.
Did we really win?
World bloody Champion.
Tell us, James, what are
you going to do now?
I shall be getting drunk.
It's wonderful, an
absolute dream...
Are you okay?
Fine.
No regrets.
Not one.
And our special guest,
Formula 1 champion James Hunt.
Wait. Come on.
There's no better motor oil
than Havoline.
Yes, me, too. Where are we going?
Anywhere I want to go.
And I don't have to
hijack it, either.
As long as I pay for it.
I'm starving. Let's get some food.
- Where are we going?
- You lot go ahead.
I won't be a minute.
Good to see you.
I heard you were spending more
and more time in one of these.
- Do you fly?
- No.
I don't think they'd insure me.
You should try. It's
good for discipline.
You have to stay within the
rules, stick to regulations,
suppress the ego. It
helps with the racing.
And there I was thinking you
were about to wax lyrical
about the romance of flight.
No, that's all bullshit.
So, what brings you here?
A friend's wedding. At least
I think it was a wedding.
Might have been a birthday or
something. It's all
a bit of a blur.
How about you? Have
you been at Fiorano?
Pre-season testing.
- You're relentless.
- Thank you.
I'm not sure that was
meant as a compliment.
When do you start
testing? Next week?
No. What, are you nuts?
I didn't just win the
biggest thing of my life
so I could get right back to work.
Why? You have to.
To prove to all the
people who will
always say you just
won it because...
Because of what? Because
of your accident?
Niki, is that other
people, or is that you?
I won, okay? On the all-important
day, when it came down to it,
we raced on equal terms,
equally good cars.
And I put my life on the
line, and I saw it through.
- And you call that winning?
- Yes.
The risks were totally
unacceptable.
You were prepared to die.
To me, that's losing.
Yes, I was. I admit it.
I was prepared to die
to beat you that day.
And that's the effect you have
on me. You'd pushed me that far.
And it felt great.
I mean, hell, isn't that
what we're in this for?
To stare death in the
face and to cheat it?
Come on, there's nobility in
that. It's like being knights.
You English, you're such assholes.
You know my position.
Twenty per cent risk.
No, no, no, Niki, don't bring the
percentages into this.
Don't be a pro.
The minute you do that, you
kill what's good about this.
You kill the sport.
James.
- James.
- Come on.
I've got to go.
Careful in this thing.
James.
You know, in hospital,
the toughest
part of my treatment
was the vacuum.
Pumping the shit out of
my lungs. It was hell.
And while doing it, I was
watching television.
- You winning all my points.
- Your points?
That bastard Hunt, I would
say. I hate that guy.
And then one day the
doctor came and said,
Mr Lauda, may I offer
a piece of advice?
Stop thinking of it as a curse to
have been given an enemy in life.
It can be a blessing, too.
A wise man gets more
from his enemies
than a fool from his friends.
And you know what? He was right.
Look at us. We were both a
pair of kids when we met.
Hot-headed jerks in Formula 3.
Disowned by our families.
Headed nowhere.
And now we're both
champions of the world.
It was not bad, huh?
No, it's not bad.
So, don't let me down now. I
need you busting my balls.
- Get back to work.
- I will, Niki, I will.
But I intend to
enjoy myself first.
Some of life needs
to be for pleasure.
What's the point of having a
million cups and medals and planes
if you don't have any fun?
How is that winning?
- James.
- We're gonna leave without you.
James.
I'll see you on race day, champ.
You will... champ.
You look good, Niki.
The only guy to
have his face burnt
off and it be an improvement.
Of course, he didn't listen to me.
For James,
one world title was enough.
He had proved
what he needed to
prove, to himself
and anyone who doubted him.
And two years later he retired.
When I saw him next in
London seven years later,
me as champion again,
him as broadcaster,
he was barefoot on a
bicycle with a flat tyre.
Still living each
day like his last.
When I heard he'd died,
aged 45, of a heart attack,
I wasn't surprised.
I was just sad.
People always think
of us as rivals,
but he was among the
very few I liked,
and even fewer that I respected.
He remains the only
person I envied.