September 10th, 1989. Kita-Kyushu.
After finishing his five year jail term for murder,
ex-gangster Yasuo Matsumura returned to his hometown.
Yasuo was then forced to shoot and kill six people
and later turned the gun on himself.
He had no right arm.
His sister Yuri and his
childhood friend Kenji Shiraishi,
who allegedly were both with Yasuo on the
day of the massacre, disappeared shortly after.
Ten long years have passed since then.
Move!
Disposal fee.
Let's go.
Gotta pee.
Over here.
Why the kid?
His dad died.
I'll look after him.
Kids fetch double.
He's not for sale.
No head for business, huh?
What about him?
I'll take him with me.
- I'll go cash out.
- Okay.
Kenji!
Yuri.
Yu-ri.
Good.
Kenji.
Yuri.
Your name?
Kenji.
Achun.
Very good! You got it!
So you're Achun, huh?
Here, want another?
Your leaving? Really?
Take care!
Don't talk like that.
Next time you see my brother, Yasuo,
tell him to hurry home.
Tell him I'll be waiting with Kenji.
You like birds, too?
I wish I could fly away.
Come on, get out.
You as well, move it!
Not yet.
Hold on.
I want you... to shoot him.
Hold still please!
Go on, shoot!
Here it comes!
Do it, shoot!
It's coming!
Was it you who took the child?
When he gets this tall,
bring him back.
Understand?
Next time you interfere with
our brethren, you die.
In fact, I'll kill you myself.
Hey, it's me.
Don't you recognize me, man?
Yeah, that's right.
What's up? Busy working?
Cut the crap.
None of your business.
I'm in Tokyo.
I'm a trainee in construction.
Doesn't mean much, though.
- Shigeo, who you talking to?
- What?
- Your girl?
- No, an old pal.
- Shigeo...
- What?
They got western toilets here?
How should I know!
Just go already!
Where are you living?
Don't tell me the ward.
That doesn't help me.
I only know five of them.
Moji, Kokura, Wakamatsu, Tobata
and Yahata, my hometown.
What?
The Tokyo Line?
Where do I catch that?
Shibuya? That ain't a ward.
Yeah, I'm coming to see you.
Just meet me at the station.
How many stops?
Your pad, huh?
Just sit anywhere.
Guess I'll have to.
Can I use this?
- What?
- This is much better.
That's mine.
Can goes on the table...
Right then.
Hang this up.
Just hold on a second.
Hurry up.
Wait, don't you have
anything better?
No, I don't.
It'll flatten the shoulders.
I don't believe this.
That's your starter?
What?
Vodka?
- That okay?
- Yeah, fine.
- What the hell were you expecting?
- Here.
Look how low your TV is.
Must be hard to watch.
Shigeo...
- Come on, let's toast.
- Huh?
It's been a while.
Long time, no see.
I should change my clothes.
Sitting on the floor like this...
my suit will wrinkle.
Got anything to wear?
Lend me these sweat pants.
Fine, whatever.
Pain in the arse.
- Hey!
- Yes?
Hang this up, too.
Yes.
Catch.
Forget the sweatshirt,
it's too hot.
Hang this up as well.
- Suits don't suit you, Shigeo.
- Shut up.
Those new glasses?
Look good, huh?
From "Optical World".
How's Mr. Sawai?
- Didn't you hear?
- What?
Poor Mr. Sawai... died last March.
Soon after Kozue's graduation.
Really?
Got any beer?
I hear you and Naoki are pen pals.
Pen pals?
Well, we write to each
other that's all.
How is "writing to each other"
different from "pen pals"?
Am I speaking the
wrong dialect here?
No, but who says "pen..."?
Who cares? I've a right to say
"pen pals" if I want to.
Fine. Say it then.
- Well, what'd he say?
- Huh?
What did Naoki write about?
Just stuff. Nothing special.
He never mentioned Mr. Sawai.
Well, after his death,
Kozue just upped and vanished.
What? Why?
If I knew that,
I wouldn't be looking.
You're looking for her?
Well, I gotta at least know
where she is.
Mr. Sawai was like a father
to Kozue, you know.
Do you have any leads?
Nope.
How did you expect to find her, then?
Damned if I know.
You piss me off.
I'm searching like crazy here.
What did I do?
I don't know. It's like I
don't see you for ages and...
you haven't changed a bit.
Not one bit.
No growth, man.
None at all.
You know?
Sorry.
- Did you just say "sorry"?
- Yeah.
Okay, then. I want you to say
"Let me join up".
- Put this on first. Don't argue, just do it.
- What? Hang on...
Put it on quick!
Put it on!
First you put on that tie.
And then you say...
- I have to tie it?
- Tie it.
Want me to smack you?
- You're such a pain in the ass!
- Just get on with it.
This is so backwater Kita Kyushu!
I don't care. Just do it.
- Like this?
- Yeah, but tighten it up. Okay now say...
"Let me join up!"
- Why?
- Hurry up, man. Say "Let me join up!"
Let me join up.
- Louder.
- Let me join up!
Okay, then.
You're in.
In what?
The "Kozue Search Party".
What's that?
Well, I'm sure she's
somewhere in Kyushu.
You want me to go to Kyushu?
Damn right! It's your duty
as a search party member.
What did you expect, you idiot!
But I'm busy. I've got work.
What kind of excuse is that?
Kozue could be lying in the street
somewhere. You're her cousin!
She took off of her
own free will, right?
No, she didn't.
Don't be an idiot.
Then what?
Beats me.
What do you know?
If you hang out back home,
you start to hear rumors.
Like what?
Not sure.
You don't know anything,
do you, Shigeo.
No.
What? Why the sudden humility?
What's with your hair? Looks like
something from a comic book.
Well, it's not.
Sure it is. What's that
comic book character?
You know.
No, I don't.
What's the name of it?
I forget.
It's got that guy with the hair
who says, "Evening, folks!"
"Evening folks"?
What comic is that?
"Mamiya Transporters"
Excuse me.
I heard you were hiring.
From whom?
A man named Matsuoka.
Matsuoka... the policeman?
"Kozue Tamura, 18."
You in school?
I graduated this year.
I can't pay much.
I don't mind.
I'd like the work.
You have a place to stay?
I see.
It's no company dormitory but
there is a room out back.
Care to look?
Without leaving so much as a memory
My summer meanders on
Into tomorrow
Hey, Yoshie.
I'm Ono. I work in the dining room.
How do you do.
I'm Kozue Tamura.
Pleased to meet you.
Hello there! I'm Kijima,
one time physician.
I can't drive a truck but
they keep me on anyway.
Dr. Kijima's sort of the glue
holding everybody together.
That lump over there is Mr. Sone.
Welcome back.
Gotoh, meet Ms. Tamura,
our new help.
There are three more
who you'll meet later.
Another newbie, huh?
Why not? The old men here
just sit around all day.
Don't mind him.
He's always like that.
Okay?
- Let me help.
- Thank you.
Thank you. Good night.
- Hey, are you tonight's designated driver?
- Yes.
- I'm finishing up. Bring my car around?
- Okay, yes.
Excuse me.
Anymore rides tonight?
No, you're the last.
Oh.
You're extremely quiet.
I'm sorry.
Why apologize?
Most drivers won't shut up.
Comes from standing around for so long.
Then again, too quiet can
be a little creepy.
I'm sorry.
Right then!
- See me to the elevator.
- Sure.
Thanks. You can't be too careful.
Can you do this on a monthly basis?
Sure.
Three days a week.
I'm afraid Fridays are busy for me.
I see.
But maybe I can work it in somehow.
- Really?
- Yeah, I'll figure it out.
Thank you.
By the way, I'm Saeko.
Saeko Shiina.
Kenji Shiraishi.
Well, good night.
Wait. Your car keys.
- Thanks.
- Excuse me.
Good night.
What? You hungry?
Achun, here.
Let's see this.
Eat up.
Hear that?
- Tastes good.
- Huh?
Tastes good.
Tastes good?
I'm diggin' in.
A bunny rabbit!
Cute...
- I'm terribly sorry. I didn't expect this to happen.
- No, don't worry about it.
I'm not used to drinking. It didn't
take much to get me drunk. Sorry.
- That's quite alright. Are you ready?
- Yes.
Did you get my address?
Yes, but I'm afraid I'll need your
help as we get closer.
Okay.
You a bachelor?
Yes.
- That's admirable. A lone wolf, huh?
- Not really...
From around here?
No.
Where?
Erm... from Hakata.
Really? Me, too.
My wife's from Moji.
Is that so?
The place has really developed.
Lots of western style
hotels and apartments.
It sure has.
But my wife doesn't care for it.
Won't go near the place.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Come in for a moment.
One more game, Doc.
You're unbeatable, Doc!
We'll all do better in our
next life, right Gotoh?
Hey, everybody!
This is...
Come in!
This man drove me home from Kokura.
Someone give him a lift back.
No, there's really no need...
- I'll do it.
- Not you, Kozue.
- I'll call a cab.
- No, no.
Come on! Someone volunteer.
- Here.
- Huh?
- She okay?
- Yes, of course. I'm much obliged.
Thank you.
Oh, right.
I need to pay you.
Hey, Chiyoko!
Chiyoko!
I need money to pay the driver.
How much?
6,000 yen.
I'm so sorry.
- Sorry to keep you waiting, thanks again.
- Thanks.
Here we go.
Excuse me.
- You okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Can I change my destination?
- Sure.
- Good.
I appreciate it.
Can I ask if your mother is well?
I wouldn't know.
Ran away?
Yes.
But not me. She did.
My mom left me and my dad, too.
She's still alive.
Forgive me for prying.
Thank you.
Something wrong?
Not really...
Just wanted to see me?
Look how bashful you are!
Come on, out with it.
I hate brooding men.
We only just met the other day.
I just saw my mother.
She abandoned my father and
me when I was a kid.
- Did you speak?
- No, I just saw her.
And your father?
Dead. He hung himself.
Maybe you should speak to her.
I suddenly felt like seeing you.
I was thinking of you, too.
Kenji Shiraishi.
At my age...
who needs a mother?
Then what's the problem?
I hated her to death.
When you were a kid, right?
Saeko Shiina.
You're funny.
- What does that mean?
- Nothing...
Thirsty?
I'd better go.
What time do I pick you up?
You really are different, aren't you?
No one's accused me of that before.
I have a hair appointment at 4.
Can I borrow your car
while you're there?
Be my guest.
Apart from looking after
a Chinese orphan, I'm pretty ordinary.
So I can't live with you now,
though I'd like to.
- What's so funny?
- Say what?
Well, whatever.
I'll see you.
Rain, huh?
Pouring, too.
Rain.
Here, look.
- Rain.
- That's right.
What else.
Sky.
Dad, mum.
What's that your saying?
Dad, mum and Achun.
I see.
You've nothing to be sad about.
Kenji... Achun.
- Kenji... Achun.
- That's right, me and Achun.
And Kyu-chan.
Welcome home.
I'm soaked.
Go help your father in the office.
I'm going out.
Why? Can't you at least
stay home when it rains?
You told me I should get out more.
Make plans to help out
all day Saturday, then.
It sure is pouring down.
Who's car is that?
Huh?
- Go see.
- Okay.
I think it's the man who
drove me home last night.
Why would he come back here?
I could be wrong.
What are you doing?
Going home.
I see.
What's his name?
The Chinese boy.
Achun.
Achun...
What a drag.
Being with me is a drag?
I didn't mean you.
Forget it.
You'd better hurry home.
I killed a person once.
Liar.
I beat two people with a frying pan.
I can still feel the pain in my hand.
Why would you do that?
I don't know.
Things just got out of hand.
Were you caught?
My childhood friend was a yakuza.
He shot some people.
I managed to get away.
Then you didn't kill them?
But I tried to, you see.
Yasuo just finished what I had started.
Yasuo, your yakuza friend?
Well, I don't care.
About what?
I still want to be with you.
Well I'm probably no good for you.
Why tell me that now?
Stop that.
That hurts!
There's something I've gotta do.
So go do it!
Will you wait for me
until it's done?
Will you?
What's your mother's name?
I forget.
Will you come back if I do wait?
Yeah.
Is your mom about?
Who're you?
Call your mom.
Tell me who you are first.
Tough guy, huh?
Yusuke, who is it?
Get to school, Yusuke.
My little brother's tough, unlike me.
Won't you come in?
How's it going?
They just sit facing each other,
not saying a word.
Is he really Chiyoko's son?
Don't know.
I've never met him before.
Well...
parent or no parent, we're all
on our own as adults.
Is Chiyoko crying?
No... she's actually smiling.
I knew immediately.
Yes, you've said that.
I guess I have.
I thought it was you when
I saw you yesterday.
At that distance?
No, but soon after you left.
Once I'd thought about it.
Know about Yasuo?
Yes, I read about it...
in the paper.
Did you read about dad, too?
Were you involved in Yasuo's crime?
What about Yuri?
- She's his sister, right?
- I'm still taking care of her.
- You were involved.
- It's none of your business.
It happened on the day
your father died, right?
I heard you'd run off
and hadn't been seen.
- I prayed you weren't a part of it.
- From wherever that was.
- Have you come to express your hatred for me?
- What would that do?
If so, I'm saddened to see
what a small man you've become.
Pretty harsh.
Can I fix you some food?
Sit down.
I'll listen to your complaints,
don't worry.
Then sit down!
Yuri's in a facility.
She thinks Yasuo will
return someday.
And I'm caring for a
Chinese boy named Achun.
I've done some "transporting"
work myself.
I took him before he could be sold.
You want me to look after them?
Only if you live here, too.
Don't be ridiculous.
Why not? This is my home.
Mamiya would certainly understand
having a step-son around.
How about your son?
He's known since he was little
that he has a big brother.
He knew he'd meet you someday.
What a horrible mom.
You don't know anything.
Dad said the same before he died.
What?
"You don't know anything."
I suppose to a parent,
a kid can never escape that.
That's right. You'll always be
a child to me.
Where are you going?
Home.
But you'll live with us?
I'll think about it.
What are you doing?
You shoplifting that?
None of your business.
Return it, will you?
If you screw me.
- Huh?
- What's your problem?
- Hey, stop that!
- Take off!
Get back here, you!
Run for it Yamamuro!
Run!
- Thanks.
- Good night.
Dear! You don't have to hit him!
I never imagined you
could be this stupid!
Get up!
I said get up!
Oh, Kenjii...
Let me go. This is the only
thing he'll understand.
He understands,
don't you, Yusuke?
Well? Answer your brother!
- Take it easy.
- Hey!
Good night.
Tamura.
You in love with Kenji?
Don't be silly.
I advise against getting
too close to anyone here.
Don't disturb the peace.
But Yusuke was...
It's still not your business.
You should've just ignored it.
Sorry.
Well, you don't seem like
you'll stay here long, anyway.
Forget it. Good night.
Good morning.
Oh, good morning!
- What's that?
- Bacon and eggs.
Great. That's my favorite.
- It'll be ready soon.
- Okay.
Kenji, come here.
My husband's in bed
with a high fever.
He is?
Yeah, he's worthless today.
Would you take over for him?
Get someone else to do your rounds.
What about Doc Kijima?
I'd rather you do it.
Why?
Morning!
- Good Morning.
- Morning.
Alright!
You know Yusuke can't handle it.
You're the only one I can count on.
What's that mean?
If it weren't for liquor, your father
would've been a very capable man.
Don't take to drinking, you hear.
What are you saying?
I'm saying I want you to take over
the business.
You're joking.
What about Mamiya?
He wouldn't object in the least.
He's too much of a softie
to be successful.
You prefer a wife beater like Dad?
Don't be stupid.
Good morning.
Morning.
Thanks for everything
yesterday, Kozue.
No, I'm sorry.
It wasn't my place to interfere.
Don't be silly.
You were a great help.
I'm counting on you, Kenji.
Okay, everyone drive carefully.
Have a good one.
See you.
Gotoh, could you give my mom
and Yusuke a lift?
- You're a good man, Kenji.
- What do you mean?
You seem good,
but a little scary.
How so?
Losers like us either follow or
run from guys like you.
Who's there?
It's Kenji.
How do you feel?
The fever just won't break.
Can I get you anything?
No, I've caused you enough
trouble already.
I don't mind, really.
Please, you need to rest.
I'm feeling a bit better
now that everyone's out.
Mr. Mamiya...
What keeps you going?
What do you mean?
Ever been betrayed?
By whom?
Your employees.
They're all drifters.
I have on occasion.
Can you trust them?
Not really.
Then why?
You should know very well why.
If I closed shop, they'd have
nowhere to go.
Maybe so, but...
Like Yuri and Achun.
Without you, where would they go?
What keeps you from
abandoning them?
Well, that's how it is.
Good one.
Soap bubbles. Don't see
those much these days.
I wish I could float away like that.
Who's winning?
The Doc. Who else?
How would you know?
You know nothing but baseball.
Get out here Kenji!
Yusuke's leaving!
Yusuke, wait!
Yusuke, get back here!
- Yusuke!
- Get away from me, hag!
Yusuke, don't.
- Stay out of this.
- I can't.
Out of my way!
Get back inside.
Screw you!
You just work here.
Butt out!
Yusuke!
Problem settled!
We owe our lives to
your folks, you know.
We're not ordinary employees.
Everyone back inside.
Impressive.
The boy is hopeless.
He's your child, isn't he?
I'll rely on you now.
Abandoning a son again?
I haven't abandoned anyone.
You abandoned me!
Admit it!
You're right.
I had it coming.
My leaving would restore the peace.
No, it wouldn't.
Please stay.
Surprised?
Give me a smoke.
You're in shipping, huh?
You like being a transporter?
I'm coming for the child.
Japanese can't raise kids right.
I'm doing all right.
Don't worry. I won't kill you.
That's not what I meant.
What's this, you've
grown fond of the child?
Not really...
Huh?
A child needs a mother.
Japanese women aren't good mothers.
The fathers are worse.
Chinese are better?
Murderers are better?
What do people need most?
The will to survive, right?
That may be so in China.
Your problem is you believe in
some beautiful ideal world.
Take a look around and show me
where that exists.
What ideal world?
I don't even believe in parents.
Kenji, playing hooky?
This your route today, Gotoh?
Come here.
Know what that is?
Do you know where it came from?
What do you mean?
It drifted here from Hawaii.
Unbelievable.
From here to Yamaguchi Prefecture,
all Hawaiian coral.
Really? I didn't know that.
Huge masses of it drifted here.
I think it actually formed
the Japanese islands.
That's a lot of coral.
No kidding.
We boast about our rich heritage.
But it's all just a collection
of stuff from somewhere else.
Kenji, let me show you something.
Okay!
Look here.
This compass only spins here.
My mom was the mistress
of the landlord here.
And his family had owned
the land for ages.
Right up until the Meiji Restoration.
I plan on exposing its secret
and destroying the myth.
What myth?
Japan's origins.
Thanks for waiting.
Hey! Now this is a surprise!
I traded shifts.
- So you could see me?
- Be careful! Stop it!
You reek of liquor.
I missed you!
Pull over a second.
Okay, okay.
I'm trying to drive here.
People are looking.
Fine. Let them look.
Kenji?
What?
Kenji!
You're heavy.
Don't be rude.
You wanted to talk?
Guess what...
I'm saving up money.
For what?
For when we live together.
Really.
That okay?
Living together?
Not sure.
I'm talking about with
Yuri and Achun, too.
You've a good memory.
Let's wait just a bit longer.
My thing will be over soon.
Well, I won't get my hopes up then.
I'll come for you.
Tell me if you change your mind.
Here.
Knock it off.
Yuri, what's wrong?
Achun was taken away.
Whose blood?
Nakanishi's.
Why Nakanishi?
Some guys came and beat him,
then carried him off.
The same ones who took Achun?
We're going to bed, Kenji.
Got an early start tomorrow.
Okay. Good night.
Could you take Yuri
to her room, Kozue?
Sure.
- Come on, let's go.
- Yeah.
Yuri,
take this with you.
Here.
Thank you.
Can I have a word with you, Kenji?
Thanks.
Here.
It's about Nakanishi.
Actually, you could say the same
for all of us here but...
Nakanishi was being hounded
by some nasty debt collectors.
So we all saw it coming
at some point.
But according to Gotoh,
who walked in on it...
at first the men only seemed interested
in Achun for some reason.
They found Nakanishi,
just by happenstance.
I see.
But what's done is done.
Why dwell on it?
I'm sorry.
You should get to bed, too.
With Nakanishi gone,
we're a little short-handed.
You're making a long-distance
delivery with the boss tomorrow?
That's right.
- Tomorrow evening?
- Yes.
Well, good night.
Kenji...
there are no coincidences in life.
We meet who we should meet.
That's how it works.
- I'm sorry.
- Please, don't be.
These kind of things happen here.
No they don't. We've never had
anything like this happen before.
Well, it's late.
See you in the morning.
Kenji, will you be able to
forget about the boy?
They spoke Chinese.
He's with his people now.
I know.
Where were you?
At a friend's.
You have friends?
Let's go to bed. Close up shop
for me, will you Kenji?
Thank you.
Is Yuri asleep?
Yes.
But now I can't sleep.
Kenji...
I'm looking for my mother, too.
You are?
I was almost killed once
when I was a kid.
Remember that bus-jacking incident?
I think so, yeah.
I don't remember a thing
from that day.
I saw it on the news.
But things changed afterwards.
My mom took off one day.
And then my father died
in an accident.
Same here.
Really?
If you saw your mom, then what?
I don't know.
I'd like to see her cheerful face.
And then what?
What's next for you?
I'm not really sure.
Revenge?
Revenge? How?
I think about it sometimes, too.
And?
But seeing you living here with
Mrs. Mamiya has made me think.
This is your revenge, isn't it?
Just by your being here...
maybe you're getting back at her.
I wonder if Achun will return
to China.
He has no place to go.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Kenji?
You don't think people really
need parents, right?
Then why would we want
to take revenge on them?
I'm sorry.
I'll go to bed now.
Good night.
How nice.
What's nice?
I wish I had something in life
worth confiding about.
I wouldn't say I do, either.
Yes, you do.
My hopes are with my next life.
Mr. Gotoh, are you scared?
Yeah.
They'll come for me next.
Then maybe you shouldn't act so
above it all.
What do you know about anything?
Who's there?
Who is it?
Yasuo?
That you, Yasuo?
What?
Get out of here.
What are you talking about?
Nobody here needs you anymore.
Your parents have forsaken you.
Why are you telling me this?
I want to see your mother
heartbroken because you're gone.
- She's yours, too.
- She's not my mother.
Just a tramp who left her family.
Just what are you up to?
She shacked up with some young guy.
Left me and my drunken
dad high and dry.
Now it's your turn.
Poor you.
It's useless for you to stay.
I'm not listening to you.
I'll be driving to Kanazawa
with your dad today.
Your mom has to visit the police.
There's your chance.
Got it?
I said, got it?
You're a man, right?
Then try living on your own.
Yasuo contacted me yesterday, Yuri.
My brother?
Says he'll be back soon.
Really, he said that?
He's coming home?
Soon.
Drive carefully.
- Have a safe trip, Kenji.
- See you.
- Watch how you go.
- Thanks.
Welcome back.
I'm home.
How did it go?
The police aren't too sympathetic
to Nakanishi's plight.
I didn't think they would be.
Yusuke! Where are you going?
Yusuke!
That brat!
He's an embarrassment!
What's wrong?
Yuri! What's the matter?
Oh God.
Was it Yusuke?
Did he do this to you?
Tell me, Yuri!
What happened?
Yuri, please!
Snap out of it!
Something wrong?
Yusuke ran off.
Seriously?
He was probably waiting
for us to leave.
Shall I go on without you?
Will you be alright on your own?
Well I'll pull over if I get tired.
Ah...
sorry about this.
Welcome back.
Long drive to take alone.
Is the boss in?
No, he's out looking for Yusuke.
What's more I'm afraid I have
some bad news for you.
- Whisky?
- No, I'm fine.
The thing is, soon after Yusuke left,
we found Yuri collapsed on the floor.
Yuri?
Though I had my license revoked,
I was once a doctor, you know.
So I had a look at her.
She was raped.
She's not there.
She's gone.
Chiyoko took her back
to the facility.
Thanks.
Welcome home.
I'm impressed.
About what?
You lived with Yuri all this time
and nothing ever happened.
Huh?
You never laid a hand on her.
I worried about that.
I thought she might wake up one day
and find herself pregnant.
And if she did?
Well, that would be fine, too.
Even if the child was like her.
We have this big house.
We could all live happily here.
Of course, you'd need a good wife.
Someone proper enough
to run the household.
She'd have to be someone who could
give you all the support you needed.
You're a piece of work.
What do you mean?
I went to that fancy restaurant
you once worked at.
One of the staff there
still remembers you.
I laughed hearing about all
the customers you slept with.
Searching for anyone
that would have you.
This lady on the staff...
mustn't have liked you much.
She had a lot of
negative things to say.
I don't see how you chose a
good man like Mr. Mamiya.
That just doesn't suit you at all,
does it?
You must've duped him good.
- Where were you the day before yesterday?
- What's it to you?
- You have a girlfriend?
- I said, what's it to you?
I have to meet my future
daughter-in-law.
Are you nuts?
Yusuke's gone.
I've got to make sure you can
comfortably take over the business now.
What world do you live in?
This one.
Come on, Kenji.
You're the heir, here.
Don't make me laugh.
Who would want to live here?
I planned it all.
I gave Yusuke his bike key.
I even figured he'd go after Yuri.
But that was fine as long as you felt
what it's like to be abandoned.
I did what I came to do.
I've no other use for this place.
And now I'm out of here.
Have a nice life.
You can't leave, Kenji.
Kenji!
You were never my mother, got it?
Will you still have me?
I told you I'd wait.
Yuri's in a nursing facility.
Then bring her here.
I'll go check in on her.
Guess what?
I'm pregnant.
- Hello.
- Thanks for seeing me.
Have a seat.
Thanks.
Your mother paid a visit yesterday.
Oh, I see.
She...
wants to adopt Yuri.
That's news to me.
I see.
Either way, Yuri's not ready
to be released yet.
Oh, I see.
I'll call you when she is.
I'd appreciate that.
So...
Which address should I contact you at?
Mamiya or Shiraishi?
Shiraishi.
Can you support her?
I think so, yes.
Mr. Shiraishi...
Yuri is very unstable right now.
I don't expect men to understand.
But you don't go back to normal
after what she's been through.
Understand?
Yes.
So I'm asking you.
Can you care for her properly?
Can you really take responsibility for her?
Yes.
What do you want?
To kill you.
If you want to hate someone,
hate your mum.
Mom would hate to see us
killing each other.
Isn't that what you want?
That slut is no longer
relevant to me.
You call your own mother a slut?
Give it up.
You can't win.
Enough.
Run home.
Stop worrying your dad.
What's the matter?
What is it?
Please calm down!
Damn you!
Hey!
Get up.
Not getting up?
Shit!
Huh!
It's Kenji!
Who's Kenji?
Rest in peace.
Thank you.
Is that your funeral wear?
Huh?
I have something for you.
Even pregnant, you ought
to be wearing a kimono.
Come.
Yes, Mamiya Transporters.
Mr. Gotoh?
There's no one by that name here.
Yes.
May I ask who's calling?
It's sure getting cold.
Yeah.
Looking after yourself?
- Yes.
- We lucked out! The newspaper...
Shut up!
Doesn't matter.
We found Kozue and she's happy.
That's enough.
Way to go.
This doesn't seem to be
such a bad place either, right?
Lots of people here like you, Shigeo.
Huh! That would suck.
What's that supposed to mean, apologize!
- Shigeo.
- Yes, what?
Come and meet everybody.
Okay.
Sure was a bizarre
coincidence though.
Wasn't it?
Chiyoko, could you say a word
to everyone?
Let me introduce you to
Ms. Saeko Shiina.
Kenji's fiancee.
Oh, I see. Pleasure.
My condolences.
And guess what?
Saeko is pregnant.
We all have to wait
for Kenji's return.
You okay with that?
Well of course she is!
She's carrying Kenji's child!
Yusuke reborn.
Ma'am!
Don't worry about me.
You have to look after yourself.
Go speak to our guests!
Honestly, men will just go
and do as they please.
But it doesn't bother me.
We have our children.
Right, Saeko?
Well if Kozue is happy here,
then who are we to argue, right?
Don't look at me.
- Idiot.
- Forgive me, Shigeo.
No need to apologize.
This is a nice place.
Looks pretty tough, though.
Behave yourself, man!
Please don't mind us.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
You're getting it later, man.
Ms. Saeko?
- Yes?
- A word if I may?
Okay.
- Ms. Saeko...
- Yes?
I'm so glad you came today.
The fault for all of this
lies with us, the parents.
Kenji's not all to blame.
Chiyoko could really use your help.
Please come again.
Certainly.
Here Kyu-chan. Let's go.
Morning.
Oh, did you sleep well?
Very well, thank you.
What's your relation to Kozue again?
I'm her cousin.
And a friend of Kenji's, too.
What a small world, huh?
The last time I saw Kenji...
he was with Yuri and her brother.
Yes, I heard about it.
You did?
Yes.
But that whole experience
was a real eye-opener for me.
I mean, until then I wasn't sure
if I was dead or alive.
That's why I had hoped
to see Kenji again.
See him for what?
I really don't know.
I thought I had quit a long time ago.
Know what my wife said
as she was leaving today?
"We can't dwell on who has died
and who's still alive."
"Let's instead focus on who
is about to be born."
I don't think that Kenji can bear that.
What exactly do you mean by that?
Kenji thought that he had finally
severed his ties to her.
Only she forgives him.
I don't think he had figured on
the depth of her mercy.
Must've horrified him.
Can you live with that?
What?
You devote your life to
helping those in trouble...
and they turn on you like this.
- Can you welcome Kenji back?
- Sure.
It was fated to be this way.
If he serves out his sentence,
then yes, we'll welcome him back.
Do your best, sir.
Huh?
I've always hated that phrase but...
I really wish you all the best.
Finally, I get to see you.
What can you see from your cell?
A wall.
Of course.
I've been staring at one, too.
I met with Saeko.
She's a good woman.
Leave her alone.
Don't be that way.
We need her to give birth
to a beautiful baby.
By the time you're out,
the child will be in grade school.
I'll have Saeko abort.
I've invited her to come and
live with us.
We'll take care of her.
And you don't mind if
we adopt Yuri, do you?
What are you scheming?
Not a thing. That's what
Mamiya told me to do.
She needs a home.
Like hell she does.
Stay away from her!
With your sister, Yuri,
Saeko and your child...
we'll all be waiting for you to return.
What?
You never knew, did you?
Yuri...
is the daughter that your father and your
aunt Matsumura had between them.
That's the reason I left.
But of course...
you never got to hear about that.
Look, I don't care.
Do as you like.
I'm not returning.
You won't abandon them...
Yuri, Saeko, and your child.
They're all with me.
You'll be back.
You're the only child
I have left in the world.
You have to take over the business.
Serve out your sentence
and think it over.
What do you want?
We want Gotoh.
No one here by that name.
He may have changed it.
Let us take a look.
You want me to call the police?
Do as you wish.
Asano Tadanobu
Ishida Eri
Miyazaki Aoi
Itaya Yuka
Mitsuishi Ken, Saito Yoichiro
Tsujii Kaori
Odagiri Joe
Written and Directed by
Aoyama Shinji
Original translation by
Anthony Kimm
Subtitle timing, editing, and additions
for this version by famitsu1
Additional translation assistance by
zen, 8thsin, theanalogkid, igarasi
Special thanks to chochoc
for additional QC and translation support
Extra special thanks to
kikujiro