"December 24, Taisho 15 (1926 A.D.)"
Let's raise the curtains now,
"Original Story: Ohji Hiroi"
♪ My wish is the same as yours. ♪
♪ Today is a special day,
so surely a miracle will happen. ♪
♪ Let everyone believe in miracles,
just for a little while. ♪
♪ Words of kindness will ring in their ears. ♪
♪ Let everyone believe in miracles,
just for a little while. ♪
♪ Bonds of love will appear in their eyes. ♪
♪ Today is a special day,
a day overflowing with love. ♪
♪ I'm certain I will be
blessed with a miracle. ♪
♪ Today is a special day, a day
when the bells of love will ring. ♪
♪ A love story for you and me! ♪
♪ Today is a special day,
a day overflowing with love. ♪
♪ Today is a special day, a day
when the bells of love will ring. ♪
♪ A love story for you and me! ♪
"Director: Mitsuru Hongo"
Thank you for attending the
Great Imperial Theater today.
Thank you so
much for your patronage!
Great work, everyone!
You, too!
Thanks for making the announcement.
Sure.
Wasn't that an amazing
round of applause, Leni?
I thought I was going to pass out!
Yes, the crowd was
especially enthusiastic today.
We must thank our audience.
I reckon we should, Miss Maria!
It was like we and
the audience were one!
I had a great time!
Well, I suppose
you all did rather well.
Is something the matter?
It's so rare for you to
compliment others, Miss Sumire.
You got that right!
Honestly, though,
this is a good kind of tired!
Orihime, you worked hard all this year.
That's right, but you
worked hardest of all, Miss Karma.
Oh, but I don't recall
Miss Karma working all that hard...
What?! You're the only
one around here who hasn't--
This is our playhouse.
This is where we members of the
Imperial Operetta Troupe's Flower Division...
...pool together our sweat, tears,
and hopes, and shine brightly.
To be here in this
spot at this exact time...
lt makes me happy-
Happy birthday, Leni!
Happy birthday!
You're 17 now, Leni.
Thank you.
Wait for me!
Please! Please, don't leave me out!
Happy birthday, Leni.
Thank you, Sakura.
How do you manage to be such a klutz?
I realize you're always this way,
but I really must wonder.
Oh, isn't Flower Division wonderful?
Hi there! Merry Christmas
and happy birthday!
Captain Kayama?
With Flower Division Captain lchiro
Oogami being away at Paris and all,
I thought I'd try to cheer everyone up.
But Maria is our acting captain right now!
It seems like we were having more
fun before Captain Kayama showed up...
C'mon, now! Let's live it up tonight!
Sumire?
Oh, Miss Maria!
What a coincidence!
I had no idea you watched
films like this, Sumire.
Would you care to join me, Miss Maria?
"Imperial News"
A powerful friend has arrived at
the imperial capital, Tokyo.
The United States of America.
Among the many
corporations to be found there,
the Douglas-Stewart Company
stands out with its advanced science.
Mr. Brent Furlong, the young
president of Douglas-Stewart,
is a man passionate about charity work.
Amazed at the rapid pace
of our nation's recovery...
...and the strong work ethic of her people,
Miss Maria...
Mr. Furlong is offering...
...to help us create a better society,
What in the world is bothering you?
--I'm sorry. It's nothing.
--working toward the brighter future...
--I see.
--...that awaits us in the 21st century.
"Imperial News" "The End"
"KAN-El"
"Kanzaki Motion Picture Company"
"Yokohama Love Triangle"
Hm?
--Thank you for coming!
Excuse me,
where do I find the manager?
Um, I'm not very good with English.
Miss Sakura?
Wha--? Oh, I'm no
good with English, either.
How are you?
Did I get it wrong? Let me see...
Nice to meet you!
Huh? What are you trying to say?
You're not making any sense at all.
Will you please stop wasting my time?
M-My name is Sakura!
Sakura is che--cherry!
Cherry is Nippon! Heart!
Miss Sakura, you're not making any sense!
--Calm down!
--No, it's, um... Japan Spirit!
I'm sorry, I was just joking.
Where might I find
Mr. Yoneda, the manager?
Mr. Yoneda?
The manager?
I see. So, the Elders
Institute has finally decided...
...to set up a Fighting
Troupe even in America.
Yes, Sir. Following in the
footsteps of Tokyo and Paris,
the third City Defense Plan will
be the New York Fighting Troupe.
So, why did you come
all the way out to Tokyo?
The Imperial Capital has successfully
fought off two great demon invasions,
and Paris has recently repelled the Parishii.
I concluded that to learn from these
successes, it would be more efficient...
...to work in the field with them
rather than study them from afar.
Efficient, eh?
As of today, I've been assigned to the
Imperial Fighting Troupe, Flower Division.
Lachette Altair, reporting for duty.
I look forward to serving under you.
So, I'm guessing you already got the
Elders lnstitute's permission for this, eh?
Knowing you, you probably brought
your own Eisenkleid to Japan, didn't you?
Where is it? We'll have to send
someone to go pick it up right away.
There's no worry there, Sir.
I already brought it with me on the truck.
As always, it seems you've
already got this all worked out.
I simply chose the most
efficient course of action.
Well, well. What to do, what to do...?
She was against the breakup
of Star Division to the very end.
More than anyone else,
she took pride in her role...
...as a guardian of the
people against the darkness.
But no matter how exceptional
their skill and abilities were,
as a group, they were just too fragile.
We'll have to see if Lachette
has come to realize the real reason...
...why Star Division was disbanded.
Our imperial capital of Tokyo is
enjoying great prosperity at the moment.
What are you worried about?
Have we not neglected our defenses
in the rush to improve our infrastructure?
You're jumping at shadows.
What do you think we've
come here to address, then?
The capital is open in all directions,
linked to the country via her waterways.
This geographic advantage has brought
about the prosperity we enjoy today.
But could we also be taking in
diseased elements in the process?
Are you talking about America?
Even if that were the case,
the capital can rely on the
Imperial Fighting Troupe for her defense.
Is it wise to be completely
dependent on those young girls?
There are, no doubt, issues we
must address, but they are trivial.
We need look no further
than our own capital and Paris...
...to see that the Fighting Troupe
program is a success.
Our nation needs a capital city,
and to be prosperous, a city needs to
be open to the free movement of people.
It is unavoidable for the bright lights
of prosperity to give rise to dark shadows.
In a sense, we must accept
this and learn to live with it.
I trust you all understand this.
What is the government's
position on this issue, Mr. Tanuma?
Well, for the city to further
develop as a powerful occult center,
our existing spiritual quarantine measures
will likely offer inadequate protection.
At this time, then, nothing can replace
the Fighting Troupe's Flower Division.
However, in the spirit of being
constantly mindful of our surroundings,
I believe we should not shy
away from introducing new blood...
...to meet new challenges as the need arises.
I venture to say that the darkness
will come upon us yet again.
But if this capital should
succumb to the darkness,
it would mean that
the entire nation would fall.
That must never happen!
So, a cutie from America, huh?
There you are, Miss Sakura.
Thank you.
So tell us, Miss Sakura,
was this person really that beautiful?
She's talking to Mr. Yoneda right now,
but she'll probably
pass through here afterwards.
True, but we need to
hear your first impression of her.
Why's that?
One set of eyes usually ain't enough
to get a true understanding of something.
Now, I don't know
how good looking she is,
but we all gotta get a look at
her to get to the heart of the matter.
Is that so?
Here comes the heart of the matter now!
Talk about awkward!
I bet she heard every word we said!
Like they say,
"curiosity killed the cat."
What's that?
A Western saying.
Already trying to act like
an American, Miss Sakura?
Of course not!
Miss Sakura!
Wow, she's a real beauty, all right!
See?
This country is not very attractive.
I know what you mean, Sir.
This country is in need of a true king.
What's rational is that the
world be under a single entity.
That, we have to teach them.
I knew you were going to say that, Sir.
Beautiful.
Kouma, fallen demons,
have appeared in Zaimoku-Cho.
We have confirmation of thirteen so far.
A fire has broken out, but Moon
Division is at work putting it out.
Fires can spread quickly this time of year,
so be mindful of the surrounding
houses during combat.
Yes, Sir!
Right! Imperial Fighting Troupe,
Flower Division, dispatch at once!
--Yes, Sir!
Deputy Commander, we've completed
calculating the path to the scene.
Put it up on the screen.
The Gourai-Go's preparations?
Ready in sixty seconds.
Flower Division members have
begun boarding their Koubu-Kai's.
--Ignition complete.
--Maria Tachibana, ready for dispatch.
Kohran here, I'm A-OK.
Karma Kirishima, ready to go!
Sakura, ignition complete!
Koubu-Kai units,
ignition complete!
All right, begin loading!
Now loading.
Moving engine into position.
Rotation complete!
Descent complete.
Moving Gourai-Go
into launch position.
"Emergency Vehicle"
Asakusa Station cleared!
Stay sharp!
-Yes' Ma.
Leni!
Lachette!
Stop fighting on your own!
We fight as a team!
What was that?
--What was that just now?
--Was it one of ours?
--What the hell's going on?
--That's some impressive hardware!
Who in the world could that have been?
How the hell are
we supposed to find out?
We were all quite startled.
A humanoid steamer
of unknown origin, you say?
Yes, Sir.
Well, it looks like it's started.
How do you mean, Sir?
You know, in a capitalist nation,
"freedom" means the freedom to compete.
Sir?
I just hope this won't get complicated.
Also, Sir, about the
new member of the division...
What about Lachette?
Sounds like it's
gonna get complicated.
Who the hell is this?
Lachette Altair, our old captain
from back when we were in Star Division.
What, you know this person?
But what's she doing here?
I have no idea.
Lachette!
Hi, Orihime. It's been a while.
Geez!
Have you met?
Lachette, it's been so long!
It sure has, Orihime.
You're looking well.
And... you, too, Leni.
Why are you here?
Leni!
Leni, wait for me!
It looks like Leni is
still uncomfortable around you.
This will be a problem since we're all
Flower Division members now.
Is that so?
I'm Lachette Altair.
I hope we'll work well together.
And so, it has been decided that
this unit will be leased to the Army...
...along with technical
advisors from Douglas-Stewart.
It may be that we
are still in the trial stages,
but I'm certain they will be officially
adopted into service within a year.
Once that happens, there will
be no need for Flower Division,
and we'll no longer have to expose
young girls to unnecessary dangers.
Will we, Count Hanakouji?
Mr. Tanuma, if you have something
to say, stop beating around the bush.
M)' apologies.
I merely wished to point out the
winds of change to my esteemed elder.
What is new will
eventually become obsolete.
While this demonstration was
typically American in its recklessness,
I believe you now know just how capable...
...the unmanned, low-cost
humanoid steamer "Japhkiel" is.
Such utter grandstanding... You knew
of this beforehand, didn't you?
But of course.
Only a fool would play poker while
showing his hand for all to see.
You're saying that you see governance
and gambling as the same thing?
My dear Count, it is often
said that life is one big gamble.
For a government, are not
deeds more important than words?
Leni certainly has changed...
W-What in the world?
A defective product.
W-Wait a moment!
This won't do!
If anyone found out what's in--
Refrain from making
such careless statements.
Or else our amicable relationship
will have to be terminated right here.
Is that your wish?
We aren't equals.
You'd do well to remember that.
"January 1, Taisho 16 (1926 A.D.)"
"Happy New Year From
Namamise Shopping Arcade!"
"Kaminarimon"
Go faster, Miss Karma!
Go faster, faster!
Leave it to me! Here we go!
" Ningyo-yaki"
"Kaminari-okoshi"
"Senbei"
C'mon, Big Sister Kasumi,
let's look around in the stores here.
Not yet, Iris. We'll go
after we pray at the shrine.
But that's boring!
The texture is reminiscent of
the Italian dish, gnocchi.
Gnocchi? What a strange name.
What do you mean? It's Japanese
food names that are strange.
Yuba, ganmodoki, tokoroten,
kiritanpo, kinchaku...
And these are miso-tarashi rice balls,
but where's the miso sauce?
It's mi-tarashi, Miss
Orihime, not miso-tarashi.
And how in the world are
you supposed to eat the last one?
Okay! And now we'll add another two!
Here's one! And here's the other!
"Fortunes"
"#100: Colossal Misfortune"
"Your wishes will not be granted.
Your health may suffer."
"Lost items will not return.
Romances and relationships will sour."
What's this supposed to mean?!
What did I do to deserve
this kind of abuse?!
Don't let it bother you, Kohran.
If it's that bad, it just
means it can't get any worse.
What about you?
The prediction for your luck is only so-so.
There's nothing special here...
You sure seem awfully happy, though...
Ah-ha! This must be it!
"The one you await will soon return."
"The one you await," huh?
I wonder who that could be?
I have no idea!
Oh, really? I was thinking
it might just be Mr. 00--
Come on, now! We should be
concentrating on our new play.
I suppose so, but I'm stuck
with a bit part in this new one.
You are?
Yeah. It's too bad, 'cause I've
always liked Izumi Kyouka's works.
Is it true that Miss Lachette nabbed
the lead role her first time out?
Yes, won't this be exciting to see?
Okay, everyone!
Let's do the next scene now!
Now remember, this is
the Dragon King's Palace.
The prince has bought the girl he
loves with a gift of treasure to her father,
and with the exchange agreed to,
he's waiting for the girl to arrive.
Souzu.
Yes, what is it, Young Master?
I wonder if they are satisfied with the
treasure I sent in exchange for their daughter.
Yes, Master.
They would not have
sent out their daughter...
...had they not been
happy with the gift you offered.
Truly, avarice runs deep in all humans.
But the maiden that won the heart of
our young master will enjoy happiness!
If only she would arrive soon!
There! That bright
beacon of light is she!
It would appear that she has arrived.
Are you all right, Lachette?!
Not a problem!
--What do you think you're doing?
--What's the big idea?!
--C'mon, fix me up!
--Same here!
--Just a little more!
--Miss Sakura, don't leave my flank!
Right!
--Do we leave this to the Japhkiels?
--Oh, no! They're focusing on Miss Leni!
--Leni! --I'll go help!
--They're certainly agile!
Too late!
Leni!
To hell with this!
--Orihime!
Two Flower Division Koubu-Kai's suffered
major damage in the last engagement.
One division member was injured.
The damaged Koubu-Kai units...
...have been transported to the Kanzaki
Heavy Industries factory for repairs.
For the duration of the repairs,
we plan to make do...
...with two Eisenkleids which
had previously been mothballed.
Next, regarding the status of the Imperial
Army 13th Special Mechanized Squad.
Five Japhkiels were
dispatched and suffered no damage.
Their Kouma kill score appears to be
rather larger than that of Flower Division.
It would seem that
the times have changed.
If I may, I would like
to make a request now.
It's a simple matter, really.
Command of a Japhkiel squad?!
Why should we have
to do something like that?!
In the military, you gotta faithfully
follow any order coming from above.
There is far too much about this Japhkiel
deployment that is suspicious.
I'm told that their deployment
is classified top secret.
Are we to be window dressing?
Military officers will be
doing the actual commanding!
That ain't window dressing!
But this is like a de facto
breakup of Flower Division!
Just because we've been relieved
of our Kouma intercept duties...
...doesn't mean Flower Division
is being disbanded.
I'll go to the Army.
Who do you think you are?!
Listening to Lt. General Yoneda
discuss the matter,
it seemed to me that I would
be the most appropriate candidate.
Well, I suppose Lachette would--
I'm going to go!
All right, all right!
If you want to go so badly,
you can go to the Army.
Oh, brother... How are we going to be able
to put together a production in this state?
What the--
Commander Yoneda's gone missing?!
Moon Division and Dream Division
are currently doing all they can to find him.
Actually, Lt. General Yoneda isn't
the only one who has disappeared.
Count Hanakouji is missing, as well.
I have one other piece of bad news.
The operation of the Imperial Operetta
Troupe has been indefinitely suspended.
As of today, we are all to relocate
to the Flower Mansion Branch.
The Imperial Theater complex is
to be placed under Army jurisdiction.
No!
I don't believe it...!
Kouma reported at Fukagawa!
Japhkiel squad has requested
dispatch of their commanding officer.
I'll go now.
Orihime...
Make me proud as a former
member of Star Division, Orihime.
This has nothing to do with Star Division.
I am a member of Flower Division now.
Pack your belongings, everyone.
We leave for the
Flower Mansion in one hour.
Miss Orihime...
Miss Orihime, disembark
from the Gourai-Go at Nihonbashi,
and head to Fukagawa
from there over land.
Roger.
Orihime...
I'm proud to be a
member of Flower Division.
That's why I don't want to let
Lachette outdo me as she is now.
It's amazing how these
things move on their own.
Where are the Kouma?
There!
I wonder if things are
working out for Miss Orihime...
I'm sorry, but all of my
information sources have dried up.
I see.
I wonder if we'll
never pilot our Koubu's again...
If it means that peace in Tokyo is secure,
it's a small enough price to pay.
But if... If Flower Division
were to be disbanded...
All the Japhkiels on this
production line are empty shells...
Where are their interiors?
This... What's inside the Japhkiels is...
Kouma... What have they done?!
It's a pleasure to meet you, Maria.
How flattering. Are you one of my fans?
My name is Patrick.
As you are about to die, I felt I should
reveal my real name to you.
You've learned too much'.!
I hate to disappoint you,
but bullets have no effect on me.
Miss Maria did what?!
I hear she left a note saying she was
going to dig around inside Douglas-Stewart.
They say no one's heard from her since.
Let's go look for her!
We mustn't act recklessly.
But we've gotta--
Don't worry about Miss Maria.
She's our captain, after all.
Then I should just
sit here and do nothing?!
I never got a
chance to give this to her.
I made this bullet
filled with spirit power.
I only managed to get
one round to Mr. Kayama.
If you don't do what you can while
you can, you'll only regret it later.
What can we do, I ask you?!
The Shogei-Maru has
been sealed, and Wind Division...
...and the Deputy Commander
are under house arrest at the theater!
What can we possibly do?!
Why not?
Let's do what we can.
I don't want to live with regrets.
Why don't we all do this together?
Yes!
Let's do it!
Let's go for it!
You're on!
I suppose we must.
Yes, let's!
Mr. Yokihiko from Rose Division!
This entire affair seems to have
to do with a branch of the Army...
...that's been goaded into action
by a politician named Tanuma.
Which means Douglas-Stewart and
this Tanuma fellow must be in cahoots.
Moon Division is searching for
Commander Yoneda and Count Hanakouji.
Let us away to the
Great Imperial Theater!
We'll use the underground waterways
to go from Hibiya to the HQ hangars...
...and grab your Koubu-Kai's there.
We have underground waterways?
We had them made when we
were building the subway system.
But how are we gonna get around in 'em?
Not to worry.
I designed something
for just such an occasion!
We'll use my Katsuryu-Maru!
Um, Kohran, what's all this
machinery you have on board?
They're upgrade parts I designed
for Koubu-Kai's and Eisenkleids!
Just you wait!
This is quite the picturesque
dusk cityscape, is it not?
It doesn't hold a candle to
New York, of course.
What is it that you want us to see?
You persist in marketing
your toys to us even now?
What have you done?
An impressive sight, is it not, Count?
Wow, so this is where it leads...
Moving in a single pack
will bog us down. Better split up.
You're right.
All clear!
Hey, halt!
Sakura!
Shit!
No!
You're going too far, Miss Lachette.
Really? Didn't I make myself clear?
I prefer to go with the
most efficient option, that's all.
In any case, let's hurry to
where they're keeping our Koubu's.
Who are you?!
Flower Division.
We're here to take back our theater.
Karma!
Stand down! Your orders are to wait
on standby at the Flower Mansion!
If I stayed there any longer,
Sumire's hysterics would drive me nuts.
M-Miss Karma!
Enough of this nonsense!
Have you no respect for orders?!
We'll follow any order if
it helps safeguard our Tokyo.
But you tell me, how is cozying up
to Douglas-Stewart good for this city?!
Deputy Commander...
With Commander Yoneda gone, I guess
I lost my nerve without realizing it.
Shame on me. At times like this,
I should be the one standing firm.
You've all taught me
a valuable lesson today.
Let's do it, Deputy Commander!
I'm gonna start upgrading the Koubu-Kai's!
There's a lot of work that needs to
be done here, so help me out, guys!
Imperial Fighting Troupe,
Flower Division! Prepare for dispatch!
What do you hope to accomplish?
It would seem that the fair
maidens of Flower Division...
...intend to defy us to the bitter end.
Some discipline would
seem to be called for.
One would think so, anyway.
However, what if I were to suggest that we
be entrusted with the defense of Tokyo?
Would you be amenable to this?
I have no intention to ask for your help.
We will guard our
imperial capital ourselves!
What do you think those girls fight for?
Do you know what goes through their
minds as they fight? What they wish for?
Do you have the slightest idea?
Those girls are tough.
They've done a fine job guarding this
city so far. And they'll continue to do so.
I believe in them.
Kouma reported in the skies
over Ginza! Huge numbers, Ma'am.
Listen, everyone! With the backpacks
that I invented attached to you,
our maneuverability is increased by 120%!
Okay, let's get cracking!
Behold the Imperial Fighting Troupe!
We will protect this city!
Miss Kaede! Looks like
we're ready to rumble!
Our spirit power's looking good out here!
Understood!
Get into formation and stand by!
Dream Division ready, Ma'am.
Spirit power sufficient!
Critical reached!
Right! Imperial Capital
Spiritual Barricade Formation!
Here we go!
Hey, look!
A Japhkiel!
What's the big idea?!
Leni?
Leni!
That's--
Miss Orihime...
Orihime!
Miss Orihime!
Look out!
Orihime!
Orihime! Snap out of it!
I'm sorry, Orihime.
Let's stop wasting each other's time.
Miss Lachette, wait!
There must be another way!
Get out of my way!
But“!
No!
Leni!
Leni! Hold on!
Thanks...
Leni! Are you okay?
I'm okay, Iris.
Thank goodness...
Orihime!
Miss Orihime!
Orihime! Orihime!
I'm sorry... I guess I blew it.
Kayama?
My apologies for the delay,
Count, General.
You can relax.
We've secured the building.
We're going to deal with that
Kouma incubation facility of yours.
Fireworks galore!
C'mon, let's pound 'em into the dirt! Fire!
You used the Navy, didn't you?
If there'd been even
one of those Japhkiels around,
it wouldn't have gone this smoothly.
Looks like your fixation on the
Imperial Theater got the better of you.
I could easily sink your entire
Imperial Navy with my Japhkiels.
I see you used those girls
as decoys, but it won't help you.
Decoys? What do you take us for?
Anyway, you've already lost.
Are you so sure?
Brent!
Behave yourselves
and watch from there!
Watch your Imperial Fighting Troupe's
Flower Division wither and fall!
Damn it!
The Japhkiels!
What in the world?
Ladies of the Imperial Fighting Troupe.
Perhaps I should introduce myself.
lam Brent Furlong.
So you're the big cheese
of Douglas-Stewart, huh?!
You have fought well.
Most praiseworthy, indeed.
But I see that your
heads have grown a little swollen.
Both you and your friends...
This behavior simply cannot be tolerated.
So I shall take it upon myself
to teach you your proper place!
That's--
Hey, look!
Captain, incoming message!
Hi, Kayama, honey!
It's me, Kotone!
So sorry to keep you waiting.
We just got in.
Is that you, Seiryuin?
Then he's--
Well, he rushed out before we
even reached our berth.
Honestly, that boy can be so impatient.
I see.
Okay, it's all yours now!
General.
Right.
Deputy Commander!
Sakura!
Just look at the size of it!
Please!
Move!
My Eisenkleid...
Bastard!
Karma, are you okay?!
Yeah, I guess.
Miss Sakura, are you all right?
Y-Yes! I can still fight.
Miss Lachette! What's
the matter, Miss Lachette?!
It's no use... It won't budge.
My Eisenkleid...
Miss Lachette...
This is bad! Everybody's spirit
power is falling off.
What are we supposed to do?
This glorious Imperial Capital
of yours comes to an end today.
I'll crush it beneath my feet.
You may call it an Imperial Capital,
but in the end, it's nothing!
It's utterly insignificant
in the face of my Japhkiel!
You.“
wrong.
It may seem like a small town to you,
but countless lives are lived here.
Each and every person spends his days...
...accompanied by sorrow,
joy, anger, suffering, or sadness.
They all live their lives
as best as they can.
How dare you... How dare you
dismiss all that as insignificant?!
As long as smiles remain on the
faces of those we love in this city,
we won't be defeated!
Miss Sakura!
The Japhkiel is taking cannon fire!
Flying object inbound at high speed!
Its speed is incredible!
Are you all right, Sakura?
Yes, Sir!
Sorry I took so long.
Lieutenant!
Big brother!
Captain!
Mr. Oogami!
Hello, everyone.
Damn you...!
Hey, that's it! That sound!
Mr. Oogami! Everybody! I figured it out!
You serious?
What are you going on about?
Sound!
All those Japhkiels are being controlled
by a special sound unique to each one!
Does that mean some
fixed frequency is being used?
Exactly!
Sharp as always, Mr. Oogami!
Just you watch! I'm gonna
make that thing go to pieces!
Those big ol' arms of his
are kinda in the way, though.
In that case...
...we'll just have to
do something about 'em!
I knew I could count on you two!
Mr. Oogami!
Iris, I need a lift!
Um, sure!
Sakura.
Sir?
You did a great job.
I can't thank you enough.
No, Sir.
Flower Division was able to carry
on this far thanks to you, Mr. Oogami.
More than anything else, it was
because you were here that we won.
What a grand victory for the Imperial
Fighting Troupe's Flower Division!
Oh, right! There's
one little thing I forgot to do!
Hey, you!
You're Japanese, ain't ya?
Show a little pride in your country!
That's what makes those girls so strong.
It's been a long time, Patrick.
You're still alive?
Here I am, no thanks to you.
This time, I'll make sure you're dead!
You really shouldn't
make threats like that lightly.
You're out of ammunition.
Not that bullets work on me, anyway.
Why?
I forgot to mention it, but that round
was charged up with spirit power.
Sweet dreams, Patrick.
"The Great Imperial Opera
House Presents Kaijin Bessou"
When Maria showed up all battered
and bruised, we were shocked.
We couldn't get back to the Imperial
Theater with the Army guarding it,
so we were at a
loss as to what to do.
Thanks for looking after her.
I appreciate it. Thank you.
We thought about telling the team,
but like they say, "To deceive your
enemies, first deceive your friends."
Everyone was pretty mad.
I can live with that. I'm just one of
Flower Division's unseen stage crew.
It's different from what you do,
but I try to help them in my own--
The intermission is about to end.
Let's watch it with the audience.
Sure.
It pleases me to see you, my Princess.
What troubles you?
I am gripped with fear.
Young Master, please remove your armor.
Dressed so, it is only
natural that she fears you.
You must not fear this!
It is because of
this that I am strong!
This was what allowed me to save
the Lady in Waiting from the sharks.
Alas, I have come
to a land filled with terror...
ls there such a thing
as a nation without enemies?
Foes abound in every quarter.
I need only defeat them!
I will be victorious!
Clad in this armor, I will protect you...
...from my enemies and the world!
What is the source
of your mighty strength?
♪ Everyone aspires to be strong. ♪
v Why is this? ♪
♪ Why, l wonder? ♪
♪ All those who gaze into the future
understand the meaning of strength. ♪
♪ Great strength changes the world! ♪
♪ Great strength protects the people! ♪
♪ I am weak. ♪
-- ♪ I am afraid of the strength...♪
--♪ I will protect you with great strength! ♪
--♪ ...that can destroy all. ♪
-♪ I will protect you from all my enemies! ♪
♪ Powerful nations! ♪
♪ Fragile dreams! ♪
♪ The strength of steel! ♪
♪ A heart of kindness! ♪
--♪ Oh, how I wish to be... ♪
--♪ ...gentle. ♪
--♪ ...powerful ♪
--♪ If only it were so! ♪
♪ Great strength learns from kindness... ♪
♪ ...to realize that strength never used
is the most powerful strength of all! ♪
♪ Love and hate, strength
and dreams, all turn into tears! ♪
♪ All flows away and is lost. ♪
♪ All flows away into the oceans. ♪
It is because I love you so...
...that I must slay you.
Why must you?
Need I a reason?
You are mine to do with as I please.
As king, should I not do as I please?
That's not her line!
Could she be under someone's control?
You are powerless before me.
I hold your life in my hands.
Such pleasure... Such pleasure
I take in knowing this.
To think I would be treated
so by one who claims to love me...
Could it be that you are under the spell...
...of the Demon King
who dwells above on land?
This is bad! This is really bad!
Get that lift down here!
Know this. My heart
is dominated by no one.
Know this. What rules my heart...
...is deep, deep...
...hatred.
A heart of hate?
How can this be?
You, who possess all?
I held power over all things.
Alas, people knew not what my
heart held, and so they abandoned me.
As will you, you who blossoms so!
But l... I was born a king!
Because I had everything...
...no one could understand my
torment at having lost everything!
I tried to be nobler than all others.
More powerful than all others.
Even after selling my soul to the demons of
the land, I attempted to protect my dignity.
--Is Lachette...?
--No, not one so noble as you!
lam now mired in mud, warped
hideously down to my very heart!
--And so my heart is now filled with spite!
--Believe in them.
Wait, I beg you!
If only for a brief moment,
we shared a common dream!
What of it?
Shared dreams join
together and become the future!
I say again, what of it?
We laughed together,
fought together, and dreamed together.
We have shared
this place with one another.
'An. 'an.
I love you dearly!
My Prince, will slaying your defenseless
wife lift the burden from your heart?
Let me bear the brunt of your rage.
Companions, companions, companions...
Ah, I feel my
heart turning cold as ice!
This world is rife with enemies!
You have already shared your heart
among us, for you are with us here.
If you say you desire my life,
I will gladly give it.
I commend your resolve.
Die, then, at my hand.
To demonstrate my power, I conspired
with the Demon King of the lands above...
...and attempted to
bring chaos to the world!
I have no place to call home.
Let us go to our deaths.
First you, and then I will follow!
Cast your hatred upon me, Princess!
I bear you no hatred.
Hatred gives rise to further hatred.
I forgive all you have done.
I forgive you.
I will not be deceived!
This is nothing but a story!
I shall bring down the curtain!
I shall bring all stories to an end!
Will it be so?
Will lowering the curtain on this
story bring all stories to an end?
As long as people live...
...the stories will never end.
Enough of this!
I shall slay this story
by my own hand!
'An. 'an.
I cannot bring myself to kill my love,
my dreams, or my friends.
This blood I shed is yours.
The blood of hatred has flowed to
the sea, and now a new story is born.
Let this moment continue a while longer.
In being able to wish so,
I have found happiness.
There are as many tales bursting forth
in this realm as there are people in it.
Flowers appear before us.
In this time and in this place,
countless flowers of dreams blossom!
They bloom with all their might!
"The End"