Misr Co. for Acting and Cinema
Misr Studios present:
Naguib El Rihany in:
Salama is Fine
Screenplay and dialogue by:
Badee Khairy, Naguib El Rihany
Based on a story by:
Misr Studios
Directed by:
Niazy Mustafa
Khalil and Naasan Hindawy
Ok.. sure.. it will be
delivered right away
Hello Aziz, send Nefertiti
House's order right now
The mail, sir
Where are my glasses?
Where are they?
Get Salama to come look for
my glasses quickly
I brought you a wonderful
collection Mr. Khalil
The factory wants to produce
unequaled stuff this time
I even want to take advantage of
prince of Bloudestan's visit
to promote our factory's goods
in his country
Go see where Salama is
1835.37
...96
Slow down! That's no floor
you're wiping
- I like to work perfectly
- No, don't
Here! Missed by 200 numbers
- Take one
- I'm broke, there you go
Good Lord! 5 'ladies'!
Just one is driving me crazy
- Looking good
- No, take these
We're so late, what's the
time now?
- Now it's...
- Nobody asked you
- What's the time please?
- The watch broke down
How rude!
- We need the customs stamp
- It's over there. Hello
I can see you're busy, sir.
I'll come back tomorrow
Hello.. what? How much is
a pound?!
Here we sell by meters.
Whom do you want?
The meat restaurant?
No, it's a wrong number
- The cupboard is locked
- Locked? The key.. Get Salama!
Where is Salama?
The manager is
asking for you
Chocolate
Why are you crying, dear?
Do you want chocolate?
You want a candy? Take it
I told you not to take dirty
things from anyone
Salama...
- Hello.. Welcome..
- Thanks sir.. what for?
I told you many times not to
move from here
You are an office man, that's
your job here. Understood?
Yes sir, an office man..
I didn't say I was a partner
Where are my glasses?
Where did you take them?
They're right here, sir.
Where would they go?
My glasses!
Don't be angry, sir. I didn't
sell them
Go get the customs stamp,
tardy oaf
What are you rambling about?
I'm saying please be patient
- I need half day off, sir
- Why is that?
- My aunt is dead
- 2 days ago somebody died
Yes, it was my cousin, sir
You took half day off last Friday
because someone died
She was my cousin's daughter
How many aunts and cousins
do you have?
Big family.. they die after
one another.. what do I do?
No more days off except when
you're dead. Got that?
Got it, sir, but what holiday
will this be?
Beat it! Go cash these cheques
Patience is driving me crazy
Mr. Rihan
I worked in this store
for 25 years
Since it was built. We started it:
me, the owner and the builders
Now he tells me I'm just
an office man
What should he tell you? Mr. manager?
You are an office man
An office man for 25 years,
Mr. Rihan?
The soldier who serves 25 years
in the army
is promoted to be a general
not just a sergeant
You are stubborn!
El Bashawat Alley
Charity please
Are you always begging? Shall I
call a doctor for your hand?
My wife is in labour, son
She's been in labour for 19 years
What kind of baby is that?
He'll be born with a moustache
Shame on you. Finish this story
Thank you.. but it's a bit erased
What's wrong, Um Yam“?
Watch it son!
That stupid boy put ink
in his sister's eye
Shame on you boy. You put ink
in your sister's eye?
She put chili in my ears
Shut up!
How are you Um Yanni?
How is Mr. Kostin?
Fine, thanks. How are you Mr. Salama?
How is your family?
They're fine, Um Yanni
Who is it?
- Hello Sattouta
- Poor thing carrying all that!
Hello, mother in law.. Wow.. soup
My guts are freezing
Where are the spoons?
What's that? A jug?
Did you cook the soup
in a barrel?
Our neighbour Um Ayousha
borrowed them
Doesn't she have anything?
She borrows a seive,
a knife and a broom. Why doesn't
she borrow your mother?
Shame on you
What's happening up there?
What is it?
Stop hammering
I said I'm sorry. If you don't
like it, go to hell
I'll show you, I'll ruin your day
Calm down, Salama
Hey you messy, foolish man!
Shut up you insolent, ill-bred,
good-for-nothing office man
You garbage can.. teaching scumbag
If you're man enough, come up here
If you only come down here
- I'll break your neck
- I'll pull your teeth out
Coward! Let me go!
Hey you people.. everyday a fight?
I'll kill you both. I want to
have some sleep
If only this man didn't want
to sleep.. Sleep Mr. Kostin
You're lucky.. you slipped
away you idiot
If I throw stones at barking dogs,
stones will have a price
Hello, Helen.. how is my wife?
The doctor says it'll be
today? 0 Lord
Keep in touch. Go away now,
I can't think
We have to finish our issue.
I'm leaving after tomorrow
Do me a favour Mr. Albert,
delay this issue for a while
I can't get hold of myself today
Why? You're changed since that
phone call from Alexandria
For 20 years my wife
couldn't get children
Today she's in labour
Imagine? For 20 years
I couldn't get children
I mean my wife couldn't
get children
OK, I understand" Congratulations
- Mr. Armanios
- Don't make me lose count
46+5 equals 51 pounds..
What do you want?
The manager wants the power bill
Last month is November
Go November, come November,
there is November
Power bill.. Power bill
71 pounds and 622 millieme
What else Salama?
Nothing. Give this to the manager
This is the week's revenue,
take it to the bank
There is 4000 pounds
and 118 pounds, equals
Take care, Salama
God help me
- Are you blind?
- You look drunk
Stop it, it's your fault
Is this you, stupid teacher?
I'll ruin your day
Is it you, bloody office man?
Crush him, driver
Crush me?! I'll crush your whole
family. Hey sergeant!
Stop it people, I'll take you
to the police station
Yes, to the police station.
I'll testify with you
He was blocking the street.
You are a liar
You have no conscience
Shut up please. What's your name?
Mr. Bayoumi Morgan
- Without Mr.
- Yes, without Mr.
- Shut up
- 0k
- Your profession
- Teacher
- Teacher in a kuttab
- Stop it
OK
You can go now
Tomorrow I'll watch you in jail
- Shut up.. you dog
- A dog should bite...
- Congratulations, sir
- Thank you
- May you see him a man
- Thank you. Same to you too
- Congratulations, sir
- Thank you
Today in honor of this great day,
we'll close this evening
All the employees have
half day off
Great. There's no way out now
It's not the time for labour,
Mrs. Khalil
Damn you, Bayoumi
What shall I do in this trouble?
Don't say.. really? Where?
Abd El Latif? What will you eat?
16 dishes” Cool.. what are they?
- Please, sir, I'm in a hurry
- Wait till I finish
- Strange
- Calf's legs? Delicious!
I love it..
And molokhia?
With chicken or rabbits? Wow!
Your turn, Mr. Salama
Please, sir
What? Vine leaves and beans?
Fresh or dried?
I'm sure coming tomorrow
It's tomorrow already
Wow! And cream soup too?
Come on, man, it's still a
long way to go
What about salads? Tehina
and pickles? Very good
I was coming, but something
bad delayed me
My wallet was stolen
and I didn't feel it
No, I'm not an idiot, but thieves
here are very clever
You scared me to death
OK, I'm coming. Goodbye, Zuzu
Is this Mr Khalil Hindawy's house?
It's me Salama
Please, get him for me.
What? He travelled?
Perfect! Now there's no way out
Your beard Mr. Salama
My wallet..
- My wallet, you theives
- What's wrong, sir?
I hang my jacket on the peg
and my wallet gets stolen?
I'll sue you
It's not right to say so.
Look for it again
Look for it? Am I lying?
Here are all my pockets
Salama! What's the matter?
Nothing. Am I hurt?
Are my clothes torn?
I'm alright. Bring me
something to eat
Don't we know you? You're changed.
What were you holding?
- A briefcase
- A briefcase?
Yes, a briefcase. You've never
seen one before?
It contains the manager's
clothes.
Where is the food?
Didn't you cook today?
- Cook in what?
- Nice joke
- There is a disaster
- Disaster?
We went out and when we came
we found the door broken
- The door is broken?
- All the copperware is stolen
- What are you looking for?
- Nothing
- What are you hiding here?
- The manager's clothes
Where are you going?
Wait till you eat
- Dirty staircase
- Insolent stairwell
Hello Mr. Salama
No hellos, where are you
Mr. Rihan?
Come tell me what to do
What happened?
I went to the bank and
found it closed
Will just one minute make a big
difference? Couldn't wait?
Where shall I put these now?
- Money?
- Lower your voice!
I go home to find the
copperware stolen
and the manager has travelled.
The street is full of bikes
- Listen, there's only one way
- Say it quickly
The Science of Palm Reading
The right hand, idiocy line
There is a VIP guest coming.
His Highness prince Kandahar
Prince Kandahar?
I heard this name when I was
a consul in Persia
Yes, his state in Bloudestan is
close to Persia
He's one of the richest
princes in the east
Huge fortune. He owns
an emerald
as big as an orange
What kind of orange, dad?
Will he stay in Egypt for long?
I don't know, my lady.
It's an unofficial visit
He recommended it remains
in secrecy
Too bad Your Excellency
will not attend it
- Well, I...
- We can delay our trip a week
But I'm not ready with
protocol clothes
Don't worry. I'll handle
this issue
Nahed. You have to come
to Cairo right away
- I'll be there tomorrow
- Not tomorrow, right now
Get the ermine coat with you
Don't forget anything,
my jewelry and dad's tuxedo
- And Fayek's too
- Wait
- I want to tell her something
- Ok.. here
It's me.. how are you Nahed?
Fine, thanks Mr. Fayek
- The cylinder is broken
- That means we can't move?
I have to replace it
I hope Your Highness is pleased
with this trip
Sure Mr. Gawdat, seeing Egypt
after all that time..
Memories of studying days
and the lovely tarbush that
I missed
I hope that depression and
boredom Your Highness felt
are gone now, especially after the
welcome from people on board
and the admiration
Your Highness noticed
Your Highness were the center
of all attention
Especially ladies who were competing
to get your attention
Because I'm a prince. Looks
have influence on ladies
If I had been a normal person,
no one would have cared for me
We can't help him.
It needs a lot of repair
- Come with us if you don't mind
- Thanks
We're going to Cairo and
we have enough room
- I'd rather wait
- Of course you're free
but this is a desert and
you may not find help
You'd better go with them
to send me help
I don't want to cause you trouble
On the contrary
It's a shame the car breaks
down in such a road
Yes, especially for a lady alone
- Shall I open the window?
- No, it'll let sand in, thanks
The weather is nice today
Yes, sunny day, cool weather
What is it?
A deer on the road, he asked..
- A deer is called Shikabi?
- Yes, in our language
- Your language?
- We're strangers
- But you speak Arabic well
- Yes, my colleague is Egyptian
I had my education
in Egypt too
- Are you Turkish?
- No, we're from Bloudestan
Bloudestan? Where's that?
The north pole?
No, between India and Afghanistan.
It's famous
Are you here for leisure?
Yes.. no, we're from prince
Kandahar's court
- Kandahar?
- Funny name, isn't it?
Why is she so late? Maybe
something happened to her
Maybe she came walking.
She is athletic
No, there's nobody
Excuse me, sir
- No one called me?
- No my lady
Strange, where did she go?
Your handkerchief my lady
- Please Mr.
- What do you want?
If somebody wants to use the
deposit box and get a room
Please Mr..
- Excuse me
- What is it?
- What do I do to sleep here?
- Get a room
- How much does it cost?
- 150 pt.. 2 pounds
- Per month?
- Month! Per night
Is there a room on the roof
or beside the stairs..
In the basement, something poor
- Poor? For whom?
- For me
For you? You will sleep in it?
Yes. What's so strange
about that?
- Go away..
- What? I don't want charity
- You are rude
- No, but be nice, it's a hotel
A client asks. You should
not insult him
What is that noise?
Get out, please
Why get out? I'm not in
your own house
- You are rude. Out
- Don't push me
Is this Nefertiti Palace hotel?
- I think so
- I live here
Please come in
Stupid barbarians
Chaotic hotel. Where's the manager?
Get lost!
Where's the prince?
- The prince is here
- Here?
Yes, outside, dressed in black
The prince? I think he
arrived before us
Great fuss about nothing..
useless employees
If it wasn't for what I have..
Where is the manager?
Welcome Your Highness
- This is prince Kandahar?
- Prince who?
Oh yes, prince Kandahar
Forgive us if the reception
isn't perfect
Reception good for nothing
and this idiot manager..
- It's me Your Highness
- Excuse me
It's strange you recognised him.
This is prince Kandahar
0k Mr. manager. A client comes here
and you insult him that way?
When a client comes to us for
1/2 meter, we give him lemonade
And you.. shame on you
Forgive us. We didn't know
your arrival time
I myself didn't know when
I was coming
I don't want any music..
just some respect
as a client entering a hotel
not someone asking for charity
Come in, please
What's all that army behind me?
All that for one client?
Strict orders..
This is a temporary prince
The special suite
Is it small this special suite?
I want something cheap
- Don't say that, Your Highness
- One must talk frankly
Don't bite more than you
can chew, right?
Yes, right this way please
This is luxurious!
- Reception hall
- Reception hall?
Where is the sleeping hall?
Strange
I can't afford all that
There's no problem,
please come in
Wow
- What is this?
- The bed
I'm afraid to sleep on it
His Highness likes the system of
your hotel and he thanks you
And who are you?
First secretary.. Second secretary
Your suite is that way.
Would you like to see it?
No thanks, don't bother
What now Your Highness?
Let's have some fun. Plus
I have something in mind
How much is this room?
It must be 2 pounds
We didn't discuss money yet
- Well, this issue is...
- Just to know, to sleep freely
- How much do you want to pay?
- Frankly speaking"
I can afford 20 piastres
You got a deal
- What? With 20 piastres?
- Yes
- All that with 20 piastres?
How cheap! With a reception,
first bathroom, second bathroom
I'll visit you frequently,
to change scenery
What do you do in this hotel?
First secretary
- Second secretary
- I just don't understand it
First and second bathrooms..
first and second secretaries
- System
- System or not, I'll pay 20 pt
OK
Mr. first and second secretaries
Look, I'm not here to sleep
or to shower
but I have something valuable.
I heard you have a safe
Yes we do
And do you both think
it is safe?
- Of course it is
- No offense, just asking
You give a receipt for
what you take?
- Sure
- Great, count these
- The car broke down
- Don't answer back
I was alone in the desert but
the prince's secretary saved me
- Prince who?
- Prince Kandahar
What does Kandahar mean, dad?
He didn't say when the prince
will arrive?
He already arrived,
I just saw him
- How does he look like?
- In my point of view-
his secretary is 30 times
much better
I'm better than him.
Right, Nahed?
I received from Mr. Salama Abd
El Sabour.. your profession?
Employee in Khalil Hindawy's Shop
What kind of employee?
Manager? Clerk?
- No, organiser
- Organiser?
Yes, I organise desks, chairs,
and papers
- A servant?
- No, an office man
- Office man?
- The manager's first office man
An office man and you have
4118 pounds?
That's the disaster,
they're my responsibility
Unfortunately, the bank closed
the manager's wife was in labour
He went to her in Alexandria,
our copperware was robbed
- What?
- What is it?
Kandahar? Who is that?
- His Highness the prince
- His Highness who?
- Who? I want a hotel receipt
A hotel receipt or one from
His Highness?
I'm not buying that talk
- Just listen...
- Listen to what, you burglars
If you don't give me my briefcase
now, I'll kill you
- Shame on you
- Shut up thief! My briefcase
You, let him go. Give him his
briefcase
Take it
Your Highness! You wanted
to steal it?
I would let you sleep in a hospital..
Your Highness..
Splendid
I see you don't care; royal bed
and 2 bathrooms.. 20 pt.
Only to steal my briefcase,
but you didn't fool me
- It's over now
- Who is this in your court?
The secretary for trick department?
- Splendid
- Let's forget it Your Highness
- Listen Mr. Salman
- Mr. Salama if you don't mind
What do you think of
a 500 pound reward
and living in luxury for
a couple of days?
You want me to join your gang
and steal together?
- See these?
- What ? Today's revenue?
Aren't those enough?
Must you steal my briefcase?
Look at this currency
You must have robbed
some tourists
Just look well
What's that?
You know who I am now or should
I get you another evidence?
Shame on me!
It's alright Mr. Abd El Salam
Salama Your Highness.. Salama
- Stand up
- I can't, sir
Good grief. I said too much..
my big mouth
- Get up Mr. Selim
- Salama, sir. I'm so embarrassed
My manners are never like
that, but...
I have a strange idea Mr. Salama
What sir? To take my briefcase?
Go ahead
No, listen. Would you like to be
a prince for sometime?
I'm an office man, Your Highness,
just an office man
Do you insist on that Your Highness?
I want to prove that money
and appearences are
everything in life
Call the hair stylist
It looks like coincidences
are chasing us, miss
This is the second time we
meet accidentally
I'm afraid you don't like
those nice surprises
No sir, on the contrary
I think your family was
worried about you
I envy myself for this chance
And I have a strange wish that
accidents like this repeat
On one condition, that I save you
You are so sweet
- Are you still here?
- I was just going, madam
I won't wait for you till you
finish talking with passers by
I'm sorry, miss. I didn't want
to cause you trouble
No, sir. It's alright
His Highness cares to
support science
I'll put up your petition to His
royal Highness and I hope...
So we may expect the honour of
his visit to school tomorrow?
- God willing
- Long live the prince
Kind and generous by nature..
Blessed and majestic his stature
Thanks
- Handsome...
- Thanks
Thank you.. I'm flattered
Perfect! Now you got the rest
of the instructions?
Yes, Your Highness,
won't you be with me?
- Right beside you, don't worry
- 0k
Take your position
Would Your Highness condescend
to meet the visitors?
What is it?
Would Your Highness condescend
to meet the visitors?
I'll condescend, why not?
- Bravo! That's perfect
- The shoe is tight
- What's the matter?
- My foot
- Smile while talking
- The shoe's tight, my foot hurts
- Get down
- Alright
They're just taking photos of you,
smile and get down
Say something
I miss you all
On behalf of His Highness,
I thank you for welcoming him
and I'm honored to give you
his high appreciation
Allow me to present captain
Blukovsky
the famous pilot
Hello
Is he a pilot?
Yes, he broke a record in altitude
Strange! Air carries much weight
Gobran pasha Elzahlawy,
Your Highness
Hello, Gobran pasha
I pray to God to keep your
grace, prosperity,
your health and your
shining beauty
Thanks a lot
Gobran pasha is a millionaire
Hello, how are you Gobran pasha?
I miss you so
What do Your Highness think of
the project I presented?
Gobran pasha presented a project
to monopolize the gas resources
That's good. Splendid
But did you take
precautions?
- For what Your Highness?
- Lanterns or candles
- Candles??
- Yes. Candles
When you monopolize all gas
resources, how will lamps light?
His Highness will handle this
issue, Gobran pasha
- Long live His Highness
- May God forgive us
Rostom pasha is one of the old
swordsmen, Your Highness
I saw your late father
prince Karim El-Din Shah
God rest his soul
I was a consul in Persia
Where persian carpets are made
I remember Your Highness was
only 7 years old
I was young and I grew up,
Rostom pasha
I remember an incident that
the newspapers mentioned
Your Highness is fond of hunting
since childhood
Yes, I used to like that thing
The horse bolted and Your Highness
fell on a rock
and the result was some wounds
in your foot
Yes, and they still hurt till now
May I dare to ask Your Highness
to attend a party
we will hold tonight in honour
of your visit?
With pleasure, why not?
Miss Maria Lukovitch the
famous Russian explorer
Lady Nahed
His Highness would appreciate
your attending tonight's party
Miss Nahed is my maid,
Your Highness
No problem, we all must gather
I don't deserve this honour,
Your Highness
It's alright, you can come.
I love company
That's strange
Since when do servants sit side
by side with their masters?
I can feel some hidden things
I don't like
Tell us, what's between you
and that silly secretary?
I can see everything,
I'm not an idiot
Smiles & impolite gestures
I did nothing to deserve
this, madam
They found me alone in the desert
and did me a favour
No, I feel I'll do something bad
I'm afraid I might lose my temper
and strangle him
Nahed, if you smile at this man
again, I'll kill him
I'll strangle him, slice him
and dice him
Miss Nahed, you know her?
The desert girl? Yes
Your Highness
That's her, I want you to
treat her perfectly
Yes I see, like flirting,
a wink, a smile
- No, no
- What then?
I mean talk gently,
show sympathy
and high appreciation,
you get that?
Yes, high appreciation. Damn you
and your bad idea Rihan
Don't you have a mind?
I thought I did, now I'm
not sure about that
I'm in the fabric business, then
you take me to gas resources..
Listen, you are not supposed
to talk
That's better but they start
talking to me
Answer in a simple way
In tonight's party,
I'll give you signs
If you're talking well,
I'll cough once
If I cough twice like that-
it means you're rambling,
so you correct your words
That's good, I like that
Watch it! Be careful
with my foot
Do you know how to read?
Be sure about that, Arabic
or your language?
Arabic, read this aloud
Future young men, students...
This is the speech you'll
read in a school visit
This one in an asylum visit
Tomorrow we'll visit an asylum
for the homeless
and in tonight's party, you'll
read this if you have to
Don't forget our deal
Did he come, Sattouta?
No mom, I'm so worried
about him
He's never that late
it's 9 o'clock
Maybe at work, in the shop,
maybe he's in the café..
His friends asked him to stay and
the time passed Um Sattouta
Dark thoughts are haunting me
Um Yanni
He was nervous and confused
when he left
He didn't even have his lunch
Sayeda Zeinab, please bring
him back
Your blessings Hussein
Oh God! May it all end well
I wonder what you're doing
now, Salama
Nahed, you were travelling
from Alexandria to Cairo
and my heart was travelling
from Cairo to Alexandria
See I..
How are you, Nahed?
That's strange about dreams,
I once dreamt I rode a donkey
I mean a horse
No, a car
- I was walking
- Then what happened?
Then I woke up
What a sweet dream!
Splendid
- I understand
- Be a gentleman
- Desert girl
- Your Highness
You know the American apples whose
ounce's worth 9 piastres?
Yes, Your Highness
Your sweetness can spit on
its own
Thanks for your kindness,
Your Highness
Your royal Highness prince Kandahar
I find no words to
thank your condescension
Finally, I repeat my thanks
along with the honored guests
Read your reply
Wretched miserables
Great miserables
They gathered you in this orphanage
from the streets
fancy ones
Rescued you from hanging out
in cafés and shops
And villas and palaces,
it's written like that
They fed you after famine,
and saved you from begging
His Highness is touched by
your hospitality
His Highness agreed to join
the roulette party
in support of the
Eye Hospital Project
What a luck, Your Highness.
Congratulations, you are lucky
You didn't see it all yet,
I'll leave you all broke
To compensate your loss, this
would please His Highness
Oh Your Highness
Take them, it's not my money
The winnings OK, but not our money.
I don't care
What's that? Are we broke
or what?
- The rest of the money
- 118 pounds Your Highness
What? How much?
Your Highness played with 4000
here is 118 so it's 4118
Good grief! 4118 Excuse me, folks
When the marble stops, sir
What? My heart stopped
- His Highness is a bit tired
- Very tired. 4118!
What kind of person are you?
Are you made of stone?
It's my responsibility Mr. Gawdat
We had no Egyptian currency
so we used your sum
How come you suspect that...
Forgive me, sir. People should
help each other
When will you exchange
currency tomorrow?
This man's presence will cause
scandals, Your Highness
- Don't utter a word from now
- I won't, sir
Just answer with one word;
yes, no, how nice..
May God bless
OK, sir. Yes, no, how nice,
may God bless
When will you exchange
currency tomorrow?
Where are we going now?
Different visits. As I told you,
don't say except yes..
No, how nice, may God bless
Shouldn't Mr Gawdat go to the
bank to exchange currency?
Back to nagging?
No, sir, it's OK
Yes, no, how nice, may God bless
With these preparations
the brigade can extinguish about
10 to 12 fires daily
How nice! May God bless
We welcome the prince
As soon as the prince enters,
you all rise
On my signal, you start chanting,
you get that?
Yes, we do
- You Abdullah
- Yes, sir
- Your voice is weak
- How come, sir?
- Raise your voice a bit
- My voice is so clear
Her heart has beaten and
she loved me
Sit down
All rise! One, two
This saluting chant is written by
Mr. Bayoumi Morgan
It shows from the good words
and the lovely voices
Bravo Mr. Bayoumi Fengan
Morgan, sir. I can't find words..
It's not important, Thank you,
Mr. Bayoumi Betengan (eggplant)
Betengan.. Betengan
It's a math class, Your Highness
- Math? You teach math?
- Yes, Your Highness
How nice
Many people cannot do math,
Mr. Bayoumi. Go on
- Alright Your Highness
- Go on!
Alright, sir. A man
bought 20 metres
of silk, 31 milliemes each
Silk with 3 pt and 1 millieme?
Where is that?
Of what kind? The Japanese
costs 7 pt,
marcilia No.2 costs 16 pt,
colorful 70 cm wide costs 22 pt
- Mahalawy extra..
- It's just a hypothesis
Oh! I thought it was real,
it would be ruin to the owner
- His Highness is a good reader
- In various fields
And he paid 1/4 of the price and
the rest on 50 installments
- Who's that crazy owner?
- Your Highness..
That's crazy, he will be dead
before taking his money
It's him, I can't miss Salama
How come? It's a strange story
Any news about him?
No, Um Mahmoud, I'm going crazy
- You didn't look in hospitals?
- God forbid
Speak good omen
Streets are dangerous these days,
trams make accidents.
Oh my God, may it all end well
What a pity!
- Be patient
- Where is he staying?
- Nefertiti Hotel
- Let's go to him
Yes, let's go
Um Sattouta
- Yes, any news?
- We found him, let's go
This is the oldest person
in the asylum
- How nice
- He's here for 12 years
He was an employee
in a fabric shop
A salesman?
No, a servant
- You clean the shop?
- No, I serve water, get papers
- Office man not a servant
- He did something bad
Stole some fabric?
No, they sent me to withdraw
350 pounds from the bank
I went to deliver them but the
shop was closed as..
- The owner's wife's in labour
- No, the owner's wife's dead
- Then what?
- I left the sum with a good man
When I asked him about it,
he denied
Good, when will you
exchange currency?
No need to hurry, sir.
Your donation..
- Will you exchange currency?
- Then what?
- They took me to jail
- Splendid
- I went out and found my house ruined
- How nice!
- And my wife begging
- How wonderful!
- Your Highness
- When will you exchange currency?
- Relaxed now? Got your money?
- Yes, thank God
You don't get it, when I took
this sum from the shop to..
There's no need for insults
anymore
- No sir, no insults. When I..
- Shut up
If you go back to nagging,
I'll hurt you
No sir, there's no need for that
When I took this sum from
the shop.. Alright!
I have an appointment with His
Highness, will he arrive soon?
He won't be late, wait for him
Sit down auntie Um Sattouta,
he's coming soon
Dear Salama!
- Who are they?
- My family
- They are so low standard
- I told you so
Impossible, I'm sure it's him
How come? I'm not married to
an Italian man
He speaks so fluently
Even if he speaks Japanese,
it's him. I'll disclose him
The factory supplies fabrics for the
Afghan, Kuwaiti and Shatt armies
We hope to supply the Bloudestani
army needs too
- How much is that army?
- 12000, your memory's weak, sir
God help me, I've got so many
things to remember
What army uses this delicate
pink color?
- Those are ladies silk samples
- I see
- The gifts were delivered?
- Yes, Your Highness
A token of admiration for miss
Nahed's charm.. Kandahar
I present this souvenir with
my regards.. Kandahar
- Wonderful dad
- A real prince's gift
This is one great souvenir
Didn't he send anything
for me, dad?
I was sure that I..
Shouldn't we go thank him, dad?
Sure
I want His Highness's suite
please, miss
How come this is natural?
It's artificial
what do you think? Princes
never bought or sold?
You get me meat telling me
it's chicken?
May I have the permission
to meet His Highness?
Who are you?
Please come in
OK, His Highness will handle
this issue
Thanks, Your Highness
Oh! Pretty woman
- What are you doing?
- Relaxing a bit
- Put your clothes on
- What is it now?
- She's here to see you
- Who?
- Miss Nahed
- The desert girl again?
I don't know what's the idea
behind all that
We haven't had dinner yet. Should
a prince work while hungry?
As I told you, be gentle.
Promise her with money, love..
With everything, I'll pay no money
- Good evening Your Highness
- Hello! Good evening
Sit down, make yourself at home.
How are you?
I'm here to thank you for the
precious gift you bestowed on me
You've seen nothing yet.
I'll give you more, I don't care
I want to buy all jewelry
for the sake of your beauty
Your Highness
You're driving me crazy
- Please stop!
- I can't stop my dear, come on
Please stop! Don't make me
ill-treat you
- Don't be silly
- Give it to whom deserves it
Your opinion about me is
very wrong
Please allow me
to explain..
Enough please. I'm sorry about
one thing, my good intentions
I thought you were better people
- You play a very cheap game
- Madam I...
Shut up! What you dream of
is never yours
Next time, pick someone
your own standard
- Madam I..
- Go pack and leave, you're fired
A wonderful gift that I'll
cherish all my life
A great souvenir
that'll remind me when I see it
of the lovely hours I was lucky
to spend beside you
Miss Nahed!
They were really sweet hours
If it hadn't been for the briefcase,
it would have been perfect
- You lost something?
- I was about to but it's OK
While I wore this precious necklace,
I looked in the mirror
I was so happy that,
while daydreaming,
I opened my arms and kissed
the mirror
- I wish I were the mirror
- Really? You...
- Yes, so much
- Is it so?
It is so and so
- I have the mayor's permit
- As the hotel manager I can't..
I also have a warrant
Do you love me, Kandahar?
Do you love Gihan?
Who else shall I love?
Small fish?
Don't play with my feelings.
Please don't break my heart
I'm going crazy
I'll die if you leave me.
What brought me here?
- Your father
- And what brought you here?
The briefcase
It can't be true. It must be
a false report
Maybe, but I have a job
to finish
See how happiness makes you feel?
Yes, I can perfectly see
What is it, hotel man?
Sorry sir, a police request
- For whom?
- Someone called Salama
Who is Salama?
Call for Salama
I have a clear report,
and I must investigate
Go ahead. Rostom pasha,
call my secretariat for me please
There is no one, they all left
Left? They did it?
They didn't say anything
or leave anything?
- No
- How wondeful!
Before the circumstances I told
you about, I couldn't
appreciate the value of your
lovely nature
and discover a proud personality
I thought it never existed
I can't believe this,
it's just like movies
That's what's sweet about it, Nahed
Can I call you Nahed?
The bank was closed. I went home
to find the copperware..
- You are really an office man?
- Yes I am
You joker, you fool, you idiot!
Thank you Mr. smart mind
Thanks a lot
Come, Your Highness, honour
the jail with your visit
>From royal suite to jail.
But the briefcase is fine
Come here, where are you going,
thief? To steal something?
Shut up! I've enough money to
buy you and your whole hotel
You think I come from the street?
You think I'm broke?
Come take a look
Good grief! What a terrible day!
It's a disaster
When they left, didn't they
tell you...
- Take him to the station
- My money!
I can't get a grip of my mind.
I haven't slept for 48 hours
- Really?
- I'm so happy, how can I sleep?
Everybody said he looks
exactly like me
How handsome!
What did you name him?
- Mankaraa
- Mankaraa? Lovely
musical name
My wife doesn't like it,
she wants to call him Joseph
Mankaraa is better. May you see
him a man, Mr. Khalil
and a great shop owner
No, no. I don't want to teach him
to be a liar
A man from Alexandria sent me
some poetry
Lovely
Where are my glasses?
Get Salama
- Salama didn't come
- Why? Another one died?
And he didn't deliver the
bank's receipt
- The bank's receipt?
- I gave him 4118 LE. on Saturday
and never heard from him since then.
What's worse Mr. Khalil..
There..
Maybe the owner sent him somewhere.
Please go ask him
- This matter is..
- Have mercy
Please sir, she hasn't slept
for 2 days
They look exactly the same
Ask about him at home,
maybe he's sick
Are you heartless? Will you tell
him or I call to him?
Mr. Khalil.. sir
What's that noise? What is it?
Who are they?
- I'm Salama's wife, sir
- You're his wife? Where is he?
I'm here to ask about him,
he hasn't come home for 2 days
Hasn't come home for 2 days?
How? Come with me
Of course I didn't buy it.
As soon as he left,
I reported it to the police
The idiot pretends to be a prince
and comes to visit the school
He knows all types of silk.
I'm not an idiot
We never would've
doubted Salama..
I have no time, I must meet
Mr. Khalil
- He's upstairs
- I'll ruin your life Salama
Tell me what are
your charges, man?
I had a fight
Just 6 months, I took 5 years
He impersonated a prince?
Didn't he have any money
with him?
Just a briefcase with
fabric samples
He must have put them away
and prepared himself
- Did he steal anything?
- 4118 pounds
Wonderful! He'll spend 6 years
in prison
What a pity, Salama!
Bank Misr?
Mr. Salama? What happened?
He's a friend of mine,
I'll pick fabrics for him
- He didn't deliver anything
- I told you he was a sly fox
He's a poisonous snake,
curled to bite and hide
May a snake bite your heart
Salama!!
- Have a nice day sir!
- Have an awful day!
- It's a dreadful day, sir
- Is this your office man Salama?
- It's me, sir
- Shut up!
- Take him
- Where to?
One minute please.
May you undo the cuffs?
OK
Give me your hand,
may it be broken
Come here, Salama
Sit down. Don't be scared
- If you only understand, sir
- I want no scandals, sit and relax
Thank you, sir. May you
drop dead Mr. Rihan
Damn you, Your Highness of
Bloudestan
You want to be saved from
serving 10 years in prison?
I'm not interested in hard labour
- The money
- That's the problem
- Save yourself and deliver it
- How?
- How much did you waste?
- All of it
Take this thief to jail
- Your hand, criminal
- There you are
Save yourself and give back
the money
Yes, give it back, you swindler!
May I have a word, sir?
I have a way out
Great! Bring him here.
Sit down and relax. Talk
Yes?
- They are 4118 pounds, right?
- Yes
You can deduct them from
my monthly salary
Deduct 4118 pound from your
8 pound salary?
How many years must you live?
Some people may live to 120
or 150 years
Take him to jail, that thief
Is that the end of it?
You steal?
Shame on you, Sattouta.
It's just bad luck
I'll fry a chicken and wait for you
at the prison
Salama?
Help me, Your Highness.
You saw it all
- Yes, it's OK
- How? I'm going to jail
No, don't be afraid.
There officer
Yes, but I'm sorry.
Take him, sergeant
- How? You have a warrant
- Yes, but he has another charge
- Another charge?
- Yes, he stole 4118 pounds
4118 pounds? How come?
Didn't I give you that sum?
Please Your Highness,
I beg Your Highness
When you suggested that I put the
money in the hotel's safe box
and I told you to keep it
with me..
- Take him to the station
- I beg Your Highness
Move, prisoner
Please, officer, may I speak
with you about this issue?
In the presence of Mr. Khalil
- Is this his office?
- Come please
- You are Mr. Khalil Hindawy?
- Yes
I have something to say
about Salama
He is the victim of a trick and
I'll pay the money for him
- till he proves his innocence
Please come in
Congratulations. May God
bless your kid
Hello. Excuse me
I'm in a hurry, I'm leaving in
30 minutes. These are the samples
and I care to finish this
issue now
I have fabrics that aren't
in the market yet
What is that?
That's not my briefcase
Not your briefcase? Show me
- This is Salama's briefcase
- Salama's briefcase?
Your delicate mood couldn't bear
hammering above
They'll break your bones
in hard labour
May a rusty train break
your bones
Wait sergeant!
I'm sorry, Mr. Salama
Set him free, sergeant!
- You are a real gem, Salama. There
- Strange
I promised you 500 pounds.
Here you are Salama
And 200 pounds from me, Salama
- Who? Desert girl?
- My fiancée
- From now you are storage manager
- How strange!
What is it, Salama? Tell me
Either they lost their minds
or I lost mine, Sattouta
Now give me back my briefcase,
Your Highness
- Is it you? I'll ruin your day
- Let him go, Salama
- How? My money
- I took it, Salama
Congratulations, Your Highness
How nice, may God bless
Let's go
Congratulations my friend, my dear
neighbour. Give me a kiss
Go away, kiss a snake
Better than you I have never seen
Sweeter than you has never been
- It is so now? Strange.. listen
- Yes
If you are no friend in bad times
then you're no good in good times
- I can understand nothing
- Better not to, take these
Ok dear, it's none of my business.
It's good that Salama is fine
And fine is Salama!