Once upon a time...
My name is Yuki.
I was born amidst a riot.
That was the day
my destiny was decided.
Help, please help me!
Hey, try not to cause
a big commotion, eh?
What the hell? Freeze!
Hey... hey!
SAMURAI CHICKS
Hello.
That'll be 924 yen.
Here's your change of 76 yen.
Thank you very much.
Yuki?
Hey, it is Yuki.
I didn't know you were
out here in Tokyo.
You don't remember me, huh?
I'm Nakamura.
I used to live behind you...
How have you been doing?
- Man, you're all so grown up now.
- You've got the wrong person.
I was born on an island in the south.
It was once a great trading port...
...a kingdom of peace.
One year ago...
...I was still a normal student
at the Orion Dancers' Academy.
They specialized in
raising future stars.
Put your back into it.
All right, girls. Stop there for a bit.
My name is Abe and I am an
instructor
from the expert program.
Step forward when I call your name.
Yuki Nakata!
Yes.
Step forward.
Your normal program is done as of
today.
Due to your outstanding
performance...
...you've been chosen to be
one of the four selected.
We'll start the expert
program tomorrow.
Be prepared.
Yes, sir.
That is all.
Congratulations, Yuki!
Congratulations!
Thanks.
Ready...
- Let me join, too.
- Sure.
From this part, then.
Did practice start already?
Oh, but the instructor's not here yet.
I'm safe, right.
Phew, that was close.
Hey!
Saki!
You got picked, too!
Congrats!
Thanks!
You too, Mickey!
Honestly I wasn't too sure
for a while there.
We're the four chosen ones, huh.
So who's who?
Oh yeah...
You're such a spazz.
I'm Aki.
I'm Mickey and this bimbo here is
Saki.
What's your name?
Oh yes, I'm Yuki.
Come on, no formal talk. We're
gonna be hanging out from now on.
Nice to meet'ya.
- Pleased to meet you all.
- You're doing it again.
It's Miss Cocoe!
It's totally Miss Cocoe!
What are you doing here, Miss
Cocoe?
Are you sure these are the four?
That'll be the last smile you get.
You'll be in the expert
program starting today.
You will abandon
all emotion from now on.
K-ing-dom.
The Orion Dancers' Academy's
expert program...
...was a program to train spies.
Spies were developed so the
Kingdom could gain independence
from Japan.
I told you to abandon all emotion.
Instructor Abe...
...I will be greeting the principal
and returning to Tokyo.
We're counting on you.
Okay.
We shall begin your lessons.
Yes, sir.
That was the day...
...we threw everything away in order
to become the greatest spies ever.
In-
In-de-
In-de-pen-
In-de-pen-dence.
Encryption.
Weaponry.
Martial arts.
Camouflage.
These were some of the special
classes we had everyday.
Your dancing is...
...our propaganda!
- Tri-bal self-determination.
- To be like Cocoe.
That was what kept us going
through
the vigorous training.
They all pass...
Yuki...
Aki...
Saki...
Mickey.
The growth you four have shown...
...this past year is incredible.
You have shown the results
that Abe has expected.
Therefore, you will be debuting
earlier than the other students.
Go to Tokyo and help
Cocoe with her duties.
But don't let your guard down.
The real battlefield is
far more intense than this.
The duty you hold is an
important part of the plan, too...
...gain the Kingdom's
independence.
Ignorance is sin.
Take a good hard look at history.
That way, you will be
forced to remember...
...the bitter and hard
suffering of the past.
And we headed out to Tokyo.
Head-to-Roppongi-tunnel
Kintaro Migihara, head of national
security. 173cm tall, 66kg, blood
type B...
...an Aquarius.
He's the target of this mission.
Well?
Yes, it still feels
a little strange, but...
I'm not talking about your arm.
I'm talking about those damn
terrorists.
Yes, pardon me, sir.
Are you getting anywhere?
Yes, well, I have been in the hospital
the last 6 months, too, and...
I don't want any excuses.
I'm tired of them.
What did I pass that
anti-subversive activities act for?
I made it easier for you
to do your stuff.
Use that new law...
...the new citizen's log
or whatever it was...
...to find all of the supporters of the
Kingdom in Tokyo.
Yes, sir.
In the name of justice,
we can't let those terrorists...
...continue to do what they want.
Yes sir. We have already started
a plan to take care of that as well...
We've got to make that entire
area a specially appointed zone...
...expand the base's territory
and have the American army...
...keep a close watch over them.
Absolutely, sir.
Kuroiwa...
Take a look around. It's like
we're in Europe or the U.S.
Absolutely, sir.
We've gotta start
cleaning this area up, too.
Absolutely, sir.
Anything unclean is bad for society.
You!
National Security
Just you wait...
You freaks!
One deer down!
Mom!
Mom, listen!
I was accepted into the academy!
I got into the academy in first place!
Mom!
Mom?
When I was 12...
...part of an army plane
hit my mother...
...and killed her.
Be-hind you
Our mole inside the government
obtained this film.
Long live...
...the Kingdom!
They say Saki died without saying a
thing, no matter what they did to
her.
...and?
Did you come all the way
to tell us that?
Well...
...I will be returning to the Kingdom.
I smell something fishy going
around at the academy.
I was wondering if you all
would like to return with me.
- Who will take over our duties in
Tokyo?
- You need not worry about that.
Is this because we've failed?
No. You are all competent.
The president and Cocoe both
have acknowledged your abilities.
We are hoping you will take part
in developing the new generation.
We're still in the middle of a
mission.
Can you do it with just the 3 of you?
We can.
Not by force, but...
...I wanted to confirm your feelings.
I don't want to retire yet.
I can continue even if
I lose an arm or a leg.
You're right.
You will be the only ones
left to protect Cocoe.
Yes, sir.
And...
...hang onto this until I return.
'Use all instruments as weapons'.
Right?
Here's your change of 76 yen.
Thank you very much.
Hey, you!
Um...
...I'm part of a dance team.
There's an event we're going to be
a part of. You can come if you like.
You're a dancer too, right?
You should come.
...according to reports,
there have been no sign of fire.
It's believed to have been
caused by an accidental spark...
...igniting the gas
within the building.
The body identified as Orion
Dancers'
Academy president Shoukichi
Ohta...
...as well as a dozen other
instructors
and students have been found.
The police are still identifying them.
Please stand by.
Aki.
What are we gonna do?
We just wait for the next order.
There's no order coming.
That's an unusually wimpy
thing for you to say.
Maybe we should go back to the
Kingdom.
We can't leave Cocoe alone.
But...
We don't even know if Cocoe...
We're still in the middle of
a mission. Don't forget that.
Even if the academy is really gone...
...there's going to be a second,
and a third academy.
I don't want Saki's death
to go to waste.
...you're right. Sorry.
Sorry. I didn't know
what I was saying...
Careful!
Yuki!
Yuki, they're coming.
Hurry.
Hurry. Run.
Follow them.
They've run into the tunnel.
Consider them like wounded
wolf bitches... be careful.
Let's go, Yuki.
Yuki!
Yuki, can you get up?
Are you all right?
Mickey, take care of her.
Hurry, go!
Over there!
Mickey.
We should be okay out here.
Let's wait it out a while.
Please... go...
Just go...
No.
I don't want to leave
any more of my friends.
Saki... and Aki...
Don't worry.
I'll think of something.
Mom...
I'm gonna die, aren't I?
Hey Namba, it's closing time
already.
- Oh, yeah.
- Thanks guys.
Come on, they're closing. Let's go.
Thanks for the food.
Thanks. Hey, be careful, eh?
- Come again. Thanks!
- See ya.
Ms. Toyo?
What's wrong?
Is she hurt?
Oh man, I'll call an ambulance.
You don't want me to, eh...
Now I get why she tried to pretend
she was someone else that other
day.
When I sold the family farm to
the army base and used that money
to...
...make this restaurant out in
Tokyo...
I guess I forgot about those
dreams I had when I was younger.
No...
I bet I was trying to forget about it.
I had given up, thinking that
it was something I couldn't do.
The adults didn't do anything
about it... but these kids...
How about it, Ms. Toyo,
you want to join me?
Hmm.
Maybe she went to the bathroom.
You were hanging in there, eh, kid?
Ignorance is a sin!
Take a good hard look at history.
That's right. Ms. Toyo is already...
Here... some new bandages.
And...
...some coca cola?
You used to love these, Yuki.
Have a drink.
And...
This...
I'll be getting stuff ready downstairs
so holler if you need anything.
Cocoe's sudden retirement!
She goes into hiding without
a press conference!
Because of marriage or illness?
- Is she?
- Yes.
She's a tough one. A normal person
would have died of insanity by now.
They were pretty insane
to begin with, I guess.
...coming. I know it's coming...
Let me out!
Who the hell?
We'll never give up!
He was still alive?
Pretty tough.
But it's the end for all these guys.
Is Cocoe still alive?
I understand.
So that's where they're being held...
Hiya.
Hey, sorry about that.
We're unusually packed tonight.
Sorry, eh? Come again.
Here you go, your tomatoes.
And here's that special pork dish.
What are you doing?
Yuki! Run!
She's gone.
The back! Go around to the back!
Over there!
There she is!
In-
In-de-
In-de-pen-dence.
In-
In-de-
In-de-pen-dence.
Uh, everyone. The Head of National
Security, Mr. Migihara, has taken
time...
...from his busy schedule to watch
our work.
Please continue the
great work that you do.
Mr. Migihara, it's almost time.
They've caused us a lot of trouble...
...but they settle down once
they're locked up in cages.
Must be a trait of the Kingdom, too.
Absolutely, sir.
It's here.
They day of independence is near.
Hmph.
The mixing of people causes
the country to deteriorate.
We must eliminate them
once and for all.
Absolutely, sir.
What's happening?
I'm not sure. Maybe there's
not enough electricity.
What's going on?
An intruder has opened the holding
cells and has started a fire.
What's going on, Kuroiwa?
Yes, it seems that someone
has pulled a trick on us...
Kuroiwa! You said those bastards
from the academy were all killed!
Yes, sir.
Idiot! I'm firing you already!
Sir, we must get to safety first.
What is this? Is there a fire?
Yes, apparently someone has
started a fire.
Why didn't you say that
in the first place?
This way, sir!
Dirty creeps!
How dare you let this happen to
me?
You're going to pay for this
when we get back, Kuroiwa!
Sir, the exit is that way!
I think it's this way.
Absolutely, sir.
Let me go, you monster!
Let me go!
Let me go, monster!
Hey! Someone! ANYBODY?
Stop!
Monster! Let me go!
Go away!
Let me go!
Help me!
Yuki!
Instructor Abe.
Kill!
Yuki! Kill!
- Kill! Yuki!
- Please help me!
No!
Kill, Yuki!
Please save me!
I'm sorry. Help me!
Help me!
Good.
Let's go.
Over there!
Cocoe, I promise to follow you.
Wait for me in the Kingdom.
I was born amidst a riot.
That was the day
my destiny was decided.
I cannot die.
I will not die.
For the independence of the
Kingdom!
Aki...
Saki...
Mickey...
Instructor Abe...
Mom...
Uncle Nakamura...
Watch over me...
Yuki...
That was the last I saw of Yuki.
But I know that somewhere out
there...
...Yuki is alive,
watched over by everyone...
What do you say?
Want to join the academy too?
Yuki, me, and you all...
let us all fight for independence!
SAMURAI CHICKS