♪ The current swings ♪
♪ The water sings a river rhyme ♪
♪ For light is the burden of labor ♪
♪ When each bends his back ♪
♪ With his neighbor ♪
♪ So each for all ♪
♪ We stand or fall ♪
♪ And all for each until we reach ♪
♪ The journey's end ♪
♪ Sandi the strong, Sandi the wise ♪
♪ Righter of wrong, hater of lies ♪
♪ Laughed as he fought ♪
♪ Worked as he played ♪
♪ As he has taught, let it be made ♪
♪ Away you go, igde ♪
♪ And make it so, igde ♪
♪ Together all the paddles fall ♪
♪ In tune and time ♪
♪ The current swings ♪
♪ The water sings a river rhyme ♪
♪ For light is the burden of labor ♪
♪ When each bends his back ♪
♪ With his neighbor ♪
♪ So each for all ♪
♪ We stand or fall ♪
♪ And all for each
until we reach ♪
♪ The journey's end♪♪
Tibbets.
- Tibbets.
- Oh, yes, sir.
What's the matter?
You feeling homesick?
Oh, well. Never mind.
I felt exactly the same
during my first 10 days.
After your first 10 years,
you gradually begin to get used to it.
Is Hamilton not back yet?
He ought to have been here hours ago.
Do you think anything
could've happened to him, sir?
Something can always happen
in this part of the world.
- Shall I take out a company and go search for him?
- No, no, no. Don't get so excited.
And for heaven's sake, stop thinking
about that Victoria Cross of yours.
What you're in for is tramping
through swamps and jungles.
The only decoration you'll get
are mosquito bites.
- You better go and see about dinner.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, hello, "Hamil."
- Good evening, sir.
- Glad to see you back.
- Thanks very much.
- Come along. Come sit down.
- Thank you.
- Hot?
- Oh, rather.
- Whiskey and soda?
Oh, I'd love one.
Thanks very much.
- You were all the way to the Isisis.
- Yeah.
- Anything happen?
- Well, I found a couple of gin bottles
in Kulubu's village.
When I told him you'd sent me
after his firewater...
he said you've got ears
as long as an elephant...
eyes in the top of your head and
in your back, and where other men sit.
- I know.
- That you were his father and mother...
but he wouldn't tell me
where he got his gin from.
Oh, that's simple.
Our old friend Farini
up to his tricks again.
Oh, another thing. I picked up
a queer bird about a mile up the river.
He came in an Ochori canoe.
- But he was not an Ochori.
- Oh.
I, uh-I took him on board
and tried to question him.
But all he would say is he had a high
and important matter to report to you...
and to you only,
to the Lord Sandi.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello, Tibbets.
Tell me, Hamilton.
Was this man tall?
As a matter of fact, he's very tall.
Very tall. I see.
Abibu.
Take the tall man who came with
my lord Hamilton into my office.
Yes, my lord.
Sanders, your black children say
you've got all kinds of magic.
But you're not gonna tell me
out of the two million souls here...
you know the man
I picked up an hour ago.
I might. Come and have a look.
Right.
All right, Abibu.
- Well?
- Lord, I am of the people of the Ochoris.
For three days have I come down the river
with strong oarsmen in my fast boat...
to tell you some very high
and important matter.
- Who are you, man?
- I am Olaba, son of Zuburu.
- I sit in my father's place, and in my fast boat-
- Olaba, son of Zuburu?
Yes, lord.
- Is that not a lie, man?
- It is a lie, lord.
It is a lie, man.
Bosambo of Monrovia,
five months ago...
you made yourself
chief of the Ochoris.
Didn’t you know that no man can be chief
in the river territories without my permission?
- I knew, lord.
- Well?
But I also knew that you also knew
that I made myself chief of the Ochori.
You knew that I knew
because of my magic.
Lord, I knew that you knew
by your spies...
who are everywhere,
who are called the eyes of Your Lordship.
You thought I would like you so much that
I would confirm you as chief of the Ochoris.
Lord, before I came, the Ochoris
were a great worry to Your Lordship.
They were just sheep at the mercy
of all the peoples of the river.
But I have taught all these peoples
a lesson and the Ochori to obey your law.
You know that every six months
I call on the Ochoris?
Yes, lord, at the time of the taxes.
Yes, Bosambo, at the time of the taxes,
in a month's time.
And you thought it
advisable to come sooner.
No, lord. I came to tell you about
a very high and important matter.
- Is that not a lie, Bosambo?
- Lord Sandi...
I lie to anybody
if I think it is good for me.
But I will never lie to you.
That will be very wise, Bosambo.
And what is this high and important matter
that you came to report to me?
Warriors came from
the Old King's Country.
- King Mofolaba's warriors?
- Yes, lord. Under a captain of his guard.
They passed through the land of the Ochori
and went towards the country of the French.
And you were afraid of them?
Lord Sandi, you rule
two million people along the river...
but there is only one man
who will not run away...
when he sees the ostrich feathers
of the old king's warriors.
And you are that one man?
I am the one man, lord.
- Then why didn't you stop them?
- Lord, because I knew that would mean war.
And I also know that this,
Your Lordship does not want.
That you know very wisely, Bosambo.
Well, your Monrovian friends
seem very anxious to see you again.
Shall I send you back to Monrovia?
Lord, everything is with God.
- Are you a Mohammedan?
- Oh, no, Lord Sandi. I'm a Christian.
Why, I went to a mission school.
I know all about the blessed
"Marki," "Luki" and "Johni."
And that other John who lost his head
about a certain dancing girl.
Bosambo, if I try you out for six months
as chief of the Ochori...
will you serve my king faithfully?
Yes, Lord Sandi. Every time I've seen
the beautiful face of your great king...
- my heart has filled with joy.
- When have you seen his face?
Lord...
on little round pieces of silver.
- Tibbets.
- Yes, sir.
Have you got the chain
and medal of chieftainship?
Lord, it is here.
Old Zuburu's.
You wore this without permission.
Lord, I had to wear it
to keep the peace of your king.
Now, listen to me, Chief of the Ochoris.
You will report to me when
the old king's warriors come back.
Let them pass if they do not attack
your people. You can write?
- Yes, Lord Sandi.
- Good.
Now, in every village there is a pigeon house
with the pigeons of the government.
Here we have a pigeon house
with the pigeons of every nation.
- What are you grinning at?
- Lord, the Ochori pigeons here...
are so old and fat that
they cannot fly anymore.
I brought four strong Ochori pigeons
and gave them to your sergeant, Abibu.
That is good.
Now go back to your people, Chief.
The palaver is finished.
Lord Sandi, I am your servant.
I don't like this news about
the old king's warriors.
They passed through Ochori
territory three days ago.
They'll be in the Congo by now.
Look at that.
- You think this means serious trouble?
- Maybe.
- Half a company, Sanders, and two machine guns?
- Yes, starting at once, please.
Embark half company, Tibbets.
Jump to it.
You can't possibly get there
in time to stop the slavers.
I know I can't.
I'm sending a pigeon to the new
chief of the Ochoris to head them off.
What chance has he got
against Mofolaba's spears?
Well, if it comes to that,
we haven't got much chance either.
- Abibu.
- Yes, lord.
Send this message
by one of the new Ochori pigeons.
Yes, my lord.
The war drums.
♪ On, on, into battle ♪
♪ Make the war drums rattle ♪
♪ Mow them down like cattle ♪
♪ Onward, on, on ♪
♪ Into battle ♪
♪ Stamp them into the dust
Into the dust ♪
♪ Charge, cheer, shoot, spear onward ♪
♪ Smash, smite, slash, fight and slay ♪
♪ On, on, into battle ♪
♪ Make the war drums rattle ♪
♪ Mow them down like cattle ♪
♪ Onward, on, on, into battle ♪
♪ Stamp them into the dust ♪
♪ Into the dust ♪
♪ Charge, cheer, shoot, spear onward ♪
♪ Smash, smite, slash, fight and slay ♪
♪ On, on, into battle ♪
♪ Make the war drums rattle ♪
♪ Mow them down like cattle ♪
♪ Onward, on, on, into battle ♪
♪ Stamp them into the dust
Into the dust ♪
♪ Charge, cheer, shoot, spear onward ♪
♪ Smash, smite, slash, fight and slay ♪
Whose dog are you?
I stop you in the name of Lord Sandi...
who is not pleased
when slaves are taken.
Stop me?
I'm the captain of the great king.
Nobody dares to stop me.
Lord Sandi says,
"Keep men and women till I come."
You turn and march in front of me
until you reach my city.
Go.
- What's your name, girl?
- Lilongo.
Lilongo.
It's like the sound of little streams
running over the stone.
Lilongo.
- Where do you come from?
- You wouldn't know the place.
- I'm from the coast.
- I know all about the coast.
We will talk about that later.
Now I have very high and
important matters to deal with...
Lilongo.
- Achmed, lord.
- Fine, show him in.
Achmed.
Achmed, did you deliver
my message to King Mofolaba?
Yes, lord. I told him that you called him to
palaver on the field in front of the pass.
- What did he say?
- He was very angry.
- But he's afraid of you, so I still live.
- Well, I'm very glad of it.
You better get some rest.
Your servant, Lord Sandi.
Here they come, Lord Sandi.
Set them at ease.
King Mofolaba, I called you to palaver,
but I didn't call your warriors.
Lord Sandi, a dog of a little chief
chopped a captain of my guard.
Your captain heard my orders,
but he didn't obey them.
Lord Sandi, you promised
we should keep our custom.
It's an old custom
in our lands to buy women.
Yes, if the woman and the father consent.
But slavery I will not have,
King Mofolaba.
My fathers ruled these lands
for 300 years.
- I am the greatest king in these countries.
- My king is the greatest king on earth.
And if little kings and chiefs
disobey his orders...
I plow them into the ground.
What do you want, Sandi?
You will take your spears
back to your own country.
And for the blood of your captain...
I will send back your warriors
who are in my prison.
I will do as you want, my Sandi,
because I am your friend.
But I have nine war drums
over which I stretched the skin...
of little chiefs who offended me.
I know the skin that will be
stretched on the 10th.
If you touch one servant
of the government...
be it so little as a pigeon...
then believe me, King Mofolaba,
you won't be king any longer.
The palaver is finished.
I'd be delighted to break his neck.
The British taxpayer
wouldn't be delighted.
- Why, sir?
- It's cost them about a million pounds.
War is an expensive thing.
Now we've got these girls to worry about.
Commission waiting for them. You better
take 10 men and get them over the border.
Yes, sir.
- Well, what's the trouble?
- Sorry, sir, but I just can't manage these girls.
- Why?
- You should hear the things they say...
especially about Bosambo.
Here. Come along.
Come outside, girls.
Come on, all of you.
Come on. Outside.
Shh, shh.
Now then.
- Has anybody hurt you since you’ve been here?
- No, lord.
Don't you want to go back
to your fathers and your mothers?
- No, lord.
- Then what do you want?
To marry the chief.
- What? All 10 of you?
- Yes, lord.
- He's a great chief.
- He can build 10 huts.
He is great enough for 10 wives.
But don't you know that he has
five wives already in another village?
- No, lord.
- Well, they're old and fierce.
- Wouldn't they beat you?
- They would, lord.
- Wouldn't they make you carry wood and water?
- Yes, lord.
Yes, well, you go back to your fathers
and your mothers.
If you obey my lord Tibbets here,
no one will harm you.
Yes, lord.
- There ought to be 10.
- Where's the 10th girl?
She has gone to the chief's house
to look through the magic glass.
How do you know?
First day, I went to chief's house
and looked through the magic glass.
Second day, I went to the chief's
house and looked through the magic glass.
- The third day, I went-
- Now, that'll do.
All right. Carry on, Tibbets.
How dare you!
Get out of here!
- What is your name, girl?
- Lilongo, lord.
Well, Lilongo, you must go back
to your father and your mother.
The chief here has already
five wives in another village...
that are old and fierce.
Lord, I know he has no wives...
because he always wanted
other men's wives.
But now he's even ready to swear
an oath that if I marry him...
he won't have other wives.
But I won't listen to him
until those girls leave this city.
- Lilongo, they're just leaving.
- Don't you marry him, Lilongo.
- Lord, there is a saying in our country.
- What is it?
A lover has strong arms, but no brains.
Well, that is also true
of other countries.
But if I find a man with
the strongest arms and great brains...
- why shouldn't I marry him?
- Do you think you can hold him?
Oh, well.
I suppose I can't object.
Lilongo, if you marry me,
no other wife will ever come into my hut.
Well, I'll take care of that...
- but I am a Mohammedan.
- Well, so am I.
- What?
- They said you were a Christian.
I'm a Christian for Lord Sandi.
But for you,
I shall be of the true faith.
Well, you better make up your mind about it.
I've got other things to think about.
Well, Lilongo.
Here's that paper
you've been worrying about.
- Thank you, lord.
- That shows that you and Bosambo are married.
You understand, Bosambo?
One paper, one wife.
- Yes, Lord Sandi.
- Do you feel everything's all right now?
Lord, in my father's house
I couldn't have had such great honor.
Take your shield.
♪ Hark ♪
♪ There is a drum ♪
♪ Tap, tap ♪
♪ Tap in the night ♪
♪ When the enemy comes ♪
♪ Be ready to fight ♪
♪ On, on, into battle ♪
♪ Make the war drums rattle ♪
♪ Mow them down like cattle ♪
♪ Onward, on, on, into battle ♪
♪ Stamp them into the dust
Into the dust ♪
♪ Charge, cheer, shoot, spear onward ♪
♪ Smash, smite, slash, fight and slay ♪
♪ On, on, into battle ♪
♪ Make the war drums rattle ♪
♪ Mow them down like cattle ♪
♪ Onward, on, on, into battle ♪
♪ Stamp them into the dust
Into the dust ♪
♪ Charge, cheer, shoot, spear onward ♪
♪ Smash, smite, slash, fight and slay ♪
♪ On, on, into battle ♪
♪ Make the war drums rattle
Mow them down like cattle ♪
♪ Onward, on, on, into battle ♪
♪ Stamp them into the dust
Into the dust ♪
♪ Charge, cheer, shoot, spear onward ♪
♪ Smash, smite, slash ♪♪
So you're teaching him
the killing dance again.
One day the old king will swoop down on
this country and there will be a great killing.
I don't want my son
to kill or to be killed.
You have enough money from
the government to live anywhere.
The coast, somewhere out of danger.
I won't stay.
Lilongo, light of my life.
It shall be as you want.
I'll have to talk to Lord Sandi, of course.
Tell him that our son
can't go into their new school.
Why can't he?
The government's building
the school for chiefs' sons.
We live at the coast, I won't be a chief,
he won't be a chief's son.
Therefore, he can't go
in the new school.
You know I don't want
to fight the old king.
Let's get out of his way.
You know, one day the old king
will attack the English.
And they will eat him up.
Then they'll look for someone
to rule all these countries for them.
On that day, your son
might have been a great king.
Of course, we'll then be living
peacefully at the coast.
You know we shan't.
You're full of cunning,
and you do just as you like with me.
Well, there you are, Ferguson.
That's the whole show.
It's all very well, stepping
into your shoes, Sanders.
- You know how I feel about it, don't you?
- Yes. Rotten.
- Rotten.
- I know exactly how you feel.
When I first came here, I thought
I never would get the hang of it.
One does, somehow.
By working hard
and losing one's illusions.
Oh, I don't know. I never had
many illusions about human nature.
- And the work isn't entirely wasted.
- Oh, no, of course not.
Do you know that 10 years ago
when we went upstream...
we couldn't stay
on the deck of the ship?
When we got near the shore,
a shower of arrows poured on us.
All over the territory,
the same thing.
War, killing, torture.
No woman dared leave her village.
And no man could sleep
safely in his hut.
And yet, crossing the territory now
is just as safe as crossing London town.
Oh, much safer. No traffic.
- Got a match?
- Yeah, I do.
All the same, I'd watch
the Old King's Country if I were you.
- Are you expecting trouble from there?
- One can always expect trouble.
I think the best thing to do
would be to call him to palaver.
And then show as much force
as you can muster.
Surely, that's asking for trouble, isn't it?
Personally, I prefer to see
the other kings and chiefs first.
Well, it's your show from now on.
I'll call them together for you.
Kings and chiefs,
there is peace in the land.
And no man's hand
is raised against his brother.
Thus it has been for 50 moons.
And behold, you grow
rich and-and fat.
Yes, Lord Sandi.
Lord, it is true.
My people are so rich that even
the common man can afford three wives.
I've called you here today
because I go on a long journey...
over the great seas.
And there shall I stay for 12 moons.
Lord Sandi, it fills our hearts with sorrow
to see you go away from us.
- Yes, Lord Sandi.
- Thank you, Bosambo.
And in my place,
the Lord Ferguson shall stay here...
and give the law
to all the peoples of the river.
I want you to obey him...
as if you were his own children.
And that you keep the king's peace...
lest a great shame
come upon me before my king.
What do you say, Kulubu?
Lord, war is very terrible.
But if one madman comes against
five other men who are not mad...
behold, they all become mad together.
Those are words of wisdom, Kulubu.
- And you, Chalo?
- Lord, we all love one another now.
Because if we did not, Your Lordship
would punish us very cruelly.
That also is very wise, Chalo.
And now, my kings and chiefs...
the big ship is waiting.
I leave you with sorrow in my heart.
The palaver is finished.
Go in peace, Lord Sandi.
Well, good-bye, Bosambo.
You will be loved by Lord Ferguson
just as you've been loved by me.
Lord Sandi, you've been father
and mother to the peoples of the river.
Well, in a year's time, I shall come back.
And everything will be
just the same as it was before.
Remember me, Lord Sandi.
I'll remember you.
Always, Bosambo.
- By tomorrow, we'll be in the Old King's Country.
- Good.
I'll build a still that will produce enough
alcohol to make the whole of Africa drunk.
Do you realize why after five years...
the iron Mr. Sanders
just went on leave now?
- Why?
- He fell in love.
With Captain Hamilton's sister...
while she was down here
six months ago.
It would give me
considerable pleasure...
to teach his black children
a thing or two...
while he's cooing
and billing in London.
His black children have
become pretty civilized.
- I have a great magic to stop all that.
- What's that?
Sandi.
Sandi's dead.
There's no law anymore.
Again and again and again.
What is it now, Hamilton?
Oh, it's always the same.
♪♪"Sandi. Sandi.
Sandi is dead.
There's no law anymore."
Oh, it's maddening.
Any more messages from pigeons?
Can't expect any more
pigeons before morning, sir.
It's pitch dark now already.
- Halt! Who goes there?
- I want to see Lord Ferguson.
This way, Father.
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- It's Father O'Leary from the Akasavas.
- Good evening, Mr. Ferguson.
- Good evening, Father. What happened?
They've fired my church.
They've fired the Baptist church
at Isisi too.
Mr. and Mrs. Jackson
have fled to Mr. Lowe's camp.
They might attack them as well.
- Just like wild beasts.
- No, Mr. Ferguson, they are not.
- They might have killed you too.
- That is not why I came.
I have no fear for my own life.
I came to tell you that those two white men
are selling them gin and firearms.
You must be quick and strong now
like a father with his misguided children.
Like Mr. Sanders would.
Or else, much, much blood
will flow very soon.
Sanders's life's work destroyed in a week.
Hamilton,
you will stay here as my deputy.
I shall wire the governor,
telling him the situation.
Tibbets, you will embark a half a company
and come upstream with me.
You will disembark at the Isisi city.
I shall take 10 men...
and go on to the Old King's Country,
the seat of the trouble.
- Ferguson, you can't do that!
- Wouldn't Sanders have gone?
- Why, I don't know.
- I do. He would.
- Ferguson, listen to me.
- Captain Hamilton, you have your orders.
- Tibbets, parade your men.
- Yes, sir.
So sorry to interrupt your dance, Sanders.
This is very serious.
- Do you know a man named Farini?
- Oh, yes. He's a gunrunner.
Ten years ago,
I sent him down here in irons.
Five years ago, he crossed over my territory,
but he slipped over to the Portuguese.
Well, he's back again.
In the Old King's Country.
- Gin and firearms?
- Yes.
- Oh, that's bad.
The whole territory's aflame.
Father O'Leary, who knows something
about it, sums it up like this:
"Please send four battalions or Sanders."
Well, Sir John, I'm afraid in this case
it'll have to be the four battalions.
As you know, I'm on 12 months leave.
I'm going home to get married.
Anyway, I shall be too late.
- I'll let you have an airplane.
- I'm sorry, Sir John.
It wouldn't be fair to my fiancée.
- She's, uh, Hamilton's sister, isn't she?
- Yes, sir.
Well, the last report
of Hamilton was safe and sound.
- What about the rest?
- Well, Tibbets went to the Isisi.
But they're out of hand.
He's lost half a dozen men.
Ferguson went over the mountains.
- What? To the Old King's Country?
- Yes.
What happened to him?
There's no news.
Ferguson, you came with your soldiers
against me. You shall die!
You shall live one day
and then another day, Mofolaba...
and then Sandi will come in my place...
and he will kill you.
- Sandi's dead.
- You're afraid, Mofolaba, because you know him.
But he will come.
Sandi, the eater of kings.
- Sandi's dead!
- No, he's not.
I tell you. He will come. And wherever
you may hide, he will smell you out...
and throw your body to the fishes!
I, uh-
I'm getting out.
- What the hell do you mean?
- You heard what I said. I'm getting out.
You confounded fool!
If the old man sees us on the run,
he'll know we were lying.
We wouldn't have a chance in a million.
We killed Ferguson.
You cold-blooded swine.
White men, lord king calls you.
You pull yourself together.
This man lied in telling me...
that Sandi will come back.
Can Sandi come back?
He can't come back,
because he's dead.
Your voice is beautiful to me
when you say that.
But if a devil is in your heart
and you have spoken lies...
then, white man,
my skinning men shall know your voice.
- I tell you he's dead!
- Then I'll send down my fighting regiment...
to bring me back the skin of a little chief.
Ah, Bosambo.
What did you hear about
the death of my lord Ferguson?
Lord, he died like a brave man...
at the hands of King Mofolaba.
- He wasn't tortured.
- No, lord. Very quick death.
Oh, thank heaven for that.
Well, we must smash the old king's army
before he joins up with the Isisi and the Akasavas.
Then, believe me,
all chiefs will come to palaver.
Hello.
- What's that?
- My Ochori men, lord...
sending messages everywhere saying...
"Sandi is not dead.
The law is back on the river."
Sandi.
Sandi's not dead.
Bring the white man here.
Listen. What's that?
Well, I -I don't know.
- Sandi the Tiger, on the river.
- What do you say?
- It isn't true. Sandi is dead.
- Sandi.
Smashed the army of the great king.
Take him away!
Oh! Oh!
Get 'em off!
Sandi won't come here
till after the rain.
When he does come and he asks...
"Who chopped Ferguson?"
what will your answer be?
White men, Farini and Smith,
chopped Ferguson.
All people listen.
White men, Farini and Smith,
chopped Ferguson.
Who chopped Ferguson?
The white men, Farini and Smith,
chopped Ferguson.
It is easy to lie to the English.
They want peace.
If you say you want peace,
they will believe you.
I can make peace with the English.
But don't we lose our honor if we don't
finish with the chief of the Ochoris?
Lord, how can we catch him?
How would you catch a leopard?
You get the right bait,
he walks into your trap.
Makara.
Makara...
I am hot for the hide
of a certain leopard.
Go and get the bait...
that will bring the leopard
into my trap.
♪ So, sleep, little one ♪
♪ Till darkness ♪
♪ Is thine ♪
♪ Sleep till the sun ♪
♪ Rises up in the sky ♪
♪ My little black dove ♪
♪ Curl up in your nest of life ♪
♪ The moon is a charm ♪
♪ To keep you from harm ♪
♪ Asleep at my breast ♪
♪ The stars are aligned ♪
♪ To watch over you all night ♪
♪ The river of sleep ♪
♪ Flows gentle and deep ♪
♪ To rock you to rest ♪
♪ So, sleep, little one ♪
♪ Till darkness ♪
♪ Is thine ♪
♪ Sleep till the sun ♪
♪ Rises up in the sky ♪
♪ My little black dove ♪
♪ Curl up in your nest of love ♪
♪ And go to your rest ♪
♪ A sleep at my breast ♪
♪ My little black dove♪♪
Call your chiefs.
My lord Sandi holds palaver
with them on his ship.
All right.
Now, 10 days ago, when I left you...
your words were sweeter
than the honey of wild bees.
But... what is the truth? This:
I had hardly reached the house of the man
who is above me in the service of my king...
and I hear this: that the N'Gombi,
the Isisi and the Akasavas...
are dancing the blood dance.
Killing, murdering, stealing.
Do I hear right?
Answer me, Kulubu.
Lord, your ears as long as an elephant.
My young men heard
that Your Lordship was dead...
and their hearts were filled
with a great joy.
- Well, now they know that I'm alive.
- Yes, lord...
and their hearts are filled with sorrow.
You have brought
great shame upon me before my king...
and I will punish
with great punishment...
all those who break the law.
This I have done with the N'Gombi,
and this also I will do with the Isisi...
and with all who break
the peace of my king.
The palaver is finished.
Bosambo, you're a very brave man.
You have made the Ochoris
the bravest people in the river...
and helped me punish the others.
- You have been my friend.
- Thank you, Lord Sandi.
How's your wife?
Lord, she's a pleasant sight...
and a great cook.
- A miracle.
- And my son grows straight, like a palm tree.
And my little one, like this.
That's splendid.
- Lord Sandi, you too soon will marry.
- Yes, I hope so, Bosambo.
She also is a pleasant sight.
May she become a great cook
and bear you many tall sons.
Thank you, Bosambo.
In the spring,
I'll return with four battalions...
and punish King Mofolaba.
You can take your warriors home now.
Yes, Lord Sandi.
Lord "Tibbeti," may you also have
many wives and many children.
Oh, thank you, Bosambo.
Oh, dear.
Hello, sir?
- Fever coming on?
- Yes, I'm afraid so.
- I had a touch of it all day.
- You'd better get to bed.
Yes, I think I will.
If it gets very bad,
keep in midstream till I'm better.
- Then we'll go up and deal with the Isisi.
- Yes, sir.
♪ The current swings
The water sings ♪
♪ A river rhyme ♪
♪ For light is the burden ♪
♪ Of labor ♪
♪ When each bends his back with ♪
♪ His neighbor ♪
♪ So, each for all ♪
♪ We stand or fall ♪
♪ And all for each
Until we reach ♪
♪ The journey's end ♪
♪ Sandi the strong
Sandi the wise ♪
♪ Righter of wrong
Hater of lies ♪
♪ Laughed as he fought
Worked as he played ♪
♪ As he has taught
let it be made ♪
♪ Away you go, igde ♪
♪ And make it so, igde ♪
♪ Together all the paddles fall ♪
♪ In tune and time ♪
♪ The current swings ♪
♪ The water sings ♪
♪ A river rhyme ♪
♪ For light is the burden ♪
♪ Of labor ♪
♪ When each bends his back with ♪
♪ His neighbor ♪
♪ So, each for all ♪
♪ We stand or fall ♪
♪ And all for each
Until we reach ♪
♪ The journey's end ♪
Lord Tibbets,
shall I stop the engine at the Isisi?
Man, you stop your engine
when you get your order.
The order is we stay in midstream
as long as my lord Sandi is ill with malaria.
- But, lord-
- You go now...
and if you ask me again,
my arm will go mad!
Next case, please.
Ears as-elephant.
Ears as long as-elephant.
No.
Oh, get out, Tibbets!
If I went-want anything, I'll knock.
Topolaka...
is it no longer the custom for the women
of the Ochori to greet their returning warriors?
Lilongo.
Lilongo!
Where is she?
Last night, the old king's soldiers...
struck down our guards and-
And?
Atua. Atua!
Take the children down the river
to my lord Sandi...
and give him this letter.
And you, Lord Chief?
I go over the mountain.
Lord Chief, not even an army
could get into the Old King's Country.
That's why I go alone.
Good-bye, my son.
I'm sending you to Lord Sandi...
who will teach you the things
I was going to teach you.
And who will make you
a great, great chief.
Good-bye, my son.
Look, Lord Tibbets.
Stop the boat.
You go below
and bring them alongside.
- Isn't that Bosambo's boy?
- Yes, lord.
- Where are you taking him?
- To Lord Sandi, at the house of government.
But what's happened to Bosambo?
Agia!
Agia, what's happening?
Why have we stopped?
- I don't know.
- Uh, send my lord Tibbets here.
Hello, Tibbets. What's the trouble?
Why have we stopped?
Topolaka's here,
with Bosambo's children.
- His children?
- Yes, sir.
Bosambo's gone into
the Old King's Country, alone.
- He's gone where?
- The old king's kidnapped Lilongo.
He's gone to try and get her back.
He sent you this note.
Listen to this.
"Even you could not
go over the mountain before the spring.
"Therefore I am going alone.
"I am sending my children,
that they may live in the shadow of your house...
"and be brought up with the money I have
from the government...
as the government's children."
Get my coat, will you?
Agia!
Agia, send Ayoko to my cabin, will you?
- What are you going to do, sir?
- I don't know.
Ayoko, we are going up to
the Old King's Country.
I want you to turn the boat round...
and go upriver
with all the steam you can get.
But, lord, no ship ever got through
as far as the Old King's Country.
Well, this'll be the first.
Go on, get a move on.
A little chief brought shame upon me.
I've waited very long.
Soon he will die.
But before he dies,
he will see you die!
Then everybody will know
what it means to bring shame upon me!
Lord, you haven't got him.
He's too great for you.
And too cunning.
Listen!
He's coming!
Into my trap!
Lord, I come in peace.
O cunning one...
where is your cunning now?
Didn't I bring you here without a spear
behind you, when I took your woman?
Lord, that is true.
This woman is life to me.
And I would rather die at her side
than live with my people.
But if you will allow her to go,
she will send you 2,000 gold pieces.
Not your gold I want.
It's your skin, for my drum!
You put shame upon me.
You shall die a slow death.
But before you die,
you shall see your woman die!
Get him.
- What are we making?
- Five and a half, Lord Tibbets.
- Not enough. Put on some more wood.
- But the boiler will burst.
- I said put on some more wood!
- More wood, Falu.
- All things are with God.
- What's that?
I believe I said
all things are with God, Lord Tibbets.
Well, put on some more wood
and make sure of it.
Yes, lord.
Now.
King Mofolaba...
do you remember what I said to you
in the field in front of the pass?
No, Lord Sandi.
I don't remember.
I said that if you touched
a servant of the government...
be it so little as a pigeon,
you wouldn't be king any longer.
- I haven't hurt any of
the servants of the government.
- Who chopped Ferguson?
Who chopped Ferguson?
- Farini and Smith chopped Ferguson.
- That's a lie.
Give me an iron. Don't move.
If you make a sign to your guards,
you will die.
All people, listen!
- You know who I am.
- Sandi the Tiger.
- Sandi the eater of kings.
- I am Sandi who gives you the law!
Where are you councillors?
Who killed Ferguson?
- Answer me! Who killed Ferguson?
- King Mofolaba.
Here, come look
at King Mofolaba now.
He isn't king any longer.
And so will I punish anyone...
who dares to make even so much
as a movement against me.
You will call your people to palaver.
That was a close one.
- Bosambo.
- Yes, Lord Sandi.
You will send for your warriors...
and all the chiefs of the lower river.
Yes, lord.
Chiefs and people of the river,
in the name of my king...
I will give you a new king.
Not one who will
destroy his people with wars...
but I will give you a king
who will make you a rich and great nation.
A king who is wise and cunning...
who will keep the peace
and treat all men equally.
Bosambo.
Chiefs and people,
will you obey your king Bosambo?
Yes! Yes!
Well, Bosambo...
you are king of the river.
Your new people like you.
I hope when I come back in 12 moons
they will still like you.
Lord Sandi, I've learnt the secret
of government from Your Lordship.
- You have?
- It is this:
A king ought not to be feared,
but loved by his people.
Go now, my friend.
Keep the peace of my king.
Lord, I promise.
♪ Sandi the strong ♪
♪ Sandi the wise ♪
♪ Righter of wrong
Hater of lies ♪
♪ Laughed as he fought
Worked as he played ♪
♪ As he has taught
let it be made ♪
♪ Away you go, igde ♪
♪ And make it so, igde ♪
♪ Together all the paddles fall ♪
♪ In tune and time ♪
♪ For light is the burden ♪
♪ Of labor ♪
♪ When each bends his back with ♪
♪ His neighbor ♪
♪ So, each for all ♪
♪ We stand or fall ♪
♪ And all for each
until we reach ♪
♪ The journey's end ♪