Dear God.
Please help your servant.
I wish someone would help me
get my telescope.
If it's a woman,
I will make her my sister
for the rest of my life.
If it turns out to be a man,
I will make him my husband.
Here's your telescope, miss.
Lengser. You.
Yes, it's me.
Did you listen to what I was saying?
Yes, I did.
Sanghyang Rumuhun
has fulfilled your wish.
You're my soulmate.
Please accept this.
This is destiny.
Humans aren't supposed to refuse it.
Come on.
Welcome, Gusti Prabu.
Pardon me, Gusti Prabu.
I have prepared the coconuts.
The ones you love, Your Highness.
Well done, Lengser.
You know what I like, right?
Take off your hood.
Lift up your face.
Kanjeng Adipati.
Pardon me, Prabu. We just got news
that Dayang Sumbi is pregnant.
What? Dayang Sumbi is pregnant?
Dammit!
Sumbi, is this how you repay
your father's kindness?
Despicable. You have humiliated me
and shamed this kingdom.
Please forgive me, dearest father.
Sumbi, tell me who stained your chastity.
Tell me!
I have asked you many times.
Answer me!
Just tell us, my granddaughter.
Whatever social class the man is,
your father will act fairly
in this regard.
All right, then.
If you choose to keep silent,
don't regret my decision.
- Bikalpa!
- Yes, Gusti.
Come here.
Chop off her head!
Have mercy, Gusti.
Please have mercy, Gusti Prabu.
I'm the one who did
the despicable thing to her.
I have done you wrong.
Please have mercy on me, Gusti Prabu.
Are you telling the truth, Lengser?
Yes. I'm telling the truth, Gusti Prabu.
I can't believe it.
You're my loyal and most trusted adjutant,
but you dare to insult me.
Curse you!
Please forgive me, Gusti Prabu.
Please have mercy on me, Gusti.
Have mercy, Gusti.
Stop! Please stop it, Father!
It wasn't all his fault!
Bikalpa!
Take care of them.
Wait!
My son, Prabu Sungging Purbangkara,
don't do anything foolish.
Because after all, Sumbi is your daughter,
your own flesh and blood.
Even though her mother,
Dayang Wulan, passed away,
and you never established her
as the empress.
Remember this, Sungging.
The baby who will also die in her womb
is your innocent grandchild.
I truly uphold your wisdom, Mother,
but this disgrace is too much for me.
No, this reality is Hyang Rumuhun's will.
What should I do, then?
Marry them
and give your grandchild
a chance to be born.
Because of your request, Mother,
I will do it.
Listen, Lengser.
I will let you marry my daughter.
But I still can't accept
your dog-like behavior.
Have mercy on us, Father.
Please have mercy on us.
You have to leave this castle.
I don't want to see your face.
Mother!
Take a look, Mother! Come and take a look.
I brought you a rabbit this time.
Please take it, Mother.
Jaka Sona, my son.
I'm so proud. Every time
you come home, you bring me game.
But sometimes, I worry.
Worry? What worries you, Mother?
You're bold going into the forest
by yourself.
The forest has become my world.
It's your world too.
Why should I be afraid?
I have Tumang by my side.
Life in the jungle is fierce.
We could live a wonderful life
if only you still had a father.
A father?
You told me that Father has left Earth.
That's true, my son.
Your father died heroically
on the battlefield.
Poor Father.
It's the will of Sanghyang Rumuhun.
Let it go, Mother.
Mother.
Tumang always takes care of me.
To me, he's my best friend
and also a father.
Jaka.
Mother!
It's me, Jaka!
I'm here, Mother!
My goodness, Jaka! Get down from the tree.
Wait a second, Mother.
I will bring you lots of firewood.
Enough. That's enough, Jaka!
Yes, Mother! I'm coming down!
Mother, look at me! I will jump from here.
Look at me!
Mom! Here you go.
All living things,
including animals,
their birth in this world was solely
by the will of Sanghyang Rumuhun.
It's the same with our births.
Everything is his destiny.
So, in this life, we have to surrender?
Indeed, but we can't give up.
We have to endure this life
despite the bad luck we suffered.
What bad luck you got, poor Tumang.
What's wrong with Tumang, Mother?
I feel sorry for his fate.
Why do you feel sorry for him?
Even though Tumang is a dog,
he's more loyal than any human.
Hey. Are you crying, Mother?
What does a dog's loyalty mean, Mother?
I'm Jaka, Mother.
Jaka Sona, your son,
who will be loyal and love you forever.
That was so touching, Son.
I'm so proud of you, Son.
Jaka.
I'm craving a deer's heart.
- Do you want one, Mother?
- Yes.
I will look for one right now.
Tumang!
Let's find a deer for Mother.
I'm leaving now.
Don't be loud.
Tumang, there's a deer over there.
Try to bring it here.
Let's go.
Why are you coming back?
We've got to bring
the deer's heart for Mother. Come on.
Come on!
Are you lazy? Off you go! Let's go.
If you don't want to go,
I will shoot you with an arrow.
Go! Let's go!
Tumang!
Tumang?
Your mother wants a deer's heart, right?
Draw your knife before I die.
Hurry up.
Hurry up, Sona.
Do it.
Quick. Do it.
Mother!
- Mother.
- Hey, you did it, Jaka!
- What's the matter, Jaka?
I can't understand you.
Tell me. What's going on?
I brought you the heart...
of Tumang, Mother.
What?
Tumang's heart?
I accidentally shot Tumang, Mother.
- He died and transformed into...
- My goodness.
Please forgive me, Mother.
You killed Tumang, Jaka.
He's your own flesh and blood.
- Murderer!
- Forgive me!
Have mercy on me, Mother!
I really regret it, Mother!
Forgive me!
Ouch! I'm terribly sorry!
- Such an insolent child!
- Forgive me!
I didn't mean it, Mother.
Crazy kid!
Forgive me!
- I didn't mean it!
- Such an ungrateful child. Get lost!
- No, Mother!
- Go away from here! Get lost!
A terrible child! Get lost!
- Get lost!
- Please forgive me, Mother.
Get lost!
Jaka.
My goodness.
Jaka!
Jaka...
Hey, human boy.
You have apparently been sent by the gods
to live with us.
What's your name?
Jaka Sona.
I've been kicked out of my house.
I got lost.
Let me take shelter in this place.
You may live here.
Live here with Guriang.
Guriang?
Indeed. Guriang means the force of nature
that you will receive
during your stay here.
We will make you into one mighty human.
Is that true?
- Indeed.
- I'm willing, then.
Thank you.
My son,
before I go,
I really want to see and hold
my great-grandchild.
The child of Sumbi.
Twelve years is such a long time
to redeem her oversight.
Please call them back to this castle.
Forgive them.
Mother, that ship has sailed.
Don't keep thinking about that.
Sumbi has done a really terrible thing.
And what about your behavior?
When will you change
your habit of philandering?
Do you still insist
on not finding an empress?
You're my everything, Mother.
My love for you
can't be shared with other women.
My son,
a boy's love for his mother
is different from his love for his wife.
Haven't you thought about
who will replace you
to lead this kingdom in the future?
If you haven't, find Sumbi,
and train your grandson
to become the crown prince.
Please forgive me.
Allow me to not answer that.
Just this once.
Sungging.
I'm worried that karma will punish you.
Jaka Sona, the human son.
Nine years have passed.
Your existence as a hermit is finished.
You have become superior.
In your body reside the guriangs.
Your body is the vessel,
or "Sangkur" Guriang.
You have the right
to bear the name "Sangkuriang."
Your name is now Sangkuriang.
Now, leave this place.
Leave this place with an honest soul.
A lot of people will be needing you.
Farewell.
Let them out of the stable.
Open the gate!
Take all of them.
Let us go!
How insolent!
Have mercy, please, mister.
She's my only grandchild.
Don't take her away.
Do you dare to oppose your own Prabu?
Have pity on us, mister.
- Have mercy.
- Silence!
One more word,
and I'll chop off your head.
- No, mister. Please.
- Let's go.
- Help, Grandpa!
- My grandchild!
Endah!
Endah, my granddaughter!
My poor grandchild!
Be strong, Gramps.
Give all of your crops to us. Hurry!
Come on!
What's going on in this village?
My grandchild...
Brother, I sometimes worry
that Gusti Prabu will find out about
our infamous ways with the subjects.
If we don't do these things,
we won't be rich.
Gusti Prabu only pays attention
to the young ladies.
That's what's important.
Kanjeng Adipati,
we've completed our tasks.
Well done. Assign them.
Listen up, all of you.
All the animals and harvests,
bring them to Kepatihan,
and all the young ladies,
take them to Keraton.
- Let's move, now.
- Wait!
All the women, harvests,
and animals must stay here!
It doesn't belong to the kingdom.
I'm warning you all
to leave this village immediately.
How dare you oppose Gusti Prabu's orders?
What's your name?
Sangkuriang.
Take care of him.
Chase him.
Surround him.
Stop!
Do as I told you or else!
Hurry up! Leave!
Forgive me, Kanjeng Adipati.
I have been rude to you.
You may leave.
Thank you for your help, son.
But this could be the start
of a huge disaster for this village.
Why?
Gusti Prabu will destroy us all.
If I'm guilty
of defending justice,
then let me bear it.
But justice is not ours.
It doesn't belong to this village.
Justice is in the hands of Gusti Prabu.
Then I will take it away from Gusti Prabu.
Mother! Take a look, Mother!
I brought you a rabbit this time.
Take it, Mother.
Jaka Sona, my son.
I'm always proud to receive
your game meat.
Mother!
Please forgive me, Mother.
Cowards!
You're all lily-livered.
Who's the young man who dares disobey?
Sangkuriang.
Sangkuriang?
Indeed, Gusti Prabu.
How will you take care of this problem?
What should we do?
- That's right.
- Let's find another way.
We must think about this.
You're all fools.
Catch Sangkuriang. Bring him to me.
Dead or alive.
If anyone helps him,
you can burn them too.
Do it!
We will follow your orders.
Open it!
Sangkuriang, come out of the cage.
Prove to us that you're a champion.
Come out, you water rat.
All right. I have a way to force you out.
Spear him!
Show me what you've got.
I want to find out
who'll win this contest.
No!
Who will die between us.
Curse you!
Pursue and seize him!
Let's go! Surround him!
Who are you? Why are you hiding there?
Don't speak too loud.
My name is Sangkuriang.
The Keraton people are hunting me.
Why? You must be an outlaw.
No. I'm not an outlaw.
Instead, I'm against their tyranny.
What tyranny?
The people sincerely accept
the way they are treated.
Miss, your voice and your face
remind me of someone.
Enough. You look so tired.
Please, have a drink.
Thank you.
Check all the houses.
Don't give that scumbag
any chance to escape.
If necessary, arrest all
the suspicious people in the village.
Do it!
Spread out.
Go and hide inside. I will go see them.
- Why are you helping me?
- I'm not helping you.
I'm helping myself.
Miss.
You're beautiful and so kind.
Excuse me!
Hurry up. Hide.
Everyone who's in this house, get out!
Quick!
What's going on, sir?
Excuse me, miss.
We're looking for a fugitive from Keraton.
His name is Sangkuriang.
Is he here?
No, mister. I'm all alone.
Let's search this house. Let's go.
Don't, sir. There's no one inside.
Don't argue with us.
We're just following orders.
Step aside!
- No, don't!
- Stop!
Greetings, miss.
I'm so happy to meet Miss Dayang Sumbi.
What do you mean, Kanjeng Adipati?
I never expected you to live
in this village, miss.
Miss, Gusti Prabu is your father.
He misses you so much.
He will be so happy to know about this.
You're mistaken, Kanjeng Adipati.
Both my parents have passed away.
I'm not Dayang Sumbi.
I don't think so.
You're Dayang Sumbi for sure.
I don't know that name.
I was born and raised in this village.
My name is Larasati.
Whether you're Dayang Sumbi or Larasati,
it makes no difference to me.
I will inform Gusti Prabu
about this immediately.
Everyone, leave this place.
Let's go.
Miss.
It looks like they suspected you.
Why was that?
It's such a bad sign for me.
I should leave.
I've become troublesome for you.
Please forgive me.
I don't blame anyone.
It looks like
they will do something to me.
You saved my life.
Now it's my turn to protect you.
What do you mean?
The Almighty has fated us
to meet each other
and also to share that fate.
Dayang Sumbi?
Are you sure it's my daughter?
That's right, Gusti Prabu.
My daughter.
I've been longing to see her again.
Miss Dayang Sumbi hasn't aged at all.
She looks the same as when she left.
Ki Patih.
I order you to fetch her immediately.
Yes, Gusti Prabu.
How peaceful my heart will be
if this young man
really wants to be my protector.
- But...
- Miss!
Miss Larasati!
Did you catch a fish?
Not yet.
Here you go.
Mother! Here you go!
I'm so sorry, miss.
Please get me my clothes over there.
Hurry up, miss.
I'm so cold, miss.
Close your eyes.
What's the matter?
Do you regret it, miss?
I'm afraid of my past.
I'm scared of losing
the one I love for the second time.
Stop worrying, miss.
I will always be by your side.
Live for love, love to live.
Living in this nation is so unfair.
The people are always victims
of extortion.
That's because of all the deeds
of Kanjeng Adipati,
led by Prabu Sungging Perbangkara.
My dream of liberating this nation
will never end.
What's the matter, miss?
As a mighty warrior,
you won't ever get hurt.
But I found a scar on your head.
What caused it?
It happened when I was a child.
I accidentally killed our dear dog.
My mother was furious,
and she hit me on the head.
Sangkuriang.
I have a feeling about you.
I'm worried that you're my...
You don't have to be worried.
Sangkuriang is here.
The man who will love
and protect you forever.
Jaka is here, Mother.
Jaka Sona, your son.
The one who will love
and protect you forever, Mother.
Miss, you should go home, to the palace.
We brought horses to fetch you, miss.
Don't waste your time with this infidel.
Step aside, Sangkuriang!
Allow us to take the woman.
Don't touch her!
Never mind kidnapping.
I'm her guardian.
Curse you, kid!
Seize that scum! And search the house.
Kanjeng Adipati,
we can't find Dayang Sumbi.
Search the whole village
until you find her.
Yes, Kanjeng Adipati.
Do it!
Chase him.
Get him.
Drag and burn him!
Let's go.
Drag him.
Keep dragging him.
Let's go outside.
- Come on!
- Wait for me. Mister.
Bring him in.
Burn the house down.
Everyone, leave this place. Come on.
Pardon me, Gusti Prabu.
I come to demand justice and truth.
What kind of justice
and truth are you demanding?
You have never taken care of your people.
And you don't know
what your two greedy Patih
have been doing all along.
They have been robbing your people
while the king was absorbed
in the pleasure of women.
Such a cocky kid!
You have guts to insult me.
And also my men.
Kill him!
Chase him!
Miss Larasati.
Miss.
Miss!
Miss Larasati?
What do you mean by all this?
Don't call me miss, Jaka Sona.
How do you know my childhood name?
Because I'm actually your mother.
I gave birth to you and raised you.
Impossible.
My mother passed away.
I buried her body.
I'm Dayang Sumbi.
Lies!
You look like her,
but you're not my mother.
Adipati from the palace
mistook you for Dayang Sumbi, too,
but you told them that you are not her.
Do you remember that?
I just made that up
to protect myself from them.
Why did you do that?
Now you don't have to worry anymore.
I killed them all.
Come on.
I'm ready to marry you.
No way. How can a mother marry her child?
You're not my mother.
I have to marry you, whatever it takes.
My Lord.
Please free me from this suffering.
Please help me, Lord.
If I am really your son,
please tell me. Who's my real father?
All right.
Your real father is...
You can't tell me, right?
Because you're not my mother.
All right, Sangkuriang.
I give up.
For what you demand,
you need to do as I ask.
What is it? Tell me.
Make a dam in the Citarum River,
transform the valley into a lake,
and make a boat for us to sail on it.
Is that everything?
Yes.
Everything should be ready
before the sun rises tomorrow morning.
All right.
You will see. It will be done on time.
Lord.
Please make him realize.
He is indeed mighty.
Hey, young man!
If you want to defeat me,
you don't have to destroy
the whole region.
What are you waiting for?
Show me your power.
Pardon me, Gusti Prabu.
Let me face him first.
Hey, Sangkuriang,
you need to step over my dead body
before you get to face Gusti Prabu.
How insolent! Curse you, monkey.
It turns out you're not that good.
Pardon me, Gusti Prabu.
Your transformation powers
won't affect me at all.
Jaka, stop fighting.
Stop it, Jaka!
Father!
Please forgive me, Father.
And also your grandson, Jaka Sona.
- My grandson?
- Indeed.
Sumbi...
I'm proud of his strength.
Wait.
You need to know this, Jaka.
Prabu Sungging Perbangkara
is your grandfather.
No!
He's not my grandfather.
He's a vile king,
the oppressor of the people.
Jaka Sona.
Don't call me that.
Call me Sangkuriang.
Where are you going?
I'm going to fulfill
your conditions for our wedding.
My dear Lord.
This world feels cramped to me.
You put too much karma on me.
I have hidden myself from disgrace
because I am ashamed to look at my fate.
But the trial is here again.
It comes and crushes me.
My Lord Romohun.
You gave me a lover,
but it turns out that he is my son.
My own flesh and blood.
But he wants to marry me.
What kind of karma
do you want to put on me?
Please help me!
Show me your greatness.
Show me a miracle.
Please forgive me.
Forgive us, Lord Hyang Rumuhun.
Stop trying, Jaka.
You failed to fulfill your promise.
What do you mean?
Do you see that?
Sanghyang Rumuhun doesn't
give his blessing for our marriage
because you're my son.
Miss Larasati!
Wait, Larasati.
Wait!
Even though I failed
to fulfill your conditions,
you have to be my wife.
No!
You have been possessed by lust,
so you're not yourself, my son.
Whatever!
You've lost your mind.
You won't escape anymore.
Stop your madness.
You are indeed powerful.
You are so mighty.
You possess
the force of nature inside of you.
But your soul is empty.
Listen to me.
Because of your blind desire,
you've forgotten the justice and virtues
that you've been
fighting for all this time.
Moreover for a woman, your mother.
If you force me one more time,
then your mother will fade away forever.
Miss.
I still love you.
Jaka Sona, aka Sangkuriang.
Your aspiration to love me
has been fulfilled.
But not as your wife.
I'm your mother.
Snap out of it.
Keep on aspiring
to free this nation
from its wicked rulers.
Farewell, my son.
Mother.
Forgive me, Mother.
Dayang Sumbi is my mother.
Forgive my mistakes
and have mercy on me for my faults.
I truly regret it.
Because I can't get a hold of myself.
Because I forgot where I came from.
Please forgive Jaka, Mother.
Please forgive Sangkuriang.
It is said
the boat of the mighty Sangkuriang
has now been transformed
into an eternal monument.
The Tangkuban Perahu mountain.
Sangkuriang is the people's warrior.
Sangkuriang is a hero.
His aspiration to free this nation
from its wicked rulers
has been fulfilled.
The huge dam created by the hero
has slowly changed over the years.
It has turned into
the most beautiful city in Indonesia.
Bandung City.
The city of flowers.
The city of struggle.
The city of the Sea of Fire.
And the first city in the world
to hold the Asian-African Conference.
One is missing, two are counted.
THE END