London
Be careful!
Is that Lady Milligan's brother?
No, that is her son-in-law, the brother of the deceased.
He can barely stand on his feet.
Is it because of grief?
What do you think?
It's because of the whiskey.
It washes away a joyful event.
Is he an heir?
Eh, no. With him, the inheritance will not last long.
No, the heir is little Robert, the lord's son.
Poor child.
He doesn't want to touch any of these toys.
It's as if understands what's happened.
Well, Robert, let's go eat.
Grandmother!
Robert... Robert, darling!
Robert, my baby!
Mr. James called, madam.
He asks you not to wait for him for dinner, he has an important meeting.
Very well.
Robert...
Nothing stirs up hunger like a funeral!
How many of them have I seen in my life?
One like this? Never!
And the procession?
Did you see how they walked?
That's enough. I need to talk to you.
Really?
I know that remorse doesn’t choke you.
Oh, you say so because one day in the bank,
you caught my hand on your wallet?
But anyone can make a mistake like that!
- I could have put you in jail.
- Yes.
But pretended to be nearsighted instead
to carefully study my criminal record.
I want to offer you a job.
Work?
And well paid.
You?
Do you know that my brother left a great fortune?
Yes, but not for you. To his son.
Precisely.
The child's room is on the second floor.
I'll arrange it so that the servants are gone.
As you can see, nothing could be easier!
Yes, nothing could be easier...
But if I get caught...
- Monsieur, would you like to dance?
- Leave me alone!
Oh, how rude!
Oh, come on, I'm tired of your stories!
It is enough to be cautious.
Cautious?
Yeah, and when they catch me...
Then it won't be enough.
Tell me, patron, have you seen my husband?
There.
Oh! Who would doubt it?
Sitting and calming himself with an aperitif.
Give me something.
No, I tell you, I don't like it.
I like working in pockets.
How much do you say?
No, I will not accept it.
It's too dangerous.
I assure you there is no risk!
Who's talking about risk here?
Where is the risk?
- Why?
- There's just not enough here!
No, no, woman, no, no!
This monsieur is telling me about games and about...
about the Grand Prix at the races.
You want to spend all your money on the races?
Like you have enough for that!
You already let everything go!
Now we have nothing!
Listen, go cry in your yard.
Leave me alone.
Cry, cry!
You won't get anything from me!
Yes, Yes! Leave us!
What a character!
Oh, these women!
Yes, well, so there...
Oh no! I will not accept it! I already told you this job is not for me!
Well, now!
Since you're being so sentimental...
Deal?
What a charmer you are!
Robert!
Madame!
Madame! Madame!
The baby is gone!
What did you say?
Are you sure?
It's incomprehensible!
We need to call them immediately!
Yes.
Yes, Mr. James.
Tonight.
Lady Milligan was distraught with grief.
She asked to tell you immediately.
Yes, yes, of course, I'm coming.
What a story!
I hope you informed the police?
Yes, I will leave immediately.
You little brat!
Did your buddies keep you warm?
Poor fellow!
With such an angelic smile!
Don't worry.
You will soon meet the angels.
How cute!
Yes, but still!
And anyway, I'm doing you a favor.
After all, life is essentially a sad thing.
But what will the client say?
And he won't know anything.
But murder goes against my principles!
Oh, to hell with morality.
You're too cute.
Maybe someday you will reproach me for this.
You will not end up in the ground.
You will live!
So much the worse for you!
Well, now, now he is whimpering!
And you have no suspicions?
No, no, Mr. Commissioner.
You cannot give us any information,
about anyone who could help us find a motive?
None, Mr. Commissioner.
In any case, we will warn all the London police stations.
There is nothing else we can do.
Ah, doctor!
Well, so far all the searches have yielded no results.
Above all, you mustn't deprive Lady Milligan of her last hope.
In her position, strong emotions can be fatal.
- What?
- Yes.
Lady Milligan is expecting a baby.
Lady Milligan?
Another child?
10 Years Later
In Chavanon, a small village in southern France
Rémi! Rémi!
I'm coming!
And I tell you that this brute is completely stunted.
Stunted? My Roussette?
She never got sick at all.
She eats nothing, but is stronger than a horse.
Okay, I know that you are embarrassed.
I will not abuse it.
Oh, Mother Barberin!
Roussette!
Say goodbye to her my little one.
My dear Roussette.
Please don't let her leave!
Come on, Rémi, pull yourself together!
You know very well that we have to sell Roussette.
Since the accident with Father Barberin in Paris,
he doesn't send us a sous anymore.
We can't be without money, can we?
Poor Roussette!
Okay, let's go.
Don't cry!
Come on, blow your nose!
Go see!
Look what's inside!
Oh!
Eggs... Butter!
Let's make pancakes!
Oh, Mother Barberan!
It will be good!
It will be ready soon, little one!
Father Barberin!
How is it you?
We didn't expect to see you!
Yes, it's me. It doesn't seem to please you!
I thought you were still in the hospital in Paris.
What are you cooking here?
- Pancakes.
- Pancakes?
And that's all?!
For a man who walked 50 km?
Make me a good omelette with onions right now.
So you haven't read my letters?
I read them.
But I told you to get rid of the little brat!
Please!
We don't have a penny.
Are we going to keep feeding the bird outside of our nest?
Oh, no tears!
Otherwise I'll kill you.
Don't be angry.
It's because of the onions.
I come back home and you just cry!
Didn't I have enough trouble in Paris?
Didn't you get compensation for your accident?
Compensation!
My employer told the judge
that I fell from the scaffolding
because I had drank too much.
And I was denied the claim,
as they put it.
What? Aren't you eating?
No, thanks. I'm not hungry.
Does he always eat so little?
No, he usually has a good appetite.
Of course.
I mean, he doesn't eat a lot.
He is very small.
An extra mouth is an extra mouth.
If it weren't for him,
you would have kept our cow.
Go to sleep, my little one.
So what are you going to do with him?
Damn it! I will hand him over to the orphanage.
To the orphanage?
You're not serious, are you?
Of course, I'm serious. And without delay!
Barberin! Hush, please, hush!
There's no use persuading me!
What's decided is decided!
I'm going to have a drink.
My little one!
No need for such sadness!
-  Did you hear everything?
- Yes.
Didn't I caress you and cherish you like a real mother?
- Oh, yes!
- Listen.
I lost a child your age.
And when Father Barberin found you at the door of the Notre Dame Cathedral,
I thought that you could replace him.
You were so handsome.
You were well dressed.
You know the little clothes
and the locket that you saw at the bottom of the closet?
They're yours.
I don't want to go to the orphanage!
Do not be afraid of anything!
I won't let him!
Come on, go to sleep, my little one!
Goodnight, my Rémi!
Your Mother Barberin is going to take care of you.
Mother Barberin!
Well, Rémi?
Relax!
Are you afraid of me?
No.
Have you forgotten that today is Friday?
Mother Barberin's market day?
Oh, no!
Do you want to go find her?
Oh yes!
Let's go together.
A bottle of beer.
We must hurry!
If we are late for the market,
Mother Barberin will already be gone!
Don't worry. We have time.
Well, have you returned to the country?
Yes, yesterday.
Ah, these insurance companies!
Why did they decide not to pay you?
A gang of crooks!
They are all the same!
Such scammers cannot be reasoned with...
We must hurry!
Ha ha!
When I tell you where we are going,
you won't be so pressed to leave!
- Ha ha!
- And your trial?
The trial? It was even worse!
Don't try to run away!
Your ass will be in trouble!
Wait for me there, don't move!
Capi!
What's the matter?
-  You are crying?
- No.
I can see that you are very sad.
What happened?
And why are you sitting here?
- Is that your father?
- No.
He doesn't want me to stay with Mother Barberin.
Why?
Well, let's go!
For you.
We need to deliver the package to the shelter.
And that's why he doesn't want me to stay.
Enough though I don't eat a lot.
- Poor little one!
- Well, Rémi, let's go!
Oh, monsieur. Do you really want to take this child to the orphanage?
What I want is for you not to get involved in my business!
Yes, excuse me.
But maybe there is another way.
And it could even earn you money!
Him? Money?
This little guy?
This weakling?
Not standing on its feet?
And besides, he doesn't eat! He's excess.
And I'm actually looking for a little boy to join my troupe.
I'll pay you well.
If you say it like that!
Patron! Two glasses!
So?
One hundred francs per month.
How does that sound?
Not enough.
This guy has never been sick!
He eats nothing, but is as strong as a horse. Come here!
Look at these calves,
at these muscles!
Two months advance payment!
Now, if you need to communicate with me,
write to me in the name of Monsieur Garofoli. 43 Rue Orsin in Paris.
Here are your two hundred francs.
Rémi! Grab him! He's running away!
I beg you!
Don't be so mean to him!
I am his master now.
Take me back to Mother Barberin!
Be brave!
See that barn over there?
We will sleep well there!
Let's go.
Go lie down in the straw.
You will see how great it is to sleep in it.
And how good it smells.
There, settle down.
Take off your shoes.
Oh, you poor fellow!
They're asking you for porridge!
Mother Barberin promised
to buy me new ones but...
Are you sleeping?
You will have nice new shoes tomorrow.
We will pass through the city, where there are magnificent shoes.
With nails?
- Yes. With nails.
You will also have a velvet jacket
pants, and a hat, like the Italians.
- Why?
- Because we are artists.
The public always prefers foreigners.
Here in France, I will dress you like an Italian.
In Italy, like a Frenchman.
Do not be afraid.
You won't feel bad with me.
You will see how we will learn,
wandering around the world.
I will teach you everything I know.
A bit of history, geography...
but above all music.
I will teach you to sing!
Everywhere I saw the most magnificent beauty
But I have never seen in any city
Your delightful eyes
Your chiseled forehead
Your blooming cheeks
Your lips that promise treasure
Oh my Lola!
Your golden hair!
I loved you madly!
I left my heart in Italy!
Since then my thoughts
Everywhere they follow you!
My wretched wounded soul
Suffering from melancholy!
Day and night
I dream of you, my tender lover
In your eyes, was a delicate mirror
I think I see it again
Italy!
- Very pretty!
- You liked it?
Now let's try to sing it together.
Yes.
Oh my Lola!
I loved you madly!
I left my heart in Italy!
Since then my thoughts
Everywhere they follow you!
My wretched wounded soul
Suffering from melancholy!
Day and night
I dream of you, my tender lover
In your eyes, was a delicate mirror
I think I see it again
Italy!
Bravo, Rémi! What a progress in just a few months!
Now we need to study geography.
Naturally, this is not as much fun.
But in life you have to learn!
So, here's the map.
This is where we left.
Here is Ussel, where I bought your beautiful shoes.
See that big blue line?
This is the Du Midi Canal.
Once upon a time for ships to get from Bordeaux to Marseille,
they were forced to sail all around Spain.
- Are we going there?
- Yes, later!
And this is where we are now.
Here we will give a performance tomorrow.
Ladies and gentlemen, let me introduce you to the famous Zerbino!
He will work in front of you.
Zerbino, hup!
Now it's your turn,
Mademoiselle Dolce!
- Careful, it's hot!
- Thanks, little one!
Come here, come.
Come on, spin!
Spin, spin, spin...
Bravo, Dolce!
Now you, Zerbino!
Get up, Capi, get up!
Get up now.
It's time to collect the fee.
Go quickly!
Sit! Sit.
You were naughty!
And as punishment I will kill you!
Attention!
Puff!
But now I am left
alone, Zerbino!
Come with me!
You don't to?
Then I'll go get the police!
Very funny.
Take the old man to the gendarmerie.
Let him sit there.
Your papers, if you please, monsieur!
Yes, Monsieur.
These are not correct!
There is a lack of permission from the
mayor!
But, monsieur, I have performed all over the country.
Nobody has interfered with me.
Here it is not the same.
- What is this?
- Let him go!
Leave the child alone!
He hasn't done anything to you!
How dare you raise your hand against me!
Well, that's enough! Follow me!
What have they done?
Do not worry!
I'll be right back.
Wait for me!
Your stomach is empty?
Mine too.
Since Master Vitalis is not with us,
we have not earned one sou. There's nothing!
There will be a big performance tonight!
What is it, Arthur?
You must eat your chicken!
These are breasts, they're the best!
I don't want it.
Think about the beggars.
What do they have?
Why are you poking at me with your chicken?
Eat it yourself if you like it so much!
- Mother!
- Oh, my darling!
How are you, my darling
- Madame, he doesn't want to eat anything!
Oh, we'll see!
My precious one, you don't want to upset your mother, do you?
- What's his temperature?
- Thirty-seven.
Over there on the road!
Look!
Oh, how funny!
Mother, please,
I want to take a closer look!
Well, of course, my darling, of course!
Stop, please.
Stop! Stop!
Come on, little one! Come on board.
Very well, monsieur.
Come here!
Come here, my little friend!
My son will be very happy to
see your artists up close.
With pleasure, madame!
Let me introduce you to Mr. Joli-Coeur, the general of my troupe.
Come on, come on, get off!
Thank you, you can go.
Oh my darling.
Do not over excite yourself,
otherwise you will get tired quickly!
Oh look! Look at them!
Here you go.
What did you just sing,
my little friend?
It's an Italian melody, madame.
Do you want me to sing?
- Oh, yes, mother!
- Yes, please sing!
Good.
Listen, listen, listen...
Oh my Lola!
I loved you madly!
I left my heart in Italy!
Since then my thoughts
Everywhere they follow you
My wretched wounded soul
Suffering from melancholy!
Day and night... Zerbino! No! No!
Shoo! Bad dog!
Madame, forgive him!
He usually never steals.
But he was so hungry...
- Didn't you feed him?
I want to... But I have nothing.
Poor animal!
Margaret please
go to the kitchen and prepare some food.
Oh, thank you, madame!
And you?
I hope you have dined?
Well, I mean...
I'm still a little hungry.
Sit down.
Here.
This is for you, just a little bit.
Chicken?
Eat! Don't you like it?
Oh, yes, madame!
Water?
No, no, don't be in such a hurry, or you'll choke!
A little water in case
you are a little thirsty.
Thank you, madame!
They are bringing food to your artists.
Eat calmly, I'll leave for now.
You're lucky!
Why?
That you're so hungry.
I never want to eat.
This is because you have too much food.
And they always give me only meat.
The bones are also a good piece!
This is true! And tastier if you eat it with your hands!
It's true.
Oh, pancakes!
Let's see whose is better your mother's or Mother Barberin's!
My mom makes pancakes just as good as yours.
By the way, the cook makes them.
But they are still very tasty.
Well, is everything okay, my little one?
Yes, mom! We ate with our hands like monkeys!
It made me hungry!
Thank you, madame.
It was very tasty!
Really? Then at 4 o'clock you will have an afternoon snack with Arthur.
You see...
it is time for us to go ashore, madame.
Not yet!
I need to find a place to sleep with my animals.
Mother, I don't want him to leave!
What if his parents are waiting for him?
His parents are far away.
They gave him to the animal trainer.
What?
- Where is he?
- He's not here.
I will meet with him in two months.
Until then, can he stay with us?
Of course, if he wants to.
Oh, yes, madame! You are so kind!
Oh, like all mothers!
Oh yes!
And your mother? Was she okay with letting you go?
Oh no, she didn't want to.
But Father Barberin forced her.
- How old are you?
- Twelve years old.
Twelve years old...
Forward!
Sit still, Capi! Don't move.
- Finally!
- My little Rémi!
My little Rémi!
Are you unwell?
You look tired.
Oh, I'm only a bit tired.
After all, I spent two months in prison!
Two months in a cell, without seeing the sky, without light...
It's hard for an old man like me !
But none of that matters!
Come on, show me yourself!
You just look great!
Let's go.
Come on, Rosie.
You know, I met a kind woman on a boat.
It's also a house.
And there is also a boy who is sick
And he became my friend thanks to Joli-Coeur.
- And also...
- Also, also, also..
You talk so fast that I hardly understand anything.
Yes, they came with me me here.
And they are also waiting for us.
You will see how beautiful their home is!
Oh, it's is such a beautiful boat!
Madame, I don't even know how to express my gratitude to you.
- What you did for Remi...
- He's so charming, your little man.
- Rémi!
- By the way, I need to talk to you.
Yes?
Do you know what mother is asking him?
- No.
- I know!
- Would you trust me with Rémi?
- Leave you Rémi?
Yes, he will be fine with us.
This boy deserves an
upbringing that you cannot give him.
Will you not answer?
Sorry, madame.
- I heard this melody from Don Juan.
- This is Serenade.
Recorded by Carlo Balzani.
If you only heard him live...
- Do you remember him, madame?
- Yes!
We applauded him so often when he sang at the opera.
Carlo Balzani!
What an incomparable artist!
It's a pity that he suddenly disappeared at the height of his fame.
At the height of fame...
Well, so what did you decide for the child?
You cannot fail to understand.
Instead of a life of vagrancy,
he will live with us as a family.
He will be treated like my son.
He will receive the same care,
the same education.
The most useful education, madame,
is what life gives us.
With me he will learn to live.
- Rémi!!
- Coming!
And you will stay with me!
Think well, my little one.
Here you will have everything that I cannot give you.
Life with me will not always be easy.
We need to move to Paris.
The season is already in full swing.
You will suffer from cold, from snow, and rain...
And you?
We will stay with you.
It won't be so difficult together.
Well, Mr. Joli-Coeur,
it's time to leave.
Goodbye, Arthur! Goodbye!
Goodbye, Arthur!
Capi, come on, my old friend!
Have courage!
You have four legs, and I only have two, but I'm still going.
Oh, Master Vitalis! Capi is very tired.
I'm afraid that he, too, will die of the cold,
like Dolce and Zerbino!
Come on, let's go faster!
We must reach the next village before nightfall.
We can't sleep outdoors in this weather.
Come on, Capi! Capi!
"At the Golden Lion"
Accommodation for hikers and horsemen. Food.
You there, what do you want?
I don't want you boring my clients.
We don't need your clients.
We just need a room that's warm.
Well, well, make yourself at home, you dirty dog!
I will pay what you want.
Could you also send for a doctor?
I have a patient with me. It's urgent
Very well.
Suzanne, take them to number five.
Come with me, monsieur.
But why?
Do what I said. Yes, hurry up.
Okay. How good it is to be in a real bed!
Soft mattress, white sheets!
Hey, it's too tight!
If it's not, you won't be warm enough to warm Joli-Coeur.
He is trembling all over!
He has a high fever.
Come in!
Doctor!
Let's see our patient.
Is it congestion?
But I'm not sick!
It's he who is sick!
A monkey?
You dragged me out in this bad weather to treat the monkey?
- Doctor!
- No!
- Listen!
- I, a former hospital expert,
certified physician of the Faculty of Castelnaudary!
But this is not an ordinary animal!
This is a great artist of his kind.
I could, of course, send for the vet.
But I preferred to turn to the luminary of science!
Just look how smart he is.
He extends his hand to you so that you can feel his pulse.
He doesn't want you to leave.
He is very ill.
I will bleed him.
You will also need to buy medicines.
We need to pay the doctor.
And for the medicines for Joli-Coeur.
I have some money saved.
- How much?
- One hundred sous.
That is not enough.
Go prepare the barn.
We will give a performance today.
- How will we do it?
- Hurry.
- Do what I tell you.
- Okay.
Is that all?
You can see that anywhere.
This is nothing special.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Please, don't go!
The show is not over yet.
Give me a couple more minutes.
A sudden cry in the night: "Wolves!"
A cry full of fear and horror.
And then the camp got up: "Wolves!"
They have surrounded the travelers.
They raise their weapons.
The grass becomes covered in blood.
One falls, a new one immediately rises.
Howling animals, wheezing.
A great white desert
Where the world is ruled by terror...
But hear them howl and roar, wolves!
And we will unite our efforts!
There are many wolves on earth.
Victory will be for a strong man!
Sooner or later, evil will be punished!
We will defeat all our enemies!
We will go through our difficult path to the end.
Our future is in our hands.
The wolves are getting more and more angry.
But nobody else complains, nobody is afraid.
For there are no more cowards!
Sooner or later, evil will be punished!
We will defeat all our enemies!
And for this we will
Always keep hope!
We made so much money!
- All thanks to your song!
- We can now cure Joli-Coeur.
You never told me that you sing so well!
This is the end.
With Capi alone, we cannot continue.
We'll have to make our way to Paris.
I'll leave you with Garofoli.
A friend, an old friend.
He'll take care of you during the winter.
And I...
I will give music lessons.
I wish I had left you with the Milligans.
It would have been better.
Mother, come look at what I've made!
This is Capi.
This is Dolce. This is Zerbino.
This is Rémi.
This is Joli-Coeur.
He came out slightly larger than Rémi. I made a mistake.
All the same, it's very beautiful!
Mother, do we have to stay in England much longer?
Yes, darling. Why?
I would like to see Rémi right now.
Come in.
- I am looking for James Milligan.
- He's probably in the library.
Why?
- There is someone asking for him.
- Who is this gentleman?
He isn't a gentleman, but a scandalous man who won't leave without seeing him.
What are you doing here?
You never invite me to your place.
I said I didn’t want to see you.
- Come on, you can't do without me.
- Beware!
Are we being mean?
Fine, go over there.
Oh, what are you doing, my darling?
Uncle James gave you this book only yesterday.
- How unkind you are to him.
- I do not like him!
But he's so kind to you.
Even so, I don't like him.
Why is he living with us now?
But he is your father's brother,
my darling. It's natural.
Well, how great it is for you to live here!
It turned out to be an interesting visit.
I will likely ring again!
Do you want money again?
Well, of course.
I'm a victim of a crisis, things are going badly.
- Your business is that of others.
- Naturally, but they are no longer there.
So, it's good to have cash.
But since you are so smart,
can you tell me how to fill one's wallet?
- Well, that is not of my knowledge.
- Naturally.
- Seeing as you're so grand!
- Enough! You won't get a sou more!
I don't care.
You will give it to me anyway.
Blackmail?
You have no proof.
And for taking the child they will hang you.
Oh, really?
What if I haven't eliminated him?
What?
What if I find him and bring him home to his little mother?
And to please his sweet little uncle?
Is this a joke?
That'll take some work.
What if I have proof?
- What proof?
- The kid himself.
Will that suffice?
You're just showing off!
You don't have him.
Naturally, a person is appreciated
everywhere except in his family.
Okay, well, go on.
Speak, I'm listening to you.
How are you going to get the kid again?
Well, that's none of your business.
Fat pig!
You are embarrassed!
Embarrassed! Embarrassed!
Listen here, tart cream!
When I left the toddler at the door of a church in Paris,
I followed the man who picked him up to the train station.
And then I checked when he took his ticket.
That's where I'm going to direct my bones.
Bones, bones...
Your bones are pounding painfully!
No one will give the boy to someone like you.
Oh, not everyone can be such a luxurious chicken like you, Marquise!
In any case, you don't have to worry.
I'll figure out how to pretend to be a trustworthy person.
Say! What about a little visit from a reverend?
- Mr. Barberin, please.
- That's me.
I am the Reverend Slum from London.
Greetings, my brother.
I have come to you on a
very important matter.
Wait, I'll call your sister.
- My sister?
- My wife.
Ah, yes-yes.
He's a reverend, like a priest.
Call him "my father".
- Sit down, Father Reverend!
- Thank you, my sister.
This is what brought me to your land...
Oh!
Father Reverend?
Excuse me, but I came for this very child!
What an honor! This is my portrait.
I am three years old here.
Oh, then no.
I was mistaken.
Listen, I was sent by
a noble English family
looking for the child
you adopted ten years ago.
- Rémi?
- Rémi, that's it!
He had a lace nightgown,
a gold medallion, and an undershirt.
Now, imagine that some fool,
shameless and immoral,
stole the kid from his bed!
That is, I mean, kidnapped this defenseless body!
What scoundrels there are on the earth!
I saved his clothes!
Ah, you saved...
How did you find the
footprints of the child?
Oh, uh, the footprints?
Oh, that?
This is the whole story!
- Once I went by accident...
- Here are his clothes.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
Oh, I recognize them!
The medallion!
The nightgown... Well, of course, recognize them from their description.
But tell me, where is the kid?
Mr. Rémi is no longer with us.
How inappropriate!
This is very outrageous!
Well, you know, I gave him a profession!
I made him an artist.
Well, where is he, your artist?
- I don't know.
- This is just great!
Wait!
Okay, let's see.
I probably have an address here.
We are not rich!
And yet I made sacrifices for his education!
- Here!
- So, let's see.
Garofoli, 43 Orsina Street.
Obviously, well done!
My dear Rémi will be so happy to meet his mother!
Yes, he will meet her...
- Here.
- I told you this not for the money.
However, we will gladly accept it.
Yes, that's not a bad thing.
Well, my children, I am leaving you.
Goodbye, my sister.
Goodbye, my brother.
- And don't forget to pray for us!
- No risk of that!
Goodbye, my children!
Goodbye!
But...
What if we gave away the clothes and the medallion in vain?
That was the only evidence of Rémi.
If you can't trust a reverend, then this is the end of everything!
And done!
Hey, Mattia!
- You'll see, it's funny.
- Give us an impression.
The horn.
Here.
That's quite the show, eh?
You will pay next time?
- Well, yes.
- The sous?
- I don't have any.
Give it to me! I saw them give it to you.
Oh, Vitalis!
It cannot be!
How glad I am to see you!
And this is undoubtedly the adorable child that
you wrote about in your letters?
Whom you will leave with me?
Whom I will leave with you.
He will become a friend to my little Mattia.
My heart breaks when I punish him.
But he breaks everything!
But I love him as if he were my own son.
Go on put on your jacket.
If you freeze, you'll have to endlessly heal
both night and day!
Go on, little one.
Go meet Mattia.
Leave us alone.
How charming he is!
I will teach him the profession.
He will be very happy here.
And then he will make a living as a waiter in a café.
- Does he hit you often?
- Constantly.
I have bruises everywhere.
You can play checkers on my back.
- And you allow it?
- What can I do?
He always beats me.
I was happy only once in my life.
When I was in the hospital.
Unfortunately, I have recovered.
And since then I have not managed to get sick again!
It's no use!
I have reinforced concrete health!
Rémi!
Listen. Do you want me to give you an advance?
Come on, Rémi. We're leaving.
Come on, Capi.
Where are we going?
I do not know yet.
I'm going to rest.
This is a very important matter.
- Do you know Mr. Vitalis?
- Yes.
He always travels with a child.
Yes.
Well, this child is a foundling.
His parents are looking for him.
They live in London.
They have been inconsolable since their firstborn was mysteriously stolen from them.
Waiter!
And you think that the boy accompanying Vitalis is him?
I am sure of it!
I have all the evidence.
So you need to find your friend Vitalis as soon as possible.
Your findings are good?
Do you think it's that easy?
Vitalis dropped by just this afternoon.
I haven't seen him for eight months.
And who knows when he will come back.
Maybe today, maybe tomorrow, or maybe in six months!
How unfortunate!
Besides, I have no time.
Things are calling me to London.
Well, just in case,
I'll leave you my address.
Okay?
Here.
If you find out anything new,
notify me immediately.
You will not regret it.
Yes.
Good evening.
No, that will not do.
Have a glass with us?
Yes, with pleasure.
In a second.
And where will we go now?
I don't know.
My little one, forgive me.
I am at the end of my strength.
- Are you sick?
- Yes.
Very sick.
I've fought it for too long.
I didn’t want to leave you until you were assured of a normal future,
at least for the winter.
I have used all my willpower to take you to a friend who will take care of you.
But now I can neither leave you with him,
nor take you with me.
Why won't you take me?
Why do you want to leave me?
I don't want to leave you. But...
I want to be with you.
Don't leave me!
- Don't leave me!
- I'm not leaving you.
Let's go, come on!
Wait.
I'll rest a little more.
What's do you have?
Do not know.
My head is spinning.
Let's go down slowly.
Vitalis! Vitalis!
What can I do for you?
Vitalis!
The theater is full!
Even the gallery!
Success awaits you again!
Vitalis!
Vitalis... Vitalis!
Vitalis...
- Mr. Garofoli?
- That's me.
I'm the police commissioner.
Today a certain Vitalis was found dead in the street.
- What do you know about him?
- Vitalis is dead?
Poor fellow!
I loved him like a brother.
- Was he Italian?
- Yes, sir.
His real name is Carlo Balzani.
Balzani? Who is that?
A famous outstanding singer from La Scala in Milan.
I met him when I was a stage director.
- Does the child have a family?
- No, this child is a foundling.
That means we’ll have to take him to an orphanage.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Vitalis was just about to give this child to me.
I have a letter from him on the subject.
Here.
But I can't stay here.
That is impossible!
- I'd rather run away somewhere.
- Run to your parents!
I have no parents.
But you do! Listen, a man came here.
Well, come on, leave it to me.
Your self-sacrifice in relation to this orphan is sympathetic.
We will take this into account, and you will certainly be allowed to raise this child.
Oh, Mr. Commissioner, I will take care of him as I do little Mattia.
And thus I will fulfill the last will of my friend Balzani.
Tell me, why did this man change his name?
One evening, not getting the usual success,
he chose to suddenly leave the stage at the height of his fame
and his greatest fame.
Poor friend.
He seemed strange, but what a genius!
What is it?
I'll explain to you later.
We have to go.
Do you have any other information for me?
- No, Mr. Commissioner.
- Thank you.
Hunker down a bit.
Or you will be too tall!
Mattia!
I pretended to wipe the tables,
but I heard everything.
And then I watched where he hid the address.
Reverend Slum.
26 Green Street, London.
But if my relatives live in England, then I am English?
Only when you are with your parents.
- Then I am going to England immediately.
- So, are we going together?
Are you going to leave your patron?
Thanks to you.
There I will be welcome!
After a trip like that, I'll be able to sit for fifteen days!
- Poor Mattia!
- Plus, I'll be useful to you!
I have savings in my money box.
- In your money box?
- Here look.
You will see!
I have fifty-three sous here.
Of course, Rothschild is richer.
But we have enough for bread.
How will we get to London?
It is further than Versailles.
I was taught that England is an island.
All of England?
I think so.
So we have to get on a ship.
How will we pay for tickets?
Let's wait for the workers to leave
and then we will go aboard.
You will see!
It's great that we don't have to pay for passage.
If we can’t go like passengers, we'll go like the animals.
- Do you think we can fit in there?
- No, let's make room.
We'll pull out the straw so we have more space.
How are we going to breathe?
I have a fish knife. I will make holes.
Give me that.
Careful! Capi, step back.
Well, we've settled in quite well!
Say, it's a really a strange feeling when you are carried through the air like that.
Oh, yes!
Oh, carrots!
Oh!
Something else would be better.
But when you're really hungry...
Delicious! So sweet.
Do you want some, Capi?
No.
Hey, we are feasting in the hold!
Are you sure my parents are good people?
Is your father a banker?
Some rich man, huh?
And my mother? My mom?
She's probably beautiful and good.
She will hold me in her arms.
And do you have any brothers or sisters?
Yes! And they will be happy to meet me!
It's great to have a family.
Yes, great...
- Why do you say that so sadly?
- Because.
Because you don't have a family?
But you will have mine!
My mother will surely have enough money to feed you.
And even to hire you a music teacher!
Doesn't what I say comfort you?
No. Because...
- My heart hurts.
- Do you have seasickness?
Oh, I don’t know. Maybe it's seasickness or the carrots, but something doesn't feel right.
Where is Green Street?
Oh, Green Street? Go straight and turn left.
- Thanks.
It's here.
My heart is pounding, you know.
- What do you want?
- Reverend Slum, please.
Slum? Don't know him.
This is on behalf of Rémi Barberin.
Haha, that changes everything.
And even with home delivery!
Let them in.
Come in, my lambs, come in
to the house of the gallant Reverend Slum.
Finally, providence has decided to take our side.
We came to see the Reverend Slum.
Yes?
- Which of you is Rémi?
- Me.
Reverend Slum must take me to my father.
Come hug your father!
- You?
- Haha!
Does that surprise you?
It's only natural that you don't recognize me.
When we last saw you, you were eighteen months old.
I have changed.
For the better.
You too, by the way.
Come into my arms, my son!
Ah, the voice of blood!
There is nothing else.
And now...
Go kiss your mother.
And who is this?
This is Mattia.
We have been traveling together for two months.
He is almost like my brother.
You don't already have enough brothers?
Meet your new brother.
Rémi Driscoll.
Tom, the most grown.
Alain, who is growing.
John, the middle boy.
He is one hundred percent Driscoll.
He will go far.
Mel resembles his father.
Little Lizzie.
Her sister Eva.
Beautiful, well-bred and all that.
Well, and the youngest is Kate.
Conceived recently from whiskey.
Well...
You still haven't said hello to your grandfather.
Shake his hand.
Not so firmly!
Can't you see he's paralyzed?
John, go see who it is.
- Come back later. He is busy.
- Tell me anyways!
The old man doesn't like when his things are taken from him.
Calm down!
At his age, people become selfish.
Who was it?
Okay, I'm going.
Everyone to their rooms!
I'm expecting guests.
Lizzie! Take both newcomers to the guest room.
Go to bed with Rémi.
- Goodnight, monsieur.
- Goodnight, little one.
- Goodnight, Papa.
- Goodnight.
- Listen...
- Shh!
Come!
- Goodnight, Mama.
- Goodnight, Papa.
Goodnight. Goodnight.
Shhh, Capi!
- Yes, it's not cheap!
- Yes, but we almost got caught.
- Why? Because of the dog?
- No, because of the alarm bell.
Any longer, and I would have ran away.
Oh, you turned red like a tomato!
What are they doing?
That's why they sent us to bed.
We interfered with them.
I tell you, it's worth more!
Oh, don't joke like that!
Listen, you weren't the one who risked getting three years!
Don't take it that way.
What were you saying? Okay, okay...
Here you go. This is for your tea.
And that, you know, is not cheap.
There is a mark on there.
It's genuine.
Are you sleeping?
Is this why we interrupted our trip around the world?
A strange family.
- They are my relatives.
- Oh, that can't be!
If only I could find Arthur!
Lady Milligan told me they have a property in London.
But how do we find him in such a big city?
Go on, Mr. Arthur, lie still!
I can't sleep.
If you keep quiet,
you will fall asleep immediately.
No, I have a headache!
- I heard him calling. Is something is wrong?
- He's very agitated today.
He was prescribed drops so that he could sleep!
Here.
Drink, you'll feel better.
What's this?
What are you giving him?
- This is for me to sleep.
- It's his sedative.
No, give it to me, my darling.
- But, mother...
- Give it to me!
What are you doing, James?
This is madness!
You know that this sedative is very dangerous.
The doctor only permitted it for exceptional cases if things got worse.
Here, little one, drink.
Now try to sleep.
- Did I sing well?
- Yes.
Even though I learned it very quickly.
But the result is deplorable.
What will Father Driscoll think?
Come on, let's go.
Children! We are not on earth to have fun.
Pancakes with radishes! You will eat your bread from the sweat of your brow.
If I let you, you will all eat from the sweat of my brow!
To succeed in life today
you have to master your profession.
Understand?
- Yes, Papa.
- Good.
Your turn.
Gently. Gently.
A little to the left!
I have given you a craft.
You should try to improve your skill
so as not to embarrass the parents who took you in!
Understood?
No, no, not like that, not like that! No, no, no!
No, no, no! You will never succeed like that! Never!
Leave the door open.
- Why?
- Because.
What is that?
Where did you take it from?
That's good, Capi!
That's good work!
Good!
That, that's a job!
So that's why you keep Capi with you!
To make him a thief!
It's a shame, Capi!
Bad dog!
You did a very bad thing!
Where is Papa?
I'll tell him everything!
Poor fool!
Father, it's a shame!
John trained Capi...
Here, Papa! I got it without cheating.
So this is what you teach them?
Watch what you say, brat!
Your lousy songs bring in six sous a day!
And you won't let your family work to feed you?
What kind of work is this?
This is stealing!
You should watch your expressions!
You will honor your father and mother in order to live long.
If you don't remember this rule,
I'll knock it into you with a good kick in the behind!
- You think he will?
- And shut up there!
I don’t need your jokes!
How much did you bring in?
That's all? Why you...
That's enough! To work, to work!
Go now!
Go on, Mel with Helen!
Rémi, take Eva!
And his friend, Mattia.
You stay here, Lizzie.
You will go to the church and sell flowers.
There's a big wedding there.
If you don’t bring in any money, there will be trouble!
Go on, run.
What are you doing here?
Go on, join them! Go do something! For God's sake!
Mr. Driscoll, if you please.
He sent a note from Madame Jeanie.
Oh no! Driscoll!
Mattia, please find Capi.
- They will make him steal again.
- Okay.
So...
Again, everything is rummaged through here!
This is all my wife's doing, the cow.
Oh, she told me...
Well, you'll see now!
- Can we speak in front of your...?
- In front of the old man?
Yes, of course.
Go ahead, he is fully paralyzed.
Including speech.
And sometimes he foams like a laundry soap.
There you are.
I hope you recognize these clothes?
Yes, these are them.
Yes.
Well?
Shall we return him to dear mother?
- You are a bandit!
- And you're innocent?
Look what you're saying!
Don't embarrass me!
Okay, I will fulfill your requirements.
But under no circumstances should Rémi and Lady Milligan be allowed to meet.
- Where is the child?
- In the city, earning a crust of bread.
- I will be back tonight.
- Very well.
However, tell me, after all there is still the second heir.
I don't think he will last long.
Despite the special care.
Shut up, grandfather, shut up!
Are you kidding me?
What else can I break for you?
Ah, the window.
Drafts enrage him.
- I am going back home.
- Yes, say hello to Lady Milligan.
- What time does the child return?
- At seven o'clock.
Just don't forget to do some formalities.
You will receive the money when the child is with me.
What trust!
- Here at seven o'clock.
- Agreed.
Pig!
How nice!
Oh, poor children!
So young and already unhappy.
- You're not stopping?
- There's no cops.
Okay, I'm going again.
- Everything is good?
- Couldn't be better.
The ranks will close again.
Go on, get out of here.
Lady Milligan is in London!
She's looking for you because Arthur asked her to.
I followed the guy over there.
I think he's his uncle.
He has a very unpleasant face.
I have the address!
Good! Let's go there right away!
Come on, Rémi! Come on!
- What's the matter?
- You will answer for the others.
But I didn't do anything!
Vile child!
I will teach you how to protect your family!
What if Rémi talks?
- We will all be caught!
- And I will cut off his tongue!
- And yours too!
- Mine?
- You're a fool!
- And you are crazy!
I swear to you, it wasn't me.
- Tell me everything you know.
- I don’t know anything, monsieur.
Don't be stubborn! We know that you are Driscoll's accomplice.
You don't know that.
We must get him out of the clutches of the police!
I'll tell Lady Milligan everything.
- Have you earned any sous?
- Yes, look!
Good! Let's take a taxi! Come on!
We need to see Lady Milligan.
Lady Milligan does not permit vagrants.
But we have something very important we need to tell her.
Come on, let's go.
How will we get in there?
- You shouldn't be stubborn.
- But I don’t know anything.
You will not say for whom you steal,
you will end up in a correctional institution.
I don't know anything.
Take him to the camera.
He's brave, that kid.
He won't give up his parents.
It's just as we thought.
We tracked the children, they returned to Driscoll.
It's always Driscoll!
We still haven't found any serious evidence against him.
This time, we'll visit him at home.
- Get off quickly! He's coming!
- Stop that, kid!
Damn it! That guy's always there!
What are we going to do now?
- Listen, I have an idea.
- What is it?
Please, Mr. Arthur, finish your soup!
- I’m not hungry!
- Well, try a bit.
No!
Oh, my Lola!
I loved you madly!
I left my heart...
Go look! Who is singing?
Some children.
Send for them immediately!
- I want to see them immediately!
- As soon as you finish your soup.
Day and night, I dream of you, my tender beloved!
In your eyes, there is a mirror...
Don't run away! Don't be afraid!
You are invited into the house.
Let's go, quick! Let's go.
I assure you, Mother.
It's definitely Rémi!
It was his song and his voice!
That's impossible, my treasure!
You know that Uncle James did everything to find him.
I'm sure that it was his song!
Madame Lady Milligan, if you please.
That's me, my little one. What is it?
Madame Lady! I'm a friend of Rémi Barberin who is not Rémi Barberin,
since he is the son of Driscoll.
And although his father couldn't force him to,
he made his sister rummage through the pockets of passers-by!
What is he saying?
Rémi was arrested, but he is innocent!
Rémi was arrested?
How? Is he in London?
- Yes, madame lady!
- Rémi didn't steal! It's not true!
Rémi is simply incapable of doing bad things.
Madame, please, help us get him out.
What if he gets sent to prison?
What do you have here?
Who gave you this medallion?
- I took it from my papa.
- And where did he get it?
Do not know. I found it in a drawer.
Take me to your father immediately.
Madame Lady, please, take care of Rémi first!
- Yes, Rémi!
- Children, do not worry.
I'll certainly help Rémi.
What is your father's name?
- Driscoll.
- Where does he live?
- London, Green Street.
- Let's go right away.
What end do you have in mind?
Was it worth being a brave constitutional monarchist all your life?
Politics has nothing to do with your robberies!
Shut up! You should be ashamed, Mr. Commissioner!
Is it possible to imprison the gallant father of the family?
Who laid down his life for the good of British soil?
Yes, and who, at the same time, robbed country villas!
That still needs to be proved!
You have already searched my place fifteen times, and found only lice!
We'll look harder this time.
Yes, please do.
The rest is downstairs. A full truck!
What do you say now?
Mr. Commissioner!
I am a victim of coincidence!
So you keep playing this game?
It's time for you to sit down at the table.
Oh, no thanks.
You've completely ruined my appetite.
The more detailed your confessions are
the shorter your sentence will be.
Then I confess completely! Let me go!
Let's have a confrontation with the child. Bring him in!
Oh, I get it. It was that bastard Rémi who betrayed us all.
You are wrong. We didn't get a word out of him.
Father Driscoll!
I swear I didn't say a single word!
- Oh, you...
- It's true!
This boy insists that he never stole and doesn't know anything.
But this is true. He never suffered from anything.
He never worked.
What can I say? It's not his fault.
- He's talentless.
- So he's not with you?
He would be! He would be had he not been given to you.
Now I know how play a philanthropist
and raise little children who don't have a family.
Let the child go.
So he is an adopted child?
- Where is he from?
- How curious you are!
I'll give you five minutes to think about your answer.
I found him in a cabbage.
I recommend that you don't play the fool.
Think about it.
Driscoll!
Your only chance to escape harsh punishment is
to lay out the whole truth.
Oh, it's silly now to clink glasses to each other's health.
But even if I tell you the name of the culprit, you will think I'm joking.
Tell me anyways.
Well, the culprit is Mr. James Milligan.
James Milligan? What are you...?
See? What did I tell you?
Go find Mr. Milligan at his house.
No, no, don't bother. He's not there.
- How do you know?
- Because he is at my house.
Your house?
This is Papa's house here.
Yes, but we must hurry!
Papa! Papa!
He's not here. Surely he will be back in time for dinner.
Tell me, my dear, where did you find this locket?
I'll show you where I got it.
It was lying there.
But...
This gown...
This embroidery...
I've been looking for them for so many years!
I absolutely need to see your father immediately!
Only he can tell me...
- Oh, Lady Milligan!
- Rémi!
How is it you?
Arthur will be delighted!
Me too, madame!
Do you know where Mr. Driscoll is?
I need to see him immediately.
No.
But... Where did you get that?
Do you know these clothes?
Of course! Mother Barberin often showed them to me in Chavanon.
Did she tell you who they belonged to?
Well, yes. To me!
You?
They were on me when Father Barberin found me.
Oh, but... My little one, you know...
I'm your mother!
My mother? My real mother?
James Milligan?
You must be mistaken!
What would he be doing here?
Madame...
So this is your first condemnation?
How long will they give us?
A year in prison. Maybe two.
I'm getting a long time because of this idiot!
Tell me, Mr. Commissioner. In prison,
are husband and wife kept in seperate cells?
- Naturally.
- Oh, then I'll tell you what!
Put me down for five years.
Idiot!
Do you think it's too early?
No, no, they should have gotten up by now. It'll be fun!
Attention!
Oh, my Lola! loved you madly!
I left my heart in Italy!
Since then, my thoughts have followed you everywhere!
My unhappy wounded soul suffers from longing!
Day and night, I dream of you, my sweet beloved
In your eyes, is a delicate mirror, I think I it see again
Italy!
- Good morning, Mother!
Good morning, Mother Barberin! Come down quickly! There's a surprise for you!
Come quickly, Mother Barberin!
There is a surprise for you!
A surprise?
This is the gift he wanted to give you for his twelfth birthday!
With his first savings!
Did you buy me a car?
No, much better! Look!
What a beauty!
My little Rémi!
Will you call her Roussette, Mother Barberin?
Lucky you! You have two mothers!
I'll lend you mine.
Well, Rémi, my old friend! Now we can't say that we are without a family.