My grandma says two things in this world
will always lack flavor:
meals without pickles,
and life without love.
Pickles, I make sure to carry enough,
when coming back to America from Punjab,
so that I can relish them
on pizza and burgers.
I've quite a few memories
attached to them.
This is something
I've learnt from my grandma.
Always cherish the memories
of the things you love.
Treasure these memories in your heart.
It's been decades since she left Lahore,
but the smallest of things remind her
of its lanes, neighborhood and her house.
And when the memories
of her house come to life,
so does the fragrance of its soil
and the taste of its delicacies.
I understood her idea about the pickles
as soon as I moved to America,
but her idea about love,
it'll take me some time
to figure that out.
I'm really sorry.
I don't want your apology.
This is your responsibility.
I'm sorry, sir.
-We'll be careful next time.
-Of what? What is left?
You have already managed
to lose my dog,
and break my father's cinerary urn.
What you need to be careful about
is your partner.
Your company is called Gentle,
but it's filled with fools.
-Sorry.
-Nothing can beat old music, Auntie.
Old music lasts forever.
Like Rahman Sir… No, he is not that old.
Like Rafi Sir.
Sardar too loves listening to his songs.
Careful.
Oh, ho!
Safe and sound.
-Don't worry.
-Safe.
We'll check the sound as well.
This music box is my mom's life.
Beautiful.
It's working.
Brother, this must have
reminded you of your father.
Really?
Let's get back to work.
What's going on?
Sorry.
Oh, no!
-Are you okay?
-Yes.
All okay? You are okay? All good?
Oh, ho!
How is it my fault?
Don't get emotional. Forget it.
Amreek, listen to me.
Don't walk away. Listen.
She had fond memories
attached to that music box.
Why attach memories
to materialistic things?
They'll eventually break.
Drop it. It's not my fault.
-Let's watch the match.
-It's never your fault.
-Right.
-You lose his dog,
you break the cinerary urn,
then you say,
"Oh, ho, how is it my fault?"
You tear the books
and say, "We'll fix them."
You make a mess and say,
"We'll make it spic and span."
Amreek, you pack a fish
and a cat together!
-To help them bond.
-I just don't understand your talent.
How… How do you manage to do this?
Please tell me.
-How do you manage to do this, huh?
-What?
You can never prepare a grocery list,
but when it comes to my faults,
you always have a list ready.
Do I point out your faults?
You aren't perfect. I don't say anything.
You can't apologize
so you start accusing me.
You keep making up things.
-Do you want me to list your faults?
-Yes, please. Yeah?
"Amreek, when you come,
please leave your shoes outside."
"Wear these other shoes and go inside."
I am entering my own house and not a gym!
And… This!
"Please eat fruits. It is very healthy."
-So?
-I am a man, not a monkey!
And this, your favorite!
"These magnets
should be perpendicular to the ground."
Don't touch them.
Will the refrigerator stop cooling
if the magnets are moved?
-Look, does it stop if I move…
-Don't…
You only know how to break things, Amreek.
You could just never fix them.
Radha! Drop it. I won't do it next time.
Please just drop it.
I'm done with your next time.
-What do you mean?
-Done means you and I are over.
Who will take care of Gently Gently?
I mean, who will take care of me?
-I was just joking.
-I don't believe you just said that.
Do you care about anything
other than the company, huh?
Me or anything else for that matter?
You have nothing to do
with anyone's emotions.
Yes, I don't get emotions. Should I leave?
This is the problem, Amreek.
Whenever we discuss this,
you start saying,
"I should leave. I should run away."
Actually, it's my mistake.
I have expectations from the wrong guy.
How can someone
who cannot face his family ever face me?
I don't want to face anyone!
Neither my family nor you!
This is who I am!
I am like this only.
Take it or leave it.
Okay?
This separation
I can endure you being away from me
I cannot tolerate
You being upset with me
My love
No…
Listen to what the eyes express
My love
Forever in my heart
I want you to stay…
Would Goldie and you
like to go on a date with me?
Without you, I cannot survive
I am surely going to die
When you get upset with me, I shatter
Don't ever break my heart
Don't ever leave me
My love, please don't ever break my heart
Don't ever break my heart
Don't ever leave me
My love
Please don't ever break my heart…
-Radha?
-Yes?
You want to be my partner?
-Gently, Gently.
-Cheers.
Just tell me
Why do you love me so much?
I'm not an angel
The world laughs at my fate
You don't know what you mean to me
You own my body and soul
If you leave, I too will cease to exist
Don't ever break my heart
Don't ever leave me
My love, please don't ever break my heart
Don't ever break my heart
Don't ever leave me
My love
Please don't ever break my heart…
Radha…
this isn't the first time we have fought.
You also overstepped.
You dragged my family into this.
Did you really have to?
I mean, I know I was wrong.
I accept it was my fault.
But who can understand me
better than you, huh?
No one.
You know, I said it
on the spur of the moment…
Hi.
Kiddo, Sardar
has taken a turn for the worse.
There's more.
She is insisting on going to Lahore.
Tell me, how can someone who can barely
make it to the bathroom on her own,
travel to Lahore?
This is just absurd.
She doesn't listen to anyone
other than you.
That's why I want you here
as soon as possible. Got it?
Yes.
And why do you look like a forlorn lover?
Better clean up your act
before you come home.
Got it?
-Bye.
Radha…
Why don't you go on a diet, huh?
What are you doing, Sardar?
-You eat all day.
-Jogi, take him away.
Sorry, doctor.
This is the limit, Sardar.
-Go. Get down, boy. Go, boy.
-You've turned a hospital into a park.
How many doctors were there?
Three, Sardar.
And just one tumor.
Yet they couldn't manage
to get it out of my body.
Shame on those assholes!
-Sardar, they can at least try.
-Rubbish!
Trying isn't good enough.
It doesn't guarantee results.
Doctor, let's go outside and talk.
Please come with me.
Where are you going? Ponty!
What are you conspiring against me?
So what has he smuggled in?
Coffee?
What!
At least smuggle in something
worth the effort.
Dimwits.
Look, we have already
tried radiation on the tumor.
I don't think she can take
any other surgery at this frail age.
She may be young at heart,
but the fact is that she's 90 years old.
So, Dr. Ponty, what will be our next step?
So what I suggest is, you take her home
and make her
as comfortable as you can. Please.
Gurki.
What are you two gossiping about?
Gurkeerat, come here.
What happened?
He's shouting
without sharing anything useful.
How will the new 2,000 rupee note look?
Stop worrying about others
and start looking after yourself.
What did the three monkeys say?
They said that you are
absolutely fit and fine.
Oh, I'd make them a part of my will
had they said that in front of me.
Come on, how many people
do you plan to add to your will?
Tell me, what do we do
with this tumor of mine?
Tumor… Well…
Speak up.
Take these pills
and the tumor will disappear.
-Really?
-Yes.
-Let's go then.
-Oh, ho! What are you doing?
You just said I am fit and fine.
It's all good.
Then let's go to Lahore.
Like there is a cab outside
you can hop in and reach Lahore.
We'll plan it
after you get discharged tomorrow.
You know who's coming here
to meet you tomorrow?
-Bhajji?
-No.
Amreek.
Oh, Amreek from America.
-Yes.
-He finally starts missing his grandma?
Hey, am I going to kick the bucket?
What do you mean?
Am I going to die soon?
What are you saying?
Don't say such things.
Okay, make a call to Amreek.
How many single malt were they?
Around 12, Sardar.
-How many do you plan to get?
-Two.
Shame on you, son of a gun!
Hey, you are cursing your own child.
Forget that
and tell me what's with this sad face?
Let's talk once I get there.
You aren't going anywhere.
Stay home and rest.
Hey, I am going to Lahore.
Didn't your dad tell you that?
What? Are you crazy?
Who goes on a world tour at this age?
-Just stay home and rest. Got it?
-That's what I told her.
Age be damned.
Tell me, why this sad face?
Bye, see you soon.
Huh? Oye! Oye!
Oye! He disconnected the call.
What do I tell them?
Taxi, sir?
Sir, taxi?
Taxi, ma'am, taxi? Taxi, ma'am?
Taxi? Taxi, sir?
Taxi?
Sir, taxi? Taxi, sir?
No, my family is picking me up.
There's a lot of traffic. You'll be home
before your family gets here.
My family's picking me up, thank you.
-Sir, taxi?
-Okay, sir. As you wish.
Taxi, sir?
Will there be traffic on the way home?
Don't worry, sir, just get in.
Stop, stop!
Joginder!
Damn.
What a welcome!
Amreek, you are the first person
to enter his own house like, a thief!
Stop! Stay!
-He bit me.
-Amreek, my child!
This dog is crazy.
Get him to stop. Take him away.
Don't break the bottles
in the duty free bag.
He won't stop barking. Stop barking!
Kiddo. Take him away.
How are you, kiddo?
How do you think?
Is that dog crazy? He bit me!
-Why are you late?
-I'm not. No one came to receive me.
Talk to your dad about it.
Didn't I ask you to send a car for him?
What happened?
Lovely bhaiya took that car with him.
-Lovely?
-Hey!
So what's the big deal?
It's not like he sold it.
He took it as he had a meeting.
Mom messaged on the way,
"Since you are there, could you please…"
-It's my fault that I asked you.
-How is it my fault?
-You're never at fault.
-What have I done?
Careful there.
This is my wheelchair,
not a video game remote.
You should look after me.
Please me
and I'll make you a part of my will.
Then you'll never have to work again.
-How many times will you say that?
-Hello, Sardar Kaur from Lahore.
Hey, Amreek from America!
Come, give me a hug.
Sit.
Now will you tell me,
what's with this sad face?
My fiancée is now my ex.
So you are miserable
because she has become your ex,
or has she become your ex
because she had made you miserable?
Tell me.
What happened, kiddo? What is wrong?
Amreek?
Stop crying, my boy. Come here.
It's okay. Stop crying.
Your dog bit me.
You were expecting
a miracle from your son, huh?
How can someone
who cannot control himself control Sardar?
Give him some time.
I am sure he has something on his mind.
He has lost his mind
after going to America.
Ever since Sardar dropped him
from the dining table when he was little,
he starts crying for no reason at all.
Our son's not crazy.
Wouldn't you cry if I pushed you down
from the dining table?
Why would you push me?
Look at this.
Already changing everything to your name?
Act your age, don't act smart.
Tell me, how is the design?
Design is fine, but the name is wrong.
-It should be Amreek.
-Why?
He's Sardar's favorite.
Champion Cycles' owner.
He is back, brother.
But Sardar promised
that she'd make me its CEO.
Yes, of course.
Like she has fulfilled
all the promises she has made so far.
Pinky!
Why did he have to come back?
Why couldn't he keep running
his company Mentally Mentally?
Gently Gently.
Gently, mentally, what-every.
Lovely was doing such a good job
handling the company.
I'm sure Gurki felt threatened.
He asked Amreek to come back.
He feared Sardar
might transfer everything to Lovely.
But the hopes of millions of Indians…
What's this "hmm"?
I am not telling you a story!
You are always glued to the television.
-I say something, you say "hmm."
-What are you doing?
No one here takes any responsibility
while I keep worrying.
-Good night, Simi.
-Good night!
Honey and your step-brother
were talking about Amreek.
Why does it matter? He's still
my brother from the same mother.
Yes, you two have the same mother,
but it was your father who started
the Cycle Company in Lahore.
But it is Gubji's father
who helped the company grow.
Planting the sapling is important,
but watering it is equally important.
So you are siding with Lovely now.
See for yourself. Lovely is doing
a good job running the company.
Our company would've shut down
if we'd followed Amreek's ideas.
Even Einstein would have been a nobody
had no one believed in his ideas.
You mean
we have given birth to an Einstein?
I don't know,
but his ideas were mind-blowing.
-It's just that no one trusted him.
-Of course, he is Newton.
-Didn't end up with the right family.
-You have to have the final say.
Anyway, it's good
that our son is back at the right time.
If he stays in her good books,
Sardar will surely make him
a part of her will.
Why are you staring at me?
There's no use being practical with you.
That's Sardar for you
Always a menace
Causes trouble
Then making a run for it…
-Come and have your milk.
-Get today's newspaper.
You know he wants you
to make the morning tea.
Where's my blazer, Mom?
-Son!
-Did anyone iron it?
Someone get me butter with these parathas.
Excellent
Everyone loves it
Nowhere to run-run, nowhere to hide
Unique and different is my vibe
Fill your heart and your soul with love
Divinity fuels the light within
Give it 100%
And take it upon yourself to win
Excellent
Chasing the horizon
Going for the dream
Excellent
Blessings all around
Chasing the horizon
Excellent
Going for the dream
Blessings all around
Excellent
I saw.
They are relaunching the hi-end cycle.
Whose idea was it?
-Bubbly worked hard.
-Not Bubbly, Lovely.
Whatever.
Your idea was good,
but your timing wasn't.
If you'd given me some time,
the timing would've worked out.
What do you keep saying?
You dropped me from the dining table,
so I am a little idiotic?
I have to say, son,
you are just like the rest.
Everyone knows that I'll soon be gone,
so they keep coming to me
with their sob stories.
Stop the melodrama, Sardar.
God will reject your request.
He doesn't want a headache.
What request will He cancel
when I didn't send Him any?
Come here.
Come on.
I said come here.
Take me to Lahore.
You'll have my word.
I'll make you
the Champion of Champion Cycles.
I have your word?
Sardar Kaur from Lahore…
What is it that you seek in Lahore?
When this country was divided,
a part of my soul remained there.
I have a house there,
which I had built with your grandfather.
I want to go to that house.
Old age does make people go bonkers.
What about you?
You've gone bonkers at such a young age.
I've been deranged since childhood,
ever since you dropped me
from the dining table.
Sardar, your cold coffee.
This is it.
Our raddled home.
You could have just called it our abode.
Why did you have to call it raddled?
Birds build their homes
one twig at a time.
We too will build ourselves one.
Is this the imported liquor you stole?
Yes, it is.
Try it. Cheers.
Perfect.
A small effort by me, for our abode.
This…
If not used for our home,
of what use are they to me?
I want to belong to you
I am all yours, my love
I don't seek the stars or the moon
I just want my love
Wherever he resides
Will be the home of mine
I'll endure everything with a smile
Wherever he resides
Will be the home of mine
I'll endure everything with a smile
I want your word, my love…
I belong to you
Don't you ever leave me
Don't let our love fall weak…
I belong to you
Don't you ever leave me…
-Higher, higher.
-Okay.
That side. Over there, over there.
A little lower.
Is it okay now?
Oh, ho!
I belong to you
Don't you ever leave me
Can you bring it closer?
I belong to you
Don't you ever leave me
You still love
having cold coffee in winter…
Fine.
Don't get emotional.
I'll go with you.
-It's not easy to get a visa for Pakistan.
-Okay.
But you'll get the approval
because of your green card.
Thank you, sir. My grandmother
doesn't have a green card.
I hope it won't be an issue.
-We'll see what can be done.
-Okay.
-Impossible.
-Impossible?
Why, sir?
Because your grandmother is…
Blacklisted.
Sardar is a YouTube viral star.
Today, during India-Pakistan's
friendly match in Mohali,
an elderly woman
from Amritsar caused havoc
by pulling the beard
of a government official from Islamabad.
Bhajji, you monkey!
She pulled his beard
and abused him verbally.
How dare you call Bhajji a monkey!
You're a monkey!
She claims that
the government official from Pakistan…
You are from a family of apes!
…addressed India's bowler Harbhajan
as monkey.
You are laughing?
You have an anti-national status
in Pakistan because of that guy.
Congratulations.
Oye! He called my Bhajji a monkey.
-So you broke a bottle on his head?
-Yes.
You know the problem is, you only know
how to break things, not fix things…
What's wrong with him? Huh?
Amreek,
the news reporters claim the world
is going to end in two years.
Then go and save it.
Like I care.
I'll be dead in a few years anyway.
You cannot sleep at night
because of these weird dreams of yours.
Then why don't you tell me a story
and help me sleep?
The story of your break up.
My break up story is not a bedtime story.
Fine, then crack open a bottle a whiskey.
Hurry up.
Be patient.
It's the one Grandpa gave you, isn't it?
No, it's not.
It's imported liquor.
I am sure we'll find it someday.
He stole it from an Englishman.
He made you a drink, a large one,
and then proposed to you.
-Right?
-Right.
-Cheers.
Then came the storm
that ruined everything,
and I ended up spending
the rest of my life in his memories.
Long live Pakistan! Long live Pakistan!
Break the doors!
No one should escape!
Get everyone!
No infidel's house should survive.
Gursher Singhji,
this house is our symbol of love.
It is our Taj Mahal.
I had a dream
when we laid down its foundation.
We'd always stay here
with our three children.
-This house is small for three kids.
-No, it isn't.
After some time, we'll buy
the surrounding land and expand our house.
Then this entire lane will be known
as the Champion Cycles owner's lane.
Then our kids and their kids too…
will have their homes in this lane.
We both will relax
and lounge here on our chairs,
under the moonlight.
-Really? Then?
-Then what?
Our story will end.
Don't you dare die before I do.
Otherwise,
there'd be no one to worry about me.
I promise.
When the time comes,
we both will leave together.
Then you too have my word.
You will have to keep your word, mister.
If we leave this country,
you'll have to carry the house along,
on your head.
I will, I certainly will.
Junior too likes that thought, Gursherji.
Destroy their homes!
Not a single house of theirs
should remain standing.
Live long Pakistan!
It is so difficult
when someone comes to you and says,
that your house is no longer your own.
Your country is no longer your own.
Fine.
Even if we manage to get there, Sardar,
everything must have changed by now.
The lanes and the neighborhoods
won't be the same.
Your home
and the people you knew won't be there.
My home will still be there, son.
Nothing will have changed there.
That home is filled with memories.
The paint on its walls perhaps has faded,
but the memories surrounding them
are too strong to fade.
I had graced it with love.
Just like you two
graced Gently Gently with your love.
No.
Come on now, show me a picture of her.
Come on, Sardar.
How can I expect you to like it here
when you've left your heart there?
You are missing her?
I never stopped thinking about her.
I can understand.
I never stop thinking
about Gursher Singhji either.
You mean you have been feeling like I do…
for the past 70 years?
When Gursher Singhji left this world,
a part of me left with him too.
I have been feeling his void nonstop…
for the past 70 years.
That's why I wanted
to go back home and fill that void.
Before I breathe my last breath,
I want to sit next to it…
and fill the void.
That's all.
Joginder.
-Yes.
-Let's go.
How about a road trip…
from Amritsar to Lahore?
Really?
You'll take me there?
Come hell or high water,
I'll help you fill the void, Sardar.
Promise.
Thank you.
Some official made a mistake.
It's not like it's written by God
that it cannot be changed.
Sorry, sir, I cannot offer you
anything other than my apology.
I have come here with a lot of hope, sir.
Please do something about it.
-You don't get it.
-No, you don't get it.
This is not possible.
Sir, it is my grandma's last wish.
She wants to go to Lahore.
I can understand, but…
No, sir, you do not understand.
Listen, give me some time.
She doesn't have the time.
Sir, she doesn't have much time left.
Can you give me two days?
Give me just two days.
Give me two days
and I'll see what I can do.
-Thank you, sir. Two days, right?
-You're welcome.
-Sir…
-Who'd believe that
our 90-year-old Sardar wants to go
to Pakistan for a heart transplant?
Like we don't have hearts or doctors here.
And you don't have any brains.
Stop bothering me. Go study.
Why are you so rude, man?
-Move!
-Hey!
Kids these days.
Radha.
Chain mail?
Yes? Hello?
Hello, this is Qureshi
from the Pakistan High Commission.
Sir! Yes, sir.
I have been waiting for your call, sir.
We had considered your request
on humanitarian grounds.
Thank you, sir. Thank you, thank you.
I said we had considered it.
What do you mean?
Actually…
the high commission has rejected
your grandma's application
because of her hot temper.
Anyway, you can go to Lahore.
I can say with certainty that
you'll come back with lots of memories.
We are unable to do anything
about grandma's memories,
but you want her next generation
to come back with memories?
I should go to Lahore
and bring the house back in my pocket.
No one will know, correct?
Today, we are going to talk about someone
who, in a small town in America,
managed to relocate a 100-year-old tree
20 miles away from its original location.
The name of the company
that pulled off this miracle is
Gently Gently Packers and Movers,
which is run by an Indian, Ms. Radha.
Let's talk to her.
Please tell us something
about this amazing feat.
Hi.
This tree that you see is 100 years old.
So our team had to move it
quite carefully.
We thought that if in this day and age,
one can move big homes
from one place to another,
then why not save a tree
along with its roots?
Roots or foundations of anything old
are often quite strong,
so it's quite easy to move them
once you get a hold on them.
I would like to give the credit
of this hard work to my team.
Sardar cannot go to her house in Lahore,
but her house in Lahore
can certainly come to her.
It'll no longer be a homecoming,
now the home is coming.
An Indian's house in Pakistan
being brought back to India.
It will certainly increase your followers.
By millions.
You should set up a meeting at the least.
Then we lift it,
like relocating a structure.
Take a temple for example.
We lift the temple like this and then…
-Then what do we do?
-What's going on, guys?
Nothing.
I was showing her Netflix on YouTube.
I'll be right back. Bye.
Sir! I just need
to talk to you for two minutes.
I am quite busy.
Why don't you speak to Asif.
-Attend to his queries.
-I want to talk to you, not Asif.
-I'll handle it.
-Sir!
Please, sir!
-I'll pass on your message.
-Just two minutes.
It is difficult to relocate a house,
but it is not impossible.
In technical terms,
it is known as structural relocation.
Take a look, sir.
We support the house with the help
of steel girders to avoid any accidents.
Then we lift it up
with the help of jacks, just like…
Sir, you have a tire?
I mean, you own a car, right?
Just like we lift a car with the help
of a jack to replace a flat tire,
we'll lift the house
with the help of the jacks.
Then we'll slowly shift it on to a truck
so that we can safely transport it.
We wrap it up, pack it, to ensure
that it doesn't move from its place,
and we can take it
from one place to another.
It's a common recurrence, sir.
When redeveloping highways and roads,
this is how we relocate temples.
This team that you see,
I am in touch with them.
No, I am in touch with them.
I am very, very confident we can do this.
I am sure about it.
The only thing we need from you, sir, is…
the permission of the mayor of Lahore.
Okay.
Sir, shifting a house from one country
to another is not a big deal,
if we keep our egos in check.
If we accept it
with an open heart and see this,
we are bringing
that house here, just like…
A villager would bring
a jar of ghee with him to the city.
Exactly, sir.
Or a jar of pickles.
I hope you got me, ma'am.
-Tell me something.
-Yes, sir?
What'd the Pakistan High Commission say?
I am in touch with them.
I haven't gotten permission,
but it'll be handled. I'll get it.
Same case with everything related to them.
Anyway, you have our support.
-Thank you.
-He means you have our moral support.
-He is right.
-Yes.
What do I do with moral support?
We mean, we support you,
but there's nothing official about it.
Yes.
Because if we initiate it
and they back out,
then our scores will dip.
-Right.
-Score?
What scores are you keeping?
This isn't a badminton match between kids.
This isn't fair.
The thing is, Pakistan can back out
from a promise any time.
Exactly.
-Then people will laugh at us.
-Right.
That's why you have our full support,
but we stay in the shadows.
Yes.
I mean, in this case India will be…
Mr. India?
Yes!
If you manage to bring your home back,
don't forget to tag the Ministry
of International Relations in your tweets.
-Right.
-Please remember that. Right, ma'am?
What company is helping you?
-Gently Gently.
-Huh?
Gently Gently.
Name of your other team members?
A. Radha Lakshmi.
Hello?
Hello, may I speak to Ms. Radha?
Speaking. How can I help you?
Take.
Hello?
Hello, Radha?
Hello? Amreek?
Can I talk to you? Just for two minutes?
Make it quick. I don't have time to waste.
-Sardar doesn't either.
-Why? What's wrong with her?
Tumor.
But that's not the reason I called you.
Actually, I need your help.
-Professional help.
-Professional?
Yes.
Sardar wants to visit her old house,
but it is in Lahore.
Radha, why do I feel
you won't be able to say no to this?
You feel wrong, Amreek.
I can't say I feel right or wrong,
but I certainly feel bad.
The fact is, like all your other plans,
you'll abandon this one as well.
You have a wrong image of me in your mind.
You call after so many days
because of work.
You won't help me
because I didn't apologize?
What is this if not your ego speaking?
You too could have called me.
Who asked me to leave, Amreek?
Thank you for giving me
your precious time.
You know what?
Good luck. Bye.
Thank you, bye.
She refused to help!
So, you are not going?
I am going there.
I am going there for sure.
And I'll do this without her help.
Why are we playing "I Spy," Mom?
Why am I spying on someone
instead of running the company?
Such an idiot!
Sometimes I doubt you're my child.
Pinky! Come here.
Why is your sense of style
so different than the rest?
Come here.
Let me check your scalp for dandruff.
I keep telling you to apply eggs,
try a conditioner, but you pay me no heed.
Your hair has become so dry.
It looks like a tail.
And you should pinch your cheeks
like this. They become rosy.
-It's all okay. You can go now.
-My whole family is crazy.
Mix an egg in the hair conditioner
and apply it.
Did you see or find anything useful?
Mom, tell me something.
The story of Amreek falling
from the dining table, is it true?
Yes it is, why?
He is planning to wrap up the house
in Pakistan and bring it back to India.
Will it still have all the things in it?
I am not talking
about the things inside the house.
The entire house.
From Pakistan to Amritsar.
Look carefully.
This is where we will lay its foundation.
Oh, ho! Don't worry, sir.
It will be handled.
I'll hold you responsible
if anything goes wrong.
Oh, ho! Leave everything to me, sir.
Get this straight.
No one other than you
knows that I am going there.
If anyone finds out,
I won't pay you a single penny.
This thing will stay between us
if you make the payment on time.
Let's go.
-Sukha! It's 30 by 40 square feet.
-Coming!
Let's get on with it.
So, what's going on out here, huh?
Did you get it?
If not for that fall
from the dining table…
Let's not discuss that again.
I am doing this for Sardar.
It's useless to share anything
with you two. A waste of time.
You weren't sharing.
It was me who found out
that no one should find out about it.
What will we tell Sardar
when she asks about your whereabouts?
Lovely will ensure the company gets
transferred to him while you are gone.
Can you think of anything
besides the company?
Well, I just have one son. My only child.
Why should I let him go to Pakistan?
Let him finish.
You are the one interrupting. Keep quiet.
Me? You're the one talking since morning.
-I won't stop talking?
-Right.
-You didn't say anything!
-Strange.
Can I say something?
Please.
Go ahead, kiddo. Shoot.
Sardar has promised…
to make me the CEO of Champion Cycles,
if I manage to take her to that house.
Simi!
Gurbaz would love some tea made by you.
This.
Once I bring Sardar's home back,
you won't ever have to worry
about Lovely or making tea.
Here, some snacks for the journey.
I am going to Pakistan,
not a school picnic.
-Keep it. What if you feel hungry?
-Fine.
-Sweater?
-Packed.
-Underwear?
-Mom!
What "Mom"? Digestive?
It's difficult to digest food abroad.
This is my first trip abroad?
Come on. Come here.
Stand still. Let me ward off the evil.
No one will cast an evil eye on me.
Don't forget to pack the coconut.
I'll go get the sweet yogurt.
Sorry.
I didn't think twice
before lashing out at you, son.
It's very easy
to lose one's temper at my age.
But you are young.
You should have just run away,
stayed out of my reach.
Do you want me to hold my ears
and apologize? Here, I am sorry. Sorry.
Please forgive me.
Poor little thing.
Is Amreek your favorite grandchild?
-Come on.
-Yes, of course.
This dog's her favorite.
Look at what she's done to him.
Where are you off to with your bag?
America, for some time.
I'll be back before you know it.
And what if I die before you come back?
No, Sardar. The thing is…
I know.
Your Gently Mentally must called you.
No, you don't get it.
And what about the promise
you had made me?
Weren't we supposed to go
to our home to Lahore?
I never said we won't be going.
Give me some time.
Pinky, you are my favorite grandchild.
Let's go.
Come on. Get out of my way.
Such a selfish boy.
He's going back to America.
He promised to take me to Lahore.
He's such a liar.
I've understood everyone's intentions.
Why don't you just kill me? Come on.
Look, we have broken all the past records.
Champion is reigning in the city.
I have made a five-year plan.
I intend to make Champion Cycles
an international brand.
I will make it the top brand.
Don't open the window.
Our child is feeling suffocated.
So am I.
But our child is feeling suffocated.
Use your brains.
I want some fresh air.
-Riots are taking place out there.
-But not in our lane, right?
Will people of our neighborhood
go against each other?
-Do we have any enemies here?
-No one is anyone's enemy.
But people are not
acting reasonable out there.
I don't care.
Everyone here is good,
irrespective of religion.
-Why don't you understand?
-I don't want to understand.
We all fought for our country's freedom,
so that we fear
and hide from our own countrymen?
You want to stay hidden here?
Everyone is right. You are indeed crazy.
If you think I am crazy, then so be it.
Get this straight, mister.
This crazy woman
wants to spend her life with you.
Do you get it?
Sardar! Open the door!
Break Sardar's door!
Break it!
Break it, guys!
Let's just break it!
Break the door!
We will kill everyone!
-Long live Pakistan!
-I have never refused you anything.
Don't be stubborn today.
-Come what may, don't step out.
-Break the door!
Don't spare anyone! Attack!
Oh, mere mortal
Why didn't you tell Sardar?
What's the use of telling her beforehand?
I am known for abandoning things halfway.
If I make a mistake this time…
I didn't want to break her heart.
You won't tell her anything
until I see this through.
Okay? You won't tell her anything.
Okay, I won't tell her anything.
We belong to Khalsa.
All victories belong to Him.
Life is slipping away
The ground is melting
Your sun has no luster
Your shore is miles away
But you need to keep walking
You need to keep walking, my friend
The blisters on your feet
Will be your guiding light
Stay determined and keep moving
Oh, mere mortal
God is with you
You are as strong as iron
Your courage is tremendous
You can win the world
Oh, mere mortal
God is with you
The Lahore Fort. What do you think of it?
It's just like our Red Fort.
So tell me, where do you want to go?
Sheesh Mahal, Lahore Fort?
What would you like to see?
No, I am only interested
in Kabootarwali Gully.
I get it.
You are not interested
in famous monuments.
That's a shortcut.
You'll have to go on foot from here.
-This is it?
-Yes.
Excuse me. Where's 36 Kabootarwali Gully?
God is the savior of all pathways.
36 Kabootarwali Gully?
The lane on the left is a shortcut.
I take that route.
Why don't you take a left,
no take a right.
First right or left, sir?
Left. First left then right.
Thanks.
Enter the roundabout,
take the second exit. Turn left.
Can I have two dozen eggs?
-Two dozen?
-Yes, pack some bread as well.
I need to make
all the preparations, sister.
What are you saying?
Yes, please.
Oh, God.
They are demolishing that house.
Excuse me, where's house number 36?
Don't make a video.
Excuse me, please.
Move back, everyone. Please move back.
What are you doing?
You will die! Hey!
Are you crazy? Stop!
Move aside!
Someone stop him! He has gone crazy.
Get down! Get down!
Do you want to kill me? It's too high.
Stop it, please.
What have you gotten me into, Sardar?
Who are you? Have you lost your mind?
Get down.
This is my grandma's house.
This is why I am here.
I have come
to take this house back to India.
Take the house?
Where did this lunatic come from?
He has lost his mind.
Someone get him off it. Get him down.
Why? How can you break anyone's house?
He is right.
You cannot just break anyone's house.
Hey, you are a tea-maker.
Go make tea. Mind your own business.
Listen? He really left to make tea!
Hey you, bring it down.
-Stop.
-Why did you guys let him through?
-Let's just talk this out.
-Hey!
While you are holding a brick?
He didn't hit you with it.
A person can't defend himself?
You're back? Don't you have any shame?
Want me to teach you a lesson?
But this kid is right.
Oh, I see.
You two have planned it together.
Plan? What plan?
The plan to take over
someone else's property.
You've illegally taken it over
for the past year.
He is not with me.
Let me talk to the person in charge.
Okay, I'll call him. Call the police.
He wants to talk to the person in charge.
Hurry up. It'll soon be six o'clock.
We need to finish this job and pack up.
I'll call the police.
-Look at the time.
-Hello.
We need to do something
or they'll demolish the house.
No, no, no. What do we do?
Yes.
You can't just demolish anything!
You just can't!
-Contractor, go back, go back!
-Go back, go back!
What is this nonsense?
-Go back… Contractor…
-Contractor, shame on you!
-Listen to me. Let me go.
-Tarzan!
The kid's saying something.
Let me hear. Yes, tell me.
Hey!
The key!
Stop!
-Tarzan, this way.
-Stop calling me that!
Stop. Where are you taking them? Stop!
The keys…
-Give me the key.
-Here you go.
Are you crazy?
Why did you throw it up there?
-We'll use the ladder.
-Yes, let's go inside.
-This one!
-This one is faster?
Help. This ladder
will get us up there faster.
Please help me out.
-Yes, set it up.
-Come on, come.
-Hold it, I'll climb the ladder.
-Get down.
We will take turns to climb up.
Are you crazy? I'll go first.
I will not spare you.
Did you call me a child?
-I called you Chhote.
-Stop!
Did you call me a child?
Where do you think you are going? Stop!
-Come down!
-No!
Sorry!
-I got the keys!
-Throw it down.
Give it to me.
-Why did you throw the key away?
-Sorry.
The police are here.
Hold this.
Where are you going?
To save my hide.
-Hey, mister. Who are you?
-Yes?
Who is this crazy boy?
Why have you caused havoc?
Troubling everyone unnecessarily.
If my temperament changes…
Sir, that is my ancestral home. That one.
-This house belongs to Uncle Feroz.
-Before the partition.
My grandma had said that it used to belong
to some cycle company owner.
Yes, before the partition took place.
Champion Cycles.
My grandfather built it.
I'm taking it back for my grandma.
-A devotee of Lord Hanuman, are you?
-Huh?
Take the mountain instead of the herb?
If your grandma wants to see the house,
then bring her here.
She cannot come here.
It's a long story
and she doesn't have too long.
She… Hear me out, sir.
What are you doing, sir?
Please hear me out, sir. Sir.
Pack up!
-Take him away.
-Let's go, mister.
We'll surely demolish this house tomorrow.
Any fake documents?
No, sir. All of them are in order.
He's from Punjab, Amritsar.
A non-resident, a green card holder.
His name is Amreek Singh.
I made a call to the Delhi authorities.
They gave me the same reason.
Get him. Get his highness inside.
Also call the builder, Mr. Khan.
-Oh, this is so simple. So very simple.
-Yes.
-Correct.
-Why don't you do this?
As you are already here,
take the entire nation with you.
You can find a nice green patch in Punjab
and place it there.
Sir… Do you have 4G network?
What will you do? Click a selfie with me?
-Later. Look at this video.
-I am not interested.
-Please.
-What is it?
A computer can make
a video of shopping on Mars.
-Forget Mars. Look.
-It is a lie.
It's Earth.
They lift and place it on a truck.
Have a look. It is true, sir.
This is how I will take it, sir.
Without troubling anyone.
Sir, where is that despicable man?
I lost 200,000 rupees because of him.
-Mr. Khan, relax.
-No one ever claimed that wreckage.
Suddenly, someone shows up
and claims it's his house.
I want to meet him
and find out what he wants.
Do you know the loss I incurred?
You owe me 200,000! Shell it out.
Why do I owe you?
For what, sir? It is my house.
I won't let
any of your usurping plans succeed.
What plan?
Usurping what, sir? It is my house.
-What will you do?
-As I please.
-Make poppadums on its rooftop?
-Yes. It is my house.
I'll file a case against you.
I won't spare him.
Old age does make everyone go bonkers,
Sardar included.
They keep shouting for no good reason.
Should I run away?
No, my bag?
Passport?
This is great. Amazing.
Come, give me a hug.
Why didn't you tell me
that you were from Amritsar?
-What's the connection with this?
-A big connection.
I am from Amritsar.
I was born in Amritsar.
We used to own a huge bakery,
Khan's Bakery. Have you ever heard of it?
Come, I'll treat you to a Lahori tea.
-Come.
-Sir, I want the house, not the tea.
You will get the house. Let's go.
Listen, you know…
My bakery was next to it.
If it is so famous,
it'll surely be on the Internet.
I wouldn't need to ask you
if it was on the Internet.
-You can take whatever you want.
-Really?
The land is what I am after.
I won't give that to you.
Nor will I let you stay here.
Let me make that clear.
I don't want the land.
That house belongs to my grandma.
I want to take it back. That's it.
You can take your grandma's house.
I have nothing to do with that structure.
May Allah bless you.
Thank you for giving it back to me.
-I cannot thank you enough.
-Be happy.
I'll treat you to a Lahori tea.
I'm yearning for it.
Let's go.
To get the house,
you first need to bail yourself out.
Uncle!
Sir, I am here from the Indian Embassy
to bail Amreek Singh out.
I can't find his passport, sir.
I had kept it here.
Check thoroughly. It must be there.
It is with me. Just to keep it safe.
Say something.
Hello? At least tell me
when will they release him?
Oye!
Stay away from me.
I went to jail because of you.
What did I do?
You stood before the crane like Tarzan.
Anyway, who would save the house
if I too had been arrested?
Shut up. Zip it.
You talk like you did all this to help me.
Oh, really? So you think God
sent the Indian Embassy staff here?
-How absurd!
-How absurd, indeed!
We are not interested
in getting into this mess.
That's me.
You are trending, mister.
On number four.
Please don't drag us with you
when the matter escalates.
Listen up.
The Indian Embassy
doesn't know anything about this,
or the fact that you were bailed out.
Got that?
Yes, Mr. India.
Thank you, sir.
-Why are you following me?
-What, you own the streets as well?
Quit following me. I won't pay you a dime.
No, sir. I don't want the money.
Just sign a paper saying
I'm the caretaker of this property.
Of your grandfather's house.
Then it'll be between the builder and me.
Why would I sign any documents?
A friend in need is a friend in deed.
Help me, and I might help you in this
foreign land whenever the need arises.
How can a tea seller possibly help me?
Your country keeps
underestimating tea sellers.
Anyway, it's cool.
Leave before I slap you.
Don't take my advice if you don't want to.
-Leave!
-I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
Bloody pest.
Gursherji…
please get our imported whiskey.
The others don't have the same kick.
Oh, ho! Please tell me
that was a glass and not the bottle.
-Nazneen?
-Yes.
-Washed the clothes?
-Hi, Dad.
-How are you, Amreek?
Calm down. Let me talk to him.
You are trending, kiddo.
I know, but make sure Sardar
doesn't find that out.
Fine.
Forget that.
I am going to meet the mayor.
I need Sardar's blessing.
Hand the phone to her.
Sardar. Look who wants to talk to you.
-Sardar!
-Just talk to him.
Dad, I cannot see her face.
Change the angle. Sardar!
How rude! What was the phone's fault?
Who breaks phones?
And who breaks promises?
Your son broke his.
My whole family is insane.
-Hello, sir.
-Yes?
Amreek Singh. I have an appointment.
Please have a seat.
During India-Pakistan's match in Mohali,
a woman from Amritsar caused havoc,
by pulling the beard of a senior
government official from Islamabad,
and cussing him.
Sir…
-Print it on the front page.
-Oh, no!
Saqlain Niazi.
Sir, if you could
please smile for the camera?
Sir, that man from India is here,
seeking your permission.
The one who wants to lift his house
and take it back to India.
People do such weird things
to stay in the news.
Right.
He thinks of himself as Sunny Deol.
Infiltrate enemy lines
and rescue the house.
Did we get any orders
from higher officials?
No, no official confirmation as of yet.
Very well.
You wanted to know how he works, right?
You'll now get
to see his style of working.
-His style of working?
-Well…
I tend to ignore all issues and riots,
as they tend to resolve on their own.
Delay the problem
and it will find its own solution.
-Call him.
-Okay.
I'll give you an example.
Please don't print this, sir.
Of course not, sir.
Look, I will hear him out.
Okay.
But come what may,
I won't react to it in any way.
Okay, sir.
Please come in.
-Please come in.
-It's okay. Come in.
Yes. Have a seat.
Now see how he defers it.
No. You cannot get this permission.
As long as I'm the mayor of Lahore,
I won't permit it.
My grandma isn't well.
Please reconsider it.
-Your grandma is crazy.
-You are the one who is crazy, sir.
You won't give us permission
because you're holding a grudge?
-This is not fair.
-Get lost before I have you thrown out.
-Get him out. Security!
-Let's talk.
-I have the permission to come here.
-Throw him out. Take him away.
-Let's talk.
-Take him away.
-Please hear me out.
-Get lost. Call the builder.
-Sir, I have…
-Raze that house to the ground.
-My grandma…
-Come with me.
Okay, okay. I am leaving.
Amreek's call.
Yes, kiddo?
I didn't get permission.
Why does this always happen to me?
My love story didn't work out.
The idea I had for our family business
didn't work out.
And the plan I had to fulfil
Sardar's dream also didn't work out.
It's okay. Don't feel disheartened.
You tried your best, didn't you?
Yes.
He didn't get permission.
I'm surprised that he expected
he’d get permission.
Movement of people is restricted
between the countries.
-He wants to bring a whole house.
-Hurry up!
Quick, come and check on Sardar.
-Oh, no!
-What happened, Sardar?
Why did you lie to me?
All of you are liars.
Who lied to you?
I know I am going to die.
I read all the reports.
Here, you read them!
What's the use of living anymore anyway?
I just asked for one thing.
I just wanted to go to Lahore.
But no one is interested in what I want.
Listen, Sardar, Amreek is working on it.
-As soon as he finds out…
-I don't care.
Why fill my body with poison
when I am going to die anyway?
I don't want to take these medicines!
Do whatever you please!
What happened? Did you get permission?
-Salaam alaikum.
-Alaikum salaam
-Mr. Khan.
-Yes?
Start demolishing the house.
Sorry.
I would have helped if I could.
It's okay.
A small gift for you.
Khan Bakery?
Thank you.
They will demolish it. It's not right.
They shouldn't demolish it.
Hurry up, mother. Walk faster.
There they go again.
-What is this nonsense?
-Those people…
There they go again.
All you need is a little hope,
and you will certainly get
the opportunity. Yes!
We have the right.
You cannot demolish this house.
You can't break this house.
Radha!
-Hi, guys!
-He's here…
-Hi.
Hey. Stop this drama.
Ever heard of K-P Antiquities Act 1997?
K-P 1997?
Isn't KP Kevin Peters?
What are you talking about?
I joined the force in '98.
The world won't come to an end if you know
something before you joined the force.
So you don't know. Let me explain.
You need special permission
from the archaeology department,
to break any structure
more than 70 years old.
Do you have their permission?
Do you have it? Please check.
-Let me check, sir.
-How do you know that?
Because an important
part of our job is called research.
Why bother with research?
I obviously didn't do it for you.
I am here to save the house.
I am here to do my job.
The mayor asked us to demolish the house.
What more permission do we need?
I am sure Mr. Khan
already has all the important documents.
-No. I don't have the permission.
-What are you saying, Mr. Khan?
Stay out of it.
There is a rule in place.
This concerns
the archaeological department.
They are senior officials,
so they will take their sweet time, right?
I suspect you have
another reason for all this.
And if my suspicion is right,
even the entire Indian embassy
won't be able to find you.
They won't need to find me, sir.
Both the countries will be
aware of every move that I make.
-Will this frame work?
-Yes.
-Come on then. Perfect. Ready?
-Rolling.
Sir, you have become
an Internet sensation.
When you were standing before the crane,
did you imagine
that your stunt would break the Internet?
No, madam,
I wasn't thinking about all this.
I did all this to save this house.
Is there a special reason
behind taking this house with you?
This house…
It is my ancestral home
that belongs to my grandma.
She is 90 years old and…
not keeping too well.
She is running out of time.
I just want to fulfil her last wish.
During the partition…
people had to leave
a part of their lives behind.
-So that's why…
-Let's record it.
…with the help of you guys…
With the help of Pakistani media,
I want to make a request…
Please help me fulfil
my grandma's last wish.
Please let me take this house.
Please.
Come on, hurry up. Tripods stay over here.
I want to fulfil her last wish.
That's me.
Please let me take my grandma's home.
Yes!
-Let me take my grandma's house.
-Do you think he'll do it?
Of course he will. He's my son after all.
That boy has become famous.
-Who?
-Look at this.
Please let me take my grandma's home.
Amreek Singh,
is attempting the impossible.
He's appealing to the Pakistani and…
This will go down in history
as a grandson's love for his grandma.
…to allow him to carry the house across…
Salaam alaikum.
This is your friend, Amreek Si…
-No, I am Amreek.
-Right.
I believe…
I want peace to be restored
between the two countries.
Any statement made by Pakistan yet?
Not yet, sir.
We won't make headlines
if they release their statement first.
-Make the call.
-Okay.
-Namaste.
-Salaam alaikum.
She is our country's grandmother.
And that house is our house.
That's why we should all welcome
this house back with open arms.
The news
about Kabootarwali Gully has reached me.
As soon as I heard it,
I felt that I should fulfil
my Indian sister's last wish.
When I learnt that
she is not keeping well…
Please have a seat.
Who am I to stop you
when our prime minister
has given you permission?
Permission isn't the only issue here.
You also need to ensure
a smooth ride back home.
Are you threatening us?
What makes you think this is a threat?
It is such a big truck.
It could easily have an accident.
What if the roads are in bad shape?
There are innumerous possibilities.
If it moves even a little from its place,
it's gone forever.
It isn't a suitcase
that you can easily put back.
So what do you want us to do?
First of all, ensure that
it causes no hindrance to anyone.
Okay, sir.
You'll need permission
for all the places you'll be passing,
irrespective of the time.
-Done, sir.
-Of course.
-Thank you.
-Hang on a second.
There's another condition
I haven't mentioned.
-That old hag of yours…
-Grandma.
She's my grandma.
Right.
She'll need to apologize to me.
She'll have to beg me for forgiveness.
-Listen to me. Talk to Sardar.
-He wasn't joking.
If he's in the mood to mess things up,
he won't let us take the house.
Sardar will never apologize
to that wrecker.
At least try to convince her.
Surely she's apologized to someone before.
You've met Sardar--
You haven't met her.
Sardar doesn't apologize to anyone.
-The whole family's like that?
-Radha, please don't drag--
Radha, my family. My family!
Family?
Hello, Pinky?
Please forgive me, son.
I didn't think twice
before lashing out at you.
Please take my age into consideration.
You are young, son. Do you want me
to hold my ears and apologize?
Here, I am sorry.
You should have just run away,
stayed out of my reach.
I am a mean old woman. Please forgive me.
Okay.
Fine, I'll sign it.
Thank you. Let's go.
Sir, why did you
give them permission so easily?
He doesn't know anything, Safiq.
He is only inviting
more trouble for himself.
He's going to have a bad fall one day.
Both him and his house.
Hey, why are you breaking the antenna?
Just pull the cables out.
There are too many televisions
in the house.
And the Internet?
I spilled some water on the router
and destroyed its cables.
Have you lost it?
Internet works on Sardar's phone
even without the Wi-Fi.
Sardar needs to have a phone
for the Internet to work.
Gurki, have you seen my phone?
-Oh, no. Let's go.
-What do we do?
-Your dog had your phone.
-He dropped it in his milk bowl.
We tried to dry it under the sun.
-We even used a dryer.
-We'll buy you a new one.
Why? It's under warranty.
As you can see,
they are widening the roads,
so they don't face any issues
bringing the house back.
-Speed up the work, guys.
-Sir, let me plan this through.
They have lost their minds.
This whole family is crazy.
-Wait.
-What is it?
That's a lot.
I'm only following doctor's orders.
-Are all of you happy now…
-Yes.
…that you're getting something?
What is all this, Sardar?
And the bangles that I had kept aside
for Amreek's future wife?
-You can have them, Meenu.
-Okay, ma'am.
How did Amreek harm you?
I don't like anyone
who breaks his promise.
First it was your father,
then it was your son.
They broke their promises
and my heart too.
Too loud.
What do I do?
God help us all. Such a nuisance!
There's so much noise, Mom.
We can't study.
Can't help it, dear.
-Are you blind?
-Sorry.
-He broke my board.
-Sorry, I'll pay for the damage.
-Don't you get it?
-What's wrong?
We have guests at home.
We've trouble commuting
due to the obstacles you've caused.
You're doing this in front of my house…
Bear with me.
I'm moving a house on a truck.
It's causing a lot of inconvenience.
-They broke the pipe.
-Where did that water come from?
What's going on, Radha?
Someone stop the water.
Hey, why did you stop the water supply?
-I need sacks.
-Put that.
Get me some sacks.
-It's my daughter's wedding.
-Where are the sacks?
Go, go, go…
Someone shut the mains off.
Stop the water.
You want more? You want more?
One more.
I told you to ensure that this does not
cause any inconvenience to anyone.
You have one hour.
Relax, Amreek.
Amreek, pipe.
Done, sir. Water pipe closed.
And gas diverted to Uncle Abdul.
And meter supply I have disabled also.
What are you staring at? Get back to work.
My champ!
Let's get back to work, guys.
-Kiddo.
-I seek your blessings.
Sardar's pain is unbearable now.
She has refused to take any medicines.
She's made our lives miserable
because we've disconnected
her Internet and television.
I think we should tell her
that you are bringing her home back.
Don't you dare. You will do no such thing.
Things can still go wrong.
Say nothing.
Hand her the phone.
I'll talk to her. She'll listen to me.
Yes, I'll make her talk to you.
That's better. Hurry up.
We can't chat on a video call.
Disconnect and make an audio call
or she'll learn the truth.
Hello.
-Put me on speaker.
-Yes, I'll put you on speaker.
Here, talk to her.
Why don't you want to see my face?
Or is it that you can't show me your face?
Sardar, the Wi-Fi isn't working.
We cannot make a video call. Talk to him.
Hey, Sardar Kaur from Lahore.
I am coming back soon,
and I have a big surprise for you.
So you need to take your medicines.
Or you'll die before you see the surprise.
Right? So quickly take the medicine.
Well, he'll be the one
who'll be surprised when he returns.
I'll be long gone by then.
What are you doing, Sardar?
It's a new phone.
What good is it without the Internet!
Don't be ridiculous. Hello?
Please, go back.
Yeah, like that…
This is Sadia from NewsPak.
They've begun
the process of moving the house.
It'll be lifted from the ground
and loaded on the truck.
It will then be carried
all the way to India.
Six hydraulic jacks--
Put the jack back in. Put it slowly.
Yeah, because even with--
-Is the angle an issue?
-Amreek, Radha. We're good to go.
The jack! How is it possible?
What's going on, Radha?
Be careful.
Get me the papers!
Calm down. What should we do now?
Everyone, calm down.
You guys do this every day.
A hydraulic jack has failed.
Who do you think we are,
people who fix flat tires?
It's not our job to load
such a heavy thing on a truck.
Puncture!
-Get them all. Amreek!
-Where did he go?
-Amreek brother!
-Be quiet.
Side. Move aside.
-Keep it coming.
-Please give way.
Move aside. Keep it coming.
-Car jacks.
-Keep it coming.
-How the hell does he plan to use that?
-Let's find out.
Get out of the way. Be careful.
Hey, don't go over there.
Move it to this side.
Balance. Move it slowly.
-Do it together.
-Now check the balance.
Hurry, before the house collapses.
You need to move it together.
Check the right one.
-Is it fixed?
-Wow.
What happened?
Is it balanced?
Yes.
Come.
Straight.
Keep it straight.
Yes, yes.
Come on, come on, come on.
Left, left, left.
Keep it coming.
Slow down, slow down.
Stop.
-Mack, load the house.
-All right.
Watch it!
-Take it slow. Take it slow.
-Be careful.
Excellent!
Chasing the horizon
Going for the dream
Excellent!
Blessings all around
What's this nonsense, DJ?
You've been at it for 30 minutes.
It's not working. My guests are coming.
They have a wedding at home.
Let's clear everything.
Let's go boys.
Stop chitchatting and come here.
-Where are the others?
-Come on.
-Lift it up.
-She's not going to pick it up.
-Lift it. Come on.
-Take it away.
Come on, guys.
-Keep it over there.
-Keep it moving.
Get it out of there.
Listen.
-Yes?
-Invite them to the wedding.
Okay.
Let me sit next to you
Have me sit close to you
Take me into your arms
Let me sit next to you
Have me sit close to you
Take me into your arms
I think I am going to die without you
I am going to die…
I don't think I can
Stay away from you anymore
Now check this out
Everyone's talking about your beauty
You are the talk of the town
Your beauty is enchanting
I don't think I can
Stay away from you anymore
How did you manage to get booze in Lahore?
One and only Chhote.
It's quite strong.
I can handle it. Strong.
Told you it's strong.
Niazi must have laced it with poison.
Don't drink it.
It's locally made, right here in Lahore.
It takes some time to get used to it.
I'm loving it.
If you like it,
I'm sure Sardar will love it.
Local Pakistani liquor
might make her feel better.
I'll take some along for her. Pass it on.
-I'm sor--
-I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Amreek. I was wrong about you.
I badmouthed you too.
You are boring, insane, crazy.
Yes, I am a little crazy.
Yes, you are.
But stay the way you are.
Thank you for coming here.
I wouldn't be able to do it without you.
Please don't thank me.
I can't wait to see the look
on Sardar's face when she sees this house.
She'll go crazy with joy.
Strange how people get so attached
to materialistic things.
It didn't break.
Dad.
Yes, Dad?
Come home immediately, kiddo.
Sardar doesn't have much time left.
I can't come without the house.
She'll be heartbroken
if she doesn't see her house.
Try to understand, kiddo.
She is on a ventilator.
We don't know
if she'll open her eyes again.
That house doesn't matter to me anymore.
Do you understand?
But it matters to Sardar.
It matters to me, Dad. It matters.
Do you understand? It matters…
Hello? Hello, Dad, it matters--
Hey, Sardar Kaur from Lahore.
Look at me.
What's wrong with you?
Listen, get up.
I am coming back. Sardar!
It's me, Amreek. Get up.
Please wake up.
Sardar?
Kiddo…
doctors have already given up.
Please come home immediately.
Dad, she'll give everything to Lovely
if I come back without the house.
Everything has already
been transferred to Lovely.
Sardar has given everything to him.
Please just come home.
She might have transferred
everything to him for now,
but once I bring this house back,
she'll transfer everything to me.
She'll make me the CEO of the company.
Do you get it?
She'll make your son the CEO--
Hello? Hello?
Just come home.
It's not what you think it is, Radha.
I was just saying it
to convince my father.
Sardar is on ventilator
so he wants me to forget about the house,
and rush back to Amritsar.
This is not fair.
Radha, do you remember
the void you felt when we broke up?
I don't know how you felt,
but I certainly felt a void.
No matter where I went, whom I met,
what I did, I felt a void. It was empty.
Sardar has been
feeling that void for 70 years.
Seventy long years! Seventy years!
That void disappeared
when you came back into my life.
Everything went back to being okay.
I want Sardar to feel that way just once.
That's it.
I am here for Sardar.
I am here for her dream.
But you can assume whatever you want.
I didn't assume anything
that you assumed I am assuming.
Now no one can stop us
from taking our house back home.
Amreek had called to enquire.
All you can do is pray for her now.
Eighty kilometers, six hours.
Route fixed.
Let's do this.
Let's go back home now.
Inshah allah.
-Amen to that.
-Come on!
Let's go. Come on, guys. Come on.
Please move that.
Someone please talk to him.
-Chhote. Come here.
-Yes?
-Take this. Break it like this.
-Got it.
-Bismillah.
-Amen.
Wait. Keep it coming.
Come, come, come.
Go slow. Balance.
-Come on, move!
-Slow.
Move back, everyone. Move aside.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Move back a little.
-It will catch fire.
-Move back?
There's a big problem.
He should have anticipated this.
A bunch of power cables
are obstructing the truck's path.
Amreek, these wires
could be dangerous for the house.
We need to do something.
We have to figure it out.
-The truck won't be able to pass.
-Switch it off.
-Chhote.
-Yes.
Switch off the main power supply here.
Okay, on it. Excuse me.
Give way, please. Excuse me.
Passing through.
-Could be something on that side.
-Please check.
Stay back. Stay back.
Chhote?
What's his problem now?
You cannot disconnect the power supply.
What's wrong, sir?
You think you can switch
the power off whenever you like?
I told you to ensure
this doesn't inconvenience anyone.
These things
take months to organize, mister.
This is the government,
not your grandma's pulse.
It doesn't speed up when it sees you.
Sir… Sir, please listen to me.
This won't take long.
I have already fulfilled your conditions.
Is this what I had asked for?
She is apologizing, sir.
To me? I am a dog?
Aren't you?
I guess the entire family has no manners.
Now this house
cannot go anywhere as long as I am alive.
You'll break my grandma's heart because…
she broke a bottle on your head?
Let us leave.
Chhote…
I don't care
about your grandma or her heart.
The sooner the old hag dies the better.
You…
You will apologize,
and your grandma will, too.
Stop.
-Let me go.
-No. Don't do it.
Control your emotions, young man.
-Look over there.
-Lift it.
Yes, I'm lifting it.
-Lift the wires carefully.
-Careful, Sadiq.
Lift it higher.
That one.
Love is an emotion
that's way stronger than hatred.
Despite how mean you are,
the people of your country are very nice.
I am going
to take this house to my grandma.
Stop me if you can.
Goodbye.
Keep it coming.
Shall we leave, sir? Come on.
Let's do this.
One.
Two.
Three. Lift the wires!
Stay back!
Come on, guys.
Keep it coming.
Lift it higher.
You'll get hurt. Please move back, sir.
Please move aside.
Wait, wait, wait. Stop, stop, stop.
I'm coming. Bye, guys.
-See you soon. Take care.
-Take the house back safe and sound.
See you soon. Let's go.
Bye.
-Where are you going?
-I'm coming along.
Let's go.
Now remove it.
Keep it coming. Keep it coming.
Life is slipping away
The ground is melting
This is a miracle.
Your sun has no luster
Your shore is miles away
But you need to keep walking
You need to keep walking, my friend…
You are racing ahead blindly.
There is a traffic jam
because of two cars colliding.
-After a lot of effort…
-He did it.
-Please.
-Fine, let's go.
Let's go, guys.
The blisters on your feet
Will be your guiding light
Stay determined and keep moving
Oh, mere mortal
God is with you
Everyone here is eagerly waiting
for Amreek Singh and his grandma's house,
to cross the border
and come back to their country.
Sardar,
Amreek is coming back with your house.
For you.
To complete your incomplete story.
For Sardar.
Bye.
You said you'd be back on time.
What took you so long, huh?
Sorry, Sardar.
Please forgive me.
I won't need to apologize
after you see what I've brought you.
Gently Gently?
Yes, there's more.
What?
You are my favorite grandchild.
Come on now. Take a sip.
-Sardar!
It tastes just like the liquor
your grandfather used
to give me back then.
-Are you sure this is the one?
-Yes.
Then I guess Gursher Singhji
was a cunning storyteller.
He gave you
locally distilled Pakistani liquor
and not some stolen imported stuff.
You went to Pakistan without me?
I'd gone there to get you something.
LAHORE TO AMRITSAR - ACROSS BORDERS
Hey, Sardar Kaur,
that's your home from Lahore.
I had made you a promise.
How could I possibly not fulfil it?
Would you like to take a closer look?
Come.
Gursher Singhji,
would you please try this on?
Come on.
It feels like I've been waiting
for you for ages.
Sardar! Open the door!
What are you waiting for? Break the door!
-Come on.
-No…
I have never refused you anything.
Please don't act stubborn today.
Come what may, do not step out.
I wasn't so bad.
You shouldn't have
broken your promise, Gursherji.
I wasn't so bad.
You shouldn't have
broken your promise, Gursherji.
Rupinder?
It is not right
to break your promise, Gursher Singhji.
Why did you leave me?
Why didn't you take me along?
How else would
all your dreams come true, Rupinderji?
Our children, their children,
Champion Cycles.
Whatever, but there's no one
who can match up to you.
I swear.
There's no one like you either.
Come on. Time for a family picture!
-Come on, they're clicking a picture.
-Hurry up, Dad.
I guess they were right.
The house did add a few years
to Sardar's life.
Stop arguing, ladies.
After seeing her house,
Sardar kept taunting me
for another seven years,
and then left us to join her Gursherji.
Say that to your mother.
When Sardar passed away,
she divided her property
into three equal parts.
In the end,
all of us had become her favorite.
I got married to Radha
and went back to America.
I have two daughters and a son
whom we call Sardar.
Cheese!