- Fuckin' dickface!
- Sorry.
You ran into me.
-  Spider, he's all
yours.
- Lights!
Darryl, Darryl, Darryl.
It is Darryl right?
- That's ri-
- Don't Darryl!
Don't step in front of our
patrons, man.
They will run you down and
stampede
right over your ass, boy.
You don't know pain until
you've had for teeny-bitches
in six inch stilettos screamin'
like a virgin on prom night!
It's simple bro, in and out.
Duck and jive ya know.
Boo then skidoo.
- Boo then skidoo.
- Bring your simple ass in here,
go.
Go, go, go!
You'll get it.
You better get it.
We open Friday!
Heh, heh, heh!
Hey now hold on,
I don't want you getting all
stiff on me.
I don't want you dancing
like those zombies
in a Michael Jackson video, ya
know.
None of that, okay?
Come here.
All right you got to stay loose.
Move.
Ahhhh!
Fresh meat!
- Hey Spider, say hello to Bart,
Tracy,
Margo, um-
- Tyler.
- Tyler and Jake.
- Okay, thank you miss Summer
and this is-
- PJ, my fiancee.
He's going to help out.
Stop it.
- Yeah, good helper.
Uh, and this is Darryl who, like
you,
is new to the ways of fright!
- Hey Bart.
- Hey Darryl.
- We know each other from physi-
- My peeps!
Welcome to Scare Zone year
three!
Now, the first thing we do,
to welcome the newest
members of our scream team,
is sacrifice a virgin!
- Hey!
- Look.
You were scared, huh?
You pussy.
And now a tour of this year's
attraction:
"Scare Zone Three: The
Psycho-Splatter
Raw-topsy Slaughter Dungeon".
- Yeah man!
- All right follow me, kiddies.
Ah, what you, no, no, no.
That's the gift shop.
Okay that's where we end.
This is where we start.
Yeah, over here, yeah!
Okay, why don't you
just stick close to me.
- All right.
- All right?
You're lookin' like you rode in
on the short bus or somethin'.
Come on, guys.
- Excellent.
Pablo!
Donde esta
the remote control?
Fantastic.
All right, good,
let's see how we're doing.
- Bravo Mr. Peters.
- Ah-heh, that is fantastic.
- I'm sorry, what?
- Ah, no, it's very
good, it's very good eh?
- All right, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- So I pulse them through in
like
six to eight at a time, no conga
line,
we want to separate
them into little clumps
that way you can get
them to shit themselves.
- Heh, that's right if they see
you coming there's no surprise.
- Boys and ghouls, meet the
owner
and creator, the Duke of
Dementia,
Scare Zone's own Sir Oliver
Peters!
- Yeah, just Oliver will be
fine.
- Hey man, good, I'm glad I ran
into you.
You know I've got that
appointment-
- Uh huh.
- And the newbies need to get
a tour from the man Oliver.
- All right.
Okay.
Go!
- All right, kids, scare ya
later.
Don't touch!
Don't touch.
Excuse me!
Excuse me, thank you, thank you.
- All right, let's go
over to the next scene.
There's more room in there.
Voila!
Ha-ha!
Welcome my pretties on your
next stop on the scare zone
tour:
The Lair of the Slutty
Cannibal Vampiress Wench.
Now, this poor fellow here is
one of the vampiress's victims!
He came directly from the
Camden dungeon of tortures.
The first time Prince Harry saw
this gag he 'bout shit himself.
You.
- Margo.
- Perfect!
You could work this room, all
right?
You are a slutty blood sucking
vampire seeking victims.
Now, let me hear you hiss!
- Hiss?
- Yep.
- Uh, hisssss.
- Okay, uh, let me hear you, a,
shriek!
- Um, ahhhh.
- Well, she's got the slutty
part down.
- Shut up Trace!
- No, no, no, no, no.
It's not a problem.
Come forth.
- Um.
- C'mon.
This is what will work for you,
this is a shaker can.
Okay, you come out of
the shadows, all right?
And then, yee-ahhh!
It jars them pretty good.
- Cool!
Mind if I-
- Oh, yeah.
All right, all right, all right,
settle down, whoa!
Settle down, champ.
What's your name?
- Tyler.
- Of course it is.
I've got a job for you
and the skinny fellow
in a big scene down the hall.
Moving on!
- Hey Bart, Tyler's pretty
good with that shaker
can, lots of practice.
And you get to work with him!
- Oh, great.
Thanks, dick-weed.
- Okay here we come,
comin' in, comin in, comin' in,
comin' in.
Over there, over there, very
nice.
Now before the big scene, our
guests
must pass through the lye vat
dungeon.
- What's a lye vat?
- Yeah, lye was used in powder
form
for cleaning hides,
chemically burning away
the hair and the fat, yada,
yada, yada.
But it also came in handy
if you were a serial killer
trying to hide the stench of
your victims.
- Gross.
- And you are?
- Uh, Jake Jacobs.
- Spectacular.
Come over here.
Now you will be in this part
of the slaughter dungeon
wielding your bloody ax.
You'll be dressed in a mask and
jump suit
like your friend there.
- Okay, ohh.
Heavier than I thought.
- Yeah, that's
because it's real.
- Okay.
Do you know how much a good
quality
fake plastic ax costs?
Damn right it's real!
It's cheaper and it lasts
longer.
The blade is not the
sharpest thing in the world,
but it could hurt like hell
if you chop somebody with it.
So, you hold it like this, and
threaten!
All right?
Now don't, let anybody grab it
from you.
- Okay.
- Good, okay, moving on.
Chop chop!
- Oh god it's real.
- Okay sexy man is crazy!
- This is sweet.
- I don't know.
I think this Oliver guy knows a
little
too much about hacking and
killing-
- Yeah, and he's got plans
for "the skinny fellow".
Chop chop!
- Ha-ha!
New for this year:
The Raw-topsy Zone where, as you
can see, a number of hellish
morticians
are watching a victim getting
sliced up on the autopsy table.
Now, sitting among the statues,
looking just like the
dummies will be Tyler and-
- Bart.
- Bingo!
You'll be frozen just like the
rest,
and then you leap up and
boo-yah!
You scream at unsuspecting
mazers.
Now, you don't want to blow
your voice out, all right?
So scream a couple of
times, and then other times
you can use this aluminum
bat to hit the railing.
Just don't hit anybody.
Remember, you scare fast then
pull back.
You don't want some macho
creep punching you out.
Dangerous.
- Somebody takes a swing
at me and he's going down!
- No, no, no Tyler.
We do not slug the paying
guests.
- Yeah, we're not supposed
to touch them at all, right?
- That's right.
No touchy.
Too much liability.
However we, the actors,
can interact physically with
each other.
- Tyler's all yours.
- For example, Summer
here will play a live
victim getting sliced up
by some mad doctor.
You see, he amputates her leg
while she's still squirming.
It's a good gag.
- Oh and I could be your doctor.
Oh!
Check this out!
- No, PJ.
No, Oliver.
I told you, I'm helping you
open this thing and then
we're going to Vegas
to get married like you
promised.
Right, honey?
- Uh-huh.
- Summer, could I talk to
you over here for a moment?
- Look, I know you want to
get the hell out of here
and start your new life
with prince charming-
- Awesome!
- Excellent choice by the way.
But I really need you here.
- No you don't.
You've got Claire, okay?
I need to get out of my parent's
house.
So we're getting married
this weekend as planned.
- Look, open for me this Friday.
If you can stay for Saturday and
Sunday
I will make the honeymoon really
special.
Come on you're the only
seasoned performer I've got.
- All right I'll open for you
Friday
and I'll talk to PJ about this
weekend.
- Fair enough.
Let's show the others
where they'll be stationed.
And we are walking-
- Oh, Tracy.
- Uh, I didn't do that-
Oh my God I'm gonna puke!
- What makes this smell?
- My own secret recipe.
- Why hello.
- Ugh that's bad.
Ah.
That is so cool.
- And we're walking.
Okay good, come on, everyone
through the body bag room.
I've turned the AC up in here to
turn this
sucker into a freezer.
Now, to the doll hall!
Isn't this fantastic!
All right, and who's left?
- Me.
Darryl.
- Bonanza!
You will be in this zone
which was last year's big hit.
It's entitled Dies and Dolls.
You'll be dressed just as you
are,
freaking people out with
your blood stained machete.
You know this still is my
favorite room.
Every child's nightmare lives in
the eyes
of these lifeless beings.
I've been collecting them for
years.
Years and years.
- Yahhhh!
You!
You are-
- Tracy!
- Superlative!
In this zone you will be a fresh
victim wearing a wedding
dress and veil working up
and down these stairs.
Yes, you are a recent victim.
Uh, you're turning vampire,
holding the bat-baby
that you just gave bloody birth
to
via the old monkey-wrench
cesarean.
- Oh my god.
Can't I just get like
a, shakey-up can?
- No.
No, you show people your mutated
newborn.
- Oh, oh.
- Sir Oliver!
It's ready!
- Ha-ha!
Now, we are in for a treat!
Ah, hello Jesus.
- No, no, no.
"Hey-Zu".
- Ex-scusi.
I'm sorry, what?
- It, it's ready.
It's ready!
- Ah ha-ha!
Buen provetcho!
And now welcome to the insanity
of the Psycho Strobelight Room!
Good!
As usual, I will be in the
finale area,
playing the pumpkin carver,
scaring people shitless with
Bloody Molly my trademarked
signature patent pending gas
powered
two cycle 20-inch chainsaw.
Now, this is where I
break one of my own rules,
and only I can do it.
Bart.
Come here.
You see?
I locked the chain on,
so no chain no pain.
Just a hell of a lot
of vibration and noise.
Grazie, Hymie.
Now, I wouldn't normally
touch anybody with it,
but if there's some complete ass
acting too cool in front of his
friends,
I might feel the need
to give him a gut check,
like ol' Bart there.
Now add to this the smoke
machines,
lots of light and sound effects,
the strobe room, the chainsaw
finale,
yada, yada, yada, we happily
freak out the customers
who happily scamper into the
gift shop to spend more money!
Jesus!
- No, no, no, "Hey-Zu".
- No, no, no.
Whatever.
What the hell was that?
De nada.
Okay, uh, right.
You go into the gift
shop and wait for Claire.
She'll give you your costumes
and talk makeup for
anybody who needs help.
Say that again but slower.
- Yeah I've been coming
here the past few years.
He's only open three
nights but at 10 bucks
a head he makes a killing.
- Oh, dude,
I heard he used to manage a
house
of horrors wax museum in London,
but he got busted for
using real blood or a real
corpse or something.
- No, no!
I heard he killed a goat live
just to watch people react.
- Bullshit.
- Yeah, no he got fired and
went to prison for, like,
animal cruelty or something.
- Oh no, no.
I heard he went to
prison because he killed
a boney, pasty virgin.
- Oh, shut up asswipe.
- Ooh, shopping!
Oh, I wonder if we get, like,
half-off.
- Who's the slut?
Perfect.
All right I designed this look
for you
with this make-up illustration
you can work from.
Your costume's over there, go
try it on
and I'll help you with the
makeup later.
The bride?
Bat-boy's mother?
I didn't design the dress.
- Thank God.
- Bought it at a consignment
shop, but it works.
And your makeup needs to be more
defined.
Okay, we need to be able
to see it behind the veil.
Why don't you slip that on, try
it out.
- Great.
- Dummies?
- Yo!
- I mean morticians.
You guys need to look just
like the mortician dummi-
♪♪ Oh, Halloween ♪♪
♪♪ Dance and scream ♪♪
- Sorry.
- Costumes are over there,
and I made boy-friendly
makeup directions for you.
- Yes!
- Makeup is with your costumes
and we don't have a lot of room
in here
so we put on our makeup here in
the shop.
We rigged up a curtained
off changing area,
it has one bench and one mirror-
- Whoa!
- That's for the girls.
Boys just use the shop mirror.
Masked psychos?
I see you have your costume
already.
Fit okay?
- Yeah.
Great.
- And your mask, it's up there.
There's lots of welder's gloves
and a mechanic jump suit,
just pick ones that fit.
Summer?
I have your hospital
gown and doctor scrubs
for PJ if Oliver can talk you
two into-
- Claire, I don't know.
Okay, we're leaving town to get
married.
- Need a dress?
- I look like a doctor.
♪♪ It's the common cause of
everything ♪♪
♪♪ You spend your life regretting
♪♪
♪♪ It's a road with obstacles ♪♪
♪♪ And you can't rely on second
guessing ♪♪
♪♪ It's all your choice ♪♪
♪♪ You have your voice ♪♪
Perverts!
♪♪ You're never gonna be the same
♪♪
♪♪ Everything's been rearranged ♪♪
♪♪ It's gonna be all right ♪♪
♪♪ You came and you don't
know what's coming next ♪♪
♪♪ We're never gonna be the same
♪♪
♪♪ Everything's been rearranged ♪♪
♪♪ It's gonna be all right ♪♪
♪♪ You came but you don't
know what's coming next ♪♪
♪♪ You don't know what's coming
next ♪♪
- So, Claire,
what part do you play?
- Yeah, 'cause I really like
your costume.
- Yeah.
- No.
I stay here and work the gift
shop.
Spider gets their money going
in, I get 'em going out.
All right remember everybody,
today Spider
rehearses you, but tomorrow
night we open.
All right?
Any questions?
- Uh, yeah.
Uh, who breaks us?
- No breaks.
- What?
- Look.
We're open from seven p.m.
until the last guest goes
through.
All right, that's usually
'till, like midnight
on the first two nights
and two a.m. on Halloween.
- What if I have to pee?
- Then pee!
There's a toilet right there.
And that's for everybody.
- Okay, where do I smoke?
- Out the back door in the
alley.
Look, just duck out, do
whatever it is you need to do.
No one in the maze is going to
say
"Hey, there's supposed to
be a psycho killer here".
Well, except maybe some
of our regulars. You!
You were here last year, right?
- Uh, I only went though seven
times.
Not like some of those
no-lifes who go through
10 times a night if they can.
- Yeah, 'cause you have a life.
- Anyway, if you have to
take a break just get back to
your post quickly so people
get their money's worth.
It's only three nights.
You'll survive.
And if we do good business,
Oliver takes care of us with
nice bonuses.
That's why I'm here.
- I'm gonna need some help!
- All right.
Uh, boys, go see what Oliver
needs.
And then everybody report to
Spider
after lunch for rehearsals.
Tyler!
- Yeah!
- Every evening one person
has to come in an hour
early to help Spider and Oliver
prep the house for our guests.
And you're up first.
So, tomorrow at six.
- I'll be here at five!
- Whatever.
- High as you can there, Pablo.
- Didn't this used to
be like, a Dollar Store?
- No, it was a porno shop.
- No way!
- Yeah!
Douche!
- You know actually this entire
attraction
can fit into two pod containers.
Yeah!
It takes me, Spider and half
a dozen man-power guys.
We can put the whole thing
up in a couple of days.
Actually, Pablo, can you
get your men together?
Uh, todos juntos?
- Ah, si si.
- Bellissimo.
I'll tell ya, the biggest pain
in the ass
is getting this sign up so hola
muchachos.
Un, dos, trio!
- "Prepare to be scared.
Scare Zone Three this weekend!"
Who comes up with this?
- Oliver does.
Keeps all this stuff in storage,
pulls it out once a
year and does his thing.
- Hey, how do you think he makes
that toilet scene smell so bad?
- Ah he shits in the pots and
waits
for the mold to grow.
- No way!
- Ha!
Jeez Bart, I don't know,
maybe he uses old socks
or fertilizer or something.
What do you think about Claire?
- Freak.
Goth gone wild.
- I don't know, man,
awful smart to be a freak.
Talented too.
- Freak.
"The Psycho-splatter
Raw-topsy Slaughter Dungeon."
- Shit mother!
- Damn!
Maybe I shouldn't have come so
early.
Hey!
I'm here to-
- What?
- Uh, I think they're ready.
Can we open early?
- No.
Hell no man!
Tyler never showed.
Me and Oliver had to open
this whole damn place by
ourselves.
Shithead.
Hold on.
All right, you can go in now.
Go!
Go-go-go hurry up!
All right you pussy worms!
You ready to get freaked out?
Yeah!
- Are you ready for some blood
and guts?
Yeah!
- Then get ready for Scare Zone
Three:
The Psycho-splatter
Raw-topsy Slaughter Dungeon!
Yeah!
- Opening in just 10 minutes!
- Yeah.
Hey, no masks in the maze.
You guys know that!
- Oh, no-no-no.
Sorry Spidey.
- Oh, hey freaky geeky.
How've you been, man?
Wow, you guys startin' to
multiply now.
It was just the two of you
comin'
in the last couple of years
over and over and over again.
I mean not that I mind.
I like that you guys have no
life.
Ha!
As is our tradition,
we have the winner of our
promotional Scare Zone
T-shirt contest officially
unlock the doors
to our chamber of horrors!
Yeah, baby!
- It's open!
- Thank you Miss Amber!
All right boys, you know the
score,
move inside to my podium and
wait there
until I give the signal we're
open and I snatch your money.
Ha!
Excuse me, excuse me
out of the way please.
Hey, man, Scare Zone 2, Dies &
Dolls, man.
I love loyalty.
That's good, that's good stuff.
- Yeah, hey, when's Oliver going
to offer
an unlimited admissions pass
for the regular customers.
- Heh-heh.
Why would he do that?
You guys are stupid enough
to pay 10 bucks every time.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Hi Claire!
- We're good to go.
- All right guys now remember no
masks,
no smoking, no cameras!
No checks, no credit cards.
Just cash, baby.
All right my fellow zonies!
Scare Zone Three is now open for
business!
- Raar!
Shit!
♪♪ Still alive ♪♪
♪♪ But then we're awake and
I just can't shake this ♪♪
♪♪ Be drowning ♪♪
♪♪ Soon it'll be the end ♪♪
- Ah yes.
- Help me!
- Help me.
Help me.
Stop it!
♪♪ We grow now, my soul ♪♪
- All clear?
Front door locked?
All right, that is it for the
night!
So we did pretty good for
the first night, right guys?
Everybody got their costumes
hung up?
Claire will pay everybody
and let everybody out.
Spider and I will close up the
attraction.
Thank you for a great first
night.
Claire, give everybody an extra
60 clams.
Spider!
Oliver!
- Bullshit.
This is why I'm leaving.
I hate this town.
This job is killing me.
I'm in desperate need of a spa
treatment.
- Hey, an extra 60 bucks isn't
ba-
- And before I get home to
my goddamn parents' house
where I'm living to try and
save money, horn dog over here
is going to want to hump me up
one side and down the other.
Of course I want him to so there
goes half
the money we just made on a
cheap hotel.
- We can do it in the car!
- We are so out of here
tomorrow, Peege.
- Um, tomorrow you're opening.
- What?
- Yeah, Spider has his
appointment,
Oliver's not in 'till seven,
you're the only one that knows
how
to run the smoke machines.
- Oh my God!
- Thanks, Summer!
-  "Thanks, Summer."
- What happened to
Amber the T-shirt pixie?
- Oh, she's waiting for you in
the car.
Bart!
I'm kidding.
Amber is only here for the
opening
and then she goes to
her regular "night" job!
- Ohhhhhh.
- Get it.
- Well, that just leaves
me, Tracy and Margo!
Hey you guys want to hit
Denny's?
- Sure.
- Uh, Darryl?
Can you stay a sec and help me
count cash?
Sure.
- Have fun with Edwina
Scissorhands.
- Is this a lot of money for day
one?
Oh.
You're pretty fast with that
calculator.
Did you learn that at school
or...
Classic.
- He's scared.
- That was awesome!
- That was better than last
year.
I'll never get tired of that
one.
- Hey, boner!
- Shut up!
Man, if I hear one more "boner"
line.
- I don't know if this is worth
an extra 40 bucks, man.
We could get killed out here.
Hey, I liked flagging
parked cars a lot better.
- What?
- I said I had an amazing night
counting money with Claire.
- Yeah, sure you did.
- Oh, we talked and laughed
and she told me about her
family.
- Yeah, who?
The Addams Family?
- Yeah!
Look, man.
She's a freak all right?
- All right, a freak that can
add.
Why are you focusing on her
when you know we can have
Margo's mangoes and Tracy's
tangerines!
- Ah man, fu, was that a beer
bottle?
- Shit mother!
- Will you just stop?
- What?
- Stop it!
Peege, can you hand me
another liter of fluid?
- You know, I'd much rather be
giving you my bodily fluids.
- That's sweet, honey,
but haven't you had enough
of me by now?
- Mmmm.
I'll could never get enough of
you.
You are my-
- Don't say it.
- You are my-
- Don't say it!
Big boy.
Come on.
To the table.
To the table!
Come on!
Take your shirt off, take your
shirt off!
Take it off!
No, stop.
- What?
- Stop, stop.
- There.
I got him.
- I have to finish opening.
- Ahhh, c'mon Summer!
- I have to turn on the
lights and the sound.
Get your shirt!
Where's the frickin' audio?
PJ!
Stop playing with the chainsaw!
Knock it off!
PJ!
PJ?
What the fuck are...
PJ!
Scare Zone!
Open!
- Will you shut up!
Oh shut up, calm down.
We're not even open for
another half an hour.
- Can't you open a little
earlier?
Yeah!
- I'm a little busy in here!
Let me find something to
entertain you until we open.
- No!
No!
Help me!
- That was awesome!
Do it again!
- Hey man, why do I have to do
this again?
It's PJ's turn!
- PJ's gone, all right?
You keep them happy.
I've got to finish opening the
place up.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- What?
- PJ's gone?
And Summer too?
- Yeah man gone and eloped!
Something.
I don't know.
Look, they opened the
place and apparently split.
Okay, good luck to 'em, good
riddance.
Go out there and keep
this crowd from rioting!
Go, be a man!
- I'm all by myself in here!
First no Tyler, now no Summer
and PJ!
- Relax my little mortician,
Oliver Peters has it all sorted.
At least for tonight.
Ta-ta-da-ta-ta-ta-taaaa!
Behold!
An international twist
to our tortuous tale!
♪♪ They just wanna dance all
night ♪♪
♪♪ Move your bodies to
the music, to the music ♪♪
Hey!
- Darryl!
You can come in now.
C'mon man go.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
All right people, we're ready
for you if your ready for a boo!
As I was saying, no masks,
no smoking, no...
Hey, what are you three, what?
You three bong turds
trying to get us shut down?
- You got a problem with it,
"mon"?
- Oh, no baby.
I love the devil's lettuce.
I also like my job.
So, basically what I'm
trying to say here is
nobody gets in until these three
puff-puff mother-fuckers are out
of here!
Smoke on that!
- Hey, hey, shut the fuck up!
- Get out of here assholes!
- Kiss my ass, bitch!
- Who you callin' bitch, bitch?
- What are you looking
at you big Sasquatch?
- Bye-bye boys.
Toodles!
And now my pretties,
Scare Zone Three is open
for the second night of fright!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
I love Halloween.
- Shit!
- Hey, I hate 20s!
- Okay, that's the real dummy
there.
This light is out.
That guy used to be a girl,
and this is a fake leg!
- Oh, what the hell happened to
this?
- Who want's a beer?
To the best "day two" in
the history of Scare Zone!
Cheers!
- We couldn't do any better
unless
we were actually killing people.
That would pack 'em in.
- It actually would, you know.
- Okay Claire.
You're gonna freak out these
kids.
Look, you guys did great
tonight.
The spirits of the dead are with
us.
- Whooooooo!
- I would like everybody
to take an extra 100
bones out of the till.
Okay, Spider, let's go and close
up.
Oh, I'm gonna need some extra
help
with a broken window and wall
facade.
I need two guys to hold it in
place while we nail gun it to
the wall.
It'll only take about 10
minutes.
I'll throw in another 20 bucks.
- I'm in.
- There you go.
- No, uh, Oliver, you've been
great.
You don't have to pay us.
- Hey!
Shut your pie hole.
I could use the "dinero".
- Heh-heh.
Tonight I can afford it.
- He can afford it.
- Let's go.
- Shut up.
- Stop tryin' to be me!
- Tracy, you've got to
help me with my make-up,
last time I about took
out a whole eyelash.
- Okay, hang on a sec.
Okay.
Let's go!
- Sexy.
- Yeah.
- Senorita Claire, tell
Senor Oliver that we will not
be performing for this job
tomorrow.
He's too, como se dice?
- Cheap!
- Cheap.
- So, you need help again
counting?
Okay.
So it looks like Summer
and PJ really went for it.
Yep, took the plunge.
- They're dead.
- What?
- Dead.
Any relationship that is
purely physical is death.
They're just going to be a
statistic.
- Well I hear today that two out
of three divorces end in
marriage.
- Not that death is bad.
Death of a relationship, of the
spirit,
death of the body.
I saw a dead body once.
Have you ever seen a
real dead body, Darryl?
- Well, I saw my granddad's
ashes,
it was kind of dusty.
- I was 11.
I was riding my bike down Old
Camp Road
when I saw, up ahead, this dust
cloud.
As I came closer I saw that a
truck
had run off the road
and slammed into a tree.
That was okay.
Kind of cool.
But further away in the grass
is what was really great.
There was a boy, about my age.
Blonde like me.
He was lying in the grass.
Not moving, not breathing.
He must have been sitting
in the bed of the truck.
Who knows how high or how hard
he hit?
But now he was on his back, eyes
open,
looking at the sky.
Still.
At peace.
- Sorry.
- Why?
It was beautiful.
And I was there.
No one was around.
I reached out, touched his face.
Touched his lips.
Then a car came down the
road and stopped to help.
It ruined our moment.
That's the closest I've ever
come to really knowing a boy.
Claire, uh, we have
a, uh, we have a question.
- Oh my god there's this,
there's this phat Halloween
party that we want to go to.
We want to go, like, and we-
- And, look we just want
to leave in our costumes.
- So, we'll see you there, okay?
- Did you just invite her?
- Huh?
- Bye ladies of the night!
All right, well, I wish Summer
and PJ the best I guess.
- Darryl, you seem like a nice
guy.
Don't be like the rest of them.
Don't force yourself on them.
Don't, don't guilt and chide
and force yourself on...
Pretty little blonde.
Come here, pretty little blonde.
Bring your red lips over here.
Black lips.
Black hair.
I'm dead.
I'm not your plaything now, I'm
dead.
Dead!
- Okay, I'm officially creeped
out.
Maybe you should relax.
- Sometimes the haze is so
thick,
the only way I can remind
myself I'm still in this world
is with the pleasure of pain.
Makes me feel good when
I'm in control of my pain.
I like that.
I've never let anyone watch me
before,
but I like you Darryl.
I've been working on this one.
This is our secret.
Makes me feel good.
- Shit, what was that?
- You'd better go see.
- Holy shit!
Can we not perform a simple
task without this juvenile
Tom-fuckery!
- I don't know what
happened, it just shot back
or exploded or something.
I, I don't know.
- Hey man.
Put the mother fuckin',
Jake, put the motherfuckin' nail
gun down.
- Put it down!
Spider, I'm gonna need your
shirt.
- Oh, yeah.
- Darryl, unplug the compressor
before it blows again.
Damn!
- Oh, for fuck's sake!
And don't you touch the nail.
We're going to let the doctors
remove it.
C'mon.
Let's get him out of here.
- I still get my 20 bucks?
- Yeah, I'd rather pay that
than for the tetanus
shots you're gonna need.
- Ah, shit mother!
- C'mon you assholes!
- Suck my balls, Scare Zone.
- What are you doing, bro?
I told you she takes the
cash when she leaves, man.
- I know that, I was just
checking.
- You guys suck.
Let's tag this this shit-hole.
Yeehaw!
- Yeah, suck my balls!
Oh, no, no, no. Check this out.
- Whatcha got? Look at this.
- Hey, how 'bout this man?
- Oh shit.
- Oh my God.
Yeah!
- He's paying for this.
- What an ass.
- He so tagged you, man.
- Let's just go back this way.
Holy shit!
Look at this toilet over here!
It's so lifelike.
- "Lifelike?"
- Whichever asshole threw me
in here, is going to get, ahhh!
C'mon bro, this is not,
who's that?
- It's not real.
What have we got over here, man?
- No idea.
- Please, please, please!
- What's that dip-shit up to
now?
- Where the hell are we?
- Where's that prick at?
- Hey, we gotta get out of here.
This is bullshit.
- Just go check down that way.
- Fuck it.
I'm gone.
And I've got the car keys.
I don't give a rat's ass
about you piss heads.
- Douche bag.
Fuck man, where're you at?
Hey!
C'mon man!
Stop dickin' around!
Bart, honey, can you
get that?
- Sorry mom, I'm injured.
- Yes can I, uh, help you?
- Yes ma'am, I'm Darryl Myers
from the Scare Zone attraction.
Is Bart home?
- Well hello "Darryl Myers",
Yes Bart is home, you know
my poor boy he's just-
- Excuse me.
- Oh.
Um, thank you for,
uh, cleaning my pipes.
Well, let me see what you have
there.
Oh, how sweet.
Well, let me just take these
from you
and get them in some water.
Can I get you anything to drink?
Oh Bart!
You have company!
I thought I
was supposed to hang out
with dad next weekend!
- No, dear.
It's your little friend
from the scary house.
He came to see how you're doing.
- I'm in too much pain!
Tell 'em to go away.
- Hello, Bart!
Heh, nice set up you big
bullshit artist.
- Close the door.
- Nice sheets.
- Close the door!
Don't screw it for me, man.
It's the first time in five
years my mom's sucked up to me.
- Looked like your mom was
suckin' up to the plumber.
- Funny, fag!
Yeah, check out this set-up.
This is sweet!
- Yeah, if you're seven.
- I'm taking this for
as long a ride as I, oh!
I love this part.
Hey, hey, hey!
- Sorry, Bart.
You and your "man-gina" need to
get out
of bed and help me with
today's marketing blitz.
- "Marketing blitz?"
What are you, an ad agency
executive?
- I need this money and Oliver
needs everyone in tonight.
- Excuse me.
Fatally injured.
- Fatal means dead,
genius, and you're lifting
your arm just fine.
C'mon, it's one more night.
- I get it.
You need me.
You can't go on without me.
I am Scare Zone.
But I can't hand out fliers.
Injured.
- Fine.
We're not actually "handing
out" flyers this time.
- Hey ladies!
"Scare Zone!"
♪♪ You're pretty good lookin' ♪♪
♪♪ Yeah, you're my type ♪♪
♪♪ I like that you're
beautiful as the night ♪♪
♪♪ You took me to the
graveyard on our second date ♪♪
♪♪ Not like the other girls
who took me to the lake ♪♪
♪♪ Let's go ♪♪
Scare Zone!
- You're terrible.
- Tonight's the last night.
- Scare Zone!
Come check it out, you'll love
it!
- Yeah happy hallo-weeny!
Thanks!
- Dude, they're so hot.
- They were hot.
- I'm going to go meet them.
- No, no, no.
Dude.
We gotta go.
C'mon!
Oliver?
Jake!
What the fuck, man!
- The back door was open, man,
my bad.
- What'cha doing here?
- Oliver told me to come help
you set up.
- Oh he tell you but he don't
tell me?
Ain't this about a bitch.
Look, I'm glad you're
here, I need your help.
I've got an appointment
downtown.
- Heh.
An "appointment" right?
Heh-heh.
- Yes an appointment I've got to
meet
my parole officer is that okay
with you?
Can you focus?
Focus!
Look, first thing I need you to
do is
take this and put it back
where I found it, okay?
Now I've got to set up this damn
dummy
because those Spanish
assholes didn't show up,
so you go finish filling
up the fog machine,
then go turn on the sound
system,
but turn it to the knob with the
little piece of tape on it, then
go
turn on the strobe lights,
oh and fill the bat baby up with
water
and if you're looking
for something else to do,
you can finish this
list, do everything on it
then after your done, wait for
Oliver or Claire because uh,
uh, I ain't givin' you my keys.
Okay?
Ya got that?
- Got it.
- Now, Oliver's going to be
pissy 'cause I'm not here.
Don't let him take it out on
you, okay?
- 10-4.
- Yeah, "10-4" wonder bread.
Just go turn on the lye vat.
Go.
Go-go-go-go-go.
Go, go!
Can you speed? Urgency, yes, go.
Spanish people don't show up.
Bitches are supposed to like
work.
What kind of shit?
Oh shit!
Ahhhh, what?
♪♪ It's Christmas ♪♪
♪♪ Merry Christmas ♪♪
- Welcome to "A Christmas to
Remember"
where it's Christmas 364 days a
year!
That's right every day but what,
what?
Christmas!
So, how can I help you?
- I'm looking for Claire, I'm
her brother.
- Brother, huh?
Funny, I don't see the family
resemblance.
'Course I guess you don't
put on the black lipstick
and the funny make-up
'till after midnight, huh?
Sandy, have you seen Miss
Claire?
Hang on honey,
I'll be right down.
- So, what's Claire's brother's
name?
- Me?
Oh.
Darryl.
- Oh, really, what a
coinky-dink.
I've got an elf around here
named Darryl someplace.
- I didn't know Claire had a
brother,
she never mentioned a brother.
But, she's not a big talker.
You'll find her right
back there by gift wrap.
- Thank you.
♪♪ I'm Darryl ♪♪
♪♪ Helping you to care ♪♪
Hey Claire.
- Oh, hey, what are you doing
here?
- You told me to come he-
- Shhhh!
Oh, you have a note from mom!
That is bad.
Oh, I'm glad you came.
Um, Sandy,
Sandy.
You know it looks like
our mom is really sick
and I'm gonna to leave
early to, um, care for her.
- You said your mother's dead,
dear.
- Oh.
Oh!
No our, our mam is sick.
That's what we call our
grandmother.
- Yeah.
"Mam".
- I'm really sorry Mrs. Kane,
I really have to leave right
now.
You know, to get to, mam.
- I understand, dear.
So, I'll see you tomorrow
morning at 10.
It's a big day!
- Okay, I wouldn't miss it.
- Mam.
- The holiday shopping season
starts
the day after Halloween now, you
know!
Toodles!
- Whoo-hoo!
Oh, get me out of here!
Ha.
Ya think vampires and zombies
are scary?
Those people are scary!
- I thought you worked at a
funeral home.
- Who told you that?
- Nobody.
- No I've worked for the
Kanes for, like, four years
and they still creep me out.
- I dunno.
They seemed like, "Really nice
people".
Thanks for
getting me out of there,
I'm running out of
excuses to cut out early.
You confused them good.
- Hey, I'm just glad you called.
Is your car in the shop?
- I don't drive.
- Well how do you get around?
- I usually walk.
- This place is, like, 20
blocks from the strip mall.
- Or I'll bum a ride or
hitchhike.
- Isn't that a little dangerous?
- No.
- Shit!
Put that away!
Can't you carry, like, a can of
mace
or a taser or something?
- Mace doesn't stop them,
it just blinds them.
Tasers you gotta keep charged.
It's not practical.
- Good point.
- Oliver keeps a taser
charged and ready to go
underneath the cash
register at the gift shop,
but I'll stick with sexy Sadie,
thank you.
- She's named her gun.
- Oh, turn here.
Turn here!
Stop here.
- How did I know this was
going to end at a cemetery?
Claire?
This isn't funny.
I knew it was you.
I just wanted to see what
you looked like laughing.
- Don't get used to it.
Let me show you something.
- God damn it.
- Darryl, I'd like you to meet
someone.
- Mary Elisabeth Landers.
- Hey, hey!
Buddy.
What are you doin'?
Do you know those kids over
there?
Are you listening to me?
- Your mother?
- No.
- Not your mother.
- No, my mother is, quite alive.
- Hello, ass-wipe,
I'm talkin' to you!
- No, she's my aunt.
My mother's sister.
Nothing exotic killed her, just
cancer.
But I wanted you to meet her.
You remind me a lot of her.
Hey Aunt Mare,
I'd like you to meet Darryl.
- Hello, Ms. Landers, how are
you?
- She can't talk to
you Darryl, she's dead.
- I know.
- You know, she was the only
person
that ever brought me a Christmas
present.
Every year she would bring me
something
and wrap it so beautifully.
She pretty much raised me 'till
I was 10.
My Aunt Mare kept me from harm.
Then she died.
One year she got me this snow
globe.
It was one of those real glass
ones,
not like the plastic
ones you see at the mall.
It had this whole little village
in it.
That became a great tool for my
mom.
She could just raise it up
and threaten to smash it.
She finally made good on that
threat.
Darryl, I really appreciate you
trying to strike up a
conversation
with me two nights ago.
- Hey, I'm sorry you lost
somebody
that you cared so much about.
It seems like things went
all down hill after that.
You seem to be fighting a lot of
demons.
- I was just a cute little
blonde
no one could keep their hands
off of.
- And, as a friend, albeit a new
friend,
I want to say something.
Go ahead.
- Be goth, carry guns
and hum strange tunes,
but you shouldn't be hurting
yourself.
You deserve better than that.
Get a tattoo and let the
professional hurt you!
- That could probably take some
therapy.
- Think about it.
Now, ready to go hack,
maim, bludgeon and slaughter
ourselves
to the delight of thousands?
- Yippie!
Ha-ha.
Bye Aunt Mare.
Happy Halloween.
- So I suppose you like "How
the Grinch Stole Christmas"?
- Love it!
- And your favorite movie of all
time,
the "Nightmare Before
Christmas"?
- Now you're getting me hot!
♪♪ Come on, do the twist ♪♪
♪♪ Do the twist... the
Frankenstein twist! ♪♪
Let us in, let us
in, let us in, let us in!
Oh, where the hell is Spider?
- Oh, how many times are
you going to say that?
- Well, where the hell is
Spider?
- He told me that he was coming
back.
- Did he say when?
Sorry.
Sorry Jake I know it's not your
fault.
Thanks for getting the place
open.
Okay.
I will work Spider's
line and take the cash.
- Oh good!
Here's your cash bags.
- Thank you.
Wait, Darryl come here.
If I'm going to cover for
Spider,
you have to cover for me.
I am entrusting you with
the chainsaw finale.
- Why me?
- Claire recommended you.
- Yeah.
I'm there!
Show me what to do.
- Nothing to it.
Here's the throttle,
this is the chain lock.
Now, keep that lock on.
Without that lock on you
could level a fucking forest.
So, for tonight, lock on.
Okay?
Now, try and rev her up.
Jam it there between your knees,
pull that cord as hard as you
can.
Straight up.
- Put a bit of mustard on it.
And off!
Good, you have earned the orange
mask.
But don't get cocky.
I don't want you trying to bury
that thing into somebody's
stomach.
Just chase them around with it.
Good.
Okay.
Everyone, take your positions!
Let us in!
- Shut up!
Shut up!
- Hey Oliver!
Hey, where's Spidey?
You too cheap to pay him?
- How do you know he's not
in there somewhere, huh?
Waiting for you!
Let the slaughter begin!
Get in you date-less wonders!
♪♪ Every word you said ♪♪
♪♪ But I can't understand
when I look and I see ♪♪
♪♪ That all these words are dead
♪♪
♪♪ You say that's fine ♪♪
♪♪ But I still trip to walk that
line ♪♪
- Everybody get batty, bloody
birth!
- And pull.
- Oh man.
Oh my god.
- This is disgusting.
- Would ya, would ya hurry up!
- All right, all right,
I'm here now I've got a
shit-load of tens.
Have a nice scare.
- Oliver.
- Yeah.
- I've got to go to work.
- Oh okay, save me a table.
I'll be there at two.
- Gotta pinch a loaf!
- What?
- Yeah, I've got to drop
the kids off at the pool!
- Hurry up!
- Damn!
- Ha, ha, ha, ha!
- Awesome!
- That was sick!
- That bloody guy coming
from the wall was new!
- Everything okay?
- Great!
I just have to 'go' bad.
- Oh, there's someone in there.
Oh, me next!
- Hey, I wouldn't go
in there if I were you.
- Man, I gotta do this
fast and get back at it.
Uh, no time for airing out!
Heads up!
- If I'm not back in three
hours, call the cops!
- Back to slice and dice!
- Oh my gosh it's all wet in
there.
- You've have blood all over
you.
- So do you!
- Hey, you found my axe-
- Dad, this is so fake.
- Uh, that's stupid.
- Not even scary.
- Try scaring somebody next
time.
This had better not
stain.
- I think it's just like
invisible ink.
I think it will just
disappear after a few minutes.
- Oh, I don't think so.
Look at this.
- Maybe it's cherry juice or
something.
- Oh God, it tastes like blood.
- Back off!
That bitch's been
following us the whole way.
Get a life!
- What's going on?
- I don't know, there's
something wrong with Tracy.
- Is she hurt or sick?
- I don't know,
I can't tell with this damn
costume.
- Oh Jesus, she's been stabbed!
- I think I'm going to be sick.
- Someone just got stabbed!
- Excellent!
- Let's go.
- Whoa-whoa, wait!
Ladies and gentlemen,
just a slight technical
snafu, I will be right back.
I will be right back.
Shit.
- Heh, yeah, this blows chunks,
dude.
- Hey sexy, you want to suck on
this?
- I don't know, I don't know.
The only thing I can think is,
we have this chair that shoots
blades
through a dummy's chest.
No, I, I know it's Halloween
and you've been getting
a lot of crank calls, but
I'm telling you this is real.
Just hurry.
Just hurry!
- Okay.
I'm calling this a night.
I'm going to-
- There's a big fight outside!
- Son of a bitch!
I'll go break it up and
wait for the paramedics.
- I'm okay, I've got
pressure on the wound.
- Okay.
Claire, you've got to get
everybody out of that maze.
- Shit!
- What's going on?
- Please move to the exits.
Thank you.
- Boo!
This place sucks!
I want my money back.
- Please move to the exit.
Oliver will refund your
admission outside.
Asshole.
Thank you!
The exit is that way.
- Oh, man, this place is
so much more effective
with music and lights.
Hi!
Claire!
- Oh, sorry about this.
Look you'll get your money back.
Please just move to the-
- Look, I said we're closed.
- I don't think you understand.
We came all the way across
town and stood in line
for two goddamn hours!
- Calm down.
Hold on.
We've had an accident.
- Oww, shit.
- We're waiting for an
ambulance.
Oh, I don't have time for this.
Where's Claire?
- I don't know.
- I'll be right back.
- Uh, I, I'm going to
wait for the ambulance.
- Two fuckin' hours!
- Claire?
Oh my God.
Claire.
Claire!
- Oh Claire.
Sweet, sweet Claire
- Have you seen Claire?
- No.
Is the ambulance here?
- I don't think so.
Bart and Margo are outside.
I'm going to call the police.
Where's Sparks Malloy?
- What?
- My fucking taser!
- Don't get up!
Don't move!
Just lie there.
That's right, just lie like in
death.
Lie.
That's you, Claire.
That's my Claire.
I did it for you.
I, I did this all for you!
Yes!
Claire!
Yes, you wanted this.
This!
And I've come for you.
I know all about you.
I know, I know how you love
death!
I know how it, it thrills you...
like it thrills me!
It took me three years of
watching you and practicing.
And you, you,
you taught me how to cut.
Oh.
We'd watch you on those
long quiet afternoons
when you didn't think anyone was
looking.
You didn't see us, but we saw
you.
We'd lean up to the glass
between the branches and the
boxes.
And we'd watch you through
the Christmas window.
- Yes, right away please.
Well, I think we have a
dangerous situation here.
Yes, I think so.
Look, one was wounded
and another was killed.
- What's going on, Oliver?
- Just get the cops here.
I don't know what's going on.
Don't go in there!
Jake's dead.
- What?
Where's Claire?
- I don't know.
I sent her in to get everybody
out-
- The ambulance is here!
- Darryl, don't do it.
They're here for Tracy.
The police are on their
way, let them do it.
- Claire is in there!
- Something else is in
there and it killed Jake.
You're a kid in a costume.
What are you gonna do?
- I'm going after Claire!
- You know what's funny, Claire?
You cut to feel alive.
I cut to kill!
I used to try to cut to feel
alive, I,
I would cut, and I'd cut, and
I'd
cut and I would cut,
but it never felt good
till I met you.
And I watched how you
did yourself so lovingly.
You inspired me so.
And I grew to love you so much.
I had to have you be a part of
me.
To show my devotion.
My devotion.
The pleasure of pain, right?
The pleasure of pain,
the pleasure. I did this
for you, Claire!
- Claire?
- Not you!
Not you, Claire!
Don't be like all the rest
of them, a squealing pig!
Oh, Claire, don't be scared.
I'm here to fulfill your wish.
I'm going to take you away from
here.
And the best part, the best
part?
I'm coming with you!
Now that I've proven my
worthiness to you,
I need to do for you what you
could not do for yourself.
- Claire!
- Darryl!
- Now my darling, it is time
for me to drain you dry.
Claire!
- Then open my veins.
- Claire!
You're not a part of this!
And then we will live together
in the eternal orgy of hell!
- Claire!
I'll be right back.
Claire.
- Come here!
- Stupid.
Stupid.
Stupid!
You ruined everything!
You ruined my moment!
It's okay.
Don't worry.
I'll be sure to tell
Claire all about th-
- Oliver!
Oliver!
- God damn it!
Darryl!
- I'm okay, I'm okay.
- Was it just him?
- That thing was living back
there!
He killed, he killed Spider.
He killed all of them because of
me.
- It's okay, it's okay.
The police are here.
They're gonna sort everything
ou-
- No!
No!
- Excuse me, I'm looking for-
- Hey Darryl.
- Hey, how are you?
- Good.
Good.
- You look great.
- Still working on those demons.
- Sorry you had to come
back to work so soon.
- Oh, me too.
Therapy's expensive for a girl!
- Selfishly, I'm glad you're
back.
- God, Darryl, where
were you 10 years ago?
You know, my psychoanalysis
revealed
that I have a clinical "3M"
issue
when it comes to relationships.
Apparently I deeply believe
that all I can attract are
maniacs, molesters and monsters.
But hiding and disguising
myself didn't seem to help.
And, it's just going to take a
while
before I can shake the feeling
that I bring out the worst in
men.
- I understand.
Take your time.
When you're ready, give me call.
Merry Christmas, Claire.
♪♪ It started out like all the
rest ♪♪
♪♪ A simple ego strokin' ♪♪
♪♪ Called curiosity ♪♪
♪♪ Then you fucked up ♪♪
♪♪ And let it in ♪♪
♪♪ And left a pure thing broken ♪♪
♪♪ And disappointed me ♪♪
♪♪ Okay, I guess ♪♪
♪♪ Yeah, I'll admit ♪♪
♪♪ I take forever choosin' ♪♪
♪♪ So, maybe I could make you ♪♪
♪♪ Make the choice for me ♪♪
♪♪ Now what is it about her ♪♪
♪♪ That drives you do goddamn
mad? ♪♪
♪♪ Step back and take a
good look around you ♪♪
♪♪ I know you would prefer if I
said ♪♪
♪♪ She was the best I ever had ♪♪
♪♪ Only she, the only one that
found you ♪♪
♪♪ While you were so far from the
truth ♪♪
♪♪ I should've known ♪♪
♪♪ Known from the start ♪♪
♪♪ That this would all end badly
♪♪
♪♪ How else could it be? ♪♪
♪♪ For you are just a paper kiss
♪♪
♪♪ A bitter complication ♪♪
♪♪ And she has what I need ♪♪
♪♪ What I want and what I need ♪♪
♪♪ Have always been so confusing
♪♪
♪♪ So tell me which one is she? ♪♪
♪♪ Okay, I guess ♪♪
♪♪ Yeah, I'll admit ♪♪
♪♪ I take forever choosin' ♪♪
♪♪ So maybe I could make you ♪♪
♪♪ Make the choice for me ♪♪
♪♪ So what is it about her ♪♪
♪♪ That drives you so goddamn
mad? ♪♪
♪♪ Step back and take a
good look around you ♪♪
♪♪ I know you would prefer if I
said ♪♪
♪♪ She was the best I ever had ♪♪
♪♪ Only she, the only one that
found you ♪♪
♪♪ While you were so far from the
truth ♪♪
♪♪ So far from the truth ♪♪
- Get lost!
Except you in the back, the hot
one.
Come here.