PERVERSITY
Not I want to ruin you the party.
However, it is not wise
to make a woman wait.
You already know like they are.
- Yes indeed, Mister Hogarth.
Go if we know it.
- All are same.
I see that you are some experts.
Frankly, boys,
it has been a veiled one stupendous.
And before leaving...
...here I have a clock of gold
with seventeen rubies.
An appropriate gift
because it is for somebody...
...that he/she has a heart of gold
and he/she is an exemplary employee.
Very well.
- He/she deserves it.
Please, surrender it.
A magnificent clock.
- What he/she marvels.
Chris.
He/she looks at what takes engraving,
For my friend
Christopher Cross...
...in recognition
of 25 years of loyalty...
...of J.J. Hogarth, 1899 -1934.
That he/she speaks that speaks.
Yes, Chris, I gave something.
- We go, Chris, I gave something.
Good...
...I don't know what to say, J.J.
It is... it is beautiful.
I never hoped to have
a clock like east.
This is as a dream.
In short, it pleases me to say...
...that we have the best boss
of New York.
Congratulations.
Congratulations, boy.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank You, Chris.
Thank you, old friend.
God blesses you.
- Thank you.
He/she walks, smoke you a cigarette.
- Good, me...
Not I can.
- He/she comes, one proves.
They make them
especially for me.
He/she Takes, Charlie.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Not you will be superstitious,
hey, Chris?
No, no, at all.
Please,
you don't interrupt the party...
...only because I should leave.
Everything runs of my bill.
Thank you.
Drink as much as you want...
...but on Monday you don't arrive me
take to the work and with hangover.
Well, good night, friends.
Good night.
You are a type with luck.
- Small clock.
It is a magnificent clock.
Boys, venid here.
Look.
What do you find?
Go treasure.
Yes.
Is their wife?
The boss leaves spree.
With a woman this way anyone.
The spring
he/she has a special scent.
Where do you go, Chris?
To the meter station
of Lade Side.
It is the quickest way
of arriving in Brooklyn.
Not you have umbrella,
I will accompany you to the bus.
No, it doesn't plunder you on the way.
- I don't care to go for a walk.
He/she will come me well
some fresh air.
I drank too much.
What annoyance, I will catch the next one.
You veto to the meter, Chris.
I don't care to wait,
I sit down a little alone.
He/she Hears, Charlie.
You believe that J.J.
does he/she have a mess with that girl?
It is what seems.
I wonder how it will be.
- What, Chris?
Because to feel that he/she loves you
a treasure like that.
To me they have never looked this way at me,
not even of young.
Yes, we are usually sleepy
that they are not completed...
...although we continue dreaming.
I remember that of young
he/she wanted to be painting.
And he/she dreamt with which one day
I would transform into a great artist.
And you already see,
I am a simple cashier.
Still spots?
- Yes, on Sundays.
It is a way of killing the time.
On Sunday is the only day
that I don't like.
Not I know what devils to make.
Why don't you come home tomorrow?
- Thank you, Chris, I will go.
Good night.
- Good night, until tomorrow.
Yes, until tomorrow.
It has stopped of raining.
- Half hour ago.
The meter station
of Lade Side?
Return to the corner
and cross the high one...
...to some four apples.
- Thank you, agent.
A mess was made.
These streets of Village
they are a labyrinth.
Is it wounded?
I will warn to the police.
- No, wait, wait.
Agent!
For where has he/she gone?
- Over there.
What aspect did he/she have?
- I don't know it.
Not I could see him/her the face.
- He/she stole me 15 dollars.
He/she didn't believe me when I said that
he/she didn't have more and it hit me.
For luck this gentleman
he/she went in my defense.
It is this way, it was there same.
Not I could retain him/her,
he/she got up and he/she began to run.
Wait here.
Please, larguémonos.
We have to wait
to the agent.
Not I want to see my name
in the newspapers, and you?
The newspapers?
- Clear.
We would have
that to present an accusation.
When they arrest somebody,
they will call him/her...
...week after week,
it is a can.
Does it accompany me to house?
- Because me...
Yes, clear, clear,
if he/she believes it necessary.
We go there.
Well, this it is my house.
I sit down not to be able to invite him/her to ascend.
I share the apartment
with another girl, Millie.
Good night
and thank you again.
How's it going...?
How's it going if we take a coffee?
Of agreement.
Hello, Kitty.
- Hello, Tiny.
This is the gentleman...
- Cross.
Charmed, Mister Cross.
- A lot of pleasure, Tiny.
Have you seen Johnny?
No, since he/she left
he/she makes a while.
Two coffees, please.
- I have changed opinion.
I will take a glass,
a rum Collins.
Only one?
- Yes, yes.
Please, cheer up, man.
He/she will see, it is that I have spent
a little with the champagne.
Does he/she want champagne?
I will take the same thing that her.
From the moment in that I saw it
let us wonder which their name would be.
Kitty.
- In fact...
...he/she is Katherine,
Katherine March.
My friends call me Kitty.
How do they call him/her their friends?
Chris.
Chris Cross.
Yes, they usually wear out jokes
with that, but...
...I don't care it.
Why does he/she look this way at me?
Do I have the dirty face?
It is beautiful.
Yes, clear.
What aspect I have.
Thank you.
Health, Chris.
Miss March.
Kitty.
Yes, young lady.
Good...
Kitty...
In short... He/she Will See, Kitty...
...the certain thing is that
he/she could be their father.
Not it is so old.
Do you believe?
Neither he/she is a boy,
he/she is a man...
...mature.
I like mature men.
Well, what he meant
it is that...
...he/she should not go alone
down the street at these hours.
It returned home of the work.
Does he/she work until so late?
To what is he/she devoted?
Guess it.
You are an actress.
- How clever it is.
Now that he/she knows everything
on of me, speak to me of you...
...where does he/she work?
- Me?
Because he/she will see...
- No, don't tell it to me.
In a bank?
- No.
We will see,
in Greenwich Village is artists.
I knew him/her in Greenwich Village.
Are you an artist, not?
Well...
Yes. Yes, I am painting.
- It was clear, a painter.
I love painting.
To think that I took it
for a cashier.
Good...
He/she knows the galleries
of the Fifth Avenue?
They have some prices.
A very small square
it cost but of 50.000 dollars.
It was of...
Sesan.
- Cezanne.
A French great painter.
I would love it
to have that square.
Ah, yes?
For that heap of dollars?
Good, it cannot put on price
to works teachers like that.
They are worth...
In short, what one can pay
for them.
For sure I saw his square
and I eat he/she didn't know him/her...
Next time
I will look for their name.
No, no, not.
I don't usually sell
my squares, Kitty.
He/she doesn't sell them in New York.
Good, me...
- I already know it.
For sure he/she sells their squares
in Europe, in Paris or something like that.
I admit that I don't know
anything of painting.
Comely to that pay him/her so much
for their squares in France...
...as to the French
here in New York.
Nobody is prophet in their earth.
Good, it is a point of view.
In fact, when I paint
I never think of the money.
To put on makeup has a good time.
- Does he/she have a good time him/her?
Yes, seriously, painting
it is as more I have a good time.
God willing he/she had more time
to make it.
Is it that he/she doesn't have it?
- No, good...
He/she will see, me... my...
In short...
...the businesses
they occupy me a lot of time.
It doesn't miss me,
if they pay him/her so much.
Tell me, what it works
is it representing?
I have already finished.
- What does it work it was?
Well... What time is it?
It is only ten to both.
- Only?
It is hour that Kitty
go to the bed.
So that I don't forget.
Thank you.
Do I see it again?
- Yes, clear, why not?
Does he/she give me their telephone number?
- Not I have telephone.
Can I write him/her?
That is the address,
good night.
Kitty, who is Johnny?
Why does he/she ask me that?
He/she has asked to the barman
for him, not?
Yes, the boyfriend
of my friend Millie, does remember?
He/she is the girl that lives with me.
Good night.
Christopher.
Yes, Adele.
Chris, you invited me.
My wife...
In short, I am glad to see you.
How well we spend it last night,
truth?
Tell me Charlie,
at what time did we return home?
After midnight, not?
You know that still
I have not gone to bed.
Ah, not?
Not I am so old
as he/she thought, hey Charlie?
No.
He/she hears, now I have
that to scrub the plates.
Don't you care it, Charlie?
- No, no, ahead.
Has this painted it you?
No, please, it is not a square,
it is an insult.
It is taken out of a picture.
- Who is?
He/she is the deceased of my...
Your wife's first husband.
The sergeant detective Higgins,
Homer Higgins.
Chris,
is that medal authentic?
Yes, they gave it to Adele.
To your wife?
- Yes.
When he drowned
in East River.
It was terrible.
Not they found their cadaver.
What it punishes.
Yes, a pain.
Thank You, Charlie.
- Of anything.
How long do you take married?
Five years.
You will see...
Adele didn't want to spend
the money of the insurance...
...so he/she rented a room.
Four dollars a week.
And I was about saving money
to buy paintings...
...and it interested me.
She was very kind.
Then I was well.
And...
You already know
as they are these things.
Do you want one?
Well...
...it will be better than not.
Where are your squares?
They are there out
in the lobby.
Do you want to see those that I made?
- Yes, yes indeed.
Where you found
a flower like that?
You mean that you see this
when you look at that?
Because yes, yes. It is simply
imagination question.
You will see, when I look at that flower
I sit down something as...
Not even
I can enter in my bathroom.
He/she Forgives, Adele.
It will be better than we leave.
You can already enter.
Why the day you spend
in the sofa, lazy?
They come here.
Is all that you can make?
Not you do think of another thing, hey?
In what you want him to think,
if not?
If he/she wants more heating here,
young lady...
...he/she will have to call to the porter.
- Not be joker.
Not you do have anything to tell me?
Not I want to speak
of Saturday at night.
I don't refer a Saturday
at night, I speak to you of this.
It seems the note of a student
that he/she wants to tie.
You are perverting a minor.
At what do you laugh?
- Of you.
It is so old
that he/she could be my father.
It is the type that he/she went in my help
on Saturday for the night, my hero.
Don't tell me.
Do you see it? You were too much
drunkard to remember it.
Of not having deceived the agent
he/she would have caught.
So the type that defended you.
Is it painting?
And rich, very famous,
besides charming.
I would not shake as you.
He/she had the opportunity
of winning a departure.
He/she only needed 50 dollars...
...and you what you brought me?
15 dollars.
It is all that he/she had.
Also, you had me waiting
two hours under the rain.
You looked at me in a bad way.
- I didn't look at you in a bad way.
He/she hears, any girl
that he/she waits to a type two hours...
...under the rain
he/she looks at it in a bad way.
Do you know which your problem is?
That you don't have imagination.
What do you want him to make?
- I want you to use the head.
Not you understand that that type
is coladito for you?
It is our opportunity.
Does it make a lot of money, not?
According to you 50.000 turkeys for square,
anything less.
While I break the head
to gather some capital...
...to you you are presented this.
Not you have why to call
to that other bird...
...for 50 dollars of shit.
The old one is crazy for you.
Write him/her, propose him/her an appointment.
I would be unable to take out him/her money
to that poor man.
He/she hears, he/she also thinks of me.
It uses your intelligence,
I know to types riquísimos...
...and with half of intelligence
of the one that I have me...
...but, as what does it serve the brain?
To make money
it is necessary to have money, capital.
The colleagues
of the shop of cars...
...they would accept me as partner
if takes the pasta.
How much money do they want?
- Three or four thousand.
Caray!
Nobody gives you anything.
I already know that it is a lot of money,
it uses the imagination.
As soon as you enter
in a business as that...
...then it is easy
to get rid of the partners.
And then you make yourself the master.
Johnny, you have a lot of fantasy.
And of the what a pasta?
Can maybe get
50 or 100 dollars...
...but never a sum as that,
he/she would not know how.
Johnny!
Johnny, where do you go?
- Not I can lose the time.
Johnny, Johnny...
Not I know why
I am so laundry for you.
Yes, undoubtedly you know it.
What do you say of my proposal?
We go,
you won't have to pluck it.
Not at the beginning.
You should get
a decent apartment.
A place to which he/she feels like go to
to see you, don't unite pigpen like this.
What do you say, lazy?
Can I enter in my house?
- Hello, ugly face.
Why you don't settle here,
Johnny?
I will charge this way you the rent.
- Please, Millie.
He/she stops to enter with my fiancé.
- How is that word written?
It is written with "F" of ugly.
Does Kitty pay the half, not?
That is what we agree
when signing the contract.
For me you can stay
with the apartment.
I last with him.
What has he/she meant?
- Anything, you already know Johnny.
Yes, I know him/her too much.
He/she has already bought you
the ring of commitment?
That seems to worry
more than to me.
A model of 45 turkeys.
Roger left it to me in 18
and above it still won.
Not you were modeling strips
for the catalog?
It is this way.
I have eaten too much.
If they return the corsets,
I swear to stop to be model.
Why don't you want to work?
With that figure.
If was not so lazy.
Who you believe that you are,
my guardian angel?
What he/she goes, rich, I lost the wings
a long time ago.
It is evident.
It doesn't miss me that says goodbye to you.
Not you arrived on time
to the work...
...since you knew Johnny.
Treasure, what has he/she spent?
What you would want
that passes you.
I am in love,
crazily in love.
Of somebody that mistreats you
as to a load animal.
Don't enter with Johnny.
You could choose the man
that wants.
Clear,
and it is him to the one that I want.
He/she will make of you a lost one.
Not you would get love
although gives you in the face.
If it is there where he/she gave you,
you should know it.
I would like to sing
as that sparrow.
There up there are two,
they are building a nest.
Where have you learned that?
I learned it being boy.
He/she already makes almost 40 years
that he/she didn't whistle.
Today I sit down as a boy.
You have sold some square
lately?
No.
Why you don't paint me
a portrait?
I would like it.
I can take the easel
to your apartment?
Not I believe that to my friend
he likes.
How long
does it take you to paint a square?
Sometimes one day,
sometimes one year.
One cannot say,
a square goes sprouting.
It is that a square
can it sprout?
The feeling yes.
That is the important thing,
the feeling.
And me, for example, good,
to me nobody taught me to draw.
I trace a line around
of what I sit down when seeing the things.
Yes, I understand.
It is as...
...to fall in love, I suppose.
You already know.
You know somebody that
he/she leaves making important...
...until you cannot happen
without him.
Interesting.
I believe that the art is this way.
Each square can be
a history of love.
He/she had never heard speak
to anybody in that way.
Good...
...neither there are a lot of people
to the one that can be spoken this way.
One is quiet it.
He/she keeps it inside
as a secret.
Yes, exact.
That is in fact
what passes me.
I have to be quiet
many things.
The certain thing is that I am in a mess.
You, Kitty?
- Have not you noticed it?
I am without a cent.
This dress Millie lent it to me,
and I owe him/her the rent.
Tell me how much it is.
- Forget it.
Not I should mention it.
I bothered you the day.
- Kitty, me...
I will already get ready them.
Not it could accept
anything of you, Chris.
No, if...
- No, no, it would not rot.
I never requested money to a man
and I won't make it now.
Not I want to ruin
our friendship.
Kitty, please.
Not it could return it to you.
Chris!
Maybe yes it can return it.
If you pay the rent
of a study...
...he/she would have where to live and you
could you paint, do you understand it?
You could paint my portrait.
What does it happen?
Not you do want to paint my portrait?
I have to tell you something.
- What?
I have deceived you.
I lied you.
I am a married man, Kitty.
And why didn't you tell it to me?
Not I am of the class of women
that they go out with married men.
You remember that Preposition
of knowing somebody...
...of how it begins to like you...
...until you only think of him?
You should say me
that you had a wife.
Not I am in love with her.
- But you married.
It felt very alone,
it could not support the solitude.
Poor Chris.
Not you are mad with me?
He should be,
however, he am not.
With you not, Chris.
I will let you to help me.
How much do you need?
- 500 dollars.
500...
I need 500 dollars.
It could return 10 every week.
It is well, Mister Cross.
Although a guarantee will need.
No, thank you.
- Somebody solvent?
Do pay?
- Pure formulismo.
Thank you.
- At your disposal.
And that tight of Hogarth...
...why it cannot go up you
the salary?
You not even win it enough
to buy me a radio.
I have to go all the below
nights to listen the serial one.
I don't make more than to save...
...and you wear out it
in paintings and canvases.
Not I know what you will make
without me.
My dear Homer.
If has a tomb
where to take you flowers.
You were not even capable
of declaring you.
I had to put on the words
in the mouth. God willing follows widow.
I support you
because we are married.
You have me full.
- Yes, I am also full.
Have you been drinking?
No, neither a swig.
It lets him to smell you the encouragement.
Then, what does he/she spend?
Why are you speaking this way to me?
Always censoring
that he/she doesn't buy you a radio.
You believe that I like to lower all
the nights to listen the radio?
You buy it, you have money.
- The money of their insurance?
I don't want a radio,
but you.
I will never play those funds,
I keep them for my age.
Homer would have bought me
a radio.
He/she had a good salary
and it provided me a house.
You continue in the same one
apartment, not?
Yes, but then
he/she didn't smell of painting.
Not I hit eye with that damned scent.
Not I want to see the lobby
full with squares.
If you don't come undone of them...
...I assure you that I will give them to him
to a chamarilero.
Adele...
- Yes.
I swear you that I will make it.
For the things that you paint.
Already bad eras when you copied
post cards.
Uti? copied post cards
and he/she is considered a great painter.
Already, I suppose that you are copying
to Utrié or like he/she calls himself that.
Every time you are crazier, yes.
Not there is more than to see
that makes.
Strange Flores, snakes...
You only lack to paint
to a naked woman.
I have never seen
It would lack more, that waits.
Date hurry.
The Hour of the Happy Home
it will already begin, lover.
Under at once, Dora,
Sr. Cross has arrived late.
He/she comes.
When you end up,
he/she washes the plates.
Christopher.
What are you making?
It was...
It was looking for the newspaper.
Are you blind?
What does it happen?
Not you had gone down to hear the radio?
It was ruined exactly in the best thing,
that apparatus is a junk.
Have you read this news?
- Which?
A murder in Queens.
A man killed his wife
with a paperweight...
...it put their body in a trunk
and he/she sent it to California.
Here he/she says that he/she had...
- I have read the newspaper, thank you.
He/she won't get rid of the punishment.
He/she will go to the electric seat,
you will already see it.
Yes, with the inspectors of
New York didn't have escape.
Why you don't leave the newspaper
and do you wash the plates?
Adele...
...you would not speak seriously
when you said...
...that you would give him/her my squares
to a chamarilero?
Of course.
Because you won't have to make it.
My friend
he/she plans to rent a study...
...in Greenwich Village,
I will take them there.
Good, if he/she is the enough idiot
as to allow it...
...ahead.
- Woman!
It is the last floor,
he/she has a lot of light and it is cheap.
They have heard speak
of Tony Riverside the designer?
He/she rented the apartment
during three years.
Not he/she could work in another place.
Do they come? This was their study.
These drawings
they belong to Tony Riverside.
He/she used to make that
with their models...
...when he/she worked
in some cover.
Today they would pay a fortune
for them.
Is artist, young lady March?
Where is the bedroom?
- Here.
How much the rent is,
Mister Johnson?
150. Tony Riverside left
some things in the basement.
Van with the apartment
if they want to use them.
Here the bedroom is.
I don't like anything the paper.
Will they paper it?
Good, if he/she rents it one year.
The paper will choose it me.
He/she stops to poke in the handbag.
Hello, lazy.
He/she has looked like each other to hear the bell.
Because I have not heard anything.
Is this all that you have?
With what you spent last night,
you are lucky that it is that.
Until you bought me a book.
According to you,
do you want to be an actress, not?
To interpret
to William Shakespeare.
It is as much as I have left.
You will know how to get more,
hey, lazy?
He/she said that he/she made a lot
that he/she didn't sell squares.
And he/she has paid me all this.
He/she Looks, Kitty.
I need at least1.000 dollars.
To that you have already softened it,
no?
Now press him/her.
It seems uncomfortable
when I speak to him/her of money.
Beautiful, you have it
about to candy.
It is already hooked,
it cannot come unfastened.
Could he/she leave me, not?
- Not forget to their wife.
Insinuate him/her that her
it could find out everything...
...and you will already see like he/she reacts.
That calls you blackmail.
He/she could only call himself blackmail,
small...
...if you allow to catch.
Is he?
- I told you that he/she had heard the bell.
Damned it is, come undone of him.
Go...
Not you do answer to the bell?
And you were not mad?
- It is a truce.
Whisky?
- Thank you, treasure.
He/she knew that you were,
it is hardly twelve o'clock.
I lowered again
and I saw the open door.
Go, go, go...
Not it is bad
for a small poor person.
Not begin another time with that.
Don't tell me
that it is under the bed.
No, lover.
You can leave, Johnny.
Not you had more than to call,
ugly face.
Have you guessed right in the careers?
It could be.
The last time that I saw you
you spoke of leaving to Hollywood.
It is possible that he/she still makes it.
I read somewhere around that a type left
to Hollywood without a cent...
...and it won a million,
and callow.
That yes, it was handsome,
he/she worked in a supermarket.
If he/she worked
he/she didn't resemble you.
Do you want to stop to discuss?
- Not we are discussing.
It is that Millie doesn't have neither he/she devises.
They say that to the actors...
...they pay them five or ten thousand
dollars per week...
...to make what?
To be made the five pesetas,
to shake the girls.
Cannot I maybe make it me?
If it is this way, why don't you make it?
He/she can that he/she makes it,
give me time.
Chris!
I have brought some
of my things, Kitty.
Tomorrow I will bring more.
And the rest on Saturday.
You have company.
- They Are Millie and Johnny.
Johnny...
- The boyfriend of Millie.
I will present them to you.
Millie, this he/she is a friend,
Chris Cross, Millie Ray.
How is it, young lady Ray?
- Charmed, Mister Cross.
And Johnny Prince.
How is it?
We have not seen each other
in some part?
It could be, it could be,
Mister Cross.
Yes.
And I am not able to remember it,
perhaps make a mistake.
Perhaps.
Good, I already leave, Kitty.
- I will accompany you, ugly face.
Don't bother you, Johnny.
Not you will think
that I will allow you to go alone?
It could run over you a tram.
Good-bye, Mister Cross,
it was a pleasure.
Thank you for the whisky, Millie.
- Of anything, good-bye.
Until soon, Kitty.
- Until soon, Johnny.
Does it happen you something, Chris?
The truth, your friend Johnny
it has just liked me.
Johnny is a good type.
Yes, clear, otherwise
he/she would not be your friend.
There is something in him that...
- Millie is crazy for him.
You would like to toss
a glance to my squares?
Still not.
They come to sit down.
Are you happy?
For the first time in my life.
- Very happy?
I think all the time of you.
I am always wanting to see you,
to have you close.
I know that I am not entitled
to wonder it...
...however,
at some time there are...?
Without a doubt,
there were other men in your life.
Only one, Chris.
Do you still see him/her?
I have forgotten him/her.
He/she looks, Kitty, if was single...
...and if he/she didn't have a wife...
- But you have it.
Yes, I already know it, but if her...
Good, if happens something
that liberates me...
...would you marry me?
Now don't speak of that,
lover.
The most urgent thing
it is that it gets an employment.
This life is expensive.
Not he/she wanted to request you he/she swims...
...because I know that you have not sold
any square lately.
Not you do have enough money?
Not you know the difficult thing that it is
to find work as actress.
The talent doesn't count for anything,
recommendation is needed.
You should know
to some fat fish...
...that an agent takes you
and that hill money.
It is needed clothes and those things.
- Kitty, you are beautiful.
Chris, the beauty is not everything,
treasure.
It is the clothes, perfumes,
the impression that you cause.
He/she would need a thousand dollars
only for dresses.
A thousand dollars?
- As a little.
Perhaps he/she requests them to Millie
or to their boyfriend Johnny.
ÉI has a lot of money.
No, no, no, Kitty.
To Johnny no way.
Why not?
I will get you the money
as it is.
Treasure, you are adorable.
I begin to believe
that you are in love with me.
He am, Kitty, and a lot.
Chris, you are very impetuous.
I know that you like,
but there are certain limits.
Yes, I know it.
I have to leave,
I have that...
I will return at noon tomorrow,
Kitty.
I will be waiting for you.
I set that you have to leave.
Good-bye, Chris.
Not forget the money.
- I will get it.
Good-bye, my life.
- Good-bye.
I don't understand it.
That unhappy one should be crazy.
A snake in the high one.
Somebody exists
able to pay for this reason?
He/she hears, you are sure that
a humbug is not?
It is too silly
to be a humbug.
In that you are right.
- How would it get the money?
If has to be won it, not him
they would give more than 50 a week.
Not you have neither art idea.
Maybe not, but that believes
that he/she has arrangement.
This it doesn't displease me.
Have you seen flowers like this?
I wonder if he/she could sell
these squares.
And what I tell him/her when
do let us wonder where they are?
Tell him/her that they are
in a guardamuebles.
You have to protect them.
Not you can leave
some squares of value...
...where anyone
it could be taken them.
It is chancy, any
expert would recognize them.
Today he/she has tried to kiss me
and I have not liked that.
They have already kissed you other times.
He/she hears, they are not even signed.
That what it cares,
they are known.
Not where I will take them.
Johnny, I don't support that he/she plays me
nobody more than you.
It disturbs me that I looks at myself
in that way.
If was cruel or vicious
or if screams me, it would be different.
You don't love me.
If you loved me you would understand me.
No?
- No.
And now, what?
Good, maybe yes.
Making overtimes,
Mister Cross?
I am about to leave, Ben,
I already leave alone you.
You don't bother.
I have caught him/her exactly on time.
Change me this check,
does he/she want, Chris? It is personal.
Yes, yes, of course, J.J.
Here he/she has.
- Thank You, Chris.
Good night.
- Good night.
Hello, Nick.
- Hello.
What do you bring there?
To the one that paints these squares
they give him/her 50.000 turkeys for each one.
What is it what spends, Nick?
From where you took out them,
of Washington Square?
The hippies of Village
they sell these messes...
...for the price of the cloth.
This didn't paint it any hippie
of Village.
That is my house of zeals,
no?
And that snake
he/she comes directly from Bronx.
That type lives in Brooklyn,
it is famous.
Yes, how does he/she call himself?
- Well...
He/she hears, I have brought you other things and
you have never requested me names.
They were jewels, he/she brings another gender
and we will continue making businesses.
Take you this to Washington Square
where you found it.
I see that he/she has good eye
for the art.
It is one of my best squares.
And this, how's it going?
Not he/she knew that was
you painter.
I am not it.
Are they good?
- Well...
...they have something.
A characteristic...
...peculiar,
the perspective.
Is it important?
- Yes indeed that yes.
Look at my squares.
Where did he/she buy them?
I didn't buy them,
I want to sell them.
He/she wants that you the bandage
for a commission.
How much does he/she believe that they are worth?
- I begin requesting 25.
Then, he/she already knows,
to sell squares is bad business.
Nowadays
people don't buy art.
Not there is sensibility,
neither good pleasure, neither proportion.
Neither perspective.
Leave me their name
and their address.
I will return later, good-bye.
Hello, Johnny.
- Hello, Tiny.
Who has given you that?
Nick.
And what is there of my ring?
Do you know what costs a brilliant one?
- I gave you 900 dollars.
Do you want to lower the voice?
You have told me
that that old one is silly.
He/she can that you are it you.
He/she said that those squares
they were worth a lot of pasta.
Did you bother yourself in checking it?
- What does it happen?
They are only worth 25 dollars
each one, that it is their price.
You have become crazy.
Don't provoke me, small.
- Don't get angry.
Then you don't call me crazy.
That old one is a humbug.
Does he/she have money, not?
And if he/she requests it borrowed
or are their savings?
Perhaps he/she steals it.
- To steal it?
What do you say?
Not it is their style.
He/she would never dare to steal.
Because it doesn't win it
with their squares.
Maybe be silly,
but he/she knows about art.
The day of the museum
he/she explained to me many things.
It is very clever,
people stopped.
What museum?
- Metropolitan.
Caray, there is squares
that they are worth millions.
Where do you go?
I will make you be
in ridiculous, lazy.
Not you can take their squares
to the museum.
Who does that say?
Does he/she know who has bought them?
Janeway, Damon Janeway.
Not he/she does know who Sr is. Janeway?
- No.
An art critic.
The biggest authority in
modern art of New York.
He/she saw them and he/she bought them both.
He/she not even noticed mine.
Neither to look at them.
He/she wants to put on in contact
with you.
He/she told me that calls him/her,
you wait a moment.
No...
Forgive.
Tell me,
what does he/she make you so much grace?
You, treasure.
You are the clever one that went
to leave me in ridiculous.
To make fun of me.
You have sold two squares
for 10 cents each one...
...and now you cannot get paid.
- He/she shuts up.
My God.
- What does it happen now?
How will I say it to Chris?
- He/she won't find out.
For sure if that Janeway
he/she is a critic...
...he/she writes in a newspaper.
We will enter in a mess,
I told you that doesn't make it.
Don't become nervous.
The type to which I sold them to him
he/she doesn't know me of anything.
Give me a glass, I need it.
Chris?
- No, he has key.
He/she walks, see to see who is,
date hurry.
You forgive...
...we are looking for a man,
I don't know how he/she calls himself.
Then I cannot help him/her.
Apologize.
Look.
And this.
It belongs to him.
There it is.
Why it disappeared
in that way?
Take,
50 less dollars 20%.
Hear, I don't know of what he/she speaks to me.
Of the square that you left me.
It will be better than we show up,
my name is Janeway.
This is Mr. Dellarowe.
- Charmed.
What is what you/they want?
We would like to know
who painted those squares.
Doesn't he/she know it?
- Undoubtedly not.
For that reason we have come.
Please,
if he/she is the painter's friend...
...put him/her in contact
with Dellarowe.
Why he/she bought them
if he/she doesn't know who has painted them?
Because they are good.
- Who did paint them?
No, Johnny, not.
Not be so modest,
dear March.
Do they come it?
They have made me be bad.
He/she made me promise
that he/she would not say it.
For that reason I faked not to know it.
It is very special
regarding their squares.
Not it lets him to see them nobody,
they already come that not even the signature.
That has observed.
It is you a great artist,
young lady March.
Oh, not.
- Do they come it?
Neither he likes
that it is spoken of it.
It is convinced that
their squares are not worth anything.
For that reason it takes to you
those two...
...to give him/her trust,
he/she knew that they were very good.
Does it allow me the money?
He/she would never have guessed
that he/she was a woman.
Neither me. Their work is
very vigorous, young lady March.
Can we see some more?
- Clear, ahead.
See as much as they want.
- Thank you.
You are crazy.
How do you dare to make this?
What fright.
I believed that they were policemen.
I know that I make,
those neither they find out.
Not I will be able to deceive the critic.
You have always wanted to be an actress,
it is your opportunity.
Many hours you have happened with
the old one, you already know like speech.
Janeway will swallow it to him, I will tell him/her
that he/she comes to speak with you.
No, he/she waits.
How long does it take painting?
Since he/she was a girl,
Mister Janeway.
Did he/she go to some school?
- No, he/she was born with talent.
I believe that I am the only one
that it has encouraged it...
...so that it continues ahead.
As friend,
unselfishly.
Non memory their name.
- Prince.
Mr. Janeway,
she is upset.
Perhaps if you speak to him/her.
I will attempt it.
Well, Mister Dellarowe.
He/she knows if Ms. March
would he/she leave me the squares?
Good, that depends.
What would you give to change?
The prices will go in increase,
however...
In general,
I can say if a square...
...it has been colored
for a man or for a woman...
...and you have deceived me,
young lady March.
It is not only original,
he/she has virile force.
How long
does it use in a square?
Sometimes one day
and sometimes one year.
One cannot say,
a square sprouts.
It is a feeling, he/she already knows.
A feeling that sprouts,
as...
As falling in love, I suppose.
A good description.
In my opinion,
each square if it is good it is...
...a history of love.
Can I write that?
- No, please.
Non scribe on me.
I fear myself that it will be
a very difficult case.
Why he/she doesn't have trust
in their work?
Because I don't know how to draw.
He/she doesn't make it bad.
I trace a line
around what I sit down...
...when I look at the things.
To speak with you
it is something that comforts me.
What? How does that go?
We have already broken the ice.
Kitty, Mr. Dellarowe...
...he/she wants to have the sole right of
does all your work, find you well?
As friend
I advise you that you accept.
They can come tomorrow
to the gallery?
To what time?
- To the one that the young lady wants.
What do twelve o'clock find it?
Later
go to eat lunch.
Good, me... Not I know...
There it will be.
Their presence has been decisive,
Mister Prince, to encourage her.
I see that it is tired,
young lady March.
It is enough per today.
We leave, until tomorrow.
Thank you, Mister Janeway,
good-bye.
Good night.
Good night, Sr. Dellarowe.
- Good night.
Good-bye.
- Good-bye.
He/she listens, lazy.
Not I know what you have told him/her
to Janeway...
...but you have it in the pocket.
He/she won't finish
with the lunch.
Good, and what difference does it make?
- If you refer to...
Not continue behaving
as a girl.
Allow it to talk of what wants,
he/she will speak to you of art.
If I was sensible
I would leave your side.
But you are not it.
Here below,
as if signs a letter.
He/she comes.
Katherine March.
- Kitty?
There that is, hide it.
Kitty?
Chris!
- Kitty, happened here and...
Hello, Mister Cross,
I have gone up a moment.
I Thought that Millie
it would be at home.
He doesn't care him to admire
their squares, not?
No, no, at all,
Mister Prince.
Excellent work,
it is a magnificent square.
He/she has very good perspective,
hey?
Yes, it is what I am given better,
the perspective.
In short, I already have to leave.
Until soon, Mister Cross.
If you see Millie
tell him/her that I am in the bar of Tiny.
Don't bother you,
I know the road.
Does it take a lot of time here?
No, why?
I don't like it.
- Not he/she is bad person, Chris.
Not I know why reason
you don't like it.
Do tell me, was he?
Him, who?
You said that there was a man.
For heaven's sake,
when will you forget that?
Was he?
- No!
Kitty...
- He/she paints if you want.
Not I plan to stay here
so that you torment me.
Kitty...
Kitty, please.
Leave alone me,
I will have dinner outside!
Kitty, don't get angry.
For that come if always
are we discussing?
I didn't request it to you.
- I beg it to you.
Sacred sky.
Start to paint.
- Not I can.
Not I can paint
when you are mad with me.
Do you want me to leave?
I want you to stay here
painting.
Chris, I sit down it.
Why you torment me with
something that belongs to the past?
Because because...
Do you want to marry me?
- Not you would rot.
Perhaps happen something.
- As what?
It offers that your wife
don't hear you speak this way.
I would marry you
if was free, but you are not it.
So don't speak of it.
He/she walks, start to work.
Do I paint your fingernails?
Good,
he/she planned to make it me alone.
However...
Yes, make it, Chris.
It will be a work teacher.
Hello, Adele.
I went to the butcher shop
as you took charge me.
They have given me
a liver buenísimo.
From when you know
to Katherine March?
He/she answers.
Not I know of what you speak to me.
- From when do you know it?
Not lose the calm,
it lets him to help you with the coat.
You have lost the calm.
It separates that, it drops the knife.
You want to behead me.
From when do you know it?
Not I know to what you refer.
- Liar.
You take years copying their work.
Faking that you are the creator
of those squares...
...while you copied
the work of a great artist.
For sure you go to Dellarowe
to take notes.
Where?
- You know it very well.
To the gallery Dellarowe in the 57.
The window is full with
squares of Katherine March.
Have you become madwoman?
A single square is worth
500 dollars, they are brilliant.
Now I understand
why he/she sometimes thought...
...that there was something in your work,
I already know why.
If I see you again
painting here...
...I swear you that I will call
to that woman...
...and I will tell him/her that you are
plagiarizing their ideas.
Humbug.
Hogarth should go carefully,
you are able to steal him/her.
That not, affection.
Dellarowe wants
that you give them to him all.
Chris finished it just yesterday.
Janeway says
that the last squares...
...they are the best.
I was right about Janeway,
lazy.
Yes, but it puts me nervous.
This week I have left
three times to have dinner with him...
...and he/she already speaks of having breakfast.
He/she looks at me in a strange way.
You limit yourself to have him/her I please.
For you it is very easy to say it...
...but,
what do you tell me of my nerves?
Dad will take charge
of Kitty.
It is possible that he/she gives him/her
a ring of brilliant...
...a limousine...
...and a house with garden.
- And to Johnny?
ÉI goes with the lot.
Chris.
As my squares they have arrived
to Dellarowe?
Chris!
Don't get angry with me.
Not I am mad,
I don't understand anything.
Not it is possible.
Forgive me, treasure. Me...
He/she needed money.
He/she had to pay the furniture.
It was so humiliating.
Not he/she could tell it to you,
you have been so generous with me.
Not he/she could.
For that reason I sold the squares.
To Dellarowe?
Seriously you did sell them to him?
Yes.
I already know that I should not sign them
with my name...
...but Dellarowe demanded to know
who had painted them...
...and he/she could not give him/her your name.
He/she no longer has remedy,
truth?
No.
The curious thing is that
he/she didn't seem to give him/her importance.
Yes, the certain thing is that yes he/she has it,
Kitty.
If the has taken me
to somebody as Dellarowe...
...he/she would not have caught them.
I am a failure.
No, you are a great painter.
Mr. Dellarowe said it
and also Mr. Janeway.
Good...
...they said that I was it.
- Because they will continue saying it.
Chris!
- No, Kitty.
Please, don't cry more.
I am happy,
it is as a dream.
Chris, you are so good,
so generous.
Not it cares what name
take the squares...
...yours or mine.
It is as
if is married.
Only I take your name.
Go, that makes that
sit down in debt.
I want to paint your portrait,
what do you say?
It ascends there.
Do you know how I will call it?
Self-portrait.
EXHIBITION
DE KATHERINE MARCH
Hello, Damon.
- Hello.
Williams.
I admit that it is the first time
that I agree with you.
Thank you.
I believe that the painter is still
more fascinating than their squares.
How is it?
As Gioconda
without the smile, hidden something.
It seems sometimes
two different people.
I speak of that in my article,
do you want to read it?
Mr. Cross, out is somebody
that he/she wants to see him/her.
Who is?
- Not he/she mentioned their name.
He/she only said that he/she was a detective.
Are you the detective?
- I was it once, Mister Cross.
Is it that it doesn't recognize me?
No.
Homer.
Surprised, hey?
Don't faint,
Mister Cross.
Calm, let him to explain to him/her.
For then
it was put in a mess.
It took out them money to the bars
secret of the port.
They gave the blow.
And the poli will make
an investigation.
One night was
in the bridge of Brooklyn...
...giving turns to the matter...
...when he/she appeared
a type screaming:
"A woman
it has jumped of the bridge."
I left running, I took off
the jacket and I threw myself to the water.
It felt so bad
that he/she wanted not to leave.
Does he care it?
Good, I began to swim
in full night...
...I caught it of the arm,
to the while it was tired...
...I heard the whistle of a tug
near me...
...I was tossed above
a barge...
...I held myself to the overboard
and I allowed myself to take.
I looked my hand,
and what was there in her?
The woman's handbag.
He/she had caught their handbag
instead of their arm.
Inside of there was 2.700 dollars
in notes.
He/she imagines to somebody that
do take off the life with that money?
And the barge discharged
in a ship barn...
...going to Honduras,
and I left with him.
Then, if it is not dead...
...I am not married with Adele,
certain is not?
How much you would pay me for...
...to maintain the closed mouth...
...and to disappear?
A moment.
Legally you
he/she is the husband of Adele.
Without a doubt, you need Adele
and I need money.
Are you a cashier, not?
He will find easy
to be made with a couple of thousands.
No, not,
I could not make something like that.
Not he/she does plan to return with her?
- No.
Although
not to favor you.
I will leave for the good of Adele.
Not you believe
that this finishes here.
It is possible
that some day it returns.
Adele would leave him/her at once
for a man as me.
I will get him/her the money.
That is more reasonable.
Although he/she will have
that to wait for me here.
I won't have it until later
of closing at six o'clock.
I Will Wait, Cross.
Hello, Johnny. Hello, Kitty.
- Hello, Mike.
Hello.
Not do forget the champagne, hey?
Beautiful car, Johnny.
Does he/she run a lot, not?
Any poli
it could reach me.
He/she hears, they are enough 25 cents
for a cube of ice?
Clear, Johnny.
Do you lend me the punch?
Not forget to return it.
- Clear, clear.
Thank you.
Only 200.
It is all that I could get.
Not he/she believes that their wife
is something worth more?
He/she will see, I want him to get that that
it corresponds him/her, Mister Higgins.
What he/she tells me
of the money of the insurance?
The insurance?
Two thousand in the event of death,
of their death.
Adele has charged them,
are his, not?
The guard in their room.
Not it is well that me the cripple,
Mister Higgins, but...
...if you take them to him,
it will be very fair.
And how, of what way?
- It is very easy.
Tonight
she plans go to watch a movie.
I allow him/her to enter,
you catch the funds...
...and it is released.
Why don't you catch them?
Good, it is necessary that
let us stay to the margin.
He/she already knows Adele.
And if he/she doesn't go to the cinema...
...and I show up,
will he/she discover me, not?
Yes, only...
...that won't happen.
- Why?
He/she will see, you will wait
in front of the house at eleven o'clock.
All well?
Why I should remain silent,
and this darkness?
Mrs. Michaels. He/she remembers
to Mrs. Michaels, not?
Yes.
- And the other neighbors.
Where are the funds?
There, in the last drawer
of the dresser.
Well, give me the lantern.
Thieves!
Police!
Who are you?
No, it cannot be.
Johnny!
Oh, Johnny!
- Hello, lazy.
I adore you, Johnny.
What has that been?
Is Chris?
Johnny, era Chris?
- You call it.
Chris.
He/she should shake.
How he/she went that is that he/she would come
tonight? I don't understand it.
You never understand anything.
- Why do you get angry?
It serves me to think as what
being with an idiot as you?
I told you that is careful.
- Clear, throw the blame.
You asked me that stays
and I wanted to leave.
Johnny,
why do you speak this way to me?
It is the true, I am fed up with you.
Johnny.
It is the only language that
you understand, we have finished.
Mr.,
sympathize with of the sinners.
The on the way to the wrong
it is easy to continue.
However, that road
it ends up in the hell.
Mr., sympathize with of me,
sinful poor person.
Sympathize with of us,
Mr..
Millie, am I Kitty, and Johnny?
I supposed that he/she would go to Tiny,
was he/she drinking?
Anything, a fight.
This cannot live without me.
The same as I cannot live
without him.
Did he/she say if he/she would come here?
To give me a beating?
Go, how he likes to show off
of hard man.
Not you should worry,
he/she only speaks to speak.
If is in love
you would understand it.
He/she remains silent,
Johnny is inoffensive.
It is this way the love, treasure.
He/she has just entered
and mo?a that takes go.
Good-bye, lover.
Hello, Johnny.
We go, Johnny, I have heard you.
You lied me, Kitty.
Was he, truth?
I have me the blame
of being in love?
No, you only believe he to be.
Not you can want somebody
as that Johnny.
It is bad.
Does he/she have you dominated, not?
He/she wanted to kill him/her.
And that is horrible.
To what have you come here?
To request you that we marry.
- And your wife?
I no longer have it, that ended up.
- For heaven's sake...
Their husband has returned,
I am free.
We go, don't cry, Kitty.
I know what you feel, but forget it.
We all make errors,
it doesn't care what happened.
I can already marry you.
I want you to be my wife.
We will leave both together
very far from here.
Where can forget
to that man.
Not cry, Kitty.
Please, don't cry.
Not I am crying, imbecile,
I laugh.
Kitty...
You are an unhappy one,
how can you be so silly?
Kitty...
I have wanted to laugh in your face
since I met you.
You are ugly and old.
And I am fed up with you.
Full, full, full!
Kitty, I beg it to you.
You to kill Johnny?
I would like that attempts it.
All the bones would break you,
him yes he/she is a man.
Do you seek me, you?
Outside of here, it was!
What will you make?
Chris! Chris!
Don't come closer, Chris.
Chris!
Hey, what do you make?
Be careful, Johnny,
you will kill somebody.
Chris, ascend.
A moment, please.
Why did he/she make it, Chris?
When he/she called me the police
he/she could not believe it.
They denounced him/her for telephone.
- Yes, a certain Higgins.
I consulted the books
before calling him/her.
Does he/she know how much it lacks?
More than 1.200.
- We will take it to us.
While it presents the accusation,
Sr. Hogarth.
Wait, Morris.
Not I can make it.
- But Mister Hogarth...
You have completed
with their duty and I thank him/her for it.
There there is a box of cigarettes,
take you her.
This well, Mister Hogarth,
what you say.
Was Chris, for a woman, not?
I imagined it.
Not I want that
go to the jail, Chris...
...but it cannot continue
working here.
I have not made anything,
I want...
I want a lawyer.
Where did they stop it?
- In Rivers Sandline.
He/she tried to escape
in the girl's car.
That car is mine.
This is also yours.
It takes your initials,
the blood belongs to the girl.
Here there are 140 dollars
that you removed him/her of the handbag.
They are mine.
This ring belonged to her,
it will be worth about 600 dollars.
Small expert is made.
I found difficult it 1.200.
Here they are
the rest of the jewels.
Not they are worth a lot,
but it took them to him all.
And why not?
She will no longer need them.
I want a lawyer.
I am a citizen,
I am entitled my.
This also belongs you,
no?
He/she has your prints dactilares.
Clear, I picked up it of the floor.
How he/she went that is
that it was dead?
He/she thought that it was only sleeping.
She didn't paint
all those squares.
Old Cross is not so silly
as it seems, he/she painted them the one.
Yes, the accused
he/she brought me two squares.
He/she told me that he/she had painted them
Ms. March.
I consider myself an expert
and there is not the smallest doubt...
...Kitty was an excellent one
painter.
When he/she rented the study...
...she told me that it was
an artist, he accompanied her.
I didn't like it then
and I don't like it now.
Yes, when he/she drank it was I force.
At two o'clock, when he/she left the bar,
he/she said that he/she would give him/her a beating.
Then I told him/her:
"Care, John,
you will kill somebody."
And it killed her with my punch.
Then I heard him/her say:
"Hello, John", and it hung.
It was there, yes.
What I don't understand
it is that he/she says that he/she painted.
I never saw it paint.
That was characteristic.
Not he/she left
that the sees paint.
I have compared their letter
with the signature.
Not there is any doubt.
That if Cross paints?
He/she only knew how to copy,
he/she is a humbug.
He/she stole me to my and their boss
and to Katherine March.
My wife, that is to say,
my former wife is right.
I don't know how to paint.
My copies were so bad
that I had to destroy them.
Not they do realize?
Lie!
I will pluck him/her.
Hello, Mister Cross.
- Hello.
Tom Crucker
of Living Road.
Yes, Tom Crucker.
John Williams of Morning Road
and Cohan of Hear.
Hello.
A cigarette?
- No, thank you.
Van to attend?
Yes, I don't like it
to witness executions...
...but I don't care this
that it is made.
He/she made him/her Easter
to Johnny Prince...
...when he/she said
that he/she didn't know how to paint.
Nobody made him/her Easter
to Johnny...
...except him
to speak too much.
Yes, when it began to insult
to the girl it signed their sentence.
I noticed the jury.
If has been quiet
it would have been life imprisonment.
The tests were only
incidental.
To what does he/she refer?
Was a fair trial, not?
Yes, but always
there is a doubt.
I suppose that you will say
that justice has not been made.
That the true murderer
it is safe.
Me not, that is impossible.
Mr. Cross, any crime
it is unpunished.
How does he/she say?
- No, don't throw him/her of the language.
Not he/she will stop of speaking,
it is their favorite topic.
It is well, you can laugh,
boys.
Anything is unpunished.
Imagine that we have
a tribunal right here...
...judge, jury and executioner.
I don't understand him/her.
The murder doesn't solve anything,
what do you say?
You have seen many trials.
In that I should admit
that you are right.
The problem is right here
and it cannot leave.
Is it here, only here, and what?
That you continue punishing you
unceasingly.
Not you can escape from it,
never.
That doesn't make sense.
You have not seen so many trials
as me, Mister Cross.
I prefer the judge to dictate my
it sentences before to make it me.
At what time is the execution?
At eleven o'clock.
I didn't make it,
I swear him/her that I didn't make it.
Why don't they want to believe me?
I have told the truth,
I didn't kill her.
I swear them that I didn't kill her,
I wanted it, I wanted it...
Kitty...
No, Kitty, not.
Coarse!
No, Kitty, was him.
You were innocent, you were pure,
he killed that.
For that reason you should die,
I have killed you.
I beg it to you.
There this passing something.
He/she calms down, friend, calms down.
Up, we go, up.
Ah, you are you.
I have not told you
that you don't sleep here?
You already know the norms.
Veto to the hospice, he/she walks.
We go, we go.
Who is that old one?
He/she has the mania
that it killed two people...
...five or six years ago.
It is a fixed idea.
It is always
trying to surrender.
He/she wants them to judge it and him
execute, he/she is a crazy poor person.
That is their work teacher.
It hurts me to lose it.
For 10.000 dollars
it should not care him/her so much.