SCARECROW
- Hey! Is she there?
- Yes.
It's freezing!
Let's go!
How are things going?
Badly.
Here he is.
The bastard.
I was hoping you'd come.
Let's have a word.
Keep an eye on him.
Things are not so good.
You are our only hope.
He's a relative of the Artemyev family.
From Berezovaya Street.
Got out of the woods an hour ago.
He was packing his rifle
and accidentally shot her
in the stomach.
It's not my business.
Please help, nobody else can.
No, I can't.
If this woman dies,
inspectors will come.
They will turn the village upside down.
Our doctor is green as grass.
She can't do anything.
She wants to send her to the city.
I can't...
I can't drive her to the city,
she's dying.
What do I do if she dies?
Two kids will be left with this jerk.
I'm asking you one last time.
Please.
We need to take her to the city.
Okay. Leave us alone.
- You too.
- Ok.
She'll be all-right.
Never call me here again.
Take this.
Buy some food.
Don't you buy vodka.
Any news?
No.
What then?
We should search in the city.
I've asked a friend, a detective.
He's on it now, he'll update.
Is he good?
Yes, he is.
Listen,
just don't buy vodka.
It's 203 rubles.
Look at her.
- What's for you?
- One bread.
- Bread, I said.
- We've run out of bread.
How's that?
- No bread left.
- It's right here.
- But it's here.
- No bread left.
- No bread left, haven't you heard?
- Get out of here!
- Yes, there is.
- No! There isn't!
Are you dumb or what? Get lost!
- Screw you!
- What!?
Relax!
- Get up, you!
- Don't come here again!
Get lost!
- Let's go in.
- Don't you ever come here again.
Hello!
We're past 40 already
we've always wanted kids.
His tool is out of order.
It needs to be fixed.
We've tried everything,
ointments, herbs.
Even consulted a doctor in the city.
Nothing works.
- Drop your pants.
- What?
- Drop them.
- Do it, Volodya!
Boxers too.
- What?
- Drop your boxers!
Remove your hand.
- Remove your hand.
- Move it!
We don't trust healers that much.
But we've heard a lot about you.
They say you really help.
That's why we're here.
- Go have a smoke.
- I don't smoke.
- Go to the toilet, then.
- I don't need to yet.
Just go, Lyuba!
Get lost, Lyuba.
What do you want?
Please, help.
I told you not to come.
I'll give you everything I have.
It's not possible.
I beg you!
You're the only one who can help.
No, no.
I know you can.
- Get away from here!
- No, I won't.
I told you before, forget it!
Enough, go away!
I said, go!
Hello!
Have a look at our grandma.
Go away! Don't touch me!
What are you doing?!
Do you want to mother a puppy?
You don't believe me?
You don't.
But I can make it happen.
Let me go! Let me go!
- You'll give birth to a puppy!
- Get off of me!
Let's go out.
Hey, you!
What were you doing there?
- Did she just come out of there?
- Yes.
Tell the owner.
She could've stolen something.
Hello!
Please come here!
- Is it a good kyrympa?
- Yes, it is.
- Are you a good player?
- Yes, I am.
- Can you play?
- Nope.
- Wanna try?
- Me?
- Want me to play?
- Yes.
- Your kyrympa?
- Like this?
- Yes.
Stay away from my son!
Let's go!
Phooey on you, bitch!
I see you've run out of firewood.
Me and my son,
we brought you some.
He's been stuttering lately,
can you have a look?
He never stuttered before.
Maybe, he was bullied at school.
Or it might be an age issue.
Cant' figure it out.
Ilya, tell the lady about our trip.
Went to the woods this morning.
Brought some for us and for you.
That's it.
It can be worse, though.
Tell the lady about your school,
about your friends.
Petya goes to another school.
But I play with him.
There's also Filip, but he's sick.
Get out.
Get out!
Are you going to do anything?
Aren't you a district police officer?
I've been telling you since spring!
Find the owners and penalize them!
Unattended dogs should be muzzled!
Otherwise, they should be chained!
It's outrageous!
They nearly bit me!
If you do nothing,
I'll file a complaint to the ministry!
The minister is my classmate!
Let's not drop names, Lyudmila.
Isn't it your own fault?
How is it my fault?!
I've seen you vexing
these dogs repeatedly!
Do I look that stupid?!
Found the one to blame,
haven't you?
- Everybody has seen that.
- I'll report on you!
You were poking the Mikhailov's
dog with a stick!
What were you doing there?
Spying on me?!
We were shutting down black market
shops that you'd been reporting!
I started complaining 3 years ago!
Those bootleggers moved to the city.
Made high living out of vodka.
Did you even know that?
Talking about dogs, look who's here.
Shoo from here.
Are you shooing me?
- Seriously?!
- I said shoo.
See, officer, she's shooing me
like I'm a dog!
- I demand some respect!
- Calm down, Lyudmila.
I promise,
I'll take care of the dogs.
I'll go buy some poison and take
care of them myself!
Whatever!
I'm fed up with you!
You see, it's like this every day!
She's provoking the dogs herself.
I would go off on her, too!
Anything new?
- About what?
- You know.
No, not yet.
- Still searching.
- You've been searching for a while.
Don't get me wrong,
I only have two hands.
I don't even know whom to ask.
I think we should search
somewhere else.
You're pretty fast when you need me.
Don't worry, we'll find a clue.
I think we should look in the city.
Of course. If she still was here my
colleagues would have found her already.
-What if you don't find her in the city?
-I'm sure she's there.
It's easy to hide in a big city.
- Can you play kyrympa?
- Kyrympa?
I only tried in school.
But now I can't.
What about you?
Shut your barn door.
Them again.
Gee, there are all sorts of parasites.
Salmonellosis.
Must be some parasite.
You eat a lot of raw liver,
what if our baby'll get worms?
- But I've eaten it only once.
- Anyway.
You eat raw liver everyday,
and you don't have worms.
Talking about liver:
what if we sell our meat leftovers?
Definitely no.
We're sending them to mom.
We'll send some to mom,
and sell some too.
- Hey, you! We're in line here!
- Stop!
Let her go.
- I can't stand her!
- Why not?
- She is a fake healer!
- How do you know she's fake?
She cons people
so she can buy vodka.
Haven't you seen her drunk in the street?
- What if she's real?
- No way!
- She's a liar. L-I-A-R.
- And you are an expert.
I just know. She is always drunk.
Haven't you noticed? Just look at her.
Stop it.
Hurry up.
Keep it dry. Come next Tuesday,
I'll remove the stitches.
I can remove them myself.
Why can't you...
Heal myself?
I doesn't work like that.
-How's that woman doing?
-I don't know, she was taken away.
Look at that self-proclaimed doctor!
- Go heal yourself!
-Mind your own wife, the baby's not yours.
- What is she saying, Stepan?
- What?
Hey, you! What did you just say?
Stop talking bullshit!
- Come here!
- Stepan!
Stepan! What are you doing? Stop!
Stepan!
Stepan! Stop! Enough!
He's mutilated you.
Want me to lock him up
for a couple of weeks?
No.
Or I can ask my guys to give him
a beating?
No, no.
Here, my city friends got something.
We have the address.
You'd better throw it away.
Just burn it and forget it.
Well, it's up to you.
- Got a sauna whisk?
- What?
- I want to have a wash.
- Sure.
Klava is about to deliver.
Breathe, Klava, breathe!
Push! Push!
Breathe! In through the nose,
out through the mouth.
Just keep breathing.
Now push! Push!
Here's water.
Relax.
Try to relax and breathe.
-Stepan!
-Get out! All of you.
Come on. Don't hurt your baby.
Breathe. It's close.
It's almost here.
It's almost over.
Calm down, be a good mum.
It's coming out!
Come here, come here!
Almost here.
- I've seen you have a kyrympa.
- Yes.
- Can I borrow it?
Fool.
- Good day! There is a vacant seat.
- Hello! Snuggle up here.
- Why are you heading to the city?
- Doctor's check-up.
- And you?
- To help my son with the dorm.
- How is your slaughter season?
- Done with the cow, now on to the horse.
You?
We're done.
I'm taking some meat to my son.
- Some other food too.
- Of course.
- Why would she go?
- You tell me.
- You're from Ivan? From the village?
- Yes.
- Were you the one calling?
Let's go.
Your mitts.
- It's chilly, eh?
- It's warm, it's just cloudy.
- Too early for winter.
- You have a girl, Anzhela Ustinova?
- Call her, we gotta chat.
- Anzhela Ustinova? No idea.
Cut the crap, Veronika!
The orphan girl, black hair.
Black hair...
And who is this?
Call her here, it'll take 5 minutes.
OK. Hope you're not taking her
to the police station?
Last time I had to pay a fine to get
her out, plus pay you and your boss.
I'm not a millionaire, you know.
Relax, I won't take her.
Ok, I'll call her now.
And let her go quickly,
she has to work today.
I will.
Hello, Nariya, tell Anzhela to come down.
Yes, hurry her up.
I've heard there is a healer
in the village. Is that you?
No, that's not me.
There goes your daughter,
look carefully.
No. It's not her.
What do you mean?
Ustinova Anzhela,
born February 14, 2002.
Raised at Khoyu village orphanage,
until she was 14.
Convicted under Criminal Rule 158,
two years in correctional facility.
- Are you sure it's not her?
- No, it's not my child.
- It can't be her!
- Take a good look!
It's not my child! Not my baby.
- Where are you going?
- It's not her!
Wait!
- What do you want?
- How it's going?
- Chilling in the crib, no clients.
- Get in.
- Again?! Give me a break!
- Stop bugging me!
- I said get in!
Hurry.
My lunch break is almost over.
My baby. My baby.
Where are you from, sister?
Any luck today?
Got cash? Lend some.
I'll take it.
Got anything else?
I got it first.
Anything else?
Wait, you jerk!
Wanna join us? We live here.
- You sure?
- Yes.
You're here.
How long has she been here like this?
Two years already.
Ok, leave us alone.