SCRATCH
Why don't you just shut your gob?
I know what's best for me.
You're fucking up my life.
What's best for you, Mille?
What kind of
fucking question is that?
Mille?
What's up?
It's just Jette.
She's got no idea.
Fuck her.
She ought to keep her nose out.
We've got to get away from here.
- What if you can't find anywhere?
I will.
I'm not staying here.
I want to live with you.
This place is for losers.
Hi.
Hi, Sami.
I'm Claus.
Why can't I shack up with you?
We've talked about
that a thousand times.
You've ignored me ever since
you moved in with that bitch.
Three people can't live in
a one-bedroom flat, right?
This is the toilet.
You share the bathroom.
The dining room and kitchen
are down there.
Our office is down there.
This is the common room
and TV room.
This is your room.
Pocket money and clothes
allowance once a month.
Bugger off!
Can't you see
we're having a fuck?
You know that's too loud.
Other people live here, too.
How about some respect
for other people's privacy?
I'm not going to argue with you.
- So just fuck off.
What are you looking at?
There.
Kenny!
Oh, yes! More!
Hey, get it together, right?
Yes, yes, yes ...
Can you feel that?
Look, Thomas is getting all horny.
Like heck.
- How can you eat that stuff?
It tastes great.
- Not two months in a row.
And why do we keep having it?
- Nobody else cooks either.
So don't look at me like that.
- Say hi to Sami.
Want some supper?
- No thanks, I'm not hungry.
Look at that hair!
Does he think it's a carnival?
Look at me! I look like shit.
- You're so full of crap.
Got anything I can borrow?
- Have a look.
Aren't we going soon?
- I can't go like this, can I?
You look great.
- And you're a prat.
How about this one?
- Yes, try it on.
Will you tie me up?
Ouch!
Nice bum.
Hey!
Chill!
- What did you say?
Next time I'll crack your head open.
- Chill! What did I do?
Oooh, taking care of me!
- Those Pakis'll do anything.
They're kids. They haven't even
got hair on their dicks yet.
How much do you want?
- A tenner's worth.
What are you doing tonight?
- Going up to town.
Do you know if
Dennis has a girlfriend?
Anja, he's 24.
So what?
A gift from the Co-op.
How about going back
to Dennis's for a smoke?
We were going up to town.
- We can go later.
We'll never get away from Dennis's.
You could go on ahead.
- And bore myself to death?
Are you coming or what?
Come on!
You said we were
going to have a ball.
We'll have a ball later.
I'm going back to Dennis's.
Me, too.
I'm easy.
Fuck you lot.
Wait a moment, Mille ...
Why not come anyway?
- I don't want to. Get it?
What are you watching?
- Just some series or other.
Aren't you going
to unpack your stuff?
I won't be staying that long.
Where are you going?
To my brother's.
Sit down if you want.
What do you want to listen to?
- You've got loads of CDs.
Mostly hip-hop.
And a bit of r'n'b.
Hi-Low.
I really rate them.
Isn't this you?
- Yes.
You made this?
- With two other guys.
What do you play?
I don't play.
I rap.
OK ...
Mille? Visitors.
Who?
I told you not to come here.
- I've locked myself out.
What do you expect me to do?
You don't answer your phone.
Come on, then.
I need my pills.
- I'll get them.
I need some water.
What are you up to with Sami?
- I'm not up to anything.
Jette said you were in his room.
- We were just listening to music.
And?
- And nothing.
You fancy him, right?
- I'm going to live with Kenny.
Maybe you've changed your mind.
Give us a drag.
I can just see you and Kenny.
Will you start a family?
Maybe.
No more milk?
Apparently not.
Who finished it?
- He did.
Go and get some more milk.
- Are you talking to me?
Your mum's not here, is she?
What about it?
- Kenny, I'll go and get some.
Like hell ...
hey, I'm talking to you.
Milk.
- You think you're funny?
Cut it out.
- He should watch it.
Kenny!
- Or I'll kill him ...
Kenny, your social worker
is on the phone.
Won't he have to clear it up?
- Yes, he will.
Yeah.
Great.
OK. That's fine.
Cheerio.
What did he say?
I don't believe it!
A bedroom and a living room.
We can move in next week.
Come on ...
Come on in.
- Thanks.
It's really cool.
We can almost wave to each other.
Don't you go thinking
you can bother us all the time.
We're going to need new furniture.
I've got some in the basement.
I don't want your old stuff.
No, but there's granny's old kitchen
things and pictures and cushions ...
Mum, I want new furniture.
This one!
- No, this one.
This one's really comfy.
Try it.
Isn't it comfy?
- I prefer that one.
We haven't got room for it.
I want this one.
Go on, Kenny, please?
It says we can borrow the money.
Yes, if the finance company
approves your application.
And they say they won't.
What if we only borrow 5000?
- Makes no difference.
Forget it.
Isn't your break over yet?
- I'm just chilling.
Whassup? I'd like to give you this.
If you want it.
I'd like it.
Thanks.
Nice flat?
- It's OK.
You can help carry stuff.
Then you can see it, too.
I was just on my way out.
Anyway ... 'bye, then.
- 'Bye.
Wait, Sami.
Come over to the flat tonight.
For the party.
All right ... Maybe we will
see each other again, then.
What made you say that?
- You want him to come.
You are so out of line, Anja!
Mille? Bring us some beer, will you?
Hi, Sami!
I didn't think you'd come.
- Shall I beat it?
No. Want a drink?
Yes, please.
Mille fancies you.
Pity she's got a boyfriend.
Hey, you've had enough.
You're doped out.
You'll only chuck up.
What are you doing, you slag?
- Don't call me a slag.
Get off me!
- Get off her.
Mind your own business,
you fruit.
Get off her.
- I'll kill you, you bastard.
Cut it out!
You're pathetic.
Wait!
Are you OK?
Mille!
I'm sorry.
What are you at?
Fucking well come back here!
I must be going.
Mille?
You're not cross, are you?
- No.
Was he good?
- He was really nice to me.
Dennis shags anything that moves.
He said he was in love with me.
- You've only shagged him once.
He was lovely.
- And horny as hell?
It wasn't like that at all.
The Centre Bakery,
Mille speaking.
Mum, I'm at work.
I can't talk to you now.
I'll phone you later, OK?
'Bye.
A loaf of bread.
Half a litre of milk.
And some tobacco.
- You've got legs. Use them!
I've twisted my ankle.
I'm not buying any beer.
Whassup?
Hi! Thomas has just
lifted Hitman 2.
What are you so uptight about?
- You just sit around all day.
Get a job
so we can afford furniture!
Like other people!
Don't go in there.
What the fuck ...
Is Dennis in?
- He's humping.
Pack it in.
- Like heck I will.
How much do you want?
Hi.
Come to bed ... I've got a hard-on.
Get off me!
- What's the matter?
Where are you going?
- Where do you think?
Do my football shirt, will you?
- Wash your own clothes.
Hello.
- Hi.
Isn't it cool?
- Yes.
The Attitudes.
We've got a gig coming up.
What are you up to?
- Not a lot. Just the washing.
What about you?
- Practice.
Want to come?
The Centre Bakery ...
Hi. She isn't here.
She hasn't been in today.
I'll tell her.
'Bye.
Have you talked to her?
- No. She's uptight all the time.
Why?
- No matter what I do.
It's not my fault
we can't afford that furniture.
This mate of my brother's
has got a place full of junk.
She wants new stuff.
- He's got new stuff, too.
Furniture, car radios,
builder's supplies.
All kinds of junk.
Hi ...
What brings you here?
Are you in trouble?
No. Kenny could do
with some furniture.
How will you pay?
Dennis said I might
be able to work for you.
You can spend up to 10,000.
- Cool.
But you'll owe me 20,000 in labour.
OK.
- Start at 8, knock off when I say.
All right?
- Yes.
Well then ... we'll be off.
Coming?
No.
- See you, Mille.
Want to sing in the band?
- No way.
Why not?
- Because I don't want to.
You are so boring!
Are you calling me boring?
Are you going in?
- I'll behave, I'll behave!
Fuck!
What an amazing flat!
Is this where you're moving to?
I was, but I've changed
my mind. It's too small.
I can borrow it
when they're not in, though.
I've got to change my clothes.
There are glasses in the cupboard
if you want.
What the hell is going on?
Sami, have you lost your marbles?
You said you'd got his key back.
- I have.
So why's he lying there?
- How did you get in?
I thought you'd be back tomorrow.
With a key, of course.
- What key?
I made a copy ...
- Did I ask you to make a copy?
I'm going.
Sami, what's wrong with you?
- Mille!
Sit down! We've got to talk.
New voice message
I've bought furniture.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Where have you been?
- Round town.
Where?
- I just said.
Come and sit down.
Who have you been with?
Nobody ...
Don't tell me you were
in town on your own till 5 a.m.
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
I don't have to look at you.
I can hear you anyway.
You're lying to me.
- I'm not.
Have you nothing to say?
Don't you care?
I'm going to bed.
I'm due at work in three hours.
Work?
- This stuff didn't come for free.
Aren't you getting up for work?
Are you going to drop him?
Maybe.
You can't do that.
He's just bought new furniture.
Don't tell Dennis I was with
Sami, will you? Promise?
Are you deaf?
You've been going out
for nearly two years.
You were going to have kids.
- Don't tell me what I already know.
What if you change your mind
and he won't have you back?
What will you do?
- How should I know?
You'll have to make up your mind.
Not right now, though.
- You should.
Who for? You?
- For you.
No.
- And Kenny, maybe.
What?
- You can't just piss all over him.
Hi!
I saw you'd finished work.
Sorry about my brother.
He's a jerk.
I don't want to live with him.
Is something up?
- No, not at all.
I keep thinking about you.
I can't figure
anything out right now.
You're not for Kenny.
He's a wanker.
I don't want to talk about it.
I'll phone you.
When?
Want some?
Can't we turn it off?
- Why?
Listen ... I ...
What?
I don't think
it's fun any more.
Why don't we ever go to
the cinema or do anything?
We shouldn't live together.
I've just got us this flat!
- I know.
And furniture and everything.
I just don't feel so much for you.
- What are you playing at?
I'm going back to my mum's.
- What the hell is this?
If you go now,
don't fucking well come back.
Collect your junk and fuck off.
You'll make it up.
I've had it with him.
It's over.
They're over there.
Say what you like,
but Kenny is a good boy.
Do you mind just shutting up?
I just think
you should think of Kenny.
You're not exactly easy,
as I well know.
Shut the hell up!
Mille!
My little darling ...
- Leave me alone!
There ...
- Get out! Leave me alone!
You were meant to start yesterday.
- Yes, but ...
I don't want to hear
your lousy excuses.
Make sure
it doesn't happen again.
You stay here till 9 every evening
for the rest of the week. Get it?
Yes.
I'm off.
Keep that guy busy.
Shall I make a cup of tea?
If you feel like it.
- Not if you won't drink it.
I will.
Who is it?
Mille?
- Let him in!
Mind your own business!
- I've got to talk to you.
You can't just leave him there!
- Stay out of it!
Kenny, go away.
- Please, Mille!
Go back inside!
What do you want?
- To talk to you.
What have you got to say?
- Let me in first.
Can't you just say it?
- You are a real slag.
Shall we go?
You and me on stage together.
It'd look so cool!
We can have a streamer across the
backdrop saying FEATURING MILLE.
No way.
- It'd be great.
No!
- Go on ... it's only for one song.
Hello? Whassup?
Where do you think you're going?
So get ready with your peeps
And come on our trips
Pump the jeeps with
love for hip-hop
Fuck the creeps
with all their la-di-dah!
What am I meant to sing?
- Let me hear ya all ...
Hear what?
Mille wants my black balls ...
- You're so vain!
Have you seen Mille?
- No.
If he finds me here he'll go ape.
- The door is locked.
Open up!
Where is she?
- How should I know?
I know you've been with her today.
Stay away from her.
Loser!
You what?
- Loser! Want me to spell it for you?
Stop that!
He shouldn't provoke me.
- You're the psychopath, man.
Stop it, both of you.
If you come here, you behave.
How could you go out with him
for two years?
He's not always like that.
Maybe I should go and see him.
Fuck Kenny.
He's history.
He's so upset.
- That's not your problem.
Just don't think about him.
Know what would be really cool?
No.
- Having a flat in town.
Know what'd be really cool?
Having a bed right now.
You're so childish.
- You're mad about me.
Who says?
Talk about drunk!
Is she always like that?
- She's not usually that bad.
I feel so embarrassed.
It doesn't matter.
Hi, Kenny.
All right?
- Yes.
John is worried about you.
We haven't seen much of you.
No. It's because I ...
- Because what?
I've been ill.
- You've been ill.
Yes.
I'll be back tomorrow.
You are too unreliable.
John doesn't like
being fucked about.
On Friday you show up at
John's office with 20,000. Right?
Stop it!
Imagine
if we could get away from it all!
We could go to New York.
- What for?
To make music.
- You?
Mille? I thought
it was Kenny who was here.
Mum, get out!
- Who's that?
I met him at the hostel.
Now, get out!
I won't have his type here.
- Oh, shut it!
Sami has come to see me.
- Get him out of here.
Like hell!
You are just ridiculous.
Sami, don't mind her.
- It's my flat.
Yes, but this is my room,
so get out!
Sami, don't go!
- I'm out of here.
Sami, wait!
- You stay here!
You fat cow!
You always ruin everything for me.
You're so fucking stupid.
You're not going anywhere.
- That's up to me.
Stay away from me.
Never phone me again.
I never want to see you again.
You're just a fucking alkie.
Just leave her
to mind her own business.
That's a bit difficult.
Why?
I don't want to talk about it.
She's an old piss head.
- Shut up!
I think she's really
mean to you, that's all.
Whassup?
- Are we going to practice?
Right on.
Open the door.
You're a real thicko, Kenny.
I can't make that
much money by today.
Can't you talk to John?
I could start again on Monday.
He won't talk to me
after the shit you've pulled.
Can't I just have my old room back?
- It's Katja's room now.
What about Kenny's room?
- Someone's moving in tomorrow.
I just can't stay
at my mum's any more.
OK, you can sleep
on the sofa tonight.
I'll find some sheets.
Sami!
You can have my room.
Your room?
- I'm going to live with Dennis.
I'm sick of living out here.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
Maybe I could rent a room in town.
And live with Sami?
- It's got nothing to do with him.
I just want to get away from here.
- You're always with him.
Because
I'm going to sing with his band.
What?
- We're playing at Stengade tonight.
I didn't know you could sing.
Shit! Don't tell him I'm here.
... It's Kenny!
Bloody hell!
What happened?
- Where's Mille?
She went out.
- Where to?
I don't know.
- You know where she is.
Her mum's?
- No, I've just been there.
In that case I don't know.
- Tell her I want a word.
You've got to talk to him.
He's in a real state.
I don't like lying to him.
Everyone keeps saying how hard
it is on him: but what about me?
I'm sorry.
Your cue is "hear what?"
- I keep forgetting.
Get it together!
I've had enough.
Come on,
we'll just go on till you know it.
It sounds like crap
and everyone's pissed off.
It's only one song.
You can do it.
I've got to go soon.
- Why?
Home to change.
You can't! We're on in four hours
and we need to practice and set up.
I know.
- Are you going back to your mum's?
Yes.
- Come on, get real!
You don't want to see her.
- I've got to get my clothes.
Run along, then.
But hurry!
Mum?
Fuck!
Please send an ambulance to
11, Vejlegårds Allé, ground floor.
Mille Laursen.
Hello?
- Where are you?
On my way to hospital
with my mother.
Get on down to Stengade.
- I'll phone you later.
Mum ...
You mustn't do stuff like this.
Yes, you and me are a real circus.
I've got to phone somebody
I was meant to see.
You can just go.
I don't mind.
Sure?
It's Anja.
Hi ...
Have you seen Mille?
I'd drop her if I were you.
- What makes you say so?
Don't tell her I told you.
- What?
Promise?
- Yes. What?
She's singing in Sami's band.
She what?
They're playing tonight.
Has she been shagging him?
Uh?
What do you think?
Hi!
Why so late?
- I really hurried.
We're due on now.
Is that what you're wearing?
- Yes.
You look so naff.
- What's the matter now?
You went home to change!
I've been to hospital with mum.
- You could've changed anyway.
You think of nothing
but you and your shitty band.
You show up four hours late
looking like I don't know what!
Sing your crap yourself.
I'm not wasting my time.
What are you at?
- Fuck you.
What are you doing here?
Kenny, don't.
Come outside for a talk.
- We've nothing to talk about.
Kenny, chill out, for fuck's sake!
Beat it!
Fuck you!
Whassup, Kenny?
Let's go back on.
- You can't play like that.
What are you doing? Are you crazy?
Come here and help him!
Help him!
Don't just stand there!
Why the hell should we help him?
- He's just lying there.
English subtitles
Jonathan Sydenham