Call me anyone.
I am one of the six billion
people alive on this planet.
My age isn't important.
My race doesn't matter.
My sex doesn't, either.
All you need to know
is that I tell stories.
And I tell them because stories
create the world we live in.
Everything is a story.
History, faith,
country, even God.
Each of us has a story.
Each of us is a character
in someone else's story.
You might even say we're all
part of the same story.
This is someone
who also tells stories.
His name is Dan Brown,
and in the spring of 2003,
he published a book
that became the fastest-selling
adult novel in history.
Why did The Da Vinci Code
generate such passion?
Why did it spark
such controversy?
Why this book? Why now?
Dan Brown has done a service
to the debates
by bringing things
like the Divine Feminine,
the Sacred Feminine, back into
public discourse, if you like.
It's the theological
equivalent of junk food.
The  Da Vinci Code
gives us this kind of fantasy,
to imagine our relationships
on a personal level
can be like Jesus and Mary.
The whole thing
is a litany of lies,
'cause I think he wins the
Guinness Book of Records prize
for the number of mistakes
historically
that are made in a novel.
If you don't learn about Isaac
Newton in your science class,
and then your first encounter
with the fellow
is from having read  The Da
Vinci Code, I'll take it.
The Da Vinci Code has done
the world an enormous favor,
um, and I think
it's the beginning of hope.
If you want to learn about early
Christianity, don't read  The Da Vinci Code,
read a book about the history of early
Christianity and get your facts straight.
My own sister came to me and said,
"I just read  The Da Vinci Code.
"I didn't know
all those things."
And I looked at her and I said,
"Hey, you still
don't know all those things."
It's become a launching pad for attacking
basic Christian beliefs and an institution
within the Catholic Church.
In this case Opus Dei.
The fear of meaninglessness coupled with
disillusionment about the various isms
has generated
a spiritual hunger.
A very broad swath of humanity
simply does not find
the Church's version
of events credible.
It shows that there are thousands and
thousands of people who're prepared to hear
something different and who are trained
to find by themselves, the truth.
The great thing about  The Da Vinci
Code is it shows people are looking.
And my hope is that
they'll keep looking.
They'll look through  The Da Vinci
Code and find something deeper.
So The Da Vinci Code
touches these raw nerves
about secret knowledge, about
sacred knowledge, the quest
to find out these truths,
about why certain people
are on a mission
to find these truths, and
certain people are on a mission
to preserve these truths, and why
other people are on a mission
to cover up or conceal
these truths.
The Da Vinci Code
begins with a murder
at the Louvre museum in Paris.
Before dying,
the victim arranges
his arms and legs
to look like a pentacle.
Like this.
Or this.
The pose is a clue.
It's the first of many clues that
send Harvard professor Robert Langdon
and French cryptologist
Sophie Neveu
on a 24-hour high-speed chase
across Europe.
Paintings that lead to a chateau
on the outskirts of Paris,
a 13th century church in London
built by Templar Knights,
a chapel in Scotland
where the Holy Grail
is said to rest.
Langdon and Neveu
are closing in on a secret
that has been concealed
by the Catholic Church
for nearly 2000 years.
A secret so disturbing,
it could change our view
of history,
and perhaps,
of Christianity itself.
So in the book, they tell you
something very important.
Jesus had a female companion,
Mary Magdalene...
and they have descendants
remaining until today.
According to the novel,
Mary Magdalene is not
the penitent prostitute
the Church led us to believe.
A prostitute who finds
redemption through Christ.
No, she is the most trusted
apostle of Jesus,
his closest companion,
and the mother of his child.
Her spirit is
the Sacred Feminine,
and her body the Holy Grail.
And apparently,
she has gone missing.
So you see in the very center
of this commercial gallery
is located very strange sculpture
consisting in two opposite shapes.
One is the normal pyramid, what we call
the Blade, which is mentioned to be
the Blade of the male sign
in the book,
and we have an
inverted pyramid in glass
which is in the book mentioned
to be the female sign.
Is it the Grail or is it
the testimony of Jesus and Magdalene's descendants?
But that's the place.
This is where the novel ends
and our story begins.
Of course, I mean it's a strange place
because you are in the center of
a commercial gallery, you're close to
Virgin Megastore, amongst the shops
it's very modern, but sometimes,
I mean, we are living in
the 3rd millennium and sometimes
we are looking for things
in unexpected places...
Maybe the Grail is close
to us and we don't see.
For me one of the worst things
I could imagine
would be to open my newspaper
in the morning,
and see a big headline saying,
"Holy Grail discovered."
Because if it's
been discovered,
then there's nothing left
to search for.
The real mystery is... is
somewhere inside.
And you come to it by making
the journey, by exploring.
We have people basically who are much
more interested in treasure hunting.
They're looking for a chalice,
they're looking for a cauldron,
they're looking
for a bloodline.
For me, it wouldn't be
the Grail
because it's what
the Grail stands for,
what it represents,
what it contains, if you like,
that's much more important.
But I am interested in finding
the truth behind the myths,
behind the stories,
behind the mystery,
and I think one of the ways
that you can do that
is to dig back far enough.
If you go back far enough,
it's not necessary that you're
gonna find an absolute truth
if you go back
to pre-historic times,
but you are going to be closer to the
earliest expression of these things,
to the... to the idea, when the
idea was born, if you like.
Like the characters
in The Da Vinci Code,
we, too, are looking
for a Grail.
Not the cup
from which Jesus drank
or proof of a bloodline
descending from Jesus and Mary.
Nothing that we can see
or touch.
But something
in the heart and mind,
and in the stories
that define us.
We are seekers
traveling down unknown roads,
looking for answers
to ancient questions,
going back to a time
when religion was new,
and the Sacred Feminine
was just evolving,
25,000 years ago,
when our ancestors
worshiped many gods,
male and female.
Women were seen
as most closely connected
to the fecundity
of the Earth itself.
You're with the... the
feminine principle
of the, sort of, Mother Earth,
who gives birth to everything.
This is a very
erotic experience.
Because what this,
what this represents
with these deeply
polished grooves
all coming in on a V here,
is probably a vulva.
The vulva, the birth canal
became very symbolic,
as the portal to that,
of that... that spiritual quest.
Nearly 85% of human figures
represented in prehistoric
cave art are female.
The richness of... of art
in this area
is sort of kept
beneath the radar.
You can imagine why.
Caves and cavities
were like a belly,
the womb that gave birth,
the womb
that you had to get into,
and you also had to
come back out of it.
It's obvious from the
architecture of the cave,
and the... the art within it
that we're within
the Earth Goddess herself.
The vulva here represents
the means of passage
between our world
and the inner world
of the spirits.
The rock is sort of the membrane
between the here and the beyond.
And the horse is
the animal of passage
that accompanies the shaman
on that transcendental journey
deep into the beyond
and then safely back.
The reverence of our ancestors
for the miracle of birth
inspired the first expressions
of spirituality.
This is probably the best
evidence that I know of
of a Sacred Feminine principle
through prehistory.
I mean, this is it.
This proves the case.
The Sacred Feminine.
The Earth Mother.
The pagan goddess.
At the core of all religion,
procreation.
The Glastonbury Tor is
a ancient, pagan sacred site
which many people come to as a
center for the Divine Feminine.
And the hill itself
has the appearance,
if you look at it from a
distance, of perhaps a breast,
or almost as if
the Earth is pregnant.
And with the tower on the top, it's
the breast idea is accentuated
because it's like a nipple.
One of the creation myths was that
creation was God masturbating.
As the... As the great creation
of the universe,
sex was very much at the center
of ancient spirituality,
as you would expect it to be,
because through sex comes life.
I mean, how incredible is that?
Every single mystical
tradition uses as a metaphor
for the union between
the human being and God,
every one uses sex as
the human metaphor for that.
If you want to understand
what the longing for union is,
think about the longing
in a sexual relationship.
You don't even need mystical traditions
and heavy analysis to understand this.
Just think about
when you're making love.
How many people say,
"Oh, God, oh, God."
Now, you don't say,
"Oh, toaster."
And you don't say, "Oh..."
You know, you say "Oh, God."
Why? Because that word
is a code word
for, kind of, the deepest, deepest
connection, communion, union, intimacy.
Where do we come from?
Where do we go after we die?
These are the mysteries,
the questions that have
fueled our search for meaning
from the beginning of time.
One of the most important tenets
about what the Christians believe
is that death is a transition from
this life to an eternal life.
As a matter of fact, the term "cemetery"
actually means sleeping place.
Slave, baby, woman,
wealthy person,
buried next to popes,
noblemen...
The catacombs offer a
representation of the universality
of the early Christian Church.
It was an absolute innovation
in the Roman world.
There were many religions,
promising all kinds of things,
but each one of these religions
had only a select elite few
who could join the religion.
Christianity offered a God
who loved everybody equally.
He didn't look at your color, he
didn't look at your bank statement,
he didn't look at your gender.
This God loved everyone.
To leave your body behind
for a short while,
waiting to be rejoined
with the body
the day of the last judgment
in the afterlife.
This God wanted
to save everyone.
Which is why the primary images of the
catacombs are always those of salvation.
This position of the raised
hands is called the orant,
and it means
"the figure in prayer".
They always look straight out
at the viewers,
one of the very few images
in catacomb paintings,
which have a very direct
relationship towards the viewer.
"Look, I am saved. I am saved through
prayer, you can do it, too."
In the years
following the death of Christ,
there were many religions
along the Mediterranean basin,
each with its own traditions
and mysteries,
all under the thumb
of the Roman empire.
Then, in 306, a general ascended to
power, and according to Dan Brown,
co-opted the message of Christ,
while diminishing
the role of Mary Magdalene.
Well, Constantine,
he was declared Emperor
by the troops
in Northern England.
He was up there at York and...
But he had a holy mother,
who we remember
as Saint Helena.
His mom was... was
a Catholic Christian,
so she was there.
And he was also
aware of the fact
there were millions of
Christians in his empire,
and, uh, he wanted some religious
glue, and he found it there.
Constantine had a dream
or a vision that in this sign,
the sign of the cross,
"You will conquer."
So he got his soldiers
to put that on their shields,
and Constantine took over.
Changing gods takes time.
But it goes faster when the new
story resembles earlier ones.
December 25th, the birthday
of the Persian god, Mithras,
becomes Christmas.
Isis nursing her baby Horus,
becomes the Virgin Mary
and the infant Jesus.
Poseidon's trident changes
into the devil's pitchfork,
and the pentacle, the symbol
of the Sacred Feminine
becomes associated with evil,
with witchcraft,
with serial killers.
This is an ancient sacred site,
which was adopted
by the early Christians.
The whole place is steeped
with mythology
and with ambience of... of ancient
spirituality, going right back,
pre-Christian to pagan days.
The name "pagan" was used by the
Roman Church, by Christians,
to put down the old religion,
and... and it kind of means country
dweller or country bumpkin.
The truth, of course, is that
the old religion,
the old paganism,
in its wider sense,
was immensely sophisticated.
This is the philosophy
of ancient civilization.
The civilization which gave us
the pyramids, the Parthenon,
mathematics, science...
It's actually... Ironically, it's
after Christianity took over...
That... And all of that
was destroyed,
that we went back to this
idea that the Earth was flat
and that you could be killed
for saying that...
Denying that the Earth
goes round the sun,
and we had, well,
the Dark Ages.
Religion, it's been about a big
man in the sky with a beard,
whose message is
"Do what I tell you."
And to women, the message
has been basically,
"Shh. Don't say anything."
You know, "Don't do anything.
"You're not really
involved in this."
In fact, there was a whole
debate in the Middle Ages,
you know, whether they
even had, women had souls.
And now we've all inherited that
and think it's Christianity.
That's not what it was about.
And we've lost
half of the equation.
We've lost the inner mysteries.
We've lost the mysteries
of the Feminine.
After the crucifixion,
various Christian sects arose,
each telling the story of Jesus
from a different point of view.
To create a uniform religion,
the first Church fathers
chose four gospels,
Matthew, Mark, Luke and John,
which later became the first
four books of the New Testament.
Dozens of other gospels
were declared heretical
and were hidden,
lost to history
until discovered in the
Egyptian desert in 1945.
The discovery of the Gnostic
Gospels was really a surprise.
It was discovered by some villagers
from a small town in Upper Egypt.
And much later, we learned that these
had contained an ancient library.
It's really a treasury
of early Christian writings,
including the Gospel of
Thomas, the Gospel of Philip,
the Letter of Peter to Paul,
the Secret Book of James,
the Secret Book of John.
Over 50 writings attributed
to Jesus and his disciples.
You know, we thought we knew something
about the early Christian movement.
Now we find out
that what we knew
is really a small slice
of a much wider range.
So instead of four gospels, as
we have in the New Testament,
you find dozens of others.
Now, we always knew
there were dozens of others,
because the fathers
of the Church had said this.
They said heretics had written
terrible other secret gospels.
And we never
knew what they were.
We just knew
that they were awful.
And now for the first time, these ancient
Christians can speak for themselves
and we can find out what the people
called heretics actually said.
While the traditional Church
sought to oversee
a person's relationship
with God,
the Gnostics believed
that spiritual revelation
could only come from within.
No intercession was required
by priests or rabbis.
If you wake up to what you really
are and discover the Christ within,
and recognize as that everything
is one, that's gnosis,
and you come into love with
everything, that's heaven.
So the original message was by
understanding this powerful myth,
you can wake up
to what you really are,
and discover that we are all
parts of one body, as Paul says.
We're all parts of the Christ,
we're all one.
Back in the second century, Saint Iraneus,
he's definitely supporting four gospels,
four gospels, no more, no less.
He knows these Gnostic gospels.
He says they're garbage. I mean, they're
just invented, they're not the real thing,
but Matthew, Mark, Luke and John,
these are the four gospels.
People have to fudge the dates
of these Gnostic Gospels
to use them for their own
purposes claiming they were there
in the middle
of the first century.
Well, that's a maverick claim
that the overwhelming majority
of scholars just don't accept.
One only needs to read the Gnostic
Gospels from beginning to end
to realize, well, thank God
this never made the list.
It used to be easy, you'd say,
"Well, which ones are true?"
Well, the Church says, "These.
They're in the New Testament.
"After all, those are the real ones.
These are the fake ones."
It's a lot harder now. If you look at
all of this range of text and say,
"What can you believe?"
There are not just the four
gospels in the New Testament,
there were hundreds, probably, of Gnostic
Gospels, many of which we now found.
And they're very mythological.
You can see that
there's a natural continuum
of a synthesis of pagan
and Jewish tradition,
and Jesus is a kind of
ancient superhero.
He's like Batman
meets Superman.
He combines the Messiah
with the pagan God-Man,
and has the attributes of both.
The most important myth
in the ancient world
is the story of a dying
and resurrecting God-Man.
He changes water into wine
at a wedding,
performs these miracles, bringing
back people from the dead,
all of the things
we associate with Jesus,
right up to the really
crucial things, of course,
which is dying at Easter,
sometimes through crucifixion.
He then resurrects
and to share in eternal life,
you take bread and wine
to commune with God.
Now that's Christianity,
and this existed
before anyone had the idea
of there being Jesus.
The Jesus story, if you stand back
from it, it looks like a myth,
it's the story of someone who's born
of a virgin, for goodness' sake,
and comes back from the dead, I've never
met anyone who was born of a virgin
or came back from the dead.
It looks like a myth
because it is a myth.
The gospels you find in the New
Testament like Matthew, Mark,
tell you what Jesus preached out on
the hills to thousands of people.
But Mark says that Jesus taught his
disciples privately, secretly,
secret things. And he doesn't
tell you what they said.
Now these other gospels often claim to be
secret teachings and they were probably meant
to be just for the few who were
going on to a deeper level.
Now what's happened is that
myth has been literalized.
It's become about a literal man
who you literally believe
came and literally died
for your sins,
as an historical event.
And what that's done is it's
cut us off from that power,
the power to actually transform
us and help us experience gnosis.
The Gnostics were mystics.
Instead of worshiping Christ
as a literal figure,
a man of flesh and blood,
they considered his life
and teachings as allegories,
stories that helped guide
their journey toward truth.
So instead of speaking of Jesus
as an utterly unique being
on whom you must believe,
they picture Jesus as someone who
manifests what anyone could become.
And that is a very different
kind of message.
The Gospel of Mary says the Son of
Man is within you, follow after him.
You don't have to find
Jesus of Nazareth,
but you have to find
what's within you.
Throughout
the Gnostic scriptures,
there is a little
bone of contention
between the fact that the
disciples have been with Christ,
but Mary has been with him
slightly longer.
She's... She's been
with him more.
She knows more of his
secrets than... than they do.
She almost acts as someone
of, not co-wisdom with him,
but as someone
whose questions of him
show an intelligence
and an understanding
that the questions from the other
of the disciples just do not show.
And so that closeness,
um, has been seen,
by many people who've read
the Gnostic scriptures,
as evidence of a personal and
literal sexual relationship.
Certainly Dan Brown
who wrote  The Da Vinci Code
took off from a few lines
that were found
in some of these secret texts
because they are very provocative.
The ones with which he started are
from the Gospel of Philip which says,
"Jesus loved Mary more than all the disciples
and he kissed her often on her..."
And then the text breaks,
and you don't know.
What actually happens in these texts
is something rather different.
There, she is described as the companion
of Jesus, and the language is erotic.
But it's the language
of a mystical writer
who talks about Mary as the
manifestation of the Holy Spirit.
If you look
at the mystical traditions
of Judaism, of Islam
and of Christianity,
you find the Divine is often
spoken of as the Father.
But there is also
a mother or a daughter,
someone who sits alongside
and helps the Divine.
And in the Jewish tradition, um,
that figure is the Shekinah,
who is the presence of God.
She's seen as female.
In the Islamic tradition, um,
she's called the Sakina
and she behaves
in a very similar way.
She is accompanying
the soul through life.
In Gnosticism,
she lives an ordinary life,
and suffers and shares what we would
understand as the human condition.
She makes mighty things to come about.
She is a very powerful lady indeed.
Dan Brown has given us
the impression
that Mary Magdalene gets this exalted
point of being, the... the equal of Jesus.
The problem is
that this cannot be.
Because Jesus is God.
So what is she, God?
In which case, we don't have the same,
we're not talking about the same religion.
I mean, you can't say this is
something that the Catholic
Church is hiding from you,
because this is clearly not the
same religion we're talking about.
There is one God,
and there are no other gods.
I mean, I was under the impression
this was kind of laid out
in the Ten Commandments
a while ago.
A lot of people today have
been concerned with issues,
both about women
and feminine language.
But many people think
it's a very new issue.
What's interesting
is that it appeared
at the very beginning
of the Christian movement.
Sometimes people say to me, "Well, you
know, that all sounds very new age."
And I think, well, you know,
2,000 years is not so new.
It is here at Chateau Villette
that Sophie Neveu is told of
the church's role in denying
the importance of the Sacred
Feminine and of Mary Magdalene.
The center story about
The Da Vinci Code,
it's all experienced right
here, at the Chateau.
The bulk of the story in history, actually,
was told right here, in this room,
and right on this sofa,
actually.
And in fact, right in this sofa
is where they hide the keystone,
underneath this sofa.
The keystone
in The Da Vinci Code
is the relationship between Mary
Magdalene and Jesus Christ.
Their story resonates
with many people,
but for some, the message
does not go far enough.
Of all the things
in  The Da Vinci Code
that makes me the angriest,
is that a man who is writing a book that's
supposed to be about the Divine Feminine
denigrates Mary Magdalene
and says she is nothing more than
the perpetrator of a bloodline,
instead of talking about her
as a passionate preacher,
as an independent woman
in her own right.
If anything,  The Da Vinci Code
suddenly raises all these questions
that, you know, that have
never been discussed publicly.
No. It is absolutely clear.
The bad guys are the Catholic
Church and Opus Dei.
The good guys are
the Priory of Sion.
It is Indiana Jones
all the way.
But it's against what we've
been brought up to believe.
Yeah. I... I... See, I,
again, I think that
when the book says this is what
you were taught to believe,
you don't remember, really, what
but when they tell you that, you
say, "Oh, yeah, that's right.
"Yeah, I was taught to believe that.
Because, hey, I slept through my classes."
But he has a talent. He made it a suspense.
It's a  polar.
It's the first book you read
in two nights.
...because I read all these other books,
and Dan Brown made a novel out of it,
and much easier to read,
and more interesting to read.
And I kept falling to sleep when I
read  The Holy Grail, Holy Blood.
It was very difficult to read.
- What do you think about...
- To use the name of Da Vinci?
Da Vinci was one weird guy.
And I'm sure he put codes
and things in there.
I just don't think they had
anything to do with what.
The Holy Blood, Holy Grail
or  The Da Vinci Code said.
Leonardo was
an interesting person,
and I don't think
anybody understands him.
Maybe his mother.
Architect, engineer, inventor.
Leonardo was so complex,
he was almost impossible
to comprehend.
Which is why we have
never stopped trying.
The  Last Supper is obviously one of the
most famous paintings in the world.
In fact, it's probably
one of two famous paintings,
the other being the  Mona Lisa,
both by Leonardo Da Vinci,
um, and they're both
very weird.
The core of The Da Vinci
Code  is the symbolism
in Leonardo Da Vinci's
Last Supper.
We were the first people to
notice what everybody now knows.
Um, and they say,
"Thanks to Dan Brown."
It's not "Thanks to Dan
Brown," it's thanks to us.
Um, that's in fact the world knows
that, or at least suspects, that, uh,
the person sitting
on Jesus' right hand
in the  Last Supper is not
the young St. John at all.
And you looked at it, and you think,
"Wait a minute, that's a woman."
Basically all you have to do
is look at it with new eyes.
Well, Jesus is sitting there, sort
of, going like this, isn't He?
And she, it was,
what, because it isn't...
Oh, hang on.
I have to be Jesus.
Yes, that's what I'm saying,
you're Jesus,
but I was just doing...
Yes, you're doing that.
And... And he or she is, you know,
is sort of leaning away like this
but almost as if joined,
still joined at the hip.
Together they make a giant,
spread-eagled M shape.
Uh, well, the M
gives you a clue.
It's some, someone
whose name begins with M.
Not the Virgin Mary.
It must be Mary Magdalene.
Oh, I see 12 male apostles.
I mean, if that figure is Mary
Magdalene next to Jesus, where's John?
Assuming that that figure
is Mary Magdalene,
a hand cuts across
her neck visually.
Um, it looks like a disciple
is leaning on her shoulder,
like this, leaning forward, but in fact,
visually the hand is threatening,
um, and that disciple is, who's
doing that, is Saint Peter.
The other interesting thing
in that painting
is that Peter is portrayed with
his hand across Mary's throat,
and with a knife.
Now what's that?
Peter, Judas and, uh, Saint
John in one group together.
Peter is so angry at this news
that Jesus will be betrayed,
and he's... and he's
right next to the traitor,
whereas John is much more
contemplative and tranquil.
And that's the normal way
it's being understood.
Once you see that Peter in Gnostic
mythology also represents ignorance,
he is the, he represents each
one of us at our most lost,
and he is shown
in Gnostic gospels
as antagonistic to Mary,
he's jealous of Mary.
Saint Peter was hugely jealous
of her and kept going to Jesus
and saying, "Lord, let Mary leave us
'cause women are not worthy of life."
He doesn't like the fact that
Mary has the ear of Jesus,
all of this,
allegorical of course.
Then you understand why
Peter is there with a knife,
and trying to silence Mary.
You know, Saint Peter founded
the Catholic Church
on the authority
given him by Jesus.
Supposing he never got it.
Supposing the authority
was given to a woman.
Mary Magdalene is not present
in Leonardo's  Last Supper.
It is a painting that has been
sitting on a wall for 500 years.
It's been looked at by some of
the greatest art historians,
some of the most
keen observers,
it has never been forwarded
that the figure is Mary Magdalene.
It is not.
Sometimes
the stories our ancestors told
are forgotten or suppressed,
but they remain
in our collective unconscious
waiting to emerge.
And like Robert Langdon
and Sophie Neveu,
we pick up the threads
of these stories,
hoping to find where they lead.
Mary Magdalene is a signpost.
She's not the destination.
She is a messenger,
and in that case,
she is a model to us all,
because she, she keeps on,
um, being a disciple.
She keeps on being faithful, even when people
shout at her, and say, "No, you're wrong.
"We're... We know better."
She is faithful and I think that's a
faith that we could all learn from.
These are what I call 'Magdalene
pilgrims' and they come here to Vezelay
looking for Mary Magdalene, for what
they call the true Mary Magdalene.
They define themselves
as pilgrims and so they
are also following in the
footsteps of medieval pilgrims
who were coming to Vezelay to venerate
the relics of Mary Magdalene.
These Magdalene pilgrims want to contact
in some way with her and with her energy
because they think most of all
that she is relevant for women.
They believe that Mary Magdalene was
not only a simple disciple of Jesus
but she actually
was his teacher.
According to these pilgrims, it is partly
thanks to Mary Magdalene's teachings
that Jesus could do
what he did.
Well, the Catholic Church treated Mary
Magdalene in a quite ambiguous way
because in the four gospels they do not
say that Mary Magdalene is a prostitute.
This came out only later,
in the sixth century
because a Pope declared that,
according to his point of view.
Mary Magdalene and two other
female figures in the gospels
were the same woman.
So, until 1969,
the Catholic Church
considered Magdalene
as a prostitute
and as a repentant sinner
who converts
at the moment she meets Jesus
and at the moment Jesus
heals her from seven demons.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women and blessed
is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
Saint Mary Magdalene,
Saint Joseph,
all you saints of God,
pray for us, sinners, now and
at the hour of our death. Amen.
Mind your head.
Relics said to be
those of Saint Mary Magdalene
were acquired
in the 11th century,
and they were,
in fact, ratified
officially by the pope of the
day, about the year 1050.
It meant that
when the pilgrims came,
they brought money for
the building of the church,
and this whole basilica was
built with pilgrim offerings.
The kingdom of God is close.
And the evidence that his message
is true is the resurrection.
And that's why Saint Mary
Magdalene is so important.
She's the first person
to hear, touch, see,
smell our Lord risen.
He says to her,
"Don't touch me."
Meaning, "Don't cling to me, don't
try and hold me in this world,
"I am ascending to the Father. I've come, in
other words, to take everything into heaven."
She's the first person to communicate
this knowledge to the world.
She goes to the apostles that first resurrection
morning and they don't believe her.
"She's a woman, you know."
"Silly woman."
Why did he choose
Mary Magdalene?
I think for the real answer to
that, you'd need to ask our Lord.
It's just part of
God's humility.
The only way God can express it
is by choosing a broken woman
like Saint Mary Magdalene
to be the first
to announce the resurrection.
And the living experience
that Christians have
in their relationship with Saint Mary Magdalene.
She's alive, not dead.
She's died, sure, in terms of
this life and this world,
but in Christian terms,
she's alive.
Spiritually, she's here
and she's at work.
She's at work wherever
the Holy Spirit's at work.
That doesn't mean to say she's some
kind of goddess. She isn't at all.
She's just a Christian saint,
but a very important one.
There is no history whatsoever
that she was married,
and there's no history
that she ever had children.
And she certainly didn't have any kind of
relationship of that kind with our Lord.
That, that's sheer
20th century fantasy.
Not because the Church, as an institution,
suppressed it, it just isn't there.
It's just not consonant with our
Lord's life, nor with hers.
It has been said that Jesus, being
a rabbi, would have been married.
But what if Jesus had lived among the
Essenes, a community of celibate Jews
along the western shore
of the Dead Sea?
One of the things
we know about the Essenes,
these people were so crazy
about ritual purity.
For example, not only did you
have to take a bath
after you came back
from going to the bathroom,
but you had to go into the  mikvah which
is a spiritual bath, twice a day.
These were a group of celibate
men who were living out here
according to
the ancient writers.
These people were fanatical
about ritual purity.
Who did Jesus hang out with? He
hung out with the prostitutes,
with the blind,
the lame, the halt.
These are the type of people,
from a Jewish point of view,
you do not want to have anything
to do with if you're an Essene.
And since Jesus hung out
with these people,
Jesus would not even have
been allowed near this place.
Well, it's clear that the Christians
were influenced by these people,
but was Jesus here? No way.
Not far from
the sea of Galilee,
where Jesus revealed
his miracles,
is the town of Migdal, said to be
the birthplace of Mary Magdalene.
The Kabbala doesn't see as a
forbidden subject that a woman
would sit and learn with men.
Jesus was a Tanach.
Tanach means a...
in order to be a Tanach, you
have to work really hard at your
inner cleanness.
You have to be
a really purified person.
Jesus was... one of them.
And he learned not only the revealed
part of the Judaism, of the Torah...
but the inner part. The
secret part of the Judaism
which is the Kabbala.
I don't think Jesus could have reached
this high level without a wife.
He had to have a wife.
The Torah says that
if you are not married
you can't go into the Torah.
The role of the man
is to bring the light.
The role of the wife
is to reveal the light
in the physical world.
If you tried to look at it
through Kabbala eyes...
...he should have had a wife
and I think he had a wife.
There is a legend
that tells of Mary Magdalene
fleeing persecution
in Palestine
and arriving
at the south of France
in a boat without oars or sail.
This beautiful door represents the two
Saint Marys with their servant, Sarah.
It is said here that on a boat,
when the two Marys arrived...
...there was also a girl,
who was from Egypt.
The story is that Mary Magdalene
had a child with Jesus Christ.
That would be Sarah.
I don't believe it at all.
I believe Jesus was
totally dedicated to God.
I can't imagine that he would
take the time to have human love.
It would be a contradiction
with His mission.
Celibacy of the priesthood, that
mirrors the celibacy of Christ.
It's only a question of time...
...the time it takes to dedicate
yourself to God and to others.
If you're married, you must spend a lot
of time with your wife and children.
With or without child,
the story of Mary was told throughout
this region, and people listened.
The fact is, the first Christians
arrived and brought the faith.
I believe in the beginning
there was a rapid conversion.
The poor class were the first to be
touched by the message of the Christians.
Jesus was a message
of liberation and love.
And the disenfranchised
were moved.
After Mary Magdalene arrived here
with the other Saint Marys...
...she just continued
on her way.
Her story picks up again
in Sainte Baume.
It's not too far from here,
up in the mountains.
In the Middle Ages, Christians
were told and believed
that Mary Magdalene
had ended her days in Provence
at the top of this mountain called La
Sainte Baume, which means 'the grotto'.
And she contemplated
and repented for her sins.
In order to do so, she divested
herself of her clothes,
because this meant that she
was close to God in holiness.
She wasn't concerned with her
worldly goods and her worldly life.
She didn't eat,
she fasted, she wept.
And in order to keep her covered,
in order to make her decent,
her hair grew down,
around her body.
Everyday she was taken up to heaven by
angels who gave her heavenly sustenance,
spiritual sustenance.
She had no need of human food.
But this is where she came,
and this is where pilgrims from the
middle of the 13th century came
to pray and to think about her.
Sweet Lover of God.
I mean, that exemplifies the whole
medieval concept of Mary Magdalene,
that she was the sweet
friend or lover of God.
They've been coming here
since 1250,
and are still coming
on their pilgrimage
to see where Mary Magdalene
spent her last days.
This is the final end of the
pilgrimage to the grotto
where Mary Magdalene spent
the last 30 years of her life.
We're entering
in this huge cavern,
which amazed believers,
pilgrims.
And they wrote back,
wrote memoirs
on how miraculous it was.
They would come here,
pray and think about
Mary Magdalene, the apostle,
and the person who converted
France to Christianity.
This is the crypt
where Mary Magdalene's bones were
believed, in the Middle Ages, to lie.
When the monks claimed to have
her relics, or her bones here,
they said they had her entire
body minus an arm.
The skull, you can see, is of
a woman around the age of 50.
Claiming to having her relics,
would bring the Church money from the...
the pilgrims that came in their thousands.
The more powerful the saint, the
more money you would have coming in.
With a powerful and popular
saint like Mary Magdalene,
the economic ramifications
were enormous.
When I was writing my book,
people said to me
why did I want to bother to write
a book about a prostitute,
or a repentant prostitute
and I said I wasn't,
and they said, "Well, what
are you writing about?"
And I said, "Well, a woman in her own
right." Which is what I felt she was.
Um...
And when I finished my book, I was
so angry at what the Church had done
to women
in the name of Christianity,
I didn't want to
think about it any longer.
I was stone-cold angry
about what had happened to us.
And having done Mary Magdalene,
it showed what women could have
been in the last 2,000 years
and what women can do now,
and what men can understand
women to be able to do now.
The guilt of, uh, sexuality, and procreation
goes back to the Garden of Eden,
because Eve has eaten
of the apple,
and Adam has eaten
of the apple, too,
they're expelled
from the garden.
The blame of the guilt is heaped
solely and squarely upon woman,
upon Eve, rather than upon
just Adam and Eve.
And we are living
with the consequences of that,
and it's... it's
a very powerful story
that affects so much
of the modern world.
More than 5,000 years ago,
we began to rewrite
the ancient stories.
In time, one God replaced many,
and the Sacred Feminine
was changed into a temptress
who brought sin into the world.
We've been taught a very, very
different form of Christianity,
which was to do with blind belief
that somebody else had died
for us because
we had original sin,
and that if we just
believed that,
then we'd go to heaven
when we died.
And if we didn't,
we'd go to hell,
and be tortured forever,
by a God of love.
It's the last of
the acceptable prejudices,
putting the boot
into the Catholic Church.
And, I mean we have, there's
a big shadow side there,
but, I mean, if it's as bad as
that, why is it still there?
People have
three hungers, really.
People want to live.
They want to find meaning,
and want to love and be loved.
I think the three basic human hungers
are for life, meaning and love.
And I think faith, real faith,
answers those hungers.
But as a Catholic Christian, I find
life and meaning and love in Jesus.
I mean, He satisfies
my hungry heart.
The men of the formative
church were so terrified
that Mary Magdalene's legacy would
come down through the centuries.
They said, "We're not having
any more...
"Any... Any likelihood
of another Mary Magdalene
"coming out of,
you know, the flock,
"so we are going to suppress all women.
We're going to lie about it.
"We're going to lie
about what Jesus said."
And the whole
of the last 2,000 years
has been a result of
t-the men of the Vatican,
the very, very early
Church fathers essentially,
about them reacting against
Mary Magdalene and her image.
Well I... I love Mary Magdalene. I'm
a priest because of her really.
My mother,
before she got married,
went to the Church of Saint
Mary Magdalene in, uh, Paris,
and prayed that if she had
a son he'd be a priest.
And I'm the result,
so I'm happy being a priest.
I'm grateful to Mary Magdalene.
The idea that she was vilified by the
official Church is just nonsense.
I mean, here in Rome
we have a lovely church
with Mary Magdalene very
prominent there on the facade.
So, she's a very notable
figure in early Christianity
and uh, remembered as such
with... with affection and gratitude.
In many ways, what books
like The Da Vinci Code  do,
is it puts in, beginning, beginning,
beginning new storylines.
Here's a new storyline.
"Oh, Jesus was really married
and had a child."
Now, right now,
that is as fanciful
as any religious story one could
ever imagine when it was first told.
The interesting thing is, 500 years
from now, 1000 years from now,
when millions of people
have heard that story,
when in generations,
it becomes a part of the expansive
nature of the earliest stories,
it just gets grafted on,
and then we see how it
begins to affect society.
I think  The Da Vinci Code has done a great
job, uh, because it stirred things up.
I think it's a great sign that people are no
longer happy with the traditional history
and meaning of Christianity.
And it's pointed quite rightly to the
fact that that traditional history
just does not stand up
to scrutiny.
But it's, uh, it... it in
itself, is very superficial.
It itself created... Creates a whole new
mythology, which it then literalizes
which is this... this idea,
that Mary comes to France
and... and there's a bloodline
and all this.
There's no evidence for that.
How depressing would that be,
if all of these people throughout
history had risked their lives
to keep
this precious secret alive.
And it was
an aristocratic bloodline,
just at the point where we're going,
"We don't need that anymore."
In fact, the real Da Vinci Code
is much more shocking than that
because, um, you know, basically
Leonardo was saying, um,
Jesus was a fake messiah.
Leonardo da Vinci
was in fact a Johannite.
He believed that John the
Baptist was the true Messiah,
not Jesus.
One of the most Johannite, uh,
works of Leonardo da Vinci,
is  The Adoration of the Magi.
So in... in the foreground
you have the wise men
and they're presenting
frankincense and myrrh
and you think, "Wait a minute,
where's the gold?"
In Leonardo's time, gold represented
perfection and kingship
so that's being withheld
from the baby Jesus.
Look above the Virgin Mary
to, behind her, essentially,
and there's
the roots of a tree.
There's a tree. Um, a carob tree
represents John the Baptist
and there's a group of young
people standing around this tree,
worshiping, or apparently
worshiping this tree.
And these young people are,
uh, well, obviously young,
and they're vibrant
and healthy and glowing
and they're the John the
Baptist's worshipers,
but the Jesus worshipers in the
foreground are horrible, old things.
To be fascinated
with a Christian saint
is not heresy in itself,
of course.
But to be fascinated
and obsessed to the point
where you believe that that
saint is superior to Jesus,
that's heresy.
Heresy means choice in Greek
but for the church,
it came to mean the enemy.
Philosophers
with unorthodox views,
noblemen who disobeyed
papal edicts
people accused
of being witches.
Dan Brown tells us
that the Catholic Church
burned five million witches
at the stake.
That would have depopulated Europe.
I mean, it's absurd.
In fact, about 50,000
women and men
died over all the centuries in...
At Salem and a-also in Europe.
And that was evil and wicked,
but five million,
I mean, he... he multiplies the real number
by a hundred, because it sounds much better.
I mean, there were things about the
Spanish Inquisition which are not good,
but there were things...
At that time many people preferred
to have their case heard by them,
because they thought
they'd get justice.
And the number of people executed
by the Inquisition was minuscule.
I mean, it's, uh... Somehow
it got a very bad name.
No one was safe from the church's
pursuit of spiritual purity.
Not even an order of knights
that had been formed to protect
pilgrims traveling to the Holy Land.
The Knights Templar
are traditionally said to have
been a group of nine knights
who were formed in the Holy Land
around the year 1118 or 1119.
The non-orthodox, or the speculative
version of the Templar story
holds that the Templars requested to
be based on the... the Temple platform
so that they could actually
carry out excavations
underneath what they believed
was the Temple of Solomon.
Well, those writers
would suggest
that the Templars
did find some documents
that proved something about
the origins of Christianity
which they then used as a
bargaining tool back in Europe.
They initially had no money,
they were basically very
impoverished to start with
and then they became
very successful.
Within about 10 or 15 years,
the Templars were,
by modern day equivalence,
um, sort of multi-millionaires.
In some stories,
the Templars were said to be the
guardians of the Holy Grail.
But it was tales of secret
rites and heretical beliefs,
that, in time,
led to their destruction.
Well, on Friday,
the 13th of October, 1307,
all of the Templars in France
were arrested on the orders of the
French king, Philip the Fair,
on the grounds of
heresy basically.
Uh, denying Christ,
spitting on the cross,
institutional sodomy,
worshiping a devil...
A group of charges
that was pretty severe.
Within a few years,
the Templars were gone.
Either killed or in exile.
Today all that remains,
are their ties to the Grail
and the places they built.
Following a false clue,
Robert Langdon and Sophie
Neveu come to Temple Church
where they encounter
a murderous albino monk
who belongs to Opus Dei,
another secret organization that
has been viewed with suspicion.
I mean, there have been conspiracy
theories about Opus Dei
since the late 1920s.
But what Dan Brown did, is,
he took those conspiracy
theories to the mass market.
And then they've got to
ask themselves the question,
"Why are so many people
willing to believe
"that they are this kind of
Darth Vader-esque,
"you know, boogie-man who
is hiding under the bed
"of every nefarious thing that
happens in the Catholic Church?"
Well, Opus Dei is portrayed,
uh, completely distorted
and there's no reality at all based on what
he's written and the reality of Opus Dei.
Uh, first of all, there
are no monks in Opus Dei,
albino or otherwise.
I got hooked
on the book myself.
I... I... I wondered who on
earth is the evil teacher.
I didn't like the fact
that the killer was an albino.
That's... That's not very nice.
I mean, there are
albinos in our world.
One of my colleagues
is an albino.
It's a group of lay people
and, uh, it has nothing to do with
people running around in religious garb
or being cloistered
in convents or monasteries.
Opus Dei is all about
a way of finding God
in work
and in your ordinary life.
That's its essence.
One of the problems
of Opus Dei is,
it's not so much they're
secretive, they're just unique.
They do things in a way
that is very different
than how most secular
organizations do business.
And it's hard for people on
the outside to understand.
Uh, but, on the other hand,
it is also historically true
that they had been
very leery about outsiders
and leery about curiosity
and so forth.
Not that intrigue
and conspiracy theories
haven't been around
for a long, long time,
but, look around,
everything you see.
Do I know the truth?
Do I know the story?
Uh, what if I believe this,
am I a dupe?
You think that you've got
some discernment,
some intelligence about you if you
can question everything you see.
You have a... An enormous range of
people out there in the secular world
who are hostile to,
skeptical of,
uh, institutional Christianity
in such a profound way
that they are willing in some ways,
to swallow a... a version of events
that is
just demonstrably false,
but nevertheless, they find that more
appealing and in some ways more credible
than the story that is being
peddled by officialdom.
Uh, and therefore I think, the
kind of examination of conscience
that has to go on within
institutional Christian churches is,
"Why is that?"
From what we know
of the human condition
and human experience,
it is more plausible that a man
should lay claim to a throne,
be married and have children,
than that he should be
born of a virgin,
walk on water
and rise from the dead.
25 years ago, Richard Leigh,
Michael Baigent and Henry Lincoln
wrote a book that includes much
of the intellectual architecture
underlying The Da Vinci Code.
The chief components
of our hypothesis were,
one, that Jesus
had a rightful claim
to the throne of Palestine
at the time.
Secondly, that like any Jew of his
time, like any man of his time,
in that context,
he would have been married.
Thirdly, if he was married,
there would have been children.
Fourthly, the Magdalene
escaped Palestine
and landed
in the south of France.
If she had a child, or if she
were pregnant with a child,
yeah, uh, Jesus' bloodline
would have, uh, been transplanted
to France along with her.
That bloodline, descended
from the Magdalene and Jesus,
intermarried with
the royal line of the Franks,
from which arose
the Merovingian Dynasty.
Holy Blood, Holy Grail
was based on a set of documents
called the Secret Files,
which contained genealogies
linking Jesus and Mary
to the Merovingian Royal Family
and to the Priory of Sion,
a secret society dedicated
to protecting this bloodline.
We knew, uh,
there was a secret society,
or semi-secret society
in France.
We didn't know how powerful
they actually were.
We still don't.
We were mystified
by their agenda,
we were mystified by the fact
that here were a group
of people in France,
some of whom
were very well connected,
some of whom had access
to the corridors of power,
whose stated objective was to
restore the Merovingian bloodline.
That sounded bonkers.
Baigent, Leigh and Lincoln got talking
to a guy called Pierre Plantard,
who claimed to be the Grand
Master of the Priory of Sion.
Plantard saw himself
as the last of an illustrious
line of Grand Masters
which included Isaac Newton,
Jean Cocteau,
and of course,
Leonardo da Vinci.
Pierre Plantard,
he wanted to be king of
France or savior of France.
And after Holy Blood,
Holy Grail  came out,
uh, the stakes were raised
and, uh, he decided
he would like to also be
a descendant of
Jesus and Mary Magdalene.
Uh, I think the man died without
convincing anyone at all of his claims,
but I always thought
he was tuned into something
and that it was hidden
behind the Priory of Sion.
So everyone's kind of swung between,
you know, one end of two extremes.
It's either kind of believe everything
about the, uh, Priory of Sion
that you read
in  The Da Vinci Code,
or that it's all just
this cheap modern hoax.
Um, in fact, the research that we've
done shows it's neither of those.
There was no Priory of Sion
in Leonardo da Vinci's day.
It only...
It was only formed in 1956.
So, Leonardo died in 1519,
so there's a bit of a gap.
Um, but, um, I don't know whether
Leonardo was Grand Master of anything.
Um, but if anybody should
have been, he should.
On page one
of The Da Vinci Code,
Dan Brown asserts
the Priory is real.
Others, however, disagree.
The Church
makes a point of saying
that contrary to fancible allegations
in a recent best seller,
that the P and the S, the two
letters in the small round windows
at both ends of the transit
refer to Saint Peter
and Saint Sulpice,
patron saints of the Church
and not to what they call
an imaginary Priory of Sion.
Now, of course, the Priory
of Sion is not imaginary
but the question is, whether
it has anything whatever to do
with what we're looking
at here at the moment.
Did the Priory of Sion
really exist?
Was there a succession of Grand Masters
protecting a sacred bloodline?
Did Leonardo include a woman
in  The Last Supper?
For that matter,
did Moses part the waters?
Did Jesus rise from the dead?
When and how does a story
become sacred doctrine?
Many of the intrigues that run
through The Da Vinci Code
come together in a town
in the south of France.
We don't know
which of them are true,
but we do know they inspired
Dan Brown and Richard Leigh
and fired the imaginations
of readers around the world.
In 1890,
a backwoods yokel priest
in a backwoods village,
in the foothills
of the Pyrenees,
suddenly and mysteriously coming up
with the equivalent of 37 million.
Where did the money come from?
What did he discover?
A treasure, or a secret,
or both?
Berenger Sauniere was a young priest.
He was 33 when he was posted
to Rennes le Chateau.
After a few years his bishop
sends him to Narbonne.
And I think this is when
a deal was made
between Berenger Sauniere and those who
wanted to find something over here.
When he came back he had in
his pocket 3,000 gold francs
which had been given to him by the
niece of the Emperor of Austria.
We are talking of the most powerful
man in the world at the time
and that man is interested in
something at Rennes le Chateau
and he's willing to pay.
So they knew some documents
of the highest importance
had been left, hidden.
They needed somebody they could
trust to find them again...
and Berenger Sauniere was the
right man in the right post.
Dan Brown chose to name the
man murdered at the Louvre
after Berenger Sauniere.
Both men had access
to secret knowledge
and both
feared for their lives.
From the moment he has found
something, yes, he is immensely rich
but on the other hand,
he's frightened.
He locks himself in the house.
He spends days and days locked
in the Tour Magdala.
He doesn't meet with
the people in the village.
And he's right
to be frightened.
Did you know that two of his
closest friends were murdered?
Murdered.
Presumably for knowing about
the documents
that Sauniere
had been paid to dig up.
Legend links these documents
to the Cathars,
a sect of Christians
who flourished in the region
during the 11th
and 12th century.
The Cathars were considered
so heretical,
that they were subject to the
first crusade against Christians.
The military campaign against the
Cathars and their supporters,
effectively finished
and what actually took its
place was the Inquisition.
The Inquisition was formed
to root out heresy,
to root out Catharism,
and to instruct people
in the ways of righteousness.
Mont Segur then became the last
stronghold of the Cathars,
and there was
a long standoff in 1243,
where the French crown and the crusading
soldiers surrounded Mont Segur.
One of the interesting myths
about Mont Segur,
is that the... That the
Cathars possessed a treasure,
which some people have thought
was the Holy Grail.
So this is another link between
the Templars and the Cathars,
because the Templars were also
traditionally said to have been
the guardians
of the Holy Grail.
The end of the
Cathar movement was close.
They were surrounded by the armies of the
King of France and they had to surrender.
Four Cathars escaped
from Mont Segur at night.
They climbed down
the rocks on ropes
and took away what is alleged to
be the treasure of the Cathars.
The Cathars were known to have
smuggled something out of Mont Segur
shortly before
the citadel fell.
So, whatever it was
that the Cathars smuggled out,
was never seen again.
When you mention treasure, people think
of gold, jewels, material treasure.
The treasure was a spiritual
treasure, probably it was documents
something written
which they had kept secret
on which they based their religion
and they had to keep it safe.
They knew their end was coming
and it was more important to them to save
those documents than to save their lives.
Is it something to do
with what the Cathars knew?
With the revelation that Mary Magdalene
was not just the prostitute?
Did she play a much more important
role in the life of Christ?
Maybe Berenger Sauniere
found the proof of that.
Maybe he found documents, maybe he
found the papers which prove that.
Everything points towards
Mary Magdalene.
We don't know
what the Knights Templar found
under the ruins
of the second temple,
what the Cathars smuggled out
from Mont Segur,
or what Sauniere unearthed
at Rennes Le Chateau.
All we know
is that secrets compel people
to reveal them.
Not openly,
but in codes, ciphers,
and symbols.
He left messages and clues everywhere,
desperately trying to tell us something
or trying to tell to those who were able to
understand, those who were able to cope...
with the news, something, and
keep the secret at the same time.
Let me show you a few things. It's unusual
to be welcomed in a church by a devil
and look who's there.
You know the Cathars
said that the world
had been created not by God,
but by the devil.
This is the perfect answer to those
who say, "Well if your God is so good
why has he created such a world
where there are murders and wars
and why does mankind
behave so badly?"
Behind the altar on your left
and on your right
you have a statue of Joseph
holding baby Jesus.
Virgin Mother and she's
holding another baby Jesus.
Two baby Jesus. And that's another
thing the Cathars used to say.
They used to say that Christ had a brother.
Another clue, another sign.
The Burial of Christ.
Everything seems to be normal.
Look at the top of the picture.
Look in the sky on the left.
What do you see there? The full moon has
been added by Berenger Sauniere himself.
If there is a full moon,
it means we are at night.
The Jewish religion forbids
to bury after the sunset.
Christ dies on a Friday. On
Friday sunset, Shabbat starts.
They're not burying Christ,
they are taking him away.
If they take him away during the night,
then it means that he's maybe not dead.
He never died on the cross. And that also
is something that the Cathars said...
that Christ survived
his crucifixion.
The origins of the Cathars
remain cloaked in mystery.
But their end
was all too clear.
Surrounded by the French army,
they were given a choice.
At the very last minute they were always
offered the choice in front of the fire...
to renounce their religion
and none of them did.
They all jumped at Mont Segur,
more than 200 people
men, women, kids jumped into the
flames singing canticles and praying.
I believe that there is
a biological human urge
to understand who we are and what
we are doing on this planet.
And in some ways,
The Da Vinci Code,
the word, "code",
has something to do with the
genetic code and the DNA code
and what makes us think the things
we think and the ideas that we have.
And what happens, it may be
a flaw in our genetic code,
is that we become wedded
to certain beliefs
and certain tellings
of these stories.
People are willing to die for a
certain interpretation of the story.
And people are willing to kill for a
And at bottom,
all these stories have much
more in common with each other
because they are all
trying to explain
the special nature of life
and of the human experience.
The act of
sacrificing one's life for God
is repeated throughout history,
among all people, all nations,
all religions.
This was a symbol of resistance.
This was a place in 66 AD,
a small band of Jews came up here,
chased the Romans out of here
and then three years later, the Romans
decided to set up a siege camp here.
We can see the camps. We can
see three camps over here,
we see the siege wall
running along here.
There's perhaps
8,000 Romans down below.
There's 960 refugees up here.
They've been up here
since the year 66 AD.
And what do these people do? They
are faced with this dilemma.
Are we gonna become slaves
the rest of our lives?
Or are we gonna commit suicide
and die as free men?
In Judaism, it's forbidden
to commit suicide,
so each man took his family,
and the father
gathered all the goods.
He killed his wife.
He killed his children
and somebody then killed him.
In the beginning, this probably
was a story of heroism.
But what a lot of people
don't realize,
the people who came up here were a bunch
of political, religious fanatics.
When they weren't fighting against
the Romans, what were they doing?
They were fighting against
their fellow Jews.
Not far from here
is a place called En Gedi.
People from En Gedi wouldn't
participate in the revolt.
What did they do? They went in and
they killed 700 of their fellow Jews.
Most people don't know
that part of the story.
But if you look at the whole
thing, the whole picture,
we're looking at, I think,
religious fanaticism.
I think one could draw
a strong parallel
between what was happening 2000 years
ago and what is happening today.
No one in The Da Vinci Code
ever sets foot in Jerusalem.
But without this city,
there would be no Crusades.
No Holy Grail,
no Abraham
offering to sacrifice his son.
No Prophet Muhammad
ascending to heaven.
No place for the Messiah
to return.
What makes Jerusalem holy?
The actual temple
that was built there?
Or it was holy
before the temple
and that's why the temple
was built there.
I have prayed at
the wall hundreds of times.
And there are times
I stand at that wall
and I say, "This is just
a bunch of rocks."
And the fact is,
any wall
I can impose meaning on.
A wall is just a way of saying
that there's
a kind of stability here
where I'm gonna rest myself on,
I'm gonna lean on this wall.
But, if I use difference
to exclude other people,
if I use difference
to make myself superior,
then I've turned that wall
not into a meeting place,
but that wall
into a separation place.
No other place brings more
faiths closer together
and keeps more people
further apart.
The Temple Mount, I mean, if any...
if anywhere symbolizes for me
the madness and the sadness of literalist
religion, it's got to be there.
We have started to divide,
to spread...
...you are an American,
I'm an Israeli, you're a Jew,
he's a Christian,
he's a Muslim,
Everything is divided.
What does it matter?
Now, all the fundamentalism, all over the
world, Jews, Muslims and Christians...
...the thing that drives them
it's not love, it's hatred.
All of us yearn to be on journeys
in which we will arrive.
No one wants to be on a journey
in which they never arrive.
Apocalyptic stories
are arrival stories.
And they make sense of the destruction
and messiness in all of our journeys.
But we have to be very careful,
apocalyptic stories
can become predictive
and then, what people do is, they
build policy on creating destruction
so they can escape
the pain of this world
into some ultimate
final solution.
And me,
I'm not into final solutions.
If we carry on
taking the myths literally,
then the myths
of the... of the end of days,
Armageddon and all the stuff
you get in Revelations
is gonna turn into
a self-fulfilling prophecy.
Once you've got people
who believe
that not only is this stuff
to be taken seriously,
but it would be a good thing
if it happened,
and you've got those people with
their finger on the nuclear trigger,
which we now have,
you know, it's a real danger
that we could... we could
kind of go into some sort of
self-fulfilling prophecy.
Has the final
chapter been written?
The Da Vinci Code doesn't say.
It pursues the stories
that begin the Bible.
We are drawn
to the one that ends it.
To the Book of Revelation,
to Armageddon.
Now, can you imagine
this vastness?
Millions and millions
of soldiers in it?
Fighting, battling?
If the Bible
is the literal truth,
then this is where the countdown
to the end of time begins.
It actually talks about the blood
being slain here will be so much
that the horses... It'll be up
to the horses', uh, breast.
The Word says what we war
against is the demonic forces.
But I still can't help
but think
at some time in the future,
there will be a battle here.
I don't fear Armageddon
as far as happening,
or I don't fear of dying in it
if... if I would be here,
I fear for the very people and the
souls that are lost within it.
The joy and the happiness
that we have,
is knowing that the promises
in the Bible are true.
And that this battle
that, uh, we're talking about,
that there's only going to be
one winner out of this,
and that will be, uh,
the Lord Jesus Christ.
So I try to focus on more
of the end of it.
The glorious kingdom is coming.
"And let him who thirst come,
whoever desires,
"let him take
the water of life freely.
"For I testify to everyone who hears the
words of the prophecy of this book,
"if anyone
adds to these things,
"God will add to him the plagues
that are written in this book.
"And if anyone takes away from the
words of the book of this prophecy,
"God shall take away his part
from the book of life.
"He who testifies to these things
says, 'Surely I am coming quickly.'."
No wonder the book ends by
saying, "Come, Lord Jesus."
You know, let's get to this heavenly
matrimony as quickly as possible,
'cause there are many good
things in this world,
but it's still not
going to satisfy
the hungers of
our human heart completely.
Revelations, um, doesn't read
significantly different
from, um, testimonials
of people on acid trips
or people who drop mescaline or
psilocybin for the first time
or schizophrenics.
No wonder it's popular.
It's... It's like  Harry Potter,
or like, uh, Tolkien's
The Lord of the Rings.
People love those stories about
cosmic battles between good and evil.
And that's a cosmic battle between
good and evil. A real one.
At some time in the future
there will be a battle here.
And it will be literal.
This is not to be taken
literally.
This is spiritual allegory,
and it can unite us
instead of dividing us,
because there is no us and them.
There's just us.
There really in reality, there
is no Jews, Muslims, Christians.
There's just us.
The end of the journey
for Robert Langdon
and Sophie Neveu
is Rosslyn Chapel.
They came
looking for their Grail.
We come looking for ours.
Our congregation
here in Rosslyn,
welcomes people from Christian
faiths, other faiths
and those of no faith at all.
Rosslyn, if you break out
from Celtic into English,
it means
a place of hidden knowledge.
It's been said, that the cubes
in the chapel's ceiling,
are a code that leads
to the Holy Grail.
Well, the thing
that brought me here,
was the musical mystery
at this end of the chapel.
The reason we have
a musical connotation to it
is because
at the beginning of each arch
is an angel
playing an instrument
and there's 13 of these angels all
playing different instruments.
They are quite
distinct symbols.
We found them in... in
one science called Cymatics.
The vibrations
of a single note,
um, form a pattern into a symbol
on a sheet plate glass with sand.
There's a figure eight right
underneath the bottom cube there.
Above us, the sign of infinity.
Below, a grave in which
two souls await eternity.
This building
was inspired by a woman.
Um, William Sinclair paid
for the chapel to be built.
Elizabeth Douglas was very much
the love of William's life.
She was actually
the inspiration behind it.
And this place was her dream.
As the work
had begun on the chapel,
just as
the foundations were laid,
and the first beginnings of
the walls were taking shape,
she died.
And she was buried
down in the crypt.
And they believed
that on the Day of Judgment,
these black slabs would open and
they would be taken to paradise.
I don't think Rosslyn Chapel
would be as elaborate
and have had so much care
and love put into it
if it wasn't for the fact
that this was the place
that William was gonna spend
eternity with his wife.
Stuart Mitchell
unlocked the code,
and the building sang to him.
I can't give an answer to when
our Lord is going to return.
Um, it doesn't matter a rap,
in... in... in a sense,
because the return
has already begun and, uh...
I can't get to heaven
quick enough.
We have no way of knowing
and that is why there are so many
stories in the New Testament
in which
Jesus always reminds us
that we never know the day,
we never know the hour,
and so we must always be alert.
Love stands for eternity.
We... I don't love people to
have my heart broken at the end.
I wanna be with them
and, of course, with Jesus,
the one I try to love
as much as possible.
And that, uh, that love
says you will not die.
Love, uh, uh, love is... is
a protest of eternity,
that our love is forever.
I'll be loving you always.
The powerful part of a,
uh, apocalyptic story,
is that, it helps make sense
of what's going on
and in a sense,
it's incredibly hopeful.
It says, "Look, look, of course
we're going through destruction,
"but on the other side of the
Apocalypse is incredible renewal."
God intended us
to eat of the apple
of the knowledge
of good and evil.
The... The seed
that was in that fruit,
it was not ripe at the time
that they ate it,
but the... the seed
is ripening in us.
That we will find
the ways of knowledge.
We are the stories
our ancestors told.
And the stories we tell today
create the world
our children will inherit.
Live out one story
and create this.
Or this.
Live out another
and end up like this.
Or this.
Whichever choice we make,
we are always part of this.
Six billion people.
Six billion stories.
No single truth
large enough for everyone.
For the truth, like the
universe, is expanding.
Rose,
time of our lives no one knows
People and places we chose
For you, the stories
and times that we've told,
The truth,
that there's nothing more
The dreams, ambitions so cold
The tree of life will unfold
We feel life will lead us
So real, we wound
and gracefully heal
Love that we endlessly seal,
so soft
Our hearts we reveal
It's dream time
Time for the roses
Time for devotion
Now is the time
It's dream time
The Lord said to Moses
It's time for your people
Now is your time
For you, the stories
and times that we've told,
The truth,
that there's nothing more
The dreams, ambitions so cold
The tree of life will unfold
We feel life will lead us
So real, we wound
and gracefully heal
Love that we endlessly seal,
so soft
Our hearts we reveal
It's dream time
The Lord said to Moses
It's time for your people
Now is your time
It's dream time
Time for the roses
Time for devotion
Now is the time
It's dream time