Madam Danton, the prefect of police,
madam Danton.
You are the widow of a hero.
Your husband as a member of
the French police served secretly.
He died pursuing his secret duties.
Now he is resting secretly
for sure that he cannot hold
its parades on the boulevard.
It must parade in
the catacombs of crime.
Cricketers
Dan Tong
in the name of the Republic of France.
I decorate you with a
cross of the legion of honor.
Madam
madam Dant.
Please don't think that
my request is ill timed.
But will you allow the
surety to care for this decoration
until your husband's murder
has been avenged by the guillotine?
So
ready now Mr
San.
Thank you.
Cigarette ash is found near
the body of Brigadier Danton
Vini
test laboratory serial four A
excuse
me. Manchuria leaf high
narcotic content. Georgian paper.
Well, that seems to cover the
cigarette ass situation pretty well
sold Paris Agency cafe cosmo
also sold in Monte Carlo, Constantinople
Berlin and London under the Shave
Persia brand.
Here we are
Cave Cosmo
47 Ruda
Garon proprietors Cecil
Rhonda
Ilias, madame Laro.
Uh-huh.
See what you can get out of madame
Laro.
All right. Sir. She doesn't like
the police. Oh woman of rare judgment.
Don't do that.
You know, you love it, madam la prop.
I have an appointment with
my banker. Tell you, Jamie,
what can I do for you?
Balance cigarettes, please?
The same kind, please.
Now, uh, what do you want me to tell you,
Jamie? Tell her that I'll meet her here at 7 30.
You want to be
ashamed of yourself? Leo. Why?
E she looks tired.
She sells flowers all the
evening and you keep her out all night.
Eugenie doesn't complain.
Cigarettes. What kind? Mind your
own business? I want to shop Persia.
20 Flags, please.
The next.
Thank you.
And there must be some mistake. I
said cigarette. That is a cigarette.
Well, if that's a cigarette,
what is gunpowder doing in it?
It's my opinion that
it's some firecrackers.
Some of our highest class
customers use them boys. I wish.
Show me a high class customer.
Well,
that love
is he high enough class for
you? He just bought a box of them.
His name is bought a box
of those. He bought them for
firecrackers
and I won't pay 25
for,
I,
I want my money back.
I
set off the whole box
right in the store. They
stuck in a nuisance. I,
but this is the,
well, who is,
I'm usually not a very particular man
but 20 Franks for
firecrackers here. You like one?
Where do you see
even he doesn't like them.
And if a policeman don't like him,
they're worse than I thought I got.
Take him home. Keep a
look out for Baron long
when he shows up
in the short,
why
the flower girl will be
at cafe cosmo pool at 7 30.
Yes, I wear the
chauffeur's uniform. Very good loo.
7 30.
I want to send the cable.
His highness, Grand Duke Maxim
Hotel, Savoy London.
Please come at once.
Princess Anastasia has been found.
Sign General
Mo,
thank you.
Go after the Princess
Marron Loo.
He will drive you,
give him this.
You know what to do.
Pardon me?
I am in terrible trouble.
What?
I have a rendezvous with the
most beautiful girl in Paris.
Is this
uh
but she is very beautiful.
Wouldn't it be terrible if I were late?
Yeah,
it would.
And then again being a man of the world,
wouldn't it be more
terrible if I were ahead of time?
No, am I right?
Yeah.
And in short, could
you tell me if it is 7 30?
You see,
you got plenty time, huh?
I thank you
£1000.
Tell you, Jamie, I'm here. Lean
right now someday you'll go too far.
I promise
Cali
Lili of the valley
leader
of the valley.
Thanks. You're welcome,
Leon. Am I late to the second?
What are you doing?
Fantastic.
What is it? What have you got there?
Kind
of surprised me
here, darling. What is it?
It's lovely.
And just what I need.
Where'd you get the money
selling garages?
And how many million would you
have to sell to get a watch? Like this?
Only two little gardens?
You
there isn't some other man then
you aren't jealous.
Not at all,
darling.
Last night, a gentleman bought a
for five Franks
and a minute later he came back
and looked at me in the strangest way.
Then he dropped 100
frank note on my tray.
Eugenie. Are you trying to make me
believe a man gave you all that money for a few
Guineas?
You've been out with him?
Yeah,
you don't either.
Leah.
I
usually
eat.
Jealousy is a terrible thing.
I like you to be jealous.
I had to be ashamed of myself.
Will you forgive me? Never.
You seen it?
I
sit down old man have
a bit.
I told you to keep away
from my daughter. Please
come with me. I'll take care of her.
You've done my girl enough harm,
Eugenie.
He'll have you on the streets.
If you were a younger man, I please,
I'll
meet
you.
I'm gonna stay right here until
in front of the upper at 11,
a glass of Sharif
and then row eight
and hurry. I have to get straight.
I have no one else in the world.
I haven't seen you for days.
Come home tonight,
won't you?
I will.
I promise.
I'll see you at home
comedian.
Yes,
there she is.
No
of the
I think.
Yeah,
on the alarm, Mr
Duran,
I took the liberty of waiting for you.
Who are you?
What do you want here?
I've come here to find out about
a girl you claim is your daughter
feel
is my daughter
don't try lying to
me. I know your record.
I know your record.
Where did you find this girl?
She couldn't
even walk
when I got her.
I brought her up.
I couldn't love my
own flesh and blood more.
But what is it to you?
Who is you genie?
We see
free
a war orphan
from Moscow.
We can prove that
only my poor friend
George.
He was an officer
and put the child in my arms.
He was murdered a few
days ago. Only Downton
and yourself.
Yes.
The light hurts my eyes.
You don't mind?
Wow.
What time is Eugenie
getting? She isn't here.
She hasn't been
home at all. Not tonight.
It's funny
what
family
I regret madam Danton to have
had to trouble you at this time.
But the
identification of Doan as a friend
of your husband's was
of extreme importance.
I understand. Thank you.
Crime of passion is never a mystery.
Leon Ronald's head is practically in
the guillotine now, a natural conclusion.
But I don't agree.
Have you noticed the
overdevelopment of the left hand?
A left handed man doesn't dip his
finger in blood and right with his right hand.
Yeah.
Careful.
The windpipe is completely severed.
Death was instantaneous.
Someone wanted to kill
two birds with one stone.
Whoever murdered Anton Dove
wanted to get rid of Leon Reynold.
However, that's only a theory.
Bring Reynolds in here.
Wait a minute, a couple of cops.
What is it? What is that?
You'll find out soon enough,
Reynold.
I want to warn you that anything
you may say will be used against you.
I understand all that. But
suppose we get to the point
you're accused of the
murder of Anton Doran,
Doran.
Where's Eugenie?
Her disappearance makes it look bad
for her too. Don't be absurd. Absurd.
Why that girl wouldn't harm a fly. Why
she's a saint? A saint is a sweetheart.
I'll finish it for you. The
saint is a sweetheart of a thief
but not a murderer.
Take him to Sante Prison and hold
him until further orders. I'm not lying.
I didn't do it
just a minute.
Suppose we give you a
chance to prove your innocence
as a thief. You have access to die
is not exactly hospitable to the police.
I'm not a stupid. I know I'm merely
asking you to clear yourself if you're innocent
and also your sweetheart.
Well,
it's a pleasure under the circumstances.
You may go.
When will I have the honor
of meeting my coworkers again?
You'll be surprised
before you leave. I'd
like to ask you one thing,
why does a fellow like
you go in for Thievery?
Well,
my father's body is
part of the fortifications of
Verone.
My brother's body is lie at the
mine.
I have a few scratches myself.
The world owes me a living
the world but not France,
meaning precisely.
I'm very patriotic.
I never love Frenchmen
cheekbone. Classification A one R
I'll find type chin 11 4 A
Arian type I, right? Classification R 10
knows
aquiline nordic 17, 8
lip, lower
Slavic type 15 A
but there are no pictures of Eugenie.
How did you? This is a spoken portrait
in a case where no photograph exists.
We make one up from
carefully checked descriptions.
A
girl.
That's all the day.
Come on.
I want you to criticize it.
Not be
quite a bit like her.
Well, that's fine.
Wait for me in my office.
I want you to note
these features carefully.
Find Eugenie do.
She's the key to the Doan
murder.
Transmit spoke important to all
undercover operatives, check all hospitals,
institutions, morgues and borders.
You'll be supplied with a
facsimile on your way out.
That'll do.
Well, how's everything going?
Oh, everything's practically done
except for finding the murderer.
Rees
Princess Anastasia,
open your eyes.
It's all coming back to you.
Your memory today is much
clearer than it was yesterday.
Remember the day your
father and mother were killed,
the guards didn't even let you dress
they ordered due to the seller.
Remember princess
who was there?
My father.
Well,
my mother, well,
my sister, well, and
they draw all of you into a corner.
You can see them raising their guns firing.
Your father went down first. Then your
mother. Please don't make me say it again.
Your eldest sister fell over you.
What did you see?
Rest our
princess.
I believe her to be the lawful
claimant to the throne of Russia.
She has all the facial
characteristics of Romanov.
She knows secrets which only a
member of the royal family could know
found the missing daughter of the
late Sir.
Away
Rosy.
You
don't believe princess
is
stay.
Yeah.
Oh
yeah,
I understand. There's
another claimant in Berlin.
Yes. But the Minister of Foreign
Affairs is getting anxious about this one.
This sort of thing is a to
become political and financial.
It isn't such a bad business being
the Prince of Anastasia. Look at this.
There is a lot of money involved
and here's another
little nest egg in London
B 12 and K 31. Work on the anesthesia
case.
A 16 reports, no
progress on the Eugenie Dorene
case.
A 21 reports. Leon Reynolds
sincerely cooperating with police to find girl
and wants instructions
whether to arrest said Reynold
while hardly
cooperating with the police.
Reynold has been
collecting other people's jewelry.
We'll deal with that later on.
Well, the Schelberg bank case
has been solved. So praise confessed.
Here's something interesting.
The court has been petitioned to appoint
a guardian for
Princess Anastasia General Molo
guardian for the princess
and a little over a
million pounds in the London Bank.
You don't think by any chance that a
million pounds might be
of interest to general molo
come in
wars.
Confidential dossier contains this
information concerning general molo
extremely magnetic personality
lives, extravagantly source of wealth.
Unknown mother Manchu,
princess, father Russian nobleman,
trace of insanity on father's side,
incidentally a
charming fellow. This molo
Paris gowns won't change that street
gon to a royal princess. I have royal blood.
I shouldn't put it on the
stage. Not that flower girl.
You are becoming tired.
I've studied hundreds of
faces and I found only one
who is a perfect hypnotic subject
and who also looks like a Romanov.
But that girl can't stand the
strain. Why she'll lose her mind.
Well, if she does, then her
guardian will rule Russia as.
But you must realize
too many people know her.
Not as many as you think.
If you have died,
identification is going to be
difficult. The way your space is passed in
the corpse can't be identified, but
there's very little doubt that it's Lonzo.
Oh,
by the way,
I have Reynold
outside. He knew the band too.
Here's a little
souvenir of their acquaintance.
Chinese
rare ancient Jade
Renault seems to be quite a collector.
Oh, there's no doubt about that
K 31 reporting.
K 31 reports she tried to get in Molo
chateau, but the place was so heavily guarded.
It was impossible.
She caught a glimpse of
the princess whose profile
cheekbone and chin line
resemble the classifications of Eugenie
doin.
I'd like to know what's
going on in that chateau.
I don't suppose we have
any right to go in that place.
On the other hand, a
burglar has, shall we say
poetic license
come in?
Won't you sit down
Reynold?
How would you like to,
you forget, I never up Frenchman.
It's just a matter of form.
How would you like to exercise
those rare talents of yours poetically
at your service?
We want to find out what's
going on in a certain chateau at
this address,
in particular. We want
you to look for a girl.
You may find that she bears a slight
resemblance to someone very dear to you.
You mean
Eugenie?
I must warn you that the
place is heavily guarded. Pardon me?
I wouldn't advise you are
trying to enter before midnight.
I won't insult your
intelligence by suggesting
how to enter a house.
Good afternoon.
Come here. Yes,
you'll lose up the valley
princes,
Princess Anastasia,
my
uncle Maxim,
Uncle
Maxim,
Maxine,
uncle Maxine,
his imperial highness, the Grand
Duke Maxim his excellency. The Count
the
Moet,
your imperial heights. General Mola
allow me to present count to Marseille.
Delighted.
I am honored.
I shall inform the
princess of your arrival.
Your highness,
a royal highness,
the princess Anastasia.
Yes,
I go.
Maxine
were a mere child
when I went off to the war
and you still remember me.
Yeah,
older
and you look
tired.
Ok,
first your father, your mother
and then your sister and soldiers.
And what happened? Then please don't
make me see that terrible thing again.
You understand my dear child, why I
oppress you with personal questions?
Are these the flowers you want? What you
come here here.
Leave it off the ballet.
God
rents
Princess Anastasia.
Yeah,
your highness come with me.
Our highness is nervous.
I am
yet your highness must acknowledge
that she has all the
features of her. Romanov
General Mola.
That girl is not the Princess Anastasia.
She's clearly a mental case.
I should advise you
to discontinue this idea
or I shall be forced to
notify the proper authorities.
I respect your opinion
and admire your judgment, your highness,
but my faith in her is not shaken.
I shall have experts
test our mind.
The moment I met General
Mullah, I had to present him of danger
was
no,
probably.
Yeah.
And the girl on the bed, well, I
don't know whether she was asleep or dead.
You see they were right on my heels and
besides, I didn't want to be in bad taste.
So I just took two quick looks.
Are you always in such good
taste? Oh, no, only when I'm in a hurry.
Yes.
The grand,
the grand duke is killed
cray
embankment third accident in this spot
in exactly the same way
we'll investigate it once get the
cars who's in charge, Cressie Lucian.
Lucian rope off the
place, hold the witnesses.
No communications, get the search
lights and the baby tests. Come on, Reynold.
Strange coincidence. The
Grand Duke just left Moloch.
They all dead
for any witnesses.
We're the buddy down man.
Come on.
Is this the man you saw at the chateau?
Yes, I'm pretty sure it is.
Come to my say
this was found on the chauffeur,
this on the older gentleman
and these on the man in uniform.
It's a lot of money for a French Officer
Marseille.
It's a wealthy family.
Go right up and talk to General Mola.
Find a way to see that girl
but be very careful. You
don't make the general suspicious
and what made them swerve off at
this point. The other car didn't skid.
This is not a signboard,
it looks like a moving picture screen,
get some keys and I
miss,
how do you help with those keys?
Could I be of any assistance? What do you
mean? I think maybe I could open it for you.
Thanks.
Why? That's a projection machine?
A knock there sound equipment.
Mm.
Yeah,
I'm worried. Get
muon.
What,
what
it
there are to be no more
cut flowers? Is that clear?
I am not a man that tolerates
what you have allowed to happen here.
Money and jewelry are missing.
That means there has been an intruder
in my house. That is not to happen again.
Is that clear
General Mueller.
I want to see General Molo.
No, come in at night.
Yeah,
this is my card.
You wait here, Justin
Ma
be wise to call a doctor.
I'm afraid her reason is going.
The are
my father
you needn't worry.
I've seen this happen before.
Every reminder of
that tragic day upsets her.
All she needs is a rest.
I shall stay with her.
Don't make me see it again.
You must be very tired.
My good night.
Flowers,
please. Leon.
The opera
11.
Leon
lay on.
Yeah.
General
stay here.
General Molo.
I am honored
by a visit from the
sit down, please. I regretted my
visitors occasioned by very sad news.
The Grand duke or his highness.
He was here early in the evening,
his automobile met with an accident.
I'm sorry to say he was killed.
Oh, this is a terrible shock.
I hardly know what to say
on the body of the grand duke was a
communication for the princess, Anastasia
that I am compelled to
deliver to her. Personally.
I dislike disturbing her highness
at this hour. I understand perfectly.
If you'll excuse me for a moment,
I will prepare the princess for this
dreadful news and arrange for her to see you.
Thank you.
I tried to break the
news as quietly as I could,
but the princess fainted.
I'm afraid any more excitement
at this moment would be dangerous
under the circumstances. I'd
better come back tomorrow morning.
Get the motor boat ready. We
are leaving by the secret passage.
Have the car meet us at high Bridge,
telephone the airport immediately hurry.
Yes, general
should ask her.
You're ready for an emergency.
Keep your eyes open. Stay close by go.
You should
you shame me?
Mhm.
Leon.
Leon,
darling.
It was near this saw that
Lazos
body was found. Yes,
this must lead directly into the
chateau. Why don't we go in the front way?
I want to surprise Muller. So he
won't have a chance to destroy any evidence
up here.
Break it down,
still get the assembly to
guard all entrances.
So you wanted to be more
of
it will take more than the police of
pace to catch me.
What a beautiful statue you would make
the most beautiful
statue I have ever made
with a keen blade
after the thirst. It is very peaceful.
It will not be like
this for you. However,
you see how quiet she
is now, how much like Mar,
I think we're just in time.
Don't touch him. You'll be electrocuted.
We don't doubt you when you
say that you're going straight,
but we prefer that you
do it outside of France.
You have just two
hours to catch your boat.
Good luck madam Reynold.
Thank you.
By the way, all the time
that you were helping us,
we noticed that various
pieces of jewelry disappeared.
We have a vague idea where they went.
But would you mind telling me one thing,
why were the counter Marseille's
valuables left untouched?
I'm sure he was a Frenchman.
So
about that,
I never robbed Frenchman,
but I had to have a
souvenir of our acquaintance.
Come on down,
overtake that car and be sure
Reynold doesn't miss the boat. Yes, Mr.