...and that's a problem
that you are both a part of.
Okay, we'll go back
and talk some more about this later.
-Aren't you selling that boat?
-Four thousand for repairs.
-You want to buy it?
-No. I get seasick right away.
This is the best.
The future is swimming around in there.
My future. Hello.
Kick if you can hear me.
-Are you wearing that one?
-Yes.
-You're not wearing your other dress?
-Come on.
Why not? It's cute.
Maybe you want it to show more,
but I feel like a bloated frog in it.
-You look great in it.
-Then why don't you wear it?
I'm sorry... Hey...
Let's not fight.
Let's have a good time tonight.
-Was it?
-Yes, of course. It really was.
...on Sunday at 3 PM.
It's almost 7:30 PM, and...
-Shit.
-...look at Walpurgis night celebrations.
-Are you leaving?
-The kids have fireworks. I have to help.
Can't Ulla handle that?
Now where the hell's my tie?
Damn it.
-I can't let the kids down. You get that.
-No.
You'll understand when you have kids.
I don't want any. I prefer a man.
You can have both.
Women always want everything.
Milla...
Bye.
-Where are you going to be?
-At Wiberg's.
Sounds really boring.
Listen up, everybody. Hey!
You see, Per and I...
We have an announcement to make.
We didn't know if this was a Spring party,
Walpurgis party or Friends party...
but now we've made up our minds.
This is our...
-..."we're having a baby" party.
-It's gone through?
Next week we're leaving
for Salvador de Bahia, in Brazil,
where a little baby boy is waiting for us.
Excuse me!
I feel I have to say a few words
as your oldest friend,
and this is just... rock 'n' roll!
You've been trying so hard,
and we've been hoping.
I know you'll be
the greatest parents in the world.
After me and Pia, I mean.
And...
Oh, that's right, Pia is giving me a hint.
Of course, we have to raise a toast
to all the moms and dads here!
-Cheers.
I just have to counterattack and show
a picture of our little cream bun
who will arrive in three months' time.
Pia finds me embarrassing now. I know
you're a fed up with me right now, love.
And I... just want to try to...
to say that...
having a child is the greatest thing...
and I promise you that I will
be the greatest mom in the world!
-You are not going to be a mom!
-No, of course not - a dad.
You're not going to be a father either!
Pia...
Because the father's name is Thomas,
and I'm in love with him.
Well, now that's been said, and
I didn't mean to blurt it out like this...
but it just happened. Thanks for
everything. I think I should be going.
-Bye.
-Pia?
Take care of Fredrik.
Thanks, that salmon was wonderful.
Pia! Wait! Pia!
Pia, wait! Stop the car!
Pia!
-Ow, calm down, will you?
-You're just wrong!
Pia, you're just stressed out.
Can we talk about this?
-Don't you get it? We're done!
-Calm down.
Close the door, we're done!
-Sorry!
-It's just the hormones.
I'm so sick of your fucking hormones!
Stop! My child, you can't just take...
No, then.
Wiberg.
WIBERG
-I didn't recognize you at first.
-No wonder, it's been ages.
-Anyway, make yourself at home.
-I will. Thank you.
-Welcome.
-Thanks.
-Milla!
-Hello.
God, it's been ages!
-I didn't know you were coming.
-I wasn't...
-Did Kjell know?
-No, I don't think so.
-How are you?
-Fine, really great.
So have you... found a man yet?
-Nothing steady.
-Isn't your little clock ticking?
-No, not for me.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Hello, Milla!
-Hello!
Sweetie.
-Arvid!
-Well, if it isn't the little babysitter!
-Hello!
-Hello.
You can't call her that any longer.
That was a thousand years ago.
Indeed.
-Do you still smoke?
-No... Well, just at parties.
Go ahead.
-Stop it.
-God, you're such an old bore!
This is no game. My kids are in there!
I came here tonight because...
I've spent every big holiday evening
alone for the last six years.
Either we move in together
or I... want to be on my own.
-You're drunk, aren't you?
-Six years, Kjell!
Let's do this:
I'm going in for a bite to eat.
You wait a few minutes
and then go straight home.
-I'm not leaving without a promise.
-Five minutes.
Idiot!
Everyone out onto the balcony!
Everyone, now!
Hello?
What the hell?
What?
This is my flat, I live here.
How did you get in?
-The balcony.
-Balcony? How did you end up there?
-Please, just let me out. I feel sick.
-What the...? Who are you?
Just leave it. I'll clean up.
-Would you like something to drink?
-Home...
Wait. I'll get you a sweater.
-Wear this.
-Cool.
-Good morning.
-God morning, boss.
-You should meet new women, Fredrik.
-Just the one would do, thanks.
You have to think big.
Fredrik? I want to ask you one thing...
-My youngest, he needs medicine...
-How much?
One thousand... but 500 would do.
And it's just a loan.
-Sure, that's fine.
-Thanks.
That Pia woman
should get a punch in the face.
-Hello, Tomme.
-You having a sneaky fuck in here?
-How about "good morning", Tomme?
-Good morning, Tomme.
Exactly.
Hello. That's 12 crowns.
There you go. Goodbye.
-Hello.
-The usual?
-No, just a quickie.
-Kjell...can you tell me one?
-I don't have any more.
Just one more, please?
This: Why do blondes stand on their heads
with their legs spread after sex?
Well, they're waiting for someone
to swipe the VISA card, aren't they?
And in...
I'm in control of my life.
I am happy and strong.
-You were drunk!
-Just a little tipsy, I wasn't wasted.
-You don't do that kind of thing drunk.
-I wouldn't have dared otherwise.
You told me to give him an ultimatum!
I did. And he disappeared!
Good, at last it's over.
Now you can meet a real man.
-Like where?
-Hush.
Let's go to the shooting bow position.
Stretch your legs forward.
Raise two fingers on each hand
and place them around your toes.
Breathe in and tighten the bow...
I am a good person.
I deserve all the love in the world.
-Does he sleep well?
-I'd forgotten how small they are.
Look, he even looks like you.
She's due in five weeks.
Seriously, forget about Pia.
She wasn't that much fun anyway.
I don't give a shit about Pia!
-Exactly.
-Yes.
See at it as shopping for food.
You want a certain kind of cheese.
If they're out of it, you just
buy the cheese on sale.
So you have another cheese for a week.
-A change can be fun.
-I don't want fun!
I want my child. It's my child too.
I think it's a boy. She has that,
you know, pointed stomach.
-It's a girl.
-Come on! No way.
Girl stomachs are wider. Hers was pointed.
It is a girl.
She's already given birth.
Pia!
Open up, I want to see her!
Pia, I want to see her!
-Pia's busy. She's breastfeeding.
-Are you the fuckhead stealing my baby?
-I don't think so.
-Thomas, I'll deal with this.
Take care of her. The pacifier is there.
-Fredrik!
-I want to see her.
Please, you can't just...
-I want to see my child!
-She's not yours!
-I want my child! She's mine...
-No.
-Prove it!
-Okay.
RESULTS OF DNA TEST
She's Thomas's, okay?
Okay? Are you happy now?
Do you know why I think that is?
It's because he's too nice.
You're so wrong. Had any of my men been
half as nice, Alice would've had a dad.
Cows are nice, not men!
It can't be a coincidence
that he hasn't got a family yet.
Women need a bit of resistance
or they'll go looking elsewhere.
What kind of a Wild West attitude is that?
-Dad, tell her she's wrong.
-Uh-huh.
Don't involve him in this now!
So let's take this out.
Say good bye to Fredrik.
-Do you need to borrow money?
-No.
-Mom, come!
-God help me, Fredrik.
-You're 41 and have no life.
-It'll be alright, Mom.
Thanks for helping me.
-Bye.
Wait, wait!
That's it.
Go for it.
You got it!
-My fault. I lost my focus.
-How about a rematch?
-How about a couple of pints? Per?
-No, I have to get home to Samson.
-Svante, how about you?
-No, the little one has chickenpox.
-But doesn't anyone...?
-Bye.
Doesn't anyone want to come along? Hey!
There's a difference.
Women have it in their blood.
And what do men have in their blood?
You've gone astray, Fredrik
Get yourself a real girlfriend.
I don't want a girlfriend.
-So make a clone of yourself.
-Thanks. More suggestions?
Place an ad: "Seeking temporary wife."
-"Relation terminated on child delivery."
-Your parents are weird, Samson.
Hi.
I'm in full control of my life.
Fredrik Lundström?
Hello, Fredrik. I'm Milla Hedborg.
Welcome. Please take a seat.
So... Let's see.
Okay, Fredrik.
"Restaurant business"? Which one?
-Fredrik's Hot dogs.
-So you're Hot Dog Fredrik?
Yeah.
-So we're talking about adoption?
-Yes... that's right.
-I gather you've tried a long time.
-Yes... Jesus, yes!
-It's so much harder than you think.
-In vitro fertilization, hormones?
Well... no... I've...
The...
The longing for a child
can be very deeply rooted.
Well. I dream about it.
I'm kind of obsessed, actually.
It's an age thing. Everyone
you know has children and a family.
And... Well, that's what's important
in my life right now.
-And your girlfriend?
-No, I've...
She's not with me now. She's...
-She's still at work.
-I see. So you work together?
Yes.
That looks good on your application.
-How do you mean?
-It suggests continuity.
I think the board will see it as a plus.
But she has to come here in person.
Of course.
How about Friday at nine o'clock?
-Is that okay?
-You mean this Friday?
That shouldn't be a problem.
-Okay, then!
-Yes.
Did you have any more questions?
Well...
Weren't you in my apartment...
on Walpurgis night?
Yes. Well, I thought
you looked a bit familiar.
That's right,
I'll give you your sweater back.
-Oh, don't worry about that.
-Okay.
-Bye.
-Until Friday.
Yup.
-Hello.
-Hi.
Oh, right.
I was thinking about something, Tanja.
-You know I want to adopt a child?
-Congratulations.
Yeah, well... But you
have to be a couple for that...
Right...
So I thought that you and
I maybe... could become a couple.
Sorry. That was a stupid idea.
I apologize. It would feel weird. I'm
exploiting you enough as it is. Sorry.
-I'm off now. Bye.
-How long would we be a couple?
Half an hour, but it was a dumb idea.
If you pay me 2,000.
Would that be okay?
-Then you wouldn't exploit me.
-Okay, wow. You know what you're saying?
-You don't want to think it over?
-No.
Okay. Wow.
Okay. Now I'd like you
to tell me about your parents.
-Tanja, would you like to start?
-Me?
Well...
My parents...
We were very close.
So close!
And they were my very best friends.
They were wonderful people.
Helpful, warm...
But now they are gone!
Oh my...
I'll just get some tissues.
-What are you doing?
-It's for your sake.
It's too much...
Here. I didn't mean to upset you, Tanja.
-How are you?
-Better.
-At home in Russia we cry every day.
-Yes.
-Let's leave that subject for now.
-Mother!
My mother....
Yes, well... You were previously
married in Sweden, Tanja. Briefly.
You wouldn't want to
meet that man, Melinka. He was horrible!
He lacked everything that my Fredrik has:
Love, tenderness, and respect
- he respects women, Milla.
I believe you, but I have to know
that the divorce has taken effect
since you two have to get married
to be approved as adoptive parents.
Well...
-So it was a bit more complicated...
-What do you think, Fredrik?
That I will move in with you
and listen to that woman
telling me how to be a mother!
I, who have given birth to two boys!
-Please, I would pay you.
-Pay me? Get one thing clear:
-I am not for sale!
-But...
Well, come on!
Come here, Fredrik.
Tomme, come here and help me.
I need to lift this.
Come on.
I want to clean under it.
-You have such a nice firm butt, Tanja.
-Shut up or get out of here!
I'm sorry, Tanja. I'm so sorry!
It's all right. You're a good man, Tomme.
-Do... do you really think so, Tanja?
-Definitely.
Tanja, I think you are lovely too.
Really? So you like Russian women?
Get out of the kitchen, Tomme!
I want 50,000.
-Okay, forty.
-Forty-five.
-In US dollars.
-No way, in Swedish crowns.
-Do you think I'm a millionaire?
-Okay, then. 45,000 crowns
-And you sign over half the grill to me.
-What?
And then we'll tear the papers up
when the baby's here.
-Are you nuts?
-Then forget it.
You bet I will.
-Alright. Would you do it?
-I want a contract.
Come on, we're friends,
we can trust each other!
One day you'll meet a girl,
and I'll be left on my own with a baby...
-...no job and not one ruble.
-I'm not like that.
You're not? You're a man,
and all men think with their dicks.
That's the way God wanted it, not me.
How about this: 20 grand now
and the rest afterwards?
I'll sign half my business over to you,
and we'll write a contract?
Okay.
You've both declared your wish
to enter into marriage.
I therefore ask you, Fredrik Lundström:
Do you take Tanja Smirnova
as your lawfully wedded wife?
I do.
Do you, Tanja Smirnova
take Fredrik Lundström
as your lawfully wedded husband?
I do.
Control of my life.
I'm in...
control of my life. Happy.
I'm in control of my life.
Happy and strong.
-You have a lovely voice, Tanja.
-Thank you.
-Are these your parents, Fredrik?
-Yes, that's right.
That's Mom and Dad.
-You can tell.
-You look very much like your dad.
It seems to have been a wonderful wedding.
-Yes, it was.
-Just lovely.
-Is it okay if I take a look around?
-Yes, of course.
-I can show you.
-Yes, do.
Okay.
-These are nice. Did you bake them?
-Yes. from powder that you mix with water.
-You can get it at the grocery store.
-Right.
Fredrik likes them very much.
Have another.
Well...
What do you think
about our chances really?
That isn't up to me, it's up to the
board. I only give recommendations.
-You've long wanted children, right?
-Yes. Always.
And I've been a stand-in dad
for my sister's kid too.
And... I don't know.
It makes you a better person.
Just to have breakfast with someone
struggling with a spoon, or bake cookies.
-Does this sound silly? Unmanly?
-It sounds very nice.
-How about you?
-What about me?
-Don't you want children?
-No, it's...
I don't know,
maybe it's because of my work.
You see so many sad cases,
and... I'm fine as it is.
I want to discuss something
many adoptive parents like to avoid:
That there is a birth mother somewhere.
Any thoughts?
Well... You worry, of course.
Can they come afterwards and...?
I mean, if you give up your baby,
you give up your rights to it.
-That's how you feel?
-Yes, I agree.
They can't be very suitable mothers.
If they were,
they wouldn't be in that situation.
Miss... What do you know about that?
A mother wants to be with her child.
-What do you know about real moms?
-Tanja, Tanja!
Do you think anyone willingly would
give their child to a cow like you?
-Of course any mom can be good...
-We're just discussing and analyzing...
-Do you need a degree to be a mom?
-Tanja, shut the fuck up!
-This is going to hell!
-This is degrading!
I'd do anything for my kids!
No one can tell me I'm a bad mother!
-They didn't. Why not just shut up?!
-Should I be ordinary like you?
Never!
Yes, five times a week.
I'll be lecturing at the university.
So don't worry, the money is coming.
Yes, Mom, we will pay.
Call the doctor
and ask what his shoe size is.
Tell him I'll get him six pairs,
like the ones the Swedish king wears.
Yes. But, Mom...
Save your tears. Should something
really happen, I'd... Okay, bye.
-This looks new.
-Get your filthy hands off it.
-I have enough problems as it is.
-Sure.
Here's 3,000. You can have 500
but you really have to pay.
-Just a little ketchup.
-I'll give you one line here.
Tomme... Tomme!
Tomme?
Do you have a crush on her?
-Hey, Kjelle...
-What?
Well... How do you do it?
-Are you talking about...?
-No.
No, no, I know how to do that.
No, I mean before.
So that the girls will like you?
Do you know what I think?
You have to reveal yourself.
That always works. All girls love that.
-Hello!
-Hello.
-Hi. Would you like a ride?
-Yes, please.
-Go, get in.
-Yes, thanks!
-Some weather, isn't it?
-I was lucky you drove by.
-Thank you very much.
-Don't mention it.
-Will you be alright now?
-Yes, no problem.
-It sure is raining.
-Yes.
-Do you want to...? Your sweater.
-What?
-Do you want to pick up your sweater?
-Oh. Yes, definitely.
Okay.
I've washed it, but I didn't dare
to iron it, because I didn't know...
-Well... see you.
-Okay.
Would you like anything?
Like coffee, I mean.
Well... why not?
...so I worked at the hospital
before they closed it down.
And I was so sick of people
always telling me: "Do this, do that."
I had been working extra at the grill,
and the old man who owned it
went and kicked the bucket.
-He just fell head first into the mash.
-No! That didn't happen.
-I'm kidding.
-I'm so easily fooled.
Well, he did die,
so I got the opportunity to take over,
and I thought: "Why not?"
And I enjoy it. It suits me perfectly.
Maybe it doesn't look like much,
but my little box there
provides security to many people
with someone to talk to,
and the hot dogs always taste the same.
That's all there is to it.
You must meet a lot of fun people too.
I wouldn't say "fun," but...
Custody battles, divorces,
loneliness. All kinds of misery.
Yeah...
Well, I guess I should be heading home.
That's right, the sweater! Oh, sorry.
Are you alright?
-Did I come on too strong?
-No, no, it's just me.
Can we like... not do it?
Of course! No problems.
-Is Milla your real name?
-No.
Camilla Renate Hedborg.
Fredrik Egon Lundström.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
-Tomme?
-Hello, Tanja.
Come in.
Just close the door behind you.
It's the very best - Moskovskaya.
Only 100 crowns for you.
-No, I don't want any.
-You don't?
-Are you sick, Tomme?
-No.
You must be.
You eat too many French fries.
Tanja... I...
I wanted to ask you...
Yes?
Sometimes, even if you don't think so...
-Sometimes it just comes up.
-What comes up, Tomme?
A chance.
It just shows up, so you have to grab it.
You just have to take it.
Tomme. I have to sleep now.
You have to go.
Bye, I'll see you tomorrow.
Wait, Tanja.
But I just... wanted to ask you...
if we could...
fuck?
It doesn't work like that, Tomme.
You have to be in love first.
-But I'm so... horny.
-Go home and have a wank.
And I'll see you tomorrow.
Bye. Sleep well!
I hope you don't think that I'm...
I just don't know what to say.
No. I'm not like this in reality either.
Milla. I would love to...
You know, Tanja and I, we've...
You don't have to say anything!
I mean, I have Kjell.
And you have Tanja.
Let's not make it more complicated.
I understand, completely.
And besides, you're my client,
so I'm not allowed to.
But I hope you realize that this won't
affect our professional relationship.
No.
Why would it?
-Once is almost never.
-Exactly.
Things like this happen.
We're not more than human, are we?
Yes, that's true.
I have to go open the grill now.
Fredrik. I hope you realize
that this has to stay between us.
Of course.
Bye.
Okay... does anyone want to say anything?
-Arne and Janine, will you begin?
-Well, I don't know.
My customers aren't happy
when they make an investment...
that doesn't grow.
In other words: I'm the infertile one.
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
-Jenny and Kalle?
-Well...
We've tried and we've tried...
-With thermometers, ice bags...
-Yeah.
nasal sprays and pills... I don't know
how we will go back to normal.
No.
Tanja?
Fredrik. How do you feel about it?
-About what? About sex?
-Yes, for example...
-Well...
-You and Tanja, but you don't have...
-Do you want to know how often?
-No, that's not necessary. Just if...
I just want to say that Fredrik
and I have a wonderful time.
You Swedish women talk about it,
we Russians just do it.
We are friends with our vaginas.
We know what they are used for.
You Swedes just complicate it
and then analyze things.
I think you're wrong. Surely
that's more to do with personality...
Wait a minute! I want you to know
I'm really in touch with my fifi.
So why are you so angry?
Have you researched this
in any detail, Tanja?
No? Swedish women are known for
being close to...
being buddies with their vaginas.
And Swedish women's attitudes
to intercourse are very open and free.
I am a good person,
I deserve all the love in the world.
I gain weight whatever I do.
I bet you cheat and eat at night.
-Bye.
No, Milla. It happens to be illegal.
Yes. But that's not the worst of it...
What?
I'm pregnant, too!
-By whom?
-I don't know.
-What are you going to do?
-Yeah, well...
I have to get an abortion, because...
I don't want to have children.
But I want to know whose child
I don't want to have.
And even if I wanted it
they're both married, and not to me.
Milla, it doesn't work like that.
-You have to decide what you want.
-But that's what I don't know!
I just don't want to end up
like my mother, alone and bitter.
I don't even know how it would work.
And I'm afraid
I'll forget the baby somewhere.
And in my nightmares
it turns into a banana
that I sit on and squash.
What do I do?
You have to decide yourself
whether to have a child or not.
But you'd better
keep your hands off Fredrik.
-Hello.
-Hi.
-Are we going to eat here?
-Well excuse me if it isn't in Paris.
Come on.
-Hello. The usual?
-You betcha. But two.
-I don't eat meat.
-So choose something else.
-Hi.
-Hello.
-Hello, Kjelle.
-Hi.
-Did you want anything?
-Do you have anything vegetarian?
Well... mashed potatoes or fries.
-No, I'm fine, thank you.
-Are you sure?
-Oh, yes.
-Tell me one?
No, not right now, Tomme.
-Just one.
-I said not now.
-Please?
-That's enough, Tomme.
-Stop that, please.
-Thank you.
-I'll do one. Do you want to hear?
-Sure.
What's the difference between
a blonde and an ironing board?
The ironing board comes together.
-Its legs!
-What?
What's the difference between
an ironing board and a blonde?
The ironing board's legs come together.
-That wasn't funny!
-Don't get hysterical.
-I'm not hysterical!
-Aren't you hysterical?
Honey...
Wasn't it a little bit funny?
Do you want a bite?
-Stop.
-Why?
Stop the car.
-Are you okay?
-No, I'm not! I'm pregnant.
What the hell...? You haven't told me.
How did that happen?
-Well, I don't know!
-How can you not know?
-Why don't you get it fixed?
-Fixed?
Fix it! You don't want to have children!
I know! But people change.
I'm up and down all the time.
One day I feel like this,
the other like that!
So you've changed your mind?
Why didn't you tell me?
Because I wasn't pregnant!
-Would that have changed anything?
-I never said that.
No. Because I refuse to be like Ulla,
who sits there alone with the kids.
Hey, I have been a very good father.
A very, very good father.
I don't give a shit about you being
a good father! I want you to love me!
But I do.
-Camilla, I do love you.
-So why didn't you ever leave Ulla?
Milla! Milla!
It's not their fault. Cheeses are by their
very nature meant for different things.
-He's no good for her.
-What do you know about that?
-I... I just know.
-Maybe she's getting just what she wants?
Come on, you've been talking about kids
ever since you did your military service.
Yeah.
Bye, I'll see you around.
I don't know if you want me...
But a little baby, Milla.
It's like starting over.
Like becoming young again.
-So... aren't you happy?
-Sure...
Yes, I am!
Ow!
It's Ulla.
No. No! What are you doing?
-Hello.
-Well...
I mean, I know we said it was nothing...
and I know that...
But I can't stop thinking about it.
It doesn't go away.
-Can I come in?
-No.
Please, please don't do this.
It's just not possible.
-How the hell can you be with him?
-You don't even know him.
-Yes, I do.
-It's none of your business.
Have you heard me
say one bad word about your...
platinum-colored boobarella?
-But, please!
-It's impossible.
Tanja ...
-Who was that?
-Just a neighbor who...
Something wasn't working.
I couldn't... help him.
I don't want this shit here!
Are you done with the cash register?
Yes!
Fuck!
Pull yourself together, my friend.
You are a kind man,
you have friends, you're healthy,
and you'll make a wonderful dad.
Or mom. You don't have to be sad. Drink.
Cheers.
Tomme Bolander, smooth as ammonia.
Come and congratulate the dad.
-Tanja. I have to talk to you.
-Not now.
-Come on, have a drink.
-That's not a good idea.
Come on, we're having a party. Go ahead!
Fredrik...
Tomme, Tomme!
Shit, Tomme.
Damn, now I need to pee.
-I love you, Tanja.
-Not now!
Yes, I do right now.
Who the hell put this here?
You have to feel the same way, Tanja.
I... I can't feel this way
unless you also feel this way.
You have to feel this way. Hey, Tanja.
-What the hell is this?
-Vodka.
-You make me so disappointed.
-Tanja, we have to talk.
You need to go home now. Oh, come on.
I own half of this.
That's none of your business!
-I want this out of my grill!
-Put it back!
-They go out now!
-You think I can live off your pittance?
That I can support a family on my salary?
I'll never get to keep the kid
if they find out about the booze!
Fuck! Bastard!
I hate you! I knew you'd do that.
What were you thinking? "Nice Fredrik."
"He's so dumb
he can be tricked into anything."
Maybe you were planning on
getting the whole grill?
I'm not giving you one penny.
No! I want my 25,000, you fucking Swedes!
You're scared to death
of everything in this country!
If you were a real man
you'd already have a kid.
You don't even know how to make one!
At least I know how to look after them!
Fredrik? Get up. Fredrik!
Oh my God!
Tomme, come here!
Tanja... Tanja!
Can you see me now?
Can you see me now, Tanja?
I'm revealing myself to you.
I'm revealing myself, Tanja.
What happened?
-Oh, my.
-What's that?
Dear Fredrik.
I can't go through with this.
I'm going home to Russia and my children.
Maybe I can give them
a better future now.
I'm bringing the kitchen.
After all, half of it is mine, right?
Please forgive me, Fredrik. Tanja.
-When is she coming?
-She isn't coming.
Yes... She said she would.
She said that.
Listen up, Tomme.
She's never coming back.
She's in Russia, where she came from.
Go home now.
It's not about what I think anymore!
The rules are clear on that point.
But what's best for the child?
My task is to assess your suitability,
and the criteria is
that all information must be verified,
that you don't have a criminal record...
And it is assumed that the couple
is living together.
I don't get it. Why did you do it?
Why?
-I want a child. Is that unnatural?
-No.
But you shouldn't go about it dishonestly.
Who are you
to talk to me about honesty?
Hello! Did you wait up for me?
Sit down.
Well... this child...
I'm not certain that it's yours, Kjell.
Hey? Hello?
Seriously, only you can decide what to do.
Men come and go.
I've never regretted having my kids.
I'd rather live alone with them
than be without them.
-I liked Tanja.
-Dad!
-Didn't you even have a crush on her?
-No.
It was a huge mistake.
Listen... I was wondering...
Can I stay with you for a while?
Yeah...
But...
I was...
I won't be living there anymore.
CRUISES TO RUSSIA
I imagine that there's
a huge change to have a child.
Absolutely. We are
very close to each other. Definitely.
I think it's important to be honest
with each other. We are, right?
And to remember that whatever happens,
the kid has the right to have two parents.
Thank you.
-Here you are.
-Thank you.
-Hello.
-A "Milla's special," please.
-Finally, someone orders it!
-No, it's on me.
-Thanks.
-Half a "special," please.
-Mustard? Ketchup?
Bye, Fredrik.
-So? Did it meet with your approval?
-Yes.
Fredrik?
Well, I'm pregnant.
Yeah, I can see that.
I've no idea what I'll be like
as a mom. Maybe I'll...
Maybe the kid will hate me,
or I'll forget it at day care.
-Then Kjell can to step in.
-We're not together anymore.
Did you get a haircut?
No.
This kid...
I intend to raise it on my own.
But...
We could do a paternity test, if you want.
And then you can see...
If you want to take part.
I wanted to ask
if you want to be the father.
-What?
-I mean, it might be yours.
You'll just be the dad, not be with me.
No changing diapers in the middle
of the night, just the dad thing.
Please say something.
Go to hell.
Do you know
why I got together with your mom?
There was this other girl...
Elisabet.
She didn't want me.
Or so I thought.
But, I met her again 20 years later.
She said that she'd never forgiven me
for getting married.
You just never fucking know with women.
No.
Come in.
You probably think I'm here because
you're pregnant, but I'm not.
See...
If I find out the baby's mine,
I couldn't stand not living with it.
And should I find out
that it isn't my baby, then...
I don't...
I don't know why women won't live with me.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
I think that maybe they don't know me,
they don't know who I am.
I know that I'm bad,
really bad, at showing...
...what I feel, and so on.
And Tomme.
Someone I know... No, a pal.
He says I'm too nice and a coward.
Well, okay, I am a cowardly person...
I'm a coward, but two people have to dare,
and you have to make a choice.
Coffee or tea? Mustard or not?
Go.
Don't you understand? Go to hell!
Hello.
Mister, you're scaring off
the other customers.
I will serve all of you.
Please stay in line.
-Volodya!
-Okay, okay.
Please hurry!
-Blabs all the time. Blabs and blabs...
-Blab, blab...
-Woman.
-Wo-man...
-Wo-mman.
-Bye-bye.
-Bye-bye... Bye.
Bye-bye!
We accept all currencies..
Oh, Milla! Milla!
-Who's Milla? My name is Eva.
-Eva...
-Eva!
-Who's Milla?
Eva!
-Just screw all this!
-Don't worry, I'll help you with it all.
-I'm going to explode!
-No, you won't. I'll help you.
-I don't want to!
-I'll help you. I'll have the baby.
I love you.
What's happening? Is it coming?
Hello? Is there anybody in there?
Yes. There you are...
Subtitle translation by: Some Rube