LONGING 202
A SOUND FILM OPERETTA BY...
IF YOU ARE OUT OF A JOB
DON'T BE A SLOB
TAKE NOTE OF THIS ADDRESS:
JOB MARKET OF OTTO HESSE!
HESSE
ADVERTISEMENT OFFICE
BUYING AND SELLING
MARRIAGE
JOB MARKET
REQUESTS
IMMEDIATELY AFTER ADVERTISING...
...ALREADY ENGAGED
THE GENERAL MANAGER
HESSE MAKES IT POSSIBLE
THIS IS HOW YOU MAKE IT
HESSE ADVERTISEMENT AGENCY DOES IT
HESSE ADVERTISING FILM
That's what I call a career. She adver-
tised, got a job, and married the boss.
"If this is what you wish,
then off to Hesse Advertisement Office."
They make it look so simple at the movies.
Why won't you try advertising?
But mother, this won't help
and it's expensive, too.
Chocolate, peppermint...
-What's going on?
How long are we going to have to wait?
Patience! What's going on here?
Stand in line, please, back there!
♫ Stand back. Only patience will help you.
Everybody will have his turn.
♫ One just has to be outraged
♫ I'll file a complaint about you
♫ Silence! No anarchy!
What is it you wish?
♫ ...in her late 30s, looking for,
in good standing...
♫ Young widow, sweet and diligent,
living in an apartment with balcony.
♫ ...a sentimental clerk,
respectable and fond of children...
♫ ...searches, for the purpose of marriage,
a Greta Garbo type...
♫ Advertising, advertising!
Brings everything out into the open!
♫ You only risk a single line and
after a while you get what you need.
♫ Rigorous teacher, free from am to pm.
♫ Teaches Russian and Spanish.
A single hit will be enough.
♫ Opera singer in Tauber style.
♫ Teaching you how to sing like this...
♫ Mademoiselle with ambitions,
comes to your home if you wish...
♫ Advertising, advertising!
Brings everything out into the open!
♫ You only risk a single line and
after a while you get what you need.
It's closed!
JOB MARKET
-How can I help you?
-Next door is closed. Maybe you can help?
Yes, hand it over. "Lady worth millions
is looking to invest in a business.
Mail to: That only happens once."
One moment...
-Good morning.
-Am I late?
-Of course.
-Has the boss been here?
-No, don't worry.
Wait a moment, please.
Cash desk is over there... will you...
"Lady worth..."
...millions..."
Have you send the cash clerk
to the Florida?
-Yes, Mr. Hesse.
-Did you call ahead?
No, I didn't.
-Why didn't you call ahead?
-I... I thought...
You're not supposed to think. You're
supposed to do as I say.
-Yes, Mr. Hesse.
-Where are you going now?
-Making a call.
-To whom?
-To Florida.
-And I'm supposed to take your place?
Yes... No... I just thought...
I was supposed to...
You're supposed to do as I say.
-Yes, Sir!
-Always you're the reason for trouble.
Always me. Always me.
-Good morning.
-Can I advertise something here?
-Of course.
"Young, intelligent girl will do
all kinds of jobs. Write to: Longing 202."
All right, thanks.
-Here you go. Cash desk is over there.
-Have a nice day!
"Young, intelligent..."
"...girl will do all kinds of jobs."
"Write to: Longing 202."
Always me.
Even when doing right, I'm doing wrong.
Miss, type this...
♫ Advertisement, advertisement,
everything out in the open.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm studying the advertisements. Maybe I'll
find a buyer for our business.
No one is that stupid.
Maybe in "Miscellaneous". Look here:
♫ "To the coachman letting his carriage
roll into my shop window."
♫ "Please collect your horses at my place."
You don't think so? Wait, there's
another one. Here we go.
♫ "Every spice rack becomes aromatic
thanks do Dr. Maier's KRAFT OZONE."
♫ "Looking for 40 year old gofer,
bail set at 1000 Schillings."
♫ Advertisement, advertisement,
everything out in the open.
♫ You only risk a single line and
after a while you get what you need.
All together: ♫ You only risk a single line
and after a while you get what you need.
Why aren't you signing?
No sense of humor whatsoever.
How could I when business is that bad?
You just had to invest all our money
into this godawful store.
It's always the same with you.
Fancy presentation and no turnover.
Stop the singing. Driving me nuts.
No buyer in sight.
Maybe this one... one Creme Debute...
-What's that?
-A beauty cream.
For massaging, morning noon and night.
Highly recommended.
-A big box, 100 pieces.
-Yes, I'll take the big one.
-Here, smell this.
-Wonderful. But now please finish the bill.
I'll do that. All together that's 580.
Maybe we'll adjust downward to 600, you...
-50!
-I beg your pardon?
-650.
-To 650! Of course!
Of course! Always convenient, a few
razor blades and some toothpaste.
-Just add on everything.
-Yes, big boxes.
-My pleasure.
-All in all 650, here, please.
One moment, please.
It will be sent to you, no need
to make an effort.
-Why don't you take a seat.
-Thanks, thanks, thanks.
Here's a payment order for 420 Schillings.
-So you are...
-...the bailiff.
So I'll proceed with my job.
-Can I assist you?
-Thanks, this way I'm sure it will stick.
What a businessman, running around in your
pajamas at noon.
As if things would go better
if I'd wear a tuxedo.
Always picking on me.
Whom else? You didn't lift a finger once
since we founded the company.
Is that so? Who was out for breakfast with
the bailiff last time? Me!
-Do you know what you are?
-You're it yourself.
-Yuck!
-What's the matter?
-This is soap!
-What are you saying?
A mix-up.
Correct.
You got the bad end of the stick, though.
-Did you find a job for me?
-Yes. Someone's looking for a lift boy.
I can do that. Take notes.
First floor, toys, clothing,
phonograph records old and new.
Upward, please!
Look here, she must be off her rockers.
"Lady worth millions. Young, intelligent
girl will do all kinds of jobs."
Have you seen
something like this before?
This goes to show that you know nothing
about business. This might save us!
Go for it right now and write to her.
And I'll go for my breakfast.
-This is unbelievable!
-What's the matter?
The advertisement didn't run. You have to
go to Hesse immediately to take care of it.
-I'll do that.
-If you hurry, I can take you there.
I'll be ready in a minute!
Mother, please close my collar.
That hurts! Goodbye!
And you come on already!
-Here I am!
-What code word did you use?
♫ Longing 202
♫ Longing, longing, longing
♫ Longing 202 (continued)
♫ Longing 202
..letting you know,
with our best wishes,...
...that we unfortunately have to...
...refuse your kind of...
Hello there! Where are you coming from?
Late again!
I'm sorry, Mr. Hesse. I've become a father.
-That's just like you.
-Yes, the child looks a lot like me.
-Always you, always you!
-This was my first child!
Off to your desk. Get to work!
Longing 2... Longing 202?
♫ Longing 202
Longing 202?
-You there! What did you say just now?
-What do you want from me?
You just talked to my wife!
-I talked to my wife?
-No, my wife!
To your wife! Oh, that changes things.
To your wife I didn't talk. No...
He's crazy.
Longing... longing... longing 202?
-Good morning.
Say, my advertisement wasn't published.
That's not possible.
Which code word did you use?
-"Longing 202"
-Longing 20...
But I did this my...
One moment, I'll look it up.
I'm sure, I... Oh yes, here it is.
There's even a reply!
There is? Thank you very much,
I must have overlooked it.
-I'm sorry, have a nice day.
-Have a nice day.
"Honorable lady,"
"we would be happy if you would contact us
immediately after receiving this letter."
"Yours truly, Florida."
-Splitter!
-Yes?
What have you done with the register?
It won't open.
-What do you mean?
-What did you do with it?
Let me look at it.
I don't get it.
Hasn't been used in a while.
Rusty... Here we go!
That's the telephone.
-Hello there?
-Do I speak with Florida?
"Longing 202" speaking.
202? Sorry, wrong number. This is B410205.
What's this with your longing?
Where do you live?
-Whom are you talking to?
-She says, she's longing...
You must be crazy. She's worth a million.
No, not a million. 202, she says.
Hello, this is Florida. Yes, in person.
If you can come over, you ask? Of course,
we already long for you.
202...
Splitter... Milady, hello?
Your connection has been discontinued.
But Mrs., we want to pay...
I'm sorry, I have to interrupt you.
-You'll have the money tomorrow.
-As if.
Hello, I'm cutting the line.
Now our phone is discontinued.
Longing 202?
-Longing 202?
-No. Gardening Street 32.
Who would've thought.
-My advertisement wasn't published.
-What's the code word?
-"It only happens once."
-Just a moment, I'll check.
I sure hope so.
♫ Longing 202
-What do you want?
-Dear Mrs., don't you recognize me?
-No, I don't!
-Naturally. We've never met before!
That's easy to change, though.
I'm a gentleman and this is...
...an inexcusable mistake. We're sorry.
Of course we'll make up for it immediately.
-"It only happens once", right?
-I sure hope so. See you.
I sure hope to see you again. One moment...
Mrs., please excuse me.
You're expecting a letter?
What a shame. If I had known this,
I would've written you one.
Or two, or three,
makes no difference to me.
Say, do you always talk so much trash?
No, only when I'm in a good mood.
So you're in an especially good mood today.
What a girl!
♫ Longing 202
-Maybe a customer?
-You must be seeing ghosts.
No no, she's coming!
-Hello, my lady.
-How can I be of service?
Here, I'm "Longing 202".
You are... Ms., I'm happy to...
-Not Ms., Mrs.
-Of course.
Please come in. This way.
So, Mrs., I hope you like it here.
-I do.
-Soon you'll like it even better.
Do you think I have a chance?
We're already waiting for you!
Hopefully the boss does, too.
That you can take for granted.
-I can?
-You can.
Can I talk to him now?
-You're talking to him already. Here he is.
-You?
-Yes I am.
-I'm very sorry, please excuse...
Just take a seat, it's alright.
Say, why are you following me?
If you tell me where you're heading,
I'll lead the way.
-What do you want from me?
-A good day. No?
Mrs., you're a model, aren't you?
-Me? Why?
-The way you dress.
Now, enough with this following business.
I think so, too. If this doesn't stop,
we'll soon be in Schönbrunn.
Mrs., a single word
and I'm gone in a second.
-So, what is it?
-When will I see you again?
-Never!
-Can't you give me a more precise date?
That's precise enough, isn't it?
It isn't.
Mrs., I have to ask you something.
Mrs., why all this chasing around?
♫ Even if you're moving too fast
even if I'm not catching up
♫ Your perfume is ecstasy for my nose
♫ As long as this is the case
you're with me, even when far away
♫ My dearest I'm in love with your perfume
♫ Because it puts me in the right mood
♫ I don't know what it is,
I only realize
♫ There's something, there's something,
there's something
♫ My dearest, I'm so fond of your perfume
♫ It brings us together,
even when you're far away
♫ It smells of kisses that only happen once
♫ I'm in love with your perfume
♫ My dearest I'm in love with your perfume
♫ Because it puts me in the right mood
♫ I don't know what it is,
I only realize
Taxi!
♫ There's something, there's something,
there's something
I won't let you leave until you tell me
if you're coming.
-Yes or no.
-Maybe.
She's coming.
♫ It smells of kisses that only happen once
Tonight at the Cobenzl!
♫ I'm in love with your perfume
Please come in.
Well, it's settled!
It is? That makes me very happy!
Me too!
We too!
It's just... things are moving so fast!
All of a sudden!
I'd like to tell my mother.
May I use the phone?
-Well...
-Of course! Over here! There's the phone!
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Hello? Hello?
No one's on the line.
Oh yes, naturally.
-What do you mean?
-Let me for a minute, I'll deal with it.
Hello... Hello!... I don't get it.
HOME
OPERATOR
What's that?
-Slow line.
-Slow line? Oh, now I get it.
The slow line is busy,
I'll transfer to the short one.
Hello? Hello!
-Operator speaking.
-Mrs., please put me through to 30206.
30206. In a moment.
-Hello mother?
-Hello, Fischer and Weber speaking.
-Whom am I speaking to?
-Fischer and Weber.
Wrong number. Please hang up.
Goddamn it!
-Mrs., I got the wrong number.
-I'm sorry, won't happen again.
-30206, if I may.
-30206. In a moment.
The line is busy.
What's this?
Have you gone mad?
What's with the lad out there?
He must be off his rockers.
I can't get a connection.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm Wiesinger.
Say, I went to the advertisement agency.
That goldfish also swam away.
It's over, we're finished.
May I introduce: Miss Longing.
-Wait... You're Longing...?
-...202!
That's... That's marvelous.
That's wonderful.
-Get a chair for the lady.
-Will do.
May I offer a lemonade... a lemon...
a cold glass of water...
-No, thank you.
-At least take a seat.
That's amazing.
-So everything's settled?
-So far yes. About the specifics...
Yes, about the salary.
-What sal...
-About the salary, naturally.
Of course, the salary is important for you.
-It is.
-Of course.
Well, what were you thinking of?
I thought... maybe... 100.
-100
-50... Maybe 150!
150! This we can do, can we?
-Granted!
-Yes, yes...
And while you're in a good mood,
I've got another request.
Another request? Granted, too!
We're very generous.
Can I have one month's pay in advance?
-A... Advance?
-Gra... Granted, of course.
He's the one granting the advances.
-Splitter!
-Yes?
Take the lady to the office
and show her the rooms.
We'll take care of the advance later on,
of course.
Out of the way. May I?
I'm sure you'll like it here.
Did I do well with the phone?
-Splitter!
-Yes?
-Come on!
-Oh yes...
Behave yourself.
No ring ring and stuff like that.
Say, moron,
you're promising her 150 schillings?
-What do you call me? A moron?
-Yes I do.
-What are you, then?
-Your partner.
You almost blew it right no. Super-moron!
-Beautiful rooms.
-Yes, they are.
-I like it very much.
-Glad to hear.
I don't get it. What does she need 150
schillings, being a millionaire's daughter?
That's just her quirk. One flies over the
ocean, the other collects Maybugs...
So what will she do in December?
And this one wants to earn her own money.
And so she should! But not our money!
Say, is it always that quiet here?
Yes... yes, how could you think that...
Sometimes... it's slower... sometimes not
that much... sometimes not at all...
But that doesn't mean anything,
it's just because...
...because... today is Friday, the 13th!
-Is that so?
-Oh yes, people are superstitious.
On some Fridays I...
almost look forward to Sundays.
So how can we get hold of 150 schillings?
Do you know what we've sold
since yesterday? A toothbrush!
In installments.
And you want 150... Ridiculous!
Say, Bobby, come here.
-I've got an idea.
-Unbelievable!
-But don't get mad.
-On the contrary. A rare occasion anyway.
So what is it?
I... I want to sell the ring.
This ring? That I gave to you as a present?
You should be ashamed.
My friend, beggars can't be choosers.
That's just a phrase.
You can't sell the ring.
And where can we find the money?
I don't care. This ring you can't sell.
-I have to.
-No you don't.
-I will.
-You won't. I forbid it.
-And why?
-Because... it's a forged rock.
To make it short: a solid business.
I can see that. So this is the register?
That's the register, but it doesn't work.
Out of order.
But here you have the list, for comparison.
In line one there's Eau de Cologne,
in line two there's lavender...
-You there!
-One moment!
And in line three there's red...
-Oh, hello!
-Where are the bosses?
My bosses? In there. But they can't be
disturbed right now. An important meeting.
-I have to talk to them.
-Think about it, won't you...
Not when money is involved.
Be reasonable, you can't barge in like...
-Who was that?
-Him? He's a money man.
He wants to force his capital on us.
But we don't need it.
I you won't pay this minute,
I'll tear down the building today.
-That's unpleasant, isn't it Harry?
-I'll say.
Then I guess we'll have to... well...
Dear Property manager, can I offer a pawn?
-A pawn?
-Yes, a souvenir, from a true friend.
All right. But if you won't pay tomorrow,
your ring is gone.
Well... well, what can we do.
-Bye.
-Go with god.
Don't you pout.
I'll return exactly the same ring to you.
-See you!
One moment, please.
A forged ring can be useful, too.
So what's going on?
Are we out on the street.
-For now we're fine.
-Thank god.
If only we had money for the advance.
-An advance? For me?
-For you? For the girl, of course.
-For the millionairess!
-Advance...
What's going on, what's going on.
Who do you think you are?
-Paul!
-Magda!
-Paul, listen, I got the job!
-How wonderful.
-So what is it you will be doing?
-I'll be a salesgirl.
-I'll be your first customer, then.
-You are?
I need a dozen razor blades for my boss.
Marvelous, I'll get them for you.
Follow me.
Here are the razor blades.
-But this is a pack of 120!
-Doesn't matter. They're always useful.
-Maybe a cream?
-For my shoes?
No, for your face. Smell this! Nice cream.
You won't find anything here.
What's this?
-Nothing, unfortunately.
-I thought so.
160 schillings altogether.
160 schillings! That's something else.
For this kind of money,
I should've bought a new tire.
This here is much more important.
-One moment!
-What is it?
Ms. Wurmser owes 300 schillings
since three months ago.
-This is it!
-No it ain't!
I already collected
the 300 schillings myself.
-And where are they now?
-Here.
-Very nice.
-Isn't it?
-What's that? How dare you...
There's only one thing left to do.
One of us has to go out and tell her
that we don't pay advances on principle.
Very well. I'm going out and you tell her.
Too bad about Ms. Wurmser.
Say, where should I put the money?
The register doesn't work.
-Where does this money come from?
-I collected it.
-How did you collect it?
-For the merchandise I sold.
-Someone bought something from us?
-Naturally.
It's not all that natural...
Mrs., we're very sorry,
your advance can't...
...be held back any longer.
150 schillings, wasn't it?
-Yes.
-Of course we'll have to subtract the tax.
-Splitter!
-Yes?
-Hand over the tax table.
-The tax table.
-We have to, unfortunately...
So that makes... No! That's the one from
yesterday, it's no longer valid today.
Sorry, my mistake.
Not your first one.
Tax on income, unemployment, bachelorhood,
crisis, salary, insurance, labor, welfare.
Altogether that makes...
We'll come out just about even in the end.
-You can't do that.
-Why not? She's got millions.
So, 150 schillings, right?
Here you go, tax-free.
Thanks a million. Thanks.
She really took it.
Well, still 10 schillings left.
For my partner... net gain.
A gentleman from head to toe.
1,2,3,4,5,6,7 This one is old, but rich.
1,2,3,4,5,6,7 king of spades,
jack of spaces, ace of spades.
Three black ones... A negro?
No, auntie, he isn't a negro. He isn't old,
either. Aside from that, you got it.
If you don't pay, I will cut the light.
-You simply can't to that.
-Oh, it's very simple.
The display window needs much more light.
More light? Only recently,
we installed marvelous effect lighting.
-You did?
-Effect lighting! Look for yourself.
I don't get it. What's going on?
My friend, think it over. There's a
millionairess sitting outside.
-So make her pay!
-She's not supposed to know!
-By the way, how much is the bill?
-80 schillings.
80 schillings. Well, turn on the light for
a moment so that I can have a look.
Will do.
-Strange.
-Indeed.
Forget it.
Maybe... for now... 5... schillings... OK?
Are you joking? That won't do, no deal.
Just as a down payment, you...
No no no, I can't wait any longer,
I'll cut it again.
And then there was light.
I just moved my hand like this.
That's the end of it. Good night!
What's going on?
Who's horsing around with the light?
What do you think? The light has been cut,
because of 80 schillings.
80 schillings? I got it right here.
Turn on the light for a minute.
If you insist. One last time.
-Did you see this?
-Yes, I did.
Suddenly it was dark again.
I just did this...
I left my coat upstairs. But do return
tomorrow, then I'll have it down here.
-Are you trying to make a fool of me?
-I swear, I'll have it down here!
I'm cutting it now. And that's that.
-Did you see this?
-Of course. I don't understand.
Me neither. I got to have a secret power.
Every time I'm doing this...
-Did you see?
-No, I don't see anything.
-Closing time!
-So early?
There's a short-circuit,
so we're closing up.
-Got it.
-No, not a short-circuit. It was me!
-If you allow, I'll walk you out.
-Thank you very much. Good evening!
-See you.
-Boss, it was me!
-What do you mean?
-One moment!
-What's with you?
I got it. If you insist.
Not like that. I'm talking about the
short-circuit. That was me!
-That was the electricity guy.
-What are you talking about?
The electricity guy switched the
light on and...
For heaven's sake!
So that's why. Now I'm beginning to see.
-Good evening!
-How nice to meet you! Good evening!
I'm Wiesinger. And you must be the mother.
The similarity is right there.
-This is my aunt.
-You're aunt! I... couldn't have known.
Nice of you to join us. This way, please!
♫ The sky over Vienna
♫ Is twice as nice as anywhere else
♫ Because the whole year long
♫ The sky is full of violins
♫ A Viennese likes to look
♫ At the stars
♫ While thinking longingly
♫ About his sweet, blonde girl
♫ The sky over Vienna
♫ Is twice as nice as anywhere else
♫ Especially while kissing
♫ During a spring night
-Can I get you anything to eat?
-No, thanks!
-No, thanks. Get us three Whiskey Soda.
-No, Whiskey I don't like.
-Then bring two.
-Two.
I don't get why a young, pretty girl
like you is out of a job.
Why... no... not at all...
you know, my boss...
Of course, the boss. It's always like this.
As soon as a boss has a pretty worker,
he's starting to work on her himself.
No? All right, something different, then.
Miss, have you been an aunt for long?
-What are you saying?
-I mean, since when you work in the shop?
Yes, yes, a long time.
You know, my aunt is the manager.
Oh, that's fine. You can dress nice and
otherwise you only have to...
...be attentive.
And when is your holiday?
Good evening! Mother?
-Mother?
-What is it?
Oh, there you are. Mother!
-Finally you're here. Where have you been?
-In the office!
I got a job now! Look at this!
-A rose for the rose.
-Gee, thanks.
Brand new. And what is this?
A Marguerite.
-What would be your given name?
-Helene.
Then this won't work out. Thanks.
-I... What do you want?
-Two schillings, please.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Thanks a lot.
What a wonderful fragrance.
This is something we humans can't emulate.
-Well...
-Believe me, I'm an expert.
-I know every perfume.
-Do you?
-Yes, indeed.
-Well, how about this, for example?
-"Black Narcissus"
-That's correct!
-Am I right?
-Yes, you are.
-And this?
-"Stone-age Lavender"
I am, in a way,
half of a boss of a perfume factory.
-Half of?
-Yes, the other half sits at home.
We used to have a third partner. We had the
money and he had the experience.
No he has the money
and we have the experience.
-Telephone for the lady.
-I'll come.
-Aunt, may I take this for you?
-No no, thanks. Please excuse me.
A marvelous invention, this telephone.
Or do you feel awkward now that auntie
has left us alone?
Look, the Kahlenberg. Beautiful, that line
drawn across the sky.
Yes, what a line.
-And the Ferris wheel over there!
-Adorable!
-And the St. Stephen's Cathedral!
-Just wonderful.
And this flame over there,
is this the Ring (street in Vienna)?
Yes, the ring.
-You're not even looking!
-Believe me, I see everything.
♫ The sky over Vienna
♫ Is twice as nice as anywhere else
♫ Because the whole year long
♫ The sky is full of violins
♫ A Viennese likes to look
♫ At the stars
♫ While thinking longingly
♫ About his sweet, blonde girl
♫ Thinking of red, hot lips
♫ In the blue, tender night
♫ Because the longing only really
comes alive
♫ At nighttime
♫ The sky over Vienna
♫ Is twice as nice as anywhere else
♫ Especially while kissing
♫ During a spring night
Kitty!
Auntie!
Bad timing!
-Kitty!
-What is it?
We have to return home right now.
Nina called, John is sick. He's got fever.
My best wishes for your husband,
whom I don't know.
-But John is my dog!
-I'm sorry. I thought the uncle... father.
Would you be so kind to drive us home
with your car?
-Oh yes, please!
-With my car? Why? I don't...
Of course, I'd love to. I don't know
if there's enough gas...
-Fill it up, then!
-I'll fill it up! Fill do!
Check please!
Right here.
Bobby! How are you?
How nice! Been a while!
Very nice.
May I introduce...
Mr. Riesinger.
My cousin.
-She's your cousin?
-Yes, my cousin.
She was my cousin once, too.
-Good evening!
-Likewise!
-Waiter!
-Yes, Sir?
Do you see the bald gentleman over there,
next to the blonde lady?
-Yes, I do.
-Hand him this note.
In four minutes. Not sooner and not later.
Right on the dot.
-In four minutes.
-Correct.
-Do you have a watch with you?
-Yes.
Fine.
Ladies, everything is settled. Now we have
to hurry, otherwise the gas won't hold.
-Bubi, please!
-Don't talk to me!
-It was just a joke!
-A joke? How funny!
-And what do you want?
-One moment.
Here you go, my lady.
It's more comfortable in the back.
-I'll sit next to you.
-Do that.
57, 58, 59, 60.
-Here you go!
-What does this mean?
The gentleman who just left handed
me this note for you.
-For me?
-Yes, here you go.
"I couldn't resist the temptation to try
out your car."
"I'll leave it corner Mary Street and
New Street."
"Thanks very much, and best wishes to our
mutual cousin."
That beats everything!
-Good morning!
-Well, so early?
-What do you mean, early? It's almost 8.
You need to put
a bit more imagination into all of this.
Imagination!
Can't help it if I haven't got one.
Invisible advertisement
isn't worth anything.
That's what I mean.
Here, in the shop window,
we must make changes.
-Something that catches the eye.
-Exactly.
-Do you think I could give it a try?
-Of course, you can do anything you want.
Perfect.
Say, is there anything special
the bosses are interested in?
They are only interested
in being left alone.
Ridiculous.
-Bobby!
-What is it?
-Telephone!
-What?
-Oh, I thought this was the alarm clock.
Hello, what...
That's ridiculous.
In the middle of the night!
Hello.
-Who was it?
-The super.
He's persistent, isn't he?
-Talk to him already.
-No, I just did. Now it's your turn.
If you insist.
Hello? This isn't possible!
We're talking about an heirloom...
Well, can't help it, then.
-So what is it?
-Your precious ring, of course.
Oh, he already found out. And now?
Eviction.
-Really?
-Yes!
What can we do?
-The bottles, please.
-Here you go.
-Beautiful.
-Isn't it?
-And the fan.
-Fan?
Why do you need a fan?
-For the burning question.
-Why?
Oh, now I get it.
You really are very skillful.
My friend, there's only one hope left.
You have to borrow from the millionairess.
-Me? Not a chance.
-Why did we hire her?
Why do I have to do everything
all the time?
Because you are more handsome. Yes, you
look like a film star.
Your charm, your sex appeal, the blank
expression of your eyes, so...
Harry, be reasonable. It's a dire
situation. Get dressed, will you!
-Finished?
-Yes, in a moment.
-Please turn on the fan now.
-The fan, will do.
-Thank you.
-The ribbon isn't in place. To the right!
To the left, from your point of view.
-Thank you. Now bring me a nail, please.
-A nail? A big one or a small one?
-Done! Now what do you think?
-Marvelous!
BLIND
Look at this! I'll have a closer look.
DEAF
-How original!
-Excellent advertisement!
-Is this fine?
-Beautiful, indeed.
-Now, please help me down.
-Just take my hand.
PLEASE COME IN. WE CAN'T PRESENT
EVERYTHING IN THE SHOP WINDOW.
Look at this!
A tiny bit of packaging goes a long way.
Marvelous.
Excuse me, please let me through.
One moment, please.
-Good morning, Sir.
-Good morning, Miss.
-I came in.
-How nice of you.
-What can I show you?
-What I couldn't see in the window.
One moment.
Good morning, Sir. What can I show you?
You? Nothing!
The young lady on the other hand...
-Hello, Miss.
-Hello, Sir.
I came in... I'd like to, I saw in the...
Please, gentlemen! Not all at once!
-Good morning!
-What do these people want?
-Tell them we pay on Sunday.
-But those are customers!
-Customers?
-Of course.
-Good morning.
-These really are customers?
-Of course.
-Where do they come from?
-The new girl rearranged the shop window.
What a pleasant thing to hear.
Four bottles of eau de cologne, please.
-Four bottles eau de cologne.
-That's the phone bill, right there.
-Five bottles lavender.
-And there's the light bill.
Marvelous. Tell her to see us in the office
for a moment.
-She's with a customer right now.
-Then you will cover for her.
-I don't know. That one guy didn't like me.
-I can relate.
One moment, one moment.
We'll make sure to deliver all of this.
-In person?
-You can bet on that.
-See you later, then.
-See you later.
One moment, now it's my turn.
Miss, out there, in the show window...
Sorry, the bosses want you in the office.
-But I'm with customers!
-I'll cover for you.
-One moment, please.
-Miss, please stay!
-Sir how can I help you?
-You can't, I already told you that.
Disgusting evasiveness. Goodbye.
-See you.
-I knew he doesn't like me.
-Good morning!
-You want to talk to me?
-My partner needs to tell you something.
-Correct?
-Yes, correct, I...
...he's a bit shy. I hope you understand.
Won't you take a seat?
-It's just...
-Now he can talk more freely. Am I right?
Well?
Well... I... I'm supposed to...
-I'd like to ask you something.
-Go on!
I wanted to tell you something
that is very close to my heart.
-But we just met.
-Yes.
-Two days ago.
-I said that, too.
My partner talked me into it, though.
-Talked you into it?
-Yes, because I was afraid to tell you.
To be honest, I'm afraid even now.
I think I already know.
Really? Thank heavens, that's a relief.
-So... can I hope?
-I have to talk to my mother, first.
Do that! When can I expect an answer?
-Is it that urgent?
-Yes, very urgent.
Maybe I'll see you tonight? I'll call you.
-Deal?
-Deal!
-You really are charming. Thanks a lot!
-You're welcome.
Miss, if you allow, might I ask
for an advance right now?
Splitter, Splitter... I'm so happy!
-What's that?
-Me... I...
What's going on? Did you talk to her?
-Yes.
-And did she give you something?
-Yes, a kiss.
-What are you saying?
You know, I think I proposed to her.
-You were supposed to ask for a loan.
-I did. But she misunderstood.
-And now?
-And now we go on a date.
How nice. You'll tell her then.
And no misunderstandings this time.
-Nothing doing?
-Sorry?
-Now that I know that she loves me I can't.
-Is that so? I'll tell her, then.
-Hey, hey, I forbid it!
-I'll do it anyway.
-I'll make sure you don't.
-No chance. Want to take a bet?
-We'll see.
-We'll see, exactly. We'll...
-Kitty!
-Bobby!
What brings you here?
I want to get to know you in your
field of action.
That's sweet of... Splitter, please
go and find out what time it is.
-It's nice here.
-It is? Do you like it?
Yes, indeed. So, what do you have on offer?
My lady, let's see. Our own make,
available in all sizes and prize levels.
Oh, how beautiful.
COURT OF EXECUTION, VIENNA
-This must be your trademark.
-Yes, our trademark.
What kind of funny animal is this?
-That's a vulture.
-A vulture?
Yes, there's one of them on all of our
bottles. How many do you want?
Not a single one. I came by to tell you I'm
free tonight and want to go out with you.
-Tonight won't do.
-Why not?
Tonight I'll have to take inventory.
I'll be busy all night.
I'm sorry about that, poor you.
I'll have to think of you all night, then.
-Kitty, you must change perfumes.
-Why?
That one's dangerous for me.
♫ My dearest I'm in love with your perfume
♫ Because it puts me in the right mood
♫ I don't know what it is,
I only realize
♫ There's something, there's something,
there's something
♫ My dearest, I'm so fond of your perfume
♫ It brings us together,
even when you're far away
♫ It smells of kisses that only happen once
♫ I'm in love with your perfume
I don't like you going out
with your boss at night.
But mother, if you only knew him.
He's so harmless.
Those are the worst, believe me, I know.
I can't go like this, anyway. My god,
nothing to wear.
What do you mean?
Your blue dress is very nice.
-No, I can't wear that.
-Why?
It's way too short.
Oh, I forgot. These days,
long dresses are in style again.
Wait a minute! I got an idea!
Well, what about this one?
-Isn't this grandma's ball dress?
-Yes, it is.
-And I'm supposed to wear it?
-It's all the rage now!
-But mother, that won't work.
-Wait and see!
Say Harry, where are you going to meet her?
So we won't end up at the same place.
-We're going to the Moulin Rouge.
-The Moulin Rouge, interesting. Have fun.
-One moment, did you hear that?
-What are you saying?
-Didn't you hear it?
-You and your jokes.
-There's something going on in there.
-Then take a look!
-I'm afraid.
-What a hero.
You go. You're the stronger one.
So, who did win the bet?
I was never smarter. And now I'm going to
get money from the millionairess.
Do not get bored in the meantime.
Open up, scoundrel!
Don't forget to bring out the shoes.
-Well, isn't this lovely?
-Yes, very modern.
And at the same time,
just like in the olden days.
That dress!
I've rarely seen anything so sweet.
-Do you really like it?
-All I can say is: cheers!
Waiter!
-Won't you tell me already about...
-...the waiter? He'll be here in a moment.
-No, I...
-Yes, he will. Just a little...
I'm talking about your partner!
Oh, you're talking about Harry. Well, as
I told you, he is indisposed,
and he asked me to fill in for him,
as far as...
Are you saying he won't show up at all?
He will!
As soon as he manages to free himself up.
Are you that unhappy about the substitute?
-You aren't? Well then, cheers!
-Cheers!
-My friend Harry talked to you today.
-Yes, he did.
-And while doing so, he...
-No he didn't, that's the thing. It was...
-I'm sorry.
-What's that?
-May I?
-Please excuse me.
-Well, that...
-One moment, how much are these liqueurs?
-4 schillings.
-Both of them?
-8 schillings.
Then bring me... one more.
♫ My dearest I'm in love with your perfume
♫ Because it puts me in the right mood
Auntie, I don't get it.
Why shouldn't I call him?
-Because it is not proper.
-Why not? The poor guy's taking inventory.
♫ My dearest, I'm so fond of your perfume
♫ It brings us together,
even when you're far away
♫ It smells of kisses that...
-I am going to call him!
-Kitty!
Yes, I'm calling him.
-Hello! Help!
-What? What happened?
-Help! The rascal locked me in!
-I'll call the police immediately!
♫ My dearest I'm in love with your perfume
♫ Because it puts me in the right mood
♫ I don't know what it is,
I only realize
♫ There's something, there's something,
there's something
You left me here... Terrible, that noise!
-By the way, we were interrupted.
-Yes, we were.
-What is it you wanted to say?
-I... Impossible with this music.
It's about... Thank heavens!
It's about making a dream come...
Here we go again.
It's about making a dream come true.
-May I have this dance?
-I don't know.
I beg you. You can't deny me this waltz.
Ain't I right, Sir?
-Please excuse me.
-Thank you.
-I'm sorry... Hey there, you!
-What do you want?
-All this dance music all the time!
-Of course, this is a dance bar.
-The orchestra plays whatever one wants?
-Yes, why not?
Then tell them to play rummy for a while.
Hello! Is anybody here?
Look over there. Someone's knocking.
Turn on the light!
-Hands in the air!
-I beg your pardon?
-But I'm the owner!
-Anyone could say that.
-Good evening.
Good evening. My good friend,
am I the owner or ain't I?
-Does he tell the truth?
-Of course.
-Why didn't you say so earlier?
-Earlier? I couldn't get a word in!
And what are you doing in there?
Who locked you in?
My partner played a stupid joke on me.
Unbelievable! Calling the cops for that?
I could've died of hunger in there.
Maybe that's what you...
-Where's Bobby?
-And who are you?
-I called here just now.
-So you were the one setting me free!
So where is Bobby? What did you do to him?
I to him? He to me! He locked me in!
Unbelievable. Let me tell you something.
I'll report you for
deceiving the authorities. On with it!
-Now you see what my partner is up to.
-Your partner? He's your partner?
-Of course!
-He told me he'd be working here all night.
Working my ass. He's at the Moulin Rouge,
with my girl.
Enough dancing already. Now we need to
have a talk before the music starts again.
-I... My friend thinks, in our business...
-May I?
Excuse me, may I?
Finally, he's left. So, my friend thinks,
we need a woman in our business.
-Do you want to be a boss at our firm?
-Me?
He told you lots of silly stuff, probably.
But the gist of it, the transaction...
-...he doesn't know anything about that.
-But I'm no transaction.
Well, to me, a few 100.000s schillings
feels like business.
It's not a lot, but we'll take it.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about the money you might...
would invest in our business. Charmingly...
Me? But I don't have any money.
That's something else.
A millionairess and no money?
Millionairess? But I'm no millionairess!
-But you advertised!
-Not that I'm a millionairess!
Don't fool around! Are you Longing 202
or aren't you Longing 202?
-Of course I'm Longing 202!
-I knew it. Here, read this.
"Lady worth millions..."
-Unbelievable! That's a terrible mistake!
-What do you mean?
-I never advertised this!
-Oh my... You don't have any money?
-No!
-Mrs., you are a swindler!
-How dare you!
-Stay on your seat, don't make a scene!
Now I get it. That's why you hired me.
And that's why you were so nice to me!
And that's why your friend asked me out!
-What a nerve!
-She must be jealous.
-Shame on you!
-What's going on?
-Leave me be!
-Magda!
Here he is, the scoundrel! Making a date
with me and going out with another girl.
-Why are you here, Kitty?
-Why am I here? For this!
Thanks a lot.
Well hello Harry! How did you escape?
You're the most insolent guy I ever met.
-You've got me into trouble again.
-Me?
-We'll talk about it at home. Just wait.
-Forget it, we're no longer friends.
-From now on you mean nothing to me.
-That's right.
You're mean less than nothing to me.
Vacuum, negative space, black hole.
What's that? Heavens, now it starts...
♫ The sky over Vienna
♫ Is twice as nice as anywhere else
♫ Because the whole year long
♫ The sky is full of clouds
♫ A Viennese looks at stars
from the office
♫ While thinking about all the
unpaid debts
Splitter, stop the singing!
That's terrible!
-Splitter, please continue. Beautiful!
-Thank you.
-If you, by chance, meet my partner...
-But he's over there!
One moment. If you, by chance, meet my
partner, then tell him,
that I went to the
Hesse advertisement agency...
One moment, stay here. ...Went there to
put up my share of the business for sale.
-Why are you still here? Go!
-Yes.
-I'm supposed to tell you...
-Silence! Silence!
Tell my inept partner that I'll sell
my shares, too. Go on, tell him!
Later. Tell this business moron that
I'm finished with him once and for all.
Tell this dubious character I'll be happy
to never see him again. Tell him!
-Never see him...
-Tell him that...
-Stay here!
-Stay here.
Splitter, over here!
You were supposed to say...
-Tell him nothing, nothing left to tell.
-I think so, too.
-Tell this bleak idiot.
-You're a bleak idiot.
-Have you gone mad? How dare you?
-But he said...
What do you mean, I said? I meant...
-Why don't you listen?
-What insolence!
-Always the same trouble with you!
-That's right!
-All these years!
-Right!
Rascal! Harry, come with me.
♫ A Viennese looks at stars
from the office, desperately
-What do you want?
-Nothing from you.
-I get it.
-I want to talk to that girl.
-You have to go to her apartment for that.
-Why her apartment? Isn't she here anymore?
She's gone, my bosses are gone,
the business is gone, I am gone.
TEMPORARY CLOSED DUE TO ILLNESS
OF BUSINESS
But why? Who is to blame?
♫ Advertising, advertising!
Brings everything out into the open!
♫ You only risk a single line and
after a while you get what you need
♫ Young girl, used to hardships,
looking for a job, as soon as possible
♫ Boss looking for help, might be poor
but rich in grace
♫ He who doesn't hope for millions
might write to me
♫ As soon as possible, write to:
Double Longing...
♫ 404
♫ Advertising, advertising!
Brings everything out into the open!
♫ You only risk a single line and
after a while you get what you need
♫ Young man hopes for a sign of life
by way of advertising
♫ From the lady who slapped him
violently yesterday
♫ Deeply embarrassed young lady who is
very fond of said young man
♫ Writes to: Two Hearts...
♫ ...and a slap
♫ Advertising, advertising!
MARRIAGE
♫ If couples end up together despite the
mix-up, the advertisement was worth it
♫ Advertising, advertising!
Brings everything out into the open!
THE END