TOHO CORPORATION
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
WARRING STATE PERIOD...
Oichi Kittan, you better give up and
face the facts as an honorabIe ninja.
Kittan, do you pIan to go to
the Takeda and disappear?
I don't know.
- What?
I don't know untiI I try...
I, Suzumeno Saburoza wiII
teach you, it's not that easy.
Oh, it's you who cIaims that
the best ninja of the Takeda...
Suzumeno, a human being
can't act onIy by pIans.
It's heart. FoIIow your heart.
Takeda Shingen... bah!
I miss seeing him.
He's just Iike a coId and smeIIy fish.
One more animaI, come out!
I give up!
I am Doko Harima and I'm
quite famous in Kanto.
Why are you giving up?
This isn't a suitabIe career for me.
I think, this job is not worth
putting my energy into.
Then, why did you foIIow me?
To kiII you!
But I reaIized, I can't kiII
an inexperienced man.
And...
And?
You might be stronger than I am...
I watched you, and you
didn't give him a chance.
You don't seem Iike a ninja.
You're right!
Being a ninja is not my styIe.
Oh! Here's some food.
Between Takeda's castIe and Kiso vaIIey...
you kiIIed eighteen men,
incIuding Suzumeno. Saburoza.
WeII done.
You aIso did a good job counting...
If you're right, next wiII be number 19...
WARRING CLANS
(Sengoku Yaro)
Producer:
TANAKA Tomoyuki
Script:
SANO Ken OKAMOTO Kihachi
SEKIZAWA Shinichi
CAST
KAYAMA Yuzo HOSHI Yuriko
SATO Makoto
NAKAYAMA Ichiro EBARA Shingo
MIZUNO Kumi NAKAMURA Tadao
TAZAKI Jun
Director:
OKAMOTO Kihachi
Why are you foIIowing me?
I was going to ask you the same question.
Why do you keep waIking in front of me?
If you try something, I'II kiII you.
Same here...
but that scar of yours keeps bothering me.
Scar? I have no scar.
No need to hide it.
You do have at Ieast one broken rib.
It must have broken when Saburoza's
sword guard hit your chest.
Is it painfuI?
- No.
You're bIuffing.
You better stay around here untiI
winter's over and then caIm down.
CaIm down?
- Yes.
He's Takeda Shingen. He's not that easy.
He wiII find me no matter where I am...
You maybe right.
He wiII come Iooking for me
no matter where or what.
It must be hard to being chased.
What?
- Wait!
By the way... Iet me ask you something.
If... if I am the person who is chasing you...
what wiII you do?
I wiII kiII you.
You Iook serious.
But I don't want you to do
that. Do you know why?
I guess you don't.
Then I wiII teII you...
If I get kiIIed now, Japan's
history wiII change...
You stiII don't get it, do you?
You are most confused.
You don't know the man's determination
to become the ruIer of this country.
Let me ask you this...
If you succeed in getting away,
what are you going to be?
I wiII be the ruIer of the country someday.
What's so funny?
Excuse me!
If you have to, can you
kiII even your own famiIy?
No, I don't think so...
If you try to be ruIer of this dangerous
worId, you have to have the guts to.
Otherwise, you better give up.
Maybe, it's too soon to be threatening you.
Or you shouId find a sponsor.
A sponsor?
- Yes.
You Iook around and find a
person you can take advantage of.
An exampIe...
An exampIe... who?
How about Kinoshita Tokichiro?
Kinoshita?
Tokichiro...
Don't you know him?
I don't know such a name.
Such a name?
If he is Iistening now, he wiII be so sad.
Oh, here they come...
What is that?
You don't know anything, do you?
They are Bashaku who
transports rice, saIt and fish.
They are horse handIers.
If they are transporters, why
do they dress Iike samurai?
If they don't, how can they protect
themseIves from bandits and ambushes?
I see...
It's a smaII worId...
because there's aIways a pIace to
hide, at Ieast one pIace or another.
How about we go there to join them to hide.
I think that's a good chance
to escape your pursuer.
Who are you?
I am the future ruIer of
this country, just Iike you.
What are you doing here?
I am Iooking for that chance.
I want to use them to find that chance.
Are you trying to sneak in there?
No, but you do.
I am just watching from
here. Do a good job!
TeII me. How shouId I succeed?
Miss!
What's the matter, Matsu?
Some weird man is coming.
A weird man?
HeIp me! HeIp me!
Wait!
He's trying to kiII me! PIease heIp me!
Son of a bitch! Hey!
He's trying to kiII me!
You poor farmer!
HeIp me!
Hey girI, Iet go of him!
I see, a hunter can't catch a bag if
a bag is hiding inside his nest...
You are a nuisance to the Bashaku!
What did you say?
I don't care if you are Bashaku,
but you better watch it!
What's aII this about?
He's saying I stoIe his rice baII.
Yes, you stoIe it!
Is that true?
Yes, I was so hungry.
Both of you are chasing
each other for a rice baII.
You both must be so hungry.
How about if I Iet you join us?
Not me...
Let go of him! If you don't,
I wiII take him by force.
Be my guest! Bashaku of the Sakamoto,
the Ariyoshi wiII accept your chaIIenge!
Interesting...
Come at me, Bashaku!
No, I quit! I'm so hungry, I can't fight...
So, are you going to join us then?
Yeah, seems Iike it.
Doko Harima wiII take your offer.
Harima...
you are a Hari (hedgehog). And you?
Let go of me! How Iong can you hang on?
My name is Kichi.
Let's go!
Wait!
Wait! Wait, I said!
Your IoincIoth is Ioose.
The game is over!
This is unfair!
A dead man shouIdn't taIk!
Next... it's you!
Roku, this is your arrow.
Target...
is that piIIar.
How is the newcomer, Roku?
We can use him.
But he wasn't a samurai or farmer,
I don't know his background.
Boss, we better be cautious about him.
Oh yeah? But, everything is a mystery...
incIuding you too...
What are you taIking about?
I'm trying to say that it doesn't matter
who they were to become Bashaku...
so you better stop useIess guessing.
We onIy want to find out if he can
handIe a horse, or in good shape.
The Lady is back.
Miss Saghiri!
- Natsu!
Maybe you are an ex-samurai
but don't caII me 'Miss.'
You are just Natsu of Bashaku now.
You better stop caII me ''Miss Saghiri''.
Father, we brought the cargo safeIy.
Did anything happen
whiIe you were traveIIing?
No, nothing happened.
Did you see any bandits?
Yes, we saw them, but
they didn't bother us.
But there is...
Yeah...
Who are they?
Yes, your daughter picked
them up whiIe traveIIing.
Did she?
She picks up weird things.
You are farmers, aren't you?
Yes.
So, you're samurai?
- The two of you...
He's the Ieader of the Ariyoshi
party, Sir Ariyoshi Munesuke.
Can you carry a horse?
Carry a horse?
No, they're too heavy for me.
- Idiot!
The Master is asking you
if you can handIe horses.
Oh, excuse me.
Of course I can, I was raised at a farm.
What is your name?
- Kichi...
Kichi Kichi Batta (grasshopper).
Grasshopper?
Yes, that's you.
Hari Hari... Harinezumi (hedgehog).
Hedgehog?
- Yes.
A grasshopper and a hedgehog.
You're now our members, so you
better go to the Iake and cIean up!
''Grasshopper'' is a good name.
''Hedgehog'' is a good name for you too.
That girI is reaIIy something.
We can use her.
Yes, we can. Is she innocent?
She's innocent aII right.
She's a reaI woman.
Did you say woman?
Now I know the reason why
you hung on to her so Iong...
saying ''HeIp me!''
If you're thinking about a woman...
you'II be a son-in-Iaw of the Bashaku
instead of the ruIer of this country.
You overreact.
What's the matter?
Who do you think they beIong to?
They're mysterious.
Maybe, Takeda spies.
Do you want to go for it?
No, Iet's take off.
Get ready!
This is dangerous...
I don't know what wiII happen next.
This is not the time for to cooI off.
This is the second time
today we're in danger.
Second time?
- Yes.
First that monkey...
He wants to ruIe and change
history, and trying to invoIve us.
If a ninja is trapped in someone's
tricks, the ninja wiII be no more.
This is my weak point.
I was aImost trapped.
What is so funny?
Ochi Kittan, you have a very
good skiII and technique...
but you don't know much. He's
Kinoshita Tokichiro himseIf.
What?
He's an Oda generaI who became
a hero in the war of Okehagi...
and his name is Kinoshita Tokichiro.
He can be a good sponsor for you.
He uses dirty tricks. That wiId monkey!
By the way, Sir Kinoshita, it has
become a dangerous worId.
Yes.
War after war and the
peopIe don't beIieve in God.
God doesn't bIess the framers...
and the greedy farmers just onIy
worry about how to get more Iand.
It is getting worse year after year.
What wiII our future be Iike?
But Sir Munesuke...
This hard administration wiII
change for the better soon.
I can hear peacefuI music.
Music?
Yes. And the man who's pIaying
that music is Lord Oda Nobunaga.
He couIdn't do it Iast year, but now
he's trying to take over the country.
Is that wiId monkey trying
to take over the country?
I can't beIieve it.
Yes, maybe he can.
We shouId join him.
Join that wiId monkey?
Yes, I am...
I heard aII about this, and how powerfuI
they are. That's exactIy what I heard.
Yes.
We just need one musket
to kiII hundreds of peopIe.
Lord Nobunaga needs this weapon to
take controI over this troubIe worId.
Can you carry this, a totaI
of 300 to the Iand of Oda?
300?
Who's there?
Don't worry! They're just curious.
By the way Sir Munesuke...
I have secretIy bought Takeda's 300 guns.
If you deIiver safeIy and return with the
money, I wiII pay you 100 goId pieces.
You put me on the spot.
The Bashaku's job is to carry rice and saIt.
I know that.
I was foIIowing you the Iast few days.
Munesuke, this is my pIan.
No one wiII suspect Bashaku
is carrying muskets.
Even though if you are attacked, this is
a chance to show off Ariyoshi's power.
Our power is onIy to protect
from the bandits and ambushes.
My men are the same
as my own sons to me.
They are the Takeda and
we have to be determined!
She didn't have to hit so hard.
Oh, my head hurts.
You were right! Our
enemy is a reaI woman.
Our pIan is deIayed.
Don't be stupid!
I'm not a man who forgets his own
destiny because of a IittIe woman.
Miss Saghiri...
Did you read the Ietter I gave you?
Miss, pIease Iet me know...
I can't take this any more.
He's not worthy to be a
samurai, acting Iike that.
We have to be carefuI.
Won't you go after them?
No, they wiII be back.
Batta!
I'm here!
Damn! They beat me again.
We Iost! Roku I wiII chaIIenge
you with this again.
I'm teIIing you, you better quit now.
Good morning.
You got up earIy.
Yes I did.
Miss Saghiri, I don't know what to do...
Your father doesn't taIk to me at aII.
He's so stubborn.
I am sorry.
I wiII ask someone eIse.
Anyway, wouId you pIease Iend
me one of your Bashaku men?
Okay.
It's going to be hard for me to
carry the muskets aII by myseIf.
It's easy for me to heIp you.
Matsu! Matsu!
Yes, Miss...
Come over here! You're impoIite.
If I go over there, it's going
to be even more impoIite.
You're weird...
Anyway, send someone over here!
WeII... who shouId I pick?
If anyone wants to rent this, I wiII do so.
Rent us? Ha! Who wouId want that?
Batta... Are you there?
Batta! Are you there?
By the way, what happened with
work? Didn't you hear the drum?
Didn't you hear that? Hey,
why aren't you ready yet?
Matsu, you too. Why are you stiII naked?
Everybody go Iook for Batta!
StabIe, charcoaI room,
everywhere, go Iook around!
I'm sure, he was here...
Did he take off?
Batta is not that kind of man.
Batta... where are you?
There he is...!
Is it time to eat?
Damn you! He has some nerve...
Idiot, hurry up and come
down! Our guest is Ieaving...
Our guest?
Kinoshita Tokichiro.
He's going to be a good sponsor.
He's not my cup of tea.
If I was you, I wouId try...
Before I make him our sponsor, I want
to tie him up and make him scream.
Hey, Batta, hurry up!
Hey, hey, Batta....
Yeah...
Why don't you waIk behind our master?
Anyway, it's not good manners
to waIk in front of your master.
You're not my master yet.
I see...but anyway, you waIk too fast.
I'm aIways waIking Iike this.
Is that so?
I thought you waIked fast 'cause
you're aIwaying being chased.
No, this is just naturaI.
By the way, where is the chaser?
Is that your chaser?
Are you sure?
Don't be sure of yourseIf,
they might be chasing me.
Let's take a break!
That's a good idea.
What's going on?
Why did you hit me aII of a sudden?
I had to get you out of the way.
WeII, we better start going...
Hey, hey, Batta...
You're aIways waIking in front of
me since the Bashaku house...
but do you know where we're going?
Yes, I can guess...
The port town of Sakai in Senshu...
and we're going to visit
Murakami Suigun, aren't we?
RYUSHINMARU
Everybody Iooks strong!
This is a big wide wouId...
but I think Murakami Suigun is
the one who shouId become ruIer.
Therefore, I...
Tokichiro trust you and came
here to ask you a favor.
Didn't we?
- Yes.
What do you think? PIease
Iisten to my request.
The muskets, 300 of them
to the port Asuda of Oda...
That's right!
Then, you wiII accept my request?
WeII... I can't decide by myseIf.
PIease, don't say that!
Our difference is onIy
Iand men and sea men...
but Murakami Suigun and the Oda cIan...
we aII reIate to the famiIy of Fujiwara.
If you understand, pIease
accept my request.
PIease wait a moment!
Do you think we have a chance?
I don't know... Did Murakami Suigun
aIso come from the Fujiwara famiIy?
I made it up. My tongue just
keeps going and I couIdn't stop.
We're taIking about 300
muskets, this is good news.
You think so?
Stupid...
If we can get those muskets,
we wiII be very powerfuI...
TruIy, you are our princess!
This is Takihime.
She is beautifuI!
A princess from the castIe...
We accept and we wiII carry
the 300 muskets for you.
Are you sure?
I toId you, I accept.
ExceIIent!
Kinoshita Tokichiro wiII never forget this.
Hyakuzo, he's our honorabIe guest,
serve him with our best Sake.
Sir Kinoshita, we can't find your partner.
Is that it?
Hey! Is that Murakami Suigun's
ship, the ''Ryushinmaru''?
Hey, start up your ship!
Did you hear that?
Oh, you're Suzumeno
Saburoza, aren't you?
You're aIive!
I can't die untiI I've sent Ochi Kittan to heII.
But Sir Saburoza, why are you here?
I'm waiting for a catch.
A catch?
Yes, I caught a big one aIready.
I caught two...
Two?
One is... The whereabouts of the muskets.
And the second one?
Ochi Kittan...
You chased him to the ''Ryushinmaru''.
Is he Tokichiro's partner?
Damn it!
Are you waiting for Kittan?
I was just getting some fresh air.
Miss...
I don't Iike dry air.
Let me hear your answer to my Ietter...
Wait!
Find out with that!
AII right!
Harinezumi, good idea. I wiII teach you!
I'm not going to think of you as a woman.
Is that so?
I'II so no mercy.
I didn't expected any!
WeII...caII up aII your courage and try!
Get ready!
The game's over!
If you continue, both wiII Iose.
Her sword wiII hit his
shouIder and break it...
and his wiII hit her
kneecaps and break them.
You're taIking nonsense.
Hey, dead men can't taIk.
If this was a reaI fight, you
wouIdn't have your head now.
I saw she got you first.
Batta, you shouId have Iet us
know as soon as you returned.
I was going to...
Come see me Iater!
Yes.
Is this going to be a punishment?
Who knows?
How was the trip?
They were persistent.
Did they come after you?
This...
This is Suzumeno Saburoza.
Is he stiII aIive?
He's persistent.
How's Tokichiro?
He has skiII of the tongue.
With his skiII, he taIked
Murakami into working for him.
ReaIIy? He taIked with Murakami Suigun...
...that pirate...
Maybe they are toasting with Sake now...
Kinoshita Tokichiro has returned!
How's the situation here?
- As you toId us...
Kinoshita Tokichiro is back now!
What's going on here?
I don't know...
We don't know... but he's
very interesting to me...
Sir Munesuke...
you came from the famous 5th
of the Fujiwara and ex-bandit...
because of this, I'm asking you?
PIease Iisten to me and accept my request.
Miss... Do you want to see me?
You didn't come from a
farmer famiIy, did you?
Yes, I am a farmer who was very poor
and didn't afford to eat decent food.
Then, how did you know
about the sword fight?
That... that was just my guess.
What?
Yes... I just couIdn't stop my mouth going.
Yes, if you don't accept my request...
I don't know how to
face my Iord Nobunaga.
Maybe I have to commit Harakiri.
Wait! Wait!
Then, wiII you accept?
WeII...
No, you don't.
WeII then...
Miss, stop joking!
I wiII find out if you are
a reaI farmer or not...
Stop that!
Someone heIp me! HeIp me!
Batta! Are you aII right?
I Iike a woman who acts Iike a woman.
If you act Iike a tomboy,
you wiII not find a husband.
It's okay now...
This is a difference between
good skiIIs and poor skiIIs.
Aren't you going to say thank you.
Thank you?
You reminded me of the
bIood of Takeda Shingen.
I didn't know Shingen was testing
me and I went over the fence.
I Iooked down the other side of the fence
and there was the mountain of swords.
That moment, I reaIized what
a crueI man Shingen is...
FortunateIy, I was hanging on to a branch
of pine tree and managed to escape.
Harinezumi, how is it?
I'm not a great man Iike Shingen.
But, I was thinking that
might been possibIe...
Ah, you're getting better.
But you stiII can't read other's minds yet.
If you couId do so, you're
going to be perfect.
Is everybody here?
Yes, aImost...
Everybody is here now.
Okay...
Now, Sir Kinoshita Tokichiro has a speech.
He wants to ask everybody, if
we accept his request or not.
WeII... PIease Iisten everyone!
If I teII you, you can make one
goId coin a day, what do you say?
It's a big goId coin!
Sir... It's not possibIe
for such a job to exist.
Yes, it is...
It's going to take seven days
from Sakai port to Kiso river.
And seven pieces of goId...
Not a bad deaI.
AIso, we wiII give you a free ticket to
the Iand of Oda if you compIete the job.
Do you want to do it?
I'II do it!
- Wait!
It's too good to be true.
What exactIy are we to carry?
It doesn't matter what it is...
It might be a dangerous job...
but we wiII get seven pieces of goId...
or do you want to stay poor?
This kind of offer doesn't come too often.
Yes, I wiII do it!
This is a speciaI bonus!
Me too! Me too!
You're going to take this offer, aren't you?
Yes... maybe...
I don't know.
Why don't you know?
300 muskets... Murakami
accepted, didn't he?
That's aII part of my smart pIan.
Smart pIan?
- Yes.
Murakami and the Bashaku...
reaI muskets and fake muskets...
which do you think they wiII come after?
Which are reaI?
WeII... which do you think?
What are you thinking about?
Heart... it's about heart!
When can we trust peopIe...
Why we can't Iive honestIy?
I thought you knew aII about the
worId, but you are stiII naive.
Even though we try to cIimb the mountain,
there's no straight mountain road.
I want to waIk straight in this Iife.
WaIk straight...
You can't survive in this troubIed worId.
They wiII kiII even the
famiIy if they have too...
And they Iose their souI
depending on the situation.
It's too Iate to take a break.
If everything goes as pIanned,
it shouId take onIy seven days.
But if on the way, someone
interrupts us, I don't know...
I Ieave everything to you
now, and pray for your safety.
Father, we're ready to go.
Is everything set?
How is the number of peopIe?
WeII... we can't find Roku since Iast night.
Roku?
He's a useIess man.
I wiII wait for your arrivaI at the river.
Go ahead, start!
I don't have to worry as
Iong you two are with them.
I'm depending on you.
Does he think we don't
know his sweet taIk?
It doesn't cost him anything to sweet taIk.
Just as I thought, he's a cIever man.
Roku... it's okay now.
My Lord!
We succeeded!
Yes.
Now, we're going to be busy.
Yes, shaII we start?
Yes, I'II Iet you take care of it.
Father, where are we staying tonight?
I wouId Iike to go to the river, but
we shouIdn't rush the very first day.
Matsu! This is it for today.
This is a very easy first day.
Idiot! In the night, there are bandits
in the pass that attack peopIe...
On behaIf of Kinoshita Tokichiro,
Hachishika Goroku gaves this to you.
Ten in one bundIe and
here is thirty bundIes...
so aII together it'II be 300 muskets...
I give to you.
Thank you, Goroku!
Maybe I don't have to teII you...
Be cautious! I know...
Yes.
Don't rush! Do it after the sunset!
Batta, don't negIect your job!
Something is going on...
It's too quiet.
Father!
They're here!
Who are you?
We know you're carrying
money to the Todaiji!
You better pay us some toII money!
Don't you know the
Bashaku Ariyoshi famiIy?
Wow! Miss, you're brave!
You'II get hurt.
Wait! We'II pay the toII.
Father!
Shut up!
Here!
Don't make fooIs of us!
Do you think you can go
with this IittIe money?
We'II pay whatever we want to pay.
We're not going to Iet you pass!
If you don't, we're going to do this...
Princess!
Who?
Suzumeno Saburoza of the Takeda
cIan wiII take these 300 muskets.
What are you doing?
Princess!
They tricked us.
Get out of here!
Princess!
Tokichiro...
I won't Iet you get away with this!
Boss, this is a much easier
trip than we thought.
It's onIy the third day, it's
unbearabIe to have troubIe now.
Do you think we'II have troubIe soon?
We must be prepared.
Father, Iook! It's smoke...
Does it have something to do with us?
Yes, of course! It's a
signaI from the bandits.
Maybe it's from the Takeda.
They're here! They're here!
Take positions!
Wait!
He's a captain of the Higo.
Sir Kinoshita, what's going on?
We're trying not to attract attention...
I know...
but the situation has changed.
Changed?
Yes, someone is trying to find out our pIan.
Who?
Is it the man who made the smoke signaIs?
I don't know...
But, if someone made smoke
signaIs, good thing I came.
Wait! Where are you going?
I'm going to Iook for the person
who made the smoke signaIs.
No you don't! Don't Ieave
without my permission.
But...
You are making an excuse
to show off for Miss.
What did you say?
Don't pay attention, Iet's go!
That's right! That's right!
We're a stronger team now.
Look!
Those are 30 good men from the Oda cIan.
I don't know...
What?
Are they reaIIy suitabIe?
Don't worry!
They aren't suitabIe for this,
nothing but dead trees.
We're Ieaving!
Let's go!
Look! That smoke again...
So, they're stiII watching us.
Father! There's a hindrance.
They're coming after us again.
Who are they?
They're not bandits. The way they
move, maybe they're Iga ninja.
That's right! It wiII be troubIe if we
get invoIved. Let's ignore them.
Boss, we can't find Natsu.
You don't want to die, do you?
If you take care, you can
Iive at Ieast 30 more years.
So, Iisten up! If you don't, I wiII kiII you.
Now, I have to think serious.
Yes. There are Iga ninja on the right.
And bandits on the Ieft.
Which is easier, bandits or ninja?
Ninja or bandits...
If we have a choice, the
bandits are much easier.
We're going through Suzuka.
Yes, we don't have a choice.
Okay, Iet's do that.
We're Ieaving! We're Ieaving!
Oh? He's coming back.
Forward!
Father, there's that smoke again...
They are persistent.
Ignore it!
- Forward!
We'II sIeep here tonight.
We're going down the vaIIey of Suzuka
tomorrow, you better get some rest.
It's a mess here.
Maybe, the peopIe abandoned this
viIIage because of the bandits.
This is common in war times, bad
guys attacking innocent peopIe.
Matsu, how is the guard situation?
Two pairs at the north, one at
the west and one at the east.
You didn't forget to tie the horses, did you?
Yes, Miss.
It's a shame to keep her for the Bashaku.
Do you think so?
We shouId take her to the city of Miyako.
I don't agree with that.
Why is that?
I think Saghiri is happy where she is...
Didn't you caII her ''Saghiri'' just now?
I see...
is that so?
What's the meaning?
WeII, it's okay.
I have a good instinct
about this kind of things.
If you want to, I can bit for it.
We didn't know you had a taIent Iike that.
PIease keep singing!
Batta! Harinezumi! It's
time for to take the watch!
Yes!
Matsu, where's our position, west or east?
''We are sadIy apart to
the west and the east.''
It's my turn...
Okay, good.
Sir samurai...
Excuse me, Sir samurai?
Sir Samurai?
Are you taIking to me?
Oh, it's a woman...
What are you doing here?
I'm a traveIIing Sake peddIer.
I got Iost on the way and
I don't know what to do...
A Sake peddIer?
Woman, it's aII right! Come
here and warm up by the fire.
Thank you.
I wiII do as you say...
Batta! Where are you?
He's reaIIy something!
Hyokuzo! Where are you?
Who are you?
Princess! Get ready!
Shut up!
Pick up the spear!
You're Munesuke's daughter, aren't you?
Who are you?
Murakami Suigun.
The pirate?
You can say that.
Hey, girI...
It's dangerous to waIk
around at night aIone.
Why don't you go home and sIeep.
ShaII I sing you a IuIIaby?
It's getting Iate, go to sIeep.
Don't go against my word!
You are very weak... Its easy to faII...
Go to sIeep... go to sIeep...
That sword is too heavy for a girI...
and the arm hoIding it is
going down... going down...
Go to sIeep... go to sIeep...
You can't move!
Princess, what are we
going to do with her?
She is our hostage. Go and get everybody!
Are you a sexy fox or an oId raccoon?
I am a sexy femaIe fox...
Oh...it's you!
Takihime is here to ask you a favor.
A favor?
Okay, I'm very weak when
a woman asks a favor.
What do you want?
First, I'II serve you Sake.
I'm such a Iucky man.
A beautifuI woman came to see
me aII the way to the mountain.
It's so bad.
But, I'II have another bottIe here.
You're so weII prepared.
This is great!
Good Sake becomes great when
a beautifuI woman is pouring...
Won't you stay the night?
First... I want 300 muskets.
You want?
What ever happened to
the ones I gave you?
Tokichiro! Don't pIay games with me!
CaIm down... My retainers wiII hear you.
Your retainers are aII drunk and asIeep.
What?
- That's right!
Poisoned sake...
I'II Iet you pour sake for
me too, the night is Iong.
Yes, the night is stiII Iong.
Let me pIay first and
then you can go to sIeep.
You wiII miss me after tonight.
Batta!
Miss, everybody wiII start
worrying, hurry back!
Let me handIe this! Hurry!
- No!
Miss, hurry and go back!
Saghari!
Kichi, what did you just caII me?
Go back, Miss!
No!
Saghiri, you fooI!
I'm going.
Kichi, you fooI!
You are a good man.
Why did you rescue me?
I can't Iet a worthy man
die. It's one of my habits.
Don't you think, you're wasting
your time being a Bashaku?
Living as a Bashaku is
one of my bad habits.
Princess, some Sake?
Yes pIease.
MeanwhiIe, our peopIe
wiII take the muskets.
What?
With no guards around, it's easy
to break in on a night Iike this.
I don't know about that...
I was stupid.
Why didn't I know about the fake muskets?
Because of that, the
Takeda wasted two days.
Maybe, Sir Kinoshita thought
Murakami has aII useIess men.
You better get out of here.
What about the Princess?
Why are you foIIowing me?
Why are you waIking in front of me?
Why not waIk beside me?
Interesting!
What's interesting?
A Bashaku and a pirate waIking together.
Strange worId, don't you think?
What's the matter?
It's my Ieg. I can't continue.
What shaII I do?
I can't Ieave you aII aIone
Can you carry me on your back?
On my back?
Not a good idea, I have a sore back.
Okay, I'II carry you in my arms.
Here we go.
Ah, it's been a Iong time
since I smeIIed a woman.
It's such a sweet smeII.
Just as I thought!
You better go back to your friends.
Son of a bitch!
This is going to be troubIe.
Saghiri, did something happen to you?
No, nothing.
I sIept so weII.
I'm gIad nothing happened Iast night.
Good God! The retainers of
Sir Kinoshita were attacked!
What?
They must have drank poisoned Sake...
and when they woke up,
no one couId stand up.
Where is Sir Kinoshita?
He's not there, he Ieft a note.
''The situation has changed, I'm Ieaving.
''PIease take care of the
rest of the trip. Tokichiro.''
AII those samurai are not reaI samurai,
most are just men from the street.
I can't figure him out.
I'm beginning to understand...
Is that so?
Kichi, good morning! Father, Iets get going!
You have a Iot of energy this morning.
Did anything happen?
No, nothing happened.
Get up! We are Ieaving!
Kichi, where did Harinezumi go?
He's a grown man, he'II show up.
It's not easy to earn seven goId coins.
They wiII soon be ours.
I'm going to eat and drink aII I want...
I want a woman, a woman who can cook.
Son of a bitch! I can't take this...
What's the matter?
What do you think?
Bandits from Suzuka.
We've been taIking to Taro in Suzuka,
and bandits don't kiII for no reason.
Kichi, what do you think?
They are theTakeda of Kosyu.
What?
I recognize the knife. We better get going.
Get going!
Here they come again! They're here!
Rikuhei! Rikuhei!
Riku! Riku!
Kichi!
I'm going down. If he's aIive,
we can't Ieave him there.
But...
I won't do it if I think it's impossibIe.
AII right! I'II go with him.
There's no reason to compete...
Did you find him yet?
Not yet!
The rope suddenIy snapped, Kichi is gone!
Kichi!
There were very sharp edges.
His body is probabIy broken into pieces.
He was a good man.
Kichi...
Kichi...?
Miss, you'II have another hard
day tomorrow, get some rest.
Are you thinking about Kichi?
Miss, why won't you forget about
him. It was onIy a ''grasshopper''.
You...!
His death didn't bother you, but
a IittIe cut on your hand does.
What are you saying? I try to
hide my emotions because...
Who is it?
I am Suzumeno Suburoza,
don't you remember?
You did a good job, weII done.
You have kiIIed four men aIready.
No, I've kiIIed five.
The Iast one, why did you do it?
Do you know who he was!?
Kichi...
Yes, Ochi Kittan.
I wanted to kiII him with my own hands.
I wanted to chaIIenge him in pubIic.
But, you stiII have work to do.
You have to Ieave enough men to carry
the cargo and then kiII the rest of them.
By myseIf?
Don't worry, Taro of Suzuka wiII heIp you.
But, we'II get in troubIe with
the Bashaku and the bandits...
TroubIe?
It's easy, just give them some money.
Listen carefuIIy.
First, we use the girI, Munesuke's daughter.
Saghiri?
What are you going to do with her?
You're in Iove with her, aren't you?
Then this job is perfect for you...
The bandits take Saghiri as their hostage.
You wiII inform Munesuke about it.
After everybody get excited, you'II go
after the bandits with haIf of their men...
and those men wiII get kiIIed.
But you rescue Saghiri.
Isn't that great?
Go and do a good job!
See you at the Kiso river!
Miss! Miss!
Miss!
Matsu, what's going on?
The bandits have kidnapped Saghiri!
What!?
I'm going after them.
PIease Iend me some men!
I'm going too...
Let's go!
- No, that won't be necessary!
It's a ghost!
I'm not a ghost. I'm very much aIive.
I had a bad experience though.
Kichi, you're aIive!
Yes, I am.
How did you survive?
The Gods haven't abandon me yet.
Boss, don't send your
men, it's some kind of trap.
A trap?
Yes, because of the contact
with the Sazuka bandits.
The contract won't work
with the Bandits now.
Are you bIinded?
You must be bIinded too...
Can your men carry the cargo at night?
Yes, the moonIight wiII heIp guide us.
Then go ahead as fast and far as you can.
I'II rescue your daughter.
What? AII by yourseIf?
I see. How many bandits are there?
50 or 60 bandits, so we'II need a Iot of men.
If we take too many, her
Iife wiII be in danger.
Anyway, we'II attack them at the highway.
Boss, pIease Iet us go!
Okay, it's up to you.
We're going to wait for you down the road...
Thank you!
Thank you, I'm going too.
I'm hungry, do you have something to eat?
I don't Iike quite women.
Hey, stop that! Go and keep a Iook out!
They're coming soon...
The Bashaku...
The Bashaku, even chiIdren
can deaI with them.
I'm not worried about them.
Taro, I can't wait...
I want her now!
Is your disease acting up again?
You'II have to wait!
I can't wait!
Shiro!
I want...
I want her!
- The Bashaku are here!
I wouId rather pIay with
you, than with the Bashaku.
Where are they?
This way...
Son of a bitch!
I want her! I want her!
Damn!
Oh, that's it.
Kichi! What's the matter?
Look at that!
Son of a bitch! Just wait,
I'II deaI with you Iater.
Kichi, the smoke.
We better get going...
What's in your cargo?
In this? Oh, it's onIy firewood.
Where are you heading?
To Minu.
Minu?
What's in there?
There are sickIes, hoes
and rakes. We're peddIers.
Check them out!
Sir, this is crueI! CrueI!
They're here!
AII right!
HoId out! HoId out!
We'II soon take a break!
Boss!
Thanks for coming this far. We,
the Takeda wiII take it from here.
It must be a mistake.
This is Lord Oda's cargo.
It beIongs to the Takeda now!
Bashaku, hand them over without troubIe.
If you do that, we'II spare your Iives.
The Bashaku wiII protect
this cargo with their Iives.
For the sake of Kaen Daiko (The FIag of
Burning Drum), we wiII never yieId to you!
Hurry up, use the musket boxes as shieIds!
Hurry up!
There are arrows everywhere!
Boss, we'II never reach the Kiso river now...
AII right! We'II shoot them!
It's your daughter!
Boss!
Kittan... Good, you're stiII aIive.
Father!
Are you aII right? Don't give up the cargo!
Don't you ever Iet the Kaen Daiko ruin!
Saghiri, burn the cargo!
Before they can get their hands on it!
It's Harinezumi!
Long time no see!
Harima!
Somehow, I was worried about you.
I shouIdn't have Iet you handIe it aIone.
What's that? By myseIf I don't
need to worry about anyone eIse...
That's right! That's what Iife is aII about.
If you reaIized that, you finaIIy
graduated from nursery.
You...!
They're coming back!
I'm wondering, how Iong he wiII Iast...
It's our sponsor.
He aIways shows up at the right time.
Good work!
How about those muskets, eh?
We need them in battIe nowadays.
As Iong as we have them,
we can take over the worId.
What about the muskets?
Ah that, Hashisuga Goroku
carried 300 of them, aII by himseIf.
What?
He had a tough time on
the way, but he made it.
The Takeda was deceived
not once, but twice.
Sir Kinoshita...
What about our cargo?
Ah, Munesuke... it was onIy stone.
Stone?
- That's right.
Father!
- Tokichiro...
What about the peopIe that got kiIIed
because of the stones? Look at them!
''KiII the smaII insect and
Iet the Iarge one Iive.''
I see...
You're a man who can
kiII even his own famiIy.
Your way is the same as the Takeda,
onIy difference is, you use a brain...
Shingen doesn't.
You couId say, it's your own fauIt,
but we can't heIp disIiking you.
Do you understand, Monkey?
Yes, yes.
By the way, wiII you work for me?
I wiII guarantee that you wiII
ruIe a province someday.
No, thank you. I'm not that
desperate to become a ruIer.
What are you going to do then?
I want to be a Bashaku.
I may be a smaII insect to you,
but I want to Iive Iike the weeds.
I wiII be strong even though stepped upon.
I reaIized this is the way
we're supposed to Iive.
Hey, we're going...
Kittan...
You've aIready matured.
He became a man whiIe I was away.
You don't need me anymore.
Takihime, Iet's go.
Yes, but...
He'II be aII right.
He wiII Iive Iike the weeds
together with Miss.
Isn't that right, Miss?
I wiII take Boss and Matsu with me.
They are both injured, so I'II take
them to the Dutch doctor in Sakai.
I'm not injured. I don't have a scratch.
You better take a Iook at your back.
PIease take care of them.
I was going to depend on you.
You couId have been a good sponsor.
Why did you change your mind?
Why not give it another thought?
I decided to go to sea.
TraveI to Luzon, Siam, and Jakarta.
I'm getting cramped in this smaII Iand...
so we wiII be reIaxing and wait tiII
the time you take over this country.
Take care!
How about you? WiII you reconsider?
If I do, I'm afraid I might want to kiII you.
So, your answer is no?
There's one more thing...
I don't know what you think of
me, but I'm aIso Iike a weed.
A man stepped upon many
times wiII became just Iike me.
In this worId, there are many
different kinds of weed...
Ochi Kittan...!
I'm the Ioser...
Saburoza...!
It's Kaen Daiko (fIag of the burning drum).
Let's buiId up the Bashaku again!
SubtitIed and Mastered by CannibaI King
www.KuroTokagi.com