Subtitles by Renatinha Tankinha
[dark rhythmic music]
[unintelligible alien dialogue]
The final item in our agenda today is
the planetary asset known as Pyom.
This remote backwater was acquired over
800 years ago by our Royddin subsidiary
an undeveloped resource-rich
"gem" of a property
with the convenience of a
preexisting atmosphere.
After mineral extractions were completed,
Pyom was still quite valuable
as a manufacturing base,
boasting a profitability index of 127.
Sadly, operations in
Pyom fell victim to
the economic collapse in
that system 73 years ago
and a freeze on maintenance
expenditure remains in effect.
Compounding the planet's woes,
decades of grade 3
smelting without any
environmental remediation
have taken a toll,
and no funds have been
allocated for cleanup.
Models are being run for
various divestiture strategies
including both cold pullout and sale,
in which case the indigenous labor
force will presumably be included.
And now, if there are no questions,
this meeting is adjourned.
You were not chosen.
It was purely coincidental that
the sum total of you was the key.
It has begun.
[dark rhythmic music]
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
- How long have you been here?
- Just a few minutes.
I'm glad I got to see
you this morning.
They posted my new
schedule for the week-
Mostly nights. But it means
I get to see more of you.
- Hope I'm worth it.
- When you're not I'll let you know.
[loud buzzer]
Lineup. I have to go get dressed.
Kana, I hate it when you leave.
See you in a few days.
[atmospheric music]
[music continues]
[music builds]
Senn! My favorite wedge maker!
- How was your weekend?
- Ahh, same as always.
Working my fingers out
to almost nothing.
Pretty soon you'll have
to call me "Nubby".
- Seriously, though, what
happened to your hands?
- Aww, nothing. Just some new chemical
in the finish coating line.
Burns like a nudge rod,
but on a brighter side, it
gives me a massive buzz,
and makes me really horny,
so I can't complain.
- That's why I love you, Resh.
Always the optimist.
- It's OK! I've been
showering my considerable
charms all over the Crew Chief.
You know she's bound to transfer
to the fluff-line any day now.
I think she likes me. If only she knew...
-She doesn't stand a chance.
Solidarity!
Alright. Oh, before I forget...
I've got a certain rare item
for a certain special someone.
-You found a copy?
How'd you get your hands on one?!
-I've got my ways.
- And you sir, are forever in my debt.
- No. Forever is not long enough.
I'll pay you back. I promise.
- That smile on your ugly
face is payment enough.
Come on! those widges
won't make themselves.
[atmospheric music]
[loud buzzer]
[changing assembly line noises]
[choral music begins]
-Senn, get over here!
There's another on for you.
This was not your fault.
You didn't deserve this.
None of us deserves this.
But... at least you don't
have to be here anymore.
[crashing noise]
[assembly line noise]
What's going on with you, Senn?
You don't seem like
yourself lately.
Nothing special.
I've been having
these weird dreams.
Could be from stress... when's
your next day off?
Our group doesn't get any
until the next prod cycle.
Bastards.
I knew I'd find you two
love units up here.
Hi, Resh.
Kana, darling, mind if I join?
I brought newfangled snacks.
Oh, my favorite kind!
Thanks.
Which planet did these come from?
Don't know, but I can't stop eating them.
What's the prize this time?
Or, is it a comic?
No, it says "Personality
test: Put your thumb here."
You have an aptitude for...
"animals." Hey, how did
it know I like animals?
Is this one of those
"join a cult" things?
No. I think it's a sneaky way
for them to track what you like
so they can get you to buy more stuff.
Sure is wasted on us.
What you love most...
"your family."
Sorry.
If only this stupid thing could
tell me where my family is...
I know exactly where mine is.
I hear from them all the time.
Especially when I'm late
getting them money!
But it's the only thing that keeps them
alive, so, you know, what the hey!
Sorry folks. I don't
have much to contribute.
Family has never been
one of my big concerns.
[choral music]
At least you don't
have anyone to miss.
Huh-I heard there's an ExWorld
passenger transport leaving next week.
ExWorld?
It would take two lifetimes of our
wages just to afford a ticket.
Those shuttles are so old they,
they blow up half the time anyway.
And if you can actually
get a ride to another
rock in our system.
They just deport you.
Well, I can still dream.
I'm gonna find my
sisters someday.
We're not going anywhere.
All we're good for
is making weird junk
we don't understand
and never afford.
That's what fills all the
shuttles that leave here...
off to rich people in other systems.
They probably have no
idea where Pyon even is.
Yeah!
Yeah. Those suckers probably think
everything they buy is made by robots.
Right! For the price of one synbot you
could buy this entire busted planet!
Hmm..We must be good for something else.
Ever known anyone to jump
the line and prove it?
Look, you two might not be good for
much, but I tell you what I'm good for.
OK? Loving, fighting, scheming
and surviving-in that order.
Gotta go, got lots to do...
We should head back soon too.
When can I see you again?
I don't know. They keep
changing my shifts.
Damn. Guess I'll just
have to miss you, then.
I don't know what I'd
do if you didn't.
[melancholy piano music]
I hate feeling so broken.
Senn, you should be proud.
All the other kids that
get sold are hopeless.
Enjoying all the big words?
I've been so buried I haven't gotten
a chance to start reading it yet.
You know, most people ask me to smuggle
in perk patches, drama vids, smutlets...
You're the only one who wants books.
What can I say? I enjoy using my brain.
It's either that or dying of boredom.
Hey, listen, I have something to ask you.
What?
You remember that group
that group-mate of mine
who was transferred to the
Biohaz about a month ago?
Uhh... the one you liked?
What was his name?
Lann. Yesterday he was
mouthing off about that
video they made us watch
for entertainment.
I think it was called...
[cheesy sound effects]
It's good that we have good the
communication systems we need
or else we'd be blown up
just like the other planets.
Aha! This is the last
planet we have to blow up!
Now-destroy them!
[cheesy laser blast]
We will destroy the base by laser cannon.
Good.
[cheesy sound effects]
Red alert! White people in the area!
Now, let's go inside and free the slaves!
Looks like it was made
by a 12-year-old!
It was. the head foreman's kid made it.
No wonder!
They forced us to watch
that a few days ago.
So ridiculous. Huge spaceships
don't land on planets.
Everybody knows that.
So, what about
Lann... don't tell me...
He's delisted.
Aw, that's awful. You must be crushed.
Look, you know the crew
chief in Bio, right?
Do you think you could
talk to her for me?
I mean, maybe she'll
take him back.
I know there's not much
of a chance, but...
[strange metal sounds]
Cuff me! What was that?
You mean you could see it, too?
I thought it was just me.
If that's the grid shorting out
again, let's get out of here.
I do not want to get deep fried
like those guys in Bunk 12.
No, it's not that.
I wanna show you something.
Cuff my balls!
What is that?
I don't know.
It comes and goes.
Whatever you do, don't touch it!
Oh, I'm definitely going to touch it.
You really, really shouldn't touch it.
I have to touch it.
Resh, do not touch it.
I need to touch it.
[piercing scraping sounds]
Ahh!
That's OK. No damage.
What is it?
I wish I knew.
Wait a sec. No, I've seen
something like that before.
It was in a spy vid.
Some sort of surveillance device.
You're being spied on.
Come on, Resh, those trashy
vids you watch aren't real!
It looked exactly like that! I swear!
If it is what you say it is, it
certainly isn't well hidden.
No, this is big.
There's got to be some
reason that it's there.
[wind noise]
[atmospheric music]
How's the book you
got from Resh?
Oh, it's super interesting.
There's a character in it with a
job that would be perfect for you.
What job?
It's a medic for
animals, just animals.
Really?! There are people
who just treat animals?
Apparently so.
I'd love to do something like that.
It'd be pretty nice, huh?
Who am I kidding?
The only experience I have with
animals is watching them in vids.
I've never even seen a
real animal in person.
I'd be hopeless.
No, you'd be terrific.
You're the most caring person I know.
Stop it! You're just trying
to make me feel better.
Ow.
What is it?
Umm...
Just a sharp pain behind my eyes.
Happens now and then.
Do you think it's
related to the...
what did you call them again?
Uhh... I don't know.
Vivid dreams?
I wish I could see them.
You might not want to.
I don't know if I should
be afraid of them or not.
I've been seeing other things, too...
while I'm awake.
It's starting to worry me.
Well, you've definitely
been dazing out
more and more lately.
Pretty soon you're not going to
be able to work, and then...
I can still manage, OK?
You're fooling yourself.
They've already had to stop the
line twice because of you,
and if it happens again
they'll throw you out.
You have to dig through the trash
dunes with the other discards.
What can I do?
I can't control the visions.
I can't stop them
from happening.
Maybe you should see
the group medic?
Medic?
I might as well go to the
Foreman and resign right now.
You know what'll happen?
At the third word out of my
mouth about the "visions",
that'll be the end of it.
They'll brand me unfit.
It will be over. And not just
for me, but for both of us.
Senn, we have to do something.
I'm worried about you,
you're sick and you don't
seem to be getting better.
Kana, I'm not sick.
Alright, I,
I know the things I'm seeing
are weird and hard to explain.
But, you know, they're important somehow.
It's not a sickness.
I just wish I knew what it was all about.
All I want is for you to be OK.
I care about you.
I love you.
I wish I were good at telling
you how much you mean to me.
You know, you're about the only
thing in this cuffed up place
that isn't rotting
from the inside out.
I just wish I didn't feel so helpless.
We'll figure something out.
[music]
What are you?
What do you want from me?
Why are you even here?
What are you waiting for?
Whatever you're here
to do, just do it.
Alright? Just get it
over with already.
Just quit hiding and
fucking show yourself!
[music continues]
Senn!
Senn, snap out of it!
You won't believe this.
It was amazing.
I busted through a new part and
all of space opened
up in front of me.
It all makes sense now.
Forget about that. It's opening
up right here, come on!
What?!
[loud booming music]
Wait!
Senn, you're going in to that thing?!
I have to, Kana.
Everything that's happened
up to this point,
every cell in my body is saying
that this is the right thing to do.
I want you to come with me.
Go? But we don't know what's in
there or what the hell it even is.
Look at it, it goes on
forever in both directions.
It seems crazy, but
but I'm asking you to
trust my gut on this one,
Alright, remember,
remember when you said
"We'll figure something out.'
Things have been figured out!
But this is insane, Senn.
How can this be happening?
I don't know exactly, but it has.
It's not something I'm dreaming. It's here.
And it's not a broken
down ExWorld shuttle.
You knew this was going to happen?!
You saw it?
No, no, I didn't know... But I do now.
The goons are coming,
you better go.
[alarm sounding]
Resh is right; if we stay here, we're dead.
I can't believe I'm doing this.
Resh, Resh, I want you to join us.
Right, I know...
Senn, my mom...
I'm torn up leaving you here, man.
You know me. I'm a fighter.
I'm going to get by.
Get that brain of yours out of
here before they wash it for you.
Go, go!
[music continues]
What is all this?
I don't know.
Welc'...
- Who are you?
- Wel-come
Welcome.
Make yourselves comfortable.
Ummm, thanks.
We'll try.
We hope our arrival was
not too disruptive.
Only a bit.
This is a space-ship, right?
That is correct.
While you are here, please
make yourselves at home.
Sure.
Maybe you should explain
what's going on.
We've been tracking
an unknown entity
which has reached deeper and
deeper strata within the Polychronom.
Levels never reached before.
Polychronom?
It's the giant construct I've
been seeing in my dreams.
I'm assuming I'm the entity.
Yes, exactly.
So, what is the Polychronom?
We have been studying the "construct",
as you call it, for some time.
But, we still do not know its
purpose, or who created it.
Wait. You mean you didn't build it?
Oh, no. Our technology is primitive
compared to the sophistication
present within the Polychronom.
Incredible!
When I'm there in my mind.
It feels like I'm trying
to solve something.
But at the same time, I'm not.
It's more like an emotional test.
But...
It's hard to explain.
What's going on in there?
We hope you can answer that for us.
Entire civilizations
have devoted themselves
to deciphering the Polychronom.
But, none have accomplished
as much as you have.
Not to mention, in so little time.
We did not even know in which part of the
galaxy to look for you until recently.
Why Senn? What's so special about him?
That is a mystery as well.
Surprisingly, he is able to connect
to the construct from afar.
So why did you come all the way here?
We see ourselves as stewards
of the Polychronom.
In that role we desire to aid whomever
the construct chooses to grant access.
I just want to be there. See it
in person, more than anything.
It is a real, physical thing, right?
Yes, it is quite as you say, "real".
Do you require rest?
Please, take some time
to get acclimated,
and then we can discuss further.
Our voyage will take many of
your days, so there is time.
Before you go,
what should we call you?
What's your name?
We... have no name.
Did he say his name was "We"?
And I was wondering...
What about a place to sleep?
Food? You know, things like that...
Of course. Our apologies.
Will this do?
That'll do.
Nicely.
[atmospheric music]
[loud crashing sound]
Hi, umm...
This thing you're doing right now-
please don't do it again.
To what are you referring?
Standing here, watching
me while I sleep.
It's disturbing.
So sorry.
Uh, since you're
here, can I ask...
how far is it we'll
be traveling?
The Polychronom is in a
system approximately
1,041 of your light years from
our present location.
One-thousand light years? Wow!
The distance is of no
consequence to us.
Can you imagine
the amazing stuff
you could discover with
a spaceship like this?
Strange phenomena, undiscovered races!
That is a difficult question to answer.
Oh, it wasn't really a question.
I was just thinking of the possibili-
The cosmos is so vast
that the likelihood of coming across
something of interest is very remote.
And time is even more vast.
Almost all of the advanced races we
found evidence of perished long ago.
Oh, well. That's too bad.
I can still dream, though.
Hey, Senn, ask for some new clothes for us.
Oh, oh, and some books.
Of course.
Still can't believe this is happening.
Me neither, it's so strange.
Well, imagine if we were
transporting insects somewhere.
Right?
We wouldn't have the first clue
to know what would make it happy.
True.
I hope Resh is
holding up alright.
He made the right decision to stay behind.
He's a tough one. He'll be OK.
You're right.
At least I hope you're right.
What are you doing?
Cooking.
I see... umm... I don't mean to
interrupt but I have a question.
So there is a higher level
part of the construct
that I can't seem to get
past and I don't know why.
Describe it, please.
The shapes there are
tightly packed together,
into a sort of wall, and I
can't seem to get around it.
Ah, yes.
You are confused because you are not used
to dealing with multi-dimensional space.
Multi-what?
Some of the "shapes",
as you call them,
in that strata exist in
dimensions higher than our own.
What you are seeing is not the object
itself, but a shadow of the object.
Huh?
To explain...
Take a two-dimensional object.
For example, a square.
If we introduce a light source onto
the flat plane the square lives in,
the resulting shadow is
a one-dimensional line.
In the same way, a three-dimensional
object, like a cube,
casts a two-dimensional shadow.
Finally, a fourth
dimensional object casts...
Casts a three-dimensional shadow!
Exactly.
The objects that are
confusing you are
cast shadows of fourth
dimensional volumes.
So how do I tell which
shapes I see are regular,
and which ones are shadows?
It is simple.
Shadows cannot cast
shadows themselves.
I see, so all I need to
do is look for shapes
that should be casting
shadows but don't.
Yes. The difference can be subtle.
But it should be noticeable.
Be cautious though-shadow
shapes are inherently unstable.
Thank you.
It's so beautiful here.
I don't care if it's not real.
I bet you're thrilled
with the animals.
Yeah, but honestly the big
ones kind of scare me.
Uh. Home feels so far away.
I can't even imagine
going back there.
We would have been
blacklisted by now, anyway.
There'd be nothing
to go back to,
except digging through the
trash dunes for food scraps.
The factories should be smashed.
What they do, or more so,
how they do it is immoral.
Yeah, but to be replaced by what?
Some other entity that exploits
people like us in the same way?
There must be
something we can do.
I don't know.
Give it some time.
Did you ever think you'd be
traveling in a massive spaceship
to a strange construct a
thousand light-years away?
Clearly, anything's possible.
You always know how to
make me feel better.
[emotional electronic music]
[music continues]
Would you like some?
Yeah.
Sure.
Cow juice?
Um...
OK.
Alright.
I was wondering, and I
hope it isn't rude, but
I assume this isn't your natural form.
What do you really look like?
It is complicated.
There is a physical
component to our being but
it is only visible
in the part of the
electromagnetic spectrum
your eyes cannot see.
If artificially shifted down,
it would appear to you as noise, or static.
It was worth a try.
How did you first come
across the Polychronom?
Long ago,
we discovered an object in the center
of the iron core of our home land.
It was communicating with
thousands of objects like it.
We followed this complex signal web
until we reached the Polychronom.
Once there, we discovered
evidence of others
who had attempted to unlock its secrets.
But by the time we arrived,
they had long perished.
And no one knows what it's for?
There are many hypotheses,
but no certainty.
We assume it is essentially
in a dormant state.
Waiting. For reasons unknown.
Why are you so fascinated with it?
In our travels,
we've never come across anything
as advanced or as intriguing
as the Polychronom.
We feel that studying it is worth the
dedication of unlimited time and resources
Sounds like you almost worship it
and you don't even know what it is.
Haven't you ever thought about
the fact that you might end up
like all the others and their
dead ships floating around it?
This concept is not one
we have contemplated.
Aren't you scared that it might
be some sort of powerful weapon?
Seems risky to tinker with
things you don't understand.
It's not a weapon.
Don't ask me how I
know, but I just do.
I don't know,
something that powerful could
easily convince us into thinking...
anything.
We feel that possible scientific
advancements outweigh any risks.
Just be careful, Senn.
[bright, atmospheric music]
Hey, Kanna!
Wow!
Senn, do you think it's
OK for us to go in there?
I think all this stuff's here for us.
What do you think this place is?
I think it's someone's house.
Or, more accurately, a
copy of someone's house.
What? What's wrong?
These are Manufactory documents.
Internal memos...
Let me see.
What's that one about?
It's umm...
It's about, acquisition
of, labor resources.
Oh, that.
It says the practice has
been banned in two systems
because of what
happened-the abuses.
I can't even imagine how
horrific it must have been.
They wanted workers who were
fastest and most compliant.
You know, one that were a good
return on their investments
So they'd drill us all day long
on how quickly we could assemble a widge.
How well we followed orders.
Ones who weren't so good
at it got the yoke, or were beaten.
Ones who couldn't never
meet the standard
always mysteriously came
down with Dramatic Fever,
and they were gone.
The worst thing they ever did
was pit us against each other.
The one tiny ray of light were the
friendships I made with the other kids,
but they had to go
poison this too.
If there's one thing I learned
there it's that hating is easy-
it's kindness that takes guts.
When did you get out?
At 12 we graduated
into the work-force.
Shifts on the line were a
vacation in comparison.
I wish there was something I could do.
It was so long ago.
You don't need to do anything.
Let's just enjoy being here, now.
[foreboding music]
Senn!
Senn-are you OK?
I thought I lost you there for a minute.
I don't know.
I don't know anymore.
You're back. For now.
Come on, we're going
to be late for dinner.
Wait, dinner?
Yeah, We's making some
sort of special meal. Here.
Oh, great! I've seen his cooking.
I'm keeping an open mind.
Fish or bird?
Fish.
Umm... bird.
Please, enjoy.
We hope the food does not disappoint.
Uh, thank you for... cooking.
Yeah, thank you.
It is our pleasure.
Oh, um... I was wondering....
about the others before
me who had the dreams...
were they OK mentally afterwards?
Did they experience any... problems?
We have never
encountered any being
who has accessed the
Polychronom before you.
I thought you'd met others,
who didn't get as far as Senn.
We have been able to recover and
analyze several data archives
from the dead ships that
surround the construct.
They tell of those who
had your ability.
But the data was difficult
to decipher, and incomplete.
Oh, um, well, did the records
mention any issues they had?
I'm afraid so.
It appears that some of those
who were able to access
the Polychronum experienced
mental disintegration.
What?
But you said some. Not all.
No. Not all. The rest died.
They died?! Why didn't you
tell me that before?
Can't you do anything to help him?
There was not much we can do.
As we do not fully understand
the processes of work.
If you would allow us to
temporarily remove your brain
we could develop a more
detailed analysis.
No, please do not do that!
Are you serious?
It is a simple procedure.
How could you even suggest
something like that?
Who do you think you are?
We have, arrived.
[atmospheric music]
Wow.
For a day or so I felt the
presence more strongly,
the connection more tangible.
At first I thought I was
just going crazy, but now...
now it all makes sense.
I wish I could have seen
this from the beginning.
I might have understood.
Oh, there was no way for you to have known.
So what do we do now?
Get into some sort of
shuttle and fly into it?
No.
The physical structure of the Polychronum
fluctuates to violently for travel within.
It is much better to access
it from a safe distance.
I agree.
I think I have a lot of work to do.
Any suggestions on how
I should continue?
We wish we could be of more assistance.
But we have no knowledge of the
advanced strata you have reached.
That's OK. I'll figure it out myself.
[music continues]
Resh!
Country A invades Country B vowing
to wipe out all its inhabitants.
Which country is good
and which is evil?
What?
Country B 50 years earlier
colonized its current lands
decimating the native
population in the process,
Now, which is good and which is evil?
Both, I guess.
Millions are dying on a
planet because of drought-
do you help them?
Yes, of course.
What if the draught is
caused by overpopulation?
Oh, uh...
Should holy books be an acceptable source
for determining a society's moral code?
What about ones that contains
rules for keeping slaves?
I don't know.
-Could the conditions ever
exist where the extiction
of a civilization is
preferable to its survival?
If an artificial intelligence
is indistinguishable
from a person, it it murder
to erase it or shut it down?
An artificial what?
You did whatever the
guards wanted even though
you knew it would make life
harder for the other kids.
You were the guards' pet.
And then you pretended to
be friends with everyone
as you knifed them in the back.
What did you say?
To get special treatment
you would even take the jobs
that no one else wanted.
like helping to get rid
of all those bodies.
It wasn't like that.
Do you know why you agreed to do
every filthy thing that they wanted?
Because you felt nothing.
You looked at those bodies and you
felt a big fat emotional zero.
You're dead inside.
You're a fraud.
You're a failure.
You left your best friend
behind on a hideous planet.
Left him to rot.
Resh, Resh, Resh, if you're in
there somewhere, I'm sorry.
I'm not proud of what I did. OK?
If I could go back and
change things I would!
Resh, I would do anything for you.
If saving your life meant losing
mine I wouldn't hesitate.
[foreboding music]
My arms felt bare without them.
I don't know what I'm...
[emotional electronic music]
Making progress?
I'm so close tho getting it.
I'm right there and then the construct
shifts and then I'm blocked again.
You know what? let's go for a walk-
maybe it will help clear my head.
Wait.
Look over there.
Oh, oh- I see them.
What are they?
I don't know.
Ah, they're beautiful.
-The papers we were looking through...
-Yeah?
...the worker roles? I found
one of my sisters in them.
Really? That's great!
Where did it say she was?!
It didn't say.
She was moved to another
system a year ago.
I don't know which one.
Well, you know, that's
a start, I guess.
Yeah.I'm just glad to
know she's still alive.
Me too.
I'll keep looking.
[foreboding music]
What is it?
My hand - It's not there.
I don't exist.
What are you talking about?
I don't cast a shadow.
Look - there's your shadow,
but under my hand, nothing!
What do you mean?
It's like the shapes in the construct-
I'm just a projection of a
higher-dimensional object.
I'm not me!
How's that possible?
I don't know. I still feel like myself but
I'm clearly not really here.
Senn, you feel fine,
you're just imagining things.
No, no, you don't
understand, alright?
What you're touching isn't real.
Someone has some explaining to do.
Senn! Where are you going?
You knew about this?
Sorry, please explain.
You knew that I was
switched out, or changed,
or whatever happened to me...
You knew that I was just a
three-dimensional shadow all along?!
Yes, we knew.
How could you not have told me?
You did not ask.
What else are you keeping a secret?
What else were you not going to tell me?
How can I trust you about anything?!
This is all about you, isn't it?
You're just using us,
we're like puppets to you.
You don't even care that my
real body's probably dead.
The conversion happened
before we came for you.
In fact, it was the conversion itself
that alerted us to your presence.
Without it, we would never have found you.
Can't you do something, anything?
There is no way to influence or
reverse whatever process changed you.
Alright, well, whatever I
am now, it's unstable, right?
I'll eventually just
disintegrate like those shapes?
Yes. The probability of
that outcome is high.
Then I'm going in there.
Into the Polychronum?
Yes. I am physically
going in there, alright?
Maybe there's a chance that I
can get my real body back.
It is too dangerous to enter...
You're going to send me in now!
We refuse.
Well, well...If you are not going
to send me in, then I'll...
I'll...I'll communicate to the Polychronum
that you're trying to destroy it.
No, we beg you do not do that.
We will ready a transport device.
And don't try to trick me!
I'll know.
Kanna, I'm dead. I don't even know
who I am anymore. I'm just a shell.
No, Senn, you're just confused.
I've let you down.
I promised I'd be there
for you, but now...
now all you have to
hold on to is a ghost.
I don't wanna lose you!
You already have!
Senn, we didn't come all this
way for things to end like this.
I'm not giving up yet.
Things that I never thought I could
ever do, like find my sisters.
There's a chance I can do that now.
I wish I could know what you're
feeling right now, but I can't.
Is it wrong of me to feel
like having you here
as you are is better than
losing you entirely?
No, no, it's not wrong.
But this is something
I have to do.
I can't stay like this.
No-I could start
desintegrating any moment.
It feels like I'm dead.
So what are we supposed to do?
Start mourning your death?
I don't know.
How do you mourn your own death?
We must insist you reconsider-
we cannot allow you
to endanger yourself.
It would be the ultimate betrayal of our
role as stewards to the Polychronum.
I already told you. I'm going.
How can we convince
you otherwise?
You can't.
We understand.
Please, remain where you are.
The craft will be leaving shortly.
[loud bang]
Senn, go quickly!
I love you, Kana.
Just promise me
you'll make it back.
[Rhythmic electronic music]
[loud crashing noise]
[metalic noise]
[atmospheric music]
It has been a long time,
but finally, you have come.
There's much you would
like explained.
You're me when I was
young, aren't you?
Yes.
Why are you here?
This is when it first began.
When what began?
The connection. It first started
when you were at this age.
Why me? Why was I chosen?
You were not chosen.
Your homw world was implanted with
the Beacon like all the others.
It was purely coincidental
that the sum total of you
was the correct key to
activate the beacon.
Wait, the sum total of me?
Your physical form, your thoughts
and actions, your experiences.
The details are not important.
So the Beacons are a
part of the Polychronom.
Yes.
What is the Polychronom's purpose?
What does it do?
You know the answer to that, already.
[stirring electronic music]
Welcome back.
Kana.
Do you remember
everything that happened?
It's a bit foggy, but, yeah.
How, I don't know.
Thinking about higher dimensional
space gives me a headache.
Glad to be me again.
I never did find out exactly
why they switched me out.
Something about needing
to protect me...
So? What was it like?
What did you see?
So hard to explain!
Well, tell me what it's
for-what does it do?
Kana,
do you feel any different
compared to before I left?
What do you mean?
How do I feel right now?
Your side hurts.
And your head feels like it was
hit by a metal folding machine.
But you're happy to be
back, and to see me.
It's what it does.
What?
It connects us.
It makes us aware of how
everyone around us feels,
how everyone connected
to us feels.
And with that comes self-awareness,
and differentiation.
That's incredible!
It's gonna change everything back home.
The effect reaches that far?
It reaches everywhere!
Well, within this part of
the galaxy, we believe.
Thank you for
everything you've done.
Please, accept our apologies.
We should not have
tried to stop you.
You were just doing what
you thought was right.
Now that the Polychronom
has been awakened,
we have much research to do.
Do you know of any way we may connect
to it directly, as you have?
Please. It is very important to us.
When I was in there I discovered why
you were not able to access it.
Because of the function
that it was designed for,
it only recognises biological life forms.
But that means...
Yeah.Since your physical
composition isn't biological,
The Polychronom doesn't
even know you exist.
[scary rumbling sound]
So many thousands of
lifetimes, wasted.
The object we have devoted
our entire existance to
has no idea who we are, or
what we have sacrificed?
I'm sorry.
This cannot be understood!
[fires burning, rumbling]
I, I want to help but
I don't know what, I
don't know what to do.
If, uh, wait, if he
can create animals,
why doesn't he create some sort of
biological component to his behavior?
[bright rhythmic music]
Of course!
Um...
Here, this might help.
[music continues]
Do you think We going as an
animal is going to work?
I have no idea. But come on,
let's go get Resh and
find your sisters.
[unintelligeble alien dialogue]
I appreciate everyone assembling for
this meeting in such short notice.
As you can imagine, the recent
psychological phenomenom,
which I can confirm all our
subsidiaries are experiencing,
necessitaded this unusual step.
It appears the automated forecasting
systems we always relied on
are no longer useful to us.
We are in uncharted territory.
In view of this development,
we all agree we need to decide quickly
about managing our populated
planetary holdings
and living conditions
for their inhabitants.
Contact has even been established with
regional persons' rights organizations
to explore more sustainable options.
For the time being,
all neew acquisitions will be
limited to uninhabited worlds.
I share the apprehension
I feel from you all
about the economics
of this new reality
but also in your collected relief
that policy changes are being investigated.
Thank you for your thoughtful
participation in this process.
The floor is now open for discussion.