SARJAN HASSAN (1958)
Malay to English subtitles by ASEAN1984
Fansub in tribute to Malaysia's
best director: P. Ramlee
My name is Hassan
A Sergeant
From the Royal Malay Regiment
I wish to share with
you, the story of my life
My mother died
When I was still very young
And I was raised by my father
But, when I was ten years old
My father died too
It was then, that I felt really alone
I remember...
During my father's burial
I wanted to cry, but...
I realised my tears were in vain
Who could I appeal to?
Only to God, I've surrendered my fate
As a sign of a son's love for his father
I could only plant one small
"remembrance tree" (pokok kenangan)
My heart felt a mix
of sadness and sorrow
My feet were heavy as I left my
father laying there alone in his grave
Only to become restless
Where would I live now?
Where?
Thank you, Uncle
Where are you thinking of going?
- To find a home
Do not worry. This is your home, too.
That is why I have brought you here.
Here?
- Yes
Minah!
- Yes, sir?
Alright now, don't cry anymore
I'm cooking rice now
- it might burn
I want to introduce my son to you
Your son?
- Hassan is his name
I thought your son's name was Aziz
That's true, but Hassan is also my son
I've worked here for quite some time.
Only now I know of another son.
- Alright, enough of your nonsense
Actually, he is my adopted son.
His father used to work with me
Before he passed away, he requested
if anything were to happen to him
- Hassan would be under my care
So, as he passed on - Hassan has now
become my responsibility
Oh sir, my rice is burning!
- Quickly, quickly
Come, let me show you to your room
Look at yourself. Your head, ears,
body, feet - are all filthy!
I want you to go have a bath
- Alright, auntie
Hey, who is in there?! Come out now!
It's me, Hassan. Your father
asked me to bathe. Why?
Get out now! You used
my towel and soap, huh?!
Hurry! Minah!
Who is this? Your father brought
him and asked him to bathe
Give me my shirt back, now!
Give me my shirt back! Aziz, enough!
No manners. Why are you siding him?
But he didn't do anything wrong.
- Then why did he take my shirt?
Enough, Aziz. Enough!
- Get out, now!
Don't bother about him. Wear the shirt.
What was all the shouting about
in the kitchen?
- But I want to know who that boy is
Sit!
He is my adopted son. I do
not want you both fighting
And I want you to be nice to him
But he is a son of a servant! He is filthy.
He wore my shirt, pants - all my clothes!
Why did you let him stay here?
- He is staying here which
makes him your brother
That's all I want to know
- Hey, Aziz. Come back!
He stayed no more than an hour, and
already my father's ring was missing.
Guess who stole it? That boy, of course
What's his name?
- Hassan
One day I'll teach him a lesson. If
you don't like him, I hate him also
That Hassan is filthy liar and a thief
Hey Aziz, enough of your
lies! Come home with me now!
If you want me, catch me first
Everything I said is
true. He is the liar.
Why are you following us? I don't
like you both following us around
I am not following you.
I'm heading to school
Aziz is the one following you, not me
I don't like walking near both of you
Hassan, hold on. Let us walk together
- Come along then
Look at that Hassan.
He thinks he is so good.
Did you know what he said? He
said he could beat you anytime
Is it true he said that?
- Of course
Alright. I'm going to wait for him here
after school. Let us see who wins or loses.
Hassan, stop there
Salmah, go home!
- What are you doing?
None of your business. Get lost!
What do you want?
Is it true you wanted to teach
me a lesson yesterday?
- No, I never said that
Yesterday you said, you could
win with your hands tied
- No, I didn't say that
Then are you trying to say
my friend is a liar?
- I don't know
If you want to fight, come on then
- Why should I fight,
when you did me no wrong
I must fight with you
- I don't want to fight
If I threw your 'songkok' down?
I pick it up
If I threw your book down?
May I go back now?
- Go back? You fight with me first
Wallop him. Whack him
Hit him, Hassan. Hit him!
Punch him. Don't be afraid. Punch him!
Aziz, I shall tell your
father you caused this fight
If you don't stop fighting,
I shall tell father
I keep telling don't fight but you still do
- It's not my fault
Then whose fault is it?
Peace be with you
- Peace be also with you
Actually, I have come here to ask if he
was in a fight with Buang this morning?
Perhaps so, but Aziz and
Buang often disturb him
One day I saw them wielding a knife
- A knife?!
So, you can't blame Hassan
It's true, Uncle!
If you want me to confront
both Aziz and Buang
- I am not afraid to do so
Hassan is not in the wrong
Why are you smiling? Glad
that she is bailing you out?
My apologies, teacher. I will go now
Uncle will go now, alright? Let's go
Salmah, come read
Hassan is good
- Yes, he is
Why did you tell on me to my father?
- I didn't. Salmah did.
Hassan, don't act so big
in this house. I hate you!
I hate you right from the tip of your hair
to the ends of your feet, do you know that?
Treacherous child! Go to your room! Go!
It's alright now.
Don't be bothered about him
Study well
Tunggu sekejap wahai kawan (/kanda)
Wait for awhile, my friend (/love)
Kerana hujan masih renyai
Because the rain is still falling
Tunggu sekejap
Wait awhile
Dalam pelukan asmara ku
In my passionate embrace
(verse not sung)
Jangan bimbang
Do not worry
(verse not sung)
Walaupun siang akan menjelma
Even if morning dawns
(verse not sung)
Malam ini
This night
Belum puas ku bercumbu dengan kanda
I haven't caressed you enough
Sayang
What a shame
Tunggu sekejap wahai kasih
Wait for awhile, my love
Tunggulah sampai hujan teduh
Wait till the rain stops falling
Mari ku dendang
Let me sing to you
Jangan mengenang orang jauh
Don't think of someone else
Jangan pula
Please don't
Jangan tinggalkan daku sorang
Don't leave me alone
Tunggu sekejap kasih
Wait awhile, love
Tunggu Wait
Hey, what are you guys doing here?
- Have a seat
Why aren't you drinking this coffee
- Who is going to pay?
Whatever you want, I'll pay
- You still haven't settled the last tab!
Still trying to tackle Salmah?
- Yes
Do you know, I'll be marrying her soon.
My father has met with her father.
Sure I'll have her.
Who doesn't know, Aziz?
Then what about Hassan?
- Who? Hassan?
You mean my step-brother?
Believe me, he doesn't stand a chance
You're serious?
Yes, when I get married
- I'll invite all of you
Go ahead. I really want to know if
Salmah truly likes you
- I'm feeling shy
You're all talk. If she really likes you,
go ahead and call her.
- Yeah, Aziz. If you're slow,
your step-brother might beat you to it
Hey, he is not my brother
- If you're correct you can whack this fellow
Let's go then
Aziz is a real coward
She has a voice of a male
Uncle?
- Who's that?
Aziz, sir
Where's Salmah?
- She's asleep
Aziz here wants to see her
Slept in the daytime
- It is already late at night
Can we come in, uncle?
- Maybe another night
Oh come on, uncle.
Enough of making noise in the
middle of the night. Just go home
Hey Hassan, don't get involved.
This is none of your business
Yes, it's true it's none of my business
But, what about the neighbour next door?
You better move along, if
you do not want any trouble
The whole village knows you guys
are strong and is scared of all of you.
Even I am scared.
Uncle, looks like you have a guard.
I'll let father know you have a new job
as a guard
You haven't slept yet?
- No, I haven't
Come here for awhile
I heard everything
- You did? Oh right, you weren't asleep
Is that all you're going to say to them?
- To whom?
To those fellows just now
- What else could I say?
Don't you have any feelings?
- Yes, I did feel a little insulted that's all
But why didn't you
express those feelings?
Sometimes we need to.
Sometimes we don't
But I've always seen you around
my house. Is there something you
wish to tell me?
Yes, in the morning I did.
But now I don't
Wait for awhile
On a quiet night like
this, do you feel anything?
I feel a bit warm
- Warm?!
I feel my hot above, but cold below
- That's because you're sitting on water
I'm tired speaking with you. Good night
Now you want to talk to me?
Will you get angry if I said something?
- No, I won't
Sure? - I'm sure
You swear? - I swear
When you left just now, you
forgot to blow out the lamp
The Royal Malay Regiment is recruiting!
This is a great opportunity. I want to join!
I want to join the Malay Regiment!
Later, I'll go tell my father
Father! Father!
Father, have you read today's newspaper?
- Not yet. Why?
The Royal Malay Regiment is recruiting
May I join the Army, father?
Yes, I give you my blessings
Hey you cowards! When are
you going to be soldiers?
All of you have no guts!
Minah, what did he say?
He wants to become a soldier
To tell you honestly, Aziz
cannot become a soldier
Whereas Hassan can
really become a soldier
Because he is fat and stronger
(has more meat on his bones)
You think Aziz isn't strong?
He is like a thin blade
of the 'lalang' weed
I can pull him out from
the ground very easily
You guys are talking
nonsense. Where's your rifle?
Aiyah, Minah. If you don't
believe me, then just watch
Father, is it true what he is saying?
Please give me your
permission to join the Army
I would rather you stayed
here at home to help me
I'm going back now
What your father say is true
If you become a soldier and Aziz
becomes a soldier, who would
take care of your father?
Don't feel sad about it.
I'm going back now
... those fellows are disturbing ...
Don't forget to send letters or news
About the situation in the Malay Regiment
- Alright, father
And if there is anything
you want, please tell me
Here is forty ringgit
Later I'll send more
- Thank you, father
Hurry and get ready. Your
friends are waiting at the station
Minah, he is leaving tonight?
Yes, he is leaving tonight by train
What a shame. Wouldn't it
be good if I could go too?
What ever for?
- To become a soldier, of course
Not everyone wants to become a soldier.
Whoever wishes to do so can become one
But you know the person in this house,
wishes Aziz to go instead of me.
I should go first, isn't that right?
I'd much prefer you being here instead
Where are you, Minah?
- Here, sir
The pants are still wet, sir
Do you expect me to bring
this to Port Dickson?
Why didn't you wash it yesterday?
I was only told this morning to wash it
- Yes, I told her to
Ah, I don't want this
I can do it by myself, don't bother
I'm going now
Father, are you following me to the station?
- Yes, I will be seeing you off
Safe journey, Aziz
- Whatever
When I'm gone, don't forget to ask
Hassan to help Minah in the kitchen
See you at the station, father
Aziz, you are always joking around
He wasn't joking
- What?
Actually, I am ashamed of living here
I want to go along with
Aziz to become a soldier
- What are you ashamed of?
You have to stay here
to help me in the field
But...
- Enough. That is my decision
Don't think of the matter anymore
Don't forget to send us letters
I won't forget. I'll send you letters
How do you do, sir
You're not here to say farewell?
- That is the reason I am here,
to wish you a safe journey
If that is true, give me that flower
as a symbol of remembrance
- Alright
As you head for this long journey,
take this flower to remember me by
- Thank you, Salmah
Friends, I shall go now
as the country beckons me
Don't forget, please watch over
your friend over there...
- Who's that?
That coward
Goodbye. Goodbye, Salmah
Goodbye, Father
- Goodbye, Aziz
Safe journey, Aziz
Take good care of yourself
- Alright, father
Alright friends, remember
to watch over that coward
(Hassan is a coward, quite unlike Aziz)
Don't get angry about something true
(...Hassan the coward...)
(...When I'm gone, don't forget to ask
Hassan to help Minah in the kitchen...)
(...Hey friends...)
(...Don't forget to
watch over that coward...)
What are you writing, Hassan?
- Nothing
What are you writing there?
- Nothing. Why aren't you asleep yet, Minah?
How am I going to sleep?
Been waiting for you to return
So what are you doing?
- Nothing important. Just a letter
I can figure it out
- What?
You are leaving us, aren't you?
What nonsense. I can't do anything
Anyway, how would you know
what I'm really thinking about?
Is it written on my face?
I've taken care of you since a child
I know everything about you
Alright, then what was I writing about?
- You want to become a soldier
Shh... don't speak so loudly
Yes, Minah. It's true
I want to join the Army
You are not angry, are you?
- No I'm not. That's because I already knew
That's why I have already packed
everything here for you.
Soap, money, handkerchief ...
You already knew I was going
- Of course!
Now hurry and finish writing your letter.
I'll give to your father tomorrow morning.
I've got to go
- Where are you going?
That's my own business. You keep quiet
Minah. Thank you.
Who is that?
- Minah
Is there anything,
especially at this hour?
Hassan is running away from home
Where is he going? He is going to
Port Dickson, to become a soldier
Did he request for anything?
- Nothing
Thank you, Minah
Here's some food
- I have enough here
Yes I know, but you will be travelling far.
So eat more it is alright
If I go, I will miss your cooking
That is alright. When you
return, I can cook for you again
Where's that letter of yours?
Please give this to father
- Alright
I'll go now
I want to talk to you
What are you doing here, so early?
- Minah told me you were leaving
Is that all?
- No
I want to personally
wish you a safe journey
Just like how you said
farewell to Aziz, isn't it?
I know that you are in love with Aziz
- No, I'm not
I went there to say farewell to you,
thinking you were the one becoming
the soldier. Instead it was Aziz.
Now I feel so happy
But I also feel sad
Why are you sad?
Because...
Don't you feel the same way as I do?
Yes, Salmah. Actually, I felt
that same way since a long time ago
At the same time, I
felt unworthy to anyone
Now is the time to
prove yourself, Hassan
But I'd rather those words
are spoken from your lips
If all this time my eyes have said so,
let my lips now tell you that 'I love you'
I feel so happy
Take this to remember me by
If you are in need of help, send
me this ring so that I will know
The bus is arriving. Goodbye, Salmah
- Goodbye, Hassan. Think of me
This shot isn't too good. But the
second shot was good. Understand?
- Understood
All the shots within this bold circle
constitutes 25 points. Which is great.
Understand?
- Yes, sir. I understand
How much is this?
- That's one ringgit twenty cents, sir
Is ninety cents alright?
- No
But all I have is ninety cents
- I can sell it to you at one ringgit,
if that is alright?
One ringgit? But I just have ninety cents.
Never mind, I'll come again tomorrow
Just buy it
I don't have enough money, Sergeant
- I'll pay
No, it's alright, sir
- I'll pay, don't worry about it
Thank you, sir
The blue one
- Alright
Is it pretty like your fiance?
- To me she is pretty, Sergeant
I'll pay you later...
- No, it's alright. It's alright
You do not need to pay me back
Thank you, sir
- You're welcome.
I really like you that's why
I shall not forget this
- It's really alright. You are really
a hardworking person
Thank you, sir
This shawl is beautiful.
So beautiful, Minah
The one you wore the other
day is much better
- But it is not the same as this one
I know what you mean
If it comes from someone you
like, it is definitely pretty
If your father asks, you just say
I bought it for you - Not as if a woman
would give another woman a shawl
I want to show you the picture again
So elegant. Don't you
think so too, Minah?
Why are you showing it to me for?
I've taken care of him since a child
Don't sulk. He is really
handsome and elegant
You're so kind hearted, Minah. But why
doesn't my hands meet when I hug you?
You are always kidding
around. I have to go now
When will you return to me?
Tunggu sekejap wahai kasih
Wait for awhile, my love
Kerana hujan masih renyai
Because the rain is still falling
Tunggu sekejap
Wait awhile
Dalam pelukan asmara ku
In my passionate embrace
Jangan bimbang
Do not worry
Walaupun siang akan menjelma
Even if morning dawns
Malam ini
This night
Belum puas ku bercumbu dengan dinda
I haven't caressed you enough
Tunggu sekejap wahai kasih
Wait for awhile, my love
Tunggulah sampai hujan teduh
Wait till the rain stops falling
Mari ku dendang
Let me sing to you
Jangan mengenang orang jauh
Don't think of someone faraway
Jangan pula
Please don't
Jangan tinggalkan daku sorang
Don't leave me alone
Tunggu sekejap kasih
Wait awhile, love
Tunggu
Wait
You're the new person who has
obtained the Corporal rank
- Yes
I will try my best to add another stripe
And if you get three?
- I might. Who knows?
You have been promoted to full
Corporal. That is really great!
I know you helped me there
- I really do believe in you,
being a full Corporal
Thank you, Sergeant
- You are welcome
All the best to you
- Thank you, Sergeant
Who told you to Stand Ea-Sy?
I said Stand at Ease.
Do you understand 'Stand at Ease'?
How long have you been here that
you still don't know the difference?
If you are not qualified to be a soldier.
Why don't you return to your village
and plant sweet potatoes?
Stand properly! Hoi, look in front!
What are you laughing at?
Thank you so much
- It's alright, we cooked quite a bit
We interrupt this programme...
The Japanese Air Force
have bombed Pearl Harbour
The American fort in the Pacific
A lot of damage was caused
The American Navy is now...
Pearl Harbour has been bombed?!
The Japanese airplanes
have bombed Singapore
And this is the final news. The Japanese
army have landed in Kota Bharu (Malaya)
The Japanese have landed in Kota Bharu?
Yes. The Japanese have
landed in Kota Bharu
Listen here, my fellow soldiers. Eat up.
Then we shall all head to the jungle
The Japanese are in Kajang now
- Yeah?
The Japs are approaching nearer and
nearer, sir. They are somewhere
in Kajang now   - Okay, Hassan
Sergeant, twenty
Japanese are approaching
Sentry, boss. Twenty Japanese
approaching, sir
- Twenty Japanese?
That makes us about even.
Right, get the men to stand two.
Pass the word, "Fire when ready"
- Right, sir
Put it out. Put it out
Cover that track
Quickly!
Pon, twenty Japanese are
approaching. Stand two.
What do you think? Can we win?
- Aren't I here, how can we lose?
Get them all back!
Who is there? Halt
I hope the Japanese didn't follow us
- Not many are familiar with this area, sir
That's good
I didn't think I'd see you again, Aziz
- Just ask the Lieutenant
Where are the rest of your fellows?
- They aren't able to come
They have all perished
in the battlefield
Food is ready. Go eat
- Thank you, Aziz
No problem
I was told that there is a Japanese lorry
no more than two miles from here
- Is that true, Aziz?
Yes, sir. But I told them earlier but they
didn't listen to me. So just forget about it
Why should we forget it, Aziz?
If that will give us an advantage,
why should we forget about it?
I don't have any power. I'm not a Sergeant
- What has it got to do with being
a Sergeant? You are making excuses
Hassan, sit down. Sit down. Tell us about it, Aziz
- Yes, sir. I shall tell about it if you wish to hear
Two miles from here is a Japanese
lorry. It has been there for four days
I've seen it, sir. There are a lot
of weapons and food supplies in there
I think it is best if we go for it, sir
When? Tonight. Everyone should go
Yes, we all go. If we sent one person,
even I would be afraid. Whosoever
does not wish to go, can stay behind
It is not that I do not want to go, Aziz
But the lorry has been there
for four days, for what purpose?
What if it is a trap?
Don't you know, the most useful human
being is one uses less of this (talk)
and more of this (action)?
So how, sir?
Sounds good. What do you think, Hassan?
It is a trap. A trap.
Want to go?
- Yes, sir
Alright, we move
Hassan, how then?
If everyone is going. I'm going too
- If you're going, then it will be fun
Alright, Pon
That's the lorry, sir
- What is in there?
If you want to know, let me go find out
- No, don't go
They might be leaving that as a bait for us
- I don't need to listen to your advice.
Let me go ahead, sir
Sure, but go with caution
- Alright, sir
Come back, Aziz! Come back!
Aziz, get up. Get up!
- Why did you return? I don't need
your help. It is better if you leave!
I don't want anything happening to you
- You better get away before
the Japanese capture you
I've already thought it over.
Now get up! Get up!
What's wrong? Get up
- My feet hurts
Just leave alone me here.
I'd much prefer to die here
I don't want to owe anyone, least to you
- Enough, you're talking too much
I'm still saving you. Sorry, yeah.
We'll head over there for safety
Open the door
What you want?
My name is Buang, master.
I know everything about the village
I can tell who is good or bad, master
That is great
Buang, why don't you work for me?
Become a Kempeitai
(Japanese military police)
Ok, master. I like that
(Take care of this new recruit)
Go and change into your new clothes
Go tell the village folks that
no one is to play the radio
If anyone plays the radio,
will be sent to Malacca for...
... their heads to be chopped off!
Alright, master
Master, is my rank high?
Oh, big. Very big just like me
Lieutenant, do we have some gauss?
What are you up to?
Gauss. For him. Okay?
I'll try and make it
You mad? You'll be shot before a yard
It is a chance I have to take
Somebody must call for help
There is nothing around
here, sir. Except grass
And we die like rats
- I'll look after the boys
And whoever you meet.
Tell them we are carrying on
- Very well, sir
Please take care of Aziz for me.
And tell him we will meet again
I'll be back
Thank you, sir
- Good luck
Gauss. Finished. Okay?
Hurry! Hurry!
Over there!
Who is that?
It is best if you just married me
I want you to wait here. Hassan is dead