That's a nice dress
you're wearing this morning, Misty.
Thanks, Dad.
Want the
entertainment section?
Not yet, Dad, thanks.
Got any donuts?
Of course not, Chip.
You know they're bad for the teeth.
Always the dentist.
Who wants fruit salad?
Oh, I do, please.
Misty, that's not gum
in your mouth, is it?
It's sugarless.
Misty, you know how I hate gum.
All that chomping and chewing.
I'm sorry, Mom.
All right.
Hey, Chip.
Mmm?
You think I could get 50 cents
for Village People on vinyl?
You might get a buck.
Carl can't believe how
much I make at swap meets.
Who, may I ask, is Carl?
Just a boy.
He's picking me up
this morning.
Here we go again.
He's really cute.
Misty, cute is not
enough. You know that.
She sure
can pick them.
He goes to college with me.
Leave her alone, Chip. I think
it's great Misty's got a new beau.
Chip, honey?
Thanks, Mom.
Listen to this.
"Hillside Strangler gets his
college degree in prison. "
That's nice, dear.
Nice? He should
have been executed.
Yeah,
the death penalty.
He killed people, Mom.
We all have
our bad days.
You'd probably date him. "He's cute!"
All right,
that's enough.
Hey, Dad, have you ever seen
Henry: Portrait of a Serial Killer?
Oh, sure, Chip.
I most certainly have not.
You've been working in
that video shop too long.
Mind your
own business.
Well, it better hadn't be
interfering with your schoolwork.
I do great
in school, Dad.
Well, your mother
has PTA today.
We'll see what your teacher has to say.
Oh, Mom,
I hate Mr. Stubbins.
Don't say "hate," dear.
Hate is a very serious word.
There! Scrambled eggs, anybody?
Who on earth...
Mrs. Sutphin?
Yes.
I'm Detective Pike.
This is Detective Gracey.
Oh, come in.
I'm Dr. Eugene Sutphin. What
seems to be the trouble, Officers?
Is there a killer loose?
No, son.
Nothing that exciting.
Oh, this is our son, Chip,
and our daughter, Misty.
Hi.
Jeez...
Oh.
Officer, I'm sorry, but we
don't allow gum in this house.
Sorry, ma'am.
We're investigating obscene
phone calls and mail threats
to a certain
Mrs. Dottie Hinkle.
I know Dottie.
She lives right down the street.
Could you take
a look at this and...
Tell us of anyone who
might be responsible?
I should warn you, this
note contains language.
Oh, my!
That...
That is the limit.
Let me see.
No, Son. This is a matter for adults.
Officers, I have never even
said the "P" word out loud,
let alone have written it down.
No woman would.
Officers, life doesn't
have to be ugly.
See, look at
the birds out there.
Listen to their call...
Chip, there's your ride.
Hey, I'm gonna be late
for work. Goodbye, honey.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Hi, Scotty.
Thanks for your time, everybody.
Bye, Detective Pike.
Hi, Birdie!
Hi, Mr. And Mrs. Sutphin.
That's Birdie. She's a
horror nut, just like my son.
Oh, Birdie, this is Detective
Gracey and Detective Pike.
Hiya, boys.
Bye-bye, honey!
Good morning, Scott.
Hey, Misty, look what I
got. A Pee-Wee Herman doll.
Can you sell it for
me at the flea market?
Wow! Still in the box! I sure can!
Oh, God,
here comes Carl.
You must be Mrs. Sutphin. Carl Pageant.
Oh, yes.
Misty's date.
Well, more
of a friend, really.
Take it easy, man. Bye.
See what Birdie gave me
to sell at the flea market?
That guy's a weirdo.
Come on, let's go.
I'll take it.
Bye, Mom.
Bye, honey.
Oh, Detectives? Here's something
you should be interested in.
A grown boy who doesn't
wear his seatbelt.
Christ, that one was
Beaver Cleaver's mother.
Oh, leave her alone.
Mrs. Sutphin's about as
normal and nice a lady
as we're ever
gonna find.
Hello?
Is this
the Cocksucker residence?
God damn you!
Stop calling here.
Isn't this
4215 Pussy Way?
You bitch!
Now let me check the
zip code. 212-fuck you!
Beverly? Beverly, darling? You home?
The police are tracing
this call this very minute.
Well, Dottie Hinkle, then why
aren't they here, huh, fuck-face?
Fuck you!
Beverly, you home?
I know you are.
Beverly?
Hmm.
Didn't I just
say fuck you?
I beg your pardon.
Who is this?
Mrs. Wilson from
the telephone company.
I understand you're having problems
with an obscene phone caller?
Yes, I am. I'm sorry, Mrs. Wilson,
but this is driving me crazy.
I've had my number
changed twice already.
I'm a divorced woman.
Please help me.
Beverly?
Well, what exactly does this
sick individual say to you?
I can't say the words out
loud. I don't use bad language.
Oh, well, I know it's difficult,
but we need to know the exact words.
I'll try.
Cocksucker. That's what she calls me.
Listen to your filthy
mouth, you fucking whore!
God damn you!
Motherfucker.
Cocksucker!
Beverly?
Rosemary.
Are you all right?
Oh, yes, of course. I'm fine.
Oh, how nice.
You remembered.
It's the least
I could do.
I heard shouting.
Oh, it's that
cable TV company.
You know
how they are.
Did you hear about poor Dottie Hinkle?
Yes, I did.
It's terrifying.
The police were at
my house this morning.
Now who on earth would want
to harass poor Dottie Hinkle?
Bye-bye.
But, Mr. Stubbins, my
son studies every night.
He's trying as hard as he can.
Well, some teenagers just aren't
college material, Mrs. Taplotter.
It's nothing
to cry over.
Now, there are
other parents waiting.
Thank you for taking
the time to come to PTA.
Hi, Betty.
Oh, hi, Beverly.
Oh, I love
your outfit.
Oh, thanks.
Hi.
Liz Claiborne.
Well, Mrs. Sutphin, where's
that husband of yours?
Feeling a little
down in the mouth?
Oh, Ralph.
You're so funny.
Oh, brother.
Mrs. Sutphin?
Yes, right here.
Mrs. Sutphin, I'm Paul
Stubbins, Chip's math teacher.
Oh, it's so nice
to meet you.
Here's a little something that I made.
Oh.
Fruitcake. Well, thank
you, Mrs. Sutphin.
Have a seat.
Oh, yes.
Well, Chip's off to a
fine start this year.
He's focused, conscientious, he participates
actively in classroom discussions...
He's a good boy.
There is one
big problem, though.
What is it?
His unhealthy obsession
with sick horror films.
Oh, no.
Chip's the assistant
manager at a video store...
That's no excuse
for a morbid imagination.
I caught him drawing
this in class last week.
Is there a problem at home?
Of course not.
Divorce?
Alcoholic relative?
Tell me, did Chip torture
animals when he was young?
No, he did not.
Mr. Stubbins, we are a
loving and supportive family.
Well, you're doing something
wrong, Mrs. Sutphin.
I'd recommend
therapy for your son.
Thank you for taking
the time to come to PTA.
Watch this.
No, thanks.
Scotty, watch this.
It's a sheep's tongue.
This shit is sickening.
Come on, put on some pussy.
Look, dickhead...
Blood Feast.
The Citizen Kane
of gore movies.
I don't know what it is about
today, but I feel great! Cookie?
Excuse me,
Mrs. Sutphin.
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Mrs. Sutphin.
Hi, guys.
Look how fake
that looks.
Oh, you kids. Here, have
a cookie and run on home.
But, Mom,
the video's not over.
Don't you
"but, Mom" me.
Mr. Stubbins seems to think
that these silly movies
are interfering
with your schoolwork.
Oh, boy.
Mom, Mr. Stubbins sucks.
Man! That one made me puke!
It's supposed
to make you puke.
You forgot something.
Are we leaving?
Yes, you are.
Bye, Mrs. Sutphin.
Bye, Birdie.
Bye, Bird-Brain.
See you, Scotty.
Now, Chip, honey, I know how
hard it is being a teenager.
I understand. I'm your
mother and I love you.
Mom...
Oh, could we watch
that scene again?
You know the one, where he
rips her heart out? Please?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the perfect meatloaf.
It looks
good, Mom.
Nothing like a home-cooked meal, honey.
Oh, Misty, I made you your
favorite, sesame broccoli.
You know, Carl says if I lose 10 pounds,
he'll take me to the University of
Maryland Memorial Day Beach Blast.
Well, honey, I think that's
great if you wanna lose weight,
but I think you should
do it for yourself,
not for some boy
you hardly even know.
Carl's a jerk.
He certainly drives like a jerk.
Carl makes me happy and that
threatens this family, doesn't it?
It doesn't threaten me,
honey. I'm happy.
I'm happy, too.
We just want
you to be happy.
I'm so happy
I could shit.
Chip, you know how I
hate the brown word.
Beverly! Beverly!
Beverly!
That's Rosemary.
Something must be wrong.
Turn on the news. A teacher at
your school has been murdered.
Murdered?
Who?
A Mr. Stuber
or Stubin...
Mr. Stubbins!
That's my math teacher. Dad...
Which channel?
It's on
all of them!
Police claim the driver
of the hit-and-run vehicle
Ran down the teacher
in cold blood. Hello?
Did you hear?
What happened?
This is so cool. It's
just like a horror movie.
It's on. I'll call you back. Okay, bye.
Mr. Paul Stubbins
was 38 years old.
Whoever did this should
get the death penalty.
So far only one eyewitness has surfaced.
Young lady,
what did you see?
It was a blue car.
That's Lu-Ann Hodges.
She's a stoner.
A what?
A pothead, Mom.
A blue station wagon.
That's like
your car, Beverly.
Rosemary, I'm not that bad a driver.
...in a second, man.
It flattened Mr. Stubbins
just like a pancake!
Oh, God, man,
puke time, man.
Oh, look
at her hair.
Blood was all over
the place and...
Turn it off, honey.
I can't believe
Mr. Stubbins is dead.
You said
you hated him.
Well, he was an asshole,
but he didn't deserve to die.
I can't stop thinking
about that poor teacher.
Well, good night, honey.
Good night, dear.
Don't read
too late.
We've got a big day
with the birds tomorrow.
Oh, I've identified
every little birdie that we're gonna
see tomorrow on the Eastern Shore.
Good night, honey.
Hey, don't I get
a good night kiss?
I thought with all this
sadness, you wouldn't wanna...
We have to concentrate on life, Eugene.
It's all right
with me, Beverly.
You want to, honey?
You think
the kids are awake?
We could be
very quiet.
I love that
you're my wife.
You're not so bad yourself, cuckoo bird.
You bring me
such peace.
Don't wake
the kids.
Oh, honey,
you are hot tonight.
Oh, yeah!
Quiet!
Yeah!
Oh, get it! Honey, I'm ready!
Now! Now...
Oh, yeah! Yes!
Now!
Oh, there's DeeDee. Oh,
she's my favorite starling.
She's here every morning for breakfast.
Well, honey, starlings are
originally from Europe, you know.
No wonder
DeeDee's hungry.
It's a long journey all
the way here to Baltimore.
Hello?
Eugene,
this is Ralph Sterner.
I've got a
dental emergency here.
I mean, this goddamn
tooth is killing me.
Well, Mr. Sterner, if
you'll just call my office,
I'm sure we can see you on Monday.
Monday?
Eugene, this is Betty Sterner.
He'll die
by Monday.
I mean, the roots are infected.
He might have
a heart attack.
All right, Mrs. Sterner. 10:00.
I'm sorry, honey, but the birds
will still be there next week.
It's okay.
I understand.
I'll go
fix breakfast.
Chip!
God! Mom,
what's the matter?
Oh, it's just time
to get up, that's all.
I don't want you
to be late for work.
You scared me.
Misty, honey,
what's wrong?
I'm stood up.
I'll kill
that bastard.
I mean it.
He should be dead, that lousy creep.
He told me he'd be here. I'll kill him.
Don't use words unless you
mean them, Misty, honey.
It's him!
No, no.
It's the police.
Good morning, Officers.
Good morning,
Mrs. Sutphin.
Hi, Detective Pike.
Morning, Misty.
Mrs. Sutphin, I presume you know
about the death of Mr. Stubbins.
Oh, yes, yes. A fine
man, a good teacher.
Contusions, fractures, rupture
of numerous vital organs.
What a mess.
Oh, no, no, honey.
That's Scotty.
Scotty, who doesn't
wear his seatbelt.
Good morning, Detectives.
Nightmare on
Calverton Court.
The Maryland
Teacher Massacre.
It's not funny, son.
Did you drive your car to the PTA
meeting yesterday, Mrs. Sutphin?
Yes, I did.
Detectives, what is this all about?
I know this sounds weird, Mr. Sutphin,
but the Department of Motor
Vehicles computer shows
only one blue
station wagon
registered to a parent of
any of Mr. Stubbins' pupils.
Surely, you don't think that
Beverly was involved in this?
She did it!
Aimed the car right at Mr.
Stubbins and mowed him down!
Shut up,
Scotty.
Well, as I understand it, the
only eyewitness was a drug user.
I got somebody you
could run over, Mother.
Misty, that's
a terrible thing to say.
Detectives, it's time for you to leave.
My wife knows nothing about
this terrible accident.
Murder, honey.
Oh! Now here's a babe.
Let's see that,
young man.
"P," as in...
People who don't mind
their own business.
Darling,
it's Rosemary Ackerman's.
Oh, you can tell
by the subscription label.
I don't like to read about
movies. They're so violent.
Besides, I always recycle my magazines.
daybreak if you wanna believe
It can be daybreak
Ain't no time to grieve
'Cause it's daybreak
If you'll only believe
And let it shine,
shine, shine
Wait for me, boys! Here! All
rinsed and ready to recycle.
Morning,
Mrs. Sutphin.
Good morning, Gus.
Good morning, Sloppy.
You know, you boys work so
hard for the environment,
I thought I'd bring you something.
A little drink
never hurt anybody.
Thank you, ma'am.
Damn,
that's good stuff.
You believe that goddamn litterbugger?
I have told her
and told her.
It takes 90 to 100 years
for a tin can to decompose
and she still
won't recycle.
It cost the taxpayers
millions of dollars last year,
but she don't care nothing
about the national budget.
I hate Mrs. Ackerman.
I hate her, too.
I hate her guts.
You know, somebody ought to kill her.
Yeah.
Give her a
Happy face,
and then recycle her.
For the sake of this
planet, somebody just might.
But your boyfriend was
convicted of killing 12 people.
I don't judge him.
I just don't get it. I mean,
how can you love a mass murderer?
Easy. He's handsome, he's famous
and we get conjugal visits.
Serial hags. Women who
love men who mutilate.
We'll be right back after
this, so please stay tuned.
Turn it off. Violence
is everywhere these days.
It's just Beverly.
Come in, Beverly!
Oh, she scared me.
Hi!
Hi, Rosemary.
Would you
like a beer?
Oh, no, no. Not me. Thank
you. Just a little coffee.
Oh, Dottie, I'm so sorry.
I heard about your troubles.
It's not fair.
No.
Mmm. Oh, thank you.
Are those
pussy willows?
Dried ones.
Aren't they pretty?
What did you
just say?
Pussy willows, Dottie.
Oh, my goodness!
What are you doing?
I didn't do it!
My Franklin Mint
Fabergé egg!
Dottie didn't mean to
be such a clumsy ox.
You're sorry
aren't you, Dottie?
Rosemary, I did not break your egg!
She did!
Dottie, you could
at least apologize.
I collect Franklin Mint!
Well, we'll go right
to the antique market
and we'll find
you another one.
Now, Misty tells me there's a whole
booth filled with Franklin Mint stuff.
But... Dottie, you'll
lock up, won't you?
But... But... I'll take
care of poor Rosemary.
But I heard her voice. It's her!
Mr. Sterner, you've lost a tiny filling.
I have to drill deeply enough
to remove all the decay.
All right, go ahead, but
be careful. It really hurts.
Open... Wider... Very wide.
Mrs. Sterner, you can't go
back there. Mrs. Sterner...
God damn you! You're trying
to hurt me on purpose.
Are you okay, Ralph?
Mrs. Sterner, please
stay in the waiting room.
Help me, Betty, he's worse than
the dentist in The Marathon Man.
I'm sorry to interrupt,
Doctor Sutphin,
but there are
two police detectives
waiting to see you
in your office.
Fine.
Good morning.
What is it, Officers?
My patient
is waiting.
Doctor Sutphin, is
your wife a big reader?
Bird books, mostly.
Like these we found in her garbage.
Urge to Kill, Mass Murder in Houston?
I'm sure those are my son Chip's books.
No, they're your wife's.
We checked.
She bought them at the
Browse and Learn Book Shop,
along with
a few other titles.
Helter Skelter.
Hunting Humans.
MasterCard reference number 7876,
dated February 5th.
This is ridiculous!
Doctor Sutphin,
is your wife mental?
Damn these gnats.
I hate them.
Always something, isn't
it? Can I help you?
Thanks for not
buying anything.
Misty, honey.
Now lighten up.
It's not the customer's fault
that Carl stood you up.
Young man, this Fabergé egg is chipped.
Yes, ma'am, it is.
I'll give you $50.
That's a Franklin Mint piece. $100.
$100? Franklin Mint or not,
that's damaged goods.
Hello. This
is a very special doll.
This veil is from a gown that came
from a bride who was left at the altar.
Only one of its kind.
I'll take this
instead.
Oh, that's
a nice one, huh?
Itll be cold
before you know it.
$3? I guess that's how
I must have marked it.
Thank you.
Did you find your Franklin
Mint egg, Rosemary, darling?
Well, I saw one, but it
was really overpriced.
Oh, want me to keep this
under the table for you?
If you don't mind.
It was on sale.
Oh, Franklin Mint.
Honey, please,
for my bedroom shelf.
Okay. Wrap it up
for the little lady.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'm thirsty.
What do you want?
The Colts.
Banner, please.
Thank you.
Honey, I have to
take a piss.
There you go.
I can't believe it.
It's fucking Don Knotts.
He's the coolest. Thanks. Bye.
Honey! Look!
I made a killing.
Mom,
watch the booth.
I want to see
what's going on.
Sure.
I hope
nothing's wrong.
Beverly, honey,
you've got some
doo-doo on your shoe.
I hate that.
There was a lady in
the men's room, I swear.
A pretty little lady in
the stall right next to me.
She must
know him.
Carl!
What happened?
I don't know...
That's $158.
New York money
good enough for you?
Certainly.
Thank you.
Mother!
Mother, it's Carl.
He's dead.
How horrible.
Oh, I just sold
the Pee-Wee Herman doll.
Mother, didn't you hear me?
Someone murdered Carl in the men's
room. I just saw his dead body.
You got your wish, dear.
I didn't wish that.
I didn't want him dead.
Beverly, it's me, Ted Bundy.
It's late at night, six
days before my execution
and it's lonely here
on death row.
Updating
the story of the hour,
the young man
brutally murdered
a short time ago
in the men's room
of the Antique Traders Mart
has been identified as
22-year-old Carl Pageant of Towson.
No, no,
no! No!
Chip! Our mother is Charles Manson.
I'm not kidding.
Carl stood me up
this morning
and then he was murdered
at the flea market.
Murdered?
Yes, murdered!
You said you hated
your teacher yesterday
and he was murdered, too.
Look, I don't know.
Maybe Mom's nuts.
That's a cool idea, Misty.
Hey, let's make a gore movie
about Mom, better yet, a TV series.
Hey, can I
borrow your mother?
My aunt's coming over for dinner
and she's always
getting on my nerves.
My stepfather's
an asshole.
She could kill him.
- How about Mrs. Ackerman?
We all hate her. Who's
gonna be the next victim?
No, stop it!
It's not funny.
Mom might do it.
Somebody else might die.
Dinner is served.
Let's say grace and
pray for the strength
to understand
the terrible tragedies
of the last few days.
Amen to that.
It's been a crazy day, hasn't it?
Bless, O Lord, this food to our
use and our self to thy service.
Amen.
Hungry, honey?
Dottie Hinkle was right.
It is Beverly Sutphin.
I tell you, I saw blood right
there on the bottom of her shoes.
Not exactly blood... It was gore,
hanging there like a runny nose.
Nice as pie, she was to me.
And then I hear her say it.
Say what, ma'am?
"Are those... " I can't
say the word out loud.
Could you tell
a policewoman
the exact words
she used?
Maybe.
It's okay. Nobody's gonna hurt you.
Come on.
Let it out.
"Pussy," that's what she
said to me. "Pussy willows. "
You know, Mom...
Mmm?
Scotty thinks
you're the killer.
Does he?
You know, for somebody who
doesn't wear his seatbelt,
Scotty sure is nosy.
Oh, just a second.
She's gone!
She's gonna
kill Scotty!
Get in the car,
both of you.
Dad, you don't think
she did it, do you?
I do.
Mom's gone crazy.
Your mother may have some
problems. That's all, Chip.
Come on, hurry.
Detective Gracey
and all units.
Suspect's family headed
east on Calverton.
Repeat, east on Calverton.
Turn right on
Timonium Road, Dad.
I will, I will.
Hurry.
daybreak If you'll only believe
It can be daybreak
Ain't no time to grieve
'Cause it's daybreak
If you'll only believe
And let it shine,
shine, shine...
If Mom is psycho, Scotty
will still be okay, won't he?
We hope so, Son.
And no matter what your mother
is, we'll love her anyway.
This is Scotty's, Dad. His
parents aren't home. Come on.
Scotty?
What was that?
I didn't
hear anything.
Got any dessert?
Doctor Sutphin said
no sweets for you.
Yeah, well,
what's he know?
How to send a bill!
I'll get the door.
Suspect's family
entering house.
Send backup
to 400 Sycamore Street.
I have a feeling
old Mom's inside.
Wheel of Fortune!
Ralph, Wheel of Fortune's on!
I'm still eating!
The world's
most popular game show...
Come on up, honey,
before the kids get home.
May I have a "P"?
Mmm-hmm.
A couple of "P's. "
Ralph!
What is it, Betty?
I think we've got
mice or something.
No, no, no. We paid the exterminator.
Betty?
It's upstairs.
I'm going in. Over.
It's the door
on the left.
Break it down, Dad.
Break it down!
Scotty, man...
Police! Freeze!
Betty? Betty, answer me!
Ralph...
Help! Help me! Help me, please! Please!
Help me, somebody!
Home, sweet home!
Everything's fine, kids.
I can't believe I thought my
own mother was a murderess.
I'm kind of disappointed she isn't.
For a while there it was
like being in the movies.
Anybody for dessert?
Mmm. Strawberries.
Let's go.
Dad, you said it would be
okay. Make them go away.
This is embarrassing.
Just pay no attention to the police.
It's all
a terrible mistake.
Do you think we'll get
on A Current Affair?
Sutphin family proceeding
west on Seminary Avenue. Over.
Beverly ain't going
nowhere this time.
She's headed for church.
I say we nail her. Over.
CAPTAIN LUECKER
Negative.
DA says no bust
until lab report is back
matching
suspect's fingerprints
on true crime book with those
on scissors and fire poker.
The senseless
killing last night of a Towson couple,
Ralph and Betty Sterner,
brings to a total
of four murders
police feel may have been committed
by Baltimore's first serial killer.
Information is still
sketchy at this point...
Beverly...
Not the Sterners!
Oh, it's a shame,
but they should have brushed
their teeth, shouldn't they?
This just in.
Police lieutenant
Ronald Habbler
has publicly named a suspect in the
serial killer case, and it's a shocker!
She, that's right,
she has been identified
as Beverly R. Sutphin
of 2815 Calverton Court...
Oh, really...
God. Now I'll never
get a boyfriend.
Beverly, I've read all
about this. Is it menopause?
Oh, honey...
Tell me the truth, Mom.
Really, it's okay with me.
Are you a serial killer?
Chip, the only cereal I know
anything about is Rice Krispies.
Don't worry, honey, we're gonna
get you good psychiatric help.
Well,
look at that.
And in the
house of God.
Who does she think she is?
Gus, Sloppy. Hi.
Hi.
Chip!
Hey, what's up, Birdie?
Can you come...
We said no,
remember?
Birdie, please, you can't
talk to him. Now, please...
Stay with us, honey.
She's awful!
She can't stay here.
Good morning, ladies.
So tell me, Mrs. Sutphin,
are you Serial Mom?
What?
No comment.
Serial Mom! Wow!
She's headed in, over.
Please stand.
Blessed be God, Father,
Son and Holy Spirit.
And blessed be his
kingdom, now and forever.
Amen.
Hallelujah!
Christ has risen.
The Lord
is risen indeed.
Hallelujah.
Bless the Lord, who
forgiveth all our sins...
This is Captain
Luecker from Homicide.
Lab reports confirm Sutphin
latent print of index finger
on true-crime book
matches those latent prints
lifted from murder weapons.
Bingo, boys!
Bust the bitch!
Copy.
Jesus said nothing to
condemn capital punishment
as he hung on the cross, did he?
No...
If ever there was a time to go on
record against the death penalty,
wasn't it that night?
Capital punishment is already
the law in the state of Maryland.
So what are we waiting for, fellow
Christians? Let's just do it.
Amen!
How you doing?
All standing.
Let us pray and humbly confess
our sins unto Almighty God.
Most merciful God, we confess
that we have sinned against thee,
by what we have done and by what we
have left undone. We are truly sorry
and we humbly repent so that
we may delight in thy will
and walk in thy ways
to the glory of thy name.
Amen.
Beverly? Beverly!
Misty? Beverly?
There she is!
Beverly!
Misty! Misty...
Misty! Come on...
You guys, come on!
Come on, come on, come on!
Please, Mrs. Sutphin.
Hurry... Get in...
We'll show them, Mom!
We'll go on 60 Minutes!
You know, you're bigger
than Freddy and Jason now,
only you're
a real person!
Do you think
I need a lawyer?
You need
an agent.
An agent?
Hey! Hey!
Is your wife a murderess?
No comment!
Please, my wife is missing.
I'm worried sick about her!
Hey... Hey, Misty.
Just a couple of shots, okay? I'm
Howell Hawkins from the Baltimore Sun.
Hi, Howell.
Misty Sutphin,
get in this car!
We're tailing
Sutphin husband and daughter
but Serial Mom
is nowhere in sight.
She got away, boys!
God damn it! Find her!
In here, Mom.
But, Chip...
Come on, Mom,
I have to open...
Oh, now,
this is so silly.
Bye, Mom.
Customers! Get the door.
Good morning,
Mrs. Jenson.
Good morning.
Haven't you had enough
violence, Chip Sutphin?
Turn that filth off.
Sorry, ma'am.
Do you have
the musical, Annie?
Sure do. Did you bring back Ghost Dad?
There you go.
I just love
Bill Cosby pictures.
Miss Jenson,
I've told you,
you have to rewind the
tapes before returning them.
Why?
Because
it's the rules.
I don't feel like
rewinding them.
You see that sign? It's a
dollar fine for not rewinding
and this time I'm gonna charge
you. $2.99 plus $1 is $3.99.
Keep the change,
you son of a psycho!
What a bitch!
It's the influence of all
those family films. Right, Mom?
Hey, Mom!
Mrs. Sutphin?
Mother? Mother?
Oh, shit!
You don't think she
would... She wouldn't...
What's Miss Jenson's address?
Jenkins... Jenson. Emma
Lou Jenson, 19 Clark Avenue.
That's right up
the street.
Come on,
just in case.
Come on, Birdie,
let's go!
What is it, Sylvester? A birdie?
Shh. Mommy's watching Annie.
The sun'll come out
Tomorrow
Bet your bottom
dollar that tomorrow
Quiet, Sylvester!
Nobody's there.
Come on,
lick Mommy's feet.
Get them all wet.
And the sorrow
Till there's none
Come on, Birdie.
Come on.
Number 19.
That's it.
Come on.
Over here!
Chip, over here!
Tomorrow
So you gotta hang on
Till tomorrow
Come what may
Come on...
Just thinking about
Tomorrow
Clears away the cobwebs
And the sorrow
Till there's none!
When I'm stuck with a day
That's gray
And Lonely
I just stick out my chin
And grin and say
Get up there, get up
there. Is she in there?
Oh!
The sun'll come out
Tomorrow
So you gotta hang on
Till tomorrow
Come what may
Tomorrow! Tomorrow!
I love you, tomorrow!
She's singing Annie.
The sun'll come out
Tomorrow
So you gotta hang on
Till tomorrow
Come what may
Tomorrow! Tomorrow!
I love you, tomorrow!
You're only a day away
Rewind!
Oh, my God! No!
I saw blood,
and it's brown!
It's not red like in the
horror movies, but brown!
Is Mom in there?
No!
It wasn't like the gore
movies at all! It was real.
Come on! Birdie, let's cut through here!
Wear your seatbelt!
It's the law!
Out, please.
What the fuck?
Yes, ma'am.
Dear God, I promise I'll never
watch another sex film again!
I promise! I promise!
It's okay.
Dad! Dad...
Have you seen Mom?
No, have you?
Scotty?
Oh, my God!
Get in!
All units, Serial Mom is
headed south on Keswick.
Proceed with caution. She
is armed and fucking nuts!
Oh, shit!
Mike! Mike!
Let me in, okay?
Hey! ID.
Can I give it
to you inside?
Hey, buddy, nobody gets in without ID.
Birth date?
December 14, 1972.
Please!
Okay, go ahead.
I won't flinch
and I won't break a sweat
When I taste
the cyanide gas
Gas, gas
Only way you're gonna shut me up
Hey!
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Hey, look, it's her.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Who?
It's the murder lady,
the one on TV.
Excuse me. Cool. Is she in a band?
Watch me wither
through the glass
Smiling as I sip
the last gas
Justifiable homicide
Almond blossom-scented cyanide
Gas chamber
The police are after me.
I beg your pardon.
Hey, hey,
hey, hey!
Hey...
You're Serial Mom.
Yes, I guess I am.
Well, come on in,
lady. Quick!
...you'll keep me down Only way
you think you'll keep me down
Coming through.
Thank you.
Help. Help!
Excuse me, please.
I think maybe you better lock the car.
Can't stop now. Is my mom in there?
Dad, now, look cool.
It's Hammerjacks.
Excuse me.
Kids! Put me down!
Put me down!
Your God says
thou shalt not kill
But here you are
dropping the pill
Legal system,
what a sham
Put me down!
Flying colors
on the final exam
Gas chamber
Only way you're gonna shut me up
Buckle up, Scotty!
Oh! Mrs. Sutphin! No! I'll
wear my seatbelt, Mrs. Sutphin.
Holy fucking shit!
Hi!
Move it!
You're under arrest!
Honey?
Shut up.
Serial Mom! Serial Mom!
Serial Mom! Serial Mom! Serial
Mom! Serial Mom! Serial Mom!
Serial Mom! Serial Mom! Serial Mom!
Can she
get a fair jury?
Misty!
Look this way!
Please just
let us through.
...your wife's innocence,
Mr. Sutphin? Please!
How does it feel
to have a killer mom?
Mr. Sutphin, how does your wife feel?
Beverly is devastated
by the charges
against her.
Just now I found a peanut
Found a peanut, right now
Cracked it open,
cracked it open
Cracked it open
just now...
Didn't I see you
at Hinckley?
I was there.
I thought so.
My husband thought
I was crazy.
She is.
Today we're covering day one
of the trial of Serial Mom...
Look!
Here they come!
Stop the violence? What is
this? Who are you working for?
What do you think
her chances are?
Excuse me!
Mr. Sutphin! Coming through.
Quiet in the courtroom.
This court is now in session.
Oh, hello, jury people.
I'm Beverly Sutphin.
Oh, I like
your jacket.
Mrs. Sutphin,
I said quiet.
Honey, hi! Oh, kids, are
you doing your homework?
You are accused
of multiple murders.
This is a court of law,
not a coffee klatch.
Mr. Nazlerod,
your opening statement.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Good morning, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury.
My name is Timothy Nazlerod
and I hope we can be friends.
I have to tell you at the outset,
however, that this is not a pretty case.
This defendant,
Beverly Sutphin,
is a woman
evil to the core,
a rotten apple,
if you will,
who beyond any reasonable doubt
killed six innocent people.
That's right,
she murdered them.
Well, they sort of deserved it. Shh.
Evilly and with
full premeditation,
with a speeding car,
a fire poker,
A pair of scissors,
a toppled air conditioner,
the lethal flames
from an aerosol can
and yes, even a leg of lamb.
Ladies and gentlemen of
the jury, this defendant,
this Beverly Sutphin,
she is not a woman.
She is a monster!
Defense attorney, your
opening statement for the jury?
And let's not
take all day, either.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm Herbie Hebden
and you and I have a
tough job ahead of us.
I've known the Sutphin
family for 16 years.
Dad, Eugene,
is my dentist.
Chip and Misty played
with my own children.
But I found out that I don't
know Beverly Sutphin at all.
Psst.
No one really knows
Beverly Sutphin. You see...
Psst.
Beverly Sutphin
is insane.
Yes, she committed
these terrible crimes,
but that doesn't make her a bad person.
Your Honor, I would
like to make a motion.
I wish to fire my
attorney and defend myself.
Beverly Sutphin is not
guilty by reason of insanity.
Your Honor, I have the right to
defend myself. I've read the law books.
Ware v. State, 1964
and Schuette v. State, 1962.
Mrs. Sutphin, the defendant who has herself
for a lawyer has a fool for a client.
Counsel, approach the bench.
I don't think
this is a good idea.
Oh, yeah. Oh, no. It's okay.
That's my ruling.
Thank you very much.
Mrs. Sutphin,
I have no legal choice
but to let you take over
as your own attorney.
How do you plead?
Not guilty,
Your Honor.
Order! Order in the courtroom.
Quiet down or I'll clear this room out!
I call to the stand
Dottie Hinkle.
Raise your right hand, please.
Do you hereby solemnly swear or
affirm under the penalties of perjury
that the testimony you are
about to give will be the truth,
the whole truth and
nothing but the truth? I do.
Thank you.
Mrs. Hinkle, did you ever receive
any obscene telephone calls?
I certainly did.
And did you recognize
the voice of the caller?
Not at first.
But then I heard
the same inflection
in a voice
at a social gathering.
And I put two and two together.
Whose voice
was it, Dottie?
It was her, Beverly
Sutphin, sitting right there.
I'm lucky
I'm not dead.
Mrs. Hinkle,
do you drink?
No, I don't.
So you were not drunk
when you received those
allegedly obscene phone calls?
I certainly was not.
Now, you mean to tell me that the
day I came over to Mrs. Ackerman's,
the day you claim
you recognized my voice,
you were not drinking?
One beer with lunch
is hardly drinking.
So you do drink?
Socially.
I'll have a beer.
So you admit
you just lied.
No, I don't,
you bitch!
Watch your mouth,
Mrs. Hinkle.
Did you see that? She just
said, "Fuck you" to me!
Let the record show
I am merely standing here.
Fuck you,
too, you whore.
I'm warning you,
Mrs. Hinkle.
One more obscenity and I'm gonna
charge you with contempt of court.
Mrs. Hinkle,
are you insane?
No, I'm not,
you motherfucker!
Mrs. Hinkle, I
find you guilty of contempt
and I sentence you to a $1,000
fine and five days in jail!
Cocksucker!
Lock her up!
You lousy pig fucker! You bitch!
You ugly whore! Let go!
Come on, they're going quickly!
"Serial Mom" t
- shirts. Get them here.
$12, while they last, plus tax.
MasterCard and Visa.
I'll take two.
All right, ma'am.
I wish they'd had something like
this at the Kennedy kid trial.
Sign right here.
Signature and home phone.
You've read about it in the paper!
Serial Mom.
She's Beverly Sutphin
and she's my mom!
Listen, you tell Geraldo
to go to hell, okay?
I don't care what Jeffrey
MacDonald's people got. He's old news.
We fly first class or we don't
do the show. It's that simple.
Are you
Chip Sutphin?
Hold on a sec.
Yeah, I am, but you're gonna
have to speak with my agent.
Your mom killed my brother. Come on!
Come on...
God...
Jeez, man!
It's cool. It's cool, all right?
Your Carl's brother,
right?
That's right.
I'm sorry he's dead.
But have you
signed off yet?
You mean
for TV or print?
TV, man. Suzanne Somers is
interested in playing my mom.
Suzanne Somers?
Who's gonna
play my brother?
I wonder if Jason Priestley's available?
Miss Hodges, could you describe the car?
The one you saw run over
Mr. Stubbins in cold blood.
I seen that movie.
It was on cable.
Miss Hodges...
Please, Miss Hodges.
Could you...
Could you describe...
Miss Hodges.
Excuse me.
Look, man, like I told you, it was blue.
The car,
not the driver.
Look, it was just blue.
You know,
like, blue.
There you go.
Enjoy my book.
Could you sign it
"To A Future Serial Mom"?
Sure. You think she did it?
I have
reasonable doubt.
I feel like killing a
couple people myself.
$8, ma'am.
And these books,
these disgusting books
that so lovingly describe the
sadistic acts of serial killers,
where did you find
these books, Detective?
In Beverly Sutphin's
trashcan.
You may cross-examine, Mrs. Sutphin.
Thank you.
Detective Gracey, if I were
to look through your trash,
what reading materials
would I find?
Objection! Immaterial!
You may answer.
Time, Sports Illustrated,
National Geographic.
My wife gets
Ladies' Home Journal.
Yet, last night, we found in
your trashcan this magazine,
Chicks with Dicks.
God damn you.
That's trespassing!
Never judge a person by
what they read, Detective.
Your witness,
Mr. Nazlerod.
I am a married man. I hope
they give you the gas chamber!
The jury is instructed to ignore
the outburst of the witness.
I call to the stand Rosemary Ackerman.
Now, did you ever see
the fire poker again
after you left it
with Mrs. Sutphin?
Yes, thirty minutes later. It
was covered with blood and gore
and Carl Pageant
was dead.
No further questions.
Mrs. Ackerman, when you
left me at the Antique Mart,
where did you go?
Browsing.
Did Carl Pageant buy
something you wanted?
I didn't want that Fabergé
egg. It was chipped.
Carl Pageant died
because of you, didn't he?
No. I would never
hurt anybody.
It was your Premiere magazine with
the letters cut out, wasn't it?
Yes, but I lent it...
And they were your
scissors that were found
in Mrs. Sterner's stomach, weren't they?
Yes. But I didn't...
Mrs. Ackerman...
Do you recycle?
No.
I don't have room in my kitchen.
Detective Pike, did you then
proceed to the stage area
inside Hammerjacks?
Yes, I did. Scotty Barnhill was on fire
and he fell to his knees in flames.
Would this be
what you saw?
Yes, sir.
A real barbecue.
May I show this photo
to the jury, Your Honor?
Chip, she's here.
They're entitled to see
Mrs. Sutphin's handiwork.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Your Honor,
may the photograph
please be received
into evidence and shown to the jury?
Oh, yeah. Yes, yes.
Jeez, that really is
Suzanne Somers.
Oh, I loved you
in Three's Company.
No further questions.
I call to the stand
Marvin Pickles.
Mr. Pickles!
Mr. Marvin Pickles!
Be right out.
The judge is waiting for you.
Okay.
Come on,
get moving.
State your name, please.
Marvin A. Pickles.
Mr. Pickles, were you in the men's room
at the Antique Trade Mart
on Saturday, May 15?
Yes, I was.
Oh, hi. What was the
rating? Well, what was the share?
Did you see anyone in
the booth next to you?
Excuse me, I...
Mr. Pickles, did you see
anyone in the booth next to you?
I'm not sure... I...
What do you mean
you're not sure?
There was nobody next to me.
Mr. Pickles, didn't
you tell the Grand Jury
that you looked down and you saw
a pair of ladies' shoes
in the booth next to you?
I just said what you told me to.
Perjury is a serious
offense, Mr. Pickles.
I... I made it all up! I've never
seen Beverly Sutphin in my life!
You'll pay for this,
Marvin Pickles.
I'm turning your file
over to the vice squad.
The prosecution rests.
The prosecution has
proven nothing, Your Honor.
The defense
rests also!
Order.
Order in the courtroom.
We'll take
a 10-minute recess.
Attorneys, be ready with
your closing arguments.
Well, I feel that
Beverly Sutphin
is an innocent woman,
wrongly accused.
A normal housewife trapped in a
nightmare of circumstantial evidence.
There she is, Henrietta
Lee Lucas, Joan Wayne Gacy.
A new face in the deck of
serial killer trading cards.
Find her guilty on all six
counts of first-degree murder.
I only hope I can portray Serial
Mom's life on the TV screen
with the proper dignity that
this feminist heroine deserves.
Look at me. I am as
normal as all of you.
But I have been
framed by the police
and perjured against by the very
people I thought were my friends.
All I ask of you...
Stop that!
...is that you have the
courage to find me innocent
of these terribly
untrue charges.
All I ask is that you find me
innocent of these
terribly untrue charges.
Ladies and gentlemen of the
jury, have you reached a verdict?
Yes, we have, Your Honor.
We find the defendant
not guilty of all charges.
Way to go, Beverly!
Oh! I'm coming home!
What should I do?
I don't know. Bring her home, I guess.
No more violence.
You think
she'll like me?
Just be nice to her and try...
Try not to get on her nerves.
She got off.
She's innocent!
Congratulations, Beverly.
Will you be staying...
Hello, Baltimore!
I love you.
Oh, I love you, too.
Thank you all for coming. Hi,
there, LA. Hello, Cleveland.
Hey, Serial Mom!
Well, hello, New York!
Beverly, who does your hair?
Excuse me!
Would you hold these for me, honey?
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Mr. Sutphin, can
I ask you a question, please?
Did the system work?
Do you think it worked?
Excuse me. The rights have been sold.
We did it.
We set her free!
I knew she was innocent
right from the beginning.
You can't wear white
shoes after Labor Day.
That's not
true anymore.
Yes, it is. Didn't your
mother ever tell you?
Now you know.
No, please.
Fashion has changed.
No, it hasn't.
Are you
surprised, Mr. Sutphin?
No comment.
Beverly?
Here I am, honey.
Beverly, hi!
I'm Suzanne Somers.
Hello!
Mrs. Sutphin, can we get a
shot of you and Suzanne Somers?
Absolutely, stand here, Beverly.
Guys, what about a nice two-shot, okay?
No, Suzanne,
really, I'd be much...
Beverly, Beverly,
stand right here!
Okay, smile,
Serial Mom!
Suzanne Somers,
this is my bad side!