Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
I'm Marie-Carmen.
I'm from Toledo,
Spain.
I'm Amparito,
from Salamanca.
I'm Marie-Isabel from Segovia.
I like doing housework,
ironing...
I can clean silverware,
but I don't enjoy it.
Sure I know how to work,
I adore kids.
I love them!
Little kids, little girls,
little everythings...
I make great paella,
potato and mushroom tortillas.
And croquettes, salmondigas
and Spanish omelets, gazpacho...
French cuisine,
I don't like.
The Women on the 6th Floor
Hello.
What's going on?
I'm in a rush, got work to do!
It's all stopped up.
Thanks.
Germaine, I said boiled eggs
take 3 and a half minutes!
Not 10, or 5, or 4...
Don't bore me with your egg!
What's it now?
It's Madame...
She wants to move Madame's room!
You realize?
My mother died 6 months ago,
the mourning's over.
Not for me.
For me, Madame's still here.
Madame Suzanne hated your mother.
She was very fond of her.
The day after she died she said...
Shall I tell you?
Please, don't.
Let me listen to the news.
Hi, Mrs Triboulet.
Mr Joubert, it can't go on.
- What is it?
- The Spaniards!
They partied all night again!
They shouted and sang!
I didn't sleep a wink.
- Tell the building manager!
- I will, Mrs. Triboulet.
- Bye, Madame Triboulet.
- Bye, Mr Joubert.
Hi, Maria!
Auntie! At last!
Such a beauty!
Great to see you!
Look,
hand it to me... The brown one.
Your bag weighs a ton.
Auntie, this is Pilar.
- Hi.
- Delighted.
We traveled together.
My pal
lost a fortune in Algerian oil.
You're mistaken, Mr Pelletier.
You have Aquitaine oil
and you're up 100,000 francs.
Old francs?
No, 100,000 new francs.
I've lost my glasses...
Mr Pelletier, be right with you.
We'll go to my office.
The stock market baffles me.
How it moves...
My dad said: it's just a market.
But it sells stocks, not veggies.
Come along.
It's a fine house.
Where you off to?
Hi, Madame Triboulet...
My niece, Maria. Just got here.
The elevator's not for you!
Mrs Triboulet,
we have heavy bags.
Elevator's for the owners.
Use the backstairs.
OK.
Let's go, kid.
''Use the backstairs!''
We'll see about that!
These hatboxes take up all the room!
- They were for Madame's hats!
- She's in the graveyard!
You're just in time !
- What is it?
- Germaine !
She won't empty your mom's room.
Your mom bullied me,
I couldn't change
a curtain, or a napkin ring!
You repapered our bedroom.
Now it's my home!
Germaine must understand!
- I'll talk to her.
- Yes, do.
Germaine...
What's going on?
Such ingratitude!
To do that
to a mother who adored you.
She never liked anyone,
you know that.
Madame Suzanne's meanness
killed her!
You're insane!
She murdered her!
You hear her?
You don't mean that.
Yes, I do!
Then get out!
Really, Suzanne!
What's with you both?
You're paid to obey!
I do! I wasted my life
for thankless people.
Thankless...
You're a bad mother.
I raised your kids!
You sent them to boarding-school!
Don't overdo it, Germaine!
I slaved years for you Jouberts.
Madame dies, and you fire me!
No, I'll quit on you!
So long, folks!
Maybe it's too old,
I can't make it shine.
I know a trick.
Use toothpaste,
spread it well, and rub.
Toothpaste!
Yes.
I had no idea...
It's perfect.
Auntie! The Frenchwoman's crying.
Let's go see.
What's wrong with her?
What's going on?
They kicked me out! ''Scram!''
Don't be sad.
We forget bosses fast.
You'll find a new family.
I don't want one!
Back in Brittany...
I have no one there now!
Maids get hired and fired.
Try this,
it's Malaga wine, warms you up.
Who are you?
She's Maria, my niece.
I got here today.
And know French?
From the nun's school in Burgos.
We maids must get unionized.
We must unite against the bosses.
Don't listen, she's a Communist!
Your praying won't help us!
Shut up!
I won't. Religious nuts
like you prevent change.
So go to Russia!
Enough, you two!
Another shot? It's not bad...
To Spain!
Hi there! It's Germaine Le Bronnec.
I'm going home!
Be of good cheer!
Germaine Le Bronnec!
Darling, I've no shirts left.
They're all dirty!
How'll I go to the office?
Wear a sweater!
A sweater?
Jean-Louis is going crazy.
We're like castaways!
Still no news from Brittany.
Brittany maids are over.
They're out!
We have Spanish maids now.
Right, Colette?
My Dolores is a pearl.
You even forget she's Spanish.
She's so clean,
even works on Sundays.
No French maid gives up her Sunday!
Not a chance!
My Dolores insists
on one thing...
going to Mass...
at 6AM.
If that's all...
A Spanish maid, why not?
It's simple,
their HQ is nearby
at the Spanish church.
Go there and pick one.
Some speak no French,
others get by.
Many learnt French in convents.
If I were you,
I'd avoid city girls...
Hello, miss. I'm Mr Joubert,
Madame's husband.
My wife spoke of you, Maria,
fresh from Spain
and here on a try-out?
If you want to stay here,
I'm a stickler for one thing:
boiled eggs.
I'm fussy about that,
got it from my dad.
An egg that's too soft or too hard
ruins my day.
You understand?
I think
you don't get what I'm saying.
If the egg is perfect,
my day is made.
In Spain,
we have superstitions, too.
No, it's not a superstition.
It's more like...
How can I put it...
It's not a superstition.
Not at all!
3 and a half minutes.
Hello.
Got the Figaro?
In the kitchen closet,
we store tablecloths, napkins...
On top, the linen,
as it's delicate.
Undersheets aren't mattress covers!
This is the Limoges china...
Don't confuse the plain glasses,
with the Baccarats!
Answer the phone, write down
the caller's name and number.
Yes, Mrs Joubert.
Call me ''Madame''!
My husband is ''Sir''.
And the kids,
Master Bertrand and Master Olivier.
They'll be home in a few weeks.
Get cracking!
Let's sum up:
we've dealt with laundry
and other chores.
The ironing is urgent:
we're way behind.
I left you a full list, right?
Yes, Madame.
Easy on the bleach! Or it'll stink
like a hospital! Got that?
- Yes, Madame.
- Fine, Maria.
See you later, thanks!
Auntie!
Open up!
Help me! This house is a mess!
No, I've got too much work.
It's my first day, I can't goof.
OK, but let me enlist
some others... Dolores!
What?
Maria needs help!
Carmen!
Let's go down to Maria's floor,
she needs help.
- OK!
- Teresa!
- What?
- Come help Maria.
- Now?
- We're coming, don't worry.
You about through?
Cut out the noise!
Yes, Mrs Triboulet.
Thanks, everyone!
Go down the corridor.
Help me with the dishes.
Auntie, the laundry!
She was afraid
to come out of the locker
She was as nervous as she could be
She was afraid to come
out of the locker
She was afraid
that someone would see...
Two, three, four...
Tell the people what she wore!
It was an Itsy Bitsy Teenie Weenie,
Yellow polka dot bikini
That she wore
for the first time today
Good evening, Madame.
You're a whiz at housework!
You're hired.
Thanks, Madame.
Monsieur decides your salary.
I had an ex-haus-ting day!
Run me a bath, Maria?
Of course, Madame.
Any calls or visits?
No, Madame.
Who sent me those flowers?
- Hello, Maria.
- Hello, sir.
Madame wants to hire you.
All work deserves a salary...
Germaine got 250 francs...
400 francs!
400?
You're mad!
250 is generous
for someone without references.
400 francs.
You realize how much it is?
You're stubborn.
I'm known as a tough negotiator.
Go to the kitchen,
I'll think it over.
OK, Maria,
you'll get 400 francs.
Officially, I'll pay you 250.
The rest, not a word to Madame.
See,
where there's will there's a way.
- See you later, Maria.
- Yes.
Maria,
when I say that, answer
''See you later, sir.''
If you want.
No, it's not what I want,
it's what's done.
Very well.
See you later, sir.
''See you later, sir.''
You got 400 francs!
- 400.
- Just like that.
Hear that, Carmen?
Her boss is paying her 400 francs.
Pretty good! You're clever.
I asked,
and he said yes, that's all.
How long
has the red mullet been here?
- Came today!
- No, I don't like its eyes!
I'll have some sardines.
5 kilos of potatoes!
What?
Thanks.
No touching!
Sorry.
Potatoes!
My God, it's the big day!
I'm so excited!
Very honored.
My office manager, Mr Piquer.
We'll be handling
Madame de Brossolette's estate.
Delighted.
Please follow me to my office.
I feel I know you.
Hubert spoke often of you.
Hubert left us too soon...
Indeed.
We'll create a portfolio of stocks
and bonds.
What do you mean bonds?
I despise anything binding!
A bond's the reverse of a stock.
A stock is a fragment of...
A friend tripled her portfolio
in a year!
Stop! If you want to speculate,
you're in the wrong place.
That's short term: buy today,
sell tomorrow.
I'm interested in the long term.
Me, too. I like things that last.
The linen stays here.
I'll deal with the screen.
There.
We'll manage.
You're moving the Chinese screen?
- It's no use in an office.
- An office?
This will be one.
I've got an office.
It's for me, not you.
For you?
Yes, for my correspondence,
my thoughts.
I want to jot down all my ideas.
Help Maria take all this to the 6th,
I'm bushed!
Here's the key, won't take a minute.
Come with me, Maria.
It's been years
since I was up there.
I know this building well:
I was born here.
Like my parents and grandparents.
The brokerage firm
was founded
by my grandfather in 1912.
I'm like a farmer who's attached
to his village steeple.
My father went to England once.
The crossing made him seasick,
coming back, it was worse.
In my family, we never travel far.
Summers we're at our beach house.
Winters,
the kids go skiing in the Alps
with their mom,
I stay in Paris.
I've spent my whole life
in this building.
I left my village when I was 16.
To go off and study?
No,
to the city to work for a family.
Then to work in a factory in Burgos.
A factory?
A tobacco factory.
We worked 15 hours a day,
slept there in a dormitory,
with noisy machines
running all night.
Here at least,
I have a room to myself.
May I see your room?
No, it's untidy.
Please show it to me.
Where's the wash basin?
There is none!
How do you wash?
We fill a bowl with water
and take it to the room.
Cold water?
Why's he here?
To store some things.
Good evening.
Good evening, sir.
I'm Dolores, Dolores Carvaillal.
I work for Mrs Bergeret,
a friend of your wife's.
Sure! My wife plays bridge with her.
I'm Concepcion Garcia, Maria's aunt.
We're delighted with her.
Keep an eye on her!
Teresa Lopez, of the 5th floor.
Good evening, Miss.
Your name, dear Madame?
No.
I'm not your dear Madame.
You don't care about us.
You came to snoop around,
then return
to your fine apartment.
Don't listen to her!
Let me talk.
You accept it all, I don't!
Come, sir, I'll show you something.
I see.
We get used to it.
It's no big deal!
When I need to, I go below,
to the toilets in the yard.
Me, too. Even at night.
Well, I'm so glad we met.
I'm sorry.
Jean-Louis!
Evening, ma'am.
I came for your toilets.
Plugged up, I hear.
That's news to me.
A cesspool, your husband said.
Please come in.
Good evening, Mr Boulard.
Thanks for coming so fast.
What's with our toilets?
I'll explain. Please come with me.
Where to?
Don't worry, come along.
This way, Mr Boulard.
Hello, sir.
Don't dump things in 'em!
No, they're just for dumping shit!
I'm too busy for this!
I said on the phone,
I'd pay you double.
Do your job.
Go on.
Glory be to God!
Hello, Mr Joubert.
Hello, ladies.
He fixed our toilets.
Hello, Mr Joubert!
Hello. And have a good day!
I don't know why, I'm exhausted!
I run around all day.
Soon we're off on vacation!
But sometimes that's worse.
Dear Maria, I really appreciate you.
And you're amazingly clean.
Thanks, Madame.
My husband
says you can't wash up there.
We do, Madame.
You can shower
in the boys' bathroom.
Thanks, Madame.
You're welcome.
I say! Antoine de Montgolfier's
getting married!
What time is it?
10 AM, Madame.
I'm horribly late for my dressmaker.
Dear Maria,
do you have a fiance?
You can tell me.
I once did love a man...
And you never told him!
Men don't know what they want.
By the time they ask,
you're an old maid.
Monsieur didn't want marriage!
He hesitated, wasn't sure...
I was a country girl,
I held out and he married me!
Once you've got a man,
never let go of him.
If a man doesn't want me,
that's his loss.
Really...
The strike is over,
and the Dunkerque
plant's output is up 20% .
Time to buy Usinor Steel.
Usinor, yes.
Mr Piquer,
where do you go on holiday?
To Spain.
I thought so.
Where exactly?
The Costa Brava.
But what village?
- Palafrugell.
- Palafrugell...
You've mixed with Spaniards?
A bit, but we French stick together.
Of course.
Is Palafrugell on the coast?
It's inland,
the sea's in the distance.
It's gorgeous.
Little streets with fountains.
Chatillon goes to Deauville.
Bettina takes him to the Casino,
he loses it all at the tables.
Still, he bought her an apartment
in Cannes.
Who?
Bettina de Brossolette!
You don't know her?
Men are mad for her,
she's the new heartthrob.
I said there's no mail for you!
- 3 weeks, no news from my sister!
- Who cares?
If I ever find those letters
you're in trouble!
What's going on here?
She says I swipe her mail!
My sister just had a baby.
Mrs Triboulet doesn't give us
our letters,
so I don't know how is the baby!
My sister said
she'd write every week.
She swore it.
Know what she did
to Maxime de Montbrial?
She grabbed his Degas,
and dumped him overnight!
Thanks, Maria. Come, Dolores.
We'll call her.
Miss,
put me through to Spain, please.
Name of your village?
- Ponte Vedra.
- Ponte Vedra, yes.
56 27 12.
Thanks a lot. You can speak now.
Hi, Jose, it's Dolores.
How's my sister?
She had a girl.
A girl!
How is she doing?
How heavy?
4 kilos!
Big kiss, and tell her to write.
I'll send her a gift.
Tell her I love her. Bye!
Thanks, Mr Joubert.
Thanks so much.
You're a saint. I'm so happy!
Thanks, Mr Jean-Louis.
God bless you.
Hi, Carmen.
For urgent phone calls
you can come here.
A phone call?
Like, to your family.
My whole family is dead.
I'm so sorry.
Heard of the Spanish civil war?
Sure, who hasn't?
My father
and my mother were murdered.
Franco's men slit their throats
in front of me.
Then,
they dragged the bodies
through the streets.
That was the Spanish civil war.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
They live in tiny rooms,
no heating or running water.
It was their choice.
They're up at 6 AM, work all day,
get back at 11 PM,
dead-tired and don't complain,
they're happy.
You never worry about anybody,
suddenly
you care about Spanish maids!
They live above us,
and we know nothing about them.
You care for those Spanish women,
but not about what I did!
Is today Wednesday?
At 11AM you had your feet done,
then to the dressmaker's,
lunch with Marie-France,
at 4PM to Carette's to buy cakes,
then off to play bridge
with Colette and Nicole.
Bastard!
I'll tell your father!
Who are you?
I'm Maria. The new maid.
What's all this?
Where's Germaine?
You could say hello, kids!
Germaine left us.
Sure! I bet you fired her!
That's vile!
You exploited her for 20 years,
then kick her out.
First, we didn't ''exploit'' her,
and she decided to leave.
And who's that one?
''That one'' is Maria. She's Spanish.
No kidding?
You hired a Spaniard?
Absolutely.
And be nice to her!
For breakfast, we want pate, salami.
- And pancakes.
- Right, pancakes.
For our snack, champagne and cakes.
Iron the washing by tomorrow.
Got that?
She didn't.
Pour me milk, girl.
Pour it yourself!
I know about rich brats,
they don't scare me.
Don't call me girl, and say please.
Tomorrow's Sunday, we sleep late.
Sunday, I go to Mass.
You go to Mass?
In a way, Germaine was our Mom.
We'll even miss her lousy soups!
She never said goodbye!
Gone for good!
And I never saw her bare-assed!
Let us pray.
Now we'll pray in silence.
Buy The Daily Worker!
The paper that fights exploiters!
It's a disgrace for Spain
and all Spaniards!
I won't force you
to become a stockbroker.
I'd rather die!
Won't follow Dad?
My French teacher says
only manual labor is worthy.
Yet he doesn't work with his hands!
To him, you're profiteers
who milk the system.
Your dad's no profiteer!
Who's this French teacher?
I'll tell Father Basile!
He says De Gaulle's a degenerate,
who betrayed France,
lost Algeria...
Absolutely!
A dictator, a tyrant!
If De Gaulle's a tyrant,
what's Franco?
Screw Franco!
What about the 100,000 executed
during the Spanish civil war?
I can't follow you anymore.
The point is, Bertrand
must take over the business.
I'll be a gynecologist.
A gynecologist?
That's disgusting!
Sticking your head
between women's legs all day?
Buenos dias, Maria.
Buenos dias, senor.
You want to learn Spanish?
I like ham... Me gusta el jamon.
No...
''jamon''.
With a hard ''j''.
- Jamon.
- With a hard ''j''.
With a hard ''j''.
No...
La jota...
Comes from here.
Say with me...
Juego.
El juego.
El joven.
No.
El jardin...
El jueves.
El jamon!
El jamon.
Very good.
Very good, Mr Joubert.
Are you happy in this house?
You care, sir?
Sure. I must know if you're happy.
Then, yes.
The most important thing
between us is trust.
Germaine
stayed in this house 25 years,
she confided in me.
She was almost family.
Really?
Where she is now?
I don't know.
And you say she was family!
Afternoons, she hangs out with boys
in the street,
but tells her husband
she visited the poor.
Hi, Maria.
- Who were you talking about?
- The bosses.
My boss comes out of the bathroom
with his robe open,
I mean really open.
So anyone can see his privates!
He might jump on you!
Very interesting. Talk to you later.
Hello?
Mrs Joubert's out!
Can I take a message?
Who is this?
General De Gaulle?
Maria, it's not General De Gaulle.
Don't believe all you're told
on the phone.
You scared me!
What are you doing, Maria?
The silverware.
That's real fun.
What product do you use?
''Gleamo.''
''Gleamo''...
Any message?
Tell Madame I'll meet her at home.
See you later, Maria!
Goodbye, sir.
To be on time we must leave now.
The theater is close by.
How long is the play?
- Only 2 hours.
- Very long!
Is this Ionesco so funny?
A genius, they say.
Madame de Brossolette dropped by
the office unannounced.
I said
you weren't in to get rid of her.
Bettina de Brossolette?
In person!
A huge portfolio,
several million francs!
You never said
she gave you her portfolio.
I didn't think it'd interest you.
She's a man-eater,
fleeces married men, ruins them.
She leaves me cold.
What's Maria up to?
I'll go get her.
What's going on?
We're due at the theater.
Sorry, sir. Be right there.
What happened to you?
Her husband beats her,
takes her money.
Let's call the police.
No, not the police.
Don't do anything, sir.
You're kind! Thanks.
Tonight, I'll take her in my room.
We'll manage.
Don't go back to your husband, OK?
They need me!
Sorry, sir.
We're off to the theater.
Enjoy, sir.
You too, Maria.
...losses
have been made up by gains,
so in spite of the downturn,
we're showing a positive balance.
I'll let Mr Joubert conclude...
Mr Blamond, are you the owner
of some buildings
on rue Raynouard?
Yes, on the corner of rue Colignon.
Could you help a friend
with a big problem?
With pleasure!
I heard
of a vacant janitor's apartment.
My friend Pilar'd love to get it.
Your friend Pilar?
Yes, Pilar Gonzales.
She must leave our building:
her husband beats her.
She needs somewhere to go.
Concepcion says a janitor's place...
Concepcion is Maria's aunt.
They came by bus from Burgos...
You're rarely home so early.
Who's in the boys' bathroom?
Maria. I let her take a shower.
- You don't mind?
- No...
Not now.
I'm checking Tuesday's guest list.
What's on next Tuesday?
Really! We're giving a party!
I'm inviting your partners,
important customers...
See if anyone's missing.
What do you mean?
Listen, Jean-Louis.
What's got into you?
- Remember that hotel in Italy?
- Yes.
On Lake Como.
- The Vincenzo.
- Yes, the Vincenzo.
It was our honeymoon.
That never should've ended...
Come along!
- Morning, Maria.
- Morning, Madame.
My husband
is bedridden this morning.
Slept like a baby,
but woke up with an upset stomach.
You called a doctor?
No time, I have an appointment.
You're not staying with him?
I'm due at a charity sale.
I can't cancel, I'd look silly.
You pamper him, Maria.
- See you later.
- See you later, Madame.
Come in.
Morning, sir.
Morning, Maria.
I feel a bit queasy.
Madame and I
had oysters at a brasserie.
An oyster can be fatal.
Here.
You have no fever.
I know what you need.
You sick, Mr Jean-Louis?
A stomach ache?
His liver's swollen.
No, it's gas. Look!
It's his liver, he's yellow.
I tell you it's gas.
No, it's his liver.
My grandpa had gas.
Your grandpa was a drunk!
We'll cure you.
Maria, the cure!
- Open your mouth!
- No, you're kind.
Open your mouth.
Feeling better?
Yes. Much better.
The cure worked very well.
Get back into bed.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
You want to help me?
Of course!
- He's a gift from heaven.
- Maria hit the jackpot!
Look, Teresa!
Hey, Brigitte Bardot,
take down the trash!
Dyed your hair blonde
for your soldier boy?
Think he'll marry you?
With no wig she was cuter.
You're jealous!
Thanks.
Here,
it's for you.
How old is he?
- I don't know.
- I mean him.
Your son. How old is he?
Hasn't that been done?
Put the rug
in my mother-in-law's room.
Fine. Get going!
Answer the door.
Tell me who it is. I'm busy.
Who is it, Maria?
Come in.
Hello.
Thanks.
The flowers!
Get a vase... Thanks.
Wait, don't move, don't leave.
There.
Thanks a lot.
- Madame Joubert?
- Who are you?
Rodolphe sent me. I'm Gerard.
Rodolphe can't come?
Countess de Morlaix needs him.
He said to replace him here.
He could have warned me!
Don't worry, I know my job.
It's a disaster, I'm way behind.
Go to the pantry, take over.
Hi, I'm Gerard.
Your first names?
I'm Maria.
I'm Dolores.
Spanish? Good, I love Spain!
Wanna watch me bullfight?
Excuse me.
Goimard!
- How are you?
- Just fine.
My respects.
Champagne, Maria?
Whisky?
When did we meet?
A long time ago. Too long.
Met him again at the club,
15 years ago. Same guy!
Like you.
I made him my broker in a jiffy!
Best to get stung by a pal!
You're rough.
Know my friend Goimard?
Your boarding-school pal.
Absolutely.
How's Marie-Francoise?
Pleased with Maria?
Definitely, Nicole.
My maid's touchy,
everything miffs her!
Spaniards aren't touchy,
they're proud, that's different.
Proud, fearless...
Fearless?
What's fearless
about using a floor-mop?
Try it, Nicole!
Madame de Brossolette,
delighted...
Stop calling me Madame,
it's such a bore.
I'm nuts about Spain.
Chorizo, paella, taboule.
- Taboule isn't Spanish!
- What?
Taboule isn't Spanish!
- Taboule's not Spanish?
- No.
But Flamenco is!
Who's that talking to Jean-Louis?
Bettina de Brossolette.
That's her?
Sure is.
Here she is...
Madame de Brossolette,
Suzanne, my wife.
Delighted.
Jean-Louis
invests brilliantly for me.
He explained it all,
but now I've forgotten!
Stocks, bonds...
I'm like you,
I find it all very complex.
I trust him implicitly.
Whatever happens, he'll protect me.
Yes, he's very protective.
- Right?
- Very.
I live far, in the burbs.
And you?
In the building.
On the 6th with the others?
Yes.
What room number?
My room's...
number 4.
4! My lucky number!
Maria, cut it out.
Don't listen to her, 4 is my room.
Very cute,
gave me her girlfriend's room!
Aren't you bored?
Alone in your little bed?
You about through?
Just kidding.
You know all men need a mommy!
But I don't want to generalize,
I've only been married 3 times!
Excuse me.
Listen, Maria,
it's for your own good.
I mean no harm.
You're needed
in the drawing-room, Gerard.
Certainly, sir.
What do you think of steel today?
Usinor's going up. Time to buy?
- Where's that guy?
- Dumping the trash.
Madame wants you.
You can leave now.
I've cleaning to do.
Scram! You get it?
I got it.
She's off limits!
Hello, sir.
You got here so late.
Madame said I could this morning.
The apartment's a mess.
Because of the party.
Don't mention the party!
My work wasn't good?
You know what I mean!
Think you'll get away with it,
because I...
I warn you, next time you're out!
What did I do?
What did you do?
You're lucky
Madame's so fond of you.
- Or else...
- In fact,
you're just a boss like the others.
Worse than they are!
Go away. Get out of my sight!
He's for Napoleon,
she's a royalist.
She's Protestant, he's Catholic...
He flaunted Bettina in your house!
For all Paris to see!
Suzanne, you don't deserve that!
Think so?
But Bettina's one of his customers.
He handles her portfolio.
He could've warned you!
The least he could do,
considering her reputation!
For Jean-Louis,
I'm still a country girl.
What he likes are...
dazzling Parisian beauties.
Don't say that,
you're so delightful.
Anyway...
Have you seen my cigarettes?
No.
I left them here.
Hello, Mr Jean-Louis.
- You OK?
- Fine.
We're partying at Pilar's place.
Really...
- Join us?
- Yes, do!
No, thanks.
Don't argue! Come along!
What fun, have a drink!
Mr Jean-Louis!
Thanks for this place.
It's so nice. Come in.
Mr Jean-Louis! You're a saint,
you'll go to heaven.
You're invited to our party!
I can't stay.
My wife is waiting for me.
She can come too!
Madame Joubert is so elegant.
Can I go, Madame?
Yes, Maria. Have a nice time.
Good night, Madame.
See you tonight,
Bettina
See, she even got giant gambas!
He got the place for Pilar.
It's a great place.
Just what I need.
Ask Mr Jean-Louis to help.
Encarnacion paid 1,000 francs
to the former janitor for hers.
1,000 francs!
But it had a shower.
In my house in Spain,
I'll have several tubs!
We've heard that before!
Does that house even exist ?
Stop it.
Here's proof.
Isn't it?
Look, Mr Jean-Louis.
It's my husband Fernando.
He's building me a marble bathroom
with golden faucets.
I saw them in a store here.
I don't trust tubs,
they're dangerous.
In what way?
Josephina
took a bath in her boss's tub,
and she got pregnant.
I'd say...
Josephina...
did more than take a bath!
When I get back to Spain
everybody will envy me for my house.
And we'll be bosses.
Sure...
I'll never go back to Spain.
While that murderer rules,
I'll stay here.
Franco won't last forever.
Maria,
one day you should make paella
at home.
If you wish, sir.
Paella for me.
Good evening!
This is Mr Armand.
Delighted.
I'm honored, ladies!
I own the beauty shop near here.
The ritzy one, where the bosses go?
That very one!
Stop by,
I'll be delighted to do your hair,
for half price!
My head's spinning!
Good night, Mr Jean-Louis.
I was wrong.
You're not just a boss.
Not in bed?
No, I waited up for you.
- You had dinner?
- Yes, thanks.
You could've warned me.
I'm sorry,
I thought of it,
but it went by so fast!
Sure... Where were you?
You won't believe it.
Go ahead.
You know Pilar,
who works for the Dubreuils,
on rue Collignon.
No... I don't know Pilar.
Doesn't matter.
I got her a place, a stall...
A stall... at the opera?
No, for a janitor.
They celebrated it
with a little party.
Can't you tell the truth?
It's true! We ate a paella!
Teresa sang a copla.
Was Bettina there too?
Bettina?
Don't deny it, she was there too!
You're so wrong!
What's with this Bettina?
You went to that gallery opening?
What opening?
Where were you?
I dined with the Spanish maids.
Don't talk nonsense!
Stop it!
For weeks you've had a smug smile
on your face,
you strut around!
I know when something's going on!
Were you with Bettina?
Yes or no?
Yes... I was with Bettina.
The humiliation...
Let's go to bed, I'm exhausted.
No, we're not going to bed.
You must leave this house.
I never want to see you again,
get out!
Go away!
Hello, ladies.
The hazards of existence force me
to leave our family home
for what should be a short period.
Fate is capricious,
and the female character
unpredictable.
I hope to be a discreet and quiet
neighbor. I wish you a good day.
Sorry.
Have a nice day.
It's a nightmare.
- You knew it.
- No way.
Hi, Mrs Triboulet!
Please bring up the mail
to the 6th floor, room 3.
Slip it under the door.
Good day, Mrs Triboulet!
Good day.
Don't make my tea, I'm going out.
Listen, Monsieur has left home.
I don't know where he is,
and I don't care!
Take care of his linen.
When the kids are back,
he can take them out.
He's unwelcome here.
Very well, Madame.
We don't distrust men enough.
Never forget that.
I have it, Genevieve.
I have it.
Well?
Isn't this better?
Hi, Carmen.
Evening.
Hi, Concepcion.
- How long'll he stay here?
- Don't ask me.
What do you care?
I don't like having a man up here.
He won't sneak into your room!
Don't be so sure!
- Hi, Carmen.
- Mr Jean-Louis,
you're the owner, do as you please.
But we stay in our own corner.
But this is my home.
No, bosses belong with bosses.
Don't mingle with the servants.
Sorry, Carmen. I'm staying here.
Why?
It's my first room of my own.
First came boarding school,
then the army,
then marriage.
I really feel free now.
- The 20 I owed you.
- Thanks.
Dolores,
where's it from?
Savings I earned
with the sweat of my brow.
And you keep it here?
Yes.
Concepcion,
what do you do with your money?
I send it to my husband
for the house.
And the money you don't send?
I keep it in a shoe-box.
Invest it!
- ''Invest it''?
- Well-invested, it earns more!
What does that mean?
In the stock market!
It's simple, I'll explain.
Don't listen.
Capitalists are bandits.
Let him explain.
In the market
there are stocks and bonds.
What are stocks?
Like when you stock up
on something?
In the stock market, it's different.
Let's say, all 5 of you want to buy
a restaurant.
Where we serve paella?
No paella! French cuisine!
You'll need capital,
let's say a million francs.
You don't have it,
so you issue 10,000 shares.
It's the capital people invest
in your restaurant.
Handle it well, Mr Piquer!
Aquitaine Oil's up 2 and a half points.
I don't trust Aquitaine Oil...
Look, Usinor's up.
That's the one I like.
Hi, Mrs Triboulet.
Thanks for the mail.
Concepcion Ramirez.
Dolores Carvaillal.
Carmen...
Hi, Mrs Triboulet!
Any mail for me?
Yes, sir.
- Thanks a lot.
- Mr Joubert again.
Yes, Mr Joubert.
- There.
- That's all.
Have a nice day!
I'll take the peonies...
Fine.
and the roses.
In fact, a mixed bouquet.
Very good.
There.
Hello, Mrs Triboulet!
Hello, Senora Joubert.
Why ''Senora''?
It's because of Mr Joubert.
What about him?
You don't know?
He's living up on the 6th,
with the Spaniards!
On the 6th?
It's common knowledge!
It's gone on for 2 weeks!
Have a nice day, Mrs Joubert.
Spanish Without Tears
Here, Mr Jean-Louis,
it's holy water
from the Virgin of Lourdes.
You were in Lourdes?
I went in the grotto,
where St Bernadette saw the Virgin.
I closed my eyes,
felt her hand on my head.
And she whispered into my ear.
What did she say?
''In 10 years,
you'll have a baby boy.
''He'll be called Javier.''
You can't give birth at 60, Dolores!
The Virgin Mary performs miracles.
Maybe in the Middle Ages,
but not now.
Listen.
Teresa has something to tell you.
The finest day of my life!
Mr Armand asked me.
What did he ask you?
To marry him! I'm getting married!
A miracle!
You'll move out?
Anyway, I'm through being a maid!
To work in the beauty shop?
She'll do shampoos?
No, handle the cash register!
At first, I'll stay home
and wash the blouses,
then I'll iron them,
and in the morning I'll mop
the floor and tidy up.
I'll buy your wedding gown.
Made of white silk and lace?
Whatever you want!
This one's the best!
My dad said:
''They're for special occasions.''
I almost opened one
the day he died.
That's not nice.
Just kidding.
But Teresa's marriage is one.
And now I know you all...
You think you know me,
but you don't.
I have a son.
He's 8 years old.
I never married.
So now you can fire me:
I made a child in sin.
Not at all.
You have a child, that's wonderful!
He was adopted by a family.
My mom was so ashamed of me,
I had to abandon him.
The father, was a man like you.
A big owner.
I'm not a big owner.
I live on the 6th floor.
You'll always be an owner.
Mr Jean-Louis, thanks!
It's good stuff, it's Bordeaux.
Sit down.
Now we'll sing. You sing along.
- I don't know how!
- Give it a try.
He's on the 6th floor!
Living in an attic room?
That's how it is,
my little chickies!
Your father is infatuated
with those Spaniards.
- It's outrageous!
- A scandal!
He's unworthy!
It's hilarious.
I never saw it coming
and I threw him out!
My darlings, your mother's an idiot!
We'll talk to him at once.
Remind him of his duty.
And of honor.
That's good of you, kids.
Our house is almost finished...
but it's taking a long time.
Who are they?
Where's our dad's room?
You're Mr Jean-Louis' kids?
Exactly!
Little blond Frenchies!
I'll show you. Come along.
What a nice surprise! Come in!
Thanks, Concepcion.
Have a nice day.
So kids, you're visiting
my little palace.
Some chorizo? A drop of Malaga?
- Dad, we came to ask you...
- Solemnly.
To come back down.
- Why?
- Because.
This can't go on.
Dad, we're very worried.
About your inheritance?
Don't make jokes!
It's no place for you.
For the first time
I feel in my place.
Here I discovered...
a family.
- A family?
- Yes.
But they're servants.
No, they're not. They're fine women.
I hope you find
some like them to love.
Go, sit down.
Sit down.
Things OK, ladies?
Yes, thanks.
Everything fine?
Very well, thanks.
Today's the day!
Aren't you ready?
Hurry! We'll miss the train!
It's at 9AM.
- Where's the train?
- St Lazare Station!
I'm ready.
- Not coming?
- No, I have a date with Mr Armand.
Where are you all going?
To Lisieux. Once a year,
we pray on St Teresa's grave.
More and more prayers!
St Teresa's day is holy.
- How do you go?
- By train.
I'll drive you.
- In a car?
- I'll drive you.
He'll take us by car!
Like great ladies!
Ladies,
your carriage to Lisieux is ready!
Wait for me!
But you're not devout!
I love the countryside.
Don't argue. Come long, Madame.
On the 6th floor?
With the Spanish maids?
How do you cope with it?
It's an outrage!
Don't let him off the hook.
Get Attorney Simon for your divorce,
he's tough.
He did the Montalemberts'.
He'll make Jean-Louis pay up!
Bleed him to death.
But maybe Jean-Louis is right.
He put some joy in his life.
Those women up there are alive.
Down here we're dead.
We need a 6th floor, too.
The boss says :
''Get the gato in the kitchen!''
I bring back the gato,
and she screams!
Really?
Instead of the cake,
you got the cat!
''Gateau'' is cake in French,
everybody knows that.
So you put the cat in the fridge!
No! The gato, I ate it!
You ate the cat?
- Pilar.
- Sir!
- You fell asleep?
- Yes.
I'll help you.
- Maria!
- Yes?
Your son...
I know where he is.
You know where Miguel is?
His new family put him in a school,
San Salvador College in Santander.
In Santander?
You've known long?
A long time.
And you didn't tell me?
I swore it to your mother.
Why did you tell me now?
Mr Jean-Louis loves you.
What do you care?
What Don Pedro did wasn't enough?
It's not the same.
As you wish.
But if you go to Santander
you can meet your son.
Thanks, Mr Jean-Louis
for a wonderful day.
Nice of you.
I'll see if Madame needs me.
Of course.
- Good night, Maria.
- Good night.
International, please.
In Spain,
the city of Santander.
Can I speak
to the pupil Miguel Sanchez?
It's his mother!
They're asleep! Sure, it's late.
Maria, what's going on?
Padre, I have to hang up.
I'll call tomorrow.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Life's hard in Spain...
more than here.
But I'll be with Miguel.
Why leave so soon?
You have time.
No. I waited too long.
All these years
without seeing my son.
Now I know where he is.
I'll miss you, Maria.
I'll miss you, too.
Will Jean-Louis ever come down?
Sir.
I wanted to tell you that...
Yes, Maria.
I must tell you...
Tell me what, Maria?
It's a port called Saint-Jean-de-Luz
on the Basque coast,
on the border
between France and Spain.
It's the perfect place for us to go.
And Madame? And the kids?
Who cares? I don't.
You're being silly.
Not at all.
It's where King Louis XIV
married the Infanta of Spain.
- I swear! It's a historical fact!
- You're not a king,
and I'm no Infanta!
What'll you do all day? Tell me?
I'll learn a new job.
Mason, cabinetmaker, dry goods.
You?
You're no handyman!
I'll settle my business,
next week we leave.
We'll see.
Don't say: ''We'll see''!
Say: ''I promise you''.
Right, I promise you.
But you must promise me something,
too.
Go back home.
No. Not that.
You can go down again,
since we're both leaving.
- Please think it over.
- I already have.
Mr Blamond will take over the firm.
And your boys?
It's a father-to-son firm.
They're too young,
and it's a poisoned gift.
It's too late, I have to leave!
Going on a trip?
Yes, a trip. You're right!
A trip
that may last quite a long time.
For me?
Of course.
You know,
I've thought a lot...
About me, about you, about us.
I've thought too.
It's funny,
I don't see life the same way now.
Like me...
I want to start from scratch.
A whole new life.
That's what I was saying,
as I came over.
- Really?
- Yes!
What are you doing?
I want to...
Now?
Not now.
Yes... That's what it's all about.
You're right.
I wanted to tell you...
- Talk to me later.
- What's this?
Mi corazon.
Mi amor.
Really... Maria might walk in on us!
Maria has left.
She left?
- For Spain!
- What?
She did!
- Where is she?
- On the bus.
She left for Spain.
Where to exactly? What place?
You have her address?
Her parents' address.
But she won't go there.
Did she say anything for me?
Did she leave a note?
She said to forget her.
She won't be back.
She said that?
Carmen?
Is she telling the truth?
Yes.
It's true.
I'm so sorry, sir.
So you knew she was leaving?
And never told me?
I thought you were my friends.
3 years later
Please, the Calle de las Canteras?
Straight ahead.
The leak's not fixed! You're a bum!
My mother was right!
I don't believe it!
Mr Jean-Louis!
What are you doing in Spain?
I was nearby and said I'll go hug
my old friend Concepcion!
So handsome! My word!
So there it is, your house!
Yes... I'll show you around.
A lot isn't done...
If my husband worked more
and played cards less,
it'd be ready now!
You must be Fernando?
Yes.
Delighted, Mr Jean-Louis.
How are you?
Just fine.
Don't bother with him.
Get Pilar,
tell her Mr Jean-Louis is here.
Pilar?
Yes.
She lives nearby, left her husband.
6 months ago.
Hurry! Move your butt!
Stingy bum!
Drives me nuts...
He's useless!
When I was in Paris,
he cheated on me with Encarnacion,
the neighbor.
I should've kicked him out,
but I didn't.
So it goes.
In Spain, you can't divorce.
But you need him
to finish the house!
Come, I'll show you around.
Isn't it great?
A tub for a movie star!
Sure it is! Look!
Golden faucets!
I brought them from Paris!
Just for me!
When it's done,
I'll bathe for hours.
You're here, Mr Jean-Louis!
How are your sons?
One is for France,
the other for revolution!
I have tea every day,
like the bosses in Paris.
And Madame Suzanne?
We divorced.
In France, one can do that.
And she met a successful artist.
And Mrs. Triboulet?
Now she loves Spaniards,
but hates the Portuguese.
Poor Portuguese!
Concepcion, I came to find Maria.
What do you want with her?
To understand.
She never said goodbye.
3 years later, it's to say goodbye?
I know, it's absurd.
I still think of her.
I expect nothing from her,
but I want to see her.
I'd like to help you,
if I knew where she is.
I heard she lived nearby.
No! She left a long time ago.
Got back her son, left for Galicia.
Then, no more news.
Well, I'll be off.
Good to see you.
Stay for dinner?
No, I'm rushed. Next time.
Mr Jean-Louis!
I know where Maria lives.
It's not far, 20 kilometers,
in a village called Escondido.
Escondido.
Concepcion doesn't understand love.
- Thanks a lot.
- Good luck.
I'm looking for
Maria Gonzales' house.
Hey, Miguel!
You're Miguel?
Yes. You're French?
Yes.
My mom worked in Paris.
I know.
Can you take me to Maria's house?
- Hey, Maria.
- How's your daughter?
Better.
I'll stop by later.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org