This is based on a true story
It was like an adrenalin rush.
I was buzzing and my head was empty.
I thought I could kill him.
That's all.
The 14th of January 1996
was a normal day.
The fact that it was Sunday
had nothing to do with it.
Most of us had left school after 8 years
and so we could do what we wanted.
Every day was a holiday.
SEVEN DAYS SUNDAY
Good morning, young man.
It's about time for church. Get ready.
Wear a warm jacket. Are you listening?
I'd like to come but I'm just too tired.
Yeah.
Make us some tea.
Thanks.
Hi.
Alright?
Yeah, good. How are you doing?
Yeah, me too. I was on my way upstairs.
Yeah, I've got to shake a leg too.
See you.
Maybe we'll see one another again?
Hey, it's about time.
I had to do something.
Did you do that girl finally?
We were in the park yesterday,
at the place where no one goes.
I showed you that.
Whatever. Anyway, we were talking
You chickened out.
Like I was saying.
We were standing there
and suddenly three wankers appeared.
Who were those wankers?
No idea.
Did you at least beat them up?
It all went so quick.
You wouldn't have scored
with Sarah anyway.
She's a bit out of your league.
I've got something here with me.
Take it. It's good.
Do you feel anything?
Don't you want to try that whole thing
some other time?
Now or never.
It was you who said it's so easy.
Somehow this place is holy to me.
Quit the crap. No one'll nail us.
You go in and I'll keep an eye out.
It's riskier for me than you.
No one knows you here.
You're such a wimp.
Get your filthy hands off me!
Do it!
Morning, Adam. Where were you?
Get ready!
We ask God the Father,
for forgiveness for the suffering
that we cause others,
that we neglect and forget others,
that we lack understanding or tolerance
for one another,
that we speak evil and
that we are full of hate and bitterness.
Let us pray for forgiveness
from all our sins
that we commit against one another
without our control.
Tommek?
Sarah, just forget about it!
Put that away.
I've got something much cooler.
Keep the needle still and it won't hurt.
Where is Adam then?
The idiot got caught.
You realised it in time?
I tried to warn him.
The wimp didn't get it.
Because of that idiot
I'm standing here empty-handed.
Ouch!
You okay?
- I'm fine.
There you are.
I thought they caught you.
I've got a plan
to get us something to drink.
Not bad, this shit. Try it.
We should have thought of it sooner.
We'll do that tattoo later,
when it's only us two.
Fuck you!
Here, have a swig.
- Forget it, kiddie.
Let him try it.
What does your sister say about it?
Are you stupid? Stop it!
Hey, I didn't steal this shit for that,
it's a waste of good wine!
It's about time you went home, piss off!
Chill out!
I can't be bothered.
Maybe it's better that he goes.
You can have your peace and quiet.
- Always causing trouble!
You don't know what stress is!
In the city it's completely different.
There's always something going on.
Robberies, fights
You see that bike there?
You think the guy had the balls
to say something?
If you wanna be something,
make sure people respect you.
Doesn't matter what you do,
just follow through.
Hey, where are the others?
I'm talking to you!
Where they always are.
Hey, we're having a party tonight.
Tell your sister!
Little wanker!
Got change!
Don't have any.
What should we do?
I'm off.
Wait a second!
Those bitches are boring anyway.
Excuse me please.
Might you have some change
for two needy youngsters
too weak to work?
We're never going to get anywhere
like that.
That never works,
you look like a famine victim.
Pay attention.
I'll show you how it works.
Excuse me, please.
Can you spare a bit of change?
That would be kind of you.
That's just enough for an ice cream.
Haven't you got any more?
Come on, show me!
Hey!
What's this?
You're taking the piss, you wanker!
That's enough for 10 beers
and some fags.
10 beers and fags!
You wanker!
Fooling me!
Come on, Tommek. That's enough.
Look at them carefully
with their furious mugs.
I'm telling you, mate.
What do all those weirdos want!
Hey, Piss off!
Have you got another beer?
Sarah really isn't so bad,
you're right.
Definitely got a nice tight ares,
one you can really get in to.
You didn't find the situation
a bit over the top?
I mean, the guy didn't resist.
We had the money already.
Imagine, if I didn't beat him to a pulp
what do you think would have happened?
Then it would have really kicked off.
He would have run and told someone.
Now he's so scared,
he won't say anything to anybody.
He can be grateful he's still alive.
Now you're exaggerating!
I'll show you something.
Everyone's got a taste for violence.
You're only free,
when you free yourself from pain.
Tell me
What's all this for?
Don't know. It's just tough!
That's complete bullshit.
What's with you?
Yeah, I just want to
You don't understand.
Nothing's going on here.
Piss off. Don't annoy me.
I didn't ask you to crawl up my ares,
now did I?
Why are you getting so wound up?
Piss off, don't annoy me!
Calm down, I didn't say anything.
I've got to check on my granny.
Check on your granny.
Yeah, he's got to check on his granny.
As opposed to you
Come on, I'm going now. Later.
Hello, Sarah.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Looking for Flo.
I don't want him to run to Mum
and tell everything about Tommek.
There'd be trouble.
If you want, I can help you
look for him.
Yeah.
I'll just pick up some fags.
Give me a second.
I'm here.
Let's forget it.
Makes no sense.
I'm sure he's already home.
If you say so.
How about a fag?
Right, sorry.
How's your granny, anyway?
Good, great.
The nightshift is turning her
into a zombie.
I can't get why she doesn't pack it in
and put her feet up.
We've all got to live from something.
What else have you got?
What's with you?
- What?
Do you really want to start tomorrow?
- Of course.
And for how long?
Getting up every morning, going home.
For shit money.
That's not something for me.
It's not so badly paid.
Whatever, it's too dumb for me anyway.
Tommek really fucked up earlier.
Why can't he just leave it?
Yeah, but nothing happened.
I thought it sucked.
But that's how it is when you're young.
When I was his age,
I couldn't hang out with the older kids,
and that got on Tommek's tits.
That's not what it's about.
Flo was lucky
that Tommek didn't knock him flat,
the way he was behaving this morning.
Come on, let's check up on the others.
What's up with tonight?
I don't know, tomorrow's my first day.
Oh, it'll be fun.
You can go home and
sleep for a few hours.
We won't miss anything here.
We're going home to crash
for a few hours. Bye.
Good idea.
One of the women, understand?
I'm off. Got some stuff to take care of.
Sarah!
Sarah! Wait a minute!
I'm sorry about all that
with your brother.
Come on, I'll walk with you a bit.
You've got to keep your chin up.
Let's get 9°I"9...
Hello.
Is Sarah there?
No, I'll call again later.
Bye.
You see, I even walk you home
to make sure nothing happens to you.
I'm not as bad as everyone says.
I'll come upstairs if you want.
Your mum's definitely not there.
You really believe you can do
what you like to people, huh?
I don't think so.
You like me.
You just don't know it yet.
You're completely wasted.
I like women who keep me waiting.
The best things come to those who wait.
Here.
You can spin on this.
Yeah, but we haven't got that far.
I thought we'd go to your place first.
I'll make pancakes.
And read you a story.
Come on, don't get mad at me.
Everyone gets a second chance, huh?
Hello, I'm Sarah. I'm new here.
I'm Sarah.
Can you help Florian
with his homework?
Yeah, coming!
Hello.
Got something planned for tonight?
Yep.
I'm going to a cool party.
I'm sure you'd like it.
Hey, just come along.
It'll be cool, I promise.
Gotta go again.
Where do you want to go so late?
Don't stay too long, you hear?
Kiss each other!
I want to see it once.
Peter told me that you did it
in the loo.
Yeah, those two were snogging
No one saw other than Peter.
I really want to see it, just once.
Just start kissing!
So, did you put your granny to bed?
No, he was confessing at church.
Someone's got to do it,
considering all the shit you do.
Sarah, I've got to go. You coming?
You got a lot of catching up.
What shall we drink to?
To all this shit.
To the shit.
Come on, hurry up, I've got to go
That's good, I've drunk a skinful.
Bartek is crazy.
HEY
What?
What then?
To the shit.
Grab Tommek,
he's head over heels about you.
It'll be no problem.
Come on.
Have you got any more cigarettes?
No.
I'll go and get some.
I'll pick up some cigarettes.
I'll do it again, huh?
Thanks.
And to whomever the bottle points
comes with me. Those are the rules.
And we'll get something to drink
with the money.
Cool.
Can you hear that?
What?
You can't hear that?
Close your eyes and concentrate.
Stop that.
Tommek, stop that!
Slut!
Shit!
Where's Sarah?
Forget the cunt.
- What are you talking about?
The bitch has gone touting.
That's not true!
Don't wind me up,
otherwise there'll be bodies
Grow Up!
Where did you leave Sarah?
She was tired.
She's got her first day
at work tomorrow.
Tommek, stop!
I don't want that Tommek.
Go away!
You want to murder someone?
I bet you couldn't do it.
Where were you?
Did you see how they were all staring?
Yeah.
No one said a word.
They all thought it was great.
I need something more to drink.
That shouldn't be
the slightest of problems.
Come on!
- Let's go to work.
Wicked.
It doesn't matter who.
The next one had better believe.
Hey, where are the others?
Hey, I'm talking to you!
Adam and Tommek want to kill someone.
What? Who?
I don't think it matters.
Where's Ella?
No idea. She went after Anna.
Now piss off!
We're closed.
We'll pay well.
Closed!
Can't you make an exception for us?
He's got money.
Thanks.
I'd like a bottle of vodka.
Are you even 18?
Of course.
So cool!
Here's the bottle.
Igor, get some vodka!
Closed!
We're closed!
What do you want?
Great, huh?
We should've done it there and then.
It wouldn't have worked with the stone.
Have a swig.
The others really think
we're going to do it.
This stuff has no effect.
Cool.
Are you crazy?
Hey you!
Got a cigarette?
Have you got one or not?
Come on.
Tommek!
Come on!
Come on, let's go!
Did you see what I did?
We've got to tell the others.
He's not dead.
We'll find another one.
The guy wasn't dead.
We just left him there.
Didn't matter.
200 metres away we met the next one.
Be quiet, you'll wake everyone up!
It was so easy.
21, 22, 23, 24
You got another fag?
I'm not cold at all.
Tommek?
Here you are!
Are you stupid? Where were you?
Don't wind me up!
That's already the second time
you disappeared.
What's wrong with you? Look at you!
Cool huh, blood brothers.
Can't you see what I'm doing?
- No, I'm blind!
You're making it dirty again.
- I am? - Yeah!
What?
I just don't want to get busted.
Why are you worrying?
You didn't do anything.
Look at you, look at me.
Do you notice anything?
You've got no idea.
I'll tell the others.
I already did that ages ago.
What! Let me tell you something, mate!
You just talk shit the whole time,
it makes me crazy.
Hey arseholel I'm talking to you!
Watch out you little wanker.
You little bastard!
Piss off!
Get out, piss off!
Shit!
Shut it!
What then, you or what?
Hey come on, yeah.
Like that? You too?
You, huh?
What then?
Another one?
Get up! Get up!
I was completely calm.
I saw everything clearly.
That was my moment.
You have a second?
Here. Some leftover soup.
Sarah?
Hey, Sarah!
It was me.
I did it.
Alone.
Tommek was just standing there.
Give the bag to me!
There's just shit in the bag!
L_6t'$ QQ!
Come on!
And take your jewellery off
They got Tommek a few hours later.
He was still at the railway station
preparing his getaway.
Tommek.
Hey, Tommek!
Tommek!
We spent the first few days
in the same prison.
Then they said we had a bad influence
on the other prisoners,
we demoralised them.
So they separated us.
I only saw Tommek once again
at the hearing.
Come, please.
Come on.
Who is that?
That's not my Adam!
Look at that, all these drawings.
Why did you do that?
Some day it'll all be forgotten,
and what will you do?
When you get out, you'll always carry
your past with you.
Whenever I visited my son,
he always looked clean and tidy.
He didn't look bad.
What were you thinking?
Don't you want to talk to
your granny?
Daily life here?
Well, I get up at half six,
then there's roll call,
then coffee,
then a bit of a stroll,
play cards, we watch TV
and then it's time for lunch.
In the afternoons we work out
and then it's evening already.
Is there no one who takes care of you?
Grew up with his grandmother.
His father is in jail.
And his mother?
You can forget her.
How many people do you share
your cell with?
How long do you think you'll stay here?
No idea.
If you could, would you try to
reverse what you did?
After months in detention and
a prison for juveniles,
Adam C. and Tommek K. were sentenced
to 25 years in prison.
At the time of their of fence
they were 16.
Because of the particularly gruesome
nature of their crimes,
they were sentenced to adult terms
despite being minors.
In the proceedings, both requested
being treated as chief perpetrator.