This is a fictional story. Characters, events, venues,
history and ideology in it are entirely from the imagination.
Fights over money between yakuza and Chinese
mafia have decreased due to economic changes.
Under the bright lights of Shinjuku, Tokyo,
Nicho-me has a gay district.
Kabuki-cho has male escorts.
This is the area where men become horny.
Hey, Ryuji!
Do you love me?
Are you in love with me?
I love you.
I love you, Denko!
You say the same thing to other
customers, don't you?
I told you I didn't.
I don't usually have sex with customers.
If I wasn't serious about it,
I wouldn't have come all the way to a hotel.
Ryuji! Put it in already!
Then you put it in as well.
More bottles...
It's hard to become the number
one seller of the month.
I'd be happy if you ordered
another 2 or 3 bottles of Pindon.
I don't have any more money.
What are you talking about? You're one
of the elite office workers from Marunouchi.
I think it's about time for you to have a bonus.
But I have already bought you
a car with my wage advances.
How about dating a guy for money?
But I'll turn 30 this year.
You are the first generation to experience
this trend, aren't you? Didn't you do it in high school?
No way.
I was studying all the time.
That's why I was able to enter a top
university and my current company.
That's why I work with my current boss.
If you don't have money,
nothing matters anymore.
Your life is now meaningless!
Onmyodo is a philosophy based on the
Yin-Yang Theory and the Five Elements Theory.
It originates from ancient China but
developed independently in Japan
It consists of physics, astrology,
magic tricks and spells.
The Yin-Yang theory states that everything originates
from Yin and Yang and has two opposite sides.
The Five Elements - wood, fire, earth, metal, and water -
which are the main elements, are added to that.
Onmyodo is called The Theory of Yin-Yang
and the Five Elements.
The one who acquires such capabilities
is called Onmyoji.
During the Heian era,
they were official members of the palace.
They would come among civilians secretly.
They even created the Ninja Magic
during the Civil War era.
Tokugawa prohibited the Yin-Yang theory
as a way to block external ideologies.
However, Japan was forcefully opened by Perry
from the US and the Meiji government was created.
This is how Japan learned about
Western science and technology.
Meiji Japan treated Onmyodo as non-scientific.
Despite its 2,000-year long history and after having
been part of Shinto, Onmyodo does not exist today.
How are you?
Are you here for worship?
Not particularly...
Holy SeimeiShrine
Present-Day Onmyoji
64th Generation of the Abe Family
Kiyoaki Abe
Luck Improvement, Bad Luck Prevention,
Exorcisms, Various other Prayers
Are you a present-day Onmyoji?
No, I am just in training.
I am...
Denko Azuma, an elite office worker
from Marunouchi, right?
You are in trouble because your lover is possessed.
Your trick isn't very good.
You've seen the email I sent, haven't you?
Kiyoaki Abe of the 64th generation
will be here for you soon.
This way.
Kiyoaki Abe is a direct family
member of the Abe family.
The Abe family took care of Onmyodo
during the Heian era.
Kiyoaki is the 64th Onmyoji in this line
and a modern practitioner of his art.
That is...
That is the Five Limbs spell.
The figure is your avatar.
My avatar?
Denko!
What are you doing here?
You haven't visited me ever since.
- I've been waiting for you.
- Ryuji!
Denko! If you keep being mean
to me, I will leave.
I knew it was some devil.
Are you an Onmyoji?
Not just any. The 64th Onmyoji of the Abe family
created by Seimei Abe, Kiyoaki Abe!
You! Go away!
Ryuji!
Father! What is...
He must have been dead already.
Some devils control dead bodies.
You told me you would exorcise the devil!
I thought you would save Ryuji!
Denko! Ryuji was already dead...
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up!
Murderer!
You're a murderer!
Ryuji was my everything.
Bring back my Ryuji!
You should've died instead!
- Die! Die! Die!
- Really?
Die!
Denko! Don't!
- Are you okay?
- Seiko! No!
Seiko!
I've not had a body this comfortable in a while.
I have so much energy.
You're a devil!
Forehead, both arms, belly...
Another Five-Elements Devil!
Abe Onmyoji, I will wipe you off this earth!
Father!
No! I will come!
I should do something!
I can't concentrate!
Can you get over your own pleasure?
Goddamn devil!
I already figured out who you are!
You are... You are...
So what?
This is terrible!
You are the worst kind!
I'll completely destroy your dick!
And I will live for 100 years!
Father!
Onmyoji! I knew you would
have a lot of energy!
I am going to let you go.
Wait! Seiko!
Father!
The Revival Spell, right?
Yes.
It's a bit awkward to say,
but you'd better wear something.
I got no say in the matter.
Only ones last appearance is reflected.
- Just get over it.
- Fine.
You can't defeat that devil.
I know, but I can't let her go either.
Seiko! It's time for you to train more.
Go to Yoshiwara and visit her.
Sayuri at Tsuchimikado.
Yoshiwara?
Also, please do me a favor regarding this.
Is this a Magical Object or Charm?
Loan Agreement
A: Seimei Abe
Loan agreement...
Yoshiwara is a gigantic red-light district which has
been going on for 300 years since the Edo era.
Ever since the opening of Japan, it became famous
for samurais with their incredibly detailed swords...
and their magical skills of sword-wielding.
Equally famous became Mt. Fuji
with its stunning landscape...
and Yoshiwara with its women
dedicated to seducing men.
Meiji Japan wanted to increase its wealth and military
power to become one of the strongest countries.
In 1904, about 37 years later, it defeated Russia in a war
with its modern weaponry and surprised the world.
And in 1941, Zero Sen, the completely Japan-made fighter,
overwhelmed American and British military in...
Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, Malaysia, and Singapore.
It thus showed the world the power
of samurais who learned science.
Pierre Boulle, a writer who was taken prisoner
by Japanese military, wrote a SF novel...
about his surprise of getting caught by Asians,
who he had considered as mere monkeys.
The novel is called The Planet of Apes
and is still popular in the world to this day.
The counterattacks of the Western world
against the colored race were devastating.
Japan was totally destroyed.
American Commander McArthur disbanded
the military and initiated a new constitution.
He prohibited karate, judo, kendo
and erased Shintoism.
Apparently, he thought Japan
had to become a state of the US.
The Women Liberation Policy of the GHQ prohibited
brothels and created laws prohibiting prostitution.
Having sex with anyone for compensation
is hereby forbidden.
In Japan, any sex for money became illegal.
However, Yoshiwara didn't cease to exist.
Brothels have private-room structures.
What we're talking about is Soaplands.
If a female companion voluntarily helps a man clean
himself, this is considered an ordinary relationship.
It isn't considered prostitution.
This legal loophole is used for AV,
Japan's porn, as well.
Since the mosaic covers the genitals,
it's not real sex.
In other words, the AV actress does not hav
sex with someone for compensation.
This is today's Yoshiwara,
Senzoku 4, Taito and Tokyo.
There is even a rumor that James Cameron
secretly visited here when Titanic was released.
This is the largest Soapland district.
Since Seimei Shrine owed a lot of money,
Seiko came here as her father instructed.
I see. Kiyoaki is dead?
Yes. He lost to a devil in a fight.
And you are his daughter?
Yes. I am the 65th generation.
Seiko Abe.
It's written as Haruko but pronounced Seiko.
Excuse me, but where did you
meet my father, Sayuri-san?
I am one of the Abe family as well.
I am the daughter of the lover
of the 63rd generation.
In other words, I am your father's half-sister.
Then you are my aunt.
That's right.
I was also a trainer once.
But I was expelled when I was 16.
And then I came here, to Yoshiwara.
So, did Kiyoaki tell you to train here?
Yes! Please accept me!
I guess there is nowhere for you
to go after the shrine is taken.
That's true.
But the work here is not that easy.
I am already prepared.
Alright, Miss "Written as Haruko but pronounced Seiko!"
How many times have you had sex so far?
Sex!
I can play some instruments...
I'm not talking about saxophone. S-E-X!
I am wearing socks.
They use natural ceramics to improve
health by facilitating blood circulation.
They are very warm.
Stop fooling around. Those are socks!
- The number six?
- Six!
- Or cigarettes?
- That's tax!
It doesn't even work well with that word.
Can't you do a better job?
Sorry.
So, what is sex?
Sorry! Sorry!
Sex is sex!
That thing between a man and a woman!
Sexual intercourse! Don't play innocent!
The sexual activity between
a man and a woman...
I haven't had a chance to experience it yet.
Sorry! Sorry!
Do you think you are fit for this job?
I admit I'm a novice.
But that's why I want to train here.
Though I'm a novice in terms of sex,
I will do my best to learn!
Even if I don't have any experience in
real life, I've seen some stuff from Shunga.
Shunga?
Well, this is very interesting.
Shunga started as a trend among
the royal families in the Heian era.
It played the role of a Shinto prayer
to prevent injuries from arrows and spears.
It was distributed to commons
via printing technology.
During the opening period of Japan, it was
exported to Europe and influenced Gogh and Picasso.
The works of artists like Hokusai Katsushika and
Utamaro Kitagawa have influenced Moe anime...
erotic games, and homosexual works in terms
of their extremely colorful style and abstraction.
These cultures are being transmitted to
the world from every otaku's holy place, Akiba...
in Taito, Tokyo and every female
otaku's holy place, Ikebukuro, Toshima.
The skillful description of sexual activities in these
works have gathered fans from all over the world...
and aroused the sexual impulses on many people.
The measures the authorities took to oppress such
a beautiful, historic culture makes us wonder...
if they are ever serious.
Please don't forget that Onmyodo
equals to the Art of Sex!
The Art of Sex?
Brightness and darkness. Science and fantasy.
Day and night. Reality and fiction.
Sun and moon. Sky and land.
Man and woman.
Everything arises from Yin and Yang.
Just like there are two sides of a coin,
Yin and Yang will become one in the end.
I'll keep that in mind!
The ideal state of Onmyodo
is the unification of Yin and Yang.
Yin and Yang, Man and Woman. The unification
of the two of them is the maximum state.
I will learn as much as I can!
Okay then. Isn't there some
other person who can train her?
It's her first time. People say that girls
will never forget the first time they have sex.
I feel sorry about her having sex with me.
Also, a better-looking guy will
make her more aroused anyway.
A good-looking guy?
What is that?
I think elastic noodles are
better for ramen though.
Where did you learn that kind of poor joke?
I forgot you had erectile dysfunction.
That's another reason.
I've become afraid of women
since I started this career.
Even if you aren't be the best candidate,
you can still do some basic stuff.
There is no one else at the moment.
Just do it.
The very first soap service is a bareback blowjob.
Yes!
Wow, it's cute.
Since I suffer from phimosis, a lot of
smegma accumulates under the foreskin.
Isn't it smelly?
No, it smells like a real man.
I am very interested in the smell because
this is my first time to smell such thing.
I am grateful.
Also, this texture reminds me of marshmallows
and brings back memories.
I got an erection!
I've never had an erection like this in my life!
This is incredibly good!
The first one is done.
The next step is... massage with soaped-up pubic hair.
I didn't know I could use my pubic hair like this.
This movement also makes me aroused
since it stimulates my pussy.
- The next step is...washing your pussy.
- Yes!
Excuse me.
Sweet!
I can't believe it! Another erection?
I got one just a minute ago.
Wood. Fire. Earth. Metal. Water.
Everything in the world consists of five elements!
We give five kinds of satisfaction!
Touch. Look. Taste. Sound. Smell.
Five satisfactions using five senses.
Let's give ideal satisfaction with five skills!
Good, cover the whole body in soap bubbles!
- Flower Clock!
- Yes!
- And 9 spells!
What a hand job!
I can't help it!
I'm coming!
The second one is done.
This skill is called periscope.
Yes!
And then do the Five Limbs spell!
Your chanting tongue rolls around
my penis and stimulates it to the max!
The third one is done.
I don't understand.
I get erection after erection.
It's definitely due to the magic
spell you cast on me.
Not magic! Onmyodo!
Finally, the time for intercourse has come.
Are you really okay with me being your first?
Of course!
Put it in please!
Bring me to the unification of Yin and Yang!
Ready...
It hurts!
There is truth and pleasure to be found
beyond the pain. Seiko! Get over it!
Yes!
What is this? This feeling?
That's right! That's the pleasure of
unification between Yin and Yang.
Raise your Yin energy to grab the feeling.
Is this the pleasure of unification
between Yin and Yang?
Why does this feel good?
She learns to feel pleasure during
her first intercourse. Incredible!
No, Seiko! I will cum right away!
Please cum! It doesn't matter how
many times! Please cum inside me!
The fourth one is done.
I can't do it anymore.
I can't have any more erections.
Intercrural Suction.
Yes.
This is incredible!
My penis is sucked into Seiko.
Her flesh is pressuring me tighter.
I still can't believe this.
But I think I'm getting another erection inside Seiko.
I got it.
Thank you for getting an erection.
I'm happy.
And this skill stimulated a different part than before.
I feel so good.
- Now, use the charm!
- Should I do it with my hand?
No, no fingers. With your privates.
Yes.
Wood. Fire. Earth. Metal. Water. The Charm!
Incredible!
I've never felt this kind of pleasure in my life!
I feel so good as well!
What is this? This feeling?
Is this an orgasm? Am I cumming?
Is this cumming?
Seiko!
I'm cumming again too.
Together! Let's cum together!
Yes! Let's cum together!
Please guide me through it.
I can't help it anymore.
That's right. That's how you do it, Seiko!
Let's do it together! You are not
just making your partner cum.
You have to fully use your senses for him!
Abandon your body to the pleasure!
Learn the pleasure!
Here it is! The ideal state of Onmyodo!
Western culture considers sexual pleasures,
which are not blessed by God, as sins.
This includes masturbation and homosexuality,
This was because of the cruel
living environment at that time.
To combat high infant mortality, the phrase Give birth,
grow in number, cover the whole world was created.
Having many kids is good. Experiencing
pleasure without conceiving is bad.
From this, we can find the difference between
Western culture and Japanese culture.
Japan has a warm climate, fertile land
and a lot of food sources from the sea.
Since ancient days, infant mortality has been low
and raising kids has been relatively easy.
Sexual pleasure is seen as neither good nor bad.
Therefore, immersion into pleasure is a holy
communion with God and the universe.
Aversion to sexual pleasure and the concept of abstinence
are imported with steam engines and Gatling guns.
They are not native to Japan.
Liberal sex was important not only for officials
and warriors but also for commoners.
According to Shintoism, having an orgy
during a festival was the norm.
There were no sexual taboos in ancient Japan:
homosexuality, lolita complex, incest,
love for fictional characters, excessive masturbation...
sexual visits at night, orgies, affairs, sugar daddies,
prostitution, porn, swingers, turtle shell bondage...
enema play, bestiality, rape, molestation, stalking...
Anything was possible.
The legalization of all sex crimes and the pursuit
of unlimited pleasure are closer to Japanese culture.
According to the Japan Chronicles,
Japan was established in 660 BC.
However, Prince Shotoku transformed
Yamato into Japan.
Show respect to the emperor at the sunrise,
show respect to the emperor at the sunset.
Prince Shotoku, who was born in a stable
just like Jesus Christ, said like this to Qing.
We learn the culture but will not be dominated.
This was announcing their equality with the country.
Meiji Japan used this policy when it learned things from
the Western world in order to make Japan rich and strong.
Land of the Rising Sun
This means the part of the eastern tip
of Eurasia where the sun rises.
It also means that the sunrise represents
the development of the country.
The origin of the sun. Japan and the Japanese
flag were created from this concept.
Showing respect with Japanese spirit.
17-Article Constitution by Prince Shotoku.
This is the unification between the
Yin extreme 8 and the Yang extreme 9.
This shows the ideal state of Onmyodo.
The unification between Yin and Yang.
The unification between men and women.
Free sex is the right kind of activity.
The great harmony.
In other words, it is the beauty
of Japan, or Yamato.
That's dangerous. That's dangerous.
Seiko! Seiko! Seiko!
Welcome!
Who do you want?
Seiko please!
It's written as Haruko but pronounced Seiko.
The rumor that an angel had come to Yoshiwara
had spread across the country.
From Hokkaido in the north to Kyushu
and Okinawa in the south...
every man started gathering
at Tsuchimikado, Yoshiwara, Tokyo.
Seiko, we earned a lot today again.
These are avatars.
I want to serve multiple guests at the same time.
Avatar Creation
Please don't overuse it.
I won't.
Seiko is always so beautiful!
She has a rich facial expression.
I will never get tired of her orgasm face.
She has a nice voice.
When I look into her eyes,
I feel like cumming right away.
Her moans are the best.
She is like an angel from heaven.
She smells good.
It's not a perfume.
It's her sweat or her body odor.
She just smells good.
She is sweet.
Her kisses taste incredibly sweet.
Her sweat, saliva and vagina are all very sweet.
There is an old saying that girls in Yoshiwara
are able to control their tasty liquids.
No way!
Maybe Seiko can do such things.
But the mysterious thing is...
When I have sex with Seiko, I feel even
more energetic after ejaculating 5 times.
I thought that was mysterious too.
I feel energized the entire next day.
Definitely, that's because she heals our nerves.
She reminds me of my past.
When I was young,
I got lost in a neighboring town.
My mother came for me.
She called me in a kind and warm voice.
I don't know it's real or not...
But when I have sex with Seiko, I
get this kind of image in my head.
In front of the girls in Yoshiwara,
every man is just a baby.
That must be one of the reasons.
Let me inside immediately!
I want the famous girl, Seiko!
Mister! Please calm down!
My name is Wakato! Worship me!
The world shows respect to me!
I will destroy the world!
I will destroy you one by one!
I'll kill you now!
I will destroy all of you with this world!
There is just one problem...
I'm still a virgin.
I've never had sex with a woman.
So, I want to have sex
with a Yoshiwara girl.
I won't die a virgin!
What should I do?
He is in already.
Will Seiko be okay?
I didn't know such a beautiful
thing existed in this world.
Such a kind thing...
I had no idea!
The world is such an incredible place!
I was wrong!
Somebody!
Call the police for me!
I want to turn myself in immediately!
She is a Bosatsu.
Seiko's sex is not just friction
between two skins.
It is an act where she pours the energy
of the universe into her partner.
People who are tired of their life and
job get healed by the universal energy...
through sex with Seiko and reflect
on their lives in tears.
This guy in his 40's who had been involved
in many criminal and antisocial activities...
was healed through sex with Seiko
and became one of her worshippers.
Seiko is also glad that she can get money
out of her own pleasure in order to pay debts.
She also got people's grateful messages, became
an idol and thought she should've started earlier.
Has an angel come to Yoshiwara!?
She is just another stupid girl
who has sex for money.
Just easy pussy. Plain nasty.
It has no business with elite
office workers like us.
That's right.
Marunouchi, Tokyo, Chiyoda.
This is a business district surrounded by the Outer Garden
of the Imperial Palace and the Tokyo Station.
It is Japan's center of finance and economy.
After losing the war, Japan created another miracle.
Decades after the war, Japan had become
economically strong on the level of the US.
Japan presented samurai who
had learned economics.
Japanese people, who can work for almost 24 hours,
always had Prince Shotoku in their mind.
Since his first appearance on the 100-yen note
in 1930, Prince Shotoku appeared...
on the 1,000 yen, 5,000 yen
and 10,000 yen notes...
during the pre-war, mid-war and post-war
eras over the course of 50 years.
The phrase I don't worship money but I collect
the faces of Prince Shotoku...
shows how people supported the post-war
economic development in the spirit of Prince Shotoku.
This is the nation where the sun rises.
We are the rising sun.
We are the oldest nation in the world
with 2,300 years worth of history.
The sunshine will definitely
come at the end of the night.
The sun will rise again.
It doesn't matter how many times
we collapse, we will soar again.
We will shine over the world.
Japan tried to transform into something
new, throwing away Onmyodo.
However, Prince Shotoku's spirit is still alive!
Seiko Abe, the 65th generation of the Abe family,
came back to Seimei Shrine after paying the debt.
What's the problem?
You want to do it, right?
Help!
How pathetic!
I'll take your energy as the rest of your payment.
Your energy, your talent,
your hopes and dreams!
I'll take them all!
Similar to Harajuku, Shibuya
is a place for young people.
Young girls gather here to buy
cheap accessories and cosmetics.
Up to 1999, when the Minor Prostitution
Act was promulgated...
this was where sugar daddies
went looking for young girls.
Even now, this place provides
some entertainment for girls.
Denko Azuma, the possessed elite office worker,
appeared here to hunt for victims.
- Good evening!
- Serial murders...
- People are in fear...
- It's Dogenzaka, Shibuya.
- None of the victims had any fluids in their bodies.
- Just like mummies...
- Discovered as mummies...
- But nobody knows how they were killed...
- The police is having difficulties...
- According to a rumor...
- The murderer is a woman...
- A woman...
- Multiple pussies...
- Multiple pussies... Sorry!
- Five...
- Five pussies...
- Five pussies... Pussies...
Sorry. A devil with female genitals...
Meaning that she can make five
guys cum at the same time.
- I envy her so much!
- No, I fear her so much...
- Many people are scared at the moment.
Do I have to fight the devil?
She knows Onmyodo as well.
Five vaginas for five senses.
That proves it.
What do you mean by that?
The most fearful enemy comes from within.
Jesus and Judas.
Buddha and Devadatta.
Jedi and Darth Vader.
And, lest we forget, Voldemort.
In other words, the enemy is an Onmyoji.
The enemy of Ryoma was Doman Ashiya.
In the Heian era, there was an Onmyoji
who was considered evil.
His name is Doman Ashiya and he had to leave
the capital after losing a political war against Seimei Abe.
Doman, who hated the capital, the world
and Abe family, planned the murder of Seimei.
Seimei died once but he came back
to life using the revival spell.
Then, he destroyed Doman after
receiving permission from the palace.
However, Doman was not an ordinary Onmyoji.
Though his body was destroyed,
his soul remained intact.
He has survived 1,200 years
by possessing the bodies of losers.
Can I fight like Daniel Radcliffe or Mark Hamill?
Actually, that'd be Harry or Luke.
You don't have to mention the actors' names.
How should I react to that?
Doman Ashiya.
Finally, I'm here again.
I was possessed by Doman Ashiya
once when I was young.
Doman's skill is his partner
of energy through sex.
I knew how powerful he was.
But I wanted to know more about it.
I've been collecting the books by Yasuaki Kamo,
who was the teacher who Ashiya and Abe share.
Those books are prohibited in the Abe family.
Learning about the devil is
a violation of Abe family rules.
Is that why you were expelled?
That's right.
I've never actually used it
but I can transfer the skill to you.
Please teach me.
It seems like you've grown big
in a short period of time.
I'll make you regret not killing
me alongside my father.
What? You are misunderstanding.
The reason I let you go was that
I don't like eating baby Onmyoji.
I think you are ripe now.
- I didn't tell you my name.
- I didn't ask.
The 65th Onmyoji generation of the Abe family, Seiko Abe.
It's written as Haruko but pronounced Seiko.
I am Denko Azuma,
an elite office worker from Marunouchi.
Or would you prefer another name?
Doman Ashiya, the Onmyoji
who hates Seimei Abe.
It's better for me to appear
like this in front of a girl.
I'll destroy you completely.
I'll take them all!
Alright, cum!
Cum now! This will be your last pleasure!
This is the last time you'll feel pleasure!
No, I won't cum alone.
We will cum together!
Avatars?
How did you figure out Ashiya's skill
as a member of the Abe family?
Even a handjob?
The first one is done.
Counterattack the enemy with the same skill.
There is no other way to beat Doman.
Whoever comes first, loses!
This is an orgasm battle!
The second one is done.
You bitch! Still doing it!?
Look at me, please.
Sweet...
This was such a sweet kiss.
Is this the taste of happiness?
Experience me with all five senses, please.
I'll experience you with all five senses as well.
We'll be united in the five senses.
The third one is done.
The fourth one is done.
Don't forget I still have one left!
It's getting big inside me.
Not only the pussy.
The range of pleasure is in more detail.
Sorry for the interruption.
We have a breaking news.
- At the moment, in Shizuoka...
- ...a magnitude 8...
...earthquake occurred.
- Because of this...
...the Fuji volcano was
stimulated. At worst...
Mount Fuji, which has been dormant,
might erupt.
Mount Fuji might erupt.
That's quite dangerous.
The lava might cover Tokyo.
Will the lava cover everything?
She is fighting.
Seiko! Seiko?
Since Mount Fuji is about to erupt, many
people have come out to make a commotion.
Let me check it out!
What are you doing here?
What are you looking at here?
Would you answer me?
This is how Tokyo will be destroyed!
Japan is finished!
The country will be plunged into despair.
In the end, my hatred for
you will become complete!
Doman! No, Denko!
Why are you consumed by hate?
What made you so angry?
What caused you grief?
When I was a student, I never had a boyfriend
because I concentrated on my studies.
But you masturbated, right?
After graduating from university,
I got busy with work.
And then I met Ryuji and was
fooled by his sales tricks.
But sex made you feel good, right?
And I seduced men in Dogenzaka.
Isn't that a good thing?
Good how? I'm a pathetic loser!
I was just prostituting myself!
Service or talent equals money.
That's the basis of capitalism.
I want to get married one day.
But I can't tell my baby about
this time in my life.
Marriage?
I've heard about it.
It sounds like a long-term prostitution contract.
Well... If you can't tell your baby about your prostitution,
you can't speak of your marriage either.
I don't understand why you can't tell your
baby, which is born from sex, about sex.
What would someone like you know about life?
Even in the most closed society...
there is something which will
broaden your views about the world.
Yoshinori Kobayashi wrote that.
I knew you were a classic nerd.
Anyway, there was no meaning in my life!
Please remember Prince Shotoku's words.
The great harmony between Yin and Yang.
Men and women do whatever they want.
That's the beautiful state of Japan.
Every life has its own purpose.
Nobody's life is meaningless.
There is no meaningless sex.
Please be more hopeful.
If you don't like the word hope,
you can use the word desire.
They are actually the same.
Please recognize your own desires.
That's the right thing to do.
I once worked in Yoshiwara.
Having sex with anyone for money
is such an incredible thing.
It was one of the best experiences in my life.
This is not a desert in Israel.
Here the sun rises. We are the origin of the sun.
This is Japan.
The influence of Jehovah can't reach here.
In this country, desire and pleasure are not sins.
Don't pretend to listen to my story!
Everything will be over soon with
Mount Fuji's eruption anyway!
No, it won't!
You still don't understand!
Tokyo and Japan are protected by Onmyodo!
What?
Shinjuku, the district for queens,
male prostitutes and rentboys.
Shibuya, where high-school
girls look for sugar daddies.
Akihabara for moe and fictional character otakus.
Ikebukuro for female otakus looking for gay porn.
And Yoshiwara, the Soapland district.
When you connect them, you
get a pentagram in Tokyo.
Onmyodo is the Art of Sex.
As long as sexual desires exist,
Japan will never die!
How ridiculous!
We'll cum together!
The earthquake stopped?
Seiko!
Seiko did it!
We made it!
Denko...
Do you think you won?
This is the great Omyodo skill
of the Ashiya family!
I'll digest you!
I'll suck your energy!
Your energy, talent, dreams and hopes.
I will make them all mine!
Seiko!
Tokyo is being destroyed!
No way! Did Seiko lose?
No way! There is no way she lost!
That's right. She will never lose!
Seiko!
My energy is being drained.
Is this how I'll die?
You can't beat Doman with avatars alone.
There is one thing he needs
in order to suck your energy.
It is guilt.
Guilt energizes sex.
Can you feel guilt?
Sayuri, I'm sorry.
It was too hard for me.
I couldn't get the secret skill of Doman.
I don't feel any guilt.
Why should I feel guilty because
of something that just makes me feel good?
Of course! You're such a beginner!
Father?!
Why do you think I made you visit Sayuri?
It wasn't about Doman's secret skill
or the debt!
You learned the joy of sex
in Yoshiwara, right?
You learned the pleasure of
the unification of Yin and Yang.
That's all of the training.
The pleasure of the unification of Yin and Yang.
I get it now.
I could've taught you about that
by myself hadn't I been diabetic.
But Father! That's incest!
You have to learn to approach
sex without taboos.
Sorry.
Incest...
The gods who created this country
were brother and sister!
Amaterasu had sex with Susanoo-no-Mikoto,
her brother.
Even I had sex with Sayuri,
my half-sister, while in training.
I see.
As you said, there is no taboo with sex.
If you understand that,
that's good enough.
Go, Seiko! Go, Seiko!
Good luck! You can do it!
Please let me fuck you, Seiko!
You guys...
Please let me fuck you one more time!
Seiko! One more time!
Seiko!
Be strong!
I can't die here.
Everybody is waiting for me.
There are a lot of misguided women who think they can
only have sex with someone who they like in this society.
This amounts to a kind of
death penalty for losers.
I have to cheer them up.
I have to create the great harmony.
- Let's fuck! Let's fuck!
- I have to let them fuck me!
Let's fuck! Let's fuck!
Seiko! Let them fuck you!
I love you!
Let's fuck! Let's fuck!
Seiko! Let them fuck you!
Let's fuck!
Go Seiko!
Win it with the five senses!
Father! Thank you for teaching me!
I, Seiko Abe, the 65th generation of the
Abe family, have just been enlightened!
It doesn't matter how strong the devil is.
It won't be enough to defeat me.
Energy-sucking is just a trivial trick.
My sex is a nurturing sex!
You bitch!
You're still alive?
Do I have to suck you in even deeper?
Do you want to lose even more energy?
If you want it, you're welcome to it.
I will give you everything.
I am one with the universe.
I am a black hole!
I am going to suck everything inside!
Then I'll connect it to my sex.
There'll be a great explosion
of pleasure in the world.
What?!
It doesn't matter how dark you are.
You can't darken the brightness of the wise.
Do you think the big bang will
lose against a black hole?
Please watch.
This is my Onmyodo.
Seiko...
She is a Bosatsu.
No, the Holy Amaterasu!
The 4th goddess of our house.
Thank you so much!
Mau Morikawa
Miho Wakabayashi
Kaoru Yamashina
Atsushi Tsuda / Fukuten
Tomoaki Sandan
Saya Kobayashi
Taisuke Matsusaka
Special Appearance:
Shungiku Uchida as Sayuri
How are you doing?
Are you here for worship?
I've seen you on the internet.
Are you Seiko?
It's written as Haruko but pronounced Seiko.
I heard you'll have sex with anyone.
Is that true?
Yes.
Can virgins and losers like us
fuck you as well?
Yes.
Screenplay: Naoyuki Tomomatsu & Yuko Momoji
DOP/Lighting: Takehiko Tamiya
Special Effects Makeup: Taiga Ishino
VFX: Shota Kawamura
Just don't forget to contribute to the shrine.
Directed by
Naoyuki Tomomatsu