Subtitle: Transhuman
The dream has returned
I don't understand...
why she continues to haunt me.
And that woman...
I feel she's the key to all the mess
in this crazy town
Here's your coffee.
Than you
Have you heard....
About a killer roaming
loose around the area?
Yes
Now everybody is afraid
and they suspect one another.
Women fear coming home
They say the killer is after women.
But, you know what...
that bitch doesn't care about our safe
She only cares about money.
She wants us to stay open until late.
The man back there...
is interesting the murder.
I think he is suspecting me
But who among us doesn't
suspect each other?
Especially if you live in this town
in a cage populated by
strange personalities
Except for...
Maybe she is the only reason...
for me to come home.
Would you like some sweets?
Thank you.
I will never let you and
Sonja leave this house.
Never
How long will you keep me here for?
Until the day you die.
I work in a place.
Where people think...
they can solve their
problems and nightmares.
That woman...
I can feel her presence every day.
I think there's something wrong
with that kid, Boss.
Excuse me.
That woman...
I can smell the scent of her body..
Even in a dream she tries
to tell me something.
Let me go!
You have to let her go.
is it true
What they say...
about the killer roaming loose...
around this area?
That's what I hear.
Do you... suspect anybody?
Do you?
I don't know
He's here.
I should go in now...
The come a great Giant.
The mother and father asked...
Giant, what are you doing here?
And the Giant answered
I came here to give you a zucchini seed.
you should plant this seed.
And... in time it will
turn into a beautiful child.
How did you get here?
Elang
Come here Elang.
Come and have a story time with us.
Come here... Uncle Elang
Come here...
Senja
Would you like me to continue the story?
And then...
After she turned seventeen
The very beautiful girl...
was taken by a great Giant...
Elang
come here
Elang, come here,
I’m telling Senja a story.
Come here, Elang
Elang
Elang, help me.
Please, help me.
Please, hep me.
Help, help me, Elang
Please help me.
I'm sorry
I thought you were in danger...
Who's in danger?
I'm sorry.
I must have been dreaming
Sorry for interrupting you breakfast..
The devil...
is after your soul!
You have to be careful!
The devil...
is very cruel!
The devil wants to steal your soul
You have to be careful!
Listen to me!
You are cursed!
You seem anxious.
Has the bunny reappeared?
But it's only a dream.
I don't know about that..
That women...
She's... the one in my dreams...
Her name is Jingga
Do you know her?
She is bad girl.
Stay away from her.
But there's something we'd like to say.
Our neighbour...
has been acting very strange.
He watches my family all the time.
I am very worried about the safety
of my wife and daughter.
I'll keep an eye on him.
You should be careful.
Do you suspect that he might...
What are you doing, Uncle Elang?
There she is...
I’m not dreaming..
You think you can play tricks on me?
You're an ass hole!
You think you're holier than
everyone else?
Asshole!
You're such a cheap whore.
Can I stay with you tonight?
I don't have a place to stay.
I was thrown out of my apartment.
Thank you.
Fate has brought us together.
Have we met before?
What about it?
I don't know.
It was like the first time I saw you.
I felt as though I had known you.
Maybe deep down...
in a different universe.
We have met before.
Perhaps you’re right.
We have met somewhere before.
Maybe.
You like coming here, too?
I really love watching
a performance here!
If the knife had missed
just by a little bit...
The woman would die.
Elang
What is it, Elang?
I have to tell you this...
so you'd know to be careful, because...
Uncle Elang!
Where did you get the mask?
How did she get the mask?
It belongs to...
Senja
You said....
you wanted to take a picture with me.
Elang, what is it?
What's wrong with him?
Senja
We go into bedroom.
Elang
Elang...
was there something you
wanted to tell me earlier?
What's really going on?
You should... be careful with... him.
Him who?
Djenar
Honey
You should leave with Senja...
Djenar
Now!
Hey
Stop!
What's going on?
What happened to you?
From now on...
no other man can ever touch you.
I had terrible vision of you.
I don't know why...
I am always haunted by terrible visions.
I don't understand.
This is nice toy.
Who got you this?
My dad gave it to me for my birthday..
That's nice..
Where's your mother?
They must die.
What's going on?// They must die.
I just bought you some food.
They must die.// Who must die?
They do.
They who?
Those who have tortured me.
raped me...
humiliated me...
Only their death...
can release me from this hell.
Only you can free me...
They are evil and inhuman.
They must die.
Elang
Did you see blood on the floor?
Blood?
Impossible... I saw blood here.
someone must gave cleaned it.
Is something wrong, Elang?
They must die
Only their death...
can release me from this hell.
They must die.
for my whole life.
Your nightmare will be over soon.
Go already.
it's my turn now.
It has been your turn for a while now.
Here
Damn it.
Now you take the bait.
He's losing again.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
What's your problem?
I don't have a problem with you.
What do you want?
You got the wrong person.
Don't kill me.
Help me.
Don't kill me. Please
I feel like everyone is suspecting me!
Don't you feel it too?
You are paranoid
Can't you act normally?
I know what happened.
I smell blood.
Bunny
They must be working together,
Don't move...
Check all the room.
What is this?
Jingga
Don't touch her.
Clear.
We're here with an
arrest order for Elang...
On murder charges.
Take him.
Yes, Sir
Let me go.
Where's Jingga?
Jingga
So can you tell us what happened now?
I will talk only after I have seen Jingga
All right
You've been charged with
multiple murder charges.
I want you.
to talk to me
About the murders two months ago.
Two months ago?
Take a good look.
You must know the people
in the photographs.
You do know them, don't you?
What's really going on?
What kind of game is this?
What are you doing to me?
Let's not play a game
That's exactly what we
are trying to ask you.
Let's not play a game
Tell us...
Why did you kill these people?
Kill? But they're not dead.
Save your lies!
Why don't you?
Ty to remember
Remember?
You're both wrong.
They're still alive.
Oh thank goodness.
You found him.
And then he run away
That's very shocking to us.
We hadn't expected it.
Did he ever try to run away before?
Never
Would you consider him
as a dangerous patient?
Most of the time he
like to keep to himself.
He is also very polite.
I don't know what got into him.
But, please.
But please.
Return Jingga to me.
Please.
When he lived here...
I had never seem him with anyone.
Not even once?
Not to my knowledge.
Okay
Sir.
Can you remember...
Maybe he had brought home a woman once?
Someone named Jingga?
No... nothing
Elang doesn't like to make friends...
he always keeps things to himself.
But...
What?
He's a little strange.
I always think that about him.
How do you mean?
One night we had a blackout.
I don't know why...
I had a feeling I wanted
to check the place out.
And on the top floor...
which was unused and empty.
I saw him standing and quivering...
while looking up.
But there was nothing above him.
And then what else?
I often saw him stand alone in the hallway.
He was silent for a very long time.
Sometimes it was as if he was talking
to someone.
Would you like some sweets?
He didn't even realize that...
I was watching him.
Oh yes...
There was another strange
thing that happened one night.
He was talking about
seeing blood on the floor.
and asked about his next door neighbour.
but the floor was clean
and there was nothing going on,
What's with the next door neighbour?
That's what was strange about it.
The room next door has been been vacant
for a year now.
Two months ago...
I saw a young man lying on the floor,
in front of the door.
He was very weak.
So I brought him in...
and gave him something to drink.
He didn't say much.
It seemed like he didn't know where he was.
I felt bad for him.
So I offered him a job here.
How did you find him?
I mean, how did he behave?
He's very quiet.
But he works hard.
It's just that sometimes.
he lives in his own world.
Was that why you fired him?
On one strange evening.
We had a customer who kept
arguing with her boyfriend.
Where's the proof that
you had broken things off?
I know your game.
You think you can play tricks on me?
You asshole!
Hey, watch you mouth!
You think...
you're holier than everyone else?
You asshole!
You're so cheap.
You mean the silent young man?
Yes, he comes here...
often to drink coffee by himself.
And he always sits in
that corner over there.
This your coffee.
How are you today?
I don't really know him.
He never likes to talk.
Except maybe to one of my waitresses.
Ningsih
I don't really know much about him.
He doesn't speak very often.
But he loves to talk
about hiss bunny dreams.
I don't know.
He seems to hate bunnies.
Bunnies.
And you didn't feel weirded out by it?
Of course, I did.
I things bunnies are the cutest thing.
One more thing.
Have you ever seen him
talk to a women named Jingga?
He always comes here alone.
What's your connection with
the men you slaughtered?
three men you slaughtered?
I didn't know them.
You didn't know them?
Here's an ax...
and here's you bloodied shirt
which you dumped into the trash.
Answer me
I really don’t know them.
I really didn't know them.
They why did you kill them?
To revenge Jingga
Jingga, Jingga, Jingga.
You're driving me nuts.
Arturo, stop it.
Sit down. Sit down.
I'm not lying to you, Sir.
Please believe me.
All right.
Why don't you tell us about Jingga.
Those three men had raped Jingga.
I simply carried out her revenge.
I love Jingga.
I will do anything for her,
Please
Believe me.
He can't tell the difference...
Between what's real and what's not.
He built...
His own world inside his head...
until he believed that...
His imagination was real.
So he could manipulate
everything to look crazy,
Right?
Are you questioning my diagnosis?
I've tested him.
I've hundreds of patients like him.
Doctor.
Doctor
So that means...
If he did commit murder...
he wouldn't be conscious of it?
Right?
That's right
Yeah.
In other words, he'll get away with it.
In other words...
He doesn't belong in jail.
I don't buy that bullshit
We're not going to let him
get away with it, are we?
I remember on the night it happened.
The sky looked darker than usual.
That's my daughter's photograph.
That's my daughter photograph.
Her name's Laras.
She died ten years ago.
In an accident.
She was 15 years old
Can you tell us...
About the three men who were murdered?
How well did you know them?
They're drunkards...
with nothing better...
To do than make problems.
Please have a drink.
Thank you.
One more thing...
have you ever heard...
involving the three murdered people?
So it's true...
those three men had raped a woman?
That's an old story...
which we all tried to cover for.
Everyone...
pretends like nothing had ever happened.
Can you talk to us about it?
Once there was a young woman...
who used to rent one of
the small houses here.
She was a prostitute.
She always kept things to herself.
She only left her house at night.
Everyone here talked about her.
as if we all much better than she was.
You know about it?
This is a small area.
Everyone here knows about it.
And then what happened?
Well, word got around...
and everybody turned into a pariah.
Everybody cornered her.
Shamed her.
What about the woman?
She died.
She hanged herself.
When did it happen?
Around two years ago.
Two years?
Was her name Jingga?
Jingga?
No one ever knew her real name.
Everyone here called her... a witch.
We should focus on Elang
and forget about Jingga.
The bloodied knife and shirt...
are enough to prove he had done it.
But how would he have know
about the rape?
And what did have to do with the three men?
Fortunately,
there hasn't been too many suicide cases...
in the last three years,
Which makes it easier for
us to compile the data.
especially for those who
cannot be identified.
I remember what happened.
The woman was very beautiful.
It was unfortunate that
she felt she had to kill herself.
Is this name of the woman
who committed suicide?
Yes. It is.
How did you know about the rape?
Jingga told me.
Jingga doesn’t exist.
And you were treated at the hospital...
the woman who was raped
had hanged herself and died.
Come on
You must have read about it in the paper...
and made up something for yourself.
Right?
Jingga is still alive.
You're smarten than
everyone thinks you are.
You're trying to manipulate them...
with your stories...
so they'll think you're crazy.
Do you still remember that?
What is this?
Do you remember?
Look at it.
These are pictures of
you wife and daughter...
you killed them five years ago.
You never admitted Ti killing them.
You said there an evil bunny...
who come to the house and killed them.
Yes, the bunny did it.
Now find him.
That evil man was you, Elang.
No... It was you.
It was you... It was not.
But you wouldn't admit to it...
you always said someone else had done it.
It wasn't me...
Do remember...
Look at all the faces!
Look
The day was Senja's birthday.
You came home earlier
after working the performance...
because you wanted to surprise her.
You're home early.
Senja.
Daddy brought you a gift.
Where are going sweetie?
Please understand.
We've talked about this.
I can't take it any more.
Please.
Please understand me.
I'm scared, Mother.
You don't have to be scared.
Everything's okay.
Where are you going?
Senja, wait over there.
I can't take it any more.
I'm leaving.
I will never let you or
my child leave this house.
Never
How long will you keep me here for?
Until the day you die.
Dad... don't
Djenar...
Senja Where are you guys?
Quickly, he'll be home soon.
So did you do to them?
That's impossible...
Open your eyes, Elang.
You remember.
That's impossible...
I couldn’t have killed the people I love.
There was no one else there, just you.
Look at them
Look at those faces closely
You are the killer.
Now you know...
There was no one else but you.
There was only you.
Hallo Haris?
Is Yosef there?
All right... please tell him...
That I am bringing him
a very important document for him.
Yes, very important.
Okay.
Please wait for me.
Please forgive me.
Forgive me, sweetie...
I;am sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Yes, Haris.
What is it?
From the report we received...
Arturo's death is not an accident.
What about the document he had with him?
I haven't received it.
We didn't find any document on location.
So the woman did not die?
No, she didn't.
The old woman who brought
her here saved her...
When she tried to hang herself.
An old woman?
Yes Jingga
Jingga
Where are you?
Let me go... let me go...
Jingga... Jingga
Where is Jingga?
Let me go... let me go...
Let me go...
Relax Elang.
I'm here.
How are you?
It's good to see you back here.
You...
you...
Jingga...
Why don't you rest.
Don't worry.
I'll always be with you.
Jingga.
We have to leave now.
You look exactly like me daughter Laras.
I'm not your daughter.
I'm not Laras.
You can call me Laras...
and treat me like your daughter.
If you can carry out my revenge...
toward the three men...
who have raped me.
This is Laras, my niece.
Starting today, she will be working here.
This is your room.
You will stay here with the other nuns,
You have one day off per week.
You will have new life...
and I will be part of that life.
You will walk into her life...
Surrender your heart and soul to her...
Your jobs is to revenge her...
and bring her peace.
You are cursed.
The devil is after your soul.
You have to be careful!
The devil is very cruel.
You must be careful.
What is going on here?
Your revenge has been carried out...
Laras, my child.
Yes... mother.
We'll have another adventure, Elang..
They must have gone far by now.
My lovely daughter...
I will always watch over you...
And will always be your guardian angel.
.