A Film Workshop Production
SHANGHAI BLUES
Starring:
Sally Yeh, Kenny Bee
Sylvia Chang
Directed by Tsui Hark
Translated and Subtitled by CHiU
SHANGHAI 1937
War of Resistance Against Japan has begun
Stop!
What's the problem?
The Japanese have landed in HK.
A curfew will be enforced soon.
So what!
This is the French concession.
They wouldn't dare come here.
I don't care, I'm going to the nightclub.
French concession...
To hell with them!
Keep your hands to yourself!
There's no place like this in the world.
So many legends, So beautiful, So great.
You and me,
There's no day or night.
It will go on, forever and ever.
Tou has raised the price of rice so high,
pretty soon we'll be eating bread.
French wines and Cigarettes, Chinese suits,
In this wonderful place, it all comes together.
Stop complaining
You've been in the French quarters,
for so long you should be used to bread.
Your stomach probably can't take
rice anymore.
This is the French concession,
This is a place to forget all your worries.
Rice, bread, it's all the same
just as long as your full.
Let's not worry about tomorrow
as long as there's wine today. Cheers!
Wait a minute!
Don't leave like this!
What will I tell my uncle?
Tell him the truth.
They're paying us double over there.
What would you do in our shoes?
Let's go!
Wait!
Me and you and me and him, we want to make!
This most fabulous place our home!
Have a laugh, sing a song, do a dance!
This tiny place is like Heaven
My nose is gone.
Where is my nose?
Uncle, here's your nose.
These noses are the other guys'
That reminds me, where are they?
They went across the street,
They're being paid double there.
What will we do?
You know what uncle, I want to
quit too.
What! Even you've turned against me?
No, I just don't want to be a clown anymore.
When the world is in a mess,
there's no better job than a clown.
-I want to enroll in the army.
-You in the army?
An Adventurer's Paradise.
A Rich man's Heaven
A Ladies place of delight
You should quit too.
The Japs are here.
You and Auntie,
should both make plans.
They re really here?
Yes.
Clown's you're on next!
Forget it, no more clowns
were leaving.
The Japanese are already here.
Go, tell the boss him and his family
can be the clowns.
Go on!
Lett's take this stuff off.
Take this, it has a really nice sound.
Why? I'm going to be a soldier
not a musician.
I know that idiot.
Sell it, you can use the money.
You can't go to war
with a empty stomach.
Going to be a soldier, eh?
Look at yourself!
Like that, much better.
Me and you and me and him, we want to make!
This wonderful place our home
Have a laugh, sing a song, do a dance!
This tiny place is our Heaven
They're bombing.
What do we do?
It's so dark!
Power failure.
Let's hide.
Why did you push me?
I couldn't see!
Are you allright?
We can swim across to the Concession!
Look over there.
Why is there such a huge fire?!
Where is that?
In Zhabei and Hong kou.
Zhabei?
My family is there, I have to go back.
No. It's too dangerous.
I have to save them!
They are still bombing. Listen to me!
Come back. Don't go!
Why is it so quiet?
The way it's burning like that,
there'll be nothing left.
- Where are you going?
- To fight in the war, Godbye.
Don't cry.
There's no use crying.
Give me your hand.
Whatt is itt?
The money I earned today as a clown.
Why are you giving it to me?
Take it. For a rainy day.
You'll find a use for it.
I'm going to fight, I don't know if I'll be back.
Wait!
Wait. You must remember this.
We will win!
Right. We'll win. there's no doubt in my mind.
Be confident.
You have to come back.
After we ve won, we'll meet here again.
We'l meet here under this bridge.
But it's so dark...
I can't even see you properly.
What's your name?
The air raid is over!
I have to see my family.
Let me get my violin.
Where are you?
We ll meet here again under this bridge.
It's a promise!
8 YEARS LATER. THE WAR HAS ENDED.
Shanghai Park victory celebration.
Why did you drag me here?
I just got back.
I made you come because the leader
couldn't find a tuba player.
But, I can't play.
Not so loud!
just make some noises with it.
I'll try my best.
There's the band leader, come quick!
How come your so late?
This is my nephew.
Nice to meet you.
Sorry, I didn't mean that.
This tuba is very heavy.
Get ready the train is coming!
Hurry! Get ready!
Stay out of my way.
Turn around.
Everyone ready.
The train is coming!
It's over there!
Why is it coming from the other side?
How would I know?
Everyone follow me!
I am fed up with you. Come.
Is everybody ready to play?
The tuba guy left.
Let's go get him!
Toilet paper, $600 Yuan... toilet paper.
How much is that?
$30 Yuan per sheet.
Yestterday, is was $10.
Tomorrow it'll be $40.
Forgett it. I'l just have to hold it then.
I've gett black market US dolars.
I don't even believe in money anymore.
It's Money! pick it up quick!
Don't touch!
Buns $500. Pancakes, $100.
Get it beefore they go up.
Here, have a pancake, one is $100!
- Two buns pease.
- Coming up!
$100 Yuan, my pretty lady.
What are you looking at?
Your the one showing it off.
EROTIC BALLET OF THE ORIENT
Hey don't grab me!
You took her money. Give it back to me.
It's ok. We're all trying to make a living.
This is yours and this is mine ok?
Make a living? Give me all of it.
If not I'll call the police.
Don't let me see you around again!
Please be seated.
Hurry, follow that one in the front!
Hurry!
Faster, You're too slow!
Forget it. I'm not taking you!
I'll do it then.
Take the tuba for me!
You've still got to pay the same.
I know.
Your mom must be so proud
to have such a smart son.
It's right here.
The shop is closed?
Obviously they've moved.
Idiot!
Then I have nowhere to go.
Don't try to swindle me.
I don't care, I just want my money.
My money, now!
Don't you have any pity for me?
Huh? Huh? Huh?
Pity costs money too.
Times are tough.
My money is in a private place.
Don't turn around.
Don't peep!
- I've almost got it.
- Sure.
Why should I listen to her?
Hey, you haven't paid.
Wait up!
Don't try to get away!
A ticket? I'm leaving right away.
Then, I'll give it to you right away.
Over here, sir, we're very clean.
Drop the price a little.
Go see your mother!
maybe she'll do it free to you.
I've made a fortune!
Forget it... I'm too tired to go on.
I quit!
How much do I owe you?
$467.60
I've never made such easy money.
Oh no,
the pickpocket must've taken my wallet.
What?
Your not going to pay?
Poice, he's not payihg his fare.
You want all the prostitutes
in the street.
Listen girls.
This big man is paying for all of you! Hurry!
No!
But I don't...
Can you tell me if you've seen...
It's a tuba!
Chief, this guy has a tuba.
A Chinese tuba and violin,
don't go together.
We're not playing western music,
tell him to leave!
Comrad es, I vwas also a soldier too.
Really? which unit?
5th army of Sanghu.
- IMe tee!
- We're from the same uhit.
Come. Salute!
Have you seen
a girl with short hair around here?
a girl?
With short hair?
Will long hair do?
What, Where?
What did he say?
Your deaf!
Don't push on my head.
You mean the girl with short hair?
Yes. You've seen her?
I don't know I'm blind!
Ask them.
Have you seen her? Have you?
Nevermind.
It seems that they haven't.
He left.
Why didn't you say so?
Don't fall into the river!
My friend, We're not hiring musicians.
Go away.
Shu Pei lin
Shu Pei lin, you're on next!
Don't rush me or I'll take the toilet
with me.
Boss.
A drink, Boss?
A Merry Widow!
Isn't any girl interested in your ring?
Don't worry,
I'll find the right person for it.
Who'd be so unlucky?
Why didn't you tell me someone
wanted time with me?
Don't you know I need the money?
I... I forgot.
Whatever, Big boobs.
What'd you call me?
Oh no!
Shu Pei lin, you're on next!
Don't rush me or I'll go up there naked.
Don't do that, or we'll all lose our jobs.
- Is that so?
- Look at her!
Those dreamy dreamy eyes
Those dreamy dreamy stars
Let that good fine wine,
Fill up that empty empty heart
Oh no... . the dress!
She went on stage with it.
This is bad!
Your dress...
It has a big hole in it!
Those piles of money,
Will find you love
A dream that's made of riches
ln this city with no sleep!
hat happehed!??
It's Big Boobs fault, she dragged me
away from ironing.
What a great performance.
What an applause!
You know your better than me.
Bitch!
I'll kill you!
What's happening?
I'm sre y'ouu can talk it outt!
Stop fighting.
Stop fighting, I m the one getting hit!
Stop!
You finished?
Yes.
Excuse me.
I'm in a hurry
I didn't mean itt.
You dare ruin my girl's dress,
You want trouble?
You better pay protection money.
If you want to work!
Otherwise, don't mess around!
Uneersstahnd!
Don't kill yourself!
Who wants to kill themsef?
You!
Don't let go!
Let go?
I can't believe you want this!
I can't swim, help!
Now, do you understand
how precious life is?
Stop lecturing me and come save me!
Only idiots commit suicide.
I'll let you marinate a little.
When you say your sorry,
I'll come save you.
Feel sorry yet?
I'm really really sorry.
Poor girl!
Don't be so stupid from now on.
In life, you have to be brave.
Look at me,
I'm all alone, no money, no friends.
I must wander in the streets,
without nowhere to go.
However, I don't want to commit suicide.
It should be me trying to kill myself.
Your right, you should die, not me.
Go ahead then!
Pedicab!
Coming.
Take a seat.
You realY don't have anywhere to sleep?
I cant believe it!
Your letting me stay with you!
There is no need to repay me.
People should help one another.
But, promise me, you won t kill yourself again.
What will happen if you do,
and I'm not there?
Shut up! or I'm changing my mind.
Here we are!
Time's up
Still eating?
Here's your money.
Thank you.
This big trunk is blocking the stairs.
Who moves at this hour?
Wateh it
Does this coolie live up here?
Nobody lives upstairs,
He's probably just moving in.
Come in.
My house is falling apart.
You, up there!
Put your coffin dowh more gently!
What a bitch.
Here's your diner, fishy.
If this light flickers one more time!
I'll break it!
Hurry!
Just in time.
Much better.
A few more drops, please.
This is beautiful!
In Shahghai you have to rely on Yourself.
Don't be meoeh.
Out!
It really is beautiful.
Great! It's working!
Each drop is invaluable
like the dew. it must not be wasted.
A Rat!
Take that!
It's either me or you.
Time to go!
Who did that?
I'll let you go free!
Go on!
A Rat!
What is it?
It's right behind you!
Where is it!?
Where it is?
In your night gown.
Help me!
I'm scared of rats too,
Someone help!
It s still on your back.
Help me catch it!
Come out, it's gone.
Really? Damn you coffin-man!
Scared the hell outta me!
Where is he?
Taking a shower.
Get down.
What the...!
Over here.
What was that?!
I've never seen a man ashaminig himself before.
Tell me what'd you see?!
Lot's of soap suds!
I always sleep alone.
You take the sofa, I take the bed.
Good night.
But, the bed is more comfortable.
The rat!
How did you get here?
Get back on the sofa!
What are you doing?
Do re mi!
Get up!
They raised the price of rice to $70.
Trading is restricted, They're all buying
up penicillin.
Banks are closing down!
How can you sleep?!
Open the windows,
let the sun in,
breathe the fresh air.
Have some nutritious Dried milk
free from the church.
Dried milk?
Everytime you bring something,
you want something.
Can you lend me $ 2 million?
I need it to pay the rent.
Bad timing.
My wallet was stolen.
Ask the pickpocket, maybe he can
lend you some money.
So, this money isn't yours?
Right, it's not mine.
Perfect
I have to return that.
I need it to save me now.
I thought we were friends?
Enough of this bul-shit. Bye.
Asshole!
I've never seen anything so beautiful.
Those Hairy legs again!
I'm sure I heard a noise, A ghost!?
Get down from there.
It's dangerous. Careful
I hurt myself.
So it's you?
I wasn t peeping.
I was only the stool.
What do you mean?
the stepping stool.
I don't understand.
It s nothing. Goodbye.
Waitt a minute.
Is it that high?
I almost fell all the way down there.
Wake up.
Where am I?
I carried you inside.
What else did you do?
Nothing. I didn't do anything.
Lucky I woke up so fast.
Wait! I want to ask you. Have you ever
been to Suzhou bridge?
- Yes.
- What for?
I jumped.
You jumped?
Yes. To save somebody.
Really?
It was yesterday evening.
What about ten years ago?
It really is you!?
I found you finally!
What are you doing?
I don't know what your talking about.
When you said "ha"!
I thought you were her.
If you embrace me when I say "ha"
You'd probably rape me if I said "oach"
I did not go there ten years ago,
it was yesterday.
I've got the wrong person.
Is this your wife?
Yes...no! She's a friend.
Is she transparent?
No.
I don't know what she looks like.
I've been looking for 10 years.
You say you know her, but
you don't know who she is?
And you don't know what she looks like.
Either youre a faithful idiot,
or just a plah idiot.
I would say you must be a faithful idiot.
Yes, your right.
Your friends must be helping you
find her.
Yes.
I want to help find her.
Great.
Rat!
Uncle.
Why are you always so late?
A woman knocked me out.
You lost your job yesterday for a woman.
Don't do the same again today.
You wouldn't understand.
Understand!
Keep away from women!
The Dollar has collapsed
Gold is soaring!
When is it my turn,
there'll be no more left.
Keep in line
10 silver dollars per person only!
I've stil got the scar from lining
you for rice.
My turn.
I was first.
Two more to go.
My head!
Are you ok?
Don't push.
The last time, it was on the left.
There, I was on the right.
Careful.
- Deoh't push.
- Comme onn.
No more, disperse!
Disperse, there's no more.
Are you alright?
I'm fihee.
That voice...
Can you say that again, "I'm fine"?
I'm fine.
Move along then if your fine!
What's wrong with him?
telling you to say I m fine, I'm fine!
Another woman?
You'd leave me to die for any woman.
It's not that.
It's her voice,
She seems so familiar from the back.
All woman look the same from behind.
From behind and the front too,
they all look the same!
They're looking for a school teacher!
I don't think the jobs right for you.
They get paid very little.
Little is better than nothing.
CALENDAR QUEEN CONTEST
WINNER RECIEVES $90 MILLION
Look.
Calendar queen contest!
Are you signing up?
Where d my eyebrow pencil go?
I have it, I'm writing down the address.
Your doing it too?
I don't want to waste my life
dancing here.
Even if I lose,
I might meet a Rich man.
Here is your pencil.
I also wrote the address for you too.
I put it in your pocket.
Caendar Quueeh, Soy Sauce Queen!
Ahd seoeh, tthe Queen of rap!
I put it in this pocket.
Don't forget.
Don't waste your time.
You know how much
these American dollars are worth?
1,000 RMB
I'll give you two now.
Now, you'll have to do whatever I tell you.
Hey!
I always knew you were a creep,
but I didn t know you would sink so low.
Here's your money back
Shu Pei lin, don't try to get away!
This is too much!
Your a cradle robber.
Even 3 year olds would be scared of you!
Get out!
Gett ggoinng!
I...was too greedy.
You're not too greedy.
Don't cry, I understand.
What...what do you know?
You wanted this money
for your opium addicted father.
Here, take this.
Take it, if you run out,
just ask me for more.
The world is full of bad men
always out to get girls.
Who's the one who hurt my boyfriend?
Big...Big Boobs.
What's wrong with you?
Picking on my boyfriend?
Poor girl!
If only your brain was as large as your behind!
What?
The guy want's a girl like this.
No!
What do we do?
Let's see who has the brains now.
Hee Hee Hee Ha Ha Ha
Hee Ha Ha Laughter.
Ha Ha Ha Hee Hee Hee
don't stop the laughter.
Have a laugh, you'll feel better!
Don't be scared, Don't be frightened!
For the world to have peace!
Me and you laugh, please don't cease!
No money in the world can buy
laughter.
A smiling face, like love
is priceless.
- Ceome here!
- Yes, Boss.
Send some flowers backstage on
behalf of Mr. Tou.
Everytime you laugh, there are true feelings.
The whole world is laughing non stop!
There'll always be peace then!
Ha Ha Ha Hee Hee Hee laughter.
Ha Ha Ha Hee Hee laugh away!
Non stop Laughter!
On behalf of Mr. Tou.
He would like to take you out
for a late snack.
I only eat twice per day,
never late snacks.
You go eat with him.
It s ok we can have breakfast instead.
Is this enough?
American dollars.
If it comes so easy, I might as
well lie down for it!
That bitch!
Never insult a woman,
because ohe day she could be your boss.
Pick up the money.
Comrades.
Come sit down.
You found the girl?
Did you try the whorehouses?
Knock it off.
Have you eaten?
Not yet.
Eat with us.
We were waiting for Hairy Ape.
Here he comes now!
Hold this.
I'll light the fire.
What s wrong with him?
He just sold blood.
Sold blood?
This man gave his blood and passed out!
and you're sitting here happy!
We take turns selling blood for food?
Today, it's him,
tomorrow it'll be someone else.
Tomorrow it's my turn.
I have to eat a little bit more.
Or, I won't have any blood to give.
If I don't have blood to give.
I'll be dead too.
Will he be ok?
He just fainted.
Look at the bright lights of Shanghai.
You're blind. How can you see?
I imagine.
We didn't survive the war
just to die here.
Our time will come.
What s wrong with you?
I met a boy today.
Me too, what a coincidence.
When he smiles, he looks so silly, but
silly and yet so honest.
I...
He's the man of my Dreams, My Hero
My prince charming...
A beautiful prince with his white horse,
just like a fairy tale...
Hey! this is getting to be too much!
When did you come home?
I've been talking to you,
you didn't even notice me!
You have a fever?
No, it's me who s got the fever.
You may thihk I'm naive, but
I know about thihgs like this.
If you had met him today,
you'd be just the same way.
I think I'm really in love.
Have you got a cold?
No, I just cant bear hearing you talk anymore.
Yes... love really is unbearable.
Oh god!
I don't like sharing my bed.
Good night.
Guess who?
Uh... Stool.
You're so clever!
Guess who I'm.
You scared me.
C'mon smile.
I'm a walking AD today, and then...
I gotta go to the radio station
to see if they like my songs.
You'll become famous.
So what?
So, I ll give you a kiss.
It's very black.
And white too.
No!
Madam...
Fight the war, and balls to all!
The toilets stink, because were finks!
Wah la ma ma pa pa!
Me, Do Re Mi knows what to see.
Look at how you "waa", it's realy
funny  to me! Ha!
Good!
Stool!
Do re mi!
- You're working as a walkihg AD??
- Yes Uncle.
Your prince charming is black?
What do you mean, black.
With you, everything that's white
turns black.
You've got a fever, are you sick.
I feel awful.
I'm hot and stuffy.
It's a good thing to be hot.
You should sweat it out, the hotter
the better.
You're burningg up.
You can't go to work today.
Work? I found you a job as a
teacher. The address is in my pocket.
You should go right away.
Is it that urgent?
Kindergarten teacher needed.
Is it the paper
with the scribbled address?
Yes. Hurry or someone else will get the job.
Kindergarten?
Is this the place?
Eight eight eight.
Doesn't look like a school.
CALENDAR QUEEN 1947
SIGN UP TODAY TO ENTER
Excuse me.
So many hands, how do l have time to stamp!
Is this the kindergarten?
When you're stamped,
you can go in. Go!
One at a time!
Have a stamp? Move along.
Take the cotton outt, before you're measured!
what are they doing?
Taking our measurements.
Is that necessary?
You scared? Yours must be fake?
Nonsense! It's the real thing!
17, 22, 17.
Your turn!
The real thing, eh?
Not so hard, please.
35, 24, 35!
Next please!
Go takke your photo.
A photo?
Of course.
We meet again this year!
Anyway there isn't much hope.
I never win, but I still try.
It's the seventh year that
I ve done it. Maybe I'll get lucky.
Ready!
You got my back!
I wasn't ready yet!
Come back next year.
Others are waiting.
That's enough!
Miss, it's your turn.
Put on this swimsuit.
Is it a swimming test?
I saved somebody once in a river!
I don't care if you can swim,
it's your figure were looking at.
Over there.
This fits me well.
There all full!
You've got nothing on underneath!
Neither have you.
Me either!?
Where did she go??
I said one by one!
Where are you going dressed like that?
What kind of kindergarten is this!?
You have to return the swimsuit!
RADIO STATION
THE VOICE OF SHANGHAI
SHANGHAI BLUES
Mr. Ma cannot see you today.
come back again later.
Zhou Xiao xian, please.
If you sign this contract,
I'll agree to anything you want.
Mr. Ma, I'm in a hurry.
Is that him, Mr. Ma?
Yes.
Mr. Ma, long time no see!
Please sign it.
Sign, please.
I'll put your photo all over Shanghai.
Mr. Ma, I...
Im not interested. Take it.
Miss Zhou, this is yours.
This is mine. Here's yours.
This contract is mine.
I will find the best composer.
to write the best song for you.
Composers in Shahghai are all the same.
This is it. Sign it.
Mr. Ma My songs are really good.
You young artists
always full of theories.
But, you disappoint me each time.
You're not in reality.
This is actually pretty good.
Pretty good?
Yes.
- She likes it.
- You see.
Don't block my way.
What is your name?
Dong GGuo-min.
She likes the song.
And the contract?
She took my contract.
There is hope.
Thank You.
My time has come!
Oh god he broke my neck again,
I've got to get to the doctor.
Friends, I'm goihg to be famous!
What a coincidence!
- Excuse mme.
- What are you doing?
Can you shelter me?
Excuse me, Mister.
You almostt knocked me owver!
Help me.
Please.
Be nice.
Please, Miss.
What's your problem lady!
you'd rather get all wet than help me!
I'll give you cover.
Watch out!
You almost ran us over!
Don't run. I have your umbrella.
I'm sorry.
it's my fault, you're soaked.
It s alright.
I guess we have to say goodbye.
Yes, goodbye.
You live on this street too?
Yes.
Then, let's go there together.
Let's go.
Now we really have to say goodbye.
Yes.
Goodbye.
ou livee upstairs too?
You're from upstairs?
And you're from downstairs?
What a coincidence!
Oh, no.
What's wrong?
I forgot my key.
Why don't you come change into
something dry at my place?
Ok.
The door wasn't locked?
There is nothing to steal.
I don't have anything valuable.
Have a seat.
You should change
before you catch pneumonia.
But it's your pajamas!
You change back when your clothes are dry.
I'm afraid it will take forever.
Have some there are no pants.
There right here.
You lost al the buttons on this??
I forgot to tell you, they all
fell off.
I didn t see anything at all.
That means you saw everything!
Not everything, just a little...
Changed yet? Can I turn around?
Telling me to change and not closing the window!
What was that about?
I never close it when I change.
You planned this all out, didn't you?
Me like this! And You like that!
If somebody saw us,
I wonder what they would think.
Do re mi!
Do-re-mi Fa-so-la-si!
Looking for mne?
Hey, Stool!
Open up.
Don't open it, with me here.
I wont open it.
Don't look at me, look at her.
Why?
Why what?
I asked first.
With me like this, she can't see me.
We haven't done anything.
Exactly, you haven't done anything.
So hurry and open up.
You can't open the door.
I can't open the door!
Do re mi! If she sees me like this
were both dead!
Do re mi!
Tell her to leave.
Do re mi, where are you?
I'm coming. Stop shouting.
Stool, where are you?
Here.
You climbed through the window?
I'm used to it.
Not bad, huh?
By seeing you all black,
Shu got scared and sick.
She's very timid.
Don't scare her like that again.
These people all look very familiar.
It's her!
- What's that noise?
- A rat.
A rat?
Have some milk.
It's good for you.
Thank you.
You're so good to me.
I looked all day for a job.
I had no money for food.
I was so hungry.
Someone stole all my money.
I'm lucky Shu took me in.
It's all that thief's fault.
If I find him,
I'll wring his head off!
and make stuffed duck out of him!
I know who stole your money.
You do?
The money you had was...
Don't open the door!
It must be Shu
looking for me.
If she finds me here,
she ll make fun of me.
I've got to hide.
Play it by ear.
I've got to play it by ear too!
We'll all have to play it by ear!
Do re mi!
There you are
Wheres the money?
I spent it all!
On Tea, oil, sauce, rice etc...
Thanks to this money, I survived.
Take this.
I'm not talking to you!
Don't be mad.
You help me, I help you...
who knows what will happen from now on?
You couldn't have come
at a worse time.
Now, you've made it even worse.
I just took a little money from you.
We cant be friends anymore?
I should've never talked to you from day 1.
Are you nuts?
what are you talking about?
Show yourself!
Come on out, or I'll get you!
So it's you?
OOk... . Stool, come over here.
He's the one who took your money.
Give it back to me!
He s the one who spent it.
Why did you do that?
Give me back my money!
Why don't you give it back to him now?
Then where did my money go?
If you pay him back, then he
can pay you back.
Then who'll pay me back!?
lf he pays you back then you'll have money.
Give me back my money!
This is complicated!
But, that's not all.
You still haven't seen what's in here.
Come on out, lets all get complicated.
There is someone else?
Shu.
I don't believe this!
I thought we were friends.
I swear to you that nothing
happened between us.
You were both only almost naked together.
Look at you, you were wearing his pajamas.
He told me to put it on,
I didn't want to.
Told you?
what if he told you not to put anything on!
You want to steal him away from me.
It's not true.
Don't talk like that.
Not true! then, why were hiding
in the cupboard?
You were hiding too.
I...
What's that?
I am not as cheap and easy as you are.
What did you say?
I said "Cheap and Easy."
How dare you! You eat my food,
wear my clothes, live in my place.
If you want to move. Move!
Don't be a mooch!
I'll go far away.
I'm leaving now.
I wont be a much to you anymore.
I thought you left?
Shu.
Can I borrow some money for some food.
I haven't eaten anything all day.
Just a little.
I will pay you back one day.
If you want money,
go earn it.
Go on. Don't try to get pity from me.
Why> don't you go upstairs to him?
Why should I?
He's not my husband.
That one, I'll let you have him.
I can live without a man.
I don't want you to let me have him.
Don't worry,
I ve been waiting for someone for a long time.
Who?
Ah old friehd it's been ten years.
It's about time he came back for me.
That's good. Then now we won't fight.
Shu, let's not talk about men anymore.
It's all their fault.
Come...Let s go home.
I'll make something for us to eat.
I'm starving. Come!
My legs are weak.
Comrades!
There's no more blood left.
You don't have to worry.
Look what I brought.
Thank you Do re mi.
Light the fire, I'll cook them.
It s dirty.
Don't put all rice.
But I must!
We'll even eat the worms too.
We're going to have a true meal.
This girl is always down here.
Is she the one the tuba players looking for?
She has long hair though.
What is it?
Shu Pei In! How dare you do what you did?
One inch on the left
or one inch on the right.
On which side do you prefer?
To hell with you!
Go to hell!
Wrong guy, It's me.
Why didn't you say so.
Stop! Stop fighting!
You dirty bums fighting?
I haven't even eaten yet.
Attention!
Let's send these bums on their way!
How dare you stab me from behind?
Don't worry I'll pull it out.
Your going away pal.
Tear this place apart!
Hold this.
This time,
it looks as if we mush part.
Perhaps, we will see each other again
on the battle field.
- Tuba payer!
- Be quiet!
I have to tell him something.
Tell him on the battle field.
- You know these beggars?
- We were in the army together.
Let me do it.
You save me once again, we'd better
not meet again.
What did I do?
I think that you should treat Stool better.
What?
She is really good to you.
And me, I am nice to you.
Why aren't you good to me?
Lot's of men are nice to me,
you're just one more.
I get it.
You want to know how I feel about you.
What are you talking about?
I don't mean that!
When a woman says that,
she means the opposite.
Why don't you carve
two hearts on the wall!
You think you're Don Juan?
What do you take me for?
For a woman.
Rubish!
Did you find a job?
Want some milk?
You women think you're the best!
She's like that, and your like
this, pouting!
Hey I can be pouty too,
Look!
If you're such a big deal,
why did you come looking for me?
You want to throw a glass?
I can do that too.
why do you do that?
Ok, Throw my cups! Lets throw to them all!
Stop! mines smaller than yours.
Why are you mad at me?
You men look down on women!
If we don't bully you, you'll bully us!
Pouting all day long, even when
you're not even mad about anything!
Pouting day and night, even on the toilet...
To hell with it!
You want to fight?
put down the trophy and fight!
Very well, come on!
Out of breath?
If you're a man, stop moving.
And let me hit you.
I'm not as stupid as you women.
Please let me hit you once.
otherwise I'll feel awful.
Come on.
How did the bottle get there?
Do-re-mi, you ok?
I didn't mean it.
If you did't mean it, when you really do<
I'l die for sure!
Don't die... . I couldn't bear it.
Look at that one.
No, she's the best.
Not only are you good with money,
Your just as good at picking girls.
You have great taste.
Who has great taste?
You, Chairman Yu.
Chairman Yu,
what can I do for you?
Many Merchants have
sponsored this contest.
Remember that the contest is aimed
towards common housewives.
Of couurse.
These girls look like whores.
Chairmah Yu.
They are the ones that we eliminated.
I know. I paid the most money to win this contest.
So, I'll get to pick who I please!
This one!
Uncle you really want to move
to the south Pacific?
I almost have enough money.
Careful!
I'll try to help you.
If you looked at fewer girls,
I would be fine.
"South Pacific"
We have to go to work, uncle.
I'll take you along with me.
Away from this poverty!
Uncle, same as usual?
No. I can't take it anymore,
you do it.
A gift for any purchase!
The more you buy,
the more gifts you have!
Without you, the old man
would have been less generous.
Enjoy it.
It's expensive stuff!
With all that I bought you,
Don't I desenrve a kiss?
You sure do!
And you? Come on!
This side too.
Let's get in.
Let's go.
Harder!
If you don't come out I'l colapsee.
If you're nice,
I'll buy the entire street for you.
What are you looking at?
We're working! It's my turn!
Shu Pei lin, why are you so quiet?
Watch it! my hand still hurts.
Stop the car! I'm getting out!
It's dangerous.
Someone's hurt, don't steal my cotton!
Where you going?
She's my friend.
our frieehd??
How is your leg?
the cotton case fell on her.
We have to take her to the hospital.
Careful.
Don't hurt her leg.
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
You can go back to work.
Young man, well done.
This is for you.
Old man, well done.
Your nuts! Let's go.
Starts.
Don't worry we'll be at the hospital soon.
Atfter my cott oh again!
you think I'm blind, come back!
Uncle!
Come out.
Where did you go this time?
I could've suffocated in there.
Let me put some oil on you.
Here, are you ok?
I'm fine.
Then let's get back to work.
What job?
We got fired once again.
The south Pacific!
I can't even buy my ticket now to go there.
You see what you do to me?
Shu.
You need to take some rest, don't
stand on that leg.
Have some tea.
He... He's here again.
Come here.
Miss...Miss asks you
to cool the tea.
You're still here?
I have something to say to you.
I leave Shanghai in two days.
Where are you going?
To Hong Kong. Someone asked me
to open a cabaret there.
Hohg Kong?? how is it there?
A real melting pot of people.
An ideal place
for a man of my talents.
Then, congratulations.
Shu Pei lin.
I wonder why
nobody wants this ring.
We're not made for each other.
I know that I'm a litte over the hill.
Don't I have any hope at all?
I have hope.
If I give it to you,
I wont have anymore.
Don't move!
You're hurt. You shouldn't move.
My plant!
Why aren't you resting.
Go lie down.
My leg.
don't move.
Shu, I've been thinking.
I'l find a job and we'll
have a menage a trois.
What a menage a trois?
You, me, and then Do-re-mi.
The three of us.
You and him can, butt leave me out of it.
Don't ever get into my line of work.
It's enough that one of us is doing it.
Once your in, it's hard to find a good husband.
Don't worry, I would never
get into your line of work.
Don't forget.
That you can't move, Ok.
I know.
I told you not to move.
I won't move anymore.
Come here!
Don't move either.
The Calendar Queen is missing.
$10 miIIion dollar reward for who finds her.
I swear I've seen her before.
Yeah right!
And I transported Ms. Universe!
I'm serious.
she was really on my pedicab once.
I never tell a lie.
EMPLOYMENT AGENCY
This Girl is so plain looking,
How did she win?
Even this girl right here is a lot prettier.
But, there's a reward of $10 million.
$10 million? That much?
If only I had that much money.
It's her!
I've got $10 million!
I already transported her.
Please hurry!
It's really her!
It's really you?
It's her the Calendar Queen!
I'll pay you back when I get the money!
I found the Calendar Queen.
Why are you following me?
Watch out!
What are you up to?
I'm the new Calendar Queen!
Look they offered a reward of
$10 million to find me!
If only we could have all that money.
That car is coming for me.
Gentlemen of the press, execuse me.
I have to go.
This evening, remember not to drink,
stay sober.
Ok, I ll remember not to drink.
Gentlemen, let's welcome
The New Calendar Queen.
Let me introduce myself.
I own a match factory.
this is the Match Queen.
I have a chicken farm.
May I present to you.
The Chicken Queen.
It's my turn now.
I sell toilet paper.
This is The Queen of Toilet Paper.
How are you.
The Milk Queen, toothpick Queen...
The queen of Light bulbs, the D.D.T.
The Soap Queen,
this queen, that queen.
She still knows how to smile.
Your uncle is a total idiot...,
an idiot...
a blithering idiot..., an idiot...
Are you talking about me?
No I'm not talking about you.
I'm talking about your imbecile uncle.
One moment.
He doesn't even have money for food,
but yet he wants to move to the south!
Uncle!
Wait for me.
I don't have anything any more.
ORIENTAL BROTHEL
Hey there, let's go have some fun.
Uncle!
What are you doing?
Give that back.
This is hard earned money.
I've no more hope anyway.
You think only of the girls all the time,
it's my turn now.
You could catch a disease.
That's better than catching your rooten luck.
Here, for you.
Let's have fun.
Uncle, listen to me!
I know a way to help you leave.
You want to get rid of me?
Let's go!
Uncle!
Your crushing my feet.
You trying to get her drunk?
Of course, I'm preparing her for
the Boss.
Remember which glass to give her.
Chairmah Yu.
Wait...
Are you the new girl?
You look just like my sister.
Sister?
That's so wonderful
Come, Let's drink to that.
Leave this Cognac. At such an event,
should be celebrated with Champagne.
Champagne!
And this toast is to you all...
Did you give her the right glass?
That drink really got me.
Only one glass of champagne
and here she is drunk.
I wasted a sleeping pill.
I want to have a menage a trois!
I feel dizzy, how will I get home?
Boss, she's all ready for you.
Power Failure, I'll go get a candle.
Don't bother.
It's even better in the dark.
Yes, sir.
Power failure?
The goldfish.
What's the matter?
Help me!
I'll be right there!
Where are you?
Don't move.
What is it?
You can move now.
- You were screaming for help?
- Because of fish.
Fish?
It will die.
Quick get something to put him in.
It's cooler up here,
not as stuffy as downstairs.
With this Power failure,
You can't see anything.
It's better than that night ten years ago.
Ten years ago?
Don't you remember?
When Shanghai...
Was bombed by the Japanese.
10 years ago.
It was chaos in the streets.
I was all alone,
I was very afraid.
Me too.
I pushed somebody under a bridge.
It was worse for me,
I was pushed under a bridge.
It was so dangerous, so we hid
underneath that bridge.
He wouldn't let me leave to go
back home to Zhabei.
Zhabei?
He was carrying a violin.
She was carrying an umbrella.
He said he was going to fight in the war.
He even gave me his money.
She even gave him a farewell kiss.
It was you?
I've finally found you.
I can't believe this.
Is it really you?
Why didn't we recognize each other
earlier?
It's not to late, now.
Shu Pei lin.
The power is back on.
Your leg.
These gold bars are really heavy.
How did I end up under here?
How come you're here?
Then...
Chairman Yu?
Quiet, there'll be big trouble
if she wakes up now.
Let's go.
A burglar?
Boss, there's a problem.
I'm glad you already know, come in.
Take off your jacket.
My jacket.
Your pants too.
My pants.
Go in the bed.
Boss, I don't swing that way.
Not with me, idiot.
With that girl in bed!
The Calendar Queen?
Yes.
Thank you, Boss.
Go ahead.
You realy look after me well.
I didn't do anything wrong?
Why do this to me?
In the bed!
If you don't, I'll shoot you.
The gun!
Don't move!
Boss, look out!
Your'e so naughty.
I've been a widow for so long.
tonight I'm a new woman.
My god!
Don't be shy, What's done is done.
As long as you take the responsibility.
Come.
How can I face people again?
See you tonight!
I'm rich!
My foot...
Shu, Listen to Me.
Yesterday evening, I learned
many things about life.
Right, You didn't come home.
That's right, I was drunk.
When I woke up,
I saw that man named Tou, he...
He was lying on the bed, naked.
Beside him, there was
a rich, naked woman too.
This dumb guy came in, he took
his clothes off and got in bed.
They were all in this mess and the
gun went off.
Who shot the gun?
Me.
Let me finish my story, please.
Looks at this! $ 90 million.
This is the prize money, We're rich!
We're rich.
With this money, we can setup our
menage a trois, and live together.
A menage a trois?
You, me and Do-re-mi.
This money can help his uncle so...
He can leave for the South Pacific.
Then we can get married.
Get married?
That's right, get married.
The three of us will all live together.
Do-re-mi and me, and I'll treat you like
a real sister.
Diddn'tt you saYy e're ikke sisters before?
What's wrong with you?
Shu.
You have something to say to me?
You want to tell me now?
You don't have ahything to say?
You should be congratulating me?
Congratulations.
The 2 of you will be really happy.
Thank you, Shu.
The fish died.
At our time,
It's not easy to suvive.
I've decided.
Tonight, I'm going with you.
I'm cooking you my specialty.
You've never had my home cooking.
Where are you going?
I've no use for these clothes,
she's selling them for me.
My cooking!
Meet me at 8 tonight, don't tell
anyone.
Are you really leaving?
Get going.
I'm making leg of pork.
because of your leg.
It is stuffed full of energy.
You'll be walking normal really soon.
At least the two of us got a job today.
If you behave, I'll take you to dinner.
Uncle.
Sorry, but I have a date.
A date?
Were gonna lose this job.
Don't worry, It'll be alright this time.
Uncle!
What is it?
Shanghai Blues
sung by Zhou Xiao Xian!
I can read,
You don't have to yell!
Young new composer Dong Guo Min...
It's easy to read.
On the Voice of Shanghai...
At 9pm tonight.
I finished before you!
Youre right, I gotta be fast, If no I'll miss It.
Hurry.
- Say... to Stool to go...
- At the station... for...
Not so hard, that hurts.
Hide.
Let's go.
Come in, it's open.
...Stool.
What is it?
Shu?
She left to... train station.
Do-re-mi.
Stool.
Where is Shu?
You know the girl I've been
looking for, for 10 years?.
Yesterday, I found her
after all this time.
Guess who it is?
It was Shu all along.
Which Shu?
What do you mean, which Shu?
Let's go.
Wait...
What for?
Nothing... nothing.
When I saw you at the station,
I thought you were her, but
it turns out she was her.
Good evening listeners,
We have a special program tonight
Miss Zhou Xiao xian:
will be performing the song...
Shanghai Blues.
This is the song, I wrote for her.
Hurry or you'll miss her.
You go ahead. Hurry.
Pease just wait a litle!
If she doesn't come back now
she'll miss it!
There are so many soldiers.
I'm really scared.
Don't be.
Is there going to be... another war?
Why isn't she back yet?
Shu, are you ok?
Don't push.
Shu!
She's leaving on the last train
from Shanghai tonight.
Go and bring her back!
Why are you still sitting here!
Wait for me!
The evening breeze is carrying
your dreams and mine.
Why did you follow me?
Why are you looking at me?
What do you want to say?
What more do you want me to say?
Goodbye!
Remember to come back to see us.
Miss, excuse me is this Shanghai?
Yes.
I wish you good luck.
How much of it will stay in your heart?
On a night like tonight,
On the borrowed time and
the borrowed breeze.
Can l send my love to your heart?
Edited by tHe.b0dY