Presents:
A film by Sergey Loban
CHAPITEAU SHOW
Two worlds must never melt together...
the real one and the fantasy world.
You now have to decide
which one you prefer.
Hey?
Hi.
Hey. CyberAlien, your
voice sounds strange.
Yours too.
I sent you something. Did you receive it?
-Yes.
Maybe you're surprised, but that's me.
-But it is not a photograph.
You promised a photo.
A photograph never shows the essence of a person.
-And this is your essence?
This is how I see myself.
But it is not fair, because I
sent you a real photo.
Sorry.
It is not surprising that I want
to see who I am talking to.
I look even worse
than you think.
LOVE
...but there is someone who
knows how to change that.
Here is producer Sergey Popov.
Sometimes a copy is more
valuable than the original.
For example, look at the pre-Raphaelites.
In the beginning they were considered
cheap imitators of Raphael.
Today their work hangs
in the biggest museums.
Hey.
Did I hurt you?
-No.
You were suddenly offline.
I emailed you but you did not answer.
They took my modem away.
My mother thinks I am
an internet addict.
I can not go online anymore.
Probably never again.
What should we do now?
-I do not know.
Maybe we should give it a try.
That would destroy everything.
-Why? No.
That's how it always goes.
But we are still talking to each other.
Why can't we meet each other?
Nothing good will come of it.
-But why?
I told you that before.
But if you want to do something stupid...
You're the only one I have.
Only you.
We never see ourselves
in the mirror.
This shell of a body is too tight for us.
But that does not matter
because we are numbers in the internet.
Nobody knows what will happen to us.
We are nowhere and do not
come to life anymore.
We are shadows awakened
by the morning light.
We are like two numbers in the internet.
Everyone can end
up here, like me.
How many gigabytes
do we get for love?
You are my dearest,
my faceless friend.
What if you disappear forever?
You will find new friends on the web.
We are only two numbers in the internet.
These are just words on the screen.
Only words, but we are nowhere.
We are only drops in the ocean.
Just numbers in the interweb.
Excuse me, are you a CyberAlien?
-What?
Are you a CyberAlien?
Do I look like a CyberAlien?
This is for you.
It is not my fault.
You never sent a photo.
Just your essence.
How could I know?
You look pretty normal.
Did you expect something abnormal?
No.
I've seen the guys you approached.
That said a lot.
I was just trying to find you.
Have you been watching me for a while?
-Yes, for a while.
Listen, I thought...
That if you picked me out,
then it was worth meeting.
I am not afraid, not afraid.
Do you like this movie?
I do not know.
And you?
I can't look at it for some reason.
Shall we go?
Are you disappointed?
Not really.
Have you read Borges'
"The Garden of Forking Paths"?
No. What is that about?
Well, it's both a book
and a labyrinth.
Where everything has all kinds of variants.
You should read it.
Hey, where are you going so fast?
We have to hurry, the
sea is waiting for us.
If you are tired we
can take a break.
Why are we even walking?
Can't we just stop
and wait for a lift?
That way you get the feeling
that something is happening.
We are moving, even though
we are not in a car.
That is an illusion.
Can I ask you not to look?
Come on, tell me a story.
What kind of story?
Does not matter.
A joke, or you can sing a song.
Tell me, how did you meet?
On the internet.
And you're not scared
to travel with him?
No way you're not scared!
Have you ever heard this story?
A maniac found victims online...
And then ate them.
Such things happen.
Look at him, he
looks scary anyway.
I'm telling you...
He has the face of a predator.
And you look delicious.
He's so hungry
he's salivating.
Did you really have to tell a
total stranger how we met?
I didn't mean it.
But you could have said something,
helped me with keeping conversation.
You've made it so that
I couldn't say anything.
I thought I would die of shame.
What are you thinking of?
I'm thinking...
That I've never understood
the beauty of travel.
And that today hasn't
convinced me otherwise.
I don't care about beauty.
You have to think about beauty...
Otherwise travel is completely useless.
I think you can only do one at a time:
either travel or think about beauty.
CyberAlien, are you asleep?
Don't you think it's
a miracle that we met?
Certainly.
Mountains.
Do you want a sip of water?
Can I ask you not to look?
There is hot water twice a day.
From six to eight in the morning...
and from four to eight in the evening.
Hey.
Here is your room.
Careful not to break the beds.
Take a shower as long as
there is still hot water.
Do you want to go first?
-No.
Alright.
You know, as a child I thought I would
look like a princess when I grew up.
But now that I am an adult, I do
not look like a princess at all.
For some reason it seems like I could still
grow a bit more and look like a princess.
But I know that soon I'll be all grown
and I'll look like my mom,
And that what's going on with me now
are the best years of my life.
Where is the shower?
No more hot water.
-Really? What a pity.
Do you want to take a walk?
You mean, you want to take a walk.
I do not know, I thought maybe you wanted to.
I don't want anything at all.
I feel like I'm in a stomach...
where food is digested.
This is not a sea, this is gastric juice.
Why do you say such things?
Why? Look around you.
Why see the bad in everything?
Why see anything at all?
Love that looks like a dream...
Sounds like a crystal.
With all my heart, I love you...
Forever I stay...
Are you thirsty?
Or maybe we'll go eat something?
You mean, you want to eat?
No.
I thought maybe you want something.
I don't want anything anymore.
You know, they say that online
people have no identity.
It is actually the opposite.
People have to distinguish themselves
in a certain way on the internet.
Here you just have to
look good, eat and have sex.
A victory of the human flesh.
I think people are enjoying their holiday.
There is nothing wrong with that.
Do you like it?
I do not know.
Maybe you have complexes around it.
Otherwise you would not
even think about it.
It is my first time in Crimea.
But I am not impressed.
Just another ugly place that I could
just ignore and never visit.
Don't you have a new
impression of it?
I am not looking for new impressions.
I think it is impossible
to find them.
I'm looking for them,
and I believe in them.
Is that wrong?
Did you know that the establishment,
the aristocracy of this resort...
The most special, select group of people
chooses to eat here?
Really?
And why?
Because the canteen service
is a great honor here.
Here?
Are you going to the Chapiteau tonight?
-Perhaps.
You should go, it's legendary.
Why is it so special?
Woah. Are you two together?
This is my friend, from LiveJournal.
What do you need that
magnifying glass for?
A scout can not do
without one, brother.
Arseny.
Alexei.
And what is your username,
Alexei, if it is not secret?
CyberAlien.
-Very strange.
And yours?
I do not have an account.
It would distract me from the revolution.
A scout must remain loyal
to the flag at all times.
I have to go now.
Goodbye.
Bon appetit, CyberAlien.
He's my acquaintance. We have done
entrance exams together.
I already figured out
that you know each other.
Why are you always so depressed?
Because I am depressed.
Do you think I should be happy?
No, of course not, but...
You could have tried it sometime.
You wanted a travel companion
and I offered myself.
You like it here, I do not.
What's the question?
Poor CyberAlien.
Why did I drag him here?
He must be suffering terribly.
You do not know
what you are doing.
You are like a leper, you do not feel pain
if you touch something cold or hot.
The fact that you do not feel guilty
does not mean that you are innocent.
It means that you are rotten inside.
You are rotten yourself.
I'm going.
Goodbye.
Lesha, stop.
Wait.
What?
Please, explain why you're leaving.
I tried to explain,
but you just don't understand anything.
I will understand.
Explain again.
Do not go away.
I will never do it again.
-Stop humiliating yourself.
No one needs that.
Lesha, I need you.
Stop. please.
Please?
Alright then.
We are like two stars.
So far apart.
From two sides of the globe,
I fly after you or you after me...
Alexandr, where are you?
-Just a minute...
Are we flying to our
happiness or sadness?
We fly, dreamless.
I come after you. Will you come after me?
If you want me to, I'll leave.
Where to?
I do not know,
just take a walk somewhere.
I don't care either way.
Stand still. Come here.
Damn it.
You red chicken. Come on, asshole.
You jerk.
Another one. Come on,
I'll kill you both.
I'll knock you rotten, stupid jerk.
Stay still, bastards. I've been here
since 1987, do you hear that?
Sunbathing.
Have you enjoyed your day?
Yes.
Good for you.
Thank you.
I hope you mean it.
Can I tell you a scary story?
I'm leaving.
I'm leaving!
I heard you.
Bye.
Would you like to
do me a big favor?
May I ask you to disappear
completely from my life?
Don't write to me, never call me.
I will do my best.
Then I'm going now.
I want to take one more thing.
Are you on holiday here?
Are you looking for accommodation?
I have a two-story villa right by the sea.
Just like in Hollywood.
On the beach? In the mountains?
Money, money?
2 and two zeros, that's it.
That's it yes, with zeros,
I can't make a discount, sorry.
That really does not work.
Goodbye.
Sorry, did you see an old man...
With a big camera and a monkey?
We'll buy a small duck.
Duck that goes ta-ta-ta-ta.
A chicken that eats beans and
goes kudah-tah-tah.
We buy a turkey for grandma.
The turkey does foldy-boldey.
And the duckling ta-ta-ta-ta...
Can I talk to you?
Why?
We have to talk.
About what?
About us.
I wanted to tell you that you
are the most horrible person...
that I have ever encountered.
How did I believe you?
I do not understand.
I lived a normal life.
I did not need anything.
Nothing.
You started this game.
Can you tell me why?
Just for fun?
To please your ego?
I get it.
You are the maniac that finds
her victims online.
That is your true nature.
You're a killer.
You have it all planned.
Bravo.
You played with me.
Played as if you were interested.
And I did not want to believe it.
I wanted to leave.
Why did you stop me?
To completely destroy me.
Was that it?
You spun a web of filthy lies.
like an insect.
You're disgusting.
You're a terrible, horny slut.
You are very funny.
Glad I could make you laugh.
I am a terrible horny slut and
I want to dance and have fun.
Vera, are you okay?
Does it hurt?
I was waiting for you.
I wanted to say that I'm sorry.
I do not know what happened to me.
I'll get my things.
Are you going? -Yes.
With that guy?
-Doesn't matter. I'm just leaving.
How can you say that
it does not matter?
I need to know.
-What?
Are you with him now?
No, not at all.
Why are you so mean?
Why did you start this
if you do not need me?
No idea.
Maybe I loved you.
You knew all my weaknesses.
-I did not know anything at all.
And now I want to forget
everything as quickly as possible.
You can not do that.
I can.
-Do not do it.
Vera, try to understand me.
I understand you very well.
I was completely confused.
I did not know what I was doing anymore.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
I picked you out of your world.
I only thought about myself.
And you did not want anything at all.
It's not true. I pretended.
In reality I actually wanted it.
I was afraid of being so
intimate with someone.
We are too different.
You get enough from your virtual
world but I need the real world.
Do not go.
Try to find your true self.
Vera, do not leave.
I can not live without you.
How scary!
This is the end of the world.
This is Armageddon.
This is impossible.
A delirium, a nightmare.
Lord, do you hear me?
Lord, save me.
I'm hideous,
I'm a dumbass,
I can not live without you.
Stop, I say, stop.
everything is wrong.
You came back.
If only I could stop time.
My girl, my darling girl.
I love you so much.
With all my heart.
I beg you, come back.
How can you be such a bitch.
Such a terrible dirty whore.
Don't you see how I suffocate.
In this burning hell.
Stop, I say, stop.
everything is so wrong.
You can come back.
I beg the time to stop.
Look at that.
Come here, quickly!
He is still alive.
And he is heavy.
Lekha!
Sergey Mikhayilovich,
this is my friend Lekha!
We used to work together
in the theatre in Moscow.
Lekha, are you on vacation here?
On holiday.
I did not know you were here at all.
I found a job here,
in a celebrity lookalike show.
Cool, right?
She was my soulmate.
You have to come to
The Chapiteau Show.
A legendary place.
What are you mumbling?
Let's lift him up, Sergey Mihayilovich.
He is heavy.
Lekha, I'll be right back.
And then you tell me what happened, okay?
My life is over.
What is the matter with you?
Stay here, alright?
I'll be right back.
I have to get her back.
You see how strange fate can be?
Here we are, just like in Moscow.
We were always the two of us there,
every day,
And here as well.
Interesting, right?
Nobody will ever understand
me as well as she did.
Nobody in the whole world.
A life without her does not make any sense.
You understand?
Yes.
I have to go. You can
see me in the show.
I was at the end of the world.
I was at the end of heaven.
I was at the end of the ocean.
I climbed the highest mountain.
I did not meet anyone who did
not want to be my friend.
My heart is full of sorrow.
I know what pain is.
My heart is filled with despair.
I know death.
I have no one that I
can sing to in silence.
I want to be with you.
My hands are like birds.
Caught in the cage of my soul.
Mama, You understood
me without words.
Mama, you knew it, even
without a confession.
Mama, how little I knew you.
Who understands me now?
Will this world ever see spring?
FRIENDSHIP
What is that?
A TV production. A program about the deaf.
What kind of program?
About the competition.
I won a competition.
So the TV show is shooting
an item about it.
Interesting.
Tell us more about it.
What kind of contest?
What are they doing in our bakery?
They're disturbing us.
Calm down.
And who is that?
Another friend of yours?
I do not want them to film me.
Do you think we are monkeys?
Want them to film you?
Go ahead, flail your arms, grab some bread.
We're not participating.
Look at him, a real star.
Hey.
You do not have to speak loudly
and annoy your surroundings here,
What's important is to party, meet people,
be happy and light up the dance floor.
A discotheque for the deaf. Is it for real?
Or simply a waste of your time?
We're going to find that out.
Hey, red!
How do you meet girls in this disco?
Never mind.
I must first learn their language.
Look at him.
Hey you there.
Who taught you
to dance like that?
I don't think many hearing people
could dance like these guys.
And now we are looking for our hero.
I am not a monkey.
What are you?
Do you only want people to be
interested in you because you're deaf?
No.
Every 6 months
a reporter appears here...
They simply must shoot our disco.
What a scoop. Deaf dancers.
What bullshit.
It is not a zoo here.
Go, tell them to leave.
Don't tell me what to do.
You think you're the smartest?
I decide for myself.
Make sure they leave.
Or you are no longer our friend.
How long can we
steep in our own sop?
You have rotted completely.
When did you last
speak to an outsider?
I do not need that.
You're just scared.
Blah blah.
You roll around in your deafness.
God forbid anyone jokes about it.
You have broken our rules.
I'm done with your rules.
And who are you?
I'm done with those rules of yours.
Enough.
Go and kiss their ass.
You no longer belong with us.
Deaf and dumb monkey.
If you come in too late,
you get a hammer on your head.
I have a deaf singer with me.
-Really?
Yeah, here he is.
Hello, I've heard a lot about you.
Does he understand what I'm saying?
Of course, he can read lips.
I'd like to come see you sing.
I also hope you can see me sing sometime.
Come, I want to introduce you to someone.
Everything okay, boys?
Sergey, this guy is a deaf singer.
Should we add him to your clients?
What a great idea, sit down.
This is Kolyan, the soundman.
Sergey, the producer.
Guys, listen.
What is he saying?
I quit.
I'll be gone tomorrow.
I'm leaving. Bye.
He says he has resigned from work.
He's leaving tomorrow.
The management knows about it.
Okay, great.
Tell him we do not need him.
Yeah, have a good trip.
Where is he going, actually?
Where are you going?
To Crimea, to Simeiz.
Where to?
I see.
Maybe they like him.
And that reporter...
has probably fallen
in love with him.
Who needs him?
They like him, they don't,
fall in love, fall out of love...
What does it matter?
You're right.
Do you remember our oath?
Of course.
We have sworn an oath, us four.
Do you remember that?
Kind of...
What was it?
That was a long time ago.
It was our oath.
An oath is forever.
Do you remember anything about it?
My brain is not working well right now.
Too much beer. Sorry.
Do you still remember our oath?
Which oath?
Our oath.
How did that go?
Oh, that oath.
We are...
What we are.
We are not second-class citizens.
What else?
I do not know.
How did you become gay?
Or were you always like that?
How did I become gay?
No idea, actually.
I just thought it interested me.
Interested?
Yes.
I do not know if I could ever do that.
Maybe if my work would
require it one day.
They all do it in Hollywood.
All those dividing lines are so vague.
If you like someone.
Perhaps.
But I'm not ready yet.
Not yet.
Nikolai. You look sad.
Have a beer.
The deaf-dumb language is a must
for people like him.
No, sign language for the deaf.
Dumb people don't have a language.
That's why they're dumb.
Okay, that sounds logical.
Do you also have indecent gestures?
To scold someone?
Yes.
How do you say 'anus'?
Anus.
You are an anus.
His brain does not work that well.
Too many trips.
The scout is not a scaredy-cat,
he is brave,
And because of that,
he has earned a sweet.
Quiet there!
You only think of yourself,
we have a deaf boy here with us.
A deaf boy?
-Yes.
If you go on like this, I'll get up
and kick your ass.
If you have friends,
never worry.
We are happy to travel together.
What are they singing?
-What?
A song from the cartoon
"The Bremen Town Musicians".
"The Troubadour Song".
Why aren't you singing?
I can not sing.
Do you want some sunflower seeds?
-No.
Yeah? Okay.
Everyone here is one of us,
as usual.
Karagodin is here, Yasha.
-Yasha? -Yes.
Divide between the rooms yourselves.
Here is another room.
But be careful with the beds.
Kolya, which bed do you prefer?
I do not care.
If you don't mind,
can we switch?
Are you going to the beach?
-Of course.
Guys, we are not going
to the beach yet.
What did he say?
That we are not going
to the beach yet.
Why not?
Senya, why can't we go to the beach?
I'm going.
We are not going.
What is going on?
Guys, only nerds go first thing
to the beach.
I want my platoon to be
ready for the water.
One two.
-We are hungry.
Three four.
-We are starving.
Open the doors for us.
Otherwise we eat the cook.
At first, it seems like there's a lot
of people here, but it's not true.
They just walk back and forth.
Up, down...
Platoon, line up in a row.
When you greet an older person, check
whether you have closed the kitchen tap properly.
Give 5 minutes of your
time to this musician.
Guys, good to see you.
This is my platoon.
A mobile explorer unit in the
name of the film and the theater.
This is a karaoke cafe.
Just look in.
This is so scary.
Have you ever worked as a pusher?
-What?
A pusher. I know deaf people
work as pushers.
Worked as who?
A pusher. A drug dealer.
Drugs?
-Yes.
Do you want to get high?
Something like that, yes.
Guys, why are you so slow?
Avignon.
Before you know it, you have
spent all your money on drugs.
I've got a lot of money.
I can buy whatever I want.
Tell me, are deaf people drug dealers?
What is the matter with you?
I'm just kidding.
Sometimes I am like that.
It is difficult for a
deaf person to find work.
That is why some people
end up in crime.
But I have little respect for them.
-Why?
They have no willpower.
They do not really want to do their best.
You're right.
Scouts, when we greet someone new,
remember that you have to work hard.
Look, gays.
-Be quiet.
You'll freak them out.
They're in their nest.
Don't.
From what distance can you read lips?
Can you tell me what
Julia is saying now?
It's not nice to spy.
Come on. I always spy.
I can not really see it.
It is too far away.
What is going on?
-Nothing.
Are you here with him or with me?
With you.
Then why are you so clearly
with him now?
Senya.
What?
I'm tired of explaining.
-What?
What is it with you?
Come here.
What is this?
That is pure ecstasy.
Is it a drug?
Of course.
So you meant it.
Really. Take it, I'll treat you.
Guys, let's not take drugs.
Senya, do you want to destroy your
life and that of your friends?
Now I know who he reminds me of.
He is exactly like Samantha Smith.
Mr. Andropov, why do you want to destroy
my country and the rest of the world?
Why? He is our saint.
From now on our platoon
is called 'Samantha Smith'.
Boys.
Let's go to sleep.
Boy scout, do not sleep and never eat.
Are you sleeping?
Yeah, god damn it,
we're sleeping.
Guys, it's time for breakfast.
Go away.
It is time to go.
-We are in quarantine.
Guys, wake up.
Let's go.
Time to get up.
Can somebody take this deaf guy away?
Somebody!
The rooster has woken up a long time ago.
Guys, I feel sick
when I look at you.
Kolya.
Tell me, these guys,
Vasya and Jim...
There is something between them, right?
Yes.
So?
Nothing, nothing.
Are you also like that?
Me? No.
I do not get it. How can
you be friends with them?
What's the problem?
Well... they are gay.
You are deaf, and they are gay.
What's bothering you?
It's not the same.
I do not know what to do with it.
Should I marry him?
If you do not love him,
you should not do it.
How is that possible?
He loves me and I'll leave him.
I love him anyway.
He's a good boy.
Yes, Senya is a good boy.
I just do not feel
enough for him.
Do you understand?
I am not in love anymore.
The fairytale is over.
Why am I so sad?
If you want, I can
talk to Senya.
Let's go to the beach already.
I do not know what's going on.
I am confused.
Please do not go away.
I really need you.
As a friend.
As a... I don't know what.
Shit.
I'm not angry, north-north-west...
with a southern wind, I see the
difference between a hawk and a handsaw.
Hi. Jim is very burned,
I want to bring him this cream.
Suffering is purifying.
Friends.
I would like to make a toast
to friendship.
I do not believe in love.
Friendship is fairer than love.
Friendship goes much deeper.
A friend is not just important
when you need money
Or to ensure that you
do not get into a fight.
A friend protects
you from despair.
A friend is your lifeboat
in a sea of misery.
What, god damn it?
Did you have your portrait signed?
I want to introduce
you to this lady.
This is Vera.
Vera, this is Lekha.
What is it?
-So you can look after her nicely.
I do not get it.
You have to comfort her.
Do you understand?
-You console her.
And who will comfort me?
Did something happen?
There is nothing wrong.
Senya, come.
I'll take you to bed.
You should not sleep at night.
Stay away from me.
Where are you going?
I want to dive from the Deva.
I want to establish a record.
This will be a record.
Do not, Senya.
Where is Kolya?
Where is our Kolya?
Maybe he already jumped from the Deva?
And then it will not be a record.
What a pity.
But I have to jump.
I have always wanted to do that.
Where is my trumpet?
So Kolya is a hero,
and I am a soft-boiled egg. -No.
Sorry.
Where is my trumpet?
Where is my platoon?
We have lost our only platoon flag.
The Samantha Smith platoon.
Get Kolya, I want
to speak to him.
Where is Kolya, I
have to talk to him.
Senya...
My house floats on
summer, and I'm gone.
Everything is simple in the summer.
Stubble grows quietly
on my cheeks.
Please hand it over.
It's mine.
Young nature's friend, the
seeds are waiting for you
I do not understand your jokes.
The Samantha Smith platoon is
ready for the morning exercise.
Platoon, our motto is:
If you have dirt under your nails,
you are not a scout.
You are dumbass yourself.
Bad mood, the native Dead Ear?
Come, then we smoke a peace pipe.
Good job, boy.
Let's go.
We are going to the beach.
A deaf and mute, native Dead Ear.
Just like in One Flew
Over the Cuckoo's Nest.
He needs a special approach.
Did I misbehave last night?
-What?
Honestly, I had to
carry you back all the way.
Lesha.
You go swimming,
I do not feel so good.
Are we going back again?
I do not get it.
Okay, we'll put the tent here.
Isn't it too close to the sea?
Maybe it's better up
there, with those bushes.
We do not need bushes.
There's another tent here, see?
So it's safe here.
This is the place.
The tent is up.
Awesome.
Now we have to make a campfire.
Why do we need a campfire?
We are not in the forest.
A tribe always meets
around a campfire.
GUYS, YOU'RE IN CRIMEA! I'M SO HAPPY!
LET'S MEET EACH OTHER.
Tell him he has a nice chick.
We scared him.
COME TO THE SIMEIZ CAFE FOR LUNCH,
I'LL WAIT AT 2 O'CLOCK.
Let him wait as long as he wants.
Damn, what's he thinking?
Tell him we can not come
because Valera is snorkeling...
And has caught a crab.
Stop saying stupid things.
Who is that guy?
Znamensky has sent an SMS again.
He wants to meet us.
And are we going?
Where to?
We need to fuck him up,
that was the deal.
I think he's in trouble.
Maybe we should just meet him.
What do you mean by 'in trouble'?
What are you talking about?
He can come and go as he likes?
That is not going to happen.
He will have to beg for it.
Who is that guy?
A tourist, he sleeps in that tent.
What's he saying?
He's saying that
he's the most horrible person.
Who? This guy?
BOYS, WILL YOU BE HERE SOON?
I SAVED YOU A PLACE.
YOU WON'T HAVE A PLACE
IN OUR HEARTS ANYTIME SOON.
I DON'T GET IT.
ARE YOU COMING OR NOT?
YOU CAN'T COME TO THOSE WHO LEFT.
I'LL COME TO YOU.
WHERE CAN I FIND YOU?
YOU WILL FIND US BEYOND THE
BORDER OF YOUR DESPERATION.
Who do we have there?
It is Samantha Smith!
Let's greet her.
What are you doing?
Stop.
I want to speak with you.
Put me down, quietly.
I want to say that you are the
most terrible people on earth.
I do not understand
why I believed you.
I have lost my friends because of you.
Why did you drag me here?
You are just having fun.
And I'm a deaf little monkey, right?
I had a normal life.
I can not hear you.
Do you even care about who I am?
If a rich guy gives you some drugs...
You kiss his ass.
That's it.
I understand.
You are werewolves.
You pretend to be good.
But inside you are rotten.
You don't even love anyone.
You just fuck, fuck, just fuck.
It does not matter
whether it is a man or a woman.
Who is in your bed.
You are spinning a
web of filthy lies.
Like insects.
You are immoral,
lying bastards.
Filthy homos, do you hear me?
I did not hear anything,
but it looked very cool, applause.
I am glad that the monkey
has entertained you.
Senya, open up.
-What do you want?
Can she sleep here in my place?
My friends are here and
I'm going to them.
Good.
Then I'll take my stuff.
What stuff?
My bag.
But you do not have a bag at all.
-What?
You do not have a bag.
It has been confiscated.
I do not get it.
Dead Ear, I calculated it.
You owe me money.
Your card, the room, the weed.
After the disabled discount,
you owe me 500 bucks.
How much?
-500.
I do not have that much money.
I can not do anything about that.
Ask your friends.
You are such an asshole.
Open up.
-You know what?
If someone spits into my soul,
I will never forgive that.
Come on, open up.
I am like a satellite without a job.
I am alone, my heart is broken.
In my world a tsunami is raging.
Kilometers of desert between us.
My ship has gone.
I want to tell you how bad I feel.
I burn, and in a thousand years
I will bring my last farewell.
It feels cold without winter.
As empty as after a plague.
And I still live.
But I am alone.
It feels cold without winter.
As empty as after a plague.
And I still live.
But I am alone.
This mold of inauthenticity.
How was it again to
belong together?
Where did our common goal go?
I fell asleep like a boring movie.
It feels cold without winter.
As empty as after a plague.
And I still live.
But I am alone.
Did they call you deaf and dumb?
Yes.
The bad news came unexpectedly.
Here is a text message
Dead Ear's friends.
We are what we are.
We are not second class.
Those who think they're better
are our enemies. Signed: The Silent Tribe.
Who are they?
Today, on the holy anniversary
of Samantha Smith's death
Germany has declared war on us.
It is time to fight.
We asked for it.
We don't need this.
Just give that bag back.
Do you think we are children
and just play games?
Senya, leave those people alone.
Soon they will throw acid in our faces
Maybe they have a gas balloon.
The fathers have left,
and the grandfathers have left.
Senya, they are disabled,
leave them alone.
Do we, children of the revolution, have
to wait for that damn bourgeoisie...
To come to fetch us and take us
to their bourgeois kingdom?
We have to accept the challenge.
One two.
-Stanley Kubrick.
Three four.
-David Lynch.
Solondz, Gus van Sant, Polanski.
Let them hear this battle cry!
Platoon, greet this hero of the revolution.
Hi, Serezha.
I am happy to see you.
How are you?
-Fantastic.
And the performance?
Where and when?
In the Chapiteau.
In the Chapiteau?
With Tsoi?
With Tsoi.
Great, Serezha.
Congratulations.
Senya, did you hear?
His Tsoi will perform in the Chapiteau.
Serezha, should I help you?
-No.
Okay see you later.
One two.
-Elvis Presley.
Three four.
-Victor Tsoi.
Lennon, Kurt Cobain, Vysotsky.
Michael Jackson, sing a song!
My little naughty. My little dirty.
Small dirty pig.
Dirtier than a chimney sweeper.
Look at yourself.
I think they will immediately
get the police.
Do not worry.
If I stomp my feet...
I call my soldiers.
This is so scary.
Friend, here I am.
Give me your hand.
Let's go.
Do you love me?
I do not think so.
I do not love you either.
What can we do?
I do not know.
I'm not sure either.
Do you think this is normal?
What?
Us, here together.
Everything that happened.
I think so.
All kinds of things can happen.
Well...
Are you sleeping or do you hear that
I'm crying because you can not hear me?
Do you think about how I cannot sleep
when I think about that?
That we are so lonely and quiet
and just breathe softly.
We are so lonely because we do
not know how to be together.
Do you love me?
-What kind of answer do you want to hear?
-I do not love you either.
We are almost strangers.
-We have been together for 100 years.
We are everything
that we were born for.
Do you love me?
-You are everything I've met here.
- No idea, but it is good that you exist.
We are so similar.
- This is really stupid.
We are everything
that we were born for.
Are you asleep or can you hear that
I'm crying because you cannot hear me?