- Come on, kid.
Man up, dude.
There we go.
Wes?
- Hey, Paul.
- So, the L1 deal is closing
and the partners are flying
into San Francisco.
- Okay.
- I hate to do this to you,
but you're the only one
I trust with this client.
I need you out there.
- Okay.
Look, Wes,
man to man, okay?
Are you gonna
be able to handle this?
- Yes. Why wouldn't I?
I have a good
handle on the account.
We'll be fine, Paul.
We'll be fine.
- Good.
Hi, honey,
make sure to pick up
some cured meats.
And we're low on diapers.
Oh, and I need tampons too.
Go to Whole Foods for
the meats, don't go to Giant.
So, you'll have
to make two stops.
And you know what?
You mind just getting
everything for the week?
I'll text you the list.
Sweetie, sorry,
I forgot to add something
to the list.
Do you mind?
Did you leave already?
- I did, yeah. What is it?
So my father just reminded me
he needs his toilet paper.
Speaking of, they're hungry
and I want to
try to put Lizzie down
before my sister and Andy
show up.
So I'm just gonna serve
everyone.
But I have your plate ready.
I'll keep it covered, okay?
Okay. I'll take care of it.
So, I said,
"I am not going out like that.
You know I'm not going out."
- Wes, oh, my God.
I'm sorry, honey.
We wanted to wait
for you, but we were starving.
- You did remember
the diapers, did you?
- Yeah. Oh, I think
I left them in the car.
- I'll get 'em.
This isn't one-ply, is it?
You got to do something
about that dishwasher.
It just crapped out.
- Hah!
Hmm.
You've reached Luke.
Leave a message.
At the tone,
please record your message.
When you have finished
recording,
you may hang up
or press 1 for more options.
- Hey, man, I don't know why
I've had so much trouble
reaching you for the past month.
Maybe you've been arrested?
Kidnapped?
Maybe you're dead?
I don't really give a fuck.
You should call me back.
But hopefully, you're out there
in that cesspool of silicone,
serving up manhood
in a more efficient manner
than I am here in suburbia,
where I am house dad to
not only my wife and kid
but also my in-laws.
One of whom just told me
I need
to get a bigger fucking house
so that he has more
bathrooms to shit in
and more room
to put his feet up.
Anyway, I won't be mad
about the hiding
if you
show up at this reunion, okay?
I've been drinking. Bye.
¶ Twinkle twinkle little star ¶
Yeah, you're tired.
¶ How I wonder what you are? ¶
It's eczema,
not a skin rash.
Make sure you tell the doctor.
- Fuck, is this
what I think it is?
- His ass? Yeah.
- Great. Thank you, honey.
Can't unsee that.
Oh.
And here's the bill
from last time.
That needs to be paid.
Make sure
they don't overcharge you.
- Goddamn!
A thousand dollars?
To treat skin
on an old man's ass?
- What do you want me to say?
It's my dad.
All right.
- Oh shit. Wes?
- Hmm-mm.
- Look at me.
- Hmm?
- I'm ovulating.
- Okay.
- Take your pants off.
Wait, okay. No--
Does that hurt?
- No, it's--
it-- it's good. It's fine.
- Okay.
- Just go ahead.
- All right.
- Okay.
You reached Luke.
Leave a message.
At the tone,
please record your message.
When you have finished
recording,
you may hang up
or press 1 for more options.
You know, a month ago,
we sat here on the phone
while I bought you
a plane ticket to this reunion.
And you kind of laughed it off
at the time,
but you promised me you'd come.
So, hopefully, you are
coasting comfortably
at 30,000 feet,
on a red-eye right now.
I'm really looking forward
to seeing you, bud.
Could use a talk.
Wes!
- Holy shit! Steve!
How are you, bud?
- How the hell you been, man?
- I'm good. I'm good. You?
- Well. Can't complain.
Still in Philly, workin'.
- Very nice.
- My wife and I
just had a little one.
- Congrats, man.
- Yeah. A baby boy. And--
- That's great.
- Yeah, thanks. It's...
- Yeah.
- How about--
how about you?
I heard you and Sarah Joyce
ended up getting married?
- We did.
- I could've said
that would happen.
You two.
You always had
a Ken and Barbie thing
goin' on.
- Here's your drink, darling.
- Thank you, my dearest.
- Hmm.
Who'd have thought
I could be so thoughtful?
- I know, seriously.
- Hmm.
- What did you do with my wife?
I don't know.
- I'll let you know
if I find her though.
- Thank you so much.
She has my credit cards.
- Is that Maggie Olson?
It is.
Is she comin' over here?
- I wish Luke was here.
How much did you
pay for those tickets?
- This is gonna be interesting.
- Hi, Sarah. Hey, Wes.
- Hey, Maggie.
- Maggie,
you look beautiful.
Thank you.
I-I hear you guys got married.
- We did.
Got married seven years ago.
- Hmm-mm.
- Not that anyone's counting.
- No.
- He's--
- Feels like yesterday.
Yeah.
- Still that
"angry old man-baby"
that I just tolerate,
so not much has changed.
- What about you?
- No, not married.
Still single.
- Got it.
Where are you now?
- I live up
in Portland, Oregon.
- Oh nice.
- Nice.
- Yeah, I really love it.
- What are you doin' up there?
- I'm a painter.
Which means I spend most
of my time bartending.
- Hey, beats
my concrete jungle.
- Um...
Is Luke here?
- No. H-he didn't make it.
- It's too bad.
Tell him I said hello.
- I'm gonna take
a couple of days off
on either side
of the meeting.
Get out west early.
You have nothing
to worry about, okay?
Nothin's gonna
jeopardize the deal.
I just need some time.
- Why don't we try this?
I'll-I'll ramp right before
his first
chorus line on the beat.
And then
we'll intercut that motif
through the rest of the chorus.
Here, watch.
- ¶ Rewind rewind it
Rewind-- ¶
- Oh fuck!
Yes! Yes!
There's it!
The fucking GENIUS.
Right there,
the fucking GENIUS!
You did that in your sleep,
like a fucking Jedi.
Why can't Harold do that?
- Well, you better get
Harold to shape up,
because we
can't afford to keep asking Luke
to save the day
from his apartment.
Speaking of... Luke...
So we are over budget again.
But we can still pay you.
It's just a fraction of the rate
for the hours you've put in.
I'm sorry.
- You know what?
Don't worry about it.
I'll just... consider it
my goodbye present.
- Whatcha talking about?
I'll keep a spot open for you
in case you change your mind
at the last minute.
- Change your mind about what?
Wes?
- Okay. We should go.
Yeah, we're gonna project
all these wacky beams of light
in all different directions.
Like green, purple,
yellow, orange, red--
like a prism, you know?
- Cool.
- Yeah. Sure. Right?
I'm gonna put Beyonce
in a TransAm.
So it'll be like Beyonce,
meets Knight Rider,
meets Dark Side of the Moon.
- Hmm.
- Are you at CAA?
- No.
I-I'll call you.
- Come here, buddy.
- What the fuck
are you doing here, Wes?
- You don't answer
your goddamn phone,
so I'm takin'
matters into my own hands.
It's a nice spot.
About 700 square feet?
- Wes, what the fuck
is goin' on?
She's in Portland.
- What? Who?
- Maggie.
What? Maggie who?
- Your Maggie.
- What? My-my Maggie?
- Yeah. So, guess what?
We're going to Portland!
What?!
- Yeah.
We're gonna drive up to Portland
and we're gonna go see Maggie.
Well, you're gonna
go see Maggie.
And I'm just gonna
stand to the side... happily.
In the bushes or something.
- You're out
of your fucking mind.
She was at the reunion
and she was asking about you.
- She was--
she was asking about me?
- And I'm telling you,
it felt like
the sole reason
she was there was to see you.
And I've got business
up in San Francisco.
We'll kill two birds
with one stone.
And where are you goin'?
- I'm showering.
I'm hungry. Hurry up.
- Calm down.
- Thank you
for getting my luggage.
Very helpful
after a long flight.
You realize how long
of a drive it is to Portland?
- Yeah. It's 570 miles
from Santa Monica Pier
to Leggett.
That's 15 hours of driving.
I figure we cut in
at Lincoln City.
Then from Leggett to Portland,
is 520 miles,
11 hours of driving. So what?
We're talking 1,100 miles,
26 hours of driving.
- Even if we do manage
to get there,
how do we even find her?
- Well, I've done some digging.
She works in this cool place
up at Belmont.
I know where she lives, too.
You're starting to scare me.
- You have wife clearance
for this?
Yeah,
Sarah's totally fine with it.
- Yeah, right.
Speaking of, how is--
how's Lizzie?
- Oh, c'mon.
What else do you have to do?
You can't move home.
What the fuck are you
gonna do in Richmond?!
- Well, my brother
got me a sales job.
- No.
- Waste disposal.
- Recycling.
- Still no.
Are you kidding me?!
That is not a solution.
I'm not lettin' you do that.
- Shh, you-you reach
a certain age,
and being broke
is just - is a bad look.
It-it gets old
trailing behind everyone else.
- Since when do you care
about everyone else?
Listen,
whenever I get frustrated
with my own life...
I think about you.
I do.
Out here living for us all.
That's just the truth, man.
Can you handle that?
- You can stay at my place
until your meeting.
I'll take you out
here in LA every night.
We'll have a blast,
but I'm not going to Portland.
- Like the first part.
Hate the second part.
We'll go to Portland.
Oh!
I oughta grow out
my beard on this trip.
Nice fuckin' thick beard,
it's what
these LA chicks like, right?
Buy a flannel.
God knows I walk into
someplace with a blazer,
they think
I'm their fuckin' dad.
- Ts-ss.
- But I diss
the blazer and buy a flannel.
Grow out my nice thick beard,
and I'll look just like the
rest of these dirty idiots
with their flannels and beards.
What?
Your little Bukowski shtick
seems to be
workin' out just fine.
C'mon, you've gotten
more ass out here
than you ever did in college
by a multiple of a hundred.
- Yeah. Okay.
Who cares? I'm done.
- What does that mean?
- I'm-- I'm taking a break
from women.
- Uh-- what?
- Look, you won't understand.
- No, I can't say
I would understand.
'Cause absolutely nothing
about a good-looking,
single guy in LA
taking some vow of celibacy,
makes any sense to me,
whatsoever.
- Well, I'm-I'm tired.
- What?
- I haven't had sex
with a girl in six months.
And quite frankly,
I haven't wanted to.
- What is goin' on here?
What have you done
with my friend, Luke, huh?
You don't return your calls.
I buy you a ticket,
you don't fly out.
What's the deal?
- Look, uh... you're not here.
You don't know what it's like.
And-- sorry.
I'm sorry about the ticket.
- No, fuck the ticket!
I just want to know
what's going on?!
- I'm fine.
- Wow. Look at that!
Look at this jewel.
It's pure Cali right there.
Oh, man!
You know,
being here in this moment,
it just makes me
really, really happy
that places
like this still exist.
What?
Hey-hey.
Oh,.
You know
I really liked you. I did.
- Ah.
- And you're just an a-,
he's such an asshole.
Why were you so mean to me?
- I wasn't mean to you.
N-- I-I wasn't mean to her.
- You-- yeah, you were.
I thought you were a nice guy.
But you just
ended up being a jerk.
- Makes a lot of sense.
- He ended up
being a jerk.
- I totally
get that, and I'm sorry.
- Do you just
want to go home? Please?
Alright.
Mallory, we're going home.
- Do you want to go home?
- It's-it's time to go.
- No, no, no, no, no.
I'm just staying right there.
- Yeah, I'll um-um I'll-I'll-
I'll catch you later.
- Maybe-maybe
I'm gonna be over here.
- Yeah.
- I'm over--
- Catch you later.
- Bye. Okay.
I just-- okay.
- Oh, wow.
Luke, what
did you do to that poor woman?
No, I didn't do anything.
Okay, we were kinda
hookin' up for a while.
And one night, she just starts
crying randomly, for no reason.
I couldn't get it out of her.
She wasn't even drunk.
And then, later
that night, I'm sleeping
and she-she tried to
stick her finger up my ass.
- Oh. That might've
done it for me.
Of course, it would.
S-so now
I'm the asshole and--
me, asshole forever.
- Uh-oh.
Look at this.
Come on,
you can't leave her like that.
Hmm-mm.
Hi.
- Hi.
A-- oh! Ah!
What?
- Oh, your-your breath from
the--
- What?
- The vomit.
- So fuckin' typical
of this city.
- Look, I'm sorry.
- Yeah, I'm sorry.
You're a fuckin' loser.
- Hey, hey, hey,
just take it easy, alright?
I took care of you all night.
- Hey, hey, no.
You're a nobody.
It's no wonder why
you're 30-something
alone in a one-bedroom
guesthouse
with nobody but a fuckin'
douchebag in a fuckin' robe.
You know, I just feel bad
for guys like you
because you'll never
have the capacity
to get your shit together
to bring somebody in.
- You know what? I'll--
I'll consider the source.
Thank you.
- Oh my God, that is
such a fucking cliché!
A 30-something-year-old dreamer
equals a fucking loser!
Loser!
Fuck!
I just think it's time
I settle into
something elsewhere.
- Luke, no.
That blackhole or whatever
that shit was in there,
that's why we got to go
to Portland.
- Oh, will you stop
with the Maggie stuff, please?
- No, Luke, I get it now. I do.
Your career right now, it sucks.
I see that.
You're not happy.
You haven't accomplished
what you want and that sucks.
But you just need
some positive momentum,
and if you get your ass
up that PCH with me--
yes, that's that one step.
That's that one fucking step
in the right direction.
And I promise you,
the momentum's gonna start
to turn in your favor.
- Okay.
- Fuck, yeah.
Pack your shit.
We leave in an hour.
- Where-where you're going?
Bring a jacket.
And bring
something nice, please?
- Wait-wait,
where you goin'?
- We're going
on a little college tour.
- Wait, what? Really?
- Why not?
We both look professorial!
Me more than you,
but we'll be fine.
Now tell me,
Luke, you got shit.
I got shit.
We're both in it. But--
You gotta admit, man,
it feels pretty good to
be back around this, huh?
Just look around.
And do this for me.
Close your eyes and sniff.
What do you smell?
- I smell ocean air.
Maybe a little beer.
- Yeah.
- Some dog shit.
- Little bit, yeah.
Now, is that--
is that strawberry lotion?
You've always been a sick fuck.
- What? Man, we're back.
We're here, right?
Oh, hey, hey, hey.
Oh, she's lookin' at you.
Did you learn
nothin' last night?
- No, this is different.
More wholesome.
Say somethin'. The first thing
that pops into your head.
Go, go, go!
- Hey.
Umm...
Do you know where we can get
some-some smoothies around here?
Smoothies? Umm...
Yeah.
Yeah, there's a smoothie
place called 'Blenders'
back on Pardall.
- Cool.
- Great. Yeah, thank you.
- Yeah.
- Welcome to I.V.!
- You just asked her
where to get some smoothies?!
- I believe I did.
- Yeah. Odd exchange.
- ¶ I said we're all gonna die ¶
¶ But I'll never believe it ¶
¶ I love this world
And I don't wanna leave it ¶
¶ Said that death is a deal ¶
¶ That you cannot refuse ¶
¶ But I love you girl
And I don't wanna lose you ¶
¶ Don't want a long ride ¶
¶ I don't wanna die at all ¶
¶ I wanna be the man
Who lives forever ¶
¶ I ain't never gonna die
And I want you to come ¶
¶ Whoo ooh ¶
¶ I said life is a tale
It begins and it ends ¶
- Alright.
Pay attention.
You may learn something.
You surfer pansies
need to put a little hair
on your chest.
So we're gonna drink some
aged distilled grain like men.
There we go.
To surfin' dudes with attitudes.
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Okay.
Here we go, boss.
- Hey--
- Yeah!
- Come here.
- Alright. One second, yes?
- Oh! Lookie here!
- Oh, my God.
- The smoothie guys.
- You know this crew?
- Oh, not too well,
but it's just how
people do it in I.V.
- Yeah, it's an open-door
policy around here.
You come in, you party.
If you enter,
you gotta live it up.
- Live it up!
I.V. Baby!
- Yhoo!
- A couple
parties down the street
are gonna rage later.
- Yeah?
- Hmm-mm.
- We're in. Let's go!
- No, no, no, no, no.
- This is--
this is just our speed.
- No, no.
This is not just our speed.
- We need more speed.
Okay.
- You guys are funny.
What's your story?
- On a road trip. Headin'
up Highway 1 to Portland.
- Ah, that's sweeeeet.
Portland's so chill.
- Wait?
If you're going to Portland,
you going up the Coast
through Big Sur?
- You bet your sweet little
ass we are!
I-is not what I meant to say.
Yes, we are.
I'm not a sexist pig.
I promise.
I just noticed earlier
that you are-- um, have a-a--
yeah-yeah, things
are going well in that area.
Yeah. She does have a cute
little bubble butt, doesn't she?
She does.
- Well, we're trying to meet
some friends up there,
but we need a ride.
- Is that so?
Alright, well hey, you show us
some fun tonight,
we'll get you
where you need to go.
- Us?! Fun?!
Oh, that's--
- It's not
gonna b- No? Roblem.
- Hmm-mm.
- We bring all the fun.
Phh.
- Ah-oh, whoa.
No thanks.
Never touched the stuff.
- Wow, never?
I don't do mellow.
I'm a grown man, I drink scotch.
- Bullshit,
that's not the reason.
- What?
- It's because when he used to
smoke back in college,
he'd turn into
this paranoid mess.
- No. That is not true.
I once had to cradle him.
He thought he was an orange.
And he-he was afraid he was
gonna get peeled.
- That-- the orange incident
did happen.
- Well, you'll just have to fare
with the
boxed wine in the fridge.
- Of course,
you have boxed wine,
because you're a classy lady.
Yes. Thank you.
Excuse me.
- You know, you
don't have to be afraid of me.
I don't bite.
- Sold.
Hmm.
- I'm gonna
smoke a little ganja.
- Oh, thank you very much.
- Hmm-mm.
- Oh, it says
refreshing on the box.
This is exciting.
Very cool, Snoop.
- You should take a rip!
And just go be paranoid
in the corner.
- Yeah, what's your deal, Wes?
You look like
a very slick banker guy.
Are you from New York?
- Close. D.C. area.
- Hmm.
I bet your closet's
full of Brooks Brothers.
- No. No. No, no, no.
Brooks Brothers
is entry level shit.
Most of my shirts
are from Geneva.
Oh.
- Just the supple cotton
is better for my chest hairs.
All four of them?
- Wes makes a lot of money
in venture capital.
- Nah, I make a lot of money
being super boring.
- And what do you do?
Work at Smoothie King?
- A, well um--
- Luke edits music videos in LA.
- Oh, wow! That's so cool!
- Yeah.
- Yeah. So cool.
- He is not super boring!
Well, you know,
my mom always says
that you can't make a "life"
unless you do
what makes you happy.
- God bless your mother.
I'm guessing she's
a super-hot yogi milf.
She sure is!
I knew I was right.
So what's in Portland?
- Good question, Constance.
I'll answer it.
I happen to have run into
one of Luke's college pals
and she inspired
this little journey
up the coast.
- Oh.
- There's a girl up in Portland,
and you guys
are going to see her?
Was it an old
college girlfriend?
- It's a love quest.
- Hmm-mm.
- No, it's not a love quest.
- It's a love quest.
- It's a fuckin' love quest.
It is.
- Yeah, I highly doubt that.
- Yeah, don't pay
too much attention.
This guy over here is probably
already in love with you.
And fun fact, he's gonna
kill me for saying this,
but Luke here has
the largest collection
of romantic films
this si ssippi.
I caught him
on multiple occasions
jerking off
to Notting Hill in college.
You--
- Hugh Grant's sexy.
- You can't--
you can't unsee that.
Well, that is adorable.
So VHS or laserdisc?
- It's a poster.
Oh. Okay.
- You two have fun.
Not too much "fun".
- Hmm.
So,
did I do my job this evening?
- Yes, you did.
You have earned your free ride.
Yes.
- Ah.
- Come on.
- What?
- Dance with me.
Oh. More dancing.
- Hmm.
- Wonderful.
- Tell me something about you?
That only some random
college girl would know.
Tell me a secret.
Make it ours.
Well,
believe it or not,
this is one of the happier days
I've had in a very long time.
- Hmm.
This day isn't even over yet.
Hmm.
- Hello?
- Hey honey, it's me.
Wes?
What time is it?
- Well, almost six your time.
- Hmm. Is everything okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
Everything's fine.
Just couldn't sleep.
How's Lizzie?
Hmm. She's good.
She misses her Daddy.
Yeah.
I miss her too.
Alright. Go back to bed.
I'll call you later.
- Hmm. I love you.
- I love you too.
Hmm.
- So, Wes, I heard
you're married?
Might explain why I didn't
get any last night, huh, buddy?
Oh, and you have a kid.
That's so cute!
She is.
Would be very proud of me
right now.
- ¶ Feel it in my bones ¶
¶ Feel it in my bones ¶
¶ Something that I can't hide ¶
¶ Put your hands in the sky ¶
¶ Love will make you feel high ¶
¶ Love will make you
Feel alive ¶
¶ Feel it in my bones ¶
- I literally have chills
right now.
- I told you. It's magical.
- I just want to look at this
and remember it.
Okay. We're good.
Mental snapshot
in my brain forever.
And what's it like
being married to someone
you met when you were 19?
It feels kind of
old fashioned these days.
- That's me.
Just an old 60's Chevy.
- The-the Bronco
suits you better.
- When you're young,
your heart is so big.
It's just racing to let in
every opportunity...
every feeling.
Everything.
But--
you don't really know
who you are at 19.
I mean, don't you love
getting to be creative all day?
Plus, why go
and leave all this behind?
- Well, what?
Should I come live with you?
- You'd do that?
- Sure. Why not?
I can totally see myself
with you.
- Oh yeah?
So, you'd just dive in with
some "enchanting" college girl
you met like 12 hours ago?
- You. Me. Here.
I can paint any beautiful
delusion for our future.
- See?
You really are romantic.
¶ This life of ¶
¶ Darlin' darlin' darling
You're my song ¶
Whoah!
- ¶ Darling you're my song ¶
- Hmm.
- What the fuck?
What's goin' on, baby?
- Hey guys,
this is Charlie and Sev.
- Hello.
- Charlie.
What's up, brothers?
Thanks for giving
the goddesses a ride.
- Sure. Yeah.
- Beats an Uber.
- Yeah.
You guys should come with us.
We're going to grill some fresh
Ahi, smoke some green grasses.
Gonna camp out.
Join us.
- Yeah. No.
Ah, thank you, though.
- Yeah, we'll take
a raincheck on the tuna.
Gotta get goin'.
- Okay.
Chill! Well, safe journey.
Very great to meet you bros.
Prosper.
- Likewise.
- And if you brothers
change your mind, you know,
we got extra tents
and good vibes.
Ganja, goddesses.
I don't think we will.
- Yeah. Unlikely,
but thank you for the uh--
for the offer.
- Nice to meet you, dudes.
- Hmm-mm. Absolutely.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
Pleasure.
What?
- Ah, I don't know.
Don't you think a little
heads-up
would have been in order?
- No. Why?
I'm not his property.
I'm no one's and everyone's.
Through me.
- That doesn't mean anything.
- I just listen to my energy
and I follow it, Luke.
Don't do anything else.
Do you.
- I'll keep that in mind.
- Well...
Hmm.
- Hmm.
I hope you find more
happy days,
old fashioned.
- Thank you.
- Go get her.
- Okay. Can we just
acknowledge something
for a second?
That was a great moment.
Whether or not
they're down there
with Johnny Dipshit
and the German sociopath.
You had fun,
I can see it on your face.
- I guess
I just thought we were
destined to run off
into the sunset or something.
Until Bodhi
from Point Break showed up.
- Ah, well, whatever.
We had fun.
- Yeah. Yeah.
I guess. Yeah.
- Ah, nothing should
surprise me anymore.
- Well...
I feel renewed.
- Do ya?
You look renewed.
- I invite you to join me
on this side of a good mood.
- Give me a minute,
I'll be right there.
How many necklaces
does that guy have on?
Hey.
- Get up.
- What?
Got us a tee time.
Spanish Bay, baby.
- I hate golf.
- No, you don't.
Come on. Get up.
- I fuckin' suck at it.
- That's fine.
I'll beat you.
Be good for my ego.
Get up.
Luke, it's your brother, Phil.
Give me a buzz
when you get a chance
to chat about the job
we talked about.
Good news is,
if you don't screw it up,
they'll probably
hire you on the spot.
Bad news is, the meeting
is now Monday morning.
I know it's last minute,
but you gotta figure out a way
to get on an airplane
and get out here.
Whatever the damage is,
we'll figure it out
between Dad and I
when you get back.
Alright, man, give me a call
when you get a chance.
- Who was that?
You really got to leave Monday?
For what? For the chance
to go sell trash in Richmond?
- I just-- I got to do this.
- You're meant
to go to Portland.
- Alright. You sink that putt,
I'll stay.
- Game on.
- Well... that's it, I guess.
What's wrong?
What do you mean?
I can tell
by the tone of your voice
something's wrong.
What's wrong?
There's this guy
I'm working with.
Can't really talk specifics,
but I think he's makin'
a big mistake.
Can you get him
to change his mind?
I'm tryin',
but he's a stubborn one.
Well, you've been known
to have the power
of persuasion.
Yeah, well, we'll see.
I got to get goin'.
Kiss Lizzie for me,
and I love you.
Love you.
Bye.
You really would have stayed
if I'd made that putt?
- You'll never know.
Oh, God.
- You know what
this night needs, Luke?
More company.
- Oh, come on, Wes.
It's our last night.
Let's just hang together.
- No.
Ladies, how's the wine?
- Not bad.
- Can't complain.
- Yeah? You-you visiting
from out of town?
- No, I live here in Carmel.
She's in town
visiting from Berkeley.
- Cool. I'm Wes.
- Rebecca.
- Ellen.
- Very good to meet you.
I don't mean to be a creep,
but do you see this scruffy guy,
over here?
Hmm-mm.
This guy
is a dear friend of mine,
and a troubled-- a troubled man,
and um, here's the deal.
Here's what I think
we should do.
The four of us
should go to dinner.
Some good food,
some adult conversations.
A couple of drinks,
maybe several drinks.
Just take some time to remind
ourselves of life's joys
and in so doing, we can help
this poor Sad Sack over here
realize that he's making
the biggest mistake
of his entire life.
Please?
He's a grouch.
- Well, maybe
he's not as hopeless
as you say he is.
Maybe he's just searching
for something more.
- Maybe he hasn't found the one?
Maybe she's in Portland?
- Hmm.
- There we go.
- What does that even mean?
The one?
No, at-at this point in life,
I think it's more
a matter of practicality.
I've given up
on this notion that somehow,
I'll just run into someone
and know that she's the one.
And that's-- that's fine.
It's totally fine with me.
- Seems a little defeatist
to me.
- Agree.
- No, it's--
it's just not worth it anymore.
It's not.
- Dating to eventually
find the right one,
how is that not worth it?
- Okay, so take Ellen and I,
for example.
We could totally go back
to some hotel room
and um, sleep together.
- Hmm.
- Mm.
But come morning,
either of us could wake up
feeling nothin' but--
but total emptiness.
And just really wanting to find
the quickest way out the door.
All for what?
A couple of hours of pleasure?
- Or we could end up dating.
And then, after a few months--
good months, where our feet
never touch the floor--
Maybe we don't want to invest
in this, you know?
How much do we want to
invest in this thing--
- Yeah.
- --That's taken time away
from meeting someone else?
Maybe I decide
that I wanna move on.
- Well--
- Only to realize of course
that, "Oh no,
that was really great."
- Or maybe I'm the one
agonizing--
--over my exit strategy
because I'm-- I'm somehow
riddled with all this guilt
over telling you that,
"I'm really sorry,
but this isn't
gonna happen after all."
- Oh!
So I'm left there wondering--
--did I mismanage my emotions
when I was with you?
If I had done this
or that differently--
- Agh!
Yes.
- --Would you have left me?!
- The pining
is the fucking worst!
It's true.
- It's pretty fucking awful.
- Yeah.
So why not just stick yourself
in a foxhole
with someone
we're comfortable with,
who cares for you,
fulfills all your daily needs--
- Hmm.
- --Even though
you're not entirely sure
that they're the one.
- Wow.
You two are clearly
meant to be together.
Best of luck to both of you--
- Thank you.
- --On that tragic journey.
Rebecca, how about you?
- Ha. Uh...
Well... it's complicated.
- Oh! Sure.
It's all complicated, right?
- To be honest... um...
This mornin',
I signed my divorce papers.
- Sorry to hear that.
- It's okay.
Actually...
it feels good to say it.
Yeah.
I'm divorced.
- There you go.
- Hmm.
- It's why I came down.
Just to give her some support
when she officially
closed the chapter.
Look at the sunset,
have a drink.
Think about a new chapter.
Come on.
To a new beginning.
- What about you, Wes?
- Uhm.
Well...
I'm married.
- Hmm.
- We have a baby girl.
She's-- actually,
she's almost two now.
- How long
have you been married?
- Uh, going on seven years.
Though, most days,
it feels like a little longer.
So, I hear ya.
Sharing your life
is complicated.
- Hmm.
- Let's get some air.
- Yeah.
- A little walk around Carmel?
- Did I bring us down that much?
A little bit. Yeah.
- Where are you guys staying?
- We don't have a hotel yet.
- Oh well, then
you're staying with her.
- Oh, no. We'll find a place.
- Yeah, come on.
No, stay with us.
She's got a full bar.
Wine for days.
You gotta help this divorcee
who doesn't wanna
go to sleep yet.
- We're grown men,
we can handle ourselves.
- Ah-uh. You're staying.
- No, the two of you
should stay with us.
It's a-- it's fine.
Plenty of room.
Were you ever married?
- No. Almost. But no.
Almost?
What happened?
- He wanted kids.
- Wait? And you didn't?
- No.
- Wow.
- I'm sorry, are we in 1952?
And I need to put on--
- my little apron and do some
vacuuming around the house?
- I'm-I'm sorry.
I guess I just--
I guess I just have
this idea that deep down,
every woman wants to be a mother
and raise a family.
- No. Not me.
- How old are your kids?
- Jesse's 11,
and Caroline is nine.
- How often
do they see their dad?
- Every other weekend.
We share custody.
He's up in Palo Alto.
- How's that been?
- Um, you can't prepare
for this kind of stuff.
- Did I trade getting married
for living a life of my own?
Sure.
But... you know,
he's married now.
He has his kids.
I don't regret my path at all.
Definitely not boring,
I'll tell you that.
That's kind of the point.
Isn't it?
- All right,
big question for Luke.
Tell me about this Maggie.
What makes her so special?
- The thing about Maggie--
- Oh, yeah, no.
I'm not allowed?
- I want Luke to say it.
Yeah, come on. Give a newly
divorced mom a little hope.
- All right.
Um...
The first time I saw her
was English class.
She was sitting by the window
as the sun was piercing in.
You know, that classic
awe moment, right.
But there was an innocence
about her that just struck me.
And for whatever
mystical reason,
from that moment on,
she was the girl I wanted.
I remember I would
walk by her on campus
or I'd see her
in the cafeteria,
or at the library
or at a party.
And, and the more this happened,
the more I began to create
this romantic idea
of something with her.
I started to dream
of us being together...
without ever even saying
much more than hello
to one another.
But, the more I did this,
the harder it was
to temper these really
intense feelings
I had for this girl
to a point where I could
actually connect with her
like a human being,
and not some angel
I had built her up to be.
- But did you actually
connect with her?
Uh-huh.
The boat,
tell them about the boat.
- Oh, a boat.
- What boat?
- There's a boat.
- My senior week,
right before graduation,
my parents had this bay house
in Virginia.
And I invited
all these people from school
to drive out there
and crash for a few days.
And somehow,
Maggie and her friends
heard about it,
and surprisingly they showed up.
- No, not surprisingly.
They knew this was
Luke's last chance.
Will you get to
the boat part, please?
Alright, so, one afternoon,
everyone was hanging out
by the pool,
and she came up to me,
and asked if I would
take her for a boat ride.
I wanted every day
to feel like that boat ride.
I remember we docked the boat
on this little man-made beach
and we just sat there for hours
and made up
for all the lost time.
We talked about our future,
our dreams...
and just what we
wanted out of life.
And for those couple hours--
she--
she made me feel
all this... hope,
like anything was possible.
And then,
I know it sounds crazy,
but all these dreams of love
and marriage flooded my mind.
It was like
I could look across...
at this girl I barely knew...
and I could see my wife.
- Now, ladies,
that is the guy I know.
- But what happened between you?
Anything?
- Um, no.
- What?
- I had my chance, but...
I was too afraid to ruin
this perfect moment.
So that night,
she and her friends left.
And graduation came.
She moved to Europe,
and I never saw her again.
- Didn't you go after her?
I mean, you loved her.
Loved her?
No, I didn't love her.
I mean, I was infatuated.
I might have felt in love, but--
- But-- See, but.
Those-- those feelings,
that story you just told us,
it's all part of being in love.
- Those are just feelings,
it's not love.
You two made it
perfectly clear tonight
that love is not something you--
you create in your mind,
it's not a fairytale.
It's a-it's a lot more
complicated than that.
- Well, hang on.
- Oh, let me tell you
something, Luke.
If you think it's all worth it
without the fairytale
at least at some point
in the relationship,
then you're wrong.
Maybe me signing
those papers today
is just more proof that
this whole idea of marriage
is a myth.
But the fairytale
that I had with that man
in those first two years,
that's the only reason
we made it through another 15.
And... to tell you the truth,
those moments
that you described,
they still happen.
They're just
tinier fragments of...
a life that just becomes bigger
than the both of you.
But it is those moments, Luke,
that ground you,
that anchor you in life.
And no matter
how far you sail away
through all the pettiness,
you need that stuff
to bring you back
to the why of it all.
To help you with the myth.
Because without it,
there's nothing.
Love is not
some form of practicality,
and you know that.
You should go.
You should go find her.
I don't care how silly it is.
Just open your heart back up
to the possibility of something.
You do owe yourself that.
- To Portland.
It would be good for you.
If it doesn't work out,
you can always find me
in Berkeley.
Are you sure
you want to give up all this?
Because corporate America
is a far cry from this.
You know that, right?
- I know this isn't exactly
what you had in mind,
but thank you.
- Don't go.
- Look Wes, I appreciate
everything you've done. And--
I feel better, I really do.
- Just stay, please.
It's not just you
who needs this.
- I have to do this, man.
I'm sorry.
- Fine, well,
you're running late, so go.
Go.
Thank you for everything.
Hey.
Hey, hon, how are you?
Just walking
into this meeting now.
I figured I'd give you
a quick ring.
You ready?
Um...
Well, I actually
have some nerves.
You nervous about a deal?
It's a complicated one.
I'm sure you'll do fine.
People gravitate towards you.
How's everything at home?
How's our girl?
She's fine.
She won't stop moving.
But that's nothing new.
She got that from her mom.
She certainly did.
Let me know how it goes.
Yeah, I will.
Love you.
I love you, too.
- Thanks again.
- Thank you very much.
- Yup.
Thank you, guys.
- We'll talk again.
- Wes, take care. Thank you.
- Can I talk with you
in my office?
Oh, I missed you.
Oh my God, I'm so glad
it's the weekend.
I have so many places
I want to show you.
But first, I've got us
dinner reservations
at this new spot.
Uh, but then, there's
this amazing overlook
I found near my apartment.
So we have to go do that.
Uh, but there's also--
- Okay, uh, just... slow down.
- Wes, what's wrong?
You're a coward.
- Come on.
You don't want to
start a life with a guy
who would have
an ex-wife and a child.
- I don't care about that.
- I love you.
I do, but I don't
want that for you.
- Don't do that.
Don't make this about me.
I know what I want.
I want you and you want me too,
so don't make this about me.
Why can't you do this
for yourself?
Why are you so afraid
to be happy?
I don't know.
I never want to see you again.
I'll forget I ever knew you.
Hey.
Hey, so it's 1:30 now.
Sunset's not until 8:00.
I figured we should be able to
make it to Leggett before nigh.
Wes?
What are we doing?
What's wrong, man?
You haven't said a word
in like five hours.
- Just work stuff.
- Let's just call it a night
and double back to Fort Bragg.
- Kind of want to power through.
Highway 1 ends in like 22 miles.
- Yeah, 22 miles of dicey roads
in the middle of the woods.
- Let's just keep going.
- All right.
Yeah, I bet it's the alternator.
Why don't we get this thing
into town,
and get it fixed up
first thing in the morning.
I know a good shop.
Where you guys headin'?
- North.
- What's the closest hotel
at this point?
- The closest hotel,
all right, well...
I know a funky little spot.
- This place
is kind of spooky.
- All right. Well--
Sorry it's not the Chateau,
Mr. Hollywood,
but it will have to do.
- You've been carrying
all this cash around
the whole time?
- Yup. Been a cash-only
kind of trip.
Another Glen?
- Uh-huh.
Let's do a double.
- Two Moscow mules.
Hello.
- Hello.
- How's your dinner?
- Just what I needed.
Been a long day.
- You visiting?
- Our car broke down, so we're
just-just staying the night.
- Oh, well, that's a shame.
- Well, it will be ready
in the morning, so--
- I'm Charles.
Hi.
- Diedra.
- Sage.
- Sage, Diedra.
Here, let me get those.
Yup.
- Thank you.
- Oh, sorry, this is
my business partner...
Gary.
- Gary.
What kind of business?
- Uh, oil business.
Yeah, we are up...
we're up here searching
for some new prospects.
- You drilling?
- Sorry.
- We are drilling.
Uh-hmm.
Why don't you
join us for a drink
when you're done
with your dinner.
You too, Gary.
- Are you for real? Again?
You're un-fucking-believable,
man.
Our car's going to be ready
in the morning.
Can we just sleep?
- No one is forcing you
to stay out late.
- Come on, Wes,
I'm here now for the endgame.
You've got me, I'm in.
We don't need any more detours.
- Yeah, you don't need
any more detours.
I--
Just be quiet and let me do
what I'm going to do.
- That's not even a detour,
it's just--
it's just a wrong turn.
- Fine.
Go to bed.
- Gary thinks you're an asshole.
How much do you love fucking?
Don't you love fucking,
Charlie?
I love fucking.
I'll take sex any moment,
anytime.
I don't know if it's my DNA,
or something from my daddy's
homemade porn videos.
It was?
What the fuck
are you talking about?
My daddy is fucked up.
When I was 12, I found this
old VHS tape in his bedroom.
Of course I was curious.
And I watched it.
And I saw my stepmom
in this old lit dark saloon,
getting fucked by a bunch of men
in gorilla masks.
Guess who was behind the camera?
Daddy.
Uh-huh.
There you go.
That is enough
daddy porn video talk.
Let's make our own video.
- Yeah.
- You want to make a video,
Charlie?
Come on, you have
too much clothes on.
- Alright.
- I'm going to do this
all for the video.
Where's your phone?
- Yes.
- Wait a sec.
- Umm, look at the oilman's ass.
That's a fucked-up story.
Are we going to make it
to Portland?
- You should be okay, but...
I'd get a proper check
once there.
My wife will get you
squared away.
- Oh, yeah,
I'll have your bill in a sec.
- Hey, babe, you good?
- Yeah.
- That was the--
- Alternator.
- Yes.
- And the check of the filter.
- Yes, that's right.
Okay. Love you.
Um, I'll put the key
in the-in the Bronco.
- Thanks.
- Hey, Rex, I'll follow you out.
I've got a quick question.
So, uh, if I turn my fan on--
- How long has it been?
- Hmm?
Aww! 51 years.
- Wow! What's the secret?
Oh!
There's been a lot of...
life since that photo.
A lot of change.
But with all that change...
I guess it's about
always working to find
each other in the end.
- That's beautiful.
- Thank you.
- All right.
What's the damage?
What do I owe ya?
- It's not too bad.
There you go.
- Great.
Fuck! Fuck!
- Are you okay?
- Ah, yeah. Sorry.
Um, I, I've got some money
in the car.
I'll be back.
- I might finally
have some reception.
Sarah called me.
Why's your wife
calling me, Wes?
She left me a message.
- Do, do not listen
to that voicemail.
- Oh, wait! She left me
four fucking messages.
Why, why do I have four fucking
messages from your wife, Wes?
- You know,
just give me the phone!
- No!
- Just give me
the fucking phone!
Give me the phone.
- Why? They're clearly for me.
- Give me the goddamn phone!
- What happened
in San Francisco, Wes?
You've been fucking dark
ever since.
Somethin' happened.
The man with all the answers.
And the one time
I actually ask for one,
you won't give it to me.
Just be honest!
- I was having
a fucking affair!
Okay?
I fell in love
with a woman from work.
Are you happy now?
But I ended it.
I ended it.
Because no matter
how much I love her,
I don't want to ruin my family.
But I did not sleep
with those women last night.
They robbed me, okay?
That's why
I'm freaking out right now.
They took my credit cards,
my AMEX cards,
and Sarah has access
to my AMEX cards,
and I'm sure she's seen
the fraud charges
and knows something's up.
You're right.
I'm supposed to have
all the answers.
You're the one guy
that knows I don't.
- Why didn't you tell me
about it before?
- You wouldn't
answer the phone.
Wes, where are you?
The hotel in San Francisco
says you never checked in.
There's all these strange
charges on the credit card.
I don't know where you are,
I don't know what's going on,
I,
you don't answer your phone.
I don't care what's going on.
I just need you to call me
and let me know you're okay
'cause I'm kind of
freaking out here.
Call me please, okay?
I love you.
- Eventually, our boss
got wind of the affair.
And he couldn't allow things
to move forward
the way they were going.
But he needed us both.
Thank God.
So he had Jennifer take over
the San Francisco office...
Left me in D.C.
And um...
for the past year,
I've been living a double life
with a woman
across the country.
- I should have
picked up the phone.
- No, man, it's okay.
- No, no. I should've.
I should have been
there for you.
I'm sorry.
- You're here now.
Jeez.
I don't know
what I'm doing. Fuck.
I don't know.
- Wes, look, man.
I don't have
a clue about marriage.
I don't know what it's like.
I'm just some single dude
who's spent the majority
of his adult life alone.
So, who am I to give you
advice, right?
But what the fuck!
You can't lie your way
through the rest of your life.
What's the point?
You're just
going to hurt people,
people important to you.
So just...
just make a choice.
And stick with it.
We are reading to begin
security screening for Flight
310 with service to Sacramento.
At this time, if you'd gather
your personal items
and have your boarding pass
and your photo ID out
and available for myself
and the TSA agents
when you get to the checkpoint.
- It was fun, buddy.
- What am I supposed to do
with the Bronco?
- Keep it.
Come here.
And I don't need to tell you
what to do with it.
You're ten miles from Oregon.
Come on, Wes.
- That Maggie thing is real.
She asked about you.
Look...
you're right.
I had to lie to get
a little freedom for myself
and, I hurt some people.
But...
You don't have to lie.
And...
right now,
you're only hurting yourself.
- Get on the plane.
Go on.
- You know what to do
with that Bronco.
Luke, it's Phil again.
Give me a call
when you get a chance.
Second voicemail.
I don't know where you are,
I don't know what's going on,
and I don't know
what you're doing,
but you gotta get on
that airplane, man.
Remember, I put myself
out there for this
so don't screw me over.
- Hey, buddy!
Want to make a quick 20 bucks?