(wind whistles)
(faint rumbling)
(objects rattle)
(rumbling and rattling get louder)
(wind whistles)
- Must be Friday.
- Yeah, must be.
- How have you been?
- You know, surviving. You'?
I'm still here.
- Busy day?
- No, you're my first.
- You on your own?
- No, he's working.
- (pump clicks off)
- Er, £24.68.
£25.16. Close, Hugh.
(Hugh chuckles)
Come on in.
(m: beeps)
Do they ever come and see you?
No, it's easier for me to go down there.
Are you looking forward to seeing them?
- Can you tell?
- I can always tell.
Thanks.
Say hi to Connor and Malcolm for me.
You know, Shell, it means a lot to me
that you always remember their names.
- Anyway, don't work too hard.
- I won't.
So, see you Sunday?
- See you Sunday.
- Alright.
(car engine starts up)
- I'm going to start supper now.
- What time is it'?
About five. I fell asleep.
Go on, then.
(Sighs)
("Walk of Life " by Dire Straits)
♪ Here comes Johnny
singing oldies, goldies
♪ Be-Bop-A-Lula, Baby What'd I Say
♪ Here comes Johnny singing...
(wind whistles)
♪ He do the song
about the sweet lovin' woman
♪ He do the song about...
♪ He do the walk of life
♪ Yeah, he do the walk of life
♪ Whoo-hoo
♪ Here comes Johnny,
gonna tell you the story
♪ Hand me down my waikin' shoes
(turns music off)
(clattering)
(tap still runs)
Shh, Shh.
It's alright. It's OK. Shh.
You're OK. You're OK.
Shh.
It's OK.
(chews loudly)
(vehicle approaches)
(vehicle engine rumbles)
Sounds like you've got a hole
in your exhaust.
(man) Aye, I know.
Does it make me sound fast?
- How much'?
- To the top.
(Shell) Are you sure?
I got paid today.
- Hows work?
- Oh, you know.
You look pretty tonight.
Do I?
- (man) Has anyone else told you that?
- No.
I saw an accident on the way up
this morning.
- (Shell) Yeah? Was it bad?
- One on the roof, one in a ditch.
- What did you do?
- There was no one there.
The police had taped it off
but the drivers were long gone.
Saw some blood on the road though.
I wonder if they'll want us
to come and take the wrecks.
It was nearer Johnny Hutch's place.
I'd say he'll get them before you.
That's £22, please.
Lovely.
(sniffs) I'd better go.
I'm working in the pub tonight.
You should come down
one of these nights.
- How would I get there'?
- I'd pick you up on the way from work.
Take you back again if you want.
Yeah, I'll think about it.
OK.
I'll see you next week?
Yeah. The guy I bought my car from
has a couple of freezer chests
he's selling off just now.
- Nothing wrong with them.
- Oh, yeah?
(man) You were saying
you had to get the chisel to your one.
Was I?
I can get them for you cheap.
Bring them up to you if you want.
No, it's alright, we'll manage.
The chisel's good for my arms.
(car exhaust rattles)
- I'm going for my bath.
- OK.
You need a haircut.
♪ I went to church on Sunday
♪ My love, she passed me by
♪ I knew her mind was changing
♪ By the roving of her eye
(faintly) ♪ By the roving of her eye
♪ I knew her mind was changing
♪ By the roving of her eye
(lorry approaches)
(lorry roars past)
(wind whistles)
(knocking at door)
Can you help us? We had an accident.
(animal groans)
(breathes heavily)
(blade slashes)
(blood gushes)
- What do you want to lift first'?
- The deer.
Where were you headed?
Home.
Edinburgh.
We just come up here for the day.
Second.
What's your name?
Clare.
- And his?
- Robert.
I'm Shell, and he's Pete.
Shell? Like the petrol station?
Shell, like the unique
and beautiful thing you find in the sea.
I'll drop you at the bed and breakfast.
Alright. Thanks.
Are you two married?
Yeah. Are you?
She's my daughter.
What brings you up here?
I'd never seen the Highlands.
Well, you have now.
(vehicle rushes past)
(grunts)
(groans)
(vehicle door closes)
(engine starts)
(vehicle drives away)
(vehicle pulls up)
- (Clare) Hello, Shell.
- Hello.
Sure is different here in daylight.
It's this way.
(Robert) He's got quite a collection.
I can't believe a deer did this.
Yeah, they're tougher than they look.
Get in there.
What happened to the deer?
- It's in our freezer.
- Ah, so it's venison now.
Yeah. Take some with you
if you want.
- (Clare) What'll happen to the car now?
- My dad'll stan breaking it up.
(Robert) Where is your dad'?
Scrap merchant.
- When will he be back?
- (Shell) I don't know.
- Is it just you and your dad here?
- Yeah.
- You live here all year round?
(Clare) I bet the winters are cold.
We sometimes don't see a car for a week.
But I don't mind.
- How old are you'?
- 17.
(Clare) Do you go to school?
I did when I was younger,
and then my dad home-schooled me.
Oh.
- I found that in the car.
- Oh. Thank you.
(toilet flushes)
- ls your mum around, Shell?
- No, she left when I was four.
My dad built this place for her.
You can't see much today.
It's wild.
(Robert)
Maybe we'll see you again, Shell.
Next time we're up.
Here, you have it.
- Thank you.
- (Shell) Thank you.
(vehicle approaches)
(vehicle drives past)
(chopping)
- Did you get a good price?
- (Pete) Good enough.
(door closes)
You've been alright here?
Yep. Making supper.
Have I time for a wash?
Where have you been?
- Hmm?
- Pub.
Yeah, I know. I can smell it.
Did you go anywhere else?
No.
(chopping)
(footsteps)
- Cold hands.
- Warm heart.
Come on, love, I'm trying to wash.
Do you love me?
Shell, move your arms.
- Shell, move your arms.
- Do you?
You know I love you.
(pilot light hisses)
(Sighs)
Shell. What's the matter?
(Shell) Boiler's out.
Just needs lit again.
- What are you doing?
- I'm freezing.
- Shell, you can't sleep here.
- Why not?
- Where are you going?
- To fix the boiler.
(boiler door clanks)
(starter button clicks)
(door clanks shut)
- What's wrong with it?
- Inlet pipe needs replacing.
- Can you do that?
- I'll cut a new piece in the morning.
At least cuddle me.
(Shell) I love you.
(faint crackling)
_ Are YOU getting up?
- (Pete) Aye.
(Pete urinates)
(toilet flushes)
- (Pete) Don't lie there all morning.
- I won't.
It's like Christmas.
- Are you wanting breakfast?
- Maybe later.
(wind whistles)
(lorry approaches)
(pipe clinks on the ground)
(vehicle pulls up)
- (Shell) Hello, Hugh.
- Hi, Shell.
Did you have a good weekend?
Aye, it was alright. You?
Yeah.
- It's got cold, eh?
- Aye.
Did you see your boys?
Apparently I got the wrong weekend.
Their mother and her boyfriend
were taking them go-karting in Aviemore.
- Oh, no.
- Yeah.
If I'd known they wanted
to go go-karting, I'd have taken them.
- Well, there's always next month.
- Yeah.
What did you do the rest of the time?
Not much, but I'd booked
that hotel for two days.
Should have come back
on Saturday, really.
- This can't be winter already, eh?
- I know.
- Got you something.
- (Shell) What?
They were a bit of a gamble
so I hope you like them.
Jeans?
Yeah. I was just going round
a few shops on Saturday killing time
and I saw a girl buying them.
She was your size, I think.
I thought you might like them.
- I do like them.
- They're Levi's.
(zipping)
- Hmm! (wolf-whistles)
- (both laugh)
- What do you think?
- Hmm, walk around in 'em a bit.
Do they look good on me?
They look a bit long.
Let me try something.
Give us a twirl.
- They look really good.
- Really?
Really.
I can't wait to show my dad.
At least I made somebody happy
this weekend, huh?
Thanks, Hugh. It's really good of you.
Just glad you like them.
Erm...
Look, I should go.
How much do I owe you for the petrol?
Oh, I never looked.
(shoes clatter)
Hmm.
(grunts)
(door squeaks open)
- You OK, Hugh?
- Aye. Just tired.
- Don't you want to guess?
- No, just tell me.
- £38.88.
- All the eights.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
(m: beeps)
(till pings open)
(coins rattle)
- Another hug.
- OK.
- Big hug.
- Yeah.
(Hugh breathes heavily)
Just let me hold you. Please.
I don't know what I'd do
if you weren't here.
Well, I am here.
I'll see you next time.
(car door closes)
(engine starts up)
(car drives away)
(car accelerates)
(door closes)
(dang)
(sawing)
You don't have to do that now.
Do you want to freeze?
I've got the heater.
It's cosier without it in a way.
How can it be cosier'?
Because you have to wear
lots of clothes
- and cuddle up at night.
- (drops saw)
Shell, I can't be doing with you
touching me all the time.
We'll have to, you know, think about
getting you a dog or something. OK?
Make sure he's lame.
So he can't run away.
(wind whistles)
(vehicle approaches)
It's cold.
Yeah, I know.
(clears throat)
ls your dad here?
Inside.
Do you want to go for a drive?
I'm... working.
I can't just leave whenever I like.
Why not?
Do you want to come inside?
Dad.
Dad, we've got company.
This is Adam.
Adam works at the sawmill.
This is my dad, Pete.
- Hello.
- Hello. How you doing'?
Sit down.
I'll make us some coffee.
Are you cold?
No.
The heating broke last night.
There's a heater in the shop.
I can bring it through.
Do you want me to get it?
Yeah. OK.
Is coffee pan of the service now?
(Shell) He'll hear you.
I can often be heard
in my own home.
There's fine. Just leave it there.
Take a seat.
Hows business?
Ticking over.
We picked up a car on Friday.
- Deer strike?
- Yeah.
There'll be more
because the winter's here.
They come looking for food.
There's sugar there.
(Adam) Hmm.
- Adam works at the sawmill.
- Aye, you said.
Yeah. (clears throat)
Yeah, there was a break-in
on Friday night.
Oh, no. What did they steal?
Er, five chain saws. Brand new.
Do they know who did it?
They think I did it.
They never said but...
They phoned the house on Saturday
morning and told me not to come back in.
They've never had anything
go missing before so it's...
That's a shame.
Aye. (clears throat)
Yeah. I can get my job back at the pub
if I want but...
I'm thinking about starting up
something for myself.
A bit like your setup here, Pete.
I mean, are you needing
any help or...?
I'm not needing any help
at the moment, no.
But what about through the winter?
I mean, there must be
a few more... breakdowns.
I've nothing for you.
OK. (clears throat)
Adam's mum's not been very well.
How is she'?
Yeah, she's much the same.
What's wrong with her?
She's our best customer.
It's his mum's pub that he works at.
She says I'm the only man
who's ever loved her.
- Can I use your bathroom?
- Yeah.
It's just down there on the left.
Come for a drive.
I'm working.
Your dad can manage without you
for an hour.
I'd like to be alone with you.
Wouldn't you like that?
(car door closes)
(cries out)
It's good, love.
A bit tough maybe.
You not hungry?
It's like eating my own flesh.
(Pete) We can leave the heating on
overnight... if you're cold.
Or if you're cold.
Or if I'm cold, yes.
Will that do?
Yeah, it's fine.
What do want me to do?
I'll say goodnight, then.
(no sound on TV)
(Wind gusts)
(vehicle approaches)
(vehicle roars past)
(door opens)
(vehicle approaches)
- Hello.
- Hi.
Erm, would it be OK
if she used your toilet?
Yeah.
- Is there a key or something?
- Yeah. It's inside. I'll show you.
Up-
She hates it if I go with her now.
- Where are you heading?
- Er, home now.
- Where is that?
- She's taking a while.
Who's that?
That's my dad.
Come on, let's go.
(car engine starts)
Wait!
(car reverses)
You left her behind.
Thanks. There'd have been tears tonight
if you hadn't caught us.
(mother) Here we go.
(breathes heavily)
(slow banging)
(banging $1095)
(metal sign rattles)
(Shell gasps)
(Pete groans)
(Shell screams)
(Pete breathes heavily)
I thought you'd left me.
Did you?
We've been happy here, haven't we?
Hmm.
I still love you.
I love you, too.
I need you to stay.
I know.
Shell needs you, too.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm sorry, love.
(Shell) It's OK.
(wind whistles)
(thud)
(brakes squeal in the distance)
Dad?
(engine runs)
(engine stops)
Dad?
(cries out)
(screams)
(Shell sniffs)
(SODs)
- Morning.
(vehicle approaches)
(vehicle pulls up)
We've got a customer.
- Do you want me to go?
- No, you're not dressed.
(Sighs)
(engine stops)
- (driver) Morning.
- Hi.
Can I get some diesel?
Must get lonely up here.
What do I owe you'?
£70, please.
- Thank you.
- Well, thank you. See you again.
(engine starts)
(lorry drives away)
(driver) What's your name?
Shell.
(driver) Do you know
where you're going?
No.
(driver) Plenty of time
to make up your mind.
Do you mind the radio?
No. I like the radio.
(radio clicks on)
(slow song)
♪ Better
♪ Listen closely
♪ I guess
♪ That I have not
♪ Got Kong
♪ Promise
♪ You'll tell her
♪ She's my favourite girl
♪ In all the world
♪ Can I
♪ Make her happy'?
♪ I guess
♪ That I have not got Kong
♪ Promise
♪ You'll tell her
♪ She's my favourite girl
♪ In all the world
Subtitles by IMS