(MultiCom Jingle)
(tense instrumental music)
- [Man] What a stupid place to live.
- [Man] He must be important.
- [Man] He is, he's that
adventurer guy, Sir John Gerad.
- [Man] Oh, the mountain climber.
Why does he live in such a shitty place?
- [Man] I don't know.
He's about a 100, lives
alone except for some old guy
who looks after him during the day.
- [Man] Tell me about the the curse.
- [Man] It's all bullshit.
- [Man] I don't care
whether it's bullshit,
just tell me about the curse.
- [Man] Whoever owns the
stone possesses eternal life.
- [Man] That's terrible.
- [Man] Sounds good to me.
Although anyone who's ever
owned it ends up with nothing.
(easygoing rhythmic music)
- [Man] Well, what about him?
- [Man] He had it all once.
All he's got now is this old house.
(slow rhythmic music)
- Are you sure the old bloke's
the only one that lives here?
- I'm sure.
Spends all day in bed sick, I think.
Probably dying.
- I thought he had eternal life.
- Yeah, well, I told you
that was all bullshit.
- Will ya do me a favor
with the credit card?
When you break into a house,
just check to see if
the door is (squeaking)
open.
(tense music)
He's really old.
- What'd I tell ya, he's a 103.
- That's really old.
(tense music)
It really stinks in here.
- Let's get the rock, okay?
(tense music)
- What a messy old guy.
- Conrad.
(tense music)
- This is a really weird place.
- [Man In Corner] What?
- Doesn't matter.
(tense music)
- This is it.
(dramatic music)
- That looks like a colored piece of shit.
- This piece of shit is a curse,
and people pay for a curse.
- Doesn't it
glow or somethin'?
- Whoo!
- Don't do that.
- You watch too many movies, man.
- I read.
(tense instrumental music)
(rumbling)
(rhythmic rock music)
♫ Blue and white gonna
stop the workin' days
♫ Bend and flex your touching heart
♫ Til you feel it start to sway
♫ Being in your arms
(throbbing rhythmic music)
♫ Your ideas
♫ Reflections in the jade
♫ Get your soul in trouble
♫ A kiss goodbye to fame
♫ Get a grip on your ideas
♫ A big burst of rain
♫ You've got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
♫ Yeah
♫ You've got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
♫ Take it on now
♫ You got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it
- You get it?
- Five.
- [Man In Blue] What?
- He wants five, and he wants it now.
(tense music)
- Not too much to pay for eternal life.
- No, it's a quite reasonable sum.
(rhythmic music)
(tense music)
Well, the 100 grand and some
weirdos willing to pay for it.
Giving us 500.
- Right, Sole.
(chuckles)
(rhythmic music)
♫ Gotta have soul
♫ Gotta get laid
♫ Gotta get your rest
of the bet to get paid
♫ Gotta have soul
♫ You gotta get laid
♫ Gotta get your rest
of the bet to get paid
♫ You got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
- Hey!
♫ You got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
♫ Take it on now
♫ You got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
♫ I'll take it on now
♫ Take it
(tense instrumental music)
♫ One, two
♫ One, two, three, four
(engine revs)
♫ Whoa
♫ Gotta have soul
♫ You gotta get laid
♫ Gotta get your piece
of the bet to get paid
♫ Gotta have soul
♫ Gotta get laid
♫ Gotta get you rest
of the bet to get paid
♫ You gotta have soul
♫ You gotta get laid
♫ Gotta get the rest
of the bet to get paid
♫ Gotta have soul
♫ Gotta get laid
♫ Gotta get your rest
of the bet to get paid
♫ You got it, I want it
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
♫ You've got it, I want it
♫ Yeah
♫ You get it, I'll take it on now
♫ You've got it, I want it
♫ Yeah
♫ Take it
(clapping)
(cheering)
- [DJ] Yeah, good morning, Sydney.
We've got some great clouds,
good music, bad traffic,
but Uncle Dave is here to see ya through
your bumper-bumper blues.
Remember, if you're thinking
swimming pools, think over.
Tell ya what, I think I'll
be getting a pool today.
Here's a sweet little diddy
just before the morning news.
(trains rumble)
Relax, smile, drive,
but don't turn me off.
And after the news, I'll
be back with more of me
to keep ya company.
(phone rings)
(voice drowned out by traffic)
(chuckles)
- Ah, let him hang there.
No, I'll call him when
I get back off the trip.
Anything else?
Uh-huh, my brother?
When did he come in?
Oh, well you didn't tell him
I was gonna come back today.
Good.
Hmm, oh, no, no, you, you've done fine.
Yeah, I'll see ya shortly.
(easygoing rhythmic music)
Davey-Joe.
- Big brother.
The bitch upstairs told
me you were out of town
and you wouldn't be back for a fortnight.
- Ah, she must've made a mistake.
I am leaving town, but not till tomorrow.
- Yeah, she must've made a mistake.
Don't know how a smart guy like you
can hire such a dumb bitch.
- So how you been keepin'?
- Knockin' the deals
back with a baseball bat.
You know how it is in
this dog-eat-dog business.
Why do you care how I've been keeping?
Look, I need some money, don't
tell me that times are tough.
Bullshit.
- We can talk about it in my office.
Pam.
- Mr. Cordeaux, I wasn't
expecting you back.
- She's good.
How much do ya pay her to lie for ya?
You been givin' her one?
- Charming.
- [Mr. Cordeaux] Let's not waste time,
I've got a lot to do before I leave.
- [Davey-Joe] I'd hate to
slow the wheels of industry.
- [Mr. Cordeaux] So, hi, Cindy.
- Hello.
- How are the job prospects?
Not too good, I take it.
- [Davey-Joe] A man of my qualifications,
no one wants to start me
where I should be starting,
at the top.
- Yeah, things are tough.
- Yeah, tough.
You got the whole box all nicely tied up.
- Nothing I haven't worked hard for.
Yeah, Pam, get ahold of Masterson,
tell him our legal departments
looking at the contracts,
and we'll get back to
him as soon as we can.
Yeah, fine.
I've got a business contact,
a delivery contractor.
Might be able to swing you a job.
- My license has lapsed.
- You'll be riding a pushbike.
It's two-wheeled couriers.
This is the bloke to see.
- I need the money now.
- Why?
- I wanna go on a holiday.
- A holiday?
- Our ever-loving sister
asked me to leave.
What do you think I'm here
kissing your butt for?
- I'll give ya 50 bucks.
You go and see that company about the job.
- Fine.
- Promise?
- Yeah.
Done.
(light rhythmic music)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
Hi, Alex.
- Just had Davey-Joe in.
He told me you asked him to leave.
- I don't know who it's gonna be
every time there's a
knock at the front door.
No, that's not true.
I'm always expecting the police.
I can't take it anymore, Alex.
I've got my hands full
with Caine as it is.
- The reason I called
was that I'm going up to, uh,
to a mountain for a fortnight.
Friend of mine's canceled
out at the last minute,
and I, uh, thought I might take Caine.
- Well, with Davey-Joe
gone, that would be a break.
A fortnight, I wouldn't
know what to do with myself.
- Get out, relax, and enjoy yourself.
- (chuckles) Right.
(easygoing rhythmic music)
(TV chattering)
Guess who's going on a camping trip?
Alex is gonna take you on a camping trip.
Won't that be great?
Yes, darling, that's good.
(voice drowned out by cartoon noises)
(TV chatter)
(rhythmic music)
♫ When you get touchy
♫ When you get mad
♫ When you wanna hurt someone
♫ For the things they said
♫ Before you use that knife
♫ Before you raise that hand
♫ It doesn't hurt a thing to oh, oh, oh
(rhythmic pop music)
♫ Went to the kingdom
♫ Let's have another drink
♫ Don't try to press no one
♫ It doesn't hurt to think
♫ Think of your family
♫ Think of your friends
♫ Think about what's
runnin' around your head
♫ Think again
♫ Think about it
♫ Think it over
♫ Think on the consequences
♫ Your commonsense
♫ Yeah, think
♫ Think about it
♫ Your logic, your logic
♫ Is it really worth it
(rhythmic pop music)
♫ Before you spread that curse
♫ Those all up in the sky
♫ Are your responsibility
♫ Before you lose that sound
♫ You'll drown in your disease
♫ You're best off and oh, oh, oh
♫ Before you let it start into a war
♫ Think about what lies ahead
♫ And what the heck you're fighting for
♫ Hey, Mr. President, do
you know right from wrong
♫ There's nothing left alive
♫ Nothing right about our war
♫ Think about it
♫ Oh, think it over
♫ Think of the consequences
♫ And use your commonsense
(knocking)
- Come on, open up, it's me Davey.
(rhythmic music)
- Davey, I heard you skipped town.
- Ya heard wrong.
You alone?
- Except for the cockroaches
and a couple of models.
Got a job offer.
- [Davey] Can we talk?
- [Photographer] Yeah, but be
short about it, will ya, mate?
I don't wanna be paying
these two overtime.
Come on, ya moved on me.
Just lick your lips for me, come on.
- I've gotta get outta town.
I still have Conrad breathing
down my neck.
- I know, mate.
Come here lookin' for ya before.
- Yeah?
Shit, ya owe me some bucks, man.
- Oh, right.
Bad timing.
I'm down to baked beans.
What do you think I'm
doin' this art shot for?
- This is not art, man.
- [Photographer] Yeah, I see what ya mean.
Tilt your had back a bit.
- You owe me some dollars, Wacka.
- Look, you know I'd give
it to you, if I had it.
- Well, find it, rat face, I'm desperate!
- What's your problem?
- Just don't hold out on me, okay?
- I'm just tryin' to help.
- Well, you can help by
getting me some money.
- Yeah, all right, uh,
you wait here and I'll go
and open the piggy bank.
(door thuds)
(tense rhythmic music)
- Bogey, you wanker!
- Hey, does this mean we're finished now?
(rhythmic music)
- G'day.
- Shit.
- Sorry, mate.
- Where's the stone?
(dog barks)
- [Woman] Beats me why you
waste your time with Davey-Joe.
- [Alex] It beats me, too.
- Well, why don't you just
wash your hands of him?
- Can't.
He's family.
- Family?
Family doesn't treat you
the way Davey-Joe does.
How much did you give him this time?
- Oh, not much.
- How much is not much?
(gentle music)
- Will you drop it?
- What's the matter, Alex?
- Gary dropped out of the trip.
- I'm sorry, what a shame, why?
- (chuckles) Business pressures.
(gentle instrumental music)
- So, what are you gonna do
with two weeks on your hands?
- Oh, I'm still going.
- On your own?
- No, I'm taking Caine.
- Caine, are you out of your mind?
- I'm taking Caine.
- I know he's your brother,
but he's not exactly--
- Normal?
- Yeah.
(gentle instrumental music)
Ever since we got back from the States,
you've been more occupied with your family
than you hae with us.
- That's because I was away then,
but not that I'm back,
I wanna make more effort
of being with them, that's all.
- You make enough of an effort.
Good God, you lend them money,
you bought Muriel her apartment.
What more do you wanna do?
- I'm going and I'm taking Caine with me.
(gentle instrumental music)
(TV chattering)
- [Girl] Caine!
Caine, where are you?
Caine!
(screaming)
(gentle instrumental music)
(TV chattering)
- When are you going to
start spending time with us?
- Give us a break, will ya?
- We hardly ever see you anymore.
Billy's beginning to
question who the stranger is
who comes home at night.
- I don't need this, Dianne.
- You could've canceled the
trip when Gary backed out.
You should've asked Billy.
- It's not for me, it's for Caine!
He's got no life, he's got nothing.
- Is this your way of
cleansing your conscience
about what happened to him?
(TV chatter)
(dramatic music)
- Don't forget to wear
your hat in the sun.
Now, you'll need plenty of
warm clothing, so.
(phone rings)
Hello?
(dramatic music)
That was Alex, he said he's gonna be here
at 7:30 in the morning.
Oh, I wish it wasn't so early.
Now, where was I?
(gentle instrumental music)
- [Driver] See ya later, Billy.
See ya in the morning.
(gentle instrumental music)
- [Alex] Billy?
- Yeah, I'm out here, Dad.
(gentle instrumental music)
- Where ya been?
- Oh, just hangin' around.
- Get lucky?
- Come on.
(chuckling)
- Been with Jeff?
- What's with all the questions?
- Ah, just like to know
what you've been up to.
- Hey, that's a change.
- Yeah, we haven't seen too
much of each other, have we?
- Well, I've been here.
- Gary's pulled out of the trip.
- Oh.
- You know, I was wondering if maybe.
- Ah, I've got other plans.
- Nothing that can't be changed.
- No.
- Yeah, it'd be a great trip.
Two weeks,
no women.
(chuckles)
No responsibility.
- The guys are really counting on me.
- Yeah.
- You're leaving first
thing in the morning?
- Yeah.
- Well, Pete's picking me up early,
but I might see you before then.
- That'd be nice.
- [Billy] Goodnight.
(gentle instrumental music)
(phone rings)
(water sprinkles)
(horse neighs)
- Hello?
- Hello to yourself, Sis.
Muriel, I was wondering--
- Davey, no, that was the last time.
You and your weirdo friends can go
and ruin somebody else's life.
I'm not having you, them,
or your drugs anywhere
near my place again.
(rhythmic music)
(voices drowned out by music)
- The bitch is there, come on,
we just have to wait till she goes out.
- Oh, I see.
Well, it better be there, Davey.
- It's there!
- It better be there!
Conrad, get him in the car.
- Get in the car.
- What was that for?
- 'Cause you stink.
(chuckling)
- [Dianne] So you're
going where we used to go?
- Yeah, it's a nice place.
I better make directions.
- Bye.
(gentle instrumental music)
Have a good time.
(engine rumbles)
(horn beeps)
- Alex is here.
Turn that down, darling.
(boinging)
(beeping)
(whistling)
(chuckling)
- Hey, sis.
- Hello, stranger.
- How are ya?
- [Muriel] Oh, good.
- And where's that man you love?
- Oh, he's through there.
He's still costing me
a fortune in Polaroids.
(chuckling)
- Want some money?
- No, I'm all right.
(TV chattering)
- Caine,
you ready for your,
you ready for the big adventure?
(TV chattering)
Don't worry about him.
You have a good time for two weeks.
- Don't forget, patience.
(chuckling)
- Phone ya from the ranger's station.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Take a photo, go on.
(camera clicks)
Give it to me.
Here.
(camera clicks)
(easygoing rhythmic music)
- [Davey] Anytime now.
She always goes out in the mornings.
Shopping, bitch lives for shopping.
There ya go.
- You got five minutes, Davey.
- Five minutes?
No problems.
- You should've given him longer.
- Why?
- So he could have a bath.
(tense instrumental music)
- Hi, Muriel.
- Hi.
Oh.
Ah, oh!
(thudding)
(tense instrumental music)
- Shit.
- You really want this stone, don't you?
- Yes, Conrad, for the last
time, I really want the stone.
Don't you?
- Sure.
- Hey, the babe's back.
- Really.
- Yes, really.
(tense instrumental music)
- Davey, I thought I told--
- Where is it?
- What?
- The package,
I had it hidden in Caine's room.
Where's Caine?
- He's away.
I don't know anything about your package.
Look, Davey, what is all this about?
(tense music)
- We got a problem, Davey?
(birds chirping)
- Now, uh, Caine, you stay here.
I'm gonna go and see the ranger,
and then I'll phone Muriel.
(camera clicks)
(birds chirp)
- Can I help you there?
- Uh, Ranger,
going up the mountain
for a couple of weeks.
Thought I'd leave you some details.
- That the route?
- Yeah.
- Good.
You seem well organized.
- Yeah, just myself
and my younger brother.
- Hey, how ya doin' there?
- Oh, he doesn't talk.
Can I use your phone?
- Yeah, it's in the office.
(camera clicks)
(tense instrumental music)
- Well, it's not here, Davey, or is it?
It's just not here.
- It's here, I swear.
Tell them, Mure, otherwise
he's gonna shoot me.
- How can I tell them anything,
if I don't know what you're looking for?
- Caine, he's taken it.
(phone rings)
He's always knocking things off.
- Where you goin'?
- Answer the phone.
- Why?
- 'Cause it's ringing.
- Stay there.
(sharp smacking)
Who's Caine?
(tense instrumental music)
- You pin that on yourself.
I'll be lookin' after you.
(tense instrumental music)
(dramatic music)
- He's my older bro, not the full quid.
- And he conveniently
went on this camping trip
with this Alex guy?
- You heard her, I don't
know nothin' about it.
- And Caine's your brother?
- Yeah.
- And Alex is your brother?
- Yes, yes.
- You got any other brothers?
- Somebody must know where they are.
(snaps)
- His old lady.
- Whose old lady?
- [Conrad And Sole] His old lady.
(tense instrumental music)
- Now, you folks have
yourselves a good trip.
You got plenty up there
to keep you occupied.
- We plan to make the most of it.
- By the way, watch that
river, she can be very tricky.
- We'll be taking it nice and easy.
Oh, thanks for the use of the phone.
(engine rumbles)
(tense instrumental music)
- [Billy] It's here.
- Thank you.
Billy, give me the report card.
- [Billy] It's not that
bad, you'll really like it.
- Fine, give it to me.
Now.
(chuckles)
Another D, Billy, come
on, this is your fifth D.
This has gotta stop.
- I'll try harder.
- Another D.
(ringing)
Fine.
- Mrs. Cordeaux?
- [Dianne] Yes.
- Oh, good, I've got the right place.
Could I speak to your husband?
- Oh, I'm sorry, he's not here.
He won't be back for about two weeks.
- Two weeks, oh.
I didn't plan on that.
Is there somewhere I can contact him?
- Well, I doubt it.
He's on a camping trip in the mountains,
but, look if you want to
tell me what this is about,
maybe I can help or.
- Surely you must know
where he can be contacted?
- Yes, but, uh, why don't you
leave me your name and number,
and then when he gets back,
I can have him call you.
- So you have an idea of his whereabouts?
- Yes.
Why don't you just come
back in two weeks, okay?
(yells)
(dramatic music)
- You, over here.
- Come on, just do as he says.
(tense music)
(thudding)
- Why did you put him in the trunk?
- Because it's bigger than the ashtray.
(Sole whistles)
(gentle rhythmic music)
- Here we are, Caine, the jumper.
Let's get out and have a look.
Come on, mate.
The water's not going to reach you.
We went fishing that time, remember?
Come on, put the bag down.
Okay, bring the back with you.
(gentle instrumental music)
Come on, Caine, don't be nervous.
It's gonna be all right,
we're gonna have some fun.
- [Davey] You're gonna kill
me, there's no air, no air!
- Now you know what you smell like.
- All right, sweet thing,
where do we find your old man?
- Why are you doing this?
- You, come here, what's your name?
I said what's your name?
- All right!
I'll tell you what you wanna know.
- Never doubted for a minute you wouldn't.
Take her, get some coffee,
while me and sweet thing here have a chat.
- Thank you.
- Where's Davey's brother?
- I told you he's gone camping.
- Where?
- Sher Mountain Park.
- Where in Sher Mountain Park?
(tense music)
- We used to camp
somewhere along the river.
- You've been there?
Look,
this Caine guy, this mute,
he's got somethin' I want.
And I want it bad.
- All I can tell you is there's a,
there's a map next to
the old ranger's station.
They'll be somewhere along the river,
and there's a walking trail right there.
- Good.
Very good.
- You wait till we get out there.
Put your stuff down.
- What do you intend doing with us?
- Nothing.
Just make the coffee, girl.
- How do you like it?
- Milk and two.
I don't want anything like this.
You know what I mean?
I don't wanna hurt you.
I don't wanna hurt the little boy.
I just wanna help my idiot friend
get this idiot stone.
Where does it hurt you?
(kettle whistles)
(tense rhythmic music)
(yells)
- Stay here, weasel.
Don't move.
Get her, man.
You idiot!
- That's an understatement, Sole.
- Get out, just get
out and leave us alone.
- Exactly what I had in mind.
(tense rhythmic music)
- Why don't ya let me hold that, baby?
- Shut up!
- Come on, Conrad, come on!
- Now where does it hurt you, baby?
(tense music)
- Come on, Conrad.
Listen, we're gonna back
outta here to the car,
nice and easy.
- Billy.
Please, don't hurt him,
please.
- Just insurance till we get
to the car.
One more step and this kid is history.
- Stink, do I?
(tense music)
- Billy!
(tense rhythmic music)
- Get in there, get in!
- Don't even think about it,
especially you, ya blonde bitch.
(tense rhythmic music)
(tires squeal)
(insects chirp)
(camera clicks)
- What the hell were you doin' back there?
- Nothing.
- What do you mean nothing?
What were you doin'?
- Nothing.
- You could've blown the whole thing.
- I know.
- She's got your gun, asshole.
- Yeah, that's a real problem.
- What the hell is going on here?
Who are you guys?
- Shut up!
- [Dianne] I'm calling the police.
- [Davey] No police.
If you wanna see Billy alive,
you won't go near the police.
- For God's sake, Davey,
who are these men?
- Some mates.
- Mates?
Who are they, tell me who
they are, what do they want?
Tell me!
- Dianne!
Take it easy!
- I will not take it easy.
- Muriel, talk some sense into her.
- Dianne,
give me the gun.
(tense rhythmic music)
Give me the gun.
- Not until I know
where I can find my son.
- Give me the gun.
(tense music)
(crying)
Everything's gonna be all right, Dianne.
We'll get Billy back.
- Sure.
- Do you think they'll
be able to find him?
- I don't know.
I told them they'd be by the river,
but they could be anywhere.
- We're gonna have to go after them.
- You can count me out.
- Don't even think about it.
You got us into this mess,
you're gonna start getting us out,
or I'll ruddy-well shoot you myself.
- Over there, Caine, paddle,
just right, paddle here.
(gentle instrumental music)
- Are you out of your mind?
We are no match for them.
- Either you go up the mountains,
or I'll call the police.
- What about Billy?
If you call the police,
they're gonna kill him.
Come on, let's go.
- What are we going to do?
- Well,
we've got a gun.
- Please, can we just go?
(tense instrumental music)
- Nice leveled spot, Caine.
What is it?
Have you lost the bag?
(tense music)
Don't worry, Caine, don't
worry about the bag.
We'll look for it afterwards.
- Got it.
You look like shit.
- I feel like shit.
I got fluid runnin' out of me everywhere.
- I gotta go to the toilet.
- Hold on.
It's for your shoulder, not your head.
- Yeah, right.
- You'll feel a lot better
once you get your hands on that stone.
(tense instrumental music)
- I'm doing a job for
Sole, he's the black dude.
He owns this restaurant in the city,
but he's into about everything else.
Last of the free traders.
At least that's what he thinks of himself.
So he picks up on this
really trippy old guy,
and old-time adventurer,
who's spent his life hunting and exploring
all around the world.
Sole hears about this precious
stone, some kind of gem.
- You mean Billy's been
kidnapped because of a stone?
- Not just any ordinary stone.
It's worth millions.
It's got a curse, magical properties.
- [Muriel] Oh, Davey, how
could you be so stupid?
- Stupid, I could be rolling in it.
All I needed was enough
to get out of town.
Wait a month or two till
Sole cools his heels,
then pick up the phone and talk turkey.
But he has it figured out all
along he's gonna get rid of me
the moment I hand over the stone.
- [Dianne] Well, that's just great.
(gentle music)
- Caine,
thanks.
We'll get some dinner.
Take a photo.
(camera clicks)
Shh.
That's a rabbit.
Come on, Caine.
(tense rhythmic music)
- I'm gonna go check out the map.
- I gotta take a pee.
- Hold on to it.
- [Ranger] Can I help you then?
- This, uh, walking trail near the river
looks like a good place to start.
- It's a great place,
just follow the arrows.
You can't miss it.
- [Sole] Oh.
- Um, there's a washing room inside,
if you wanna freshen up.
- No, I think we'll take a rain
check, thanks all the same.
- Suit yourselves.
(tense instrumental music)
- Yes!
The walking trail.
- The walking trail?
- Walking, it's gonna lead
us straight to the stone
and the good life, man.
- Did you feel that before?
- Feel what?
- Nothing.
- Conrad, man.
(tense rhythmic music)
(chuckling)
- I can smell it cooking, Caine.
He's not too far ahead.
Stay close. (chuckles)
(crying)
(knocking)
- [Muriel] Dianne.
- Yeah?
- We're losing precious minutes.
- I'm ready.
- We're going to find Billy.
- I know.
- He's not in the van.
You go out on the path and get this thing
and I'll stay here with the kid.
- I got a better idea.
- Sure.
- We stick together like always.
- Walking?
- Walking.
- Great.
- I've gotta take a pee.
- [Conrad And Sole] Hold on to it.
- Shh.
Shh.
(camera clicks)
(soft instrumental music)
Now I've lost him.
(tense instrumental music)
- Have you seen a boy and two men pass
this way?
- Dianne.
- Yes, as a matter of
fact, just awhile ago.
Anything wrong?
- No, my brother's up in the mountains.
He said he'd call me from here.
- What is the name?
- Cordeaux, Alex Cordeaux.
- Yes, they came through this morning.
They said they were gonna
follow the river down.
Anything urgent?
- No, no, it's just a family thing.
- Well, maybe I can help.
It's a long way up those trails,
and it's gonna be night soon.
- We'll, we'll find 'em.
- Your boy's gonna be okay.
(tense music)
- Dianne.
(tense rhythmic music)
(ducks quack)
(urine trickles)
- That'll do, kid.
- [Billy] Give me a break.
- That was a joke, kid.
- They can't be too much further.
- God, I hope not.
- Hey, kid,
your father ever take you up here campin'?
Hey, kid, I'm talkin' to you.
Your father ever teach you any manners?
- My father never had
time to teach my anything.
- Good, then you won't mind
if we have to shoot him then.
- It'll be up here soon.
(tense music)
Oh, there's dinner, Caine.
(camera clicks)
Give me the camera.
Ah, I was only joking.
Come on.
(tense instrumental music)
There he is, get down, Caine, down.
(gun bangs)
- Bingo.
- Walking?
- Walking.
(tense rhythmic music)
- They've gone.
- No shit, Muriel.
- We're never gonna find 'em.
- Oh, we'll find them.
- Alex and Caine are
probably dead right now.
Billy with them.
- They're alive, and we'll find them.
- It'll be dark soon.
- Just once in your life, Davey-Joe,
you are gonna follow through on something!
- (sighs) Dizzy female.
- He's right, this is useless.
- We are going to find them.
They're alive.
Let me hear it, Dianne, they're alive.
- They're alive.
(gentle instrumental music)
- Yeah, he tried to outfox us, Caine,
but we won the hop.
(camera clicks)
(gentle instrumental music)
Lucky we did, would've been baked beans.
(tense instrumental music)
(yawns)
After we have something to
eat, we might have a nap.
(tense instrumental music)
(birds squawk)
- I'd feel a lot safer
if I had the gun, Muriel!
- [Muriel] Oh, come on, Davey.
(tense rhythmic music)
- Ah, watch the hole, Conrad.
- Oh, thanks.
(tense rhythmic music)
(birds squawk)
(groans)
G'day.
Where's the stone?
- Billy, Billy, what are you doing here?
- We ask the questions.
(yells)
Where's the stone?
- What stone?
- Which one's the mute?
You, tell us?
- He doesn't speak.
- Oh, he's the mute.
Listen, man, we don't wanna hurt ya.
Your brother Davey took
somethin' that belonged to us.
He said the dummy here's got it.
Where is the stone?
- I'm telling you the truth, I. (groans)
- You know, I think the
whole family's in on it.
I think they're a bunch
of lyin', thievin',
I'm gonna kill this kid.
- No.
- Last chance, man, where's the stone?
One!
Two.
- No, don't hurt the kid, man.
- What?
(yells)
(camera clicks)
(dramatic instrumental music)
Come on, after 'em!
(dramatic rhythmic music)
Go on!
Come on, man.
- (coughs) I've got an incredibly
bad feeling about this.
- I'll give you a funny
feeling right up your,
come on, man.
If we don't get that
stone, I'll eat the fire.
Now, come on!
- You all right, Billy?
- I'm okay.
- Who are those guys?
- They came to the house.
- They what?
- Had Davey-Joe and Muriel were with them.
- Muriel?
- They held us down.
Somehow, Muriel got the
better of one of them.
She stabbed him.
They grabbed me and they came
out here looking for Caine.
- What about your mother?
- They didn't touch her.
- Thank God for that.
(thudding)
So whatever mess Davey, shh.
Now, what's wrong?
Ah, the badge.
- What badge?
- Oh, the ranger gave him a badge.
Look, don't worry about the badge.
We'll get you another one.
Now, come on, that way, quick.
Come on, Caine.
Caine, come on.
(birds squawk)
(tense music)
- Damn, we lost 'em!
- I really don't care.
- You don't care?
- Conrad,
you all right, man?
- I have a really,
really, really--
- Really bad feeling.
- That's it.
- Conrad, man,
get it together.
We've been through worse than this, man.
Remember?
- Oh, yeah.
- Remember?
- I remember.
(laughing)
(gentle mystical music)
- Hey, we can't stop now.
- I'm staying here.
- Great, I'm into it.
(gentle instrumental music)
(tense rhythmic music)
- [Billy] I didn't know
anyone lived up here.
- Neither did I.
You two stay here, and I'll check.
(tense music)
(insects chirp)
It's empty.
Well, stay here the night and
get our bearings fixed up.
Go down the mountain in the morning.
Come on.
Caine, come on.
(tense instrumental music)
- Sole,
you know how much I hate jails, don't ya?
- Yeah, man, I know.
- Well, if I ever get real bad,
you'll finish it,
won't ya?
- Yeah, man, I'll pop ya
off, don't worry about it.
- You promise me?
Finish it.
- Yeah, man, I told ya I'd do it.
(solemn music)
(chuckles)
- I've gonna have some sleep.
- Yeah, you go rest, man.
- Sure.
(solemn instrumental music)
(tense eerie music)
(birds chirp)
- Hey, I'm sorry about all this.
- Well, that doesn't help
the situation, does it?
- Well, I feel pretty stupid
tryin' to take on these guys.
- That's the story of
your life, Davey-Joe.
The next big deal,
the next get-rick-quick scheme.
(birds chirp)
- You're not gonna attempt
the housekeeping, are ya?
Mom would love this place.
- Clear a spot on the floor.
Caine,
come here, mate, come here.
You two, get some rest, in ya go.
I'll keep watch for a while.
- Dad, you need some sleep.
- I'll be okay.
- We could take turns.
- Not a bad idea.
I'll wake you up in a couple of hours.
- Deal.
(tense instrumental music)
- Sole.
- What, man?
- I got a really bad feeling about this.
- Conrad, go to sleep, man.
(insects chirp)
(clattering)
- Alex, Caine!
(tense eerie music)
- [Billy] Dad,
what happened to Caine?
- Hmm?
The way he is?
It's from an accident.
A long time ago now.
He was mooring out from the shore.
We should've known better,
there was signs all around
saying how dangerous the current was.
We swam,
and when we got to the mooring,
there were only four of us.
No sign of Caine.
He was on the bottom with
about six feet of water,
trapped in the kelp, weeds.
When we got him to the
surface, he was unconscious.
Well, they revived him,
but due to the lack of oxygen,
the brain, he suffered brain damage.
He never spoke another word from that day,
not a word.
(birds chirp)
- Hey, Conrad, come on.
Come on, man, let's get
on the case, come on.
Come on, we gotta go.
Hey, man, why'd you let
that bitch stab you?
- 'Cause I thought it was a
really great idea at the time.
- You're bent, you know
that, you're bent, man.
- Well, I've had a really
great teacher, haven't I?
- (chuckles) Come on,
we need that stone, man.
Come on.
(tense music)
- Caine?
Billy!
- I-I'll take over the watch now, Dad.
- It's morning, I fell asleep.
Where's Caine?
- Well, he was just over there.
- The badge.
Oh, he wouldn't be that stupid.
- That stupid, what do
you think he's done?
- The badge, you know how small
things take over his mind.
- You don't think he's
gone out looking for it?
- Well, it's the only explanation.
Why else would he walk off?
(tense music)
- Gone.
I'm ashamed to say he's my brother.
We've got to find Billy.
- Davey's got the gun.
I think we should go back to the ranger.
- Looks like our only option.
(tense instrumental music)
- [Billy] I can't see anyone.
- Doesn't mean to say
they're not out there.
- We can't just stay here.
What about Caine?
- Muriel!
Muriel!
Here!
- What are you doing up there?
- I went looking for Alex and Caine.
Somebody hit me on the head.
I woke up here.
- How'd you get up there?
- [Davey] I don't know.
- [Muriel] Well, come on down.
- I can't.
(tense music)
(leaves rustling)
(chuckling)
- Together again.
Where's the dummy?
- He's wandered off, we're searching.
- Come on, man, you can
do better than that.
- Dad.
- No, I.
(smacking)
- Where is he, Where is he?
Where is he?
- He's lost.
- Do him.
(tense music)
(groans)
- [Alex] Run, Billy!
(groaning)
- [Sole] I'm gonna go after them!
(tense music)
- Jesus!
- Damn!
Damn, damn, damn!
(tense music)
- Dad, who is it?
- I don't know, but they're a good shot?
(tense music)
(roaring)
(rumbling)
(tense music)
(birds squawk)
- What the hell's goin' on?
(tense music)
You all right?
- I don't think so.
- Stay here, man, I'm
gonna check this out.
- Sure, I'm not,
I'm definitely not going anywhere.
(tense music)
(thudding)
(tense mystical music)
- I know what they got planned,
but it ain't gonna work.
(tense mystical music)
Yo, Conrad!
Up here, I got the dummy!
- I can't!
I just can't.
(tense mystical music)
- It's useless.
Where's the bag?
(tense mystical music)
The bag you left home with.
Where is it?
(tense mystical music)
Come on.
(swooshing)
(tense mystical music)
Come on, man, get up!
- Sure.
- I want you on your feet!
- Fantasy.
Pure fantasy.
(chuckles)
(coughs)
(tense music)
(gun bangs)
- Billy!
(tense mystical music)
(fire crackles)
- [Davey] I'll drive ya
to the ranger's station.
You can call the cops from there.
I'll take my own chances.
You can forget you ever had a brother.
- It's a bit late for that now.
- Just get to the ranger's station.
- I wonder how I got up that tree.
(slow mystical music)
- Come on!
What's the matter?
It's around here, isn't it?
Where's the stone?
(tense music)
Where is it?
(tense mystical music)
(rumbling)
Come on!
Where, where is it?
(soft tinkling)
Good boy.
(soft mystical music)
- [Davey] What the hell is goin on, Mure?
This is the place, isn't it?
(tense music)
(rumbling)
(chuckling)
- Kid, I love ya!
(chuckles)
(rumbling)
(swooshing)
(chuckling)
(dramatic music)
- What's happening?
(gun bangs)
(tense music)
(yells)
- It's okay.
- Dianne?
(tense mystical music)
Dianne!
(rumbling)
(tense mystical music)
(yells)
(swooshing)
(soft mystical music)
(birds chirp)
- What happened here?
(bird squawks)
(engine rumbles)
- You all right?
- Where's Dianne?
- Caine, you all right?
- Oh, she's in the cabin, or the ranger's,
or whatever the hell you call it.
I don't know what's going on.
She won't come out.
- You're in the shit.
- Thought I might be.
- They didn't hurt you, did they?
- No, except they wouldn't
let me wee for three hours.
(chuckles)
- Caine.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
Do you remember when we
used to come camping here?
This was just an old ranger station,
hadn't been used for years.
Yesterday, when I.
- I made a phone call from here yesterday.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, the phone was,
the phone was over there.
You know, something happened to Caine
up on that mountain, too.
- Caine, what?
- I don't know, something
strange, I don't know what.
(camera clicks)
(easygoing rhythmic music)
(rumbling)
(tense mystical music)
- [Reporter] Alerted the
police when they noticed blood
on the passenger seat.
The police searched the area
and subsequently arrested a man
in connection with the mystery.
Davey-Joe Cordeaux told
police he last saw Sole
en route to Sher Mountain Park
and knows nothing about the incident.
Charges against Cordeaux
are expected to be laid
following an inquiry into the matter.
In further news.
- The magic word you will dream
for the rest of your life.
- [Cartoon] But we don't
have the magic word.
- [Cartoon] Then go find it.
- [Cartoon] But how?
- [Cartoon] You'll take a
magic boat and search for it.
- Where?
- [Cartoon] In the ocean.
- [Cartoon] In the ocean, why?
- [Cartoon] Because it's such a big place,
we're bound to find it there.
(insects chirp)
(easygoing jazzy music)
(camera clicks)
(easygoing rhythmic music)
(easygoing jazzy music)
♫ There's not one single
person in this world
♫ Searching for that out-stretched hand
♫ We are all wandering islands
♫ Looking for a better land
♫ And as we travel down the road of time
♫ We're doing fine
♫ It's the same old story
♫ Born with eyes, but still we're blind
♫ Easy
♫ Sounds so easy
♫ Simple
♫ Oh so simple
♫ Easy
♫ Sounds so easy
(MultiCom Jingle)