HEY, MISS.
ER, UH, MISS.
I THINK YOU CAN SEE BETTER
FROM WAY UP HERE.
CAN Y'ALL HEAR ME?
WE CAN SEE ALL RIGHT
FROM A-WAY DOWN HERE.
HA HA HA!
HA HA! DOESN'T
SEEM LIKE IT.
YOU BETTER
COME ON UP.
DON'T PAY ANY
ATTENTION TO HIM.
HE'S JUST PRETENDING
HE DOESN'T REMEMBER ME.
OH, I REMEMBER YOU,
ALL RIGHT.
HE DOES, HUH? BETTER COME ON UP, HUH?
THANKS.
COME ON, TED, UNBEND AND
HELP THE LITTLE LADY UP.
OOH!
CAREFUL, NOW.
WAIT, NOW!
OOP!
OH, THANKS.
AHH.
THERE YOU ARE.
YOU KNOW, TED'S HAD A GRUDGE AGAINST ME
EVER SINCE THE DAY I SHOVED HIM
INTO THE SEVERN RIVER YEARS AGO.
SEVERN?
MM-HMM.
DID YOU LIVE
IN ANNAPOLIS?
WELL, I WAS THERE
WITH MY DAD.
WHEREVER HE WAS STATIONED,
I WAS STUCK THERE, TOO.
THEN YOU'RE NAVY.
NO, BUT MY DAD IS, AND
HIS FATHER BEFORE HIM,
HIS FATHER BEFORE HIM...
I GET IT. NAVY,
RIGHT DOWN THE LINE.
AH, BUT THE LINE SANK
WHEN IT CAME TO ME.
NO NAVY FOR MINE.
WELL, AS, UH... AS LONG AS
TED DOESN'T SEEM TO BELIEVE
IN THE FORMALITIES
OF INTRODUCTION,
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
I BEGS TO REPORT,
MA'AM,
THAT MY NAME IS
RICHARD MELVILLE III...
OR THE SECOND
OR THE FOURTH.
HAVEN'T FIGURED
IT OUT YET.
ARE YOU ADMIRAL
MELVILLE'S SON?
YOU GOT ME.
YOU DON'T LOOK
LIKE A MELVILLE.
HA HA HA!
WHY NOT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I SUPPOSE IT'S BECAUSE
I JUST COULDN'T PICTURE
A MELVILLE WITHOUT
A UNIFORM.
WHOA, THERE.
YOU SOUND LIKE MY DAD
WHEN HE OPENS UP HIS
FAMILY BROADSIDES ON ME.
I HEAR THAT SO OFTEN.
THERE'S HIS FLAGSHIP
OUT THERE NOW.
WANT TO TAKE A GANDER? A PEEP?
DO YOU GET A KICK OUT OF
THOSE CAST-IRON BATHTUBS?
ARE YOU A NAVY GIRL?
I WAS A NAVY GIRL.
MY FATHER WAS
CAPTAIN BLACKBURN.
HE WENT DOWN WITH HIS SHIP IN THE WAR.
OH, I'M SORRY.
MY BROTHER JIM WAS A LIEUTENANT
- NAVAL AIR SERVICE.
YES.
NO WONDER YOU THINK I
SHOULD BE WEARING A UNIFORM.
NO, I DON'T.
THE NAVY TOOK MY FATHER
AND MY BROTHER,
AND MOTHER DIED
BECAUSE SHE THOUGHT
SHE SHOULD BE WITH DAD
ON THE CHINA STATION.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH NAVY
IN MY FAMILY.
WELL, HERE WE ARE
- TWO AGAINST THE NAVY.
MAYBE JUNE'S GOT SOME
REASON FOR WHAT SHE SAYS,
BUT WHAT RIGHT HAVE YOU
GOT TO POOH-POOH THE NAVY?
I SUPPOSE YOU'RE
A SUCKER FOR A UNIFORM
JUST BECAUSE
YOUR DAD WEARS ONE.
I'M NOT GOING TO TRADE
MY CHANCE TO WEAR ONE
FOR THE PRIVILEGE
OF BEING A CROONER.
NOW, NOW, NOW.
HEH HEH HEH!
YOU KNOW I'M VERY SENSITIVE ABOUT THAT.
I LIKE YOUR MUSIC.
DON'T MIND TED.
YOU TWO FIGHT LIKE BROTHER AND
SISTER, OR LIKE YOU WERE MARRIED.
TED'S MY COUSIN. HIS
FATHER SORT OF ADOPTED ME.
OH. WELL, AT LEAST I'M
GLAD YOU'RE NOT MARRIED...
TO HIM.
WE DON'T MARRY FIRST
COUSINS WHERE I COME FROM.
BESIDES,
TED'S GOING NAVY-
GOING TO TRY FOR THE ACADEMY THIS YEAR.
I'D NEVER MARRY
A NAVY MAN.
THAT'S THE BEST NEWS
I'VE HEARD TODAY.
DOES THAT MAKE ME
ELIGIBLE?
DO YOU WANT TO BE?
YOU AND TED COME DOWN
TO THE SKY CLUB TONIGHT,
AND I'LL SWEAR OUT
AN AFFIDAVIT.
IF YOU THINK I'D PAY
A $5.00 COVER CHARGE
TO HEAR YOU SING,
YOU'RE CRAZY.
JUST PUT A LITTLE COTTON
IN YOUR EARS, TED.
BRING LITTLE JUNE ALONG, AND I'LL
TREAT YOU TO THE COVER CHARGE.
I'LL TREAT YOU
TO A...
OH, GO TAKE A HOP,
SKIP, AND A JUMP.
YOU KNOW, IF FAMILY
INFLUENCE MEANS ANYTHING,
YOU'RE GOING TO
LIKE ME A LOT.
I THINK I'LL TAKE
ANOTHER GANDER.
MY NAME IS RICHARD MELVILLE.
THE ADMIRAL EXPECTS ME.
OH, YES.
THE ADMIRAL IS ON DECK.
WELL...
HELLO, SON.
HELLO, DAD. NICE FLEET
YOU BROUGHT HOME WITH YOU.
YOU EVIDENTLY GOT MY TELEGRAM,
OR YOU WOULDN'T BE HERE.
UH-HUH. WELL, HAVE
YOU COME TO A DECISION?
YOU EXPECT ME
TO CHANGE MY MIND?
I SINCERELY HOPE SO.
WELL, I HAVEN'T HAD
ANY REASON TO CHANGE IT.
COME HERE, SON.
DICK, DOESN'T THE SIGHT OF THE
FLEET TODAY BRING ANY RESPONSE,
ANY DESIRE TO SERVE
IN IT?
NOPE, DAD. GUESS I'VE
SEEN TOO MANY NEWSREELS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE SOUND
OF THOSE ANCHOR CHAINS
RATTLING DOWN A FEW
MINUTES AGO MEANT TO ME?
IT MEANS THE END
OF MY LAST SEA DUTY.
TOMORROW MORNING, I'M TO
BE RELIEVED OF COMMAND.
YOU STILL HAVE 4 MORE
YEARS BEFORE YOU'RE RETIRED.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE SUPERINTENDENT
OF THE NAVAL ACADEMY.
YES.
SEEMS LIKE A GREAT HONOR-
GOING BACK TO THE ACADEMY
AND BEING HEAD OF THE SAME SCHOOL
THAT YOU ENTERED AS A PLEBE.
IT'S GOING TO BE
A VERY EMPTY HONOR
UNLESS YOU CHANGE
YOUR MIND.
IT WOULD BE A GREAT
HONOR... IF I COULD KNOW
THAT YOU WERE GOING TO WALK THROUGH
THOSE GATES TO BECOME A MIDSHIPMAN
THE SAME AS I DID AND
MY FATHER BEFORE ME...
THAT YOU'D BE
THE NEXT MELVILLE
TO WRITE A NEW CHAPTER
IN NAVAL RECORDS.
OH, I KNOW, BUT THAT'S JUST
WHY I DON'T WANT IT, DAD.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
JUST ANOTHER MELVILLE.
IF I WOUND UP ANYTHING SHORT OF BEING
AN ADMIRAL, I'D BE A BLACK SHEEP.
YOU KNOW, SON, I THINK I
COULD UNDERSTAND YOU BETTER
IF YOU'D CHOSEN TO BE, SAY,
AN ENGINEER OR A DOCTOR...
SOMETHING TO SUSTAIN
THE IDEA OF SERVICE.
OH, WELL, I...
I'M SERVICING.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
PEOPLE GOT TO BE ENTERTAINED.
YOU KNOW THAT I ALREADY MAKE 3
TIMES AS MUCH MONEY AS YOU DO A YEAR?
THAT'S NOT BAD
FOR A YOUNGSTER.
TOOK YOU 40 YEARS TO GET TO
THE TOP OF YOUR PROFESSION, DAD.
IT'S ONLY TAKEN ME
TWO YEARS.
MY FOREBEARS HAVE ALWAYS
SERVED COUNTRY AND FLAG...
NOT DOLLARS.
OH, DAD. YOU'RE
A SENTIMENTALIST.
TODAY, EVERYTHING BOILS
DOWN TO DOLLARS AND CENTS,
NOT THE STAR-SPANGLED
BANNER.
I SEE.
OH, I DON'T MEAN THAT
REALLY, THOUGH.
I MEAN THAT I'VE JUST HEARD
"NAVY, NAVY, NAVY, NAVY"
EVER SINCE I'VE BEEN OLD ENOUGH
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT IT MEANT.
I WANT TO STAND
ON MY OWN.
I'VE GOT A DIFFERENT
KIND OF A JOB.
THERE IS SOMETHING I
WOULD LIKE YOU TO DO, SON,
IF IT ISN'T
TOO MUCH NAVY.
I'D LIKE YOU TO BE
ABOARD TOMORROW MORNING
WHEN I SAY GOOD-BYE
TO MY LAST SEA DUTY...
WHEN I TURN OVER
MY LAST COMMAND.
SURE, DAD. I'VE GOT A COUPLE
FRIENDS WHO'D LIKE TO SEE THE SHOW.
CAN I BRING THEM
ON BOARD?
WELL, THIS ISN'T EXACTLY
GOING TO BE A SHOW, DICK.
I'D, UH, PREFER
THAT YOU CAME ALONE.
OK, DAD.
WHAT TIME WILL IT BE?
4 BELLS.
4 BELLS?
4 BELLS IN THE NAVY...
THAT'S, UH, 10:00 IN
THE MORNING TO ME, HUH?
YES, YES.
OK, DAD.
I'LL BE HERE.
GOOD-BYE.
Melville, on radio: GOOD EVENING,
EVERYBODY. THIS IS DICK MELVILLE SPEAKING.
TONIGHT IS "WELCOME NAVY NIGHT"
HERE AT THE SKY CLUB.
I'VE WRITTEN A NEW SONG THAT
I WANT TO DEDICATE TO THE NAVY
AND TO ADMIRAL RICHARD MELVILLE,
THE BOSS OF THE FLEET-
DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP.
* SHIPMATES, STAND TOGETHER
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
* FAIR OR STORMY WEATHER
* WE WON'T GIVE UP,
WE WON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP *
* FRIENDS AND PALS FOREVER
* IT'S A LONG, LONG TRIP
* IF YOU HAVE TO
TAKE A LICKIN' *
* CARRY ON AND QUIT
YOUR KICKIN' *
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
TABLE FOR TWO, PLEASE.
SORRY, SIR. EVERY TABLE IS
TAKEN. HAVE YOU RESERVATIONS?
NO, WE HAVEN'T, AND I'M
GLAD EVERY TABLE IS TAKEN,
AND I HOPE YOU HAVE A VERY
PLEASANT EVENING. COME ON, JUNE.
BUT MR. MELVILLE
WAS EXPECTING US.
OH, ARE YOU MISS BLACKBURN AND ESCORT?
YES.
ACCEPT MY APOLOGIES.
THIS WAY, PLEASE.
* SHIPMATES, STAND TOGETHER
* DON'T GIVE UP...
"MISS BLACKBURN AND EXCESS
BAGGAGE," HE SHOULD HAVE SAID.
WHY DIDN'T DICK LEAVE
THE TABLE IN MY NAME?
MAYBE HE LIKES ME
BETTER THAN YOU.
WELL, I HOPE SO.
* FRIENDS AND PALS FOREVER
* IT'S A LONG, LONG TRIP
* IF YOU HAVE TO
TAKE A LICKIN' *
* CARRY ON
AND QUIT YOUR KICKIN' *
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
HE OUGHT TO BE MARCHING
BEHIND THAT DITTY
INSTEAD OF YELPING IT
OVER A MICROPHONE.
SHH!
GOOD EVENING,
MISS BLACKBURN.
AND A SOUR EVENING TO YOU, MR. STERLING.
AFTER HEARING YOU SING,
IT REALLY IS SOUR.
MAY I?
NOT IF YOU'RE
A MIND READER.
DEPENDS ON WHOSE
MIND HE'S READING.
THANK YOU. NO SOONER SAID THAN SAT.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T HAVE TO SING
ANOTHER SONG FOR ABOUT 10 MINUTES.
I WISH IT WERE
10 YEARS.
OH, YOU'RE A PIKER.
WHAT'S 10 YEARS?
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD OF THE
ASTRONOMICAL TERM "LIGHT YEARS"?
MILLIONS OF YEARS,
BILLIONS OF YEARS?
WHY, DO YOU KNOW
THAT-
WHY, DO YOU KNOW I'M NOT THE
LEAST BIT INTERESTED IN ASTRONOMY?
ARE YOU?
OH, INTENSELY.
THEN I SHALL TAKE THIS RARE
OPPORTUNITY AND SHOW YOU
AN ASTRONOMICAL PHENOMENA WHICH
YOU REALLY CAN'T AFFORD TO MISS.
WILL YOU EXCUSE US, PLEASE? NO.
OH, THAT'S VERY SWEET
OF YOU, TED. THANKS.
AND NOW FOR THAT RARE
ASTRONOMICAL PHENOMENA
WHICH YOU CAN'T
AFFORD TO MISS...
OR MYSELF, EITHER,
FOR THAT MATTER.
LET'S, UH...
LET ME SEE.
LET'S CONSIDER THE STAR "R," PLANET "Q."
IT, UH-I THINK YOU CAN
SEE BETTER FROM OVER HERE.
WE CAN SPECIFY
ITS POSITION
BY GIVING ITS ZENITH DISTANCE, ZQ...
AND THE AZIMUTH FROM THE SOUTH POINT
- THAT'S ANGLE QZS.
OR BY GIVING THE NORTH
POLE A DISTANCE-PQ-
AND THE ANGLE QPZ,
WHICH, OF COURSE YOU KNOW,
IS CALLED THE "R" ANGLE.
YOU KNOW MORE ABOUT ASTRONOMY THAN I DO.
MAYBE.
THEN WHY DID YOU COME OUT HERE WITH ME?
BECAUSE YOU
WANTED ME TO.
I WISH I KNEW SOMETHING
ABOUT THE LAWS OF GRAVITY.
WHY?
THEN I'D KNOW WHY
I'VE FALLEN FOR YOU
FASTER THAN
A TON OF BRICKS.
CAN I SEE YOU
TOMORROW...
AND EVERY TOMORROW
FROM THEN ON?
YOU'D HAVE TO FALL ALL THE
WAY TO ANNAPOLIS TO DO THAT.
OH, WHY MUST YOU GO
BACK TO ANNAPOLIS?
I LIVE THERE
AND I WORK THERE,
TEACHING 8-YEAR-OLD
NAVY JUNIORS
HOW TO PUT THEIR HEELS
IN FRONT OF THEIR TOES.
AH, NEW YORK CAN'T KEEP ME
HERE, WITH YOU DOWN IN CRAB TOWN.
YOU MEANT WHAT YOU SAID
ABOUT NOT MARRYING NAVY?
UH-HUH.
THEN, BY THE GRACE OF THE
STARS AND LAWS OF GRAVITY,
I'M GOING TO MAKE YOU
WANT TO MARRY ME.
I WISH I KNEW SOMETHING
ABOUT THE LAWS OF GRAVITY.
WHY?
THEN I'D KNOW WHY I'VE
FALLEN FOR YOU FASTER...
OH, MY.
GOOD OLD ZENITH.
HA HA! OH, POOR OLD TED'S
ALONE. COME ON.
ALL RIGHT.
SORRY, TED.
I'VE BEEN WORKING ON A DREAM
PORTRAIT OF YOU, MR. MELVILLE.
Melville: WELL... IT
HARDLY DOES ME JUSTICE.
Ted: OH, I THINK SO.
A LITTLE MORE PRACTICE,
YOU OUGHT TO BE ABLE
TO DRAW FOR
THE FUNNY PAPERS.
I'VE GOT TO GO TO WORK,
DARLING. SEE YOU LATER.
THAT'S VERY PRETTY,
TED. WHAT IS IT?
WHY, IT'S A...
* WHEN SOMEONE TELLS
ME TO MARCH *
* OR TO HALT
* MY SOUL REBELS
* I'M THAT WAY
TO A FAULT *
* NO RULES OR REGULATIONS
* WOULD I OBEY
* THEN I MET YOU,
AND I KNEW RIGHT AWAY *
* IF YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN
* I'LL BE THE CREW
* 'CAUSE I'D JUST LOVE
TO TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
* YOU BLOW THE BUGLE
* AND I'LL JUMP THROUGH
* OH, HOW I'D LOVE TO
* TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU
* I KNOW THAT RULES
WERE MEANT FOR FOOLS *
* THAT'S ONE THING
I HAVE LEARNED *
* BUT I'M GOING IN
FOR DISCIPLINE *
* WHEREVER YOU'RE CONCERNED
* IF YOU SAY, "KISS ME,"
* THAT'S WHAT I'LL DO
* 'CAUSE I'D JUST LOVE TO
* TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU
CONVERSE!
YES, SIR.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
10 OF 10:00, SIR.
10 OF 10:00. I'VE ONLY GOT 10
MINUTES TO GET TO THE FLAGSHIP.
GET MY CLOTHES DOWN TO THE CAR. CALL
THE DRIVER. TELL HIM TO HURRY UP.
WHAT CLOTHES, SIR?
ANYTHING! ANYTHING! I HAVEN'T
GOT TIME TO DRESS HERE.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
TELL HIM TO MEET US
DOWN IN FRONT.
COME ON! COME ON!
OK, ORIN!
MY DAD WILL NEVER
GET OVER THIS.
WHEW! WHY DIDN'T I
GET TO BED EARLIER?
STEP ON IT,
WILL YOU, ORIN?!
AM I TOO LATE
FOR THE CEREMONY?
NO. THE ADMIRAL
IS STILL BELOW.
THANK YOU, SIR.
HELLO, DAD.
I'M LATE.
SO I SEE.
HELLO, DICK.
HOW ARE YOU, SIR?
TO THE OFFICERS AND MEN
OF THE UNITED STATES FLEET,
AND TO THE PERSONNEL OF
THIS SHIP IN PARTICULAR,
IT IS WITH GREAT REGRET
THAT I TURN OVER MY COMMAND.
BEFORE DOING SO, I WANT
TO EXPRESS MY APPRECIATION
FOR THE COOPERATION AND LOYALTY
THAT I HAVE RECEIVED FROM ALL HANDS
DURING THE LONG PERIOD
OF MY COMMAND.
AND IT IS A MATTER OF
GENUINE SATISFACTION TO ME
THAT MY SUCCESSOR,
YOUR FUTURE COMMANDER IN CHIEF,
IS MY LIFELONG FRIEND
AND CLASSMATE,
ADMIRAL GRAVES.
AND MY PARTING WORD
TO ALL HANDS IS, "KEEP
THIS FLEET FIT TO FIGHT."
I WILL NOW READ
MY ORDERS.
"NAVY DEPARTMENT,
WASHINGTON.
"FROM SECRETARY OF THE NAVY
TO ADMIRAL RICHARD MELVILLE,
"COMMANDER IN CHIEF,
UNITED STATES FLEET.
CHANGE OF DUTY.
"BEEN RELIEVED OF DUTY
ON OR ABOUT 29th OF MAY.
"YOU WILL REGARD YOURSELF
AS DETACHED FROM DUTY
"AS COMMANDER IN CHIEF
OF THE UNITED STATES FLEET
"AND PROCEED TO ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND,
WHERE YOU WILL REPORT FOR DUTY
"AS SUPERINTENDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES NAVAL ACADEMY.
"THIS IS A PERMANENT SHORE DUTY,
REQUIRED FOR THE PUBLIC'S INTEREST.
SIGNED,
SECRETARY OF THE NAVY."
CAPTAIN, HAUL DOWN
MY FLAG, SIR.
AYE, AYE.
OH, HELLO, SON.
YOU'LL HAVE TO EXCUSE ME A MINUTE
WHILE I GET INTO CIVILIAN CLOTHES.
I'M FLYING TO WASHINGTON.
OK, DAD.
THANK YOU, DICK.
YOU'LL BE STANDING
IN YOUR FATHER'S SHOES UP THERE SOMEDAY.
AND AFTER 40 YEARS
OF SERVICE,
ALL I'D HAVE TO SHOW
FOR IT IS ONE OF THESE?
NO, I'M AFRAID NOT.
NO, FRED. DICK'S NOT GOING
TO TRY FOR THE ACADEMY.
HE'S EVIDENTLY FOUND OUT
THERE'S A LITTLE SOMETHING
MORE TO IT THAN JUST GOING DOWN
THERE AND KNOCKING AT THE GATE.
IT'S STILL A PRETTY
TOUGH PLACE TO GET INTO.
HE REALIZES THAT BEING A MELVILLE
DOESN'T MAKE A BIT OF DIFFERENCE.
LOOKS TO ME LIKE
A CASE OF COLD FEET.
HE KNOWS HE COULDN'T EVEN
PASS THE ENTRANCE EXAMINATION.
WHY, DICK, I DIDN'T THINK YOU
WOULD SHY AT THOSE EXAMINATIONS.
ALWAYS UNDERSTOOD
YOU WERE PRETTY SAVVY
IN YOUR STUDIES
AT COLLEGE.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
I AM, DAD? A NINCOMPOOP?
HA HA! WHAT DO
YOU MEAN, SON?
TELLING ADMIRAL GRAVES I HAD COLD FEET
AND COULDN'T PASS THOSE EXAMINATIONS.
WELL, THAT'S
THE TRUTH, ISN'T IT?
OH, I SEE.
YOU THINK ALL THOSE
MIDSHIPMEN DOWN THERE
ARE SMARTER THAN
YOUR OWN SON.
SINCE YOU WANT TO PUT IT
THAT WAY...
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I THINK.
I'VE GIVEN THIS THING A
LOT OF CONSIDERATION, DICK,
AND MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT IN
THIS SINGING CAREER OF YOURS,
SINCE YOU COULDN'T BEAR
THE DISGRACE OF FAILING
IN THE ENTRANCE
EXAMINATION.
DISGRACE? FAILURE?
I COULD PASS THOSE
EXAMINATIONS WITH MY EYES SHUT.
YOU THINK SO?
I KNOW SO.
HA HA HA!
I DOUBT THAT.
I'LL SHOW YOU THAT
YOUR SON IS NO NITWIT.
I'LL PROVE TO YOU
THAT I'M SMART ENOUGH
TO GET INTO THE NAVY
IF I WANT TO.
I'LL PASS THOSE EXAMINATIONS, BUT I
DON'T HAVE TO ACCEPT THE APPOINTMENT.
WELL, FRED...
A WORLD OF LUCK
TO YOU.
THANK YOU, DICK.
GOOD-BYE.
TIME'S UP, BOYS.
TURN YOUR PAPERS IN.
PRINCIPALS AND ALTERNATES WILL RECEIVE
WORD OF APPOINTMENT OR FAILURE BY MAIL
FROM THE NAVY
DEPARTMENT.
GOOD LUCK.
TRY THIS ON YOUR
RADIO, SPARKS.
I'VE PASSED!
Sparks: HA HA!
HEY, SPARKS!
YOU GOT CHINA!
YOU CAN KEEP CHINA!
YOU CAN KEEP THE RADIO!
I'M GOING TO
THE NAVAL ACADEMY! HEY!
HEY! LOOK HERE, Y'ALL!
I GOT IT! HEY, LOOK!
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
MY APPOINTMENT! I'M
GOING TO THE NAVAL ACADEMY
TO LEARN HOW TO GIVE
YOU MUGS ORDERS!
HEY,
WE'LL TAKE ORDERS!
All: YEAH!
ALL I COULD READ WAS
"NAVY DEPARTMENT."
WHAT DOES IT SAY, SON?
IT JUST SAYS
I PASSED, MA.
HA HA. I PASSED!
DICK, HERE'S THAT LETTER
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT
FROM THE NAVY
DEPARTMENT.
YOUR CHAUFFEUR
JUST BROUGHT IT OVER.
THANKS, HARRY.
WELL, I PASSED-
PASSED MY EXAMINATIONS
FOR THE NAVAL ACADEMY.
HA HA HA! WHAT A JOKE THIS
IS GOING TO BE ON YOUR FATHER
WHEN HE FINDS OUT YOU'RE
GOING TO TURN IT DOWN.
OH, BUT THE JOKE'S
ON ME, HARRY.
I CAN'T TURN THE OLD
ADMIRAL DOWN.
YOU MEAN,
YOU'RE GOING TO...
THAT'S WHAT I MEAN.
Melville, on radio:
GOOD EVENING, EVERYBODY.
THIS IS DICK MELVILLE SPEAKING
TO YOU FROM THE SKY CLUB
IN GOOD OLD NEW YORK CITY.
TOM, TURN OFF
THAT RADIO.
TOM!
Melville: THIS IS
GOOD-BYE TO RADIO, FOR ME,
BECAUSE I'VE PASSED MY ENTRANCE
EXAMINATION TO ANNAPOLIS,
AND I'M GOING NAVY!
Tom: DID YOU CALL,
ADMIRAL, SIR?
YES! YES, TOM, YOU POUR ME
A GLASS OF THAT OLDEST PORT.
Melville:
*... THE SHIP
* FAIR OR STORMY WEATHER
* WE WON'T GIVE UP,
WE WON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP *
* FRIENDS AND PALS FOREVER
* IT'S A LONG, LONG TRIP
* IF YOU HAVE
TO TAKE A LICKIN' *
* CARRY ON AND
QUIT YOUR KICKIN' *
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
NO SMOKING, SIR.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I FORGOT.
THANK YOU.
WHOA, YOU DUDE!
ARE YOU ENTERING HERE?
WELL, WHAT DOES
IT LOOK LIKE?
FROM WHAT I HEAR TELL OF
THE ACADEMY, MY FRIEND,
YOU'RE GOING TO LIVE
TO REGRET THAT ENTRANCE.
DID YOU PAY THOSE GUYS TO DO THAT?
YOU BOYS KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE GOING?
NO, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, FOLLOW ME. I'LL SHOW YOU.
SAY, "AH."
AHHH.
HEE HEE.
WHOA!
MERCY, DOC!
Doctor:
TURN YOUR HEAD.
NOW COUGH.
THE OTHER SIDE.
COUGH AGAIN.
WHOA!
DID YOU EVER THINK OF
TOTING THEM UP ONE AT A TIME?
CAN YOU DO THAT?
SURE. WHY NOT?
I'M DOING IT.
NOTHING IN THE REGULATIONS AGAINST IT.
THAT'S FUNNY.
IT THOUGHT IT WAS A GAME OR SOMETHING...
TESTING
THE MANHOOD IN YOU.
OH, NO.
THAT COMES LATER.
WELL, ROOMMATES,
IN CASE YOU DIDN'T CATCH
IT, THE NAME'S BROWN.
THEY CHRISTENED ME
LAFAYETTE,
ON ACCOUNT OF THAT'S WHAT PERSHING
SAID THE MORNING I ARRIVED.
YOU KNOW, "LAFAYETTE,
HERE WE ARE."
ONLY IT WAS ME, SPARKS, IN
ARKANSAS, AND PERSHING WAS IN FRANCE.
I CAME IN FROM
THE FLEET, FELLAS-
JOHNNY LAWRENCE,
FROM THE TEXAS.
UH, THEY CALL ME
COXSWAIN.
MY NAME'S LINCOLN-
ARIZONA.
CALL ME COWBOY.
DICK MELVILLE,
NEW YORK.
Sparks: BOY, YOU DON'T
NEED TO TELL US WHO YOU ARE.
WE GOT A LOAD OF YOU
WHEN YOU WALKED IN.
Cowboy: I'LL SAY.
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT,
FELLAS?
HAVE YOU GOT
A LITTLE ICE WATER?
I- HA HA HA.
YOUR PLEBE SUMMER WILL
BE A BREEZE, MISTERS,
COMPARED TO WHAT YOU'LL GET WHEN THE
FIRST CLASS COMES BACK FROM THE CRUISE.
WE CAN TAKE IT,
SIR.
WE'LL SEE.
IN THE MEANTIME,
BEAR A HAND.
GET YOUR MARKING DONE,
YOUR LOCKERS STOWED.
WHEN ASSEMBLY SOUNDS, FALL
IN BELOW TO BE SWORN IN.
I'LL MEET YOU THERE.
AND DON'T FORGET...
THE FIRST CLASS CRUISE
GETS BACK IN SEPTEMBER.
AND THAT GOES FOR YOU,
MR. MELVILLE.
HE JUST SAID THAT
TO SCARE YOU.
WHAT DOES HE MEAN,
"GET YOUR MARKING DONE"?
GET OUT YOUR INDELIBLE INK AND
YOU MARK AN OUTFIT. I'LL SHOW YOU.
ASSEMBLY! LET'S GO!
Melville:
LIKE WE ARE?
BOYS, WHEN THAT
BUGLE BLOWS,
YOU GO
HOWEVER YOU ARE!
Man: RAISE YOUR RIGHT HANDS,
GENTLEMEN, AND REPEAT AFTER ME.
I, HAVING BEEN APPOINTED A MIDSHIPMAN
IN THE UNITED STATES NAVY...
All: I, HAVING BEEN APPOINTED A
MIDSHIPMAN IN THE UNITED STATES NAVY...
DO SOLEMNLY SWEAR...
THAT I WILL SUPPORT AND DEFEND THE
CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED STATES...
AGAINST ALL ENEMIES,
FOREIGN AND DOMESTIC...
AND I WILL BEAR TRUE FAITH
AND ALLEGIANCE TO THE SAME.
AND I TAKE THIS OBLIGATION FREELY...
WITHOUT ANY METTLE RESERVATION
OR PURPOSE OF EVASION...
THAT I WILL WELL AND
FAITHFULLY DISCHARGE THE DUTIES
OF THE OFFICE ON WHICH
I AM ABOUT TO ENTER...
THAT I WILL WELL AND
FAITHFULLY DISCHARGE THE DUTIES
OF THE OFFICE UPON WHICH
I AM ABOUT TO ENTER...
SO HELP ME, GOD.
HANDS DOWN, GENTLEMEN.
YOU'RE NOW MIDSHIPMEN IN THE
UNITED STATES NAVY. CONGRATULATIONS.
FOR THE BENEFIT
OF MY ROOMMATES,
I WILL NOW READ FROM THE REGULATIONS
OF THE U.S. NAVAL ACADEMY'S
THE STOWAGE OF LOCKERS.
DO YOU FOLLOW ME?
ONE FOR EACH OCCUPANT.
"4 INCHES FROM WALL
OR CASINGS.
"CONTENTS NEATLY ARRANGED
AS FOLLOWS:
TOWELS, SHEETS, PILLOW CASES,
"SPREADS, CLOTHES, BAGS,
AND SPLASHES, SO ARRANGED
"THAT SMOOTH FOLDS,
AND NOT ROUGH EDGES, SHOW.
BOTTLES,
"WRITING MATERIALS, LETTERS,
PAPERS, BRUSHES, SOAP BOXES,
SMALL ARTICLES,
SEWING KIT."
SEWING KIT?
YOU MEAN, WE HAVE TO DO OUR
OWN SEWING IN THIS PLACE?
Coxswain: I DON'T KNOW WHAT
ELSE YOU DO WITH A SEWING KIT
BESIDES SEW WITH IT.
I'LL DO ALL YOUR DARNING
FOR A DIME A SOCK.
I WAS THE BEST LITTLE
DARNER ON MY BATTLESHIP.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW THEY EXPECT US
TO GET ALL THIS JUNK
IN HERE, ANYWAY.
JUST LISTEN
TO PAPA, CROONER.
HE'S READING YOU
HOW TO DO IT.
HEY, YOU-YOU. DON'T CALL
ME CROONER. GET ME?
OK. OK. OK.
CAN I HELP YOU
WITH YOUR LOCKER, DICK?
MINE IS ALMOST DONE.
NO, THANKS, COXSWAIN.
I CAN STOW MY OWN.
Cowboy: I COULD USE
A LITTLE HELP, COXSWAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
SAY! ARE YOU REALLY THAT
SINGING FELLA FROM NEW YORK CITY?
I THOUGHT SO.
I NEVER CARED MUCH
FOR YOUR SINGING MYSELF,
BUT I ALWAYS SAYS, "EVERY
FELLA TO HIS OWN OPINION."
I'M NOT ASKING ANYBODY
FOR ANY OPINIONS.
I CAME HERE AS A MIDSHIPMAN,
NOT AS A CROONER.
THE SOONER YOU FORGET YOU EVER HEARD ME
ON THE RADIO, THE BETTER I'LL LIKE IT.
YOU OUGHT TO TELL THAT
TO THOSE UPPERCLASSMEN.
THEY SEEN YOU
WHEN YOU DONE IT,
IF I MIGHT LAPSE INTO
THE COLLOQUIAL.
YOU KNOW, IT'S GONNA
TAKE YOU A LONG TIME
TO LIVE DOWN THAT
ENTRANCE OF YOURS.
WASN'T A RADIO ISSUED
TO ANY OF YOU GUYS?
I DIDN'T SEE ANY
RADIO ON MY LIST.
I DON'T THINK PLEBES
RATE RADIOS.
I WAS RAISED ON A RADIO.
GOT TO HAVE A RADIO.
HOW'S ABOUT A RADIO
FOR 3305?
WE DON'T SALUTE WHEN
WE'RE UNCOVERED, MISTER.
HAVE YOU STOWED
YOUR LOCKER YET?
OH, YES, YES, YES.
WHOSE STUFF
IS THAT?
MINE, SIR. YOU SEE,
IT DIDN'T QUITE FIT.
BETTER START OVER AGAIN AND MAKE IT FIT.
THERE ARE
YOUR RULES.
YES, SIR.
HOW'S ABOUT
A RADIO?
YOU'LL HAVE TO WAIT TWO YEARS
TO RATE A RADIO IN YOUR ROOM.
A MAN THAT'S BEEN
RAISED ON RADIOS
CAN'T LIVE
WITHOUT A RADIO.
AND SINCE I'M A MAN WHO
KNOWS SOMETHING ABOUT A RADIO,
I'M GOING TO HAVE
A RADIO,
EVEN IF THE GREAT DICK MELVILLE
ISN'T ON WEDNESDAY NIGHTS.
AND TO BE SURE,
I WAS ALWAYS ONE
TO LISTEN IN
ON WEDNESDAY NIGHTS.
I STILL GOT TO HAVE
A RADIO,
EVEN IF MR. MELVILLE IS IN
ANNAPOLIS AND NOT STATION WBNY,
AND FURTHERMORE, I'M
GOING TO HAVE A RADIO!
SQUEEZE HARD.
200.
225.
180.
OK.
PULL. PULL HARD.
60.
NEXT.
SQUARE YOUR HATS!
SQUAD, ATTENTION!
RIGHT FACE!
LEFT FACE!
MR. LINCOLN, HOLD YOUR
HAT IN YOUR RIGHT HAND.
YOU SURE THAT'S
YOUR RIGHT HAND?
YES, SIR.
REMEMBER IT.
HOW YOU FEELING?
OK, PAL.
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
MORNING.
WHO'S IN CHARGE?
I AM, SIR.
MIDSHIPMAN MELVILLE,
FOURTH CLASS.
PLACE HIM ON THE REPORT.
DUST BEHIND THE RADIATOR.
SORRY, DICK. NEXT TIME,
ONE OF US WILL BE IN CHARGE.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW WHAT BEARING
DUST HAS ON MY BECOMING AN OFFICER.
YOU THINK WE'D LOSE
A NAVAL BATTLE
JUST BECAUSE WE LEFT A SQUARE
INCH OF DUST BEHIND A RADIATOR?
I WASN'T GONNA
SAY ANYTHING,
BUT INASMUCH
AS I HEAR,
YOUR FATHER WAS THE ADMIRAL
OF THE FLEET AWHILE BACK.
SEEMS TO ME LIKE
AN ADMIRAL'S SON
WOULD KNOW MORE
ABOUT THOSE THINGS
THAN A MERE GUY FROM ARIZONA
WHO WAS WEANED ON DUST
AND JUST DON'T LIKE IT
BY INSTINCT.
MIDSHIPMAN MELVILLE?
YES, SIR.
REPORT TODAY TO
THE SUPERINTENDENT.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CARRY ON.
YOU SENT FOR ME, SIR?
WELL, HELLO, DICK.
HELLO, DAD.
I HAD HOPED YOU'D
CALL ON ME AT THE HOUSE.
I DIDN'T WANT ANYONE TO FEEL
THAT I WAS TAKING ADVANTAGE
OF OUR RELATIONSHIP,
SIR.
THAT'S COMMENDABLE,
BUT I DON'T THINK ANYONE
IS GOING TO CRITICIZE A SON
FOR CALLING ON
HIS OWN FATHER.
YOUR WHITES DON'T
SEEM TO FIT YOU YET,
BUT THEY'LL SOON SHRINK
DOWN TO YOUR SIZE.
I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE TO
CONGRATULATE YOU BEFORE, MY SON.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
TELL ME, HOW DO YOU
LIKE THE ACADEMY?
I THINK I MADE A FOOL OUT OF
MYSELF BY COMING HERE, SIR.
MIDSHIPMAN MELVILLE, YOU HAVE A
GREAT MANY LESSONS TO LEARN HERE,
AND A FEW IDEAS OF YOUR
OWN YOU'D BETTER FORGET.
I SUGGEST YOU REPORT
BACK TO YOUR QUARTERS
AND THINK THEM OVER.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
EXCUSE ME, PLEASE.
HELLO, MISTER.
HAVE YOU A TWIN BROTHER
IN NEW YORK WHO SINGS
AND DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN THE NAVY?
NO, I HAVEN'T
A TWIN BROTHER.
I'M THE SAME DUCK YOU
TALKED TO IN NEW YORK,
ONLY I SUDDENLY WENT
SOFT IN THE HEAD.
WHAT HAPPENED, DICK?
I DON'T KNOW.
BANDS PLAYING
STARS AND STRIPES,
PEOPLE SCREAMING
AND HOLLERING,
DAD GOING OVER THE
SIDE, BLOOD WILL TELL,
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST WENT OFF MY NUT AND HERE I AM.
FURTHERMORE, I WISH
I HAD A TWIN BROTHER
SO HE COULD TRADE
PLACES WITH ME RIGHT NOW.
I HAVE TO BE AT BANCROFT
IN TIME FOR FORMATION.
DICK...
FORGET WHAT I SAID
ABOUT NAVY IN NEW YORK.
I'D LIKE YOU TO COME
SEE ME.
I'D LIKE TO
SEE YOU, TOO.
ONLY UNFORTUNATELY,
THEY HAVE A BOOK OF
REGULATIONS AROUND HERE,
AND PLEBES AREN'T
ALLOWED OUT OF THESE WALLS
EXCEPT ON LABOR DAY
AND WHAT IS LAUGHINGLY
CALLED INDEPENDENCE DAY.
GOOD-BYE.
HEY, WAKE UP,
FELLAS!
THE CREWS IS IN!
THERE THEY BE.
LOADED TO THE GUNNEL
WITH FIRST CLASSMEN.
NOW WE GET IT! NOW THE
REIGN OF TERROR STARTS!
REIGN OF TERROR?
I SUPPOSE YOU THINK THIS PAST
SUMMER'S BEEN A SWEET DREAM.
PULL OUT
YOUR CHEST.
DROP YOUR
SHOULDERS.
WHAT'S THAT?
TH-THAT'S ME, SIR.
WELL,
PULL IT IN.
PULL YOUR HANDS
BACK.
SQUARE THAT CAP,
MR. MELVILLE.
A LITTLE MORE.
MR. LAWRENCE, DID YOU
BRUSH OFF THIS MORNING?
YES, SIR.
WITH A BLANKET OR
WITH A BATH TOWEL?
WITH A BL-UH, WITH
A CLOTHES BRUSH, SIR.
YOU SURE YOU HAVE
A CLOTHES BRUSH?
YES, SIR.
DO YOU USE IT?
UH, YES, SIR.
DON'T COME DOWN HERE TO
FORMATION AGAIN LOOKING LIKE THIS.
NO, SIR.
"AYE, AYE, SIR."
AYE, AYE, SIR.
REGIMENT, ATTENTION!
ATTENTION!
TURN SQUADS RIGHT
AND LEFT!
TURN SQUAD
RIGHT!
SQUAD RIGHT!
MARCH!
HUP! HUP! HUP! HUP!
HUP! HUP! HUP!
SEAT!
WHAT'S YOUR NAME, MISTER,
AND WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
MIDSHIPMAN MELVILLE.
NEW YORK, SIR.
WHAT DO THE GIRLS
CALL YOU, MISTER?
DICK, SIR.
WHY, MISTER?
THAT'S MY NAME, SIR.
ARE YOU DICK MELVILLE,
THE RADIO SONGBIRD?
ARE YOU?
YES, SIR.
THOUGHT SO. WE'VE HEARD ABOUT
YOU AND YOUR MUSICAL INTRODUCTION
TO THE ACADEMY.
WE'LL DO OUR BEST TO
GET MIDSHIPMAN INTO YOU
AND CROONER OUT OF YOU.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THE PAIN AND PLEASURE
WILL BE OURS.
WHO ARE YOU, MISTER,
AND WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
WHO, ME, SIR?
YES.
MIDSHIPMAN LAWRENCE.
EX-BLUEJACKETS, SIR.
HOW ARE YOU WITH
THE DRAGS, MISTER?
I BEG YOUR PARDON,
SIR?
THE DRAGS, THE FEMMES,
THE LADIES.
HOW DO YOU GET
ALONG WITH THEM?
OH, VERY WELL.
VERY WELL
INDEED, SIR.
WHAT DO THE GIRLS
CALL YOU, MISTER?
THEY DON'T HAVE TO
CALL ME, SIR.
WHEREVER THEY ARE, I'M
GENERALLY JOHNNY-ON-THE-SPOT.
SUBMERGE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME AND
WHERE ARE YOU FROM, MISTER?
MIDSHIPMAN BROWN, SIR.
ARKANSAS.
STARBOARD RUNNING LIGHT,
MASTHEAD LIGHT,
BRIGHT LIGHT, SIR.
LIGHT BUOY WATCH ALERT.
WIPE IT OFF.
TOOT, TOOT,
TOOT, TOOT!
I REQUEST PERMISSION
TO COME ABOARD, SIR.
COME ABOARD AND EAT
A SQUARE MEAL.
WIPE IT OFF.
IN THE FUTURE,
MR. MELVILLE,
DON'T TURN ON THAT PERSONALITY
SMILE FOR OUR BENEFIT.
WE'RE YOUR PUBLIC NOW,
AND WE DON'T LIKE IT.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
WHY DON'T THEY GROW UP AND
FORGET THAT CHILD'S PLAY?
MR. MELVILLE!
YES, SIR.
COME HERE.
WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO GET
THE WORD, MR. SONGBIRD?
PLEBES AREN'T ALLOWED
TO TALK IN THE CORRIDORS.
WHO'S SPONSORING YOU?
NOBODY, SIR.
YOU MEAN TO TELL ME THAT YOU
HAVEN'T GOT A FIRST CLASSMAN?
NO, SIR.
THEN YOU'RE ASSIGNED
TO ME,
PAINFUL THOUGH
THE DUTY WILL BE.
COME TO REPORT BEFORE
EAST FORMATION AFTER DINNER
AND AFTER RELEASE
FROM STUDY HOUR.
WHAT FOR, SIR?
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN A GREAT
ADMIRER OF THE WORKS
OF ABDUL ABULBUL AMIR,
AND SO HAVE MY ROOMMATES.
WE FEEL THAT THE SOONER YOU GET
THE CROONER OUT OF YOUR TONSILS
AND MIDSHIPMAN INTO
YOUR HEAD, THE BETTER.
FOLLOW ME.
I GAVE THIS NIGHTINGALE
AN ORDER, GENTLEMEN,
AND HE ASKED, "WHAT FOR?"
AND I'VE SUGGESTED A LITTLE
MUSICALECTOMY FOR THE ANSWER.
FINE IDEA.
WE ONLY HAVE TIME FOR THE
FIRST 100 VERSES OF ABDUL
THIS AFTERNOON.
BEAUTIFUL,
BUT WE PREFER
ABDUL.
ABDUL ABULBUL AMIR,
FIRST VERSE.
* OH
* THE SONS OF THE PROPHET
ARE BRAVE MEN AND BOLD *
* AND QUITE UNACCUSTOMED
TO FEAR *
* BUT BRAVEST BY FAR
IN THE RANKS OF THE SHAH *
* WAS ABDUL ABULBUL AMIR
SECOND VERSE.
* OH
* IF YOU WANTED A MAN
TO ENCOURAGE THE VAN *
* OR HARASS THE FOE
FROM THE REAR *
* TO STORM FORT OR REDOUBT,
YOU HAD ONLY TO SHOUT *
* FOR ABDUL ABULBUL AMIR
THIRD VERSE.
* OH...
NICE. NICE, PEAR-SHAPED TONES.
* OH
* THE HEROES WERE PLENTY
AND WELL-KNOWN TO FAME *
* IN THE RANKS THAT WERE
LED BY THE TSAR *
* BUT BRAVEST BY FAR WAS
A MAN BY THE NAME *
* OF IVAN SKAVINSKY SKAVAR
FOURTH VERSE.
I THINK THE ACOUSTICS ARE MUCH BETTER
OVER HERE
IN THE SHOWER.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
FOURTH VERSE.
* OH
YOU'RE QUITE
RIGHT, SIR.
* OH
* HE COULD JUMP 50 YARDS,
TELL FORTUNES AT CARDS *
* STRUM ON THE SPANISH
GUITAR... *
HUNDREDTH VERSE.
* OH
* THIS MUSCOVITE MAIDEN
A LONG VIGIL KEEPS *
* EACH NIGHT 'NEATH
THE COLD WINTRY STAR *
* AND THE NAME THAT SHE MURMURS
IN VAIN AS SHE WEEPS *
* WAS IVAN SKAVINSKY SKAVAR
OH, MR. MELVILLE?
YES, SIR.
I'M A LITTLE MIXED UP ON THE
38th VERSE OF ABDUL ABULBUL AMIR.
WILL YOU SING IT
FOR ME, PLEASE?
RIGHT HERE, SIR?
RIGHT HERE AND WITH
GESTURES, PLEASE.
* OH
* ONE DAY,
THIS BOLD RUSSIAN *
* HE SHOULDERED
HIS GUN *
* AND DONNED HIS MOST
TRUCULENT SNEER *
* DOWNTOWN HE DID GO
* WHERE HE TROD
ON THE TOE *
* OF
ABDUL ABULBUL AMIR *
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MISTER,
AND A HAPPY ABDUL
ABULBUL TO YOU.
ABULBUL TO YOU, SIR.
DISMISS THE BATTALION!
THIRD BATTALION
DISMISSED.
WELL, HERE I AM.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
"HERE I AM"?
SORRY, FELLAS,
HERE I AM.
COME ALONG, JUNE.
THE MORE I STAY
INSIDE THESE WALLS,
THE MORE I FEEL
LIKE A CONVICT.
ALL PLEBES
GO THROUGH THAT.
IT'S THE WAY YOU EARN YOUR
LIBERTIES FOR NEXT YEAR.
I DON'T WANT
ANY NEXT YEAR.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I'M JUST FED UP ON BEING
A MIDSHIPMAN, THAT'S ALL.
BUT YOU'VE ONLY
STARTED.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO TELL ME THAT.
BUT IF YOU THINK I'M GOING
TO GO THROUGH 4 SOLID YEARS
OF THIS NAVY RATTLETRAP,
YOU'RE CRAZY.
OH, THERE, THERE,
MR. MOUNT VESUVIUS.
AFTER THE WAY YOU
TALKED IN NEW YORK,
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHY
YOU CHANGED YOUR MIND
ABOUT THE ACADEMY.
BUT NOW YOU'RE HERE,
IT'S DIFFERENT.
NO, NO, IT ISN'T.
I'M GOING TO GET OUT OF THIS
PLACE ON A GREASED SLIDE.
WHAT DOES YOUR FATHER
SAY ABOUT THAT?
I HAVEN'T SEEN MY DAD
UP CLOSE IN 3 MONTHS.
NOBODY'S GOING TO SAY
I'M GREASING MY OLD MAN.
I'M NOT GOING
TO SEE HIM, EITHER.
I'M JUST GOING
TO CLEAR OUT.
IT MAY BE TOUGH
TO GET IN HERE,
BUT THEY SAY IT'S EASY
TO GET OUT IF YOU WANT TO.
I'M JUST GOING TO
RESIGN, THAT'S ALL.
WE CAN PICK UP
WHERE WE WERE
BEFORE I MADE THE
MISTAKE OF COMING HERE.
DICK... IF YOU QUIT
THE ACADEMY,
I NEVER WANT TO SEE YOU
AGAIN AS LONG AS I LIVE.
BUT I THOUGHT YOU WANTED
ME TO STAY OUT OF THE NAVY!
WELL, THAT WAS TRUE.
WE TALKED OF STARS
AND GOT A LITTLE DIZZY.
AND WE TALKED ABOUT
MARRIAGE AND THINGS.
BUT I'M TALKING ABOUT
YOU AND NOW.
YOU CHOSE TO ENTER
THE ACADEMY.
IF YOU CHOOSE
TO GO YELLOW
ON WHAT YOU SWORE TO DO
WHEN YOU BECAME A MIDSHIPMAN-
BUT I'M NOT GOING
YELLOW, I'M JUST QUITTING.
IF YOU QUIT ANYTHING
YOU SWORE TO DO,
WHETHER IT BE NAVY
OR THE NORTH POLE,
I WOULDN'T THINK
VERY MUCH OF YOU.
OH, YOU DON'T
MAKE SENSE.
IF I STAY IN THE ACADEMY,
YOU WON'T MARRY ME
BECAUSE THAT
MAKES ME A NAVY MAN.
YOU LOST YOUR FATHER AND
BROTHER THAT WAY, IS THAT RIGHT?
AND IF I GET OUT
OF THE ACADEMY
NOW THAT I'M IN IT, YOU
WON'T SEE ME ANYMORE.
IS THAT RIGHT, TOO?
YES. THAT'S RIGHT, TOO.
WOULD YOU MIND IF I
SAID GOOD AFTERNOON?
I'M GOING SLOWLY AND
COMPLETELY DAFFY.
AND THAT, SIR, IS THAT
MIDSHIPMAN'S OPINION
OF THE UNITED STATES
NAVAL ACADEMY.
IF YOU WERE HE, SIR, WHAT WOULD
YOU DO? STAY IN OR GET OUT?
IF I WERE THAT BOY,
I'D GET OUT AS FAST
AS I COULD.
YOU WOULD, SIR?
YES.
BUT I DON'T KNOW OF ANY
MIDSHIPMAN IN THE ACADEMY
ANSWERING THE DESCRIPTION
YOU'VE GIVEN ME.
IF HE IS HERE,
HE CERTAINLY OUGHT NOT TO BE.
BUT I DO KNOW THAT THE
BELLIGERENT YOUNG NINCOMPOOP
YOU'VE JUST DESCRIBED
ISN'T MY SON.
THE SPIRIT OF THE ACADEMY
INCLUDES MANY ELEMENTS
BESIDES THE QUALITIES
OF HONOR,
PERSONAL INTEGRITY,
AND LOYALTY TO THE SERVICE.
IT INCLUDES
SPORTSMANSHIP-
THE SPIRIT THAT ENABLES A MAN
TO BE ABLE TO GIVE AND TAKE.
AND UNLESS THAT MIDSHIPMAN
CAN LEARN THAT QUALITY,
HE MAY FIND HIMSELF
IN THE UNFORTUNATE POSITION
OF WORKING UP THROUGH
HIS CLASSES WITH NO PALS,
NO FRIENDS... ALONE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
PERHAPS THAT'S
THE COURSE
THAT MIDSHIPMAN
MAY CHOOSE TO STEER.
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
MISTER?
I'VE NOTICED
A FADING AWAY
OF YOUR SPIRITS
OF LATE,
AND I FEEL, MISTER, THAT
IT'S PERHAPS DUE TO THE LOSS
OF YOUR LATE LAMENTED PUBLIC ACCLAIM.
AND AS AN ANTIDOTE TO
THAT GRIEVOUS CONDITION,
THE FIRST CLASSMEN ARE
WILLING TO BE GENEROUS.
THEIR DRAGS ARE WITH
THEM IN SMOKE HALL.
THEIR HEARTS ARE INFLAMED
AT THE VERY THOUGHT
OF HEARING THE GOLDEN
VOICE OF PLEBE DICK MELVILLE
SING A HEART SONG
TO THEIR LADYLOVES-
WITH, PERHAPS,
THE VAIN HOPE
THAT THE LADYLOVES MIGHT
BECOME AMOROUSLY AFFECTED,
SENTIMENTALLY
INCLINED,
AND WILLING TO WAIT FOR TWO
YEARS AFTER OUR GRADUATION
FOR THE CONGRESSIONALLY
DELAYED NUPTIALS.
IN OTHER WORDS,
MISTER, FOLLOW ME.
THERE YOU ARE,
MISTER.
NOW YOU CAN TURN ON
YOUR PERSONALITY.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
WHAT WILL BE
YOUR FANCY, SIR?
OH, JUST TURN IT ON.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
* WHEN SOMEONE TELLS ME
TO MARCH OR TO HALT *
* MY SOUL REBELS,
I'M THAT WAY TO A FAULT *
* NO RULES OR REGULATIONS
WOULD I OBEY *
* THEN I MET YOU,
AND I KNEW RIGHT AWAY *
* IF YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN
* I'LL BE THE CREW
* 'CAUSE I JUST LOVE TO
TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
,
* YOU BLOW THE BUGLE
* AND I'LL JUMP THROUGH
* OH, HOW I'D LOVE TO
TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
* I KNOW THAT RULES
WERE MADE FOR FOOLS *
* THAT'S ONE THING
I HAVE LEARNED *
* BUT I'M GOING IN
FOR DISCIPLINE *
* WHEREVER YOU'RE CONCERNED
* IF YOU SAY, "KISS ME"
* THAT'S WHAT I'LL DO
* 'CAUSE I JUST LOVE TO
TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
* IF YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN
* I'LL BE THE CREW
* 'CAUSE I JUST LOVE TO
TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
* YOU BLOW THE BUGLE
* AND I'LL JUMP THROUGH
* OH, HOW I'D LOVE TO
TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
* I KNOW THAT RULES
WERE MADE FOR FOOLS *
* THAT'S ONE THING
I HAVE LEARNED *
* BUT I'M GOING IN
FOR DISCIPLINE *
* WHEREVER YOU'RE CONCERNED
WAS THIS YOUR
BRIGHT IDEA, GIFFORD?
DO YOU REALIZE WE'RE LOSING OUR DRAGS
TO THE PLEBE
OF THE VOICE?
* THAT'S WHAT I'LL DO
* 'CAUSE I JUST LOVE TO
TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU *
THAT'S ENOUGH.
I BEG YOUR PARDON,
SIR?
I SAID,
THAT WILL BE ENOUGH.
AW, NO! NO! NO!
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
CERTAINLY, NO GENTLEMAN IN THE ACADEMY
COULD DENY THE REQUEST OF LADIES,
NO MATTER HOW GREAT
THE SACRIFICE.
IN MY CASE, IT'S A
DISTINCT PLEASURE TO OBLIGE.
THAT IS, IF YOU
DON'T MIND, SIR.
* EVERY TIME YOUR LIPS SAY,
"NO, SIR" *
* I WON'T LISTEN,
I'M TOO WISE *
* I WOULD RATHER LISTEN
* TO YOUR EYES
* THEY HAVE TOLD ME
LOTS OF THINGS, DEAR *
* THAT YOUR BETTER SELF DENIES
* SO I'D RATHER LISTEN
* TO THOSE EYES
* THERE'S NOTHING
YOU COULD EVER SAY *
* THAT COULD CONVEY
* THE PROMISE
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR *
* I LOOK IN YOUR EYES
* AND REALIZE THAT
THEY CAN TELL ME MORE *
* EYES CAN BE SINCERE
AND TRUTHFUL *
* LIPS CAN TELL A LOT OF LIES
* SO I'D RATHER LISTEN
* TO YOUR EYES
THANK YOU,
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, LADIES, FOR
LISTENING. YOU'RE VERY SWEET.
AND THANK YOU, SIR,
FOR THE ASSIGNMENT.
IT WAS
A REAL PLEASURE.
Women: AW...
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
LET HIM SING MORE?
WELL, LOOKS LIKE
WE LOST A ROOMMATE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
ALL I KNOW IS
HE WANTED A ROOM ALONE.
SAID HE WANTED TO
CONCENTRATE ON HIS STUDIES.
HE'S MOVED IN THAT SINGLE
ROOM DOWN THE CORRIDOR.
HE TOLD ME ROOMMATES WERE DESIGNED
MERELY TO SHARE THEIR ROOMS,
NOT THEIR THOUGHTS
AND CONVERSATIONS.
AS FAR AS
HE'S CONCERNED,
THE WHOLE CLASS CAN CONSIDER
HIM DEAF AND DUMB FROM NOW ON.
HE DIDN'T WANT
ANY PART OF US.
ALL I GOT TO SAY, BOY,
IS THAT HE'S GONNA
FIND IT A LONESOME ROAD.
Dick on radio:
* SHIPMATES STAND TOGETHER
* DON'T GIVE UP
THE SHIP... *
Announcer: THIS IS
A DICK MELVILLE RECORDING.
* FAIR OR STORMY WEA-
UH, TREE'S UP.
COXSWAIN'S
UNSATISFACTORY AGAIN.
OH, I'M NOT SCARED.
I'M GOING TO BEAR DOWN
FOR THOSE FINAL EXAMINATIONS.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
SAY, DO YOU KNOW
WHO STANDS
AT THE HEAD
OF THE CLASS NOW?
UH-HUH.
DICK THE MELVILLE.
RIGHT. AND IF THAT'S ALL
HE'S GETTING OUT OF THE ACADEMY,
I HOPE HE ENJOYS IT.
GANG...
I'M ABOUT TO UNVEIL
THE MIRACLE
OF ROOM 3305.
Prepare yourselves
for a surprise.
Shh...
RAISED ON RADIO,
WEANED ON RADIO.
GOT TO HAVE
A RADIO...
GOT A RADIO!
ANTENNA DOWN
THE SHOWER PIPE.
GROUND THROUGH
THE LEG OF THE BED.
RADIO!
Where?
YOU GOT ME!
* IN THE MATTRESS
SPARKS, YOU'LL GET WORSE
THAN DEATH IF YOU GET CAUGHT!
CAUGHT?
YOU MAY NEED THOSE BRAINS,
SPARKS, WHEN YOU GO INTO THE FLEET.
GET THAT THING OUT OF THERE
AND THROW IT IN THE SEVERN!
YOU DON'T KNOW-
THOUGHT FOR A MINUTE
I HEARD A RADIO IN HERE.
UH... DIDYOU, SIR?
HMM...
I DON'T SEE ANY RADIO.
I DON'T SEE
HOW YOU...
COULD, SIR.
YES, A RADIO IS A HARD
THING TO HIDE, ISN'T IT?
YES, SIR.
YES,
INDEED, SIR.
WOULD HAVE SWORN
I HEARD A RADIO.
CARRY ON!
All: OH!
YOU GOT DYNAMITE IN YOUR
MATTRESS, SPARKS! DYNAMITE!
Oh.
I GOT ONE.
GOT WHAT?
A LITTLE
TECUMSEH.
Cowboy: HEH!
Sparks: AH!
WHO SHRIVELED HIM UP?
DON'T TALK LIKE THAT!
DON'T GET HIM SORE AT YOU,
OR ELSE THEY'LL BE ASKING YOU
TO WALK OUT THE FRONT
GATE IN CIVILIAN CLOTHES!
THAT FELLA'S A VERY
TOUCHY LITTLE GUY, COWBOY.
YOU BETTER PRAY TO
HIM FOR FORGIVENESS.
HEH! WHAT FOR?
WELL, HE'S THE GOD OF
ALL WOODEN MIDSHIPMEN.
IF YOU WANT TO GO THROUGH
THIS ACADEMY WITHOUT ANY GRIEF,
YOU BETTER START GETTING
CHUMMY WITH HIM RIGHT NOW.
PRAY TO HIM, COWBOY.
WHEN YOU GET THROUGH PRAYING FOR
YOURSELF, PUT IN A WORD FOR ME,
BECAUSE IF I DON'T PASS THIS TEAM,
I'M NOT GOING TO BE HERE NEXT YEAR.
TECUMSEH, EH? HEH HEH!
YOU KNOW, I'D FEEL KIND OF SILLY
PRAYING TO A THING LIKE THIS.
Coxswain: YEAH? A LOT OF MIDSHIPMEN
THAT ARE NOW ADMIRALS DIDN'T FEEL SO.
WELL... HOW DO YOU
DO IT, THEN?
I'LL SHOW YOU. HAVE YOU GOT ANY PENNIES?
PENNIES?
YEAH. HERE.
HERE.
TECUMSEH, OLD BOY,
EVERYTHING ISN'T
EXACTLY HUNKY-DORY
WITH COXSWAIN
AND COWBOY.
WITH ME, EITHER,
FOR THAT MATTER.
GIVE US A BREAK ON
THESE EXAMS, WILL YOU?
THE 3 OF US STARTED
TOGETHER AND...
THAT'S THE WAY I THINK WE
OUGHT TO FINISH UP, DON'T YOU?
SO DON'T BEAR DOWN
TOO HARD ON US.
REMEMBER, YOU'VE GOT
A WOODEN HEAD, TOO.
YOU KNOW HOW IT IS.
HOW'D YOU COME OUT,
COXSWAIN?
OK!
GOOD!
WELL, I GUESS I WON'T
HAVE TO GO BACK
TO LASSOING STEERS
FOR ANOTHER YEAR.
YEP. UNCLE SAM, IN
HIS INFINITE WISDOM,
HAS DECIDED TO KEEP 3305
INTACT FOR ANOTHER YEAR.
HA HA!
Man: YIPPEE!
WELL, DAD, THAT'S
ONE YEAR CHECKED OFF.
YES, YES.
WHY AREN'T YOU
WITH YOUR CLASSMATES?
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
SOME OF THESE TRADITIONS
SEEM LIKE HORSEPLAY TO ME.
THERE'S NOTHING IN
THE BOOK OF REGULATIONS
THAT SAYS I HAVE TO DANCE
AROUND THE HERNDON MONUMENT
JUST BECAUSE I PASS
PLEBE YEAR.
HEH!
YOU'RE... STUBBORN.
YOU'RE YOUNG,
AND YOU'RE WRONG.
SOMETIMES I WISH
I WERE ALREADY RETIRED,
NOT SUPERINTENDENT
OF THE ACADEMY.
IT WOULD PUT ME IN A BETTER
POSITION TO SPEAK TO YOU-
AS A FATHER,
NOT AN OFFICER.
BUT REMEMBER THIS-
I'D FAR RATHER HAVE
A SON WHO DIDN'T STAND
AT THE HEAD OF HIS
CLASS IN STUDIES
IF IT ALSO MEANS THAT HE STANDS
AT THE FOOT OF HIS CLASS...
IN FRIENDSHIP.
YOU WANTED ME TO
GRADUATE FROM THE ACADEMY
AND I'M GOING
TO DO IT,
BUT I HAVE MY OWN RIGHT TO
CHOOSE THE WAY OF DOING SO.
OH, SON...
YOU'RE TYING
YOUR OWN HANG KNOT.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE HERE
AND GO INTO THE NAVY
AND EXPECT TO SERVE
WITH FELLOW OFFICERS
WHOM YOU REFUSE
TO MEET AS FRIENDS.
I HAVE NO DESIRE
WHATSOEVER
TO ENTER THE NAVY
UPON GRADUATION.
OH.
I WON MY WAY
INTO THIS PLACE.
I HAVE A CHANCE
TO GRADUATE.
I HAVE THE RIGHT
TO ACCEPT OR REJECT
MY COMMISSION WHEN
IT'S OFFERED TO ME.
WELL...
SINCE THAT IS YOUR
DECISION,
SINCE YOU'RE WILLING
TO TAKE FROM YOUR COUNTRY
WITH NO THOUGHT
OF GIVING IN RETURN-
EVEN THOUGH IT'S YOUR
PRIVILEGE UNDER THE LAW-
FOR THE REMAINDER OF YOUR
CAREER HERE AS A MIDSHIPMAN,
I PREFER THAT YOU REGARD ME AS THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF THE NAVAL ACADEMY.
YOU'RE NOT MY SON.
AYE AYE, SIR.
Man: HELLO,
MR. MELVILLE.
UH, MARCELLUS,
YES, SIR?
IS MISS BLACKBURN
STILL IN THERE?
YES, SIR. SHE'S BEEN DANCING
THOSE KIDS FOR AN HOUR OR SO.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME, SIR.
WELL, JOE, WHAT'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
I'VE BEEN A SISSY
LONG ENOUGH!
OH, YOU HAVE,
HAVE YOU?
WELL, YOU GO OVER THERE AND SIT DOWN.
ALL RIGHT, CHILDREN.
COME ON.
HERE, WHAT'S ALL THIS?
WHY AREN'T YOU DANCING?
WE'D RATHER SEE YOU DANCE,
MISS BLACKBURN.
OH, NO, NONE OF THAT.
NOW, COME ON. LET'S FINISH
THIS ROUTINE. LOTS OF PEP.
1, 2, 3, 4.
JUMP!
OH, THAT'S FINE.
GOOD-BYE, DARLINGS.
THAT'S ALL FOR TODAY.
Children: BYE! BYE!
GOOD-BYE.
WELL, TEACHER, YOU'RE DOING A
GREAT JOB WITH THOSE CHILDREN.
I DON'T THINK
I'D HAVE THE PATIENCE.
GOOD-BYE,
MISS BLACKBURN.
I WON'T BE COMING TO YOUR
DANCING CLASS ANYMORE.
WHY, DARLING?
ARE YOU GOING AWAY?
WELL, DAD, MOM, AND ME GOT
ORDERS, FOR THE CHINA STATION.
CHINA?
OH, DARLING,
WE'LL MISS YOU!
ARE YOU GLAD YOU'RE
GOING?
WELL, DAD AND MOM
AND ME'S IN THE NAVY.
WE GOT ORDERS, SO WE'RE
GOING TO CHINA NEXT SATURDAY.
SO GOOD-BYE,
MISS BLACKBURN.
GOOD-BYE, DARLING.
I'LL SEND YOU
A POSTCARD.
THANK YOU.
GOOD-BYE, SIR.
SOMEDAY I'M GOING
TO BE A MIDSHIPMAN
LIKE YOU, TOO.
BE A GOOD BOY.
YES, SIR.
I'LL BE WITH YOU IN A MINUTE,
DICK. I WANT TO CHANGE.
ALL RIGHT, DEAR.
I'VE GOT BAD NEWS,
DICK.
MY UNCLE HAS BEEN PASSED
OVER IN THE LAST SELECTION.
HE'S AUTOMATICALLY
RETIRED.
THAT'S THE NAVY
FOR YOU.
HE SERVES 25 YEARS, AND
OVERNIGHT HE'S THROUGH.
THERE'S ONLY ROOM FOR SO
MANY CAPTAINS IN THE NAVY.
SOME COMMANDERS
HAVE TO BE PASSED BY.
WELL, ARE YOU, UH...
IS HE LEAVING HERE?
HE'LL HAVE TO START IN
AGAIN AT A CIVILIAN JOB.
THERE'S NOTHING
HE CAN DO IN ANNAPOLIS.
ARE YOU GOING WITH HIM? NO.
I HAVE TO START OUT
ON MY OWN, TOO.
WHERE?
WELL... ALL I KNOW
HOW TO DO IS DANCE.
I GUESS THAT MEANS...
NEW YORK.
I'LL GIVE YOU A LETTER TO
THE BOYS IN THE BAND, DARLING.
THEY'LL HELP YOU.
AH AH!
THERE'S THE LONE WOLF OF
BANCROFT HALL DEAD AHEAD, BOYS.
WHAT DO WE DO
- TURN AROUND OR GO BACK?
LET'S RECOGNIZE HIM AND IF HE
SPEAKS TO US, ASK HIM TO JOIN US.
WELL, IF HE DON'T SPEAK
TO US, WE'LL JUST SUBMERGE
AND GO RIGHT ON BY.
IT ALMOST SEEMS LIKE I'M
DESERTING YOU, DOESN'T IT?
HELLO.
Men: * O THE LIFEBOAT
CREW ARE WE *
* AND WE SAIL
THE STORMY SEA *
* DA DA DA DA DA...
Men: * WHOA,
THE LIFEBOAT CREW ARE WE... *
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO
WHEN I'M GONE?
I DON'T KNOW.
OH, BUT WE'LL HAVE
SEPTEMBER LEAVE TOGETHER.
WE CAN HAVE A LOT
OF FUN IN NEW YORK.
WE'LL GO OUT IN CENTRAL
PARK AND TAKE A RIDE
IN ONE OF THOSE
FUNNY HORSE THINGS.
AND WILL WE GO
TO THE ZOO?
MM-HMM, THEY'VE GOT A
NEW PINK RHINOCEROS THERE.
AND WILL WE GO
TO THE AQUARIUM?
UH-HUH.
AND CONEY ISLAND?
SURE, AND
TO GRANT'S TOMB.
WE'LL HAVE A LOT
OF FUN IN NEW YORK.
OH, DARLING,
WHEN I GET TO NEW YORK,
I'M NOT GOING OUT
WITH ANYBODY.
I'M JUST GOING
TO BE YOUR GIRL.
STEAM EXAM'S GOING TO GET ME!
STEAM! WHO KNOWS HIS STEAM?
DON'T HAVE
THE TIME.
SAY, YOU FELLAS WANT TO SEE
ME BILGE OUT OF THE ACADEMY?
DOESN'T ANYBODY KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THESE STEAM PROBLEMS?
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU
ASK DICK MELVILLE?
Man: SURE, HE'S
THE SAVVY MAN.
HE STANDS FIRST
IN THE CLASS.
HE COULD HELP YOU,
COXSWAIN.
THANKS.
TECUMSEH...
THEY DO A LOT OF TALKING
AROUND HERE ABOUT...
HOW YOU'VE HELPED DUMB GUYS
LIKE ME PASS THEIR EXAMINATIONS.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE THEY'RE KIDDING ME.
MAYBE THEY'RE NOT, BUT...
I CAN'T AFFORD
TO TAKE A CHANCE.
IF YOU'LL HELP ME...
I... WELL...
I WON'T FORGET IT, EVER!
AND I'LL TELL ALL
THE FELLAS
HOW SWELL YOU WERE
TO HELP ME WHEN I NEEDED YOU.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
THE SECTION AS A WHOLE
DID VERY WELL ON
THE FINAL EXAMINATIONS,
BUT ONE OR TWO OF YOU
FAILED RATHER BADLY.
WITHOUT A PERFECT
RECITATION TODAY,
I'M AFRAID SOME OF YOU
ARE GOING TO BE LEAVING US.
ANY QUESTIONS?
DRAW YOUR SLIPS,
GENTLEMEN.
MAN THE BOARDS.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO FEEL, LAWRENCE,
BECAUSE YOU'RE LEAVING HERE,
THAT YOU'VE LOST ALL CHANCE
OF BECOMING AN OFFICER.
COMPETITION HERE
IS PRETTY STIFF,
AND MAYBE YOU WEREN'T
QUITE READY FOR THE ACADEMY.
PERHAPS YOU'RE
A LITTLE TOO YOUNG.
YES, SIR.
BUT THERE'S ONE THING
I'M CERTAIN OF, BOY-
YOU'VE GOT THE HEART
FOR NAVY,
EVEN THOUGH ACADEMICS
LICKED YOU THIS TIME.
AND THERE ARE SOME
MIDSHIPMEN HERE WHO...
HAVE THE MINDS TO MAKE
OFFICERS, BUT THEY COULD USE
A LITTLE OF THE NAVY
THAT'S IN YOUR HEART,
BUT...
THAT'S THE WAY IT GOES.
WHAT DO YOU INTEND TO DO
AFTER YOU LEAVE HERE?
WELL, I'M GOING BACK
INTO THE NAVY, SIR.
WHETHER I CAN GIVE
COMMANDS OR TAKE THEM,
IT'S THE NAVY
FOR ME, SIR.
WELL, YOU'RE STILL
WITHIN THE AGE LIMIT.
YOU STILL HAVE A CHANCE TO WIN YOUR
WAY BACK HERE AND START OVER AGAIN.
SO, GOOD-BYE
AND GOOD LUCK TO YOU...
AND I HOPE THAT WE'LL
BE SHIPMATES SOMEDAY.
THANK YOU, SIR.
HELLO, COXSWAIN.
I JUST WANT TO...
TELL YOU HOW SORRY I AM,
ABOUT YOUR LEAVING
THE ACADEMY.
I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL.
DO YOU MEAN TO TELL ME
YOU KNOW HOW I FEEL?
DO YOU?
THE ACADEMY'S NEVER MEANT
ANYTHING TO YOU, AND IT NEVER WILL!
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH YOUR STUDIES
LIKE GREASED LIGHTNING AND FOR WHAT?
SO YOU CAN TURN DOWN YOUR
COMMISSION WHEN YOU GRADUATE!
DON'T YOU TRY TO TALK TO ME
ABOUT WHAT THE ACADEMY MEANS.
SAVE YOUR SYMPATHY
FOR SOMEBODY ELSE.
FORGET YOU EVER WASTED
ANY ON ME.
I CALL IT
DARN BAD LUCK.
NICE KID.
HI, FELLA!
COWBOY BROUGHT
YOUR BAG UP.
THANKS, COWBOY.
IT'S OK, KID.
THE SUPERINTENDENT
HAVE ANYTHING TO SAY?
YEAH.
HE SAID HE HOPED WE'D
BE SHIPMATES SOMEDAY.
THAT'S SWELL.
WE HOPE THAT, TOO.
SURE.
GEE, COXSWAIN, WOULDN'T IT
BE FUNNY IF WE WERE
TO COME ABOARD YOUR SHIP
AS ENSIGNS SOMEDAY
AND YOU HAD TO SAY,
"YES, SIR" TO-
HEH HEH! YEAH.
I'D LIKE TO SEE YOU TWO GUYS
TRY TO GIVE ME ORDERS.
FUNNY!
IT WON'T MAKE ME
LAUGH, KID.
I HATE
TO SEE YOU GO.
THAT KIND OF GOES
FOR ME, TOO.
REMEMBER HOW TOUGH IT WAS
TO STOW THOSE LOCKERS?
YOU KNOW HOW DUMB WE WERE, TOO,
COXSWAIN, AND YOU HAD TO HELP US?
WELL, AT... LEAST
IT WILL BE EASIER
GETTING YOUR STUFF OUT
THAN IT WAS
GETTING IT IN,
WON'T IT?
YEAH.
I GUESS I BETTER START
PACKING NOW, SPARKS.
I GUESS I BETTER BE
ALONE FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
DON'T WANT YOU TO SEE ME
MAKE A JACKASS OF MYSELF.
OH, MR. MELVILLE!
HELLO, SUSIE.
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
GLAD TO SEE YOU, TOO. WE
SURE MISS YOU AROUND HERE.
YOU KNOW, YOU LOOK
YOUNGER THAN EVER?
THE NAVY HASN'T CHANGED
YOUR LINE ANY, BUT I LOVE IT!
HELLO, MR. MELVILLE!
HI, MABEL!
HELLO,
MR. MELVILLE!
HELLO, JIMMY!
HOW ARE YOU?
BOO!
MR. MELVILLE! HAVE YOU QUIT THE NAVY?
ARE YOU BACK
WITH US FOR GOOD?
NO, NO. I'M JUST HERE
ON A LITTLE LEAVE.
IT WAS NICE TO SEE YOU.
NICE TO SEE YOU, TOO.
DICK!
HELLO, HARRY.
WELCOME HOME! HOW DO
THEY LIKE JUNE HERE?
HOW DO THEY
LIKE HER?
COME ON OVER HERE
AND SIT DOWN.
OH, BOY, THE OLD PLACE
LOOKS JUST THE SAME.
UH-HUH. YOU CAN FORGET
THE COVER CHARGE.
I'LL DO THAT.
I'M A SCHOOLBOY NOW.
I ONLY MAKE
$3.00 A MONTH.
HELLO, SWEETHEART.
OH, DICK!
HOW ARE YOU?
OH, YOU'RE A SIGHT
FOR SORE-
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
DICK MELVILLE IS HERE
IN THE SKY CLUB TONIGHT.
LET'S HAVE HIM SING!
COME ON, DICK, A SONG-
FOR OLD TIMES' SAKE.
NO, HARRY. THEY DON'T
WANT TO HEAR ME SING.
YES, THEY DO.
COME ON.
* JUST A GLANCE
* AT A DANCE
* AND IN MY HEART I KNEW
* THAT IF I EVER SHOULD CARE
* THAT I WOULD CARE FOR YOU
* THOUGH I HEARD
* NOT A WORD
* YOUR EYES BEGAN TO SAY
* A LOT OF THINGS YOUR LIPS
HAVE NEVER TOLD ME *
* TO THIS VERY DAY
* EVERY TIME YOUR LIPS
SAY, "NO, SIR" *
* I WON'T LISTEN, I'M TOO WISE
* I WOULD RATHER LISTEN
* TO YOUR EYES
* THEY HAVE TOLD ME
LOTS OF THINGS, DEAR *
* THAT YOUR BETTER SELF DENIES
* SO I'D RATHER LISTEN
* TO THOSE EYES
* THERE'S NOTHING
YOU COULD EVER SAY *
* THAT COULD CONVEY
* THE PROMISE
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR *
COME ON.
* I LOOK IN YOUR EYES
* AND REALIZE
* THEY CAN TELL ME MORE
* EYES CAN BE SINCERE
AND TRUTHFUL *
* LIPS CAN TELL
A LOT OF LIES *
* SO I'D RATHER LISTEN
* TO YOUR EYES
MIDSHIPMAN MELVILLE, SECOND
CLASS, REPORTING, SIR.
COME IN.
MELVILLE... I THINK IT
WOULD BE BETTER FOR YOU
AND FOR THE SPIRIT OF
YOUR COMPANY IN GENERAL
IF YOU SHARED A ROOM WITH SOME
OF YOUR CLASSMATES THIS YEAR.
YOU STAND FIRST
IN YOUR CLASS,
YOU'VE KEPT OFF
THE REPORT,
BUT YOUR APTITUDE- FOR-SERVICE
RECORD IS NOTHING TO BE PROUD OF.
DO YOU KNOW WHY?
YOU'RE NOT IN
A COLLEGE, MELVILLE.
THE ACADEMY IS MORE
THAN THAT.
AT A UNIVERSITY, YOU COULD GO
YOUR OWN WAY AND DO AS YOU PLEASE.
WITH YOUR SCHOLASTIC
RECORD, YOU'D GRADUATE,
PROBABLY WITH GREAT
DISTINCTION.
THEN YOUR COLLEGE
PRESIDENT WOULD SEND FOR YOU
TO WISH YOU GOOD-BYE AND
GOOD LUCK. YOU'D LEAVE.
THE COLLEGE WOULD CEASE
TO BE A PART OF YOUR LIFE.
IT'S DIFFERENT HERE.
WHEN A MIDSHIPMAN LEAVES, WE
ALWAYS SAY, "GOOD-BYE, GOOD LUCK...
AND I HOPE WE'LL
BE SHIPMATES SOMEDAY."
WHO ARE YOUR FRIENDS
IN YOUR CLASS?
I HAVE NONE, SIR.
WHY NOT?
IT WAS MY OWN
CHOICE, SIR.
I THOUGHT THAT, SINCE
I DIDN'T INTEND...
TO BE SHIPMATES
WITH MY CLASSMATES
THAT PERHAPS FRIENDSHIP
WASN'T NECESSARY.
WHAT YOU INTEND TO DO IN REGARD
TO THE ACCEPTANCE OR REJECTION
OF YOUR COMMISSION IS NOT
MY BUSINESS. IT'S YOURS.
WHAT YOUR LIFE
IS HERE MUST-
BECAUSE OF THE NATURE OF
THINGS-BE PART OF MY BUSINESS.
YOU'RE FAILING COMPLETELY IN
ONE THING THE ACADEMY HAS TO GIVE
TO A VERY GREAT
DEGREE-FRIENDSHIP.
NOW, YOU'VE HAD TWO YEARS TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS ON YOUR OWN, MELVILLE.
IT'S TIME YOU CHECKED ON YOUR
COMPASS AND CHARTED A NEW COURSE.
YOU SAY YOU HAVE
NO FRIENDS HERE.
WHOM DO YOU TRUST
AMONGST YOUR CLASSMATES?
BROWN, LINCOLN,
EVEN TED STERLING,
BUT THEY HAVE NO REASON
TO LIKE ME, SIR.
PERHAPS NOT.
MAYBE THEY HAVEN'T
BEEN GIVEN A CHANCE.
THEY MAY BE YOUR
NEW ROOMMATES.
YOU MAY GO NOW.
YES, SIR.
THIRD BATTALION, PLEASE.
THIS IS CAPTAIN DOUGLAS.
I WANT TO SEE MIDSHIPMEN
BROWN, LINCOLN, AND STERLING.
RADIO SOUNDS
MIGHTY GOOD,
RIGHT OUT IN
THE OPEN LIKE THIS.
Cowboy: SOUNDS BETTER THAN IT
DID IN YOUR MATTRESS, DOESN'T IT?
HA HA!
YOU KNOW, DICK,
I HAD A RADIO IN MY
MATTRESS WHEN I WAS A PLEBE.
YOU DID?
YEAH. SURE DID.
HI, FELLAS. SAW
A LETTER FOR YOU.
THOUGHT I'D
BRING IT OVER.
I RECOGNIZED
THE HANDWRITING.
IT'S FROM OUR GIRLFRIEND. THANKS, TED.
OH, ANYTHING FOR A
ROOMMATE, I ALWAYS SAYS.
Man: HOORAY!
OH HO! HEH!
IT AIN'T PRIVATE
ENOUGH HERE.
THEY'RE MARCHING
THROUGH THE RING, DICK.
LET'S GO BACK
AND GET IN LINE.
DARLING, I CAN'T WAIT
TO PUT THIS RING ON YOU.
LET'S SKIP IT,
DO YOU MIND?
I'D BE AWFULLY UNCOMFORTABLE UP THERE,
REALLY I WOULD.
OH, COME ON!
I'M GOING ON MY
LAST CRUISE TOMORROW.
LET'S DON'T WASTE TIME
WALKING THROUGH A RING.
I WON'T SEE YOU
FOR 3 LONG MONTHS.
WHY DID YOU PUT YOUR
RING IN YOUR POCKET?
WHY DON'T
YOU WEAR IT?
OH, THERE ARE ABOUT
450 CLASSMATES UP THERE
WHO WOULD RATHER
I WOULDN'T WEAR IT.
BUT YOU WROTE ME THAT YOU WERE
MIXING WITH YOUR CLASSMATES.
I'M TRYING TO,
BUT...
IT'S A LITTLE
TOUGH ON THEM.
I GUESS I JUST
DON'T FIT.
DARLING, WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO ON THE CRUISE?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT LET'S
DON'T TALK ABOUT IT.
ALL I WANT TO DO
IS BE WITH YOU.
OH, DARLING!
Officer: I'M LOOKING
FOR MELVILLE.
YES, SIR.
I WANT BROWN,
LINCOLN, AND STERLING.
YES, SIR. BROWN, LINCOLN, STERLING!
HAVE YOU GOT ALL THE GEAR
YOU'RE REQUIRED TO HAVE HERE?
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT,
SIGN UP ON THIS LIST.
YES, SIR.
OH, I WAS SCARED. I THOUGHT
I WASN'T GOING TO FIND YOU.
WELL, HERE WE ARE.
OH, DICK, I HAVE SUCH A
STRANGE FEELING IN MY HEART.
MINE ISN'T EXACTLY
JUMPING FOR JOY.
I DON'T MEAN THAT. I
MEAN ABOUT THE CRUISE
AND WHAT IT'S GOING
TO MEAN TO YOU.
IT JUST MEANS THAT
I'M TRADING THIS JAIL
FOR A FLOATING ONE,
THAT'S ALL.
YOU'VE MADE UP YOUR MIND
TO HATE IT, HAVEN'T YOU?
NO. IT'S JUST GOING TO BE ONE
LONG, LOVELY YACHTING TRIP.
HAVE YOU SAID GOOD-BYE TO YOUR FATHER?
NO.
I DON'T THINK
HE EXPECTED IT.
YOUR SON LEADS HIS CLASS
AGAIN THIS YEAR, SIR.
CONGRATULATIONS
ARE IN ORDER.
I KNOW WHERE HE STANDS, EVEN
THOUGH IT'S NOT ALL ON THE RECORD.
AND I KNOW THAT
YOU KNOW, DOUGLAS.
PERHAPS HE'LL GET HIS
BEARINGS ON THIS CRUISE.
HE'LL HAVE A CHANCE
TO FIND HIMSELF.
THIS CRUISE IS GOING TO
MAKE OR BREAK THAT BOY.
THIS IS HIS LAST CHANCE
TO PROVE HIS COURSE.
AM I ALL YOU'VE GOT TO
SAY GOOD-BYE TO, DICK?
LET'S JUST MAKE IT
"YOU'RE ALL I'VE GOT."
THAT COVERS EVERYTHING.
Sparks: WELL! IF IT ISN'T
LITTLE JUNE AND BIG RICHARD.
Cowboy: MIND IF
WE CRASH HERE?
WHY, SURE I'D-
YOU SEE, MY FOLKS ARE
ARKANSAS HILLBILLIES,
AND HIS FOLKS HAD TO MILK
THE STEERS IN ARIZONA.
WHOA, YOU
DARN FOOL.
YOU CAN'T
MILK A STEER.
YOU OUGHT TO
COME TO ARKANSAS.
WE CROSS OUR STEERS WITH
GOATS, AND THEY MILK FINE.
WHAT SPARKY'S
TRYING TO SAY IS
THAT SINCE
WE FELLAS HAVE
NO FOLKS OF OUR OWN HERE
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO US,
WE MIGHT AS WELL SAY
GOOD-BYE TO EACH OTHER.
OH, I SEE.
WELL, I-AH-GUESS
IT WON'T BE LONG NOW.
YEAH, I-I GUESS
WE MIGHT AS WELL
GET DOWN TO THIS KISSING
BUSINESS RIGHT NOW.
HOW'S ABOUT IT,
SWEETIE?
READY AND WAITING, SIR.
LOOKS LIKE WE CAN'T DO IT
IN PRIVATE THIS TIME, KID.
KIND OF LOOKS
LIKE THAT, COWBOY.
WELL, LET'S GET
AT IT THEN, HUH?
WELL, I GUESS
WE MIGHT AS WELL.
I FEEL AWFULLY
EMPTY, DICK.
I'LL BE BACK
IN 3 MONTHS.
WILL YOU BE
DIFFERENT THEN?
DO YOU WANT ME TO BE?
IN A WAY I MEAN YES,
WITH ALL MY HEART.
I'M-
I WAS A NAVY GIRL.
I'VE SAID GOOD-BYE LIKE
THIS TO DAD, JIMMY...
BUT IT'S DIFFERENT
WITH YOU.
BUT NAVY WAS THEIR
LIFE, DARLING.
DON'T LISTEN TO ME.
MAYBE THAT'S
WHAT I MEAN.
MAYBE I WANT NAVY TO BE YOUR LIFE.
GOOD-BYE, DARLING.
GOOD-BYE, DEAR.
GOOD-BYE.
All, shouting:
NAAAVY!
N! N! N! N!
A! A! A! A!
V! V! V! V!
Y! Y! Y! Y!
NAAAAAVY!
SWEETHEART!
BROTHERS, THE OPEN
SEA HAS GOT ME.
IT'S SHIPBOARD,
NOT CLASSROOMS.
THE WIDE OPEN SEA.
Sparks:
NOT GRAY WALLS.
NO BOOMING THE BOOKS
AND NO PEE-RADE.
PIPE DOWN, YOU!
All: COXSWAIN!
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
Sparks: WHERE'D YOU COME FROM?
BEG TO REPORT, SIRS, THAT
I'VE JUST TAKEN AND PASSED
MY NEW EXAMINATION
FOR RE-ENTRANCE
TO THE UNITED STATES
NAVAL ACADEMY, SIRS.
AND THIS TIME, BY GOLLY,
I'M GOING TO MAKE IT.
BECAUSE YOU
KNOW WHERE I AM?
Together: WHERE?
I'M IN THE OLD
BOILER ROOM,
RIGHT DOWN IN THE STEAM
THAT I BILGED OUT ON.
ASK ME SOMETHING ABOUT A DOUBLE
REDUCTION GEARED TURBINE, I DARE YOU!
BOY, I'LL BE A
FIRST CLASSMAN
WHEN YOU START IN AS A PLEBE AGAIN.
COXSWAIN, YOU MAKE
IT THIS TIME, BOY,
AND WE'LL BE
ENSIGNS TOGETHER.
SAY, WHATEVER HAPPENED TO DICK MELVILLE?
HE'S RIGHT
OVER THERE.
Coxswain: I WANT TO TALK TO DICK.
HELLO, DICK.
HEY. HELLO, COXSWAIN.
BACK IN THE NAVY, HUH?
UH-HUH.
IT'S NICE
TO SEE YOU.
THANKS. NICE
SAY, DICK... SOMETHING
I WANT TO SAY TO YOU.
I REMEMBER ONCE YOU
HAD A LOT TO SAY TO ME.
THAT'S JUST IT.
I HAVEN'T FORGOTTEN
HOW I BLEW UP
MY LAST DAY.
OH.
OH, YOU MEANT
ALL RIGHT.
I KIND OF
SHOT OFF MY MOUTH,
BUT I WAS SORRY
ABOUT IT AFTERWARDS.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
SHALL WE?
SURE, FORGET IT.
GEE, THAT WAS
AN AWFUL BAD DAY.
EVERYTHING'S SWELL NOW.
I'M STARTING BACK AT
THE ACADEMY NEXT TERM.
YOU ARE?
YEAH.
HEY, THAT'S GREAT. I KNOW
HOW MUCH THAT MEANS TO YOU.
I
- I HOPE WE'LL STAND ON WATCH TOGETHER SOMEDAY.
THANKS, COXSWAIN.
DICKY.
WHERE'S YOUR CLASS RING?
LOSE IT?
NO. I'VE GOT IT,
SPARKS.
BOY, I WOULDN'T GO
TO SLEEP WITHOUT MINE ON.
WHAT ARE YOU SAVING IT FOR,
YOUR GRANDCHILDREN?
I SURE LOADED ENOUGH
DUMMY SHELLS TODAY.
THAT'LL KEEP
YOU FROM BEING
A DUMMY WHEN WE REALLY
GET STARTED SHOOTING.
HOW ABOUT
A SONG, DICK?
WE HAVEN'T HEARD YOU SING
SINCE WE WERE PLEBES.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
LOST YOUR VOICE?
COME ON, DICK.
SING SOMETHING
FOR US, WILL YOU?
NO, YOU FELLOWS GO
AHEAD AND SING A SONG.
THAT HEAT HAS KIND OF
WARPED MY VOCAL CORDS.
Sparks: HEY, DENNY.
DRAG OUT AND DUST OFF THAT
NAVY SONG DICK GAVE BIRTH TO.
Denny:
OK, SPARKS.
All: * SHIPMATES,
STAND TOGETHER *
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
* FAIR OR STORMY WEATHER
* WE WON'T GIVE UP,
WE WON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP *
* FRIENDS AND PALS FOREVER,
IT'S A LONG, LONG TRIP *
* IF YOU HAVE TO TAKE A LICKING,
CARRY ON AND QUIT YOUR KICKING *
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
* SHIPMATES,
STAND TOGETHER *
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
* FAIR OR STORMY WEATHER
* WE WON'T GIVE UP
THE SHIP *
* FRIENDS AND PALS FOREVER
* IT'S A LONG, LONG TRIP
* IF YOU HAVE TO
TAKE A LICKING *
* CARRY ON
* AND QUIT YOUR KICKING
* DON'T GIVE UP THE SHIP
GENERAL QUARTERS, ALL HANDS.
MAN YOUR BATTLE STATIONS.
GUN TWO,
MANNED AND READY.
GUN TWO, MANNED
AND READY.
COMING ON THE RANGE,
COMING ON THE RANGE.
RANGE 1-8-DOUBLE 0,
RANGE 1-8-DOUBLE 0.
SCALE 9-6, SCALE 9-6.
RANGE 1-8-DOUBLE 0,
RANGE 1-8-DOUBLE 0.
SCALE 9-6,
SCALE 9-6.
RANGE 1-8-DOUBLE
0, SCALE 9-6.
SET TWO.
STAND BY, STAND BY.
STAND BY,
STAND BY.
COMMENCE FIRING,
COMMENCE FIRING.
YOUR BOILER.
CLEAR THE FIRE ROOM.
CASUALTY IN BOILER ROOM NUMBER TWO, SIR.
CEASE FIRING,
CEASE FIRING.
WHITE POWDER TOPSIDE.
CLOSE THE AMMUNITION HATCHES.
WE GOTTA
SHUT OFF THE OIL!
HEY, COXSWAIN!
COXSWAIN.
COXSWAIN!
FLAREBACK IN BOILER
ROOM NUMBER TWO, SIR.
BUGLER, BUGLER!
SOUND FIRE CALL.
AYE AYE, SIR.
COXSWAIN!
Dick: COXSWAIN. COXSWAIN.
Doctor: ONE OF
THE BOYS IS DYING.
I DON'T KNOW WHICH ONE IS
MELVILLE AND WHICH IS LAWRENCE.
SCALDING AND FIRE
MADE THEM ALIKE.
POOR KIDS.
Nurse: WE'RE READY,
DOCTOR.
THIS BOY WAS WEARING
AN ACADEMY RING.
HERE IT IS, SIR.
THEN...
THIS IS MY SON.
LET'S DOUBLE-TIME IT
OVER TO THE HOSPITAL.
WE GOT PERMISSION
TO SEE HIM?
WE'RE HIS FIRST VISITORS. LET'S GO!
HELLO, SON.
HELLO, DAD.
WHAT'S THAT, SON?
DID... COXSWAIN
COME OUT OK?
COXSWAIN CAME OUT FINE,
SON.
HE WON WHAT HE LIVED FOR.
GEE. THAT'S GREAT.
WE HAVE PERMISSION TO
SEE MIDSHIPMAN MELVILLE.
Nurse: THE ADMIRAL IS IN THERE NOW.
YOU'LL HAVE
TO WAIT.
Midshipmen:
GOOD AFTERNOON, SIR.
GENTLEMEN.
NOW YOU MAY GO IN.
HI, DICK.
HOW DO YOU FEEL,
DICKIE BIRD?
YEAH.
YOU LOOK SWELL.
GEE, FELLAS, IT...
DON'T TALK IF IT'S
HARD FOR YOU, BOY.
WE'LL DO
THE TALKING FOR YOU.
Sparks:
WON'T WE, FELLAS?
Cowboy: SURE, DICK. WE'LL DO
THE TALKING. YOU JUST LISTEN.
I... I JUST WANTED
TO TELL YOU
THE BOYS WERE ALL
ASKING HOW YOU WERE.
SENT YOU THEIR BEST.
Nurse:
TIME'S UP, BOYS.
WELL,...
HASTA LA VISTA, DICK,
AS WE SAY BACK HOME.
THERE'S A LOT I HAVEN'T SAID, DICK,
THAT I
- THAT I WISH I COULD SAY.
HURRY UP AND
GET WELL, SHIPMATE.
WE WANT YOU BACK.
THANKS, SPARKS.
I'LL GET WELL.
NO, NO, NO. I'LL GET IT, THANKS.
I WANT TO SURPRISE THE FELLAS THERE.
THANK YOU.
Men: DICK!
MELVILLE'S BACK!
Man: GLAD TO
SEE YOU BACK.
I'M GLAD TO BE BACK, CHIEF, THANKS.
Men: HEY, DICK!
HELLO, GANG!
HOW ARE YOU?
WELCOME HOME,
DICK!
GLAD TO BE BACK.
HOW WERE THE NURSES, DICK?
OH, THE NURSES
WERE SWELL!
IN THE ROOM...
I WON'T TELL YOU.
HERE IT IS, 3305!
Man: BOY, IT'S SURE NICE
HAVING YOU BACK, DICK.
Crowd: SEE YOU LATER, DICK! SO LONG!
Man, outside: OK, FELLAS. LET'S
GIVE A YELL FOR DICK MELVILLE.
READY, Y'ALL?
HIP, HIP-
Crowd: HOORAY, HOORAY, RAH, RAH!
MELVILLE, MELVILLE,
MELVILLE! HOORAY!
IS THIS MY UNIFORM?
YUP. COMPANY COMMANDER
FOR THE NEW TERM.
THAT'S YOU, DICKIE BOY.
Cowboy: YOU
EARNED IT, DICKIE.
I'M SORRY, FELLAS.
I CAN'T HELP IT.
Officer: ORDERS!
HO!
CALL OUT COMPANY 4
FOR PRESENTATION!
FORM A COLUMN OF SQUADS,
LEADING PLATOON.
RIGHT FACE SQUADS.
Second Officer:
RIGHT FACE SQUADS!
MARCH!
THIS IS THE HAPPIEST
DAY OF MY LIFE-SO FAR.
THERE ARE MANY HAPPIER DAYS AHEAD
FOR YOU,
MY DEAR.
BUT I ASK
FOR NO MORE
THAN THE DAY HATH BROUGHT TO ME.
Speaker: I PROPOSE 3 CHEERS FOR
THOSE WHO ARE ABOUT TO LEAVE US!
HIP, HIP-
Class: HOORAY!
HOORAY!
HIP, HIP-
I PROPOSE 3 CHEERS
FOR THOSE WE LEAVE BEHIND US!
HIP, HIP-
HOORAY!
RELAX.
FOR THE
HUNDREDTH TIME,
THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED
STATES WON'T LET ME MARRY YOU
UNTIL TWO YEARS
AFTER GRADUATION.
NOW, PET.
HOW DO I LOOK?
LOOKS OK, COWBOY.
FEELS OK.
YOU'RE OK, TOO.
OH, NO. IT AIN'T
PRIVATE ENOUGH HERE.