RUTH ELIAS (ISRAEL)
Crematorium V
At the end of February,
I was in a night squad
at Crematorium V.
Around midnight,
there appeared
a man from
the political section:
Oberscharfuhrer Hustek.
He handed Oberscharfuhrer
Voss a note.
Voss was then in charge
of the 4 crematoria.
I saw
Voss unfold the note
and talk to himself,
saying, "Sure, always Voss.
"What'd they do without Voss?
How can we do it?"
That's how he talked
to himself.
Suddenly he told me,
"Go get the kapos".
I fetched the kapos,
kapo Schloime,
and kapo Wacek.
They came in,
and he asked them:
"How many pieces
are left?"
By "pieces" he meant bodies.
They told him:
"Around 500 pieces."
He said: "By morning,
those 500 pieces must be
"reduced to ashes.
"You're sure it's 500?"
"Just about", they said.
"Assholes! What do you mean
"just about"?"
Then he left
for the "undressing room"
to see for himself.
Where the bodies were.
They were piled there:
At Crematorium V, the
"Undressing room" also serve
as a warehouse for bodies
After the gassing?
After the gassing the bodies
were dragged there.
Voss went there to check.
He forgot the note
leaving it on the table.
I quickly scanned it
and was shocked
by what I read.
BIRKENAU
The lake of ashes
The crematorium was
to be gotten ready
for "special treatment"
of the Czech family camp.
In the morning, when
the day squad came on,
I ran into kapo Kaminski,
one of the Resistance
leaders in the "special detail"
and told him the news.
He informed me
that Crematorium II
was also being prepared.
That the ovens were
ready there, too.
And he exhorted me:
"You have friends
and fellow-countrymen.
"Go see them. They're
locksmiths and can move around
"so they can go
to Camp B II B.
"Tell them to warn
these people
"of what's
in store for them
"and say that if they defend
themselves, we'll reduce
"the crematoria to ashes.
"And at camp B II B,
they can immediately
"burn down
their barracks."
We were certain
that the next night,
these people
would be gassed.
But when no night squad
went out, we were relieved.
The deadline had been
postponed for a few days.
But many prisoners,
including the Czechs
in the family camp,
accused us of spreading panic
of having
circulated
false reports.
That night I was
at Crematorium II.
As soon as the people
got out of the vans,
they were blinded
by floodlights
and forced through
a corridor
to the stairs leading to
the "undressing room".
They were blinded,
made to run.
Blows were rained on them.
Those who didn't run fast
enough were beaten to death.
By the SS.
The violence used against
them was extraordinary.
And suddenly...
Without explanation?
Not a word. As soon as
they left the vans,
the beatings began.
When they entered
the "undressing room",
I was standing near
the rear door,
and from there
I witnessed
the frightful scene.
The people were bloodied.
They knew
then where they were.
They stared at the pillars
of the so-called
"International Information
Center" I've mentioned,
and that terrified them.
What they read
didn't reassure them.
On the contrary,
it panicked them.
They knew the score.
They'd learned
at Camp B II B
what went on there.
They were in despair.
Children clung to each other.
Their mothers,
their parents,
the old people all cried,
overcome with misery.
Suddenly,
some SS officers appeared
on the steps,
including the camp
commandant, Schwarzhuber.
He'd given them his word
as an SS officer
that they'd be
transferred
to Heidebreck.
So they all began
to cry out,
to beg, shouting:
"Heidebreck was a trick!
"We were lied to! We want
to live! We want to work!"
They looked their SS
executioners in the eye,
but the SS men
remained impassive,
just staring at them. There
was a movement in the crowd.
They probably wanted
to rush to the SS men
and tell them how
they'd been lied to,
then some guards
surged forward,
wielding clubs,
and more people
were injured.
In the "undressing room"?
Yes.
The violence climaxed
when they tried to force
the people to undress.
A few obeyed,
only a handful.
Most of them refused
to follow the order.
Suddenly, as though
in chorus
like a chorus...
they all began to sing.
The whole "undressing room"
rang
with the Czech
national anthem,
and the "Hatikva".
That moved me terribly,
that...
Please stop!
That was happening
to my countrymen,
and I realized
that my life
had become meaningless.
Why go on living?
For what?
So I went into
the gas-chamber with them,
resolved to die.
With them.
Suddenly, some who recognize
me came up to me. For
my locksmith friends
and I had sometimes
gone into
the family camp.
A small group
of women approached.
They looked at me and said
right there in the gas-chamber.
You were inside
the gas-chamber?
One of them said:
"So you want to die.
But that's senseless.
"Your death won't give us
back our lives.
"That's no way.
"You must get out of
here alive,
"you must bear witness
to our suffering,
"and to the injustice
done to us."
RUDOLF VRBA
and h is friend WETZLER
escaped on April 7, 1944.
Several prisoners had previously
tried to flee, but all were caught.
JAN KARSKY,
University Professor (USA)
Former courier of the Polish
Government in exile
NEW YORK
WASHINGTON
The RU H R
AU SC HWITZ - BIRKEN AU
WARS AW
Next figure:
Dr FRANZ GRASSLER,
deputy to AU ERS WALD,
the Nazi Commissioner
of the WARS AW ghetto.
You don't remember
those days?
Not much.
I recall more clearly
my pre-war
mountaineering trips than
the entire war period
and those days in Warsaw.
All in all,
those were bad times.
It's a fact: We tend
to forget, thank God,
the bad times more easily
than the good.
The bad times
are repressed.
I'll help you remember...
In Warsaw you were
Dr. Auerswald's deputy.
Yes.
Dr. Auerswald was...
Commissioner of the
"Jewish district" of Warsaw.
Dr. Grassler, this is
Czerniakow's diary.
You're mentioned in it.
It's been printed,
it exists?
He kept a diary
that was recently
published.
He wrote on July 7, 1941:
July 7, 1941? That's the
first time I've re-learned a date.
May I take notes?
After all...
it interests me too.
So in July I was
already there!
He wrote on July 7, 1941:
"Morning in the Community"
- the Jewish Council HQ...
"and later with
Auerswald, Schlosser..."
Schlosser was...
"And Grassler,
"on routine matters."
That's the first time...
That my name is mentioned...
Yes, but there were 3 of us.
Schlosser... was in...
the "economic department".
I think he had to do
with economics.
And the second time
was on July 22.
C ZERN IAKOW was president
of the Warsaw Jewish Council
He wrote every day?
Yes.
Yes, every day.
It's quite amazing
that the diary was saved.
It's amazing
that it was saved.
BURLINGTON - VERMONT
(U.S.A.)
RAUL HILBERG
Did you go
into the ghetto?
Seldom. When I had
to visit Czerniakow.
What were
the conditions like?
Awful. Yes, appalling.
Yes?
I never went back when
I saw what it was like.
Unless I had to:
In the whole period
I think I only went
once or twice.
We, at the Commission,
tried
to maintain the ghetto
for its labor force,
and especially to prevent
epidemic, like typhus.
That was the big danger.
Yes.
Yes?
Can you tell us
about typhus?
I'm not a doctor.
I only know that typhus
is a very dangerous
epidemic
that wipes people out
like the plague,
and that it can't be
confined to a ghetto.
If typhus had broken out...
I don't think it did,
but there was fear
that if might...
it would have it the Poles
and the Germans.
Why was there typhus
in the ghetto?
I don't know if there was,
but there was a danger,
because of the famine.
People didn't get
enough to eat.
That's what was so awful.
We at the Commission,
did our best to feed
the ghetto,
so it wouldn't become
an incubator of epidemics.
Aside from humanitarian
factors, that's what mattered.
If typhus had broken out...
and it didn't...
it wouldn't have stopped
at the ghetto.
Czerniakow also wrote:
That one of the reasons
the ghetto was walled in
was because
of this German fear.
Yes, absolutely!
Fear of typhus.
He says Germans always
associated Jews with typhus.
Maybe. I'm not sure if there
were grounds for it.
But imagine that mass
of people
packed in the ghetto...
There weren't only
the Warsaw Jews,
but others who came later.
The danger kept
on growing.
The Germans had a policy
on the Warsaw ghetto.
What was that policy?
You're asking
more than I know.
The policy that wound up
with extermination,
the Final Solution...
we knew nothing about it.
Our job was
to maintain the ghetto,
and try to preserve
the Jews as a work force.
The Commission's goal,
in fact, was
very different from
the one that later
led to extermination.
Yes, but do you know
how many people died
in the ghetto
each month in 1941?
I don't know now...
if I ever knew it.
But you did know.
There are exact figures.
I probably knew...
Yes: 5,000 a month.
5,000 a month? Yes, well...
That's a lot.
That's a lot, of course.
But there were
far too many people in
the ghetto. That was it.
Far too many.
My question is philosophical.
What does a ghetto mean,
in your opinion?
History's full of ghettos,
going back centuries,
for all I know.
Persecution of the Jews
wasn't a German invention,
and it didn't start
with World War II.
The Poles persecuted
them too.
But a ghetto like Warsaw's,
in a great capital,
in the heart of the city
that was unusual.
You say you wanted
to maintain the ghetto.
Our mission wasn't
to annihilate the ghetto,
but to keep it alive,
to maintain it.
What does "alive"
mean in such
That was the problem.
That was the whole problem...
But people were dying
in the streets.
There were bodies everywhere.
Yes.
That was the paradox.
You see it as a paradox?
I'm sure of it.
Why? Can you explain?
No.
Why not?
Explain what?
But the fact is...
Jews were being exterminated
daily in the ghetto.
Czerniakow wrote...
To maintain it properly
we'd have needed
more substantial rations,
and less crowding.
Why weren't the rations
more humane?
Why weren't they?
That was a German
decision, no?
There was no real decision
to starve the ghetto.
The big decision to
exterminate came much later.
That's right, later.
In 1942.
Precisely!
3 years later.
Just so. Our mission,
as I recall it,
was to manage the ghetto,
and, naturally, with those
inadequate rations,
and the overcrowding,
a high, even excessive,
death rate was inevitable.
Yes.
What does "maintain" the
ghetto mean in such condition...
the food, sanitation, etc?
What would the Jews do
against such measures?
They couldn't do anything.
The Final Solution Conference
was held here
BELZEC - Site
of the extermination camp
Why did Czerniakow
commit suicide?
Because he realized
there was no future
for the ghetto.
He probably saw before I did
that the Jews would be killed.
I suppose the Jews
already had
their excellent
secret services.
They were too well informed,
better than we were.
Think so?
Yes, I do.
The Jews knew more than you?
I'm convinced of it!
It's hard to believe.
The German administration
was never informed
of what would happened
to the Jews.
When was the first
deportation to Treblinka?
Before Auerswald's suicide,
I think.
Auerswald's?
I mean Czerniakow's. Sorry.
July 22.
Those are dates...
So the deportations began
July 22, 1942.
Yes.
To... Treblinka.
And Czerniakow killed
himself July 23.
Yes, that is...
The next day.
The next day. So that was it,
he'd realized
that his idea...
It was his idea, I think
of working in good faith
with the Germans,
in the Jews' best interests.
He'd realized this idea,
this dream, was destroyed.
That the idea was a dream.
Yes. And when
the dream faded,
he took the logical way out.
Did you think this idea
of a ghetto was a good one?
A sort of self-management,
right?
That's right.
A mini-State?
It worked well.
But it was self-management
for death, no?
We know that now.
But at the time...
Even then!
No!
Czerniakow wrote:
"We're puppets,
we have no power".
Yes.
No power.
Sure... that was...
You Germans
were the overlords.
Yes.
The overlords. The masters.
Obviously.
Czerniakow was merely a tool.
Yes, but a good tool.
Jewish self-management
worked well, I can tell you.
It worked well for 3 years,
1941, 1942, 1943... 21/2
years... and in the end...
In the end...
"Worked well" for what?
To what end?
For self-preservation.
No! For death!
Yes, but...
Self-management,
self-preservation...
That's easy to say now.
You admitted the conditions
were inhuman.
Atrocious... horrible!
Yes.
So it was clear even then...
No! Extermination
wasn't clear.
Now we see the result.
Extermination isn't so
simple. One step was taken,
then another, and another,
and another...
Yes.
But to understand
the process, one must...
I repeat: Extermination
did not take place in
the ghetto, not at first.
Only with the evacuations.
Evacuations?
The evacuations
to Treblinka.
The ghetto could have been
wiped out with weapons,
as was finally done,
after the rebellion.
After I'd left.
But at the start...
Mr. Lanzmann, this is
getting us nowhere.
We're reaching no
new conclusions.
I don't think we can.
I didn't know
then what I know now.
You weren't a nonentity.
But I was!
You were important.
You overestimate my role.
No.
You were 2nd
to the Commissioner
of the Warsaw
"Jewish district".
But I had no power.
It was something.
You were part of the vast
German power structure.
Correct. But a small part.
You overestimate the authority
of a deputy of 28 then.
- You were 30.
- 28.
At 30, you were...
you were mature.
Yes, but for a lawyer
who got his degree at 27,
it's just a beginning.
You had a doctorate.
The title proves nothing.
Did Auerswald have one too?
No. But the title's
irrelevant.
Doctor of Law...
What did you do
after the war?
I was with a mountaineering
publishing house.
That so?
I wrote and published
mountain guide books.
I published a climbers'
magazine.
Is climbing
your main interest?
Yes.
The mountains, the air...
The sun, the pure air...
Not like the ghetto air.
N EW YORK.
GERTRU DE SC H N EIDER
and her mother.
LOHAME HAGHETTAOT
KIBBUTZ MUSEUM.
Ghetto fighters' Kibbutz
- ISRAEL.
The Jewish Combat Organization
J.C.O. In the Warsaw ghetto
was officially formed
on July 28, 1942.
After the first mass
deportation to Treblinka,
which was interrupted
on Sept. 30,
some 60,000 Jews
remained in the ghetto.
On January 18, 1943, the
deportations were resumed.
Despite a severe lack
of weapons,
the members of the J.C.O.
Called for resistance,
and started fighting, to the
Germans' total surprise.
It lasted 3 days.
The Nazis withdrew
with losses,
abandoning weapons
the Jews grabbed.
The deportations
were stopped.
The Germans now knew
they had to fight
to conquer the ghetto.
The battle began on the
evening of April 19, 1943,
the eve of Pessach
Passover.
It had to be a fight
to as the death.
SIMHA ROTTEM,
know as "Kajik".
ITZHAK ZUCKERMANN,
know as "Antek",
2nd in command of the J.C.O.
I began drinking
after the war.
It was very difficult.
Claude, you asked
for my impression.
If you could lick my heart,
it would poison you.
At the request
of Mordechai Anielewicz,
commander-in-chief
of the J.C.O.,
Antek had left the ghetto 6
days before the German attack.
His mission:
To ask Polish Resistance
leaders to arm the Jews.
They refused.
I don't think the human
tongue can describe
the horror we went
through in the ghetto.
In the streets, if you
can call them that,
for nothing was left
of the streets,
we had to step
over heaps of corpses.
There was no room
to pass beside them.
Besides fighting the Germans
we fought hunger
and thirst.
We had no contact
with the outside world,
we were completely isolated,
cut off from the world.
We were in such a state
that we could
no longer understand
the very meaning of
why we went on fighting.
We thought of attempting
a break-out
to the Aryan part of
Warsaw, outside the ghetto.
Just before May I,
Sigmund and I were sent
to try to contact
Antek in Aryan Warsaw.
We found a tunnel
under Bonifratrska Street
that led out
into Aryan Warsaw.
Early in the morning,
we suddenly emerged into
a street in broad daylight.
Imagine us
on that sunny May 1,
stunned to find ourselves in
the street, among normal people.
We'd come from
another planet.
People immediately
jumped on us
because we certainly
looked exhausted,
skinny, in rags.
Around the ghetto,
there were always
suspicious Poles
who grabbed Jews.
By a miracle,
we escaped them.
In Aryan Warsaw,
life went on as naturally
and normally as before.
The cafés operated normally,
the restaurants,
buses, streetcars...
The movies were open.
The ghetto was an isolated
island amid normal life.
Our job was to contact
ltzhak Zuckermann
to try to mount
a rescue operation,
to try to save
the few fighters who might
still be alive in the ghetto.
We managed
to contact Zuckermann.
We found two sewer workers.
On the night of May 8-9,
we decided to return
to the ghetto
with another buddy,
Riszek, and the 2 sewers.
After the curfew,
we entered the sewers.
We were entirely at the
mercy of the two workmen,
since only they knew the
ghetto's underground layout.
Halfway there,
they decided to turn back,
they tried to drop us,
and we had to threaten
them with our guns.
We went on through
the sewers,
until one of the workmen
told us
we were under the ghetto.
Riszek guarded them
so they couldn't escape.
MILA 18. J.C. O
bunker headquarters
I raised the manhole cover
to go up into the ghetto.
At bunker Mila 18,
I missed them by a day.
I had returned
the night of May 8-9.
The Germans found the bunker
on the morning of the 8th.
WARS AW the monument
to the ghetto fighters
Most of its survivors
committed suicide,
or succumbed to gas
in the bunkers.
The replica of the monument
to the ghetto fighters
I went to bunker
Francziskanska 22.
There was no answer when
I yelled the password,
so I had to go
on through the ghetto.
I suddenly heard a woman
calling from the ruins.
It was darkest night,
no lights, you saw nothing.
All the houses were in ruins
and I heard only one voice.
I thought
some evil spell
had been cast on me,
a woman's voice talking
from the rubble.
I circled the ruins.
I didn't look at my watch,
but I must have spent
a half-hour exploring,
trying to find the woman
whose voice guided me,
but, unfortunately,
I didn't find her.
Were there fires?
Strictly speaking, no, for
the flames had died down,
but there was still smoke,
and that awful smell
of charred flesh
of people who had surely
been burned alive.
I continued on my way,
going to other bunkers
in search of fighting units,
but it was
the same everywhere.
I'd give the password:
"Jan".
That's a Polish first name,
Jan.
Right. And I got no answer.
I went from bunker
to bunker
and after walking
for hours in the ghetto,
I went back
toward the sewers.
Was he alone then?
Yes, I was alone
all the time.
Except for
that woman's voice,
and a man I met as
I came out of the sewers,
I was alone throughout
my tour of the ghetto.
I didn't meet a living soul.
At one point, I recall
feeling a kind of peace,
of serenity,
when I said to myself,
"I'm the last Jew.
"I'll wait for morning
and for the Germans."