Sorry, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Hey, you could help me.
I'm sorry.
Since we left
Saint-Lazare, I no longer exist.
And Félix, my canary?
Here. Here you are.
Thank you for this.
What a trip.
3 leagues of walking,
2 hours by patache,
a night on the railroad
and the omnibus.
At last, we've arrived.
Paris is beautiful.
But big.
We'll get lost.
Uncle Baudu will pilot us.
He doesn't even know us.
He'll be
all the happier for it.
Where does the emperor live?
We'll deal with that later.
We'll get the uncle.
Monsieur?
Rue Saint-Augustin?
First on the left.
What next?
"What's next?
You need to be led
by the hand?
We're not from around here.
It's obvious you're coming.
You have to be a hillbilly to get lost.
Be kind.
Or else what?
Little brat!
Redneck! Dummy!
Oh, look.
Au bonheur des dames.
It's a real palace.
That's where he lives,
the emperor?
I'd never have thought
stores this big.
We sell everything.
Even drums.
Oh, look.
The sales girls are pretty.
We have to choose them.
Yes. Especially for you.
I'm sending you
my portrait?
Yes. As soon as I have
an address.
Monsieur Baugé,
the top hat is compulsory.
Excuse me.
First
and final warning.
The assistant manager
supervises the entrance.
He's going to force us
to wear frac.
No comments.
Final warning.
Hello everyone.
With this, it will be?
A gibus, one.
And shiny.
- A rosé, quickly.
Yes, monsieur.
White wine?
No time.
- Why do they change
their hats?
- They have several.
Why do they do that?
To look cool.
Since it's expensive,
we put it on just to get in.
Like this,
we don't wear it out.
Why did he tell me that?
This is the place.
Come on.
How small.
And sad.
The other houses
suffocate him.
Mr Baudu,
please.
Is it here?
Can we see it?
- Not in a million years.
Do you want to strangle me?
It's theft!
- Monsieur Baudu.
Anger leads you astray.
I'm not angry.
I say what is.
Baudu never minced
mince his words,
nor hidden his opinions.
For 35 years
of serving you.
35 years!
Yes, you're one of
one of our longest-standing customers.
That doesn't stop you
from upselling me.
Come on, come on...
Don't be
your sacristan air.
The Lyonnais,
is calotin and company.
Thank you for your time. Not in the morning.
We make this fabric for you
3.50 francs per meter.
We earn almost nothing.
What's up?
Why do you sell it for 3.40 francs
at Le Bonheur des dames.
I asked around.
Le Bonheur des dames
orders 10,000 meters.
I won't sacrifice 34,000 F
to please you.
We'll give you
credit.
You'll sign drafts.
"Drafts?
Me?
Why not?
Baudu has never owed anyone anything.
He only buys what he can afford.
"Drafts! An honest man
doesn't sign drafts!
Le Bonheur des dames has signed some.
You're not going to compare
Old Elbeuf to this bazaar.
It's an insult
to honest businesses.
With his fake luxury,
he steals our customers.
He who laughs last, laughs hardest.
Come on.
To get back to the question...
3,40 F. No more
than Le Bonheur des dames.
Impossible.
Well, bye.
I'll take my business elsewhere.
I'm sorry.
Tell the Carrezou house
that I'll be waiting for them.
When Mouret
won't pay his bills,
they'll know I was right.
But it will be too late.
For Le Bonheur des dames will collapse
with a crash of scandal,
dragging homes like yours
homes like yours,
who let themselves be tricked.
Too bad for you.
I'll be watching this revenge
on my doorstep.
I want to see Mouret
chased away by the bailiff,
taken away by the police.
He will pass in front of me
between the gendarmes.
I won't say anything to him.
You don't insult a defeated man.
But I'll buy drinks
for the whole neighborhood.
What can I do for you?
Good morning, Uncle.
Hello.
- Hi, Uncle.
Who are you?
We are the children
of your brother Charles.
So you've
left Valognes?
Jean found a job.
At an ivory works.
I had lost mine.
We remembered your letter...
Ah...
I wrote you this 2 years ago,
when your parents died.
Well,
I said what we usually say.
But you'd be surprised
into people's homes without warning.
And three, all of a sudden.
Penniless, of course.
Excuse us, Uncle.
Where are you going?
You stay here.
What a character!
I don't have the right
to say what I think, then?
Geneviève!
But today..,
we'll work it out as best we can.
Then we'll try
to fit you in somewhere.
What's your name?
Denise.
And you, Amédée?
No. Jean.
And me, Pépé.
And him, Félix.
Here's your cousin.
Charles's children.
They come from Normandy.
We need to house them.
Jean and Pépé will sleep
in Jules' room,
my daughter's fiancé.
Jules Colomban,
my first clerk.
As for Denise,
she'll sleep with you.
If you hadn't
postponed my wedding,
my room would be free.
You could have shared it.
Uncle...
What do you want now?
We won't be disturbing
for long.
I'm going to look
for work.
"Work,
you poor thing?
There's none
for anyone here.
From 3 clerks,
I went down to one.
We don't sell anything.
Why not?
"Why?"
A buccaneer, an adventurer
has moved in next door,
and he hustles customers
like a carnival barker.
Here, take a look.
That's the one.
From the back,
near the car.
It's Mouret.
All night long,
it's a wedding.
It's a waste of money
with funny girls.
And by day, other women
enrich it.
Look at them laugh.
They're tickled.
He has to tell them
to them, the arsouille.
Be the pretty one,
murderer!
What if we could hear you?
He killed his wife.
"Killed?
- No, he's not. Daddy exaggerates.
She fell
while visiting the works
du Bonheur des dames.
A house
she had brought him as a dowry.
She was a holy woman.
But he forgot her.
He has a portrait of her
in the office.
It's the least
he owes her.
Le Bonheur des dames
can proudly display its façade,
there's blood
under its stones.
A woman like you
can't hesitate.
I have a small store here.
Next door, Father Baudu's store.
Further on, the hotel
you want to sell.
I already have a buyer.
Who's interested?
You.
You?
It's to buy it
that you brought me here.
I've got something better than that.
What is it?
An association.
You're the land.
You're the genius.
Let's just say my business sense.
I shoot the Duvillard Hotel,
Baudu's store...
Will he want to sell?
Yes.
And we'll make Le Bonheur des dames
the world's biggest department store.
As you go,
dear sir.
It's an excellent deal.
What about customers?
"Customers?
Yes.
Come and see for yourself.
Customers?
But here it is.
All women.
In the palace
that I will build,
there will be
everything they need.
That is to say
that which is useless to them.
How well do you know them?
I like them.
That's why I'm in this business.
Business
in an alcove atmosphere.
Charm to sell.
I return the compliment.
My word, looking at you,
I've come to desire
a closer association.
Combining business with pleasure.
Why separate them?
Oh, no, you don't.
Don't mix love with business.
It makes doing business
pleasant.
Or boring love.
I don't get the impression
we'd bother.
I'll give your proposal
about your proposal.
I love you guys.
The hardware department,
Mr.
In the basement.
Thank you.
Lace?
On the first floor.
Looking for something?
No. Just looking.
Watch everything at your leisure.
Au bonheur des dames,
customers are at home.
- Here you are, madame.
You're stealing my turn again!
The next customer is mine.
Go back to your farm.
And you, to your sidewalk.
We're not
in the wash-house.
Each in your place,
in silence.
Mademoiselle Badon,
you are a witness
that she's cheating.
You're wrong
to bicker.
What does she think she's doing,
this one?
You're no stronger than anyone else.
I'll prove it to you.
The 1st one that goes by,
I drop it from a coat.
And even more expensive.
Bonjour, mademoiselle.
Looking for a coat?
We have an exceptional
opportunity.
A must-have item.
And the price...
100 francs.
You won't hesitate.
I don't hesitate.
I'm not taking it.
It's not the desire
for it.
Do I look like the kind of person
who can afford this?
You'll have to come back later.
Are you abandoning me?
You're wrong.
The 1st quality
of a saleswoman is to be polite.
The 2nd, to be patient.
- Well done.
Learn from them.
The customer is always right.
We have to act like it.
And then curse her.
You're in the business.
I was a saleswoman.
Would you look for work?
Yes.
I've been told there's nothing.
There is for working women.
Bourdoncle, the register.
Conditions:
1st year as an au pair,
fed and housed
in the house.
What's your name?
Denise Baudu.
Your address?
For the time being,
I live next door, in Le Vieil Elbeuf.
Are you related to Monsieur Baudu?
I'm his niece.
I don't think it's necessary,
Monsieur Mouret...
Is it you?
Yes, mademoiselle.
Your uncle hates us.
Well, he's wrong.
We're broad-minded.
Miss Baudu is hired.
She will start tomorrow.
Look at this old wreck come
to stock up on fresh meat.
He wouldn't be shy.
These ladies are for sale.
We close the store,
and continue along the sidewalk.
I'm waiting for someone.
Good evening.
Aren't you going to change
hat?
Tonight, to hell with greed.
We should put a big number
on this mess
and change sign :
Au bonheur des messieurs.
That's how it'll end: in a whorehouse!
Ah, there you are.
I was expecting you for dinner.
Colomban is rehearsing at the Philharmonic,
and Geneviève will be back later.
She took little Pépé
to the country,
in Auteuil,
to Mme Gras, who will keep him
for 30 francs a month.
He can't be.
He's going to be miserable.
But he'll be
like a rooster.
As for Jean,
he found a room.
It makes everything better.
Uncle?
I hope you like soup.
It's my specialty.
Yes, Uncle.
I wanted to tell you that...
What's up?
You're not going to get in the way
with me.
We'll tell you:
Baudu has his outspokenness,
but he's got a good heart.
Here you go. Already?
I thought Madame Gras
would keep you for dinner.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing's wrong.
A little tired.
I'm going to get some rest.
Tomorrow will be better.
- It doesn't look good.
You should call a doctor.
I know what she's missing.
It's marriage.
The poor girl was getting impatient.
So is Colomban.
Why don't you marry them?
I promised to give my son-in-law
Old Elbeuf
in full bloom,
as I received it
from my father-in-law.
I have only one word.
What's all this?
Have a look.
Since you broke the other one...
Does that make you happy?
You're a Baudu, aren't you?
Heart in hand.
Did you buy this next door?
Yes.
Nothing from Mouret
from Mouret's should come in here!
He's my personal enemy.
He hates me.
No.
How would you know?
He told me.
Did you talk to her?
Don't be angry.
I have to work. I cannot
stay in your care.
I found a place
at Le Bonheur des dames.
Uncle...
Not another word.
I offered you hospitality
this night.
I have only one word.
But as of tomorrow,
I don't want to see you anymore.
Come on, ladies.
Come on. Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Downstairs in five minutes,
or face the fines.
Final warning.
Come on, miss.
This is a disaster.
2 like me would fit into this dress.
Too late. Too late.
Tonight we'll arrange it.
Come on, hurry up.
How many letters?
535.
What do customers think?
They don't think.
Like a flock of sheep,
she follows.
My respects, Madame.
Very good, your display.
Excellent initiative.
You'll give him a bonus.
What's your name?
Favier.
You've eaten garlic.
A simple clove
rubbed on bread.
Just enough to
suffocate customers.
I'll cancel the bonus,
and no more garlic.
First
and final warning.
Recognize me?
I bought you this vase.
It can be done.
My husband hates it,
he wants to throw it away,
and he sulks.
Please, I beg you,
exchange it for me.
The regulations
strictly forbid it.
Make the switch.
You may choose.
Thank you for your time.
At your service.
This one will please him.
It's much more expensive.
6.95 francs.
Never mind.
An unfortunate precedent.
It's an innovation.
The items
can be exchanged.
How many drinks
have you had?
I'm perfectly lucid.
Do you want to ruin the house?
I don't want
a customer to stay away from my store,
that she has her mistake
in front of her eyes.
This vase had become
a source of remorse for the woman.
Well, my dear,
I don't sell remorse.
Show me something
I like.
You want a coat,
then a cape.
After that, it's a dress.
That's my right.
And you must satisfy me.
You still have to make up your mind.
Don't be cheeky,
or I file
a complaint against you.
What's up?
Your saleswoman
doesn't know her stuff.
She didn't sell me anything.
She refuses everything.
Because you present it badly.
Well, then...
Don't fight back.
Madame Aurélie,
take care of Madame.
Mademoiselle Rémy,
Make sure you're dressed
and your hairstyle.
First
and final warning.
Do you mind?
You're a
a lovely hostess.
You'd be a perfect partner.
We'd do great things.
We could also
pleasant ones.
The figure for my takings yesterday
was 150,000 F.
We'll reach a million.
No. Yesterday, you made
113,000 francs in revenue.
How do you know?
Do you have spies
in my house?
113,000 francs,
not bad at all.
Your land
will earn you 6%.
7 %.
It can be done.
That's for sure.
You're nice, attractive,
I like you,
but my trust in you
has its limits.
Thanks anyway.
You offer me the association
because you can't buy.
If I wanted...
Come on.
Every time you go on sale,
you play your store.
All I can offer you
is a forward sale.
We'll set deadlines.
7 %. How's that?
You're strangling me.
But with such beautiful hands...
Flattering.
Then 6%,
due in one year.
7%, maturing in 6 months.
Take it or leave it.
I'll take it.
The rules want us dead.
No sitting down,
going out after 11 p.m,
forbidden to marry
without permission...
Don't be happy.
"Au bonheur des dames"!
I'd like to sell.
I was counting on it.
If I were you,
I'd take someone.
What do you mean, "someone"?
Are you serious?
Yes, I am. Why should I?
You wouldn't be the 1st.
In the beginning, I was like you.
We're getting married on the sly:
he works here.
Baugé, from the pottery department.
A kind, hard-working
serious, a musician...
Without his varicose veins,
he'd be perfect.
That's awful.
What's awful? Varicose veins?
No. What you say.
Love is wonderful.
Who's talking about love?
I like my Baugé,
but the great passion,
is for those who have the time.
This is a luxury item.
Bells.
At 11 pm,
they cut off the gas.
I'll leave you my candle.
Tonight, I won't be reading.
Good evening.
Good evening. Thank you for your time.
How did you get in here?
I'm not allowed
visits.
No one saw me.
We had to talk.
About what?
I met a
a little brunette...
Some other time.
We had lunch
and dinner together at the hotel,
but I didn't pay.
I don't care.
If I don't pay,
the boss kicks me out.
Quite a drama.
For 5 francs.
"5 francs?
Meals are expensive,
in Paris.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Here they are, your 5 francs.
I'll do without shoes.
Now go.
I won't do it again.
I broke up with the girl.
I'm ruining myself for her,
and she doesn't care about me.
I've learned my lesson.
Women and I are over.
File.
Discussion.
And this new floor?
We work there.
People can't sleep at night.
We're talking about a petition.
And you agree with them?
No. It comforts me.
I suffer from insomnia myself.
At the end of the month,
I want 50 more homes
and 3 new departments.
What are you doing here?
What's going on?
I'll take you there.
Whose house are you going out to?
Nobody's.
What are you doing here?
How, sir?
I'm on duty, sir.
I came to see
if you were doing it right.
My compliments.
You will be promoted.
I'll teach you
how to make fun of me.
Mr. Mouret!
What's the matter?
Mademoiselle,
your outfit is indecent.
Oh...
Who are you?
I can't say.
We'll see.
I'm not the first one here.
No more jokes.
We'll investigate.
It'll cost you.
To you and your accomplice.
Really?
Which way did you come in?
Well...
WELL?
This way.
He's got guts.
He's a fool.
No. He's a lover.
Bell.
If you're not downstairs in 5 min,
beware of fines.
Come on, come on.
I would have hidden it
at home.
A guy from the top.
Silence, ladies.
Sanctions will have to be taken.
They will all
in my office.
So you deny it?
I wouldn't have my friend
in my room.
The bed is too small.
You want to be comfortable.
This is an investigation
of the incident.
Thank you.
You're dismissed.
Send in the next one.
A few documents to sign.
It's urgent.
Well...
Management has the utmost concern
of the staff.
A serious error
would oblige us...
Thank God for that,
you look better than yesterday.
My compliments.
There's that
that devil of a wick...
This young man
didn't leave your house?
No.
You're new,
you didn't know.
This young man could have been
a relative or a friend.
Oh...
Loving is not forbidden.
If I ever love,
it will be my fiancé.
And I'll walk on his arm
for all the world to see.
I won't be ashamed.
I believe
and congratulate you.
All that's left for me to do
to apologize.
Monsieur...
Well done.
Very gallant.
This little
is not like the others.
You think you know
women,
but one day one will come
that will avenge the others.
Watch out!
Are you trying to asphyxiate us?
Close the window.
We're entitled to sunshine
and fresh air.
Even on Sundays?
Slaves!
This Mouret has sworn
to drive us crazy.
He imagines we'll cry for mercy,
we'll go away.
It's an egg yolk
beaten in garlic stock.
This'll fix you up.
No. Thanks, Dad.
Bell.
Here are the last of the conspirators.
I'm planning a master stroke
that will leave Mouret out in the cold.
It'll do you good.
Hello, Uncle.
You? What do you want?
I'm the one who called her.
Leave us alone.
You have business downstairs.
Denise will keep me company.
Do you think I look different?
But it's nothing.
Just a little tired.
It's morale
is affected.
I've got good news for you:
you're getting married.
I sold the house in Rambouillet.
It will be your dowry.
BAUDU! BAUDU! BAUDU!
I'll be right down.
Are you happy?
It's too late.
Colomban has grown tired of waiting.
He loves another:
Mlle Prunaire.
You can't love Clara.
She may have dazzled him for a moment,
but it will come back to you.
Think so?
He loves you.
You'll have to forgive him.
Do you want me to talk to him?
Oh no.
But if you were telling the truth,
I think I'd be cured.
Fracas.
What's going on?
An attack?
They dig a tunnel
to reunite the old stores.
It's like this all the time.
Hellish.
The time has come
to react against Mouret,
the enemy of us all.
He wants to nibble us all.
I say, "Enough is enough."
Hello.
Ladies...
What are you up to?
Mr. Mouret knows
of the little plot you're cooking up.
But he sends me to you as a friend.
It's an unequal struggle.
You'll break your back.
We'll see.
I've come to make you
an honest proposal.
We can buy back your funds
at very attractive prices.
What do you have to say?
Your business is doing badly.
Say...
Our fault, I grant you.
Well, we'll buy it from you
30,000 francs.
"30,000 francs?
Enough is enough!
I'll give you 50,000 F
for your store.
"50 000" ?
I won't do it!
60 000.
Never!
80.
Not even for 1 million!
Mr. Vincard is less stubborn,
and Mme Bédoré would accept 30,000 F.
Get out of here!
This is my house!
We're not for sale.
So be it.
If you come back here,
watch your back!
Capitulate
at the moment of victory!
30,000 F is a lot of money.
This visit proves
that they are afraid.
Maybe you're right.
You have to beat Mouret
with his own weapons:
sell cheaper
than he does.
Let's modernize our stores,
let's advertise...
"Advertising"?
Yes, advertising.
We have to fight.
Yes. But with what money?
Let's scrape our drawers,
let's make a joint fund.
The more employees he has,
the more glasses I sell.
Ah, the selfish one.
Since you're generous,
prove it.
I'll take your word for it.
I sold my house
in Rambouillet for 60,000 F.
They are at your disposal.
Well spoken.
VIVE BAUDU.
Uncork the champagne.
You're just going to leave
without saying a word?
Geneviève's dowry.
We're going to crush
le Bonheur des dames.
And Geneviève's.
Her wedding is only delayed.
Her dowry,
will be doubled, tripled.
The whole neighborhood will be invited.
And the cars in the motorcade
will pass over the ruins of the store.
BAUDU! BAUDU!
Tell her to be patient.
She'll die.
A la mort du Bonheur des dames.
A LA MORT DU BONHEUR DES DAMES!
They want war?
They'll get it.
We'll sell each item
10 cents cheaper.
It's ruin.
They'll get tired first.
You're dismissed.
You look like one.
I'm interested in profits.
You'll make up for it
on future revenues,
when we've
eliminate Baudu.
Just a moment.
I've got an idea.
What else?
This is the coup de grâce.
We're going to change
the layout of the shelves.
Hardware
instead of crockery.
The first to the second...
Execution.
It's pure madness.
No, it isn't.
Customers get into the habit
to go to the department that interests them.
now,
she'll have to look.
And then she'll be tempted
by new articles.
We'll sell twice as much.
And at a loss?
That's nice.
What do you think of my display?
Do you like it?
Bravo, Madame Bédoré.
Need a hand?
I'm good. Thanks for your help.
Ah, very well.
We do our best.
I posted the prices,
too.
I'd expect nothing less
from you.
They sell their flannel for 4.60.
Displays ours at 4.55.
Look at the frame.
You can touch it, ladies.
It's indestructible.
Good afternoon, ma'am.
You won't find it anywhere else.
6 m.
Colomban, 6 m for Madame.
I wouldn't want
to be Mouret.
4,50 ? Are you sure?
And prettier than this one.
You won't find
higher quality.
To happiness,
it's thicker.
But it's the same one.
The same supplier.
So
they present it better.
Well, go ahead,
and leave me alone.
Colomban,
pass me the 4.45 label.
Everything has changed.
I can't find my way around anymore.
Umbrella holders?
Porcelain,
glassware.
Bamboo, in the China department.
In copper, in the household section.
Wall-mounted,
with hardware.
And wooden models,
with a variety of furniture.
Thank you for your time.
You're welcome.
What do you do?
I'll get her dressed.
What do you say?
It's the best way
to show off our models.
Models?
Like in a workshop?
Are you crazy?
I think the idea
an excellent idea.
Let me give you a hand.
Reminds me of my early days.
I was a simple calico,
to begin with.
All the hope
is yours.
Can I help you?
Thank you for your help.
You love your job.
That's great.
How can you work
without passion?
Your friends are thinking
time to get out.
They don't have
your motivations.
They receive nothing
on profits.
Of course
Forgive me
for being so frank.
I congratulate you.
I like you very much.
M. Mouret is very gallant
with the female staff.
And who is this
this young person?
A simple saleswoman.
Her latest whim, probably.
I didn't say that.
He cares a lot.
Too much.
You will?
I'll take care of that, too.
Madame, what a surprise.
Unpleasant?
Happy.
Mme Desforges wants a cape.
Excellent.
Madame Aurélie...
No. Mademoiselle.
You're interested
interest.
Miss Baudu,
take care of Madame.
If you want to follow me...
See you soon.
You've been neglecting me
for some time now.
I'm only thinking of you
and your deadlines.
Monsieur!
Madame?
There is no
porcelain department.
Yes, it is. He's on the second floor.
That scared me.
You think...
It's for a trade.
If you can't see
that this collar is too narrow,
you're blind.
It has
distinction.
So don't talk
what you don't know.
Monsieur Mouret...
she tries to persuade me
that it suits me.
Is she stupid?
I was explaining...
Say right now
that I'm an idiot.
Such impertinence.
I thought you were more difficult.
If Mr. Mouret requires it,
I'll apologize.
For that to happen
hurt me.
But for me, your opinion
is of no importance.
I'll be seeing you.
I'll buy a cape somewhere else.
I'm sorry, sir.
It's not your fault.
The customer is queen.
Without abusing her privilege.
You have my full confidence
and friendship.
You've caught
the boss's eye.
Hopes are high.
It's been a long time since I pointed out
your qualities to Mr. Mouret.
You did well
to blow that poser's nose.
Good for you. Very good.
Unfortunate incident.
Some customers...
This one is a creditor.
The delay we were going to ask for,
don't count on it.
I'll pay.
With what money?
I'll manage.
Our competitors
are out of business.
I'm giving up my salary.
You too, of course.
No, you don't.
I don't agree anymore.
It would be a drop of water
in the sea.
We need to take
drastic measures.
You have to...
Listen to
You're giving me carte blanche?
Please go ahead.
All right, then.
This is bad.
It's a disgrace.
They'll end up making us
to eat...
It already is.
We should complain.
Miss Baudu should
talk to the boss.
They have other things to do,
when they're together.
Miss Prunaire...
Isn't Mlle Baudu
the boss's mistress?
Of course not.
No one will have Denise
to have fun.
But you can get it
for 100 cents.
Say it again.
Yes, 100 sous. And you with it.
You lying bitch!
Hush, hush...
If I sign a treaty
despite my reluctance,
is that my situation
is exceptional.
I've sold all my merchandise.
I need to renew my stock.
Business is good.
Very well.
The more I sell,
the more I lose.
Only, Mouret
loses 10 times as much as I do.
He'll die for it.
And at that point,
I go back to the old prices.
And to me, the profits.
You think so?
You don't know a thing.
It will dismiss
over 300 employees.
It's the end, I tell you.
Cracking sound.
It's an escalator
he installed against my wall.
Thud.
A lady breaks her face.
Another one who shows her ass
to society.
Voice bursts.
Hear that?
The saleswomen.
Sales assistants who argue
with customers.
That's a good sign.
It's as if I were giving you
gold bars.
Monsieur Lafont,
it is forbidden to sit down.
You'll
checkout.
How much is that?
148.
"148" ?
We're still 52 short.
Monsieur Grimaut, you...
You look terrible.
You'll have to check out.
There's Bourdoncle.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Oh...
Quickly,
into a fitting room.
Is she ill?
No.
Mlle Cugnot is a little pregnant.
"Pregnant?
You are...
Monsieur...
No girl seduced.
I'm married.
"Married? Since when?
For 3 months.
"3 months? And with whom?
I...
A friend of mine
who doesn't work here.
A good boy.
"It is forbidden to marry
without notifying management."
You'll have to check out.
These rules give you
all the rights!
I will not tolerate...
Just throw me out.
You think you're
very protected,
but don't be fooled.
First and final warning.
Let's get to work.
And smile.
I have an errand to run.
I'll be back in 15 minutes.
I've had enough.
If he doesn't pay me the 30,000,
I'll put his drafts into circulation.
In other words, I'm executing it.
It will be bankruptcy.
I must confess, Madame,
I'm surprised by your visit.
I came here as a friend,
Monsieur Baudu.
As an ally.
Rather say that Mouret
sent you to spy on me.
You've come to see
if I succumb soon.
What does it take
to convince you?
I hate Monsieur Mouret.
Yes, I was his friend.
But when he got
what he wanted: my buildings,
he betrayed me.
I have only one idea:
revenge.
I know he wants to ruin you.
I've come to give you
my help.
Thank you for your help,
but I don't need anyone.
It's a fight to the death,
but a personal one.
So you're
sure you're going to win?
I believe in justice.
It would be wrong of me to insist.
I came
to offer you some money.
In any case, Mouret
is out of breath.
Just a little more effort,
and you'll win.
Excuse me
for this step.
You have my deepest sympathy.
Please understand, ma'am,
that I cannot accept gifts.
A question of dignity.
Oh, Monsieur Baudu,
far be it from me to humiliate you.
We both hate
the same man.
We could have united
to bring him down.
You can't possibly know
what it is to hate a woman.
How do you propose
offer me money?
I don't know...
An advance, a loan,
a guarantee
on your building
or your fund.
Old Elbeuf? Never.
I refused Mouret 60,000 F
for the building.
He could take it off your hands
for less.
That's its purpose.
You know that.
I'm well aware of that,
by God.
You know, I'm not
a businesswoman.
I'm angry
with numbers.
But I'm intuitive,
and despite your pride
to hide your difficulties from me,
I can guess.
I'm buying your house
to save it from Mouret.
I promise to sell it back to you
whenever you want
at the same price
and without any profit.
I will be rewarded
by Mouret's demise.
20 000.
Are you all right?
No, I can't be.
What is it now?
Gaujan.
Tell him I'm coming.
30 000.
It's worth much more.
But since you'll be buying it back
at the same price.
I've prepared a paper
just in case.
This close is planned.
I'm not a woman of money,
but a wounded woman
who just wants
revenge on a cad.
Say bandit,
a shark.
But this time,
we've got him.
Just sign here,
below.
We also put
"read and approved", I believe.
You'll have to excuse me,
I don't know anything about it.
What's up?
Is it for today?
Ah...
See you soon.
Goodbye.
Look, I've been patient,
I've been patient...
And you've been rewarded.
Here's your 30,000 F.
I never doubted,
believe me.
An old customer like you...
Always at your service.
Here you go.
I'll sign a few more for you.
You deliver to me
60,000 francs worth of merchandise.
I'm going to sell like crazy,
make Mouret die.
Despite our losses,
we'll settle our debts.
But then there's
Monday's deadline.
You were supposed to get an extension.
Mme Desforges refuses.
Especially after the incident
the other day.
Offer her 8%.
She won't see me.
It's tomorrow, Sunday.
You could pay him a visit.
The chore is not unpleasant.
Far from it.
- Still here, miss?
I helped Mrs. Aurélie
finish her inventory.
Would you do me a favor?
Yes. If it's in my power.
You need
a change of scenery.
Come and have dinner with me.
Thank you very much.
I've already had dinner in the refectory.
In fact, not too bad,
for once.
Well, all right.
Then come to dinner.
But I have
I have to be home by 11.
You will give 5 cents
to the doorman.
Management is concerned
of the staff.
Go put on a dress,
I'll be waiting.
No, sir.
Why not?
I don't want to.
I want to.
Let me be.
I'll furnish an apartment for you.
You won't work anymore.
No, thanks. I'd be bored.
I'd be bored.
A man in your life?
No. Too many women in yours.
It's up to you.
Please let me go,
I beg you.
Coughing.
Are you free for dinner?
I wonder.
You're going to be
in a foul mood.
I drew up a list
of staff to be made redundant.
That makes 199.
This is not
an account, that, 199.
You will tell Mlle Baudu
that she has been appointed second.
...
How's that?
One more turn, Denise.
It's the 6th.
You have to be reasonable.
What are we going to do now?
You're going to taste it.
What about your work?
You can't go.
Why do you ask?
Jean told me it was big.
Tell me, Denise.
Once upon a time
a gentleman
who, walking
in front of poorly lit stores,
decided to change that.
Was he Prince Charming?
Yes.
With his magic wand,
he built
a palace from the ground
full of light,
and toys.
Have you seen the prince?
Yes. He often comes
to visit his subjects.
What's it like?
Is it pretty?
He's very likeable,
very attractive,
always very cheerful.
Everyone greets him low,
but passes him carelessly.
He smiles at me.
You're his favorite,
say, Denise?
Orchestra.
Squeaking.
Laughter.
Applause.
Like this,
you like acrobats?
Do you mind?
What you offer me
enchants me.
In what way?
You're taking me
in a bellowing.
Does that shock you?
No, it doesn't.
I was expecting
an excess of tenderness
I was about to resist.
to resist.
As you can see...
Oh!
Just to justify
my reputation as an honest woman.
Too late.
But perhaps
you're concerned
to think about love?
"Concerned", me?
Why should you be?
Tomorrow's deadline.
You think of everything.
Of course you do.
You want
to ask me for a delay,
and you don't know
how to attack.
And you would resist
just enough
to justify
your reputation.
I'm prepared to grant you
a one-month extension.
How much is this going to cost me?
Oh...
7%, as usual.
The usual rate.
I'd like to ask you
a small favor.
Granted in advance.
You fire
this little saleswoman.
You're above that.
I'd like to ask you a favor.
Don't make me
to make it an obligation.
I refuse.
Too bad for you.
It'll cost me
what it will cost me.
It'll cost you
Baudu's house.
Where's the report?
Baudu borrowed money from me
that he can't pay back.
So she's mine.
You did?
I couldn't resist.
I know how much it meant to you.
I wanted to give it to you.
At what price?
80 000.
How much do you earn?
Isn't the most important thing
to get what you want?
You want this house,
and I...
I don't want to see
that little girl.
No, no, no, no, no.
Don't make that face.
Applause.
You're right.
They're charming,
these acrobats.
Drum rolls
and applause.
I present to you
your new second.
Keep working.
She got this job
thanks to his initiative
initiative and leadership.
I hope you'll make it easy
him an easy task.
Mademoiselle,
no brooch on the blouse.
First and final warning.
Monsieur...
Yes ?
Is this a joke?
No.
I'd rather be a saleswoman
than second in the cellar.
You are free to refuse
and resign.
Do I owe it to you?
No, mademoiselle.
It belongs to Mr Mouret himself.
He'd rather
not to see you again.
Is Madame Desforges in?
Do you have an appointment?
I was just...
What's this about?
Announce Mr Baudu.
I'll see if Madame is in.
Madame has left
a commission for you.
"Regarding your building,
please contact Mr Mouret.
"He has all the power."
"Mouret?
Madame assigned her claim to him.
He is now your
your landlord.
The exit is this way.
Have you come to contemplate
your work?
A murderer returns
to the scene of the crime.
You should be proud:
Quinette filed for bankruptcy,
Tatin is in receivership
liquidation,
Vincard went bankrupt,
Bouras wanted to kill himself
in despair.
Fortunately
I didn't follow you.
You've done very well.
A real hunting ground.
2 pints of red!
There you go.
What the
this?
Bailiff's certificate.
Mouret bought back the drafts
signed in Gaujan.
He did?
He sues you
in bankruptcy.
The wretch!
Failli, moi, Baudu?
My poor Colomban,
I wanted to give you
a prosperous house...
I'm too old
to continue the fight.
I'm passing the torch to you.
You're young,
you can succeed.
With what?
You have savings.
What I paid in your name
at the Savings Bank.
You'll pay Mouret,
you'll pay Gaujan.
I have a rich cousin.
I'll borrow from him.
We still have
loyal customers.
With Geneviève,
you will adapt
to the needs
of modern commerce.
All is not lost.
I'll have you married in no time.
What do you say?
Speak up!
Don't look at me
like a fool.
I give you my store.
I give you my daughter.
Would you refuse,
by any chance?
Please answer.
Do you think she's too poor?
Come on, talk.
I've never liked
your daughter.
You dare?
Oh, that's all right.
The store is ruined,
just like your daughter.
I love another.
She is a salesgirl
at Le Bonheur des dames.
For 10 years,
you've been living with us.
For the past 10 years,
I've thought of you as my son.
Get out of here!
You bet!
I'm offered a seat next door.
I'm running.
Scumbag!
Geneviève!
I killed her.
I, Baudu, killed my daughter.
I only thought of myself.
I was selfish.
I should have listened to Geneviève.
I can't anymore.
I'm an old beast,
a brute.
I ruined my friends,
killed my daughter.
- Step right up, ladies.
1,95 F.
Our latest innovation.
Sale of the week :
1,95 F.
Please follow me.
What's on your mind?
No scandal.
What's up?
I caught Madame
in flagrante delicto.
He's crazy.
You don't know who I am.
I know you well, Madame.
It would be preferable
if you returned the lace.
But...
Take Madame to number 3,
so we can search her.
I'll complain to Mr. Mouret.
If we're not being considerate,
please let me know.
Check it out, ladies.
1,95 F.
All done.
Thank you for your time.
You're dismissed.
It's an ambush.
Someone slipped them on me.
For your family's sake,
we will hush this up.
Here, have a seat.
Make yourself comfortable. Good.
Write to
"I stole some lace."
Never, never.
I'd rather die.
Then I'll accompany you
to the superintendent's office.
We will return this paper to you
when you bring us
1,000 francs.
Terrible blackmail.
That's a big word.
Thank you.
Thank you for your time.
Dated and signed.
Without it, it's...
Your paper
will be in good company.
I have a collection
of society ladies' autographs.
Greetings.
I'm not answering you.
That, madame...
How did it go?
They apologized.
These misunderstandings
are appalling.
Open the door.
Be reasonable.
You can't stay.
For the last time: open.
What's up?
Father Baudu went bankrupt.
We're going to evict him
and demolish his house.
He's barricaded himself in.
We'll find him hanged.
We're going to break down the door.
- Uncle, please,
I beg you, open up!
- Come on, miss,
step aside.
The first one who touches me,
I'll knock him out!
Tear the house down.
I won't get out!
I want to be buried.
Be reasonable.
I want to die here.
I want to die here!
Leave it alone. It's all right. It's all right.
Take him away.
Come, Uncle.
No. I want to see.
No more...
It's all over.
Come on, Baudu,
cheer up.
Let's go to my place.
Don't worry about a thing.
I'll take care of him.
I will have lost everything:
daughter, home, health.
And the other builds,
grows, triumphs.
There is no justice.
I want to go,
run away from this noise.
These workers are murdering
my neighborhood with their pickaxes.
As soon as I can
stand on my own two feet,
I'm off to Valognes
end my days among good people
good people, far from this jungle.
You too, Denise,
you should leave with me.
But you prefer to exhaust yourself
in your airless basement,
in this cellar,
doing this stupid job.
Yet you are
a good girl, Denise,
but you'll let me go
on my own,
old and abandoned.
Is Mouret holding you back?
Is it?
So admit it.
What is it about him that makes you
that you prefer him to your uncle?
He doesn't care about you.
He loves only himself
and his Bonheur des dames.
- It's been tough,
but I made it.
My dream came true.
Look at that, Bumblebee:
Europe's largest
in Europe.
I want to inaugurate it
in a sensational way.
In January?
Why not?
After the New Year's gifts,
in the middle of the off-season?
I'm getting rid of the off-season.
Easy for you to say.
Easy to make.
It's all about attracting
customers.
I want to make her want
to buy in all seasons.
What do you expect to find
when it snows?
Now that sounds
just right.
We're going to do
an exhibition of white.
"White?
Linen, lace...
I can see it now:
a symphony in white.
It will be unexpected.
All Paris will crash here.
It'll be crowded.
Exactly.
Brouhaha.
From management,
madam.
From management.
No, I'm fine.
Look at these handkerchiefs,
ma'am.
A real opportunity.
Don't you buy any?
No, not here.
It's a house
of thieves.
Two 16th century Chinese vases
at 350 F each.
700 francs.
Minus 600 francs return.
This means you only
100 francs to pay.
Do you have to have them delivered?
No.
I want to surprise
surprise my husband.
Be careful with them.
They're fragile.
Don't worry.
I won't take them back.
Au revoir, madame.
All the best.
2 imitation China vases,
sold at 9.95 each.
- 19.90 for madame.
Sold out.
Mr Mouret.
Summoned?
Yes.
Please wait.
The boss is busy.
Your white exhibition
is a real triumph.
You're a great man.
Besides,
I never doubted it.
What is it?
It's for the summer.
I live 6 months ahead
ahead of customers.
This summer, women
show off their calves at the beach.
It's indecent...
We wouldn't dare wear that.
We'll see.
You're having dinner at my place.
A small gathering
in your honor.
That's a shame.
I dine with my staff.
At my place, there will be
Baron Haussmann
and the Duchess
de Maufrigneuse.
And here,
will be my employees.
You prefer the company of your
to that of my friends?
We're not meant
to get along.
Let's part without bitterness,
shall we?
What did you say?
Our adventure could not last
longer than our deadlines.
But one remains,
the strongest.
I'll pay it in advance
with interest.
It was a good deal for you
and, I hope, not too unpleasant.
I'll always have fond memories of our
a fond memory.
You're very good,
Mr. Mouret.
A bit of a cad.
Sloppy education.
I'll send you
you a receipt.
please,
for accounting purposes.
Farewell.
Mademoiselle...
I want to tell you
a decision...
No need to go on.
I get it: you're firing me.
When you stop pleasing,
you're thrown out into the street.
You do everything for advertising,
nothing for the employees.
The saleswomen are fed
like dogs,
watched like thieves.
"Customer sulks,
proceed to checkout."
"You're old,
check out."
"You're ugly,
"You're going to be a mother,
check out."
"When you stood up
the boss,
"a Desforges whim,
please proceed to checkout."
Are you finished?
Yes.
Good.
I have summoned you
to tell you
that you return to confection
in first-class quality.
Thank you, sir.
A gentleman
is waiting for you in the tea room.
You mean me?
Yes, miss.
Madame...
By the way, Mr. Bourdoncle,
I wonder why
you remain second to Mouret.
He's vulgar,
you're distinguished.
He's a primary,
you're cultured.
But come on,
you've got the makings of a chef.
What are you waiting for?
a store like this for the better?
Alas, dear lady,
I'm missing the essential.
Is it? Money.
Come to my place tomorrow.
We'll work it out.
You can count on me, ma'am.
You promised me
not to come back.
Take this and come quickly.
I saw Uncle Baudu,
and I've come to kiss you.
I've got something
to tell you.
Then come quickly.
You look cheerful.
Bad news?
Curious things are happening
in the basement.
Where?
Handling.
You should come down and have a look.
Interesting stuff.
What's up?
A young woman
who is dear to you
is not alone.
Signed: two people
who wish you well.
Just listen.
It'll cost me 5 francs.
But I work.
I'm well paid.
I'm saving up
to get married.
Do you want to get married?
Yes.
But with whom?
A mystery.
Do I know her?
She's a colleague.
She didn't tell me.
She doesn't know I'm your brother.
What did you invent?
Denise, remember.
You said you didn't
you didn't know me.
I'm so happy.
I'm happy too.
I'll come and see you tomorrow.
Follow the corridor.
I love you.
Goodbye.
Not so fast.
No more
of you.
You deceived me, fooled me,
and I loved you.
I wanted to marry you.
Was he your lover?
"Lover?
You're not going to deny it.
I recognized him.
But...
A relative? Your brother, perhaps?
Give me a valid explanation.
I'm not staying
another day.
"Not a day?
But not an hour.
Go back
from whence you came.
I'm hunting you!
- A little white?
No time.
I'm going to the party.
Ah, yes.
Is it true that we're going to dance?
I'm the one
who conducts the orchestra.
- A party?
That's all we needed.
He's no longer amused,
doing the wedding by himself?
It's going to be pretty.
A nice pinch.
I predicted
it would end up like this.
How about you?
I leave
Le Bonheur des dames.
Give me a kiss.
With this news,
I'll be on my feet in no time.
Yes, Uncle.
Get well soon,
and let's leave for Valognes.
I'm going to pack.
Go quickly, my boy.
Go quickly.
"Lost and found: 2 bags,
1 muff, 3 umbrellas.
"Lost and found: 2 gloves,
a petticoat, 3 garters.
"Arrested: three thieves,
one professional,
"a fake inspector."
Nothing sensational.
On the other hand,
an appalling scandal:
a saleswoman
kissed a customer.
She's here now.
She would like to justify herself.
Kick her out.
That's all for today.
Thank you for your time.
Here we are.
I can't believe my eyes.
I had to count
several times
to realize the obvious.
1 million 39,000 francs
65 centimes.
We've never seen that
in any store.
It's a date.
Here you are.
Thank you very much.
If Mr. Mouret knew,
he'd understand.
Don't insist.
Here are 100,000 francs.
You will give them
to Mr. Baudu.
Can I have a receipt?
Don't give him
explanation.
Don't send me away.
Did you make
all this scandal?
He's my fiancé.
That's no excuse.
I'm in the wrong,
but I was so happy...
He is Miss Baudu's brother.
His "brother"?
Yes.
This is the young man
we saw in the corridor.
That was the day
I met him.
It's getting serious.
I take her to the checkout.
Take her to the goldsmiths
to choose her gift.
Bring me Miss Baudu,
dead or alive.
Bumblebee!
Take this pad
and this pencil,
and write down the names of two people
who are referred.
Clara Prunaire,
dressmaking saleswoman.
Bourdoncle, Emile...
What does this mean?
You're a couple of bastards.
I'm throwing you out.
You're trying to set up
a competing company.
- Me, Monsieur Mouret?
I've got
have my own police force.
As a bonus, I give you
her lover, Colomban!
A great team!
Don't make me
to throw you out.
First
and final warning.
What can I do for you?
We can't
continue without you.
You're wanted.
Without you, the party is incomplete.
We insist.
It's OK, it's OK.
Come on, I'll follow you.
Ballroom music.
Here's your 100,000 francs.
Baudu doesn't accept
charity.
You've ruined me,
thrown me out on the street.
But you won't triumph
for long.
You have created
a cruel machine
that will stop at nothing.
You too will meet
your Mouret,
a forban more powerful than you
who will crush you
as you have crushed others
and will be crushed in its turn.
In 20 years, commerce
will be an ugly battle,
where quality, integrity
and trust
will be trampled underfoot, murdered,
like Old Elbeuf.
Take care, Mouret,
you establish the reign
of junk and glitz.
But patience pays off.
You too will one day experience
unemployment and poor sales.
You'll become
the slave of financiers,
and your shoddy cathedrals
will collapse
in a chaos of ruins,
of scandal and blood.
I'm too old.
I'll be lucky to die
before I've seen it all.
Yes, my friends,
Mr. Baudu is right.
My company could only be built
by ruining good people.
That's the price of progress.
But success also imposes
duties.
If unintentionally,
I have done harm,
I consciously want
do good.
It was my collaborators
I thought.
Here is my program:
reinstatement of employees
dismissed without cause.
Applause.
Introduction of marriage loans.
And construction of a maternity hospital,
a hospice,
guaranteed retirement
for those who have toiled here.
Applause.
Don't thank me.
I've been thinking about you
because one of you
made me understand
your misery and your hopes.
Thank Mlle Baudu,
who, I hope,
will soon be Mrs Mouret.
What does this mean?
I have the honor
of asking for your hand in marriage.
Applause.
Watch out!
Ah!
- Oh! Oh!
Applause.
You are no longer my employees.
You're my partners.
And Le Bonheur des dames
belongs to all of us.
Applause.
Ballroom music.
Subtitles : Télétota