♪ I'm an expensive guy
you want cheap side? ♪
♪ Can't strong-arm
me with a weak vibe ♪
♪ If I decide to
let the beat ride ♪
♪ It's a major move to
over the minor dudes ♪
♪ Everyday some hater
dey write love song ♪
♪ E dey funny me, the
irony it's quite strong ♪
♪ I'm in a dark place, write
to keep the lights on ♪
♪ With blind ambition set
my sights on greatness ♪
♪ Ramadan make fast
no time for lateness ♪
♪ Young Cassius, I
am the greatest ♪
♪ Mr-always-dey-talk-without
Hey sweetheart, you need a lift?
Oh, I'll be honored.
Wow.
Nice car!
Sweet.
Hi, my name is Baaba,
nice to meet you.
You must be rich.
Well, my boyfriend isn't rich,
but you are definitely rich.
Are you single?
Well, she's not single,
but she's single.
I'm well, I'm...
- Baaba!
- What? What?
Just get in.
Okay, yeah.
Well, yeah, nice.
Yes, it's nice.
Open it.
It's locked.
Oh! Oh!
Now why did he leave?
Learn to keep your
mouth shut, Baaba.
You talk too much.
I talk too much?
I told you not to
talk to me like that.
You pay bills when I talk.
Do you pay bills?
Do any of you pay
bills when I talk?
Eh?
Do you pay bills when I talk?
Blah-ba-la-la-la-la-lo-lo-lo-lo!
This is talking too much.
Say I talk too much.
Oh, there's a car coming.
Now run, move.
Go, go, go, go!
Hey, come back, o'.
Come back, it's a taxi.
Hah.
Let me run up.
I nearly fell down.
Hey, wait, wait.
Okay.
We're here.
Yeah.
It's good, it's a busy street.
Busy people.
Okay, Baaba, you take left.
Mm-hmm.
Fella, you take right.
I will go ahead.
We converge here
in the next hour.
Okay, all right.
Cool.
All right, ladies, please
do not forget your lines
and keep a broad smile.
♪ Oshobo
♪ Mmmm
♪ E be like say everybody
dey want money ♪
♪ Dey want money
♪ E be like say everybody
dey search money ♪
Oh, sorry.
Excuse me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
- All right.
- You look very nice.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Very patriotic.
Please, my name is Fella.
Okay.
That's me and
these are my friends.
Okay.
So we have an ushering agency,
so if you need any
ushers, weddings,
you know, conference, party,
please, we can usher it.
Sorry, I have to go.
- Okay.
- All right.
- But our number is here.
- All right, all right.
Just call us, okay?
Hello.
Here, see, this is me
and these are my friends.
We run Pokbafell
ushering agencies.
Mm-hmm.
Please call us if you need
our services for anything,
your programs and everything.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Hello!
Hi!
Hi.
Hello, my name is Pokua
and this is me and these
are my two friends.
- Oh, okay. Nice.
- Yes.
We run an ushering business,
call us if you need
ushers for your program.
- Okay.
- Yes.
Hi.
Hello.
This is me and
these are my friends,
we run Pokbafell Agency.
Please call us if you need
any ushering services.
- Oh.
- Okay?
Oh!
Please, please do call
us for your engagement,
your wedding- No, I know.
Any ushering services you need.
- Right.
You guys look good together!
Hi!
Hey.
I'm sorry.
My name is Pokua and
we run this company,
Pokbafell.
Can you speak Twi for me?
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Hello, sir, sir, hi.
Hi.
This is me and these
are my friends.
We run a Pokbafell
ushering agency.
Po? Po, what?
Sorry.
Madam!
- Hello.
- How are you?
Fine.
My name is Fella.
Well that's me and those
are my friends and-
- Okay.
- We have an ushering service.
Okay.
So if you need anything
for ushering, you know,
we are there for you.
- All right, sure.
- Yeah.
- What-
- It's Pokbafell.
Is it French?
No, it's a combination
of our names.
You see, Pokua, Baaba and Fella,
but the F is
silent, so it's vuh.
All right, sure.
Okay, thank you.
I'm here with my two friends.
Okay.
We have this ushering
business that we provide
ushering service for events.
So you can call
us if any program-
- Yeah, it's very nice, man.
- Yeah, and...
Hi, hello.
- Hello?
- Yes.
Have this.
You've given me one already.
- Already, hey?
- Uh-huh.
Okay, we'll be very
glad to hear from you.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
I'll pick you
up 2:00, tomorrow.
Oh, sure.
That works, yeah.
Is that okay by you?
Yeah, that's fine.
Okay, so then I'll
also send you the check.
- Thank you, I love you.
- Give me a kiss.
Ah.
Kiss.
Mr. Sampah! Mr.
Sampah! Mr. Sampah!
Oh, hi.
Hi.
You're looking good.
Thank you.
Anyway, what are you doing here?
Oh, my friends and I have opened
a small ushering business.
That's good.
And we're here to share flyers.
Oh, wow.
And what are you
also doing here?
I, I, I...
You see, you see my office
is just around here,
I came for a business meeting.
I'm just leaving.
Anyway, let me excuse myself.
See you around, okay?
Okay.
Have a nice day.
Pokua! Pokua!
?
Let me tell you.
She has to know.
It's none of your business!
If there's any trouble,
I am not part of it,
I told you to not to do it.
It's not.
Please go.
Do you understand?
What?
Okay, just...
I had nothing to do with this.
If there's any trouble, I-
She has to know.
Just go.
Hey, hey!
Hi, Pokua.
How are you doing?
- Very well.
- Yeah.
Come on, come on in.
- No.
Auntie Vero, I suspect your
husband is cheating on you.
I didn't like what I saw today.
I thought you should know so
you can keep an eye on him.
Auntie Vero, maybe you
didn't hear what I said.
Oh, I heard you.
That's no news.
So many people tell
me this all the time,
but he denies them all.
It does haunt me,
but I have no proof
so I just pretend that
it's not happening
and that's how I deal.
Auntie Vero, we're so sorry.
Eh?
Congratulations,
reporter.
There must be
something we can do.
Listen, Pokua,
this woman is suffering
enough torture already,
leave her alone!
Yes, she is.
But that's why I want to help.
We need to free her mind.
She has to know the truth.
Free her mind from what?
Truth, truth.
Everyday, truth.
What truth, Pokua?
You're the only one
who knows this truth.
Pokua, let's just leave her be.
I mean, she's living her life-
Eh?
She's happy.
Pokua, what else do you want?
She's not who?
She's not happy.
Didn't you see
the way she talks?
The way she banged her door?
She's definitely not happy.
Look, I'm a married woman too.
- Oh.
- Eh.
Okay.
I see it when
another is in trouble.
I see it.
Okay, madam married woman,
tell us, what should
we do to help?
I heard him say he'll
pick her tomorrow at 2:00.
We can go with Auntie
Vero so she finds out.
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
- Hey, no!
- No.
- Leave me out of this.
- Mm-hmm.
This is insane.
I want no part of this.
Do you understand?
Count me out.
Did you think about this?
Pokua, she's right.
That's such a...
That's an awful idea.
That's the only
thing on my mind.
I don't know how
to give her proof.
But maybe there's something else
we can do.
Okay, okay, okay.
How do we get proof?
Pokua,
do you know what
you're asking for?
Yes, I do.
Are you that heartless?
No, I am not!
I am not.
How did we even become friends?
Babs!
Oh, oh, you too, you
agree with this, eh?
Not entirely, but you
people shouting and screaming,
it's not going to
solve anything.
Just bring your voices down.
Okay.
I understand how this
is a problem for you.
I can handle it myself.
Help is all I want to give.
Pokua!
I'll go.
She's right.
I mean, it's gonna cause
a whole lot of drama
and you don't want that scene.
But I have an idea.
I mean, if it's really
going to help her,
maybe we can just
record him secretly.
If we get him like once
or twice on camera,
that's proof, right?
Hmm.
You have money for camera?
Oh, we can use our phone camera.
Our phone camera will be fine.
And that easy, right?
Just gonna record him?
It was just a
suggestion, like...
Hmm.
Okay, if you wish not to
be in, fine, we carry on.
Baaba? Baab?
Baaba?
See, look, eh,
my next friendship, yeah,
I'm going to make sure
that there's a contract
so I can get out whenever I
feel like it without any guilt.
Ah, this friendship
thing is hard.
And now by force, I have
to go and do this thing
and I don't want to do.
No!
Next time, I'm serious,
we are signing contracts
so I can get out.
It's okay.
And this better be worth it.
.
Go!
Guys!
Hey, I want the front.
I want the front.
Give me the front!
Front!
V, what is going on here?
What's happening?
Jesus.
Stand here and talk to me.
V, look at you.
Sweetheart, what has you
working you up like this?
Are you cheating on me?
What?
Oh, ,
.
Sweetheart, did
you just ask that?
I've lost count
of the many times
you've asked this question.
Just answer me.
Are you cheating?
No!
How could I?
Never.
Tell me, where from this?
, I told you
that the next time
I get a report
that you're cheating on
me, I won't ask for proof,
I will just walk away.
Too many people can't be
reporting the same lie.
It's just not possible.
Hold on, hold on,
hold on, hold on.
Sweetheart, it means someone
came to report me again?
I see.
And are you breaking your mind
because of what
you have not seen?
Goodness!
I've asked you to stop
listening to people
because they envy our marriage.
In case you want
to walk out of this
maybe 'cause you are tired
of me, then so be it,
but don't blame it
on unfounded hearsay.
Sweetie, when I step out there,
there are a lot of pretty girls,
even some of them are married
women who try to hit on me
but I refuse them.
You know why?
It's because I
respect our marriage.
Unless I forget, what
do we have for dinner?
This is the plan,
the two of you will
do the recording.
I can't be part,
he'll recognize me.
When his car arrives, walk
towards it and pretend to chat.
But hold on.
So how would you have pulled
this off if we pulled out?
I haven't thought about that.
I know you'll never leave me.
Hmm?
The lady will come from here.
Turn your backs towards them
and hold your phones casually.
No direct cameras.
See, this thing is very risky.
I can't believe we're
about to do this.
I can't believe I got
myself involved in this.
Baaba!
I thought we all agreed
that we're gonna do this.
And I'm not saying
I'm pulling out,
I'm just telling
you that it's risky.
He's here.
And Fella, you first.
Okay.
Let's go.
Baaba?
Yeah?
When the lady's approaching
the car, call her,
she'll stop, get closer
and start a conversation.
Okay.
Get closer.
Okay, okay, okay.
I'm going. I'm going.
Fella!
Baabs!
Oh my goodness!
How are you?
I'm great.
Baabs, how long has it been?
Ah, it's been a very long time.
- Many years.
- Yes!
You're looking good.
Oh, thank you, it's
through the grace of God.
Oh, gosh.
- Yeah, okay-
- Yeah.
So I came for a walk.
A walk?
Yes.
Yes, it's very breezy, yeah.
Yeah, it's nice, plenty birds-
Yeah.
- Lots of air.
- Oh.
Yeah.
- Ah.
- Oh, Fella!
Baabs, oh.
Yeah, Fella.
It's good to see you.
- Oh, good to see you too.
- Yeah.
Good to see you.
Baabs.
What?
- They kissed.
- They what?
No, no, no, no, no, not here.
Where did they kiss?
On the lips, mwah, mwah.
On the lips?
Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- What-
They kissed.
And look.
They kissed!
Auntie Vero, we caught
him, your husband.
We have a proof of him cheating.
Why are you doing this?
I'm a wife too.
I can't stand the torture of
hearing my husband is cheating.
I thought I should expose
him to free your conscience.
I don't like it when you
see wrong and go quiet.
Let me see it.
Okay, okay, show, show.
Looking good.
Oh, thank you, it's
through the grace of God.
Oh, God.
Auntie Vero?
- For a walk.
- A walk?
- Yeah.
- Please, are you okay?
Plenty birds, yeah.
Yeah.
Auntie Vero,
please say something.
Do you think we made her cry?
No.
She decided to cry on her own.
She saw a video of her
husband cheating and cried.
Look, look guys, let's just...
Let's just go, okay?
I mean, clearly the woman
is in a lot of pain,
let's give her some space.
This was a bad idea.
Here, have this.
What for?
It's your reward.
Oh, no, no, no.
No, Auntie Vero, you
don't have to pay us.
Mm-hmm.
You know, anyone could
have done this for me too.
I've been so unhappy
the past three years,
so thank you
for giving me this freedom.
I'm just tired of
living in oblivion.
And here,
put the video on this.
Just put it on.
- Miss, we are so sorry.
- Sorry, Auntie Vero.
We're sorry.
Thank you,
through the grace of God.
We may go now.
We shouldn't of done this.
Oh, okay.
So I came for a walk.
- A walk?
- Yes.
It's nice, plenty birds-
- Yeah.
- Lots of air.
- Oh!
- Yeah.
V?
V!
V for Vero.
Honey, I'm home!
Where's this wife?
VV!
V, darling!
Ah.
Thank you,
through the grace of God.
Oh, gosh.
- Yeah, okay-
- Yeah.
So I came for a walk.
- A walk?
- Yes.
Yes, it's very breezy, yeah.
Yeah, it's nice,
there's plenty birds-
- Yeah.
- Lots of-
♪ Get it, get it, get it,
get it, get it, get it ♪
This is a lot of money.
Yeah, it is.
We should split it.
Yeah, everybody takes their cut.
I mean, whatever you wanna do
with it is your business, but-
No, no, no.
No, no.
Let's open a proper
ushering agency,
you know, with a registered
office and everything.
Think about it, Pokbafell.
Vuh.
The F is silent.
You know what, it makes sense.
Yeah.
Pokua, are you here?
Of course, I'm here.
Okay, so what's your take?
I think I need some
time to think through.
Okay, let's all take
some time to think through.
Yep.
But you know what?
I think it's perfect.
Yes!
Ow!
Honey?
Get my phone!
Yeah.
Um-mm.
Not ready.
Hi, is this Pokua?
That smells good.
Shh, shh.
Yes, Pokua here.
Vero tells me you helped her
catch her cheating husband.
Can you help me too?
Pardon?
I suspect my
husband is cheating.
I want proof to face him.
A friend also suspects
her boyfriend,
she needs your help.
Hello?
No, no, no way!
No way we're getting into
something like that, Pokua.
No!
I told you she was crazy.
Did you believe me?
No, I am not.
Come on guys.
Okay, look at it this way,
if we treat this as business,
we are going to expose a
lot of cheating husbands
and boyfriends.
And if they pay for our
service, it's a lot of money.
Think about it.
Lots of money to make.
Then what happens to Pokbafell?
The ushered business
is nothing to us.
It makes us nothing.
For how long?
We just keep trying.
We need to try
something different.
And getting into
people's private lives,
that's your solution, Pokua?
I mean, what kind
of job is that?
What?
Our work will be very simple.
If you suspect your
partner is cheating on you,
just tell us about it.
We give you a proof, you pay us.
Easy, huh?
It doesn't sound easy, huh?
Not one bit, huh?
You know what I think?
I mean, she's crazy.
She's insane-o
but...
I'm game.
I mean, we don't
have a choice, right?
Yeah, me too.
I mean, if it's going to
make us money, let's do it.
- Yeah!
- Brilliant!
Going after the side chicks.
- Yes!
- Mm-hmm.
- Get the bad ones.
- Yeah.
We're the good cops.
It's so funny.
Maybe we can name it
Side Chick Task Force?
Huh?
That don't sound...
Why is there a police unit?
- What else?
- Wait, wait.
Let me think.
Instead of task force,
let's put gang.
Yes!
Gang!
SideChic Gang!
- Pa-pow!
- Poo-ooh!
Pa-pow!
SideChic Gang.
Okay, good.
Wait, let me help you.
SideChic Gang.
Draah! Draah!
Skraah!
Go, go.
Is it...
Yes, it is.
Okay.
Now, office supplies.
Yeah.
Two cameras.
Hmm, and a printer.
Papers and stamps.
Office table, office chairs, TV?
- TV.
- Yes.
Office chair.
And a fan.
No, no, AC.
But wait, wait, wait.
Pokua, wait.
I mean, I think we should
hold on on this list.
Why?
Get an office first.
Too expensive.
Guys, guys.
Hurry up.
For rent.
Oh.
03-02-123-231.
Hello. Hi.
We saw a structure
you're renting.
We want it.
Okay.
What do you think they do there?
I think they find
young girls for old men.
Eh?
Hi, welcome.
Thank you.
How may I assist you?
Well, I am told you
arrange young, sweet looking,
beautiful girls for old men.
Can you help me?
And who told you that?
My friend.
I'm sorry,
we don't offer
such services here.
Oh.
So, what do you do?
We help women catch
their cheating husbands.
Yes, like the side chick police.
Oh, sorry, my friend lied to me.
I apologize for that.
But you see in case you
start my kind of service,
remember me.
You look great.
Yes.
Goodbye.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Hi.
Welcome.
Hi, we spoke, yeah.
I'm Vero's friend.
You directed me here.
Oh, yeah.
Nice to have you.
These are my colleagues.
Hi.
I'm told you can help me.
Is that true?
Well, it depends
on what you need.
Please have a seat.
Here.
Talk to us.
How may we help you?
I'm a career woman
married to a politician.
He used to accuse me of not
having time for our marriage.
I didn't want to lose him.
So I changed jobs to
a less demanding one
just to create time.
But now I feel he's the one
who's denying me attention.
He doesn't touch me anymore.
Always acting tired.
I refuse to believe that
he was cheating on me
even when I found condoms hidden
that's where his spare tire is,
I blamed the mechanic.
Last night he didn't come home.
I called him this morning.
He said he went on
an impromptu trip.
He'll be back tomorrow.
His phone went off, that's why
he couldn't call to tell me.
An hour later, a friend
called to tell me that
she saw my husband's
car drive past her area.
Shocking, huh?
You know, I've been
crying since that moment.
You need water?
Fella, get her water.
No.
I'm fine.
Now I'm convinced
he's cheating on me.
I need help.
Would you help me?
- Do you have his pictures?
- Yeah.
Yes.
Here.
Fill in all your details and
your husband's office address,
okay?
.
It will cost you.
How much are we talking about?
I have 10,000 on offer.
- Oh, oh.
- Okay.
Oh, all right, I
mean, we can manage.
Right.
That's about half of the money.
When the job is
done, I pay the rest.
Oh, fine.
I count on you.
Please help me.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
So ladies, I'll show
you some of the best
collections we have
here in this garage.
You see this one,
this white car?
It came in just last week
and it is just 45K, just.
And then this one, this
one, this black one,
it arrived just yesterday.
Yeah!
.
And that one, I haven't
priced it yet, but 55,000.
Or maybe 52, last.
You ladies are very sleek and
when it comes to sleek ladies,
you need something of a class.
Thank you very much.
You have beautiful cars.
Ah, thank you, thank you.
But do you have any for rent?
Hey...
Madam, rent?
Ren-Rent?
Okay, so these collections
are from nineties,
right up to 2005.
So you can choose any you
want for that rent then.
Ah.
How 'bout that?
Ah, madam,
that is from the eighties.
It's too old but strong anyway.
I don't think it's
something you want.
Well, I don't mind.
It looks cheaper.
We want it.
♪ I feel good
Hi, Mr., cheese!
Who are you?
What do you want?
Oh, sorry to interrupt.
- You set me up.
- No.
You, you set me up.
No, I don't know them!
I promise, I swear,
I don't know them.
Take it easy, ma'am.
We are sorry this
is happening to you.
Thank you.
Look, I have a date.
I have to go.
I always want it to
be you, no one else.
Give me your hand.
No, the left.
Promise to be mine
and mine only.
I...
I promise.
Cheers.
Love you.
I love you too.
What are you thinking about?
♪ To think that I'd get
through this sober. ♪
Us.
And what have we done this time?
I'm just thinking
about my friends.
I mean, Pokua is my age and
Baaba has a fiance
that she's happy with.
♪ And now we see there's
something different. ♪
I'm just here not knowing
what's next for me, you know?
You think we don't
have a future together?
Jesse, I'm way too old for you.
Please, no high hopes.
Does it really matter?
Yes.
Yes, it matters!
You still depend
on your parents.
That matters to me.
♪ 'Cause love came
from nowhere ♪
You know, this was just a
bad idea to start off with.
♪ It's all in my eyes
I should have just taken
time out after my breakup.
Jesse, you're too young for
me to see a future with.
I'm sorry.
♪ Took me by surprise
♪ Took over my eyes
♪ You took over my eyes, baby
♪ You took over my eyes
♪ You were always
a good friend ♪
♪ And I didn't want
it to be different ♪
♪ I didn't wanna push
my luck with you ♪
♪ 'Cause in my life
you're all that's good ♪
♪ Oh, yes you are
♪ But there's some things
that I can't deny ♪
♪ I'm feeling them
things and I cannot lie ♪
♪ Oh
♪ Is it little wrong
to love you back? ♪
♪ 'Cause in your
eyes I see you do ♪
♪ You love me too
♪ Love came from nowhere
♪ Took over my eyes
♪ You took over my eyes, yeah
Oh.
♪ Oh, yes, you did
Hi, honey.
♪ You don't even
know where I am ♪
♪ Took me by surprise
I've been calling
you since 6:00 PM.
I'm sorry.
My phone went off and
I forgot to charge.
♪ Love came from nowhere
Well, I cooked dinner,
I hope it's not cold.
Oh,.
You're being bad.
♪ Took me by surprise
♪ I didn't think that
I would love you ♪
♪ I didn't know it
feels this good ♪
♪ And all this time you
were two feet away from me ♪
♪ All this time I
just couldn't see ♪
You overslept?
I didn't sleep at all.
I was up all night
just thinking.
Thinking about what?
I don't
wanna bore you, let's just go.
Mm-hmm.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, madam, I was sitting there.
Ah.
What's going on here?
Excuse me, this is our office.
What are you doing here?
You were in the news.
I heard you busted
all the politician.
That's very brave
and taking some of us forever.
Yes.
- Okay.
Welcome.
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
We'll catch them.
Ready for this?
Yes.
My husband is cheating on me.
He has made it obvious,
but I want to know whom
he's doing that with.
I suspect my best friend.
She pretend she was helping
me grow in my marriage,
but I doubt her now.
Do you have his pictures?
Yes, yes.
I do. I do.
3,000.
Hmm.
Okay.
What's your story?
I bought three packs of
condoms for him last week
and it's finished.
We made love only once.
Do you think he's
cheating on me?
- Um...
- Hmm.
You will fill this form, hey?
But what does she
need condoms for?
Is she not going
through menopause?
Maybe she's sleeping
with a younger guy.
Ah.
You know, they
have plenty disease.
Eh?
.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
What's your story?
I chanced on his phone and
went through his pictures.
I saw nude pictures, nude
pictures of a particular girl.
When I asked him,
he said, what, what,
they were from a
WhatsApp group chat.
Okay.
So I stole his phone and I
went through his group chats.
I went through all his chats.
Those pictures were from a girl.
They were from a girl.
Did you hear me at all?
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Sorry, fill that form.
That's awkward.
- Yeah.
Someone saw my husband in
hotel with a lady.
I believe strongly
he's cheating with me.
Madam, tissue.
He's cheating on me.
I want to know if he's
really cheating and with whom.
Fill this for me.
Hmm...
Not too far.
We just charge you 3,000 cedis.
Yeah.
It's fair.
Cheese!
♪ Yeah
Driver, move, move!
Quickly.
Quickly, move!
♪ Yeah
Hurry up, quick.
Hurry up!
Cheese!
Yes!
You know, I caught him once.
He said he has repented, but I
suspect he has started again.
I need help.
I know he's married,
but I'm starting to enjoy
being with him.
He says he's going to break
up with her and come for me.
I just want you to find
out if they've broken up
or are still together.
It will cost you 15,000.
What?
Yes.
Madam, this is a special case.
Mm-hmm.
You guys are not serious.
♪ Yeah
No.
He's not serious.
He's starting to enjoy his self.
?
Should've told 20,000.
Next!
It has happened several times.
I haven't caught him
though, so he keeps denying.
Would you please
help me find out?
We'll just charge
you 3,000 cedis.
It looks like it's
just business.
Let's go.
Hey, wait.
3,000.
3,000?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hmm.
Hey.
I used to be his side chick
and he got divorced
and married me.
But I think he has
a side chick now.
I want you to investigate.
- That'll cost you 10,000.
- Mm-hmm.
Huh?
Cheese!
Ooh!
Hey.
I'm sorry, is Ama in?
Yes, Sister Ama,
you have visitors.
Wait, you actually
know someone here?
No, I it.
Hey!
Hurry up!
Wait for me!
Your man goes to play
video games with his friends
and gets drunk.
Okay.
Hi.
- Hi.
How are you?
So babe, can we drop Fella home?
'Cause she wants a lift
home, can we do that?
That's fine.
We will bring you down tonight.
Hmm.
Who is there?
Huh?
- Madam.
- Hi.
I salute you.
Go ahead.
Ah.
Hi.
How can we help you?
I need your service.
Oh, I'm sorry.
We don't...
Don't work for men?
I know.
But I'll offer any amount
for this exception.
You see, I'm dying slowly.
You have to save me.
Have a seat.
Talk to us.
I'm a mining engineer.
I deal in gold and bauxite.
I've been dating my
fiance for two years.
We decided to marry next year.
I have bought
everything for her,
anything she's asked for.
She uses two cars, has her
own house, supermarket,
all from my account.
See, I just thought she
would just focus on me.
But no, she acts weird
and she's never satisfied.
She never answers my
call on the first ring.
And even when she
does, she whispers.
Why would she do that?
I suspect she's
seeing another man.
You see, I don't care how
much money I've spent on her,
on the man she's seeing,
I just want to be
sure she's cheating.
I wanna be free and walk away.
Any amount you want, I'll pay.
Okay.
Do you have her picture?
Sure, I took time out to
find out your requirements.
.
Please fill this for us.
Here, there you go.
I need an express job.
Oh.
Sure.
Yes, we'll do that.
Let me know if you need more.
- Sure.
- Okay.
Okay.
Let me hear from you soon.
- Oh, you will.
- Yeah.
Wow!
Wait, I thought
he bought her a car.
She's smart.
I wouldn't use my car too.
No one want to be
caught cheating.
She's coming!
Keep calm, no panic.
She's coming.
What a nice house.
Keep calm, no panic.
Oh, hi.
You need help?
Why are you following me?
Oh, who are you?
Heh?
Hmm.
What do you want?
Look, I've heard about you
girls in the green ride.
Girls in the green ride?
There must be a mistake.
Yeah.
We are girls-
- Girls on the road.
- Yeah.
Girls on the road.
Ooh, yeah.
Who's paying you to follow me?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I mean, that's gone too far.
I mean, what would
make you think that?
So why did you
stop when I stopped?
Slow down, sorry.
Ooh, ooh, ou-ou-...
We s-
Our engine broke down
a- and the car stopped
a- and we stopped.
Yes.
You know, this is a
Lancia, so...
- Yeah.
.
Hmm.
This is screwed!
Damn!
Damn.
Damn it.
We need spice.
What for?
For tip off.
We can't be following
her like that,
it will ruin everything.
Pokua, that means more money.
More money,
where are we gonna get it from?
I doubled the amounts
to speed up the process.
I hope it pays off.
Do you need some more
pictures for this?
Oh, no, no, don't worry,
we just want copies of the
old ones we have.
Okay.
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
I mean, why wouldn't
she use one of the cars
that you bought her?
Excuse me?
Yes, I mean, she hired a taxi.
She's in to hiding, she
doesn't want me to find out.
- Oh yeah, I figured.
- Oh.
That's smart.
You'll hear from us.
I count on you.
Yeah.
We got spice at
the west and east.
We're targeting hotels,
restaurants, and guest house.
Please hold on. Mr. Sefa.
Hello?
Hello.
I just saw your target.
Just checked into our hotel.
.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Can I call you back, Mr. Sefa?
Ladies, we have a tip off!
Ooh!
It's good you're here.
I just went in there,
there in the bathroom
and.
Room one.
- This has-
- Shh, shh, shh!
Calm, honey.
Honey, calm down.
I- It's not what it looks
like, I can explain.
Eh.
I can explain.
?
What?
Honey, listen, listen.
Honey, listen.
Calm down.
Honey, wait.
Wait, wait.
Calm down.
I can explain, it's
not what it looks like!
Honey, wait, wait!
Thank you.
Ex-excuse me?
Payment, please?
Oh, that.
Yeah, we're here.
Yeah, someone will
handle your payment.
Did you enjoy
seeing your husband
with another woman?
You are happy destroying
marriages for money.
We helped you find
your cheating husband.
You should pay us.
Is that not what you do?
You see, that lady
is not my fiance.
I don't know her.
But thanks for your service.
I admire your speed.
Have a good day.
O- okay.
Okay.
Hmm?
- It's okay?
- You okay?
Let's go back to.
Let's go, let's go.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
No, I'm fine.
Please, have a seat.
So, talk to us.
I suspect my boyfriend
is cheating on me.
My friends say he
hangs out with a woman,
which obviously isn't me.
I can't remember the last
time we went out together.
It's been over a year.
Wow.
Mm-hmm.
I will need you to help me.
I want to know if he's
seeing someone else.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Um...
Is-is-is this
your-your boyfriend?
Yes.
How long have you been together?
Three years.
Any problem?
Um, no.
No problem.
This is just the regular
background check.
Oh.
So are you gonna help me?
- Yeah, sure.
- Hmm.
We'll help you.
Splendid.
So I will await your feedback.
Baaba?
Hmm?
Hey, Baaba, there must be
some explanation to this.
No, it's hot.
- Baaba?
- Hmm?
Oh, wow.
Babe, are you okay?
No, I'm fine.
Are you sure?
No, I'm very fine.
Hi?
♪ They play and they
roll with me, Chaley ♪
♪ And act like they
down with me, Chaley ♪
♪ But the joke is
on me, Chaley ♪
♪ This pain for leave
♪ I wonder why people
dey hate on me, Chaley ♪
♪ They hate when I
elevate, Chaley ♪
♪ Sometimes they hate
the pain, Chaley ♪
♪ But I no dey biz
♪ Man for wake up
Do you want?
No, it's fine.
No, don't do that.
Is she okay?
I'm okay.
Adam has a girlfriend.
Maybe this SideChic
Gang is not worth it.
Maybe we should close
it down and move on.
Perhaps there are more
important things to focus on
than this.
Yeah, maybe.
♪ Edey pain edey pain
♪ Ah
You don't have to
come to work again.
There's a six month
salary to take care of you
whilst you find another job.
I know how angry you are.
I messed up.
No excuse can restore you.
I'm so sorry.
I just needed you a little
more, but you were always gone.
I've been angry and I
even wanted to break up,
but I changed my thoughts
'cause I don't want to lose you.
A lot of things changed
when you started this
SideChic Gang business.
You leave home before I'm awake
and you return when I'm asleep.
I mean, it was just crazy
spending all those nights alone.
It almost felt like
I was single again.
I was frustrated,
I couldn't concentrate at work,
so I started doing crazy stuff.
Howcome we never
spoke about this?
I didn't know how
you would take it.
My friends told me that's
how to calm myself down and
I listened to them.
I am so sorry.
I want my wife back.
I love you so much.
I need you to spend a little
more time with me, please.
I don't want this to end.
Finally responding to
my calls and messages.
So now you know why I'm
not responding to your calls
and messages.
Maybe I got tired of
being a side chick.
I deserve a boyfriend
that's committed to me.
Baabs, come on,
I can explain this.
Please open up.
Please?
I can explain.
♪ Know you tell me, say,
you no want boyfriend ♪
♪ Tell me why me,
I take 'em slower ♪
♪ But you take me to
all your best friends ♪
♪ We didn't come out for
quite some time now ♪
♪ Everybody knows
in me then you ♪
♪ All of a sudden
The number you called is busy.
Have regular
call charges, please
stay on the line.
♪ Lovey, you take me, go
your house, go greet mummy ♪
The number you called is busy.
Have regular calls-
♪ This love will last forever
♪ Lovey, you tell me, say,
not only me you love ♪
♪ I see you blast
some guy for town ♪
Is this what you want,
a break up?
That is the only thing left.
Look, I'm done with this.
I work so hard for us.
Oh, you think that is easy?
I work hard too.
Very hard.
But I still find time for you!
You are so obsessed
with yourself,
your work and the numerous
business meetings.
Maybe you should
start dating them.
Mm-hmm.
They'll be better
girlfriends than me.
I'm sorry!
So, so this is what
I deserve, right?
I have an idea.
Girls, it took too
much courage for us
to set up SideChic Gang.
We can't just let it
die just like that.
There must be something
that we can do different.
So, I was thinking that
instead of using SideChic Gang
to fight side chicks,
maybe we should use it to
counsel couples, you know,
to help them prevent it.
Look, I know we've had our
own share of harsh lessons,
but let's use our experiences.
Let's use it to tell
these couples what to do
to keep their partners,
save their relationships,
their marriages, their homes,
and the end result, there'll
be no more need for side chicks
or side dudes or
anything like that.
So, what do you think?
Brilliant.
Yeah.
Come here.
Oh!
So, how may we help you?
My husband has not been
the man I married lately.
You know, so many
things changed.
I think he doesn't find
me attractive anymore.
I used to be the only thing
he ever dreamt of, but now,
he's unbothered.
I see why I don't exist.
It hurts.
Truly hurts.
I feel he's finding another
woman beautiful somewhere.
Please,
I need you to help me.
I want to know if there's
someone in his life.
What were the things
you did together
when you were the only
thing he needed in his life?
We even went to watch movies,
went on dinner
dates and shopping.
Why did that stop?
Well, personally, I
feel we were growing up
and it was time to leave
some of such things,
so I took a break.
So when's the last time he
said something nice to you?
Yesterday.
Wait, wait, look.
It's nice if he means
the nice things he says
and that's the problem.
And when was the last time
you said something nice to him?
Hmm...
I can't recall.
I can't remember.
Look, see,
my husband is very
annoying, trust me.
You wouldn't like him
when you meet him.
Anytime I thought to say
something nice, he ruined it.
What did he do?
Uh...
Are there that many?
Oh, yeah.
A lot of them.
I can't even remember.
I can't even think of one.
And have you
tried talking to him
to find out what the problem is?
I did not.
I mean, I'm scared
it will upset him.
Ma'am, it's hard
for us to tell you
if your husband is
cheating or not.
First, you stopped
doing the things
that sparked up
your relationship,
the dinner, the
movies, the shopping.
It's a terror.
All because you felt too
old for them.
And he started seeing you
as an old, boring woman
without spark.
That aside, he still
compliments you, but you do not.
I think you're creating
your own side chick.
Get rid of her before she
takes away your marriage.
Okay.
How much do I owe?
It's a free service,
but we'll charge you for
your next appointments.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
♪ Yeah