(Projector whirring)
*
(Woman) Please come back.
(Panting)
Okay, okay, okay.
*
(Rustling)
(Panting)
Please, please, please, please.
I'll... I'll do
anything you want.
I won't say anything.
Please.
Just... please.
Please come back!
Please!
I promise.
(Sobs)
(Sfx)
*
(sounds of birds and insects)
(Janey) Excus...
(Albert) No talking.
*
(Unlocks doors)
(Door opens)
(The Doctor) Janey Andrews.
This is the only conversation
you'll have here.
To respect the process we keep
things as quiet as possible.
Arrested for assault.
(Janey) I didn't do it.
My job is not to
determine guilt.
Judge Prince already
decided that.
My job is to rehabilitate you.
If you fail you will go to
jail. So, if you comply, follow
the rules, embrace the silence,
we won't have a problem.
Now everyone requires a
different amount of time.
The judge said I only
have to stay a month.
A month for some.
For others...
You should be grateful this is
the option you've been given.
Now we're a family-run business.
It's just myself
and my two sons.
We only cater to five
patients at a time.
Our success rate is very high.
The rules are simple.
No talking.
No phones.
No Internet.
No music.
No reading.
No writing.
No eye contact.
No gestures.
No touching.
No sexual misconduct.
We sleep at sunset,
get up at sunrise.
It is imperative that
you stay quiet at night.
(Whispers)
You went through my bag?
You can't do that.
Distractions!
They cloud the mind.
They interfere.
That's all that's
left of my family.
Well, that gives you one more
reason to follow the rules.
You'll get it back
when we're done.
It's an invasion of privacy.
Here you have no privacy.
You have no voice.
No name.
No identity.
It's time to clear your mind
of all that unnecessary noise.
Is that clear?
*
(Girl clears throat)
Are we waiting for dinner?
(Clears throat)
I just...
Shhh.
(Girl) Ha!
(Kicks plate)
(Howling)
(Muffled music)
(snarling)
(Music sounds)
(Music stops)
(Creaing and rattling)
(Bang)
*
(Sfx)
(The Doctor)
Close your eyes.
Relax and let go.
You're floating through the air.
Nothing is around you.
Now, as you relax, let
your thoughts disappear.
Let your mind wander.
Relax.
(Girl) Psssst...
(The Doctor) Slowly, slowly...
an image comes into your
mind, through the darkness.
An empty theatre.
You're in the front row.
There are soft noises,
comforting noises.
Listen to the soft sounds.
(Pink Stripe) No. Let go of me.
I'm not going with you.
(The Doctor)
The sound will disappear.
10, 9...
(Sfx)
Don't tell
them I'm in here.
(Struggling and shrieking)
No!
Nooo!!
Don't put me in there.
Don't put me in there. Please.
Please I'll do anything.
Please. No. No.
(Muffled music)
(Growl)
*
(Paul) Now.
I'm not going with you.
(Growl)
Now.
(sound of film
projector running)
(The Doctor) You're lucky
my son picked you up.
There are things here that
only come out at night,
things you don't
want to encounter.
Besides, we're
miles from anywhere.
(Door closes)
I saw them drag her away.
What do you think happened here?
I...
You?
I don't know.
You have no idea who this girl
is, why she was sent here,
and yet you sit
there and accuse me.
We are turning her into
a respectable person.
One day she'll make a good wife.
We have a two-strike policy.
This is strike one.
Strike two - you go to jail.
Nod if you understand.
Don't disappoint me again.
(Hypnotic voice)
The noises are vanishing.
8,7.
All around you.
Silence.
6, 5.
The quiet is so comforting.
The deep silence.
4, deeper, 3,
2, deeper, 1.
1,2,3.
Open your eyes.
(Whispers) What happened?
(The Doctor) Close your eyes.
Relax and let go.
You're floating through the air.
Nothing is around you.
Again. Again. Again.
(Gagging)
(Alexis) Come on.
*
Wooo.
I've been dying to
do that for weeks.
You should try it.
(Janey) No.
I'm okay.
So, how did you do it?
Special ingredient in the food.
The older brother likes me.
Let me in the kitchen.
We probably have,
like, 20 minutes.
I'm Alexis.
Janey.
You know I've been
thinking you're a Susan,
or a Julia for the last week.
Janey's not even close.
You got the J right.
Been here for three weeks.
Got to do something to keep
from going insane here.
They're changing us.
Somehow.
One day you're fine,
the next it's like
you're Little Miss Stepford.
Just like the girl
with the pink stripe.
And the others too.
That's pretty much how you last
around here. You have to keep
quiet and keep your head down,
and act like it's working.
She was here just
before you were.
I woke up one morning and she
was gone. That was on her door.
Okay. So she left.
You're not an idiot.
They took them to the
cabin didn't they?
Yeah.
What happens in there?
You tell me.
You were there yesterday.
I don't...
you don't
remember either.
They took you there today.
I... what?
Why haven't we changed?
I don't know.
I don't want to know.
We have to get out of here.
You need to help me.
I haven't seen a phone
around here, but if we...
No.
I tried to leave last
night and it's just one road
miles before we could get any...
If we take the car we
can get out of here.
There's a car parked
outside the office. I saw it.
Well where are the keys.
If I knew that I'd be gone.
I need you on the
lookout tonight.
We should go.
(Janey) We have to be careful
if we're going at night.
They're scared of something.
We outnumber them.
No.
I tried to leave last night.
He was scared of
something, in the woods.
The cabin.
What, now?
When else?
**
(Whimpering)
(Door closes)
Janey?
He tucked me in.
Okay, we have to go.
The cabin?
There's nothing in there.
What do you mean nothing?
(Car starts)
The car.
No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We'll try again tomorrow.
My ex used to say that.
Tomorrow will be better.
She used to say "we'll
win it tomorrow".
Doesn't do shit about today.
She?
Yeah.
Small town.
You know?
It was... a thing.
My family... well...
I don't exist to them.
I, uh, started an impromptu,
permitless pride parade and
I sat in the middle of the
busiest intersection until
the police took me away.
Yep. And now I'm here to
curb my radical tendencies.
Well, they're right.
Nothing we say matters.
Did you accomplish
anything with your parade?
Or did things just go on
like they always have?
I tried to explain to
them what happened to me...
that he had his
hands on me... that he...
but it didn't
make a difference.
That's why we're here
because no one cares.
Someone must. I mean,
what about your family?
They... died.
The car hit ice.
It was night.
We went over the shoulder.
It was a long way down.
Mom's neck snapped
when we landed.
Dad... he was still alive.
He couldn't say anything.
He was hurt.
His eyes though...
he wasn't scared.
He was smiling.
He didn't want me to panic.
I couldn't get out of my seat.
I was stuck, so I just
started to scream.
I thought if one person
could hear me, somebody.
I could see the headlights
through the window.
All the cars driving above us.
I screamed for hours and hours,
and the entire time he just
looked right into
my eyes and smiled.
He did it for me.
I couldn't do anything to
help him and he just died.
Right there.
He just died.
All that noise for nothing.
But you were still fighting,
and you're still alive.
I mean, that's why we scream,
to let the world know
that we're still here and
that we haven't given up.
(The Doctor) An empty theatre.
You're in the front row.
There are soft noises,
comforting noises.
(Foot steps)
Don't go with him.
You've broken the silence.
I just..she should stay here.
Oh. So you're running things
now? You seem to think that
your words are more
important than everyone elses.
Go to Hell.
What?
Good.
These girls could have
spent a lifetime behind bars,
but now they're going
to serve society and raise
families as nature
intended them to.
But you... I tried.
I did.
But that's two strikes.
I can't do anything with you.
Take her to her room.
She'll be leaving
in the morning.
- Is she asleep?
- Yes.
Get Cabin 9 ready.
You. Take over for your brother.
(Albert)
I'll take care of the cabin.
You'll keep watch.
But that thing out there.
It's been more sensitive lately.
Damn it.
Aaahhh!!
(Drops)
Going now.
Where did he go?
Oh God.
I hope these keys
are easy to find.
Keep an eye out.
Janey.
Alexis.
The Doctor's name is Prince.
It's Doctor Prince.
Doctor Prince and Judge Prince.
They have the same name.
They're brothers.
(Alexis) It's my release form.
It's already been signed.
Both of their signatures.
(Janey) Mine too.
Why are they signed?
They want people to
think we're free.
*
Oh shit.
They're covering their tracks.
That girl who left the note.
She never finished
her treatment.
What day was it
when you came here?
What?
What day?
- October 22nd.
- What year?
What the Hell are you
talking about? This year.
- Which is?
- 2014.
No.
I can't remember any of this.
What are you talking about?
I can't remember... why
I can't I remember this?
(Sobs)
What are you talking
about Alexis?
I came here September 1st, 2012.
*
We need to find the keys.
Come on.
(Keys jingle)
Janey.
(Muted voices)
(Door squeaks open)
So you thought you'd
just drive away did you?
(Chuckles)
You're a very bad
influence, Janey.
I had such hope for you.
You had everything
the others didn't.
I thought you
were the one for me,
but disobedience like
this cannot go unpunished.
(Squeals)
Bring her inside.
We don't want it to hear.
You.
Where's your friend?
Is she here with you?
I thought we weren't
supposed to talk.
(Slap)
When she's out take
her to the cabin.
I'll grab your brother.
Son, this is her last chance.
(Squeals)
(Falls silent)
Please let this work.
We can finally be together.
Did she have any keys on her?
No.
Alright. This is the last time.
If it doesn't work...
I know.
Now find the other girl.
Now I'm going to count
backwards from 10.
(Film projector)
10, 9, 8,
7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1.
(Snaps fingers)
(Rattles door)
(knocks on door)
Hello?
You can't keep me locked
up in here forever.
(Door squeaks)
(The Doctor) Now comes
the unfortunate moment
where I inform you that
you have failed the test.
(Alexis) Two years?
And what... you're just
going to make me disappear?
You're going to have to
try harder than that.
Let go of me.
You want me to be an animal?
Argh!!
An animal would be better.
Animals can be trained.
Women?
Women are trickier.
So hard to find
a good wife these days.
Someone for your sons.
A wife that can be tamed, that
can learn to uphold your values.
So why not create them?
The demand is there, we
just supply the product.
What? We're part of a
matchmaking service?
I'll kill you.
No you won't.
My ex-wife said the same thing.
Right over there after I
caught her cheating on me.
And then something evolution
forgot came out of the woods
and gave me the solution
to all my problems.
What?
I don't know
where it came from,
but it kills for
me when I need it to.
Say goodbye.
He loved you, so much.
We tried.
We really tried, but you
didn't want to be fixed.
Please.
(Rustling)
Are you okay?
Those bastards.
I know. Get me out of here.
It's locked.
Find a rock.
I think I found
something sharp here.
Oh shit.
What the Hell is that?
Hurry up.
(Growl)
- Janey...
- Shhhhhh.
(Growl)
(Rustling)
(Sfx)
(Screams)
Oh Janey!
(Growling, scrunching)
(Growls)
(Puff)
There you are.
You sick fuck.
You chained her to that tree
with that thing out there?
(Punch)
This is why I called you here
in the middle of the night.
These girls suffer from
paranoid delusions.
Is this a delusion?
There's something in the woods
and he tried to feed me to it.
Now listen to yourself.
Something in the woods.
Think of everything
you've been through here.
You know something's off.
These girls have
accepted their treatment.
They're getting better.
How long have they
been here for?
Alexis has been
here for two years.
She doesn't remember any of it.
You told me this
place was bullshit.
(The Doctor) They're just
trying to undermine the good
works that we're doing here.
(Janey) How many of you even
knew her name before I said it?
If you continue to...
I'm Janey.
I'm Sara.
Come here.
Show them you...
Katie.
You would have been so perfect.
(Alexis) You can't
hide in there all night.
* Cello plays
* Cello plays.
(Girl) Something's moving.
We need to stay quiet.
*
(Thwack)
Shut it.
(Scream)
Oh my God.
What is that?
Oh no.
My glasses. Oh no.
(Rattling)
(Scream)
Help me!
*
(Crunching)
(Scurrying)
*
(Scream)
(Loud noises)
(Silence)
(Drips)
(Clatter)
(Gasp)
(Alexis) Janey.
Leave her.
(Janey) No.
I don't know how we're
going to do this.
Go.
No.
(Deep panting)
(Puff)
It's hurt by every sound.
Did it see you?
No.
Shhh.
Could come back.
The sound hurt it more
than usual tonight.
10 years.
It's never made
a mess like this.
It's protecting something.
One.
Two.
Three.
Two missing.
Well, the others
must have escaped.
Get them.
I let them go,
I'll get them back.
Fine. Go.
Start cleaning.
Shit.
He's coming.
(Rock music)
(Whimpering)
(Loud music)
(Growling, screaming)
Do something.
(Scream)
(Glass hatters)
What are you doing?
It's busy.
(Tearing)
It should have never happened.
What was that?
Quiet.
You let him die.
I've got two more
bitches to put down.
(Banging)
(Growl)
***
(Soft growl)
(Crack)
(Door closes)
(Car doesn't start)
- No.
- Try again. It's okay.
(Car doesn't start)
No, no, no, no.
Okay. Pop the hood.
Pop the hood.
Okay.
What's the problem?
They disconnected the fuel line.
I'm going to need some pliers.
Didn't think a girl would be
smart enough to figure it out.
No I didn't.
Alexis!
(Locks door)
Alexis, get under!
Get the crowbar.
(Car horn)
(Agonized sounds)
(Whimpering)
(Janey) Wait.
No. No.
(Whimpering)
We're almost there.
We'll go in here.
You need to stay quiet.
Please stay quiet.
(Crying)
You have to be quiet.
Look at me.
(Loud crying)
(Bang)
Stop, stop, stop.
Please be quiet.
(Loud bangs)
(Wailing)
I don't know what to do.
(Bangs)
No. No. No.
I'm dying anyways.
Please.
It's okay.
I can't.
I can't do it.
Please.
Do it.
Make sure they know
you're still here.
No.
*
(The Doctor)
Looks like we got a rabid one.
(Albert) I found the crowbar.
(The Doctor) Come on.
*
Aaahhh!!!
(Growling)
*
I want you to do
something for me.
Scream!
(Loud screaming)
(Growl)
*
Go to Hell.
Go to Hell!!
(Agonized screams)
(Repeated loud screaming)
(Whimpering, crying)
(Loud scream)
(Very loud scream)
*