(thunder booming)
(wind whistling)
("The Star-Spangled Banner")
- [Announcer] Ladies
and gentlemen,
the President of
the United States.
- [President Roosevelt] This
generation has passed through
many recent years
of deep darkness,
watching the spread of
the poison of Hitlerism
and Fascism in Europe,
and the growth of imperialism
and militarism in Japan,
and the final clash of
war all over the world.
Then came the dark days
of the fall of France,
and the ruthless
bombing of England,
and the desperate
battle of the Atlantic,
and of Pearl Harbor.
- [Reporter] Less than
three years before,
Hitler had addressed
the Reichstag.
(Hitler speaking
foreign language)
(Nazis cheering)
- [Reporter] A delirious
madness possessed
the German nation.
- [Reporter] In Rome, his
fascist partner had declared:
- [Mussolini] Fascist Italy
and Nationalist Socialist
Germany, ever closely linked,
participate from today on
the side of heroic Japan
against the United States.
- [Reporter] A
Japanese militarist
joins the directive corps.
Americans have radios,
automobiles, big beef steaks.
When a people have those things,
they don't want to fight.
- [Donny] Listening
to war reports?
- [Reporter] Americans
won't sleep in hammocks
or lie in trenches.
- Did the radio say the
Germans might attack us?
- [Reporter] They are like
a tiger selling his wool
They are sleeping.
- Smells really good.
- Why don't you go out and
fetch some fresh water, hm?
Don't forget your coat.
- [Donny] Yes, sir.
(light music)
(light music continues)
(plane roaring)
(ominous music)
(explosions booming)
(suspenseful music)
(Rudy clears throat)
(gentle music)
- How was your morning flight?
- Oh yeah, good.
Pretty chilly this morning.
The crows are starting
to pick at the crops.
I'm gonna fly like them one day.
(gentle music)
- Chilly this morning.
You enjoy that too.
I know we're struggling
right now, but it won't last.
I promise.
- We defying mama's
rules by doing this?
- No, you are.
(Rudy laughing)
Let's take these
out to the barn.
(light music)
(engines rumbling)
(light music continues)
(Eduard's wife speaking
foreign language)
(light music continues)
(brakes squeaking)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
- Hello.
- Welcome to America.
- Oh, thank you.
- [Soldier] Sit back!
- I think Mom's up.
- [Rudy] Let's get at it.
(light music)
- Mom was so mad
at you this morning
for not wanting to go to church.
- [Rudy] None of
your concern, Donny.
- Do I have to go to church?
- What would your mother say?
- It's not fair.
You never let me-
- [Rudy] How was that coffee?
Not gonna win 'em all.
(light music)
(engines rumbling)
(light music continues)
- The Germans.
Were those Germans?
- Yes.
Let's finish up.
(light music continues)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(prisoner speaking
(hand slapping)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(suspenseful music)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg chuckles)
(dramatic music)
(Jorg speaks foreign language)
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(dramatic music continues)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Jorg chuckling)
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(soft music)
- (exhales) I think
these are the last ones.
(Rudy groans)
(wood cracking)
You okay?
Your back?
- I'll be all right.
I'll be all right.
Go on and set those down.
- You sure?
- Yeah, yeah.
Let's leave 'em
in the truck okay?
- Okay.
(Rudy sighs)
(light music)
(Rudy groans)
(Rudy panting)
(ominous music)
Not in my town.
(explosions booming)
(gunshots banging)
(planes roaring)
Come on.
Come on, win it.
(ominous music continues)
(plane roaring)
(gunshots banging)
- Did we get them?
- No.
I think they
ruptured my gas tank.
- Ah, man.
Next time.
Come on, let's go
get something to eat.
- Yes, sir.
- [Rudy] Oh.
(drums beating)
- So my quartermaster looked
into the accidental drowning
death of Fronz Braun.
And he is gonna be given
a simple grave marker,
two feet high, marble stone,
just like any soldier in any
American military cemetery.
- Sir, I speak for
the German men.
I must inform you I have applied
delegation of Switzerland
on this matter.
- And if they respond
any differently,
then we can open this
up for discussion again.
But until then, this
is what I authorize.
Dismissed.
- Danke schoen for the coffee.
- Morning, sir.
- Good morning.
Have a seat.
- Complaining again?
- Not any more than normal.
Report.
- Yeah, sorry sir.
The prisoners are in transit
back from the cannery.
Provost Marshal Klein is
overseeing them personally.
- Good.
- Night shift detachment
completed their assignment
at the Hormel Cannery.
All is present
and accounted for.
In fact, Hormel donated
several cases of product.
- Linda?
- Yes? Here, sir.
- Let us get a
thank you note out
to the Hormel plant immediately.
- Hormel? Yes, sir.
Anything else?
- [Lodell] That is all.
- Hello, Lieutenant Grant.
- Ms. Schuler.
- [Lodell] That is all, Linda.
- Good girl.
- How's the wife, Lieutenant?
- Good. Good.
Very good, sir.
- Good, good.
So is was that fence repair
near tower six coming?
- Already done, sir.
- And that sewage?
- Completed as of yesterday.
And all these men, they,
they work exceptionally well,
I must say.
- Maybe the mess hall could
use a second coat of paint.
- We took care of that
about two weeks ago, sir.
Do you think it needs another?
- Lieutenant, what I need
is a new list of duties
to keep these men occupied.
Honest work, Lieutenant.
That's what keeps their minds
off troublemaking and escape.
Do you know why most of
the Civil War soldiers
tried to escape?
- [Grant] Can't say that I do.
- To reunite with
their loved ones.
So until these men are
reunited with their loved ones,
it's our job to
maintain the peace.
- Yes, peace.
Sir, speaking about peace,
the Red Cross has
sent another shipment
of goodwill art supplies.
- Good.
See that they're
dispersed accordingly.
But give that Eduard
fellow first look.
Have you seen what
he's been working on?
- I have.
I caught a glimpse
of it the other day.
Gotta say, it's, it's
quite impressive.
Beautiful works of art.
- Good.
Dismissed.
(drums beating)
(phone ringing)
(car engine rumbling)
(ominous music)
(gunshots banging)
- [Donny] Grandma!
- [Rudy] Donny!
(suspenseful music)
- [Checkpoint Soldier]
All right, keep it moving.
Just follow them.
- Sure is a lot of them.
(fist knocking)
- Hey, good morning, Clara.
- [Clara] Carl.
- I hope you don't
mind me stopping in.
- Why don't you come inside?
I was just warming some milk.
Can I get you anything?
- Oh, not for now.
Thank you.
Where's that little
blessing baby Jean at?
- Should be up soon.
Uh, I wasn't expecting
to see you today.
- No, I wanted to
see you, Clara.
You're special to me.
We missed you at our gatherings.
Again.
- Been busy helping
Rudy make ends meet.
- You know, Clara, I can
make things easier for you.
That man of yours is broken.
A father with a
bad back is like a,
a singer without a voice.
- You should leave.
I'll see you at
service, I promise.
(Carl scoffs)
- You know, Clara,
you and the boys,
you could have it better.
- Please go.
(door rattling)
- Get your man over
here and fix this door.
(door slamming)
(car engine rumbling)
(Donny sighs)
- You think them
Germans are dangerous?
- Can't say.
- You're right.
Can't say, can we?
- [Tom] You shouldn't
have them Nazi brats
around here nohow.
- Well, let's not be spouting
off with all that hate talk.
Now, Tom, them boys over there,
they're not any
different from our boys.
And in the same situation and-
- Frank, you've got a grandson
fighting in the Navy, right?
You're gonna be singing that
same tune when a Jap sub
sends your grandson to
the bottom of the ocean?
- Tom Barrett, you're
coming darn close
to crossing a line with me.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let's calm down now.
- I fought the Germans in
the first war, remember?
And I still don't think we
need to blame all Germans
for the actions of some.
- Many folks in our community
come from German stock.
- That's right.
- And good stock it is too.
- Well, maybe some of
your fine German folk
may have treasonous thoughts.
Do you ever think about that?
- Oh, come on, Tom, you don't-
- Not what we're saying is it?
- Why don't you go ask some
of our Jewish neighbors
how they feel about those
Nazi death camp reports.
- Algona has been called upon.
It's our duty as Americans
to look over the-
- Shut up, Clip.
If all you wanna roll over
and let these Nazi bastards
live here among us,
well you watch what
happens the first time
something happens
to our families.
(light dramatic music)
- Warm-ups?
- Oh, definitely.
- Yeah, I think that'd be good.
- Helen, I'll take one.
- Make that two, please.
- What do you say, William?
- [William] I don't say.
- You must have some say
on the matter, don't ya?
- [William] You don't want
to hear what I have to say
on such matters.
- Well, do you think how
these PWs here in town
is a good idea?
(William sighs)
- I enjoy my peace and
quiet here in the morning.
Time to read my paper, I
have my coffee and biscuits,
but this morning is turning
into quite an awful ruckus.
- Yeah, I do apologize
for all of that, William.
But you, this is
your hometown too.
You must have some thoughts.
- You must know about enslaved
people and such, right?
- I was born in the north.
I'm not an expert
on nigger affairs,
which disqualifies me from
being any sort of expert
on Nazi affairs.
- But you do have a say, right?
(William sighs)
- If I give y'all my say, will
you leave me alone in peace?
I know that fear can
create hateful feelings.
It's easier to be
angry than to own fear.
But them boys in that camp,
they're just like your
sons and your grandsons.
They're just doing
what they're told.
And I'd be willing to wager
you that them boys are more
afraid of us than
we are of them.
Now, I sell products at
that camp all the time,
and I see no reason
to hate anybody.
This war will be over soon,
and them boys are
gonna go back home.
Home to whatever's left
and whoever's left alive.
I wouldn't lose
no sleep over it.
Okay, so why don't you
gentlemen go about your business
and leave this old
negro to his coffee
and his newspaper in peace.
Hm?
(William sighs)
- You know where coffee
beans come from, little man?
- No, where?
- Not from Iowa.
- I just brewed a fresh pot.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You want anything to eat?
- Just the usual please.
Hey, I need to go have
a word with William.
Okay?
- Okay.
- William, may I speak with you?
- Oh, what can I do for
you, young Mr. Tietz?
- You were saying that you
sell goods to the camp?
- You heard right.
They get most of their goods
from corporate accounts,
but they do buy
some things local.
- Well, I might
have some surplus
that I could sure stand to move.
- Well, they buy
milk, eggs, pies.
Most anything you
can get in there.
They see it as good relations.
- You wouldn't mind
if I moved a few items
over there would you?
- Oh, absolutely I'll do that.
And you can go with
me on the next trip.
I'll make some introductions.
- I'd really appreciate that.
And I'm more than
happy to drive.
Hey, Helen.
His breakfast is on me.
Thank you.
- Mr. Tietz.
(drums beating)
- [Lewis] Hate paperwork.
I'm always doing paperwork.
Every day I'm doing paperwork.
- Ah, Sergeant Lewis.
- Hey.
- The men who were working
lumber further north
claims they saw,
how you say this?
Indians in the forest.
- [Lewis] Indian head penny.
- They were afraid
of getting their hair
and the skin removed
with a knife.
- What, scalped?
- Huh?
- Indians, nah, not likely.
So you found those coins
in the back of the truck?
- Yes.
- Well, hey, lemme trade you
up for some, some coupons.
Prisoners aren't allowed
to have currency.
- Ah.
- So I'm gonna give you
some of these.
Thanks.
- Ah.
I will use it to
try this hair piece
you speak so highly of.
- No, nein, no.
Hershey's.
- Oh.
- It's a chocolate bar.
- Ah.
- You're gonna love 'em.
Little piece of heaven.
Hair piece, whole
different thing.
You don't want that.
- I could use a little heaven.
Yeah.
- Hey, hey.
So I heard you krauts was
working on some sort of project.
- Yeah, we've been working
hard on it in our spare time.
- Spare time.
Hey, this time of year,
Christmas, I miss my girl.
- Mm.
- She's back in Brooklyn.
That's New York City.
- Hm.
- I get real excited
about Christmas.
She doesn't care
that much about it,
on account of her
being Jewish and all.
They don't really
believe in that,
well the same things
that, that all of us...
Yeah. Yeah.
But I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to bring that up.
- It's okay, I-
- I know not all
Germans are, you know-
- You don't have to
explain yourself.
- Okay.
Okay, yeah.
- Yeah.
- See you, Eddie.
See you.
- Bye, Helen.
- Take care.
- Miss Fitzgerald is real
nice, don't you think?
- I think we've had
enough coffee for the day.
(rag rubbing)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(door slamming)
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(prisoners of war chuckling)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(suspenseful music)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
- Hey, hey, fellas.
Everything okay?
- [Alios] Yes.
Everything is fine, thank you.
- [Alan] What's going on?
(Jorg panting)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
- You shall have
no Gods before me.
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(paper rustling)
- Go with peace, my friend.
- I can fix that.
My father was a
librarian in town.
He repaired many books.
I helped him when
I was a young boy.
- I would appreciate that.
Thank you.
- Yeah.
- What set that off?
(Eduard sighs)
- We all love our country
in, in very different ways
and it's harder for
some to face the facts.
- Yeah, I know.
I also know that you've been
volunteering for night shifts
at the Hormel Cannery.
- Yeah.
I was hoping the extra pay and
more time would help me work
on the project during the day.
- That's actually why I
came to speak with you.
Might have some good news.
Colonel Lodell is thinking
about having you and your men
go full-time on the project.
- Oh.
- [Alan] With pay.
- With pay?
- With a little pay.
Possibly as soon as next week.
Okay, he's also thinking
about assigning you
an empty warehouse
to use as a studio.
- Wunderbar.
This would help our
time schedule greatly.
- Well, it's truly wunderbar
what you and your men are doing.
- We might be able to finish
the new one by Christmas
with a little faith.
- Amen.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard chuckling)
- Hi, Mr. Tietz.
Hi, Donny.
- Good to see you and
your mother getting
by with the store.
- Hi.
- I was thinking about
working at the PW camp
as a clerk in the canteen.
But you know who
won't let me go.
Yeah, she works there.
- Yeah, your mother's just
trying to look out for you.
That's all.
- Mm hm.
Well, you have that right.
And I'll have to keep
looking out for my daughter
until she starts
making better choices.
- Hello, Mrs. Heckler.
You look great in your uniform.
- Miss.
Or, or is, is it?
- No, it's okay.
You know, since
Howard was killed,
I'm not really sure what
to call myself either.
Did you ever get around
to trying that ointment
for your back spasms?
- Oh, no, no.
Not yet.
How is the second
job at the camp?
- It, it's okay.
Just doing my part to help.
- I was just telling
Mr. Tietz here
about how you won't
let me work there.
It's not fair.
- Fair has nothing
to do with it.
- Afraid them German soldiers
might try and kill us all?
(hand tapping)
- Oh, no.
It isn't the killing I'm worried
about with those soldiers.
And the danger can be found
on both sides of the fence
for a girl her age.
- Mother, I'm 17.
- [Donny] What are
you worried about?
- Enough, Donny.
- [Donny] What?
- Hush.
- Okay, that's enough.
I don't wanna hear
another word about it.
I need your help with the store.
Understood?
- Yes.
- Good.
Okay, I need to get going.
Let's catch up soon over coffee.
And oh please tell
Clara hello for me.
- I would like that.
And I will.
- Anything else?
- One chocolate bar, please.
- [Sally] Hm, of course.
- [Donny] Thank you.
- Take care.
- Bye.
Come back soon.
Bye, Donny.
- [Donny] Bye.
- Hello, Chaplain Fluke.
- Eduard.
- Hi.
- Two pickles please.
- Oh, yeah. Thank you.
- Three.
(Eduard chuckling)
Thank you.
- We need more supplies.
Some of the materials
have been weeks incoming.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
- There is a war on.
Some of the supplies
are hard to come by.
What do you need?
- We need more plaster,
fire, paint, it's...
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- I'll, I'll see what I can do.
- Yeah, it's, this war has
really ruined the spirit of
connection between us all.
- Yeah.
That's why it's good you're
doing what you're doing.
It brings people together.
- Yeah.
We need more wisdom in the
choosing of our leaders.
- Ah, careful.
That kind of talk could
get you in trouble
with some of your own.
Assuming you're talking
about your leaders.
- Oh, ours today,
perhaps yours tomorrow.
- Hey, if I do get
you the supplies.
- Hm.
- What do you think of
this chiseled profile, huh?
One of the wise men.
- Oh.
Ah, perhaps I make an
ugly camel after you huh?
- Get outta here.
I'll see what I can do.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
- That's amazing.
You're doing so well.
Okay, I'm just gonna
get in a few here.
Oh, ease back.
Lower you back.
You're doing really great.
Oh, very good.
Okay, I'm just gonna take
off your boots now okay?
One moment and I'll
help you lean back.
Okay, here we go. Ready?
(gentle music)
(injured soldier speaking
foreign language)
We're gonna help you.
It's okay.
(gentle music continues)
(crops rustling)
(corn husk cracking)
(light music)
(Rudy groaning)
- You okay?
Dad?
- Pray with me, kid.
In our time of need, give us
answers and give us strength.
(Rudy sighs)
(Rudy groans)
I'm gonna have to find
some help for the harvest.
We're late already.
(Rudy sighs)
This war's left most of
the farms short on hands.
Those Germans we saw today.
- Nazi bastards.
- I don't wanna ever
hear that kind of talk
out of you ever again.
- But, Mr. Barrett and
even Uncle Sam were saying-
- Have you ever
talked to any of them?
- No sir.
- Then don't go making talk
based on what others say.
Look, in a small town like this,
someone's always
gonna have an opinion.
The best opinions
are the ones you make
based on your own experiences.
- Yes, sir.
- I love you, kid.
Let's get on back
up to the house.
Momma's got food fixed.
(soft music)
(soft music continues)
- Welcome, sir.
We do not get American
soldiers here very often.
- Why we allow this
rubbish, beyond me.
- [Clerk] This is just news.
- Well, it looks to me
like Nazi propaganda.
(cigarette pack tapping)
- Do you plan to compensate
for those cigarettes, sir?
We try to keep very exact books.
- I bet you do.
Bet you do.
(Alfons speaking
foreign language)
- How's your day been?
- Long.
Just finally got
Gene down for a nap.
- Crops need to be harvested
and we can't wait much longer.
- Yeah.
Not sure how we're gonna
manage with your back and all.
Can't ask my daddy
for any more handouts.
- I didn't ask for any
handouts the first time.
- We needed it, Rudy.
- I've been thinking
about selling some surplus
at the prison camp.
- Lord knows we
could use the money.
This house is about ready
to fall down around us.
Winter will be here soon.
And the house does
little to keep warmth.
- I'll get the
house more insulated
after we bring in the harvest.
Which reminds me,
I plan on talking with
someone about using them
German soldiers as field hands.
- What?
- Hm?
I heard that the Hormel Cannery
and certain local
companies have used them.
"Hard workers," they say,
and they actually pay
the Germans to work.
- Those prisoners
here on our farm?
- Clara, they send guards.
Look, we need help.
I need help.
The normal hands we hire
are off fighting a war.
- Do you think
that's responsible?
- Responsible is
paying our bills.
Clara.
Clara!
(silverware clanging)
- Are you really thinking
about having the Germans
here on the farm?
- Eat.
(Rudy sighs)
(paint brush tapping)
(ominous music)
(ominous music continues)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(ominous music continues)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(canvas clattering)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(suspenseful music)
(foot thudding)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios coughing)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(light dramatic music)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Alios whimpering)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg chuckling)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(ominous music)
(dramatic music)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(suspenseful music)
(Eduard groans)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Alios speaking
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Alios coughing)
(saw rustling)
(hammer scraping)
(nail clinking)
- [Rudy] All right,
let's move it.
- [Donny] This is heavy.
Why can't you do it on your own?
- Hey, without
discipline, we're nothing.
All right?
- [Donny] Yes, sir.
- One, two, three, go.
(Rudy groaning)
Come on.
- [Donny] Mayor Hewitt's here.
- All right, kid, finish up.
- [Donny] Yes, sir.
- Afternoon, Rudy.
- Frank.
- I got your message.
It seemed important.
- Well, it is.
It is.
I've...
Well, I've been thinking
about the harvest
and the shortage of farm hands.
- Yeah.
- And many of our neighbors
have been facing the same issue.
- Yeah, I'm aware of
the labor shortage.
And you with your bad back,
I'm sure that doesn't
help matters any.
- You know that
Pioneer and Hormel
have been using those Germans.
- What are you getting at?
- Well, I was thinking
maybe them boys would work
all right in the fields.
- We've been having quite a
ruckus just having them in town.
Working on a family farm?
I don't know about that.
- Come on, Frank.
What choice do some of us have?
Huh?
I mean, we're gonna let the
crops spoil in the fields
because we're too
proud to ask for help?
- So, you know this idea is
gonna create some resistance.
- Resistance?
You should have heard me drop
this idea at the supper table
with Clara.
(Frank chuckling)
Resistance.
- I bet.
So you think them German boys
would behaved themselves?
- If it was me cooped
up inside that compound,
I think I might take to working
in the outdoors just fine.
- And you'd be
willing to go first?
- Well, someone has to.
- This could blow up in my face
if something went
wrong, you know?
- Or you could be the
politician who solved
the labor shortage in the area.
- Now, I do like
the sound of that.
I'll tell you what,
let me mull this
over in my mind a bit
and see what we
can come up with.
All right?
- Fair enough.
- Hey, Donny.
- Hi.
- Mind your pop now.
- Dad.
- Hey, I need you to trust me.
Okay?
Now, please finish your chores.
- Yes, sir.
(hay rustling)
(Clara sighs)
(picture frame clinking)
(saw whirring)
(hammer pounding)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
- Welcome, Captain.
- Quite the operation
you have here.
- [Eduard] I, I thank
you for the new space.
- Well, that was not my doing.
So, why, why you building
this project again?
- I, we just want to
bring a touch of joy
and the Christmas
spirit to everyone.
- Right.
I read the article
in the newsletter,
but I wanna know why
you're really making it.
- I, I, I, I don't
understand you, sir.
- No, of course you don't.
- Very surprised to
find you here, Captain.
- Oh, sir, I heard so
much about this project.
I thought I'd take
a look for myself.
- It's gonna be magnificent.
- Yes, sir.
Magnificent.
- Yeah, Colonel,
I want you to meet someone here.
Colonel Lodell,
this is Eduard Kaib.
Eduard's the one responsible
for this project.
- Oh, it is an honor, sir.
I am very thankful for
the extra space here
and grateful that you're
allowing us to do this.
- We thought it'd be a very
unifying endeavor for everyone.
But I didn't mean to interrupt.
I have things to attend to.
Carry on, men.
- [Klein] Hey, sir,
if I could just have
a moment of your time.
- It's looking good, boys.
Who wants a candy cane?
- Oh yes.
- Okay, yeah.
Here you go.
(thunder booming)
(light dramatic music)
(light dramatic music continues)
(Rudy sighing)
(lips smacking)
(Rudy groaning)
(water splashing)
(dramatic music)
(light eerie music)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(Klaus panting)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(light eerie music continues)
(bell clangs)
(car engine rumbling)
- Good morning, Carol.
- Morning, Mr. Tietz.
Hello, Donny.
- Hello, Ms. Valentine.
- Are you gonna hold
your father up all day
or would you like to
come and join the class?
- All right, get going.
- Thanks for taking me, Dad.
- Hey, study hard.
- I will.
- Rudy, this is Colonel Lodell.
- Colonel.
- Mr. Tietz.
- Rudy is fine.
- Rudy, heard a lot about you.
- Well, can't believe
everything you hear.
- Why don't we sit down?
- Yeah, please do.
- [Waitress] Hi, Rudy.
Would you like some coffee?
- Black coffee would be great.
- [Waitress] How about
a danish or roll?
- Oh, no thank you.
- [Waitress] All right.
- Frank here is telling me
that you wanna be the first to
volunteer our camp
labor at your farm.
- Yes, I heard that a
few companies in the area
are using the Germans.
- Yeah, but out on the
farm with your family.
That's a different situation.
- I'm aware there's a risk.
- These could be Nazis,
enemy walking amongst-
- A calculated risk.
My father used to talk about
how the path to success
is not a sure one.
If I don't get those
crops harvested,
I'm not gonna make it.
(somber music)
- Well, I heard you was in here
plotting to put them Germans
on our farms.
We'll just see about that.
(Colonel sighs)
- I like the way
you think, Rudy.
We're gonna help you.
- Thank you, sir.
- No, thank you.
(wind rustling)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(prisoners speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Alios speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Klaus speaking
(Altman speaking
foreign language)
- New York City?
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Altman speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Altman speaking
You see, those mobsters,
with their illegal
businesses all over America,
are patriotic.
(Altman speaking
foreign language)
- Klaus, (speaking
foreign language).
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(prisoners chuckling)
(Altman speaking
foreign language)
(light dramatic music)
- What's wrong?
- We're having the Germans
come here, aren't we?
- It's nothing for
you to worry about.
You have homework to do?
- A little.
- All right.
After supper, you get it done.
- I will.
(light dramatic music)
- Are these the last to go?
- Yes, sir.
- Shackles for him.
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
(Jorg panting)
- Shut up!
- Look, I don't know what
the hell you just said,
but I do know that cutting
trees in the freezing cold
will suit you Nazi
bastards just fine.
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
- The tattoo under their arm
helps in identification, sir.
(Grant speaking
foreign language)
(Jorg chuckling)
Jewish hunter.
- [Klein] Move him out.
(Jorg speaking foreign language)
- Move it!
(thunder booming)
- [Clara] Sounds like
a bad one's brewing.
- It's close.
- Maybe we should all
go down to the cellar.
- I'm going to bed.
Tomorrow morning, we
have workers coming.
- You actually
decided on your own?
- [Rudy] Clara, please.
- To bring the enemy-
- Enough!
- God forbid something
should happen.
- Unless God decides to
send a group of angels
to help by morning, I'm
hiring them German boys
because we need the help!
You know, I'm
really trying here.
And I'm sorry if you
don't agree with me.
This is what needs
to happen, okay?
(thunder booming)
- Bring your stuff.
Donny, now!
(thunder booming)
(thunder rumbling)
(rain pattering)
(Clara sniffling)
(wind whistling)
(thunder booming)
(birds chirping)
- Can I stay here today, please?
- You need to go
get your learning.
Giving prisoners corn knives.
Seems like a good idea.
What? I was joking.
- I, uh, I think they're here.
- Here we go.
(Rudy sighs)
(light patriotic music)
- [President Roosevelt]
But in perhaps every home
in the United States, sad
and anxious thoughts will be
continually with the
millions of our loved ones
who are suffering
hardships and misery,
who are risking their very
lives to preserve for us
and for all mankind the
fruits of his teaching
and the foundations of
civilization itself.
(Seip speaking foreign language)
(light patriotic
music continues)
(barn door rattling)
(light patriotic
music continues)
(corn stalks rustling)
(birds chirping)
(birds cawing)
(dramatic music)
(Donny screaming)
(prisoner speaking
foreign language)
- Dad!
Grandma!
(suspenseful music)
(light dramatic music)
Dad!
Grandma!
(intense dramatic music)
(gunshot banging)
(birds cawing)
- Donny!
(corn stalks rustling)
Donny!
Donny.
(triumphant music)
(Rudy sighs)
Hi, you're all right.
- Hi.
I am.
- You're all right.
It's okay, kid.
You all right?
Come on, kiddo.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
(corn stalks rustling)
(birds cawing)
(soldiers speaking
foreign language)
- The boy's frightened.
- This lad's a marksman.
Lined a feather with an M1.
- Um, it's a turkey.
Good looking bird, though.
- You were supposed
to be off to school.
- I know.
- Get going.
(Rudy sighs)
(hammer tapping)
(saw whirring)
(sandpaper scraping)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
- Eduard.
foreign language)
(Alios speaking
(prisoners laughing)
(wind whistling)
- Well, everything worked
out just fine today
with those Germans.
- You can call them prisoners.
Glad the gamble worked
out in your favor.
You were right, today.
(Rudy sighs)
There, you happy now?
- What'd you learn
today in school?
- Ms. Valentine taught
us about Harriet Quimby.
- Who?
- The first female to
get her pilot's license.
- [Rudy] Really?
- That's right.
How'd you know that?
- You don't only get your love
of flight from your father.
- She was also the
first female pilot
to fly across the
English Channel.
- Never heard that.
- You know why?
Don't tell him, Mama.
- I know the answer.
- Great, just tell me.
- Because the day Harriet Quimby
crossed the English Channel
was the same day
the Titanic sank.
- April 15th, 1912.
No newspaper stories.
It was all about the Titanic.
- Oh, the press.
(wind whistling)
(door thudding)
- What's up, doc?
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
- Bugs Bunny.
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
- Dedrick, (speaking
foreign language).
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(both chuckling)
- Yeah, that's good.
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
- Oh, good.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(dramatic music)
(prisoners laughing)
- [Bugs Bunny] Eh,
what's up, doc?
(prisoners cheering)
(light music)
- You went too far, Frank.
- Don't want to argue
with you today, Tom.
- That's just too
damn bad, Frank.
If you're gonna go off and do
something stupid like this,
you're gonna get a
piece of my mind.
- [Frank] Tom, please.
- These German bastards
killed my grandson.
Now I know we got
some Nazi loving
sons of bitches in this town.
I know it.
But now you're gonna go off
and put the families in danger.
- Morning, Tom.
- Don't you "Morning"
me, Sheriff.
Did you know about this?
- Yeah, Norm and I checked it
out and it looks like it might
just work out fine.
- Might?
Sheriff these ain't
supper guests.
These German bastards
are the enemy.
- I know you're frustrated
and hurting badly,
and I'm sorry about
your grandson, Tom.
- I can see that the law
and the politically inept
are of no help to me.
- Tom!
- But don't you
worry none, Sheriff.
I understand the situation now.
Around here we take
care of our own!
- Oh, Tom sure is mad, isn't he?
- Yeah.
He was born mad.
- He sure did love that
grandson of his though.
Practically raised
him as his own.
- I just hope he don't
go do something stupid.
(wind whistling)
- Man, those German boys
worked really hard this week.
I mean some of the hardest
workers I've ever come across.
- Yeah, farm work allows
these men to spend time
in a meaningful way.
That's a good
situation for us all.
- [Rudy] Mm hm.
- You know Rudy,
you have really done
something special here.
It takes one man to stand up
and have courage and foresight.
- Yeah, it was bound to happen.
- Oh don't sell yourself short.
I mean, it's special.
It takes a special man to
stand up to be the first.
- Talking about being the
first Black man in the area?
- No.
I'm talking about being
the first Negro President
of these entire United States.
Yes, I'm talking about being
the first Negro in the area.
(Rudy chuckling)
- You know, we may just see
a Negro president one day.
- Not in my lifetime.
- [Rudy] Don't sell
yourself short.
(Rudy laughing)
- You got me all right.
- [Ruby] Let's
get this business-
- Let's go young
Mr. Tietz. Let's go.
(car doors slamming)
(soft music)
My daddy used to say,
that when the sun sets
it puts a long day to rest.
- Your daddy was right.
- Indeed he was.
William Hobb, sir.
- Aaron Thompson.
- Ah, Lodell.
Commissioned to the
Corps of Engineers
with the Army Officer
Reserve Corps.
Indeed.
My boy used to work at the
newspaper before he left
for training in Alabama.
I like to know what
goes on in our town.
- Hm, where's he stationed now?
- We got the Western
Union eight months ago.
He died in Italy.
- You drink?
(William chuckling)
- If you mean alcohol, I
do partake on occasion.
- Never been to our club before.
(William chuckling)
- Your club?
Well, I don't believe any
Negroes have been in your club
unless they were
playing music on stage.
- Well, Negroes are
starting to make their mark
in the military, William.
I say that we have
a toast to your son.
- Well, to answer your question,
it'd be a pleasurable first
to have a drink at your club.
- We're doing a lot
of firsts around here.
All right.
- [Waiter] Everything
was acceptable, yeah?
- Oh, very good. Thank you.
- This is, this is classy.
- Not bad.
- Mm hm.
- I think we need a toast
to your son's service.
- Indeed.
(glasses clinking)
Yeah.
- Ah, that's, that's smooth.
- Templeton makes a nice blend.
- [William] Hm.
- So William, how do you
think the town views our camp?
(William sighs)
- Oh, I think most respect
the work you're doing,
but others wish
you'd never showed.
But the merchants in town,
oh, they like your business.
(William chuckling)
- Well, we all probably
wish we were at home,
that's for sure.
- And perhaps one
day you will be.
But for now, welcome
to Algona, Iowa.
The corn capital of the world.
- That it is.
(glasses clinking)
You know, at least these
German and American boys
are not gonna die.
And the parents may
thank us one day.
I just hope our own
boys are getting
the same kind of treatment.
After dinner smoke?
- Oh, no, no, no.
I, I have to limit my vices.
- Oh.
(William chuckling)
I like the way you
limit your vices.
- Ah, indeed.
On the occasion that I do-
- Yeah.
Partake in the smoke,
I'd rather it not be
with those dainty fags.
Try one.
- Don't mind if I do.
- All right.
Let's do it.
- Nice.
- [Waiter] Would
you like another?
- A couple of beer chasers.
- That sounds great.
Two pints, please.
(William chuckling)
- Ah, yes, the A and
Eagle have learned to fly.
- That they have.
(glasses clinking)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Alfons speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Alfons speaking
foreign language)
- Ah, Thanksgiving.
- [Alfons] Yeah.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Alfons speaking
- Yeah, (speaking
foreign language).
(Alfons speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Eduard sighs)
(horn honking)
(drums beating)
(audience cheering)
(audience applauding)
- Hey, hey, Algona.
Happy Thanksgiving.
I'm Smooth Dick and
these are the Dynamos.
Let's get this place going.
Let's get in the mood right now.
One, two, a one, two, three.
(upbeat jazz music)
(upbeat jazz music continues)
- Those German boys
did a fine job.
- Don't get him started
about how right he was.
- Well, everything looks
and smells real nice, Clara.
- Sure does.
Is there anything
that hasn't been done
that you could use help with?
- Um no, I think
we're ready to eat.
(fist knocking)
- I got it.
- You expecting anyone else?
- Wow, little Donny.
- Hello?
- Oh, Happy Thanksgiving.
- Carl.
Why, let Mr. Herman in, Donny.
- Didn't mean to
disturb you all.
Missed you at our
gatherings, Clara.
You know you promised.
- I'm busy.
- Too busy for the Lord.
- You can leave
that Bible outside.
- Well, today is a day
of glorious thanks.
- Would the IOA people agree
with you on that point, Carl?
How about the Dakota Sioux?
- Father.
- So how long have
you been a sheriff?
- I'm, I'm not
actually a sheriff.
I'm a sheriff's deputy.
See, I was one, but-
- Oh.
- Well, they pulled
me outta retirement
because the young guys
were off fighting.
- Okay.
- Carl, I'd like you
to meet Ms. Valentine.
- [Ms. Valentine] Pleasure.
- [Carl] Can't say I've seen
you at a church Sunday service.
- No.
- Um and this is-
- We've met.
- Yes, yes we have.
- Yeah, where would
that be, Norm?
- Well, now Mr. Herman here
decided to set up a holy rolling
fire and brimstone deal
at the courthouse one day
and got him a PA system and
almost got himself three days
in the lockup too, didn't he?
- Well, the freedom
of speech, deputy.
- Yeah, that was
disturbing the peace.
You took freedom of
speech all the way
to freedom of screech.
And that's a civil
infraction in this community.
- Well, we don't have
a microphone, Carl,
but if you'd like to
sit and say grace,
I guess we can feed you.
- I can get you a chair.
- No thank you, Donny.
Well, if we'd all bow our heads.
(Carl clears throat)
Dear heavenly Father,
thank you for bringing
us together today
to celebrate this
joyous occasion.
I pray that you bless the food
and the hands that prepared it.
And Lord, we ask that you
allow us to glorify you
in all that we do for
this festive night.
In the powerful name
of Jesus we pray.
Amen.
(chairs creaking)
(Alan speaking foreign language)
- I'm gonna speak in English.
So most all of you know me.
I've had the pleasure
of meeting many of you
and hearing about your families.
It's funny that we
are all here together
at this place in time.
The war aside for a moment,
we should be grateful.
We all know fellow men,
soldiers, friends, brothers,
sons who have died
in this conflict.
So I would like to take
a moment of silence
and recognize our
fallen comrades.
A moment of silence, please.
(drums beating)
(soft music)
Thank you.
You know, I don't know how the
lines on a map will be drawn
in the future, but I do know,
I pray that one day
soon you will sit across
from a loved one at a
table and share a meal.
Here in the United States, we
call this day Thanksgiving.
And I'm truly thankful to
be here with all of you.
And I hope that you can
remember your days as,
as guests here in Algona.
(prisoners laughing)
With a few smiles.
And with that, I pray for peace.
Please.
- Yeah, surely.
I would like to respond
to our gracious hosts.
Thank you Chaplain Alan for
those kind and true words.
I've met the good
people of Algona,
and I salute all the Americans
who performs their duties
with honor and kindness.
The hearts are
grateful and thankful.
I too see the future
day when we all,
all of us will sit a table and
share the banquet by choice,
and not confinement.
Danke schoen.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
(Seip speaking foreign language)
(prisoners speaking
foreign language)
(Tom belching)
(dog barking)
- [Rudy] You okay, Tom?
- I was a friend of
your father, Rudy Tietz.
Traitor!
- Hey, hey, whoa, whoa, Tom!
All right, I got
no fight with you.
(Tom groaning)
Tom.
- This whole town has
lost its way, you know?
And I tried, I
tried to warn you,
but nobody's gonna listen to me.
- [Rudy] Just tell me what?
- Luke Luginsland, I told you.
- Told me what?
What, what did Luke do?
- Oh, you can't understand.
I don't know how a whole
town could be so blind.
- I'm sorry, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Okay?
What about Luke Luginsland?
- Anyway, don't you
worry about it now.
(Tom chuckling)
You know, I used to come here
and I talked to your father.
Now he was a man.
- Tom.
- [Tom] He was a good man.
He was a man that
would understand.
- You shouldn't be driving.
Hey.
(car engine rumbling)
It's Thanksgiving, Tom.
(dog barking)
(somber music)
Luke Luginsland.
- Missed a good speech earlier.
They're good men.
- Yes, they are.
- Oh, you don't like turkey?
No sauerkraut or schnitzel.
- It's, it's fine.
- You're too noble, my friend.
Can I tell you a story?
- Please spare me the thankful
stories of the Indians
and, and turkey, and,
and how do you call them?
The men with the
boats and the hats.
- Pilgrims.
Yeah, no, no.
You'll like this story
better, especially the ending.
When Mary and Joseph
arrived in Bethlehem,
Mary was in labor.
She was about to give birth.
Joseph, he, he knew
that something amazing
was about to happen,
but he had nothing.
So, with hope and
humbleness in his heart,
he went door to door
asking for help;
for a place to stay, a manger.
You have to ask
for help, Eduard.
- What are you talking about?
- The project.
Your project.
- What about it?
- No matter how many
night shifts you pick up.
(Eduard crying)
- I cannot.
I'm tired and this is so hard.
And I cannot finish
by Christmas.
- Hey, not alone you can't.
You have to ask for help.
Your men, they respect
you too much to offend you
by acting without
your permission.
Do you need help, Eduard?
(gentle music)
(Eduard crying)
- Yes, yes.
(gentle music continues)
(prisoners whistling)
Klaus, Klaus.
(prisoners humming)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(prisoners humming continues)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
Okay.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Alfons speaking
(prisoners singing
in foreign language)
(Chaplain Fluke chuckling)
(prisoners singing
in foreign language)
(Rudy groans)
- How is everything today?
- Good.
- [Helen] No school?
- We go back tomorrow.
- It's slow in here today.
- Yeah, only the two of you.
Well, and that smooth
talking preacher earlier.
Did he come by your place?
- What?
Carl Herman?
- Yeah.
He said he was going out
to meet with you all.
- Donny, let's go.
(coins rattling)
(children giggling)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(Klaus softly panting)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(somber music)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(Klaus whimpering)
(Klaus crying)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(somber music continues)
(Klaus crying)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(somber music continues)
(Klaus crying)
(car engine rumbling)
- Are we meeting
with Carl Herman?
- So I'm told.
- [Donny] He's
here kind of early.
- He shouldn't be here at all!
(car doors slamming)
(Clara giggling)
- Good morning, Rudy.
(Rudy sighs)
- I, I thought you were out
running errands all day.
- Oh yeah, I guess I
forgot we had a meeting.
- A meeting?
- Yeah.
Didn't you tell Helen at the
diner you were coming out here
to meet with us?
- Well, Rudy, what I meant was-
- Carl was just dropping
off some literature.
Donny.
You smell like coffee.
You've been drinking coffee?
- Yes, mama.
(hand slapping)
- Donny, outside.
- But-
- I said go outside now!
- You undermine my
every word and action.
- It's coffee, Clara!
- I think maybe
I should just go.
- Don't you move!
I'll get to you in a moment.
- Maybe if we had a little
more godliness in this house,
we wouldn't have
such disobedience.
- Oh yeah, I think we've
had enough godliness
visiting this household.
- Rudy, what I believe
that Donny needs-
- Don't you ever tell
me what Donny needs.
You understand?
(baby crying)
You may have my
wife's attention,
but you'll never have my son's.
- What, what are
you talking about?
- You and Gene can leave
with the preacher here
if that's what you truly want.
But Donny stays with me.
- Now, Rudy, I believe
we're having a bit of
a misunderstanding here.
Can you let go?
- Are you going, Clara?
(baby crying)
(light dramatic music)
- No.
(somber music)
(baby crying)
(Rudy panting)
- When I come back, you
better be gone for good.
(Carl sighs)
(wind rustling)
Donny!
Hey, Donny!
(wind rustling)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Klaus speaking
(speaking foreign
language continues)
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
(Klaus speaking
- Yeah.
(Alios speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Dedrick speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Altman speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Altman speaking
foreign language)
(Eduard speaking
(Altman speaking
foreign language)
(Dedrick speaking
- Hey, Klaus, (speaking
foreign language).
Come on, let's go.
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
- Okay.
(wind whistling)
(grass rustling)
- I'm running away and
I'm gonna be a pilot.
(wind howling)
(prisoners cheering)
(prisoners laughing)
If I were a police officer,
I would arrest that
creepy Mr. Herman.
Stupid coffee and
calculated risk.
(wind howling)
(prisoners cheering)
(prisoners laughing)
(prisoners gasping)
(prisoners cheering)
(leaves crunching)
- [Prisoner] There it is.
(prisoners cheering)
(leaves crunching)
- Mister, please, no.
- You German bastards
killed my grandson.
See, I knew you were
working with the enemy.
I just couldn't prove it
until I got my hands on these.
Huh?
What is this?
Trying to smuggle
letters on the inside.
What is that about?
- My younger brother.
He was left in Germany.
- [Townie] You are a traitor!
(fist thudding)
(Luke groaning)
- Tom, no.
(wind howling)
(grass rustling)
(light dramatic music)
My brother, he
raised by our uncle,
forced into the Wehrmacht.
I just want to know if
Martin is dead or alive.
I'm not a traitor.
I'm an American.
Still, I love my brother.
(dramatic music)
- And I love my grandson.
(suspenseful music)
(prisoners cheering)
- [Wade] Shoot him, Pa!
- [Donny] What are you
doing, Mr. Barrett?
(dramatic music continues)
- [Wade] Pa, please
don't shoot the boy.
- Donny!
- Please don't hurt him.
(dramatic music)
(prisoners cheering)
(suspenseful music)
(Tom panting)
- I'm sorry.
Wade, I wronged you,
and I'm so really sorry, son.
Do you forgive me?
- What are we gonna do?
(dramatic music)
(prisoners cheering)
(gunshot banging)
- Donny!
Donny!
(Donny panting)
- They shot him!
(soft music)
(soft music continues)
(car engine rumbling)
- Hey, have you seen Donny?
- Yeah, yeah, I've seen him.
- Where?
- Well, we, um, I saw
him out on Orton Road.
(car engine rumbling)
(soft music continues)
- Yes (speaking
foreign language).
- Hey.
(prisoners speaking
foreign language)
(gunshot banging)
All this good will to men,
peace and art talk.
You're up to something
and I know it.
- I, I don't understand, just...
(body thumping)
- Leave him alone, asshole.
We are like you.
We are all like you!
(Eduard speaking
foreign language)
- What did you just say?
I know you're spitting
your Nazi poison.
- I, I'm just a
German, not a Nazi.
I only wish to see
my family again.
Please, don't become
what you wish to destroy.
(light dramatic music)
(light dramatic music continues)
(prisoners chuckling)
(prisoners speaking
foreign language)
(light dramatic music continues)
- Sergeant.
Gather the troops.
- Yes, sir.
(door slamming)
(Lodell sighs)
(wind whistling)
- Hey, where's home boy?
Where's home? Home.
No, no, not play.
Home.
(leaves crunching)
- [Lodell] Your name, soldier,
for those who don't know you.
- Sergeant Conrad Lewis of
Brooklyn, New York, sir!
- Are we not the one and only
United States of America?
- [Soldiers] Yes, sir.
- Those uniforms
that you all wear,
they're a symbol of duty,
honor, and sacrifice.
But they're just a reflection
of the soldier within.
From now on, I expect
your behavior to reflect
the fine reputation
that has become known
for the United States military.
Is that understood?
- [Soldiers] Yes sir.
- We are common men.
But together we are capable
of uncommon acts of courage,
bravery and compassion.
History will remember our
actions for generations.
We will determine how the
world sees and remembers us.
Dismissed.
Find me Provost Marshal Klein,
have him report to my
office immediately.
(light dramatic music)
- Hey, hey.
- I did this.
- No, don't, don't
do that to yourself.
(Clara sniffling)
Don't do that.
- We can't lose him.
- Hey, hey.
We're gonna find him.
Okay?
Okay, we're gonna find him.
(Clara crying)
(somber music)
(somber music continues)
- Now, Donny has good common
sense and I need to think
that Buster's with him.
- Yeah, he may have
good common sense,
but he doesn't
have a coat on him.
Okay, Buster can
only help so much.
(Clara crying)
- Listen, listen to me.
I know you're scared.
But we're gonna find him.
Okay, you have to believe me.
I know we are, we're
gonna find him.
- [Clara] Okay.
- Okay, come on boys.
We are.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Come on.
Okay, okay, listen up everyone.
We need to start
west of the woods
and work our way
back to the river.
We should be able to cover
a lot of ground that way.
What?
Did you think I was
just gonna sit back,
serve coffee and fret?
Absolutely not!
Now, let's go!
Let's find him!
We have to find him!
- All right, let's go.
It's only gonna get
colder out here.
- God bless you all.
- We're start on this road
and work our way back.
(wind whistling)
- It's getting cold
out there, sir.
- I'm gonna get right
to the point, Captain.
Who organizes the tower
shifts and the escort duties
for this camp?
- I do, sir.
- Who do the men
look to for guidance
on their day-to-day
duties and actions?
- Sir, I'm not getting your
line of questioning here.
- I did not ask if you got
my line of questioning.
I asked, who do the men
look to for guidance?
Who sets the example of
what kind of behavior
is acceptable or tolerated?
- Okay.
Is this about the incident in
the yard with a soccer ball?
'Cause I can explain that-
- Enough, Captain.
I swear if you dodge one
more direct question,
you're gonna be court-martialed:
Insubordination.
Do you understand me?
- Me, sir.
Yes, they look to me.
It was a soccer ball, sir.
Those men were
being disrespectful.
Herman Seip reported
this, didn't he?
You can't trust
their reports, sir.
These men are criminals.
- No, I saw what happened.
All of it.
These men are prisoners of war.
Many of 'em forced to
fight in a conflict
they wanted no part of.
Do you know what the main
requirement of leadership is?
- No, sir.
- The main requirement
of leadership
is that you must
be a human being.
The eyes of the
world are upon us
and how we perform our duty.
Our own boys, our
prisoners in German camps,
and how we perform
our duty may affect
the way they're treated.
Did that ever occur to you?
- No, sir.
- You have a brother
that serves, yes?
- Yes, sir, a B-17
pilot based in England.
- And if he was shot
down and taken captive,
how would you want
him to be treated?
The golden rule, Captain,
respect has to be earned.
It cannot be demanded.
You don't respect these men
and therefore they
don't respect you.
You crossed a line
and broke their trust.
- [Linda] Sir.
- Poor leadership.
Poor leadership.
You're no good to me anymore
except to make an
example out of you.
You're hereby being
transferred to another site.
And Captain, I sincerely hope
that you make better choices
in the future.
The train leaves 0700.
Dismissed.
- Yes, sir.
- Yes, Linda?
- Sir, Mayor Frank
Hewitt called and said
there's a local boy missing
in the surrounded woods.
- Tonight? In this?
Who is it?
- It's the young
son of a Rudy Tietz.
- Sergeant, step aside.
(ominous music)
- Yes, sir.
(ominous music continues)
(prisoners speaking
foreign language)
(suspenseful music continues)
- Hold on here.
- Whatever I've
done to you, sir.
I'm deeply sorry.
- No, Eduard, I'm sorry.
My actions were inexcusable.
(light music)
I sincerely hope that soon
we can get back to our lives
and our families.
Accept my apology, please.
(light dramatic music)
(light dramatic music continues)
(Eduard exhales)
(Seip speaking foreign language)
- Men, we need your help.
(soft music)
- [Donny] Please.
(search crew
indistinctly talking)
- We should be able to cover
a lot of ground that way.
(soft music)
(light dramatic music)
(light dramatic music continues)
(Seip speaking foreign language)
- How can we help?
(light dramatic music continues)
- [Harriet] Donny!
(indistinct yelling)
- [Rudy] Come on, Donny!
- Donny!
Donny!
- [Tom] Donny!
- Donny!
(muffled yelling)
- [Harriet] Donny!
(leaves crunching)
Donny!
(light eerie music)
(Klaus speaking
foreign language)
(light music)
Here, he's here!
- We surrender, we surrender.
- [Klaus] You okay?
(light music continues)
You're safe now.
- [Alan] Let's get you home.
- Thank you.
(gentle music)
(gentle music continues)
- Is it Donny?
Donny!
(triumphant music)
Oh, you scared me good.
- [Donny] I'm sorry I ran away.
- You're safe now.
- I knew I should
have taken my coat.
- Yeah.
- You always tell
me to get my coat.
- Yes, sir, you should have.
Thank you.
- Hey, I once knew a
boy as brave as you.
And he gave me this.
Helped me through very hard
times and I want you to have it.
(gentle music)
- Thank you.
- [Rudy] Thank you.
(gentle music continues)
(leaves crunching)
(light music)
(Clara crying)
- Donny!
I'm sorry.
We found you.
(light music continues)
(baby crying)
(Clara hushes)
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Come here, come here.
Hero or no hero, kid,
he needs his feet wiped.
Hand me that rag.
Yeah, yeah, I know, I know.
Thank you.
I know.
Yeah.
It's okay boy.
- Just gonna leave all that
mess at the door, Donny?
- I was gonna go
back out with Buster
after I got some hot chocolate.
- Oh, we're out
of hot chocolate.
But we do have some coffee.
If you'd like some.
- Really?
- We've been invited to
go down to the PW camp
for some Christmas presentation.
- That sounds fun.
- That sounds really nice.
- Well then, looks
like the Tietz family
will be in attendance.
(glasses clinking)
My little man.
(Clara giggling)
("O Holy Night")
- [President Roosevelt]
Here at home,
we will celebrate in our
traditional American way
because of its deep
spiritual meaning to us.
Because the teachings of Christ
are fundamental in our lives
and because we want our
youngest generation to grow up
knowing the significance
of this tradition,
and the story of the coming of
the immortal prince
of peace and goodwill.
But in perhaps every home
in the United States,
sad and anxious thoughts
will be continually
with the millions
of our loved ones
who are suffering
hardships and misery,
who are risking their very
lives to preserve for us
and for all mankind the
fruits of his teachings
and the foundations of
civilization itself.
The Christmas spirit lives
tonight in the bitter cold
of the front lines in Europe,
and in the heat of the
jungles and swamps of Burma
and the Pacific Islands.
(Sally sighs)
Even the roar of our-
- Well, you better
go get cleaned up.
- [President Roosevelt] The
guns of our ships at sea.
- I mean, if you wanted to
go to the Christmas gala.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Oh!
Thank you.
- All right, hurry up.
- [President Roosevelt]
Around our Christmas tree.
("O Holy Night" continues)
(prisoner speaking
foreign language)
(townspeople talking
over each other)
- It's a beautiful
night for a surprise.
- Yeah, this is the most fun I
have had in a very long time.
- You good?
- I'm good.
- Are you warm?
- Yeah, I'm warm.
- All right, we
gotta keep you warm.
- I'll keep warm.
- They should be
out in a minute.
- Oh, Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas.
(indistinct whispering)
- It truly did.
I can't thank you for
everything that you did for me
and for my family.
(indistinct talking)
Is he warm enough?
(lips smacking)
- Merry Christmas.
I love you.
- I love you too.
(prisoners singing
in foreign language)
(prisoners singing in
foreign language continues)
(singing in foreign
language continues)
- Welcome, everyone.
Thank you for coming out tonight
on this Christmas Eve of 1944.
We're here to celebrate
an opportunity for peace
in this world.
These men, who are so
far from their home,
have created something
for our home,
and hopefully it'll be with
us for many years to come.
So with the Christmas spirit,
I pray for peace on earth.
Silent night
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
Round yon virgin
mother and child
Holy infant so
tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly peace
- Please come and see
this symbol of peace.
("Silent Night")
("Silent Night" continues)
(gentle music)
(gentle music continues)
- [President Roosevelt] We
all know how anxious they are
to be home with us,
and they know how anxious
we are to have them.
And how determined every one
of us is to make their day
of homecoming as
early as possible.
And above all, they know
the determination of
all right thinking
people and nations,
that Christmases such as those
that we have known in these
years of world tragedy
shall not come back again
to beset the souls of
the children of God.
(gentle music)
("America the Beautiful")
("America the
Beautiful" continues)
- Mr. And Mrs. Kaib.
Good morning.
I'd like to introduce
you to Mr. Don Tietz.
And Kim, our local
news reporter.
- [Kim] Nice to meet you.
- Yes, when I was a young boy,
I remember your men
working on my dad's farm.
I recall them being so
nice to us, so thank you.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Kaib, how does it feel
to return to the very spot
where you were once imprisoned?
- I find this second
visit to Algona to be
much more pleasurable
than the first.
I've seen more of
the town this time.
Would you care to walk with
me to where the camp was?
- [Don] Yeah.
- Yes.
(drums beating)
(light music)
- Mr. Kaib, what was
behind such a huge endeavor
as the nativity scene?
(light music continues)
- [Eduard] I never intended
to create a piece of art.
The only intention when
making the nativity scene
was to help to bring the joy
of Christmas to our camp.
And you can imagine
that I was very glad
that the nativity scene,
still after 40 years,
help to heal the wounds of war.
(light music)
(light music continues)
(light dramatic music)
(light dramatic music continues)
(soft music)
(soft music continues)
("Silent Night")
("Silent Night" continues)
(light music)
(light music continues)