"This film is based on true accounts..."
"...that took place at a school
for the deaf in 2005"
It will either rain or snow
at some cities.
It will also be foggy in the morning.
There will also be some cities in the
east and west region which will be foggy.
Temperature will be similar to yesterday.
Negative two degrees Celsius in Seoul.
Negative one degrees Celsius in Daejeon.
Negative one degrees Celsius in Gwangju.
Negative one degrees Celsius in Mujin.
You're still not there?
I can't tell where
I am because of the fog.
That means you're almost there.
Mujin is a foggy town.
What's Sol doing?
She's sleeping.
She cried all night saying she misses
her dad and just fell asleep.
She cried a lot?
Kids cry when
they're away from their parents.
Don't worry, son.
Just do your job well there.
You went through a lot to get that job,
so stick to it like glue.
Got it?
Mom, I'll call when I get...
"Welcome to Mujin"
"Silenced"
How much longer do I need to wait?
It's a busy day from the fog.
You'll have to wait for quite a bit.
Is there a bus to Ja Ae Academy from here?
Ja Ae Academy?
The school for the deaf?
There's no direct bus
to such a secluded place.
Cab fare's is about 50,000 won.
Wait.
You're going to leave just like that?
I'm in a rush, so I'll come back tomorrow.
You should just leave the car here!
Damn it...
Hey, Mister.
Why did you suddenly back out
without even looking!
Check your rear when backing up.
-What? I didn't even move.
-Mister!
Think you can talk your way out
just because I'm a girl?
But you got the wrong girl.
Mr Lee! Spray, please!
She's the one who hit me.
Smile.
"Mujin Human Rights Center"
Look, Miss.
I haven't even started my engine.
Hey! Are you out of your mind?
Mr Lee! Come look.
This man is reeking of soju!
What?
I don't believe this.
Ms. Seo, I guess you drank
all night long again.
I'm sorry.
My insurance will cover the cost.
I guess you can't stand the cold.
I came out after drinking with co-workers.
And my glass was broken.
The fool ran away after messing my car but
he chose the wrong person to mess with.
Excuse me. Are we almost there?
In my line of work,
people can hold grudges.
It's similar to police inspectors.
I deal with pimps and bastards
who hit their wives.
I asked you how much further
do we need to go!
A grown man whining...
Why are you going to Ja Ae Academy?
I'm going there to teach kids.
Really?
You're a teacher?
Do you know sigh language?
What does that mean?
I can tell why people
have grudges against you.
"Mujin Human Rights Center, Seo Yujin"
Call me with the estimated cost.
Don't try to pull a broken neck on me
or anything like that.
I'm really tight with
the cops in this town.
"Congratulations for being nominated as
the best academy in Mujin"
Hello.
Tell the Chief of Administration
to come to the principal's office.
You were Professor Kim's student?
Yes. He was my college professor.
He drew that himself for me.
I see...
If you're his student...
I can trust you 100 percent.
He and I were in the same class throughout
the whole three years of high school.
If he didn't suddenly switch to arts...
...we would've gone to college together.
You can just speak casually, sir.
No, I can't do that.
You're our teacher now.
I shouldn't talk down to you.
Chief Lee?
Meet our new art teacher from Seoul
who was recommended by Professor Kim.
I'm Kang Inho. Nice to meet you, sir.
You've never seen twins before?
Sorry, sir.
It's okay.
That's how everybody react to us
the first time they saw us.
You must be tired from the trip.
Rest up and see you on Monday.
Chief Lee will direct
you with the details.
But what about the problem we have,
Brother?
Chief Lee.
We're in school right now.
Principal Lee?
How do we solve the problem?
I todl you that he came
on Professor Kim's recommendation.
Are you kidding right now?
Why's a man from Seoul so senseless?
It's usually one big one.
But since Professor Kim recommended you,
I'll take just five small ones.
You mean money?
Thought you could get
a teaching job for free?
My goodness.
I want it in cash.
School development fund?
Yes. Everyone has to pay.
How much do they want?
5,000,000 won.
What? They ask for that much?
They said it's a discount rate for me
since Professor Kim recommended me here.
Dang! How are we going to come up
with that much money?
You're doing a really good job.
You have a talent in art.
Why are you so late for class?
Hey!
Minsu?
His younger brother died
in a train accident a few days ago.
He's not himself these days.
His one and only brother just died.
How could he not feel sad?
It's not just Minsu who's a bit strange.
There's something strange about the kids.
What's strange about them?
I can't really explain it one word.
It's your first time
at a school like this, right?
Don't think of the kids here as normal.
A disability in body leads
to an impairment in mentality.
I've been with them
for over 10 years here.
But they have yet
to open their hearts to me.
Jeon Minsu?
"His father is bedridden
and his mother ran away."
My gosh.
Jin Yuri.
"Mentally disabled.
Mental age is 8-years-old."
"Has voracious appetite.
Needs special care."
Kim Yeondu.
"Father: Dead. Mother: Dead"
She's an orphan?
I'm about to leave.
Have you had dinner?
I had something simple.
How's Sol? Did she eat?
I fed her a few spoonfuls earlier.
Why do you feed her so little?
She had a fit because
she wanted pizza instead.
Why didn't you buy it for her then?
It doesn't cost much.
I won't starve her.
Don't worry about her.
Check your account on the way home.
You got the money?
Ask for new bills when you withdraw.
Is someone in there?
Did something happen?
What are you doing?
I heard strange noises from inside.
Still, you can't go
into the girls' bathroom.
What if a student sees you?
You must not know since you're new.
Kids here make strange noises for fun.
Since they can't hear,
they make those sounds on purpose.
I'm locking the front doors.
Go home, sir.
The audit is enough of a headache.
And the kids act up, too.
Sorry for all the trouble, Inspector Jang.
It's okay, sir.
Guiding kids to the right path
is a cop's job anyway.
But the kids never listen.
I told them over and over
not to go out at night.
What's the use of telling them
when they can't hear?
Oh, that makes sense.
Come on in.
School development fund is not illegal.
Right, Inspector Jang?
If my salary was bigger,
I'd donate to this school, too.
So, I heard you're from Seoul.
Are you settling in?
There's nothing much
to Mujin but the fog.
-It's fine.
-Excuse me.
Let's have drinks sometime.
This town is pretty good
for guys to have fun.
The girls are nice too.
Minsu.
It's not polite to stare
at your teacher like that.
-Hello.
-Stand straight.
Mr. Park?
What did he do
that you're treating him like that?
This kid sneaked out
of the residence last night.
With two girls at that.
I was so worried.
I didn't sleep a wink last night.
His brother sneaked out and died.
Mr. Park? The principal wants to see you.
Minsu.
Don't you know how I feel?
Let's open up to each other more, okay?
What are you doing there?
Go back in!
Go back in, now!
Hey!
Come down from there!
What are you doing?
You could fall down!
What's wrong?
I'm sorry if I scared you.
I was worried about you.
What are you doing?
I'm giving her a lesson.
Who are you to give
her a lesson like that?
I'm Yoon Ja Ae, the residence counselor.
I'm in charge of after school education.
This doesn't concern you.
You put a child in the laundry machine
and I'm supposed to let that happen?
Are you insane?
The new teacher from Seoul...
...is a fool who doesn't know
to mind his own crap.
You think I can't do anything?
All my friends in Seoul
are prosecutors and lawyers!
Try that again and I'll make
sure you end up behind bars!
Yeondu!
Hello?
Who?
Oh, right.
What is it?
I paid for your repairs.
There's beatings?
The disabled children?
This isn't discrimination. It's assault.
What were you doing
while she ended up like this?
Let's call her parents, first.
She's an orphan.
I heard from the Chief of Administatrion.
There was a problem with the way
Ms. Yoon disciplines a child?
Since she was a student from your class...
...I understand why you're upset.
I gave Ms. Yoon a firm warning.
I hope you'd understand.
Ms. Yoon deeply regrets what happened.
She wants to apologize to Yeondu.
But Yeondu didn't come back
to the residence last night.
We're very worried about her because
she might get involved in an accident.
She wasn't well, so
I took her to a hospital.
Really? Is it really bad?
No, they said she can leave tomorrow.
No need to worry, sir.
We'll bring her back then.
-So, which hospital is she at?
Yeondu couldn't come because she's sick.
Let's try this.
You draw me and I'll draw you.
Why? You don't want to?
It's because of my bruises and scars...
Don't worry. I'll make sure
to draw you prettily.
"Emegency Medical Treatment Centre"
Where are you?
We have to meet.
I'm just getting off work.
I'll meet you at the hospital.
Not the hospital.
Let's meet outside.
Okay, then.
Bye.
Is something wrong?
Yeondu was...
...sexually molested.
By the principal.
By force...
He tried to but in the end, he failed.
It's because she's too young.
That's nonsense.
Who said that?
You must've drunk again.
How many bottles this time?
Yeondu wrote this last night.
-"Who forced you to do the act?"
-"It's the principal."
-"He forced you?"
-"I got beaten when I said no."
-"Who else were forced to do it?"
-"Minsu, Yeongsu, Yuri."
There are other kids
who are going through the same thing, too.
And there are other assailants too.
There's a teacher called
Park Bohyun.
He even molested boys.
Don't you know how I feel?
-"Who else molests the children?"
-"The Principal, Chief Lee, Mr. Park."
Then...
You should report it to teh police.
The cops sent the kids
who went to report this back to school.
That's why they were beaten.
The teacher, Yoon Ja Ae,
who beat Yeondu...
...is actually
the school founder's adopted daughter.
So, she's the principal's younger sister.
Kim Yeondu is admitted here, right?
Do you know what's even crazier?
Yoon Ja Ae and the principal...
...are lovers.
She warned Yeondu while cutting her hair.
If she flirts with the principal...
...she's dead.
Mister!
Wait!
"Mujin Human Rights Center"
Last Thursday,
you were sexually molested...
...by the principal of Ja Ae Academy.
Can you tell us what happened?
After school that day...
...I changed clothes at the residence.
And then I went out to play in the yard.
I was playing with Yuri.
She went to the bathroom...
...but didn't come back.
So, I went into the school
to look for Yuri.
The principal...
...called me over to his office.
He took me...
...to the Principal's office.
The TV was turned on.
A man and a girl...
...were naked on the screen.
The principal came in...
...and he...
...took off my pants.
Hey!
It's raining cats and dogs outside.
The sound of rain falling
on budding trees...
...seems to whisper that
the long, cold winter is finally over.
Open your windows and
listen to the falling rain.
It's okay.
Yeondu says she saw what happened.
If you tell anyone else about this...
..."I'll kill you".
You don't know because you're new.
Kids here make strange noises for fun.
-Dad!
-Yes. Mom!
What took you so long to get the door?
Does teaching the deaf made you deaf too?
Why didn't you call?
What? A call? Do I need to make
a reservation to come to my son's place?
What? Is this a hotel or something?
Still, why bring a sick child out here?
What? Did you forget?
Today is your late wife's
first year death anniversary.
So, how's school?
It's all right.
Why? They don't welcome newcomers?
Bear with them.
Country folks can be like that. My gosh.
What's that?
I heard the principal loves orchids.
Professor Kim says your principal
has a lot of connections.
Some teachers got
recommendations from your principal.
And landed good jobs up in Seoul.
Mom!
Do you know what kind of people they are?
-Those people are...
-Yes, I know.
He demands cash for giving you a job!
Do you think a good guy would do that?
Do you know how I got that money?
It was my rental deposit.
You moved out?
That's your house deposit?
Yes.
Think I stole that money or something?
You never once brought money home.
How else would I get it?
Still, that was your house!
Come on.
Suddenly acting like
the head of this family?
When you went
around the country to draw...
...have you forgotten how your wife
and I raised Sol and supported you?
Your wife worried about Sol and
you till the day she died.
Dad, are you fighting with grandmother?
I don't want to hear
one more word out of you!
Just like the kids you teach,
close your ears and mouth...
...and just do your job.
Sol! Are you okay?
Mom! Hurry!
Oh my goodness.
My gosh. Here you go. My gosh.
-Oh, Sol.
-Sol. Breathe in.
One more time. That's good.
-Good. My gosh.
-That's right. My gosh.
I got a room in our old town.
It's tiny, but good enough...
...for just Sol and me.
Inho.
Don't think of anything else but Sol.
Okay?
We request the principal
of Ja Ae Academy be discharged...
...and the sexual offenders be punished.
Sorry to interrupt.
Did the sexual...
...molestation...
...occur during class hours
or school period?
If you watch the recorded testimonies...
...after school, the kids...
After school?
That's not our jurisdiction.
What?
Mr. Kim?
Is it within our jurisdiction
if something occurs after schooling hours?
That's under the City Hall's jurisdiction.
But the Principal,
Chief of Administration...
...and a teacher sexually
assaulted students at school!
The things is...
...Ja Ae Academy is in our jurisdiction.
But the residence...
...is under social welfare's
jurisdiction at City Hall.
Please go to City Hall
and talk to them about it.
I've already been there.
They said it happened
at school and to come here.
What happens after school
is not our jurisdiction.
Look lady!
Children were abused at school!
But everybody says
it's not their jurisidction!
Who could actually do something
about this then?
The Blue House? The White House?
City Hall.
Why aren't you investigating?
Children were molested
by the principal of the school!
Shouldn't you investigate?
Of course we should.
Then, why aren't you?
Ms. Seo.
The principal
is the elder of Mujin Church.
He's a devout Christian and is
well-known as a respectable man.
Here.
I have the children's
recorded testimonies.
This is the evidence!
But why can't you bring him in?
Look.
How can we handcuff him based
on what some deaf kids say?
He received the governor's award
a few days ago.
Even with human rights and such
I can't just bring people like him in.
You know that very well.
What rights are you talking about
when he molested kids?!
Then, I'll go straight to
the district prosecutor's office.
By all means.
I'd be grateful if you do so.
Don't think it's because
we don't want to investigate.
It's because the prosecutors
haven't given us the okay.
Bring us the order
from court or something...
My goodness.
I hope my son becomes
a prosecutor not a cop.
Hello?
It's me Younghoon.
A TV station from Seoul
called to cover our case.
Really?
Yes. Hurry back.
They're on their way right now.
Okay. I'll be right there.
Minsu?
Get up. Don't lie down there. Come here.
Get up. Hurry.
Where are Yeondu and Yuri?
You're close friends. Right?
Stop grumbling and speak!
I can't understand your grumbling!
Looks like you're getting old, Mr. Park.
Kids aren't scared of you anymore.
Mr. Park?
This is the principal's office.
Go some place quiet.
"Mujin Human Rights Center"
If I open up...
...can you make them get punished?
Yes, I promise.
Why did your brother go
to the railroad at dawn?
Can you tell us what happened
to him before he died?
As Mr. Park Bohyun was getting off work...
...he told us to go to his house.
We didn't want to go.
But if we said no...
...he will hit us.
Minsu?
He took off...
...my pants.
Then...
...in my butt...
Couldn't you resist or run away?
If I tried...
...he'd beat me all night.
Did it happen before, too?
At his house...
...and the showers at the residence.
My brother was so weak.
...that after that happened...
...he couldn't walk from the pain.
Inspector Jang?
What are you doing?
You have the right to an attorney
and the right to remain silent.
-Let's go.
-Hey.
You must've seen the TV show
but it's not true!
Think I could do such a thing?
I'm the elder of Mujin Church.
I'm a servant of Christ!
-You know that very well.
-Let me go, fools!
I'm friends with the police chief!
What's your name?
-I'll have you all fired!
-Don't worry! It'll be okay!
Those who framed you
will definitely pay for this!
-What misfortune!
-Inspector Jang!
You! Who do you think you are?
Just get int!
Inspector Jang!
Don't you believe me?
How can you do this to us?
After everything we gave you!
Mujin Police Headquarters
flipped upside down.
Even prosecutors are
about to lose their jobs.
I won't say this twice.
Stop whining and listen up.
Use all your connections and get
a lawyer who used to be a judge.
A chief prosecuting attorney at least.
Someonf from Mujin would be better.
Say crap like you didn't do it
and this accusation is upsetting.
Before you find a lawyer...
...I suggest you close your ears
and mouths like the kids.
You understand me?
Beloved citizens of Mujin.
Elders, Lee Kangbok, and Kangsuk...
...have worked hard for years....
...for the development of
our church and Mujin.
He served the God above...
...and the poor disabled children below,
he devotes himself to voluntararily jobs.
Do not forgive those evil
forces who frame our elders!
-It's a good thing.
-Everybody.
I repeat!
That the kids can't hear this.
They've worked hard for years for...
...for the development
of our church and Mujin.
He serves the God above...
Younghoon?
Did you find out anything
about their lawyer?
Hwang Woosik is a very
famous attorney from Mujin.
He graduated magna cum laude
from Seoul Law School.
He used to be a judge and recently
opened private practice.
This is his first case.
Privileges of former post.
What's that?
Retired judges are given a favorable
ruling at their first trial in practice.
How can they be so alike?
Their looks and their acts.
For the last few days...
...I trembled in shame.
I thought about why God
gave me this adversity.
Our father and teacher, Lee Junbum...
...had pity on the deaf.
He used his entire fortune
to establish Ja Ae Academy...
...for the past 50 years ago.
Since we were young...
...our father taught us to care
for such young sheep.
We have never once forgot his teaching.
Interpretation, please!
Order!
Your Honor.
Deaf people here cannot hear you.
If you speak without permission,
I'll order you to leave the court.
I'm Seo Yujin from
Mujin Human Rights Center.
This trial has to do with deaf people.
Please bring in a
sign language interpreter for them.
Ms. Seo is ordered to leave the court.
-Objection!
-What are you doing, guards?
Escort her out of here!
I object! Your Honor!
Your Honor!
I object, sir!
It's only fair that a sign language
interpreter be here for this trial!
Let go!
From now on...
...anyone who disturbs this court will
be dealt with strictly by law.
Defendant, please continue.
We pray in Jesus' name.
-Amen.
What? Sexual molestation?
You filthy fools can
only see dirty things!
What are you doing?
How dare you little bitch!
Who are you?
I'm Principal Lee's wife! So?
You devilish bitch.
What are you doing?
You wheedled kids to scam money
off my husband, didn't you?
Madam!
-You got the wrong man, bitch!
-Why are you doing this?
Stop it! Let go!
You devilish bitch!
Be gone Satan! Be gone!
She should be begging day and night
for God to forgive her husband.
You're such a kind person.
She spits on you and all you
say is, "What are you doing?"?
Can I stay at your office for a while?
Why? Did you run away from home
or something?
You got fired?
They can't fire you like that!
Don't worry.
I'll throw them in prison
and get you reinstated.
You must be happy.
Life's easy to you.
You got me all wrong.
My life's no peaches and cream.
I have no time to date anyone
because of all the work I have to do.
My grades are really bad
that I can't get another job.
With the tiny money I make...
Inho.
Do you regret it?
Jumping into this case?
How dd you know it's my pay day?
I wired some money.
Go check the bank.
Yeah, everything's fine.
No, don't come over. I'm busy.
I got a lot of school work to do.
I'll visit some time soon.
Bye.
I swear...
...to tell the truth
and nothing but the truth.
I will be persecuted if I were
to provide false testimony.
Witness, Oh Jungsik.
Counsel? Your witness.
Mr Oh Jungsik?
What is your job title at Ja Ae Academy?
I'm the night guard at the school.
How long have you worked there?
It's been five years.
For the last five years...
...you've worked under the defendants.
What is your impression of them?
They're both great men.
-They're always so thoughtful to me.
-Your Honor.
Question is irrelevant to the trial.
Sustained.
Ask questions pertaining to the trial.
You patrol the school every night?
I'll patrol the school
once in three hours.
I see...
Then, for the last five years...
...have you ever seen the principal
or his brother call in children...
...to their offices or drag them there?
No, I haven't.
Interpreter, please convey clearly.
Commotion is not tolerated.
On the night in question when
Yeongdu was sexually molested.
You saw Kang Inho
outside the girl's bathroom?
Yes.
What did he say?
He said he heard screams
from inside the bathroom.
So, what did you do?
He asked me to check.
So, I went in and looked.
Was someone in there?
No, no one.
I see. No further questions.
Please cross-examine prosecution.
What did you do before working
at Ja Ae Academy?
I was a janitor
at Mujin Elementary School.
Then why'd you move to a special school?
The salary is much lower
than at a public school.
Well...
While working at Mujin Elementary...
...you were indicted for stealing....
...and selling school supplies.
Is that right?
You were jobless for three years
because of that, weren't you?
Your Honor, Prosecution's questioning
is irrelevant to this case.
Objection!
The staff and teachers at the school
all have weak points.
That's why the unfortunate events
were kept silent and hidden.
This could be the main issue
pertaining this case.
Sustained. Continue.
How did you come to work
at Ja Ae Academy?
With your background, it
wouldn't have been easy.
Someone introduced me ther.
Exactly. Someone introduced you.
You even paid them.
If the school should
close due to this case...
...you have nowhere else to go, correct?
No further questions.
You examined Jin Yuri when a human
rights center employee brought her?
Yes.
What was your diagnosis?
Her vulva was inflamed
and her hymen was damaged.
Can a girl's hymen only be damaged...
...by sexual relations?
No. It can be damaged by riding a bike...
As a gynaecologist, I'm sure that
you've seen...
-...many sexually abused patients.
-Yes.
What kind of state are they in?
Usually, there are
severe lacerations to the vulva.
And they are about to lose
their minds from humiliation.
How was Jin Yuri, when you first saw her?
She was calmly eating cookies.
Too calm for a girl who supposedly
got sexually molested.
There were no other
bruises or wounds either.
So, she didn't seem like a child
who was sexually abused?
Yes...
No further questions.
That doctor is the head council
of Mujin High School alumnus.
And she's the president.
Your Honor.
What is this?
This is the witness'
first diagnosis of Jin Yuri.
This is your first diagnosis, correct?
Did you write your diagnosis twice?
But...
Answer yes or no.
Yes...
The first diagnosis says the lacerations
to the vulva and damaged hymen...
...are not suspected to be
from recent sexual relations.
The later diagnosis says it's not from
sexual relations but other causes.
In your second diagnosis...
...you ruled out sexual relations.
-Why did you rewrite your diagnosis?
-I...
I didn't know this case was so serious.
Does a doctor's diagnosis
change depending on the case?
The first diagnosis said "not from
recent sexual relations," correct?
Yes...
Then you saw signs of
sexual relations from before, correct?
Witness.
Why did you change your statement?
Is it really because the case
got too serious?
No. It's just that...
...her hymen wasn't damaged recently.
It seemed to be about five years ago...
That makes her only 9 years old.
-It's too young to have sex so...
-Please!
Is it possible for such a young girl and
a man to have sexual relations?
Even if it was...
...without the girl's voluntary
consent, it's impossible!
Order!
Minsu? It's not good?
Do you want something else?
Yeondu, aren't you hungry?
I used to come to the beach
with my parents.
Before I lost my hearing...
...I could hear the waves.
Now, it's too quiet.
The most beautiful and precious
things in the world...
...cannot be heard or seen.
But only felt by the heart.
Helen Keller said that.
It's my favorite quote.
What did she say?
She wishes I was her dad.
And that you're her mom.
Hey!
He's a widower with a kid.
I have never dated anyone yet.
That's absolutely crazy.
Don't even dream about it, okay?
What?
Why aren't you answering?
Answer me right now!
Don't overreact.
Tell her there's nothing between us.
Alright, alright.
First, I'll ask the defendants.
How do you feel upon seeing this child?
Though it came to this...
...she is still your student.
I was curious to know
who started...
...such ridiculous lies.
Now, that I see her...
...I think I can remember her.
Are you saying that you don't even...
...remember the girl you molested?
I've seen her a few times.
Principal Lee is right.
She even has a mental disability.
So, I remember feeling sorry and
patting her head a few times.
What about you?
Of course I know her. She was in my class.
I loved her and cared for her a lot.
Which one...
...took off your clothes
and hurt you, Yuri?
All three of them.
How many times did it happen?
A lot.
Many times...
Can you remember when it started?
Since I was in grade 3.
The chief gave me money
every time he hurt me.
He gives me 1,000 won
to buy cookies.
He pulled off my pants.
I said no because it hurts too much.
I ran away because I was scared.
He grabbed me hard...
...and forced me on a table.
He tied my hands...
...and feet to the table.
That's all a lie!
-She's crazy, Your Honor!
-He's right!
-Don't believe her!
-Stay quiet and be seated!
It's all a lie!
-Stop lying!
-God knows the truth!
-Order!
-Huh!
Who told you to lie!
-Who put you up to this!
-Order!
A settlement?
Why would there be a talk of settlement
when they molested children?
The prosecutor said sexual
molestation to kids under 13...
...can be annulled if they settle
with the victim's parents.
What parent would settle
after what happened to their child?
Yeondu doesn't have parents.
But Yuri and Minsu's parents
have mental disabilities.
Damn bastards.
They purposely chose kids who don't
have parents to take care of them.
If Yuri...
...and Minsu's parents
accept the settlement...
The only thing...
...which will be left is the Principal...
...sexually molesting Yeondu.
"Professor Kim"
Professor!
I'm sorry to ask you to meet so suddenly.
It's fine, sir. I should've called you.
I heard from Attorney Hwang.
I'm the one who introduced
you to that school.
It puts me in a tight spot.
I'm sorry, sir.
No, don't be.
It's not good for you to be
caught up in this any longer.
It's the money you donated.
I added a little more.
We hope you will help...
...in settling with Yeondu.
Once everything's settled...
...we'll support Yeondu
untill she goes to college.
And you should continue to draw.
Your talent would be
a waste if you just stop drawing.
I found a spot for you
at a school in Seoul.
You might have a hard time
for the time being...
...but they promised to hire you
as full-time after a few semesters.
I'm sorry, Professor.
I have something to do,
so I'd better get going, sir.
Mr. Kang?
Think of your little daughter.
I heard she's quite sick.
The case is over.
Yuri's relatives convinced her father
to accept the settlement.
You know this, don't you
He's mentally disabled.
Are you sure you want to testify?
I can do it.
This is school?
You said you were too busy at school.
Is this school work?
You think folks stay quiet because they
don't know what's right like you?
If you want to take care
of yourself and family...
...you can't always just
do right and speak up.
I have to go in.
You!
Is she more important to you than Sol?
I was there...
...when she was being abused.
But...
...I did nothing.
If I let go of her hand now...
...I don't think I can be
a good father to Sol, either.
Kim Yeondu.
You said the principal sexually
molested you, correct?
Yes, that's right.
Did you see the principal often?
No.
Then, how do you know the principal
sexually abused you?
I saw him a few times at school.
And he dragged me to
the principal's office that night.
Then out of those two men...
...which one is the principal?
Objection!
Asking the witness to verify the
defendants now is meaningless.
It's a very important question!
Claiming that the principal...
...molested the victim is circumstantial.
The principal's twin brother
could've committed the crime.
That means Principal Lee Kangsuk
is not guilty of the charges.
Sustained. Continue.
Which one sexually molested you?
Your Honor, she'd like to
go up closer to look.
Granted.
Defendant 4022.
He is defendant Lee Kangsuk.
But, how did you know?
How can you tell the difference?
They both cannot do sign language.
But, when the principal dragged
me to the bathroom or hurt Yuri...
...he'd say one thing in sign language.
What's that?
If you tell anyone else, I'll kill you.
When I did the sign language,
one understood and grimaced.
So, this man is the principal.
Yeondu.
According to your
testimony of that night...
...you realized that Yuri was missing when
coming back from buying cup ramyeon.
Then, you said you saw Yuri get
molested in the principal's office.
Is that correct?
Yes, that's right.
You said you were heading
to the residence...
...when you heard faint music
from the principal's office...
...so you went there, correct?
Yes.
Your Honor, that's just it.
Faint sound of music.
Yeondu is deaf.
How can she hear music?
She claims she followed the music.
Then she found the principal
sexually molesting her friend.
Your Honor, how absurd is that?
-Making up such ridiculous lies to...
-It's not a lie.
I definitely heard
a faint sound of music.
It's a song by Cho Sungmo.
Witness?
You said you'd lost hearing.
But you still heard music?
Yes.
Yeondu?
We will test to see if you
can really hear music.
Raise your hand when you hear the music.
Let's begin.
I accept the witness' account.
Prosecutor, submit an expert diagnosis
of Yeondu's auditory state.
The court will be back
in session on Friday.
Notify me of any further witnesses.
How can adults do
that to these poor children?
Come back as soon as this is done.
What brings you here?
You must have sensed something.
Yup, this is it.
A signed settlement.
Minsu's grandmother saw
the money and signed right away.
This is so funny.
Though she's poor and uneducated...
Her grandsons went through all that...
...and she signs over a few lousy bucks?
Well, it's understandable.
Her only son is sick in bed like a corpse.
Her daughter-in-law ran away.
And her grandsons are...
...mute and deaf.
At times like this...
...I think that God is being so unfair.
Can I look at this while I testify?
I want to do a good job
like Yeondu, but I'm not sure.
So, I wrote it all down her about what
Mr Park did to my brother and me...
Minsu...
About you testifying...
It's been cancelled.
But why?
Your grandmother forgave him.
They begged for forgiveness.
Your grandmother is a good person.
He killed my brother!
He hit us and pulled our pants down
whenever he could!
Minsu.
Who forgave him? I didn't forgive him!
He didn't beg forgiveness
to me and my brother!
How can he be forgiven!
You promised they'd get punished!
You promised! You promised!
I'm sorry, Minsu.
I'm so sorry, Minsu.
Yeondu?
What is it?
I have something to tell you.
What?
There's something I didn't mention.
When I was dragged to the office...
...and saw the scene on the TV...
About the naked man and girl on TV.
I'm not sure...
But I think he's...
You think there really
is something like that?
It might've been there but I don't
think he'd just elave it over there.
The principal was arrested
suddenly that day.
He must've been too shocked
to even do anything.
What if he asked someone
to get rid of it?
Who? His wife?
So, he can tell her, who worships him
like Jesus, that he's a pervert?
Or tell his lover Yoon Ja Ae?
True.
She would've tossed him right
into the laundry machine.
Such bullshit.
The date on the tape is the same
as the date Yeondu claims.
You said this before.
Cases involving kids who are 13 years and
above can be solved with a settlement.
But the date is March 14th.
That's before Yuri's 13th birthday.
That's right. Those who sexually abused
children under 13 may be punished...
...regardless of a settlement.
And with definite evidence...
...even their attorney won't
be able to do anything about it.
Not many days are leftuntil the verdict.
Is it possible to have another trial?
Still, we can't show this
as evidence in open court.
Then what sould we do?
Don't worry. I'll take this
evidence to the judge directly.
"Liberty, equality, justice"
Defendants.
As teachers of a school
for deaf children...
...sexually molesting young
students is a terrible crime.
You have the social responsibility
to protect the children.
But you sexually molested and abused them.
Therefore,
you should be severely punished.
However...
...they have allowed for great
to the development of society...
...and have no prior criminal record.
Also, the guardians of Jin Yuri
and Jeon Minsu...
...have agreed fro a settlement
with the defendants.
Considering how well
their children were taken care of...
...they wrote petitions
for lenient sentences.
Thefore, I give the following sentences.
Defendant Park Bohyun.
8 months imprisonment
and 2 year probation.
Defendant Lee Kangbok.
6 months imprisonment
and 1 year probation.
Defendant Lee Kangsuk.
6 months imprisonment
and 1 year probation.
Prosecutors should immediately take
necessary steps...
...for the defendants' release.
I'm sorry.
For being unable to help till the end.
See the kids before you go.
I should thank that judge.
No need. That's not necessary.
Privilege of former post is a given.
I'll buy him a drink sometime myself.
By the way...
...how did you win over that prosecutor?
He's been circling the countryside
with no career advancement.
Basically, he hit rock bottom
with nowhere to go.
He was ecstatic when I said
I'll take him in my law firm.
What's wrong? Are you hungry?
Suh Yujin
Minsu went to Park Bohyun's place
to get revenge.
I'm going to his house right now.
Please hurry over.
Are you listening?
It's you, Minsu.
Are you here because you missed me?
You're soaked from the rain.
Let's go in and wash up.
Okay?
Minsu!
Is anyone there?
Damn this hurts.
Shit!
Minsu!
How can you do this to me?!
This is an announcement
from the Mujin Police.
Your demonstration is in direct
violation of Article 6 Section 1.
You are illegally blocking the roads...
...and disrupting peace.
Please disperse at once.
You are holding an illegal rally.
I repeat.
You are occupying...
...the street illegally.
If you don't disperse at once...
...you will be charged
with traffic violations...
Shit.
They can't hear.
Hurry up and shoot!
This boy...
...cannot hear or speak.
This child's name is...
...Minsu.
He can neither hear...
...nor speak.
This boy's name is...
...Minsu.
He can neither hear...
...nor speak.
Please.
His name is...
...Minsu.
He can neither hear nor speak.
This boy is...
...Minsu.
How are you doing, Inho?
Sorry I haven't called in a long time.
A lot has happened since then.
Some are good, some are bad.
I'll start with the bad news first.
Our appeal was rejected.
The settlement was the problem.
The good news is...
...there are people who
help these kids now.
The kids who quit Ja Ae Academy
now have a place to stay.
Some volunteers cook meals for them.
Yuri is receiving psychological help...
...and has gotten much healthier.
She's even teaching me
sign language these days.
Yeondu says she wants
to become an art teacher.
Merry Christma!
She wants to help sick children like you.
I asked Yuri and Yeondu this
during a meal.
What changed the most before
and after this whole thing?
Do you know what they said?
They realized they're precious
just like everyone else.
Watching them grow so well,
it makes me think...
...that we should not fight...
...to change the world.
But it's to stop it
from changing who we are.
The weather got very cold.
Winter is cold...
...so that we can feel the precious
warmth of those around us.
Though we're not with you...
...I'll pray...
...that you'll feel the warmth of us
around you.
"Please come to Mujin,
the city of the white fog"