Mom...
l wanted to be with you longer.
l wanted to talk about
all kind of things with you.
We never talked about Dad...
Miss Katsumi.
Here.
Ms. Fuyuka figured
she may never see you again...
...so she wanted me to give this
to you directly, together with a message.
lt's up to you
how you wish to use it.
She says the path you ought to take...
...is written in this book.
''To my daughter Katsumi''...
Gigelf Liqueur.
Dad?
The wind. Spirits of the atmosphere.
Speak your master's name.
Why this?
l don't want any of Dad's magic...
No way. Not this.
NO!
Mom...
Attention to all passengers boarding
flight 205 for Los City via Hawaii.
We are now commencing
pre-boarding procedures.
Make your way to counters 633 and 634.
Here you go.
l'm sorry, Miss, but you cannot depart
the country with this ID.
Huh? What do you mean?
l've been here for less than ten days.
Besides, why can't l leave here
to return to my own country?
Miss, you became a citizen of
this country yesterday, didn't you?
Your residence is registered as Tokyo,
so please return after acquiring a visa.
No way. Who would do that?
l should've figured it was you guys.
Um, did Kiddy do something
by any chance?
That's right! This is the work
of that muscle woman.
She's the one who changed my ID
without my knowledge!
l have no idea what you're talking about.
We've been told by our chief
to continue guarding you.
We don't know anything beyond that.
ls that so? So that's how it is.
Then take me to your chief!
Well, l would be happy to take you there...
...but this is a two-seater.
l'm sorry but if you wanna see her,
go there on your own.
The Chief is in Department 65.
All right, then! Forget it!
Um, Miss Katsumi!
l'm sorry.
Kiddy, you didn't have to be so cold.
She just lost her mother.
Nami. Hurry up and get on!
We're gonna lose sight of her.
Could it be that you dislike Katsumi?
There are no likes or dislikes on the job.
l like Katsumi.
She actually seems a lot like you.
Hey Aida, who was that?
Apparently she's here to see
the chief of AMP.
Really. So she's not a friend of yours?
No, she's not.
l would love to be friends
with such a beautiful woman.
You've got bad taste.
What in the world
do you think you're doing?!
Changing the address on my ID
without permission?!
l thought l was done with you guys!
Let me return to Hawaii!
Then everything will be over, right?!
Regrettably, things haven't even started yet.
Also, you have become
a member of AMP starting today.
What?
Chief!
We've made living arrangements
for you here.
You'll have everything you need.
Why...why me?!
Over the past few months...
...the number of Lucifer Hawk victims
have been on the rise.
The helpless humans...people of this city
who are powerless against them...
...are killed with no means
to fight back.
That's got nothing to do with me!
Whatever happens to
complete strangers...
...or whether the city is
infested with monsters.
These things have nothing
to do with me!
l couldn't help, anyway!
l'm sure you've realized by now
that you have the power.
Tremendous power
inherited from your parents.
No way!
Are you...
are you telling me to use magic?!
The same magic that killed
my mom...and my dad?
You're telling me to use that magic?
Absolutely not!
Katsumi, Ms. Fuyuka was...
Stop it!
l've had enough! This talk of
magic and monsters...l want no more of it!
Katsumi, um...
Chief!
l don't know what kinda power she has,
but she doesn't even wanna...
Kiddy!
She is...Katsumi is crucial
to AMP's operations.
That's right.
Not only AMP.
Her existence is necessary to humanity.
And the same can be said
for our enemies.
Hey, it moved!
lt finally moved. That was a long wait.
But it'll still  be a little longer.
Hey Mom, please.
l'll keep my promise.
No. l just bought you one the other day.
But it's not the same
as the other one. So please.
Please!
Maybe next time.
No, right now!
Please. l'll help you
around the house. Please.
See, the lady's laughing at you for
being naughty. So wait until the next time.
Okay...
Huh? It's raining.
Welcome.
Excuse me.
l'll have a coffee please.
Sure.
Are those tropical fish real?
This shop isn't making that much money.
Ah, hey! Wait!
Wait a minute!
Oh, l'm sorry...
l'm sorry. l'm sorry!
That person...
Ow! Let go of me, you idiot!
You could learn to shut up!
Katsumi!
Um, it would be wise
to stay out of the rain.
lt will make you sick.
You run into problems like this
because you're absentminded.
Would you stop giving us extra work?
Why?
Kiddy!
You're the ones following me
without my asking!
Come on! Would you try and
understand the position you're in, already?!
Again? And those people too.
Like l said, don't meddle in my affairs!
Leave me alone!
How long will you keep
talking like a brat?
Then fine, l'm a brat.
You... !
The wind?
She's back.
Where is she?
Hey, what's wrong?
l feel it. Gigelf's power.
No way...
Hey, come on, what's the matter?!
Kiddy...
ls it here?
Yes.
lt's very slight, but there is a disruption
in the spiritual pressure.
What?
Are you okay?!
What in the world just happened here?
This is terrible!
Contact the Chief.
Right.
Are you all right?
Hang in there!
An ambulance
will be here right away.
The wind...suddenly.
Yes, l'll report when l find out more.
My daughter...where's my daughter?!
No! No way!
l can't take this anymore!
NO!
Katsumi!
Seems like the wind is stirring.
They likely awakened
after sensing the power.
All that power is going to
belong to us, right?
Yeah. But there appears to be
too many obstacles getting in the way.
We must do a little cleaning up.
You're right.
That's the general outline of this incident.
lt doesn't seem to be caused by
any type of explosive.
And you, Nami?
Yes. l did sense something.
But it's inconclusive?
Yes.
And what about Katsumi?
Well, she suddenly...
You lost sight of her?
Yes, l'm sorry.
l understand.
We'll trace her signal from our end.
You can call it a day
once you're done.
Yes. Roger that.
All we know is that it was windy.
We know that there were irregular winds
for 3.8 seconds in that area...
...coming from Tokyo Bay.
However the energy level of the wind itself
was rather small.
lsn't that a restricted section?
Yes. Restricted area D-13.
But there's practically nothing here
other than the former Tokyo Bay Bridge.
Hmm...
Wait. Could it be the bridge...?
l'm sick of this city.
l wanna go somewhere.
Mom.
What should l do?
And where can l go?
Huh? What's going on?
l can't move.
This rain. She warned me that
it would make me sick.
lt's cold.
This suit was expensive, too.
l'm gonna die here. l can...
...l can be with Mom.
Darling.
Huh? Where am l?
What happened?
Oh, you're awake.
You should stay there.
You need to get some more rest.
l'm making some coffee.
Who is this girl?
Come to think of it, l collapsed after
getting soaked in the rain.
l'm still alive.
Are you okay?
Do you have a headache
or anything?
Ah, l think l'm all right.
l'm glad.
You did get soaked pretty bad,
so you might not feel well for a while.
But give yourself a good night's rest and
you'll feel fine in the morning.
Oh, sorry!
l'll bring your coffee right away.
Feel free to wear that gown over there.
It's mine so it may be a bit small for you.
How do you take your coffee?
How was it?
Did you like the coffee?
Yeah, very much.
Really? l'm glad.
lt's my special blend.
Hmm...this is good enough
to serve at a coffee shop.
By the way, l came across these delicious
cookies the other day, so l bought some.
But eating at this time of night
might add to the waistline.
l haven't asked you your name yet.
Oh, right.
l'm Yuki. Yuki Saiko.
l'm Katsumi Liqueur.
Thank you for saving me.
lf you hadn't passed me by chance,
l might've been dead by now.
Did you perhaps think
you didn't mind dying at the time?
Uh...l'm not really sure.
l was feeling kinda lightheaded.
l know l was thinking how l hated this city
and wanted to go somewhere fast.
But there was no place l could go.
Please don't say such sad things.
l like this city.
And l like you too, Katsumi.
Um, wait.
l'm not at all saying that
l dislike you personally, Yuki.
Besides, l only met you today...
or more like moments ago.
There's no like or dislike
toward you yet.
And as far as the city's concerned...
l can sorta tell.
It's fate. Probably.
lt's the same with our encounter.
We'll be working
at the same place, and...
Don't tell me you're into
fortunetelling or prophecies!
Huh? Um. It's my hunch.
Like an inspiration, maybe.
l can't stand that sorta stuff!
Stuff like fortunetelling, prophecies,
the future, fate, and magic!
Huh?
l'm sorry. l just remembered
something unpleasant, so...
No, l'm sorry too.
Why don't we call it a night?
Huh? Oh, l guess.
l'm really sorry. Don't worry about it, Yuki.
l didn't mean you...
lt's all right. l understand.
What's important right now is that
you get some rest so you feel better.
Everything is normal in the Kerberos
district of the restricted section D-13.
And nothing particularly abnormal
by the Bay Bridge.
Lebia, don't you feel it?
Then this is...
Right. The fierceness of these waves.
And their numbers...Lebia!
We were being careless.
Lebia, are you all right?
l knew you would come,
Rally Cheyenne.
l know about you.
Today, l'm just here
to give you a warning.
Do not get in our way,
for your own good.
That's not a warning.
It seems like you're begging.
l waited a long time for
Gigelf's blood and power.
Then why don't you hurry and do it?
We are not so foolish as to
attack someone guarded by that power.
First, we will have
Gigelf's daughter learn the truth...
...and then wait for our chance.
Chief!
Please stand back!
Lebia! Watch out!
Lebia!
A second-rate monster like you
should think twice before pissing me off!
Dad...
The great sorcerer Gigelf who had
perfected the powers of magic.
What did you do in this city, Dad?
That dream...where was that place?
Mom was calling out to Dad.
Was that my memory?
Mom...
Dad...
That red blood...
l like it very much.
There was a time
when l cursed this blood.
Humans are so self-centered.
They're the ones
who guided us to this world.
And the humans broke the agreement.
You're referring to only
a few humans.
l will never let you try to kill
all the people in this city.
What?
Another enemy?
They got away.
How am l gonna explain that
to everyone?
Lebia.
Are you all right?
Chief, where is the Lucifer Hawk?
Sorry. They got away.
Chief, you're hurt!
l'm okay. Your injuries are worse.
No, l'm fine.
Are you sure?
lf this next enemy awakens,
it could be a big problem.
Thank you.
Your coffee was delicious.
Katsumi!
Where are you going,
so early in the morning?
Well...um...
Oh, of course!
Breakfast, right? Give me a moment.
l'll go with you.
You have quite the appetite
for someone your size.
You think so?
But breakfast is the most important
meal of the day, right?
Besides, l'm still growing.
Why would you wanna get any bigger
than you are now?
Katsumi. That pendant...
Huh? Oh.
It's my dad's keepsake.
Although l don't remember his face.
You don't?
l'm not surprised that's
a keepsake.
You held it tightly and wouldn't let it go
even when you were unconscious.
l was holding this?
You're fortunate, Katsumi...
...to have a keepsake
and memories of your parents.
But l have bad memories too.
But it's better than nothing.
l have nothing.
Yuki. We'll part ways here.
What do you mean?
lf you stay too close to me,
you'll find yourself in all kinds of trouble.
Besides, l need to get back
to my hometown.
You're lying!
Katsumi, the truth is...
The truth is...
l...
l don't think
l'll ever learn to like this city.
l have no friends
or acquaintances here.
You're wrong!
There are people here
who are important to you!
Thank you. Bye.
Katsumi, wait!
One person has come out.
What? It's too early.
It must be someone else.
We'll know right away.
lt's confirmed. That's Katsumi.
There she goes bustling about
this early in the morning.
l can't even eat my breakfast in peace!
Hey Kiddy!
You mustn't throw away
your trash here!
Nami!
How dare you!
Stop it!
U-Um...
Leave me alone. Please.
Just stay away from me.
But, your...
l'm not the kinda person you think l am.
lf you continue sticking to me,
you'll get hurt.
Why is that? Why?
Why are you throwing
everything away, Katsumi?
Why do you insist on dying?
l know what you're thinking.
But l don't like it.
It's not right.
You deny your existence
and live in your memories.
Katsumi, you are very important to me!
l like you very much!
Chief!
You should be taking the day off.
You may not realize it,
but l'm quite busy.
How's your shoulder?
Does it hurt?
l've wrapped the wound
so it's a bit stiff, but it doesn't hurt.
Good.
What about Katsumi?
Right, Kiddy and Nami have been on her
since this morning.
Who's this girl?
Right, her name is Yuki Saiko.
She's been with Katsumi
since last night.
Gather whatever data is
available on her, just in case.
Sure. Please give me a minute.
What's the matter?
lt seems there are people
who don't want us finding out about her.
l'll disable the block.
What is it?
There's significant protection
on the data.
lt's likely a very large organization.
The government?
Probably.
lPER Project.
Do you know of it?
Yeah. l've heard rumors about it.
Mind wave enhancement
through genetic manipulation.
lf l remember correctly, that project
was abolished a number of years ago.
l'll check into it myself.
Don't tell anyone about this.
Yes, l understand.
Here you are, Katsumi.
Thank you.
ls this place really okay?
Yes. At first sight, it's the same
as the restricted areas...
...but it is on the outside.
Being as it is,
people don't come here.
After all, if you step into a restricted area,
the police would come flying to catch you.
We wouldn't be able to talk like this.
l'm an orphan.
So l have no idea
what my parents look like.
l don't have the experience of having them
play with me, or scold me.
But one thing l do remember well
is that large bridge.
l think l lived in
this neighborhood when l was small.
Every single day l would look
at that bridge.
l told myself that
good things would happen if l crossed it.
There would be many fun things.
There would be
wonderful encounters.
And l'd find many nice friends.
l know your secret, Katsumi.
What?
You grind your teeth a lot
while you're asleep.
That's the first time you laughed!
The Katsumi l know
the one l saw in the future! re...
...always had a wonderful smile.
That story again?
lf you don't stop it,
l may end up hating you.
Huh? Come on!
Don't worry, l'm kidding.
Really? What a relief.
What's the matter, Katsumi?
l know this bridge.
l always saw it too.
Katsumi.
Katsumi!
A little further down.
Looks like she's finally arrived.
lt appears so.
lt's checkmate at last.
This is the place. l'm certain.
What's the matter, Katsumi?
l was looking at the bridge from here,
together with Mom.
Katsumi, this house...
This place...
(PICTURE)
lt says Hazuki.
Hazuki...
Fukuya Hazuki.
That's Mom's maiden name.
Before she got together with Dad.
Her name before she married.
Then is this Mom's home?
No way. What is this?
Katsumi!
Don't go inside!
Huh? Why not?
What do you mean?
Um, anyway, you must not go in.
What?! Is this some vision of yours again?
My mom used to live here!
And l've lived here too!
What could possibly be inside?
l don't know what we'll find in here...
...but there may be memories of
my mom and my dad in here...
...that far outweigh any dangers!
But...um...
l'm sorry, Yuki. l'll be fine.
l'll be right back.
Katsumi!
This room...
Mom's photo.
lt's addressed to Mom! From Dad?!
l doubt l'll ever be able
to return to you two again.
Should my body be ripped apart
by the claws of a Lucifer Hawk...
...l would have
been rightfully punished.
Should my body disintegrate...
...It would still not compensate
for the crimes l have committed.
Fuyuka.
When Katsumi' awakens to her powers...
...hand her my pendant.
l've even burdened
Katsumi' with the destiny to be the key.
My destiny?
Yes.
Gigelf entrusted you with the last of
his magic when you were a baby.
Who are you?
A monster?
What would you do if l were?
You guys planted this letter!
How could we touch anything within
Gigelf's barrier protecting this house?
Acknowledge the truth,
Katsumi Liqueur.
You, as well as us
are Gigelf's victims.
Would you please make use
of your powers for our good?
Fine! Do as you wish!
Kill me if you'd like.
l have nothing in this city.
No place to go, and no one to see.
You're a pathetic fool...
...willingly throwing away the protection
given to you from your parents.
Humans are strange.
They continue protecting
their loved ones, even after death.
They can now come to greet you
with nothing to fear.
l will not kill you.
You will become one with us
and live in darkness through eternity.
Katsumi went in there
and hasn't come out!
Huh? Um, we're...
l know!
You are Katsumi's friends, right?!
Yes.
l'll go ahead!
Kiddy!
Looks like we were a little too late.
No way!
Where's Katsumi?!
How should l know?
That selfish girl.
l'll go check the other rooms
just in case.
Nami. Report to the Chief.
Katsumi...
l see. l understand.
l'm sorry that we weren't...
No, l know what they're after.
Go to the Bay City district
of area D-13 at once.
Roger.
Chief.
l'll go there too.
How's your shoulder doing?
Well, my right shoulder's still
bothering me a bit, but...
Very well.
l'll have Dewey go there.
l'll have you provide support from here.
Huh?
And l want you to use that system.
l understand.
l'll need 20 minutes to set and locate
the target, and to charge the machine.
Thanks. l'm counting on you.
Don't mention it.
It's for a colleague...for a friend.
Katsumi. Judge for yourself.
The meaning of battle...
and magic.
Where am l?
What is this?
Are you awake?
Why, that's right.
You do not know what happened here.
Watch closely...
...and regret living on forever.
Those are our friends who got stuck
within the warp of time-space...
...when the gate to
Nemesis suddenly closed.
Can't you hear them?
The voices of those who have awakened
after sensing your power.
But they can't move.
They've been teasing the humans
by sending curses on the wind.
But you know, if we have
your blood and power...
...our friends will be resurrected.
That listless expression
is good.
That listlessness is something that
will be necessary for you from now on.
lf you're gonna bear a grudge
against anyone...
...bear one against your father
who gave you all of that. Do that, and...
This gun is different from anything
in the past.
lt's the Graviton!
You keep getting in our way.
They're here to save me?
Katsumi!
Get away from there, quick!
You'll get caught in the blast!
Katsumi!
NOOO!
Katsumi, over here!
Yuki!
Are you all right? l'll bring it closer!
Dewey!
Yes, just a moment.
Get in!
Dewey, okay!
Fasten your seat belts.
Well done. Let's go, Nami.
Lebia, you're good to go.
Okay, Kiddy.
Louie, have you located the target?
Already completed.
We will begin our countdown.
Go ahead.
Ten seconds to go.
All clear.
Trigger timing to Miss Lebia.
Thank you.
Marker on!
The bridge is gone.
Yuki, why do something
so dangerous just to save me...?
Because you're an important
friend of mine, Katsumi. It's only natural.
Yuki...
Are you two all right?
No way!
They're still alive?
How dare you do that to our friends.
Come to think of it
there's another.
Yuki, run away, quick!
Katsumi.
Here...
Thank you, Yuki.
lt's an important item to you.
Damn you...
Very well then.
lf you're eager to give up your life,
l'll take it for you.
Damn it.
Kiddy!
Nami, take those two and escape.
Hurry up. Nami, take them.
Right!
You're not getting away!
None of you!
That person's body...
Now, hurry!
Kiddy!
l will not forgive you,
after what you did to Kiddy!
NO!
Are you in pain, Katsumi?
But you must realize,
we've had to endure a lot more pain.
Stop it!
l will not kill you, because
you are the all-important living key.
First...
No way. The sacred water...
You shall see the end of those
who turned our friends into ashes.
Stop it! Stop it!
Now, come to our world.
Why? Why is everyone helping me
at such a great cost?
Wait! Don't take Katsumi!
Katsumi is an important friend of mine!
l...no, we all like Katsumi!
We need Katsumi!
So...so, don't take her!
Don't take Katsumi...
Well, let's go.
Unfortunately, l've always
had a problem with giving up.
l'm not letting you take the princess.
Damn humans!
You still insist on getting in our way?!
That's right.
Katsumi's annoying,
but l kinda like her.
This time l'll finish you off for sure.
Stop it!
Don't hurt my friends anymore!
You needn't be afraid of your powers.
All things in this world have
a spirit living within them.
No way!
l hoped that you could live your life...
...peacefully and happily,
as an ordinary woman. But...
Go, Katsumi'.
Go and fight with your fate.
Dad...Mom...
Use your heart to communicate
with the spirits...
...and give instructions on exerting power.
That's what magic is.
You must become strong. Become strong
enough to protect the ones you love.
Your father and l will be watching...forever...
There are people who say
that they like even a person like me.
People who need me.
l wanna be able to love those people!
l wanna protect them,
using everything that l have!
With the use of magic!
So you're saying you won't come
to Nemesis with me?
l won't go!
l will never again run away
from this real world!
No matter what may happen!
l see. That's a shame!
The five stars of protection surround me
with their flame!
The six stars of protection shimmer
in a pillar of light!
Mom, Dad...
Right now, l am about to willingly
use magic for the first time.
The power to this barrier... ! Impossible!
The stream of my power...
l can hear the voice of the spirits...
This is...
This is magic!
This can't be happening.
This...power...
Ater marcto ve gepura ve dedura orum!
Amen!
Purify all evil within this light!
You will regret this, Katsumi.
l did it, Mom.
l defeated the Lucifer Hawk.
l protected my friends...
...with magic.
Mom, l'll be on my way.
Net open to normal police!
As of nineteen hours and thirteen minutes
this is now a category three case...
...classified as a Third Attraction.
Present situation, rank C.
This case is now under
AMP's command.
To my front...Raphael.
To my rear...Gabriel.
To my right hand, Michael.
And to my left hand, Uriel.
Ater marcto ve gepura ve
dedura orum! Amen!
Did she get it?
l almost had it.
Kiddy, the Graviton!
Katsumi.
You still have a ways to go.
l'm just getting started.
Just watch me.
A heartbreaking night is coming
To a place that overlooks the city
Unable to trust each other
after two thousand years
Why do people still welcome tomorrow?
The swirling winds are murmuring
lt sounds like a nostalgic voice
Sleep now,
you will surely meet them in the morning
lf you are willing to love someone
Battles are always for oneself, ah
They are not for hurting others
Even though l was so depressed, ah
l was able to refrain from running away
Because l came to know you
(PICTURE)
Battles are always for oneself, ah
They are not for hurting others
Wiping a tear somewhere on Earth, ah
Hoping this will somehow reach a friend
l will surely pledge this to the skies
(PICTURE)