A film by Ildik¨® Enyedi
Simon the Magician
Music:
Director of photography:
Written and directed by:
I'll tell you an old story.
1998, Paris. We barely remember
what it was like.
The end of something, but not yet
the beginning of anything.
Like ancient Rome around 100 BC,
to where Simon Mágus arrived,
from some far corner of the empire...
Yes?
Shot...
Why me?
Okay, fine.
100 thousand franks.
No.
100 thousand.
No planes.
Train. I'll take the train.
Look at me when
I'm talking to you!
Take your stuff,
and piss off!
Hey, are you listening?
Get it?
- Are you well?
- Yes and you?
I'm sorry, what just happened?
No, believe me,
I was there the whole time.
I talked to the conductor too.
I have no idea.
Maybe he missed
the train and is still in Budapest,
having breakfast somewhere.
Why, what else
could I have done?
They didn't tell me it
would be this cold in Paris.
All is well,
he's arrived!
Good afternoon! Oh,
I'm so glad you found me.
I'm Liza,
good day!
Please get in!
I'll take you to your hotel.
Then we have to
go see the commissioner.
- I've already got a room.
- Oh, but this is a very elegant hotel.
That doesn't matter.
This will do for me.
My staff is leading the
investigation...
and they are very
pleased you are here.
They will help any way
they can.
The pressure is building.
We have to produce results.
Of course we have
French psychics.
We are in contact with
a few soothsayers.
But they haven't
gotten anywhere in the case.
As to confidentiality...
it's an issue of
professional prestige.
None of this is public...
so I would ask
for discretion.
That's all.
He thanks you.
Do you need anything?
The money in advance.
He'll write a check.
I'd like cash.
They say it
can be arranged.
Did you travel well?
The placement of the corpse,
points to violence...
The approximate time of death...
Liza dear!
I need to work alone.
Please understand,
the master needs to work alone.
Of course.
We are leaving.
And you dear?
I'm eating cake.
Really?
Put it down!
You're not allowed.
Right, right,
down, down.
Yes.
Would you please...
leave with the others?
Me?
Yes, yes.
I'm going.
Excuse me.
Can you hear anything?
- He must be concentrating.
- He better be.
He has about as much chance
of finding the killer,
as me finding water
with this key chain.
Do you have
a pack of cards?
I'll write the report
if you go to the bakery.
I'm bored to death!
Bring beer instead!
He wasn't quick
about it.
Liza my dear!
Tell them,
to bring a micro voltmeter
and an Oscilloscope.
- Okay. - Oh, and a biologist,
he'll know what he needs to do.
- What did he say?
- Can we go in?
One sec!
Come here!
He needs a micro voltmeter.
Call a biologist!
What's this?
With this we can measure
the energy of the plant.
First we put gelatine
on the leaf,
then we place the
electrode on it,
which we connect to
the oscilloscope,
and it shows on the monitor,
the changes in the
feelings of the plant.
- The plants energy?
- Exactly.
By examining the state of
the plant we can conclude,
what the plant felt.
- He wants to ask something.
- Go ahead!
- He's interested in your method.
- Why? He doesn't understand?
No method.
No magic.
The plant has
been well taken care of.
It's owner must have loved it,
and it hurt the plant, to lose him.
Yes but he still doesn't understand.
If we show it the killer,
it will recognize him.
I'll turn on the machine.
Put the wire on the leaf.
The gelatine will
be the conductor.
The receiver
is on the leaf...
everything is ready...
Careful!
Don't touch the plant!
Watch the monitor.
I've had enough.
- So now what do we do? - Round up
all the people who knew him.
- All of them?
- No just the left handed ones.
Hold on, I'll show
you something!
See my lighter.
I'll put the flame closer
and watch the difference!
The curves go higher.
Pull it away,
they lower.
Closer, higher.
Okay, but...
If the killer is in the room,
the curves will
change.
Is this a trustworthy method?
Yes. Though it's never
been used in crime solving.
Let's go a little closer!
Yes, that's him.
He's gotten older.
Careful, slower!
I don't want him
to see me yet.
You see, this man is
my only adversary.
If he's still in shape.
We'll see.
Put some music on.
That's good.
Now you can go closer.
Well... well...
Oh!
Good evening!
Get in!
No, no.
I'll walk.
Don't insult me! Now that
we ran into each other...
Let's talk!
No, no, no! I just
need a little air.
Tell me honestly: when you
saw me, did your recognise me?
- What?
- I haven't changed too much?
Sorry, I didn't hear
you well!
- I asked if you knew me?
- Oh, yeah of course.
Get in!
Don't make me beg!
That's a nice car.
No, no... really.
It looks good.
That's it?
This is a Bentley.
1 Bentley for every 200 Rolls-Royce's.
- Alright fine... - Tell me,
would you like to get a drink?
Come on, I'll take you
too a special place.
I'm a member there.
My treat.
Maybe that's too
classy for me.
Alright then a bar.
Well, that sounds better.
I don't drink anymore,
but okay.
Just get in already!
My neck is getting sore.
So that's the type of shows
I had last year.
- Not bad.
- Right?
- And you?
- Nothing, little things.
Come on...
You're planning something,
that's why you're so secretive.
- I guessed it?
- No.
I don't really care
about the profession.
Want to hear something surprising?
I'm going underground.
- then...
- In the metro?
Don't joke around
I'll raise from the dead.
In a sense.
No tricks.
- Totally natural.
- I see.
Tell me honestly,
it's a big thing no?
Yes, yes.
Classic.
The Church is upset of course,
but that's free publicity.
- So...
- Nice, nice.
Isn't it?
Now it's your turn.
- What would you like to hear?
- You know that!
- I have no idea.
- You can guess.
Or you think you're
that much better than me?
- Well it's... possible.
- Impossible.
- Hey, hey, hey. - The truth is
I'm the best.
- Wow! - Look, I know
all your tricks...
- Cigarette?
- ... all of them.
No, thank you.
How deep your
telepathy goes.
I know them all
and can do them.
- You don't believe it?
- Sure you can.
Fine... hold on!
See that street lamp.
If you want,
I can turn it off.
- Oh, god no!
- Just say the word.
Didn't you say
you'd take me to a bar?
This is it.
My hotel, let me out.
I was happy to see you.
No, don't stop!
Step on it!
Very good.
- Good evening!
- Good evening, sir!
Sit down!
You must be surprised
that I called you in.
No.
Really?
Well... yes.
What's his method?
I know he only spoke to
you. I was informed.
See, I know everything.
Really.
By the way
he solved it.
We caught the killer,
he confessed too. Did you know?
No, I didn't hear.
Surprised?
No, sir.
It doesn't.
It doesn't...
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Then find him!
Fast!
There was a picture here.
Some soil plan thing.
- Looks nice.
- Nice?
Maybe that's
not the right word.
Go back an image!
- Yes, yes.
- Here it is.
- This is it.
- Here. Here.
It's a nice drawing.
I printed it.
I have it here somewhere,
let's see.
Here.
This is the pit.
This is where
they'll bury me.
Well you've
gone all out!
You're being ironic.
But you're wrong.
Look, I'll show you!
Wait, you just stepped in
when I was looking at this.
- Careful with the program...
- No, wait!
- Listen, I'll show you something.
- ... something got into it.
- So!
- Here.
- So?
- Yes.
- Here.
Wait!
Just wait!
- Wait... see. - I don't
think you need all this.
You can do all
this without the mouse.
- Okay, but...
- Let's see a test!
- Look at the screen!
- I see, I see.
Hey!
Move the cursor!
That's not such a big deal.
Move it again.
Voil?
That's not my style.
I know your very good,
but this isn't what I do.
I know you have some sort
of natural power,
that I don't. I
needed lots of work,
so I could perfect
what I do.
That's something too.
What's this?
Let me see!
Hold on. If you indulge me, I'll get back
to this drawing, it's interesting.
140 centimetre deep pit.
It's exactly that much,
because my chest would be
crushed under the weight.
I don't know about your chest...
- Sorry but...
- I apologise!
So.
Back to the experiment,
the three days,
I'll spend underground,
do you know why
its unique?
Because I'll do it
without air.
I can't tell you how,
hope you understand.
It doesn't seem
too complicated.
Really?
- Then tell me how it's done.
- Fine, fine, fine.
It wasn't an insult.
- Continue!
- Wait, I'll help.
I'm going to use the system bears
use, so my brain won't get damaged.
The brain waves of
the bear are the key.
But you won't guess
from that either.
Tell me, why is
the press chasing you?
I had an affair with
police.
Murder,
dirty deeds.
How did it go?
Rich corpse, pictures, beider,
rococo, baroque, whatever you want.
It was cold. Do they
never heat in Paris?
Master, forgive me!
The commissioner is waiting.
A car is here.
Come on, let's
get a drink?
Don't look at me like that!
Let's drink!
Then we can go on.
No, no!
I'd like some red wine.
Vino.
Rouge.
- What's he doing?
- Can't you see? He's drinking.
He waved to you...
Cheers!
A coffee please!
This is good wine.
You're a strange guy.
Sitting here. Don't come in,
then you come in,
then you drink
the wine.
Interesting.
What should I do with you?
I have no idea.
Look...
I can see in your eyes,
that you'll come tomorrow,
and ask me if you
can be my student.
And I won't know what
to do with you.
Don't look at me like that!
Just keep sitting here?
See it's not so devilish.
Your buddy can wait
outside right?
Keep drinking! Hey, sir!
Two more please!
Wait, you don't know how much
I can drink. Just wait and see!
Good morning viewers!
You're watching the TV5 weather report.
Let's take a look,
at the December 7th
projections!
Clouds cover most of Europe...
Thank you, good bye!
Good day, would you answer
a few questions? About religion...
No thank you.
Would you answer
a few questions?
I only speak English.
- Would you answer
a few questions? - I'm in a hurry.
- About religion in France.
- No.
Sir, please!
Would you answer a few questions?
It's only five minutes.
Are you catholic?
- No.
- Protestant?
- Jewish?
- No.
- Buddhist?
- Atheist?
- Yes.
I've seen you somewhere, right?
No.
I was positive.
Sorry.
- Do you go to confession?
- No... yes.
- Yes?
- Yes.
- Sometimes?
- No.
- Never?
- Everyday?
- Yes.
Really?
That's rare.
Do you go to
mass once a year?
No.
- Never.
- No... yes, yes!
Are you making fun of me?
You say you confess daily,
but you're an atheist?
And I'm sure that
I've met you before.
- A coffee?
- I didn't say that because...
Do you believe in
the use of contraception?
A coffee?
What are you reading?
A cook book...
Surprised again.
Can I see?
Wow, seems complicated,
I can't cook at all.
- Sir, what would you like?
- Coffee.
- Two?
- Yes.
Can you cook?
Look, it's funny,
it looks like America.
This is California,
this is Texas,
and Florida,
and the tail is
New York. Right?
I heard something
about pigs.
If you would lock up all the animals
with one week's worth of food,
they would all eat the food
at once, except the pig.
The pig would
spread it out.
It proves it's the
most intelligent.
It's musical too.
I love music,
you must too.
They say music is man mad,
but that's not true.
If you slow down
bird calls,
the tunes are worthy
of great composers,
and... so...
that's all I wanted...
- Am I boring you?
- Aha.
Tell me honestly,
why am I here?
Do you like me?
No, no.
- You were bored?
- Yes.
What do you expect of me?
You think I'm stupid?
This isn't the way to woo someone.
But you're not wooing me.
Fine.
Thanks for the coffee.
Bye.
You think you're so
mysterious being so quiet?
I thought about what you
said about the birds.
You're wrong.
I know you like me,
why don't you admit it?
Do you want to
sleep with me?
Yes, yes.
And the rest
doesn't matter?
No.
You didn't say anything
about my experiment.
Tell me what you think.
There's a draft.
Should I close the window?
Why won't you answer me?
The thing is I need a favour.
So! Even the big
instinctive needs help.
At your service!
But that doesn't change the fact,
that you didn't answer me.
I said we should close
the damn window.
I don't mind the draft.
I don't even mind
the smoke.
Even though that
disgusts me.
I counted: You smoked
47 cigarettes in my house.
It hurts me that you
don't answer my questions.
But I'm a calm person.
It's hard to make me mad.
Fine.
Let's not talk about the experiment.
Though I don't need to say it's a little
condescending, in fact it's insulting.
What was the favour?
Well... umm... Nothing,
it's not important.
Out with it!
It's nothing.
I just though you could
teach me a few things.
Oh! Well that's
another story.
That's very humbling.
Okay, but I won't
tell you just anything. No!
You mean the
levitation right?
Or the disappearing act?.
Well, I can show you
that if you want.
No, of course not, no!
I was just thinking that
that you could teach me some French.
It can come in handy.
- What?
- That's all.
You know, you choose a
very sneaky way to insult me.
You solve crimes. As if there
aren't enough cops in the world.
But what I'm
doing works.
You're just a show off! You can't
do all that I can.
Houdini tried. 50 years
ago to go underground.
It didn't work for him.
It will for me.
Right, Houdini.
Very good.
- Okay, congratulations!
- Go ahead! Can you do it!
You wouldn't dare!
You can't!
- Just admit it!
- I don't like all the hype.
Like I said, it's
all talk! Show off!
Do it after me, if you can!
What? You want a duel?
Fine, let's have a duel!
It's not a bad idea.
Okay, fine.
I'll do it.
When?
- Are you kidding...
- No, I'm not joking.
But this is insane.
- You're not ready.
- Well... I have time.
What did you say,
tomorrow afternoon?
Okay fine.
I have to tell you something.
A cop is here.
He waited all night.
So go, and I didn't see you.
Understand?
I'm coming.
Just because...
I'd like to clear something up.
I... I...
I would gladly help.
But is this
a professional conversation?
It's okay I know what he wants.
To take me to his boss.
Master,
I thought about last night,
and I would like to
be your student.
He wants something else.
To be your student.
My student?
Surprising.
You're prettier
as a burnet.
What should I tell him?
Continue!
I read a lot after work,
but I have no one
to guide me.
I'd like to know the
meaning of life.
Sorry!
Hello?
Yes, I do know where he is.
He's right in front of me.
Yes, sir.
We're going.
They have a celebration planed.
You might get an award.
Anyway congratulations.
Let's get a taxi.
Taxi! Taxi!
Well be on time.
No, no!
Stay, I'm going alone.
But how? If I need to
translate, and...
I don't have the time now,
maybe later.
- Don't take it to heart!
- I'm not.
- Good bye!
- I'll walk you.
- I'm not bothering you?
- He's not very nice.
- Don't make that face!
- What face?
I'd like to know
your opinion.
- Some legal issues?
- No.
You're a sensitive boy.
How do you see me?
That's a hard question...
Forget it, don't answer!
It was a silly question.
You're very sweet.
- No really leave it!
- Yes, yes. Just a little wired.
What do you mean wired?
Well let's say...
not loose enough.
Thank you.
- Where was I?
- The sprits freedom.
Right, yes. I think
the state of the body...
- The fries are good.
- So the mind and body...
Stop it!
Look!
- Did he die?
- No, he's breathing.
Put it under his head!
Careful, don't wake him.
It's him!
Yes, it's him.
Sir,
do something for me!
Life is so hard!
Please, help!
A little sign, please.
It's important
for my scholarship.
You have to fill out the
papers and send them.
Otherwise?
Hold on, I'll call
you back.
Just a second! Calm down,
I'll call someone, okay?
Hello.
Good afternoon!
I was just thinking about you.
Sure. Of course
I'll help, any time.
Of course.
Wait, I don't understand.
- Okay, well I guess...
- Tell her to stay!
I don't want her to leave.
Will you help?
Here she is.
Hello?
Who am I talking to?
I don't understand,
what's going on.
No, of course I'm not afraid.
No it's not that,
it's just strange.
My dear,
believe me he
could really love you.
The thought never crossed
my mind that he doesn't speak French.
I had a conversation
with him.
Now I feel a little silly.
Yes?
Don't let her go! Get
her to stay!
Thank you.
No I'm not laughing at him.
Fine.
Thank you.
Good bye.
Hello?
- An autograph.
- Me too.
How do you feel?
Very well, thank you.
Say a few words
to the viewers.
No, not right now.
See you in three days!
Why isn't Simon here?
Don't detest him for it.
It might not be that he's a coward.
This is an extremely
dangerous experiment.
We have no right
to judge him.
Why are you alone?
I'm always alone.
I think he's not coming.
Looks that way.
- What do we do now?
- Do you want to go? I'll walk you.
No, it's okay I want to stay.
- I want to see what happens.
- He's right not to have come.
Maybe he just forgot.
I'd like to know
what he's doing now.
No, sir, it's a
restricted area.
Hey, old man,
stay outside.
I illiterate again that
this is not a trick.
He's here!
He came!
I'm coming!
Look, it's Simon!
Excuse me, master,
I didn't recognise you.
There's no
problem right?
We we're worried,
and we're waiting for you.
Go on, go to him.
Can I see you?
Here.
I have an exam,
but in three days.
Ten at night? Okay?
Ten at night here?
- Good bye!
My friend, Simon!
Late again.
Nice markers.
You'll get some too.
You know...
I thought I wouldn't see you.
I promised, no?
But I'm here now.
Can we start?
Smile!
- Camera.
- We have different styles.
Don't deny it.
This is a race.
You smoke a lot?
Your blood pressure
is too high.
You know what? Tell him
I have stage fright.
You don't seem like
the type.
Now he'll tell you
about suffocation.
First you feel a pressure...
then the breathing quickens...
and the heart.
The head throbs,
the ears ring.
You begin to panic
and become afraid.
That's it!
Swats, nausea, vomiting.
The body shakes...
trembles,
then the pain...
Don't do it!
Don't try it!
If you want I'll come
up with some good excuse.
This is totally, crazy...
and the truth is,
you know it too.
How could I go on
if something happens to you?
What could happen?
I don't think this is what you want,
you were just dragged into it.
I'm glad I met you doctor,
you're a good man.
Where's the
paper I need to sign?
Viewers! A few minuets
and the experiment will start.
In three days the graves
will open, and hopefully,
the two magicians will
be alive.
My friends!
Then... in three days!
Move the microphones.
- On last photo!
- Me too!
Sure you don't want it?
Thank you now.
I feel fine.
I rested a little.
- Something's wrong.
- Yes.
Let me through.
The doctor, quickly!