/Death be not proud
/Though some have called thee
/Mighty and dreadful
/For thou art not so
/One short sleep past
/We wake eternally
/And death shall be no more
/Death, thou shalt die
I told Charlie it was over.
You wouldn't dare,
would you, Vinnie?
Kassie, do you want some candy?
Or do you prefer cold turkey...
...thick-sliced?
Hey, Eddie, how's the plantation?
- I'm making the desert bloom, Cal.
- Goddamn.
What gets you up with the sun?
I don't know how you did this with one
arm. I couldn't have done it with two.
Just tell me why you're here.
Look, Kassie was arrested
last night.
She had an eight-gram deck
of Bart Simpson in her pocket.
The arresting officer recognized her,
brought her to me.
Kassie would die
before she touched that shit.
She must have been carrying
for someone else.
Eddie, I saw the track marks
on her arms.
Now, I tore up the charge sheet.
I tried to bring her out here,
but she jumped out the car...
...at the red light.
- Who's the balloon?
When she was arrested
she was alone.
I mean, I could put some time in
if you want.
Eddie!
You stupid useless fuck!
You killed everything
that ever mattered.
I want you to die!
Do you understand me?
I want you to die.
I want you to fucking die!
Bella's raising hell.
She wants the camera.
Take it.
Send Kassie up to my room.
She don't look too proud now.
I said, take it.
It was pure number four
when it left Hong Kong.
That's as far
as my guarantee extends.
Hey.
Leo, I know I'm new to this game.
But don't treat me
like a fucking asshole.
From now on
I'm handling things stateside.
This problem won't arise again.
Charlie, conflict is bad for business.
You have our apologies
and a new guarantee.
You also asked me for a favour.
These were much more difficult to find
than I anticipated.
And more expensive.
We've been running a blackmail scam
out of the Patpong girly bars for years.
Child prostitutes
and American tourists.
We have the supply,
you have the demand.
A white boy getting a blowjob,
so what?
Look again, Vincent.
Add a decade to the face.
How much?
Accept them as a goodwill gift
from your friends.
Well, tonight...
...we've scheduled some entertainment.
Which I hope will repay the favour.
What do you mean,
too tired?
I was hired for two cum shots
and that last one was it.
And it was a monster, I might add.
That was the three-way
dyke scene...
...you're only supposed to watch.
- I don't watch, lady. I fuck.
And dyke stuff is for faggots.
I had to go with the truth of the scene.
They wanted me, I felt it.
You ever heard of going
with the moment? The Method?
- You know, Strasberg and Stravinsky.
- It wasn't in the script, Marlon.
When the script gives me nothing,
I have to write the character.
You just wrote yourself a brand-new
ending. You're fired. Now fuck off!
Hey, Bella!
How's it going?
Jeff thinks we're doing a remake
of "On the Waterfront." Otherwise, fine.
- Hopefully this shit'll cut together later.
- Where's the pride in your craft?
I left it in New Jersey in a rat hole.
Charlie, this bitch
is breaking my balls, man.
- I'm not used to being treated this way.
- I know you're not, Jeff, honey.
In "Shaving Private Ryan" he was taking
enemas from a squad of Nazi troopers.
He's a better actor
than you give him credit for.
He looked like he was enjoying it.
Oh, and when you're finished in here,
leave the rig...
...and put the camera in the other room
behind the mirror.
A little home movie.
Consenting adults only.
Jeff, let's see some wood.
- Hello?
- "Eddie?"
Kassie, where are you?
It's going to be okay, sis,
just let me come and get you.
Eddie, I'm so sorry.
- I'm just so sorry.
- Come home, Kassie.
- I can't do that.
- "We've been through worse than this."
/But if you stay in that city
/it'll burn you down so far...
/... you'll never come back up again.
/Let me bring you home.
/Are you still there?
/- Kassie?
- I'm here.
Just tell me where you are
and I'll come get you now.
I can't do that.
/I can get a doctor.
- I have to go.
/- Kassie, wait!
I love you, big brother.
- See you later, Eddie.
- Who is this?
You called him Eddie.
You know him.
I know a lot of people.
I'm leaving, Charlie.
I've had enough.
I own the pink slip
on your life, baby.
I say suck my cock,
you get down on your knees.
I say fuck a dog with yellow fever,
you spread your legs and you bark.
Why should I give two shits
what you say?
You want me to invite Eddie
down here?
You see, angel...
...in a world where men
screw children...
...what else is there
for a girl to do...
...except get high?
She's a survivor.
She's been using for months.
Why the emergency?
Because I served that cesspool
of a city for 15 years...
...and never so much as
took a free turkey at Christmas.
Now I've got one arm, a pension
and a cage to count the hours in.
Maybe I'm nobody,
but I want my sister safe.
The department owes me that,
and even if they don't, you do.
- I'll talk to the captain.
- We'll both talk to the captain.
Eddie.
She might call here again.
She might show up.
Stay here.
Remember...
...I don't have your patience.
- Going somewhere, madam?
- I need to go to the bathroom.
You...
You are nothing.
You feel nothing.
You...
...want nothing.
...are nothing.
So...
...nothing matters, right?
Can you get me out of here?
I mean now!
Charlie doesn't like when first-timers
cheat on a deal.
- No, you don't understand.
- Oh, I think I understand well enough.
Please help me.
Oh, shit.
Looks like we both
had a pretty tough day.
Let's go.
Party's upstairs, Kassie.
It's so easy to get lost in this place.
If you want a ride, just say so.
Whatever you said you'd do,
they've no right to keep you here.
When we need a lawyer
we'll give you a call.
Go scare some schoolgirls, Vincent.
Do you want to leave or not?
- I took a wrong turn.
- You sure?
You bitches finished?
- Kassie?
- I took a wrong turn.
Go home and feed your cats.
Pre- Noh style.
Very special.
Very rare.
No, no.
No! No!
No, no!
No!
I didn't know gooks
were so big on ink.
- I told you to go feed your cats.
- That girl was scared. I wanna know...
Get the fuck out of here.
You know, I don't know if this is the
best time to open up my heart to you...
...but the truth is, I kind of had a crush
on you ever since Charlie dug you up.
You don't believe me?
Seriously, yes.
Can't you see us together?
I mean, I think we make a great couple.
- I lost her.
- Well, go up to her apartment.
Clear it out.
Anything that might connect us.
/- One number at the Public Safety
/Communication Centre.
/All 911 operators are currently
/handling calls. Please...
Now we've all got debts to pay.
I'm sorry, Kassie.
Do it.
- Yeah?
- "Hey, Eddie".
You still awake? I thought you cripples
went to bed early.
I hope you believe
in a forgiving God.
- It's time for redemption of sin.
- Where's Kassie?
She wanted to spend some time
with her parents.
I'd hobble on down there if I were you.
Right now.
Kassie!
You did a great job getting her here
alive. She was in respiratory arrest.
- How is she now, doc?
- She's breathing on her own again.
If it wasn't for her tolerance
she would have died instantly.
- What are her chances?
- Of survival, excellent.
But she is still in a coma.
It's too early for MRI scans.
We won't know if there's residual
neurological deficit...
...until she regains consciousness.
- Was she abused?
I'd like a minute alone with my sister.
Hello, Bella.
Mr. Burns?
- Yeah?
- How is she, Eddie?
- Alive.
- "Well, there's always next time."
- What do you want?
- Well, I got what I want, cripple.
- I got you shitting blood.
- Cut to the chase.
/You sinned, Eddie.
And you're gonna pay.
In this world and the next.
I'm gonna take you on a slow waltz
through hell.
When you wanna dance,
you let me know.
Otherwise, stop wasting my time.
Someone wants to hear
me scream, Cal.
Who?
I don't know.
I want a guard on Kassie's room.
Check the files, find out who's got
the motive, patience, imagination.
- You run that plate?
- Bella Schuman.
I got people checking her apartment.
- Where you going?
- Home. No guards, no surveillance.
- I want him to come to me.
- Eddie.
This isn't your job anymore.
I just made it my job.
You don't wanna help...
...stay out of my way.
- Yeah?
- Two thumbs up, Eddie?
Or maybe in your case
I should say one.
You enjoy the show?
I've seen worse.
Have you?
See, that's the difference
between you and me, kingfish.
Whatever you've seen...
...I've seen worse.
/And whatever you've done...
/... I've done worse.
And what's keeping me warm inside
is knowing that whatever I did to you...
...I hurt you real bad.
Listen to me, half-man.
You want me? Good.
You bring all the muscle you can get.
/But take my advice.
I won't be reading anyone their rights.
And I won't be taking prisoners.
That's some heavy shit, Ed.
Damn, man, this shit
is beyond pale, Ed.
Man, who is she?
My sister.
Oh, Jesus, Eddie.
This is cut so we're only meant
to see Kassie's face...
...not the animals in there with her.
- That's right, I don't see them.
Fast-forward.
There. They missed one.
Let's just see who you are,
motherfucker.
Hey, hold up.
Wait a minute.
Yeah, there's somebody else here.
Can't see his face, but...
Here you go.
Hey, Ed, man.
You need some help, I know some
people that'll do these motherfuckers.
Gratis.
I'm gonna take care of them.
- Thanks, brother.
- Hey, no problem.
I saw tats like this in the '80s
in Bangkok.
These symbols are a lucky charm.
Face looks Thai too.
- Smack peddlers?
- I don't know.
I'll try to get these ID'd.
- Captain.
- Eddie.
Cal called me at home last night.
I'm sorry.
- How is she?
- Still unconscious.
Targeting a former officer is unusual.
In fact, it's almost unknown.
Whoever did this knows we'll throw
everything we've got at them.
Intelligent psychopath with brass balls.
It won't matter once I've got
my hand on them.
We'll bring these animals in, Eddie.
I'll put every other case on
the back burner until we do.
But hear me now.
I'll say this only once.
You're not a cop.
Not anymore.
You have no authority
from this department.
There's another side of that coin,
captain.
This department has
no authority over me.
How many men would it take
to get him in a cell?
I figure no more than five or six,
if you include me and you.
Hell, let's call it protective custody.
When you took the cat-bird seat,
captain...
...there were a lot of people here who
wanted to see you fall and fall hard.
There was one man you could trust
who stood by your side.
That doesn't mean I can
let you break the law.
- I wasn't asking your permission.
- You didn't ask last time either.
Well, then...
...that makes us even.
- Lf anything breaks, you'll know first.
- Thanks.
And, Eddie, thanks for keeping my poor
old ass perched on the cat-bird seat.
You're welcome.
Only a son of a bitch would want it.
So where's our friend, Mr. Lakorn?
At his motel. Too much whiskey
last night. Head sick.
No, they'd be disappointed.
Vincent and I thought you should
make more each day...
...so we laid on another adventure.
Thorazine. She'll be out
for a couple of more hours.
Vincent will recommend
somewhere really quiet.
You see, Leo...
...there are places in this state that
could be on the dark side of the moon.
We'd very much prefer it
if she didn't come back.
Jesus Christ, what the fuck?
Don't tell me I fucked you,
too, last night.
You should be so lucky, Conrad.
Those sheets cost me 300 bucks, man.
Cressida's hair-dressing bill
is gonna break me.
Oh, jeez.
I haven't even had my morning fatty.
You don't mind if I skin one up,
do you, Eddie?
- Help yourself.
- I can't think straight when I'm straight.
There we go.
You disappoint me, Conrad.
I thought you were a pitcher.
Age does terrible things to the libido.
A man's gotta seek new horizons.
I thought they'd farmed you out. I know
guys who celebrated for two weeks.
What's the beef?
- Burns.
- Yeah, we lucked out with the photo.
Face works for the
Thai Trade Delegation in L.A.
Name of Lakorn.
/U.S. Customs had an eye on him.
/Suspected smuggling scam.
/Never found out what.
Now, get this: He's got
diplomatic immunity.
- Where's he staying?
- At the Triple- X Motel.
I'll be there in 30. And wait for me.
I'm looking for people
who abducted and raped a girl.
- Her name is Kassie.
- Who is she?
She's... A dope addict.
Eddie, smack ain't for me
these days. Or crack.
I put all that shit behind me, I swear.
Just grass now.
Okay, maybe a little coke.
I'm Mr. Clean, man. I'm Mr. Happy.
I just want everybody to have fun.
- Know what I'm saying?
- Okay, Mr. Happy.
Check out the dealers,
jugglers and thoroughbreds.
Especially any with Thai connections.
- I wanna know who was supplying her.
- Eddie, that's not my scene, man.
That's not my scene at all.
Those guys are pure fucking poison. L...
I'll see what I can do, okay?
- Can I keep this?
- Yeah.
I also want a line on a New Yorker,
Bella Schuman.
Thirties, black hair about so long,
good-looking, wears leather.
That's it?
This is Reno, not Waco.
- Half the waitresses look like that.
- So get dressed and get to work.
Eddie, you ever tried taking
common courtesy for a spin?
Maybe you knock on the door
instead of breaking in?
Maybe a tap on the shoulder instead
of the Bloody Mary wake- up call?
Just little politesse, man.
You know what I'm saying?
Please, Conrad...
...get the fuck to work.
Kind of.
Brody.
- Yeah, we need to talk, lieutenant.
- Who the fuck is "we?
About your service days in Bangkok.
/In the 80s?
/You remember, don't you, Cal?
R&R in Patpong Row.
- You're the cocksucker working Eddie.
- I hear you got two little daughters.
It must be hard for a man
like you to resist.
- Who is this?
- Now, speaking of cocksuckers...
...I'm looking at a picture
of a 12-year-old girl...
...with a U.S. Government-issue hard-on
in her mouth.
Gee, lieutenant, I wonder
if it could be yours?
Sammy's Lounge, 15 minutes,
or I e-mail a high-res JPEG...
...of this Hallmark moment...
...to your wife, your kids' school
and the entire Reno police.
Captain.
You look as if you just swallowed
a large poisonous insect.
Yes, sir.
That's what enables me
to work 17-hour days.
- I eat them instead of donuts.
- The time I protected Eddie...
...kept Internal Affairs and the DA
off his back, it's been on my mind.
- Sir?
- Eddie's last case before retiring.
The boy who hung himself in his cell.
Kraken, Marty Kraken.
Yeah, cop-killer.
You and Eddie made the collar
together.
You figure there's a connection
to Kassie?
Kraken was a low-life,
a punk, a nobody.
As far as we could tell,
he wasn't connected to anyone.
No family, no Mob ties.
Whoever's leaning on Eddie
is hardcore.
What did Eddie do to the Kraken kid?
That kid blew Tommy Mullen away
with a 12-gauge shotgun.
A lot of guys would've shot the punk
and claimed a citation for valour.
We made him shit in his pants,
so what?
We told him how many blowjobs he'd
be giving at Lovelock, so what?
If Eddie laid one horrible beating
on him that night, so what?
What's a cop-killer suicide got to do
with finding the psychos out there?
Maybe you should lay off
those insects, Cal.
Yeah, well, I need to be somewhere.
We live with the dregs, lieutenant.
We talk to them, we touch them.
We smell what they ate for dinner.
We see how they squandered
the lives God gave them.
And if we become contaminated,
we squander our lives too.
The rules that we follow, the rules
I insist we follow, protect us.
You and me and Eddie.
Not them.
That's the "so what."
And if you're already contaminated?
If you've got something to tell me, Cal,
there's no better time than right now.
I got a lead on the Thais.
I told Eddie he could come
along with me.
Just remember who's the one
with the badge.
What do you want?
You want trouble?
I saw a photo of you this morning.
You were laughing.
That's my sister.
Yeah.
Let me hear you laugh now.
Come on!
Let me hear you laugh.
Let me hear you laugh!
Come on, big man, laughing boy!
You have fun?
You take turns making her scream?
The guy with the tattoo.
The tattoo, his name.
- Thamaree.
- What?
- Where's he staying?
The El Royale Motel.
Who's the guy who set this up,
the American?
The man who set this up, who is he?
I have diplomatic immunity.
I'm trying to be diplomatic.
Police. I'm looking for Mr. Thamaree.
Did you realize, Vincent,
that but for our vigilance...
...copies of that photo would be
circulating right now on the Web?
Friends in need, Charlie.
Friends indeed.
There are 500,000 paedophiles
in North America...
...they consume 85 percent
of the world's kiddie porn.
Imagine what it must feel like
having that many scumbags...
...jerking themselves off
over your image.
I don't have to listen to this shit.
You're sick.
Sick?
I'm sorry, lieutenant, do you know
what she has in her mouth...
...and who it belongs to?
- Listen, asshole...
...I was 22 years old, I got shitfaced
on Mekong whisky and Thai stick.
Fucked a teenage hooker.
If I wanted, I could do the same thing
down the street.
But it was a one- off and when
I woke up I threw my guts up.
We understand, Cal. You know,
we're not judging you, but...
...other people...
- Others.
- Captain Oakes.
- Your lovely wife.
Eddie Burns.
What did Eddie do to you?
Eddie has sinned.
God may plan to punish Eddie
in the next world...
...but I intend to punish him
in this one.
And you're gonna help me.
I'll help you. I'll help you scrape
your brains off the wall.
In all those e- mails of your
private parts and it's...
It's just as well you carry
such a big handgun...
...because I couldn't use you in my
pictures. They're set to fly in an hour.
If you run, you can make the airport.
Who are you?
I'm a man offering you a chance
to redeem yourself.
You do want to redeem yourself?
Don't you?
By the way...
...you remember a kid
called Marty Kraken...
...that hung himself with a sheet...
...in one of your cells?
You remember him?
Marty was my brother.
Vincent here will tell you what to do.
It's Tommy Mullen. Shotgun.
Eddie, wait for backup!
Eddie, that's enough!
Cop-killer!
Cal, watch out!
Eddie!
Thamaree!
Bella, it's Eddie Burns.
- Can he understand me?
- I don't think so.
Do exactly as I say.
Count off 10 seconds,
turn to the back door...
...and shout my name like I'm there.
Thamaree! Thamaree!
Eddie!
I wanted to keep this one alive
for a while.
Guess you're gonna have
to tell me who I'm looking for.
You got things to tell me?
Have you any idea what
they were gonna do to me?
Yes, I do.
Have you?
Don't you get tired of being so tough?
Don't you ever take a break?
Those scum are your friends,
baby, not mine.
I have been drugged, kidnapped
and driven through the desert...
...in a trunk of a fucking rental car...
...and forced to watch you shoot two
men, which I am willing to forgive.
But I will not have you call me "baby."
Is that clear?
Here.
There's more in the cooler
if you need it.
- Conrad?
- "Eduardo, my boy!"
This Kassie chick was seen leaving
a club early hours yesterday morning...
...with a dealer named Grady White.
- "Where is he?"
On a life- support machine in Washoe
County Hospital, brain-dead on arrival.
My guess is the guys you want
gave him the bad haircut.
Well, thanks anyway.
Politesse, man, politesse.
Well done, well done.
Say, Bella Schuman, that's two you
owe me for, she directs B-grade porn.
/Two chicks lick each other out then
/find a basketball team in the closet.
- Who for?
- For the likes of us, I guess.
The film company, Conrad.
The producers.
It seems she was an avant-garde
filmmaker in New York City...
/...but we don't know who she directs...
- Find out.
Eddie, I have done
my good deed for the day.
I'm swamped here.
I gotta get back to work.
I'd forgotten something
could be so beautiful.
Yeah, it must be a nice change from
filming gangbangs in cheap motels.
I made my deal with
this messed- up world.
I never broke the law or hurt anyone.
- You mean anyone like Kassie?
- Do you think I'm responsible?
- You ran out on me.
- I didn't want to get killed.
So why'd you try to help her?
I know what it's like to be a piece
of meat in a pack of dogs.
- Who tried to kill my sister?
- I won't tell you.
- I figured you for guts, Bella.
- Well, figure me for brains too.
You didn't see what they did to Kassie.
Who are they?
I film gangbangs, Eddie.
Goods don't come any
more soiled than me.
The lawyers would take me apart,
if they didn't whack me first.
- There won't be a trial.
- I'm going to New Jersey.
- I can't help you.
- You wanna talk some more...
...about beauty first?
- Out of my way.
- You don't get off so easy.
- Get your hands off me.
- What?
- I kept Kassie alive.
Where were you when she needed you?
I want his name!
I want a name!
- Go to hell!
- His name!
- Fuck you!
His name, his name!
No!
Why not?
Because this is wrong!
Because you don't scare me.
Because I know you're not like them.
They're Kassie's.
That bother you?
- Yeah?
- The guy we want's a scumbag.
Makes porno films.
Name of Charlie Strom.
/I've never heard of him either. He's got
/a hard-on to make you scream.
Wants to see you tonight,
just you and him.
Sounds like he's been watching
too many Westerns.
Yeah, I hear you.
But listen: Legally, Strom's clean.
If you want to nail him,
this is the only way.
Be at Jansen's Gas and General
at 9: 15. You'll be contacted there.
/9:15, got it.
- Did you tell the captain?
- No.
- Thanks, partner.
- Hey.
Just let me know where
to find the bodies.
You should work for us full-time,
lieutenant.
- Keep him here till 11:00.
- You got it.
And why don't you buy
yourself another.
It's Eddie, Kassie.
You're safe.
You're safe now.
He kept calling me.
He bought me flowers, Charlie did.
He told me it was just coke.
Just one line, just one
little line, that's all.
- I knew you'd hate me.
- That's not true.
No, I knew, I knew.
In my head...
...I knew what it was.
It was this cradle...
...rocking me to sleep.
And it made everything okay again.
Mama.
Papa.
Everything.
- I tried to run away, but I couldn't...
- Listen to me, Kassie.
And believe me...
...I don't care what you've done...
...or who you did it with.
I only care that you're safe...
...and that you get well.
I love you.
I'll always love you...
...no matter what you do
or where you go, I'll love you.
They hurt me.
I know.
They won't hurt you again.
They'll never hurt you again.
I promise.
There's no one in the store.
It's only me. Can I help?
I'm meeting a friend.
Out here?
I'm an outdoors type.
It's a dying breed.
You want some coffee while you wait?
Sure, why not?
Thanks.
You know, I'm tired.
- I'm so fucking tired.
- I know what you mean.
You know, you work all your life
to get where you wanna get...
...and like that...
...it's gone.
You look back through
the photo album.
That kid who was you...
...on the football team, he's gone.
The girl you took to Mexico
who you swore you'd love forever...
...she's gone.
The friends who said they'd stick
by you till the end.
The wife...
...and the kids she took away.
Bank loan, business...
...house on the hill, gone.
Castles made of sand, man,
that's all we fucking build.
Castles made of sand.
We're in the right place for that.
And what's your story?
No choice...
...no prospects...
...no future.
The past I try to forget about
except when I'm drunk.
Why would you want to forget it?
One day you turn around
and you realize...
...you're only the man you are...
...and not the man you wanted to be.
And what man was that?
It was so long ago
it's hard to remember.
It had something to do
with working the land...
...raising a family...
...having people smile at you
when you walked into a room.
But I came to a fork in the road...
...and made the wrong turn.
It doesn't look like
I'll have time to go back.
It's never too late to change.
Only if you include being dead.
No, that's the one thing
we can count on.
Yeah, sometimes that
thought is a comfort.
You're Burns, right?
St. Francis Xavier Church,
10:00, come alone.
Thanks for the coffee.
It was nice talking with you.
- Yeah?
- Cal.
St. Francis Xavier Church, 10:00.
- You sure you don't want backup?
- No, brother, stay at home.
I'm Eddie Burns.
I come to dance with Charlie Strom.
I'm Charlie Strom.
Motherfucker!
Hold him! Hold him up!
I...
...am Charlie Strom.
Go!
You still don't know what this is about,
do you, Eddie?
You still don't know who I am.
Cal sends his apologies.
Deep breath, Eddie.
You've seen the trailer, Eddie.
Now here's the director's cut.
/You fucked up my life.
/You killed everything
/that ever mattered.
/I want you to die,
/do you understand me?
/I want you to die.
You're not drinking?
I've had enough. You drinking?
Yeah, why not?
You mother...
/Stop it, please! Please, stop!
She was tight, Eddie.
Now, that's how come
she screamed so much.
How we laughed.
Oh, how we laughed.
Vincent?
Do it.
You want to know why, don't you?
Even though you're too fucking
stubborn to ask.
No, that would be too easy.
I'll tell you why.
In hell.
Eddie.
I told you not to come, Cal.
Eddie...
...it was us, man.
It was us.
What do you mean?
You and me, man, it was us.
Who is Strom?
Cal?
I'm sorry.
/Bella, Strom got away.
I need you.
All right. Let me get my motherfucking
money and get the hell...
Shit.
What's up, man?
About the church...
Kneel.
Just keep out of my fucking skull.
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone, Marty.
Marty's dead.
He's dead.
Get out of my fucking skull.
Leave me alone.
Out.
Welcome to the funhouse.
No, that would be too easy.
You tried to kill Kassie.
Yeah, that's right.
I tortured her.
And I shot her full of H.
Do you know how l...?
Do you know how long I've waited?
Do you know how long it took me?
You've been screaming
for your bitch sister...
...for 24 hours.
I've been screaming for fucking years!
You want to know my real name,
Eddie Burns?
It's Kraken. Charlie Kraken.
And my...
My little kid brother?
His name was Marty.
Coming back to you?
Now, Marty was a good kid.
He weren't too bright...
...but he was good. He was decent.
You had him...
You had him so scared he couldn't
even remember his own fucking name!
- Marty was a cop-killer.
- Marty, he never hurt anybody.
- His prints were on the murder weapon.
- So were mine!
Charlie!
Charlie, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Marty, get out of my fucking way!
Get out of my fucking way!
Charlie!
Freeze! Drop the weapon!
Oh, you like killing cops?
Eddie, stop!
Eddie, that's enough!
Cop-killer!
So you see, Eddie...
...I'm your cop-killer.
I shot a crooked cop.
You drove an innocent kid...
...to suicide.
Did you...?
Did you help?
Cutting him down?
You help untie the sheet
from around his fucking neck?
Don't you get it, cripple?
Don't you get the fucking picture?!
Perfectly.
You let your little brother
take the rap for you.
But I don't think you see
the picture clearly.
Marty didn't tie that sheet
around his neck because he wanted to.
I was there.
I made him do it.
I watched him die, Charlie.
And I laughed while he pissed in his
dirty little drawers like a bitch.
Oh, how I laughed, Charlie.
See, that's the difference
between you and I.
You have a conscience.
That's your sin...
...not mine.
I forgot to load the weapon.
Eddie, we've got it. Eddie!
Eddie! We don't need this.
Kid, Marty, was innocent.
I know.
- Killed an innocent man.
- Eddie, now is not the time.
Bella, go!
Breathe out.
Come on.
Apply pressure.
Okay. I'll be okay. Go.
Strom!
Bye, Eddie.
Fuck!
Here we are, brother.
Down in hell.
Up to our necks in shit.
We worked for this all our lives.
We deserve it.
But Marty didn't.
Clear his name...
...for both of us.
Pull.
Forget it.
Make it easy on me.
Say after me:
/Death be not proud
Say it to me.
/Though some have called thee
/Mighty and dreadful
/For thou art not so
Captain.
- What should I do with this?
- Put me on trial.
Read it, Eddie.
You brought down smack dealers
and pornographers.
If you ran for the governor of Nevada,
you'd probably win. You're a hero.
- And Cal Brody?
- Cal's a hero. Died in the line of duty.
Marty was innocent.
You should've considered
that before you killed him.
I'm going to clear his name, captain.
Do what you have to, but the only
thing I plan on clearing is my desk.
What about your rules? Honesty,
integrity, playing it by the book?
The rules are for me and my men,
they're for cops.
I told you this when you started.
You're not a cop, not anymore.
I'm guilty as sin, captain.
Then live with it.
Case closed.