How are you?
Are you okay?
So I… I took the test.
- Good morning.
- Morning!
Yes?
- Er, madam is expecting me.
- Really? What is your name?
Sista.
- Sista what?
- Just say "Sista," the cleaner.
Okay.
- Morning.
- Welcome, ma'am.
My madam is not around.
But she said I should
give you the house key.
- What did she say?
- She said I should give you the key.
So am I supposed to just go in to clean
and nobody will be there to watch me?
She said you should call her
when you get here.
So maybe she will tell you
what to do when you call her.
- Really?
- Yes ma'am.
Hello, ma.
- Ah Sista, you are in my house?
- Yes.
Then uh.. they say you say that
I should just enter
the house like that and start cleaning.
That nobody will watch me.
I say, "Ah, no."
Dabike and Mrs. Fisher
spoke glowingly about you
so I absolutely trust you.
Madam, no.
What of inventorying?
You know I'm not used
to just going to people's houses, clean,
then when I leave they tell me,
"Oh, something is now missing."
You know I don't do it.
Even at that, I will never accuse you.
Ma, is there camera?
- Why? Why do you ask?
- So that something is seeing me.
Sista, don't worry. There is nothing
to even steal in the house.
Just go in and do what you have to do.
Okay, ma. Will you come
back before I will finish?
- Yes. I will. I will be back.
- Good.
Just tell my security to give you
the key, and make sure you eat something.
- There's food in the fridge.
- Okay, ma.
Okay.
- She say you should give me the key.
- Okay.
So what are you going to do about it?
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Your WAEC is in a few weeks
and I'm leaving for school next week.
My sister… she knows.
She said she's coming to see
your mum at the shop tomorrow.
Ah!
I don't know what to do.
- Yeah, who's that?
- Open, open, open!
Erm, please tell Nonso
to go to the vulcanizer
- at the junction and pick up my car.
- Yes, ma.
- You're still here?
- Yes. Welcome, ma.
- Why? You didn't get my alert?
- I got the alert, ma.
I'm inventorying.
Sista, you need to leave all that, please.
I'm really pressed.
- I need to use the restroom.
- I will wait, ma.
- You can go.
- I will wait, ma. I will wait.
Inventorying, inventorying, inventorying.
I will wait. I'll wait.
- How was lesson?
- It was fine, ma.
Yes. Right.
- Mummy, guess what happened today?
- What happened?
Hmm. Risi's mummy
came to look for her today.
Apparently, Risi has been lying to her
mum that she has been coming for lesson.
I was just shocked.
- Look…
- Anu.
- Ma?
- Remember the daughter of whom you are!
Especially now that
you're going to the university.
Don't do these kind
of things. Don't do anything
that will make me sorrow over you.
Hmm! It is four eyes that born a child.
- But now it is only two eyes that...
- Eyes that is nurturing. Argh!
Be calming down!
This is why I don't like to give you gist.
Small gist I gave you,
you've turned it into a lecture.
I wish, above all things,
- that you shall prosper.
- Yes!
Have I given you reason to doubt it?
- Still...
- Oh Mummy, come on!
- Who?
- Your son!
Anu, go and open the door for him.
Wow, really?
No problem?
- We're on strike.
- Again?
I'm tired of that school.
Any small conflict, a strike starts.
Anu, go look for something for him to eat.
But you could have waited
till tomorrow morning before coming.
You should have waited till morning.
How long is this strike for now?
Hopefully not too long. But…
at least we will spend time together.
Did you wear a belt?
Three days.
Anu. Anu said I should tell you
that she has started the small chops.
Really?
She said that you should send a sample.
Yes.
He even showed up yesterday.
He said that UNILAG
has sent them back due to a strike.
Oh okay, ma.
Okay. See you. Thank you.
- Mummy, good morning.
- Good morning.
Have you swept?
Have you swept the compound?
Yes, ma.
- You have swept the compound?
- Yes, ma.
After taking your bath,
go and buy something…
something we can cook for soup.
Because this evening,
maybe I won't come back.
That my customer, the one in Ikoyi…
The one with the baby, she has come back.
She has brought her baby back.
- So I'm going there for three days.
- Mummy, I want to follow you.
- Hmm?
- To go and do wetin?
Sista. "What," not "wetin."
Okay. To go and do what?
To go and enjoy AC.
When you have money,
you will buy AC for us.
For now, go and be watching television.
Alright, alright. Go on with you!
I want to read the book
of Proverbs in the bible.
- So…
- Ah, no "so"!
- There's nothing like "so."
- What is the decision?
Eh she can't stay with me.
She should just follow her husband.
They should start living
as a couple and that's all.
- Neither can she stay here.
- Indeed!
Look, it's not possible.
Fola, it cannot work.
Since you decided to taste
what married people are eating…
What's left? You should
go and live together as man and wife.
But it cannot happen under my roof.
- No way. No.
- Mummy, please…
Fola, so you knew
that but went ahead and slept with her!
Don't provoke me! Eh?
You are now saying, "Mummy, please."
- You see? Tell them.
- Right?
- You know how we are.
- Of course.
What I gathered from my meager earnings
that I managed and I suffered
to send you to school…
you then went and got someone pregnant?
Is this my reward? Eh, Fola?
Do I deserve this?
- Mummy, please.
- Shut your mouth!
Which Mummy are you asking "Please"? Argh!
Victoria!
He did all sort of things
to your body while enjoying himself.
My sister will be rolling in her grave!
- Uncle, please. Please, sir.
- Erm…
- Fola?
- Sir.
Victoria… You both have heard your mums.
- Please, sir.
- The ball now is in your court.
- Ah, it's not, sir.
- Both of you need to make a decision.
- Uncle.
- Hmm?
Why are you talking like this?
- They've already made the decision.
- That's right!
They've chosen the right path
that they prefer.
Don't let us waste our time on them.
Fola.
Since you believe in yourself
that you are man enough
to become a father,
I cannot be feeding you,
feeding your wife and this unborn child.
- That's not possible.
- Come on! Do you want to kill me?
I have your siblings
that I want to take care of.
So let me take care of them.
Don't kill me, okay?
- If I stopped school now…
- I'm not asking you to stop school now.
Then what about you?
Eh, after this exam we will have a break.
I can use that break to look for work.
Who would give you work
in your pregnant condition?
- Where will you live?
- Can't I live with you?
Live with me, how?
Didn't you hear what my mother said?
Oh, I'm not staying in your house.
You said you live off campus, right?
I can live with you there.
How will you feed?
I can barely fend for myself.
Isn't it at school?
There'll be plenty students in school and
I'm sure there will be different types
of businesses I can do in school.
I'll… work on that.
- Wow, Super Noodles Maker!
- Leave me alone.
Everyone is talking about your noodles.
Me, I'm just happy.
At least by Saturday
we can get new baby stuff.
- Wow.
- I saved up some money already.
- The baby is due anytime soon.
- Hmm.
- So this one is for the House Seven boys.
- Right.
Quadri and his friends asked me
to make saari food for them.
I'll make it, but you have
to help me deliver by five a.m.
No problem.
Erm, let me go with this one then
I'll tell Victor to come and pick me.
Thank you. Thank you for everything.
Petrol.
Don't turn it on by…
in fact, eight thirty.
Don't turn it on before eight thirty p.m.
I know there won't be light,
but eight thirty. There it is.
Ah-ah.
- Leave the way for me please!
- Mummy, you are not going anywhere.
Fola, tell her.
Really?
If not that I have these
many mouths to feed, you think
I will go to work everyday like this?
- "Ee rees wharree rees." Alright.
- Sista, you say, "It is what it is."
It is… what it is.
- Mummy, "it is what it is."
- Oh, idea is need, you these children.
I need to go to work.
Come on, leave the way.
- Let's follow you. Let me follow you.
- To where?
This one is an office.
But I want to help.
And Fola can help too. Fola, tell her.
Yes, Mummy. You are tired. And remember we
still had to rub your body the other day.
If you don't go for this one,
will the earth stop?
Really? Will it stop?
All these payments of this,
payments for that. Won't it stop?
Right.
I have to go to work. I know
you children are trying to help.
But this is new customer is an office, eh?
If anything goes missing there,
how will I buy it?
Stay at home. Let me go and work the work.
All this stress I'm going through
is for you children to have a better life.
And to have all
these things that I did not have.
And I am praying for both of you,
that you will succeed.
And then, save me out
of this trouble I'm going through. Right?
You think I don't want the good life?
Rolling my buttocks on a ship?
- Or a motorboat?
- You better not do it in a thong!
- What is thong?
- G-string.
Ah! Catapult? No.
Lace. You'll buy me lace. Two of you.
I'll be dancing like this.
I hope that with these few points of mine,
I have been able to convince
and not confuse you that…
I need to go to work
for the betterment of all. Did I get it?
Now, move or I move you.
Oh, these children!
Come on, come on. I have to leave now.
- I love you so much, Mummy.
- I love you too, hmm?
I love you.
Argh! Allow me go to work. Don't forget…
Don't put it on until eight thirty,
in fact nine thirty.
- Okay, Mummy. Bye.
- Okay, bye-bye.
Rolling your buttocks…
Wow, Auntie Jay?
- I hope there's no problem?
- Erm…
- Ah. Hope no problem?
- No problem.
Um, Mrs. Uzo…
Erm, actually, she accused you…
No, she insisted that we
- come here that there's...
- Um, so
my set of gold is missing. A whole set.
And seeing that you were the last
person to my home before I traveled,
we need to search your house.
Ahn-ahn. Aunty Jay, I don't understand
what she is saying?
She insisted that um, we come here
- so that she can check…
- Why is she accusing me?
No, she's not accusing… ahn-ahn.
No, she's not
accusing you, I swear by Allah.
I've told her that I trust you.
I told her that I trust you so we should
come so that she will see for herself...
I don't have all day.
- Guys. Nonso, come check here.
- Wait! Wait.
- My children are inside. Just wait for me.
- I don't understand.
So you will go
and have them hide my stuff?
Come on, Mrs. Uzo!
- Oh please.
- Mrs. Uzo, I beg you in God's Name,
Stop doing that. Be easy here.
In my 11 years of doing this job,
nobody has ever accused me of stealing!
Nobody!
No problem.
Hmm, Anu! Fola! Come outside!
- What's happening?
- She said I stole her gold.
- Ma'am, I think...
- Hey Fola! Come. Come here.
This is part of the stigma
experienced in this job. Just come here.
Alright, go in.
You can go search everywhere.
- Ifeanyi, quickly.
- Search the house everywhere, no problem.
Please search everywhere.
All the nooks and crannies.
You, Aunty? In my house?
Ah, no problem, Aunty Jay.
There's no problem.
Um, come. Ifeanyi.
Nonso!
Let's go Come. Let's leave here.
Go? You are not searching again?
Erm, I just found out who took it.
Huh?
What did just say?
- Erm, Sista, I am so sorry, I...
- Aunty…
- Please go.
- Oh my God.
- Sista, I will give them money...
- Madam I say, come and go!
Aunty Jay…
You are back. How did it go?
I'm pregnant.
Ah-ah?
How, how come?
What do you mean, how come?
I don't mean it that way.
So what do you mean?
I have been pulling out, have I not been?
So, who says pulling out
means 100 percent guarantee?
Vicky, I've been pulling out.
This pregnancy cannot be mine.
I don't understand.
Maybe you should go and help me
to do erm, a newspaper advert or…
yes, a publication.
To know who the real owner is.
Because I don't understand.
What do you want me to say? Huh? What?
What do I want you to say?
To say that everything will be okay.
And that everything will be fine.
You don't have to deny the baby.
Ah! That's a very
big insult on my character.
That is a very, very big
insult on my character, Fola!
Sorry, okay? Sorry.
- Sorry for yourself.
- But I don't need this now.
We don't need this now.
I have a professional
exam I'm preparing for.
I go for service in one month. A baby
doesn't fit into this picture at all.
We already have one
that we're struggling to take...
No, no, no. Fola, wait.
You mean that I, Fola,
that I am struggling to take care of.
Feeding you, the baby and me.
- Paying for your school fees.
- Wait, wait!
So I've not been doing anything?
I've not been doing anything, right?
So I'm useless now?
Eh? I don't help you? Don't I help you?
Don't I clean the baby's bum when he poos?
Even in the night
when he cannot sleep, I help you!
I do something in this house!
Don't tell me that I don't do anything.
Don't say that!
Alright, sorry. I am sorry, eh?
Sorry, don't be angry.
See, I don't want us to fight.
Tomorrow, I'll go and see
the doctor and I'll do… maybe an abortion.
And, we will see how it is.
I think I'm 16 weeks pregnant.
I can still…
- I'll have to abort it.
- Sixteen weeks?
You've been 16 weeks pregnant
and I didn't know?
Fola, I've not seen
my period since I had Junior.
Where did you keep it?
Oh God!
Vicky, why? Why?
Shit, shit, shit!
Which one is all this
"shit, shit" you are saying?
I said tomorrow, I'll go and see Doctor.
Sixteen weeks… they should be able
to remove it. What's all the "shit"?
I said I do abortion,
you're saying "shit, shit." Ah!
Look, that's all I can say.
I will see you later.
- I can't do more than this.
- What?
- Am I happy being pregnant?
- At every little touch, you get pregnant.
She doesn't listen.
She just does not listen.
How do you live your life
just to please a man?
There is more to a woman
than just pleasing a man.
Hmm, true.
- Truth, Aunty Jay.
- Mm-hmm.
But this thing… Hmm.
It's not straight like that.
Anyway…
You miss him, right?
Who?
Ah-ah? You late husband, of course.
How many years has it been now?
I stopped keeping track
when it was ten years.
So you mean that none of
your in-laws came to look for you?
It's better this way, Aunty Jay.
It's better this way.
- Hmm, Aunty Jay.
- What is it?
This man. This your lover…
When are you going to…
When are you going to let him marry you?
If you are a bit
submissive, he will put a ring on it.
Me I should "put body for ground"?
Or he should put his body on the ground?
Or even, he should put
his head on the ground.
Because that is the problem.
The woman is putting her body…
All the time. What about the man?
If he put his head on the ground,
me I will put my head on the ground.
- Two of us we will marry. Until then…
- Aunty Jay!
I like your fire!
Aunty Jay, thank you for this food.
So it means today no more cleaning?
- Have we not finished talking about that?
- Aunty Jay!
- Let me hurry fast and start going home.
- Um, before you go…
There's something I need to give you.
- Again?
- Hmm.
- Ah-ah! Aunty Jay…
- Hmm?
Hope it's not from that erm, Mrs…
- Mrs. Uzo?
- Mrs. Uzo.
- It is not from her.
- Aunty Jay, I don't want problem.
Already, I have promised myself
that after what happened yesterday,
there is no business
joining you and her together again.
Did you see what happened yesterday?
What happened yesterday
can never repeat itself.
I did not like it at all.
Aunty Jay. And that day
when I was heading there,
I was double-minded about working there.
I even called her, so she can
take an inventory. She said no.
Not knowing
she had plans to put me in trouble.
That thing she did in front
of my children, Aunty Jay?
I'm sorry. Please.
Just forgive her and let it go.
I beg you in God's name.
I use God to beg you.
But should I tell you who was
the person who took the jewelry?
Who?
Hmm! You will not believe.
It was her husband.
Ah!
- Shocking!
- They said he has uh…
a gambling problem. So, he used her
gold, her full set to go and pay for it.
Oh! Now, I'm feeling sorry for her.
Ah, I forgive her. I forgive her.
Anu, so you take all these for school.
Ha! Sista, no.
This is you trying to say
you will not take me for shopping.
- Promise is a death.
- "Debt," ma.
"A promise is a debt."
Nobody is dying here, please.
So, it's the person
that will take you for shopping
that you are talking to like that?
- Thank you.
- Hmm.
- Mummy, I want to go back to school.
- Have you resumed?
English, ma.
- Have you resume?
- Has school resumed?
Argh, Fola, just answer.
No. But I got a tutoring offer for some
carryover students. And they're paying.
Fola?
Did you ask me for money and I say no?
No, but it's just that
this cleaning stress is too much.
And if I can make
some small money on the side,
maybe you'll stop working
on Sunday, at least.
So Sunday is the problem. I will stop.
Mummy, it's not that. It's not that.
I'm already an adult now.
And besides, you said you
and daddy had me around this age.
So why can't you allow me to help?
Fola, you see that school?
I want you to go there, focused like this.
No distraction.
I want you to focus.
This stress you are complaining about,
in two years' time now, you will forget.
Then you will face me. Me too,
I will now relax and be taken care of.
- What's making her laugh?
- Mummy, don't worry.
I promise.
I will work hard, and
I will spoil you with plenty money.
Don't spoil me.
You will repair me with money.
Fola, do we have a deal?
- Do we have a deal?
- Yes, Mummy.
Uh, who is that? Come in.
- Ta-da!
- Tiwa!
Tiwa!
Look at you! I cannot believe this.
Yeah, we came in a couple of weeks ago.
- A what?! A what?!
- Couple of weeks. Relax!
- Come on, Tiwa!
- We were in Abuja. FA had some work to do
So we had to stop by the office.
I couldn't get a phone number
because it's like,
you literally have to draw blood
- to get a phone number in Naija, honestly.
- Hmm.
- Hmm?!
- I'm serious! Come on.
- Nothing beats a good surprise though.
- Nothing beats a good surprise.
You know, I thought it was my client.
I was already working on her designs.
Although I could be your client.
- Cheers!
- Hmm. This is really good.
- It is, right?
Yeah. So, the kids are now
in boarding school in England.
And we're going
to be here for a year and a half.
Yes, to start the company's
Africa-side of things.
That is amazing!
- Um, so have you found anything yet?
- Er, the company got us some space,
but I really need your expertise.
I need you to do it up.
Look, I cannot wait to do it.
I hope you know
you are going to pay me in euros.
Because there's no way I am going
to collect naira currency from you.
Please don't just charge me
too much, I beg you by God.
- What did you say, "Danallah"?
- Oh stop!
I am guessing that you haven't had
anyone to speak Hausa with in ages.
- Nobody at all. Nobody.
- Ah, that is why. I can only imagine.
But for the space, we have to set up
an appointment so that I can see it.
And then we can know what we
are renovating, how you want it to look.
And then run ideas by you,
whatever it is that you want us to do.
- That's totally fine. Is tomorrow okay?
- Oh, tomorrow is perfect.
Make sure you text me the address and…
Ooh! The food is here!
- It is?
- It is.
- OMG!
- Thank you so much.
I promise you, Tiwa,
- you will love this ofada.
- Thank you.
- The sauce is amazing.
- I need to take a picture.
- Take a picture.
- Oh my gosh.
Did I offend you?
No.
So why are you not talking to me?
You didn't do anything.
I'm… I'm just nervous.
Nervous about what?
Is it about me?
Or the baby? Or Youth Corper?
Youth Service.
It's Youth Service, not Youth Corper.
Sorry.
So…
When are you coming back?
- After service.
- That's like one year, right?
At least, before they pay salary,
you will have something small to use
to fend for yourself.
No. You need this more than I do.
I'm okay. Me and the baby will be fine.
- I have shop.
- No.
- Ah-ah..
- Please just take it.
I'm sorry if I offended you.
Sister erm, my cousin's husband
just uh, he works in Amsterdam.
But they have like
a new branch of the office here.
Really?
- What of her?
- Hmm.
She is a full time housewife.
But I'm thinking, now that she said that
the children are in boarding school,
maybe, she might decide to get a job.
Having a job is good.
Look at you now, Aunty Jay.
Hmm, I don't have a husband.
Aunty Jay, have you
chased um, that brother away?
I did not chase him but
he has not asked me to marry him.
For a while now,
we've been doing "relationship."
- A good man will ask you.
- Amen. The right man has to come.
You hear me, all you right men out there?!
But Sista, there is
something I want to tell you.
Okay.
This house that we are going to,
you will clean it very well.
I know that you clean well
but you know this is a first time client.
So I want them to retain you.
So I want you to clean it very well
so that when they see it,
they will know that, "Ah!
This one, we are keeping her."
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Hello!
- Sista?
- Ah, Aunty Jay!
- I've finished!
- You have finished?
This extra one is just dusting.
Sorry I take long.
- It is okay. This is my cousin, Tiwatope.
- Good afternoon, ma.
- Nice to meet you. You did this yourself?
- Ah, yes. Yes.
When I clean people's house and
office, I don't use to take anybody.
I always go alone.
So that if something miss
or break, I can only know my own heart.
I can't know for the other person.
That's FA.
- Oh, he's coming?
- Yes, I asked him to come see the house.
- Oh, okay.
- Yes.
FA, my guy! Ah-ah, come on.
- Hello. It's good to see you again.
- Good to see you. How are you?
- Hello, darling.
- Oppress us.
- Erm Sista, this is my husband.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- FA, this is the cleaning lady.
- Good to meet you, madam.
- Yes, sir.
- Good to meet you.
So are you ready
to see what the house looks like?
Sure.
Alright baby, let's go.
Let's go check it out.
Sista, I hope you are well. Are you okay?
- Are you sure you're okay?
- Yes. Please help me do transfer.
Because after I finish
just mopping the step, I will be going.
No, just wait. I will drop you off.
- Let me just enter quickly.
- No, I'm going to market.
Oh okay, no problem.
But you know the phones
you said that I should help you get… ah.
- They are in the car.
- Am I owing you something?
So if you are owing me,
you think I'll collect the money from you?
Lord, thank you.
Ah! Fola has ruined me. Someone help me!
Fola.
I'm dead!
No. No, Fola! No!
Ah! Fola!
Ah! Yeh!
Oh my Defender!
Come in.
- Good morning, Mummy.
- Fola.
My mother.
My rock.
My everything.
Thank you for all you do for us.
- Mummy, is everything okay?
- It is fine.
Everything is fine, Fola.
Everything is fine.
I'm just thinking.
About what? About us?
You are also part
of what I'm thinking about.
Mummy, you know we try not to stress you.
- Are we putting you under any pressure?
- God forbids it.
God forbids it.
Sit down.
You are my children. You and Anu.
And it is you, the two of you,
that gives me the strength
and the power to smile.
You are not a problem to me.
Have you heard?
- Yes.
- Have you heard?
Yes.
But are you sure?
You know I'm your stand-in husband.
So you can always tell me
if anything is wrong?
Olu… Olufolarin. Olufolarin.
There is no problem.
- So you will talk to me?
- I will talk to you.
Anu is making custard and akara.
And we are watching Rofia Tailor Loran.
Sista will go now.
Sista will brush her teeth.
I will wash my teeth,
white, white, shining.
I will come and drink ogi
with you, and akara.
Have you heard, my dear?
I will come
and join you soon. I'll take the ogi.
Fola, you make me happy.
You and Anu, okay.
- I'm coming.
- Okay, Mum.
Hello, lya lyabo?
What happened?
Town council?
I'm in trouble! Hello?
Okay.
Hello, Aunty Jay.
Do you have something good for me?
Really, Sunday?
Oka… ah.
I promised Fola
that I will not work on Sunday again.
Ah, Anu small chop?
Are you sure, Aunty Jay?
- She is not much of an expert.
- Aunty, I am a pro. Don't mind Sista.
She wants to talk to you.
Hello, Aunty Jay.
Hi. Can I get a drink?
Oiza, this is really amazing, I swear.
Yeah, thank you…
- for the house. It's beautiful.
- It is, right?
I love to do amazing interiors
for houses that I am well paid for.
Judging by the dent in my bank account,
yes, you were well paid.
Thank you.
- Er, the cleaner…
- Hmm.
- How long has she worked with you for?
- Oh, Sista?
Hmm. Many years now.
And she's so good at what she does, right?
Why do you ask?
Oh, it seems
like she's a very hardworking person.
Oh, she's very hardworking, truly.
I'd like to know
if she can come clean the office.
Sista is a full definition of,
um, booked and busy.
But, I think I can help you talk to her.
And see if she can fit you
into her schedule.
Cool.
- Have you seen Tiwa around?
- Hmm…
- I think she is in the kitchen.
- Okay.
Angels bow before him
What a mighty God we serve
What a mighty…
Any problem, sir?
- I'm looking for the small chops lady.
- Oh, my daughter.
Ah-ah, she's in the parlor.
I left her outside, sir.
- Your daughter?
- Yes. Do you need anything, sir?
- No, no.
- My son, he will, he can do it.
- That's your son?
- Um, okay.
- What do you need, sir?
- It's just, um,
some new guests just arrived and I was…
I wanted them to be served so…
Ah, new guests. I'd do it, sir.
- I'll follow you now, sir.
- Okay.
So, basically just trying to manage
the whole work-life balance,
family, business and all.
Yeah, it's really important
- Thank you.
- Sir?
Thank you, Vicky.
- Yeah, enjoy.
- And you too.
What year did you say you are in again?
- Two hundred level, sir.
- Two hundred level?
You sound a lot more mature
than a 200-level student.
- I get it from my mom.
- Fola, go on. Go and help your sister.
Okay, Mom. Sorry excuse me, sir.
Totally ridiculous
but it was such a great one, Jems.
Hey, baby.
- FA, my guy.
- Hey.
- That was exactly what happened that day.
- Yeah.
We're just going to
make it work. My schedule…
Hey, um…
You should come visit me
sometime soon, okay? Here's my card.
Oh okay, thank you very much, sir.
I also enjoyed our conversation.
Fola, it is time. Ma'am, we have finished.
Ah. Thank you so much for today.
You have really amazing children.
They're very well behaved.
Thank you very much, ma.
Is Aunty Jay dropping us?
You see, Tiwa hasn't released me yet.
- I… I can drop you off.
- Our house is a very far, sir. Thank you.
Look, these two are still gossiping.
You better just let me drop you.
Erm, my daughter
already call taxi. Let's go.
Anu, head that way.
- Thank you, sir.
- Goodnight, sir.
Fola, come on.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight. Thank you so much.
- Aunty Jay, Jay, Jay!
- Goodnight, Sista.
- And the small chops was amazing!
- Goodnight, Aunty Jay.
Is it the office?
You've been pensive all week.
Did something happen at work?
- Can you forgive me?
- What for?
What have you done, my darling?
There's something I need to tell you.
Okay.
I made a mistake.
Who is she and how far gone?
No. No, I'm not cheating.
I cheated but not on you.
Someone else. I don't know how to fix it.
Who is it that you cheated on?
What are you talking about?
- What, who with? I don't know.
- Oh my God.
God forgive me.
Tiwa, I…
Tiwatope.
There is no better way to say this.
I umm…
I… I have… I had…
a family.
Folarin, I'm so… A family. I don't get it.
I was 19.
She was 17.
We had a baby.
Two and half years later, she had another.
She was pregnant again and…
I was just 21.
Just graduated. I…
It was too much. So…
So I left.
I left her and the kids.
Tiwa, say something.
Are you having a laugh?
Folarin. Oh my gosh, you're joking, right?
You're not joking?
- You have a wife and children?
- No. We were never married.
We dated as kids. She got pregnant.
We both got got kicked out of our homes.
So she moved into school with me.
While I was schooling,
she was trading to support us and…
- And…
- And err…
And you what? You abandoned them?
You left!
Left the mother
of your children. You left!
- A 19 year old woman.
- Tiwa, I…
I what? You what, Folarin?
Oh my God, this is a bit too much.
Wait, hold a second. So…
If you had a child, at 19,
- that child is probably 21 now.
- Almost 21. Just a few months.
Are you bleeping stupid?!
Is this supposed to be
some sort of age contest?
Oh. Hold on.
So that means when we met at camp,
you had just walked away from your family.
You had just walked away from
that woman and your children.
Who are you? What sort of man does that?
Tiwa, please.
Folarin!
Folarin no, no. This is a lie.
No.
- My life is a lie. You are a lie.
- No.
Me, you, us, everything is a lie, Folarin!
Tiwa, please...
Don't touch me! Don't touch me.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't touch me.
So why are you telling me this now?
Huh?
Why are you telling me this now?
It's the cleaner. Sista.
Her real name is Vicky.
Who?
- No way!
- Yes way, Jems!
Yes way. Yes, freaking way.
I don't understand.
I know she told me
that her husband is late.
- For like ten years plus now.
- What would you have her say?
Better dead than abandoned.
- Ah, Tiwa, I don't understand this.
- Neither do I.
How are you feeling?
I feel like I've been lied to.
Twelve years, and I married a stranger.
He abandoned his kids, Jems.
Like, he didn't look back. He didn't say
anything. He didn't talk about them.
He just boom! Like they never existed.
So, what does he want to do about it now?
What does he want to do
or what do I want to do?
What do you want to do?
He is going to have
a conversation with that woman
and he is going to try to make amends.
While we lived in the lap of luxury,
that woman was busy washing toilets to
provide a barely good life for her kids.
Actually she lives slightly above average.
Jems, you cant compare it to what we had.
Or what we have.
After he got that offer at Finland,
we've been touring Europe.
Our kids have attended
the best private schools.
But she was washing toilets.
Washing toilets.
- Actually, she was washing houses.
- Oh stop, Jems. You know what I mean.
Don't piss me off.
- Sorry.
- What if she was my sister.
I saw how she worked
tirelessly cleaning our home.
What if she knows?
Look, that is not the kind of conversation
- I want you to have.
- What do you mean?
I mean that, this is not the reaction
I am expecting from you.
- You are supposed to be angry.
- I'm angry. I'm livid!
Then why do you want him to…
To what? Take amends? To do right by her?
Jems. I am a secure woman.
And another lady, another girl,
another woman taking FA away from me
is the least of my worries.
He committed a grave offense
and I feel responsible.
- Responsible for what?
- Come on, Jems, for everything.
It has nothing to do with you.
It has everything
to do with me. I met FA at camp.
I made him accept the offer.
I first made him apply for it, and then
I insisted that he left with me.
But that is not your fault.
It was his decision to accept the offer.
It was his decision to abandon his family.
What you should be thinking now is,
what are you going to tell your children?
And what is she going
to tell her children?
Oh my God.
Maybe they already know. She saw him.
I don't think she knows.
She knows.
How are you so sure?
I called her by her name.
Vicky.
She looked at me. Deadpan.
And walked away.
So those are your kids?
Will you forgive me?
Forgiving you
is a different kettle of fish.
Will Vicky forgive you?
Please help.
Folarin Anuoluwa Abrahams.
You are a cold, soul-less man.
Aunty Jay, my children's father is dead.
- Sista.
- He is dead.
It's better this way.
Sista… I am a woman.
I totally understand
your plight right now.
I know how hurt you are.
Hurt? Hurt.
This man left me.
He left me eight months pregnant!
He didn't even tell me
anything the night before he left.
He wrote me an ordinary letter.
He wrote me an letter.
One letter.
Then he sent me text message.
Me. Me.
I left school
so that he can finish his education.
Yes. I left school so that
he can finish his education
Yes. Ah, Aunty Jay, I suffered!
I suffered!
After he left,
I was pregnant with Anu.
Then the State task force came to my shop,
broke everything, scattered everything,
including what I collected on credit.
University was on strike.
So I didn't have a job. No work.
No money, no food, nothing.
Then I started selling
sachet water inside a primary school.
And my water was always cold.
That's where the headmistress saw me
and asked me to come and clean her house.
Then she referred me to a friend that
in turn referred me to another and so on.
I will go and be cleaning
their houses, until I met you, Aunty Jay.
Aunty Jay…
since I met you,
my children have never suffered!
Aunty Jay, my children
never suffered since I met you.
And so I will continue to work hard!
I will work hard, so that my children
will not serve them like I am serving.
So that when my children
see their dead father, yes,
they will not be below their mates.
Oh yes. And if
they see the other children,
they will not be below them.
Aunty, I'm not
saying anything against you.
No. But… their father is dead!
So I cannot go back to them
and tell them that he has resurrected.
No, I cannot do that. He is dead!
And about the rod…
the rod doesn't actually mean cane
or you should beat your children.
- Does Mummy beat you?
- Well…
- Well, what? She doesn't beat you.
- But she's always saying she wants to.
Oh, good evening, sir.
I didn't think you'd come.
- You invited him.
- Yes, Mummy.
He said he was going to be around
the area and I just thought maybe...
Anu, go and open the gate.
I'm sure you
and your visitor can talk outside.
- Go on.
- Good evening, sir.
Vicky, please.
Anu, open that gate.
Do you know each other?
- Yes.
- No
So, you are our dad?
Father.
There is a difference
between the two. I am your dad.
Please.
Vicky. Please.
Please, what?
Folarin, please, what exactly?
You left me with
an eight months old pregnancy.
And a two-year old baby boy,
without looking back.
You are such a wicked man.
Ah! We are not lost.
Except you're the one who is lost.
Vicky,
you have every right to be angry.
So you can say that, Fola?
You, you want to tell me when I should
be angry and when I should not be angry.
Just listen to the rubbish you are saying!
Why did you leave?
- Did she do something wrong?
- No.
Nothing.
I was 21 years old.
I felt choked.
I felt like I was sinking.
And so I ran… like a coward.
Did you ever think about us?
Every time.
Rubbish.
But you couldn't be bothered
to come search for us? To come see us?
There's nothing I can…
Fola.
I'm here now.
Please let me make this right.
Let me make it up to you.
All of you.
You are not my husband.
I am not your wife.
These ones, they are
your children. It is up to them.
Let them decide. Alright.
- Sista!
- Eh?
- Yes?
Mummy, guess what? Guess what?
- Folarin bought you something else.
- No!
Mummy, I just got admission
into SSP Academy.
See, see, see! Mummy, take it.
Open it, Mummy. Oh!
- What happened to your admission now?
- Nothing, nothing.
Dad wants us to school in Europe.
So I have to do some exams.
A-levels, and some exams, anyway.
Mummy, he is also transferring Fola
to another private university.
Call me, Fola.
Go and call me your brother.
Fola!
- Fola, what happened to your admission?
- Nothing.
Really? Nothing?
So why do you want to change admission?
Mummy, you know that
there are a lot of strikes.
And besides Dad want me
to finish in record time
so that when he's relocating to Europe,
I can follow him back to do my masters.
- Oh.
- Mummy, we are going together.
Good. When are you people going?
- Not for another year.
- Another year? That's too long.
You people should go now.
- Sista?
- Hey! You people should go now!
Folarin should come
and get you out of here!
- Folarin should come and just take you!
- Sista!
- If you utter another word!
- Mummy?
Go to your father's house.
Both of you, go to your father's house!
You will hear from me!
Folarin will hear from me!
Folarin, you cannot
take my children away from me.
You cannot!
- What do you mean?
- You know what I mean.
You cannot come and
bamboozle my children with money!
No! Eh, you can not do that. We are okay.
I accept you only because
my children accept you.
But all these buying
of iPhone, spending lavishly…
It has to stop.
Sista, please calm down. Please.
Aunty ma, help me and beg him.
Tell him to stop! Was he there
when Anu took her first step?
It was all me.
Was he there
when Anu almost died of jaundice?
Or when Fola fell
from a two-storey building?
Was he there? It was all still me.
I even lied to my children that
their father died just to protect them.
So that they will not think
that he abandoned them.
Warn him!
Because now, you want to come and
take my children away from me suddenly.
I won't have it. Never!
I'm not trying to take the children away.
I'm trying to be their father.
Well, then be their dad from here!
It shouldn't go beyond here!
Fola, it shouldn't go beyond here.
Nothing is wrong with them.
Don't fix anything
that is not spoilt in my children!
Nothing is wrong with their school!
Nothing is wrong with their clothes!
Nothing wrong with their phone!
I am telling you.
Leave my children alone!
You didn't talk to her about all these?
- Well, she said she didn't want...
- No!
My children, Fola…
I repeat, my children go nowhere!
Ahn-ahn. One letter, is
what you wrote for me.
Fola, you wrote me only a letter.
I thought we don't fit
into your future plan?
So now my children look
like they fit your plan, right?
I won't have it.
What did I say? I won't have it.
- Vicky?
- Hmm?
They are my children too and
you cannot stop me from seeing them.
You want to see madness unleashed, right?
Fola, you will see…
First, I'll take off my wig and curse you.
Be careful.
What did I just say? Be careful.
Try it.
Oh yes. You people should go to him!
Since I don't know
how to do it anymore. Well, so go!
- Mummy…
- Hmm.
That man is just trying
to help. Why are refusing him?
I don't need his money.
I don't need his money!
And I'm not cheap like you children. Yes.
Because if you children considered
all the things I went through
to raise you without a father figure…
It's not like he was dead,
he just left you people.
You will not just
accept him, just like that.
- Mummy, but you taught us to forgive.
- Oh sorry, Minister Anu.
And have I said now,
that you should not forgive him?
Have I said that? Hmm?
Mummy, you really need to chill.
Yes, what he did was bad.
But let that man do right by his kids.
That way you don't have to work so much.
You are younger than him,
yet you look much older.
Please Mummy,
let this man carry your burden.
Okay. No problem.
I have never seen her this angry before.
She has every right to be.
Even if she takes it a tad bit too far.
Look, I don't want
to get between you guys.
She doesn't speak to us anymore.
She just goes for
her cleaning job and she comes back late.
What do you think I should do?
Her reason is valid. And you need
to see this from her perspective.
- I am.
- No, you're not.
You're being selfish.
How?
Really? You're asking how?
Have you…
asked me how I feel about all this?
I… I thought…
Oh you thought. You thought.
You thought I was okay with it?
So it didn't occur to you to discuss me,
your wife,
whom out of the blues, you just spring it
up on me that you've got another family.
Have you thought about how we are
going to break the news to our children?
How we're going to tell them,
"Oh lyin, Feranmi, guess what. You've got
a big brother and a big sister!"
Have you thought about
what goes through my mind
when I think of that moment
when you walked out on your children?
I swept my feelings
under the carpet,
just so you can have peace.
And also because
I felt really sorry for Sista.
But you, Folarin… you didn't think,
ask, inquire. Nothing.
You just didn't care. You just
thought I was okay with it.
Throwing two children
at me, just like that.
And boom!
Because she accepts, she's okay with it!
The same way you assume that
that Sista and her children need saving!
If you want to be a good dad,
if you want to make up for lost time,
then get to know your children.
Folarin…
I support you because I love you.
But I realize now,
you don't think about anyone else
but yourself.
Same way you didn't think
about the implication
of walking away from your children
that morning you left for camp.
That night, I decided
to get away from it all.
I wrote that letter.
Then I got to camp and I met you.
I just felt like I was
given a chance for a do over.
You became my reality.
Vicky and the kids were like a dream.
But they are real.
Tiwa.
I love you, very much.
I thank you for being so amazing.
I am grateful that I've always
been surrounded by strong women.
You and Vicky.
Vicky is my past. You are my present.
Our children, that's our future.
I need to fix this.
I need you.
I need to know
that you're okay with my past.
With them being in my life, in our lives.
I can't do this without you.
I love you, Folarin.
I love you too.
Sista.
You know
that children are easily excitable.
They get excited
by little, little things, eh?
But your children, they miss you so much.
They really, really miss you.
He left us.
He erased us from his memory.
He forgot about me.
He forgot about his two children.
If I had not gone to their house to work,
do you think he would have remembered me?
Or you think
he'd have looked for those children?
You see?
No, think about it.
Hmm?
You did not consider that?
So, if not that…
So you children
just accept him without thinking.
If he did not see me, or if not
that he see us in that party,
will he look for you? Hmm?
- But he said he did.
- Where?
I'm asking you, where?
Just one letter.
Just one letter!
That's all he wrote to me.
I showed you children the letter, right?
You read it, didn't you?
I'm asking, didn't you read it?
I still talk with lya Afusat,
our landlord at that time.
If he wrote me
another letter, I'd have known.
He did not look for me.
But look at you children.
After all I suffered because of you.
After all my hustling.
After all the stress
I went through because of you.
I won't cry.
No problem.
You know nothing of what I've
suffered because of you. You have no idea.
Why do you…
Why do you children think
that I told you he was dead? Why?
I don't want you
to think he's a bad person. But now,
you children make me look like I am the
bad person. Is that not so?
Sista.
Mummy.
I don't think you are the problem.
I am sorry if I
ever made you feel like the problem.
Please forgive me.
Sista, you know you are my everything.
I'm sorry I got carried away.
I just imagined what my dad
would be like had he not died.
And when I met him,
he was everything I imagined.
I didn't stop to think about your pain.
Mummy, please forgive me. I'm sorry.
Come here.
Are you ready?
I guess.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- How are you?
Fola, who's there? Why are you outside?
I'd like to have a word with your mother.
Fola. What are you doing outside?
To be honest… I don't think I would have.
I was too big a coward and…
I couldn't bear
the consequences of my actions.
I… I used to think to myself,
"What would I say?
How would she react?"
I couldn't even bear
the thought of looking at you?
That's the honest truth.
Then fate brought us together.
And I tried to seize the opportunity.
You are an amazing woman and mother.
You selflessly
raised these kids, all alone.
But I'm here now.
It will be an honor,
if you'll let me help.
Let me help you
give them the kind of life
that I'm sure that you want them to have.
And…
I would love to be a father
to Folarin and Anuoluwa…
the way that I should.
I went about it the wrong way.
I was excited and eager.
I got caught up in the euphoria,
and I'm sorry that I hurt you.
And my wife. I'm sorry.
I'm grateful for everything
you ever did for me.
So even if it's not for the kids, please
allow me show my appreciation
for putting me through school.
Yes, kids.
Your mom here saw me through school
making the "baddest" noodles in Ife.
My sister…
Please.
Hello?
Yes, yes.
Ah, the car is here.
We are just waiting for Fola now.
Fola has checked us in, yes.
Is, erm, only something…
Something about a baggage dropping.
Baggage drop. It's your daddy.
Oh yeah, yeah um…
Yeah, yeah.
It's your daddy. Yeah, okay.
He said he will wait for us
in Schipol. Which area is that?
- Sista.
- Hmm?
That's the airport.
Lock the door and give me the key.
Is the key in your bag?
Alright, alright.
Hmm! Catch up with us, Fola.
Hello, Uncle.
Go and get in through that side!
Doing this…
Quickly.
Fola, did you lock the back door?