Hey.
Morning. Oh.
- Thank you.
- No, thank you.
Hello? Hi.
I'm across the street.
Who?
No. No, no, there's
nothing wrong with
the ad layouts. I
checked them myself.
Marjorie just must've gotten
the months wrong again.
Yeah. Okay. Have you
talked to Laslo yet?
I don't care if he's upset.
Call Peter back and tell him the
fashion layouts have
to be four pages.
Not seven, not six,
not five. Four.
That's because we
changed photographers.
You must be kidding. I
doubled-checked everything.
What's wrong with the ad layouts?
What's wrong with the
ad layouts, Leo?
I'll tell you what's
wrong. Practically
everything, because they're
the wrong ad layouts.
Marjorie, I have no idea...
Why am I standing here looking
at 30 pages of wrong layouts?
I'll tell you why.
Because someone...
Leo... didn't do their job.
Okay, the copy on the cover
reads "Office Love Affairs:
How to Get Him and Your Raise."
- Good.
- Yeah?
Okay, look at me. Good.
Come in a little closer.
Okay. Right here.
Great. Good. I think we got it.
Carry on. Papaya diet?
Big problem. They're talking
about changing the fruit.
What type of fruit?
I don't know. They said
kiwi or something.
I don't like kiwi.
These came for you.
They're from Frank.
My goodness. He is so
sweet. He was in London.
Very exotic and expensive.
"Can't wait to see
you. It's felt like
an eternity." How
long's he been gone?
- Two days.
- Two days?
Yes.
"Meet me here at 7:30."
Ooh, good choice.
"Bring doll"?
Doll. He does this kind
of thing all the time.
Hula dolls, Polynesian restaurant.
Now just what are you up to?
- It's all part of the surprise.
- Thank you.
- Surprise?
- Huh.
Sur... You're not breaking
up with me, are you?
No.
Okay. Are you sure?
Because %69 of all
relationships break
up in restaurants.
We're not breaking up.
In fact, I want to increase
the romance in our lives.
- You do?
- Huh.
- First, close your eyes.
- Now?
- Close them.
- Okay.
Now remember all the times you
said we never go anywhere...
and we're always working
and we never have any fun?
Well, yeah.
Well, open your eyes and
look where I'm taking you.
Come on.
- Oh, you're kidding.
- You and me in two weeks.
- In two weeks? I can't.
- Oh-Oh, you can.
I can?
Huh. I cleared it with Marjorie.
You did? Oh, you're a sneak.
Yeah. Six days and seven nights...
on the secluded tropical
island paradise of Makatea.
Yeah. Yeah. We arrived
50 minutes late.
Oh, is that a problem?
No, no, that's fine.
I'll tell you what.
Why don't I go find
the bags, and you,
you get to go find
the charter, okay?
I do?
Yeah, I'll see you in ten minutes.
- All right. Okay.
- Sweetie.
- Love you.
- Excuse me.
- You son of a bitch.
You miserable piece of rat shit.
Could you help me? I'm looking
for Tropical Charters.
- You going to Makatea?
- Yes.
Well, we'll be ready
in ten... 20 minutes.
But this... this isn't the plane?
- What?
- The plane.
Where's its mummy?
Oh. Tropical's plane
is laid up in Fiji.
We're filling in. You're
in luck. I'm your pilot.
No. I can't...
No. I can't go in this.
It's, It's broken.
No, it's not broken.
It's being maintained.
- This is my plane.
- Huh.
This is the De Haviland
Beaver. This is one of
the safest, most reliable
planes ever built.
Sweetie, there a problem?
Yes.
He, He seems to think we're
gonna go in this old thing.
What?
I think... I think we could
find another charter.
You won't find one. There's a
boat leaves from the port.
It takes three days.
- Honey. Frank.
- All right, all right.
Sweetie, I'm sure the
plane is perfectly safe.
And I'm sure the pilot is
a trained professional.
- He is the pilot.
- He...
Well, if you're going,
it'll be 20... 30 minutes.
Gotta get some oil.
Oil. He's gonna get some oil now?
- Need help with this luggage?
- No. - No, we're good.
All right, everybody tied down?
Listen, are these
really necessary?
Only if we crash.
Hi.
Everybody, this is Angelica,
our flight service director.
Hello. Thank you. Hi.
Hello. Sorry. Excuse me. Ooh.
Oh, I'm sorry. Excuse me.
- Ooh.
- Come here, baby.
Hello. Are you guys
going to Makatea?
We hope.
Oh, you'll love it. Are
you from the States?
Yes.
I lived there for a while
too. It's very fun.
Hey, Quinn, look. Look what I got.
- Check it out.
- What's that, baby?
It's a bathing suit, silly.
I thought it was an eye patch.
Welcome to Makatea.
Here we are. Thanks for
flying Harris Freight,
where frequent flyers earn bonus
points good for
valuable merchandise.
Hey, you're not trying to
steal my vest, are you?
- Miss Monroe?
- Yes.
- Welcome to Hanaiti.
- Thank you.
I'm Phillipe St. Claire,
the general manager.
Hi.
Can we have the reservation
for Mr Martin?
Oh. Oh, this is beautiful.
Wow.
Okay. All right,
we're never leaving.
Yes.
I want this to be the most
unforgettable vacation
of our lives.
Having a good time?
Oh, honey, I'm
having a great time.
- Hey, you know what today is?
- What?
- It's our anniversary.
- We have an anniversary?
Yeah, unofficially.
Three years ago
today, we first met.
Today?
Today. You don't remember?
We fought over a cab.
Oh, I called you a jerk. Yes. Yes.
Oh, great, that you remember.
Sorry.
That's okay. It was all
part of love's odyssey.
Odyssey?
If I asked, "Would
you wear something
special for me tonight..."
What'd you have in mind?
This.
Will you marry me?
♪ The Calypsonians ♪
♪ Were all gathered together ♪
♪ Singing such a mournful tune ♪
♪ I don't know if it was
in the summertime ♪
♪ It could be the month
of May or June ♪
I'll be back in a second, okay?
All right.
♪ Over loving over, over, over ♪
♪ Over loving you ♪
I always thought this
was a beautiful island,
But with you here, it
is even more beautiful.
How long have you been on Makatea?
- You're kidding, right?
- No.
You brought me here... today.
Five hours ago?
Oh. So much has
happened since then...
Oh. Oops. Oopsy.
Wow. There you go.
- I slipped.
- Yeah.
So where is your, copilot?
Oh, she's busy with the tourists.
Well, that sounds like
you don't like us.
Oh, no. Never bite the hand
that feeds... your mouth.
Whatever.
Besides, you know, they're...
they're good for a laugh.
- You're a big laugher, are you?
- Oh, yeah.
Oh.
They come here looking
for "the magic,"
expecting to find romance...
when they can't find
it any other place.
Maybe they will.
It's an island, babe.
If you don't bring it here,
you won't find it here.
Oh, heavy. Pilot and philosopher.
- Let me buy you a drink.
- Hey, I'm here with somebody.
You remember him?
He came in with me.
I meant both of you.
No, you didn't.
You're from New York, aren't you?
Hey, is everything okay?
- Well, hi. Nice to see you again.
- Yeah, you too.
- Let me buy you a drink.
- Oh, that's very...
- Let's go.
- Oh, but we're leaving. And so...
- Well, maybe some other time...
- Ta-ta.
I'll buy you a drink.
Okay. Bye.
- Was he bothering you?
- Oh, no.
Was he hitting on
you? From over there,
it looked like he
was hitting on you.
Maybe a little...
He was? Do you want me to
do something about it?
Like what?
Hey, I don't go to the gym every
day just to watch old guys shower.
- You know, I will...
- Really? Really?
Well done, ocean. Well done, sky.
Well done, mai tais.
Well done, silicone. Oh, my.
- Hey.
- Ow.
Hey, I'm getting a
little toasty here.
You want me to put some
cream on you, honey?
You'd do that for me?
You'd cream me up?
Only for you. Where is it?
Excuse me. Miss Monroe?
You have a phone call.
- I do?
- You could take it at the bar.
What... Who would be
calling you here?
I have no idea. I'll be back.
Could I get two mai tais, please?
Yes, madam.
Thank you. Hello?
Look, I know you're on vacation,
but this is a dire emergency.
Oh, no.
The photo shoot's on, but it's
an availability nightmare.
Vendela and Evander Holyfield only
have a mutual 17-hour window.
If we don't get them now, nobody's
available for four months...
and we lose them
for the May cover.
There's got to be somebody closer
whose life you can screw up.
That's the ironic thing,
dear. There's not.
Vendela's in Sydney.
Evander's in Osaka.
I threw Taylor on a plane
this morning to Papeete.
- Tahiti?
- Yes. They're all coming to you.
All you have to do is
fly back to Tahiti,
babysit the shoot, fly back out.
- Fifteen hours at the most.
- Look, this is complicated.
Frank proposed to me last night.
Oh, my God. This is so exciting.
Sweetie, I'm so happy for you.
Well, I'm glad, but
the point is...
what kind of message
am I sending to
Frank if the day after
our betrothal...
I'm leaving him to go
on some photo shoot?
An excellent message.
This is the perfect
opportunity to
establish parameters.
Oh, God.
I read somewhere that
%38.6 of all women...
are pressured into quitting their
jobs in the first
year of marriage.
Marjorie, you read that in our
magazine, and we made it up.
Oh, please, Robin, please.
Please, please, Robin. Please.
Deal.
Oh, good. Do you have
a way back to Tahiti?
Oh, yeah. I can...
Feels good? Yeah?
Don't move a muscle.
Lay down. Stay.
- Hi.
- Oh, hi.
- I'm looking for...
- Quinny, it's for you.
Hi there.
I'm really sorry to interrupt
you. I sort of have an emergency.
Emergency? What's going on?
Well, my boss called me, and she
wants me to go to Tahiti tonight.
Well, I'm sort of
on my layover here.
Right. Would $500 cut
your layover short?
Baby, wanna go to Papeete?
I can't. I have a show tonight.
Tuesday is Tamure night.
It's Tamure night.
My hands are tied.
Oh. That's for later.
You know, I'm stuck. I...
This is really important.
You'd be doing me a tremendous
favour. How would 700 be?
Okay.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Great.
I'll meet you at the plane,
and give me an hour.
Great. Thank you.
Honey, it's a known fact
that %38.6 of all women...
are pressured into quitting their
jobs the first year of marriage.
That was in your magazine.
You probably made it up.
If you had to work,
I would understand.
That's because you're not
as romantic as I am.
So come with me.
- No.
- How come?
Because if I go with you, I'll
resent the fact that I'm there.
If I stay here, I'll miss
you, but you'll feel guilty.
I like that better.
Come on. It's only for one night.
- Hubby.
- Say that again.
What, hubby?
- I like that. Say it.
- Hubby.
- Ready to go.
- Is it safe to fly?
- It is with me.
- Oh, you're that good, huh?
I'm the best you've
ever been with.
I'm not sure I trust
your equipment.
We may be old, but we're sturdy.
What's all this?
Hotel overstocks, local trinkets.
I was gonna fly them
to Tahiti tomorrow,
but with your job, I got a twofer.
How handy for you.
Excuse me. I just wanna keep
this from flying at you.
There we go.
- Do you have my, money?
- Oh, yes.
- Thank you.
- It's all there.
I trust you.
So what kind of work do you
do back there in New York?
I'm an assistant editor for
a magazine called Dazzle.
- Dazzle?
- Yeah.
Never heard of that one.
You're not exactly the
demographic we shoot for.
This is it.
Dazzle.
"Your Derriere: Five Exercises
to Tame the Beast."
"Ten Ways to Light His Fire."
For pete sake.
Ten ways to light his fire.
You know how a woman
gets a man excited?
How?
She shows up, and that's it.
We're guys. We're easy.
Of course, for that you can't
charge six bucks
an issue, can you?
Does that advice
come with the 700...
Or do I need to pay
extra for that?
It's on the house.
Thanks.
Island flight watch, Beaver 0318.
We are 3,500 on a heading of 110.
Looking for a weather update,
please, along our route of flight.
Be advised...
southwesterly...
Say again.
I'm sorry. This weather came up
quicker than anybody anticipated.
We're gonna have to
turn back to Makatea.
- It's just not worth the risk.
- All right.
A line of squalls has
got us boxed in.
Tighten up your seat belt.
It's gonna get bumpy.
Wha...
You don't... you don't mind if I
just... come sit up here with you?
Get your seat belt on.
- What are those?
- Xanax.
My doctor prescribed
them for situations
of tension. I think
this qualifies.
- Give me a couple.
- You just drive.
- What are you taking now?
- Xanax.
My doctor prescribed them for
situations of "sension."
Give me those.
Whoo. Hey.
That was close, huh? Whoo.
That was more than
close. That hit us.
- No?
- Shit. Fried the radios.
Oh, no. That's bad, huh?
Mayday, Mayday,
Mayday. Beaver 0318.
We're unable to maintain altitude.
Can anybody hear this?
- Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
- Attention Kmart shoppers.
Snow shovels are
on sale for 12.99.
Put that down. I'm unable
to maintain altitude.
Forty miles,
south-south-east of Makatea.
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday
How many of those
things did you take?
You know, I just don't know.
- Look.
- What?
We're in trouble here. I want
you to sit back, be quiet,
Keep your seat belt tight
and let me fly this thing.
Yes, sir.
There's an island down there.
I can see a beach. I'm
gonna set us down.
Okey-dokey.
Rock on the beach. There's
a rock on the beach.
Son of a bitch.
Blah.
Good morning.
Could you get me a cup of coffee?
Oh, sure. I'll get
right on it, madam.
Oh, God. What...
- Where are we?
- Here.
Where? Where?
Somewhere between
Makatea and Tahiti.
That's... That's the
best I can do for you.
Whoa. What happened?
It crumpled the landing
gear when we hit.
Well, aren't you gonna fix it?
I mean, can't we... can't
we reattach it somehow?
Oh, sure. We'll, like, glue
it back on. How's that?
- Aren't you one of those guys?
- What guys?
Those guy guys. You know,
those guys with skills.
- Skills?
- Yeah.
You send them out
into the wilderness
with a pocket knife and a Q-Tip...
and they build you
a shopping mall.
- You can't do that?
- No. No, I can't do that.
But I can do this.
Does that help?
I can get us out of here.
- Oh, good.
- Yeah.
Hey. Right? Huh?
Phone, huh?
I'm gonna get us out of here...
Pronto.
Come on, phone.
So, what are we,
like, shipwrecked?
- How do you want it?
- Excuse me?
Do you want it sugar-coated
or right between the eyes?
You pick.
We've only got one wheel,
so we can't take off.
Lightning fried the radio and the
emergency location transmitter.
Air-Sea will probably
try a rescue,
but without a beacon to hone in,
it's like trying to find a
flea on an elephant's ass.
The only thing we've got is...
this flare gun and a single flare.
Is it too late to get
it sugar-coated?
That was sugar-coated.
Well, then, what's the bad news?
The bad news is we may be
here for a... long time.
You and me,
for a long, long...
long, long, long, long time.
Well, I want my $700 back.
What?
You heard me. My $700,
I want it back.
You said you were gonna take
me to Tahiti. You didn't.
Give it back.
Come on.
One, two,
three...
I figure I got you halfway.
Halfway? Halfway?
- Halfway.
- Halfway? Whoo.
Halfway. Oh, boy, you're good.
Whoo. You got me halfway.
That's fantastic.
Wha... What are you doing? Hey,
hey. Get away from my plane.
- Goddamn it, get out of there.
- I'm gonna do something.
- Hey, leave that stuff alone.
- You shut up.
Come on now. Get out of there.
What do you think you're doing?
Leave my stuff al...
Hey, hey. Come on.
- What's this? It's a boat.
- It's a life raft.
We can use that to
get off the island.
Where are you gonna go?
You don't even know where you are.
Last thing you wanna do is...
go bouncing around the ocean
in an eight-foot blow-up boat.
- Don't tell me what I want.
- Give that to me. Give it.
Hey, don't pull on
that. Leave it alone.
Wait. Wait. Get me out... No.
Get me out of here.
Get me... Get me out of here.
You gonna stop acting
like a lunatic?
- Fuck you.
- Pardon me? What'd you say?
That's what I thought you said.
Yeah.
Mr Martin?
There's a telephone
call for Miss Monroe.
Oh. I'll take it.
Hello? Hello?
This is Frank Martin. Who is...
Oh, hi, Marjorie. It's Frank.
No, she... she left yesterday.
What?
Marie, it's Phillippe at Makatea.
Quinn flew a lady back
to you last night.
Can you look if the De Haviland
is at the gate? No, I'll wait.
I ran into Tony. He said that
Quinny didn't make Tahiti.
Hold on, Angelica. We don't know
anything yet. Yes,
Marie, right here.
Bon. Get Air-Sea Rescue,
Marie, and call me back.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, no.
Come on. You wanna drink
water, you got to haul water.
Let's go.
- What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
- Something.
Oh, don't give me that.
You were ogling.
- "Ogling"?
- Yeah.
Ogling? Let me ask you something.
What?
When you go into a store to
buy something like that,
what do you say to
the clerk, "Give me
that outfit so nobody
will look at me?"
No, I like people
looking, just not you.
If it makes you feel any
better, you're not my type.
Oh, good.
- Why?
- "Why"?
Yeah. I'm making
conversation. Why?
You talk too much.
You're opinionated.
You're stubborn,
sarcastic and stuck-up.
Your ass is too narrow, and
your tits are too small.
Hey, you wanna know why
you're not my type?
Nope.
Bonjour. Bonjour. Parlez vous...
- I'm American.
- Oh, thank God.
Tom Morrow. I'll take you up.
Frank. Listen. So how
do we find them?
We're gonna fly over the water
and look out the window.
Wha... Whoa, whoa,
whoa. That's it?
What about the modern technology?
Don't you have satellites, lasers,
- Mr Martin, just take your seat.
- Heat-seeking kind of...
- I'm Ricky.
- Yeah, great. I'm Frank.
Listen, money is no
object, all right?
Yeah. Just get in.
Try breathing very deeply.
I find that helpful.
If they went into the
water, it's only been
12 hours. It's a good
chance we'll find them.
Okay.
Hey, Bwana, why don't you
let me lead for a while?
Okay. This'll be interesting.
Now there. You see? I found it.
Come on, Quinny.
Oh, my God.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Quinn, this is...
Ooh. Oooh.
- Hey. Hey, hey, hey. Hold on.
- Whoa.
- What are you doing?
- What the hell's that?
It's a pig. What are
you worried about?
He's more afraid of
us than we... Watch.
Ha. Go on. Go on. Go
on. Get out of here.
Ho-ha. Ha.
Come on. Come on.
- Whoa.
- Come on.
- Hey, Quinn.
- Huh? What?
What?
I'm sorry to interrupt you, but...
I'm having a bit of a problem.
What's the problem?
Some sort of creature has
just swum up my pants.
I'm guessing... I'm
guessing a snake.
Oh.
That's bad.
So, what do I do?
I mean, I could reach
down and... and grab it.
No. That... That could be
risky. Might be poisonous.
Well, right. But
on the other hand,
if it's poisonous
and will bite me,
do I want to allow it to continue
to swim around in my shorts?
All good questions.
Would you just give
me some advice?
Just advice, input,
anything. Give it to me.
I'm very open at this
particular juncture, all right?
- Just stand still.
- Still.
- Stand still.
- What are you doing?
- Relax.
- Right.
Oh, God.
- Oh, no.
- What?
- Not good.
- What? Wha...
I'm trying to concentrate here.
Okay. Okay.
Now, let's see.
Better not catch you smiling.
Ooo-ooo.
Thanks.
Well, I'm not without skills.
Whoa. You going on a date?
- Do you like it?
- Why the fashion statement?
- Going hunting.
- Ooh, for what?
No.
You wouldn't.
They are magnificent creatures.
And I hear they taste
just like chicken.
Chicken?
♪ Paradise ♪
Hey.
Maybe I should have a taste.
You know, just in
case somebody asks me
someday, "Have you
ever had peacock?"
- I can say, "Yes, I have."
- You won't regret it.
Okay, perfect.
Whoo. Ah.
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Wow.
Chicken. Okay, chicken.
Have you always been a pilot?
All my grown-up life.
- Like doing what?
- All kinds of flying.
I had my own very
successful business.
What happened?
Well,
I found a better way
of life, that's all.
Like what?
Came out here, got a nice little
house on a beautiful beach.
Got my plane.
Doing what I want to do.
Got peace and quiet.
Living the life every
man dreams of.
Well, yeah, until they're 12.
I'm sorry. That was out of line.
- No.
- I'm just...
I'm just cranky, you know,
from being shipwrecked.
Look at that sky. You don't see a
sky like that in New York City.
No, that's a good sky.
- Whoa.
- All right. Sorry.
I'm just a little tipsy.
Good night.
Suave.
Really suave.
Oh, my God. It's a plane. Oh.
A plane. What do... A
flare. We need the flare.
Quinn?
Quinn? Get up.
There's a plane.
Okay.
Flare. Jesus. Okay.
- Hey, baby.
- Oh, no.
Oh, boy. Oh.
Oh, no.
Oh. Oh. Oh, no.
Oh, nuts.
What's...
What the hell did
you do? What the...
You... You wasted our only goddamn
flare... to shoot a
goddamn palm tree?
I wouldn't have shot the goddamn
tree if you hadn't rolled into me.
I was trying to signal
the goddamn plane.
What goddamn plane?
That goddamn plane.
- That goddamn plane?
- Yeah.
That's a commercial
airliner. It's five
miles high going
600 miles an hour.
They wouldn't see a
nuclear explosion if
they were looking for
it, much less a flare.
How was I supposed to know that?
If you hadn't drunken
yourself into a
coma, maybe you could
have told me that.
You know what you've done?
What?
You've taken our one good chance
of being found and pissed it away.
Don't you dare blame
this on me. If you were
half a pilot, we wouldn't
be on this island.
I am the best goddamn pilot
you're ever gonna meet.
Ha. I've flown with you twice.
You've crashed half the time.
And there is nothing
wrong with my tits.
There's so much water.
Don't worry.
Wherever they are,
Quinny is going to
take good care of your girlfriend.
What do you mean by that?
Come on. Let's pick
up the pace a little.
I wanna get to the
top before dark.
Goddamn.
I've had just about as much
vacation as I can stand.
- Stop. Stop.
- Stop?
- What?
What?
We better find the beacon.
This way.
That beacon better be up there.
Look. The storm blew us
south-west 40 minutes.
A good chance this is Tamitange.
Ah, Tamitange. Well, that
explains everything.
There's a radio navigation
beacon on top of Tamitange.
We find it. We shut it down. They
come out and fix
it. We're rescued.
It took them two years to fix the
street light outside my apartment.
Wow, this is beautiful, huh?
So where's the beacon?
Huh?
Oh, let me see.
It's this one?
Tamitange, the one with
the funny-shaped
peninsula to the north.
Yeah.
Well, that... that's north, right?
- Right?
- Yeah.
There's no peninsula.
Who stole the peninsula?
No.
This isn't Tamitange?
So there is no beacon...
that we're gonna
turn off and they're
gonna come fix it and find us?
Well, we could be...
We could be further to the south.
This could be Mata Nui.
Mata Nui?
And what's on Mata Nui?
Us.
What? Wait, wait.
What are you doing?
Son of a bitch. Goddamn it.
Please don't do that again.
I just want one goddamn
thing to go right.
Oh, God.
I know. Come on.
Ever since we've been here,
you've been so confident.
You have all the answers.
Well, I'm the captain.
That's my job.
It's no good for me to go waving
my arms in the air and screaming,
"Oh, shit. We're gonna die."
Doesn't evoke much
confidence, does it?
No, no, that does not.
I need you to be my
confident captain.
I can't tell you how difficult
this is gonna be for me...
if you lose it.
Okay.
- I'm all right now.
- Good, good. Good.
Qui-Quinn. Quinn.
What? What?
What do you need? Hey. Come on.
Get out of that. What do you want?
I... Look, look, look.
Come here. Oh, yes.
It's a boat.
Looks like they're
putting into that cove.
Yeah, well, how do we signal them?
A flare'd be nice.
Don't start. Come
on. What do we do?
How do we get down there?
- We go, down the mountain...
- Yeah.
Up the mountain,
down the mountain.
We get to our life
raft and... hope
they'll still be there
in the morning.
Huh.
Come on.
Oh, God.
- Come on. I'll take over.
- Oh, God. Thanks.
So what's the deal with you and...
Mm.
- Angelica.
- Yeah.
There's no deal. We're friends.
She works at the hotel a
couple of months a year.
We have some laughs,
keep it simple.
Well, has it always
been simple, or has
there ever been
anyone complicated?
That's a yes. Yes?
How complicated? Scale
from one to ten.
- Twelve.
- Twelve? God, what happened?
Well, tragically, she, she...
Died? Oh, my God, I'm so...
- No, she didn't die.
- I'm so... Oh.
Why... You gonna let me
tell the story or what?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sure. Tell it.
She...
fell in love with somebody else.
Not just somebody
else. My best friend.
My partner. The guy I
was in business with.
God. What did you do?
Well, I, bowed out,
gave them my blessing.
Are they still together?
No. They broke up.
Not before I sold them
my half of the business.
I came out here, got my
plane, never looked back.
Best thing that ever
happened to me.
- There are two boats.
- What? Two boats?
Two boats. Ah.
Look. God, this is great, huh?
Hello.
Whoo.
Sit down. We got to
get out of here.
- Why? Why?
- We got to get out of here.
What? "Get out of here"?
What are you talking about?
Shit. Shit, shit, shit.
Oh, my God.
- Who are they?
- Pirates.
Pi... Pirates, as in "argh"?
Smugglers. Thieves.
They rob boats.
"Rob... Rob boats"?
They just killed a guy.
They could kill us, too,
just for being here.
- Just for seeing them.
- What?
- Shit. He just saw me.
- We got company.
- Oh.
- Out, out, out.
Oh, no.
They just lowered a boat.
- What kind of a boat?
- A motorboat.
- Shit, shit.
- Oh.
Whoo-hoo.
Let's go. Move them out.
Oh, God. Row faster.
Go, go, go.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
What? What?
- Go.
- Where? Why?
God. Oh.
Don't.
Let's not make this difficult.
That was a very
stupid thing to do.
Now I'm gonna have to
kill you. Say goodbye.
We've got gold.
Up.
- Gold?
- Gold.
Yeah. We've got gold. I'm
a jewellery designer.
I design jewellery with
gold and precious stones.
Precious stones I-like...
I have... I have sold to
all the finest stores,
and, we've got display
cases on the boat...
because, we're expanding the
business in the Far East...
But that's my husband's
end of the business.
- Cause I'm in marketing. I'm...
- Whiz. You're a whiz.
Take us to the boat.
Hey. Hey.
Come on.
Oh, my God. Now what?
- We go on three.
- Oh.
- One, two...
- I can't. You go. Save yourself.
- I'm sorry.
- For kissing me?
No. For this.
Huh.
Damn. Damn.
You know how some
people say you... you
don't know what you had
until you lose it?
- Mm.
- It's a load of crap.
I knew what I had. I...
God, I loved her...
love her. Love her.
Not to insult you,
but I don't think
men know what love is. I mean...
- I do.
- Yeah?
I do.
Well, guys... They tell me
they love me all the time.
Well, I'm sure at least
some of them mean it.
No, they don't.
- Do you think they gave up?
- I don't know.
We shouldn't go back to the camp.
The plane's too easy to spot.
I am so scared.
If it makes you feel any better,
I'm a little scared myself.
No. No, that does not
make me feel better.
I thought that's
what women wanted.
What?
Men who weren't afraid
to cry, who were
in touch with their feminine side.
No, not when they're
being chased by
pirates. They like
them mean and armed.
Whoa.
This is not a good
island for aeroplanes.
It's a Japanese World
War II float plane.
It's been up there for 50 years.
Jesus.
You don't think there's
any way that you could...
Nah. Nah.
This looks like a safe
place to spend the night.
I'm gonna see if there's
anything I can use up there.
Hi.
Hey.
This is me here.
Whoo. We got to meet
them at 6:00 a.m
They're gonna widen the search.
I may be too drunk to
wake up at 6:00 a.m
I know how...
Are you sure you're okay?
You're... You're fine?
Yeah, I'm...
I'm just going to... take a
shower and get into bed.
- Are you okay?
- I'm good. Yeah.
I mean, do you want
to stay here tonight?
Stay?
Yeah. With me?
I mean, you probably think I'm
being slutty or something,
but I'm feeling bad and
you're feeling bad...
and I'd really like
for you to stay.
I just don't... Yeah.
Sure. Why not?
- Yeah?
- No, no, I can't.
I mean, I'm still
clinging to hope.
And if I mean, if
we... You know...
Holy...
- No.
- No?
- No. I...
- Mm. Are you sure?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. No, I seem to
be leaving the room.
Breadfruit.
- It's not bread.
- It's not fruit.
I wanna kiss you.
I really liked kissing you.
I liked kissing you.
But?
But if I start, I'm not
gonna be able to stop.
- Sounds good.
- Doesn't it?
I, oh... can't.
We should get some sleep.
Come here.
This feels good...
and safe.
It feels good and safe.
- Good morning.
- Wh... What are you doing?
- I got a plan.
- Good.
Anything I can do to help?
Yeah.
Yeah. Just a second.
What is it? What's wrong?
Angelica, the helicopter
is going up in 20 minutes.
- If you're going, vite, huh?
- Twenty min...
Oh, jeez, I didn't realise it
was... Okay. Thank you, Phillippe.
Tell them I'm on my way, okay? Oh.
The helicopter's going
up in 20 minutes.
Oh, God, what did...
what did I do?
And how many times did I do it?
Are you okay?
Huh? No, no, this was
wrong. This was all wrong.
Excuse me. How could you say that?
N- No. I mean, everything
you did was very right.
But what I did was
wrong. This is wrong.
No, no.
It's just we are going
through a terrible ordeal.
It's like... when
after a funeral...
- Yeah?
- Everybody has sex.
- Not everybody.
- No?
- No.
- Oh.
What?
Nothing.
You know that woman I
was telling you about?
The heartbreaker?
She was my wife.
- Oh.
- Twelve years.
Do you have any kids?
No, we didn't have
any kids, thank God.
But I always wanted
kids. Bunches of them.
Really? There's still time.
Look. Come on. How old are you?
Well, what do...
How old do you think I am?
Let me think.
Guess.
Forty-five?
Forty-eight?
Fifty. You 50?
- You still look good.
- I still am good.
Let's get these apart. We got
to take them down one by one.
You first.
Careful.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
- Okay, your turn.
- Eeew.
How can I eat? I'm
scum. I'm garbage.
This experience has
tested me and has
revealed no character whatsoever.
Stop beating yourself up. You're
a guy. You can't help it.
Mr Martin, forgive me.
I just heard they decided
to call off the search.
I'm sorry.
But that's it? Wh...
Okay.
It's working.
Keep coming.
Push.
- Ready?
- All right.
Put her down.
- Oh, shit. Look.
- Oh.
Get out of here.
Too far back to the right.
Oh, God. Are you okay?
Oh.
Oh, you're hit.
It's not bad.
- It's not bad.
- Oh.
Come on. Come on.
I'm in. I'm in. Get
in the plane. Hurry.
Hurry.
Hurry, hurry up.
Okay. Come on. Come on.
Fire.
Damn. Get out of my way.
Reload.
Take off.
We're gonna hit them.
Give me a hand. Pull.
- Pull, pull.
- Pull.
Let's do it.
Hit the...
Come on. Come on.
Stay with me here.
Stay with me. You're doing great.
Come on.
Look, I should tell you a few
things about aeroplanes.
Why is that?
Because I may not
be conscious when
it comes time to land this thing.
Oh, shit.
Take the controls. I want you
to get a feel for the yoke.
You're serious, aren't you?
I got it. Okay.
- Okay.
- Okay, sw... Hey.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Small corrections.
- Sorry.
- Small.
- Just look at the horizon.
When we get there,
you're gonna line up...
about a hundred feet
out from the beach.
A hundred feet out from the beach.
We are here today...
to honour two fine
people: Miss Robin
Monroe and an old friend, Mr...
Father, please forgive
me, for I have sinned.
I've been bad, very bad.
Oh, God. Quinn?
Quinn, don't make
me do this alone.
Please, Quinn, don't make
me do this alone. Shit.
I would say a few words about
our friend, Quinn Harris.
He was the kind of man who...
It's Quinny. It's Quinny.
Look.
All right. Lined
up with the beach.
Throttle to 65 knots.
What the hell's a knot?
It's Quinny. Look.
- Oh.
- Thank... Thank you, God.
Flaps. Flaps, flaps.
Okay. All right.
Nose slightly elevated
for landing. Here we go.
And, help me, God.
Oh, my God.
I'm coming, sweetie.
Hurry. Hurry.
Oh. Quinn.
Quinn. Quinn, Quinn.
Oh. Hey.
We did it.
I'm coming, Robin.
Sweetie, hold...
- Robin. Oh, my God, you're alive.
- Hey, Frank.
- Wh... You're hurt. You're hurt.
- No, no. I'm fine, I'm fine.
He needs a doctor. Get
him... Get him a doctor.
A doctor. We need a doctor.
Come on. Come on, sweetie.
- Quinny, are you okay, baby?
- Can you move your leg?
Be careful. Are you okay, baby?
- Be careful.
- Steady, steady, steady.
They brought the tea.
- Oh, great.
- Do you want some honey, sweetie?
Sure.
The guy said the, hotel's offered
us a month's free
stay anytime we want.
Oh. They're probably
afraid I'm gonna sue them.
How are you feeling?
Are you all right?
Oh, yeah.
I'm just, you know, tired.
Ooh. Ah.
There we go. I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I didn't get much sleep.
Frank. Come here. Come here.
Sit down.
It was terrible.
I mean...
I think deep down, I never
expected to see you again.
You know? I was... I was lost.
I was...
We're just people, you
know? You know, Robin?
We're not perfect. I mean,
under that kind of pressure...
I mean, people do
things, you know? I
mean, you don't know
right and wrong.
You're cra... You're
nuts. You know, you...
Hi.
Oh, hi.
Keeping busy?
Yeah.
- How are you?
- Good. Good, thanks.
This is... not so bad.
How about you... your...
- It's fine.
- Good.
What's the deal here?
Deal?
With us?
- What do you mean?
- You know what I mean.
Was what happened on
that island anything?
Or was it just something that
happens to two people...
when they're alone on
an island together?
It was something.
- "Something"?
- Yeah.
So...
now what?
Look, I'm pretty set
in my ways, and...
you got all kinds
of possibilities.
You deserve someone...
fresher.
Don't you think that's
up to me to decide?
Let's be smart about this.
You're not gonna move out
here and become my copilot,
and I'm not gonna go to New York
and be your receptionist, so...
Where does that leave us?
I don't know. I guess
it leaves us nowhere.
So let's not complicate things.
Oh, I forgot you
like things simple.
- Right.
Well, good luck.
Good luck to you too.
I hope everything
works out... for you.
So how's that shoulder today?
Need something for the pain?
Yeah.
Well, 14 more hours,
then back to reality.
Frank?
I don't think we
should get married.
What?
How come?
Because I think it's
wrong for two people...
to get married when something
is hanging over their heads.
Oh, God, I'm sorry. Robin,
I'm sorry. I was... I was...
I was distraught,
and then she took
off her blouse. I
was, "Oh, my God."
But I walked away. I did.
I went back to our room.
I tried to go to sleep, but I
thought of you. I thought...
Oh, I didn't know if
you were dead or what.
So I went back to her bungalow,
you know, just to... and she...
Robin, she answered
the door with...
On.
- Who?
- Angelica.
You slept with Angelica?
Who slept? Are you ki...
Didn't you know?
How would I know?
Wait a minute. You just said there
was something hanging over our...
What do you... Wh...
What do you mean?
Quinn and me.
Aha.
Oh, Frank, something happened.
Something happened
that shouldn't have
happened if you and
I were really...
In love.
Flight number 38 to Honolulu,
all ticketed passengers
should board immediately.
Bon voyage, madame.
Monsieur? Bon voyage.
Madame?
Bon voyage.
Monsieur?
Hey.
Sorry.
Hey-Hey.
Where's the p...
plane to New York?
Right there.
I'm sorry. I just had
to get off the plane.
I... Well, I'm sorry I
delayed the flight.
Listen. I just wanted...
I don't speak any French. I just
needed to get off the plane.
Where are all my bags?
You don't speak any? Neither one
of you speak any English at all?
What's in my bags is illegal?
W- Wait a minute. Oh, please
don't search my bags.
It's just important
that I stay h...
- You're here.
- Bonjour, Quinn.
Mon ami. Merci.
Why... Why did you
get off the plane?
Wha... Why didn't you...
Why did you come here?
I've decided my life
is... too simple.
- It is?
- Yeah.
I wanna... wanna complicate
the hell out of it.
So, where are we going?
Your place is in New York, right?
Huh.
I don't think I can
wait that long.
How about my place?
Oh, yeah. Your little
house on the beach.
More like a shack, actually.
- A shack?
- It's, It's not much.
Huh. You do have a bed, don't you?
Are you gonna be this
fussy about everything?
♪ I wanna love you ♪
♪ And treat you right ♪
♪ Every day and every night ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ With a roof right
over our heads ♪
♪ We'll share the shelter ♪
♪ Of my single bed ♪
♪ We'll share the same room yeah ♪
♪ But jah provide the bread ♪
♪ Is this love, is
this love is this ♪
♪ Love, is this love
that I'm feeling ♪
♪ Is this love, is
this love is this ♪
♪ Love, is this love
that I'm feeling ♪