- I don't know.
I don't know why.
I'm trying to clear my voice
so I can speak louder.
I need to shout.
I need to shout!
I need to fucking shout!
I'm sorry.
My language.
Do you forgive me?
- What would you do if we got pregnant?
- We?
- We.
- Did you study biology at that
private school you went to?
- You know what I mean.
- Would we keep it?
- Why wouldn't we keep it?
- I don't know.
I keep hearing poetry.
I hear poetry of all.
Keeping my mind at bay
and only on the shore.
I heard your voice.
I shouted out to you.
You never came.
You never come.
- I am a political prisoner.
I'll get out early on good behaviour.
I am a political refugee.
I make my home with good behaviour.
I am a political slave.
I'll be freed when I am dead.
- That ain't nothing much.
Where's she at?
In the park?
- Yeah, we're going.
- Yeah, yeah.
- You want to take some people.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, get
the boys down there.
Get a few cans and stuff like that.
- Well, it is your birthday.
- Well, yeah exactly.
Yeah, you need to party.
- Bring it in right, you know.
Hey, I didn't know you were
coming today, Stall mate.
- Dog it, did I?
- Hey, it's my birthday.
- Happy birthday.
- Cheers.
Do you like my outfit?
- Yeah, real dapper.
- Yeah, I got it at discount.
One hundred percent, mate.
Oh yeah, how'd you manage that?
- The riots, mate.
You went rioting?
- Well, yeah.
Well, didn't you?
No.
- Mate, you missed that.
Some proper bargains.
Got my mum a fur coat.
- Now, where's she gonna wear that?
Out the door.
- Now, I hear you're
living in a mansion, huh.
Not me.
- Well, that's what they says.
They lied.
- It just all made sense because
I haven't seen you on TV boxing
and that, so you know know it makes sense.
I don't box anymore.
- Oh yeah, they said that too.
Then why would you see me
on TV boxing?
- Just thought you might.
You know.
You should, Stall mate.
You're a fucking legend.
The unbeaten Stallion in all that.
- Pencil, lad, why are you...
It's a beautiful day.
Why are you here sucking my dick?
- What?
- What do you want?
- Well, I just wanted to say hi.
- Mate, it seems like you
said everything but hi
since you've opened your fucking mouth.
- Hi, Stally?
- Hi, Pencil.
Now, do one, mate.
- Stall mate, Stall.
- What do you want?
- George is pissed, mate.
- So?
- He's pissed at Chris.
- George is always pissed at something.
- No I know, but this is serious.
He's talking about doing him.
- Why?
- Some deal went well rank
like money or drugs or something.
I don't know but it's serious.
- Thanks for the info.
- Now, do one again, mate.
- Stall?
Have you got a Century, mate?
- Do one, Pencil.
- Well now, come on.
It's my birthday.
What...
What about a score?
A pony even?
He lives in a mansion
and can't even give his mate
a bit of financial aid.
- Mom.
Oh, Stally!
How have you been?
- Been good, how are you?
- Chris is in his room.
Maybe you can talk some since into him.
He needs a job.
Also, you can have a word with her.
She's a bloody mess too.
- I'm sure Chris will sort
himself out anyway, mom.
- I love it when you call me mom.
Come here.
I've missed this so much.
- Me too.
- Go on.
Go to see, Chris.
- Alright.
And what's this one doing?
- She does not clean this bloody place.
She'd rather go out with her mates,
her little twat mates
from around the block.
- Mom, I cleaned yesterday.
- FFS.
- FFS, you know.
- Go take a piss.
- Don't talk to him like that.
Who do you think you are?
- I can talk to anyone how I'd like.
- Oh really?
- Yeah I can.
- You think you can do anything, do you?
- Yeah, I can actually, just like Chris.
- Mom.
Mom.
Mom, leave it.
Mom, she'll do it herself.
Leave it.
- Oy.
What?
- What?
- When fucking mom talks to you,
you fucking listen, alright?
Fuck off, Chris.
Fucking what?
Yeah, fuck off.
Who the fuck are you talking to?
You talk that
shit to mom all the time.
Yes, but I'm the fucking daddy
in this fucking house.
I'm the man here.
Oh shut up.
What the fuck?
You're bringing boys here.
I fucking here you
shagging them all the time.
I'm trying to fucking relax in here.
Who the fuck are you talking to?
I'm not the only one
who talks shit around here, okay?
You're talking to mom like shit.
I've fucking had enough of you.
For fuck's sakes.
What?
- Nothing, mate.
- Nothing?
Don't fucking shake your head
in my fucking house, mate.
I'm the fucking daddy in this house.
I do the daddy shit.
- Hitting women?
- It's my fucking sister.
- Alright, mate.
Whatever.
- You like my sneaks?
- Yeah they're not bad, mate.
- Got a 100 % discount on those.
- You went rioting.
- Damn right, I did.
- Wow.
- So, mate.
It's 500...
- Mate, mate, mate.
I'm not in all this no more, mate.
- Oh yeah.
You left all this slum
life behind, ain't ya.
You ain't none of us no more, are you?
- You ask me questions you
already know the answer to.
I don't box.
I don't deal.
I don't run like a little girl
when the 5-0's on the block.
Fucking hell.
I'm all grown up now, Peter Pan.
- Alright, Tinkerbell.
Fucking hell.
Calm down.
- Look.
I've just came here out of courtesy.
- Courtesy, aye?
- Yeah, mate.
- You're being courteous right now?
- Yeah, I'm telling you to your face.
Look, I thought I'd tell you to your face
that I'm away from all this.
- You shouldn't have bothered, mate.
- You need to get away too.
- Just send a text, you know what I mean?
I was talking to Pencil.
- Oh, that clown.
- He was telling me you're
in large with George.
- Oh, fuck George and fuck Pencil.
- Fuck George?
What do you mean "Fuck George"?
- Fuck him.
I mean fuck him.
- Seriously?
- Fuck him.
- George is not someone you fuck with.
- Yeah, fuck him.
What are you doing now.
- Nothing, mate.
Got a job, got a girl.
- No, you fucking nut.
Not your fucking life story.
Like right now.
- Talk to a funking wanker.
- Come with me, come.
- What?
- Come with me.
Dickhead.
Okay.
That's a lot of game.
- Damn right it is.
- Please tell me this ain't George's.
- Made a coupe of bob on that.
Wow.
You're mad.
- You love it.
- You're actually mad.
I go away for a couple of months,
and you've got up to this.
- You fucking love it, mate.
You're crazy.
- You fucking love it.
- You are crazy, you know that.
You're fucking crazy.
Fucking hell.
Come on, let's
have fucking tickle.
What?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
What are you doing?
- What do you fucking think I'm doing?
Look.
Have a bit.
- No, I'm not having it. I'm not involved.
- On the house.
- I'm not involved.
You're already in enough shit.
Fucking leave it alone.
No, behave.
- Leave it alone, leave it alone.
- For fuck's sake.
- Leave it alone.
I can't believe you stole...
- I know.
- What I'm trying to say is...
What I'm trying to say is...
What you're trying to say is...
- Fucking listen for once in your life.
- Fucking Badge, the Greek philosopher.
Yoga's in the ass, come on here.
- Alright let him speak.
- You robbed the old man.
Now the old man's gonna do
what old men do, get bitter, get angry
and join our fucking removes.
- Oh is that what old men do?
I thought they did the opposite actually.
I thought they got old,
got weak and fuck...
- You think this is all a joke,
you think this is a fucking joke.
- Your mate is about six feet deep.
Balls expunged from our body.
- Come on, Badge.
Just give it a rest.
He can just give the gear back.
- What gear?
He just sold half of
it for half the price.
- For half the fucking price.
You gonna say anything.
- About what?
- Fucking lost cause, mate.
- You now, fuck.
He's pissed me off, I've got him back.
We're square.
- This guy.
Are you fucking listening to this guy?
- George don't do square.
He also don't do people blatantly
shafting him up the rear
and boasting about it.
- Boasting?
Fuck off, boasting.
- Guess what he does
at Wax's the other day?
He goes up to this bird, goes,
"You know I'm the guy that robbed George."
Big fucking grin on his face,
trying to impress this flag.
- It fucking worked though, didn't it?
- It fucking worked.
- It fucking worked on your sister.
- Smell, it's still fucking stinky.
- You're a fucking idiot, mate.
- You are.
Come on.
- My name's all over this shit too, you know.
Leave it.
Calm down.
- It's mine now.
- "Mine now"?
- Look if he cries about it,
I'll take the profits, give it all to him.
- They'll be no profits!
You sold the gear for half.
What part of that simple mathematical
equation don't you understand.
- It's all profits, mate.
I didn't pay for it.
- He's going to kill you.
- I'll talk to George.
I'll sort this out.
He'll listen to me.
- I don't need you fighting my battles.
- You need a coffin, mate.
- Badge.
Give it a rest.
- He shouldn't bumped me from that fight.
All I wanted was that
chance, that one fight.
I could've beaten him.
- Who?
- Missile.
Me versus Missile, mate.
Title fight.
I have my right to
fight and I worked hard.
I beat the piece of shit wankers
he put in front of me,
and could barely stand
up straight in a ring.
But I did my time.
I beat them one by fucking one.
He just wanted me on the leash,
like the one he had on you.
But I can't be leashed.
I'm a demon.
I'm a winner.
- He's gonna kill you.
He really is.
- So be it then, mate.
So be it.
At least I'll be free of this shit.
- There is this squire.
I know who he is.
You feel it.
Hear the trimmings on the ground.
Just squire.
I know it is the squire.
I can smell it even.
It makes me uncomfortable.
I never asked my dad for nothing.
Not even solitary shilling, never once.
I was proud little turd.
- No one's ever beaten me.
That means something to me.
I don't even fight anymore.
But it means something.
- To live is the rarest
thing in the world.
Most people exist.
That's all.
Oscar fucking Wilde.
- What does that mean, George?
- Riots.
Pointless.
The few always beat the many.
Aggression is such a
primitive human response.
More powerful is that of
silence and stillness.
That's the sign of a true man.
Adversity
followed by restraint.
- Maybe,
if you give him a bit more time,
he can pay it back.
- The reason
the few beat the many
is the many are typically
stumbling.
The few
are elite.
That's why there's so few.
Life, my dear,
is simple.
One goes down,
another makes money.
One does right,
happy ending.
Exit own this.
- Chris.
Can't lose.
I just can't.
- Of course,
the Hindus believe in reincarnation.
But if you come back as yourself?
- Hi, madam.
My name's Daniel.
I work for Natural Gas.
I'd love to talk to you about
your current gas provider.
- Gas?
- Yes, madam.
I'd love to come in and talk to you about
how we can benefit you.
- Okay.
You want to come through.
- Yeah, sure, thank you.
- It's something with those riots.
It's terrible, isn't it?
They shouldn't have shot that black guy.
That's police racism.
- Well, if he was a criminal,
then maybe...
Oh that's awful.
- A little bit.
- Any trouble down your way?
- No.
- Oh, nothing here either.
I was watching the TV earlier.
It's the mainly the whites
that are causing all of the problems.
The world's gone mad.
- So, I'd really like to show you
what our policies are and
how we can save you money.
Let me show you on the tablet.
- What's that?
- It's our policies,
our savings and many...
For what?
- For the gas we provide, madam.
I told you earlier.
- Oh, I thought it was the telephone.
- Oh, no.
- I'm so sorry.
- I did say gas earlier, madam.
- Oh I wasn't listening.
I'm so sorry.
I don't need gas.
- Everyone needs gas.
Mine is perfectly alright.
- You should still look at our policies.
- I'll look but I won't
be going with you guys.
- No problem.
- I'm sorry.
Oh no, don't put it away.
I mean, I'll look.
- There's no point.
- But don't put it away
because I might be swayed.
- Do you think so, madam?
- Not really, actually.
Sorry.
- I'm gonna go.
Well done.
- Well done?
- For not rioting.
- I have no need to, madam.
I have a job.
- Just well done.
- This country needs more young men
like you.
- Thank you.
- Okay, I'll show you out.
- Do you enjoy your job?
Yup.
I'm serious.
It's alright.
Do you wish
you were back in the ring.
Nope.
- I'm asking you serious
questions here, come on.
- What do you want me to say?
I hate my job and I'd rather go back to
beating the crap out of humans.
If that's how you feel, yes.
All I'm asking is for
you to be honest with me.
- Honest?
You're starting to sound like
a Charlotte Bronte novel.
I'm gonna stop calling you mermaid
and call you Charlotte.
- Charlotte Bronte?
Magnificent reference.
Did they teach you that when
you were in public school?
- Unfortunately.
Torture.
- Yeah okay, I hated it too.
- Really?
So why do you sound like one
every time we speak then?
- Your mum.
- I see you.
I'm serious.
Do you enjoy your job?
Who enjoys their job?
It pays.
- You could always come
work with me if you wanted.
- Arrange weddings?
Sure.
Where do I sign?
- I'm sorry sir, but the
position has just been filled.
We decided to go for someone in the
opposite end of the color spectrum.
- Ah, fresh racism.
My favourite.
Yum.
Tasty.
- Dan, if you hate it,
quit.
- Life ain't that simple.
Commitment and loyalty is everything.
So is our rent.
- Life is that simple.
We're given choices from birth.
I chose you.
It's our greatest weapon.
Choice.
- You're right.
- I'm always right.
- Sometimes.
- No, I'm always right.
It's called being a woman.
- No.
I think I need to fight one last time.
- You think you do?
- No, it's a situation.
- Situation?
Talk.
- My mate, Chris.
He's a good guy.
- Yeah a real charming fellow.
- He is.
Maybe if you met him a couple more times.
- I have requested such an occasion
and you have yet to grant me this.
- We've been busy.
- Oh what, we embarrassed?
- Of what?
- Definitely not me.
I'm way too pretty.
I think maybe.
- No.
- Maybe he's like a window into your past,
something you don't want me to view.
Maybe the view isn't...
Anyway.
He's got into some shit.
- And you fighting is gonna
solve his life problems
and his mentality towards life.
- No, but I...
- If so, then by all means, indulge.
- My old manager George,
he wants me to fight him and lose.
- Oh George, such proper geezers.
- Well, that's the long and short of it.
- And this solves the problem how?
- If I lose, George makes money.
- Are you sure?
Because it seems to me like George
is trying to teach you a lesson
in the face of Chris's transgressions.
- Maybe.
- By the way,
is this us discussing it
or are you telling me
this is gonna happen?
- Honestly,
both.
- You don't need to fight anymore.
I can't do it.
- Do what?
- Fight you.
- You mean lose to me.
- Yeah.
- I might beat you, mate.
- It's unlikely.
- Cocky for someone who
ain't even swung an arm
in 18 months.
- No, I mean I ain't fighting you.
- Okay.
- Is that it?
Okay.
I mean, I'll fight you but I can't lose.
I just can't.
- What do you want me to do?
Oh please, Stally.
Please fight me and lose
so you can save my life.
Is that what you want?
- Yeah.
- Go fuck yourself.
- Mate.
I'm unbeaten.
It means something to me.
- I took three months for you.
Don't you forget that.
- Did you know there are over
150 billion stars in the sky.
That's roughly the same amount of people
who have ever lived.
- That means that one
day, we can all be a star.
And a shooting star would be a star
that has excelled in this life.
Because a shooting star gets to see
the whole entire universe in death.
I wanna be that star.
And that one.
You want to be all the stars.
- Every last one of them.
Don't you?
Is that it?
- What?
I'm not losing to you.
- So now you're fighting?
But you're not losing.
Or you're not fighting at all.
Make your mind up, son.
- You don't wanna fight?
Argue?
Get your point across.
This fight could save your life.
I'll save your life.
What?
What's so fucking funny?
- You are, mate.
Save my life.
Save your life, fuck you.
- If I don't fight you, he'll kill you.
- Don't then, mate.
- Why are you so determined to fuck up?
Did you piss George off
just to fuck my shit up?
Missed me so much,
you did some stupid shit to get me back
in your fucked up life?
- No I fucked up because I am a fuck up.
- Damn right, you are.
Your shit is fucking up my shit.
- Your shit?
What?
Your perfect life in some swanky flat?
With your virgin white girl?
Your unbeaten record?
You're not Mike Tyson, mate.
This is amateur fucking boxing.
You only got that record because of me.
I took three months for you.
You should've been behind bars
when you're beating those dudes.
But instead you're beating
a six-month stretch
because of me.
- Leave it.
- No.
I took the rap.
I'm the fuck with a criminal record.
I'm the fucker who took
your fucking drug charges,
Mr. Fucking Unbeaten.
- Leave it.
- Do you know why?
Because George told me to.
Because fucking George told me to.
You were the safer bet.
You'd make him more fucking money.
The man sentences me to the slammer
so that you can make
him more fucking money.
I'm pretty sure there's some irony there.
- I thanked you over and over again.
I've been behind you over and over again.
Chris,
this time I can't.
I don't wanna die.
I don't want to die.
I only ever wanted to be someone.
I just wanted to be...
Just six rounds with me Stall, mate.
Just six rounds.
- Alright.
Alright.
Remember our first dance.
It was to some hip-hop track.
You insisted we slam dance to it.
Yep.
It was you and I dancing.
You and your
mermaid-like dress.
- Some heavy bass hip-hop track,
whilst everyone else was
freaking out on the dance floor.
- Freaking out?
Is that a term?
It is now.
- That's never going to be a term.
- I remember thinking
that this guy is the definition
of going against the grain.
I wanted to fuck you right there and then.
- It took you that long?
I kinda thought that when I first saw you.
- It makes sense.
I'm incredibly hot.
- I was thinking that about
most girls I saw that night.
You were the only one stupid
enough to dance with me.
- Well clearly, I'm incredibly hot
but incredibly stupid.
By fighting, you're
symbolically telling me
you're never gonna be detached from it.
- It?
- It.
- Boxing.
- It's a bit more complex than that.
Someone's life's at stake.
What should I do?
Let him get taken out?
Let him suffer?
- Yes.
- Wow.
I always liked you because you're...
Because I'm intelligent.
Because I'm ambitious,
because I know what I want.
Save it, I've heard it all before.
You're in awe of me because,
in your mind,
I'm something you cannot have.
I take you to a place
you could only dream of.
You don't believe you deserve me.
You don't.
I'm real.
You're fake.
- What are you talking about?
What are you talking about?
I wanna be with you because I love you.
Simple as that.
- Nothing's ever that simple, Dan.
Or should I call you Stally?
Nothing's ever that simple.
When you fuck me at night,
what do you see?
More highrises.
No hustling.
No heavy burdens.
- What are you talking about?
Fucking hell.
Listen, if you wanna fuck off,
fuck off.
- That's the easy option for me.
- Do it then.
Fuck off.
- Okay.
- Where are you going?
Where are you going?
No, no, no, no.
I need you.
Stay.
Fucking stay.
♫ How I ever went without you
♫ Is a mystery
♫ Searching for my heart
♫ Til you threw away the key
Shut up.
- Fuck off.
Fuck off.
I'm a fucking loser.
I can't fucking lose.
Why not?
I can't fucking be beaten.
I can't be fucking beaten.
Why would I lose?
Why would I be beaten?
Why not?
Fucking why not?
I can't fucking lose.
So I am.
Fucking.
Fucking why?
What's around me
is all I have.
It's fucking all I have.
Shit.
She's my fucking life.
Do you not want me in it?
- I don't need you.
Don't need you.
I don't need anyone.
- No one's ever beat me.
That means something to me.
I don't even fight anymore.
Fuck.
Please.
It means something.
No wait.
No, no wait.
I can't lose that.
I can't fucking lose that.
I can't lose it.
I have no mother.
I have no fucking father.
I fucking did it by myself.
I got it by myself.
I worked my way up all by myself.
All by myself.
No help.
I'm gonna fucking stay unbeaten, me.
I'm fucking unbeaten Stall.
I am.
I can't lose that.
I can't fucking lose that.
I have half of her.
One whole brain.
One half heart.
You hold the key to my iron lung.
When I breathe, you lock the door.
I keep hearing poetry.
I hear poetry of all.
Keeping my mind at bay.
Don't leave.
I'm sure.
I make decisions.
I make choices.
I made decisions.
And I made choices.
Choices.
I made decisions.
I made choices.