Do not forget your papers.
Everything is good.
No reason to be nervous.
- I'm not nervous.
You look really handsome today.
- I gotta go.
I have to work late tonight.
Your lunch is in the refrigerator.
Give me a kiss.
- Mom, I would prefer ...
Go ahead, otherwise you will still be late.
Okay people, sit down.
We have much work to do today.
We begin where we stopped yesterday
with physics projects.
Remember to people. This contract,
counts for 50% extra for your figure.
So if I turn a light
battery see,
or a volcano with bath salts.
I'll send you back to the second class.
What can I do for you?
I'm new.
Welcome.
Just wait, come here.
I would like to introduce you nicely.
Everyone.
This is Kyle Barrett.
Where are you from Kyle?
Everywhere and nowhere.
Okay, I believe I have ever been.
A couple of times.
Find a spot.
Okay everyone, back to work.
Look where we are now,
with our projects.
We ended yesterday with Cindy.
And today we start with Jason Mclntyre.
Come forward Jason.
Stop laughing.
There is nothing funny to.
Sit still, please.
Jason, what happened?
I stumbled.
It was an accident.
He did it.
Sorry.
He let him stumble.
Is that true?
Jason is that true?
He lies.
Richard, you go directly
to the office of Mr. Armstrong.
I do so.
- What a nonsense.
Now, I said.
They lie.
Go.
Everyone stay calm and remain seated.
We go back to our work.
You're dead.
You picked the bucket, what David suit
paper wipes, everyone remains seated.
You go pay,
because you helped him in the classroom.
McIntyre?
Guys, please
Hey bag.
I'm suspended for two weeks.
Any idea,
what my old man is going to do with me?
This.
Hey, I'm still not ready.
Get him, Rick.
I grab him, keep him quiet.
Kyle watch out.
I'm Jason.
Jason McIntyre.
Hey, where did you learn to fight?
What do you want from me?
I want to thank you.
You know and ...
I thought maybe we could be friends.
Or something.
You should not let you fool,
by those guys.
I know.
I think,
which I boy who got his nose broken.
Really?
- Yes, I think so.
I have lived a while in Denver.
Have you ever been?
There I lived
in San Antonio in Texas.
And in Chicago.
Since I was born.
Have you ever been?
You traveled around a lot.
Why?
No idea.
- What does your father?
I have no father.
Actually ...
Somehow, I think.
I've never met him.
This is Jack.
Who is Jack?
Rick's brother.
Are you new?
Are you the brother of the nursery?
He said you two,
with a few friends, have robbed him.
That is not,
how I remember.
You call my brother a liar?
- Yes, absolutely.
Listen codger.
Let me tell you something,
what everyone in this stupid town already knows.
Nobody, except me, save my brother.
You understand that?
Catch them, let them not escape.
Here is your chain, bastard.
You ball ...
Dirk, get in the car.
- Jack, is it?
They, in our view, get out.
They are not killed,
I do not want any trouble.
Here he comes.
We drive too fast man, driving slowly.
- Slow down, Jack.
Faster.
Jack, what are you gonna do?
Slower.
- Jack, let it sit, okay?
We deal with them tomorrow.
- Shut up.
Watch out for that truck.
Come on, back there.
I go with him.
- Keep you sit.
Jack, please.
Sorry.
- Get outta here here.
Watch out.
From the road.
Sorry.
Get out.
Road, going from the road.
Man, you almost hit him.
- Almost.
Where?
- There is a ski jump.
We try to jump over the canal.
Nobody has ever tried.
That never succeed.
If we do not go fast enough,
we get it.
They are dead.
- That there has been.
Holy ...
- Hell.
It is our success.
I'm going to murder that child.
That was crazy man.
- No one will believe us.
There were witnesses at.
Who, these two idiots?
That will not repeat.
Yes, you're right.
Man, we jumped on the channel.
Maybe someone has seen us.
Nobody saw it.
- So we must do it again.
Just do again.
- I do not yet agree.
Where are we going?
- I see you so well.
Look.
Hello Uncle Ed.
- Hey partner, no problem, I hope?
Well.
- Something to drink?
Thank you.
Who is your friend?
- This is Kyle, he's new in the city.
Is this your plane?
Uncle Ed save for their own plane.
Do you like airplanes?
No idea.
No idea?
I've never flown.
Do you do this often?
- As often as I can.
I may never my mother,
they hate flying.
Why is that?
- I do not know.
My grandfather was pilot,
in the Second World War.
He shot down 17 enemy planes.
He is a hero.
He is alive,
if you want, you can meet him.
Again.
We are far too late for dinner.
Thank you Uncle Ed.
- Yes, thank you Mr. Thomas.
It is all right, let's say Ed.
Say no to your mother,
I've flown with you.
Love you kidding me?
- And certainly say nothing about that spin.
Or about those somersault.
Or that nosedive.
Shall we again tomorrow?
- And the school then?
We have no school tomorrow.
Is that so?
- Yes, teachers consultations.
Really, huh?
Okay, come to seven hours to the airport.
- Seven o'clock in the morning?
Yes, we are going to make a couple's somersault
and ensure that you are at school on time.
Nice to meet you Kyle.
- Yes, same to you.
Hey, make sure your nose clean.
- We are not ready for eight hours.
Did your uncle with your impact?
- Of course not.
This is Kyle, he's new here.
We have great hunger.
Stop blowing bubbles, baby.
- This is already two months on date.
If there is no mold on state
it is still good.
Katie, if you do not stop,
there is no puppy.
Who said anything about a puppy?
- Hey, we can call him Ace?
That is a stupid name.
- So they called Grandpa.
Okay, we are still talking about it.
Like Grandpa wants, that a dog
is named after him, little gay.
Sorry, what?
Such words we use here.
What's a gay?
This is not just word.
See what you did?
You would be an example
for her to be.
Can I maybe some chicken?
- Of course, grab a drum stick.
There is also still a pup.
He does not talk more,
since he has the surgery twice.
That is okay, he talked not much anyway.
He was always on the veranda
and smoked a lot.
I do not know why they bring him his meals.
He almost never eat something.
Grandpa.
Here is your food.
Are you hungry?
You want some water.
See you there.
That he received for saving a pilot,
when they were both shot.
He took it from there sometimes,
for them to show me.
Then we began to polish them.
You had me today
not only must leave behind.
Since that alley.
When that thing with Jack.
You had no way to go.
I'm sorry.
I thought that you have saved.
And did you, or not? You came out.
And if I did not
road could have been?
Earlier at school, I helped you.
You had to help me.
I'm sorry.
I was scared.
It is all right.
We have reports, or not?
Are we already in the area, Kyle?
It's here somewhere.
That one, with the lights on.
- Is that your house?
Are you sure?
- Yes, that's him.
Thank you.
Today I had great fun.
- Me, too.
See you tomorrow morning.
Are you here, or at the airport?
I see you in the channel.
Nice to meet you Kyle.
- Nice to meet you.
Sorry I'm late.
- Ready to go?
I have taken walkie-talkies.
Let us now but around bicycles.
This is so cool.
Owns one of your uncle here?
No, he maintains them alone.
Hey, come take a look.
Can this be?
- Yes, everyone here knows me, I'll do this more often.
Is it difficult to fly?
- No, Ed taught me how.
He takes me everywhere.
You want something really gaafs see?
Where are we going?
- Wait and see.
What are you doing?
That is so cool.
- Great, huh.
What type is it?
Wait until you see the cockpit.
Wait.
Are you sure this is okay?
- Sure. Here is none.
Look.
- It looks like a camper or something.
Yes, come inside.
Do not. Nowhere in print.
- Calm down, I do nothing.
Not start, okay?
Want to see what gaafs?
Put your hand on it.
Look at the wings.
What have you done?
- Nothing.
Hide.
That is probably the owner, we gotta get outta here.
- No, they will see us.
Hide it.
Fast.
The walkietalkie.
We gotta get outta here.
And what if he goes off?
They probably just find something.
They go off
It is time to go.
They have weapons.
What should we do?
What do you think we go?
- No idea.
There is always something bad happens,
if you spijbelt.
What do you see?
There are still more.
Where are we?
I do not know.
Are we on car?
- Are you crazy.
Maybe now we fly back.
Maybe.
Wake up.
Come on, wake up.
What time is it?
I need to find the bathroom,
I needed to pee.
I am hungry.
Would this be something to eat?
Come here.
Is that what I think it is?
Where's the door?
No idea.
Where is everybody?
I do not know.
We tell the pilot, fast.
You should fly.
- I can not fly.
You said you could fly.
- No, not this one.
He is huge, there are too many buttons.
This is not the same.
You gotta fly, otherwise we die.
And that bomb then?
You fly, and I care for the bomb.
I can not fly.
SOS.
Help, please.
My name is Jason McIntyre.
I'm just a kid.
Hello, help me.
Can anybody hear me?
What are you doing?
- I have the bomb.
And that drag you here?
- What should I do with it then?
Sucker away with it.
- Outdoor throw?
Help me, please.
SOS.
Is there someone, anyone hear me?
Are you lost him?
Can anybody hear me?
Is anybody there?
Answer.
Please, is there anyone?
Is anybody there?
I think that we will get that mountain.
Jason, I think it is.
Well then.
What should we do?
- We must act.
Pull on, hurry up.
You must help me.
What are you doing?
- I try him stabilization.
What should I do?
- Take off your belt to.
Help me to stabilize him.
That is too many.
- Go right.
We need countries,
for we have no more fuel.
Where do we land?
- On an airport or a road.
I see neither.
I see a road,
further to the left.
Slow.
I pull him right.
And what now.
- I know a lot.
What does Ed, before he lands?
- I do not know anymore.
Come on,
which buttons to press him?
Landing.
Look at something that state.
Okay, I got it.
Should I print out?
And now?
The flaps should be lowered.
- Press?
We drive a plane.
What was that?
Turbulence.
I hope.
Are you sure that this is going to succeed?
There are too many cars,
this does not succeed.
I hope that those cars we see coming.
- Of course it does, here we go.
There are too many cars.
We're going too fast.
- I know.
Are those cars still on the side?
- I do not know.
From the road.
Keep him stable.
- That I try, help me.
On the side.
And back to right now.
We have no horn or something?
- Airplanes have no horn.
From the road.
Watch out for that truck.
Trap on the brake.
- He does not stop.
This thing has no brakes?
- Stop.
We are like this.
Is everything okay?
- I do not think I need more to the bathroom.
Thank you!
- Would you like coffee?
Can I take your order record, sir?
Wake up please.
- That very sorry. Is it?
Does it hurt?
I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
Can you see anything?
- No, not really.
But I can call an ambulance,
if you want.
Would you like coffee?
- Yes, one liter or four, if possible.
Thank you!
Milk?
Sugar?
- No, thank you
Would you order something?
Surprise me.
This is a fantastic story boys,
can you tell what happened?
We were on board
and suddenly there was no pilot more ....
That is my son
- That is my cousin.
And Jason was in the cockpit ...
Jason, how can you have countries?
Kyle threw the bomb out
and helped me in the cockpit.
And helped me to have a mountain to fly.
- Hello Jason.
The plane will remain here,
the owner is known.
We take the two boys in custody,
they did something that clearly was not.
There is no evidence,
that there were problems with this plane.
There is no evidence of a crime.
- One of ours?
The police are still mistrustful ...
- Those kids are super.
We think that there are about four million
on board was this week.
Most comes from the casino.
There is nothing found on board.
Find out who did this.
- That all may have been Angelo.
Search Carmine.
And call my brother.
The police is outside,
the plane leads to you.
They want a few questions.
Super, keep them busy Sal,
make them a couple sandwiches, or something.
Okay, I call Silvio.
- Good.
I want my plane back.
I want to know who did this,
so I 'm can be murder.
And I also want to talk with those guys.
That is regulated.
We have been there.
- This is unbelievable.
What should we do?
What should we do, man?
Silvio, where have you been?
Silvio, where are you?
Listen. Kloten man.
Lenny and I were from
and we missed the plane.
You know what happened?
- Only that what I saw on the news.
What is wrong?
Do you know who did this?
Not yet.
- Can I do something?
Yes, I want you to come here.
To the house?
- Yes, to the house.
I am currently not
whom I have confidence.
It may have been an inside job.
I need you here.
I am tomorrow.
Great.
- I see you then.
We go to Angelo.
- You like me for a ride?
If we disappear,
he knows that we were.
We have the money, let's flights,
Mexico, somewhere, let's disappearance.
We can go nowhere.
Wherever we go,
he will find us.
And if he can find us, he will kill us.
What about those children?
When they saw us now agree?
We must find those children.
Mom, Dad, they're there.
Hello men, come inside.
Son, what have you done?
You got house arrest.
Is everything okay?
- Yes, I've missed you.
Mom?
Take a few lessons before you
with a twin plane will fly.
Mom.
It feels good to be home.
This is not our home.
This is just a motel,
until we have a house.
It feels like home.
Really.
Soft dream, boy.
Sleep good.
Do not bite the bedbeestjes.
Hey Lenny.
Have you ever thought,
a child to murder?
But I do it, if necessary.
Hi guys.
Hi Jason, how are you?
- Good.
Nice.
The second day at school
and everybody knows me al
I know. We are in the news
and in all newspapers.
They call us the Flyboys.
Really?
- Yes, seriously.
Some children asked a signature.
- No shit.
No, I mean it.
Oh, man.
How do we get from them.
- What should we do?
Run away, no idea.
I'm special agent Clinton and this is Agent ...
- Bush.
We are of the FBI.
We wish you happy
a few questions.
Are you with us?
Yes, OK, of course.
Along here.
What a lucky,
that they were long.
I told you that we
in the break had to intervene.
They sit in high school.
Then we have this bag of candy
finds no longer needed.
We need to Angelo.
- What, are you crazy?
He has children.
They can identify us.
We do not even know whether they saw us,
we need to see him.
This is insane.
If we do not go,
He thinks a moment,
that we were.
He said that he wanted people around them,
he could trust.
There was very happy to adopt you.
What do you mean?
- Eat some more candy, but again.
Where do we go?
Quiet guy, we like that.
Hey, if you like beer or soda,
there is behind a refrigerator.
I do not believe,
FBl that people driving Cadillacs.
Come boy.
Whose house is it?
- From Mr. Angelo Esposito.
He wants to thank you,
for saving his plane.
Come on guys, but quiet.
Come, it's good.
Hey, the Flyboys.
How does it feel to be famous?
The boss wants to see them.
Sal, bring the boys to the dungeon.
The dungeon?
Do not worry,
so we called the cellar. Come on.
You can play,
what you want.
Behind the bar and fridge,
is filled with snacks and fresh.
Pretend you're at home.
Mr. Esposito comes in a few minutes.
Okay, thank you
Gaafs something I have never seen.
Weapons.
Difficulties with the boys?
- No, these are good guys.
Well.
If something goes wrong, we should quickly leave.
- If it goes wrong, I shoot first.
Give me the keys.
- That little bastards.
Give me the car keys.
Why?
- Now.
Do nothing, before I do something, understand?
Silvio is there,
with that stupid friend of him.
Bring Silvio here
and keep the other busy, okay?
Angelo wants to see you downstairs.
Is that where children are?
- Lenny, are you hungry?
Sal, give him a sandwich.
- I care for him.
I am sorry for what happened.
Not half as sorry,
as the person who did this will have.
Do you have something done by guys?
No, I have not talked with them.
Look.
Thus did we have fun.
The two of us.
That was long ago.
Not so long ago.
I've paid your debts by Hiroshi.
I got paid, you're free.
I have not said,
because I wish you would learn something.
We now have more important things,
to keep us busy.
I tell you,
so you can focus on this.
Do you remember when we were kids?
You had a tape recorder
and I could not arrive.
On one evening,
when mom and dad were fighting back.
I was so scared and you knew that I just
quiet again would be if you let me listen.
Bad Company.
I know the year, 1974.
I fell asleep to that music.
I thought.
My brother will always care for me.
- I do too.
I'm glad you're here.
Come, go get something to eat.
I'm going to see what these kids know, okay?
I got you.
- Loser.
You is not even close.
You almost had me.
I have touched you.
- No, not true. I've touched you, too.
I saw you hit bone.
- I felt nothing.
This is not?
- This does not count, you can not shoot.
I do not hear called timeout.
- All right, timeout.
Who is that?
- No idea. But we deal with him.
Let your arms fall,
and come out with your hands up.
You get me not live in isolation.
- Okay, I count to three, then we tackle him.
One, two, three.
Search Kyle coverage.
- Cover me.
I got him.
Not true.
- Attacks, now.
Search coverage.
Come on, cover me.
Hey you, you can hear me,
you're there.
He does not easily,
Come on.
Wait.
You're dead.
You're dead, whoever you are.
You should better do your best,
if you want to tackle me.
Do not move.
You have me to deal with.
- Who are you?
When you hear the good or the bad?
- That depends on who asks.
Give you about?
Stop.
- You too.
I got you, too.
Grab his weapon.
- I got you.
Do you need help boss?
Maybe, stay in the neighborhood.
Exactly between his eyes.
He has future.
- A nice shot, huh?
Okay guys, we go up.
Get off me. I'm old.
You guys are rough. Nice shot.
- Thank you!
Have you to your sense here?
You bet.
You do me to my two boys think.
They are about as old.
Where are they?
They do not live here.
They live in Boston, with their mother.
I see them not as often.
Therefore, you have this room.
- Yes, I made them for him.
But I do not use it often enough.
Anyway ...
I want to thank you,
for saving my plane.
Of course.
- No problem.
I've brought you here,
because I want to give you something special.
Ask what you want.
Do you think that?
I want you to think about it,
make a good choice, OK?
Whatever you want.
Cool huh.
Can I ask you what,
when you think about it?
Of course.
- Ask.
The police do not know who you guys up there
let alone, so I must pick it yourself.
The men who did this,
have something taken away from me.
Two large bags.
- What was in?
Personal things,
I mean many things.
Have you seen these men?
Boys.
These are Kyle and Jason.
You see him there,
that the food in his mouth packed?
His name is Lenny, the loser.
Believe me, it's true.
The other is my brother.
His name is Silvio.
- Nice.
Similarly.
- Sal, give them some ice.
Which flavor whatsoever.
- Come on guys.
I do so, okay.
What did they say?
- They have not seen anything.
They even knew what the bags Saturday.
Bring the boys home, it's getting late,
I do not want to go ask their parents.
I need to call,
I am so down.
This will you find tasty.
Snacks and lolly's.
Since I always get energy.
Here, take it.
Have you, you are entertained?
Listen. Let's keep this secret,
as something between us.
How about with you guys want?
Have you already thought something?
Not yet.
Think about it there,
if you know something, call me.
Whatever you want.
Whatever.
My brother brings you back home,
make it easy with him,
he is not nearly as tough as we do.
See you guys.
- Bye.
Bring the boys home
Lenny and make sure you lose.
Then come back, then we eat,
you and me.
Day.
- See you guys.
They have not recognized us.
- Shut up.
No smoking.
I got my ice.
Where should I leave the cover?
Throw it on the ground.
Silvio Hey, your brother is cool.
I like him.
- Yes, me too.
I wonder,
why someone would steal something from him?
Look.
Beautiful.
- Hey, how are you there?
Angelo has given us.
Do you think that guys who deal with them?
- No idea, kid.
What would happen to them,
if he gets them?
No more questions.
Time for a nap.
I wish that you had yours.
Those men in the aircraft,
have taken him, I guess.
Give agree.
Hey, Angelo's men
come back to you ...
Can I go to the bathroom?
- You're going nowhere, son.
If our something happens,
they know that you were.
You bring us,
in a delicate position.
Put the gun away.
- Why were they in that plane?
- It was not them, that's a foul.
Put the gun down, now.
You have violated the law
and now you pay.
He is your brother, he will forgive you.
- Shut up.
You continue to sit there,
Lenny step.
Get out of the car, now.
- Why?
If you try to flee,
I shoot you down.
I swear.
What are we doing here?
I told you that you walkie-talkie
had to leave.
That was a bad idea.
What should we do?
- We come here not leaving.
Later someone sees us,
we should work with the children in the desert.
I'm not Lenny murder children.
- Well, I do it, let's go.
You also do not.
What should we do?
Hire someone, to do it?
These guys should disappear.
It is past Lenny.
We need to tell Angelo.
Do you think he forgives us?
Do you think he forgives me?
- Shut up.
Stupid idiot.
This was not done, if you walkie-talkie
on the plane had left behind.
You don 't understand, huh?
He has repaid Hiroshi.
Angelo trusted me.
Silvio, listen.
- Shut up.
This is not in your head, huh?
Because you're stupid. You're an idiot.
I have betrayed my own brother,
because of money.
You are not me two million decrease
because you suddenly have a conscience.
Run away.
Run.
- Here along.
Help us, please.
One at a time.
What happens here?
Stop boy,
I just want to talk to you.
I wish you nothing ports,
I just wanted to ask a question.
Kyle,
please answer, you hear me.
He is here kid.
And I agree. Listen well,
I say this only once.
You come in 15 minutes,
to the hangar of Angelo.
15 minutes.
And not a second later.
Talk to anyone.
With no one.
Not with the police.
Not with an adult.
If you're not afraid to come,
or if you come with others to you,
I pop a bullet in the head
of your little boyfriend.
Do you understand me?
Well.
15 minutes.
Go.
Come on.
Silvio, wait I get Angelo.
These vegetables are overcooked,
I blew it.
He says, tell him that I regret.
- Angelo, excuse me.
What happened?
You sound strange, what is it?
Say on, what is it?
Lenny and I have done something stupid.
I could not tell, but I wanted to do ...
You stole the money.
He stole the money.
I'm tipsy Ang.
Make the helicopter ready.
- He shot me in my back.
- You're shot, where? In your back?
I can not breathe.
Listen, calm down.
- I can not breathe.
Easy. Where are you?
Ang.
- I'm here.
He wants to murder children
and then catch a plane.
Ang?
- Yes, I'm here boy.
I can not breathe.
- Yes, that get you. Where are you?
You must say where you are,
so that we can come and collect them.
We will fetch you.
But you must say where you are.
Where are you?
Stop it.
Do you remember that song yet?
- Which song?
Thank you,
for me that you've ensured Ang.
Come on.
Come boy.
Faster.
What is wrong?
- Are you a pilot?
Sit down.
It seems as if your size is not.
Coward who let you die.
He is not a coward.
O no?
Where is he?
What happens here?
- Are you a pilot?
Kyle, is everything okay?
Good answer.
You fly me here.
I fly nowhere,
unless you let the boy go.
And if I die instantly once you shoot?
- Okay, I'll do it.
Can you drive this plane?
- Yes.
Not look at him, look at me.
- Okay, yes, I can drive this plane.
Come on.
We get something from the trunk.
Come boy.
Come on.
Back to the plane.
Give me that.
Faster.
Come on, hurry up.
Bring this thing moving.
Sit down.
Come on.
Listen, I fly you to where you want to go.
Let the kid go.
- Shut up.
Or I care that he is no longer important.
Flies with this stupid airplane.
The plane is still not refueled.
How far do you want?
- Fly but to the south.
I got a destination needed.
Mexico.
Cooper, to tower ...
- No talking, just leave.
Sit down boy.
Fly now.
I'm glad you could come.
You dare do.
Listen, we need somewhere refueling.
Take me high enough,
so I can jump.
What are you looking at?
Angelo is your murder.
Time to go kid.
- Ed help, he has Kyle.
I make you.
Jason, take on the plane.
Ed, help.
I get 'm not under control.
He zwabbert there.
I can not check him Ed.
Kyle watch out.
Jason, come here.
Get the parachute.
I make you.
Hang on.
Jason, I got you, hang in there.
I must put on the parachute.
Help.
You like to me.
Hang on.
Help.
Keep your right.
I got you, hold on to me.
Love so tightly as you can.
Let me not go.
- Hold on. Firmly.
I pull the parachute open.
- Hold me.
Here we go.
Watch out.
Okay, hold on.
Is everything okay?
Everything okay?
- I thought that I was going to die ...
It is good.
It is our success.
Everything is good.
This is Angelo.
Everything good?
Guys, are you okay?
Unbelievable.
I saw you in the air.
Lenny has Silvio shot.
I know.
- Silvio wanted to save us.
Where is Lenny?
Fly.
Stupid airplane flight.
Well.
I need to know where my brother is.
Can you cause me to him?
And it now?
Let's go.
Here it is.
Drive through.
Driving by, Vince.
I'm sorry boss.
- Excuse me, too.
I will never forget
what you have done today.
We're sorry for your plane.
I do not for that plane,
or for the money.
Have you already decided,
what I can do for you?
You know what?
I got something.
I think of something fun.
You did great up there.
You are ...
unbelievable.
I needed a pilot, would you ...
Thank you.
But ...
Of course.
I bring these men just go home.
Yes. Good luck.
- Thank you, you, too.
Is everything good guys?
Not to tell your mom.
I see you guys later, Flyboys.
To look.
I'm sorry, I lied to you.
We do not live in that house,
that I showed you.
My Mom and I live in a hotel.
We try to save.
It does not matter to me where you live.
It is all right.
Thank you.
You're the best friend,
that I've ever had.
That goes for me.
I see you tomorrow?
Yes, a new day full of adventure.
We take each other in the channel, OK?
- I will be there.
Hello boy, where have you been?
Have you already seen the newspaper?
You're a hero.
AIRCRAFT READY
BY 12 YEARS Flyboys.
You are dirty. Go out and knock you off,
wash your hands, we eat in five minutes.
Mom ...
- Now.
Grandpa?
What are you doing here?
I get it.
This?
Would you?
This was for bravery.
Thank you Grandpa.
How was your day?
Well.
At work we had everybody over,
that was you in the newspaper.
You're quite a celebrity.
And you?
How was your day at school?
You're in my light.
I said ...
What can I do for you gentlemen?
Wait.
Is your attention,
Rick suddenly makes that nice?
Yes, you're right.
They saw us on TV.
- Yes, probably.
Wait, no one talked about a plane,
with an open cockpit.
You can no longer retreat.
Trust me, you'll find the magnificent.
You'll see the sunset at 2400 feet.
- Mom, it will come good, come.
Okay, I trust you.
- It is beautiful.
Hey, you can not park here.
- Are you Ed Thomas?
With the compliments of Angelo Exposito.
Sorry, I can not accept.
- Of course it does.
There is nothing in commitment.
Really?
- Really.
There is obviously a prerequisite to adopt.
You have to go fly with the boys,
as often as they want.
This is a joke, right?
- Hey, this is no joke, okay.
This is a brand new airplane
and it is all yours.
Is it?
Well. Enjoy it.
A brand new airplane?
Who is Angelo Esposito?
That is a long story.
Let's go fly.
Heaven.
- This is cool.
Put your belts around.
Are you ready?
What are we waiting for?
Let's go.
Okay, then.
Look what this box can.