(slow rock and roll music)
- [Voiceover] This is KFAT radio.
K F A T Lakeside, it's straight up 10 o'clock
with Captain Fogel on a beautiful moonlit night!
(woman gasps)
- Wow, I thought we were the only people
that knew about this place.
- I guess not.
- Well, who is it?
Your wife? (gasps)
Sorry, only kidding.
Sorry.
- That's Skip Thompson's jeep.
And the Mustang belongs to Kevin Matthews.
- Oh Dave, I don't like this, let's just keep going.
I don't want those kids to see us together.
If word ever got back.
Hello, I'm talking!
- Shh!
Quiet for just a minute.
- Well, what's wrong?
- I don't hear anything.
- Maybe they're all making out.
Like we should be doing, come on!
- I'm gonna check this out.
♪ With the keys to your heart
♪ With the keys to your mind
♪ Stand open to life
(tense ambient music)
(woman screaming)
What in the hell?
- It's Buzz!
Hey Dave, it's buzz, it's buzz.
- Shit, you guys!
- [Long-haired boy] Scare ya?
- Hey man, hey Dave, we didn't mean to scare ya that much.
- Yeah, sorry about that.
Sally Jean?
Say, what are you guys doing out here anyway?
- Maybe I oughta ask you the same thing.
- Beginning of a four day weekend, Dave.
(chuckles) Besides, we're just practicing for Liz's
horror video that she's gonna make.
- Dave, I think we should just go.
Officer Thomas was kind enough to take me back
to the town, my car got stuck out here.
(teenagers laughing)
- Hey, you guys haven't been drinking, have ya?
- Nah.
Nope!
- Dave, let's just go.
- Right.
Don't stay out too late.
And Liz...
don't mention this to anyone, okay?
- Hey uh, hey,
don't you stay out too late!
(teenagers laughing) (car starting)
(dark ambient music) (growling)
Shit!
You couldn't have pulled ol' Sally
off of Dave with a crowbar.
- Oh man, you should have seen her little boobs
shaking when she hit the windshield.
(teenagers laughing)
- You guys have a little class for a change.
- Yeah besides, there's ladies present.
- Tell us, Miss director, did we pass the audition?
(teenagers laughing)
(dark ambient music) (growling)
- That sounds like a pig.
(growling)
- Hey you guys, it's too creepy out here,
let's get back to town, okay?
- Good idea.
- Guys, come on!
We got plenty of beer,
nice warm night, don't chicken out now!
- We got all night, school's out!
- I'm for staying.
- Count me in!
- I've got an idea.
I bet Dave and that Sally Jean are parked
just down the road makin' out.
We could sneak up on 'em!
- I got an idea.
- I think once tonight is enough.
- Um, I'll see ya.
(car starting)
(girl giggling)
(boy laughing)
- [Boy] Hey, come on! - [Girl] Take it easy will ya?
- [Boy] What do you mean, "take it easy"?
Hey! (girl laughing)
Hey!
(dark ambient music)
(girl giggling) Hey!
(rattling)
(growling)
(girl screams)
(boy laughs)
Hey! (girl giggling)
(boys growls melody)
- [Girl] Kevin! (giggling)
- Hey.
(girl giggling)
(pigs snorting) - Oh, hey!
Woo!
(pigs squealing)
Woohoo!
(clanking)
(swooshing)
(girl screaming)
(thud)
(swooshing)
(girl screaming)
(smashing)
(splatter)
(rooster crowing)
(jaunty jazz music)
(door creaking)
(saw grinding in background)
- He's an obstinate old fart, always has been.
- [Man in cardigan] He's just a little headstrong, Tom,
that's all.
- Harold, I've already made two offers on that property
and the son of a gun's rejected both of 'em!
- I know, Tom, I know.
You've been very patient.
But you're not making it easy for me, either.
Les Bacon and I have been friends 30 years.
And I've spent a great deal of my career looking after his
meat packing plant 'til it closed down eight years ago.
- (chuckles) Hey, you're forgetting
I put in a couple years there myself.
- [Harold] I know you have, I know.
(Tom sighs)
- Well, as his friend and attorney,
I suggest you persuade him to accept my final offer
otherwise the county's put it up for auction
and he's gonna lose it all.
- We, will lose it all.
(Tom sighs)
- [Tom] Bonnie, I'm goin' over to lakeside on business.
I'll be back about noon.
- Okay, Mr. S.
(door opening)
(car starting)
(birds chirping, dog barking)
- Morning, sheriff.
- You know you're not a bad kid, Skip,
but someday I'm gonna be scrapin' you off the highway.
(car horn)
- [Skip] Morning, baby!
- Hey, good lookin'.
- [Skip] Gimme a kiss.
- You damn punk!
(cows mooing)
- Oh, this whole thing rubs against my grain.
Really pisses me off makin' another proposition to this guy.
- Well, the one thing I learned in the legal profession, Tom
is you gotta take care of number one.
Everybody else is number two.
So let's just say, I'm helping myself,
you and ol' Les Bacon by doin' this.
- Nah, this just ain't good business.
The last thing I need is an old fart...
oh, no offense, Harold.
(sighs)
Well hell, you know what I mean!
It would make it a hell of a lot easier just to let
the county foreclose on the property and buy it from them
no strings attached.
You got a light?
- [Harold] Yeah, if you don't call me "old fart" no more.
- [Voiceover] It's nine o'clock and time
for the national hog report.
Good news for hog raisers,
the price per pound hanging weight,
has risen from five cents to a record high of 95 cents.
A welcome relief from just one year ago when low pork
prices almost bankrupted many of the nation's corporations.
H.C. Hardrally, president of the
Southwest Pork Raising Association stated that,
"It shows that the free enterprise system works,
"without the need for federal subsidy."
And now, for the weather.
A randomly approaching storm-front
promises warm showers and some magnificent light
displays tonight.
(upbeat music)
- [Voiceover] Hey, all you KFATsos, the KFAT jocks
hope you can join us tonight for our annual KFAT Pig Out!
(crowd cheering)
And yours truly, Captain Fogel will meet ya at the
VFW Hall for a big all-out dance!
(crowd cheering)
All weekend long, KFAT jocks will play music recorded
by local groups throughout the county.
You can hear some of the best bash their way to glory
at the (drowned out by car horn) KFAT Pig Out!
(crowd cheering)
Doors open 7:30, no booze or you lose,
be there!
(dark ambient music)
(sign clanking)
- Tom.
Harold.
- Well I guess this is it.
(rattling)
- My God.
(flies buzzing)
So he's gettin' worse.
(door knock) Lester?
(door knock) Lester!
(door knock) Lester.
(door knock)
(man snorting)
Good morning, Lester.
- [Lester] Sheriff.
- Lester,
Tom Samford and I have been talkin'.
He'd like to make you a new offer.
- Final offer, I'll give you $55,000 for the property.
You can stay here.
And...
work for me as my consultant.
- [Lester] And the slaughterhouse?
- That's too far gone to be useful for anything but storage
and then it'll be tore down, replaced by a modern plant.
- Mean more than 100 new jobs to community, Lester.
You can be part of it.
- And it'll get the county assessor off your back.
- [Lester] Harold, you've been my adviser for many years.
You helped me start my meat business.
We watched it grow and we watched it die.
- I told you to mechanize, Lester.
Mechanize, but you wouldn't listen to me.
Me and ol' Tom Sanford saw it comin'.
- [Lester] When it died, you were the one that advised me
to convert to citrus packin', you, Harold!
"People always drink orange juice for breakfast", you said.
"But they can't always afford a steak dinner."
- And it would have worked too if you had put your
heart into it.
- Look at these!
These aren't the hands of an orange picker!
These are the hands of a skilled butcher.
I've spent my life preparing the choices cuts of meat.
The finest sausages, and we did it all
with the skill of craftsmen and sharp knives!
Not sinew chewing chainsaws!
- I don't have to listen to this maniac.
- [Harold] Wait, Tom! - [Tom] No, forget it.
It's over, just let the county take the property.
- [Harold] You're being pigheaded, Lester!
- You young hotdogs are all alike.
You've no sense for what I could do with 20 good men,
what you have to do with 100!
- Just hold on, Lester!
- And I'd never allow 30% fat!
- You're an old fool, Lester.
- 30% fat, Harold!
Men like him are plugging up our young people's arteries!
- Lester, it's my duty to inform you that the
county assessor's office hereby forecloses on your property
to be sold at public auction.
You have 30 days to leave the premises.
I'm sorry.
- No one's kickin' me off this here property.
Not the law,
no meat hacker,
and no conniving lawyer.
You're all conspirators!
Evil conspirators!
Taxes, shit!
I've paid my taxes for the last 30 years when I could!
I bet I paid your salary 100 times over, buddy-boy!
And this is what I get after 30 years?
(dark ambient music)
- Well you have 30 days left!
(Harold sighs)
- Well, you still got time, Lester.
Think this offer over.
Call me at the office.
(man barking)
(electro-pop music)
- Hi, Liz.
- [Liz] What's up, Ronnie?
- Not much.
Say, you guys goin' to the party tonight?
- Uh, yeah, I guess.
Are we?
- You bet!
Are you bringing Pauline?
- Yeah, I guess.
- Hey, why don't you catch that window?
- This is self-service bay.
(car horn)
- Hey, where's the party?
- [Skip] What's up, Buzzard?
- Hey, well we just heading over to get a Coke and fries.
Y'all wanna go?
- It's nine in the morning!
- Hey, whatever trips your trigger, sweetheart.
- Come on, Liz, we'll meet you over there!
- You, uh,
you buyin'?
- Hell no, you're the one with the bucks!
Oh, you broke my heart.
We'll see you over there.
- Should have done that a long time ago.
You know, this place has been nothin' but a
hangout for bums and vagrants for years.
- You still got power to the ol' slaughterhouse.
- Yeah, I wonder if he still keeps his office up there.
- You know, I remember when the train used to come in here
loaded with hogs.
They'd run 'em down the streets into the pens while it
loaded the processed pork on reefer cars up front.
Yeah, it was just as if the rail roads sold each one
a round-trip ticket, in one day, out the next.
- Yeah, ol' Lester ran a pretty tight ship alright.
- What ever happened to those underground corridors?
- I don't know, I ain't been down there in years.
- It's just a home for spiders and critters now.
That's for damn sure.
Now, a holdover, from the good old days!
You know, 20 years ago,
this whole area used to be one huge pen.
Thousands of pigs you could smell the damn things for miles.
- You can still smell 'em.
- I'm glad that son of a bitch fired me.
That's when I decided to go in business for myself.
I wouldn't even be talkin' to the man if I didn't have
this big contract coming up, I gotta have some extra space,
and this place is perfect.
That boy of his, he sure is an odd-lookin' son of a gun.
What, did Bacon whip him with an ugly stick?
- No actually, Lester's always been pretty good to the boy.
A little light-headed, though.
- Yeah, the younger boy, what ever happened to him?
- No one seems to know for sure.
Momma died giving birth to him.
- [Tom] Well if he looked anything like Buddy,
he's probably so ugly the hog's ate him.
(Tom and Harold laughing)
(rock music) (car accelerates quickly)
(police siren)
- Aw, shit!
- I refuse to bail you out this time.
- Damnit!
- [Voiceover] This is KFAT radio and it's time now for
our official weather report from our very own
weather adviser. Here's Commander FAT!
- [Voiceover] Hey everybody, bad news,
there's a storm approaching from the northwest,
it could bring lots of rain today!
- [Voiceover] Oh, what a bummer, but hey!
What better reason to be indoors at the VFW Hall.
Watch some of our local bands doin' it to it,
it's the big KFAT Pig Out, you oughta check it out!
- Hi Dave, how ya doin'?
- When are you gonna learn, Skip?
- I wasn't doin' over 45.
- Yeah.
But this is a 25 mile an hour zone.
What's wrong with you, boy?
You've already got two tickets in the last three months.
Judge Parker's gonna take away your license.
- I am sorry about last night.
I promise to cool it, okay?
Not more speedin'!
- Look, I'm not trying to hassle you kids.
I was a kid too, once.
And I got my share of speeding tickets,
but dog-gonnit, now I'm on the other side of the fence.
I gotta wife, and a couple of little screamers,
and I'd like to see them enjoy life in one piece.
And not end up splattered all over the
front end of your jeep.
- I promise, okay Dave?
(titters) Honest!
- You're okay.
(sighs) Damnit, stay out of trouble!
- Well, that was close.
- You're lucky my dad didn't pull you over.
(pigs snorting)
(cat yowling)
(Buddy growling)
- I can't believe you!
9:30 in the morning and you're pigging out on french fries?
Hey, has anybody heard from Kevin and Michelle?
- Not since we saw them last night.
- I didn't see his car when I passed by his house
on my way to pick you up.
- He's probably helpin' set up for the party.
- (chuckles) Knowing Michelle, she's there partying already.
- Hey, party animals, that's what we should be doing!
How often do we get a four day holiday anyway?
Hell, we got tomorrow to sleep it off.
- I have a feeling you're gonna need
more than tomorrow, pal.
- [Buzz] Depends on how wild the party gets.
- I doubt they'll let it get too crazy.
- Then we'll just have to move it somewhere else.
- Hey, what're you girls gonna make us wear
for this video thing?
- I don't know, I've been trying to think of something good.
Something different.
- I know, why don't I strap a mattress to your back
and we'll go naked? (Liz giggling)
- Cool it, Buzz.
- Why not? We might win the boobie prize!
(all laughing)
- Buzz, you're sick, okay?
Maybe we can get some masks or something.
- Yeah I bet Leo's got some.
I gotta go over there to get some video cassettes.
Let's go check it out.
- [Annie] Sounds good to me.
- Why not?
- Hey, I bet you're anxious.
- For what?
- To get a mask over that face. (laughing)
(dark ambient music) (pig snorting)
- [Lester] 30 years, buddy-boy.
30 years and now they're skinnin' our hides.
(Buddy snorts)
What's the matter with you, boy?
Have you been up to some kind of prank?
(Buddy snorting)
My God, boy!
What have you done?
Why? Why?
(Buddy snorts)
You mean they were messin' with your pigs?
Jesus Christ, boy, you can't just slaughter people
'cause they messed with your hogs!
Well now we're in a heap of trouble.
Oh, shit!
I buy you new cleaver for your birthday,
and this is how you repay me?
Sometimes you really piss me off.
At least you made good clean cuts.
Listen boy, these people aren't to be feared.
They are harmless.
There are other heads I rather see rolled than these kids.
Murdock, Sanford and the sheriff.
Those sons of bitches who were schemin'
to take our property!
They're the ones that deserve this!
(Buddy snorting repeatedly)
(upbeat rock music)
- [Buzz] Beware, of the fiend!
The sex fiend!
- Oh, come here, handsome.
Where have you been all my life?
(Buzz panting and moaning)
- [Skip] Hey, how about these?
- Uh, try these.
- [Both] Radical!
- [Skip] Where to?
- [Liz] I don't know, I'm open for suggestions!
I just need something really creepy looking.
Something I can build a story around.
- [Buzz] How about the old lumber yard
outside of town?
- It's pretty much burned out.
- How about old lady govlin's house?
That always makes me shiver when I see it.
- Well sure, like we're gonna go up to the old lady
and ask if we can use her house for a horror film.
(Skip chuckles)
How about the old pond?
There's tons of crap to shoot around there.
- Yeah, he likes to feel at home.
- Hey, why don't we check out the old slaughterhouse?
- That's all boarded up now, isn't it?
Dad said they were gonna tear it down.
- It's worth a look.
- Okay.
- [Liz] Let's go! - [Skip] Let's do it.
- Eight to one, good.
Yeah, good ahead and put 20 on the notice for me.
Right.
Well, she better.
Alright, goodbye.
(phone ringing)
Yello, this is Murdock.
Les, I was just sitting here reviewing the legal documents
on your place.
- [Lester] Good, Harold.
Now listen, I wanna apologize for my behavior this morning.
I was upset.
- [Harold] I know things haven't been easy for you, Les.
- These are troubled times, Harold.
- Yes, but you know I got your
best interests at heart, Lester.
You know we've been friends a long time.
- A long time, Harold.
I've been thinkin' about the offer.
I've decided to work it out with Sanford,
if you're willin' to help.
- [Harold] Sure Les, fire away.
- Thanks, Harold.
There's a few points I'd like to discuss with ya
before I make a deal with Sanford.
- [Harold] Sure, Les.
- I was hoping you could come out here.
I'd feel more comfortable!
- You know, let me check my schedule.
What time?
- [Lester] As soon as possible.
- Alright, I'll be there around 1:30.
- I knew I could depend on you, Harold.
- Yes, you can always count on me, Les.
Hi, it's Harold Murdock.
I'm out with a client this afternoon,
I'll be back around three o'clock.
Please leave your name and number at the beep.
(electronic music) - [Voiceover] K-F-A-T, KFAT Radio
weather forecast not lookin' too good, there's a chance
of showers on the way, in fact a big storm is comin'.
So get those umbrellas out and come to out KFAT Pig Out!
- It looks empty.
- [Liz] It looks creepy.
- [Voiceover] 153, this is central.
- 153. Go ahead, central.
- There's been a bad accident about 15 miles out
on highway 13.
Sheriff Borden's on his way out there now and he
wants you to take over until further notice.
- Are you sure he doesn't need any help?
- Not at this point, just keep an eye on things.
Be advised that Eleanor Mitchell called.
Michelle was out last night with Kevin Matthews.
And Kevin's parents haven't seen him either.
Dave!
- Jan, I'm gonna check somethin' out.
Notify me immediately if we get an update on them, okay?
(dark atmospheric music)
(wind whistling) (moving water)
(squeaking)
(dark ambient music)
(door creaking) (upbeat music)
- Whoa.
♪ Off they go
♪ They end up little weenies
♪ In a supermarket store
♪ Just like me
♪ Just like you
♪ We're all better off where we
♪ Had a little stew
♪ You got skin in your mouth
♪ You got blood in your eye
♪ I don't know what you want with me
♪ But I think I better try
♪ To get away from you
♪ Away with you
♪ Away from you
- Let's blow this pop stand.
♪ In the house where we live
♪ You got so much to give
♪ In the house where you die
♪ Gonna make you cry
♪ In the house locked
♪ You have no way of control
♪ In the house where we live
♪ You got so much to give
♪ And nobody knows
♪ In the house
(ominous ambient music)
- I've been acting like an old fool, Tom.
I'm ready to make a deal.
Harold's on his way.
I know you're a busy man.
Just come on up and we'll get it over with.
Oh, what I said about 30% fat?
I understand profit margin.
Okay, I'll see you about five.
(pigs squealing)
- How'd it go?
- Bad, real bad.
I'll let you in on the details later.
My stomach's upset, it must have been something I ate.
- [Jan] Or that accident, maybe?
Nerves, that's what it is, nerves!
- Have you heard from Dave?
- [Jan] About a half hour ago.
I'll give him a call and let him know you're back.
- Hold on a minute, I'd like to talk to him.
(dark atmospheric music)
- [Dave] Kevin!
Michelle!
(clanging)
(click) (machine hum)
(repeated clacking)
(chains rattling)
(thuds)
(dripping liquid)
(squealing behind door)
(screaming and groaning)
(swooshing) (Dave screams)
(Buddy grunting)
(Dave panting and groaning)
- Psh!
(Buddy snorting)
(Dave panting)
(thud)
- [Jan] Central, car 153.
Central to car 153, Dave!
Do you read me?
Dave.
Central clear.
- My God!
You've gone hog wild! (Buddy snorting excitedly)
I told you son,
Murdock, Sanford and the sheriff.
They're our enemies, not these people!
He's not the sheriff!
Just the deputy.
It's okay, son, I know.
Clean up this mess and put him with the others
before Murdock gets here.
And maybe we can make good use of 'em.
(Buddy yowls)
I'm glad you could come, Harold.
- No problem, Lester.
- Bring back memories?
- Yeah, I haven't been in this room in years!
Since we put the padlock on the door.
- Eight years ago, Harold.
- Eight years. Boy times flies, doesn't it?
- For some people.
- You know, maybe your arrangement with Sanford
will be a new beginning for you, Lester.
Where is Tom anyway?
I didn't see his car out there.
- He's waiting for you.
- And I didn't know sheriff Borden was coming over.
- [Lester] He's in here.
- What the hell is this, Lester, some kind of Prank?
- [Lester] No, just deceit, Harold.
Something you understand all too well.
- Wait just a minute, Lester.
- [Lester] I have been waiting eight long years, Harold.
Eight years you've been conspiring with others
to steal all that I've worked and planned for.
And you've managed to do it all through one of the most
conniving methods known to civilized man.
Taxes!
- You know, Borden and Sanford are right.
You are crazy.
Let me out of here, Lester.
(thud)
- I have something to show you.
(haunting ambient music)
- Oh my God, man.
- God had nothing to do with this, Harold.
(swooshing)
(snorting)
I see you've met the bailiff.
Better not move, Harold!
Remember Buddy can split the head off a chicken
on the run at 20 feet.
Not exactly a jury of your peers,
but then Buddy has never been very discriminating.
- Listen to me Lester, it's not too late!
I can still help ya!
- Help me?
I'm not the one on trial here.
- I can help you cover things up!
- Deception!
Do you see what I mean, Harold?
You've been deceiving people for years!
- I haven't screwed you in 30 years, Lester.
- Why don't we ask the jury what they think?
- Damnit, Lester, let me out of here!
- Honorable men and woman of the jury,
you've heard Mr. Murdock's story.
If you believe this man to be lying,
please signify by raising a hand.
I guess there's only one dissenting vote, Harold.
- God damnit, Lester, let me out of here.
- Say your prayers, Harold.
You won't feel a thing.
We do things kosher.
(Buddy growling)
(Lester cackles)
(Harold groaning)
(gurgling) (Lester cackling)
(blood dripping)
- [Liz] (laughing) You hot dog.
- [Skip] Yeah, that's what they all say.
- [Liz] You wish.
Think you're pretty hot stuff, don't ya?
- [Skip] Yeah. - [Liz] Yeah.
Come here.
- [Skip] What?
- I'm pretty lucky.
- About what?
- About you!
You always treat me so good.
You're always so gentle.
Unlike Kevin or Buzz.
- Hey, those are great guys, you know?
It's...
it's just everyone's different.
- Yeah, well Kevin attacks every girl he's with.
- Well that's Kevin's style.
- [Liz] Well I like yours.
(dark ambient music) (flies buzzing)
(Buddy grunts)
(Buddy snorts)
- I got two kids missing, one deputy on vacation,
one I can't find and a town full of kids
loaded for a bear tonight.
Jan, I'm gonna check around
and see if I can come up with something on Dave.
- Why don't you try the Lakeside Hotel?
He's been stopping there for lunch lately.
- Oh, really?
How long's this been goin' on?
- Last couple months.
- Hm.
Keep in touch.
- Sheriff!
Don't tell him I told ya, huh?
(Borden clicks tongue)
(mellow rock and roll music)
- Jerry Blatchet told me that last storm destroyed about
20% of his crop.
Lord knows what this one's gonna do.
What's up, sheriff?
- Herb, Ernie.
You haven't seen my Deputy, Dave, today have you?
- No, but he's been comin' in here for lunch lately.
Didn't show today, though.
- Well he's been missing since this morning
and he doesn't answer his car radio.
So can you help me out here?
- Ernie, you seen Dave Thomas today?
(Ernie mumbles)
Anybody here seen Dave Thomas today?
- I saw him this morning, sheriff.
- You are?
- Sally Jean Duncan, I work over at the cafe.
- Miss Duncan, when was the last time you saw Deputy Thomas?
- This morning.
Early this morning.
(jaunty rockabilly music) (police siren, pigs squealing)
(car starting)
♪ He's a real gone daddy, he's a shootin' star
♪ And they can't touch him when his hot-rod's goin' ♪
(police siren)
(Buddy laughing)
- Car 153, this is central.
Dave?
(Buddy squeals loudly)
(Buddy squealing)
Dave...
this is Jan, are you there?
(Buddy squealing)
(police siren)
- David! What-- (siren)
♪ He's a real gone daddy, he's a shootin' star
♪ And they can't touch him when his hot-rod's goin'
♪ He just a hot-rod rebel with a
♪ Hot-rod devil when he screams
♪ When he's out there on the highway
♪ He's looking for a thrill
♪ He gives a thrill to the ladies
♪ A thrill to the boys
♪ A thrill to the men and their
♪ Hot-rod toys
Hey, hot-shot!
What are you doin'?
Tryin' to impress me?
(Sally screams) (Buddy snorts)
(maniacal music)
(repeated thuds)
No! Please no!
Oh God, please!
(screams)
Stop, stop it!
Please, leave me alone!
(Buddy snorting)
(screaming)
(whines)
(screams)
Shit.
No!
(screaming)
Help!
(screams)
(gurgling)(knife slicing juicy tomato)
- [Liz] Anything else you want in the salad, mom?
- Mm, no. It's okay, I'll take over.
Go get ready for the party. - [Liz] Thanks.
Mm, instant cardboard. (Mrs. Borden laughs)
I'll be upstairs if you need me.
Hi, pa.
- Honey, you're home early.
Have an easy day?
- Hardly.
Oh, my favorite!
Now sweetheart, I won't be home for dinner tonight.
Vern's on vacation, Dave's missing,
and Jan's minding the store.
- I know, what is this about Dave missing?
- I don't know, nobody's seen him since this morning.
- You know, I talked to Kevin Matthew's mother today.
She hasn't seen him since last night.
(sighs) She's petrified.
You know, I think I'm gonna go over there tonight.
- I put out an APB in the other counties
for Kevin and the Mitchell girl.
- I hope it's nothing serious.
- Hopefully they just eloped.
(door knocking)
- [Liz] I'll get it!
- Oh, that's Skip!
They're going to the KFAT dance.
- The whole town is.
- Hi, Skip.
- Hi, Mrs. Borden.
Hi, sheriff.
- Hi, Skip.
- Any word on Kevin?
- Nothin' yet.
Now, you two take it easy tonight.
I don't want any shenanigans.
- [Liz] We'll be good.
Bye, pa.
- Honey, I'll bring dinner by the office.
- [Sheriff] Thanks a lot!
- You know, your dad's really concerned about Dave missing.
- He's probably out with that Sally Jean!
- That's not nice.
- Well maybe it's true!
You know, you oughta say somethin' to him about that.
(dark atmospheric music)
(door creaking)
(clanging)
- Harold!
- It's still an effective method of getting
rid of waste.
Remember when we processed maybe,
fifty, sixty thousand head a year?
Not bad for human muscle and sharp knives.
- Yeah well, it's a museum piece now!
Where's Murdock? I saw his car out front.
- He's down in the coolers.
You remember Buddy?
Buddy's a good boy.
But he has what you might call, basic hygiene problems.
- Well let's, uh, get down to business.
Where's Murdock?
- Well let's just say he's, indisposed.
- What the hell's goin' on here?
Don't play with me, Bacon!
Let me go, fat boy!
(Lester laughing)
This isn't funny, Bacon.
(Lester chuckling)
(machine humming)
Are you crazy?
Whatever you think I've done, I'm sorry.
- (laughing) What do you think, Buddy?
Does he really mean it?
Buddy doesn't really think you're sorry! (chuckles)
(Tom screaming) (Lester cackling)
(Buddy snorting)
(background conversations)
- Hey, you KFAT partyers,
welcome to the annual Pig Out!
(crowd cheering and applauding)
We got the champions here from the battle of the bands,
The Playground Slap, and they're gonna be doing a thing
for us in just a little while but first,
for the folks listenin' live at home,
let's do three big "sewies" on a count of three.
One.
Two.
Three!
- [Crowd] Sewie!
Sewie!
(cheering and applauding)
(upbeat electronic music)
♪ Cars down in the city
♪ Rollin', I'm rollin'
♪ In the crowd I hear her
♪ Callin', she's callin'
♪ I can feel it getting near
♪ Suddenly it's crystal clear
♪ What I need is what I fear
♪ Turn on, face the sun
♪ Just stand alone
♪ You are the one
♪ Turn on, face the sun
♪ You stand alone
♪ You are the one
(rumbling) (screaming)
- [Fogel] Whoa, that's what happens when you
rock and roll a little too hard there.
Just a little power failure, there is a storm you know.
If you wanna just exit out that back door or the side doors
here and everyone don't panic anybody, it's okay.
(crowd murmuring)
- That party's a bit of a drag.
- You just don't like to dance.
- I just like to party!
- Hey, you know now's the time to shoot the slaughterhouse
with the lightning and all.
- Are you kidding me?
Who in their right mind would wanna hang around that
dirty, smelly old slaughterhouse at night?
- That place is scary enough during the day,
I wouldn't wanna be there at night.
- Aw, are you scared?
- I think you're just scared.
- Yeah!
- If you guys are so macho, why don't you go out there?
- Yeah, put your money where your mouth is.
- Okay.
Ten bucks
says you won't last an hour out there.
- Yeah, alone.
- Make it worth my while.
Make it 20.
- They've never seen a 20, Liz.
(girls giggle)
- I'll toss in 10.
- Okay.
20 bucks says you won't last an hour in that old place.
(thunder roaring)
- You're on. (thunder claps)
(thunder claps)
- We should have held out for 40 bucks
'cause of this storm, Annie.
- Jan, give Dave's wife a call
and see if he's reported home.
Jan, don't get her alarmed,
but something crazy's goin' on here.
(thunder booming)
- Let's go back to the party, this is really dumb.
- Uh, and lose the chance of a lifetime?
To show up these guys and make 20 bucks doin' it?
- Oh, that's what I like, spirit.
Now, if you girls want us to come pick you up,
just signal with this.
We will be down the road, sippin' a few cool ones.
- See you, girls.
- [Skip] Bye! - [Buzz] In an hour.
(thunder) - Or less.
(Skip and Buzz chuckling)
(thunder roaring)
(thunder clap)
- [Liz] Hi, I'm Skip!
And I'm Buzz!
And we're really stupid!
'Cause we're gonna lose 20 bucks!
Yeah!
(Annie and Liz giggling)
That was dumb!
So was this.
- [Annie] I know, I can't believe we're doing this.
(gasps)
What do you think?
- I think you go first.
- No way, it's your 20 bucks!
- What do you say we split it, and we'll go together?
- Deal.
(pigs squealing) (thunder roaring)
- [Buzz] Skip, wait up.
I can't see worth a damn in this thing.
- [Skip] Just follow me!
- [Buzz] Just take it easy.
(pigs squealing)
- [Skip] Oh, are you alright?
- [Buzz] Yeah.
Crap, I lost my beer.
Oh God, hog shit!
I hate pigs.
- [Skip] Just take off that stupid mask and let's get goin'!
- [Buzz] Oh, once it's on I get used to it.
(dark ambient music)
(thunder roaring)
- 152 to central.
- [Jan] This is central.
- Patch me through to the Medford County
sheriff's department.
(rattling) (scratching)
- [Liz] Annie, we should have held out for 40 bucks,
look at this place.
- [Annie] Yeah, it's straight out of Good Housekeeping, huh?
(rattling) (scratching)
- I knew it!
I got an idea.
I'm gonna find a way out and sneak around behind these guys.
- Oh Liz, I really think it would be better
if we stuck together here.
- No, you stay here and act as bait.
I'm gonna go down behind and scare the hell out of them.
(dark ambient music) (thunder roaring)
- [Skip] Buzz, buzz.
Listen.
You go around this way.
I'm gonna go around this way,
see if you can't find some place to sneak in.
- [Buzz] Well how about the front door?
- [Skip] No no no no no, that's too obvious.
We gotta be sneaky about this.
- [Buzz] Oh yeah, this is gonna be great!
(creaking)
(tense atmospheric music)
(Skip groans)
- Oh Skip, come on!
Skip, cut it out, okay?
Will you stop it?
Stop! (Skip grunts)
You're gross.
(chuckles) Oh God.
I can tell that it's you, why don't you just cut it out?
Gross!
Oh come,
Skip,
Skip!
(screams)
(screaming)
(Buddy grunts)
(Annie screaming and panting)
- [Liz] Annie!
Skip!
Buzz!
(creaking)
Annie?
(thunder clap)
(Buzz makes whooshing sounds)
(clattering and grinding)
(grunting from behind)
- [Buzz] Skip?
Skip, you nearly scared the shit out of me!
(Buddy squeals sharply)
(thud)
(Buddy snorts and grunts)
(dark atmospheric music) - [Liz] Skip?
(thunder clap)
Control.
Annie!
(roaring thunder)
Annie?
Skip?
Come on, you guys, you can keep your 20 bucks.
(Annie screaming in distance)
Annie?
(door creaking)
Skip.
Buzz.
Come on, you guys, I've had enough.
I'm ready to call it quits.
Annie!
(screams)
(Liz screaming) (thunder booming)
(Liz sobbing)
- This little pig went to market.
This little pig stayed home.
This little pig had roast beef.
And this little pig had none.
And this little pig ran wee wee wee,
all the way home!
(cackling) (Liz screaming)
- [Jan] Go ahead, sheriff.
- I've got an emergency over here, Al,
can I get some help from your county?
- [Voiceover] You bet, Fred.
We'll get 'em right out there to ya.
- Thanks, Al.
I may need 'em for the next couple of days.
- [Voiceover] No sweat, we'll manage.
Uh, speaking of missing persons,
you haven't seen Tom Sanford over there, have you?
- Not since this morning.
And, uh,
he was headed back towards his plant.
- [Voiceover] His old lady's upset 'cause he
hasn't been home yet.
Listen, we'll get those men right out to ya.
Keep me posted.
- Thanks, Al.
Car 152 to central.
- [Jan] Go ahead, sheriff.
- Jan, any word on Murdock?
- [Jan] Mrs. Murdock called his office again.
But his answering machine's on and it says the same thing.
That he's out with a client and he'll return about three.
- Sanford.
Murdock.
Out with a client?
Murdock out with Sanford.
Jan, let me know the minute you hear anything about Murdock.
I'm gonna play a hunch.
(Liz sobbing and whining)
- Believe me, your friends never felt a thing.
A large price to pay for trespassin'.
Easy on her, son.
We don't wanna hurt her.
Yet.
What's your name, miss?
- [Liz] Liz.
(Liz sobs)
Borden!
- Borden?
Lizzie Borden?
Well I'll be a suckling mule!
The sheriff's daughter?
Lizzie Borden?
(Liz whining and sobbing)
You know, this is almost better than
having your old man here.
Gives Buddy something to play with besides himself.
(Buddy grunting)
Tender as a suckling pig.
Used to get a lot of call for suckling.
Folks used to have big pig roasts every summer.
Lots of 'em.
(sighs) Times have changed.
These knives, each one has its own purpose.
Bonin', carvin', slicin'.
This one's specially made for skinnin' off the hide.
(Liz screaming)
I can skin a hide off a hog in 30 seconds.
Without jigglin' one ounce of fat.
(Buddy squeals) (Liz screaming)
Don't scare the poor thing, boy!
Take off that damn mask!
(Liz sobbing)
That's better.
(Buddy groaning)
(Liz screaming)
Most folks prefer not to think how their
steaks and chops are produced.
No, they just pick 'em up all wrapped in plastic
in neat little disposable trays and never give it a thought.
People think butcherin' is a crass, violent way.
But they don't realize that a good meat cutter
must have the knowledge of anatomy,
and the skilled hands of a surgeon.
(Liz sobbing and screaming)
Delicate, but not much meat.
Good for soup. (chuckles)
Did you know that one of the most sensitive parts
of the human body is the fingertip?
It's just that the tiny cut on the fingertip
is more painful than a slice across the belly.
(Liz screaming)
(Lester chuckles)
(Liz screams loudly)
You see what I mean? It helps to know the
beast you're going to carve.
Little girl, I bet I could skin you out in 90 seconds flat,
and dress you out in less than three minutes!
(Liz screaming)
(thunder booming)
Recognize this one, little girl?
(Liz screaming)
Watch closely and you'll see what I'm gonna do to you.
(Liz screaming and sobbing)
(thud)
(splatter)
(Liz screams loudly)
(Lester screams) (dramatic music)
Get her, damnit!
(Liz screaming) (clanging)
(Buddy squealing)
(Liz screams)
(Buddy snorting)
(Liz screaming)
- Hold it right there!
(gunshot) (chink)
(Buddy squeals)
(pig squeals)
(Liz screams)
Where are the others?
- (sobbing) They're dead.
They're all dead.
- Come on, we gotta get the hell out of here.
(thud) - [Liz] No!
No! No!
- You're next, little pig. (tense music)
(gunshot)
(Liz whines)
(Liz sobs)
(Liz screams)
(thuds on window) - [Liz] Dad, the keys.
(whining and sobbing) (Lester groans)
(engine revving)
(thud)
(sobbing) It's okay, dad.
I'll get you to the hospital.
- [Sheriff] Liz.
The radio.
Call for help.
(buzzing)
(squealing)
(snorting) (Liz screams)
(Buddy squeals) No!
("Slaughterhouse" by Mortician)
♪ Deserted house of morbid death
♪ Chopped up bones and rotting flesh
♪ All that enter will be killed
♪ Cleaver splits your head in two
♪ Grinding up flesh
♪ Blood splattered death
♪ Corpses hang from sharp tell hooks
♪ Gutted, skinned, prepared to cook
♪ Deranged fuck squashes your head
♪ Laughing while you writhe in death
♪ Hacking off limbs
♪ Screaming victims
♪ Deserted house of morbid death
♪ Chopped up bones and rotting flesh
♪ All that enter will be killed
♪ Cleaver splits your head in two
♪ Grinding up flesh
♪ Blood splattered death
♪ Deserted house of morbid death
♪ Chopped up bones and rotting flesh
♪ All that enter will be killed
♪ Cleaver splits your head in two
♪ Grinding up flesh
♪ Blood splattered death