Good luck, sister.
Oh, Dorothy.
All right honey, get
it out of your system.
Let's have a great
big flood of tears.
You know what they
told me in there?
They said if you'd
paid the store
for what I took,
maybe I wouldn't
have had to serve time.
You know how much it was, Dor.
I didn't have the money.
I'm not blaming you, Junie.
I'm gonna take care of you now
and do all the things I should
have taken time to do before.
You mean, if
there's a next time
you'll have the money?
I'll have the money, but
there won't be a next time.
This
all yours, June?
Legally, I mean.
All mine, come on, climb in.
I wish the dames
in there could see
what a big success my sister is.
Let's get out of here.
Mm, Dorothy Lyons,
first arrested
for petty theft,
placed in custody
of sister June, two years later
arrested for shoplifting,
six months paroled.
Two years ago arrested
for jewelry theft.
Sentenced three to five
years, served 18 months.
Will be released because
of ill health next Tuesday.
Today.
She'll be on
parole, won't she?
For three years.
Thanks, Dave,
I'll see you later.
Oh, just a minute Ben.
Forgot to tell me why
you're so interested
in this girl.
- Building a library.
Kind of a who's who.
For Solly Caspar?
No, who's who for Ben Grace.
- Why, Ben?
- Good idea.
Quite an idea.
Like to tell me about it?
You'll hear about
it soon enough.
You're a dreamer, Ben.
Man's only as
big as his dreams.
We're gonna pull you
out of the river some day.
That's not part of the dream.
By the way, did you ever dream
of being Chief of Police?
Long time ago, lots of times.
Maybe I'll make
you Chief of Police.
You got an in with the Mayor?
Depends on which Mayor
you're talking about.
Oh, Ben?
This dame, she's dynamite.
Yeah, thanks again.
Hop out.
Ah, here we are, home at last.
Home, huh?
This is where you live.
Mmhmm, that's right,
now it's your home too.
You must be quite a secretary.
To a very successful man.
- A bachelor?
- Well, as it happens,
Mr Jansen is a bachelor.
Oh, Martha.
I saw you drive up.
- This is my sister, Dorothy.
- How do you do, Miss Dorothy.
Hi.
Oh, Martha, the
flowers are lovely.
Mr Jansen's chauffeur
brought them over.
No card.
- Any messages?
No, just the
mail and the paper.
Join me?
No thanks, honey,
not right now.
- June?
- Mmhmm.
What are you gonna tell people
while I'm staying here with you?
That you're my sister.
And that I popped up
from under a cabbage leaf?
Nobody knows
anything about you.
And nobody will know
And my probation officer?
That is all confidential.
Where I come from, you learn
to figure all the angles.
Hey.
Who's this?
That, is my
boss, Frank Jansen.
He gave it to me a year ago.
You gonna marry
him, Junie, or.
Do you think I should?
I think it's a very good idea.
The bathroom towels'll
look sensational.
JJ.
When I want a new
monogram, I'll let
Frank Jansen know.
Don't you wanna shower
and see your room?
Hot water, soap, clean sheets.
Come on, sweetie,
I'll show it to you.
Know where I was
yesterday at this time?
In a sewing room
with six hundred
dames making denim uniforms.
Let's not talk
about that ever again.
You're here now
and you're starting
a new life and neither of us has
a worry in the world.
Hi, Ben, Solly's
watching television.
Thanks.
Bout
time you showed up.
Solly's been asking for ya.
- So I'm here.
This
Marlowe's getting rough.
I've published a
newspaper in Bay City
for 30 years and
never have I used
its columns for a crusade that
I thought was more
important than
the one to elect
Frank Jansen Mayor.
Obviously, the city
government is rotten.
Rotten, corrupt, evil.
Well everyone in City Hall knows
who actually's running our city.
Sol Caspar, and when
Sol Caspar doesn't steal
he bribes, and when he
doesn't bribe, he murders.
For 15 years his
syndicate of vice
has grown and grown and grown
because the men
elected to protect you
from crime have been on
Sol Caspar's payroll.
I urge you, I beg you.
Sol, how's Marlowe
get away with that?
Shut up, I wanna hear this.
To elect a man who's
never been in politics.
A man who is free from
ties to politicians
and gangsters, a man who
will clean up Bay City.
Ladies and Gentlemen, vote
for Frank Jansen for mayor.
Oh, Ben, come
on in the office.
Who dealed them?
Glad to see you,
genius, that Marlowe
is a rough old man.
You must have a file this
thick on Jansen's girlfriend.
I got a file, Solly.
And I knocked the boy
scout right outta the box.
I told ya there was a
way to get to anybody.
A way to get to a
reformer, just to prove
that he's not such a
lily white angel himself.
That figures.
Well what do we use, genius?
Pictures of him,
tapes, check zeroed?
I gotta file on
Jansen's girlfriend.
All it proves is that they're
both clean as a whistle.
You been working on em a week.
If she's clean, she's clean.
I can't help it if
Jansen's too smart
to leave any tracks.
Oh this is great.
This is fine news to
get at ten o'clock
Tuesday night, a
week before election.
Do you know what
happens to bright boys
like you and us
if Jansen gets in?
You can take all
your fancy gimmicks
and your camera
rifle and you can,
a dame is a dame, there's bound
to be something you
can nail her on.
I couldn't get one
picture of June Lyons.
You mean you didn't
even get a picture
of her coming out of his
house at two in the morning?
What kind of a secretary is she?
Probably a nice secretary.
Maybe a nice girl.
If you wanna nail
Jansen, you better try
something else, something good.
You may be right, genius.
If I can't get the
girl alongside Jansen,
I'll get the guy behind him.
Marlowe?
Marlowe.
Without the journal,
nobody'd ever
have known about Frank Jansen.
I'd advise you to take it easy
where Marlowe's concerned.
You'd advise me.
I'm gonna take care
of Marlowe tonight.
You're coming with me.
Uh-uh Solly, count me out.
What's the matter, rough stuff
not in your line or something?
Scare ya, genius.
No, it doesn't scare me.
I don't believe in it.
If you're smart, you
don't have to use it.
So I'm not smart?
You're a bright boy, genius, and
I'm glad to have
you working for me.
But you know why you'll always
be working for me
and not vice versa?
Why, Solly?
An operator, he runs things.
Up, down, sideways, rain
or shine, he runs things.
You got no jet
engine in your belly
that makes you operate.
You'd rather read a
couple of good books,
wouldn't you, genius, wait,
I'll show you something.
Lenhardt, all you
fellas, come in here.
Boys, I called you
in here to give you
a demonstration of
how I'm gonna operate
on Mr. Norman B. Marlowe.
Genius, you're just
a chiseller out
for a soft buck,
you're not crooked
and you're not
straight, you take
what you can get
where you can get it
but you don't want any trouble.
You'll die at age 66 in bed with
three grand in the
bank but you'll never
be an operator, now
go on out and get
yourself some
fresh air but don't
let it go to your head.
Remind me never to
send my son to college.
That is, if I ever have a son.
Sure, Jansen's honest.
Even if he gets
elected, so what?
He don't understand politics.
In six months, they'll
have time tied up too
I've seen em come and go, why
this town'll be so lily
white you'll be able
to eat your dinner
off the pavement here.
- Hello?
- Hello, Miss June Lyons?
- Yes.
- Listen carefully to what
I have to say,
Solly Caspar's gonna
take care of Norman
Marlowe tonight.
Call Jansen, tell
him to warn him,
better still, warn him yourself.
Don't lose a minute.
Who is this?
- A friend.
- Why don't you
tell him yourself, who are you?
Hello?
Hello!
Who's that?
Nothing, honey,
go back to sleep.
I thought I heard
a man's voice.
Probably just
some political crank
trying to cause trouble.
Why didn't you get his number?
I wish you had.
The men elected to
protect you from crime
have been on Sol
Caspar's payroll.
Thank you, Gloria,
thank you for working
so late and goodnight.
Mr. Marlowe?
Good night, Mr. Marlowe.
Just a little talk, Marlowe.
Caspar!
You.
Well now we, we can
discuss anything tomorrow.
I'm a sick man, my
doctor's just warned me.
You'll talk about me
whenever you want to,
I'm talking to you now.
- You can't frighten me
you can't stop me.
- You're going to stop
backing Jansen,
you're gonna stop
printing all that
stuff about me.
I'm gonna print all the truth
about your vicious scheming.
Rich boy, you're gonna
stop, or you'll get
a working over like
those newspaper boys
in Scenic City, now we talk.
Listen to me.
Get some water.
- Looks like he's dead.
- Don't make a Federal case
out of it, get some water.
It's too late for
water, you killed him.
You sure?
Guess I did at that, didn't I?
Well, that's getting out
of a jam the hard way.
Open the window.
Give him some air.
Give him plenty of air.
Come on, let's see if
we can beat him down.
I was half asleep,
I looked at the clock
a little before
two, I thought about
calling you, Frank,
but who takes
a phone call seriously
at that hour?
Now this horrible murder.
Phone call in the
middle of the night
doesn't prove
murder, Miss Lyons.
Well it's just too
much of a coincidence.
Lieutenant, you
don't see to be
very anxious to dig into this.
What else could it
be but a murder?
Mr. Marlowe was your friend.
He was backing you,
of course you're going
to jump to conclusions,
me, I take it
a little easier, I
don't mess around
with politics or politicians.
That's how I've lasted 22
years in the department.
Thanks, Miss Lyons, I
know how to reach you.
Are you sure you didn't
recognize the voice?
Could it have been
someone from the office?
Maybe if I heard it
again I'd recognize it.
I'm sorry, Frank, but it
all seems to fantastic.
Don't blame yourself,
June, you probably
couldn't have done
anything about it anyway.
- Thanks.
- I've gotta get downtown.
I'm glad you were
here with me anyhow.
See you this afternoon.
- Bye.
- Buh bye.
Lieutenant!
You know, I don't
think that policeman
believed a word I said.
They never believe anybody.
Come on, let's get some sun!
- Yes?
- Good morning, Miss Lyons.
Remember me?
No, can't say that I do.
Name's Ben Grace.
What do you want?
I want Frank Jansen for mayor.
Oh, come in.
Mm, nice looking
place you have here.
Thank you.
Nice looking girl.
Supposing you tell
me why you're here.
All right Miss Lyons,
I'll get to the point.
Last night I telephoned
you about Marlowe.
You.
I wouldn't bother,
I waited till
they drove away.
How did you know?
I knew, that's enough.
- But.
- Mr Jansen is a nice man.
But he doesn't know
how to win elections.
I'm not a very nice
man, I know how.
Takes a little dirt.
And you have dirt to sell?
I have dirt to sell.
What do you want for it?
Money?
Not a penny.
What then?
Oh, decency.
Clean government,
Frank Jansen for mayor.
Jansen's an idealist.
You're a practical girl.
He needs you and you've
made him pay for it.
Oh, that's all right,
I don't trust people
who are not a little greedy.
What do you want to tell me?
Did you know Marlowe?
Yes.
Sit down.
Listen.
You're going
to stop backing Jansen.
You're going to stop
printing all that stuff
about me.
- I'm going to print
all the truth about
your vicious, evil.
Listen to me!
Get some water.
It's too late for water.
You killed him.
Where did you
get this, Mr Grace?
It's not a question
of where I got it.
It's what you and Jansen
are gonna do with it.
Uh-uh, I don't buy
your villain goods.
Who sent you to me?
Sol Caspar himself?
I assure you, this is genuine.
All I can do is give you a gun.
If you haven't got guts enough
to pull the trigger,
I can't help it.
No dirt, tonight, Mr. Grace.
I don't like your brand.
It's too cheap, it smells like
some kind of trick, you probably
invented it for some.
- Oh, there's too much
to invent, for instance,
there's your sister
out there, her
first arrest was for
petty larceny, then
two years later
the rap was for shop lifting.
Get out of this house.
Now do you believe me?
I don't like
blackmail, I said
get out and I mean it.
I'm in the book.
Name is Ben Grace, G-R-A-C-E.
I'll let Mr. Jansen
decide if he needs you,
but I assure you,
my sister and I.
Somebody talking about me?
I'd much rather do the
talking for myself.
Goodbye, Mr. Grace.
How do you do, Mr. Grace.
Meet Junie's little
sister, Dorothy.
Hello Miss Lyons.
Please cal me Dor, won't you?
A frank and open door.
Dorothy, Mr.
Grace is very late.
Hey, I love that material.
I love the feel of it.
I'll wear it the
next time I see you.
Oh, you don't
have to put it on
just for me.
Your sister's a nice girl.
And she's going
to stay that way.
Remember, the
number's expert 36567.
- Expert 36567.
- You got it.
You tired too?
Not too much, honey.
I guess I just have an
awful lot on my mind.
A lovely girl like
you, you shouldn't
have to worry about
a thing, except
looking beautiful
and running home
to a man who loves you.
- Thank you.
I guess I could have
timed this a bit better.
We'll set up a more
romantic atmosphere.
Fiddles playing
offstage, bongo drums
and all that sort of
thing, but really.
Why don't we get
married and stop
all this foolishness?
- Oh, Frank, not now.
Not right away, will
you hold the offer
open for a while?
In other words, no?
No, I don't mean
no, I just can't think
about it right now, I
wanna get Dorothy settled.
Preferably some
place away from here
where she might not embarrass
her prominent brother-in-law.
You've known about her?
What difference does it make?
I wanna marry you
because I love you.
She has nothing to do with it.
So if that's the only reason,
there's no reason
at all anymore.
I know there isn't another man.
No, of course not.
May I come in?
The door's open.
what made you change your mind?
Well, I talked it
over with Mr. Jansen.
After all, if it's
what you say it is.
What can you tell me that
will help elect Mr. Jansen?
Well, aside from Solly Caspar,
who's a low grade moron
with delusions of grandeur
there's Wilson and
James, they were
in the room when
Marlowe was killed.
The FBI's been looking for
those boys for a long time.
The Blue Gross is
up 4% over last month
or 220,000, and
this is the green,
Mr. Caspar, it's down a little,
but all in all
everything seems to be
running well ahead.
- Yeah, what do you
want, genius?
- Your boyfriend Jansen's
on TV, I thought you
might like to look.
Well, why not watch
the clown for a while.
Okay, Ames, thanks,
go on, hit the books
for that fancy degree, you know,
it's a pleasure having
geniuses in the organization.
I had a speech prepared
for this last address
before you go to
the polls, but after
thinking about it all day,
I decided not to use it.
Instead, I'd like to
talk for a few minutes
about a crime which shocked
all of us yesterday.
A crime that should
be the concern
of the Chief of Police
and the District Attorney
but which, for some
strange reason,
they don't seem to
want to look into.
The crime, ladies and gentlemen,
the murder of Norman Marlowe.
The criminal,
ladies and gentleman
that leader of all that
is vile and corrupt
in our city, and one
whose influence obviously
reaches into the City
Hall itself, Solly Caspar.
How'd he get that?
Please, please,
you know I wouldn't say
anything to anybody.
Not about a murder.
You know too much, Gloria!
Maybe you talked too much!
Wilson, James,
you're under arrest!
Get him out of here.
Take em out!
It was a
good tip, Mr. Caspar.
Chief went out and acted
on his own authority.
Mr. Caspar, from
where I sit, I'd say
you better get outta
town, maybe the state.
Maybe the country.
You tell the man
on top he better
cover for me all the way.
Say, Boss, Wilson
and James have been
shooting off their
mouths all morning.
There's 9000 pages
of stuff up at
the State's Attorney's office.
Sure stinks, doesn't it, boys?
Who gave em the word, Sol?
The more I think
of it, the more
it figures maybe
bright boy did get
some big ideas.
- If Ben Grace is that
stupid it would be
a personal pleasure.
No, not you, not anybody else.
Let the genius go ahead.
Give him rope, if it
was him, I'll be back.
I'll be back to do
the sweetest job
on the genius you ever saw.
I got 40 minutes to
make it to the airport.
Quiet!
Quiet everybody, please!
An announcement
from the news room.
Mayor Robbins concedes defeat.
Here's to the new mayor.
Everybody'll
wonder where I went.
Oh it's so good just
to sit here with you
and relax and try to
realize it's all over.
How does it feel
to back a winner?
You oughta know.
You know, the strangest
thing for me tonight.
All those people
I don't know them,
they don't know
me, all of a sudden
I realized that you
and I and Frank,
all of us are were
really working
like the devil for them, to help
somebody else
I don't think
I was ever that
altruistic before.
You talk too much.
Why'd you do that?
To see what you'd do.
And how'd I do?
You did fine.
Hey!
You know, I don't
know you at all.
Ben Grace Investments,
and I haven't been able
to find out anything, either.
I made one good investment
for you, didn't I?
Mmhmm, when do I get the bill?
Maybe it's on the house.
What?
I was just thinking.
Poor Frank, mayor
elect and all night
people have been
buttonholing him for favors
and from now on,
everybody'll want something
from him.
- And you've been
playing hooky.
- Mmhmm and I don't think
I can write a very
good excuse, either.
Want to do him a favor?
Certainly.
Tell him to put Dave Dietz in
as the new Chief of Police.
Dave Dietz?
Mm, he's a good man.
I thought he was one
of the City Hall bunch.
Well, he's a good
lieutenant who maybe
never had a chance to do the job
he'd like to, best
you could find.
Well, you've been
batting a thousand so far.
I'll think about it.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Ben.
Why didn't you invite him in?
Oh, don't look
around for Martha,
she kept her eye on me for you
but she clocked off hours ago.
All right honey,
come on, let's get
to bed, it's late.
Oh, I heard the
good news about
the election.
- Oh?
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- Jansen called up.
- Oh did he?
- Twice.
- Oh.
Wondered what had
happened to you.
Very disappointed.
It runs in the family.
What's that?
Having people
just elected mayor
calling you up all
hours of the night.
Good deal.
- Oh it is.
Especially when you're spending
all hours of the night
with somebody else.
Aren't you asleep yet?
I'm not sleepy.
Do you want something?
- Yes.
- A glass of hot milk?
Ben Grace.
Oh sweetie.
You don't really.
He just happens to
be the first man
you've talked to in a long time.
Look, I don't expect
you to understand
my feelings, all
head and no heart,
planning every move
to better yourself.
I'm not like you,
I've got a heart.
And I've gotta do
what it tells me
no matter what.
How long are we
going to sit around
waiting for that guy
to tell us what to do?
I got news for you guys,
nobody's gonna
tell me what to do.
But, if I were running
this organization.
What would you do, Giant?
I'll tell ya
what I'd do, Tiny.
I'd won a lottery,
that's what I'd do.
Everybody likes the
lottery, everybody
and I'd split the take
right down to the middle.
One fifth of the
payoff in charity
and one fifth for the boys.
What about the
other three fifths?
Well, a guy's
gotta get something
for his big ideas.
What's the
scoop, the play,
what are we doing, genius?
We're not doing
anything for a while.
Maybe you ain't,
but we're taking up
where Solly left off.
You'll end up in jail.
If you goons read the newspapers
instead of the comic
books, you'd find out
we have a new city
administration.
Look, don't go
Joe College on us.
We know what's happened
just the same as you do.
I want time for
everything to settle down.
And I don't want
you knuckleheads
screwing up my plans.
- Your plans?
- You heard it right
the first time.
- So you're the planning
commission now?
- That's right.
I'm the planning commission.
Pretty smart.
How'd you get in so
good with the new mayor?
I went to the library
and read a book.
I see, thanks for telling me.
All right now
get this straight.
We're staying out of
the rackets for now.
You wanna know something, Ben?
Why don't you shut
up when I'm talking.
I didn't hear a word you said,
I must be getting deaf.
All right Grannar, I'll
say it again for you.
Nothing moves till I say so.
Until the first snow, is that
what you said, genius,
ha, he doesn't want
anybody screwing up his plans,
stay out of the rackets till I.
I may have to kill you, Lenny.
I don't like killing
people, never did.
But you're not
people, I don't think
I'd mind a bit.
- You talk big.
Solly was a big operator.
Yeah, I know Solly was
big operator, jet propelled.
I'm gonna handle things
a little different.
Anybody can talk.
I can deliver too.
What did you
deliver lately, Benji?
City hall.
I got it unlocked with
an old friend of mine.
The new Chief of
Police, Dave Dietz
is gonna be the
boy with the star.
And Lenny, you'd be
impossible to miss.
You're not much of
a Chief of Police
if you can't pull enough
rank to get a better office.
Next week.
Ben, I, don't know what
to say except that.
Well, however you did it,
you know I'm grateful.
Yeah.
You bring this?
Your first bribe.
I just came from Jansen's.
He's gonna be all right, Ben.
I think everything's
gonna be all right.
Wanna listen to me?
Sure, Ben, shoot.
You may be the richest
cop in 11 western states.
Oh?
Jansen's gonna be
happy, the voters
are gonna be happy,
as a matter of fact
it's gonna be one
big happy family.
Nice, if you can do it.
I can do it, meantime
you do your job,
clean up the city,
stop prostitution,
nail the thieves
and the grifters
and make the taxpayers feel safe
in their beds at night.
- What's in it for you?
Oh I'll take a 30,
nice, clean, quite
gambling locations
where the suckers
can lose their money to
their hearts content.
No trouble, simple.
Just let them throw their
money at little Benji.
Playing both ends against
the middle, aren't ya?
Of course, I like you Dave,
we understand one another.
You forget two things.
Frank Jansen's got
six million dollars.
He owes nobody nothing.
He can pick up the
phone real easy
and tell his Chief of
Police to close down
those nice, 30 locations.
And you also forget
Solly's boys.
They're likely to jam
you in a barrel of cement
and dump it in the Bay.
Nice of you to worry
about me, Dave, but don't.
I got it figured
right down the line.
Apparently there's
some confusion
all the way down
the line, Mr. Grace,
with the election and all
and Mr Caspar leaving.
That might account
for the lower figures.
You worry about
the books, Ames,
I'll worry about the reasons.
Oh yes sir, I didn't
mean to say that.
Oh, Mr. Grace, what do
you hear about Mr. Caspar?
I mean the word is
that he's in Mexico.
That's as good a place as any
if you're up for a
Grand Jury indictment.
How much cash do we have?
Personal?
You mean Mr Caspar's?
Well, the last audit I
remember three months ago
Mr. Caspar had 160,000 on hand.
Hmm, where is it?
Why I imagine the beach house.
I think we better get it out.
Oh I can't get
to it, Mr. Grace.
I'll talk to you
about it later.
Hold all the
appointments, Betsy,
Mrs. McCullough's
coming by to pick me up
and I'm not even dressed yet.
Come in!
Mrs McCullough here already?
Not exactly.
Don't tell me
other people see you
this early in the morning.
Hi there,
you're hard to contact.
- Mmm.
- Sit down.
- Coffee Mr. Grace?
- No thanks.
- I'll be there shortly.
- Miss Lyons, it's
nine o'clock.
- Oh, you better get started
with Miss Dorothy
if she's ready.
Oh I'm sorry I look like this.
Couldn't you have
telephoned first?
I like to send my
thanks yous in person.
Thanks for putting
Dave Dietz in.
You won't be disappointed.
Ben, Frank wants very
badly to talk with you.
I have to drive
up the coast today.
Isn't he satisfied?
Naturally.
He just wants to meet the
man who made it possible.
I'll buy him lunch sometime.
After I've bought
you three or four.
Mm, if I had my choice,
I'd prefer dinner.
Have you and Junie
settled the problems
of the world?
Couple of em.
You all ready to go, Dor?
Martha said so.
The appointment at Dr.
Mapes is for 9:30, isn't it?
And don't forget,
Martha will wait for you.
Looks like everybody's
clearing out.
I'll see you later, you two.
Oh, are you driving somewhere?
Well then you can drop me,
no need to bother Martha at all.
Oh honey, all our
plans have been made.
Oh it's right on Ben's
way, the Professional
Building on Woodward,
the doctor's gonna
check my eyes.
- I'll drop her off.
Oh Ben, you're
busy, and, Dorothy,
how would you get home?
Oh, he'll drop
me at the doctors,
I'll take a taxi home,
don't you trust me?
Miss Lyon's residence.
It's Mrs. McCullough.
Yes?
Oh yes dear, I'll be waiting.
I thought you'd
maneuvered us together
long before this.
- Maneuver?
I didn't maneuver anything.
I knew the first
minute I looked at you
we'd end up together,
and so did you.
What made you so sure?
We're two of a kind, both bad.
Cigarette please.
Look, kid, we've
both got things to do.
Don't you think you
should get in there?
You did know I was going to
a head shrinker, didn't you?
Nope, but it sounds
like a heck of an idea.
You're quite a problem.
Wanna solve me?
Hey, the lighter.
I'll give it back.
Come again.
You crazy!
You play rough, don't you?
Oh I can play smooth.
Hey!
Where you going,
the Professional
Building's back there.
I'm not going in
for that couch fit.
Can't go home for
a couple of hours,
so I thought I'd take a
look around the stores.
How'd you like to drive
to the beach with me?
The best offer I've had today.
Hey, what place is this?
Used to be a road house,
now it's a beach house.
Hey.
This is a beach house?
How about that?
Smooth.
What a layout.
Ah, ah.
This.
- Solly liked
the simple things,
he liked girls too.
Should we see if it fits?
Sure, try it on.
If it doesn't fit,
the closets upstairs
are full of em.
Eenie, meanie, minie, mo.
You go on upstairs and change.
Over there, I'll see you later.
No argument.
I won't be long.
Yep!
I got ya covered!
Put the thing
down, it's dangerous.
This little thing?
You screwballed little idiot!
Haven't you got any sense?
You could kill somebody
with that thing!
You play rough too.
I told you we were the same.
I should have skipped
Dr. Mapes weeks ago.
Come here.
Go take a swim,
cool off a little.
Just a little.
Beach is down there.
I hope we won't
be interrupted.
Solly's in Mexico.
Cut it out.
- June ever been here, Benji?
- No.
Score one for little sister.
Do you have any
idea what time it is?
On Dr. Mapes couch
I watch the clock.
On your couch?
Come here.
Here, take my car
and get out of here.
Meet me at the Medical building.
No arguments.
Hold it right there, baby.
I said freeze.
You want your girlfriend
to get it, Ben?
Do as he says.
Get outta here!
Solly sent bail for James too.
He'll take care of
you, bright boy.
Solly Caspar?
You idiot.
Get up.
Solly went bail, I went
bail for both of ya.
Here's a receipt.
Read it.
Ben I, I didn't know.
All right, now you know.
Get outta here, go
the way you came.
How is she?
She's fine, she's asleep.
I'll run along.
She uh, she talked a lot,
before she went to sleep.
All about this afternoon.
What about this afternoon?
The beach house, what went on.
You two, she said enough.
And you believed her?
I don't know what to believe.
Believe me, it's you I want.
Are you sure you
don't want both of us?
Oh Ben, hold me, don't
let me go, hold me tight.
Hello Martha.
Pralines for my
sister, she loves them.
How is she?
Oh, she hasn't come in yet.
- Are you sure?
- Yes ma'am.
There she is!
Yes?
Sergeant Chaney,
Police Department.
Oh, what is it, Sergeant?
We just tagged a
cab from downtown.
Driver said he
brought the fare here.
I'd like to talk to her.
Well there must be
a mistake, officer,
nobody's come here
except Miss Lyons.
Red hair, 5'5" to
5'7" in her early 20s.
Green dress, green shoes.
What do you want her for?
Theft, Hathaways
Department Store.
Pearl necklace, sales
girl wasn't too sure.
Was afraid to do anything
till she checked her stock.
Told somebody to
get the cab license.
Couldn't have been
Dorothy, she's not here.
Wonder if I could take
a look around for Dorothy.
Yes, I wish you would,
I'll show you to her room.
Dorothy!
This man is from Hathaways.
How do you do?
Those pearls are mine,
I've had them for years.
Sim pearl neck, 152.50,
tax 10%, Hathaways.
Had em for years, hmm?
Put on your green dress
and your green shoes
and let's go.
- Junie, help me!
Let her go, I'll pay for them.
Please don't arrest
her, she's sick.
Five minutes, I'll
leave the door open
if that's all right.
- Junie!
- Oh Dorothy!
- You promised.
You promised.
- Dorothy!
- Let me go, I didn't
take them, let me go!
June, June, don't
let em take me!
You promised you'd
take care of me!
Can't you see
what you're doing?
You said this
wouldn't happen again.
- Junie help me.
- I will, I will.
June, June, don't
let them take me.
I promise, I
promise I'll help you,
I will, I'll fix
everything
Extension 449 please.
Betsy, Miss Lyons, I wanna speak
to Mayor Jansen immediately.
I'll wait then.
Betsy?
Never mind, no don't
even tell him I called.
- Miss Lyons, come in.
- Yes.
Okay boys, break it up.
This way.
Three grand,
add four is seven.
Hey Ben, here's Miss Lyons.
Take a breather, boys.
Ben, you've gotta help me.
Dorothy was arrested
this afternoon.
- Same thing?
- Hathaways.
The police came right
to the house for her.
Tell me about it.
She took a pearl necklace.
A Sergeant Chaney came
to the house about five
and took her to Lincoln Heights.
Hello, Dave Dietz still there?
Ben Grace.
Dave, there's a girl
in Lincoln Heights,
Dorothy Lyons, L-Y-O-N-S.
Theft or grand larceny,
I want you to get her out
and I want you to
make it look like
she was never booked.
I can't do that,
Ben, I'll have
the board down on my neck.
I don't care how you
do it, it has to be done.
This comes straight from Jansen.
All right, call me back.
- I can't believe it.
- Believe what?
You, lying to Dietz.
Everything Ben, this
house, and what's
going on in it.
- It's Sol Casper's house.
He's holed up in Mexico.
Then it's true,
all the terrible
things I've heard
about you lately.
I didn't wanna believe that.
It's the same old
operation, isn't it?
And you talked me into
suggesting Dave Dietz
for Chief of Police, and you go
right on your merry way,
well Sol Caspar's out,
but it's the same system.
As long as people
gamble, there's
gonna be a system,
if I don't operate it
someone else will.
- If I had any sense,
any courage, I'd go
straight to Frank Jansen
and tell him.
- You think that would
stop it, oh a
little while maybe,
but before me there was Caspar
and there'll be
someone else after me.
Grow up, the money
is here, I'm gonna
get mine.
Hello.
- What about the file
on the girl.
- Yeah, Dave, we'll talk
about that tomorrow,
right now, I'm interested
in getting that girl
here as soon as possible.
All right, goodnight, thanks.
She'll be here within the hour.
Good service.
You gonna tell Jansen?
You know I won't.
For two reasons.
I know you won't
because of Dorothy
what's the other reason?
You know that too.
Told you it was all a mistake.
Why would I want to steal
a little thing like that?
Junie!
- Darling, it's all right.
Ben Grace managed
to get you out.
Oh Ben, thanks, oh
you saved my life.
It was horrible, horrible.
Forget it, it never happened.
I think we could
all use a drink.
Oh, you bet I could,
three feet high.
Nice layout you got here.
I can stay for a while?
Might not be a
bad idea, be safer.
She needs guilt,
care and rest.
Oh Ben must have
a housekeeper.
I can get lots of
rest right here.
Darling, you'll be
much better off at home.
Now, drink your drink, then
we'll all go back, huh?
All right, if you say so.
I'll have plenty of
time to see Ben's house.
But Dietz you
assured me you were
after the same
thing I was, clean,
honest government,
what good does it do
to get rid of a Solly
Caspar if you're taking
orders from another hoodlum?
Mr. Mayor, nobody
should have even
heard about it, I still.
- That's not the point,
I did hear about it.
I want a complete
report by tomorrow
even if it means
I go out of office
and you go back to
pounding a beat.
Yes sir, after all, Mr. Mayor,
it was Ben Grace who told me to.
What's that got to do with it?
I mean I figured
that after all,
you and him.
- That's all, Dietz.
Yes sir.
June, will you come in please?
Yes, Frank?
I'm going to be
pretty blunt, June.
I know all about
Dorothy's arrest,
especially how she was let go.
She should never
have been arrested.
She's not a criminal, she
needs psychiatric care.
But she was
arrested, and she's got
to face the charges,
the Governor's given me
till five tomorrow afternoon
to have her arraigned.
We'll let normal
procedure follow.
The Governor.
The Governor, who
could have me impeached.
Dorothy was on probation.
But you don't
have any idea what
it would do to her to
have to go back to prison!
Do you know what Dr. Mapes said?
That she's on the end
of a real breakdown
that any emotional shock.
- I'll do everything
I can to see that
she gets to the right
kind of institution,
she's not going to be
thrown into a dungeon.
All right, Frank.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to bring
her in tomorrow.
I'm not going to have them
issue a warrant for her.
June.
This can't change
how I feel about you
except feeling sorry, knowing
what you have to live with.
I know, you're
very kind, Frank.
I should have known
you'd be like this.
Don't you know by
now I don't judge you?
I just love you.
Come on,
we've gotta get busy.
Oh, Junie, you're home early.
- Yes.
- These gonna all be
all right here?
- They're lovely, honey.
Hello, Martha.
No one called, Miss
Lyons, she's been
fine, absolutely fine.
How do you feel?
Never felt better.
Slept like a log.
Dor, things are in a mess.
I hate to have to
tell you this but,
you have to go back, tomorrow.
To jail?
Oh honey, Frank
says it doesn't
have to be prison,
just a nice quiet
rest home, some place close by.
But you have to
face the charges.
Nice state institution,
all the modern conveniences.
Steel bars at every window.
- Don't talk like that.
Shock treatments in
different buildings.
- Dorothy, please.
- I've been there,
I know what it's like,
I've been to the good ones,
the crummy ones, the
ones you wear uniforms,
the ones you don't,
I'm an expert.
Honey, it's for your own good.
You've got to get well.
Don't you see what
happened yesterday
could happen anytime and
then it will be prison?
All I want for
you is what's best
All you want is
to get rid of me.
You want Ben for yourself.
Let's leave Ben
Grace out of this.
Press the button
and little Dor
is shipped off to
some nice nut house.
Dor, how can you
talk to me like that?
I've tried to look
after you ever since
Dad died.
- Oh, looked after me.
I've been shoved
off on more people
than you can shake a stick at.
Well I had to make
a living, didn't I?
Oh sure, you had
to make a living.
You had to get
ahead, be promoted.
One day you woke up and realized
suddenly you hadn't been
on the cover of Time yet.
I gave you everything I could.
Because you felt
guilty, you had
a bad conscience, you
know how it started.
That charm bracelet, the
one Mama gave to you.
I had to have it.
So I stole it.
I liked taking it, I
liked the sensation.
It was fun, so it
was you, June, yoU!
And all the things you bought me
they pay off a lot
of years, don't they?
A lot of years,
what do you think
I've been through
in lot of years?
Holding my breath
every time I saw
a cop pass by the
house, trying to
fix things and
square things and pay
things off, all
because my sister
didn't have any more
morals than an alley cat.
Oh, you're a fine one to tell me
how I should have lived my life.
If I didn't earn
money, who'd get you
out of trouble,
and who'd pay off
those lovely friends
of yours you seem
to attract the way
garbage does flies?
Oh Dor!
Dor!
I'm sorry.
You're right, June,
you're always right.
I'll have to go back, tomorrow.
All right
Sergeant, that's all.
What's the idea, Dave?
That cop was rousting
me like a pickpocket.
I told him to bring you in.
You think you've
got more privileges
than any other citizen.?
All right, Chief,
what's your problem?
My problem I'll worry about.
Jansen wants you in his
office this afternoon.
Oh, I think you
better calm Jansen down.
He's liable to get
an earful about
honest Dave Dietz.
- You'll be there, Ben
or I won't send out just a cop.
I'll have squad cars
all over that beautiful
driveway of yours.
I seem to remember,
Chief, that you're the one
who sprung the lock on her.
Good with a knife, aren't you?
Use your friends till
they start dragging
then cut em right off.
What are you beefin' about?
Those look like fifty
dollar shoes to me, copper.
Now you listen,
Ben, Dorothy Lyons
is just another thief right now.
And you're just another
guy who asked me
to do something outta line.
Yes, all right in a minute.
You both better be
in Jansen's office.
On time.
I kept it on hand as
you told me, Mr. Grace.
30, I think.
Is that all?
No sir, no, there's
an additional six
that I always keep here.
I'll take it.
What's that?
Mr. Coulter asked for it.
Solly's attorney?
Yes, Coulter was afraid
that Mr. Caspar's
safe deposit boxes
and everything
would be subpoenad but
the State's attorney.
What's the key to?
The vault at the beach house.
- The vault?
- Yes, in the basement
you know behind the furnace.
I'll look after that.
How do I charge
the 36,000 Mr. Grace?
Charge it to the blue account.
- Yes sir.
- I'll put it back next week.
Betsy, no more appointments,
the mayor's gone for the day
and I'm just leaving,
cancel everything.
- Everything but me.
- Ben, Frank wanted
to see you, but he.
- I've got a better idea.
What's that?
You and me, no
Dorothy, no Jansen
no Dietz, I wanna
pull out, with you.
You know I can't
leave Dorothy.
Why not?
What'd she ever do for you?
I can't run away
from anything.
Because of him?
No, not anymore.
Alright then lady,
you got yourself a deal.
We're two hours
from San Francisco.
After that we just
put a pin on a map.
Scare ya?
Yes, it does scare me.
I've got $36,000 in cash here.
After I stop up the
beach, I'll have
another 160,000 more.
Two weeks ago maybe,
even two months ago maybe
but not now, Ben, it's
too late, I'm sorry.
That's too bad, lady.
We'd have made a
great combination.
Dorothy?
I thought I heard you.
Your sister hasn't
come down yet.
She hasn't?
Haven't you seen her at all?
No, I imagine that sedative
you gave her, you know.
I've got a lovely
crab salad for lunch
but I wondered about the melon.
Dorothy!
Dor!
Honey!
Martha!
She's gone.
I've got to find her!
My name is Dorothy.
Well, how do you do?
I just walked in,
where is everybody?
- Are you a friend.
- Are you a friend of Ben's?
That's
uh, not exactly
the expression I'd use, are you?
That's not the expression
I'd use exactly, either.
I wonder when
he's gonna get here.
Not that there's anything wrong
with the people who
are here already.
Just that I'm anxious.
Don't you know
when he'll show up?
Who knows with Ben Grace.
But I bet if he
knew I was waiting
here for him, nice and
quiet on his couch.
He'd be here sooner than this.
He thinks that
much of you, Dorothy?
much of me, Dorothy.
Stand up, Dorothy.
No arguments.
Put on your shoes.
You wouldn't put me
away anyplace, would you?
Of course I wouldn't.
I know Ben
wouldn't, that's why
I came to Ben's
house, but no Ben.
We'll see him, real soon.
Nice material, I
love it.
- Hi Jim.
- Hi, Ben.
The old buss all gassed up?
Yeah, she's set to
go, but what do you
want it for, you can tool
around in this tiger?
I'm driving to the
coast with this bull.
Turned us all to my uncle.
You're the boss, but
gee, I spent two days
polishing this up, you know Ben,
driving that new
one, everyone knew
it was Ben Grace, now
you're just gonna be
another schmo on the highway.
I never thought of that.
Say, Mr. Grace, as long
as you're not gonna use it,
I got a real hot date tonight.
Sure, sure.
Here, knock her dead.
- Thanks.
Doesn't anyone
answer up there?
Ben'll answer,
always takes Ben
a little time to get
around to things.
Just ask him now.
Tell him you're
having a little party
all by yourself
and you miss him.
That wouldn't
be quite the truth
would it, all by
myself I mean.
Ben, are you here?
Ben, answer me!
Dorothy!
Ben!
Hate to say it, I don't think
he's gonna answer.
Hello, hello?
Oh, is that you, Mr. Grace?
What's keeping you, Mr. Grace,
here I am all by
myself in Solly's
nice little beach house
if you'd be here, it'd be
a lot cosier, wouldn't it?
Dorothy!
- Okay?
- Fine.
I like you.
How'd you know
where to find it all?
I'm an old friend of Ben's.
Never saw so much
money in all my life.
You uh, you gonna give it
all to Ben when he comes?
I'll give it to him.
Could I have some, just once?
Sure, why not?
You earned it, Dorothy.
I did?
If you want more, just
ask for it, I don't mind.
No fun that way.
You ever been
to Mexico, honey?
- Never have.
- Like to go with me?
Maybe I'd like that very much.
There's Ben!
Wait a minute.
You'll spoil the game.
Now you sit over
there in that chair
right there, facing the door.
Come in, that's all
you say, come in.
Come in.
Come in!
Dor!
Where's Ben?
Are you all right?
Who's this, Dorothy?
My big sister, June.
Always walks in at
the wrong times.
I'm taking you home.
I know where
you wanna take me.
Dorothy.
I'm taking you home.
Leave her alone.
You leave her alone, Caspar,
can't you see she's sick.
Sick that's a terrible way
to talk about a cute kid.
Come here, honey.
Sick?
I think she's
nothing but a laugh.
He doesn't
think I'm sick.
So you're that
smart girl Jansen
always had on the side.
I got a real good
reason to kill you.
I got you to thank for
Mexico, you and Ben.
Back up smart girl.
Are you really
gonna give it to her?
Run, Dorothy, run!
Why should I, honey bunch?
Yes, why should she?
The boys'll be here about
nine, and we'll have
ourselves a barrel of laughs.
Then I'm taking little
Dorothy and flying
down to Mexico with
her and we'll be flying
like bats upside down
and every which way.
You sit there where I can keep
an eye on ya, honey.
Hey, maybe we'll have
ourselves a ball right here.
Keep walking backwards,
slow, so you don't
stumble over anything.
Feel the door, you feel
the handle behind you.
Dorothy, no!
Back out on the terrace.
Too bad you won't be
around for the rest
of the floor show, smart girl.
Pretty soon, the tide'll
be taking you bye bye.
Dorothy!
Listen to me, it's June.
Ben, help me with her.
Let's put her on the couch.
Knew she was crazy
but I didn't think
she was crazy to kill anybody.
I did it, I shot him.
You?
Well come on, let's
get out of here.
Come on, help me
grab some of this.
I'm not going with you.
What do you mean
you're not going?
You're mixed up in a killing!
What kind of a witness
do you think she'll make?
You weren't any
part of this, go on
take your money, you've got
everything you ever wanted.
You're quite a
girl, aren't ya?
Ben, you've been hit.
Yeah.
Solly's men'll
be here at nine.
You better get out of
here while you can.
How far do you think I'd
get with this bullet in me?
Five, four, three.
What are you doing?
Three, let me
speak to Chief Dietz.
Dave, this is Ben, oh shut up.
Look I want you to
get up to Solly's
beach house at
nine o'clock sharp.
Bring a full squad and
bring an ambulance.
Dave, be on time,
nine o'clock sharp!
Lenny, Bruce, Grannar!
Get me in the house,
the rest of you guys
go round the terrace, I got
Ben Grace holed up in there.
Let's get her upstairs.
- Junie?
- Yes, honey, I'm here.
- Take care of me.
- I'll take care of you
darling, you're
going to have help
lots of help, don't
worry, you're going
to be all right.
- Yes, but.
June, you come with me.
I'll be with you, darling.
Go to sleep, rest.
Up there!
- Oh, Junie.
- Yes, darling, I'm here.
Turn that chair around.
Ben!
It's all over.
We're all here.
We got you, Ben!
You gonna come out, or
you want us to blast?
Solly says if you
come out first,
nothing will happen
to the girls.
- You got a deal!
- Ben!
Hi Solly.
Come on down.
What's the matter,
this type of work
outta your line?
Gotta bring Lenny and
all the boys, big man.
That the kind of
odds a big man needs?
Got me zeroed
in and you still
can't do it yourself.
Big man.
Shut up, bright boy.
No dirty hands, no guts.
No guts, oh I forgot, you work
on the brain level
now, too important
to the organization, Solly
Caspar, gutless wonder.
All right, you
asked for it, genius.
You asked for it once too often.
Little by little I'm
gonna cut you to pieces.
The old man can still
handle it, can't he?
How's about the other side?
Still got your legs, genius.
- Make a move and you get it!
- Hold up, Lieutenant!
- Ben!
- Get em outta here!
Ben, Ben, darling.
June!
June?
Hang on,
Ben for me, hang on.
Can't, can't say I'm worth it.
Ssh, don't talk, darling.
Don't talk.
Get a stretcher.
Let me decide if
you're worth it or not.
June, June?
Junie?