Subtitles by explosiveskull
Excuse me.
Are you all right?
Am I beautiful?
What?
Morning, Claire.
Good morning.
Everything OK?
What?
You're usually up by now.
Bad dream?
Yeah.
Her mouth was cut.
On both sides.
It was dark.
I saw her.
I don't know.
Do you know anything?
This woman, was she
wearing a red dress?
A dress?
Maybe.
The slit-mouth woman.
Slit-mouth woman?
What's that?
It's an urban legend
from Japan that I've been
researching for my masters.
They say her dress
is red from blood.
Urban legend?
So it's not real?
Don't know.
There are various stories and
accounts of sights as well.
This is what you
study in school?
I mean, I don't know.
Well, I went to Japan to
research the urban legend.
Why are you having this dream?
I don't know.
You tell me.
I mean, I hadn't even heard
of the slit-mouth woman.
That's Monica.
Thanks, Sarah.
Gotta go.
Hi.
Good morning.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Yeah, I had this really
weird dream last night.
Yeah?
I hear there's a rumor
going around about it.
What?
Why haven't I heard about this?
I've only heard of
it recently too.
Well, but you should
be careful, though.
Or what?
If you actually see
the slit-mouth woman,
they say you die.
Ugh.
Why would you say that?
Anyway, mine's only in my dream.
It's just a rumor.
There are ways for
not getting killed.
How?
If you're asked if
she's beautiful,
you say she's average.
That's it?
Mhm.
And apparently, the slit-mouth
woman has two other sisters.
Really?
So there are three of them?
Mhm.
Just like our family.
Wait.
What does this have to do
with not getting killed?
I thought it was
just you and Sarah.
No, I have another elder sister.
Really?
That's more news to me
than the slit-mouth woman.
No, I don't know much about her.
My dad's first
wife was Japanese.
So you don't know anything
about your sister?
I mean, no.
They put her up for adoption
for before I was even born.
You never met her?
I don't even know
what she looks like.
I mean, I've heard she had
taken her mother's blood,
but she looks more
Japanese than Sarah or me.
She was also raised in Japan.
What?
Claire.
Claire!
Yeah, yeah.
Sorry.
I thought I saw
something over there.
It was nothing.
Monica?
Monica!
Monica, where are you?
Monica.
Ugh!
Monica, why, why?
Monica?
In our next story,
in Westwood, it
has been reported that the
gruesome crime took place
in less than a minute.
The weapon used has not
been found, however,
the wounds on the victim suggest
it was a sickle-type object
that was used.
There are no other casualties.
LAPD...
Claire, maybe when things calm
down, tomorrow or the next day,
will you come with me someplace?
What?
I think what happened
has something
to do with the dream you had,
about the slit-mouth woman.
I think my professor
may be able to help.
What are you talking about?
You know, we may be able to
find something out about Monica.
There's a chance.
This is what we research.
Well, what your
research is insane.
I knew a time like
this would come.
I didn't expect it to
be so soon, though.
I'm predicting the
Japanese people
who come to the
States are affecting
the phenomenon in some way.
I'm sure Sarah has already
told you what you saw
was a slit-mouth
woman, kuchisake-onna.
Your friend was probably
killed by the slit-mouth woman,
but no one knows exactly what
or who she is, even in Japan.
What do you mean, you knew
a time like this would come?
Recently, we've
noticed an increase
in Japanese urban legend rumors.
It was a matter of
time before something
like this manifested itself.
The professor's
original research
was about how rumors spread.
But with this new
Japanese influence,
we've widened our research.
I don't really care.
I just wanna know why
was Monica killed?
Claire.
It's only recently the
killings have happened.
Something as gruesome
as your friend's death
never occurred before.
It's only in the last few weeks.
It's not just the
slit-mouth woman.
There are other urban
legends, such as Kokkuri-san,
which has been known to
cause deaths as well.
Kokkuri-san, please come.
Kokkuri-san,
That's him.
Kokkuri-san, is Yuri in love?
Hey!
Kokkuri-san, Kokkuri-san, will
I be together with this person?
What I'm about to
tell you is a story
of three women who worked at a
Maid Cafe called "Butterfly."
Kate is blonde, beautiful,
mysterious, a little cold
at times.
Mint, the manager,
always has to remind
Kate of her customer skills.
Lisa Lisa is a great girl.
Good service, always
cheerful to everyone.
She has many secret admirers
among the customers.
But Yuri is by far the best.
I mean, she is the perfect
embodiment of what a maid is.
But her smile is gone forever.
She was stabbed to death
in front of Butterfly
in her maid's outfit.
I heard the news three
days after it happened.
We were enjoying another
peaceful, regular day.
You say that, and
then she does...
No way she's gonna like
that response, man.
Yeah, she is.
Watch, watch, watch.
There you go.
There.
See?
What?
Yeah.
Oh, now you go to beach level?
Yeah, the beach level's coming.
Hey, Nobby.
Oh, wait, Nobby.
I was just getting to the
final stage with Yuri-chan.
I was just telling
Rob how it's done.
You... you guys don't know?
Yuri's dead.
Seems like an unlikely ending!
Not this Yuri!
The Yuri from Butterfly.
Look, it's Yuri's ihai.
We should place incense, though.
That's what you
do, though, right?
Yes, in front of the ihai.
Pray for the dead.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I've had too many scary
encounters with Kate.
Are you kidding?
I can't just go in there.
She looks down on me!
I'm pretty sure she's a lesbian.
And a sadist.
She's an ultra-sadist.
I'll be having a conversation
with Yuri-chan, having
a pleasant time, and
then she'll come over
just to ruin everything, 'cause
she loves to see people suffer.
The giant bing!
Here for Yuri?
Come in.
Kate, I just got a
call from the police.
It's Lisa Lisa now.
She's dead.
What?
Lisa Lisa?
Is it connected to Yuri?
What's going on?
How should I know?
Well, they don't know
the cause of death yet.
It's an unusual death.
She may have been murdered.
Hey, wait.
Wait, wait.
You need help?
Where you going?
I know there's something between
Yuri's death and Lisa Lisa's
death, right?
We all really liked Yuri.
Well, not just Yuri, but all
maids from Butterfly Cafe
are great.
But... but if something
was going on,
if... if Yuri and Lisa Lisa
got involved into something,
I mean, I don't know.
We... we just want to help.
And you too.
What if something were
to happen to you too?
I know you're thinking that
Yuri and Lisa Lisa's death
are connected in some way.
It may not be obvious, but I
have this really good skill
about me.
I can... I can solve things.
I mean, my game skills
allow me to... you know,
the mysteries that I go
through with my girl games?
Shut the fuck up!
Angie.
Kate.
I don't know what to do.
We were just hanging out and...
and smoking pot, you know?
And then I went to the bathroom.
I heard Lisa Lisa start to
yell, and she ran outside.
And then I came back
and no one was there,
and she was in terrible shape.
No...
Oi, can you show us again
what happened inside?
Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
Bye, Kate.
Angie!
You know, she said your
friend's name when she went out,
your Japanese friend.
You mean Yuri.
We went to this really
weird warehouse,
and she looked at it.
And, guys, I think
Kate's in trouble.
So that's how it is?
Yuri-chan to Kate?
Yuri-chan and Lisa
Lisa are dead.
And you just move on to Kate?
I didn't know you
could be so heartless!
What are you talking about?
I just wanna know
why Yuri was killed.
And?
And what?
And you can't do
anything about it.
It's the cops' jobs now, OK?
Leave it to them.
It's a curse.
Yuri-chan was Japanese.
She could have put
a curse on someone
with Kokkuri-san or something.
Kokkuri-san?
Kokkuri-san is the Japanese
version of the Ouija board.
Yuri was into it.
Remember?
The three of them would
play at the cafe sometimes.
The one with that coin?
Yes.
But so what does
this Kokkuri-san have
to do with all this?
Japanese Ouija board summons
the spirit of the fox,
or spirits possess people, and...
and if you're disrespectful,
misfortune will come.
Bullshit!
No, he's right.
I've been hearing a lot of
Japanese ghost incidents
happening here in the States.
Wait, wait.
So you're saying that Kate is
going to be the next victim?
I'd better call her.
Joe, you don't even
know her number.
Hey, Manager Mint.
Joe!
Manager Mint!
Relax!
He can't help it.
Kate's the only
thing on his mind.
Manager Mint, we need to get
in touch with Kate, like now.
It's you, isn't it?
Following Kate around?
Are you trying to take
Kate from me as well?
No, Manager Mint, please.
We just want to help the case.
It might the curse
of Kokkuri-san.
Kokkuri-san?
Haven't you heard on the news?
The Japanese [INAUDIBLE]
being reported.
I think Lisa Lisa and Yuri's
incidents are connected.
Yes, we saw them do
Kokkuri-san here,
and we think it may
have triggered a curse.
And if that's the case,
then Kate is in danger.
Yes, they once told me there's
a secret spot to do that.
Secret spot?
So we wanna inform
Kate of the curse.
So can you give us her number?
Guys, I appreciate your
concern about Kate.
But this is real,
not your anime world.
Besides, the extent of your
relationship with my girls
stays in the shop!
You can't see them privately.
So get out.
Go, go.
Get out.
I think she's a sadistic
feminist lesbian as well.
Ralph, it's OK.
I think I know
where the place is.
It's Kate's car.
Nobby.
Nobby, I can't do this!
I'm going home.
Seriously, this is too much.
I'm not even talking
about ghosts.
We could find some
whack job here.
Ralph, it's still daytime.
Nothing is going to happen.
I seriously can't go further.
Hey, I'm gonna check
out what's out there.
OK.
We're gonna go over there.
If Joe and Kate
gets closer, that
means we get a chance
with the other maids.
He acts as if those he's hero.
That's what's going through
your mind right now?
Well, we'll finally get
to live in the real world.
A satisfying offline existence.
This ain't happening.
It's a dream.
Ralph, Ralph, Ralph, relax.
Just start breathing.
Come on.
Hey, what are you
guys doing here?
Get out!
What about you?
Don't worry about me.
Get out... now!
What are you talking about?
Everything's fine.
Ralph's just freaking out.
Kate!
I know what's going on.
It's the curse, the
curse of the Kokkuri-san!
You and Yuri and
Lisa-chan did something!
You crossed the line somewhere!
Son of a bitch, Kate!
You're the one who...
Yuri, stop it!
Joe.
Joe, we have to go.
We have to go!
We gotta go.
Joe, Joe, come on!
Come on!
What are you gonna do?
Turning Yuri back.
Turn her what?
You saw her.
She's dead.
Yes, she is.
But... but she came back.
What?
After she was killed,
I came here every night
to talk to her,
through Kokkuri-san.
We talked about the good
times we had together.
Sure, it was through this board,
but I knew she was right there.
It was the third night
after she was killed.
She told me she had been
cursed and killed by Lisa Lisa.
Kokkuri-san, Kokkuri-san,
Kokkuri-san, [INAUDIBLE]..
Lisa Lisa?
Hi, Kate.
You didn't come
in to work today.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
I... I just had...
Why are you doing
Kokkuri-san alone?
Kate!
Lisa-chan.
I knew it.
You are together.
That's right.
Kate, I...
What's up, Lisa-chan?
I hope you guys are happy.
I knew that she
liked me as well,
but I just wanted the
three of us to be friends.
No one is allowed
ever near Kate!
You geeks, Lisa Lisa, no one!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
I... I don't like Kate.
I like you!
I'm with Kate!
We're going to rest Yuri's
spirit, using Kokkuri-san.
Then Yuri will...
I know, but... but she killed
Lisa Lisa and your friends.
She's not Yuri anymore, Joe.
She's not who she was anymore!
She's not who she was!
I'm sorry.
Look, I"m sorry!
No, no!
OK, OK, OK.
Let's do this.
Kokkuri-san, Kokkuri-san,
please put Yuri to rest.
Why?
Kate, maybe... maybe
the Kokkuri-san
isn't the reason Yuri came back.
What, then?
I think it was you.
You.
You brought... you
brought Yuri back.
So I think you hold the answer.
What?
It wasn't Kokkuri-san?
Oh, Yuri.
I'm so sorry.
You said you'll always love me.
And that's why I'm here.
I'm always, always, always
gonna be with you, Kate.
Kokkuri-san, Kokkuri-san, will
I be together with this person?
And that's why I need to
kill everyone around you!
Please.
Please, don't do this.
It's OK You and I can
always be together.
Yuri, stop it!
Yuri, stop!
Maybe You brought Yuri back,
so you hold the answer.
Yuri, we can't be
together anymore!
I'm with Joe now.
You're lying.
You're a lesbian.
No, I'm not.
No!
Kate!
Stop, stop!
Stop it, Kate.
Kate!
Kate.
Stop!
Stop.
Kate.
You said you'll always love me.
Monica?
Monica!
Monica.
Monica?
City police suspect that
the recent gruesome murders
in the Westwood area
have connections
to Japanese urban legends.
The police are requesting the
assistance of Japanese experts
on the matter.
And it is reported that
a team of researchers
are arriving next week.
Recently, there
has been an influx
of reports regarding a
Japanese urban legend,
the slit-mouth woman.
The reports range from
sightings of the woman in person
to appearances of her in dreams.
However, the...
Claire.
Claire, Claire!
Claire!
Claire, Claire, Claire!
Did you have a dream of
the slit-mouth woman again?
Sarah, Are you...
What?
What are you saying?
In the dream, I was
the slit-mouth woman.
What are you talking about?
It was just a dream.
Sarah, I was the
slit-mouth woman!
It's just a dream!
I was... please, help me!
Claire, Claire.
Sarah!
You said you had never heard
of the slit-mouth woman before.
No.
Maybe...
Maybe what?
No.
I have to check
something out first.
Remy, I'm gonna ask
you just one more time.
Where's the shipment?
There is no shipment!
Everything is to set you up.
What, you think you're
gonna get away with this?
Where the hell's the shipment?
I want an answer!
No!
No, Murdoch.
I don't think I'm
gonna get away with it.
What the hell are
you talking about?
You're not the boss anymore!
Nadal, what the hell do you
think you're Doing Nadal.
Nadal, put the gun down, Nadal!
Ow.
Your time was way over.
Shit, that hurts.
Jesus.
Did you have to go so hard?
Couldn't you take it
a little easier on me?
Well, to have the
boss believe it.
Hey!
Who's the fucking boss?
I'm sorry.
That's right.
I'm the fucking boss.
OK, we
got a plane to catch.
Hey, who the fuck are you?
Hey, get out of here!
Sinners full of hatred.
Feel the wrath of hell!
Hate.
Hate!
Fuck!
Who are you?
What the heck?
Fix it!
Help.
Ugh.
No, no.
Please, I need you to stop.
Stop pulling away from me,
and you need to stop whining.
No, no!
This is a really
important day, OK?
I need you stop playing games.
You know I need to go to work.
I don't wanna go to school.
You have to go to school.
I need you to!
You know what?
I... I just have... have
had enough of you!
Ugh.
Oh.
Wait, wait.
I don't even know
how to thank you!
Most
Help!
Thank you.
No, please.
Help, please.
Dead bodies are coming
alive again because of him.
He's trying to rule the world
by using people's hatred.
Please, please!
Please, help!
Stay out of my way, monk.
I'm gonna give you
the death you deserve!
This
Monica?
Why?
No, no, no!
Claire.
Stay away!
Get out!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Claire.
Stay away from me!
Claire, hello?
Get out!
Slit-mouth woman!
Relax, relax.
It's the slit-mouth woman!
Claire!
Get out!
Please, please.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Claire.
Get out!
Claire.
Stop!
What are you saying?
Give me the knife.
Look at me.
Look me in the eyes.
Can I have the knife?
I'm going to take
the knife away.
Help.
The slit-mouth woman.
Yeah, OK.
Give me the knife.
Claire, give me the knife!
No.
Claire, please.
No, Claire.
Claire!
Slit-mouth woman!
Slit-mouth woman.
Sarah.
You need some help?
Oh my Buddha!
You didn't remember me!
What's going on?
This makes no sense to me.
I'm Ken.
What's my Buddha's name?
Uh, your Buddha's name is Jack.
What are you, Chinese?
I'm Mongolian.
Mongolian?
I think you're the
first I've met.
Japanese joke!
I'm Japanese.
You're funny.
Uh, all right.
Let's see.
Now, it shouldn't be
that difficult, actually.
Look, you just have to
tighten this guy up here.
They're connected.
Just go ahead and start it up.
Try it now.
You really are my Buddha?
Just basic mechanical
work I've done before.
You see?
Yeah.
Wow!
Thank you!
Whoa, whoa, geez.
Arigato.
Hey, you know what?
Please, I want to invite
you to dinner tonight.
That's all right.
It's not a problem, man.
Don't worry.
I don't hit on you.
I have a sister.
So the three of us, yes?
What, for like sushi?
No, Japanese food
is not just sushi.
I'll prepare more
fun, more tasty.
And my sister?
Very beautiful.
Come on.
Beautiful sister, good food.
OK, you don't trust me?
It's not that I don't trust you.
Here.
This is my business card.
Oh, so you import Japanese...
exotic Japanese food?
That's interesting.
Yes.
That's why.
Our food is very special.
Well.
Um, can I have
your card, please?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Oh, graphic designer?
Ah, nice.
OK.
Follow me.
Follow me, follow me, huh?
Follow me, OK?
And I have a beautiful sister.
Hey, Ken, Ken, Ken.
You gotta...
Oh, thank you, thank
you, thank you!
It's all right.
Just close this.
So I'm gonna follow you.
Yes.
All right.
Sounds good.
Umeko, Umeko?
Sorry, she's a little shy.
Shy like her brother, right?
What are you talking about?
I'm not shy.
No, I was just making a joke.
You know.
I don't get American joke.
Well, it wasn't an
American joke, but...
Umeko is a shy girl.
She's still new to this country.
She don't have a friend.
Mhm.
So Jack, will you
be her first friend?
Of course.
Yeah, why not?
Thank you.
Umeko experience
such a bad thing.
An awful thing in Japan.
So I worry about her.
So worried.
Uh, can I ask you
what happened to her?
She's going to be so pretty.
Ah, Umeko!
Again you're so pretty tonight!
Jack, thi sis Umeko.
Umeko, this is Jack.
Hi.
How you doing?
I'm Jack.
OK.
Hi there.
Come on.
Let's eat.
Come on, come on.
Sit down.
Jack, let's try this.
No, no.
It's fine.
Thanks.
It's... it's inago.
Locust.
Yeah, OK.
I'm... I'm good with the rice.
Thank you.
It's... it's good for you.
I'm good with the rice.
That's why I import this.
So Ken, your... your
English is pretty good.
Have you been in
the States long?
Hm.
Yes, 20 years.
But Umeko, she just
arrived last month.
Do you speak any English?
Umeko is a shy girl.
She can't speak
English yet, so Jack, I
hope you'll be her friend.
Yeah, no.
We're... we're all friends now.
OK?
Umeko had a traumatic
experience in Japan.
Yeah.
Yeah, you were saying
something about that.
Our parents died.
I'm sorry.
That's... that's really sad.
It's not a sad story!
I'm angry!
OK.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to, like,
dishonor or anything.
Do you know word
"karoshi" means?
"Karoshi?"
It's a Japanese word!
It's like "harakiri?"
You know, the world is trying
to using these Japanese words.
It's like typical
Japanese things.
OK, what does it mean?
Death by overworking!
The company killed the workers!
OK.
Um, so why doesn't anyone
just sue the company?
The organizational system
in Japan is not working.
Worthless.
They don't protect individual.
They protect the company.
Our father worked in the
same company for 40 years.
40!
Yeah.
And he died from karoshi,
exploited like a slave.
And what happened?
Our mother, she
cannot deal with it.
She hang herself
in front of Umeko!
And poor Umeko, she
was under her dead body
hanging for a month!
She just have to
watch our mother rot!
That's why I brought
her here to America.
I cannot leave her there.
Yeah, no.
It must have been really
tough on you guys.
But you know,
you're here now so,
you guys have a...
a new life, right?
Yeah.
Um.
Oh!
Yeah.
I remember something.
Um, there's something wrong
with Umeko's room upstairs.
The light is not working well.
Yeah.
So, um, is it possible
for you to fix?
Because, you know,
you're a mechanic, right?
Please, Jack?
It would be nice to be
two of you, you know,
to get to know each other.
Please?
OK, just... It was a light?
Hello?
Hey, hey, wait a second!
Oh man.
I'm so happy for you.
Ow!
What the?
Umeko, Umeko, Umeko!
What are you doing,
you crazy American?
Umeko!
Who is it?
Hey, wake the fuck up.
Hey.
You wanna fucking
explain this to me?
Wake up.
You're running a prostitution...
What are you talking about?
This!
What the fuck?
Where did you get this?
Where did I get what?
First, you tell me where
you were fucking her!
I wasn't, Angie!
Hah!
Wow.
Great.
So you just jizzed yourself from
her blowjob and then, you know,
stood there with your limp
fucking dick in your hand?
It was like, "oh yeah, we'll
fuck again later," huh?
No, no.
It wasn't anything
like that, OK?
I'm the victim in this
whole fucking this!
Angie, she fucking jumped me!
Oh yeah, get the fuck out.
No, listen to me!
Get the fuck out!
Please, fucking listen!
Goddamn it.
Get out, get out!
Angie, Angie, chill!
Goddamn it, chill!
You don't know the
whole damn story!
And besides, you don't
get to kick me out
of our own fucking house!
Fucking impotent whore.
Get the fuck out!
You know, fine.
Fuck you, Angie!
You know what?
It's because of your
lazy-ass blowjobs
that we're in this whole
fucking mess in the first place.
Fuck off, bitch!
Fuck off!
Why are you here?
Are you following
me or something?
Is that it?
Hey, hey.
Listen to me.
Listen to me!
Where is your
freak of a brother?
Where is he?
Say something!
Hello?
Tell me where he is!
Where is your brother?
Whoa, whoa.
Jack, what the fuck?
Get off of her.
What the fuck's your problem?
Calm down.
Angie, Angie.
This is the girl.
It's her fault.
I don't give a fuck.
Ow!
Umeko!
Oh my god.
Jesus.
I'm sorry.
Did you really fuck her?
No, Christ!
Listen.
Angie, I'm sorry.
Look, I really think we
should just call the police
on these people.
Yeah, the police?
She's a fucking minor.
Yes.
Do you get that?
You're gonna be in huge trouble.
Fuck.
You fucking white
trash son of a bitch!
You hit my sweet
Umeko with a rock?
What are you talking about?
Now you're trying
to beat me up, huh?
Are you trying to rape me?
Huh?
As you raped my sister?
Umeko really loves you.
Umeko really loves you!
Stop it, stop it.
Get off of me!
This is the guy!
Calm down.
Baby, calm down.
Damn it, Angie.
This is him!
Calm the fuck down!
Goddamn it, Angie.
Stop it.
I'm gonna fucking curse
you, and I'm gonna kill you!
Fuck.
I still don't understand how
they knew where our place was.
Well, it's easy.
The guy gave me his business
card, and he asked for mine.
I was just being polite.
So I gave him mine.
Oh.
We can't go to the
police, so we can just
hope they won't
do anything else.
I just wanna know
what they want.
Angie, these people are sick!
I think it's very simple.
That Umeko girl
has a crush on you.
Well, it's creepy.
Yeah, well, you seemed to be
enjoying yourself in the photo.
What?
Oh my god.
Move, move, agh!
Oh!
What's wrong?
Baby, oh my god.
Calm down.
What's wrong with you?
Come here.
Whoa.
Jesus.
Hey, stop.
Stop it.
Stop it!
Angie, Angie, Angie!
I don't know what's happening!
Angie, Angie!
What did the doctor say?
No visible injuries,
no broken bones.
He didn't see anything, so
he couldn't say anything.
He only gave him a prescription
to help calm him down.
No physical injuries?
It really could be
a Japanese curse.
That guy's face looked insane.
Kate, you're... you're
familiar with Japan.
Can you help us?
Well, there was this one guy.
His name is Furen.
He's an onmyouji.
You're in luck.
He's in town.
An onmyouji?
It's like a ghost hunter.
I'll bring him over tomorrow.
Thanks, Kate.
Surprise.
Jack.
He says he needs to
use a stronger force.
But if he does, whoever
cast the curse will die.
Do it.
He's OK now.
Arigato.
Oh, Angie.
Angie.
Well, nothing's happened
since, so I think you're safe.
I just... I still
can't believe it.
You know, like, I
was actually cursed.
No, seriously, a made
in Japan curse, Angie!
Yeah, well.
Well, you know, we... we
gotta be careful, though.
That Umeko girl still
may be out there.
And Ken, he's
probably still alive.
You know, I think this...
this might sound crazy,
but I think...
I think we should check.
What?
Yeah.
Seriously?
Yeah, we should go
to their house, and...
and check and see if
they're still there.
We have to be sure.
I mean, you... you remember
where it is, right?
He gave me his...
his business card.
Yeah, he's in
Torrance or something.
Oh yeah.
No.
No, this is right
near my cousin.
So we'll go tomorrow, huh?
Yeah?
Yeah.
I guess so.
We'll go tomorrow?
Yeah, OK.
OK.
We'll... we'll go
tomorrow, Angie.
Whoa, two times in one night?
Seriously?
I thought we had a
big day tomorrow.
Oh man.
Jack?
What, you want me
to follow you now?
You stupid fucking bitch.
I know where to find you!
Fuck!
Jack.
Jack, are you here?
Umeko, come out!
Umeko!
Oh my god.
Jack.
Oh.
No, no.
No.
No!
And they're saying that
everything is somehow
related to the slit-mouth
woman, but it's not true.
There are various other
Japanese urban legends
that are involved
with the incidents.
Just the other day, there
was another slit-mouth woman
incident, but the description
is different from the rumors.
I saw the news.
It said she was Japanese.
Yes.
The name hasn't made
public yet, but it's
different from what your sister
and other eyewitnesses saw.
What do you mean?
When the girl,
Monica, was killed,
there was no
slit-mouth woman there.
Professor, why do
you think Claire said
she saw the slit-mouth woman.
Rumors spread, even though
no one actually sees them.
Do you think she's lying?
I don't think so.
Ghosts, urban legends are
born from people's minds.
So she sees it.
Sarah, you're thinking about
the slit-mouth woman too much.
Sarah?
Sarah.
Sarah!
Sarah?
Sarah.
Sarah!
Professor, what's going on?
Sarah.
Hi, I'm Detective
Evan from the LAPD.
You must be Sarah.
What?
Sarah.
We have our information.
The slit-mouth woman
is in this house.
Professor?
He says he just saw
it inside this house.
The woman is a key
witness to Monica murder.
And you are under
suspicion of hiding her.
We need to search the house.
What?
Wait!
Hey.
Wait.
Sarah, it's my conclusion
there was no slit-mouth woman.
Who killed Monica was...
Oh, shit!
Sarah.
Sarah, tell me what's going on.
Sarah?
Is this the girl you saw?
Yes, but she was just
in the other room.
Why is she here then?
This smell.
You said you taped
her on camera?
Mhm.
She was... What are you doing?
Impossible!
Huh?
What is going on?
We are filming her,
but she is not here.
What?
What the...
What's going on?
A ghost?
She's coming?
Sarah?
Where are you, Sarah?
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Sarah, your research was...
Sarah, did you kill
your sister, Claire?
I'm sorry, Claire.
Sarah, stop.
Sarah.
Sarah!
Stop, Sarah!
Sarah.
This is Detective Evan,
requesting [INAUDIBLE]
Claire, Claire!
Get out!
Claire.
There is nobody there.
What are you saying?
Stop, stop!
Give me the knife.
She was having hallucinations.
Claire, Claire!
I should have
recognized it sooner.
Claire.
Claire, calm down!
You bitch, can you hear me?
I had to kill her to save her.
It's all my research's fault.
I should have never pursued
the slit-mouth woman this much.
It's what I feared.
I think I just wanted to see
her, the slit-mouth woman.
That's why I went to
Japan to investigate.
But once you're cursed
by the slit-mouth woman,
there's no escaping it.
Claire, I'm sorry.
Sarah?
If you actually see
the slit-mouth woman,
they say you die.
Ugh.
Why would you say that?
There are ways for
not getting killed.
How?
If you're asked if
she's beautiful,
you say she's average.
That's it?
And apparently slit-mouth
woman has two other sisters.
Just like our family.
I thought it was
just you and Sarah.
No, I have another elder sister.
Really?
My dad's first wife is Japanese.
So you don't know anything
about your sister?
I mean, no.
They put her up for adoption
before I was even born.
I don't even know
what she looks like.
I mean, I've heard she had
taken her mother's mother,
so looks more Japanese
than Sarah or me.
She was also raised in Japan.
She had a Japanese name.
Umeko.
What?
Claire?
Yeah, yeah, sorry.
I thought I saw
something over there.
What?
Claire?
Claire.
Claire!
Monica?
Ugh!
Why do you even...
what?
See something?
Um, nothing.
Do you see me?
Erika.
Am I beautiful?
Average.
Subtitles by explosiveskull