Once, an evil magician
Troll
devised a mirror in which
all good and kind vanished
while all the foul and disgusting was,
on the contrary, reflected
and seemed even worse than it was
Troll's students dragged this
mirror all over the Earth
and caused much evil
and then they desired to
get to the heavens themselves
but the mirror fell from their hands
crashed and broke into
tiny pieces
millions of its splinters scattered
all over the world
a person, in whose eye such a
splinter got inside,
would start seeing only
defects in everything
and his life would
become unbearable
a sad tale
TEARS WERE FALLING
Oh, excuse me, Gennady, my
husband came in.  Just a second.
Pasha, the table is set and
the soup is on the window sill
Sorry, Genady Akeevich,
I'll start over
"Our fate can turn on us at times
So let us say in farewell hour..
...We'll say to Kovalev in chorus
That times without you will be tough."
"That times without you will be tough"
we say that one all together
Then I'll print it tomorrow
and hand it out to each department
Of course I'll do it
in time.  Of course
Alright.  I will read on
"You've never been too strict with us
Perhaps at times just too much so...
...When dedicating these lines to you
We love you so!  We love you so!"
"We love you"--chorally again.
In fact, all the last lines are done chorally
"May your good life flow on as ever
As ever sparkling with its youth...
...We give our love in being hopeful
That you'll forgive us everything."
"You are a foe to those who flatter
But we're not scared you'll take offense...
...What?  What did you say?
The word "foe"...
"Foe" sounds good, but...
...Her pregnancy is not visible
to strangers just yet...
but society should not scorn her...
I agree with the complexity
that a boy, a twin is growing up...
How can one separate them, knowing
that twins are biologically so intertwined...
Daddy-o, whatcha doing?
Not enough chairs in the house?
...whatever has happened in another family...
There's a child degenerating in there,
and none of you could care less
Not good.
...one can say that the whole
procedure of this surgery...
Sorry, Gennady, what
was that?
Dad, maybe I can open
the can of sprats for you?
Will you have some?
Lucy, can you please
stop calling me "dad"
--Why is that?
--I'm just asking
OK
Still, why?  I've called you that
from the very beginning...
I don't want to get into it.
Then what should I call
you from now on?
Comrade Vasin, is it?
My name is Pavel Ivanovich
Oh, no, that's for close relations.
I, being a stranger here, will
call you Comrade Vasin
Officially!  Hello,
Comrade Vasin
How was your sleep, Comrade Vasin
--Eat your salad, Comrade Vasin
--Get out of here!
What?
Out!
...And here Teterin is now present...
no Gennady, it
must be there!
"And here Teterin is now present
He will replace you in your job
...But he'll be the first to feel the loss of
How you are leaving us at last"
"An irreplaceable loss"?
--May I please?
--But that doesn't rhyme
Hello, this is her
husband
I have my own version,
please listen to it
"And now Teterin's been promoted
And everyone feels truly blessed...
...And now let's everyone together
Bow down so low and kiss his ass."
I think the rhyme is good,
and Comrade Teterin will like it, too.
What have you done?
That was Teterin on the phone.
Even better
Pavel, what are these silly jokes?
Do you understand how you
made me look?
I will dial it again,
you go and apologize
Do you hear me, Pasha?
Pasha, what's happened?
Do you have troubles at work?
My little hampster,
please answer when asked
Oh come on, I ironed this
dress, and now I have to do
it all over again
--I find your flattery distasteful
--What flattery?
A person is retiring with a
farewell party.  Some warm words for him...
--Who is retiring, Teterin?
--Kovalev is.  Kovalev.
--And Teterin is taking his place
--Precisely
What, precisely?! What?!
--Lucy is in tears
--What happened?
--What else has he done?
--I do not tolerate calculating people
--Dad, you choose your words
more carefully
--Go, dad has some troubles
Dad, who's calculating?  Lucy? How?
That she married a student
without a stipend?  It's laughable
--Laugh then!
--Gera, don't pay attention to dad...
She wasn't marrying you
--Who then?
--Me
--This is news
--She thought this student's
dad took bribes
--...she'd have a summer house and a car
--pure nonsense!
And who asked me
to set up a new apartment?
I asked!  What's wrong with it.
Every woman wants to have
her own home to manage
Do you have your own premises?
Go and manage them, then.
--Have you seen those
premises, Comrade Vasin?
--I've seen all kinds of things.
--Comrade Vasin, read me a fairy tale
--You have a daddy, he can read to you
Gera's busy with his
diploma work
Tell your mommy, if she doesn't
like it here, the door is wide open.
--Excellent!
--I am not keeping anyone
Dad, Lucy is actually no
stranger here. I forbid you to speak
to her in that tone.
Young man, you have no
right to prohibit me in anything
--You are an absolute zero
--Pavel, stop, it's unbearable!
I'm in everyone's way
Pavel, where are you going?
Can you explain this?
What, have you lost it?!
I tell this overgrown boy for 3 years now
that the tile is falling out, he won't life a finger!
Pavel, I feel so sorry for you
Pity yourself for how they'll
cripple you!  Poor girl.
--Here, take it as a keepsake from grandpa!
--Pasha, calm down!
--Egoists
--Pasha, where to?
Comrade!  Why do you
look at me that way?
--Me?
--Yeah, you
I wasn't looking at you
No.  You clearly were.
Familiarize yourself.
A monthly pass!
Hey, pal!  May I join you?
She kicked me out
Now she'll start begging me back
"Come in" she'll say.  I'll say
"No" out of principle
I have no home, no corner
of my own.  That's how it is, pal
--And where's yours?
--Who?
--Fedor!
--And I keep silent
--Fedor
--Whaaaaat!
Nothing
See that?  I trained her
And you don't just go back either.
Train her good.
What do you need?
--There are no vacancies.
--There are.
--I need a room.  What must I do?
--Give me your passport
--And put a $10 note in the passport?
--$ No need for the $10
in your passport, citizen.
Then is it $15?  Maybe $20?
Will you leave on your own,
or should I call the police?
--Your room key, please
--I'm going to the buffet
The buffet is for the
hotel residents only
Why do you all sit on your butts?
Get up and open the door for me,
as you're supposed to
--Merci!
Bobylev, this is Vasin.
--Do you live alone?
--Yes, Pavel Ivanovich
--May I sleep over at your place?
--With whom?
Hmm...yeah.
Good lad!
"People are lost
only once...
"...and having lost their trace,
it cannot be found"
"A person pays a visit to you,
Stays awhile and leaves into the night"
"Leaves..."
"And if he leaves by day,
he still leaves you
"Let's bring him back this instance
As he is crossing the square"
"Leaves..."
"Immediately, bring him back!
We'll chat and lay food on the table"
We'll bring him home, we'll settle it,
And throw a fiest in his honor"
--I came home
--Very good
--Did you get wet?
--None of us are infallible
Pasha, they left.  They
flagged down a car and left.
36-63-13
--Yes?
--Please call Lyudmila to the phone
--Could you call even later at night?
--Do excuse me
--Just a moment
--Hello
--Gera?
--Yes
--I was calling Lucy
--She's asleep, dad
Please call her
Let them stay overnight there.
Don't drag the child back and forth.
She's traumatized as it is.
Good evening, comrade Vasin.
To what do we owe the honor?
Lucy, you guys come back
home in the morning...
--Yeah?
--Well, that is...
--...if you can review your moral code?
--Really?
Dear Comrade Vasin, we won't come
until YOU review your moral code
--our moral code is doing just fine.
--just fine?!
Did you take my casette player
with you by accident?
--Or did you simply steal it?
--Oh, that's what it's about!
Grandpa, you accidentally forgot that
you gifted this junk to your grandaughter
for her birthday
So if you're missing your music,
please buy yourself a new one
And do check that all your
forks are still in place!
Why do you need that
casette player?
--What for?
--Yeah, what for?
--In order to record how you snore
--Who? Me?!
Enough.  I endured it for 30
years.  Now, enough.
--I snore?!
--Enough, Ira dear.
--If I were you, I wouldn't touch this topic.
--The lowliest dog has a right to mercy.
Tell me why you all hate me.
--For what?
--Who ?
Who hates you?  What
are you talking about?
I've always given you my money
to the last penny.  I never
cheated on you.
I devoted my whole
life to you people
--Pavel, what are you...?
--Don't!
Just don't say that
I am old and bald
--When did I ever say that?
--...that you are ashamed to
be seen with me.  I am only human.
I have nerves like
everyone else
--Pasha, the thought has nevereven crossed my mind...
--Excuse me, I must wake up early tomorrow
Good night
Pasha, you and I
never used to fight
Just tell me,
what has happened?
Have you fallen ill,
my little hampster?
--What's with you?
--What for?
--What, my little one?
--What do you paint your
lips for in your old age?
Whom are you
trying to tempt?
Swamp-Queen!
Alright, you chased out the kids
Now chasing me out too
Good boy!
Ira
I am at Dina's
Dina, good morning, this is Vasin
Lightened up a bit?
Pavlik, listen to me carefully
First, you need to seek treatment.
Take a vacation, drink some herbs, and so on
Second, Irina doesn't see that
you're having a nervous breakdown
And you must keep that in mind
--Third...
--Dina, tell her that I regret
last night
There you go!  Only you
will say it to her yourself
I'm listening.  Go ahead, Pavel
--Desert
--What?
--Nothing
--Pasha, do you recall
the first word little Masha said?
Remember?
"Give"
No, hampster, her first word
was "grandpa"
"Gradpapa."  And that's when you spent
your paycheck on the casette player
and said we would record her
Remember now?
Pavel, you hear me?
No, I am not listening
to you.  So long.
Hi, Pavel Ivanovich!
Again you made a draft.
You have a cold.
Acting like a child.
--I'm listening
--Tell me, people are saying you're planning
to take all dogs outside city limits
--Does that apply to medal-winning dogs?
--What dogs, what for?
For them to do
their doggy business...
--Citizen, lady where are you calling?
--I'm calling you, "vice-"
My dog has 2 medals and one diploma
Listen, there's a special organization
for dogs.  Let them take them out.
--Zenaida Petrovna, did Vasin come in yet?
--Not yet, Valentin Maksimovich
When he gets in,
send him to me right away
--Valentin Maksimovich, please pick up
--Say that I'm at the pharmacy
It's Mamaev
--Hello, Igor Igorevich
--Sorokin, what's with
your garages
People go to work, and
meanwhile their garages
get knocked down
--Everyone had been warned
--When?!  A year ago?!
Should have demolished
them then
--It was Vasin's idea...
--And now it was more appropriate
to give the owners some time
Understood, Igor Igor'evich
--Zinaida Petrovna
--Yes
--Immediately halt the
demolition of garages
--Is that an order?
Consider it an order
Pavel Ivanovich had asked
that such an order must be in writing
What for?  Starting a paper trail?
There's a paper shortage in our
country as it is.
To have an official document
for why those wrecks
are still standing
Alright, I'll get you
a written document
--Hello
--One minute
--Is this the communal department?
--Yes
--I'm calling about the garage
Comrades, your children will
play on green grass in that spot
--One minute please
--This garage hardly bothers anyone
I'm not authorized to change
the management's decision
So sorry
What's this I hear about our Vasin
going rabid mad?
I told you he was
kicked out of the house
Last night called me all enraged,
asking who I lived with, and could
he spend the night over
Please stop your gossip,
nobody wants to know that
Don't shout at me
I told you that this is all
under Sorokin's authority
Yes.  Hello?
Pavel Ivanovich, is it true what they say
that now all dogs will be walked behind the far lake?
--They will
--How will they get there?
--Individually, or on an express bus?
--They'll get their on their own
--Go straight here
--I'll take Lomonosov str.  It's quicker
--Keep going
--Come now, Pavel Ivanovich,
don't I know this city?
Spending government money
driving around in zig-zags
So you caught me now?
Yes, we caught you
--Wait here.
--It was supposed to be 20 minutes
and it's been almost 2 hours now
You may go. I no
longer need you.
--Aren't you ashamed?  No?
--Pavel Ivanovich...!
I called but couldn't reach you,
try to understand me
Knock it down!
--Young people why are you
stealing the materials?
--No, the guard let us take it
--Hello
--Howdy
OK, guys, stand up, get
closer, let's take the photo
--Hello
--Hello, Comrade Vasin
Sasha, look who's here
Comrade, please move
over to the left
Cut in a little more
--Ready?
--One second.  Sasha!
Comrades, I want to know
what is happening here?
A wedding
In that case, I wish to
congratulate the young couple
--that's first of all.  And second...
--The young couple is us
Then I congratulate you, but
I request that you clear the premises.
But we had permission
Nobody could permit to have a
drinking binge in an unfinished building.
You are all adults here, you should...
I knew this would happen.
Shouldn't have lied to people!
Attention, I am
taking it now!
Smile!
Only hurry up.
Pavel, I came for you
--Hello, Pavel
--Hello, Dina
Pavel, there's a therapist, Sklyansky,
a brilliant professor
People wait for 2 years to see him,
but he agreed to see you now
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Pavel, I know all your principles,
but could you get him into a co-op garage?
He's a worthy person, and
it's nothing so bad really...
--With pleasure
--Really?
Yes.  This instance.
With great pleasure.
Pavel...well... get in, let's go
--I cannot
--Why not?
Dina, I already cured myself
I used cowberry leaf!
Galkina, write this down: fire the
guard from construction site 3
for negligence
--Where should I write it down?
--You'll find where
Sorokin's been looking for you
--Pavel Ivanovich, may I take an hour off?
--You may not
I wish to knock down
my garage with my own hands
--ask Sorokin
--we know better than that
What is this?
--A sauna
--Precisely.  A fire hazard.
--And these are?
--Tennis courts
--How many of you work in that factory?
--11...
--Thousand?
--Speaking
--Pavel, I'm calling
regarding the garages
I just want to know whose
order it was, Vladimir Nikolaevich's?
Mine.
So that 2 people can
swing their raquets.
But it was your idea to delay
the demolishion of these garages
Timing creates the
necessary adjustments
Could you please sign this.
It's my reprimand for
professional misconduct
--Did you call Mamaev?
No
--When he calls, will you let me know?
--Where?  In the clinic?
--Go make copies of this
--Cut it out.  You created this mess,
and you fix it
--I said it's a severe reprimand
--I was hoping it might be a basic one
--Young lady, you forgot to tear off the label
--I cannot, I haven't bought the pants yet
--Pavel Ivanovich, what do you think...
--Call Galkina here immediately!
--Will you sign it or stare at her pants?
--I will not sign
I already told you that
I will not sign
--But why, Pavel? We had an agreement...
--That doggy playground!
--The district will put it on this spot
--What playground?
--What do you have in mind?
--A place to walk the dogs.
Cuz they've crapped all over town
And some people are
following the dogs' example
--Is this some kind of a joke?
--This is no place for jokes
--Pavel Ivanovich, did you call me?
--Comrades, that's all I have.
--Alright, we'll talk elsewhere
--We'll tell Efimov about your ideas.
He'll give you dogs to remember!
--Don't intimidate us.  Efimov
is also quite manageable
--We'll see about that
No, comrade general, no
exceptions for any Gaeva, sorry!
Gaeva has a permanent garage
that is not subject to demolishion
--Galkina, write this down:
Solov'ev gets no bonus
--For what?
--For wasting time dressing up at work
--Please don't.  She's a dedicated worker
She works saturdays and sundays
--May I?
--See Sorokin about garages
--No, she's here to get
a piece of my apartment
--Yep
--Did I guess it right?
You're mistaken,
Comrade Vasin
I am returning all the
stuff we stole from you
There!
And there!  I lost
the other one.
I'll reimburse you
at first opportunity
--Check it, it works
--Lucy
Yeah, I'm a fool and a simple nurse
and no match for your son.
But we'll manage to live without your charity
Lucy, wait!
I'm just saying, if you are standing
on principle, then you should return everything
The bag?  We bought it with our
own money.  The bag is ours!
"It is a good omen,
ice is melting in the heart..."
--Vasin speaking
--Comrade Vasin, this is Kuziatin. There's a
person threatening me with a rifle here
--Where?
--Here, building # 7
I'll be right there
These are my mother's earrings.
My most precious possession.
She lost the second one on purpose,
so as to hit where it hurts most
Don't worry, Pavel Ivanovich,
everything will get resolved
--You're gathering evidence on me?
--What evidence?
Don't.  Don't, Galkina. I can
see right through all of you
--Raya
--Yes, Pavel Ivanovich
--May I get Kostya for 15 minutes?
--No, his carburator is not working
--Got it
Zinaida, why are you
wasting time in here?
Go, start digging!
--Dig where, Pavel Ivanovich?
--Dig dirt on me.  Maybe you'll find some.
So here we are
Nikolai Vanechkin is out with a
rifle to protect his property
What a pretty picture!
Have a look at him.  Have a look!
Not property, dear Pavel,
but justice
Fedor is a war veteran-invalid,
has a Medal of Glory, and he is entitled.
--Medal of Glory, you say?
--Yep
--Did you know that this medalist
of yours stole my soap?
--How come?
In 1943, took a whole
brand new piece of it
Happens a lot
But the main thing here is that
Nikolai Vanechkin, my best friend's father
is out in the street...!
Beat it, or there's no
telling what I might do
Pavel Ivanovich, leave or
he'll kill you for sure
Hands up!
Get down!
Shoot me.  Go ahead.
Shoot, uncle Nikolai.
Maybe I'll even thank you.
It's not loaded
A piece of soap
Comrade Vanechkin
take your weapon
Take a hike, scumbag!
Kuziakin, where are you?
--Did he leave?
--He did
--I'm here
--Turn the weapon over to the police
Take a bulldozer and demolish everything.
--Everything!
--What bulldozer do you mean?
--It's been called off
--Who called off?
--Sorokin called me.
--Why didn't you say anything, moron?
But our main thing was to
liquidate this military cell
in a touristy spot
--So you haven't knocked down a single garage?
--Sure did.  Gaeva's.
--Did it early in the morning
--Gaeva's was permanent and
not subject to demolition
You're mistaken, Pavel Ivanovich.
It was subject to it
I started off with hers.
You need to see me?
--He's not in, Pavel Ivanovich
--I know, I know, he's at the clinic
When he shows up,
connect us
Why are you following me?
I thought I explained it all
in detail
What else?
Natalya, where's Galkina.
Don't you hear me?
--I'm talking to you
--I'm on my break
--Everyone has a right to take a rest
--We know all about that right
--Run out and find her
--Let those with bonus pay
run around
--In that case, you're fired
--Oh, I'm so scared
Comrade, are you Vasin?
Vasin speaking.  Hello.  Hello?
Comrade, so then you are Vasin?
I am Vasin
--Hello
--Semenov?
--Yeah
--Is your bulldozer gone?
--It's leaving
--Hold it back
Hold it there at any price.
It's not over.  The night is young.
I am from the local newspaper
--From where?
--the newspaper
We're preparing a feature about
how living arrangements affect
family relationships
--I think you could help us
out with this question
--I'm on my break
Till 2pm
Hello?
--5 minutes
--Be so kind as to
wait outside
--Darvatov?
--Speaking, Pavel Ivanovich
Listen, don't halt the
demolition.  Understood?
Do not halt it!
I cannot, Pavel Ivanovich.
Let Sorokin call me himself.
--Your Sorokin will call you
--When?
--I said he'll call you
--Raya, did Sorokin show up?
--No, Pavel Ivanovich
--Have a nice stay
--The law lets you work
here 2 more weeks
Nope.  Find yourself
some other fool.
"Drops are falling on the rooftops
Pouring rain is falling..."
"...as if somewhere a distant drummer
beats his little drum."
--Now you go ahead
--Me?
--Yeah
"Drops are falling on the rooftops
Pouring rain is falling..."
Good job, Masha dear
"...as if somewhere beats his little drum
a distant drummer."
Other way around. Drummer first.
But it sounds good anyway.
Now let's sing together
Grandma, leave
cuz we're shy
--1,2,3... Daddy, close the door
--What, did you buy the whole store?
Yeah
I got nothing today.
Go to the cafeteria
Today I have. See?
Ellie baked them
Pastries with jam
Blintzes with cabbage
So, Pavel Ivanovich,
shall we take a ride?
I dug up some worms.
Made kasha for the road.
Stanislav, let's take
you as an example
While you bring this
woman along with you
So, am I to keep silent
about that?
Of all people, you should know better
that she is practically my wife
--So let's not touch this topic
--No, let's!
Since you started this
conversation, then let's!
It's not clear to Masha "practically"
whose wife she is, yours or
that soccer players.
Vasin speaking.  Hello
--Press the button!  Hello!
--What soccer player?
I don't know. There's lots of them.
Raya, did Sorokin show up?
No, Pavel Ivanovich
How do you know about a soccer player?
Is it rumors, or are there facts?
Ask your second real wife,
she's telling everyone
--May I speak to Kuziakin please
--Nonsense!
She knows nothing at all
...about Ellie's existence.  She
never even heard of her name.
Dammit.  Nobody's
working today.
--Doesn't know?  --Nope
--Never heard?  --Nope
Sofia, good afternoon.
Vasin is troubling you.
--Cut that out
--Hang on
Sofia, do you know about the love
affair between your husband and
your neighbor Elvira?
Who doesn't know
about it?
--Then tell him that
--Hey!
--He's in my office.
--[Reporter] Now can we talk?!
--I of course understand that you're kidding...
--I'M ON BREAK!
--But this is a bad, cruel joke, and doesn't become you.
--It's 2 PM!
--1:57
Sofia, try to see that you're
creating an odd situation
for everyone
Why do I have to raise my
grand-daughter in a lie?
She hung up
Now you know that
she knows.  So what?
--Vasin speaking
--Hello!
--Hello, do you hear me...?
--She knows.  And so what?
--I hear you
--The phone here is not working
--Comrade...sorry, don't know your name...
--Pavel Ivanovich
--Turn off the pot
--Sasha Ermakov is
renting a room from me
--Bon Appetite!
--...the one whose wedding
you visited
--Hello?  Hello?
--I am listening
When you left, there
was a break-up
--They quarreled badly
--How can I help?
You must let them hold
their wedding there
moreover, your colleage had given
them permission...forget her name
That's a lie
Comrade, understand, this is
a question of a person's life.
I'm speaking to you, but I
had to hide the rope from him
--He's in such a state that...
--Where do you live?
Anyusin Lane, #5
Citizen, that's not in
our district
Sorry.
On Wednesday, I came straight to you
in the presence of Manohin and Kakaev
--What for?
--And I said...
...that Ermakov, the tram depot
carpenter,
...is requesting to hold a wedding
in the one-room apartment
that was allocated to him
--Why?
--Because he had already
sent out the invitations
--You told me to
let him go ahead
--So...
I said that this doesn't fall
under our authority
You said that it's not the
guy's fault that the fire inspector
hasn't approved the building for move-in
--So...
--And that I was being
a bookish bureaucrat
You wanna hang a
suicide on me
Let me ask Tolya to
drive you home
--you have a cold, and the city is...
--Galkina, this is so primitive!
Take me home and
put you in my place?
Only you sign me off too soon.
The night is young.  I'll knock down
those guarages and stop that wedding!
And your extortionist won't
get the apartment either
--He will get it
--He won't. I'll speak out against.
I will speak for it,
and everyone will support me.
Then there will be no room
for both of us under this roof
In that case, it will be
me who will stay
At last!  I tore off
your mask.
Pavel Ivanovich,
Sorokin just came
Coming!
Galkina, I thougt you were my friend.
I even wanted to marry you.
--When?
--This morning.
--What about your wife and kids?
--That does not concern you.
I never cheated on my wife,
and I never intend to!
Holding on to your power chair?!
Trying to please everyone?!
You double-checker!
Raya, instantly connect Sorokin
with the 5th SMU, and say they
must return the machines NOW!
Watch how you poke those fingers.
This is still my office!
--FOR NOW!
--And no need to yell at me
I can also shout so the
windows will shatter
--You're with them, dammit!
--Why are you intimidating me?
Why do you all try to intimidate me?
Look at you, commandeering around here
His wife busted him, so
we all have to tip-toe around
your hysterical persona
--That's personal!
--Do excuse me...
My mother-in-law tore out a lump
of hair from my head on Wednesday?
You know about that?  Does anyone?  NO!
Did it show in my work?  No!
Because I keep myself in check
--I don't mix personal with professional
--Valentin Maximovich, 7th SMU is on the line
Raya, I am not here.
Here, have some.  From Finland.
You can bring me some in the evening.
Why are you staring?  Take.
I know where to get more.
And one more thing.  Use words.
They mostly care about words
"Little chicken, little birdie..."
Raya dear, 2 teas please
--Buying me off?
--Please, like I'd bother with that
Pavel Ivanovich!
It was Vladimir Nikolaevich's order
I just came from
his office. Wish I never did.
Know what he said to me?
--That it doesn't fit the place
--Fine.  Let's see if he's in the right place!
Don't get into it!
--Raya, please connect me with
the birdie
--Sorry, with whom?
Forgive me, my head is all confused.
With my wife.
--Bobylev!
--Pavel Ivanovich, it's my
lunch hour now...
--Drive me to the city council
--Of course.  With pleasure.
I thought I'd run out and
find a bumper during lunch
It's in my garage.  I came there,
but I forgot my key
--It was in my coat
--Hey there, Pavel!
--I need to see you
--Hi.  Bad timing, come by later
Listen, what did you say
to my dad?  That I stole some
bar of soap from you...?
Forgot?  I'll remind you.
May 1943, Boys Village
in Amur Region
My soap vanished in the morning.
In the evening you brought
a bottle of booze.
--What "Boys"?
--Where we were demoted together
That girl Manja gave it to me.
Remember, the one with the braid?
--Why did she give you the booze?
--What? For soap?
--What else?!
And you kept it
for 40 years?
Bobylev, have some tact.
No, just remembered it this morning.
Saw your daddy-o and remembered.
Like father like son.
Degenerates
Wait, little hampster
Here you go.
Go buy yourself some soap.
Wash the dirt off.
Bobylev.  See that?
Childhood friend.  Let's go.
And this one... get acquainted...
--Pavel, I was just...
--This is Dina, a friend of the family
--Hello
--Come this way please
--Pavlik!
This is Elena Kirilovna.
You probably don't know her.
Stay in there, snowqueen.
Take rest, snake.
These 2 dames try to get rid of me
by sending me to shrinks
--Looky here!
--Pavel, what shrinks
This turkey, professor Sklyansky...
...him you know.  He lectures
alcoholics on television.
--Let's go.
--An totally normal jerk!
Pavel!
--Oh Lord!
--Bye
Poor man!
Heart problems,
Pavel Ivanovich?
--Do you have a pen?
--Left it at work
And garage keys, too.
Can we stop over and get those keys?
--My new bumper is there...
Bobylev...
If we open up your brain,
what will we find there?
--Brains.
--A bumper!
--One ball-point pen, please
--Can you read, sir?
It says we're on break
from 14:00 to 15:00
It's 15:00 now
Can you hear the music?
When it's over,
that's when it's 15:00
Lady, there's 3.5 billion of us
on this tiny planet
We can reach out and touch
each other with our hand.
But we live as if the
entire universe separates us!
I am speaking to you from Venus
and you cannot hear me on Mars
And I shout over to you,
lady, darling, sweetheart...
please sell me that ball-point
pen for 37 cents!
I really need it.  My
life depends on it.
And what?  How can one
live this way?  What for?
Get in line, sir.
--What do you want, boy?
--An eraser.
5 cents
--You?
--The complaint book
And a pen.
You may be from Venus.
But I am not from Mars.
Think I'll give you a pen so you
can write that I never gave you one?
I request your attention!
I was not given a pen,
so I will express it orally
Vladimir Nikolaevich, if you do not
instantly cancel your order
to halt garage demolition...
...then I am instantly
going into retirement.
I am counting to three
One!  Two!...
Pavel Ivanovich, this doesn't
seem to be the time or the place
to discuss this issue.
No, it is!
I am counting.
Two
Two and a half
Three!
Three and a half...
Pavel Ivanovich, nobody can
take away your right to your
lawful rest...
Pavel Ivanovich...
Pavel Ivanovich
Our car is over there...
--Where to now?  Back to work?
--Home?
--I have no home, Bobylev
How about my place?
There's no one there.
We can watch hockey.
Doesn't matter
--I am leaving you all
--Where to?
Where to?
To take Sorokin's place?
Just my own
Where once was a feast
There now stands a coffin...
What?
--An aimless coffin
--Sorry, which coffin?
No.  Hold it, Bobylev!
Anyutin Lane!
I can't pay them all back.
But I will return one small debt.
Stop.
Make a left
--There's a ditch there.
Take pity on the vehicle.
--I said, go left!
Faster, faster.
Why are you crawling?
--Now what?
--A puddle.  Need to check its depth.
Give me the steering wheel!
Step on it.  We'll cross it
by accelerating
I tell you like an ex-tank driver,
step on it hard.
There we are.  I didn't get
a chance to buy insurance on it.
Oh, Bobylev.
Can't even entrust you with
a simple task.
And to think we're leaving
the nation in your generation's hands...
Open the door for me.
Why do you sit there like an ass?
Give it a rest, Pavel Ivanovich.
I am not your lackey.
--I'm an engineer.
--Engineer?!  Where did you get
the money to buy this car?
My dad gave me
the money.
--And who's your dad?
--A lieutenant colonel
Which division?
Oh, whatever.
Do what you people want.
I no longer give a damn.
About everything.
Anyutin Lane.
Taken
Stop
--Where is "she"?
--She?
--I don't know when they woke up
--The rope you hid from him, where is it?
--Oh...it's here in the kitchen
--Give it to me.
--Here
--Thanks
You're welcome.
I am so glad you arrived.
You spoke so strangely on the phone.
--I must inform you in advance...
--No need.
See, Sasha speaks of you in not
so flattering terms.  But please
pay no mind to it.
Please give me the knife.
--Here you go...
--Thanks.  Hold here.
--Well hold it!
--I am...
--Where is he?
--In his room.
--No, no, this room is mine
--Where do I go?
Right this way, please
--Thanks
--Sure
Sasha, see, Pavel
Ivanovich arrived in person.
That hook
--A hook...
--What was here?
--A chandelier
--What kind?
--Crystal, with attachments
--It was sold during the war.
--Please hand me a pen and paper
--Got any other kind of paper?
--No.  Only the graph paper.
--Aleksandr Ivanovich Ermakov
--Move away please
Alright
See, Sasha.  He'll sign the permission,
I'll go get Nastya, and all will be well.
You already brought one here.
That's quite enough.
Shame on you.
What are you doing?
By the way, I'll tell you as a woman...
Citizen, the note is
in my pocket.  Don't forget.
--Be so kind as to give me a chair
--Pavel Ivanovich, why do you bother?
--I kindly ask you.
--We can do it ourselves...
--Thank you
--You're welcome
And hand me the rope, please.
--Thanks
--Sure
--Take this
--Thanks
Be careful.  You're too heavy
for this shaky table.
--Move away please
--Where to?
--There
You wanted to hang yourself and
be a burden on my conscience
It won't work, Ermakov.  Now,
I'll be like a rock on your conscience
Pavel Ivanovich,
what's that for?
--Can you keep quiet?
--I can.
Thank you.
--Pavel Ivanovich...
--Why?!!!!
Why lie?  Why this low lie
that there used to be a chandelier?
But there was.
Magician!
My respected ones!
I tell you as a construction expert that
hooks to crystal chandeliers are
designed to hold 200 kilos
of vertical force
--Where do you work?
--In a kindergarden
--Last name?
--Belozerskaya
--Which kindergarden?
--Chukovsky Kindergarden
Alright.  We'll keep it in mind.
I keep requesting a full overhaul
repair of this place.
And here's the result.
Deceivers!
In my death I request to blame
the blackmailer Ermakov, A.I.
--Vasin.
...and comrade Belozerskaya
Quiet, Reddy boy!
Reddy, quit barking
Silly boy
Pavel Ivanovich!
Solov'eva, humanity will flicker
into infinity of space and time
Like a singular wicked instance
It will devour itself
like a scorpio
Once, the depth of this water
was this high
We used to dive from
the shore, head down
Nobody will even believe it now.
Dear Pavel Ivanovich, what
are you doing to yourself?
Let's go to my place.
I live here.  There's my house.
I will feed you tea with jam.
You like apple jam?
--I do
--Very good.
--Solov'eva,
--Yes?
--The lake must be cleaned
--Seaweed is such a gem
--...yes...
--And it's wasting away
--Solov'eva, you know what...
--What?
--Don't go to work today
--OK, Pavel Ivanovich
Now go change, warm up.
You can make it up some other time.
--I give my permission
--Sure.  I don't keep a grudge.
Do you know Aleksandr Ermakov?
Who? Sasha?  I do, why?
--As soon as you change, run over to his place.
--Watch your step, Pavel Ivanovich
Tell him Vasin gives
permission for the wedding
--Just as planned before
--Sure
Tell them I'll come later on
Sunday to repair their table
I'll tell.  What's your size,
I'll give you my daddy's pants
--if they fit
--Thanks, but I can't now.
--I have much to do, Natasha dear.
You run ahead and tell him...
--He's not home anyway
--They're at the wedding hall
--Solov'eva, you'll catch a cold.
Go change immediately
--Run ahead
--I am
OBLProject.  Hello.
Dina.  It's me, Pavel.
--I'm listening.
--Dina, please call
Ira to the phone
--She's not in.  She left.
--Where?
I don't know.  Pavel,
I hate you.
I   h a t e   y o u
--Vasina speaking
--Masha dear
Hi.  This is grandpa.
--Hi Pavel.
--How's life?
Life's fine.  Pavel, you didn't
lose my toys, did you?
No, little one.  Masha dear,
is grandma at your place?
No, she's not.  Did aunty
Ellie buy the Hercules kasha?
She did.  Masha dear,
please get daddy on the phone
No, Gera went to
drop off your junk
--Mama's home.  Want her?
--No
--Don't disturb her
--She's free.  She's crying.
Want her?
Please tell her to forget
all the stuff I said to her
Tell her grandpa was under
lots of nervous stress
Did you get that?  Nervous...
Solov'eva!
Sorry, Mashen'ka...
Solov'eva, I can see you.
--What, Pavel Ivanovich?
--I entrusted a man's life to you,
and you're roaming around here.
--If you don't want to, I'll go myself.
--OK, I'm off.  Don't worry.
Vasin speaking.  Oh, sorry Masha dear.
Where were we?
Stress.  Only don't let them lead
you by the nose, grandpa.
You don't have any stress.
You have a magic piece
of glass in your eye
And you must shed some tears
very urgently for it to fall out.
Or else your heart
will turn to ice
Cry this instance,
you hear me!
I already cried,
Masha dear
You did?  Then, grandpa,
you must now sing a song
So that all the imps get scared
and threw back their hooves
all the way to Tar-tar-are, right
into forest-demon's forehead
Russian style.
Grandpa, Tar-tar-are--where is that?
That's in the fairy tale,
Masha dear
Comrade, pardon me,
is this horse yours?
--The horse?  No, not mine.
--Masha dear, I'll call you back
Comrade, then it would appear
that that's your piano?
--It would
--Then I must apologize to you
I was the one who
brought the cart here
It just happened.  I was in
a rush.  Guilty as charged.
--At your mercy
--And what?
--I wanted to ask: does the owner
know that we dragged the horse here?
--He doesn't
--Then it must be returned
--What for?
--So he doesn't think to worry...
--He's not thinking.  He got wasted for my $5,
and now crashed sleeping by a boat around here
--So what do you want?
--Me?  Nothing
--Nothing?!
Then go your own way
Look at them!
Good Samaritans!
Some get drunk,
others chase me out
Comrade, you're wrong.
I repeat: I stole the horse.
While the horse driver whom we are
now badmouthing is totally innocent.
One must not think badly of people,
not having any convincing proof for it.
Believe me, it's horrible for everyone,
and first of all, for oneself.
--Prove it.  Prove it!
--What must I prove?
That you steal horses.
Where are your witnesses?
I have none.
Just this horse.
That's just it
But you have the same witness
--What?
--Let's ask the horse about
your false logic
--Is that your piano?
--Yeah
No, comrade, I can actually
prove that this instrument is mine
How was that?
That's no proof.
Anyone can do that.
Oh, anyone?!  Then I will
ask you specifically.
I am waiting
What will you play for us?
Gershwin? or maybe Beethoven?
Buddy
Hey, buddy!
--Don't make noise.  There's people around.
--Oh, there he is!
And what did I tell you?
--Friend, I feel sorry for you
--Now do you see?
Please don't
"Drops are falling on the rooftops
Pouring rain is falling..."
"...as if somewhere a distant drummer
beats his little drum."
"Rain and sunshine signify a breaking point of fate...
"...Skipping barefoot through ringing puddles
I rush to your arms"
Thanks, Natasha dear
The End
Mosfilm studio, 1982