You left home again?
For a bit.
No work today?
I quit.
In this economy?
You shouldn't act on a whim.
I guess not.
I'm like someone I know.
Who?
You, Grandma.
Want a crope bun?
From the Station?
Great!
I can stay till New Year's, right?
Let's see it in together for a change.
If your mother says it's all right.
She's mad at me for my quitting the job.
At least call her.
Aw...
Oh, this came for you.
An older man brought it.
Oh?
A Mr. 'Hagio'.
Never heard of him.
Yasuko, don't just accept
Whatever people bring around.
He could've been an old school friend.
He knows your maiden name.
He said he'd come back tomorrow.
He seemed nice enough.
Ms. ARIMA, Sayo
Hagio
Mother...
Yes?
I've practiced a lot!
So?
So I can go, right?
Sayo... be back in time for dinner, you hear?
Yes, ma'am!
Suddenly you have manners!
Bye!
Off you go.
Sota!
Don't!
You've practiced?
I'm getting better.
I'll play for you.
Sure.
What are you painting?
Why no leaves?
I like the roots.
The leaves and the flowers
are there because of the roots.
Roots work hard.
And they're the color of paint that Grandpa makes me.
He makes paint?
Yeah. He grinds up mugwort leaves.
Yeah?
I love your paintings.
When you're an artist, paint me.
Sure.
Together again!
Real good friends!
What do you want?
Wow!
Lt's really good.
He doesn't go to school,
That's because...
he's too poor to go to school,
So he paints all the time.
So if I was poor, I could paint?
Sure!
Play with him too much
and you'll smell like he does.
Come on!
In here!
We'll be safe here.
Good!
Chicken! Why did you run?
I don't want to fight.
Because you'll lose?
Stand Still.
Someone's coming.
Don't stop here!
Keep going!
Move!
This is no place to quit!
We're almost in town!
You had to have pups, huh?
Lie here till the crows get you, then!
Stupid dog!
That's horrible.
It's not moving.
It's dead.
Come on. Don't be scared.
This must be her puppy.
You can come with us.
It's OK, little 'Chibi'.
Little 'Chibi'?
Yes, his name... We'll call him 'Chibi'.
Chibi...
We called him 'Chibi' because
he was small, but within a year...
he wasn't small any more.
Sota, Shall we eat?
Chibi must be hungry.
Come on, Chibi!
Here, Chibi.
Wow, potatoes!
What's the occasion?
Lt's getting colder.
We'll need our strength.
Eat up.
Sure!
That's sweet!
Chibi! Ready to work?
Here comes Chibi!
Good morning, Chibi!
Off you go!
Good morning.
Work hard, like Chibi!
I'll try my best!
Six bags in all, right?
Yes.
Sign here.
You write it.
Sure.
The Snow must be bad out your way.
Yes.
You can write!
I've been teaching him.
Aren't you lucky!
Harada, Sota
Chibi's Mother
Come on, Chibi.
I've got something here.
What?
What are those?
'Biscuits.'
My aunt brought them from Tokyo.
Good?
Sweeter than a potato.
My heart's pounding.
You're strange.
Draw this.
I'm learning a piece by Debussy.
When he died,
Erik Satie was very sad.
Are you listening?
Finished!
Wow! Good enough to eat!
There's some for you, too.
There.
Father!
What are you two up to?
You shouldn't be in here.
How did you know?
Parents know when children do wrong.
Is painting wrong?
No.
Sneaking around and hiding is.
Come on.
Sit properly.
What does drawing accomplish?
Bring me a small dish, would you?
Lt's done. Let's all have some.
Yes, ma'am.
Meet the payment schedule.
I'll leave that with you.
Oh, and put lights in the warehouse.
Wait a bit.
Light the Whole place.
That way we can work at night, too.
Take care of it.
Curry and rice! Sayo's favorite.
She's learned to play that piece of hers.
This is a reward.
Play it for me sometime.
Bon appetit.
Sayo, would you like a dog?
No. We've got Chibi.
Father, what don't you like about Sota?
You need more friends from school.
Why?
To broaden your horizons.
Sota teaches me all about insects
and plants and things.
And he draws really well.
Do as you're told!
Telephone, Sir.
Oh, there's some sponge cake.
Let's have it later.
Are you OK, Grandpa?
It's just a cold.
Look, Grandpa.
Come on, Chibi!
They've got a trapeze.
Have you ever been to the circus?
No circuses. Circuses are bad.
Why?
Because...
Never go there.
We don't have any money for circuses.
Here.
This is about you.
Who wrote it?
I wish I knew.
Is it all true?
Probably.
'Probably'?
There are things I didn't know.
The circus?
That part's true.
The circus definitely came to town.
This is a piano, everyone.
Sayo Arima's father
has donated it to the School.
This will allow us to improve
our music program.
Let's express our gratitude.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much!
Mr. Arima, Would you say a few words?
Lt's easy to make sounds on the piano.
Touch it at first,
and feel the pleasure in that sound.
If you want to know anything, ask Sayo.
Miss Arima, would you care to play for us?
Come on, let's hear you.
Grandpa, wait...
She was practicing that...
Grandpa!
Sota, can you go to
the warehouse by yourself?
The usual place.
All right.
And while you're there...
get the money, too.
I will.
Don't lose it.
There.
Well done.
How's your grandpa, by the way?
He says he just needs rest.
Overwork.
You and Chibi will have to
help him out.
Yes.
Here's this month's pay.
Go straight home, all right?
Whoops!
I'm Sorry, kid.
You OK?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
That's OK.
What's wrong?
It's OK.
Come over sometime.
Thank you.
Take care.
They're nice kids.
Let's have them over at Christmas.
Full of nutrition! Fresh-laid eggs!
Good hard-boiled, too!
4 cents each!
Fresh-laid eggs! Good for sickness, too!
Laid by our chickens this very morning!
I wonder if that'd make Grandpa better...
Cash up front, kid. You got money?
I had it here...
Yeah, sure! Get lost.
You'll hurt my business. Go away!
Chibi...
There it is!
Ah, you're back.
What's wrong?
Come here.
Grandpa, I'm sorry.
A man bumped into me.
Chibi barked, but I didn't notice
I'd been pick pocketed.
I went to buy you an egg,
and the money was gone!
Sota...
It's all right.
Grandpa, I'm sorry!
There was someone
Who needed it more than we do.
Let him have it.
Tomorrow we'll just
go to work and make some more.
It's all right!
Sota...
you mustn't hate people,
or hold grudges against them.
That just makes you sad.
It's all right.
A bean-cake!
That's charcoal!
Chibi!
Why did you walk away?
No reason.
Want to go see the circus?
The circus?
Lt's started.
Really?
Wow!
What do they have in there?
Lots of kidnapped kids, they say.
Really?
Let's go see.
Grandpa says circuses are bad.
You're scared!
No, I'm not!
Then come on.
Chibi wants to.
I brought some money.
I don't want it.
What do we do, then?
Where are the kids?
There aren't any, of course!
This looks like fun!
Don't touch anything!
Chicken! This is an adventure!
Look at this stuff! What's it all for?
Chibi!
You can't come in here!
I'm sorry!
Where did you sneak in?
We're sorry!
Your names?
Tell me!
Sota. Sota Harada.
Sayo Arima.
Sota and Sayo... perfect!
Lion's hungry.
We're sorry!
Forgive us!
Then maybe we'll take this dog.
You'll be a big hit with us, you know.
Don't take Chibi!
I do anything you want.
Anything?
Yes.
I will look into your heart,
and see if you're lying.
I'm starting to see...
Little by little...
Oh...
I see...
All right.
Let's run for it.
They'll catch us right away.
No, they won't.
We'll let you go this time.
You will?
Yes.
Thank you!
Take this.
What is it?
Something I found in your heart.
We're safe.
I told you!
What did that clown give you?
Eggs?
He's a god!
A god?
He saw my whole heart!
That clown's a god!
Oh, no! That's father's car.
Mother!
Did you have fun?
Yes.
Where's father?
He'll be late tonight.
I'm sorry we're late.
Sota, this is for you and your grandpa.
Thank you!
Grandpa, it's time to eat.
White rice... it's glittering!
How did you?
A gift.
From who?
Sayo's mother. It's for you.
Well! Isn't that nice.
I accept with thanks.
With thanks!
You got eggs, too?
Yeah.
Let's eat!
Ah, that's good!
We owe this to Mr. Arima.
I'm only able to live here...
because I can work for his place.
Sota, never forget the feeling of gratitude.
And...
never lie.
No matter how small a lie,
one day you'll be found out.
And then people will feel hurt.
That's a sad thing.
I didn't tell a lie. I was given the eggs.
Not by a man from the circus,
but by a god.
Minori!
Yes?
What?
Thank you.
For what?
Giving us a ride.
That was great!
How's Sota?
I heard something he'll really like.
What?
Shoji...
A pond with a legend.
A pond?
Blue, shining, and round.
Bottomless.
Why will Sota like that?
The earth there makes paint
With fantastic colors.
Different from other paint.
'Night-Sky'.
'Night-Sky'?
What color is 'Night-Sky'?
The color of the sky at night,
I guess.
That's just black, stupid!
Oh.
Why'd you invite me?
We're friends.
Friends, huh...
Shoji, are you sure this is the way?
Yeah, it's a short-cut.
But if a train comes...
Chicken!
Well?
We keep going, of course.
But...
How else do we reach the pond?
We should go back.
I've got a bad feeling...
Are we nearly there?
Maybe.
I'll go alone.
We've all come this far...
What's wrong, Chibi?
Run!
Hurry! Hurry!
Quick! Quick!
You OK?
Where were you?!
Sayo! What happened?
Mother!
Get her a bath.
Where were you?
We were going to Round Pond...
Round Pond?
You took Sayo to such a dangerous place?!
Was it her idea?
It was mine.
I'm sorry!
I see.
Where's Sayo?
Asleep. She's very tired.
The boys asked Sota to come with them.
Did you forgive him?
So he took the blame...
Kiyo, keep Sayo away from him.
Haven't you been hard on them lately?
He's trouble.
That'll be him.
Coming!
Please...
Thank you.
So it was your father
Who wrote this manuscript?
Yes.
He died more than ten years ago.
I found it recently sorting out his things.
I glanced through it...
and remembered things
he talked about when I was young.
Then I realized the story written there was true.
Does your father appear in that story?
Yes. My father was a clown in a circus.
'So many eras have been,
and always brown war.
and always the blizzards of winter.
'So many eras have been;
the one here tonight, in its prime.
'The one here tonight, in its prime.
'The high top of the circus tent.
A lone trapeze.
'A trapeze you can barely see.
'Upside-down, arms hanging.
The dirty cotton canopy.
'Hyuu, hyaa, hyuu-hyaa... '
Look who's here!
Did you write that?
No. It's by a poet named Chuya Nakahara.
'Poet'?
Someone who finds the words.
Did you draw this?
To thank you for the eggs.
It got wrinkled, though.
Thank you!
My father joined the circus as a boy
and traveled the whole country.
In one village he met a girl...
and a boy was born.
But my father left the village
and returned to the circus.
Are you that boy?
No.
That boy was named Sota.
So that clown was Sota's father?
Yes.
But he was your father, too...
He met another woman,
married her, and I was born.
So you and Sota are half brothers?
Yes.
I've never met him,
but he's my elder brother.
After ten years, my father went back
to the village and met Sota.
There. You'd never know
I was the clown, would you.
Yes, I would.
Why?
Your voice.
I See.
Your face is filthy.
You wipe it.
It's cold.
Stand up.
Wear that.
You're a god.
Me?
You looked into my heart.
I still can. You love that girl.
You want to marry her.
No!
Your face says so.
What I'm thinking now is that
I want to be an artist.
Well, this is really good.
I wanted to do it in 'night-sky' paint.
A legend says you get it
from the mud by 'Round Pond.'
'Round Pond'?
Yeah.
With that color,
it Would've been even better.
Is it impossible to get it?
The way there is too dangerous.
Let's go together.
There?
Let's go.
Wow!
Let's look.
Sota, is this it?
It's really true!
'Night-Sky'... the legendary color
my friends told me about!
Now I can do your portrait again.
I'm happy with the one I have.
So what'll I paint?
Something you really want to.
Will I find that if I look for it?
Sure.
Never give up.
Find what you love most, and
feel that in your heart as you paint.
I'll try.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
Take care.
Can I come back and visit you again?
I'm back!
Grandpa!
Oh, Sota...
I'll get help!
Don't worry. I tripped, that's all.
Get my stick for me.
Thanks.
Take this bell and put it on Chibi.
Can I?
Yeah. It doesn't look like
I'll be going out for a while.
Look after things. Will you?
Sota's mother seems to have died
Soon after she had him.
His grandfather took him in.
He was poor,
but he made sure his grandson was raised properly.
Are you eating right?
Yes.
Come to me if there's trouble, all right?
Thank you.
You're hungry too, huh?
But I want to use this money for paper.
I want good paper.
God said that I should feel it in my heart as I paint.
Keep quiet, OK?
OK, let's go.
Now I feel like I can paint.
You really must see Sota?
This is a present for Sota from me.
Be back by the time your father gets home.
Mother... thank you!
Sayo, do you know why winter is cold?
The gods made winter so we wouldn't
forget each other's warmth.
Now off you go.
This is from Mother.
Let's go.
Where?
Follow me.
Stand!
Bow!
Sit!
I will now call the roll. Harada, Sota.
Present.
Harada, Chibi...
Say 'present'.
That's a piano.
It's all shiny!
Shall I play?
Sure!
What's wrong, Chibi?
Someone's coming!
The janitor! What'll we do?
Go out here.
Go!
Chibi!
Come on.
The police called this morning.
That kid sneaked into the school.
What happened?
I spoke for him.
He broke an expensive
Specimen in the lab on his way out.
I had to pay for it.
If you play piano there,
everyone knows!
I let her go.
Don't let her see him.
Sayo...
Understood?
Sayo!
You want them together?
I think they should be free to choose.
I simply want things to follow their own course.
One day, we will find a fiance for Sayo.
They will eventually be separated.
That's best done now.
It doesn't look like Mr. Arima
Will forget this for a while.
There's something I want to tell you.
Your mother...
died giving birth to you.
She left her life to you.
So you have to live her life as well as yours.
Sota, whatever happens...
you mustn't hate people,
or hold grudges against them.
Give my regards to your daughter, then.
Today has been a fine day!
And for me as well.
Make the Arima Company grow.
That will benefit us both.
Thank you very much!
Good morning, Chibi.
Good morning, Grandpa.
Grandpa?
Grandpa!
O God...
Why does everyone go away?
'The circus tent, gone like a phantom.
'The site on which it had stood
Was smaller than Sota remembered.'
It ends here.
My father regretted that he'd abandoned Sota.
But he didn't want him pulled into
a circus life, never settling down.
As I read this...
...I found myself wanting to know
What happened afterwards?
The village office there told me
your father's company failed...
after the war.
My father kept it a secret,
but his company was in trouble.
Things weren't well.
So my father...
was secretly hoping to marry me off
to some businessman's son.
So he kept you away from Sota?
Please tell me the rest of the story.
There was a bad blizzard that day.
Not like this.
A vicious storm.
Sota had nowhere he belonged any more.
All that I think he had on his mind...
Was to give me that painting.
Good evening.
I'm sorry about your grandpa.
Give this to Sayo, please.
It's a picture I painted.
You give it to her.
Good night.
Sota?
Sota!
You'll be all right?
Who was it?
Just a salesman.
You're flipping cards.
Let's play a card game.
That's what men do.
Grandpa, as you said...
I don't hate anyone,
or hold any grudge.
That's what you wanted, right?
Stay there.
Fire! Fire!
Kiyo!
Sayo...
Was Sota here?
'Night-sky'! He went to the pond!
We're all friends, we said.
You sent him away!
Sir! There's a fire!
Where?
The warehouse!
How is it?!
The inside's fine.
A light shorted out.
It was good that we caught it in time.
I see.
Who found it? I have to thank him.
A boy with a dog. He left right away.
Sir!
Get some people! Find him!
You there go that way.
We'll go this way.
Sota!
Where is he?!
He's not dressed for this!
Mr. Arima's looking too, isn't he?
Ma'am! He's not at home.
Sayo, can you think of anywhere?
Um... Um...
Sota had gone to the place
that remained in his heart.
The place he'd found
what he really wanted to paint.
Sota?
Chibi?
Sota!
Sota, wake up!
It was just as if he was quietly sleeping.
Oh no.
He was listening...
to the piano coming from the classroom.
It was love.
I really loved Sota.
Sota!
Lt's all right...
...to keep the manuscript?
Certainly.
Thank you very much.
No, thank you.
I'm glad I heard this.
I want to thank my grandmother, too.
She went through hard times,
but she didn't despair.
That's how I come to be alive now.
So, thank you.
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1436464
Sunô Purinsu Kinjirareta Koi No Merodi - Snow Prince (2009) English.srt
FPS: 29.970
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) All DVDs to be subtitled
2) All VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled
3) All videos/DVDs used in lessons at school to be subtitled
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV
____           __            ___   __              ___        __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _   /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /    /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
/                              /                        /