The Year 1971 Africa
Democratic Republic of Guinea
In the aftermath of November 22, 1970, the President,
Ahmed Sekou Toure, said the Guinean people have
finally triumphed over imperialism, courageously
repelling the Portuguese mercenaries paid by
opponents of the regime... An important
wave of arrests will follow throughout 1971.
My dear friend, do you still remember Guinea?
Jacques, I often think of you, your sister,
your parents, older brother Diallo.
May Allah bless you all.
Nothing that belongs to this forest,
will ever be foreign to you.
Since our separation I pray
every day to find you,
in order to understand what happened here.
"Somewhere Towards Conakry"
I was twelve. I had left the Koran school...
...for the high school at Dézié.
I was going to meet you at last.
- Hey!
- Who is it? Fuck.
Hey!
Perhaps a spy for the Chicken gang.
Shit, he'll look through the
look and he'll tell everything.
Lift it up. We'll talk with him.
- Yeah, let's tie him up. We'll tie my
pretty bomba around his neck. - Oh no!
He shouldn't see the hut.
There is no.... It's too dangerous.
- I know that guy.
- Hey!
- Well then, what did I say?
- Okay, I go down to talk with him.
Watch out, eh?
- Are you the leader?
- Who are you? What are you doing on our turf?
But I came to congratulate you with the hut.
You know I live here in Green Boal.
And by the way, I saw it.
You saw what? You never saw the hut,
else you better watch it, you hear?
Hey, Madiou! Let your mother
grind cassava! Go guard your herd!
(Local dialect)
Is that understood? If we find you
on our turf, I'll box your ears!
Madiou, what did he say?
I warned him that tomorrow I'm going to
Kimbou in the same class. He's too smug.
Down with imperialism.
The traitor. At the stake!
Down with the fifth column!
Long live President Ahmed Sekou Toure!
Down with imperialism.
The traitor. At the stake!
I present you the new boy: Madiou Léhouma.
Sit down children.
Now we'll find you a seat. Over there.
This is your desk.
"He's a Chicken spy."
- Hey, that's yours?
- What do you think?
But did you make it yourself?
Of course! I have others,
but this one is the best.
For how much you sell it to me?
If you give me 10 comics, it's yours.
How much you said , ten?
Five is already a lot, you know.
- No, ten.
- Anyway, I don't have ten.
If you want, I teach you how to make them.
"A lease" becomes "leases".
- "A coral" becomes "coral".
- Yes, go to your place!
Jacques Séverac. Get up!
Can you recite other special cases?
Have you learned your lesson, Jacques?
"Window".
- "Window" becomes "Windows".
- Yes.
"Stained Glass".
- "Stained Glass" becomes "Stained Glasses".
- Continue!
You see, when you want to, you
can learn your lessons. Go on!
- And "Work" becomes "Works".
- Good.
One more to go.
Madiou.
- "Leaf" which becomes "Leaves".
- All right.
Take your arithmetic exercise
book, we'll make an exercise.
Well done grumpy.
Hey, I agree about the car, I'd like to learn.
I've no time, I have to learn my lessons.
- Mayaté!
- Visiting your aunt, Madiou?
You're curious, Madiou.But only
you will know my secrets one day.
But Mayaté, I sorted out the oil.
Come here my child.
You should thank your uncle for letting
you go to the factory school.
- Are you pleased, Madiou?
- Oh yes, Mayaté.
- Hello, uncle.
- Well Madiou.
- How are you? Learning good things over there?
- Yes.
Hey Madiou, since you're going to the white school,
you never visit me. I always find you here.
Huh, what did I do to you, Madiou?
(Local dialect)
Please Diallo, you promised
me your pants. I'm big now.
(Local dialect)
- Diallo please, can you can fill my water bottle?
- You just have to wait!
Magalie, it's done. Where are you going?
Magalie, you shouldn't hang out in the bush.
Come on, guys!
- Look!
- The old men have entrusted me this field.
The thugs will set it on
fire and it's your fault!
We must make them leave! We must make them leave!
- I know: we'll go see Yamou.
- Let's go!
Hey look! Some guys are coming from the savanna!
(Shouts of panic)
Hey Magalie! Go hide behind
the bushes with the others!
Hurry up! Hurry!
(Battle cries)
The cavalry, attack!
The Guinean Democratic Party told imperialism:
Your dreams, you'll swallow them.
It is me who shall bury you.
Therefore to denounce the enemies of the people,
the attitude of corrupt party officials,
and lackeys of imperialism, is effectively
fighting against imperialism.
- Long live the revolution!
- LONG LIVE THE REVOLUTION!
Down with imperialism!
Down with colonialism! Thanks comrades.
Hey old man, where are you going?
- Can't you see where I'm going?
- Didn't you hear what I just said?
This day is a holiday for the
revolution. No one has to work.
Ah well. But it's always holidays with you guys.
- But who'll cultivate my field and feed my family?
- The party has decided, comrade.
The party feeds its people.
- The party isn't the father of my children. Nor you.
- You know who I am?
I'm the representative of the
government. The party here is me!
The party of your mother, yes! Who are you?
Me and all the old men here, we saw you being born.
You were sent to the capital. You got fat
there. And now you want to decide for us?
(Local dialect)
So, old man, didn't you work
enough for the colonists, eh?
- You know I can make you stop?
- Me? - Yes, exactly!
Comrade farmers, comrade farmers.
The party is thinking of you: ration cards will
be distributed at the end of the session.
Thank you fellow member of the
federal office. Comrade activists,
there are problems in the countryside.
- I'm scared, Madiou.
- Mayaté.
I'm afraid that you don't see me enough.
One day you'll leave school for another.
You'll go to Conakry.
And I won't see you any
more to tell you your story.
(Local dialect)
Come on, go! Come on, come on...!
It's Magalie.
Push yourself up!
Be brave, Magalie! Be brave!
(Unintelligible)
Does it hurt? Can you move your leg?
Magalie isn't afraid of anything. She's strong.
- Then why does she want a plaster?
- It doesn't matter, will you tell my mother?
- You'll be in trouble tonight.
- Sorry, Diallo. You're my big brother. Let's forget it.
If I was your big brother, I would've spanked you.
Hey Jacques, come look.
(Unintelligible)
... go see your hut, take a look,
we'll tear it down.
I tell you to stop.
- We'll demolish your hut.
- It was you who sent us.... !
(Unintelligible)
- It serves them right.
- It serves him right.
- Hey Jacques, where are you going?
- (Unintelligible)
Ah, Magalie. You're fine?
Magalie, the little orange bowl, please!
See the little crocodile, I could save it.
Now you got my pants. You see
in what state you bring it back?
You'll wash it yourself.
I go wash MYself.
- Did you find one?
- Yes.
- Hey Mom, you know what happened this afternoon?
- You wait and see when your father returns.
Don't worry, I saved you, nothing will happen.
I hope you bit them, eaten their fingers.
- You'll stay home with us.
- I want to give an injection.
Jacques, I told you not to touch my paint.
- But Dad, it was for painting the hut.
- Na, Na, Na, did you see your face?
You think you painted the hut?
Well, well, well, a new tenant.
Well, Jacques, Magalie, in the shower! Come on, hop!
- Hey Jacques!
- What?
I know what we should do. So that
Chicken no longer comes to the hut.
- I'll show you.
- And why would you help us?
Now we all take off our clothes, wash hands,
feet, head, and visit one by
one the spirit of the hut,
to ask him for protection.
- Naked?
- Yes, naked like this.
- All the same, eh.
- Go guys. Like he said, do it. Get naked!
- Hey guys, I can go down, there's nobody.
- No, you keep watch.
Hey Ismael, are you afraid we'll see
that you got no hair on your butt?
You know, Jacques, it's not right,
it's forbidden to practice witchcraft.
So are you afraid? You rather
leave the hut to Chicken?
But if there is a sorcerer, he could be
sent by Chicken to destroy the hut.
Yes, but it's true.
This is counter revolutionary, the president
himself said so. I won't go along.
What are you talking, you're not even from Guinea.
I'm not from Guinea?
I'm not from Guinea? And my grandfather
is not from Guinea either?
(Local dialect)
Come back! If you leave
the hut, you're finished.
- You're a traitor!
- Yes he's right, they're conspiring with Chicken.
Yeah!
Hey, you lead me?
- That's it, you made your wish?
- Yes, that's it, I did.
Above all, don't open your eyes.
Now you can open your eyes. You know
I heard everything you told the spirit?
- Why? I have not spoken aloud.
- It's like that in my family.
So you really think I risk nothing more?
- The spirits will protect you.
- Even when I grow up?
Now they'll follow you until death.
And when you have a serious problem,
you must come see the spirit
here in the sacred cabin.
Only you can come. You alone know the secret.
Tell me Madiou, why is there
food in front of the altar?
The spirits eat. They are very greedy.
When you bring cookies, they'll eat them.
So, how much you paid for your badges?
I gave him an American cigarette.
They also gave me a little red book.
- It is tiny.
- Don't they have bigger hands?
Hey guys, I still can't see them.
- Hey! There's Magalie.
- Hey Magalie!
- Do you know where your brother is?
- Can I come up?
No! We said no women here.
- But that's not the same.
- He's right: no women here. Let her speak from below!
I agree with Lom. Let her come
up as long as she doesn't talk.
- Bunch of savages. It's Jacques' sister.
- Savage yourself!
Ah, this is your hut, it's really big.
- Well, you saw it. Now tell us where Jacques is.
- Give her a minute!
You mean she's taking us for a ride.
She doesn't even know where he is.
- He said...
- You tell us or I'll toss you in space.
- Can't you see you scare her, big dummy!
- So Magalie, what did your brother say?
Hey guys, they're coming! I see Chicken!
Look, the leaf men!
- They live like that?
- They are farmers.
They'll dance in the woods and
around the village, to bring rain.
But nobody should see them.
Especially not the children.
- If they catch you, you knock there.
- Madiou (local dialect)
- Jacques, you have to go home.
- You not coming home with me tonight?
- I thought you lived with your uncle.
- I have to leave for a few days.
Where to?
It's like a journey. I have to be circumcised.
- They'll cut your bangala?
- Yes.
- Why? What did you do? Is this to punish you?
- No, for me it's a great honor.
I'll be a great muslim. I'll be able to
pray, alone, and make all men pray.
- See you tomorrow?
- No, not tomorrow.
Hey, Cat? Where are you going?
(Whispering)
... all of a sudden the wind picked
up, the trees got uprooted,
Bushes flew away and Chicken's gang dashed off like rabbits.
They were scared stiff.
I myself don't believe it,
but then he's fierce, right?
Jacques, you know me, I fear nothing, but then...
Go, go, go home!
What you got on your shirt?
Serge, answer me! Serge!
Take that shirt off!
Take off that shirt! Never, do you hear me,
should you wear such things.
You know what this is? Do you know?
(Local dialect)
I've already told you a hundred times. Well?
Who gave that to you? Who
gave it to you, tell me! Who?
It was a very nice man. He gave them
to us... What have I done wrong?
They start as in Romania, with
badges, slogans, communist filth.
- Why you refuse to understand? Why? Look at me!
- I've done nothing wrong.
Mom.
- Mayaté.
- If you are brave, men will know who you are.
So you should pass the first test.
- Are the others afraid as well, Mayaté?
- Yes.
Nothing can happen to you that you can't handle.
Since September 28, 1958,
as one man, the Guinean will
understand Africa's voice,
thus proving to the whole world,
no people can... our people,
that all the people are capable,
that all people can exercise
their sovereign right to life.
Go, grab that one, grab it!
Catch it! Come on, catch it!
Go ahead, grab the others! Go!
Come on, catch that one!
You, go home now! Thief! Get the fuck out of here!
Fuck off!
I recognized you. I know where you live. Thieves!
Jacques! Come here!
- I won't repeat it, Jacques come here!
- No, Daddy, no!
Anyway you're never here, so it's easy to judge.
You want to jump in the sandpit, I won't
stop you, especially when it's 40 degrees.
Maybe if you talked to him more
often, he would do less bullshit.
Of course, that's easy, of course.
You expect me to be everywhere,
he does this, he does that.
Don't you think that if you got more
involved, he would do a bit better?
So after barter, it's theft and politics.
With all the crap we're dealing with now.
But I won't tie my son to a chair! If he won't
listen to me, what do you want me to do?
Look, it's decided. Any way, it's boarding school.
If there's something I can't stand, it's lying.
We have to conform to what is said in the meetings.
Aren't you a soldier of the people as well?
Stealing a chicken from a prominent
party representative. How dare you?
You know what they do to thieves?
They cut off their evil arm.
- But uncle, it's to make a sacrifice.
- Fetishism is forbidden! You know that very well.
How do you dare, after your initiation?
If only I knew this before, I would
never have let the old men initiate you.
You know what the party said, right? Soon
you won't go to the school of the whites.
Besides, you don't need to go
to school to be respected.
You're a good pioneer and
you'll be a better militiaman.
And finally, you won't play
with this white boy no more.
The white boy is my friend.
The white boy is not your friend! You
dishonor your people. Shame on you!
Will you stop harassing this child?
(Local dialect)
Go read your Koran.
(He's reading the Koran)
My uncle has spoken bad because
he's upset about the guard.
- I should never have done that after my initiation.
- You know Madiou, we could run and hide.
Otherwise they'll lock me in a boarding school.
I don't want to live with them.
Jacques, you have to think. If we don't
know where we're going, we may get lost.
We must go back to where we came from.
Then Magalie will join us. I promised her.
(He's reading the Koran)
Jacques.
Jacques!
(Local dialect)
People went looking for him
in the bush. It'll be okay.
(Local dialect)
Leave him with us.
Nothing can happen to him here.
He's Madiou's friend. Our son.
He will return later. Now go!
(Local dialect)
I put Madiou in the white school
because you've asked me to.
In regard to the party I took a big risk.
Now I feel targeted. My driver
reports all I do to the party.
And I just learned that Madiou took his white
friend to the sacred cabin. Why didn't you tell me?
The whole village knows you help the father
of this child. That's not good for my career.
Sinou.
You never listen to me. You always get your way.
Nowadays your father is the
party, your mother is the party.
The future of this child is not in your hands.
Allah is great.
You know, in France, it's not like here. There at
night everything is lit in green, yellow, blue, red.
Yes, but we're also rich. We
have a lot of mineral resources.
Yes of course, but it's different.
Over there, there are even lights
shaped as glasses over the shops.
And at night they blink. It's beautiful!
- You give them to me?
- The glasses?
- Won't you give me your glasses?
- No, not the glasses.
(People talking)
- I go find my friend Jacques.
- Are you crazy?
I warn you, if you betray me I'll hit you.
If you go there, they'll mess
you up. They'll even eat you.
Are you crazy! Don't you
know Jacques is my friend?
(Local dialect)
Come on, it'll be fun. We're always going with mom.
(Unintelligible)
... reactionaries are putting a mortgage...
...on the future of a Guinea...
...placed in the shackles of Neo-colonialism...
- (local dialect)
...They'll always deceive Guinea
from the shackles of colonialism...
Mr. Séverac, how are you?
- Okay, thank you.
- And the family?
Do you have your pass?
But you know, after 9 pm you can't travel.
- We were visiting friends, seeing off Diallo.
- Well okay.
That is fine for now. But we must be vigilant.
There are mercenaries about.
- Mom, can I get out too?
- No, stay there, we won't be long.
- Good evening, all well?
- Hello madam.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Okay.
Oh, thank you, that's nice.
I have to ask for a holiday, sir.
Tell me, Diallo, what's your
problem? Why are you afraid?
The scheme with the Portuguese.
They're looking for the Guinean traitors.
And I am Fulani, ma'am.
They say I am a conspirator.
- That I miss too many Friday meetings.
- Who is it, Diallo, tell us.
Oh, the people of the local revolutionary committee.
Those blokes of BPN came to investigate.
They say I am a former French military
in the service of imperialism.
- So tomorrow they want to interrogate me.
- You did nothing, you don't have to worry.
- Baccari was arrested, Madame.
- They arrested Baccari? - Yes.
- Then you must leave at dawn.
- With Jacob.
- You know where to go?
- Yes I know.
- You think your brother can replace you?
Abel? Yes, he'll be there tomorrow.
- You keep us informed. Okay?
- Okay.
- Be careful!
- Thank you ma'am. Thank you.
Jacques, Oh Oh!
(Local dialect)
- Diallo, when will you come back?
- Soon.
Comrades!
Given the perilous situation in the country,
the Politburo dispatched last month,
in each administrative region, a delegation...
...to make direct contact with the comrades activists...
...to conduct investigations.
Comrade Keita will give a report
of these investigations.
Comrades, know that a man who once...
was a friend of the people,
he can later become the enemy.
The counter-revolutionary loves
the people like the goat likes grass.
So we found, thanks to the patriotism of a militant,
3 accomplices concealed inside the revolution.
Individuals suspected and summoned,
to be accountable to the people of Guinea are:
Boubakar Bari, baker,
Lamin Kaba, trader,
And Amadou Diallo, servant chef.
Ready for the revolution.
Militants Comrades! The people
of Guinea threw a net.
No reactionary will escape.
In the meantime, I have great news for you:
The federal office will set up in each federation,
a local regional school. So,
The bravest young boys, in initiation trials,
will be taken automatically to the regional school,
in order to complete their ideological training.
- Long live the revolution!
- LONG LIVE THE REVOLUTION!
Away with imperialism!
Away with colonialism!
Dad, why are you taking us by car this morning?
There are many people in town because of
manifestations. I don't want you to be late.
- Hey, where are you going?
- I told you to close the window.
- Where are you going?
- Will you shut up, Jacques!
Go! Hurry up!
Come! They're all over the place. Come quickly!
- Come Ishmael, come with us!
- No, you shouldn't go there! Don't go!
"the 5th column"
I hate you all! Why didn't anyone tell me?
Why was he hanged? And you knew it!
And you did nothing to stop them!
But why? Why didn't anyone tell me?
Madiou! I have to congratulate you
for your courage, for your self control.
You've shown yourself worthy of the
revolution by marching past the traitors.
We must support the revolution at all costs.
And you are an example for others.
Of course your father, my dear brother,
wanted you to frequent the factory school.
After all these years of study, he
thought you could become in your turn,
a brilliant Guinean intellectual.
But you see where all this has led, eh?
The poor man didn't yet know
that imperialism was not dead.
If he was alive today, he would tell you:
"You must continue your ideological training among
the pioneers and you have to leave the Quimbo school"
Sorry uncle, but I really
want to go to the factory school.
- I want to learn.
- What?!
Madiou, if I understand correctly, you
want to disobey your father? Is that it?
Oh my uncle, you must forgive me.
Go, I forgive you.
- My father knows all about those who were hanged.
- I'll beat Madiou up myself.
It was him who marched past Diallo.
If they did that to my servant,
I swear I'd kill him.
I won't contain myself and they'll
have to hold me, otherwise...
- You should learn how to contain yourself, my boy.
- Eh, sir!
- Excuse me.
- Come on, everyone go to class!
- We'll beat the crap out of them.
- Yeah!
- You are dead!
- Sure they're dead!
Hey, where are you?
Hey guys, why didn't you come
to school? You scared or what?
(Various insults)
Fuck you! We'll smash your face! We'll kill you!
Yes, and did you see your face?
It looks like a chicken!
(Various insults)
And where is Madiou? Is he hiding? Is he scared?
That's it, go! You french had a good laugh.
Now you will have to pay!
Go away. I'm no longer walking
with rancid chickens.
I don't care about you, you're out of the gang!
And don't come to the hut no more!
Go hide peasant, go to your bush!
Your father was a slave to my father!
And you'll be my slave! You'll all...!
(Shouting an insult)
(Various insults)
- .... smash him...
- Kill him!
- You're finished?
- Come on guys, we're done here.
(Various insults)
You're okay, Madiou?
We sometimes hear funny sounds from the train.
My dad says that it's the snipers or
the Roumèque watching the house.
Mamane, switch on the lamp, please!
It seems that you won't come
back after the summer holidays?
- Because of the militiamen of the revolution.
- I've never seen any snipers.
- They must be really hairy.
- Right.
We are going to live in Rodez, near my grandmother.
- I'm going to find myself all alone?
- No, I'm staying. My mother says it'll work out.
- And then she wants to go back to Romania.
- Anyway, I'll stay at my new father's home.
- And you're going too?
- Anyhow, we'll all leave.
We will never leave.
I know. I explained this to your manager.
I understand.
But I have instructions.
Starting today, I can not renew the pass.
You and your compatriots must stay
here in the plane or leave the country.
It's the decision of the national political office.
Remain seated, gentlemen, please.
You know, Mr. Séverac, the Guinean
revolution is not an illusion.
It's the essence of our people.
Until Nov. 22, imperialism believed
it would kill the Guinean Revolution...
to enslave us better again.
The Focar clique did not stay
inactive in the funding of 22 November.
Thanks to their servants still present on
Guinean soil, they thought to eliminate us.
But no! We killed imperialism and
showed, in face of the world,
that the Guinean Revolution triumphed in the end.
You are listed as a reserve in
the French army, Mr. Séverac.
So you have 15 days to leave the country and go home.
That's ridiculous! I am here with my
family. I work in Fria for 10 years.
You don't have a choice, Mr. Séverac.
Let me tell you that you're very luck. Very.
Come on, boy!
Is this what you wanted to show me?
Now you understand why we're here?
You see, if you'd ask me, "What is Africa?"
I would show you that.
And it's so immense, you
could never put it on a photo.
Then there is all the noise,
the colors, the smells.
You give me the camera?
- No, Daddy, no!
- Come on Jacques! Give me a smile, Jacques!
- Jacquo!
- No!
Dad, I don't want to go to boarding
school. I want to stay here.
You know, we'll surely return to France.
No, Dad, that's not true! You're lying Dad!
- My home is here. We can't leave! I'll never leave!
- Jacques.
- No!
- Jacques, son! - No!
- Stop it!
You can't behave like a child
anymore. You'll be 12 soon.
You know there are serious things going
on here, that it's difficult at the moment?
So it's better to go back to France.
And your buddies, the Goberts,
the Pétrojacs, they're going too.
And Madiou!
- Will you at least eat well?
- Yes.
You can't blame him who feeds you.
Your uncle has made many sacrifices
for you since his brother's death.
But men are like the birds. They can't stay
on the branch, they need the whole sky.
But Mayaté...
Leave! Go meet your friend!
If your friend is good, he will forgive you.
Dad, can I go now?
Go son! Try to be here at six o'clock!
- Hi grumpy.
- So what have you got to say now?
Jacques, we'll always be friends.
You must forgive me for Diallo. I didn't know.
I was forced to march past.
We could do nothing for Diallo.
It was the decision of the party. And
then my uncle forbade me to see you.
Sorry Jacques. I was obliged to talk
bad about him in front of my cousins .
So you do everything your uncle says?
If he tells you to jump in a well?
But no. My uncle is good to me.
He wouldn't think of hurting me.
- Diallo was good as well. He did nothing wrong.
- Hey Jacques, where're you going? Wait for me!
- I go to "Concouré".
- It's forbidden! The militia keeps watch over there.
Are you afraid of them? I'm going.
But you know, Jacques, the
militiamen are bad right now.
Dad!
Madiou, there's the militia. Madiou, wake up!
Awake, Madiou. The militia is there.
Give me back Madiou. I beg you.
I should have remembered he can't swim.
I know you can. If only you return him to me.
Please. bring him back.
Jacques!
I'm here.
It's been an hour since we
called you. You'll get a hiding.
I don't want him to touch me.
He won't do anything to you. Come Jacques.
- I'll go hide. I'll never get back.
- You're not leaving?
Come on Magalie, come to the table! There's pie.
Hurry up!
Madiou?
Madiou! My friend.
I waited for you.
You know I wanted to play on the sacred river.
And there I met a great white spirit.
This spirit is a good one, brave.
I saw him fight against evil spirits. And he won.
Is it true what you thought just now?
You will really come someday?
When I grow up I'll come back
for you. We'll both stay.
Come on, gather! Militiamen, service men,
it's the hour of the meeting. Be quick!
Quick!
What are you looking at? Give me that!
Magalie be nice, bring it back to Mrs. Korsky!
Tell her I'll come see her tomorrow, eh?
Next time we'll persuade you, Ms. Korsky.
Give me that!
(Shouts of indoctrination)
The young must remain vigilant,
strengthen their ideological
and political education.
They must observe the behavior
of activists, executives,
because the conspirators are not only
among the corrupt unconscious elements.
Do not hesitate.
The hesitation of a youth would amount to
the reduction of the revolutionary potential.
You must fight everywhere, denounce if necessary,
such local committee, such federal office.
The future is you!
Never forget!
Jacques!
Subtitles by Subransu
"Whether you go around the world till your feet are worn out,
I swear that you will return to Guinea..." Sory Kandia Kouate