[man's voice through megaphone]
No to closing our factory.
- [Quiet music]
- No to the loss of our jobs.
No to shareholder dividends.
[Chorus] ♪ The Big City ♪
♪ Mange la ville ♪
♪ La grande vie ♪
♪ Mange la vie ♪
♪ Marie si belle ♪
♪ Marie vaisselle ♪
♪ Marie chandelle ♪
♪ Plume d'hirondelle ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, elle ♪
♪ Fleur sans colline ♪
♪ Pleurs en cuisine ♪
♪ Marie sans fard ♪
♪ Fog Flower ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ Si on chantait ♪
♪ Let's sing, let's sing ♪
Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ Si on chantait ♪
♪ Let's sing, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ Marie divine ♪
♪ Si on chantait ♪
♪ Let's sing, let's sing ♪
♪ Let's sing, hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ Let's sing, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ Si on chantait ♪
Super.
We got something!
Oh good ?
Jean-Claude is great.
Press more
on the "la, la, la, la", it's great.
Oh good ? Isn't that a bit too much?
No, a little more.
[Laughs]
- Oh good.
- [Choir leader] Solange.
Come ahead, your voice will carry better.
I don't like it,
it's "I'm pissed off".
But no !
Come show off in front of me.
[The crowd] Solange! Ah, Solange!
[They chant.]
Solange! Solange! Solange! Solange!
So that will soften the management.
They won't dare fire us.
I'll give you one,
it'll relieve everyone.
Hey, calm down...Rihanna!
I swear to you, it will go away.
[Choir leader]
10 min break and we resume afterwards.
How are you ?
Take. Hop, hop, hop!
- We need you.
- Bim!
800 flyers! Hand cut.
I put on a megaphone
for the vindictive side.
There is the date, the place.
So ?
The colors are gross.
It's not tip-top anyway.
There is more yellow in the printer.
The cartridges are on the 1st,
I don't know where it is.
Should have asked Jean-Claude.
No but, stop with that!
I am a technical manager!
I have nothing to do with management.
It has to come in, that!
I'm not distributing that, it sucks.
It's ugly.
So, I can't sing, can't fly, I can't do anything!
It's not that you can't sing, José...
[Homme] Christian !
We will be able to buy the factory,
because your son
is preparing the concert of the century.
[Laughs]
Everyone struggles in their own way, Dad.
Already starting to struggle.
[Laughs]
[Man] No, but look...
If the factory closes, you can
beg with your songs!
Wait!
She's right, Sophie,
it feels so good.
- Hey, hey!
- Okay okay !
Leave him alone,
he can walk! Its good !
You are really childish,
it's distressing.
[Man] It's good!
We don't want to see you again.
I have no intention of returning.
- Bunch of idiots!
- [Worker] That's it! Clear !
-Frank!
- Frank, come back.
Fuck them.
It's too stupid, we're ready.
I don't care about the choir!
If it closes, I'll be happy
to see their faces!
We do this for us, not for them.
You are hurting yourself.
I didn't know him that way.
To know him, you would have had to
grow up like us,
like a pro.
Hey, ho, be careful, Jose...
I'm not part of the management!
Technical framework, it has nothing to do!
OK, Jean-Claude. See you.
That's crazy.
[Calm music]
[radio] RTL2 North, it's 11 a.m.
It's over for Valosteel:
the 118 employees,
on strike for 3 weeks,
find themselves unemployed.
A cataclysm.
[Thunder]
[Male voice] ♪ Live ♪
♪ Under the Brazilian equator ♪
♪ Between Cuba and Manila ♪
♪ Summer time is easy ♪
♪ Take my hand, come dance ♪
♪ I have sun on my skin ♪
♪ I have a bongo in my heart ♪
♪ I have a bird in my head ♪
♪ Who says out loud "Come dance!" ♪
♪ Under the sunlights of the tropics ♪
♪ Love is told ♪
- ♪ To Music ♪
- [Happy Screams]
♪ We have all night to love each other ♪
[Honk]
Oh fuck !
What's this ?
- I had a problem.
- I don't want to know,
you go back.
The restaurant is half an hour away!
It's in bulk but it will taste the same.
You want a rotten comment?
Nope ? So you go back.
Not, but wait!
[Calm music]
Oh damn, no! No no no !
Damn!
Excuse me,
but I don't really understand.
It's simple, you are 2 candidates,
and we only have one position.
The one who best presents
his competitor will win.
But, I... am supposed to sell myself,
not sell sir.
[The man] A good salesperson sells everything.
Even what he doesn't want.
Be convincing.
Who starts ?
I will.
Jean-Claude, here present,
is a mature man
and experienced. Given his age,
he inspires confidence
and knows how to listen to his customers,
particularly fathers,
with high purchasing potential.
It would be a mistake
not to choose Luc for this position.
Even though he is young,
and therefore by definition,
less experienced than me,
his youth is a major asset.
It is synonymous with energy,
what is essential for this position,
and as a young adult,
he will be in tune with this generation
which constitutes the majority
of our clientele,
while knowing
the needs of a father
since he himself is...
a son!
[Intriguing Music]
Mr. Guedon...
Your pitch was outstanding.
Thanks.
Oh no, we didn't understand each other.
You're right: Mr. Terrier
is the best for the job.
[The man] The young clientele,
it was well seen. You prevent us
from missing the rare pearl.
Thank you. Really.
No problem.
[Calm music]
Guedon!
What was it this time?
Did you have a swimming pool?
Did you switch to summer time
before everyone else?
Go to work.
- Hi, Jean-Claude.
- Hi.
When it quivers like that,
you put the honey.
It just needs to melt.
Don't let it cook.
Quiet, see?
Look at this.
- Your mother is not tired of you squatting?
- You laugh ?
She has a cook, a cleaning man
and a repairman. And that ?
Me !
She puts her feet
under the table and let's be done with it.
- [Door]
- It changes her from my father.
[Mother] It's me!
Hello Frank. It smells good !
What's this ?
It's a chicken with prunes
with small almonds, honey.
It simmers.
I'll call you when it's ready.
You stay, Frank?
No, I can't, that's nice.
I eat with my father, it's Wednesday.
Ah.
[Calm music]
How's your new TV?
I don't look at her
seeing the bullshit going on.
It's funny,
putting away mom's records,
I found a photo of you
in a Sardou album.
You had seen him in Anzin, hadn't you?
Can't you throw away those records?
And you, can't you make an effort?
A question,
an answer makes a conversation.
Like normal people.
And incidentally,
it allows to talk about mom.
But even that,
it sounds like you want more.
Saying nothing,
it avoids saying bullshit.
Why am I coming to see you?
Don't come anymore.
You're right.
Delete me from your contacts,
it will make room!
[He slams the door.]
["Can the can" - Suzy Cuatro à la radio]
She's pissing off your roommate.
She's my owner.
Still sucks.
Henriette, can you lower it a bit?
Oh yes, yes.
You know I saw them
on the Isle of Wight in '69?
Yeah.
We must hear in the street.
It 's so that
we don't hear you.
It's true ?
I even said to myself
that it must carry as far as Béthune.
I'm the one going down, then.
Are you preparing
for a sale?
You have 3 minutes
if you still want...
OK see you soon.
See you soon.
Already ? You only stayed 20 minutes.
I forgot, Louise's teacher
called us at 3 p.m.
I told Sandrine that I would be there.
It is quarter past twelve.
Eh ? Well yes, I know, it sucks.
I have errands to run first, and...
OK...
Tomorrow, I promise you, I'm staying
longer. I promise, my cat.
In addition, Sandrine sees her mother.
We'll have plenty of time tomorrow.
Go on. Well, see you tomorrow, my cat.
Is she there, Henrietta?
[Henriette] Hello,
girls, come in! Come !
I have lots of new stuff.
Come !
Go on !
[Henriette] How are you?
You look good, Claudine!
My girl says to me: "You haven't filled it
up, you're irresponsible."
I said to him: "We were on the reserve,
there were 50 kms left."
But in fact, it depends on the models.
As soon as it lights up,
you have to be super careful.
- Do you want chips?
- Nope.
It's chemical but it's super good.
Fortunately, I had a can behind.
There were a few drops left.
doorbell
- Good evening.
- Come in.
Come in.
Yes. Come in.
Oh yes, yes.
Yes, Mr. Mayor,
I will be there at 8 o'clock.
Yes, 8 hours on site. I note it.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Mr. Mayor.
Mm !
Ah, super !
What?
Is it my birthday meal?
No !
- A four cheese?
- Nope.
Are you kidding me ?
No no !
- You forgot ?
- No, I haven't forgotten.
Looked ! Everyone
thinks about it, except you!
No, but Bibou...
You're just a sucker! A moron,
- a moron!
- Bibo!
You, there, your face! You disgust me !
["Let's take our time" - Poetic Lovers
on TV]
♪ I'm an expert on this ♪
♪ Yes, you will see my craftsmanship ♪
What's his favorite song?
- What ?
- Your wife's favorite song?
Knowing how to love by Florent Pagny.
Why ?
Madame,
excuse me,
but your husband didn't tell you
for the surprise.
For your birthday.
- What?
- [The acquiesces.]
This is the "Pizza Plus" formula.
"Pizza Plus".
"Pizza Plus" ?
"Pizza Plus", yes. What?
- Uh...
- [He clears his throat.]
♪ Know how to smile ♪
♪ To a passing stranger ♪
♪ Keep no trace of it ♪
♪ Otherwise that of pleasure ♪
♪ To know how to love ♪
♪ Without expecting anything in return ♪
♪ Neither respect nor great love ♪
♪ Not even the hope of being loved ♪
♪ But knowing how to give ♪
[Soft music]
♪ Giving without taking back ♪
♪ Do nothing but learn ♪
♪ Learn to love ♪
♪ Love without waiting ♪
♪ To love everything ♪
♪ Learn to smile ♪
♪ Just for the gesture ♪
♪ Without wanting the rest ♪
♪ And learn to live ♪
♪ Et s'en aller ♪
[She cries.] And leave.
[Sobs]
It is too beautiful !
Oh ! Bibou !
See, you didn't let me finish.
I did not understand.
And happy birthday.
Thank you my love.
That's too beautiful, too beautiful...
[Soft music]
Hey, you saved my life.
- At least the evening.
- Yes.
Hold.
Thank you!
Hey...
You have a really nice voice, too.
Yes really.
Hi.
[Soft music]
[José] Do you want us to deliver songs?
- Like flowers?
- There.
People choose one,
and we deliver it.
Like flowers,
but it's a song.
Would it work?
I am sure.
It's touching and original.
Birthdays, parties...
It would hit!
So ?
Yeah !
Of course, are you kidding or what?
Get paid to sing
in people's homes, I say yes!
There's nothing to discuss, go!
In fact no...
For you, I was thinking more
of taking control,
answer the phone,
advise people...
Yeah.
...on the adapted song.
That's important.
Operator.
Yeah, that's it...
OK, cool.
Super, cool...
- You'll never trust me, actually.
-Yes.
Nothing to see.
It is...
He sings like shit.
- What ?
- Nope.
Nope ! It's not... I... It's not...
- Well, anyway...
- Sophie, please.
You don't really sing in tune.
Not really. There is still work.
Yes.
Hm.
You know what ? Ok I would like to.
I set the standard,
I welcome people...
"What occasion ?"
I point them to everything,
and you teach me to sing.
Give and take.
I do everything, you have nothing to do.
I manage from A to Z. You, you sing,
and you give me lessons. Go!
Go on !
Go on.
And There you go !
Are you in?
It won't be worse than
what I've done so far, so OK!
- Go on.
- [Happy music]
- We come to your house and we sing.
Nope ? Ah thank you !
Home songs. "Let's sing".
Hello. "If we sang",
home delivery of songs.
- Like pizza.
- Thank you.
Madame.
Good morning sir.
[indistinct chatter]
"Let's sing"!
We come to sing at home.
- OK.
- For birthdays...
- Great.
- Even for fun.
- It's nice.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Have a good day.
Hop hop hop!
Hold the riders. OK, kiss.
- Hello, "Let's sing".
- It does not interest me.
Thank you.
[Child] My skateboard!
My skateboard!
[Radio] We're live
for "Questions Quiz".
A new listener needs
to answer a question about Quiévrechain.
What is your name?
My name is Jean-Michel.
[Radio] Jean-Michel,
I'm telling you the question:
what is the total area
of ​​Quiévrechain?
To deliver a song,
call "If we sang"
at 06.68.54.68.43.
06.68.54.68.43, "If we sang"!
Blah!
[He's laughing.]
Wow!
Frank !
So that !
How long has it been?
Wow, 2 years. Hello.
Bonjour.
- What brings you here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
With José and Sophie, we launch a box.
Oh good ?
Song delivery.
We deliver songs to people,
like flowers.
They choose songs,
and we sing them at home.
It's original.
Yeah. I was wondering
if you wanted to join us.
You sing really well,
that would be a plus.
- I'm sure it'll work.
- Yeah...
It's nice,
but I don't have time.
I have one...
a job...
who...
Responsibilities and so...
I interview...
I interview.
And... it's a lot of involvement,
the box is counting on me.
Yeah, and it's not just her!
Yes, Lolo has just finished
her studies in horticulture,
she passes the competition
for the flowery house.
She can win!
No, it's too much stress,
too much work.
No, but don't worry, I understand.
[melancholic music]
But it was nice, huh.
When we sang together at the factory.
Yes, it was good. See you next.
Good luck.
If I let you close the trunk,
will that be okay?
Pardon !
Excuse me.
- [Whistling.]
- [Barking]
[Frank] It's going to call.
100 posters in Quiévrechain,
impossible to miss.
Plus the radio ad.
[Mobile ringtone]
You go.
[Alarm]
"If we sang", hello!
Mam?
What is this number ?
Ah OK.
I will charge it for you.
- We do not care.
- What time will you return ?
With whom ?
Abbreviate!
No, I'm not stalking you.
But as usual...
OK.
Yes, I remove the keys from the door.
Good, kisses.
She is having dinner with a friend.
So what ? She does what she wants !
How old is she ? 70?
58.
Yes, no, but she is great!
She can even still fuck.
It's not okay or what! Not mom.
[Mobile ringtone]
José.
- Eh ?
- Off hook !
- What ?
- Answer!
Oui.
The smile in the voice.
"Let's sing", hello.
Yes. Yes of course.
Has what name ?
And for the address?
Super !
I have everything, it is noted, thank you.
Good bye have a good day.
I already saw myself, you know?
Who do you take him for,
he knows them all!
Hou!
[Jose] Come on!
[Rhythmic music]
[Frank]
♪ At 18, I left my province ♪
♪ Determined to grab life ♪
♪ The light heart and the thin luggage ♪
♪ I was certain to conquer Paris ♪
♪ At the fanciest tailor
I've had made ♪
♪ Ce complet bleu ♪
♪ What was state of the art ♪
♪ Photos
Songs and orchestrations ♪
♪ Ont eu raison ♪
♪ From my savings ♪
♪ I already saw myself at the top of the poster ♪
♪ In 10 times bigger than anyone ♪
♪ My name was spreading ♪
- ♪ I could already see myself... ♪
- [Laughs]
[The music continues.]
Ah OK.
[He turns off the music.]
Poor jerk.
Do you remember 2 years ago?
That's 1 everywhere, asshole.
Shut the door, he's bloodthirsty!
[Laughs]
[Doorbell]
Oh, Sophie !
Do you know
Henriette, my landlady?
[Henriette] Hello! Sophie told me
your little starting problem.
No problem.
It's the beginning, it's normal.
Look Apple, that wasn't it.
And where is Steve Jobs?
Bah...
Bad example.
[Henriette] Do you know Facebook?
- All the same.
- How many friends?
I don't know, me... 30, 40.
So you don't know.
[She laughs.]
[Henriette] Look.
I have 3 full accounts,
5000 friends per account.
3 times 5, 15,000. 15,000 friends!
Everyone in the corner.
Happy for you. It's a star.
Are you dumb? That's
15,000 potential customers.
You film a delivery,
you put it on my pages,
if it doesn't take off...
There's a problem,
it's that we don't have delivery.
Invent one.
A little slow, your friends.
It's true.
[He laughs yellow.]
Oh ! What a surprise !
No Madam,
that's 4 times...
Be more natural. Just "hello".
Oh yes okay. Sorry.
We are with you.
You can do it.
- OK.
- We go back.
[Sophie] Go ahead.
[He clears his throat.]
Bonjour !
Hello ma'am. I come to deliver
a song to you from your son.
My son ?
Yes, I will read you his word.
Ah.
"My little mama, I am far from you
"but know that I love you,
"and that I miss you. Your son, José."
- That's wonderful.
- Is she playing there?
It's for fake,
I'm here, everything is fine.
It is so beautiful.
Stop.
It's good, it's emotional.
We continue !
And there is a song.
Ah ?
[Soft music]
♪ When I'm not ♪
♪ Up to par ♪
♪ She lifts me
higher than the sky ♪
♪ She is the splendor of splendors ♪
♪ She's the sap, she's the honey ♪
♪ It's his blood
running through my veins ♪
♪ And hundreds of memories ♪
♪ Cradle my heart with a thousand stars
She is my quest ♪
♪ She is my Grail ♪
♪ Oh my God, leave them to me ♪
♪ Mama's beautiful eyes ♪
♪ Even take everything else away from me ♪
♪ But not the gentleness of his gestures ♪
♪ She carried me before the world ♪
♪ She still carries me
Every second ♪
♪ She'll take me with her ♪
♪ I will always be faithful to him ♪
[She sobs.]
[mother] Very, very beautiful.
[Soft music]
[Henriette] Already 425 views,
75 likes, 22 shares.
- Doesn't she tear up my landlady?
- You rock, Henriette.
José, watch your phone,
it's going to ring.
[Portable]
But no ?
- "Let's sing", hello.
- [Client] It's for a song.
[Cheers]
That's good ! Oh !
- [Customer] Hello?
- Yes, of course, which song?
[Rhythm Guitar]
[Frank] ♪ We wish you
All the happiness in the world ♪
- ♪ And someone reach out your hand ♪
- [Applause]
♪ May your path avoid the bombs ♪
♪ Let it lead to quiet gardens ♪
♪ We wish you
All the happiness in the world ♪
- ♪ For today... ♪
- Yes, in what name?
♪ May your sunshine... ♪
Great. And the song?
♪ ...of daily love ♪
[Sophie]
♪ Do you want to dance, grandma? ♪
♪ Do you want to waltz, grandpa? ♪
♪ Just like the good old days ♪
♪ When you were 20 ♪
Noted ! Yes, noted,
I'm sending someone to you. Thank you !
♪ Sapped like never before ♪
[They all sing]
♪ Undercut like never before ♪
♪ Loulou' and 'boutin ♪
♪ Coco na Chanel ♪
Sophie, are you grading? For Mrs. Bronsard.
Bronsard, with an "o".
♪ Come on, come and have
a drink at home ♪
[Chorus] ♪ There's white
There's red, sausage ♪
♪ And Gilou with his little accordion ♪
♪ Long live bottles and friends ♪
♪ And the songs, hey! ♪
[Calm music]
Cinderella?
[His wife] You never knew how to lie!
I knew him
the way you talk
about it so that I don't worry,
like it was your dream job.
I can see that you are gnawing your blood.
Hey, I'm interviewing.
I will find a better job.
You've been looking for 2 years!
If your job is not enough for us
to earn as much as before,
I work too, that's all.
Yeah.
When we met, I had...
a nice post. I was...
Hey. That's not why I liked you.
[Soft music]
Do you see what I'm making you do?
Are you afraid that I'm leaving you
like your ex?
She was a bitch. Even
though I earn more than you, I love you.
I have to go back there.
[Foreman] Guédon, hurry up!
What did you have? Sewing?
I will do it to myself.
Stop it, it's not worth it.
He would be so happy to fire you.
[He sings out of tune.]
♪ When the music is good ♪
♪ Good, good, good
When the music gives ♪
♪ Give, give, give
When the music rings, rings ♪
♪ Ring, ring, ring
When she's not cheating ♪
♪ When she's not cheating ♪
OK.
It's a bit high.
I think
you have a breathing problem.
Oh good ?
You breathe too high.
You need to breathe lower.
There ?
♪ When she's not cheating ♪
It's better !
Oh no. Lay down, you'll understand.
- Go ahead !
- Yes ! I...
The voice is a wind instrument.
So singing is 80% breathing.
Breathe without dropping
the stones.
Without singing.
It has to go up and down.
Like that, there?
No more.
It's annoying.
That's the secret, breathing.
[He blows.]
Half an hour a day
until it's natural.
Where are you going ?
We keep in touch.
Half an hour a day.
Hello.
[Doorbell]
Shit.
How are you, my pussycat?
I have 20 minutes.
Do you find me pretty?
Yeah, great, as usual.
Oh yeah !
Fuck your zip!
["Can the can" - Suzy Cuatro]
- [He breathes in.]
- [Quiet music]
[He blows.]
[Portable]
"Let's sing", hello.
- It's me.
- Who ?
Frank !
I do the breathing exercises,
I have a great technique
with a fanny pack...
[Frank]Great, no, listen...
I just came across...
the director of the EHPAD
of Quiévrechain,
and he asked me for a song
but I can't.
Can you tell Sophie to go?
- Ça urge.
- [José] OK.
Why don't you call her?
Uh...
You're the center point of the box,
I'm not going to pass you over.
It is not false.
So... It's for Geneviève...
[José] A message ?
"Have a good stay at the nursing home."
- [José] What song?
- The song is...
It is ?
- Little Santa Claus.
- [José] Little Santa Claus ?
We are in April.
Yes, but you know, the old...
Yeah.
I call him.
- Right away, it's urgent.
- Yes.
- Kisses !
- Kisses.
[Intriguing Music]
- Kiss.
Check that guy out.
[Calm music]
[He mutters.]
[He blows.]
Go on...
Get out, my little one.
[Sigh of relief]
[Barking]
Ah...
Jean Claude ?
What are you doing?
- Oh...
- Where were you?
No... I water the flowers.
It's for the competition, it's important.
But it's not true !
Oh dear, watch out. Come.
I was at the bistro,
and they are nice, at the bistro.
Normal, how many rounds did you pay them ?
I'm not bad...
I'm not bad, my Lolo.
But no, you're not dumb.
- [He cries.]
- Come on, come on. Attention.
Oh...
[He blows.]
[Shouting]
I am Jean-Claude Guédon!
Chut.
- I'm a technical executive!
- Hush.
Barking
I brought you together because
it's still a small event.
I will sing ?
No, that will be the next event.
It's funny, that.
Come on, I'll order the fries.
- There.
- No, I didn't do anything.
Share it among yourselves.
We are a team,
we share everything at 4.
Without you, it wouldn't have started.
140 euros for 2 weeks?
It will go crescendo.
There's interest.
I'm going, see you later.
Won't you stay with us?
I celebrate my salary
at Fouquet's as a couple.
Can't you just say no to him
for once?
He whistles, and you come back.
- You're jealous ?
- From that married asshole? Nope !
Get involved in your life.
140€ and you run mine?
- She's not eating with us?
- Nope.
That's more fries.
What's the good news?
But no ? 140 euros?
[She laughs.]
Oh yeah ! It's for me, the fries.
Oui.
We made 140 euros!
Looked !
Why don't you tell her, Sophie?
- Tell him what?
- That you love him, simpleton.
We've known each other since we were 10 years old.
It would screw up our friendship.
If you don't try anything,
you'll spend your life moping
seeing her with that big jerk
Philippe, or some other jerk.
- Look.
- What ?
It's Frank's company.
You know, song deliveries.
Ah! It's a bit amateurish
though.
Oh.
oh well...
[Soft music]
OK, let's go ?
Yeah.
You come ?
It's shit, my life.
35 ans.
No girlfriend.
A shitty job to be able to eat.
These bullshit songs suck.
Stop it, that's a great idea.
The proof, no one had thought of it before.
Now I understand why.
No, but forget what Sophie said.
You know her, always there bitching.
Why do you bother with
each other all the time? That's crazy.
I believe it !
Oh ! It will work, look.
[He blows.]
[Rhythmic music]
♪ This is the dessert the Abominable Snowman serves ♪
♪ À l'abominable enfant teenage ♪
♪ Un amour de dessert ♪
♪ Bananana ♪
- ♪ Banana split, whoo ♪
- Stop, stop.
- Why ?
- You can't.
You too
can't do it.
- Even with the fanny pack?
- But yes...
At the same time,
the lyrics are stupid.
A snowman, a dessert...
That's not the meaning.
What do you mean ?
You kidding ?
No what is it ?
What dessert is she talking about?
A banana split.
To say something else.
What's next?
"Frosty kisses
on the white mountains, banana."
Finally, "na na na"
Continue.
"It looks
like things are kicking in.
"The whipped cream collapses in an avalanche,
"banana, banana..."
There. So ?
What ? It's a banana
with whipped cream.
Damn, Jose!
Banana, whipped cream!
The whipped cream collapses like an avalanche!
A banana... Can't you see?
- A banana, yes.
- No, but the whipped cream...
- But no ?
- Yeah.
But no... I... Ah, yeah!
Like Gainsbourg with lollipops.
Gainsbourg with lollipops?
Not the lollipops.
I have everything. All pictures.
OK, that's it, what!
OK, wait, I'll try again.
[Rhythmic music]
♪ This is the dessert the Abominable Snowman serves ♪
♪ To the abominable teenage child
A love of dessert ♪
T'y arrives.
♪ Banana... ♪
You just sing.
- Did I just sing?
- Yes !
- It was right ?
- Yes.
Because you understand the lyrics!
But no, here...
I have 50 years of French songs
to explain to you.
- It was right ?
- Yes.
I just sang! I just sang!
- Who sang in tune? It's me.
- It's you.
That's good !
[En chœur] ♪ Banana ♪
♪ Banana ♪
♪ Banana split ♪
♪ Bananana ♪
♪ Banana split, hou ♪
It's okay, stop following me!
You stress me out.
You understood ? "I promise you salt",
it's not table salt, really.
[Laughs]
[He laughs yellow.]
It's funny, that.
Go away !
Further, I see you.
Again, go.
- Yes ?
- "Let's sing", hello.
Ah! Come in !
Go on.
[door]
I have a message from
of your husband.
"Madeleine, I have loved you for 50 years
"and I will love you another 50 years
if I can."
Oh.
I like you.
He dedicates this song to you.
Oh !
[Soft music]
♪ I promise you salt
at the kiss of my mouth ♪
♪ I promise honey
to my touching hand ♪
♪ I promise you heaven ♪
♪ Above your diaper ♪
♪ Flowers and lace
To make your nights sweet ♪
♪ I promise you the key to secrets ♪
♪ De mon âme ♪
♪ I promise you life ♪
♪ From my laughter to my tears ♪
♪ I promise you fire instead ♪
♪ Des arbres ♪
♪ And never goodbye ♪
♪ Nothing but goodbyes ♪
- Madeline! - Shit.
I was beckoning you!
It's not me !
She fell on her own!
[Radio] Sports: after the draw for
the Coupe de France,
for the semi-final,
Valenciennes' opponent will be Lens.
Valenciennes fans
hope for qualification,
a joy they haven't known
since 1951.
[Soft music]
Don't worry,
it'll be fine, it'll be fine.
I'm sorry, I haven't...
Everything is fine !
Do not worry.
You are one hell of a killer.
Don't worry.
[Mobile phone]
- Hello ?
- [Jean-Claude]Hello, Frank?
Tell me...I think it would do me
good to sing with you
and... I wanted to know
if your proposal still holds.
Good. If we want to make the box
economically viable,
need to professionalize it.
Make it visible.
Find him an identity.
And a place
where to physically settle.
It requires an investment.
Not big, but still.
- It's not a start-up, either.
- He is right,
we're not going to continue
in your kitchen.
Is my kitchen better?
- You were happy to have it.
- What do you have ?
You have a problem ?
No, but the box,
we didn't need him
to mount it.
There, he arrives, he swings the words
"investment", "viable",
and there you are: "Great, Jean-Claude."
Are you dumb? We're trying to make sure it's not
a killer thing.
- Stop the fuck!
- I can quit.
No. Nope !
Yes, do that.
Nobody quits.
Continue.
I go.
You have to canvass
with companies
that may be interested in the concept
for birthdays,
retirements...
We can sign contracts
with works councils.
And when people go see
it works in their boxes,
they will order songs for them
in the family circle.
It has a snowball effect.
And the companies here,
I know them all.
I spent all my...
All...
Hm.
And I have acquaintances
in Valenciennes...
You can even aim higher!
No need to be afraid ! There you go, don't...
I go there because I too
have connections everywhere, like that.
I know people in New York.
[And if you didn't exist - Joe Dassin]
♪ What if you didn't exist ♪
♪ Tell me why I exist ♪
430 all, okay?
♪ To hang out in a world without you ♪
♪ Without hope and without regrets ♪
♪ What if you didn't exist ♪
♪ I'll try to invent love ♪
♪ Like a painter
Who sees under his fingers ♪
♪ Born the colors of the day ♪
[She sighs.]
♪ And who can't believe it ♪
Hello. Here, my dear.
It's for you.
That's nice, Henriette,
but it bothers me.
But no, it makes me happy.
You know, I sell well,
they are addicted.
- To Tupperware?
- Oh no !
To that !
- Hey!
- Ah ...
We have to stay active at our ages.
Two vibration speeds
and I offer it to you at €29.95!
Goodbye.
[In chorus] Goodbye!
Well here it is.
[Doorbell]
- It's okay ?
- Flawless.
- Am I not too dressed up?
- But no !
Tip Top ! Go on !
It's stupid, but I'm nervous.
Stop, you're handsome as a truck.
Did you sell your car?
Yes. You know, what is a car?
It helps you get from point A
to point B, that's all. Go on !
En route, les winners.
[Calm music]
Hello. We come to see Mr. Turpin.
Who do I advertise ?
Mr. Chesnot, Mr. Guédon
from the company "Si on chantait".
- Good.
- Thank you.
- [Indistinct talk]
- [Soft music]
Sorry, I have almost nothing.
- We put what we can.
- No it's OK.
Vinyls sell pretty well.
It's normal, a car
pays more. It is...
And José, isn't he here?
Anyway, I don't have time.
I have lots of stuff to do.
I have delivery notices,
I have to go to the post office.
Ah.
Geraniums are all...
[He hesitates.]
I have to...
I have lots of stuff to do.
Anyway,
I don't sing that well,
it doesn't matter.
You finished ?
You know what's missing
from this box?
It's not the money.
It is enthusiasm.
Enthusiasm
is not mine.
Me, I doubt and I piss you off.
Sophie is a pain in the ass,
and Jean-Claude holds the reins well,
but it's not him who has the potato.
It's you !
Only you can galvanize us
because you are like that.
You run on enthusiasm.
[Soft music]
You are the soul of the group.
And we need you, damn it.
Really ?
Don't force me to repeat it.
Come on, come on.
I don't even have geraniums.
- [Light hubbub]
- [Knock.]
Hello.
I have a delivery for Marc.
It's me.
- Oh! Hello.
- Hello.
So... It's a message from Melanie.
"Marc, I find out that it's been 4 months
"that you're cheating on me
with the switchboard operator in your box
"and brag about it to all your friends,
"So I'm breaking up.
"Goodbye looser."
- What is this bullshit ?
- There's a song.
Eh ? A song ?
- [He clears his throat.]
- [Rhythmic music]
♪ Leaving for a day of no return ♪
♪ Erase our love ♪
♪ Without looking back, don't regret ♪
- ♪ Keep the moments we stole ♪
- Get out!
- ♪Leaving one day, without luggage... ♪
- You get out.
- Go away.
- ♪ Forget... ♪
♪ Your face, without turning around ♪
- Sors.
- ♪ Ne pas regretter ♪
Clear.
♪ Thinking about tomorrow, starting over ♪
You leave !
[Laughs]
Hey ho! Let's go back to work.
Why are we here?
At least they haven't reopened?
I don't have my outfit, it's stupid.
It's less crowded than before.
Yes of course.
The town hall doesn't know what to do with it,
so we can use it.
Have you been to town hall?
Yes ! They love the project,
they are behind us.
Oh ! That's good ! Check.
[Squeak]
I thought we could
settle down here, right?
Bah...
- Yes.
- Yeah !
- Super.
- Tip-top !
[Attention ladies
and gentlemen - Michel Fugain]
You go. Stop!
Lower the tone.
Well, that's good.
♪ Attention ladies and gentlemen
In a moment we will begin ♪
♪ Have a nice seat in your chair
♪
♪ 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0, go
All spotlights will turn on ♪
♪ And all the actors will come alive at the
same time ♪
Go on !
♪ Attention ladies and gentlemen
It's important, we'll start ♪
♪ It's always the same story
Since the dawn of time ♪
♪ The story of life and death
But we'll change the scene ♪
♪ Let's hope we'll play it again
in 2000 years ♪
Yeah !
♪ We're 20
And full of songs ♪
[Phone]
"Let's sing", hello.
Yes ? What song do you want?
Very well. What address ?
Noted.
I'll send someone to you right away.
♪ Attention ladies and gentlemen
In a moment it will begin ♪
♪ We obviously ask you to
be indulgent ♪
♪ The show isn't running smoothly
Give us a few more years ♪
♪ It will only get better
Over time ♪
[The music continues.]
♪ Attention ladies and gentlemen
In a moment it will begin ♪
♪ Have a nice seat in your chair
♪
[Horns]
♪ 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0, go
All spotlights will turn on ♪
♪ And all the actors will come alive at the
same time ♪
Thank you.
♪ We are 20 years old ♪
- ♪ And lots of songs ♪
- [They laugh.]
♪ Like spring
We will dance in your house ♪
♪ Our bread is white
Our wine is good ♪
♪ If you want
it, we'll gladly share ♪
♪ Attention ladies and gentlemen
In a moment we will begin ♪
♪ You may get shocked
from time to time ♪
♪ But don't worry
Don't cross yourself ♪
♪ And remember that one day
You turned 20 ♪
♪ Hey ♪
[Upbeat music]
It's almost well done.
[Player] Hey, isn't that your son?
It works, his song deliveries.
My neighbor had one delivered.
A true entrepreneur!
[Laughs]
- Cheek.
- Ah OK.
Eh no!
Oh, there you are!
Donne.
It's not his favorite, but hey.
- Did you buy them at "4 pavés"?
- Yeah.
I wanted to tell you...
I set up a box
with old ones
From the factory.
Custom songs.
Are you going to make a living with this?
For the moment, it starts,
but we hope.
It's more fun
than delivering meals.
People, they want to eat.
You sell them air.
Do you have a more stupid idea?
I try to get out of it.
There were other ways.
You are never happy!
Always something to say!
Mom would have encouraged me.
What do you know about it?
She is no longer there.
He also sometimes
said bullshit.
[Rhythmic song on the radio]
I liked this box.
[The acquiesces.]
It's going to be a real party,
it'll be fun.
Yeah.
Yeah, but...
I don't know, something is missing, something
big.
Something
that blows up the box,
who drives it!
I don't know, what... I...
Hm ?
Stop it, JC!
That's our big thing!
What?
Between the two of us, we can do it.
[They laugh.]
José, Angèle says things
without saying them.
Do you understand, anyway?
No.
But if ! Yes ! When she sings...
♪ D'aller te faire en... mmm ♪
It's to hide a swear word.
Did you understand which one, anyway?
Well no, I haven't... I...
But if !
♪ D'aller te faire en... mmm... ♪
But no ?
Oh yes okay !
[He's laughing.]
She tells him... Absolutely!
- Yes.
- You knew ?
Obviously !
Ah yeah, everyone, what. Hold on.
[Rhythmic music]
♪ So let me sing to you ♪
♪ D'aller te faire en... mmm ♪
♪ I won't be on the radio ♪
♪ Because my words are not very beautiful ♪
Attention.
♪ Balance your what
One day, maybe, it will change... ♪
[Frank] Guys!
- The girls and the guy.
- Yes.
We got
the contract of the year. Guess.
Well then?
We are going to sing at half-time
in the semi-final of the Coupe de France!
- But no ?
- Hold on.
That's crazy.
Lens-Valenciennes?
- Goodness!
- But how ?
We were at the stadium.
You would have seen Jean-Claude
- sell them the thing.
- Stopped.
It's especially when Frank
sang to show them.
They went, "Wow!"
[Frank] We will reach 25,000 people.
It will be full.
Let's go.
[Laughs]
I'm going to tread the lawn of Hainaut.
[Henriette]
I put a bottle in the fridge
for when the box takes off,
here we are!
Yeah. After that,
no more checks for 140 euros.
Sorry, I don't have time.
A delivery to be made.
What?
- This machine has been working for 12 years.
- Yes.
There is a red button!
Even that, you don't know how to do.
It's not complicated !
- No...
- An 8-year-old retard would spin it.
You need to raise yourself a little...
What is this suit?
Hello.
- He's getting married.
- There.
I have a delivery for you
from me.
Well, Guedon? There you go, surprised.
[Calm music]
♪ I came to tell you that I'm leaving ♪
Oh no, listen, it's okay.
♪ And your tears
can't change it ♪
Stop and go take your post...
♪ As Verlaine said so well
To the bad wind ♪
Guédon, stop it!
To your post and stop singing.
♪ I came to tell you that I'm leaving ♪
♪ You remember the old days
And you cry ♪
I swear to you that if you continue...
♪ You're suffocating, you're turning pale ♪
♪ Now the hour has come ♪
[He screams.]
- ♪ Goodbye forever ♪
- You hurt me.
- ♪ But I'm sorry ♪
♪ To tell you I'm leaving ♪
We will manage it.
♪ Yes, I loved you, yes but... ♪
[Calm music]
[He sighs.]
[He blows.]
[Applause]
You are fired.
It's over!
Hello, is it delivery?
- Yes.
- Come in, come in.
Thank you.
I'm going to look for my husband.
[She sighs.]
Hello.
OK, you...
"To my man
whom I love a little more every day."
So...
There is a song.
[Soft music]
♪ I stole that blood from you ♪
♪ That we shouldn't have shared ♪
♪ Out of words, out of dreams ♪
♪ I'll scream ♪
♪ Je t'aime ♪
♪ Like crazy, like a soldier ♪
♪ Like a movie star ♪
♪ Je t'aime ♪
♪ Like a wolf, like a king ♪
♪ Like a man I'm not ♪
♪ See, I love you like this ♪
Excuse me.
Wait, is that all?
Wait, honey, that was great.
- It's true ? You liked ?
- Yes.
[Door]
[Scooter]
[She's crying.]
What ? It's not okay ?
No.
- It's not okay.
- Is it him again?
It will never change!
He takes you for a bitch.
Come on, come on.
[Sobs]
It saddens me
to see you so unhappy.
A guy like that doesn't deserve you.
You are a great girl.
You might find
someone who really loves you.
Lots of guys are worth it.
But you don't see them.
[Incomprehensible remarks]
- Eh ?
- I know, but I love him.
You do not understand.
[Portable]
- You don't pick up.
- Yes.
Okay, you pick up,
but you tell him to fuck off.
He must respect you.
- Yes.
- It's understood ?
You don't let yourself go.
Yes!
It's me speaking. I'm tired
of being thought of as a bitch on duty!
I don't calm down.
Do you realize the humiliation?
Are you front?
[Soft music]
I don't know, are you coming?
- I go.
- No Please.
[She runs.]
[Philippe] How could I imagine
that Sandrine would do
such a thing to me? Eh ?
- I had to pretend.
- Nope.
I couldn't do otherwise.
Well... I didn't come empty-handed.
- It's not enough.
- I have other things for you.
[Soft music]
I'll take you. I will take care of you.
It suits you well, your little shorts.
Oh !
Well, there you go !
Ah, mam!
How was it this morning?
It was, it was.
Very well.
[She sighs.]
Uh...
Darling. Honey, come here,
I have something to tell you.
What is happening ? You're ill ?
No why do you say that ?
I don't know, you look like...
when you're sick.
Oh but no, no.
I met someone.
A man.
I have a lover.
[embarrassed laugh]
Wait, I'm not done.
I haven't known that since your father.
Yes.
Tonight he is coming home.
I would like to be alone with him.
Alright, yeah. Bah...
I'll go up there, don't worry,
I'll leave you alone.
José...
I would like to be "alone" with him.
You go sleep somewhere else.
Because...
She coughs.
[She mumbles.]
Here it is.
What ? No, okay, I got it.
- Yes...
- Yes!
I had already understood.
HM okay.
Well, well I... I finish the...
At least it's clean.
Alright, that's nice.
Go on.
Come on, boom.
Oh !
It's for me ?
Of course, my pussycat.
I was uncomfortable yesterday.
I was bad for you.
Oh !
- She is magnificent.
- [He nods.]
I am happy.
It's good that you wear it.
Why do you say
"it's good that I have the door"?
Well because... You, at least...
I mean, she's really good.
You will be sublime in it.
She's not your wife's?
Wait.
She doesn't like him.
She didn't wear it once.
It's stupid, isn't it?
It's like
I bought it for you.
Hey, my pussycat?
You offer me what your wife wants more?
Do you think you are at Emmaus?
No...
Take your shit back! I don't want to
see your face anymore, get the fuck out!
I never want to see you again.
Get out, get the hell out of here.
I don't want to see you anymore.
- Don't push me either!
- Go back to your wife!
I don't want to see you anymore.
[Tears]
It was not the same cries
as usual.
You were brave, my dear.
[Sobs]
Oh, my little cat.
Go ahead, cry.
José, she is 58 years old!
You are not his father.
Neither her husband. Let her live.
She has the right. It's a woman.
No, it's mom.
Move on.
Even for you, I swear, it's better.
I don't know who he is.
You suck.
[Doorbell]
- Am I bothering you ?
- No.
What are you doing here?
He got dumped by his mother.
Frank, drink with me, please.
I started alone,
but alone, it's pathetic.
You have always been my friend.
Please.
[She sighs.]
[Jose] Yeah!
Yeah, she's right.
We're going to do that!
We get drunk all 3.
Great idea!
[Sophie] Can I sleep here tonight?
What?
- Yes yes.
- OKAY.
[Whisper] Get out.
What?
- Oh !
- I am tired.
No...
no ? OK.
I prefer to
sleep there because... Just a little.
[Very loud]
I'm going to bed because...
Oh ! I am exhausted.
Big day.
Have fun.
Do you want to sit down?
All the times he left
right after fucking me
because he had
"an important meeting". You speak !
There are even birthdays.
Every year,
I found myself like a bitch
because he couldn't free himself.
[Sigh]
You were right:
never gave a fuck about me.
[The acquiesces.]
Why didn't I listen to you?
He never loved me.
You are nice.
Your girl will be lucky.
Uh...
What are you doing ?
[Soft music]
Bah... I kiss you.
But why ?
Non ?
Aren't you in love with me?
We're friends
so we can't be in love.
Well, you see, you're like my brother.
I can't be in love
with my brother, it's weird.
[She laughs.]
Damn... Oh, that's so funny.
We're tired, that's all.
[Laughs]
No but Frank...
Are you serious ?
Are you in love with me?
Alright, come on, I'll take you back.
[Soft music]
I'm sorry.
Good night.
[Scooter]
It's better ?
Hm...
Here, I brought you this.
Drink it, you'll feel better.
- Hmm.
- There's an order for you.
[She growls.]
there.
I know the song.
I've always wanted
to sing to see.
Do you agree?
Hmm.
Well...
Well, I'm going.
I go.
[Rhythmic music]
♪ Two lives, two voices that meet
Two stories that tell each other ♪
♪ A song to say it ♪
♪ There are words, images to describe it
Nice old-fashioned meeting ♪
♪ Take a flash ♪
♪ There's magic on stage ♪
♪ The curtain falls, and it's over
Come on, baby ♪
♪ Give me your heart, baby
Your body, baby ♪
♪ Hey, gimme your good old funk ♪
♪ Ton rock, baby, ta soul baby, hey ♪
♪ Sing along with me ♪
♪ I want a woman like you
To take me away ♪
♪ At the end of the world
A woman like you, hey ♪
♪ Give me your heart, baby ♪
♪ Ton corps, baby, hey ♪
♪ Give me your good old funk ♪
♪ Ton rock, baby, ta soul, baby, hey ♪
♪ Sing with me
I want a man ♪
♪ Like you ♪
♪ Bad boy, you know I like you ♪
♪ Un homme like you ♪
♪ Hey ♪
[Enthusiastic shouts]
Hou!
I'm sending you someone.
Goodbye.
Come, I have to talk to you.
- I don't want to see you here anymore.
- What ?
[Frank] You drink, and that's none of my business?
- I had a problem...
- I don't care.
You never come back here again.
Either way, you don't care
of this company.
Why are they bickering?
- Philippe will comfort you.
- [Sob]
Bah ?
What is happening ?
Why is she crying ?
Nothing. She will no longer work with us.
What ? What do you mean ?
She's not motivated enough.
We'll find someone else.
She told you that?
Is it because of the delivery
I made?
It's my fault, Frank!
I wanted to see
how does it feel to deliver.
And people were awfully happy.
Henriette, this does not concern you.
- Bah.
- I do not understand everything.
- Me niether.
- There is nothing to understand.
She never gave a fuck
about the company. She leaves.
- Oh?
- Did you fire her?
No, I made a decision.
Go to work, there are deliveries.
- If anyone has to go, it's me.
- Henriette,
go back to your standard.
I disagree.
We all decide together.
You suck.
Sorry ? Who do you think You Are ?
For the one who was the only one
to believe this idea.
- What ? No I think not.
- Where were you at the start?
At home, with your risk-free shitty job .
In fact, you started this company
to become a motherfucker boss
like the one who fired us.
You got the idea
but without the group,
your idea, it's worth nothing!
I leave with the idea
that is worth nothing.
- Screw you.
- But Frank!
Frank, stop your bullshit!
Don't mess it up, it's starting
to work. We play at the stadium!
Shut up !
Pardon me?
He has gone mad.
Me, I continue. We'll find
another singer and call Sophie back.
I can't go on without him.
Emancipate yourself!
Are you going to be his dog all your life?
- Oh no !
- What about ?
He just walked off,
and you already want to take his place?
You wanted this from the start!
Take his place
and play the little boss!
That's enough now.
You're a real asshole, actually.
Yeah ! That's good,
that makes two,
and besides,
you too have not changed:
that shabby little executive that you were
and always will be.
OK, kiss !
I can not believe.
You're
screwing it all up.
[melancholic music]
[Messaging] Hello, this is Frank.
Please leave me a message.
[melancholic music]
[Joseph] M. Chesnot !
Have you seen Frank?
We have to sing tonight at the stadium,
and he's not answering.
No, not seen.
Thanks.
[Mobile on vibrate]
[melancholic music]
[Phone]
"Let's sing", hello.
Oh no, sorry, sir.
The company is currently closed.
Yes I...
I don't know when it will reopen, no.
Call back later, huh? Thank you.
Goodbye.
See you soon.
[He coughs.]
You know what ? If you tell me
that my CV is perfect,
but that unfortunately,
I have too much
of experience,
which would harm the company,
I give you a slap.
With the flat of the hand.
I...
Screw you.
[He slams the door.]
[Soft music]
[Henriette] Sir?
You wish?
[Host]Welcome to the Hainaut stadium
for this semi-final
of the Coupe de France, a
historic moment for supporters.
We're counting on you
to push behind our players.
[Soft music]
[Female voice]
♪ What if you didn't exist ♪
♪ Tell me why I exist ♪
♪ To hang out in a world without you ♪
♪ Without hope and without regrets ♪
♪ What if you didn't exist ♪
♪ I'll try to invent love ♪
♪ Like a painter
Who sees under his fingers ♪
♪ Born the colors of the day ♪
♪ And who can't believe it ♪
Honey, no! What are you doing?
Stop. Sto !
[Laughs]
Stop.
I loved recording your mother
when she sang.
She was singing all the time
so I was recording all the time.
I no longer have his records...
But I still have his voice.
I haven't forgotten her, you know.
Your song deliveries, there...
That's true...
It would have made him proud.
Then you're not that bad.
You're doing pretty well.
Come on, don't be stupid.
Go join your friends.
- [Rhythm Music]
- [Call Tone]
- [Jose] Frank? Damn, where were you?
- I'll tell you.
- Do you still want to sing at halftime?
- Bah...
- Yes or no ?
- Yes.
Go get Jean-Claude.
[José] It's complicated him and me.
Halftime starts in 12 minutes!
Lay low and bring it back.
[Calm music]
Oh, Frank !
Put on your coat,
we need you, and...
please tell Sophie I'm here
.
Oh...
Sophie !
If you want to tell me that I'm
a fool, that I'm unforgivable,
I deserve to die on my own,
you're 100% right.
But could you tell me after
we sang in the semi-final?
Jean-Claude, I'm sorry,
you're not a lousy executive.
No, nicer.
Hey ! Jean-Claude, how...
Maybe too nice there.
Dear Jean-Claude...
It's not a letter.
[Doorbell]
I won't make it anyway.
I'm sorry, that's it, shit!
We're not going to spend 15 hours on it!
But sometimes you're boring too,
with your little lock
and that you take
a little superior tone!
It's annoying, because...
I'm sorry, Jean-Claude, sorry.
Frank needs us.
- Shall I explain to you in the car?
- Yes.
News, news.
[Calm music]
[Host]It's half time,
don't move,
because a surprise awaits you!
I ask you for
a maximum of applause!
[distant screams]
I didn't have the courage
to cancel.
- They must be wondering what we're doing.
- I was stupid.
It's me, I shouldn't have.
- Me too.
- Me, even more, frankly.
- Frankly ?
Yes, you won.
[Henriette] Hurry up, young people,
we're late.
- Come on, Henrietta.
- I'm coming.
- Do you want me to carry you?
- Nope.
[Host] Small change:
our surprise is not there.
- Hello.
- Where are you going ?
- We come to sing.
- They're expecting us.
No, I haven't been told anything.
Tell the leaders,
and in 2 minutes, it will be settled.
- Get out, I'm going to be less nice!
- Oh...
But finally !
♪ I came to tell you that I'm leaving ♪
♪ And your tears can't change that ♪
Jean Claude !
Do you remember ?
You know him ?
A former colleague.
It was great what you did.
It gave me the courage to walk away.
I owe you a good one!
But no, you're kidding!
But yes.
Oh yes ! Exactly !
[Moderator] Valenciennes, are you there?
We are here !
- What were you doing?
- We are here !
Did you see the time?
[José] We agreed.
[Henriette] Can you film us?
This is for my followers. Thank you.
[Host]Finally,
our surprise is here.
Please give them
lots of applause!
- [Enthusiastic Music]
- [Clam]
Good evening everyone.
My name is Frank
and I represent
the company "Si on chantait".
We deliver songs to you
for a birthday, a party,
a celebration or...
simply to tell
a loved one that we love them.
[Clamor]
You call "Let's sing",
and we'll come sing
the song of your choice.
And... And tonight, precisely,
I would like to dedicate a song to...
- to my friends.
- [Applause]
José.
[Soft music]
Jean-Claude, Henriette, Sophie.
I would like to tell you that...
I wouldn't have achieved anything without you.
That this adventure,
we all did it together.
That I need you and...
never again will I let you down.
Never.
[Applause]
Come on, this is for you. Yeah.
[José] You're going to rock!
[Soft music]
♪ La grande ville ♪
♪ Mange la ville ♪
♪ La grande vie ♪
[Rhythmic music]
♪ Mange la vie ♪
♪ Marie si belle ♪
♪ Marie vaisselle ♪
♪ Marie chandelle ♪
♪ Plume d'hirondelle ♪
Hey, hey, hey, hey, elle ♪
♪ Fleur sans colline ♪
♪ Pleurs en cuisine ♪
♪ Marie sans fard ♪
♪ Fog Flower ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ Let's sing, let's sing ♪
Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ Si on chantait ♪
♪ Divine Mary, let's sing ♪
♪ Let's sing, let's sing ♪
♪ Let's sing, let's sing
Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ Si on chantait ♪
- [Enthusiastic clamor]
- Wow!
That's good !
[Cheers]
[If we sang" - Julien Clerc]
[Soft music]
[Calm music]