Cemre.
Cemre!
- Cemre.
- Yeah? I'm here.
Yes? What's up?
Did you change our dance song?
Oh, that? Yeah, honey. Don't worry.
- Cool.
- Of course.
Who changes their song every half an hour?
- Hey, Tuna.
- I'm here.
- What's up?
- Hand me a banana, babe.
I think you should stop eating.
Listen, honey.
The playlist, the seating, the food…
I'm handling them all.
- Don't worry, okay?
- Thank you so much, honey.
- I'm so nervous.
- Look at your hair.
Let it go. I'm going to do a bun too.
- It's your hair.
- Come on.
Where's Leyla?
Who knows?
I'm sure she's after some free stuff.
Not that anyone would take her seriously
in that costume.
- What's wrong with our costumes?
- Pose.
Hang on.
There we go. That's it.
Oh, Gulliver's here.
I'd never think I'd agree with you,
you pain in the ass,
but the bartender
laughed at me for minutes.
He laughed at me!
This is supposed to be
just the time for scoring guys,
but we have zero chance like this.
So you're bringing your chances
from zero to one with those glasses?
Girl, I don't need chances.
I'm fighting for Cemre.
What?
Just so you know,
the bartender's really hot.
- My eyes are bleeding just looking at you.
- Don't mind her, Cemre.
Mete's a suitable candidate. I like him.
Yeah. I totally agree.
He's handsome, smart,
sophisticated, and rich.
You know, I think he's going to propose!
What?
When?
Did you see the ring? Was it big?
He's cheap, though.
He probably bought a fake.
Let's have a jeweler check it.
- Shut up.
- Mete's no good.
I've been telling you that
for eight years.
Eight years!
- Think about the bartender.
- No.
- But not in that costume.
- Come on.
- You go get the bartender, then.
- Yeah. Go ahead.
But I don't want to get married.
We're fine the way we are with Emir.
I'm sure you are.
You know, since the guy
saw you three times in total.
He'd run away if he spent a week with you.
- As if you're doing any better.
- I'm doing perfectly fine.
Stop arguing already.
We're almost ready to go here.
- Tuna, the shoe and the pen.
- Okay. Got it.
- Here you go.
- Oh, I know.
Add my baby's name too.
Sure. Let's get it
its wedding present too.
- Cemre...
- Give it here.
- She took it.
- Go ahead, honey.
Put yours in capital letters
right in the middle.
I hope you get married soon
so we can have some peace.
I swear I'll stab you with the heel, Tuna.
Just shut up.
I'm adding yours in the corner
with tiny letters.
But it's so small.
You don't even want to get married.
Why is mine so small?
See that small speck? That's you.
- Give it to me!
- No, I'm doing it.
- Come on! Hand it over!
- Let it go! Come on!
You're going to tear it apart!
- Let it go!
- Let me have it!
Tuna!
It was her, Cemre. I swear.
You hexed me, Tuna.
Listen. I swear I'll hold you accountable
if Mete doesn't propose.
I'll kill you!
Come on. Don't be like that.
Let's stay positive.
- You brought me seven years of bad luck.
- Don't be ridiculous.
Shall I take a picture of you?
What do you say?
Look at you all dolled up.
Forget the superstition.
- Come on, girls.
- Let's go.
- Wow! Come on.
- Come on.
- We don't have a single picture together.
- You're all so pretty. Beautiful.
Look at you! Oh, come on already, Cemre.
It's not the end of the world.
Yeah, man.
Where are you, Mete?
Hey, baby.
Hey. Who do you think
is going to catch the bouquet?
I'm betting on Leyla. A hundred bucks.
No way. Cemre's here.
- I'm thinking Cemre too.
- Oh, yeah?
Let's hope so, then. Let's go.
- Hold that. Come on.
- Do try, though.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
I'm here!
Throw it!
- Three, two…
- This is my favorite part.
One…
Come on.
- Do it.
- Come on already.
I caught it! I did it!
- There we go.
- I got it.
Nice.
Mete?
He's here. He's going to propose!
Yes!
Yes.
I mean… Yes, I'm listening.
I'm Cemre. What's up?
Cemre.
I wasn't planning on doing it here,
but I can't wait any longer.
Cemre.
I can't do this anymore.
I'm sorry.
I can't be in this relationship anymore.
I'll come get my stuff sometime, okay?
Don't throw them out.
Cemre.
I can't do this anymore.
I can't be in this relationship anymore.
I'll come get my stuff sometime, okay?
Don't throw them out.
Why did this have to happen?
I can't spend eight more years
for someone else now!
Shame on you people too.
Shame on you
for throwing this bouquet to me!
Honey, please stop crying.
There's plenty of fish in the sea.
You're an educated,
strong, beautiful woman.
You'll find someone else.
Even if you don't, it's fine.
You don't need a man.
- Yeah.
- It's not a necessity.
But why? We were going to get married.
Everything was fine.
I bet there's someone else.
What else could it be?
- Oh, come on!
- No way.
- Come on, honey.
- Yeah.
The mirror! It's because of you.
You cursed me!
I'm going to be a spinster because of you.
I'm blocking him on everything.
- Do it.
- You'll regret it, Cemre.
- Shut up.
- Do it.
If my honeymoon blows up on my face
because of that dumb-ass,
I swear I'll tear him a new one.
It already did, man.
Remember our wedding
when he didn't show up,
so Cemre was bawling,
so the girls stayed at our place,
so you and I slept on the couch?
Don't remind me, bro. Just don't.
Look at him. Look.
"Diving is important, Cemre!"
I'm scared of the sea, man.
"Let's climb the Everest, Cemre!"
I can't even live on the second floor.
Mete! It's Mete! I bet he's sorry.
- I'll get it.
- Cemre, stop.
- Don't.
- Why?
- Stop. Where are you going?
- Why? Shall I freshen up?
Leyla, you go get it.
- Go.
- What? Why me?
Leyla!
Let's not get judgmental.
Everyone makes mistakes.
- Yeah.
- Oh, honey!
We'll do our honeymoon
after they make up, right?
Is this the right time for that?
It's still ringing. I know that ring.
He just can't give up on me.
- It's Mete, and I'm getting married.
- No. Stop.
- Leyla, come on.
- Sinan!
- Let's go. Give me that.
- What's going on?
- Stop.
- Guys, we all need to leave.
- Come on.
- No.
- What are you up to?
- I'll explain. Ozan, help.
- Of course. Come on, people.
- Let's go.
- What's going on?
- Let's leave.
- You too, honey. Get her dress.
- All right.
Come along.
It's best to keep visits short, honey.
- Come on.
- What's up?
I realized I couldn't be without you
this past month.
Wherever I am,
I want you to be at my side.
Leyla, will you marry me?
Emir?
Cemre?
Honey, what's going on? Are you all right?
Leyla.
I realized I couldn't be without you
this past month.
Wherever I am,
I want you to be at my side.
Leyla.
Will you marry me?
Yes!
- Yes?
- Yes! Yes!
Yes?
You said yes?
Yes!
Baby!
I'm in shock.
Your hand.
Let me see. It looks beautiful.
You look beautiful.
Let me look at you. You're so pretty.
- I missed you so much, honey.
- Me too.
Bro.
I couldn't have done this
without you. Thanks.
- Without you?
- What?
Well, his flight was delayed,
so he couldn't make it to the wedding.
I invited him
so he'd have a place to stay.
- How was I supposed to know, honey?
- Shut up, Sinan.
All right, then. If everything's okay,
our honeymoon awaits, honey!
- Are we going?
- Oh, no.
- Melis?
- Is it time?
- What's going on?
- Is it happening?
- Hold her!
- Sinan!
- Be careful.
- Where's my van?
- Where is it?
- How would I know?
- They must be near.
- Careful.
- Let's go. Hold her.
- Here!
- Where?
- Come on!
- Let's go.
Why are we going to the van?
- Bring it around!
- Stay calm.
- Is it far?
- The door.
- It won't open.
- I got her.
- Hold her.
- What's going on?
Get in, honey.
Calm down.
This is important to us.
- Where are you going?
- Come on, honey!
Where are you going?
It's happening. Step on it.
The baby's coming.
I'm so excited! My friend's in labor!
See? It's kicking. What a rascal.
- Sinan?
- Ozan, go faster. Hurry up.
- Sinan, Melis is not here.
- What?
Melis? Melis is not here!
- Honey, Melis is not here!
- What?
- Ozan, where's Melis?
How would I know? Emir had her.
- Did you leave your wife?
- I trusted him with her!
Don't be stupid, man.
I wasn't carrying her alone.
It's not my fault.
- Did you run her over?
- Turn around.
Don't be stupid.
My husband's not a murderer.
I'm going to prison
instead of going on my honeymoon.
Screw you all. You left her there.
Let's just turn around.
- We just left her here.
- Get the door.
- Why is the band here?
- How could you do this, man?
- We'll talk afterwards.
- Emir, help us.
- Easy.
- Is she okay?
- Melis, breathe.
- Breathe, honey.
- Breathe.
- Hold me.
You found just the day for a false alarm.
Come on. As long as the baby's okay.
Honey, the baby's okay.
Is it time for us to do the deed yet?
Honey, you're being obnoxious.
Well, then. We have some news for you.
- You're not pregnant, are you?
- Leyla?
Don't be ridiculous.
You know, since everyone's already here
and in one piece,
we figured we'd get married right away.
- What? Come on!
- Oh, you.
Cemre, I know today was tough on you.
If you want...
No, on the contrary.
I think it'd do me good too, honey.
Not that I'd ever think you'd get married.
Guys, you know this is
about the shoe, right?
She's getting married
because I put her name there.
I'm putting your name and your name only
this time, Cemre.
We figured we'd have the wedding
on Emir's family's ranch.
Honey, we'll be happy with it
as long as you're happy.
But we need to hurry up
if we want to do this before the birth
because the baby definitely wants out.
It feels horrible
sending you off all alone.
Don't be ridiculous.
I want tons of pictures
from the dress rehearsal, okay?
Sinem, hold down the fort while I'm gone.
Leyla, move.
Don't worry, babe.
The invitation samples came in today.
We'll be done with our first item
by this afternoon.
Good. Since everyone knows their task,
I should head out.
- Okay.
- Melis.
- Yeah?
- Don't tire yourself out.
I won't. I'm going to the dry cleaner's
this afternoon.
A nice walk will be good for me.
Good. If everything's okay,
I'm leaving.
Hang on. The key to the ranch.
Sorry we're in such a rush
that you have to handle everything.
It's fine. I'll handle everything.
Don't worry.
Oh, let me know if you find my necklace.
- All right.
- I'll go check right now.
See you, then.
- Goodbye.
- Drive safely.
- See you. Kisses.
- Bye-bye.
Maybe we shouldn't have
left her by herself.
Nah. I think it's for the better.
Maybe being alone can help her move on.
You really are a weird bunch.
She doesn't get her stereo fixed
because it's a memento.
She can't forget her ex in ten days.
I'm so tired of your pessimism, Tuna.
Maybe you should've left too.
We'd have some peace.
Am I wrong, though?
God give me patience.
Let's go to the spa after the tasting.
I reserved three spots.
- Awesome.
- Three? What about me?
Tuna, I'm seriously sick of you.
I told you girls he'd be a pain.
- I'm leaving.
- Me too.
- Let's go get ready.
- What about me?
I told them not to let you in our group.
- You're killing me, Tuna.
- But…
- Leyla, please.
- Bye-bye, Tuna.
Eight years, man.
He just left me.
Damn it, Mete.
No tears.
Nothing can bring me down!
Something's bringing me down.
Just don't. Please.
What is it?
Why are you flat all of a sudden?
Here we go. The spare…
Mete!
What is this, even?
Damn your gear.
I better call the girls.
No reception.
Where even am I?
Come on.
Still nothing.
I'm up too high.
Don't look down. Just don't.
It's okay. Don't look.
What's up?
Are you doing a video or something?
Yeah. I love doing videos on top of vans
in the middle of nowhere.
You're tense. That won't work.
Dude, I'm already mad. Just leave.
Yeah, I can tell that from here.
Just so you know,
you can't change the tire from up there.
You need to get down.
Oh, really?
How did I not think of that?
You're so smart. Thanks.
Need a hand?
No. No, thanks.
You might be a criminal for all I know.
Bravo. Seriously.
How can you tell
without even looking at me once?
- I can't.
- Oh, right. Got it. Right.
Yeah. You're scared
you're going to fall in love right away.
Fair enough.
I'm used to it. You can look.
All right. Let me just help you out.
- Please work already.
- You can look. Here I am.
For God's sake.
Dude, I'm scared of heights.
I literally can't look.
I'm not wild about
checking out strange men anyway.
You don't even have a spare.
Listen. The weather's unpredictable here.
I can take you wherever you're going.
I'm just saying.
What was that?
- Let me go!
- All right.
I'm not touching you.
All right. Calm down.
Fine. I won't even look. All right.
You sure can climb down fast.
Look. Okay.
Stop being stubborn. Let me drop you off.
Not many people use this road.
Don't come near me, or I'll scream.
Just go away.
Go ahead and scream. Be my guest.
I'm sure people will run to your aid.
Give it a try.
You're in the middle of nowhere.
I was just being a good Samaritan.
Look. Let me just drop you off.
No. Go away.
Suit yourself. I can't with you anymore.
I'm leaving.
Go ahead! No one asked you to stay.
I wouldn't even if you asked, all right?
I'm not fond of cranky stranded women.
You're annoying.
No woman in their right mind
would ask your help.
Take a hike. Come on. Go.
Good luck.
Damn it, Mete!
What am I going to do?
Damn it.
I'm so glad we chose these cakes.
They're delicious.
Tuna, give Sinan a call
so he doesn't forget to bring pizza.
I already did. Don't worry.
Also, we had to choose those cakes
because you ate everything else they had.
You went through everything they offered
without any shame whatsoever.
- Unbelievable!
- "Unbelievable!"
Cemre's phone is still off, right?
I wonder if she's there yet.
It's off. The battery must've died.
I'm sure she's there by now.
Imagine it. Maybe she embarked
on the journey of her life
and met a hero or something.
In half a day? Come on.
Nothing.
I'm glad she's not here.
She can just chill all by herself.
- All by herself…
- Yeah.
Poyraz… I didn't tell her about Poyraz.
Who's Poyraz?
Here we go.
What's going on?
Who's Poyraz? Is he a guest?
Cemre's going to tear me a new one.
She's going to chop me up into pieces.
What? Why?
I hope you're not trying
to set her up with someone.
She got dumped just yesterday.
Don't be ridiculous.
Leyla would never even
dream of something like that.
She barely had any wits
which she lost at the proposal.
I'm losing it over here. Just tell me.
I swear, Melis, you're up to anything
except giving birth, honey.
Oh, come on.
Poyraz is Emir's cousin.
He lives near the ranch.
Emir asked his help
with the wedding preparations.
How nice.
He's just there to help.
That's a good thing.
She still doesn't get it.
Girls, I'm not
the only optimist here, right?
Just imagine. Cemre's a bit cold.
With his strong arms,
Poyraz chops some wood and makes a fire.
Such romance!
Maybe that'll help Cemre
forget about Mete and move on.
Yeah, right. Don't be ridiculous, man.
I blame your high-carb diet, Tuna.
You can't even think properly anymore.
You all are just boring.
- Should I give Emir a call?
- Call him.
All right.
He's not picking up.
What do you mean? Just text him, then.
I will.
I thought no one was at the ranch.
Oh, no. A burglar.
Let's go, Cemre.
You've come this far.
You can do it.
Damn…
You?
Are you insane, woman?
You almost cracked my head open.
How did you get in here?
What are you up to?
You're a burglar! I knew it.
I'm calling the cops.
- Don't you run! I'm calling them.
- Shut up already!
Are you Cemre?
You know my name? You pervert!
- How do you know my name?
- Emir told me.
I'm his cousin!
They asked me to come help you.
I'm the one who needs help, though.
Look at us.
- Emir?
- Yeah!
Emir, Leyla… Remember them?
Are you going to just stand there?
You look proud, even.
Will you at least try to help me
and get me some ice or water?
I'm dying over here!
Oh, come on. Don't be so dramatic.
You'll survive. Don't worry.
Guys, we're all just chilling here,
but we still haven't heard from Cemre.
Should we call the police?
Oh, come on, girls.
My cousin's not a murderer.
For God's sake.
I'm sure they're mingling
with each other already.
I mean, they must be having a chat.
Her phone probably died.
Just chill, please.
Jeez. All right. I'll call him.
- Yeah.
- Call him.
Let's put your minds at ease.
- We're so worried about her.
- All right, honey.
You're overreacting.
See?
Yeah, cousin?
Hello? What's up, cousin?
- Ask about Cemre.
- Ask him what happened.
- God...
- Give it to me, for God's sake.
- Poyraz?
- Ask about Cemre.
Honey, just…
Hey, Leyla. What's up? You okay?
Is it Leyla? Hey, Leyla.
But…
Yeah, I'm finally at the ranch, but…
What a sicko.
When were you planning on
telling me about this guy?
He's there to help you.
Help me? Why would I need help?
You're right, honey.
But we were so worried about you.
Yeah, she was so worried
she was setting a manicure appointment.
I had a flat tire on the way.
Then a maniac insisted on helping me.
What? Did he touch you? Scumbag!
He wouldn't dare.
But I was still so mad at Mete,
I basically cussed the guy off.
Then it started raining.
I arrived here
all drenched and covered in mud.
- Guess what happened next.
- What?
Oh, no! Did the scumbag follow you?
I noticed someone was in the house.
I didn't know what to do,
so I grabbed a log
and hit him in the head.
Then I realized
he was the maniac on the road.
Poyraz?
Yeah, Poyraz.
Cemre, did you crack his skull open?
Did you just murder him?
Don't be dumb.
Yeah. Then I made him answer the phone
so you wouldn't get suspicious.
Don't be stupid.
I'm alive.
For now, at least.
Dude, what happened?
You okay? You want us to come over?
I'm all right, cousin. Thanks.
Don't worry about me.
Who cares? Cemre, are you okay?
Let us know about the progress.
Call us once in a while.
All right. Talk to you later.
Here.
- See?
- She's fine.
- See, honey? Here you go.
- All right.
Have fun.
Here.
A shower might make more sense.
Oh, yeah? You're going to rub my back too?
Go home. Don't you have a place?
I sure do. It's not like
I want to stay here with you.
Enjoy the secluded house.
Off you go, then.
What's that noise?
It's so early.
Hello!
Hello! Can't you hear me?
I can't deal with this so early.
What are you doing?
Who told you to do this?
Here.
Good morning to you as well, Cemre.
Morning. So, what are you doing?
I'm mowing the yard for the wedding.
What's wrong?
You're welcome.
I didn't say thanks.
I know.
Why wouldn't you run it by me first?
Since I'm the wedding planner and all.
The wedding is in ten days.
We can't have the planner
waking up at 10:00.
All right. Okay. I was just joking.
Don't look at me like that.
I don't want you
mowing me down or something.
Here. You're in charge.
I was just helping.
If you're so mad about it,
you can do it yourself.
Are you going to be
in the way all day long?
I don't think you realize it,
but I'm the one
who should be avoiding you.
Go, then. Avoid me.
You can run from me too.
I can handle everything by myself.
I swear you're the expert
on making a guy run away.
You're trying my patience.
Suit yourself. I don't care.
- Give it back.
- Take it.
Give me my coffee back.
Go make your own coffee.
Jeez! I can't deal with you right now.
Cemre, please help me out.
I want to dance at the wedding too,
but they won't let me.
Please make them let me.
Forget about the dance, Tuna.
We're trying to talk.
Tuna, why would you be dancing?
Don't be ridiculous.
You know what? Let him. Poor guy.
How do you like the baby blue ones?
Come here. She's wants baby blue.
Is that Cemre?
Hey, Cemre. How are things with Poyraz?
Are you two getting along?
Don't even let me start.
We're getting along so well.
- Oh! Are these blue ones the same?
- Yes, ma'am.
Well, I don't think so.
Don't you have more?
They're the same flowers, ma'am.
- I hate them. No.
- No.
Don't they have any pink ones?
Like, powder pink?
What about these lilac ones, girls?
How many baby blue ones can you get me?
- Twenty, maybe thirty.
- All right.
I liked the bright orange ones too.
Bring them over.
I want to compare. That's pretty much it.
Do you have more yellow ones?
Oh, the invites! We haven't shown her.
- No yellow.
- Cemre.
What do you think? We loved it.
It looks awesome.
How many guests will be there?
You know, just us.
- Like, 25 to 50 people.
- Tops.
What? 25 to 50? "Just us," huh?
Add ten more and book a venue, girl.
- You have more of these?
- No, ma'am.
Fine, then. Pack them up.
Everyone's insane over here.
I shouldn't have trusted you anyway.
Of course he'll go insane
if you ask him for ten different flowers
of the same shade.
They were not the same color! Jeez!
How do you know?
I hear about everything around here.
It seems the news
spread like Wi-Fi over here.
All right. Don't get mad.
Just tell me what you want.
I'll go get them from Osman.
I don't want anything from him anymore.
Cemre, stop!
I mean…
What the heck? What is this?
You saw me with the brush and the paint.
What did it look like I was doing?
Jeez!
CATERING COMPANIES
- Yeah?
- Hey, Cemre.
I swear I'm going to kill Tuna.
Please ask her what I even said
for her to get so mad.
I just told her
she should wear this black dress.
I only told her to be modern and bold.
Is that Cemre?
Hey, Cemre.
What's up?
How's Poyraz? Is everything okay?
Let's not talk about him.
He's so annoying.
I've spent my morning
trying to get the paint stains off.
Forget about me now.
Tuna, what's with the black dress?
Why are you so dismissive, honey?
Look how elegant it is.
It's so different.
Tuna, you can't pick her dress too.
Leave her alone.
Jeez. Fine!
You look nervous.
Is there something wrong?
Well, I can't find my locket necklace
or any caterers.
Honey, we looked everywhere
but couldn't find your necklace.
But hear me out.
Make sure we have pickles and plums
at the cocktail before the wedding.
- It's crucial. Okay?
- Hang on a minute.
- Wait.
- What's up?
Is that Poyraz? Cemre!
Kisses. Talk to you later. Bye.
I'd ask if you needed any help,
but you'd say…
I'd say yes.
- Did you hit your head? You okay?
- Fine. Just leave.
I was just joking.
I was born here.
Just tell me what you need.
Catering. All caterers are booked.
You hungry?
How is this helping, Poyraz?
It is.
We'll eat and take care of the catering.
What do you say?
Okay.
- Come on. Let's go.
- All right.
Stop! Pull over!
What is it?
Damn it. Someone stole my van.
Oh, that? Calm down.
I had it towed this morning.
They'll fix it up and bring it over.
Why'd you do that?
You were exhausted and busy.
I did it so you could
focus on the wedding.
Oh.
You're welcome.
I didn't say thanks.
I know.
MEATBALL &amp; SAUSAGE SANDWICH
Here you go.
- So?
I mean, look around you.
It's a small town.
There's no catering company.
- You won't regret it.
- Right.
Poyraz!
Where have you been, kid?
I haven't seen you in days.
- Welcome, honey.
- Thanks. Hello.
- Tell me about it, Suna.
- I was so busy.
- And you know, Emir's…
- I heard. He's getting married.
Yeah. At the ranch too.
I guess it's your turn now, huh?
What would you like to have?
How about an olive oil dish?
We'll trust you with it.
Right away.
Hey. Don't pout. Just trust me.
- Trust has gotten me nowhere yet.
- What'd you say?
I was just saying Emir and you…
You're so different.
Oh, that? Yeah, we are.
Emir's the spoiled one in our family.
I'm more of a planner.
Never mind us. What about you?
Leyla, you, the others…
Who are you? What do you do?
Leyla, Tuna, and I are childhood friends.
Our moms were friends in high school.
We stayed in touch.
I see. And the others?
Melis and Sinem.
We met them in middle school.
Emir had told me about you guys.
I wish he'd told us about you.
So you live here, right?
I was in the UK, but I came back.
Emir stayed there.
I guess he's coming back too,
with Leyla and all…
Maybe they'll go together.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Here we go. I'll get that.
Bon appétit.
Thanks, Suna.
Leyla and Emir are
like two peas in a pod, right?
They just met,
and we're planning the wedding.
They've been together
for what, four months?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
Love at first sight, huh?
Yeah, right. Love.
Oh, come on.
I mean, you're not against love, are you?
What? Of course not.
But you're pouting.
- No, I'm not.
- You did it again.
Did what?
You're like, cringing or something
when I mention love.
I'll hit you with this fork so hard
you'll be counting stars.
Jeez! Love this, love that.
You can't shut up about it.
We were just having a nice conversation,
but you had to do what you always do.
I didn't do anything. It was you.
And it's not about me. It's about them.
What? It was never about you anyway.
We're talking about
how they fell in love with each other.
Why are you even offended?
God give me patience. Fine, dude.
Fine. They're very much in love.
They're so in love
that Emir just shows up and proposes
and we're planning a wedding the next day.
Bravo. I wouldn't bother
if I didn't have respect for love.
You're here for your friend, not love.
Good morning.
Oh, no. What time is it?
Almost 9:00 a.m. Morning.
- Damn. I need to handle the fabrics.
- But it was on track yesterday.
They emailed me after you left.
They can't get the ones I want in time.
Nothing goes my way.
That sucks.
May I help?
No, I'll handle it.
I'm going to the town today anyway.
I'll get to the electrical, then.
- Okay.
- See you.
- Do you even know about that stuff?
- I'm not here for that, ma'am.
What? Oh, sorry. Hang on.
I totally forgot about you.
Follow me.
You know what I need?
Hi, Poyraz. This was in the van.
Let me see.
Well, I can't find my locket necklace
or any caterers.
I want some flowers.
The bride and groom will be here.
Some flowers up here so they can hang.
That's what I'd like.
Thanks. Let's go.
- Here's your hot chocolate.
- Thank you.
Is this what you do?
I mean, are you a wedding planner?
No. I'm actually a veterinarian.
But when I lost my dog
on my first year on the job,
I took a short break.
As in?
Ten years.
What a short break.
I'm currently a columnist
for a pet magazine,
and I plan my friends' weddings
as a hobby.
I think you're really good.
You should go for it.
I had decided I'd do exactly that, but…
But what?
Mete didn't like the idea.
- Mete?
- My boyfriend.
No, I mean… My ex-boyfriend.
- Your ex?
- Yeah.
I see.
I think that was really unfair of him.
You're good. You should do it.
You think so?
I don't know. I think he was right.
I had fights with literally everyone
since I came here.
I even drove you insane.
I mean, if you consider
what we've been through in two days,
I think we've come a long way,
don't you think?
You're right. It's a miracle we survived.
All joking aside, I wouldn't have been
able to do it without you.
What about your friends?
I mean, if you didn't have me,
all by yourself in a strange place…
They wanted to come, but...
Right. I know the story.
I'm not surprised.
You think men don't gossip?
I think we need
something stronger than hot chocolate.
I'll be right back.
What's up with you?
- I was at the dress rehearsal.
- And?
It was bad, Tuna.
It was too fluffy and then not fluffy.
The beads weren't working.
I don't have time. I'm nervous.
What's up with you?
I watched another romance flick
with a sad ending.
You're an adult, Tuna. For God's sake.
You're callous.
- Yeah?
- Hello? Tuna?
No, we don't use gas cylinders.
Hello? Tuna? It's Mete, man.
Well, we don't use that either.
It's Mete, not the cylinder salesman.
- Hello?
- Well, see…
I'll call you later.
I'll give you a call later.
- It's Mete, man.
- Yeah.
- What are you talking about? Come on.
- All right…
Hello?
Sorry for disturbing you,
but I couldn't reach the others.
They blocked me.
I was worried about Cemre.
I hope she's okay.
Hello?
I wanted to tell you something.
Hello? Tuna?
Anyway, hit me up when you're available.
I need to talk to Cemre. It's important.
Bye.
- What's going on, Tuna?
- What do you mean?
Why are you talking to him?
Well, you heard him.
You all blocked him, so he called me.
There was a reason we did that.
How are you going to justify it to her?
I don't know, Leyla.
I'm going to kill you, Tuna.
So, what's your story?
I don't have one.
I won't let you off the hook so easily.
You have to have an awful story
since you moved from the UK to this town.
Are you always so sure of everything?
Maybe I just missed my hometown
and moved back.
Nope.
Did you go bankrupt?
Oh, you were cheated on!
With your best friend too.
And you got conned.
Wow, man.
You have a strong imagination. Jeez.
That's basically
three-seasons worth of material.
Tell me. Which one was it?
My girlfriend.
Your girlfriend?
I mean… My ex-girlfriend.
She chose to go on yacht tours
with my boss
over living with me.
What a hussy.
Why did she do it
when she had a guy like you?
A guy like me?
I mean, look at you.
I mean, knock on wood,
you're totally a snack.
You have this mysterious aura,
but that makes you even cooler somehow.
And when you laugh…
Yeah, right there.
You have that dimple over here.
That's pretty neat.
Well, enough chatting. Coffee?
With you pissing the florist off,
we should talk about the wedding.
What do you say?
Can we just
not talk about the wedding tonight?
Huh?
He even took his shower.
What did you do, Cemre?
- Take it.
- Come on, guys.
- I missed this. The three of us.
- A selfie?
- Don't tell the girls about it.
- We'll send it to them.
- There. Awesome.
- I'll send it to you.
So? How's it going?
Any movement?
How do you not remember the night at all?
I just don't.
It's all quiet. When will you get here?
We're on our way, babe.
It wouldn't help even if we teleported.
You can't hide from the guy.
For God's sake.
I mean, I didn't say I was going to hide.
- Right.
- Listen, Cemre.
Escaping that cool guy's strong arms
is a true test of will, girl.
If you can pull it off,
I'll give you a kiss when I'm there.
Oh, shut up.
Morning.
Leyla, you have to look.
- Leyla, you have to look!
- Oh my God!
What are you doing here, huh? What?
I'm getting coffee.
Why are you getting it topless?
Go put a shirt on. Shame on you.
Or just go home.
Well, that's not
what you were saying last night.
Oh, no! He's talking about last night.
- It was amazing.
- Don't touch me. Shut up.
- Damn it!
- All right. Calm down. I was just joking.
- Were you?
- Of course I was.
- Oh.
- I was home. Don't worry.
Good. Why did you take
a shower here, then?
Well, I had an incident with a rascal,
so I had to.
You're seriously acting suspicious.
My little girl.
- Your little girl?
- Yeah. She had pissed on me.
What else was I supposed to do?
What's up with you and your vibe morning?
You're acting like a homicide detective.
I'll leave if you don't want me here.
Hang on. Wait.
You have a little girl?
You should really see her sometime.
You'll fall in love with her.
She's so cuddly and all.
Yeah, I'm sure she is.
Why didn't you tell me before?
Tell you what? That I had a little girl?
- Yeah.
- Does it matter to you?
I would've told you first thing if I knew.
You know, when you fall into my arms.
Where's she?
She's probably strolling around.
Strolling around?
You left her?
What if she fell or got lost?
Oh, come on. Don't be negative.
I'm sure she's around.
"Come on"? What the heck?
You're a terrible dad.
Hey, kid! Where are you, kid?
What? "Kid"? That's rude.
You can't call her that.
Tell me her name, then.
- Little Girl.
- Little…
- "Little Girl"?
- Yeah.
Who names their kid "Little Girl"?
Me. Little Girl!
Little Girl!
Hey, Little Girl. Come here.
Come. Where are you going? Come on.
Come here. Come here, you.
Look how adorable she is.
Were you talking about a dog?
Please. She has a name. Little Girl.
I'll show you her name. Give her here.
For you.
For me?
Would you look at that cute face?
What a cutie-pie.
Good. You're not like your dad at all.
You never miss a chance
to taunt me. Bravo, Cemre.
Yeah, right. "Bravo, Cemre."
What a cute tiny baby.
Hey, Little Girl.
You're so adorable.
Oh, are you swimming in the air?
That's pretty much it.
We're childhood friends with Leyla.
Cool. I had Emir instead.
He started fights and ran away,
leaving me behind.
You used to fight?
There's a reason I have such strong arms.
All the beatings I endured.
You mean these things?
Let's check.
We never talked about their first dance.
Which song are we going with?
I have a few on my phone.
Let's see.
How about this?
Wow. They're flirting hard, aren't they?
"My cousin would never
try something with Cemre."
"He isn't interested in a relationship."
He's basically glued to her.
- Oh, come on.
- Don't be like that, Tuna.
What do you mean, "glued"?
What's so bad about it?
They're getting along.
Wow! Incoming kiss. Let's go.
- Let's not, please.
- I can't miss it.
- Why are we doing this?
- Come on.
- Oh! Hey, girls!
- Hello.
- Here we are.
- Welcome.
- Hey.
- Cousin.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
- What's up?
- Checking stuff.
Come here, you. Come.
- Get over here, you.
- Come on.
- Hey.
- Okay.
- Hi.
Hello.
I guess you're going to explain
what we just saw, Cemre.
We were just checking the song.
A little dance.
- That's it.
- Yeah? This started with that too.
Don't be like that.
Is everything set for tomorrow?
Yeah, babe. Everything's ready.
- What are you looking at?
- Just the decoration.
- Yeah?
- We did well.
- Are those muscles made of whey?
- What?
He's asking if you mean business.
- Don't be ridiculous...
- Hang on.
- What's going on between you two?
- Between us?
Yeah, between you two.
Just show me the table ornaments.
- We'll talk about this.
- Spill. Let's go.
Do you always
answer questions with questions?
Sorry. I didn't catch that.
What was the question?
Is this your actual height?
Any surgeries on the knee?
Jeez, guys. Stop with the dumb questions.
Let's just go carry our luggage.
We're going to get a heatstroke.
Hang on. Our lives are at stake here.
- What are you talking about?
- You know.
We don't get married as couples, man.
We do it as a group.
- Okay?
- As a group? Okay.
- What?
- What do you mean?
You brought up the right topic for once
but messed it up so badly. Jeez.
I'll explain. I got married ten days ago.
I haven't been able to level up.
That means as soon as
I start attacking on the right wing,
I hear the ref's whistle
and he decides to go to VAR.
Dude! What does that
have to do with anything?
I'm sorry, cousin.
Go discuss your issue with your wife.
This is not the place.
I'm really sorry, cousin.
Well done. It looks beautiful.
- We'll see how you'll do, Emir!
- It does, right?
We'll see you on the pitch
trying to attack and attack.
Don't worry about it, man.
"As a group"? Seriously?
What was I supposed to say?
You got what I meant.
- Teamwork.
- Yeah.
- Honey.
- Yeah, baby?
Grape, please.
- Here we go.
- You got it?
- Who wants some?
- Me.
Honey, try this.
How is it? You like it?
Easy. It's hot. Easy.
I approve.
- Another one?
- Here.
Thank you so much, Poyraz.
We've been a burden.
Don't mention it.
It was all Cemre anyway.
But if it weren't for you…
I mean, if it weren't for your help,
everything would be so difficult.
You had it all planned out anyway.
I just helped with the small stuff.
And you deserve the credit.
Well, I'll just go check the meat.
Hey, you. You two are so cute together.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Just leave.
- I was just being polite.
- Hey. I get it.
- Just go.
- All right, honey.
- You want anything?
- Leave.
How did you two meet?
Well, we met here.
You're a good guy.
You really are.
Come on. Of course he is.
It's in our genes. We're all good guys.
Cemre, talk.
What was that today?
- Cemre, you two were totally...
- Don't be ridiculous.
Be ridiculous, Leyla.
Girl, he's smoking hot.
You won't find anyone better,
I'm telling you.
Smoking hot? Him?
Also, he introduced his dog
like she was her daughter.
Who in their right mind
does something like that?
So you were up for it
if he had a daughter?
You're really running wild,
aren't you? Jeez.
Want some processed meat?
Hey.
Well, I'm off.
Guys, I should head home.
The wedding's tomorrow.
I'm sure you have things to do.
Enjoy the meat.
- See you.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
- Good night.
- Nice meeting you. Bye-bye.
- See you.
Should we believe our eyes and ears?
Tell us what's going on, Cemre.
Okay. I got carried away a bit.
Seriously, though. Tell us.
Listen, Cemre. Open your eyes already.
See, even Leyla
outperformed our expectations
and found someone. Kudos.
Wow. Tuna, thank you so much
for saying nice things about me
on this beautiful night, bro.
To be honest, I keep looking at her
trying to figure out
what I did to deserve this girl.
- I keep thinking and thinking.
- Oh, honey.
I still can't.
You keep thinking and thinking
yet can't figure it out.
- I can't.
- Yeah. Anyway.
Look. You obviously like him a lot, babe.
I can tell. You're smitten, even.
Fine. I admit Poyraz made me feel good,
but I spent eight years on Mete.
And that night…
I just want to call him and tell him off.
He didn't explain himself.
Didn't even call.
Well, Cemre, I'm kind of sleepy.
- I am. All right.
- Oh, wow. I ate a lot.
- Good night.
- Let's go.
Honey, the wedding's tomorrow.
I don't need bags under my eyes.
- There's so much meat.
- You can have them.
- You're going to bed? Come on.
- Yeah.
What? We're not hanging out?
- Nah.
- Huh?
- We'll talk later.
- Call me, okay?
- Kisses.
- Let's go.
- Good night.
- See you all.
- I'll be back, honey.
- Bye.
- Come.
- Let's go.
Let's just not tell her.
Just forget about it.
I wasn't even there.
Don't be ridiculous.
- No secrets. We took an oath.
- Jeez. Who cares about the oath?
We never keep our oaths.
She's so happy, you know.
Why tell her Mete called and stuff?
Let's just go.
- I agree.
- Me too.
- Go.
What just happened?
I have no idea.
I know my wife very well, guys.
She wouldn't give up the gossip
even if her water broke. Something's up.
- But what?
- No idea.
- Hey, Cemre.
- Yeah?
I might've called him a dumb-ass,
but Poyraz is a good guy.
- I figured him out at the grill.
- Well… Come on, man. Shame.
He's my cousin, after all.
Why did they leave?
How would I know?
Jeez. Would I ask you if I knew?
- God give me patience. Jeez.
- She's leaving too.
- Why is everyone on edge?
- Good night.
- Weird. I don't get it, man.
- What happened?
Seriously, man.
We were having a nice time.
The vibe was amazing.
Just when it was getting exciting…
You think this is exciting?
You want me to tell you
about the night Mete dumped Cemre?
- Now, that was exciting.
- Oh, right. What happened?
- Tell me.
- It was like a cup final.
- Yeah?
- So Mete showed up…
Put that in the back.
Nice.
- Morning, Suna. Hey, guys.
- Morning, Poyraz.
- Morning.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Last night was cool.
- After I left, did your friends...
- Hey.
Who are you anyway?
Why would my friends talk about you?
Cemre, you can at least look at me.
I mean, at least when we're talking.
Here. I'm looking.
What's up? You satisfied?
Fine. You're a bit tense.
I'll just bring you some coffee.
You'll have calmed down,
and we'll talk. All right?
I already had coffee.
Cemre, are you okay?
I mean, everything's fine, right?
- Jeez.
- Cemre?
Cemre.
What? What do you want?
Are you really okay?
If we could just talk...
What do we have to talk about?
You men are always the same.
You think the world revolves around you.
Jeez. This usually takes me just a minute.
It's like I have two left hands. Help me.
- Ozan.
- Let me.
- I swear I'm sick of this.
- Let me see. Hang on.
- Stand tall. There.
- There.
You look amazing, man.
What a beast of a groom!
Thanks, bro.
Don't get him too hyped up.
He's going to be us after the honeymoon.
No, man. Why would I be you?
What's wrong with us?
We love and respect our wives.
The golden rule is to obey.
That's the way.
Hey, cousin.
What's… What's wrong? You okay?
I'm fine. Nothing's wrong.
Look here, you.
I know that face by heart, man.
Cemre told him off.
Man, everything was nice between us
before you guys showed up.
Now she's avoiding me.
She won't even look at me.
Sounds like she was poisoned.
I bet she talked to the girls.
Dude, what could the girls
possibly have said?
Look, cousin.
If you really like her that much,
just go tell her.
Bang, bang, bang. What's the big deal?
She wouldn't even look at me.
Are you not listening to me?
Well, okay. Here's what we're going to do.
Emir has a poem he wrote for Leyla.
Just read it to Cemre,
and everything will be fine.
- A poem?
- Right.
- Since when you're a poet?
- Yeah.
I just wrote the one for Leyla.
You'll just change the name.
Just hear it out. It's a nice poem.
Leyla, I fell for you
An autumn night it was
Oh, how I fell for you
Your hair shone like wheat under the sun
Your eyes bluer than the ocean
- Keep going.
- Leyla, Leyla…
It's not finished yet. I'm working on it.
- Bravo!
- Amazing.
A poem dedicated to Leyla
and the fertile soil of Anatolia.
What are you talking about?
A poem? Anatolia?
You guys have lost it.
Did I hurt her feelings somehow?
I mean, why is she mad?
No. Man, you're forgetting something.
We don't have to do anything
for them to get mad at us.
See, breathing alone is enough.
Just go look her in the eye
and tell her you care.
Be bold. Be assertive.
Don't be reciting poems
like this dumb-ass, okay?
What do you guys know about art, anyway?
She wants me to care. Of course.
The necklace.
- Does it look okay?
- Yeah.
- What's up? What did you do?
- I cracked the case.
Oh, yeah? Nice.
Hey, listen.
Do I need a boutonniere or something?
Hey, Leyla.
- Is your makeup done?
- Nope.
- You're going to be late.
- We'll be fine.
You look stunning.
Hey, Sinem. Hand me the water, will you?
Where's Tuna?
What…
I saw my brother-in-law off.
- Which one?
- You're right.
I have so many brothers-in-law now
I get them confused.
Well, not that husbands don't go anywhere.
I meant the new one. Poyraz.
Where did he go?
That's a mystery you're responsible for.
He looked so crushed
because of whatever you said to him.
He was punching trees
with his strong arms and all.
He also told me
he loved me very much as he left.
A small detail.
What did you say to him?
Handsome, educated, well-mannered…
- Understanding.
- Successful.
Jeez. You don't even know
how old he is or what he does.
Electrical engineer, 30 years old, single.
Listen. Whatever you said broke his heart.
I didn't say anything!
He was all like, "We need to talk."
I already know how that movie ends.
No, Cemre. You're confused, honey.
Now, in your movie, the protagonist
was a slimy guy named Mete.
This is a totally different movie
with a different guy.
Yeah, exactly.
Plus, there's a big difference
between the guy
who tossed your spare tire out
and the guy who got your car fixed.
Between the guy who didn't leave your side
even though you cracked his head open
and the guy who told you
to renew your bus pass
because gas prices were rising.
Also, what role does Poyraz play
that you don't want to watch it again?
I love new movies.
Well, I'm glad he left.
Leave me alone. It's for the better.
- I don't need him annoying me.
- Yeah, right.
Oh, honey.
Your hair looks awful, Sinem. Come here.
We need to fix it. No time.
Look who's there.
Give me a minute.
- Huh? What's going on?
- Oh my. Girl.
- Poyraz is here.
- He's here.
I thought you weren't coming.
- Why?
- Because you told Tuna you weren't.
I didn't.
- I told him I was going to get something.
- Get what?
This.
I think you were looking for it.
I was going to give it to you earlier...
It's the last thing I have
that was Mom's. Thank you.
- Shall I put it on?
- Sure.
There. Here we go.
Done.
- Everything turned out amazing.
- Thanks to you.
And I'm sorry.
Why?
I took it all out on you.
I was way too harsh.
I enjoyed it. Every second of it.
Cemre?
Mete?
You blocked me on everything?
I've been trying to reach you.
I called Tuna too.
He answered but never talked.
- What? Girl, it's Mete.
- Mete's here.
- What? What's he doing here?
- Who knows?
- Vermin.
- Filth.
Dude, do you have anything
to do with this?
Why would I? He just showed up.
I swear Melis will tear you a new one.
No, I had no idea. He just…
Weird. Anyway.
Finally, I tried Sinan
and he told me you'd be here.
Why are you here?
Are you seriously hearing him out?
I left my diving gear with you.
You know that stuff is expensive.
I haven't slept in days.
I'm scared you'll throw them away
out of spite.
When can I get it?
What?
My diving gear, Cemre.
You didn't throw them out, right?
Your diving gear?
Yes. It's expensive stuff.
I hope you still have them.
Diving, huh?
- What is he going to do?
- Jeez.
I spend eight whole years,
and you're here
asking for your diving gear?
- I just wanted to talk.
- Just leave. Jeez.
I will. When are you coming?
I don't know. Maybe I will, maybe I won't.
I owe someone coffee.
Let's go.
Where are you going?
Oh, fuck off.
- They're holding hands.
- They are.
He went for it.
- You were holding hands.
- Honey.
Unbelievable!
My new brother-in-law!
Ms. Leyla Özay, do you,
by your own free will
and under no one's pressure,
take Mr. Emir Ergin
to be your wedded husband?
No!
- What?
- It's coming!
- Jeez…
- Sinan!
- Honey?
- I hope you're just peeing!
- Pick her up! She's in labor!
- All right.
- Let's just...
- It's all right, honey.
Hey, come here.
- You all stay here.
- Let's get the van.
- We'll bring it around.
- Go! Pick her up!
We need to sign...
- She's in labor.
- Careful.
- Let's think about the baby stuff.
- What did you get for it?
- Let's go, people!
- I'll drive.
- Okay.
Let's go.
- The baby's coming!
- Bring the van!
- Do you have a crib?
- All right.
- Clear the way. Go.
- Come on, people.
Here we go.
- I'm in labor!
- All right.
Come on. Drive safely.
- Come on.
- Hey.
- Keep it coming. Come on.
- Damn it, Sinan!
- Is everyone here?
- Yes!
Let's go, baby.
Let's go!