- [ Microphone Feedback ]
- [ Woman ] Ouch. Shit.
- [ Man ] Turn that down, Bitsy.
- [ Bitsy ] Sorry.
[ Woman ] Wardell, do you think
God killed Peggy as a punishment...
for having that affair with G. W.?
- You know I don't believe
in that shit, Juanita.
- [ Bitsy ] Testing.
- Can y'all hear me?
- [ Wardell ] We sure can, Bitsy.
[Juanita ]
Bitsy, have you ever had an affair...
with anybody with missing limbs
or anything?
Not that I can remember, Juanita.
I once had an affair
with a man with only one testicle.
[ singing: And who's a sinner ]
You're my 27th therapist
in the last three years.
[ singing: Lord, it's tough enough
to trudge from brunch to dinner ]
I'm from the South.
Uh, Texas, actually.
[ singing: We seek the light of truth ]
[ singing: Between our white lies ]
I was raised rigid Southern Baptist,
I'm an actor, and I'm gay.
[ singing: We sleep away our youth
under tattletale skies ]
[ singing: Who's a sinner and who's a saint ]
[ singing: Who's to say who you can love ]
[ singing: And who you can't ]
[ singing: Now it's easy for the pot
to call the kettle black ]
[ singing: They're just jealous of the hot
and lusty, sordid lives they led ]
[ singing: Ain't it a bitch
sorting out our sordid lives ]
[ singing: It's a bitch
when you come to realize ]
[ singing: Crack yourself a box
of CrackerJacks ]
[ singing: You can get a really shitty prize ]
[ singing: It's a bitch
sorting out our sordid lives ]
[ singing: Now there's trouble
coming down the chute ]
[ singing: To take our first breath ]
[ singing: And we struggle for acceptance
from birth to death ]
[ singing: But the Lord's too busy
trying to keep the world on its feet ]
[ singing: He ain't got time to give a damn
about what goes on between the sheets ]
[ singing: Ain't it a bitch ]
[ singing: Sorting out our sordid lives ]
[ singing: It's a bitch
when you come to realize ]
[ singing: Crack yourself a box
of CrackerJack ]
[ singing: You can get a really shitty prize ]
[ singing: It's a bitch sorting out
our sorry, little ]
[ singing: Sordid lives ]
- ] Oh, yeah ] ]
- [ Clapping ]
- That's real good, Bitsy.
- Thank you, Juanita.
When I was a kid, I was fat.
[ Horn Honking ]
A fat boy.
[ Sighs ]
Waddle-butt.
That's what the other kids
used to call me.
I just wish they could see
my ass today, 'cause I've worked
really hard on my ass, you know?
[ Sighs ]
Anyway.
One year--
I think I was in the fifth grade--
my mama took me shopping
for school clothes...
and I had gotten fatter.
I had to try on jeans.
Well, the only ones that would fit
were the husky ones, you know?
They had that label on the back
that said ""Husky.''
It was kind of announced
to everyone behind me I was a husky.
I started crying.
I didn't want everybody
to know I was a husky.
And my mama...
sat me down right there in Sears
and told me no one else had to know.
Just me and her.
It was our little secret.
So, she bought the Husky jeans.
She took 'em home.
And then she went to the Goodwill,
and she bought some used jeans.
Well, she took the label
off the Husky jeans
and sewed on the ""Slim'' label...
from the Goodwill ones.
Slim. Shit.
Like I could pull that off.
It's just the kind of mama
she was though.
Never made me feel bad
about being fat. She--
She always just made it okay.
And I've always thought that
that is unconditional love, and--
Well, maybe if I told her
I was gay, it'd--
you know, it'd apply.
And this other thought
just keeps running through my head:
She'd just try and change the labels...
from gay to straight.
I tried to do that for years.
I love your new song. You gonna
sing it at the dance on Saturday?
That's the plan.
- See you boys in the funny papers.
- All right.
I just can't get Peggy
off of my mind, Wardell.
- That's some serious-ass shit
you've been through, G.W.
- I'm in agony.
- Yeah, I can tell.
- I remember it so vividly.
We met at the Bonanza over in Abilene,
had us a nice steak supper.
She followed me back to the motel.
Jacob's ladder.
Witch's hat.
You do Jacob's ladder, then witch's hat.
Two tricks in one.
Well, one trick,
and then you do another by just
pulling the string with your teeth.
You have too much time
on your hands, Odell.
- Ain't that somethin'?
- You know what I can't
get off of my mind?
- Oh, here we go again.
- I can't get that...
- pig-bloating incident off my mind.
- What?
Please, G. W., if I have to hear
that goddamn pig story again...
- I think I'll just shit.
- All happened at the Tyler County Fair.
I guess now's a good a time as any.
Was that steak tender,
the one you ate that night Peggy died?
Thank you, hon!
I'll see you at the funeral!
Well, I'll tell you one thing...
I sure as hell wouldn't have
quit smoking if I had known
my sister was going to die.
Three days now.
I am about to die myself.
H-H-Hold on.
Ouch. Oh, Lord.
Huh? Oh, nothing.
Well, if you must know,
it's a little quit-smoking therapy...
that Roger over at the Beehive
shared with me while he was
back-combing my hair.
He paid $2,000 at this clinic
over in Snyder...
and they give him a rubber band--
told him to pop his arm with it
every time he wanted a cigarette.
It's called, uh...
behavior modifi-something another.
Roger can tell ya the exact wordage.
Anyway, it ain't workin'.
See, I go down to Tyler every year
for the county fair. Broom.
Oh, I just love all them animals
and them displays of macramé...
and the cooking competition and all.
Besides, it gives me a chance
to see me and Wardell's sister.
I once made a rooster out of beans
and lentils when I was a girl...
in vacation Bible school.
- It's almost lifelike.
- Uh-huh.
- How is old Mozelle?
- Oh, she's fine.
Me and Mozelle, we had us
some good times once upon a time.
You know, her and Darrel
have had a bunch of marital problems.
He beat her up a few times.
Tepee.
Mama hung old Cockadoodle
in the kitchen.
That's what I called him.
""Cockadoodle.''
- That's amazing.
- But, uh, boll weevils
started eating them beans.
- And that was all she wrote.
- That's amazing.
- You know, any man who hits
a woman is no man at all.
- You got that right.
- Darrel's in group therapy
for abusive husbands now.
- Oh.
A bunch of wife-beaters
gets together once a week with
this specialist, and they purge.
Some of them
are deadbeat dads too.
Used to be two groups.
One for wife-beaters
and one for deadbeat dads.
But so many of them crossed over
from one group to the next,
they just merged.
Hey. They merged and they purged.
[ Chuckles ]
I've seen boll weevils in flour...
in, uh, oatmeal and parik-- paprika...
but never on a rooster
you made in vacation Bible school.
I probably should have married Mozelle
instead of Noleta...
and then I wouldn't have been
compelled to fool around...
and Peggy would still be alive.
Well, it's just somewhat awkward
when your neighbor's husband
kills your sister.
[ Gasps ]
Oh, Noleta has emerged.
- [ Yelling ]
- She's throwing all of G. W.'s stuff
out in the yard.
Goddamn sorry, cheating
son of a bitch!
Oh, Lord have mercy on my soul.
- There goes the TV.
- [ Yelling, Cheering ]
Life is one big, ol' pile of shit,
Odell.
You know, G.W.,
no offence now, but, uh...
you're starting to get on my nerves.
I mean, get off the cross, buddy.
We need the wood.
[ Laughs ]
- That was a joke, G.W.
- [ Laughing ]
You know,
to try and lift your spirits.
My God. My God.
- Woo-hoo.
Woo-hoo.
Come on in, Noleta.
Thanks, Sissy.
I brung you this. It's, uh--
It's my mama's tuna casserole.
You know, the one I always make
with the Lay's potato chips
and the Cream of Mushroom soup.
Well, that is mighty nice of you...
given the circumstances and all.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
Oh, Sissy.
- Oh.
- [ Sobbing ] I don't know what to do.
Everybody's laughing at me, Sissy.
G.W.'s made a complete fool out of me.
- Can I bum a cigarette, please?
- Oh, hon, I quit three days ago.
- Threw 'em all out.
- [ Sobbing ]
Why don't you sit down...
and I'll make you
a nice glass of ice tea.
There you go.
- Would you like a Valium?
- Uh-huh.
[ Dog Barking In Distance ]
I know this has to be
awkward for you, Sissy.
I mean, my husband
killed your sister with his, um--
I threw him out.
I threw his sorry ass out, Sissy.
Threw all his stuff
out on the lawn.
If he don't get it by tonight,
I'm gonna have a yard sale.
- But what am I gonna do now?
- Oh, hon.
I mean, I have no skills.
I'm just a mama and a wife.
What the hell
am I supposed to do now?
- Aw.
- [ Sobbing ]
[ Whimpering ]
- [ Crying ]
- Aw.
Ouch.
[ Whimpering ]
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't be telling you this.
- Should I take one or two of these?
- I'd take two if I was you.
And you'll feel a lot better
when those kick in.
And you can tell me
anything you want, Noleta.
I feel for you. I do.
This whole thing
is just one, big, unfortunate mess.
Cup and saucer or a pocketbook.
Two tricks in one.
- Didn't even use my teeth.
- What happened to the pig, Odell?
- The other white meat.
- I'm getting to that, G. W.
I had to go to the can real bad,
on account of the fact
I had one of them corny dogs.
I got real thirsty. I bought
one of them big, old jumbo sodas
to wash it down with.
- So I headed right on down
to them porta-potties.
- And I strongly believe...
that mama just didn't like
old Cockadoodle...
and she made up
that boll weevil shit...
because I sure the hell
never saw no goddamn bugs.
I'm in hell.
Today I was at the Shamrock,
filling up--
I needed one more full tank
for a complete set of them
Dallas Cowboy mugs--
I'm gonna get you
a little refill.
And that trashy thing,
Lynette Walters, was there.
Well, she was there
talking to her friend...
that Gloria Other-piece-of-trash,
old man Holmes's youngest girl...
the one with them
two illegitimate mulatto kids...
and they were staring at me, pointin',
talking all hush-hush.
Those two, all skinny
in their tube tops and short shorts...
like I was some kind of circus freak
or somethin'.
Those two, Sissy, of all people,
like they was better than me.
- Well, they're not.
- Well, I just went up to her window...
threw down a 20,
didn't wait for my change
or my Dallas Cowboy mug, and left.
- Good.
- Drove down Highway 84...
sobbing to high heaven,
going nowhere.
Finally had to pull over
'cause I couldn't see the road no more.
Aw, hon.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't be telling you
all this, giving you troubles.
You've got enough on your mind.
- Well, I gotta go, Sissy.
- So soon?
The kids get out of school at 3:00,
and I gotta explain to 'em about G.W.
I am so sorry about Peggy.
She was a really good woman,
in spite of--
- Tell LaVonda to call me.
- I will.
And those Valium ought to kick in
any minute. Oh, here.
Take these with ya.
I got another bottle.
- Oh, thank you.
- Aw.
Bye-bye, hon.
Thanks for the casserole.
Now you hold
your head up high, ya hear?
- I'll try.
- I mean it.
[ Crying ]
Oh, shit.
Ouch.
And as I rounded a corner,
these kids was a-holdin'
down that pig...
while they was
a-stickin' a garden hose
down that poor pig's throat...
trying to get it to gain weight
right quick like to qualify.
All for the sake of a durn blue ribbon.
Oh, those dang kids. They all looked
like juvenile delinquents to me...
squattin' that pig down there,
shovin' that hose down his poor throat.
Well, she's just gone crazy
over this whole ordeal.
Who wouldn't?
Uh-uh. No, no. Uh-uh.
No. No, no, no.
No, ma'am.
No, sirree. No.
I don't believe Brother Boy
is mentally stable enough
to come to the funeral.
The last time I seen him,
he thought he was Tammy Wynette.
Had on a real pretty wig
and a sequin pantsuit though.
And if you'd squint your eyes
and kept a good distance away...
he looked just like Tammy...
in the early years.
Lord, Lord, Lord. Sometimes
I just can't hardly stand it...
thinking about him
all cooped up like that.
Poor Brother Boy.
But at least he is someplace safe...
where he will not be ridiculed.
Hey, faggot.
What happened to your hair?
You crazy, cock-suckin',
motherfuckin' faggot.
I'm talking to you.
I can see your pussy.
- [ Horn Honks ]
- Oh, I gotta git.
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- That is Latrelle.
Oh, she does not look happy.
- Her and LaVonda have
been arguing all morning long.
- Sissy!
- I just refuse to referee anymore.
Thank you.
I-I need those prayers.
Prayers mean so much.
I'll see you at the funeral.
I gotta go. Bye-bye.
- [ Panting ] Ouch.
- [ Footsteps ]
Sissy!
Oh, well. You're just never gonna
believe what she's done now.
- [ Object Thuds On Floor ]
- You just won't.
- What did she do?
- LaVonda wants to bury Mama...
- in that ugly mink stole
with the head still on it.
- Well--
I know Mama loved that stole,
but, good Lord, Sissy.
- It's 1 08 degrees out.
- Well, I--
No person should be wearing a mink stole
in the middle of summer.
- Well, she was--
- It's not appropriate.
-Well, I--
-It's not right, and I will not have it!
- And I hope you'll support me on this.
- Well, I--
I will not have her
making a mockery of my mama
at her one and only funeral.
It's just not gonna happen.
Lord, it's hot in here.
Your air conditioner working?
Well, yeah, but when it gets like this,
it just don't seem to help a lick.
Probably needs Freon.
Well, I never did like
Sister's mink stole noways.
Gave me the heebie-jeebies
with them glass eyes staring out at ya.
-Of course, she was awful partial to it.
-I know it.
But it's summer, Sissy.
Hot, hot summer. Oh, thank you.
I knew you'd back me on this,
I did. But you know how she is.
- She won't listen to me. Gotta tiddle.
- Well, I--
Thank you.
Ouch.
I'm sorry, G.W., but the vision...
of that poor, pitiful pig's
anguished face--it haunts me.
[ Wardell ]
Don't tell me you ain't finished.
- I got sidetracked.
- No.
Hey, do you all think I'm pretty?
Then that poor, old pig fell over,
started rollin' around, convulsing.
And then it just laid down
and-- and--
And died! The damn pig died.
Done. Finished. Kaput.
-End of story.
-Didn't even get to compete in the fair.
- Well, ain't that too damn bad?
- Yeah.
I guess life can go on, huh, G.W.?
Except for the pig's.
Except of the pig's!
Goddamn.
Oh, that's a good un. Shit.
- But it ain't funny!
- Yeah it is.
This is the first time G.W.'s laughed
since Peggy died.
Shit.
Well, I tell you, Latrelle--
Now, you know I never
say nothing bad about my sister--
She was like a second mama to me,
being so much older and all.
But, honey, she just sort of
went a little crazy towards the end...
after your daddy died.
Just kind of cut loose.
- Started honky-tonking.
- Honky-tonking?
Honky-tonking out at Bubba's
almost every night.
Her best friend toward the end
was Bitsy Mae Harling.
Bitsy Mae Harling
who used to date blacks in high school?
The one and the same.
She's been singing
on the weekends out at Bubba's
since she got out of jail.
- Said she was framed. [ Laughs ]
- Prison trash.
[ Coughing ]
- [ Coughing Continues ]
- That's a cigarette cough.
- No shit.
- You're gonna die of lung cancer
just like Aunt Bertha did.
You mark my word.
Lord, that was an awful death.
She suffered so.
Well, for your information,
Miss Smarty Britches,
I quit smokin' three days ago.
We'll see how long it lasts.
Besides, the damage
you've done to your lungs
is most likely irreparable.
I read all about it in a magazine
at the doctor's office.
Bitsy Mae Harling and Mama.
Yes, ma'am. Then the last couple
of months she started carrying
on with G.W. Nethercott.
- Shit.
- Listen, buddy. I know how you feel.
I still have nightmares
over that pig myself.
I don't give a shit about that filthy,
dirty, slop-eatin', mud-wallerin' pig!
I have killed a woman!
By irresponsibly leaving my legs
in the middle of the motel room...
after making long, passionate love
with the woman of my dreams.
You'll get over that pig, Odell.
I ain't ever gonna
get over killing Peggy.
G.W., take it easy on yourself, buddy.
She tripped on your legs
on the way to the bathroom.
It was an accident.
It's not your fault. It could
have happened to anybody.
- You mean anybody with two wooden legs.
- Shut up.
- Well, they are, Wardell.
- Shit.
I want to remember Mama
the way I want to remember her.
Not shacked up in a motel
with a seedy lowlife
with two wooden legs.
Ooh, apple pie.
- Do you want a piece?
- No, not right now.
Maybe in a little while.
How's Ty?
Is he still out in Los Angeles?
Uh-huh. Too busy to come to
his one and only grandmother's funeral.
My grandmother died yesterday...
and I do not want to
go back down to the funeral.
Maybe that's why I'm here.
I just can't be who I am down there.
At least here I can choose to be
in the places where I can be who I am.
Down there I'll have to butch it up.
I just get so tired of butching it up.
I mean, not that
I'm a big, old girl or anything...
but, you know, it's Texas.
Rednecks.
For the life of me,
I never understood that boy.
Mmm, this pie is good.
- Who made this?
- Evelyn Crawley.
Oh, maybe
I will have a little piece after all.
I swear, I'm gonna get
as big as Vera Lisso
without my nicotine.
Oh, my Lord.
I saw Vera today.
I stopped by the Corner Stop
to get a cold drink.
I had a craving for something sweet.
- My Lord, she's gotten big.
- You could move in.
Well, I almost didn't recognize her.
Do you know that she can't even
stand up behind that cash register
no more?
They had to put in a bar stool
for her to sit on.
And Leticia Bustamante,
that sweet, little Mexican girl
that stocks the shelves...
told me that Tom Ed had to
reinforce that stool with lug nuts.
I swear!
Oh, Vera's
so sweet though.
She used to always slip me
a few extra Green Stamps.
And she never bothers to look
at the expiration date on my coupons.
She's my best friend.
But why on God's green Earth would
anyone let themselves get that big?
Well, she says it's glandular.
[ Laughs ]
Glandular.
Oh! Oh, I saw Ty's Alpo commercial...
the one where the dog licks his face.
Ooh, that is real cute.
He is so good-lookin'.
- Y'all must be proud.
- Well, we're not.
When I got off the soap,
I rebelled...
and started seeking out gay roles.
I was always so scared to play gay.
Scared someone would...
you know, suspect.
After he got off the soap opera,
he started doing theater, Sissy.
Awful. Awful stuff.
I got this play
in this tiny, little theater
known for doing gay plays.
Male nudity, the works.
Every night the theater
was just packed. It was just
one big, old homo hoedown.
He calls it art.
I call it trash.
Did this one play--
begged me and Wilson to come out
to Los Angeles and see him in it.
Well, I was just dying
to see Bernadette Peters
in Annie Get Your Gun.
So I talked Wilson
into going out there.
The play was called--
Oh, I forget the name.
Some musical term.
Allegro. Allegre.
- Crescendo?
- No.
Whatever it was,
it had nothing whatsoever
to do with the subject matter.
And I invited my parents...
Latrelle and Wilson.
Oh, God.
What was I thinking?
Anyhow, the play
was going along all nice-like.
And, all of a sudden, my son...
walks out on the stage... naked.
- Buck naked, Sissy.
- Oh, sweetJesus. Naked?
And you could see everything.
His tallywhacker?
[ Sighs ]
Everything.
[ singing: [ New Age ]
[ Ty ]
It was the single, bravest
moment of my life though.
Came out on the stage
completely, balls-out naked.
Hidin'nothin
Nothin
[ singing: [ Continues ]
[ Latrelle ]
Then, all of a sudden,
these other boys...
start parading out naked too.
And they start touching each other...
sexual-like.
I mean, there was dim lighting and all,
but the provocative movements...
the illusion was complete,
thank you very much.
And he was playing a homosexual.
[ Ty ]
I had come out to my parents.
Or so I thought.
[ Latrelle ]
Wilson walked out early on.
I just looked down at my lap
till it was over.
I have never been so humiliated
in all my life.
Oh, and you know what
he had the audacity to do?
Came up to us after and said...
""So, what did you think?''
What did I think?
What was I supposed to think?
I just stared at him
with my mouth open.
And then he said,
""Okay. Let's go get some dinner.''
All through dinner
we just talked about nothin'.
Absolutely nothin'.
Wilson said we're not ever
going back to Los Angeles.
Said it was worse than Dallas.
I raised him better than that, Sissy.
I did. Oh, and on top of everything...
when we went to see Annie Get Your Gun
the next night...
Bernadette Peters had lost her voice.
And this other girl
that I never heard of in my life
did the role of Annie Oakley...
who they said had once had a part
in The Bold and the Beautiful...
but I certainly didn't remember her.
The entire trip was one big bust.
Well, that's too bad.
[ Typing ]
- [ Whispers ] Oh, shit.
- Ty.
Sara? Hi. Um--
- I didn't see you there.
- Liar.
[ Phone Rings ]
So, what are you doing here?
Getting my head shrunk.
You think you're the only one
who's screwed up?
Well, I'm coming back in two hours,
double session. So I win.
How long have you been coming here?
This is my first session.
You know,
I hop around with these guys.
Yeah. Yeah.
I remember.
Maybe you ought to explore that,
you know, see what it's about.
I've been coming here
about six months now.
She's great.
So, um, how you been?
W-W-What have you been up to?
Oh, you know, same old, same old.
Auditions, struggling, waiting tables.
You know,
after you kicked me to the curb...
and broke my heart
into a million pieces...
I just started doing anything I could.
I have finally finished my musical.
Yeah. I'm showcasing it
over at Theater/Theater.
Well, that's great.
[ Phone Ringing ]
- You're angry.
- Look, I am not angry, okay?
- I know. Sara, I'm sorry.
- No. I mean, I am so over it.
You said you'd call, keep in touch.
You didn't.
- Sara, I--
- Didn't return my calls.
So I just put you in my--
in my loser/flake file.
[ Bell Dings ]
I'm sorry.
Dr. Applegate keeps telling me
to get in touch with my real feelings...
and to tell the truth
to myself and other people.
So, that's what I'm doing lately.
Maybe she can help you do the same.
But after that trip, I called him,
and I told him:
"If you're gonna play a homosexual,
don't waste it on theater.
""Win an Academy Award,
for God's sake, like...
""that famous actor
in that Spider Woman movie...
""or Tom Hanks in that other thing
that I didn't particularly care for.
- But don't waste it on--'"
- [ Woman ] Noleta.
That's LaVonda.
- Morning, Miss Hinkle.
- Oh, hi.
Oh, Lord. Noleta!
You're gonna back me
on this mink stole thing.
- Well--
- Thank you.
- [ LaVonda ] It's me.
- [ Pounding On Noleta's Door ]
I can't believe how she dresses.
[ Latrelle ]
In public.
- Getting an eyeful, honey?
- Struttin'like a bally rooster.
[ Door Chimes Jingle ]
-Well?
-Well, what, Latrelle? Oh, hello, Sissy.
- How you doing, shug?
- I'm fine.
- Where's the stole, LaVonda?
- On Mama, where it belongs.
Ooh-ee, look at all this food.
You're just doing this out of spite,
LaVonda Jane.
Mama's gonna look like a fool
wearing that fur in all this heat.
Noleta came by and brought
a tuna casserole, and I refrigerated it.
She's real worried how this is gonna
affect y'all's friendship.
She kicked G.W. out,
and I gave her some Valium.
- That's sweet.
- You mean it's true?
Of course it's true.
There's a police record
on it and everything.
Why wouldn't you think it was true?
This ain't gonna affect our friendship.
Well, I told her that,
but she's real worried.
- You ought to go see her.
- I can't believe it.
- Did they arrest G.W.?
- For what? Leaving two wooden legs
in the wrong place?
No. They just had to investigate,
you know...
given the circumstances and all.
I read the coroner's report.
Mama hit her head on the sink...
and the blow caused her brain
to be flooded with blood.
- She internally hemorrhaged to death.
- Oh.
Subdural hematoma
is what they called it.
- Oh.
- [ Sissy ] Bless her heart.
They say she never suffered.
I just think Sister felt cooped up
all those years with your daddy.
You know how he was.
- She just, you know, had needs.
- Needs?
Yes, needs, Latrelle.
Some of us have needs.
It's run in this family.
Although, I'm quite convinced
it must have skipped a gene or something
when you was born.
- [ LaVonda Chuckles ]
- I have needs too, I'll have you know.
I just don't make mine public.
Well, I don't recall any of mine
being made in a public place, Latrelle.
Unfortunately, I can't say the same.
- You are awful.
- Guilty.
- [ Both Laughing ]
- Our one and only mama has died...
by tripping over two wooden legs
and hitting her head on the sink
in a seedy motel room...
where she was committing adultery,
and y'all are laughing.!
I don't think it's funny.!
Oh, Latrelle.
No! Leave me alone.
I thought you were gonna
back me on this.
Well, I'm sorry, hon...
but I believe all these decisions
ought to be made by Sister's kids.
I just decided that--just decided it
right this very minute on the spot.
Fine.
Well then, I should be in charge,
and I should make all major decisions.
Bullshit.
We should all get an equal vote.
Sissy, you ought to get a vote too.
- You've always been more like
a sister to us than an aunt.
- I don't really want a vote.
And Brother Boy should get a vote.
Of course, it's hard to vote
when you're locked up in a loony bin.
- Can't argue with that.
- Would you stop?
I have enough on my mind
without you bringing up Brother Boy.
[ Woman ]
Hmm, dead. Got out. Don't know how.
- Dead.
- Faggot.
Shoo, Bumper!
Lord!
Just ignore him, honey.
I know I do.
- [ Buzzer Buzzes ]
- [ Woman ] Send him in please, Ethel.
Yes, ma'am.
It'll all turn out, sweetie.
Oh.
Well, I did it.
I walked right down that hall
without my hair on.
I feel naked but I did it.
How are you, Dr. Eve?
Oh, good for you, Earl.
Oh, I'm fine. Sit, please.
That mean security guard Bumper
was catcalling at me...
but I did exactly
what you assigned me to do.
I came in here with one less item
of female attire.
That is if you can
count a wig as attire.
Good for you.
I am so proud of you.
Well, thank you.
I washed and set this an hour
before my appointment.
So I'd have just enough time
to dry it up under my portable...
but I would not have time
to finish fixing it.
So I'd have to
bring it here to my session
to put the finishing touches on it...
beings as I got a show
after this in the rec room.
Can't disappoint my fans.
They're crazy, but they're loyal.
- [ Chuckles ]
- They're always there.
Maybe that's because they're locked up
and don't have anywhere else to go.
- That was a joke.
- Okay.
I caught your last show.
Woo!
That was a little bit out of control.
Usually I perform after
the patients have been medicated.
If you'd talk to NurseJackson,
tell her that was a much better system,
I'd sure appreciate it.
I'll see what I can do.
This is a big step, Earl.
Very big.
You coming in without the wig on,
I believe we have made some progress.
I gotta tell ya, I feel a little bit
like a whore in church.
You look a little bit like one too.
That was just another little joke.
- [ Zipper Unzips ]
- Okay.
- No offense.
- None taken. Listen, Dr. Eve...
how long is this gonna take?
- It's a regular session,
about 45 minutes.
- No, no, no.
This whole
dehomosexualization thing.
Because it just seems to be
going at a very slow pace.
Well, Earl,you really haven't been
participating in your own recovery.
- I don't have a magic wand.
- I do.
In a drawer back in my room somewhere.
I got it when I was little.
- I used to pretend that
I was Glinda the Good Witch.
- Earl!
- What?
- Could we please just
stay with our session this time?
So sorry.
But, you know, Dr. Eve...
I resent-- I resent you saying that I am
not participating in my own recovery.
I walked right down that hall
without my hair on.
Came in here looking like
something the cat drug in.
Yes, I know.
And that's good, but, Earl...
in three months, 68 sessions,
this is your very first effort.
Well, I don't like to rush into things.
And in my own defense, you did say
I have a severe case of homosexuality.
It's one of the worst I've ever seen.
And with the transvestism--
well, it's very, very complicated.
-Well, I am well aware of that, Dr. Eve.
-Now...
did you try my masturbation exercises?
- Yes I did.
- How did that go?
Well, I--
I did exactly what you
asked me to do.
I started masturbatin'
by fantasizing about a man.
- I thought about
Wardell from back home.
- Of course you did.
Then I switched to a woman.
Good. Good.
Well, at first I--
I couldn't decide who to use.
I thought about using Tammy Wynette,
but, oh, that did not seem right.
I mean, you know,
with her gone, it just--
it's evil and wrong.
Well, Earl, fantasies are very healthy.
Well, not with dead people.
But there doesn't have to be
anything evil or wrong about sex.
Well, that's not what
my mama told me, missy.
I miss my mama.
Um--
I haven't seen Mama in six months...
and four whole days.
My sister LaVonda's been
coming out here to see me.
I know. We've had several
conversations, and we need to
talk about your mama, but not...
- till the end of the session.
- My sister LaVonda's wanting
to get me out of here.
- I know that,
but you're not ready yet.
- When will I be ready?
I've been here for 23 years.
Brother Boy thought he was
Tammy Wynette the last time I seen him.
- About a year ago.
- Before that it was Loretta.
Didn't he used to do Kitty Wells too,
way back when?
Oh, my God.
I had forgotten about that.
""It Wasn't God Who Made
Honky Tonk Angels.''
- [ Laughs ] That is a good song.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, somebody ought to redo that.
I believe that Trisha Yearwood could
just sing the shit out of that song.
- You eat with that mouth too?
- Mostly.
Loretta was always my favorite though.
I swear, in that getup
and that big, ol' white gown...
Brother Boy was her spittin' image.
You know, Sissy Spacek could not
hold a candle to Brother Boy's Loretta.
Mm-mmm.
No. She could not.
When he'd pretend to sing along
to those records, you almost forgot.
Lord, he could tear up
""You Ain't Woman Enough
(To Take My Man).''
- Woo-hoo.
- I gotta tell you...
about the only thing
that has kept me sane...
has been my career.
My country queens.
Kitty and Loretta.
Then Tammy came along.
Lord, I felt like
I had found my soul mate.
I followed her rise
all the way to the top.
She had such a rough life.
Oh. Illness after illness
and financial woes.
And George Jones was a drunk.
Mm. Tortured genius.
- Earl.
- Then they exhumed her.
- Earl.!
- What ever happened to ""rest in peace''?
Just dug her up.
Earl, please!
- You always do this.
- Oh.
You get extremely sidetracked
in our sessions, and I truly believe...
it's so you won't
have to face the truth.
You are living your life
vicariously through Tammy Wynette...
- and that is just not healthy.
- Well, somebody has got to
carry on the legacy.
Now that--
Now that she's gone.
Earl, you've been doing this
for over 20 years.
What was your excuse before she died?
My mind's a blank.
Well, it has to stop.
It's just not healthy.
It gets me through this hell.
All right?
Locked up here with a bunch
of Looney Tunes like I'm crazy?
Tammy Wynette gets me through life,
Dr. Eve.
And now you're trying to take her
precious, precious, precious memory
away from me.
I just--
[ Sobbing ]
I don't think I can take it.
- [ Sobbing ]
- [ LaVonda And Sissy Laughing ]
Oh, you remember that year
that Brother Boy was in
the Christmas pageant?
Oh, Lord, yes. He couldn't have
been more than five or six.
And he talked Wanda Jean Hilltop
into switching parts with him.
And Wanda Jean showed up
as a shepherd, and Brother Boy
prissed in as the Virgin Mary.
[ Both Laughing ]
Oh, well, honey...
you know that Wanda Jean
lives with a woman over in Abilene...
and she delivers for the UPS.
Oh, it all tracks back.
- Who cares?
- Me and Sissy.
- Why?
- 'Cause he's my baby brother, Latrelle.
- And I want to get him out.
- Out?
Let's go back
to the masturbation exercises, shall we?
Okay.
Now, when you switched to a woman,
who did you fantasize about?
You.
[ Wheezing Laugh ]
I masturbated...
and I fantasized about you.
Oh.
Well.
Well, well, well.
My. Thank you.
Well, actually,
it didn't turn out so good.
When I switched over to you,
I got kind of nauseous...
and, uh, I don't mean to be ugly, but--
[ Whistles ]
[ Chuckles ] It sort of went south,
if you know what I mean.
I'm sorry.
Oh, that's okay.
Don't worry about it.
- So, did you try again?
- No. I threw up.
Then I wasn't in the mood no more.
You know, Dr. Eve, I think next time
I'm gonna masturbate...
and I'm gonna fantasize about a woman
that's a little bit more masculine.
Um, oh! How about, uh--
What's her name?
Oh, Miss Jane Hathaway
from The Beverly Hillbillies.
She's kind of manly.
Earl, that is not the point.!
Well, I'm sorry.
I'm not quite sure what the point is.
The point is for you
to start fantasizing about a woman.
A real woman. A woman who is
feminine and sexy and all woman.
Not some butch stick of a woman
like Miss Jane Hathaway...
who could be a man in drag,
for all we know.
Well, I don't know about that.
I don't think a man in drag
would go out looking that bad.
I mean, even when Jethro
portrayed Jethrine.
- [ Screams ]
- Oh.
I don't know what to do
with you anymore, Earl.
I'm at my rope's end. I try and I try
to make progress-- and nothing!
You are not participating
in your own recovery!
- I called the institution this morning.
- You what?
- You called 'em?
- Called 'em. He needs to
know about Mama.
They said that now that Mama was dead
that you and me are responsible.
If we sign the proper papers,
we can get him out. He can live with me.
I just think that he ought to be here
for his own mama's funeral.
I think LaVonda might be right.
Well, I don't. We can't have Brother Boy
at the funeral. He'll be a spectacle.
Mama's death is enough of
an embarrassment without having
Brother Boy at the funeral.
- In case you're forgetting,
he's crazy.
- Brother Boy is not crazy.
There's something wrong
with him up here,
and you know it.
I'm not sure what's wrong with him
is up there.
The only thing wrong with him,
if it's wrong...
is that he likes to
dress up like a woman.
- That's wrong.
- According to who, Latrelle?
According to the Bible.
According to God.
- Off and runnin'.
- You mean to tell me that there
is a scripture that says...
- men shalt not dress up
in women's clothes?
- Y'all!
- Maybe you're the crazy one, Latrelle.
- LaVonda!
I'm not the one who wants to
bury a woman in a mink stole
in the middle of a heat wave.
- Mama loved that stole, Latrelle.
- Yes. And she had
the good fashion sense...
not to wear it in the summertime.
[ Latrelle ]
Sissy.! Sissy.!
Say something!
I thought you were on my side!
I am not on anybody's side!
I don't care, quite frankly!
I am trying to quit smokin'!
[ Breathing Heavily ]
And the two of you
are gettin' on my nerves!
[ Breathing Heavily ]
And my arm hurts.
It don't matter if Sister
wears that mink stole or not...
because she is dead.
And she's gonna be buried shortly...
and everybody will just forget about it
in no time flat anyway.
It don't matter!
So just hush up!
Both of ya!
[ Breathing Heavily ]
- You wanna know why she don't
want Mama buried in that stole?
- No! I don't want to know!
'Cause she wants it for herself.
Why would I, of all people,
want that mangy, old mink stole?
It's an antique and it's valuable.
And that stole is in real good shape.
- [ Scoffs ] Please.
- Don't try to deny it, Latrelle.
Although, that is your specialty,
if I'm not mistaken: Denial.
What are you talking about?
Denial. Denial about what?
Denial about everything.
About how Mama died.
And about why you want to
keep Brother Boy cooped up
like some damn animal.
- And why is that, pray tell?
- Never mind.
No, I want to hear this.
[ LaVonda ]
Look, all I am saying is that--
- You know how close me and Ty are--
- Don't you dare...
bring my son into this sordid picture.
What does my son have to do with this?
All I'm saying is that Ty
has more in common with Brother Boy...
- than you're willing to admit.
- Oh, Lord.
I think you blame Brother Boy
for the way Ty is.
Ty isn't anything. So you just
shut your mouth about my son.
I went out to L.A.
to see a play he was in.
- You did what?
- I went out to L.A.
To see Staccato.
Opening night.
And he was real good.
Sissy, the play was spectacular.
It was very... sensuous...
with a powerful message.
And I went out afterwards
with Ty and the all-male cast,
and we went to an all-male bar.
-That's when he told me.
-My son is not a homosexual! So shut up.
- I don't wanna hear this.
- You're in denial, Latrelle.
I am not in denial.
Would you quit saying I'm in denial?
- I am not in denial.
- All right. I'll quit saying it!
- But it ain't gonna change the truth.
- I don't wanna hear the truth!
Did you ever think
I don't wanna know the truth?
[ Sniffling ]
- [ Sniffles ]
- Hey. Hey.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Shh.
- [ Crying ]
- It's okay. Oh.
[ Crying Continues ]
I'm sorry.
Well, I never would have
quit smoking if I'd have known
Sister was going to die.
[ singing: I was standing
[ singing: By my window
[ singing: On one cold
[ singing: And cloudy day
[ singing: When I saw the hearse ]
[ singing: Come rolling ]
[ singing: For to carry ]
[ singing: My sister away ]
[ singing: Will the circle
[ singing: Be unbroken
[ singing: By and by, Lord
[ singing: By and by
[ singing: There's a better home
[ singing: Awaiting
[ singing: In the sky, Lord
[ singing: In the sky
[ singing: I will follow
[ singing: Close behind her
[ singing: Try to hold on
[ singing: And be brave
[ singing: But I cannot
[ singing: Hide my sorrow
[ singing: When they lay her
[ singing: In her grave
[ singing: Will the circle ]
[ singing: Be unbroken ]
[ singing: By and by, Lord ]
[ singing: By and by ]
[ singing: There's a better home ]
[ singing: Awaiting ]
[ singing: In the sky, Lord ]
[ singing: In ]
[ singing: The sky ] ]
When I was on the soap,
I'd do interviews, you know, press.
And I did this one with
this hysterically funny, queeny guy...
from Soap Opera Digest.
I don't know.
I-I dropped my guard.
Started being, you know, me.
Suddenly we were just laughing,
talking about Madonna's new
""Ray of Light'' video.
You know, her new black hair.
And had she had plastic surgery or not,
'cause she looked so great...
or was it just her newfound spirituality
and motherhood agreeing with her...
or just good lighting?
Well, this is not a conversation
that a couple of straight men
would be having.
And he leaned in to me,
and he said...
""I'm glad you're one of us.''
I just looked at him...
and realized I had fucked up.
So I put it back on,
you know, the butch thing.
And I said, ""I don't know
what you're talking about.''
And he just said, ""That's okay.
I understand.''
""That's okay. I understand.''
Well, they do not understand down there.
- Do you know what you're doing to me?
- No.
I have a book deal,
pending on my success with you.
- Ooh.
- Simon & Schuster.
And you're my ace in the hole, Earl.
If I can dehomosexualize you,
I can dehomosexualize anyone.
That would mean my theory works.
And I'd be famous.
I'll be on talk shows.
But you're not helping me, Earl.!
Well, I tried.
I did them
stupid masturbation exercises.
I can't help it
if you don't float my boat.
And I walked right down that hall
without my hair on...
everybody catcalling at me,
making fun.
Just-Just looking like
some kind of a damn fool.
You always look like a fool.
Well, that's not very nice.
""Nice.'' ""Nice.''
I don't give a shit about ""nice,'' Earl.
I am on a deadline.
This has got to work, so I can
get the hell out of this shithole...
and get on Oprah.
Is-- Is that so complicated?
Is that too much to ask for?
- No.
- Can you just get that
through your head?
Or has the heat from all the wigs
all these years caused you some kind
of brain damage?
Oh, you're starting to scare me.
And I don't particularly care
being called a fool.
- I need a tissue.
- No!
And don't start blubbering again,
because I am not in the mood.
Well, I just... don't...
consider myself a fool, Dr. Eve.
I consider myself a lot of things...
but I do not consider myself a fool.
His name was Ben Flack.
The guy from Soap Opera Digest.
Oh, Ben just loved our show.
Kind of became a friend of the cast.
He'd come and hang out at the set...
and parties and stuff.
But he stopped coming around,
and my friend Bobbie Eaves--
she played my fiancée on the show--
won the Emmy--
'cause they killed me off.
She got to play grief for six months.
[ Scoffs ]
Anyway,
Bobbie told me that Ben was sick.
And he didn't want any of us to come
to see him, so I sent him a card...
just telling him that I missed
seeing him around and...
just hoped he was feeling better.
The new meds...
they don't work for everyone, you know.
And he wrote me back.
He said, ""Ty Williamson...
""You're a beautiful man.
""So talented.
""Your soul runs deep...
""and you ain't hard on the eyes either.
I'm glad I knew you. Love, Ben.''
""Glad I knew you.''
Past tense.
Then there was:
""P.S., come out, come out
wherever you are and get happy.''
But I can't.
'Cause I care too much.
Especially down there in Texas.
Why do I care?
Why the fuck do I care?
I'll tell you another thing
I can't get off of my mind.
- Oh, hell.
- That eleven-hundred pound man.
I swear to Christ,
if you tell that one again...
I'm gonna beat you half to death.
- They had to rescue him--
- Put your hands over your heads
and don't anybody make a move!
Right now! Move it!
Noleta, what the hell
you think you're doing, woman?
We just watched Thelma and Louise
and we're pissed.
-At men.
-All men! Especially the three of y'all.
- Hey,Juanita.
- Hey, sugar. How you doing?
What are you
pissed at me for?
What'd I ever do?
You live and breathe, Odell.
So just shut up and stop
asking questions.
- We'll ask the questions, okay?
- Okay!
You make me sick, G.W.
Just lookin' at you makes me
wanna kill you dead.
- Come on, Noleta. Now--
- It's Thelma!
- I thought I was Thelma.
- No. Thelma's the one
with the shitty husband.
Hey, I said hands over your head, G.W.
You too, Wardell!
I mean it. Now.
- Okay. Okay.
- Well, hello there, Wardell.
Hi, LaVonda.
You're lookin' good.
Yeah? Well, I work at it.
You and your nitwit brother over there
beat up any queers lately?
- Hey, I ain't no nitwit.
- Liar!
- Y'all are drunk.
- No shit. And I'm on Valium too.
Thirty-two-O-nine.
LaVonda, I feel real bad
over that incident with Brother Boy.
- Ohh. You feel bad, huh?
- Yeah.
- He feels bad.
- Bad.
You feel bad and he's rotting
in a crazy farm because of you!
Well, big deal, Wardell.
It's time to get even.
- That happened over 20 years ago!
- I don't wanna hear about it...
so you just shut the hell up.
- And I mean it.
- Okay. Okay. Don't shoot.
- I don't like this.
- I don't know why you boys
are peeing in your Wranglers.
Them guns ain't loaded.
And even if they was, they wouldn't
have the gumption to shoot.
[ Wheezing Laugh ]
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Screams ]
Whoo-hoo-hoo! In the words ofThelma,
""I think I got a knack for this shit.''
- Oh.
- You sure do
That was a nice shot, Thelma.
Thanks, Louise,
but I was aiming for his head.
- Now, come on, Noleta.
- It's Thelma, you shithead!
Okay! Okay! Thelma then!
Now, listen. I know I messed up,
but what you gotta understand...
is that I wasn't exactly
getting what a man needs at home.
- What?
- Uh-oh.
- Ooh.
- I hope you're not gonna try
to justify your actions, G.W....
'cause, buddy boy,
you don't have a leg to stand on.
- Except them wooden ones. [ Cackles ]
- Oh! That's a good one!
- That's a good one.
- What we need to do, you and I--
Shut up until I say otherwise...
'cause I have something I gotta say.
Why'd you do it, G.W.?
-That's what I'm trying to--
-Don't answer that.Just think about it.
Do you know what it feels like
to be humiliated?
-Just--
-Don't answer that!Just think about it!
Well, I do. I can't even go out
in my own hometown anymore,
because everyone knows.
Everybody's out there pointing
and whispering.
""There she is. Poor pitiful thing.
Bless her heart.''
God! White trash even feel sorry for me.
That's true. That's very, very true.
I mean, everybody knows
that you were carrying on
with my best friend's mother.
And that coulda really ruined
me and LaVonda's friendship, you know?
Did you think about that?
-I--
-Don't answer that!Just think about it!
But it didn't. And you know why?
Because we're big enough not to let it.
- Mm. You got that right.
- Ooh. You know,
he shouldn't have said that.
- What'd you say?
- I said...
you're certainly big enough.
Why do you think I did it?
You got as big as a barn.
And who the hell
wants to climb that mountain?
I am on a diet, you asshole!
- That's it! Take off your shirt!
- What?
- Take off your damn shirt. I mean it.
I'll blow your head right off.
- Okay. Okay.
You too, boys. Take off your shirts.
- What are y'all doing?
- Getting even. What the hell
are you waitin' on, Odell?
- [ Shotgun Blast ]
- Okay! Okay!
- Oh! This is gettin' good.
- That one. Take off that one too.
No. What this is gettin' is ridiculous.
Ridiculous?
You wanna hear ridiculous?
- Okay.
- It's ridiculous...
for you to bitch about my weight...
when you go around lookin' like
you're six months pregnant!
- I mean, look at that gut, LaVonda!
- Lord.
- It's time to butcher that hog.
- He's sucking in too.
I raised your kids, G.W.
I was as faithful as the day was long.
Cooked you supper every night.
And you just shit all over
our wedding vows.
You just shit all over 'em!
And I've lost weight!
We did Jenny Craig's, lost 42 pounds.
Forty-two goddamn pounds.!
And he didn't even notice!
Never even said one thing!
Yeah, well,
that'd kinda be like the Titanic
losing a couple of deck chairs.
- You know, you really are a shit, G.W.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Hold this for me.
- I just wonder what my mama
saw in your sorry ass anyway.
Look at me.
Damn!
[ Chuckles ]
Too late. Take off your pants, G.W.
What? I ain't gonna--
Take off your goddamn pants!
- Whoo!
- Aah!
- [ Laughs ]
- I'd take 'em off if I was you.
- [Juanita Laughing ]
- Okay. Okay.
I'm taking 'em off. Shit.
You too, boys.
Quit your grinnin' and drop your linens.
- What did I do to deserve this?
- You ruined my brother's life.
You and this nitwit brother of yours.
So just take 'em off!.
I ain't no nitwit. I don't much
appreciate you callin' me that.
How about half-wit?
- I don't like that either.
- Okay.
There. You satisfied?
You ain't satisfied me in years.
- This ain't right, LaVonda.
- I loved you, Wardell.
You had to go and ruin it
by beating the shit out of Brother Boy.
I beat the shit out of Brother Boy
because you told me
he was in love with me.
You know what my mama said
the day the sheriff brought him home
all beat to a pulp?
- Huh? Do ya?
- No, I don't.
She said,
""Well, this just proves my point.
""He can't live in regular society
like a normal human being.
'cause it's just too dangerous.''
And the very next day...
her and Daddy drove him
over to Big Spring...
and signed the papers
for him to rot in that crazy farm.
You ruined his life, Wardell!
So what do you wanna talk about now?
What are you doing, Dr. Eve?
More therapy.
What are you thinking right now, Earl?
I was wondering where you got that bra.
I want you to fuck me, Earl,
because quite frankly I think
it's time you fuck a woman.
- Oh, dear sweetJesus.
No, I don't think I can.
- Come on.
Yes. You can.Just like
that little engine that could.
Say it, Earl. ""I think I can.''
- I think I can. I think I can.
- That's it.
- Now, let's go. Fuck me!
- Oh, I don't think I can!
Yes,you can, Earl.
I can change any man.
Just look at these, Earl.
Just look at 'em.
Ohh. Do you have any Mylanta?
- Fuck me, Earl. Fuck me now!
- Oh, my God, Dr. Eve!
- You don't have on any panties!
- I know. Now take yours off...
and fuck me, Earl, fuck me.
No, I can't. I can't because
I-I'm about to throw up.
I'd throw up all over you.
I had enchiladas for lunch. Oh!
Oh, shit! You are just
one hopeless pathetic freak!
- [ Gags ]
- Shit!
Oh, now, come on, boys.
You can do better than that.
Put your arms around each other.
Act like you love one another. Come on.
That's good. That's good.
Yeah. Get in there.
[ Laughing ]
Okay.
G.W., look longingly
into Wardell's eyes...
like you did with that tramp
you cheated on me with.
Hey. That was my mama.
I'm sorry. Do it, G.W.!
- Ohh. Oh, these are good!
- Oh, honey.
[ Giggling ]
They sure are!
Shit. Are we done yet?
Almost.Just as soon as you reach over
and kiss Odell on the mouth.
Okay. That's it.
Just shoot me. Go ahead.
Just kill me dead right here and now...
because I'll be damned
if I'm gonna kiss Odell.
Shut up, G.W.,
and take your punishment like a man!
Like a man? Like a man?
That would be
a little hard to do, Wardell,
while wearing a black brassiere!
You made your bed,
so why don't you just by God lay in it?
Maybe she's doing you a favor,
did you ever think of that?
A favor? What the hell
are you talking about? A favor?
What I'm saying is at least she's
getting even right after it happened.
I beat the shit out of
my little homo best friend...
sent him packing to the loony bin
for the rest of his life...
and I have been carrying that guilt
for some 20-odd years now.
Wish you had done this sooner,
LaVonda.
Maybe by now my life would be
just a little bit better.
And maybe your life
will be better too...
for wearing that pretty little
lacy black brassiere.
That is all I'm saying.
What can I do, LaVonda? Huh?
What can I do to make it better?
What can I do for you?
Shit. What can I do for Brother Boy?
There's gotta be something I can do.
Just please tell me what.
There ain't nothing you can do, Wardell.
Not now.
- I-I'm so sorry. Yeah.
- Yeah?
Well, I just wish Brother Boy knew.
Yeah. Me too.
Well, I think we have
done some good here today.
- [ Giggles ]
- I feel like I've been to church.
Amen. PraiseJesus.
Let me get my pictures.
You feed the jukebox.
- It's time for a little dancin'!
- Aha.
- Dancing?
- These are good.
- Here's a good un.
- You boys are real photogenic.
Okay, G.W. You and Odell dance
and then we'll be gone.
[ singing: [ Country ]
Son of a bitch.
- [ Tammy Wynette ]
[ singing: Sometimes it's hard
- I'll be the man.
- ] To be a woman
- Lookin' like that?
- ] Givin'all your love
- You know...
- ] Tojust one man
- he never took me dancing.
Not once.
- And that hurts.
- Men!
Okay, Wardell.
Ask Odell if you can cut in.
Go ahead on. It'll ease that guilt.
All right.
And I'll gladly do it.
- Odell. Can I cut in?
- Yeah?
- Sure thing.
- Oh, shit.
[ singing: But if you love him
I had to do it, Wardell.
- For Brother Boy.
- I'm glad you did.
- I feel better now.
- Oh, for shit's sake.
- Hey, Louise.!
- Yeah, Thelma?
[ Both Laughing ]
Hey, let's go on over to Tiny's Liquors
and stick him up.
- He short-changed me last week.
- Why that son of a bitch.
- Let's go.
- No! Wait! Girls!
I'll drive the getaway car.
- [ Exhales Deeply ]
- Y'all are drunk.
Well, come on, honey.!
Get on out there. Can you drive a stick?
- You better believe it!
- [ Cackles ]
There's Bitsy.!
[ Laughs ]
- Damn.
- Oh, hey.
Oh, shit.
I ain't saying a word.
[ Car Starts ]
To each his own, Odell.
- [ Tires Squealing ]
- [ Laughing ]
I'm never gonna get out of here, am I?
Shut up.! Damn sob sister.
They're never gonna let me outta here.
I can't pass any of your tests.
If you can't be homosexual as me,
they're never gonna let me out of here.
[ Exhales Deeply ]
Nope. You're stuck.
Stuck here forever.
[ Chuckling ]
Mm.Just like me.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughs ]
Stuck here forever.
Like a monkey in a zoo.
[ Laughing ]
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- I really don't see anything funny,
Dr. Eve.
[ Continues Laughing ]
Oh, well, I do.
[ Laughing Subsides ]
Oh.
I almost forgot. Your mama died.
- What?
- [ Snickering ]
What?
Your mama died.
[ Snickers ]
My mama's dead?
As a goddamn doornail.
[ Gulps, Snickers ]
[ Laughing ]
Oh, my God.
My mama's dead.
Hmph. Well, I quit crying.
I'm not even crying.
When Tammy Wynette died,
I sobbed like a baby for days
and days...
but my mama's dead, I'm not even sad.
Why, Dr. Eve? Why?
- Beats the hell outta me.
- Ohh.
- [ Timer Rings ]
- Okay. Session's over.
What?
[ Huffs ]
You drop a bombshell on me,
you tell me that my mama's dead,
then just say, ""Session's over''?
Hey. I'm beat, okay?
You think this is easy? Now get
your little monkey ass outta here.
And next time, please, make more of an
effort with my masturbation exercises.
- Yes, ma'am.
- And show up with no wig and no makeup.
- It is time you start--
- Participating in your own recovery.
Because I am at my rope's end
with you, Earl. I'm fed up!
- Do you understand?
- Yes, ma'am.
I'm, uh--
I'm sorry. I-I'm so sorry.
[ Sniffles ]
Uh, I'm gonna do my best.
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
What did you say?
I said, ""No.''
I'm not gonna do it,
'cause I don't understand--
I-- [ Huffs ]
I'm not gonna show up wigless.
I'm not gonna show up
without my face on.
And I sure as hell am not gonna do them
stupid masturbation exercises...
if I can't at least masturbate
and fantasize about a woman
that's manly!
You will if I say you will!
No! I won't!
And you can't make me.
I'm not doing nothing else you say,
Dr. Eve.
Do you hear me? Nothing.
If I am stuck in this shithole
for the rest of my life...
then I am not participating
in my own recovery.
And you can't make me.
And you wanna know my opinion?
I think you're nothing
but a flat-out evil, bitter...
mean, old, alcoholic sex fiend...
who needs a lifetime of therapy herself!.
I'm in therapy, you little faggot!
Well, it ain't a-workin'!
Now, if you'll please excuse me...
I got a show to do!
[ singing: ] [ Country ]
[ singing: Now, when the Lord ]
[ singing: Dips us in the gene pool ]
[ singing: We get more ]
[ singing: Than Granny's green eyes ]
[ singing: We get Mama's warmth
and our daddy's cool ]
[ singing: And that thing between our thighs ]
[ singing: That's the start of all this trouble ]
[ singing: In our sordid lives ]
- ] Ain't it a bitch ]
- Bitch!
[ singing: Sortin' out our sordid lives ]
- ] It's a bitch ]
- Bitch!
[ singing: When you come to realize ]
[ singing: Crack yourself
a box of CrackerJack ]
[ singing: You could get a really shitty prize ]
- ] It's a bitch ]
- Bitch.!
[ singing: Sortin' out our sorry, little ]
[ singing: Sordid lives ] ]
- [ Music Ends ]
- [ Whooping, Cheering ]
Did you see Tiny's big ol' red face
when I said...
""This is for short-changing me,
asshole.''
[ Laughs ] Acted like
he was gonna have a heart attack.
Oh, fuck yeah.
[ Laughing ]
Need a drink.
Hey, hon. What you in for?
I caught my husband cheatin' on me
with my sister Jeanetta.
So when he went to sleep...
I got him hard...
and super-glued his dick
to his stomach.
- He pressed charges.
- Mm-mm-mmm.
- [ Maniacal Laughter]
- You, what are you gonna do
if your ears...
your eyes fail you?
You're not gonna see
or hear the signs of Satan.
It feels good.
I have a fish in my ear!
I can't-- Help me! Please!
[ Noisy Commotion ]
- [ Blows ]
- When you're staring face-to-face
with Satan herself.
- The Lord Jesus Christ,
my personal savior--
- We gonna have a show now!
Settle down, y'all!
You gonna let that boy into your heart.
That's what you're gonna do.
[ Noisy Commotion ]
[ Blows, Smacks Lips ]
Ladies and gentlemen...
please make welcome
the first lady of country music...
Miss Tammy Wynette!
[ Commotion Continues ]
Thank you. Thank y'all.
Thank you. It is so nice to be back here
at the Opry tonight.
- [ Commotion Fades Out ]
- This one...
is for George Jones.
[ singing: [ Country ]
- [ Sobbing ]
- [ Man Barking ]
[ Lip-Synching ]
[ singing: I'll need time
[ singing: To get you off my mind
[ singing: And I may sometimes bother you
[ singing: Try to be in touch with you
[ singing: Even ask too much of you
[ singing: From time to time
[ singing: Now and then
[ singing: Lord,you know I'll need a friend
[ singing: Till I get used to losin'you
[ singing: Let me keep on usin'you
[ singing: Till I can make it on my own
[ singing: I'll get by
[ singing: But no matter how I try
[ singing: There'll be times you know I'll call
[ singing: Chances are my tears will fall
[ singing: And I'll have no pride at all
- ] From time to--
- [ Gunshot ]
- Don't kill me, Daddy.!
- Everybody, hands up! Nobody move!
- Daddy, don't kill me.!
- I mean it!
- [ Man ] It's Jesus.!
I told you he was coming.!
- It's Jesus!
[ Whimpering ]
- Wardell?
- Brother Boy.
Oh, no! You--
My hair fell off. You can't--
Oh, my God. No. Don't look.
So this is Wardell.
Um, I've heard a lot about you, Wardell.
Dr. Eve Bolinger.
What I need for you and everybody else
is just to stand back...
and stay calm till we're out of here
so nobody'll get hurt.
I don't think I'd mind gettin' hurt by
a big ol' handsome cowboy like yourself.
- Back off, bitch.
- Excuse me?
No. You heard me.
You get your damn paws off of him
and you get the hell on outta here.
Like I'm scared of you,
you little monkey freak.
Hey! Don't talk to him like that.
Shoot her, Wardell.
Shoot her in the head.
- Go on! Git!
- Get the hell on outta here!
- Brother Boy.
- Wardell.
- I'm sorry.
- Ohh.
Uh-- [ Chuckles ]
It's-It's okay.
I'll never hurt you again.
And I won't let anybody else hurt you,
either.
I'm taking you home now.
You're, um--
- You're taking me home?
- That's right.
[ Sniffles ]
Dear sweet Jesus.
[ Crying ]
I'm going home.
Come on. Come on. Let's go.
You stay back.
- Stay back!
- Bumper, grab him!
- Come on!
- Give me the gun!
Come on! I know the way!
- Hurry! Go on! Go!
- Keep runnin
[ Grunting ]
Shit!
- Hyah!
- [ Screams ]
Where'd they go?
Hey.! Come back here,you little faggot.!
If I'd known you was comin',
I'd have wore flats.
- Come back here.!
- [ Gunshot ]
- Oh!
Oh! Whoa!
Hey! Goddamn it.
Shit!
Here we go. Run, run, run!
Fast! Run fast!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Goddamn it!
- Asshole!
- Ow.!
Do you see my pussy now? Ha!
Haul ass, Wardell.
[ Tires Squealing ]
After I left your office...
I just went home,
laid down on the couch...
and just started drifting, you know--
let my mind float from place to place.
And I just wondered
what my life would have been like
if I'd been honest with myself...
and everybody else.
That's when I decided
I'm not going back down to
my grandmother's funeral...
basically because I'm gay
and I don't wanna deal.
Then I started feeling guilty.
[ Sighs ]
And I prayed.
I don't know why.
I haven't prayed in years,
but I asked for a sign.
You know,
just like I did when I was a kid...
back when I went to church--
when I believed.
[ Ty, Narrating ]
And this feeling of peace...
of serenity...
just swept over my entire body.
[ Chuckles ]
When I was a little boy...
I just loved church.
But I stopped going.
Because how do you embrace something
that doesn't embrace you.
But lately...
I've been missing God.
So I finally prayed.
Then...
I just opened up my eyes
and flipped on the TV.
Wizard of fuckin'Oz was on.
Right at the part where
Glinda's singing, ""Come out,
come out, wherever you are.''
I swear to God.
So I got up and I just
went straight over to the theater.
- ] [ Sara Singing ]
- It was this quest.
It was this spiritual quest.
[ singing: Helplessly I watch ]
[ singing: Both girls and guys cruise you ]
[ singing: So please, please don't be gay
[ singing: We don't wanna lose you
[ Man ]
Too late, honey.
- ] It makes me sad-- ]
- Okay, kids. Let's take ten.
And then we start the second act
run-through. That was great.
- I wasn't flat?
- Not at all.
I got such a fuckin'headache?
We got any Motrin?
I got some of that generic shit
in my bag.
Sara?
Don't tell me. You've come to
beg forgiveness, ask me to marry you...
and we will run off
and live happily ever after.
[ Exhales Deeply ]
Look. I basically came by
just to say that I'm sorry...
and to tell you something.
Okay.
Sara, you are such a great girl.
- I know.
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Exhales Deeply ] And the reason
that I broke up with you...
is be--
[ Sighs ]
It wasn't--
Oh. I'm gay.
- I know.
- You know?
Most people do.
Oh, God.
It's okay.
You're-You're Ty.
Okay. Look. So we can't
run off together...
have wild sex and get married.
Whatever.
But you know what really hurt me...
is that you just dismissed me
from your life.
And you have to understand,
if someone loves you, Ty...
they're not gonna toss you out
just because you're gay...
because of who you are.
I'm so sorry.
You don't have to be. It's okay.
[ singing: I've wandered far
[ singing: Away from God ]
[ singing: Now I'm comin' home ]
[ singing: The paths of sin ]
[ singing: Too long I've trod ]
[ singing: Lord, I'm comin' home ]
[ singing: I've wasted many precious years
[ singing: Now I'm comin'home
[ singing: I repent
[ singing: With bitter tears
[ singing: Lord, I'm comin'home
[ singing: Comin'home,yeah
[ singing: I'm comin'home
[ singing: Nevermore to roam
[ singing: Open wide
[ singing: Thine arms oflove
[ singing: Lord, I'm comin'home
[ singing: Comin'home,yeah
[ singing: I'm comin'home
[ singing: Nevermore to roam
[ singing: Open wide
[ singing: Thine arms oflove
[ singing: Lord, I'm comin'home
[ singing: Comin'home
[ singing: Yeah, I'm comin' home ]
[ singing: Nevermore to roam ]
[ singing: Open wide thine arms of love ]
[ singing: Lord ]
[ singing: I'm comin' ]
[ singing: Home
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Sobs ]
Hey.
I guess you don't mind if I smoke.
It just wasn't the right time to quit,
with you dyin' and all.
I only lasted three days.
I failed again.
But after five husbands,
what else is new?
[ Sighs ]
It has not been a good day, Sister.
And I am blaming you!
I am! I can't help it!
Now, you know that
I am not one to judge.
And quite frankly,
I was glad that you cut loose...
and had some fun towards the end.
But I wish you had been more careful.
I mean, you turn on a light when you
get up to go to the bathroom!
Especially in a strange motel room.
If you are gonna have affairs,
you have got to be more careful!
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Of course, this is useless information
for you now.
I don't know why the hell
I'm wasting my breath.
[ Sighs ]
""Jesus called, Peggy answered.''
Ohh.
Oh, God.
You look real good.
I loved you, Sister.
[ Weepy ]
I did. I do.
- Sissy.!
- Oh! Good Lord, Latrelle!
Don't you have better sense
than to yell at somebody
when they're talkin' to a corpse?
We got a situation.
Mama's funeral starts in 30 minutes
and LaVonda is in jail.
In jail? What on Earth for?
She and Noleta Nethercott
held up Tiny's Liquor Store
and they're both in jail.
Juanita Bartlett drove the getaway car.
- She's in jail too.
- Oh, my Lord.
Now, I need you to get down there
and bail her out.
Here. Nine-hundred dollars cash.
Had to go to the bank.
Now go on.
Okay.
Aah! Wait! Come back!
[ Huffs ]
Hurry!
- You gotta help me get off this stole.
- Ohh.
[ Radio ]
[ singing: Get off the cross
[ singing: Honey, we need the wood
[ singing: [ Continues ]
[ Gruff]
Peggy!
One, two, three.
- [ Grunts ]
- I got it! I got it!
Good. Good job.
Now go get LaVonda.
Oh! Wait!
Take the stole, throw it
in the trunk of your car. Go! Hurry!
I'm hurrying!
- ] Get off the cross
- Peggy!
Ohh. Hey, G.W. How are you?
Peggy!
Quit that screaming
right now, G.W.
-I'm gonna burn up my legs!
-Show some respect, for crying out loud!
- Burn the son of a bitches up!
- Quit using such vulgar language
in the church house.
- You're the only woman I ever loved.
- You are drunk. I want you out.
- [ Crying ] Peggy. Peggy.
- Now, go on.
I have no use for you, you understand?
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Latrelle.
- Wha--
- Peggy's good girl.
Oh, the tight-ass. Well, I'm gonna
burn 'em up like firewood.
- And don't you tell me
I'm not, 'cause I am.
- Well!
I'm gonna douse them
with lighter fluid...
and light 'em up
in front of God and Peggy...
so she can witness it
and see how sorry I am.
She can't witness anything, G.W.,
'cause she's dead.
I know she's dead.
It's all on account of
these sorry-ass legs of mine.
Sissy!
[ Exhales Deeply ]
Baby...
I'm gonna do it for you, Peg.
Right now. You'll see.
- No! No!
- Yes.! Yes.!
- No! No! No, no, no!
- Oh, yes!
- Oh, yeah.
- The day has been hard enough.
- These damn childproof lighters. Damn!
- Now, go on! Git!
Go on! Get Noleta now!
Okay. I'll git. But first I wanna
say something to Peggy, okay?
I wanna say my farewell...
to the only woman I ever loved.
Okay. Well, you just go on now.
Make it quick, and I mean it.
[ Sobbing ]
Peggy, Peggy, Peggy...
Peggy, Peggy, Peggy, Peggy.
Peggy, Peggy, Peggy.
I can't think of nothing else to say.
It's probably for the best.
Now, go on. Now, git.!
- Can I have my lighter fluid back?
- No!
Now, you have a family to support, G.W.
Think of your family.
You need your legs.
Now, go get Noleta out of jail. Go on!
Life is one big ol' pile of shit,
Latrelle!
Well, he's right about that.
Ooh! I could just... kill you, Mama--
if you weren't already dead.
What got into you, Mama?
Why on Earth would you run around
with the likes of Bitsy Mae Harling?
A convict!
- And G.W. Nethercott...
- [ Tires Squealing ]
who just tried to set fire to
his wooden legs in the church house...
to make amends for killing you.
That is not a smart man, Mama.
You taught us
not to cavort with trash like that.
How could you leave me
in a quandary like this?
Mama?
- Ty!
- I made it.
- Oh, Ty. You did!
- I made it after all.
Oh, honey, thank you.
[ Gasps ]
Oh. Let me look at you.
- Are you okay?
- Okay?
Okay? No, Ty, I am not okay.
I have had a horrible, horrible day.
But you're here now.
Things are lookin' up.
Mama, I'm gay.
You don't know
what I've had to deal with...
while you daddy's been off
building houses for poor white trash...
with Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter.
Your Aunt LaVonda?
Held up a liquor store and is in jail.
- Oh, aren't these flowers pretty?
- Did you hear me? I'm gay.
And I got the bail money to Sissy.
Nine hundred dollars,
which I better get back.
And we were able to pry
that god-awful mink stole
off your grandmother...
that your Aunt LaVonda insisted
that she wear in the heat of summer.
Mama! I'm gay.
I know you're gay!
I've known you're gay
since you were five years old...
and you wanted that doll Suzy Q
for Christmas...
instead of the dump truck
your Daddy wanted to buy you.
I know you're gay, Ty.
I've always known.
But could we please
just bury your grandmother
and get on with life? Could we?
Because I think
I'm gonna explode any minute...
if any more shit hits the fan today!
I've had 27 therapists
and you knew...
since I was five.
Did you just say ""shit''?
I did.
I did. And I said ""damn'' today too.
And ""hell'' and ""bitch'' and ""dookie''.
And you know what?
I feel like saying more.
Damn. Hell. Bitch. Shit. Dookie!
- Damn! Hell! Bitch!
- Okay. Mama, calm down.
- Shit! Titty!
- Mama!
[ Exhales Deeply ]
Thank you.
For what?
I don't know. Sewing those Slim labels
on my Husky jeans.
Oh, Lord. I forgot all about that.
- I didn't.
- Slim.
[ Laughing ]
You were fatter than Baby Huey.
I know!
Ohh! You think...
we fooled anyone with that?
No.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
Ah. It feels good to laugh.
- [ Sighs ] Yes. It does.
- I haven't laughed all day.
Me either.
Why'd you change those labels, Mama?
All I ever wanted for you
was for you to be happy.
I couldn't make you happy.
And I blame Dr. McCright.
- Dr. McCright? For what?
- For you being gay.
When I was pregnant with you, he gave me
this drug that had estrogen in it...
to keep me from miscarrying again.
I am positive that's what caused this.
Mama, I don't think that
that's what caused this.
And I'm getting happy now,
and I want you to know that.
Well, I'm glad someone is.
Well, uh, Nan Nan looks good.
Now.
Oh, Lord.
What she did to Brother Boy.
She would roll over in her grave...
if she knew you were gay too.
That is, if she was in her grave.
[ Snickers ]
Hey, Nan Nan.
Guess what. I'm gay!
Yup. Gay as a goose.
- Oh! Stop it!
- [ Chuckles ] Just as gay
as Uncle Brother Boy.
Oh, you are not! Nobody's that gay.
So what is it exactly...
that you... do.
- What?
- You know.
When you're gay.
Oh, dear God.
I hope my mama
isn't asking me about my sex life.
Well, if I have a gay son,
I need to know about gay sex.
Well, then read a book, Mama!
I don't ask you what happens
in the privacy of your bedroom!
I'll tell you exactly what happens.
- Nothin'.
- [ Huffs ] No. No, no, no, no. No.
I am not about to explain gay sex...
and the details
of my own sex life to my mama
in front of my grandmother's coffin.
- You wanna step outside?
- No!
Oh! I-I'm not gonna
discuss this with you. Period.
- Well, fine. Be that way!
- You know, I will!
-Just trying to be open.
- You know, maybe I don't
want you to be.
[ Sighs ]
You've always been my special boy.
I never felt closer to anyone.
No one.
We always had that special bond.
- Yeah.
- And, you know...
I'm not sure we woulda had that...
if you weren't gay.
So...
I don't regret taking that drug...
after I lost those other babies.
'Cause I can't imagine
life without you, Ty.
I'm happy with who I am now, Mama.
Instead of blaming Dr. McCright,
maybe we should just thank him.
Maybe.
But he's dead.
I love you, Mama.
I love you so, so much.
I love you too, baby.
So...
are you the woman or the man?
[ Sighs ]
- [ Large Bells Toll ]
- Come on, LaVonda! Quit primping!
They've already started!
[ singing: In the sweet by and by ]
[ singing: We shall meet on that beautiful ]
Lord. Cover up your titties.
- ] By and by ]
- ] We shall meet
on that beautiful shore ]
- [ Gasps ] Ty!
[ singing: On the shore ]
- ] In the sweet by and by ]
- [ Whispers ] Latrelle!
- Oh, baby! Oh. I'm so glad you're here.
- ] We shall meet on that
[ singing: Beautiful shore ]
[ singing: Amen ] ]
Yes, brethren.
We shall meet on that beautiful shore.
Praise Jesus. Praise the Lord.
- Praise the Lord.
- Amen. Praise Jesus.
Today we are gathered here together...
to pay our respects to...
and celebrate the life
of our beloved sister...
Peggy Sue Ingram.
[ Guitar Clangs ]
- Peggy was born February 26, 1 933...
- Who is that?
Bitsy Mae Harling.
- Who?
- Bitsy!
...right here outside of Winters.
- Peggy died July 23, 1999.
- Oh!
And at this time,
Peggy's younger daughter...
Latre--
- Latrelle.
- Latrelle...
would like to say a few words
in memory...
of her dearly departed mother.
Thank you, Brother Barnes.
And, uh, thank y'all
for coming here today.
What a nice turnout.
[ Sniffles ]
As many of you know,
my mama was not right...
for the last six months of her life.
- Scootch over, honey.
- She abandoned her sense of
morality and upbringing...
and started running around with...
riffraff.
Oh, Lord.
[ Murmuring ]
I took her to the doctor
over in Snyder a few months ago...
and they found a lemon-sized
cancerous tumor on her brain.
- No!
- Yes!
- What'd she say?
- Un tumor.
It was inoperable
and growing... rapidly.
Mama asked me to tell no one...
and I kept her secret till now.
But it's time to clear your name, Mama.
What happened was the tumor grew...
and it pressed up against...
the-- well, the, uh...
sexual part of her brain.
This is gonna make us look better?
The tumor turned my mama
into a nymphomaniac.
She wasn't no nymphomaniac.
I'll tell you that.
So I wanna ask on behalf
of my grieving family...
that y'all... forget...
the circumstances
surrounding Mama's death...
and remember her for the good
Christian woman that she was...
before the tumor destroyed
her health and her morality.
Thank you.
[ Sobs ]
[ Murmuring ]
[ Clink, Hiss ]
Thank you, Latrelle,
for those... revelations.
Cancer can be so cruel.
Now I'd like to read--
Hey!
Can I say a few words too?
What's she doing?
She's gonna say a few words too.
This isn't open mike.
I... suppose so.
I had no idea about the tumor.
I am so sorry. But I got to tell you,
Peggy touched my life--
the nymphomaniac Peggy...
with all due respect.
We were close. Very close.
After we closed up at Bubba's...
I was all wound up
after a big show and, well...
me, Peggy,Juanita...
sometimes G. W. over there-- Hi, G. W.
[ Snoring ]
We'd all sit around, get drunk,
sing hymns.
Lord, Lord, Lord.
This was Peggy's favorite hymn.
I'd like to sing it for her as she
passes through those pearly gates
to meet her maker.
""Just As I Am.'' Listen to the words.
They apply on so many levels.
I'm gonna wake up any minute now.
Excuse me, darlin'.
This is for you.
[ singing: ] [ Strumming ]
[ singing: Just as I am ]
[ singing: Without one plea ]
[ singing: But that thy blood
[ singing: Was shed for me
[ singing: And that thou bidst me ]
[ singing: To come to thee ]
- ] O Lamb of God ]
- I'm so glad you came.
[ singing: I come
[ Group Singing ]
[ singing: Just as I am ]
[ singing: Though tossed about ]
[ singing: With many a conflict
[ singing: Many a doubt
[ singing: Fightings within
[ People Gasping ]
- Is-- Is that--
- That's your Uncle Brother Boy.!
- No!
- Latrelle, get back here!
[ Both Shouting, Indistinct ]
- Calm down. Stop it!
- Stop it! Stop it right now...
or I am gonna knock you into next week!
- But--
-Just shut up and sit down
and you let him stay!
Mama, he's family.
Let him stay.
[ Sighs ]
Okay.
Tough crowd.
[ Murmuring ]
Thanks, Wardell.
[ singing: [ Guitar Strums ]
[ singing: Just as I am ]
[ Group Singing ]
[ singing: Though tossed about ]
[ singing: With many a conflict ]
[ singing: Many a doubt ]
[ singing: Fightings within ]
[ singing: And fears without ]
[ singing: O Lamb of God ]
[ singing: I come ]
[ singing: I come ] ]
Well, I guess you didn't
think I was gonna make it...
did you, Mama?
[ Sobs ]
[ singing: [ Country ]
[ singing: Now, when the Lord
[ singing: Dips us in the gene pool
[ singing: We get more than Granny's green eyes
[ singing: We get Mama's warmth
and our daddy's cool
[ singing: And that thing between our thighs
[ singing: That's the start of all this trouble
[ singing: In our sordid lives
- ] Ain't it a bitch
- ] Bitch
[ singing: Sortin'out our sordid lives
- ] It's a bitch
- ] Bitch
[ singing: When you come to realize
[ singing: Crack yourself
a box of CrackerJack
[ singing: You could get a really shitty prize
[ singing: It's a bitch
[ singing: Sortin'out our sorry, little
[ singing: Sordid lives
[ Song Ends ]
[ singing: [ Country ]
[ Tammy Wynette ] I've never
seen the inside of a barroom
[ singing: Or listened to a jukebox
all night long
[ singing: But I see these are the things
[ singing: That bring you pleasure
[ singing: So I'm gonna make some changes
in our home
[ singing: I've heard it said
[ singing: "If you can't beat 'em join 'em'"
[ singing: So if that's the way
you've wanted me to be
[ singing: I'll change if it takes that
to make you happy
[ singing: From now on you're gonna
see a different me
- Oh! Here we go!
- ] Because
[ singing: Your good girl's gonna go bad
[ singing: I'm gonna be the swingingest swinger
[ singing: You've ever had
[ singing: If you like 'em painted up
powdered up
[ singing: Then you oughta be glad
'cause your
[ singing: Good girl's gonna go bad
Oh, you better believe it!
[ singing: I'll even learn to like
the taste of whiskey
- ] In fact, you'll hardly
recognize your wife
- Yeah!
[ singing: I'll buy some brand new clothes
[ singing: And dress up fancy
[ singing: For my journey
to the wilder side of life
[ singing: Because your good girl's
gonna go bad
[ singing: I'm gonna be the swingingest swinger
[ singing: You've ever had
[ singing: If you like 'em painted up
powdered up
[ singing: Then you oughta be glad
[ singing: 'Cause your good girl's gonna go bad
- Yee-haw!
- ] Oh, yeah, your good girl's
gonna go bad
I could be available.
[ Song Ends ]
[ singing: [ Soft Rock ]
[ singing: I need to tell the truth
[ singing: I can't lie anymore
[ singing: I need to do what's right
[ singing: I know that's what my life is for
[ singing: I can't be quiet anymore
[ singing: About what I'm supposed to do
[ singing: I need to tell the truth
[ singing: And do what's right by you
[ singing: I need to speak my mind
[ singing: Let my heart run free
[ singing: Your pain will heal with time
[ singing: And one day you'll thank me
[ singing: And as I follow my dream
[ singing: And there is no room for you
[ singing: Just know there was no scheme
[ singing: It's just what I had to do
[ singing: Trust yourself
[ singing: You know all the answers
[ singing: You know what is right
[ singing: Trust yourself
[ singing: It's all there inside you
[ singing: They've been there forever
[ singing: Just show them some light
Hello?
Where is everybody?