All right, let's try somethin' else.
Uh, from the top.
Ready. One, two, three.
One, two, three, four.
Stay on the beat.
Two, three, four.
That's C-sharp, horns.
Two, three...
I see you, Caleb.
Rachel, now you.
Forgot my sax, Mr G.
Okay, she forgot her sax.
And now, all you, Connie.
Go for it!
Way to go!
Hang on, hang on.
What are y'all laughing at?
So Connie got a little lost in it.
That's a good thing.
Look, I remember one time
my dad took me to this jazz club,
and that's the last place I wanted to be.
But then I see this guy,
and he's playing these chords
with fourths on it,
and then with the minor...
Oh, oh, whoo.
Then he adds the inner voices,
and it's like he's...
It's like he's singing.
And I swear, the next thing I know...
...it's like he floats off the stage.
That guy was lost in the music.
He was in it, and he took
the rest of us with him.
And I wanted to learn...
...how to talk like that.
That's when I knew...
I was born to play.
Connie knows what I mean.
Right, Connie?
I'm 12.
I'll be right back.
Practise your scales.
Sorry to interrupt, Mr Gardner.
You're doing my ears a favour.
- Hey!
- Not you, though, you're good.
He's not.
What can I do for you, Principal Arroyo?
I wanted to deliver
the good news personally.
No more part-time for you.
You're now our full-time band teacher.
Job security.
Medical insurance. Pension.
Wow. That's, uh, great.
Welcome to the M.S. 70 family, Joe.
Permanently.
Thanks.
After all these years,
my prayers have been answered.
A full-time job.
Working man, coming through.
Yeah, Mom, but I...
You're going to tell them yes, right?
Don't worry, Mom, I got a plan.
You always got a plan.
Maybe you need to have a backup plan, too,
for when your plan falls through.
A backup plan never hurts.
Joey, we didn't struggle
giving you an education
so you could be a middle-aged man
washing your underwear in my shop.
Walking around with a hole in his pants.
- Yeah, but...
- With this job, you'll be able
to put that dead-end gigging behind you.
And Lord knows we need
more teachers in this world.
And just think,
playing music will finally
be your real career.
So you're going to tell them yes, right?
Please say yes.
Yeah, definitely.
Good.
Hello?
How you been, Mr G?
Uh, it's Curley. Lamont.
Lamont Baker.
Hey, Curley!
Hey, good to hear your voice, man.
Uh... Listen.
You can call me Joe now, Curley.
I'm not your teacher anymore.
Oh, okay, Mr Gardner.
Hey, look, I'm the new drummer
in the Dorothea Williams Quartet,
and we're kickin' off our tour
with a show at The Half Note tonight.
Dorothea Williams!
Are you kidding me?
Congratulations, man. Wow!
I would die a happy man
if I could perform with Dorothea Williams.
Oh, well,
this could be your lucky day.
- Whew, there he is.
- Hey, Curley.
Leon skipping town
really put us in a bind, man.
- Yeah. Uh, I'll bet.
- I'm glad you made it.
My boy, Bishop, said he sat in with you
on a set last year in Brooklyn.
Said you were great.
Well, you know,
for a coffee shop.
Hey, Dorothea.
This is the cat I was telling you about.
My old middle school band teacher,
Mr Gardner.
Call me Joe, Dorothea.
Uh... Uh, I mean, Miss Williams.
It's a pleasure. Wow.
This is amazing.
Uh, Joe is Ray Gardner's son.
So, we're down to
middle school band teachers now.
Get on up here, Teach,
we ain't got all day.
What... What are we playin'?
Uh, sorry.
I zoned out a little back there.
Joe Gardner, where have you been?
I've been, uh, teaching,
middle school band.
Uh, but on the weekends, I...
- You got a suit?
- Uh...
Get a suit, Teach.
A good suit.
Back here tonight.
First show's at 9:00.
Soundcheck's at 7:00.
We'll see how you do.
Yes! Whoo-hoo!
You see that, Dad?
That's what I'm talking about!
Hey, look up, look up.
You know what that's gonna say?
Joe Gardner!
You're never gonna believe
what just happened.
I did it. I got the gig. Yes!
I... I know.
Dorothea Williams!
Can you believe it?
Hey, pal, you're gonna get hurt!
Just don't tell my mom about this. Okay?
Forget class. I'm in a different class.
I'm in a Dorothea Williams class, buddy.
You know what I'm saying? I'm...
Whoa! Sorry!
What the...
Hello?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hello!
Hello.
Oh, what's your name, honey?
Uh, I'm Joe. Joe Gardner.
Look, I'm not supposed to be here.
Ah. Must have been sudden for you.
You see, Joe, I'm 106 years old.
Been waiting a long time for this.
- For what?
- The Great Beyond.
The Great Beyond?
- As in, as in beyond life?
- Yeah.
That's death right there?
Exciting, isn't it?
No, no, no, listen.
I have a gig tonight.
I can't die now.
Well, I really don't think
you have a lot to say about this.
Yes. Yes, I do.
I'm not dying the very day
I got my shot. I'm due.
Heck, I'm overdue.
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
I'm outta here.
I don't think you're supposed
to go that way.
This can't happen.
I'm not dyin' today.
Not when my life just started.
What was that?
Wait. I'm not finished.
I gotta get back.
I don't wanna die!
I'm not done.
I'm not done. Run!
- Why aren't you running?
- I don't know.
- What's wrong with you people?
I'm not done.
Ahh!
Oh, my goodness.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Help! I'm not done.
I gotta get back.
Oh, my... Oh, my goodness.
What?
Ow!
Now, now, everyone,
let's give the mentor some room.
Sorry, new souls.
37, that's enough.
Hey, everyone, look here.
Quiet coyote.
Shh. Quiet coyote.
Who... Who are you?
I am the coming together
of all quantised fields of the universe.
Appearing in a form
your feeble human brain can comprehend.
- What?
- You can call me Jerry.
Jerry, okay.
Uh, hey, is this heaven?
No.
Is it H-E-double hockey sticks?
- Hell.
- Hell, hell, hell.
- Shh. Quiet coyote.
- Hell.
It's easy to get turned around.
This isn't the Great Beyond.
It's the Great Before.
The Great Before?
Oh. We call it the You Seminar now.
Rebranding.
Hell.
No, no. You're here!
Does this mean I'm dead?
Not yet.
Your body's in a holding pattern.
It's complicated.
I'll get you back to your group.
Come on, little souls, get on up here.
Welcome to the You Seminar.
You are in for a treat.
- Mm, that's weird.
- What is it?
- The count's off.
- Excuse me?
There's a soul missing.
The count's off.
Huh.
Okay, first stop
is the Excitable Pavilion.
You four. In you go.
You five, you'll be aloof.
And you two, why not?
Oh, wait a minute.
This is where personalities come from?
Of course. Do you think people
are just born with them?
So, uh, how do they get to Earth, then?
Well, they use the Earth portal.
Once they get a complete personality,
of course.
Hello? Hello?
Goodbye.
Whee!
Whoo-hoo!
Wait, wait, wait.
You sure get lost a lot.
All righty, mentors.
- Just find your name here...
- Hello, Jerry...
...and join us inside.
...got a lost mentor for you.
Thanks, Jerry.
Uh, look, I'm not sure
I'm supposed to be here.
I understand.
Mentoring isn't for everyone.
You're more than welcome to opt out.
Actually, on second thought,
you know, the mentoring sounds like fun.
I'm glad to hear it.
Jerry will take it from here.
Thanks, Jerry.
Head right on over there to Jerry.
Thank you, Jerry.
Is everyone here named Jerry?
Good luck!
Jerry, we've got a problem.
Oh, hello, there, Terry.
The count's off.
I seriously doubt that.
The count hasn't been off in centuries.
151,000 souls go into
the Great Beyond every day.
That's 105.2 souls per minute, Jerry.
1.75 souls per second.
And I count every single one of 'em.
Yep. I'm aware.
It's my job to keep track
of this stuff, Jerry.
I'm the accountant.
And we all think
you're doing a wonderful job,
- don't we, everyone?
- Absolutely.
Looks good from where this guy's standing.
I'd say no.
I'm always counting.
I'm counting right now.
You blinked five times
since I started talking. Six.
Right. Since accounting is your job,
why don't you figure out the problem?
- Maybe I will.
- Wonderful.
Hello again, Terry.
Don't play dumb with me.
Okay, here we go.
"A."
Hello, there, mentors.
I'm Jerry, a counselor here
at the You Seminar.
Now you don't remember it,
but you've been here before.
But don't worry,
forgetting the trauma of childbirth
is one of the great gifts of the universe.
Here at the You Seminar,
all new souls are given unique
and individual personalities.
I'm an agreeable sceptic
who's cautious yet flamboyant.
I'm an irritable wallflower
who's dangerously curious.
I'm a manipulative megalomaniac
who's intensely opportunistic.
Oh-ho, this one might be a handful.
But that's Earth's problem.
You'll notice these souls
are all missing something.
What goes in this spot?
Well, these souls need their "spark".
And that's where you come in.
Maybe you will find their spark
in the Hall of Everything,
where literally anything
on Earth could inspire.
Or perhaps you'll prefer the Hall of You,
featuring a selection of moments
from your own inspiring life.
And just what is this spark?
I know you're all excited to get to work,
so good luck finding the spark.
Find the spark.
Wow, that was informative.
Now, it's time for my favourite
part of the programme,
matching you mentors with your soul mates.
Our first mentor is Maria Martinez.
Maria, come on down.
Maria was a rare disease specialist
from the University of Mexico.
I'm cured. I'm cured.
She'll be matched
with one of my favourites,
soul number 108,210,121,415.
Congratulations! Off you go.
Our next mentor is Bjorn T. Börgensson.
Dr Börgensson
is a world-renowned child psychologist
who was recently awarded a Nobel Prize.
I see pain, death, destruction.
- How about now?
- A pretty butterfly.
Dr Börgensson will be matched
with soul number 22.
Oh, we're gonna get into this now.
Excuse me.
22, you come out of
this dimension right now.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
I don't wanna go to Earth.
- Stop fighting this, 22.
- I don't wanna.
You will go to Earth
- and have a life.
- Make me!
22 has been at the You Seminar
for quite some time
and has had such
notable mentors as Gandhi,
Abraham Lincoln, and Mother Teresa.
I made her cry.
Ignore that.
Put me down.
We're truly glad to have you here,
Dr Börgensson.
It is an honour having you
prepare 22 for Earth.
I'm gonna make you wish you never died.
Most people wish that, 22.
Off you go. Bye!
Where are we?
That's great progress.
You should be very proud.
Step by step.
In celebration of
Dr Börgensson's body of work,
we are pleased to present him
this honorary...
These past few weeks,
I have seen such growth.
So many people I'd like to thank,
of course.
Okay, look,
I'm sure your life was amazing
and you did amazing things,
but here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna stand here
in silence for a little bit,
then we go back out, you say you tried,
I go back to not living my non-life
and you go to the Great Beyond.
- No, look.
- Talk all you want, Bjorn.
It's not gonna work, anyway.
I've had thousands of mentors
who failed and now hate me.
Mother Teresa...
I have compassion for every soul.
Except you. I don't like you.
Copernicus...
The world doesn't revolve around you, 22.
Muhammad Ali...
You are the greatest pain in the butt.
Marie Antoinette...
Nobody can help you! Nobody!
Thanks, but no thanks, Doc.
I already know everything about Earth,
and it's not worth the trouble.
Come on, don't you want
to fill out your pass?
You know, I'm comfortable up here.
I have my routine.
I float in mist, I do my Sudoku puzzles,
and then, like, once a week,
they make me come
to one of these You Seminars.
It's not great, but I know what to expect.
Look, kid, I'm not...
Can I just be honest with you?
I'm not Bjorn Borgenstein
or whatever his name is.
I'm not even a mentor.
Not a mentor?
Ah...
Reverse psychology.
You really are a good shrink, Doctor.
Carl Jung already tried that.
Stop talking!
My unconscious mind hates you!
Is there any way
to show a different life in this place?
Wait. You're really not Bjorn Börgensson?
It's my life.
Um, excuse me, what's going on here?
Binaca breath spray?
Cheap cologne?
Man, who curated this exhibit?
You did.
♪ I go to Harlem, it's no problems
Oh, my goodness.
It's Cedric's rap group. No!
♪ Now everybody bow down
To the Kings of Queens ♪
No, don't look at that stuff.
Let's look over here.
Dad, I don't wanna go.
I don't like jazz.
Black improvisational music.
It's one of our great contributions
to American culture.
At least give it a chance, Joey.
This is where it all started.
This is the moment where
I fell in love with jazz.
Listen to that.
See, the tune is just an excuse
to bring out the you.
And that's why I became a jazz musician.
It's not what we're looking for.
Wait a minute, that's not how
I remember it going down.
Come back when you have something.
- Sorry, Joe.
We're looking
for something different.
Two, three, four.
My life was meaningless.
No, no, no.
No, I will not accept this.
Kid, give me that badge.
I'm goin' back to my body.
Oh, yeah, sure. Here.
Unless it becomes an Earth Pass,
I'm stuck with it.
Well, what if I help you
turn it into an Earth Pass?
Will you give it to me then?
Wait...
I've never thought of that.
I'd get to skip life.
So, yes!
But we gotta get
this thing to change first,
and I've never been able
to get it to change.
Come on.
I know all about sparks.
Because mine is piano.
- Really? Nothin' at all?
- Eh.
Oh, no, not jazz, just music.
I don't like music sounds.
It feels like a little too much.
Well, I'm not going out like this.
Where's that, uh, Hall of Everything?
I'll be right back.
Don't get ahead of yourself, pal.
By the way, why do you sound
like a middle-aged white lady?
I don't.
- This is all an illusion.
- Huh?
This whole place is a hypothetical.
I could sound
like this if I wanted to.
Or sound like this instead.
I could even sound like you.
Life is so unfair.
I don't wanna die.
Somebody call the wambulance. Wah!
I just use this voice
because it annoys people.
It's very effective.
Don't worry, they're fine.
You can't crush a soul here.
That's what life on Earth is for.
Very witty.
Okay. Here we are.
This is the Hall of Everything.
Whoa!
Yes!
- Whoa.
- Congratulations!
So, where do you want to start?
Come on.
Croissants, cakes.
Baking could be your spark.
Yeah! But, um, I don't get it.
- Just smell it.
- Can't, and neither can you.
What?
You're right. I can't smell.
We can't...
We can't taste, either?
All that stuff is in your body.
- No smell, no taste.
- Or touch. See?
Okay, I get it. Moving on.
Isn't this exciting?
The fire is so pretty.
I kinda wanna let it spread.
Nope.
Hands are hard.
How about a librarian?
They're cool.
Yes, amazing.
Who wouldn't like working
at a thankless job
you're always in danger of
losing due to budget cuts?
Though I do like the idea
of randomly shushing people.
- Look, obviously this...
- Shh!
Oh, yeah, that's good.
Meh.
Well, I think that's everything.
- Sorry.
- You told me you'd try.
I did. I'm telling the truth.
If there's one thing I'm not, it's a liar.
Unlike Abraham Lincoln.
You're really okay being on a penny?
Well, of course. It's an honour.
Okay, but they put
Andrew Jackson on the 20.
Jackson!
What can I say, Joe?
Earth is boring.
Well, what else can we do, then?
Because we're running out of time.
Yeah, you know,
time's not really a thing here.
Time's up!
Nice try, Bjorn, but no need to feel bad.
22 here can be a bit of a challenge.
Even though I can't feel it,
please don't touch me.
So, let's get you to the Great Beyond.
Um, wait.
We forgot to try breakdancer.
Yeah! I think that's gonna be my thing.
Poppin' and lockin'. Windmills.
Settling my disputes with dance.
Can we have one more minute
to go back and try breakdancer?
Please, Jerry?
You look really good today, Jerry.
Oh, okay.
I've never seen 22 this enthused.
Good for you, Dr Börgensson.
Run.
In here.
Here it is.
Where does it lead?
Hey, you ask too many questions.
How about you zip it for a minute, m'kay?
- And we're going there why?
- 'Cause I know a guy there.
A guy who can help.
A guy like you.
Like me? As in, alive?
Wait, are you actually helping me?
Joe, I have been here
for who knows how long,
and I've never seen anything
that's made me want to live.
And then, you come along.
Your life is sad and pathetic.
And you're working so hard
to get back to it.
Why? I mean, this I gotta see.
Okay, let's go.
What is this place?
You know how when you humans
are really into something
and it feels like you're in another place?
Feels like you're in the zone, right?
- Yeah.
- Well, this is the zone.
It's the space between
the physical and spiritual.
Wait a minute. I was here.
Today, doing my audition.
This must be where musicians come
when they get into a flow.
Not just musicians. Watch this.
O, Romeo, Romeo, wherefore art thou...
Line!
Oops.
Check this out.
I have been messing
with this team for decades.
And the Knicks
lose another one.
All right. All right.
Where's this guy you know?
I gotta get back to my gig.
- Okay. I mean, he's usually down here.
- What the...
Make a trade.
Make a trade. Make a trade.
- What is that?
- Shh!
Make a trade. Make a trade.
Run!
Make a trade,
make a trade, make a trade!
Oh! Ahoy there, fellow astral travellers.
Good to see you again, 22.
Moonwind, how are ya?
On the brink of madness,
thanks for asking.
Hey, got a request for you.
Uh, yeah.
I'm trying to get back to my body.
Can you help me?
That's what we do.
We are the mystics without borders.
Devoted to helping
the lost souls of Earth find their way.
I'm Moonwind Stardancer at your service.
That's Windstar Dreamermoon,
Dancerstar Windmoon,
and that's Dreamerwind Dreamerdreamer.
These weirdos are going
to help me get back?
Just wait.
Let's get this lost soul back home.
Make a trade.
Make a trade. Make a trade.
Poor fellow.
Some people just can't let go
of their own anxieties and obsessions,
leaving them lost
and disconnected from life.
And this is the result.
Make a trade. Make a trade.
Make a trade?
Looks like another hedge fund manager.
Now, to reconnect to your earthly body.
Whoa. That's me.
Thank you.
What am I doing with my life?
I'm alive! I'm alive! Free yourselves!
It's beautiful!
Whoa. He got back just like that?
So this is all I had to do
to get back to my body?
Egads, man!
Joe, are you dead?
No, no. Well, not yet.
Can you help me get back?
We've never connected an untethered soul
back to its body before.
But perhaps if we travel to a thin spot...
Yes! All aboard!
Anchors away!
So if your souls are here,
where are your bodies?
Well, on Earth, of course.
My body is in a trance in Palawan.
I'm playing the Saraswati veena in Tibet.
I'm a shamanic healer
meditating in Berkeley, California.
Mm-hmm. And let me guess,
you're drumming, chanting, and meditating?
Yes. Something like that.
I'm in New York City,
on the corner of 14th and 7th.
Oh, yeah, that's right up
from Tony Tony Tonios.
Yes, precisely.
And what about you?
I thought you hated Earth.
Yeah, I'm not stuck with a body.
So I can go wherever I want.
I'm a nobody, get it?
We mystics meet in this glorious landscape
every Tuesday.
So many of them. Sad.
You know,
lost souls are not that different
from those in the zone.
- What?
- The zone is enjoyable,
but when that joy becomes an obsession,
one becomes disconnected from life.
Gotta find it.
Gotta find it. Gotta find it.
For a time, I was a lost soul myself.
- Really?
- Tetris.
There you are.
We'll have you back in no time.
Now, since you don't have
a connection to your body,
you will have to tune back
into your physical surroundings.
Close your eyes.
Breathe into your crown chakra.
Do we really need all this?
Yes!
Do you have a piano on board?
I could focus with that.
No pianos, Joe. You must focus.
Imagine silence.
Shh.
Now, concentrate on where your body is.
Listen for cues.
That's it. You're doing it.
No peeking.
Maintain your meditative state
or you'll break the connection.
Now, see if you can smell
and feel where your body is.
I hear a heart monitor.
I can smell hand sanitiser.
Yes. Yes! Good.
I think I can feel my feet.
Hmm. I feel fur.
Did you find a next of kin?
I feel fur.
Did you hear that?
Oh, the therapy cat is working.
Am I close?
When can I jump in?
Look! There I am.
There I am.
His heart rate is increasing.
I'll get the doctor.
Mr Mittens, you stay right there.
- What are we waiting for?
- No, Joe, don't rush this.
- It's not the right time.
- No, it's my time.
Wait, not me!
I did it.
I did it! I'm back.
What the...
No.
No. No. No.
I'm in the cat?
Wait a minute.
If I'm in here, then who...
- What?
- You're in my body!
- You're in the cat?
- Wait, wait, that's my body.
- I'm in a body! No!
- Why are you in my body?
I don't wanna be a cat.
I hate cats!
Oh, it's disgusting.
That Moonwind guy, he messed this up.
Doc, you gotta help me.
That's my body, but I'm trapped...
Oh, no, they can't understand me.
They think you're me.
You gotta try.
Miss Doctor, we have a problem.
I'm an unborn soul
and I wanna stay at the You Seminar.
Yes, well, that drug doesn't
seem to be working at all.
No, no, no, you don't understand.
- I'm not Mr Gardner.
- Shh!
They're gonna think you're nuts.
I mean, that I'm nuts.
Oh, how did this happen?
I fell into your body because
it doesn't have a soul.
Then why am I in a cat?
I don't know!
Is there anyone we can call, Mr Gardner?
A next of kin or friend?
- Tell her no.
- Uh, no.
Can you tell me what day it is?
It's the worst day of my life.
I don't wanna be here. I hate Earth.
Tell you what.
We're going to keep you here
for observation. Just for a bit.
Perhaps our therapy cat can go
to his next appointment.
Okay. Okay.
- You gotta talk to her.
- Okay.
Miss Doctor,
this body's soul is in this cat.
Stop talking.
So naturally, he wants to stay close.
Uh, keep the cat.
Just get some rest.
A lot of it. Okay?
I'll come get Mr Mittens in ten minutes.
Ten minutes?
We gotta get outta here.
No way! I am not moving!
I can't believe I'm in a body
on this hellish planet.
I have bendy meat sticks.
I can feel myself feeling myself.
Hey! Focus! Listen to me.
We gotta get out of here
before they take me away.
Take you away?
You're gonna leave me?
No way! That's my body you're in.
Okay, do you think you can walk?
I don't know!
I failed Body Test Drive, like, 436 times.
But will you try?
Okay. Gotta find Moonwind,
he can fix this.
I'm a cat. I can make this.
Okay, come on, you're doing great.
Keep going. Keep going.
I'm just gonna rest here for a minute.
No, no, no, no.
They'll be back any minute. Come on.
Okay!
In here!
Whoa.
Okay, good.
Now push the down button.
Move your... Nope. Careful.
Those fingers are my livelihood.
Ugh.
Now get in.
Phew!
Hmm.
Okay, what did Moonwind say?
He said on the corner of 14th and 7th.
Yeah, that's Chelsea.
Near Jackson Square Park.
Exactly. Wait.
How do you know all that?
It's all in this stupid brain of yours.
Hey, hey, hey, stay outta there.
Oh, relax. There's not much here.
Jazz, jazz, more jazz.
Oh, and someone named Lisa.
Who's that?
Uh, never mind.
I, um...
It's all happening too fast, you know.
Let's just take a minute and, um...
Come on, let's go.
They could be here any second.
Don't worry, it's okay.
Just keep walking.
Aah!
No, don't stop.
What are you doing?
This is New York City.
You don't stop in the middle
of the street. Go, go, go.
Oh, no. 22. 22!
22. Oh, no.
Oh, no. 22. 22.
22! 22!
22, I didn't know I had claws, okay?
Look, I'm sorry.
But come on, let's go.
No way.
I am staying right here
until your stupid body dies.
Which will happen any minute now
because your stomach is earthquaking.
Yeah, this place is worse than I thought.
It's loud, and bright, and...
Hmm.
What is that in my nose?
That's smell.
And if you think that's good,
just imagine what it tastes like.
Hmm.
Go on.
It's so good!
It's, uh...
It's not horrible.
Good. You can eat on the way.
Let's go.
Or you just take a few minutes. Sure.
Hmm. Strange,
I don't feel so angry anymore.
That's great.
Ready to find Moonwind?
Maybe.
I'm telling you, Joe,
it's pronounced yee-row.
Yeah, but in New York,
we call them gyros. It's Greek.
No, I got in a fight
with Archimedes about this.
He said it's...
- Yee-row.
- Yo-yo.
- YOLO.
- Yee-row.
- Sergio?
Yee-row!
I miss that guy.
This is 14th and 7th.
That's gotta be him.
Moonwind, you gotta help me.
Joe! You made it into your body.
No, he didn't.
That is my body.
You're in a cat?
That's marvellous!
Hey, Moonwimp!
That sign won't spin by itself, hear me?
But, Marge, look!
I put this man's soul in a cat.
Who cares? And you!
We only have room for
one weirdo here, so, scram!
Get back to work!
No one understands my art.
Moonwind, listen,
I gotta get out of here and back in there.
Well, we'll have to perform
an old-fashioned astral
transmigration displacement.
- A what?
- It's simply a way
to get your souls back where they belong.
And it's a glorious ritual, indeed,
full of chanting, dancing,
and best of all, bongos.
I need to be at The Half Note by 7:00,
so this needs to happen right now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Not so fast.
You must wait for another thin spot
to open between Earth
and the astral plane.
And that won't occur
until Orcus moves
into the house of Gemini.
When is that?
Well, the government calls it 6:30.
Look, I'll meet you at The Half Note.
6:30? You serious?
I'll gather all
the necessary provisions...
I said, get out of here! Go!
See you
at The Half Note at 6:30!
I'll take care of everything!
And stay away!
Sure are a lot of Garcias in here.
You're out there somewhere, little soul,
and I'm gonna find ya.
All right, this is the last snack.
I can barely fit into my pants as it is.
6:30 is cutting it close. Too close.
We gotta get back to my place
and get you cleaned up and...
Ahh!
We gotta hail a cab.
Hold your hand out.
Hold it up and out.
Man, this would be hard
even if I wasn't wearing a hospital gown.
Go, go, go!
Just run to that one.
Is that Teach?
Mm, pepperoni.
Aah, Dorothea Williams saw me.
What am I gonna do?
She's gonna think I'm crazy.
Maybe you should call her up
and tell her that we're not crazy.
I've only been a person for an hour,
and even I know that's a bad idea.
I just gotta get back in my body
and really bring it tonight.
How come this part is stinky
but this part smells fine?
Never mind.
Just put those pants on.
Sheesh, I can't believe I've been
walking around in this city
with no pants on.
I don't even wanna be here, remember?
I don't want you here either. I just...
I just wanna get back to my body,
then get back to the club.
What's the matter with you?
Uh... I don't know.
It's the sun. It's just so...
My phone!
Um... Okay, your clothes
are rumbling again.
Curley! Uh... No, no.
Oops.
Hey, Mr G, it's Curley.
Um...
I hope you're doin' okay.
Dorothea freaked out when she saw you,
and she called this other guy, Robert.
He's got the gig now. I'm sorry.
No, no, no.
Look, honestly,
your class was the only reason
I went to school at all.
Like, I owe you a lot.
So, here's the plan.
Clean yourself up, put on a killer suit,
and get to the club early.
I'm gonna try and talk to her.
Just make sure you show up
looking like a million bucks, all right?
I hope I see you, man.
All right. Peace.
Oh! I can get the gig back, 22.
I need your help. I have a suit.
I'm gonna need you to try it on.
No, no, no.
And then I can line
my hair up a little bit,
- and I can...
- Nope. No way, no how.
22!
- Mr Gardner?
- Ah!
It's Connie.
She's here for her lesson.
- What do I do?
- I can hear you!
Just tell her that you can't do it today.
Hi, Connie.
Sorry, but Joe can't do it today.
- You're Joe!
- I mean, me.
Me can't do it today.
Good. Now let's go
check out that suit.
I came to tell you that I quit.
Quit?
We don't have time for this.
The suit is in the closet.
Band is a stupid waste of time.
This kid is talking sense.
What are you doing?
Here, I quit.
I think jazz is pointless.
Oh, yeah, jazz is definitely pointless.
Hey!
In fact, all of school is a waste of time.
Of course. Like my mentor,
George Orwell, used to say,
"State sponsored education
"is like the rattling of a stick
inside a swill bucket."
Yeah!
The ruling class's core
curriculum stifles dissent.
It's the oldest trick in the book.
What are you talkin' about?
She doesn't care about any of that.
I've been saying that
since the third grade.
You know, you seem really smart.
What is your position on pizza?
- Uh, I like it?
- Me, too!
What are you doing?
I'd rather hang with Connie.
What? Come back here!
You open this...
Um, I think your cat wants to get out.
Ugh, he thinks he knows everything.
22! Don't you walk away from me.
Come here right now.
I'm gonna go in
and I'mma scratch up the sofa.
Oh, wait a minute, that's my sofa.
You really got things figured out, Connie.
I'd better give this back.
It belongs to the school.
Sure.
You know, I really am glad
there's someone else
who sees how ridiculous this place is.
You're right to quit.
I learned about quitting...
You know what, Mr G?
I was practising this one thing yesterday
and maybe you can listen to it
and tell me to quit after, okay?
Uh, okay.
Wow. You really love this.
Yeah.
So, maybe I'd better stick with it?
Bye, Mr G.
See you next week!
22!
So, Connie came here to quit,
but then she didn't.
22, forget about that. Listen.
I need to know this, Joe.
Why didn't she quit?
Because she loves to play.
She might say she hates everything,
but trombone is her thing.
She's good at it.
Maybe trombone is her spark, I don't know.
Please. If I'm gonna get this gig back,
I need your help.
Okay.
Really?
I'll help you,
but I wanna try a few things.
'Cause I don't know,
some of it's not as boring
as it is at the You Seminar,
and if Connie can find
something she loves here,
maybe I can, too.
- Great!
- So, what do we do first?
- This water hurts!
- It's okay.
You just have to turn the other knob.
Oh, okay, that's better.
And I wouldn't be mad
if you put a little lotion
on me when you're done.
I washed your butt for you.
Ah! Spicy! Spicy!
You five will be insecure.
And you 12 will be self-absorbed.
We really should stop sending
so many through that pavilion.
Found him!
See that, everybody?
Who figured out why the count's off?
That's right, Terry did.
It's Terrytime.
- Wow. Nice work.
- Well, who is it?
Right.
Uh... Joe Gardner is his name.
Looks like he's back down on Earth.
That's not good.
That... That's the mentor
we set up with 22.
All right, all right.
Easy on the hysterics.
Terry's got this under control.
I'll handle it.
How?
I'll go down there and get him.
Set the count right, lickety-split.
Okay, whoa.
Are you sure that's a good idea?
Look, you all are the ones who beefed it.
I'm trying to un-beef it.
But you cannot be seen.
By anyone.
Don't worry. I'll make sure
no one else sees me.
I'll move among the shadows, like a ninja.
Please, just do it quickly and quietly.
And also quickly.
And quietly as well.
This won't be a disaster, that's for sure.
Mm. Trusty old brown suit.
Still a perfect fit.
It's a little tight in the back-here part.
It'll loosen. Sit down.
I'm a cat.
I'll do it.
You couldn't call an elevator, remember?
No way. I just need to line me up.
Now be still.
Uh, it's like a little tiny chainsaw.
- Don't move.
- I'm not moving. You're moving.
Oh, no!
Don't worry, I'm okay.
Oh, no, no, no! My hair!
My hair is not okay!
This is a disaster!
We gotta fix this. Right now.
- Okay. How?
- We gotta go see Dez.
Great. Who's Dez?
Yo, Ian, man, how you get
that big peanut head?
What happened to you?
Man, shut up, man.
You know I'm sensitive about that.
Dez is the guy in the back.
He can fix this.
Talk about havin' a spark.
This guy was born to be a barber.
But I can't pass for you
in front of all your friends.
Dez is the only one that I talk to.
We usually talk about jazz,
but this time, just sit there,
get the cut, and get out.
Hey, Joe. What are you
doing here on a weekday?
You didn't call for an appointment, man.
It's gonna be a while.
Ah, I was afraid of this.
Go ahead and sit down.
Oh, my Lord.
You gotta wait, son.
This is an emergency.
What? That ain't cool, Dez.
You could always let Harold cut your hair.
His chair's wide open.
Nah. I can wait.
Joe, get your butt in this chair now.
Should I even ask you how this happened?
- The cat did it.
- Stop sounding insane.
I mean, um, I was distracted
getting ready to play with
Dorothea Williams tonight.
Dorothea Williams?
That's big time, Joe.
Congratulations!
Joe ain't getting no gig, Dez.
You know he Mr Close-But-No-Cigar.
This guy.
Joe, ignore him.
Now let's fix you up.
You keeping that cat on your lap?
Is it okay that I do that?
Suit yourself. You're the boss.
- I am?
- When you're in this chair,
yeah, you are.
So can I have one of those?
Uh... Sure, Joe.
Cool.
Mmm. I like being in the chair.
Hey, get your head in the game.
Little chainsaw.
You need to settle down.
If you keep this...
Look, I can deal with some freaky stuff,
but if this cat don't chill,
we're gonna have to put it outside.
Well, what's it gonna be, kitty?
Meow.
Sometimes, change is good.
You have been rocking
that same style for a while.
Well, Dez, for hundreds of years,
I've had no style at all.
You can say that again.
Mmm. But then my life changed.
Oh, yeah? What happened?
I was existing as a theoretical construct
in a hypothetical way station
between life and death.
I heard that.
And by the time
I got to mentor number 266,
I was seriously asking, like,
what is all the fuss about?
Like, is all this living
really worth dying for?
You know what I mean?
I never knew you had
such an interesting education, Joe.
I just thought you went to music school.
And another thing,
they say you're born to do something,
but how do you figure out
what that thing is?
I mean, what if you pick up
the wrong thing?
Or somebody else's thing, you know?
- Then you're stuck.
- Been there before.
I'll take one of those.
I wouldn't call myself stuck,
but I never planned on
cuttin' heads for a livin'.
Wait, but you were born to be a barber,
weren't you?
I wanted to be a veterinarian.
So, why didn't you do that?
I was plannin' to
when I got out of the Navy.
Then my daughter got sick,
and barber school
is a lot cheaper
than veterinarian school.
Well, that's too bad.
You're stuck as a barber
and now you're unhappy.
Whoa, whoa, slow your roll there, Joe.
I'm happy as a clam, my man.
Not everyone can be Charles Drew
inventing blood transfusions.
Or me, playing piano
with Dorothea Williams.
I know.
You are not all that.
Anyone could play in a band
if they wanted to.
Don't pay Paul any mind.
People like him just bring
other people down
so they can make themselves feel better.
Oh, I get it.
He's just criticising me to cover up
the pain of his own failed dreams.
You cut deep, Joe.
I wonder why sitting in this chair
makes me want to tell you things, Dez.
That's the magic of the chair.
That's why I love this job.
I get to meet interesting folks like you,
make them happy, and make them handsome.
Wow! Am I crazy or do I look younger?
I may not have invented
blood transfusions,
but I am most definitely savin' lives.
I don't know about
this crazy cat guy thing, man,
but it is nice to finally talk to you
about something other than jazz, Joe.
Huh. How come we, um, never
talked about your life before?
You never asked.
But I'm glad you did this time.
- Looking good, brother.
- Have a great show.
I grabbed
a couple of road lollies.
Dr Charma, call 3-1-6-2.
Mm.
Mm-hmm.
Oh.
Julia Child didn't succeed
till she was 49.
Hey, Paul. Here, have a lollipop.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
Thanks, man.
There you are.
No hard feelings, right? All right.
Just friends.
Just friends goofing on each other.
All right.
Okay. Goodbye, Paul.
Come to Terry.
Gotcha!
Thought you could cheat the universe?
Well, you thought wrong.
I'm the accountant,
and I'm here to bring you in...
Oh, whoa...
You're not Joe Gardner.
My mistake.
We'll just get you back into
your meat suit.
There you go.
No harm, no foul.
Oh, boy. Look, uh, fella,
I'm thinking there's no reason
we can't keep this little
incident between us, eh?
Mistakes happen.
And, uh, it's not your time.
Unless you keep eating
those processed foods,
am I right?
But seriously, stay away
from those processed foods.
You know what,
you did all right back there.
How did you know how to deal with Paul?
I didn't. I just let out the me.
Hey, like you said about jazz.
I was jazzing.
First of all,
"jazzing" is not a word.
And second, music and life
operate by very different rules.
It says take one.
Don't... Or do. Okay. Fine.
"Man with a van."
I got a few in case we need a lot of vans.
Uh-huh. Now, let's get back to the plan.
We go to The Half Note
and wait there for Moonwind.
It's around 4:00 p.m. now...
You know what?
You are really getting good
at using those legs.
Why don't you try runnin'?
Hey! I made a song.
I'm jazzing.
Okay, enough of the jazzing
and everything like that.
We need to get somewhere.
Now, I...
- That tickles.
- Uh, what are you doing?
Whoops. I got it.
Would you hurry up?
Okay.
You were right.
These pants are loosening.
Oh, no, no, no.
Don't let people see your butt!
- It's your butt.
- It doesn't matter whose butt...
Take off the jacket.
Tie it around your waist.
Quick! Cover the butt!
What are we gonna do?
I can't find a tailor this late...
Oh, no. We're gonna have to go to Mom's.
Okay.
No, no, no, you don't understand.
Mom doesn't know about this gig.
And she's not gonna like it.
Okay.
We don't have any other choice.
She's the only one that can fix this.
- Okay.
- Stop saying "okay"!
We gotta catch the subway across town.
Come on.
Okay... Got it.
My mom doesn't know
anything about the gig,
and I wanna keep it that way, okay?
Right, because she thinks
you're a failure.
- What?
- I didn't say that.
You did. Up here.
Uh, look, my mom has her own
definition of what success is,
and being a professional musician
isn't it.
So, let me see, I need the suit fixed
for a, uh, school band recital.
I'm not looking forward to this,
but there's no reason she needs to know...
♪ We shall come around
To touch eyes again
♪ If love is the foundation
♪ If the purpose be
To recycle life
♪ I promise you
I'll bring us to one
♪ Bleeding heart in the end now
♪ Though we're apart
I don't know.
All the times I've been
so close to getting to my dreams,
something always gets in the way.
You know what I mean?
♪ How true lovin' began
He's good.
And I've heard music before,
but I've never felt like this inside.
Of course, you love music now,
because you're me. Let's go.
♪ Now, love
Let's go.
♪ Love
♪ Love, love
♪ Talkin' about love
♪ Love
♪ Love ♪
Whoa!
Hey, take it easy, eh?
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
It's the subway.
It does that to some people.
- Does what?
- It wears you down.
It stinks. It's hot. It's crowded.
Every day the same thing,
day in and day out.
But once I get on the stage tonight,
all my troubles are going to be fixed.
You're gonna see a brand-new Joe Gardner.
Where'd you get that?
Under the seat.
Can you believe it?
It's still half-full.
All right, remember,
I need the suit fixed for a band recital.
Got it?
- Joey! Oh, baby boy...
- Joey!
- Oh, I'm so proud of you.
- ...we heard the news.
Oh, crap. She knows.
Your momma's in the back.
- You gotta go in there.
- No, I don't want to.
You have to.
We need the suit fixed.
You forgetting something, Joey?
- What?
- Kiss her.
I always kiss Melba when I see her.
Just do it.
No, no, no. Not on the lips.
Joey!
What has gotten into you, boy?
Let him finish.
Cougar. I knew it.
I'll take another kiss
when you get back, Joey.
So much for being done
chasing after gigs, huh?
I hope that cat isn't supposed to be
some kind of peace offering.
Come. Come on.
Just say you rescued it.
Um, no. It's mine. I rescued it.
Hmm. Too bad you can't rescue your career.
Oh.
Just ask her nicely
if she can fix my suit.
So, Mom, is there any way
you can fix this?
Whoa! I don't need to see that.
I know. Embarrassing, right?
So, you'll fix it?
- No.
- What?
How long are you going
to keep doing this, Joey?
You tell me you're going
to accept the full-time position...
Here it comes.
...and instead,
I hear you've taken another gig.
Tell her that this one is different.
This one's different!
Does this gig have a pension?
Health insurance?
No? Then it's the same as the other ones.
It's like you can't even
be truthful with me anymore.
Fine, we'll get the suit
off the rack somewhere.
My mom has never understood
what I'm trying to do with my life.
Fine, we'll get the suit
off the rack somewhere.
My mom has never understood
what I'm trying to do with my life.
- 22!
- What did you just say?
Oof. Can I run away now,
like you usually do?
No. Not this time.
Repeat after me.
Mom, I know we've had some rough times,
but you're right,
I can't be truthful with you.
Because it seems like
no matter what I do, you disapprove.
Look, I know you love playing.
Then how come except for church,
you're the happiest when I don't?
I finally land the gig of my life
and you're upset.
You didn't see how tough
being a musician was on your father.
I don't want to see
you struggle like that.
So Dad could pursue his dreams,
and I can't?
Your father had me.
Most times,
this shop is what paid the bills.
So when I'm gone, who's gonna pay yours?
Music is all I think about.
From the moment I wake up in the morning
to the moment I fall asleep at night.
You can't eat dreams for breakfast, Joey.
Then I don't want to eat.
This isn't about my career, Mom.
It's my reason for living.
And I know Dad felt the same way.
I'm just afraid
that if I died today,
that my life would've amounted to nothing.
Joey.
Oh.
Let's make this work instead.
That's my dad's suit.
Lulu. Melba.
Bring your good scissors in here.
We got work to do.
Wow. This feels really nice.
- You look marvellous.
- It fits perfectly.
You see how I did that?
That is one fine wool suit,
if I do say so myself.
- Can I try on that?
- Of course you can.
Just handsome.
Thank you, uh, Mom.
Ray would have been so proud of you, baby.
Like I've always been.
You heard me, right?
The suit is wool, not polyester.
So, don't go putting that cat
on your shoulders again.
Yes, ma'am!
Oh,
there's a nice little taper there.
Thanks, Mom.
Oh, that was amazin'.
You know what that felt like?
It felt like jazz.
Yeah, you were jazzing.
Ha-ha. Okay, jazzing.
I'm telling you, Joe.
You really should call Lisa again.
I don't really have time
for a relationship right now, 22.
Oh, busy right now?
Wanna wait till you die a second time?
Cool, cool, cool.
I can't believe
I'm getting romantic advice
from an unborn soul.
I can think of worse.
There it is.
We made it!
This is going to work.
Whoa! I can't believe how good I look.
The suit, the cut.
Just look at me.
- Ooh, just turn a little bit right there.
- Like this?
- Angle the shoulders, and...
- Oh, hey, who's that?
- And from this side.
- That's it.
What? Who's back here?
- Still me. Uh-huh.
- That's a winner.
Right?
This can't be happenin'.
Now, I'm not gonna believe this.
The Half Note.
He made you pay for dinner?
Yeah...
- So, you ready?
- Huh?
To go home.
I bet you're ready to get off
of this stinky rock, huh?
What do you think of Earth, anyway?
I always said it was dumb. But...
I mean...
Just look at what I found.
Your mom sewed your suit
from this cute spool.
When I was nervous, Dez gave me this.
A guy on the subway yelled at me.
It was scary.
But I kind of liked that, too.
Truth is, I've always worried
that maybe there's something
wrong with me. You know?
Maybe I'm not good enough for living.
But then you showed me
about purpose and passion,
and maybe sky-watching can be my spark.
Or walking.
I'm really good at walking.
Those really aren't purposes, 22.
That's just regular old living.
But, hey, when you get back
to the You Seminar,
you can give it an honest try.
No, but I've been at the You Seminar
for thousands of years
and I have never felt this close.
Joe! Who's ready to go home?
Moonwind.
The stars are almost in alignment.
All right.
I'll have you back
in your bodies in no time.
No. I've gotta find it here, on Earth.
This is my only chance to find my spark.
22, you're only loving this stuff
because you're in my body.
You can find your own thing to love
when you get back to the You Seminar.
Now, come on,
I need my body back. Now!
No.
I'm in the chair.
- 22!
- Leave me alone!
I'm trying to find my purpose!
22, you come back here!
22!
Mr Mittens.
Oh.
TERRY: There they are.
You come back here right now!
You stole my body!
It's your time to go, Joe Gardner.
Oh, no, you don't.
Gotcha!
No, no, no.
No, no!
I was gonna play with Dorothea Williams!
And I was about to find my spark!
Find your spark?
My life was finally going to change!
You promised, but you wouldn't
even give me five minutes!
I lost everything because of you!
Joe!
You cheated.
Found him.
- Joe Gardner.
- You're back!
Terry, you found them.
No need to thank me.
It's so nice to have
everything back in order, and...
22 got her pass?
- Oh, my goodness.
- 22! You got an Earth Pass!
This is amazing!
I knew you could do it.
This is cray cray.
But what...
What filled in the last box?
I'll tell you what filled it in. I did!
It was my spark that changed that badge.
She only got that because
she was living my life in my body.
- I was...
- Come on, Mr Gardner.
Joe, it's time for you
to accompany 22 to the Earth portal.
Give you a chance to say goodbye.
Of course.
It's standard procedure.
Just hold on a minute.
I get to set the count right.
Terry, you have done a super job.
We'll take it from here.
You're amazing.
Well, thank you.
Terrytime.
Go ahead, you two.
You don't know.
You can't be sure why my pass changed.
Come on, 22.
Think about it.
You hated music until you were in my body.
You hated everything until you were me.
I hope you enjoy it.
Uh...
I have to ask,
how the Dickens did you do it?
Get that Earth Pass to change?
Oh. You know what, I...
I just let her walk
a mile in my shoes, you could say.
Well, it worked.
Yeah.
Well, you should probably
get going to the Great Beyond.
Hey, um, we never found out
what 22's purpose was.
- Excuse me?
- You know, her, uh, spark.
Her purpose. Was it music?
Biology? Walking?
We don't assign purposes.
Where did you get that idea?
Because I have piano.
It's what I was born to do.
That's my spark.
A spark isn't a soul's purpose.
Oh, you mentors and your passions.
Your purposes. Your meanings of life.
So basic.
No, no, it...
Wow.
It is music.
My spark is music. I...
I know it is.
I'm no good.
I got no purpose.
No purpose.
Mr G?
Curley, I made it.
I'm ready to go.
You're too late, man.
Let me talk to Dorothea.
No, no, no, man.
She don't play that.
These rappers act like...
Who let this lunatic in here?
Listen, you gotta give me another chance.
This is my band.
I decide who plays.
And if you don't go with me,
you'll be making the biggest
mistake of your career.
Oh, yeah? Why's that?
My only purpose on this planet is to play.
It's what I was meant to do.
And nothing's gonna stop me.
Well, aren't you an arrogant one?
I guess you really are a jazz player.
Tell Robert he's out. For now.
Nice suit.
Get ready, Joe Gardner,
your life is about to start.
Welcome to the quartet, Teach.
That's my Joey!
- What a show!
- That last solo was brilliant.
That was amazing!
I'm not gonna cover
that bridge for you again.
- Whoo! Later, Mr G.
- Congratulations.
You did great. We love you.
I'm so proud of you, Joey.
Gotta get to bed. We old.
You play 100 shows,
and one of them is killer.
You don't get many like tonight.
Yeah.
So, uh, what happens next?
We come back tomorrow night
and do it all again.
What's wrong, Teach?
It's just I've been waiting
on this day for my entire life.
I thought I'd feel different.
I heard this story about a fish.
He swims up to this older fish and says,
"I'm trying to find this thing
they call the ocean."
"The ocean?" Says the older fish.
"That's what you're in right now."
"This?" Says the young fish.
"This is water.
"What I want is the ocean."
See you tomorrow.
- Hey, man.
- Sorry.
Maybe sky-watching can be my spark.
Or walking.
I'm really good at walking.
Those really aren't purposes, 22.
That's just regular old living.
- Joe?
- Huh?
Joe!
Good heavens, man.
What are you doing in the zone?
Moonwind. I messed up.
I need to find 22.
I'm afraid she's become a lost soul.
- What?
- I'll explain on the way.
When neither of you returned
to The Half Note,
I suspected something had gone wrong.
I came back here,
and that's when I spotted her.
Lost souls are obsessed by something
that disconnects them from life.
And now that 22 has technically lived,
she's become one of them.
- There!
- Good show.
22!
- Ready the net.
- I'm on it.
She's got us!
Moonwind!
A captain always
goes down with the ship.
It has been a...
22!
Come back, 22. It's me, Joe.
Easy, 22, easy.
I just came back to give you this.
Easy.
22, listen. Come back!
And for correcting
our absent-minded mistakes
and setting the count right,
we are awarding you, Terry, this trophy.
As you requested.
I am happy to accept this
very special award I requested,
but that I absolutely deserve.
Joe Gardner?
And I'll just take that back.
Hey.
Oi, noob!
You're not where you belong.
Uh...
22, stop.
I have something to tell you.
Stop that. No.
22!
Whoa, watch out!
Take it easy.
- There, there.
- There's no need to be afraid.
Don't worry. Calm down.
You have to stop running. Please.
22, stop.
22, I was wrong.
Please, will you listen?
You are ready to live, 22.
I'm not good enough. Nope. No.
Nothing. I just need to
fill out that last box.
22!
You're dishonest.
All you make are bad decisions.
You are unwise and you won't
make it in the world.
You're so selfish.
No one would ever want to be around you.
Loser.
Oh, the world needs remarkable people
and you are the least
remarkable soul I've ever met.
You'll never find your spark.
Imbecile.
I cannot help you.
22!
I just need to fill out that last box.
I'm not good enough at all.
You will never find your spark.
There's no point.
Those aren't purposes,
you idiot.
That's just regular old living.
This is a waste of time.
You only got that badge
because you were in my body.
That's why you ruin everything.
Because you have no purpose.
No, no, no.
There's no point.
You'll never find your spark.
Because you have no purpose!
I'm not good. Nope.
Nothing. I just need to fill
out that last box. I give up.
You ready?
Huh?
To come live.
I'm scared, Joe.
I'm not good enough.
Anyway, I never got my spark.
Yes, you did.
Your spark isn't your purpose.
That last box fills in
when you're ready to come live.
And, the thing is
you're pretty great at jazzing.
But, Joe,
this means you won't get to...
It's okay. I already did.
Now it's your turn.
I'll go with you.
You know you can't do that.
I know.
But I'll go as far as I can.
Hey! Take a look!
Wow!
Mr Gardner?
Yes?
Do you have a moment?
I think I'm speaking for all the Jerrys
when I say thank you.
For what?
We're in the business of inspiration, Joe,
but it's not often
we find ourselves inspired.
Huh. Really?
So, we all decided to give you
another chance.
Hopefully, you will watch
where you walk from now on.
But what about Terry?
We worked it out with Terry.
Mm. That's weird.
Hey, Terry, what's that over there?
Look immediately.
What? What are you talking about?
- Oh, nothing. You were saying?
- Hmm?
Were you even talking?
I can't remember.
Never mind.
Well?
Thanks.
So what do you think you'll do?
How are you gonna spend your life?
I'm not sure.
But I do know...
I'm going to live every minute of it.
♪ Rappin Ced is the name
♪ And you should get it right
♪ Blowin' up on the scene like Dynomite
♪ Joey G on the keys
KP and Tommy with me
♪ How much you wanna bet?
♪ We can take the whole city
♪ You see us stylin' from the island
♪ All the way to BK
♪ Boogie down made the sound
But we took it away
♪ I go to Harlem it's no problems
If you know what I mean
♪ Now everybody bow down to
The Kings of Queens ♪
Hey! Movie's over.
Go home!