"The civil war built a wall of hate
between the North and South."
"And on each side great
armies fought and died."
"But south of St. Louis,
across the Mississippi."
"Was a no-man's land."
"Where guerrilla raiders led
by men like Luke Cottrell."
"Left a wake of ruin burning and
plundering ranches and homes."
"Riding across the great flat plain."
"With gun and torch they
pillaged the countryside."
"In the name of the Union Army."
"And against the Texas sky rose
the slow dust of wagon trains."
"Settlers driven from the
land by the fury of war."
Looks like we lost more than our cows.
Nobody but a Yankee would
do a thing like this.
Somebody around here don't like us.
Kip.
They must have been watching.
They saw you and the men
ride off after the herd.
They came to all the ranches that night.
They dragged off all they could carry.
Stole the horses. Burned the houses.
Who did it?
- Cottrell.
Luke Cottrell and his guerrillas.
Bronco. I want you to take
good care of Deborah.
What are you going to do, Kip?
Your horse's alright?
- Sure. They'll pull to Hampton.
Where you going? I want to go with you.
- Deb needs you with her.
Where are you going, Kip?
Brownsville.
- That's Union headquarters now.
And Cottrell's.
Don't do it, Kip.
Come to Edenton with us.
Leave our land and let them
burn us out and do nothing?
They've burned out all of us.
Finding Cottrell won't bring it back.
Lee, tell him you won't go with him.
Tell him not to do it.
The three of us been together
a long stretch, Deb.
Charlie?
I wouldn't mind getting a look
at Cottrell myself right now.
It isn't Cottrell I'm thinking of.
It's the three of you.
You came out here and made
something out of the land.
There were troubles then too
but they didn't turn you to hate.
Building Three Bell kept you together.
This can only end by
splitting you apart.
Don't you see? Don't go.
We're going to Brownsville, Deb.
What about me, Kip?
You asked me to marry you.
We made all kinds of plans.
What happens to them now?
Nothing's changed.
We'll all be coming back.
Maybe sooner than you think.
Kip is right.
Edenton is the place for you now.
I'm afraid we're going
to Brownsville, Deb.
We're pulling out.
You had better go now.
Hold it there.
What are you carrying?
- Contraband.
Cannonballs and used rifle bullets.
I grow them on my ranch when
nobody is looking at me.
I wouldn't throw that word 'contraband'
around so free in these parts.
I've seen men shot for
much less than that.
He's carrying hay.
Alright. Let him through, Cal.
Go ahead, Reb.
And next time save
your jokes for Jeff Davis.
We're Union to a man, sir.
Yankee doodle never fails
when he decides to try, sir.
We'll lick the pants off Johnny Reb,
so have another ride, sir.
We'll have another ride, sir.
Yankee doodle does as
well any other dancer.
And like the ladies, he is
brave and Union to a man, sir.
Yankee doodle never fails
when he decides to try, sir.
We'll lick the pants off Johnny Reb,
so have another ride, sir.
Hello Jake.
How are you, Kip?
Lee?
Hello Charlie.
- A full house today.
Yep.
I don't see Luke Cottrell.
Luke?
Cottrell? Oh.
He's been in today?
I don't think he was
in today but I can ask.
Jake.
Does he usually come by?
Who?
Cottrell.
He comes by.
Sure.
A man gets thirsty, don't he?
Kip.
Please don't start anything.
I don't want any trouble in the place.
Don't worry, Jake.
There ain't going to be any trouble.
Can I buy you a drink while we wait?
Some other time.
If it's just the same to you.
Rouge. Rouge, come here.
Sing Yankee doodle again. Sign anything.
But sing.
Boys.
Whiskey.
Our brave guerrilla allies.
Hello Cottrell.
You celebrate?
You ain't crazy enough to
start anything here, Davis.
I'm not starting anything.
You figure on making me draw first, huh?
Maybe.
Then the three of you
start pumping lead.
No. They're patient boys.
They will wait their turn.
If you get past me.
You got a name for being
pretty fast on the draw, Davis.
I'm still living.
But I've heard them
say Charlie is faster.
Yeah?
What about him?
He outdraws both of you?
I don't put bullets in my guns.
I just carry them for ballast.
If you boys are looking for a fight
you'll have to fight each other.
I ain't drawing.
Pick up your gun, Cottrell.
Listen, Cottrell.
Get out of Texas and don't come back.
You've earned yourself a drink, mister.
I'd like to buy you one.
I don't drink with Yankees.
Easy does it, Kip.
See, Jake? There wasn't any trouble.
Alright, you border rats.
Get in on the winning side.
If there's a man among you
he'll join up with the best ..
Fighting force west of the Mississippi.
Come on, step up.
Sign your name or make your mark.
And ride to victory with
the Seventh Cavalry.
Yeah. Join the army and steal cattle.
Say, you look strong
enough to carry a gun.
I already got one.
But it's got a funny habit of
shooting only one way. North.
A Johnny Reb, huh?
Or maybe you're too scared to fight.
Easy does it, Lee. Easy does it.
How much more of this
do you think I can take?
For months now we've
tried to raise a stake.
We ain't got the stake and I'm sick
of looking at Union soldiers.
Living with them. Easting with them.
And marching through my dreams.
Why not march something else through
your dreams? Something like blondes?
Come on, let's get a drink.
- I'm going to Edenton.
What for? There's nothing in
Edenton but more soldiers.
Yeah. But they're Confederate soldiers.
I am going to sign up.
You, a soldier-boy?
Stripes on your sleeve? Yes, sir.
No sir. Saluting every minute?
You sure that's what
you want to do, Lee?
Yeah. I'm sure.
I ain't got nothing against shooting.
Why change clothes to do it?
Maybe he's right.
Maybe all three of us ought to join up.
Wait a minute.
No. Not you two.
You wouldn't be in the army five minutes
before they'd hang the both of you.
Inciting to riot. Striking an officer.
Disobedience to orders.
Wearing the uniform improperly.
What about you?
Well, it's different with me. You know.
It means we got to break up.
We never broke up before.
We've never had a war like this before.
Alright, Lee.
You're the only one who
knows what you ought to do.
Well.
So long, Kip.
- Good riding, Lee.
So long, Charlie.
- So long, Lee.
What's Lee supposed to do now?
Turn in his bell?
Quit joking, Charlie.
He is my friend too.
We still need a stake.
Maybe I can win a herd
at Jake's card tables.
Hello cowboy.
How do, ma'am.
I've been wondering about you.
What does a cowboy do
when he runs out of cows?
I've wondered the same thing myself.
I got fifty dollars looking for a job.
What kind of a job?
Driving that wagon.
High pay for a muleskinner.
Where you aim on driving it? St Louis?
Just to Point Isabel.
Point Isabel?
That is confederate territory.
What is in your wagon?
- Furniture.
I brought some fine
things into this town.
It's getting a little rough
here so I'm moving out.
Every stick of it came
over from the East.
That chaise there. It came from France.
It's all mine.
You haven't been listening.
I've been wondering about you
ever since I drifted into town.
That's a healthy color
you got in your cheeks.
Rouge.
I thought for a minute it
was the Texas climate.
Even Texas needs a little help.
Just rouge.
Is that how you got your name?
No.
It's because I came from
Baton Rouge, Louisiana.
You wouldn't call a lady 'Baton'.
No.
I reckon not.
Well.
For fifty dollars I'm willing to
believe it's all mahogany.
Holy smoke. Look at that.
Our forces have occupied this area.
To stop the traffic in smuggled war
supplies from Mexico to the rebels.
And I intend to stop it.
Now I ask you once more.
Who hired you?
I've told you all I know, Colonel.
Unless you tell us who involved you in
this you may see yourself shot as a spy.
Alright, Billings.
Take him down to the stockade.
Get out.
What's the idea?
I get shot trying to escape?
Hello cowboy.
What's going on?
- Any objections?
I got objections to furniture
that shoots bullets.
You knew that mahogany was loaded.
Maybe I did.
What about those marshals?
- At heart, they're southerners.
For a hundred dollars of gold.
You still owe me fifty.
You never did deliver the chaise.
You still looking for a stake, cowboy?
You got some more furniture?
- Lots of it.
Some very interesting pieces.
Maybe even enough to furnish a ranch.
The chairs on our ranch weren't
much but the cows didn't mind.
What was it worth?
About fifteen thousand
when they burned us out.
You can make it back in a year.
Where?
Across the river with me.
You really don't have much of a choice.
Are we going?
Charlie.
Just in case a hundred
dollars wasn't enough.
Two bullets would be cheaper.
- Save your bullets.
You'll need them where you're going.
Come on. Climb in.
Sam.
Charlie.
Look at this town.
One more war and it'll
be another New Orleans.
There's enough stuff piled up here to
blow Brownsville into the panhandle.
You're looking at the supply depot
for the whole Confederate army.
Matamoras is the back door to the south.
Who owns all this?
Brugnon bought it. Papa Brugnon.
Buys it in Europe and sells it
here to anybody with the cash.
And nerve enough to run
it across the border.
There enough floaters in this town to
double every gun hand west of Pecos.
Go ahead, Kip.
You two go and talk to Papa and by the
time you come out we'll have an outfit.
Let's get started.
Rouge.
Baby. Ma petite.
Papa.
Sit down. Sit down.
You look hungry. When did you eat last?
Lobster?
Business first, Papa. Lobster later.
Business.
I've formed a new partnership, Papa.
Mr Davis.
Monsieur Henri Brugnon.
A foolish man.
Alas, Monsieur.
You come to me at the wrong time.
There isn't a sou of
merchandise in my warehouse.
Who's buying in such quantities?
I have new customers, Cherie.
Let them wait.
- I'm obligated, Cherie.
They sound more like
partners than customers.
Partners?
Never.
I have no partners.
Then you'll always have
something for friends, eh Papa?
Old friends.
Whatever you want, Cherie.
Whenever I have it.
Any more in the warehouse, Brugnon?
Monsieur Cottrell.
Is this your new cash customer?
Yeah.
Henri and me have been doing some
nice pieces of business together.
Ain't we, Henri?
It's been a pleasure, Monsieur Cottrell.
You don't care which
side you're on, do you.
I like it here.
There's no army around making rules
about how you're supposed to kill a man.
Bucky.
This ain't Texas, Davis.
Go on back to hustling cows
and keep out of my business.
I'm not asking for
your advice, Cottrell.
I told you before.
You can draw first any time, any place.
Why should I get mad at you, Davis?
I took your advice and
got out of Texas, didn't I?
You take my advice and
get out of Matamoras.
Keep hustling cows. It's a lot safer.
Go on, Henri.
Finish your lobster before it gets cold.
Hey, Kip.
Are those the men you lined up?
- Matamoras's best.
You. What is your name?
- Jim Morland.
Can you handle a gun?
- Sure.
Any objection to
shooting it if necessary?
What's a gun for?
Alright.
You?
- Ted Johnson.
Can you ride a horse?
- I was born on one.
And you?
[ Spanish language ]
A muleskinner, eh?
- Best.
Alright, Manuel.
Slim Hansen.
You a Texan?
- Yeah.
I'm a Texan.
Are you as good with
that knife as you look?
Good enough.
I've seen you around.
Maybe.
Weren't you riding with Cottrell?
For a while. I didn't like it much.
Get out.
He hired me. You didn't.
Who is running this outfit?
He said he quit Cottrell.
We can't be choosy, Kip.
I don't trust him.
I'd say he's alright. I picked him.
Well, pick another.
I want him in.
Alright.
You've got him.
That's a fine band of
cut-throats he picked out.
We got our outfit. What about your end?
My end?
- Yeah. Brugnon.
Can we take his word he'll deliver?
It will take a few months
but he'll deliver.
For me.
Can you get it through the lines?
We'll get it through.
You've a lot of confidence, haven't you.
I hope it carries you
600 miles to Edenton.
You know, the Yankee patrols don't ride
the river just to look at the scenery.
We ain't going to spend too much
time looking at scenery either.
Sam.
Is this where we cross the border?
- That's right.
See anything?
Nothing but lizards and tired rattlers.
This Texan sun is too
hot for Yankees anyhow.
They're all back in Jake's saloon.
Don't be too sure.
We ain't at Edenton yet.
Come on. Move 'em up.
I always knew there would be one good
reason for letting you go to Edenton.
Now I know what it was.
We aim to please, and nothing pleases
us more than tangling with Cottrell.
What's doing in Edenton, Lee?
Anything more interesting than
broken-down cowboys turned sergeant?
Everybody is there. The Jasons, Bronco.
Deb?
Yes. She's there too.
She's nursing at the hospital.
How is she?
She is fine, Kip.
Are you in charge of this wagon train?
- We are.
It's lucky for you we were on patrol.
Alright, Sergeant.
Let's get them to Edenton now.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. No, sir.
You salute real pretty, Lee.
You run guns real pretty too.
Sergeant, get unloaded.
- Very well, sir.
Alright men. Get on those wagons.
Start breaking it up.
Where is that hospital, Lee?
Go on down the road. You can't miss it.
Thanks.
I knowed it. I knowed it.
I seen them cowpunchers.
I sniffed that saddle leather.
Wait until Debbie hears.
- She won't hear, Bronco. She will see.
Go and trade brands with Charlie.
Wait a minute, Kip.
There's one thing we
got to settle right now.
I'm going with you on that next trip.
I know that border like
I know my own hand.
I can drive a team like nobody.
Alright, Bronco.
Go and tell Charlie you're hired.
Yes!
Deb.
Oh Lee. You're back.
I was so worried.
- Guess again. It ain't Lee this time.
Oh Kip. Kip, you did come.
You did come.
You didn't think I'd let a couple of
armies stand in the way, did you?
You should have let me know you were
coming. I'd have got you a room to stay.
I know. Jason's attic.
You don't mind climbing a few flights?
But I ain't staring, Deb.
You're not staying?
Me and Charlie brought a load of guns
and powder through the Union line.
We are pulling out tonight.
I didn't know.
I thought you came to Edenton because ..
Don't you think I missed you?
You don't think I wanted it this way?
Me down in Matamoras and you up here.
- Then stay here.
Stay here for what, Deb?
Hang my thumbs in my belt?
There is money in running guns.
Money to buy cattle and rebuild.
They burned us out but
we ain't staying burned.
The ranch isn't so important to Lee.
Lee is different to me.
No-one knows how long the war will last.
We cannot wait forever, Kip.
Not thinking, not feeling. Not living.
I'm no good to you, Deb.
To myself or anyone else until
I get back on that ranch again.
It wasn't the ranch I wanted to marry.
I'll see you before we pull out.
Yes.
That just about does it, Sergeant.
- Alright, Danny.
All unloaded?
Yeah. Nothing like doing
business with the army.
They'd buy the buttons off your shirt
if they came in packing boxes.
It figures. Split three ways.
Three ways?
Yeah.
You're not figuring me in on it?
It all goes back to Three Bell.
Last I heard that was a 3-way deal.
Still wearing that bell on your spurs.
Good enough for me.
And if he got shot crossing the river
you two would have to commit suicide?
Is that supposed to be funny?
Before we start dividing we'd
better get something to divide.
Sergeant.
Supplies all checked?
- Yes, sir.
The Confederate Army is grateful, sir.
- We'll run all you can take, Captain.
You keep the supplies coming and we'll
have enough soon to retake Brownsville.
Pay the men off, Sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
You heard what he said.
Pay the men off.
Come on, boys.
Let me show you where we keep it.
You can't accuse this outfit
of confiscating anything.
We pay in full.
There you are.
When did they start packing up
confederate money in bales?
That's good old Texas cotton.
Legal tender for government purchases.
All you do is haul it away.
No wonder you didn't
want to be a partner.
Why? Don't you like it?
What are we supposed to do with it?
Stuff it in our ears?
That Louisiana crush of yours. I had an
idea she didn't know what she was doing.
How would she like two of
these bales in her bustle?
Gentlemen.
The quartermaster told me I might find
someone about here with cotton for sale.
You mean you buy cotton for money?
- Yes, indeed.
My name is Cecil Middleton.
I represent the firm of Cartwright
& Bonesteel of Manchester, England.
We pay.
With British pounds.
Mister, you just bought
yourself some cotton.
That is wonderful.
Let's see the British pounds
or do you pay in tea leave?
No, no. Gold pounds.
Perhaps you don't quite understand.
I shall be glad to pay for the cotton.
When it is delivered.
In Matamoras, Mexico.
Hello cowboy.
How is the cotton business?
I ain't so sure yet.
I got wagons stretched down
the road for about a mile.
Now, what are we going to do with them?
Hello Charlie. Nice work.
Have any trouble getting through?
- Yeah. Coming back.
We sighted a Yankee patrol but made
it across the river before they did.
They were probably laughing
so hard they couldn't fight.
Why didn't you tell us they
pay off with this stuff?
What's the matter with cotton?
You can run it up into petticoats.
Or maybe you'd like a little
cotton doily for your horse?
Listen. All we've got is the promise of
some Britisher we may never see again.
Maybe.
Cecil, old chap. They're here.
- Good.
So gentlemen, you brought the cotton.
I have the British pounds.
And may I say your partner
drives a hard bargain.
Come on in. We'll settle the account.
So, she doesn't know
what she's doing, huh?
Good old Cecil.
What do you think he's going
to do with all that cotton?
For the price you got him to pay he
ought to cash it with his gold dust.
Did I do alright?
You did fine.
I am a good little girl.
Very good.
Very very good.
Up in Edenton they're talking
about retaking Brownsville.
[ Singing ]
Too much love.
Can make you unhappy.
Can leave you alone.
Too many times I've had it happen.
Love caught me napping.
Now I am alone.
Too much time is wasted in waiting.
For the one.
Who will call you his own.
That is why my heart.
Is yours for ever.
Complaining never.
I can't have too much ..
Love.
Do you know what?
You don't look any
different in champagne.
Not any better.
Not any worse.
Just Kip.
Come here. Come here and I'll show you.
I'll put some on the end of your nose.
- Hey.
Alright. No champagne.
I think you've had about enough too.
Alright. No more champagne for anybody.
You know what?
You love your ranch too much.
Do I?
You love everything too much.
Too hard.
You love your friends too much.
You get hurt that way.
Maybe.
Three Bell.
You loved it, didn't you?
It was a good place to be.
- You and Lee and ..
Charlie.
Me and Lee and Charlie.
We worked it together.
Think you'll ever work it again?
Together?
There won't always be a war.
Ranch.
Friends.
Is that all there was in your life, Kip?
Let's get out of here.
It's getting late.
No girl?
I got those wagons to unload tomorrow.
How pretty is she?
Very pretty?
Kip.
Kip, is she very pretty?
Come on, Rouge.
It will be a long day tomorrow.
It's a long day today.
Besides, I couldn't leave
this here all alone, could I?
Goodnight, Rouge.
- Goodnight, Kip.
Where I was born one frosty morn'.
Look away, look away, look away.
I wish I was in Dixie.
Away, away.
In Dixie Land, I'll take my
stand to live and die in Dixie.
Away, away.
Away down south in Dixie.
This is the greatest thing to happen
to Texas since Sam Houston.
Bartender. Set 'em up.
For these two.
Don't whistle too hard, Jake.
Your teeth will fall out.
Rouge.
It's a real pretty tune.
I knew you wouldn't forget it.
You know how I felt.
I was born in Missouri.
No state is perfect. You can't blame
Missouri for everybody born there.
Kip. Charlie.
Nice to see you boys again.
- We ain't boys anymore, Jake.
We are full-grown now.
What about him?
Hey, Kip. Charlie.
You son of a gun.
Gosh, it's good to see you.
You boys finally caught up
with the army, huh?
They made you an officer?
Lieutenant Price.
The conqueror of Brownsville.
Sure. I drew them a secret map to
the back door of Jake's saloon.
You look mighty fine
in that uniform, Lee.
If not for the gold braid
we've smuggled in.
He'd be wearing brass
buttons on his underwear.
Boys.
You know, I'm mighty proud of y'all.
Any time I have a roof over my
head and a dollar in my pocket.
Anything you want for, you just ask for.
Thanks, Jake. We appreciate that.
We'll start with your office.
We need a place to work out of.
Charlie, you're not going
to take my office?
Rouge. They're going to take my office.
What am I going to do?
Just get up there and whistle Dixie.
You're real good at it.
Let's get down to business.
Manuel, go down to Matamoras.
Tell Brugnon we'll buy every shipload
of supplies he has coming in.
Si, senor.
This is a way around the blockade.
Only got a 2-mile haul. No risks.
And the confederate army protecting
you every inch of the way.
Right, Kip?
No, Charlie.
I've been thinking different.
I got a feeling this may be the
turning point for the South.
I hope you're right, Kip.
We took Brownsville back.
That means it will turn that way
all the way down the line now.
Alright. What's your point?
The fighting will be moving
farther and farther north.
So?
We can go back to Three Bell.
Go back to herding cows?
What for?
This war isn't over yet.
Until it is, there's a lot more
money in guns than cows.
Guns smell nicer too.
We weren't in this just to
pile up a lot of money.
Who says so?
I'm going back to Three Bell.
I am staying.
What about you, Lee?
I never was part of this gun running.
I got no right to say now.
It's a big job to handle
a ranch all alone, Kip.
Lee is in the army.
Charlie is staying here.
I wasn't aiming to handle it alone.
Bronco won't be much help to you.
- I wasn't thinking of Bronco either.
I was meaning to ask Deb.
Not the first time a man has turned to
the land with only a wife to help him.
You know what you want, Kip.
Is Deb in town yet?
Where have they set up the hospital?
- Over at the boarding house.
Sadie's place.
Well, boys.
I guess I'll be drifting along.
I got a couple of fences
that need mending.
Hi, professor.
Give that piano a tinkling.
As the brass band plays
for the soldiers on parade.
I'm afraid the army caught my eye.
And I don't know when I would
have that chance again.
But then they continued marching by.
I am fair of face and curved
in just the proper place.
There is none more loveable than I.
To the men who pass.
I am a most attractive lass.
But alas, they continued marching by.
It must be fun to have a soldier.
Any soldier.
To hold your hand.
But it takes a lot to hold your soldier.
When they strike .. up the band.
I detest a flirt.
So I slyly raise my skirt
past my shoe tops.
Almost ankle high.
I could feel their eyes.
I could hear their murmured sighs.
Otherwise they continued marching by.
Hello Deb.
Kip.
Lee told me I'd find you here.
We haven't had a minute
since we got here.
There is so much to do.
- You got a minute now?
Two.
I brought you something.
As long as it isn't another cotton swab.
It came all the way from Paris.
Papa Brugnon says it's the latest
thing they're wearing over there.
I know they ain't the
right thing for here.
Maybe someday there will be a time for
wearing pretty things like that again.
I want you to have them.
Thank you, Kip.
That isn't the only reason I came,
bringing them to you.
I'm going back to Three Bell, Deb.
Just like I said we would.
I'm asking you to marry me, Deb.
Kip. I can't leave here now.
There is too much to be done.
And too few of us.
They need me here.
- I need you too, Deb.
I don't know, Kip.
What don't you know?
Don't ask me anything.
Don't make me say anything.
If there's anything to say
maybe now's the best time.
Remember that day at the ranch.
I knew it then.
I knew then that ..
Things would never be the same again.
Let's wait a little while.
We've waited so long now.
It won't hurt to wait a little longer.
Whatever you say, Deb.
Miss Miller.
When are we pulling out, Charlie?
Pulling out?
We don't want to leave Cottrell down
there with Brugnon too long.
That would be bad business. I thought
you were forgetting gun running.
I'm remembering it again.
There is a detachment leaving
for Santiago county on Sunday.
I am going with it.
It is a long haul from
Matamoras to Edenton.
It takes time.
Lots of things can happen
in Edenton between trips.
I trust my friends.
I trust mine too.
Sometimes.
Partner.
Mister Kip.
Where is Mister Kip?
He's in the office. What's up, Manuel?
Mister Kip. Mister Kip.
[ Spanish language ]
Cottrell? Cottrell, what about him?
Cottrell. He tried to kill me.
He said no more loads.
If we go to Matamoras he's
going to kill all of us.
Did you hear that?
Cottrell is sitting as top
man in Matamoras now.
He can stop any ship of supplies that
comes in. He's put us out of business.
Alright.
We're out of business.
I don't like to be put out of business.
- Not so fast.
A big shipment just came in.
It will be freighted from the
sea to Matamoras tomorrow.
It don't have to reach Cottrell.
No. It don't.
- It will mean a fight.
Not if we're smart.
Don't forget.
We're meant to be Yankee cavalry.
Try to act like them.
Bronco, button up that collar.
Ain't it bad enough wearing a Yankee
coat without having it choke you?
I don't like it, Kip.
Ain't there another way of doing it?
Yeah. You can go on back to Brownsville.
We don't need you anyhow.
Let him alone, Charlie.
We never should have brought him.
Here they come.
This is going to be
like flushing rabbits.
Get down off that box.
But, Senor. This is Mexico.
You have no right.
Come on, pronto. Move.
Manuel.
Mount up on this wagon.
Alright, boys. Let's get moving.
Yanks.
Dismount. Take cover.
Hold it, Charlie. They're confederates.
Their bullets can kill you just as dead.
Stop shooting. We ain't Yanks.
Stop shooting.
Hold your fire. We ain't Yankees.
I knew it.
We ain't Yanks. We ain't Yanks.
You see, Charlie? You got us into this.
If it hadn't been for you we ..
- Shut up.
Looks like we've stopped them.
You had no call to do that.
It was him or me.
Better get out of these Yankee suits.
We're in confederate territory.
Alright. Let's get the wagons unloaded.
I didn't know you were
bringing a load tonight.
Yeah.
Did you see anything of Captain
Jeffrey's patrol? He's way overdue.
No. We haven't seen him.
Looks like you got shot up a little.
Did you run into some trouble?
No. There wasn't any trouble.
Hi, Lee.
Where did you get the
fancy pants, Bronco?
I told them there would be trouble.
I told them, Lee.
Yankee pants always bring trouble.
I told them I didn't
want to put them on.
Don't go jumping to things, Lee.
He don't know what he's
talking about. He is drunk.
You ain't mad, Lee?
You ain't really mad, are you?
Charlie.
Lee is mad at me.
You go and tell him I didn't
want to put these pants on.
You know, Bronco.
They should have killed
you down at the port.
I told you not to let
Bronco ride with us.
Look. I had an old dog once.
I loved him too.
But when he went lame
and blind I shot him.
Where's Bronco now?
- Never mind, Bronco.
When news of that patrol gets through,
Lee will know what happened.
What about that?
Yeah. What about it?
The news has come through.
You wiped out that patrol, didn't you?
Killed Jeffrey. Murdered men
wearing the same uniform I am.
We couldn't help it. They started
shooting and we defended ourselves.
Defend the wagons you mean.
You were willing to fight us
or kill our men or anything.
To be sure you get your money.
That ain't exactly the way it was.
- Just a minute, Lee.
We ain't running guns for love.
We don't sit and swallow your lead
because of the pretty uniform you wear.
Cut it, Charlie.
At least Charlie makes sense.
Only I ain't having any part of it.
With you anymore or the ranch.
I'm walking out.
It ain't that easy, Lee.
How do we know you're going
to keep your mouth shut?
Bronco.
Why did you take him with you, Kip?
Why did you let him
ride with you at all?
Bronco. Bronco.
Get the boys together.
We're going after Cottrell.
What's the good of killing Cottrell now?
Or getting yourself killed?
I won't kill him.
I'll bring him back here so he
can see the ranches he burned.
And the graves of Bronco and the others
he murdered who had no chance.
Then let them hang him.
I ain't going with you.
Bronco ain't worth dying for.
You're smart enough to go, Charlie.
You have too much to lose.
Half of the biggest gun-running
business in Texas.
If Kip happens to get a bellyful of lead
down there you'll have the whole thing.
A few men riding into Matamoras
make mighty easy targets.
Especially if Cottrell happens
to be waiting for them.
Listen, you.
Take your hands off me.
You could be top man, Charlie.
Run things just the way you want it.
It will take Kip a while
to round up some men.
You won't be needing me for
anything, will you Charlie?
I'm kinda restless.
A good fast ride is just what I need.
You stay here.
Something's wrong.
Manuel!
Davis.
Cottrell.
Don't, Davis.
Don't.
You're coming back with me, Cottrell.
You'll get on your knees over Bronco's
grave and then I'll let them hang you.
Wait. I'll make a deal with you.
There's things you don't know.
That you won't find out until too late.
Others knew you were coming here.
I thought you needed a little help.
You said you were good with that knife.
- Yeah.
I didn't think Charlie was right
letting you come here alone.
You are lying.
You're leaving?
Yes, Kip. I am.
Because of Bronco?
Seeing Bronco dead there in the dirt.
I can't stay here now.
Not anymore.
You're not coming back?
No, Kip.
Is Bronco the only
reason you're leaving?
You've got a gun.
Why don't you draw?
Yeah. We can draw on each other, Kip.
Maybe it would be a tie. Then what?
What good would that do
for you or for me or for Deb?
Don't blame Lee.
It wasn't anything he did.
It was something that happened to me.
Being near him.
Watching him ride out to fight.
Not knowing if he was coming back.
Praying that he would.
Suddenly and not really facing it,
I knew that I loved him.
I tried to fight it, Kip. I did.
Three Bell.
We were always going to be together.
You took Deb away and ..
Charlie tried to kill me.
Are you alright, Kip?
I'm fine.
You got back fast, Slim.
Yeah. I got a good horse.
Slim told me how it went, Kip.
I'm real glad. I was worried.
I know you were, Charlie.
What are you looking for?
How much we got stacked there?
I don't know exactly.
Why?
It don't matter. It's all yours now.
My share and Lee's.
Take it. I'm giving it to you.
It's what you wanted.
The whole gun-running
business right in your lap.
You ought to make a lot of money now.
A lot of friends. Like Slim here.
He's willing to do almost
anything for you, ain't he?
If I was Kip I'd cut your
throat with your own knife.
As you've made a clean
sweep today I'll pull out too.
You can have my share.
You don't have to go, Rouge.
You and I could be a lot
of help to each other.
You can be a lot of help
to me right now, Charlie.
Yeah.
Where does a cowboy go
when he's on the move?
Don't be a fool.
He ain't got nothing but
the clothes on his back.
It's how you wear 'em, Charlie.
It's all in how you wear 'em.
We're making a mistake.
He's likely to come back someday.
We'll have to do then what
we ought to be doing now.
Let him go. He can't bother us.
Nobody can.
'Proclamation'.
'Hostilities have ceased and a state of
emergency exists in the State of Texas'.
'Authority to maintain law and order is
hereby delegated to the Texas Rangers'.
'By order of the Governor
of the State of Texas'.
Now, Slim. That wasn't nice.
They went to a lot of trouble
to get all them signs printed.
It ain't funny.
We don't want no Texas Ranger
sticking his nose into our business.
Lee.
Hello Lee.
- Hello Charlie.
Hello Deb.
Been a long time.
I heard they'd made you a ranger but
didn't figure you'd come to Brownsville.
I go where I'm sent.
- Are you all they sent?
One ranger?
There's only one town, ain't there?
You aiming to find out which of us is
quicker on the draw after all this time?
Maybe.
If it hadn't been for Kip we'd
have found out a long time ago.
I'm thinking Kip made a mistake.
But he ain't making any more.
He's living over in Matamoras.
Nice and peaceful.
Not bothering anybody.
Why don't you take a
lesson from him, Lee?
Or do you figure I won't do anything as
you still wear a bell on your spurs?
You're wearing one too, Charlie.
Don't figure it counts for anything.
I don't.
Then go back, Lee.
Get out of Brownsville.
I came down here to do a job.
And I'm staying to do it.
I got what I want now, Lee. Nobody will
take it away from me. Not even you.
Get him out of here, Deb.
If you want to keep him alive.
I got a fair old game at 4 o'clock and
I ain't stopping it for a shooting.
Be out of here before then.
I'll be down to take a look
at your game, Charlie.
Don't do it, Lee.
Don't make me kill you.
Go over to the hotel, Deb.
Wait for me there.
Much time.
Is wasted in waiting.
For the one.
Who called you his own.
That's why my heart is yours forever.
Complaining never.
I can't have too much love.
Don't bother, Pedro.
It sounds better flat.
Jose Alvorado said he'd be needing
a top hand around branding time.
Why not ride down and see him?
Let Alvorado handle his own cows.
I don't like his brand.
Dominic.
Tequila.
What about this one? It is not paid for.
Give me that.
Vamoose.
You?
Sure.
Hello Kip.
- Hello Deb.
I'm so glad to find you.
I've looked everywhere.
Just ask anyone in Matamoras.
They all know Kip Davis.
You never met Deb, did you Rouge?
No. We never really met.
Kip used to tell me
about you in Matamoras.
Papa Brugnon.
He's told me about you too.
What are you doing down here?
Last I heard was about San Antonio
with you and Lee getting married.
Something like that.
- Yes.
He's here with you?
The rangers sent him to Brownsville.
Rangers?
Lee ought to like that.
You know how he feels.
Yeah.
Yeah. I know how he feels.
He needs help, Kip.
He sent you down here?
- No. He doesn't know.
But you've got to help him.
Why me?
They ran out of rangers in Texas?
Come to Brownsville. Talk to Charlie.
Me and Charlie ain't been
exactly on speaking terms lately.
He'll kill Lee.
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
Lee's pretty handy with a gun.
One man against Charlie
and Slim and all the others?
What do you expect me to do?
- He'll listen to you.
You've got to stop him.
No-one asked Lee to join the rangers.
All he has to do is resign.
You know he won't.
That ain't my business.
Alright, Kip.
No-one can make you come.
I only thought ..
Stop it.
You're a real big hero, aren't you?
You've got him under your thumb.
You're going to get even with him.
What are you going to do, spend
the rest of your life getting even?
That's about the shape of it, isn't it?
And I'm the girl who's supposed
to sit here and watch it.
What have you got against Lee?
That he was in love with Deb?
What do you want him
to do, eat his heart out?
To forget he ever knew her
or saw her or wanted her?
Cut it, Rouge. Cut it.
You're not even in
love with Deb anymore.
At least that was an honest excuse.
But it's not honest to sit here with a
bottle eating your heart out with hate.
Forget Lee. Forget Deb. Forget them all.
There. Do your own forgetting.
But count me out, Kip.
Lee was your friend and he
couldn't help what he did.
But you can sure help what you're doing.
Kip.
I didn't mean it, Kip. I didn't mean it.
You were right, Rouge.
About almost everything.
I'm going back to Brownsville.
I can't keep hating Lee or even Charlie.
Maybe we had to split.
I can't see it ending in a killing over
the last of what's left of Three Bell.
Kip.
You were wrong about one thing though.
It wasn't only hate that kept me going.
Did they always call you Rouge?
Even when you were
a kid back in Louisiana?
No.
What was your real name?
Charlotte.
That's a real pretty name.
You'd better go back
and sing now, honey.
Save an encore for me when I get back.
Don't let me waste that encore, cowboy.
I want you around to hear it.
Sure.
Hello Lee.
Hello Kip.
You figuring on taking a little walk?
The weather seems to
be clouding up some.
I was figuring to.
Mind if I go along?
If you don't mind a little rain.
That's Kip.
Where did he come from?
He has no business here.
It looks like he thinks he has.
That makes it our business.
The boys are ready any
time you are, Charlie.
The gun in that window
is waiting for the signal.
[ Spurs tinkling ]
What are you waiting for?
What's the matter with you?
Give him the signal or I will.
- I still run this outfit.
Then what's stopping you?
The tinkle of those spurs?
Three Bell was burnt a long time ago.
Forget it.
You can sit this one out, Charlie.
I'll take good care of your friends.
You won't go changing
the brand, will you Kip?
No, Charlie.
It will always be Three Bell.
Well, Mrs Davis.
We got a big job ahead of us.
I'll have to get a couple
of boys to help us out.
It takes three to run this place.
Give me a few years and I'll
see what I can do for you.
Giddy up.
..r-s..