Hello, Paolo? It's Nicola.
- Who?
- Nicola Cellammare.
Nicola! Where are you?
I'm in America. I'll finish my race
and come back to Europe.
- Really?
- I have a race in Germany, in Neuerburg.
I'm going to Neuerburg too!
Let's meet and go together.
Sure! Where will we meet?
- Is the Punterito crossroad okay?
- Perfect.
- See you there in three days.
- Very well! Bye.
Paolo! I'm here!
- What can I do for you?
- Have you gone crazy?
You're two hours late,
and you pretend you don't know me?
What is it?
Nicola!
- It's you! How are you?
- I get by.
- Everything okay? Problems on the trip?
- No. I'm coming from Genoa.
You came from Genoa?
What road did you take?
I don't have a license plate or
headlights, so I came through the fields.
- America didn't change you.
- It tried.
- Must we talk on the street?
- Right! Load up your motorbike.
- Wait. Let's eat something first.
- We'll eat on the way.
I'm freezing.
This is a very unwelcoming place.
Nicola, must we talk on the street?
Okay! Come on. Help me.
- How did it go in America?
- The United States! Wow!
Come here. It's a strange country.
You have to pay taxes!
Or you have to leave the country.
That's it. Go on.
What women did to me... What is it?
Take care of the motorcycle.
You'll tell me later.
Paolo. Paolo!
Give me a hand!
Alright, fine.
What did you do in America
these last four years?
What did I do? I raced.
I raced again. I always raced.
The last race never ended.
24 hours, always racing.
- Those Americans!
- My head spun like a top!
- So it was tough?
- Yes, but I made it.
- You won?
- Yes, but it all went to pay taxes.
- They even took my trophy.
- And you?
There were two women on
the podium with such long legs!
- You found comfort looking at them?
- Yes.
Yes, just looking!
- What did you do?
- The usual.
I participated in some local races
and kept training.
You call that training?
In and out of a garage?
I even trained on the street.
TRAFFIC POLICE
- Who is that madman?
- A real lunatic.
- He's a jerk!
- No. He's just crazy.
Wow! What a flight!
When I stopped,
they had such faces on them!
Here I am, ready to pay.
Go ahead and laugh! Now we'll laugh.
No weapons. I was just kidding.
Driver's license and registration.
Were you frightened?
No headlight, no plate.
You're in trouble. Give me your license.
- This jerk is a colleague!
- Oh, that too!
- It's Corti, the motocross guy.
- Yes.
Instead of bothering us,
train properly so you'll win on Sunday.
- That's what I'm doing.
- Yes. Go away.
- What are you drinking?
- You want some?
- No, thanks. You drink?
- A drop, once in a while.
- I decided to leave the police.
- Are you kidding?
- You left it four years ago.
- I was born to be a racer.
- I wasn't? Darn it!
- What is it?
Something is wrong. The water light is on.
I see.
The fan belt broke.
We need an automotive parts store.
I'll go by motorbike.
I don't know if you'd be able to make it.
Let's go together. I'll show you I can.
- How can you get past there?
- Go. You teach me.
Look at him!
Stop! Slowly! Slowly!
It's hot today, huh?
- Can you give me a belt like this?
- Yes.
Nicola, a little sip
to stimulate your reflexes?
"Welcome to Neuerburg." And here we are.
- I saw a beautiful girl!
- There are many beautiful girls here.
- Don't start now.
- You don't start!
- My gosh!
- What?
This place is ancient, it's beautiful.
Did you see the architecture?
Better than America!
What a beautiful cathedral!
This city will go down in history,
thanks to the two of us.
You don't believe me?
Stop, Paolo! Stop!
- What is it?
- Wait. I'll show you.
Good morning.
- My God!
- Good morning.
Me Tarzan. You Jane?
No, huh? You're not Jane?
Not Jane. I'm Inge.
What do I do now?
I don't know what you do here
when a boy likes a girl,
but I know how it's done where I'm from.
- Excuse me.
- Wait, I must talk to her.
The boy says to the girl,
"Hi. How are you? You're cute."
- "What are you doing tonight?"
- She has to pump my tires.
Be quiet a minute. I was saying...
There are two possibilities.
I suggest you choose the second.
If the guy is unpleasant,
she says, "Mind your own business."
- I choose the first.
- No. There's the second possibility.
- She's nice and will go for it.
- You know, you're right.
Why are you getting into this? Go away!
No. This is an interesting conversation.
- Do you need gas?
- What?
Do you want to fill it up?
Yes. It depends on the light.
Sometimes it's red, sometimes not.
Come see. This is it.
At times it's red, at times it isn't.
No, no. This one...
Paolo? Darn it!
Will you stop it?
Nicola, we have gas. Everything is okay.
- Yes, everything is okay.
- Get inside!
Hi! I'll call you, huh?
- See what I did?
- Yes. Good work.
Learn!
I'm coming!
Paolo!
Come on. Let's hurry. A nice shower...
Let's go! Calm down. You never stop!
- I'll find you some, too.
- I'll take care of it.
I'm going out with Inge tonight.
I don't want to leave you alone.
You know what I'll do? Hello!
- I'll ask Inge if she has a friend.
- What do the gentlemen want?
- Two singles with bathrooms.
- Did you see the technique?
- American style. See?
- Two with a shower. IDs.
IDs.
My God! Paolo...
I'm going to the coffee shop.
- Fill this up.
- Your reflex medicine!
- What would you like?
- Grappa.
Excuse me. Are you
from the International Federation?
- Yes. Federal inspector.
- Are you here for the race?
- Yes.
- So am I.
Sorry. Sometimes I forget my good manners.
- Nicola.
- I'm Muller. Are you a participant?
- Yes. One of the best.
- Is my canteen ready?
Paolo is a participant too.
Mr. Muller, from the Federation.
- Very pleased to meet you.
- A federal inspector!
I'm Paolo Corti.
We are private participants.
- We don't have a sponsor yet.
- A big problem!
- We must do everything ourselves.
- You are brave.
- Are there many participants?
- Yes, many.
Not bad, huh?
- She's cute.
Yes, but I think she sells love
at variable prices.
I noticed that too.
- My friend loves all of them.
- It's not true!
Damn them! When will they stop?
Gentlemen...
Good evening, everyone.
Have you seen this?
"The Mafia that lord over our area
have got their hands on sports, too."
"The world of racing is another one
of their dirty businesses."
"In order to keep us docile, they use
the rod and carrot system."
"But these systems don't work on us."
"The races are a big business
for only a few."
"Here, to see fanatics kill one another,
you must pay."
And a lot, too.
A very interesting article,
you must agree.
- Who wrote it?
- It's mine.
I spiced it up a little,
to increase interest in the races.
Very good! You deserve a drink.
No, thanks. Next time.
Oh, no. Now.
Accept, or we'll take offense.
Give it to me.
Here you go. Drink!
- Stop it!
- You must oil your brain.
- Stop!
- You write bullshit. You're rusty.
Come on!
Must I take offense? I told you to drink!
Drink... drink.
Excuse me, but...
what if he doesn't want to?
The joke has lasted long enough.
My friend is right.
What is going on?
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Make love, not war.
Yes, maybe you're right.
The lesson was enough.
See? He's a good guy.
After all.
You two mind your own business
next time, okay?
Yes, we got it. Isn't that right?
Clear.
If you want to go on being a journalist,
I suggest you change pens.
Yours writes bullshit!
Let your elders teach you the job.
What is your article
for tomorrow, Fischer?
I'll snipe at Town Hall.
It doesn't provide toilets for dogs.
You're right.
It's time to stop with this disgrace.
It's a serious problem.
Let's go.
Bye, beautiful.
- Thanks. Can I offer you something?
- No, thank you.
I never refuse a glass. A double one.
- Bourbon, right?
- Yes.
Break a leg, boys.
Your drink, sir.
Hey, guys! Let's go somewhere
that's made for love.
No?
That's for the best. It could be bad
for you. Can you believe that?
- You don't want anything else?
- No, we are tired from the trip.
Some other time. Let's go.
Consider it accepted, okay?
Go ahead and laugh!
There's not much to laugh about.
The situation is terrible here.
They say "women are objects".
Women are objects?
Nobody will buy this object here.
Not even rent it.
Don't write bad things about your host,
or have others solve your issues.
See how many problems you've caused?
Now I'll teach you how to live.
Nicola! Quick.
They are beating up the journalist!
Stop! Come on, let's go.
Get up. They beat you up good.
They really are upset with you.
What do they want?
Nothing. Leave me alone!
What a nice place!
Instead of racing,
we've come to this town to fight.
Hello? Excuse me, miss.
I need a phone number.
The girl who works
at the gas station outside. You have it?
Thanks a million.
She gave it to me, but I lost it.
Thank you. Can you give it to me?
Let me talk to her.
Thank you.
Hello? Who is it?
Who am I? How can I explain?
Yes. Or course!
Me Tarzan. You Jane. Do you remember me?
Yes, sure. I remember.
You've no qualms in calling.
Do you need anything?
Nothing,
I just have a little plan to propose.
Dinner wherever you choose.
Dancing in a place you choose, and then...
Then... we could end
the evening somewhere.
- I choose the place this time. Okay?
- No.
- You said yes?
- Sorry, no.
- Did you get offended?
- No, I'm glad to hear from Tarzan.
- But Jane is already in bed.
- Okay.
Goodbye now. Say hi to your friend for me.
Bye.
It won't end here.
Why don't you say hello
to his friend right away?
Why not?
This time, Eric, I prefer to bet
everything on just one racer.
Take it over there.
- You can also bet on the test races.
- I prefer betting on the real race.
- Welcome back, Countess.
- Thank you.
Hello, Mayer.
This year, there are some strong racers.
Thank you.
The best time on 18 as a winner.
Twelve.
Are you crazy?
- I was kidding.
- Take this!
Paolo, look at them. Are they crazy?
Nobody is separating them?
Don't get involved.
I've had enough of being a policeman.
- Who will win?
- Get the bike. Let's go test them.
Actually, today...
I want to see what you do
to get an idea. You mind?
Are you scared of me?
Come on. They are only test runs.
- I know.
- Come on, get busy!
Okay.
Whoever bet on 22 was right.
We can try too, dear.
Bet on something, too.
Waiter?
Bet it on 18.
- See how he speeds?
- Wait.
Better take it easy on initial laps.
Let's study the racetrack first.
Okay. Holy smokes!
If he keeps goosing the engine,
it'll break.
Those people go fast.
It'll be hard to get qualified.
Paolo, are you scared of someone
with a broken exhaust pipe?
His exhaust pipe isn't broken!
He's speeding!
When I was in the United States...
When I was there, a guy did it
on purpose to make more noise.
It sounded like he was speeding.
He's doing the same thing.
- His time will be terrible.
- I don't give a darn!
- Mr. Mayer?
- Yes?
- Kurt is on the phone.
- Excuse me a minute.
Mayer.
How are the bets going?
Kurt, do you have the final balance
of the other bookmakers?
Is there anything else?
I think Muller, the Federation guy,
is looking for trouble.
He'll be at the racetrack
in a few minutes. Any orders?
- No, but tell me when he arrives.
- Alright.
Are you racing, too?
Muller is here.
Wow! You got an excellent time!
- You didn't even speed that much!
- I just tried the racetrack.
The bumps are the same,
but the curves throw you out.
Especially the one after the small valley.
You must widen up high when turning,
downshift two gears and give gas.
Two gears?
If I downshift three, are you happy?
- I saw. I start with an advantage.
- Nicola, go try it out.
I'm going!
Tell camera three to center Muller.
Camera three, center Muller.
Put him on the big screen.
Eighty-five.
How did I do?
Better than me, you did two tenths less.
I speed like a rocket. When you
want to race with me, let me know.
- When I was in the United States...
- Okay, I already said it.
I'll go practice.
The wolf came out of its den.
How many will you kill on Sunday?
How many guys
did you find ready to be killed
to please your respectable clients?
You left the races
because you were afraid,
and you hid amongst
the paperwork of the Federation.
Don't bother those
who still have the courage to race.
Go away, Muller.
Your presence is not needed here.
You know I didn't quit
because I was afraid.
It's not about that.
You are done, Mayer.
Your races are just massacres!
I have evidence of your activity.
Here, there's everything
your men do during the races,
and your circle of bets.
I'll throw it in your face before Sunday!
You'll never hold another race again.
You have Walter Muller's word!
You were right,
Muller is really looking for trouble.
Take care of it.
- Fill it up, please.
- Yes.
- Fifty marks, please.
- There you go.
- I'll bring you the change.
- Okay.
- Here.
- Thanks.
There's nothing here.
Come out, Muller! We have to talk to you!
Muller!
Why did you shoot?
He was reaching for a gun!
Damn! He just has this.
Idiot! Get rid of him.
You came here because you like the races?
- No. I like the racers.
- I see!
- We're racers.
- I know, that's why I'm here.
Would you do me a favor?
- Just to you?
- No. I'm fine as it is.
I'm waiting for the girl who works
at the gas station, she's coming.
I spoke for him, he's a bit shy.
He's right, I'm shy. Very shy.
He, instead, is very good,
but not with women, with motorbikes.
Good for you.
You'll see her coming in a bit.
She has a date with me.
- I don't believe it.
- Okay. You'll see in a bit.
- I'll leave you alone.
- He's crazy!
I'll make a pass at you now, okay?
- As a joke. I'm already in love.
- Sure.
How should I make a pass?
Some put their hands on you.
Yes, very efficient.
Excuse me a moment.
A friend is here. Excuse me.
Inge!
Stop!
You're making me run a lot.
If I'd known, I'd have taken the bike!
What happened?
Something happened
at the gas station. No more gas?
- No. That's not it.
- What happened?
I'm not used to finding a guy
who invited me to dinner with a...
- I don't know how to say it.
- Whore!
I mean... she's called a whore!
It was a joke. Paolo was making fun of me.
Understand? Will you stop? Please.
Stop! Come on. Smile!
Peace?
Paolo, open up. I must tell you something.
- What is it?
- It's very important.
Go away. I have things to do.
It'll only take a moment.
I went out with Inge.
- You went to bed with her?
- No, much more.
- Something more important.
- I'll be quick.
- Are you with a woman?
- Inge, the first day...
- Is there a woman here?
- Yes.
- I wanted to tell you...
- We'll talk later.
- When we arrived...
- Tomorrow.
What is it?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
I don't understand women!
Paolo, I see strange movements here.
Something's up.
- Hi, guys.
- Hi, Resi.
Hi. What always happens happened.
Mayer told someone that
the real jackpot is 50,000 dollars,
not 5,000 as it was initially.
Why? You didn't know?
No, not really.
We always thought
it was 5,000 dollars, not 50,000.
Man, 50,000 dollars!
- What does he want in exchange?
- Your life.
Mayer wants your life.
Leave, while you still can.
This is not just speed cross.
It has nothing to do with sport.
Last year, three boys died.
They were all 20 years old.
- Swept away on the first lap.
- Mayer has decided who wins.
If someone blocks him
and ruins the bets, he's done for.
50,000 dollars to race against
other people's lives. That's the price.
Isn't there a little bit of fanciful
exaggeration going on here?
- I wish!
- I mean...
Cross races are tough, maybe this one
is tougher than the others.
In America, speed cross races are
clandestine. In Nevada, Mexico.
But almost nothing happens, nobody dies.
There can be some accidents,
but they're just accidents.
Listen. What do you say if we relax
before the final tests?
Big champions do it, too.
Thanks, but it isn't the right moment.
You don't mind, huh?
Resi is a good girl. You don't mind,
do you? Let's go test them.
We are betting 15 and 85 at one
and a half. They're the favourites..
Okay, go. Thanks.
Mayer?
Congratulations, there are
some very brave boys this year.
Right.
Are you ready? Set a good time.
Kurt, one of the two Italians is
getting good times. The other one?
He's at the pit boxes getting times.
Wow, Paolo! You are awesome!
- Are you Nicola?
- He's good, huh?
Someone wants you on the phone.
A girl called Inge.
- Who?
- Inge!
Thanks!
Hello Inge? Hi, love. How are you?
Please, speak louder. I can't hear you.
I can't hear anything!
I'm speaking out loud! Hear me?
Yes.
Paolo and I will qualify for sure.
We are doing great!
- I love you! And you?
- Yes. I think so, Nicola.
Hurry up. Come now!
No. I can't right now.
I have to do a couple of laps,
then I'll come. Do you love me?
- Yes!
- Say it again!
Yes!
Bye, baby! Bye! I have to run. Bye!
Paolo! You know who was on the phone?
I don't care. Go qualify.
You got a shitty time.
Yes, you're right. Guess who it was? Inge.
Who?
Inge!
- What did she say?
- My gosh!
She loves me.
- This is a love story.
- Take my time.
Yes, okay.
Watch out for the third curve up there.
Use second gear or...
Did Muller stop at the gas station?
He could've left his documents there.
- I told you you as soon as I remembered.
- Those documents are important.
They must be there.
We must get them. Take care of it!
- Without revealing yourselves.
- Okay.
The gas station girl talked
on the phone with the Italian guy.
I don't think it was about documents.
Mayer, the two Italians are getting
good times. We must do something.
You're right, they're too fast.
They could mess up the bets.
It won't be a problem.
You've fixed up tougher guys during races.
Now, let's get those documents back.
Be careful.
Weird, Kurt and Ramirez are leaving
without the first position time.
It might be a racing tactic,
but I don't like it.
What do we care?
- Hello, we need some information.
- Sure.
The other day, a gentleman
got gas here, Mr. Muller.
- He left an envelope for me.
- Yes, I remember Mr. Muller.
- But he didn't leave any envelope.
- Think about it.
It was an envelope like this.
I'm sure he left it here.
Listen. It's closing time.
I said...
Fischer, on the phone!
Fischer, you're wanted on the phone. Come!
Here on the right. Just as you turn.
Fischer.
What?
I see.
Thanks.
- Did you try S-5?
- S-5? Sure.
The gas station girl.
She just got robbed.
- When?
- Just now.
Go.
Yes? Yes, she's dead.
No, nobody noticed anything.
It looks like a robbery.
She has an injury on her head,
as though she banged it.
Sure, I'll wait for you.
Come on, let's go.
I can't wait to leave
this disgusting place.
Nicola, hurry up.
Why should we leave?
Nicola, I don't like this place.
Strange things happen.
Threatened journalists,
Muller vanishes into thin air...
And then Inge. No.
I'm convinced it wasn't a robbery.
Something's up here.
Nobody would rob
a gas station at that hour.
You realize that? It's too risky.
Besides...
At that time of day,
they haven't made much money.
They do most of the work in the afternoon.
In the morning, everyone
is at the racetrack for the tests.
The sooner we leave, the better.
Nicola, these people
are willing to do anything.
If someone doesn't play their game,
they get rid of him.
Maybe these are just
the stupid thoughts of a policeman.
Anyway, we're leaving this place.
I'm not coming.
What did you say?
You heard me.
- I'm not leaving.
- Is this race so important?
It's not about the race,
even if I could use those 50,000 dollars
to go back to America.
There are doubts about Inge's death,
you said that.
Yes. Listen.
Nicola, we are just racers,
and we only know how to race.
Not how to be policeman!
Yes, I know what you're saying.
Races, fame.
- Millions.
- Does that disgust you?
No!
So, what do you want to do?
I don't know.
I want to know how Inge died.
I must know. Understand?
Inge meant something to me, Paolo.
We loved each other, Paolo.
I can't leave
without knowing who killed her.
I don't want to disappoint you, but...
She doesn't deserve
the respect you give her.
I don't understand. What did you say?
Paolo.
What do you mean?
I wanted to say that...
The first day we arrived,
Inge slept with me.
Aren't you ashamed?
Jerk!
She's dead, jerk!
I just wanted...
It's not true.
I just wanted you to come away.
I told you to be careful!
It was a pointless murder.
We needed that girl alive!
Who will tell us where the documents are?
Kurt, you've been making stupid mistakes
this whole time.
Now, we must fix things.
Hello?
- Who knows that you're here?
- My men.
I put a couple on the Italians,
maybe they know something.
Yes, it's Kurt.
One of the two left.
The one who was with Inge stayed in town.
Strange, huh?
We must keep an eye on them.
Threaten them if it's necessary.
But you must not kill them. Is that clear?
Okay, don't lose sight of them.
I hope we didn't underestimate those two.
Maybe they even know
where the documents are.
Hurry up.
- Who is it?
- The waiter.
- What do you want?
- Hold still!
Okay, guys, let him go.
He knows he'd better behave.
- What do you want?
- We just want to talk.
I hope you don't mind.
What were you doing
at the gas station?
Looking for something?
I'll tell you.
You were looking for an envelope
with documents in it.
- So what if I was?
- You want to end up like Inge?
Buddy, pull over. We need to talk to you!
Let's see if you're still interested
in what isn't your business.
If you have half a brain, leave!
Forget this town.
Drag him out.
Down!
That's one dealt with.
Hey, careful!
Nicola!
Nicola! What happened?
Who did it?
It doesn't seem serious at first glance.
Anyway, I'll wait to see the x-rays.
Then I'll be able to be more precise.
- Doctor, the x-rays.
- Thank you.
We'll know more with these,
and I can give you a diagnosis.
- Doctor, you're wanted on the phone.
- I'll be right there. Excuse me.
Please.
Hello? What?
Yes, number 12. I remember.
He has a broken femur.
That's normal, he had surgery.
Yes.
What did you give him?
It's what's best, right?
You can give him everything.
What? No, I wouldn't suggest
traction, at least not right now.
Yes, you can dismiss him.
He must return in 20 days.
Shoulder, femur...
We'll see what's to be done.
And tibia. There.
What did you give him?
Fine.
Alright.
I'm sorry, it's a continuous
back and forth in the hospital.
We need patience. Let's see.
What an ugly fracture!
A really ugly fracture, look.
That's a total horizontal break.
It must heal.
He will need a cast,
and hopefully the bone will heal.
- Will it be painful?
- Somewhat.
We'll try to make it
as painless as possible.
- Must he remain immobile?
- Absolutely.
- For a long time?
- Yes, unfortunately.
But you... hadn't you left?
Good thing I came back.
As soon as I leave you a for minute,
look what happens.
Nicola...
Do you feel like telling me how it went?
What's wrong with me?
Nothing. Just a broken leg, don't worry.
Kurt and the other two assaulted me.
They wanted some documents
that they think were at the gas station.
Documents? About what?
I don't know, they didn't tell me.
They...
They beat me up.
Then they threw me down the stairs.
They wanted to scare me.
"Go away", they said. Then...
They made me drink a bottle of whiskey.
I don't know why.
To make it seem like you fell by yourself.
- Seem to who?
- The police.
To make sure the doctor
didn't file a report.
Those bastards gave you whiskey
to cover themselves.
They created an alibi.
Just worry about getting better now.
Don't have too much fun with the nurses!
I'll come back when I can.
You don't have to come back.
Take care, Nicola!
- You go over there, I'll go here.
- Alright.
I'll be right back.
Honey, I must run home.
Will you wait for me? I'm sorry.
Kisses, kisses. Big kiss!
Bye.
I'm glad you made a decision.
Sooner or later,
you need a Resi in your life.
"He who goes with Resi will be happy",
that is my motto.
You're a handsome guy, not like...
You're not here to make love, huh?
No.
No. I'm sorry, but...
I don't want you to lose out.
Here.
No, thanks.
- Take it.
- No, really.
What did you come here for?
They're looking for me, and I have to
hide.
- You don't ask me who?
- I've stopped asking such questions.
I mind my own business now.
It's much better this way.
- Do you want something to eat?
- No.
Can I stay here tonight?
Listen.
Do you want scrambled eggs or fried?
Fried, thanks.
Yes, better fried.
We can scramble them later.
Do you know if there's a red soil quarry
in the area?
Red soil?
No.
The only red things here are the bricks.
He disappeared?
He couldn't have vanished.
- The car?
- It's in the hotel parking lot.
- The motorbike is still there.
- He can't have left town.
He's hiding. Find him.
We must know what he has in mind.
Get going. Now!
I bought some stuff.
Cheese, canned meat, beer,
vegetables. A bit of everything.
You did well. I'm starving.
How far have you gotten
with the investigation?
I can only make assumptions.
Didn't you want to mind your own business?
Well?
I changed my mind. So what?
I'm sure that everything
revolves around the racing business.
Muller must have found something out
about Mayer.
Weren't they more reassured
after getting rid of him?
Maybe Muller had gathered some documents.
They killed Inge, and went
to Nicola looking for the documents.
Because he had an affair with Inge.
Muller, Inge, Nicola,
and me too.
We must solve this equation.
- What?
- Muller gave Inge the documents.
Since they're still looking for them,
evidently...
They couldn't find them on Inge.
They are looking for me
because they think I have them.
Where are these documents?
Excuse me, but why does...
Why Mayer cares so
much about those documents?
What's so incriminating about them?
Please, caress me again like that.
It's been a long time,
I'd almost forgotten.
Excuse me. I have an idea.
Are you going out?
Be careful, those people are dangerous.
- They don't mess around.
- Don't worry.
I'll be careful.
If something should happen to me,
go to Nicola.
Tell him there's nothing wrong
with his leg.
Help him, if he needs to run away
from this shitty place. Bye.
I trust you because
you are a policeman, too.
Thanks. Chief...
Schultz. Handcuffs, please.
We know everything about Mayer
and his gang, the worst in the area.
Everything you told me
couldn't have happened by chance.
Mayer is responsible
for those three accidents.
I can't do anything,
Mayer has connections up high.
One misstep, and I'm done for.
But if you gave me proof, just one piece,
I would be the happiest man in the world.
I found Muller's documents,
and they can incriminate him.
- You have them with you?
- I wasn't able to get them.
May I know where they are?
I'll tell you at the right moment.
It's still early.
What do you want to do?
I don't really know, exactly.
Listen.
Try not to let Mayer leave the city.
Have everyone believe
that I'm under arrest. Can you do that?
Tonight you can sleep in cell number four.
Thanks.
Don't forget
to tell the warden to leave me the key.
The situation is not clear.
Pick up all the bets,
and get as much cash as possible.
- We must be prepared for the worst.
- Is there a problem?
- Maybe. I'm going to the racetrack.
- Alright.
Hey, Resi!
You came to see if I'll be a client?
Everyone's at the race.
I came to bring you news on your friend.
- How is the policeman?
- They arrested him.
- They arrested him?
- It's a long story.
- Are you crazy? I'm all broken up.
- You're fine!
- I'm fine?
- There's nothing wrong with you.
Paolo set everything up
to get you out of this mess.
- Really?
- Really.
Paolo said to tell you that
you must leave immediately.
- Before it's too late.
- Really?
You tell Paolo to mind his own business,
I can take care of myself.
We are close to the moment of truth.
Only the power of the engine matters,
along with the guts under the suit.
I wanted to organize a race
that thrills my supporters.
This year, I'll offer a show
worthy of my traditions.
What you will soon see
is something you'll never see again.
You can be sure of that.
They won't ever see it again.
We are almost ready
for the race to begin.
Participants are leaving the boxes
and heading to get checked.
The bikes get checked
by federation commissioners.
They embody the fairness
typical of speed cross races.
After the check, the participants
rush to reach the racetrack,
for the last test.
I remind you that we are watching
the Neuerburg circuit live.
Here's the patron of the race, Mayer,
talking to the head of his team.
We foresee a wonderful show.
The press grandstand
is crowded with journalists.
The checks are almost done,
and the participants receive last
minute advice from the mechanics.
Wasn't he supposed to be at the hospital?
Sure. How did he do it?
You are imbeciles.
Sabotage him during the race.
And don't mess it up!
If he wins, it'll be a financial disaster.
- Almost everybody bet on him.
- Got you.
- What is it?
- A little something.
Cute, huh? It cuts like a knife.
See you at the starting line.
I'll go fix the exhaust pipe.
Kurt!
You like to play rough, huh?
You'll see.
The race will begin in a few minutes.
The participants
are reaching the starting bar.
We see number 85, a favourite,
who is here despite what was announced.
The participants are reaching
the starting point.
Ramirez, number 39,
is the reckless local racer
who won first place last year.
We still don't see number 60, Kurt,
the other fearsome local champion.
He's usually on time.
He's coming out of the pit box now!
Mr. Mayer asks him to hurry up.
Number 60, Kurt, takes his position, too.
Another few participants,
and the race will begin.
There we go! They're off!
A flying start!
Two participants are on the ground,
while all the others
are headed to the first bump.
A group of three racers
is firmly in the lead.
Here's number 85. Incredible!
He steps up and attacks
with extraordinary determination.
We are holding our breath.
Number 85 is not a veteran,
unprepared for this kind of race.
He is in the most difficult position,
heading the group.
He can easily be attacked
by those behind him.
We just saw something
very rare in speed cross!
Kurt saved 85 from getting hit!
28 and 68 haven't made it
through the fifth lap.
Mr. Mayer. Mr. Mayer!
I was looking for you. We must tell
the race director to stop Kurt.
He's not racing.
I was coming to advise you.
The police arrested him.
Someone beat him up.
- He was tied up in the storage closet.
- Who is that son of a bitch?
Get all the cash.
Put it inside the briefcase in my car.
Mr. Mayer is going up the stairs
to the VIP section,
where the representatives
of this town are seated.
Next to him is the well-known
Chief Brown.
"Brown the Tiger",
as some affectionately call him.
He seems satisfied.
He loves races and is having fun.
But let's get back to the race.
There's been a collision between two
motorbikes, and a third was involved.
This is the latest information.
The rescue team is heading
to where the flames are rising.
We've reached the last laps
of this exciting race.
The crowd is standing
for this final round.
The authorities are getting ready
to give the awards.
Mayer is totally fascinated by this race.
85 is still leading,
followed by number 60
and 39, the other local champion.
87 has sadly gone off-track, too.
A few laps to go before the finish line.
We are at the last lap.
The participants face
the final hurdles of the race,
which is being dominated
by a group in the lead.
Three racers are fighting
to win first place.
Mr. Mayer?
Yes?
The race is about to end.
You don't want to miss the finish.
Please, come this way.
Please.
After you, sir.
39 and 60 are vying for first place,
firmly held down
by the amazing number 85.
39 is out of the race, too.
There is a duel between 60 and 85
over the few meters remaining.
85 crosses the finish line
and wins the race!
It's me, Paolo!
Don't you recognize me? I'm Paolo!
Well done!
Nicola, are you still upset with me?
Come on. Let's stop this!
Cheers for the champion!
Great! Great, guys! You made it!
Come up!
Bravo, Nicola!
You are the best!
- Shall we go?
- No, no!
Just a moment, please.
One...
two, three,
four, four and a half and five.
Thank you very much! You may go.
Congratulations!
Half to me...
and half to the champion!
When I was in Italy...
Hey. I'm here, too!