2 kilometers from Thailand's border
Check-Point Trade Border at Siam Trang bay
Here you are.
Why do you come to Thailand?
To deliver some goods.
What's in your bag?
Let me see.
Pour it.
What's all this rubbish?
Okay pass. Go go.
Go.
Go. Hurry.
Hold on. Hold on.
What is that?
That's around your neck.
That's right.
Take it off.
What is it?
Love potion.
Love potion?
Holy shit. Love potion.
Look, it's Love potion.
Have you ever seen it for real?
It's used for love and lust spells.
Wow, I've only heard of it.
Is this the real deal?
Hey, you want to try some?
No!
What a nonsense!
Go, go.
What a waste of time.
Map Kha Industrial Estate
250 km. - Thailand's border
After we'd been through the big flood crisis,
our company had to recover
and restore in several aspects.
The staffs from all departments
had been co-operating very well.
Therefore, our company
managed to recover quite fast.
I want you all to congratulate
yourselves on this success.
However...
I believe that you all can do better.
Better and better,
A lot more.
Just like our company's motto:
The company's our life,
committed like slaves,
with the greatest quality
for the ASEAN Community.
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray! Yippee!
Oh my, you all lightened up my day.
Well, now we can go back to our work.
Attention...
Dismissed!
Yeah!
Hey, Prae. Do you mind going through this?
Do it, please.
Prae, Boss Toy wants to see you.
Come on in. Sit down. Have a seat.
You know, I just landed last night.
Japan was so beautiful. Really.
Oh, I went to Japanese hot spring.
I got to be naked in pool.
Everybody was naked in all that glory.
What do you need to see me for?
Oh, here it is.
I have something for you.
Straight out of the plane from Japan.
You see?
It costs me 8,000 yen.
Watch this. You'll see how it works. Hold on.
Oh, right here. Gotta turn it on. See this?
Cut it off now. Enough. Or she'll pass out.
I bought this specially for you, Prae.
You can put it on your desk, okay?
I'd rather pass on this.
Why not?
Are we done yet?
Then I'll go back to work now.
Prae. Prae. Prae.
Prae.
Hold on. Hold on.
What's wrong with this?
It's so cute.
Here we go. Here we go. Give her hard, man.
So damn fucking cute.
I told you it's not about work.
Come on, pay me now.
There goes my money.
Prae.
Well, can I ask you for something?
It can be more than one thing.
What do you want?
I...
I want you, Prae.
Come again, Lek?
I, well...
I wanna bang you, Prae.
Of course, you can.
You dickhead, Lek.
Asshole.
What the heck is wrong with you?
I almost shit my pants.
What are you doing?
I was thinking about work!
About work, my ass.
You were bending yourself.
What do you want?
You told me about that sexy chick Prae.
You still wanna tap that ass?
You're saying bullshit. She's my friend!
I stopped thinking about that long time ago.
Well, alright, then.
Because I was gonna help you with that.
Help me?
How would you do that?
Snatch her!
Damn.
Do that and you'll end up in jail, Moron.
Just kidding. I really know how to help you.
You remember Boss Tong?
A few months ago,
Boss Tong gave this to my uncle.
Your uncle who died last week?
Yep.
What the hell is it?
My uncle told me it's gotten out of Cambodia.
Someone else gave it to Boss Tong.
There's a abracadabra to go with it.
What is that? Love potion?
Vacuum clean it, please.
Want to test drive as well?
Is it really work?
You want it or not?
If not, then suit yourself.
With a face like this,
I have no need for that potion.
Duck face, you're full of shit.
Miss, follow me to the finance office.
Why you come back home so late
these days?
I stopped by the hospital.
I told you. It's a waste of time.
Your mom won't make it through,
no matter what.
You should just sell that old
junk car of hers already.
She has no need for a ride anymore.
Someone will come to see this house
in a few days.
Make sure you keep the place clean
and neat.
I'm not selling this house, uncle.
My mom won't let you, either.
Is she able to talk to you yet?
This house's
under my name and your mom's.
When she dies,
I can do anything I want with it.
Don't forget that.
Who has provided for you
since you were young?
The debt your father left us,
who's been paying for that?
I'm asking you now.
Have you ever thought of repaying me a bit?
Hi, there.
Not now, darling.
You're sure this is the place, Prae?
I can't believe it.
Meeting a customer at a Karaoke restaurant.
Okay, that's nice.
Hello, guys. What kind of room do you want?
I'm here to talk business.
Oh.
They said the room is booked for Boss Pravit.
Oh, Boss Toy, the V3 room.
Go upstairs to the second floor,
it's on your left.
The V3 room.
Alright, girls, escort them there.
Go ahead, sir.
This way, please.
The V3 room.
Hey, candy boy, no need to hurry.
Why don't you take
one of these cute girls with you?
Very nice.
Oh. Hold on now.
Prae, you've made it here.
Come on in and have a seat. Sit, sit, sit.
Can you move over a bit?
Come on, Prae. Go ahead. Sit here.
The customer's not here yet?
Oh, the customer...
He called me to postpone the meeting
to another day.
Well, the room is booked
and the food is ordered.
So I think why not inviting you tonight.
Here, can you fill it up with beer a bit?
Come on here. Sit down. Sit.
Well, it's good that the customer bailed.
I happened to bring my friend along.
You brought a friend?
Hello, I'm Lek.
He's a colleague.
He works in the maintenance team.
Go ahead and order something.
That's a menu.
Nah, let me help you order.
The fish-bone spicy soup.
The nosy sauteed salad's not bad.
Well, the meddled pork leg is...
...very tasty, actually.
Prae, I think I'll leave now.
Hold on, Lek.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry, boss.
Gosh, now I'm a mess.
So I'll leave now, all right?
Come on, Lek.
Goodbye, sir.
Fish-face.
Meddling alligator.
Lek, are you hungry?
You haven't eaten anything.
Wanna stop and grab some bite?
No need to be shy.
Think of it as my apology to you.
Hello?
Hey, did you ask about how to use it for me?
Nobody knows.
The potion must be for the body.
Fuckface. So...
Just tapping it on the body and that's it?
Just using it, man. It'll work just the same.
Gotta go now.
Damn it! Do me no good, you homo.
Are you full?
I'm not that hungry.
So how is it going?
Are you getting along
with your new work place?
My department has only guys. It's been fun.
That's good.
Mine is all-girl.
I can't trust anybody.
Just my boss alone
is already hard to deal with.
If you weren't there,
I would have felt so lonely.
You wanna drink something?
I'll order it for you.
Nah, I'm good.
But if you wanna order some beer, go ahead.
Don't worry about me.
I can drink with you.
You drink beer?
Just a little bit.
Go ahead and order.
I'll go to toilet.
Right. Okay.
Hey!
Hey, you!
Hey, you bastard!
Yes, sir.
One bottle of beer and two glasses.
No. Don't. I'll take care of that.
Just stick to your business.
Jon. Jongjood.
Jongjood. Hood. Dong-i.
Salai. Salai-i.
Jongted. Pong-i.
Jong-slong.
Pong-i.
Shit!
What?!
You carry it all yourself?
The waiter is busy so I thought
I'd handle it myself.
Cheers!
Just one glass, okay?
Then I'll just sit with you.
Sure. Sure.
What's the matter, Prae?
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
It tastes so weird.
Weird?
Mine tastes normal.
You want a new one. I can order that.
I think it's because I don't drink it that often.
I'll just sip along.
Yeah, could be.
Prae.
Are you alright?
What are you doing, Lek?
What the fuck?!
No!
Prae. I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
Get out now!
I'm...
I'm sorry.
Get out!
Prae.
Prae, are you alright?
You want it so bad?
You are not saying that we?
Just keep it slow.
Whoa. That's right.
You've been so timid. I never thought...
you would be on fire like this.
You must have some feelings for me.
Right, Prae?
Ghost! She's a ghost!
No more!
Help me! Help!
No!
No more!
Yeah, that's right.
Hey!
Don't come home late again tonight.
Please do come in, officer.
This is very unusual.
We tried calling him home,
no one answered. He's gone missing.
Prae. Going through it line by line.
Just like usual.
Thanks.
Excuse-me.
You're Prae, right?
Thana...
What a coincidence!
How have you been?
We haven't met for ages.
Since the senior year in high school...
It's probably been 10 years now.
Yeah, such a long time.
I didn't mean to
stop keeping in touch with you.
It's alright. It's nice to see you again.
You're doing fine, right?
Well, I can get by.
You're in town for business?
You remember where I used to live?
Yeah, I heard someone's renting it now.
Yeah, but I've had it renovated.
I turned it into a restaurant.
That's why I have to
be here every weekends.
And go back to work on Mondays.
You could come whenever you're free, Prae.
That's so awesome.
I'll stop by later, okay?
You haven't changed a bit, you know.
How so?
Well, back then...
if my parents didn't have to move to Bangkok,
it would have been great.
Well, however...
can I have your number?
Sure.
Okay. This is my number.
I'll have to go now.
Let's catch up next time.
Prae,
Yes?
Boss Toy wants to see you.
Oh, hey, Prae. You're here.
Come on in.
This is Inspector Eak.
Hi.
Sit down. Have a seat.
You're Prae, right?
Boss Pravit said that you and Lek are close.
Yes. We've been friends
since junior high school.
What's going on?
Well, actually,
when someone's gone missing less
than 24 hours,
there's nothing wrong.
Except for this man's case.
Yesterday, he was picking up
some cash for the company.
Last night, he had over 400 grand with him.
According to the procedure,
he's supposed to deposit this
money to the company's account.
But up until now, 1:50 pm,
nothing's in the system yet.
Moreover, Lek cannot be reached at all.
Considering that you're close to Lek,
I would like to ask you
whether you know where he is.
I really have no idea.
Sayan.
Puckish.
I've been told that last night
you picked Lek up
and left together.
Yes. Boss Pravit set up a
meeting with me and our customer.
That's right. The customer called
and postponed it.
I asked Lek to accompany me.
You shouldn't have brought that fuck-face.
That meddling dick ruined my mood.
Boss Pravit told me
you and Lek were sitting there
only a little while
and left the place together.
Yes. At the same time.
Only the two of them.
So if that's the case,
you are the last person who saw him,
correct?
You should know where he was going.
Or at least, you could tell me
where you were going with him
after you guys left.
Think hard.
Otherwise, you'll be an accomplice
of an embezzlement case.
Hold on, officer.
It shouldn't be that serious.
I, personally, don't think
Prae is that kind of person.
So you know it or not?
Where is Lek now?
I know nothing about that.
How can she know?
Last night, she was with me.
That fuck-face duck face headed home alone.
Me and Prae, we were having dinner there
til we were more than full.
Then we each went our separate ways, right?
Huh? But you said...
Oh, I forgot it.
It just came to my mind now.
Let's say it like this:
When anything comes to your mind again,
call me.
I'm tired of this shit.
Sayan, let's go.
I feel something in my bones.
Something bad must have happened...
for sure.
Prae, now you owe me, you know that?
I really don't know where Lek is.
Okay. Alright. You don't have
to tell me that now. Later.
For now,
let me buy you one meal to calm you down.
See, I know where we can
get good bouncy meatballs.
I bet you'll be addicted to it.
Here you are, the bouncy pork.
Excuse-me.
Where is the man who came with me?
He's taking a shower over there, Ma'am.
Taking a shower?
Yes, Ma'am.
It's hot and humid.
A shower can make you
feel much more refreshing.
But, boss, we agreed to
just have dinner together.
Calm down.
They make good bouncy meatballs here.
And that thing with the police,
I put my neck on the line for you.
You see now how much I care about you?
400,000 baht is totally nothing for me.
I just want you to repay me some time.
Just a little bit.
I think you misunderstood me, boss.
Hold on. Hold on, Prae. Wait, please.
If you're doing this to me,
plus that friend of yours who
stole the company's money,
I think you can definitely get into trouble.
It's not what you and the police think.
Lek did leave the restaurant with me.
But on the way, I fell asleep.
And Lek tried to...
The fact that Lek went missing
or that money thing
has nothing to do with me.
Hold on. Alright then.
Just come up to the room
and tell me the whole story.
I can listen to you all night long.
Let go of me.
Let me go, boss.
Let's think of this as an early year-end bonus.
When did you find him?
Early in the evening.
These two civilians found him, sir.
I never dream that this would come true.
What do you want me to do first?
Take off your top? Sure.
Not good?
Then your skirt. Let's take your skirt off.
Why now? Not the skirt?
I know now.
You like it in uniform, right?
Wow.
Blue.
That's right.
Just like my taste.
I'm going in now.
I'll give it to you.
So this is how it feels.
Are you awake now, darling?
Just do nothing.
Let me give it to you.
Oh, lord has mercy.
Zeus bless me. Oh my god.
I cum. I cum.
Ghost!
Help me! Help me!
Get off!
Shit. Ghost. Ghost. Ghost.
Hello? Yes.
That's right.
Really?
When?
What do I have to do now?
Mhm.
I will donor her body.
I've arranged everything for the hospital.
"House on hot sale."
Who fucks you best?
Who's the best?
You, sir!
Shit. Fucking bitch.
You never saw people fuck?
Stupid whore. Just like your damn mother.
Don't ever show your face here again.
Oh, hey, Prae.
What about your mom? How is she?
You looks not good
Oh, my mom?
She's better now.
Hey, can I have the bill?
We're closing, sir.
Bring me the bill, then.
Prae, there are rooms available
next to our restaurant.
If you still don't want to go home,
you can rest here.
Take some rest here, Prae.
I'm around here anyway.
Thank you.
But I'd rather not.
We can split here.
Prae, are you sure that you
can go home alone?
What about Ning? Is she fine?
We broke up long time ago.
It just didn't work.
Just like you said.
Then I'll leave now.
Thanks for keeping me company.
I'm... I'm sorry, Prae.
I think...
I think we shouldn't do it yet.
I don't know how to explain.
There's something weird happening to me.
Prae, you don't need to be afraid.
We are always meant to be, you know.
If anything's meant to happen, just let it be.
You're the one who captured Pravit?
Yes, sir.
Last night, he was running out naked,
shouting about some ghost in the market.
So I put him here to calm him down.
I heard him raving the whole night.
Then this morning, I found him like this.
This shit is getting out of control.
I saw you smiling.
Why were you smiling?
He fell for a spell.
My spell.
You understand what he says?
No, sir.
What is he in for?
Someone accused him of making potions.
He's waiting to be identified today.
What do you know?
Want to tell me about it?
If I do, would you let me out?
It's a long story.
It has to do with...
the Virgo woman
who entrusted
her heart
her body
and her life
to this one and only guy.
Before she found out
that she was too naive.
The reality hit her in the face.
Love... does not exist.
But what's worse is that she was pregnant
with a baby...
that no one wanted.
That's where you came in, right?
I will revenge you all.
I will haunt you,
damn you for all your life!
I will haunt you!
The blood and pus
from the unforgiving woman
was processed in the ancient voodoo cult
and reunited with the spirit.
If you use it right,
it will manipulate the fire of lust
that belongs to its slaves.
But if someone's using it...
with no regard of the ancient rules:
Stealing the love potion...
using force...
without the owner's consent,
they must face the consequences
and they can never control the vengeful spirit.
Someone took love potion from you?
It was...
taken away from me
since the first day...
I ever put my feet on this country.
The potion you talked about
used to be in here, right?
Human Resource Manager
He was running naked in the market at night.
Hello?
Hi, Prae.
Why didn't you wake me up this morning?
It's a good thing I didn't.
Oh, really? Well, about last night...
Are you alright?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I told you, don't worry.
But...
It's not that I don't believe you. But last night,
we proved that there's nothing.
You're right...
Good, then.
So can we meet again today?
I miss you.
Thana, let's not see each other for a while.
Why, Prae? But we...
I've gotta go now.
I miss you, too, you know.
Let me get back to you.
I just checked out the footage
from the mini-mart close to where you
and Lek were eating the other night.
I followed the trace of you that night.
I found this.
Have you seen it before?
Never.
Do you know 'Boss Tong'?
No, sir.
I think...
I can get you some explanation on this
but probably not all of it.
This kind of thing happened to a
dirty old man who's already dead.
I don't want it to ever happen again.
What happened?
Some women fall under the spell
that's gone wrong,
making those men
they slept with die or go mad
again and again.
Are you saying that I'm one of them?
Are there anyways to revoke the spell?
There's a way to get that
black magic out of you.
You can do that?
Someone can.
But the woman
has to cooperate.
Let me ask you frankly,
in these past few days,
you remember whom you have slept with?
Does it matter?
If you are under the potion from this bottle,
you probably can't remember or realize it.
But for those men you slept with,
there's a real danger.
It can't be true, then.
Because he just called me.
He sounded normal.
Are you sure...
that he's alright?
Someone's here for you.
Oh, Prae, didn't you tell me you want
some time off?
We haven't met for ages, Prae.
We've been together for so long.
Our fire's never burnt out.
Wanna join, Prae?
What do you say, Prae?
It's such fun.
Cool.
I've always wanted to try it.
What's this?
You'll see.
No. Come on.
Hey, Prae, why are you standing there?
Come on in.
Thana, Prae is here.
Cool. It's down here, right?
Yeah. Why not.
I told you, Prae. We're meant to be.
Ning.
Shit!
Ning! Ning, what's wrong with you?
Dear Inspector,
I'm aware that you've been
investigating this case for a while.
You must think I am the cause of it all,
the one who's hurt Lek, the manager, Thana
and probably, Boss Tong
or any other guys that you're aware of.
In fact, there's more to it.
It's much more complicated than you knew.
Well, I have no need to tell you about it.
"House on hot sale."
You must be wondering
about why I left this note to you, then.
I just don't want you to
waste your precious time.
A good cop like you
should be spending time
pursuing other cases
that are more beneficial for the people.
I just want you to quit tracking me down.
Quit finding the truth.
Because, in the end,
you'll never know what really happened.
You should just let me go.
There're a lot of bad guys
out there who deserve it.
So long, Inspector.
I hope we'll never meet again.