In the 30’s, an American secret
society became quite notorious.
Its members rejected
the whole idea of love,
deemed art evil, and claimed
to find the so-called" RAPTURE OF BEING "
through a total liberation of the senses.
After a congress was held by those
adepts in New York, in September 1937,
they weren’t heard of anymore.
One year later, a reporter
thought he found them again
in the middle of uncharted territories.
He vanished too.
This movie tells the
story of how some of their daughters
came back to live among us.
We can’t leave her like this.
I gave orders.
They’re coming to get her.
Stop erasing this drawing..
They’re waiting for us.
I’m ready.
What’s this laughter outside ?
Samantha is initiating Leonardo.
- Group eight is expected at eight thirty. -
They’ve already reached group eight.
- The packing teams are
required to make haste-
Ah, here you are !
She couldn’t take it anymore.
- All seduction objects leaving
with the commando are expected-
Get up, little Felicia.
- Group six. Group six is expected-
I don’t want to see my body.
It’s too large for me.
- The packing team in charge of
group six is required to make haste-
The others are following us.
Let’s go, children.
I can’t get used to
the voices they gave us.
Their females still
have voices like that.
I’ve been told they hide to make love.
Let’s go.
This is my last will and testament.
You have been chosen to build the
foundations of our coming invasion.
Your willpower is
now strong enough
to win over the world
that once exiled us.
We made you beautiful,
because where you’re going,
beauty is still a privilege.
Go, and fight this world where
love is still considered a virtue.
Go, and castrate
all of their masters.
All those, who make
them live in fear.
Here are your roses !
Somewhere in our world.
Are you crazy ? No, stop !
- Her name is Cascade
No. No, leave me alone.
Stop it. Stop it.
You’re such an animal !
I’m getting married tomorrow
anyway, you know.
Will you cut the bullshit already ?
Pierre, the gardener.
Don’t you know everybody’s getting
fed-up with your stupidities ?
Madame Papadéous, Cascade’s aunt.
Don’t touch Sala’s dress, will you !
She’s getting married, you’re not.
You’d better prepare
Choupeti’s chocolate.
I’ve got to hurry !
Mr. Grop is waiting for me.
Choupeti, the son.
Your chocolate is coming,
little angel.
Cascade is making it now.
You still haven’t kissed me today.
Oh no, don’t do that.
Come on, are you mad ? No...
What about the bloody chocolate ?
What the hell are you doing ?
Choupeti is waiting.
It can’t go on like this,
you know, I’m warning you.
And don’t forget the cousins’ book.
I wonder where those two are.
Can you tell me ?
Goodbye, my darling.
- Goodbye, Mom.
Bloody bugging fly !
Ah, here you are. Follow me.
Hello, my dear friend.
- Yeah, hello, sorry.
Mr. Grop, the mayor.
Please forgive me,
I’m in a hurry,
I can’t keep you long,
'cause I’m very busy.
Please, take a seat.
I asked you to come,
because I’ve been
commissioned with a sale.
The house next door,
you know,
the Fogle villa.
Well, it’s been sold.
Werner, Grop’s right hand man.
It all happened in
quite an unusual fashion.
First, there was an intervention
of some big wig at the Prefecture.
Some phone calls from the capital city
You know me, I like to
be aware of everything.
Yes..
Those people will
probably move in soon.
So I’m going to ask you,
since you’re their neighbour,
to take a look, just so we
know who we’re dealing with.
Excuse me, but I’m in a real hurry,
I’m a very busy man.
Werner, will you be nice
enough to see
Mme. Papadéous to the door.
- Good morning, Madame.
How is Sala ?
- She’s fine.
Oh, yes, let’s talk
about that wedding !
I think it’s ridiculous.
For a young man who
fancies dabbling in politics,
to marry Sala Papadéous,
is madness !
Blanche, M. Grop’s wife,
and her servant.
Please do it again.
I love it.
I see your pleasures
are high brow as ever.
We’re having fun.
Don’t you have
anything else to do ?
What?
Don’t forget you’re Madame Grop.
As some of us might remember,
during the 1930’s,
the American public opinion got
all excited about a secret society
whose adepts were believed
to have acquired
supernatural powers through
various training practices.
I must have left
a handkerchief around here.
Here, wait. I let him get away
with everything. Oh, I’m such a coward.
Why do you say this ?
- How I wish I weren’t that way.
In late May 1935,
the members of the sect,
gathered in the lounges of the
Waldorf-Astoria Hotel in New York.
it seems a decision was reached
at the end of this congress since,
from this moment on,
they were never heard of again.
The town’s cabaret.
Did you see the glasses ?
- What do I care ?
You’re too much, you know that ?.
- Time to go to bed, gramps !
Oh, here they are now.
- Hi, guys !
Hi !
Oh shit, enough is enough !
Here’s your bloody rag.
I’ve got work to do.
Fucking artists !
Cut the bullshit, will you.
Here are Ruth and Ivan.
They live with Tristan, a painter.
Hi.
Can you still see anything ?
Yeah, I’ve got to finish
this panel for tomorrow.
Aren’t you asleep ?
And how’s our star ?
Come on, come on,
you’ve got to sleep, now.
Don’t you think you’re
slightly overdoing it ?
Fuck you.
Why are you like this ?
- Because he’s making fun of me.
The little girl we just saw,
is Ruth’s daughter.
As for the blonde, her name is Rita.
Trying to make yourself pretty, are you ?
- What seems to be the matter ?
God, this is something else !
I think...
the cross-dressing boy, the painter,
the sassy black girl and her poor child.
You’re on the wrong path, father,
if you begin to feel indulgence
for such creatures.
Nowadays, people tend
to forget the devil !
Yes, absolutely, the devil !
The point is, the devil may not always be,
where you expect him.
M’Lord ?
- What do you want ?
Your permission to go to bed.
- Go, go !
This is the cardinal’s house.
He lives between his secretary
and Marie, his housekeeper.
Is she as submissive as she seems ?
She’s going to be the first one.
Why she ?
- Because she’s fed-up.
I don’t like much the stupidities that
you entertain these days, father.
Give this ring to whom it belongs.
The one he wears on his finger
is a fake
since 07.07.1957.
Come and visit us.
We shall quench your appetites.
Our voices are already wandering
among the monsters.
This one is unhappy, isn’t she ?
She’s only saved by the tangos in her head.
Tangos ?
This is one of their ways,
to feel less lonely.
She hates him.
Yes, but there’s a strange perfume
of tenderness.
Werner visits Sala Papadéous, his fiancée.
Good morning, madam.
- Good morning.
Come on, get inside, will you !
I forbid you to go out.
Mademoiselle has a rendezvous.
- Yes, I know.
Liberte, Sala’s sister.
Look !
Blanche ! Go and fetch the plane !
I wonder who’ll rid me of that woman !
Grop,please stop being childish.
- Well, what’s so important ?
You know my housekeeper ?
Yesterday, she came to me claiming
that she had a... visit.
A visit ?
- Yes..
Yes. She was visited by a being...
some sort of female being.
Well, she doesn’t really know. So, yes,
I roared with laughter, as you would have.
But the strange thing is:
the visitor left proof of her passage.
Proof ?
- A ring.
A ring absolutely identical to mine.
She claimed that mine was a fake,
and hers was genuine.
And you believe this bullshit ?
Look. The point is not
believing or disbelieving.
It might be more than just poppycock,
and I think that perhaps it is a matter
concerning your police.
Because this morning I had the
rings examined by an expert
mine is fake, hers is genuine.
Is that you ?
I threw everybody out.
It’s so difficult for us to meet.
Do you recognize your tiny ass ?
Look what I do to it.
Do you love me today ?
Did you successfully manage your aunt
and your two bitchy cousins ?
What is it ?
She won’t come...
Why are you here ?
I came because...
I told myself...
You were supposed to see Cascade,
with the intention of...
So, I thought...
You’re a tramp !
Get lost ! Get lost !
Tramp...
Asshole !
The cardinal’s housekeeper
answered the Spermulas’ call.
Well, you see, you came.
- Why are you afraid ?
Freedom frightens slaves.
It forces us to invent ourselves, when
their world annihilated their imagination.
My name is Gilda. I’m the one who
came to you the first time.
Today, you won’t see our mistress.
No, I changed my mind.
Are you aware of being
a fantastic medium ?
Why do we inspire fear ?
They’re so afraid of being different.
Did you see the dread in her eyes ?
She couldn’t bear her
newfound freedom.
Now she’s one of us.
When she wakes up,
you will take her back.
We need her outside.
Oh, it’s you, mom.
Hey, look at her !
What is she ? Crazy ?
Some people care about politics !
We care about music,
partying and magic !
On the next morning...
I bet the nigger bitch never fed him.
Where’s my dog ?
Well, here’s his meat.
Look how the stupid girl
put that plane down !
Don’t you know where the dog is ?
Can’t you stop this ?
Will you stop already !
You sure are pretty like this.
You make me want to puke.
You make me want to puke...
If only you knew !
- If I knew what ?
A pig, that’s what you are !
A monstrosity !
If only you knew.
How I love you
How I love you...
You’re a nice guy, officer.
Good. Very good.
Perfect.
You are perfect.
You pretend to like it,
don’t you, bitch ?
You pretend to like it ?
Yeah!
- No!
Come in.
Mr. Werner is here.
- Tell him to come in.
You really are a bastard.
Good morning, Mme Grop.
Good morning, Werner.
You’ll excuse me...
The green-eyed young man who
came to see us. Was he on our side ?
Yes. His name is Werner.
He's weird..
He has very hard to fathom vibrations.
He’s the right hand man of the
most powerful man in this town,
but he has also been an adept
of ours for ten of their years.
Nevertheless, he seems very preoccupied
with matters of material powers
Whatever. We need him.
You always come at the right moment.
You still are your old
hugely vulgar self.
Your own rudeness proves
you’ve got good news for me.
What do you mean ?
What I mean, you little cocksucker,
is that you wouldn’t dare to insult me
if you weren’t on the right track.
I think I found the money.
Bravo. It was about time. Who ?
We’ll see about that later.
But I have one condition.
A junior partner title and...
Don’t be abused by their stories...
It doesn’t matter what confidence
trick those two men may have pulled.
And it doesn’t matter that it was pulled
on the small town they are in charge of.
It doesn’t matter
that this woman is searching.
The only thing that matters,
is the rotten perfume...
...bathing their lives.
I already told you I was
opposed to this marriage.
I’m off.
- All right, all right.
As you wish.
I don’t care. When will it be ?
I thought the day after tomorrow.
Who’s giving the money ?
He thinks we’re going
to give him the money.
To them, money is everything.
Leave them alone.
You’re exhausting yourself.
Let’s go back to work.
You’re right. Are you all ready?
We shall resume our immodesty drills.
You ! Go and fetch the male witness.
To be alive, always alive.
On the other side, there is sunlight.
It’s there, within reach of the skin.
You must hate man and his tyranny.
Girls !
The best of them will gladly oblige,
and will give life to their poetry.
At last !
I knew you were here.
Sala Papadéous. Liberte’s sister
and Werner’s fiancée.
Is mom sleeping ?
What about Choupeti ?
- Don’t know.
Superstitions are afraid
of mirrors for a reason.
Mirrors have a secret,
and a frightful secret it is.
There’s something true
on the other side.
In this other space to which
nothing serious can happen.
Look at my face.
Watch it closely.
As if you were seeing it for the first time.
My face is a show.
You are attending my face’s show.
You are with me.
My face is becoming an eternal object.
A landscape.. Follow me...
I’m now crossing to the other side
Yes... yes...
I don’t love you anymore.
We will never see each other again
The sun.
Sala !
Hey, here’s your fiancé.
- Hi !
You seem pretty self-assured.
- If you knew.
If I knew what ?
If I knew what, Werner ?
Stop it ! You know perfectly
well that you don’t want to.
It drives me crazy.
Kiss !
Do I smell good ?
- Like a flower.
It takes a gardener,
to water such a flower.
I’m fed-up with it.
Ruth ! Ruth !
- Yes.
Ok.
I love you.
I love you too, little man.
No, no, of course not !
You’re missing the point entirely.
You don’t have a clue.
It was like this, I tell you.
Here you are.
You’re beautiful.
What the hell are you doing ?
I’ve got work to do in the garden.
He was a...
great hairdresser.
An artist..
There...
Make sure that your own beauty
does not trick you.
Remember your true faces.
Gilda ! Are you crazy ?
You may not become
attached to anything.
Do you understand ?
You must hate your faces,
these jewels, those ludicrous dresses,
everything that makes you
objects of desire in this world.
I’m telling you this,
because I can feel some of us
weakening.
I can feel everything.
From childhood, you know ?
We must act. We’ve got
the cardinal’s housekeeper.
This one will be next.
They’ve been here for three weeks.
In order to know so many people, I tell you,
they already had supporters in our town.
She even met Tristan,
the painter you don’t like,
and commissioned a portrait from him.
She met all my former
friends from the cabaret.
I think those women have
abnormal powers. They are mediums.
What are you ? Mad ?
What’s all this bullshit?
First the cardinal, now you.
A madwoman, that’s what you are.
Mediums !
Have you already seen any medium ?
You’re mad. You’re unhinged.
Here ! Look at yourself!
Look ! Remember. The oh-so-fresh
Blanche Dubois.
The beautiful artist.
A sick wreck, no more.
What do you think ?
Mme Grop is tired.
- That’s not what I mean.
If you’re referring to those presences,
I think... please forgive me, madam...
but I think the whole thing
is preposterous.
You can say that again.
I’m going to bed,
that’s the best thing I can do.
Preposterous ?
I’ve known you for a long time.
Do you remember, Madame Grop ?
Please, do not get
interested in their stories.
Stories are good for men of the past.
Know only that in this instant,
a being exists is this very light.
If you fuck with me, even a little,
I’ll destroy you.
Little Werner.
This is great, I must say.
He’s terribly repressed. Look.
Yes. He can’t rise
above common visions.
He knows only the primary phase.
We’ve got to mutate him.
I can’t.
Yes you can. He’s now gone to
the other side.
He’s ours.
Now you’re free. No pride, no anguish.
You’ll never be a man of the past again.
It’s so good.
She was the most profound,
the most visionary of them all,
and she allowed herself to fall into
the crudest, the most illusory of traps.
Love..
- Did she have a bad night ?
Yes.
- I’ll go and see her.
I fail to understand why they chose her.
She lacks strength.
Here, take this. It will do you good.
Close the curtains, will you ?
The light is killing me.
Are you not feeling well, darling ?
It’s nothing. Probably this world.
I miss teaching.
Today, we’ll resume our listening.
You know, I’m receiving a weird
thing since earlier today.
There is love around here, I can feel it.
It makes me want to puke.
You’re being silly. There’s only
hate among our neighbours.
Shut up ! I feel it, I tell you !
You’re tickling me.
You’re really crazy, aren’t you ?
It’s funny. I feel like
biting you like this.
I’ll swallow you. I’ll digest you.
You’re being gross.
That’s rich, coming from you
who likes talking only about sex.
That’s true. I like it.
Why do I like it ?
It’s because... because you’re...
Well, shit !
This is really fucking good. Really good.
My Man ! You’re so silly !
What’s happening with the gardener ?
It seems to have failed.
- Why do you say that ?
Because I can see it.
He’s not been freed in the right way.
What do you want ?
- Is your mother home ?
No...
What’s the matter ?
Are you crazy ? What’s with you ?
You’re not yourself !
Take a seat.
Blanche, my darling,
will you close the door ?
I asked you to come here tonight
in order to announce Werner’s promotion
and his engagement to Sala Papadéous.
I’m really happy.
But I also want to talk
about something else.
It makes me think that what happened
to you is somehow happening to me.
If you’re anything like me...
Oh, no ! My love is much lower
than that. Will you excuse me ?
...and I asked Werner to investigate.
No result.
What’s really bothering me,
is that each time I asked a question
about those people to
someone in the capital city...
Would you like a drink ?
- I’d like a glass of water, please.
Each time, they led me to
understand that I’d better... well,
in a nutshell..
leave the matter alone.
That’s why I think it’s our
responsibility to shed light on it.
So I’m going to ask you, Countess,
and also you, Your Lordship,
to kindly pay a visit to those people,
in order to learn who we’re dealing with.
Yes. I understand.
Thank you.
Werner warns us that the cardinal
is only willing to come to dinner
in order to learn about us.
An investigation of sorts.
Come and see. It’s strange
she kept looking over her shoulder,
as if she could feel my presence.
I think she’s a natural at listening.
When was it ?
- Thirty-six hours ago.
We should be able to do it.
That man, Grop,
doesn’t receive any fluid.
We can only reach him through her.
Blanche will be theirs soon.
As for the cardinal, they’re
waiting for him this very evening.
And the next morning...
Some friends told me you
weren’t feeling very well.
I’m all right, don’t worry.
Images are coming back to me.
When was that dinner with the cardinal ?
I must say the colour of your robe,
your complexion and those
tiny prawns create a harmony...
Thanks.
Nice of you to let me come.
- I’m glad to see you.
Why have you covered
the paintings like this ?
It’s soothing me.
Do you know what ?
No...
So this is their solution
to cross to the other side...
Love... My little trick...
In fact, M’Lord, you can understand us
better than many others.
My girls and I are living
in a kind of community.
Yes, I see.
Do you know we own absolutely
exceptional collections ?
Do you ?
And we’re going to show
you some of our treasures...
I’d like to know how to draw.
Would you like it ?
Maybe I would, yes.
What’s wrong with me. I’m crazy.
Are you all right ?
I cannot stay.
I need to wash my hands.
Thank you.
Oh, yes, I’m all right. Well...
I think we’ll take a break.
Please excuse me.
Feeling a bit dizzy.
I... er... I leave you here.
You may stay as long as you want.
May I take your drawing ?
Well... yes...
Although I don’t like it much.
Thank you.
What happened ?
- Don’t know.
She’s scaring me.
She’s just a little weird.
You’re pretty when you’re scared.
You’re crazy. She’ll be back.
Concentrate. Let’s lead him
to the swimming pool,
where our girls are waiting for him.
Erase this drawing, Ingrid.
Erase it now.
Like before. Nothing must remain.
I can’t. I can’t anymore.
Time is shifting. It’s their doing.
Their love is destroying you.
Free yourself from them, Ingrid.
- I can’t.
I’ll do it for you.
- No. They’re mine.
Help me !
You’re our master, Ingrid.
- Leave me alone, then. Leave me.
I’m leaving you.
But remember that you
must flee only poets,
those who already own
a version of the rapture.
substitutes of life that they excrete,
help people weathering the bad times...
He’s coming closer.
He’s almost here. He’s here
As for this couple,
I think you see too much of them.
And I think asking him for
that drawing was ridiculous.
Before, you loved erasing them,
it was so simple...
- This is none of your business.
I like them. If only they didn’t
reek so much of love...
You must free them of this crap.
What are you waiting for ?
Do what must be done.
They’re grotesque.
I make the decisions.
- You make the decisions.
We’re not well. We have to
take up the listenings again.
Tell me, how many times
did the artist come here ?
He came three times in the flesh,
and several times more as waves.
When was the first time ?
- The first time wasn’t important.
I think it was the second
time which did the trick.
I don’t remember what I was doing.
Oh, yes, I was painting my nails,
or some absurd thing like that.
Hello.
- Good evening.
It’s strange. Before, when I saw you, sir...
- Don’t call me sir.
When I saw you, Tristan, I felt ill.
An when I see you now,
I feel very very well.
Where is Cascade?
I tell you they’ve been drinking.
This is not normal.
Why are you staring at me ?
Maybe it’s time for you to know.
Come and see.
Come and see, will you ? Come !
You see, you’re not exactly
up to date, honey.
Don’t you think it’s time to let her know ?
She must know that you visited next door,
and you’ll never be the same again,
so she’ll shed her oh so proper attitude.
And it’s not only you. I went there too.
Pierre put in my womb,
something from next door.
Something from madness.
Oh, I forgot, you didn’t know.
Pierre has been fucking me for
a long time. Yes, he does fuck me.
And he fucks Sala too. Princess Sala!
She takes him full in the arse.
Yes, my dear mommy, full in the arse.
Several miles worth of prick.
Isn’t it true, little Sala ?
Sala ? It’s not true, is it ?
- Can’t you see they’re crazy ?
Come. You’ll stay in Grop’s house
until our wedding.
Everything will be alright.
Grop isn’t home.
The maid will let you in.
Wait for me !
Tell me, Liberte was telling
the truth, wasn’t she ?
Our victory is imminent.
How is it going with the mother ?
It’s done. She’s with us.
Shall I tell or shall I project ?
Project. Let’s not indulge
our awful physical voices.
It wasn’t hard. She already
lived a parallel life.
I put her in contact with her late husband.
He was a hairdresser.
Don’t fret. I was sure he would come.
Give me my curling iron, Sausage !
He wasn’t always nice to me.
The seconds. All the seconds !
The billions seconds of life !
Like ants ! A regular anthill !
They eat me, they bore in me,
they get fat on me !
Darling ? Darling ?
Do you still love me ?
I would like to see your face !
She’s done with love.
She’ll never be the same again.
- She’ll never be the woman she was.
What became of the cardinal ?
And what about the rich man’s wife ?
The Blanche woman.
Blanche !
- She’s on her way.
What bitches...
Where are the fucking sluts ?
Their violence is a strange thing.
They don’t know how
to live in freedom.
No matter. He’s ours.
- Yes, he’s ours.
Oh, my God ! My God !
Hello ?
- It’s me. Blanche is gone.
Yeah ? Well, she’s gone anyway.
She must be at the cabaret.
See that it’s raided.
But...
- No buts, little Werner.
If you don’t see that
the matter is settled tonight,
don’t count on me tomorrow
morning for your wedding.
Get it ?
Alright !
Tell the blokes in the militia not
to pull their punches
we don’t often have the opportunity
to teach a lesson to those degenerates.
See you tomorrow.
I can’t do it. I can’t do it.
They do not receive me.
I can’t unscramble.
Take a hold of yourself, Ingrid.
We must go on.
The Black girl ?
You had her, didn’t you ?
Yes. I called her this morning.
- Was it hard ?
The Black one. The Black girl.
In the cabaret.
Ruth... Yes, that’s it, Ruth. I met her.
In a big, in a huge city...
Very far. In 1950.
- That is not possible.
You weren’t born.
I need her.
She’s threatened.
Images came back to me.
Images blocked my sight.
Oh, those harassing images !
Ruth...
Ruth... Ruth...
You’re one of us now.
It’s hard ! Help me, I’m loosing her.
So what ? You succeeded. She’s ours.
Don’t you understand ? I’m not worried
about our victory, but about my defeat.
Can’t you see this world is taking us ?
Diamant !
Help me ! Help me !
I’m coming with you for the very
last time. This is outrageous.
Hey, you, human flesh merchant !
While Ivan and Tristan are taking a stroll,
M. Grop’s policemen are
doing their job at the cabaret.
Up you go !
- Yes.
Are you OK ?
- Yeah.
How happy will M. Grop be !
- No !
You’re a funny sight upside down.
I like you.
I like you too, little man.
Who else among you feels pleasure in
looking at their reflection in a mirror ?
Strangely enough, recently, I’ve been
having emotions that were unknown to me.
Which ones ?
Tell me.
Must I really, Diamant ?
It’s necessary. This is the reason
why we’re losing our power.
Is this a new feeling for you ?
To take those feelings away from them,
is the very reason why we came here
It was shame, wasn’t it ?
That’s what you felt ?
- Yes.
Pride too, and you wanted to be loved.
Is that why you did what you did ?
You knew ?
- Here we know everything.
And you know what’s coming to you.
- No, please !
Oh shit !
What is it ? What happened ?
Where’s the kid ?
Oh, God, I’ll get him !
Ruth is all right.
She’s gone to see the women
in the villa across the road.
Who did this ?
- M. Grop.
Here. Put this on.
Are you all right ?
- Yes, I’m better.
You feel better, don’t you ?
Can I introduce him ?
Yes.
Good morning, Werner.
- Good Morning, Ingrid.
Don’t touch that.
This is a very good copy.
- No, an original.
This is genuine.
The one in the Prado is a copy.
The same goes for the Mona Lisa,
the picture in the
Louvre museum is a forgery.
For forty years,
we’ve been working on the
exchange of your valuables, you know
I know. Yours is a formidable power.
That’s why I’ve been wondering,
why are you unwilling to help me ?
We have many contacts
in the whole world,
and many of them have
already been compromised.
We’re none the worst for it.
I’m not sure I can trust you, Werner.
Look. I’m on the verge
of reaching my goal.
I’ve been fighting for it for ten years.
You say you’re one of us,
little Werner.
I can see you’re still motivated by things
which are utterly meaningless to us.
To us, this power is nothing.
If it leads to slavery, it’s nothing,
just like money.
For you, other people are rabble,
but you’re proving that
you have no nobility.
None at all. You know nothing
of the beauty of failure.
You know nothing of the absurd.
What gives you the right
to speak to me like that ?
Obviously,
you’ve never been humiliated.
What do you know of my problems ?
Nothing, that’s for sure.
Nothing at all.
You should take me too,
while you’re at it.
Why don’t you try it with me ?
You took Pierre, after all.
And the bishop didn’t escape you.
And Liberte through Pierre.
And the bishop’s housekeeper
through the bishop himself.
What about me ? Why not ?
Take me.
Make me one of you,
so I can be free your way.
Werner, no ! Werner... Werner !
Werner ! Stop it ! Werner, no !
Werner, no ! Please, Werner.
Stay back. Stay back !
Stop !
Werner !
I know a lot about
your activities here.
And elsewhere too.
Beware !
You’re very strong,
but you’re not invulnerable.
Remember that.
Tell me. What is love ?
Love ?
It’s a river in Russia.
Stop !
Stop being stupid.
Just stop it, alright ?
If you don’t,
I’ll punch you in the face.
But I tell you I loved her.
Can’t you understand ?
Why are you saying you loved her,
when she’s all right ? She’s here !
Don’t do this, you dummy !
Come on, hurry up ! Come on !
We’re going to... hurry up !
Let’s go and see Ruth.
Bastards ! Motherfuckers ! Bastards,
I’ll get them !
Come ! Oh, come ! Come !
So many are left here !
Their pleasures ! Their pleasures
don’t take them anywhere.
Satisfaction. Only satisfaction...
This party is going to be our victory.
- Yes, maybe.
What’s the matter with you now ?
- Don’t bother.
Pierre !
Look, nobody came
to our wedding dinner.
We’ll tell them the truth,
of course, but that truth,
believe me, most of them
can’t understand it.
I’m afraid they’ll think it’s absurd.
Most of them have...
only feelings as they say.
My duty was to
report to my superiors.
I’m disappointed.
I’ve been told to forget it all.
You don’t say ?
You’re completely drunk, poor chap.
The father is not drunk.
You are, Grop.
What the father just said is true.
It’s part of the truth.
I’m going to tell you the rest.
You uttered the word,
love
Yes. Yes, I’m becoming
a mortal again,
since love makes one mortal,
at the same time giving life.
Beware. You know I’m prepared to do
anything to save you.
Are you sure you
won’t touch Tristan ?
This is why I told you
that we would be able,
to pose as saviours in the public eye,
just by exposing the case.
If that were true,
you wouldn’t frown like this.
You would already be calling
the press on the phone.
Sir !
For ten years,
I was an adept of those people.
What I just revealed...
- What game are you playing, Werner ?
Follow me, M. Grop, and you’ll see
that what I’m telling you is true.
How does your religion
deal with people who sin ?
They’re being punished.
- Yeah ? How are they punished.
They’re flogged.
Where is there a phone ?
It’s too early for that, M. Grop.
Before that, I want to
show you something.
What ?
Open the door, Werner !
Fuck me. Don’t mind him.
How is it going, Gramps ?
- How handsome he is in his tuxedo !
Come on.
- Yeah, I’m making space for you.
Oh, Albert, don’t tell me
you’re freaking out.
I’m even sure that you love it.
Don’t you ?
Oh, no, he’s really in pain.
He can’t stand losing.
Your pride is what’s hurting you,
Albert. Your pride.
Those strangers have been
telling me a lot of things.
Come with us ! It feels great.
Come... with us.
Come. Come.
I love you !
I love you, little one.
They’re right. Everything is beautiful,
it’s true. You are beautiful.
Don’t say things like that.
I’m ugly as hell.
No. Why do you say that ?
If I were beautiful,
what with all the trouble
I take to make you love me,
would you love me anyway ?
Well, she’s going
to give herself to him,
and he will lose what
he still calls his love.
Before, I liked you.
Now I really love you.
Come ! I’m going to show you
the images haunting the little man.
You’ll never be a man of
the past again. Never again.
As long as no woman of our race,
is crazy enough to give herself to you.
I spilled everything to her.
The truth.
It’s true, I told her everything.
Can’t you see that it’s killing me ?
I need her now.
I need Sala.
And I absolutely need the money.
Not for me, of course,
but for her.
Because I love her.
I do love her.
I also need that swine, Grop.
I was your ally once.
Help me !
What’s with you ?
Gilda ! Follow me !
No, Diamant, no. I don’t want
my former face back.
You drove me mad, Ingrid
I don’t know how to draw anymore.
I don’t know how to draw !
He’s mad, Albert.
Albert is mad.
You’re free now.
- You knew ?
I suspected.
I can feel it when I see you.
So I’m free ?
But free to do what ?
Free to live on a large scale
what your miserable love
allows you to think
you’re living on a small one.
To live ?
What do you mean, to live ?
I’m living ! In order to have lived !
To remember !
And to extract from those memories
something that will allow
other people to live.
Ersatz.
- Maybe so.
But what are you suggesting ?
Maybe there, in you little
confined world, but not here.
No in this huge mess.
Freedom!
I’m not even free to love her !
And I want to love,
do you hear me ?
I can give you back,
what was taken from you.
How ?
- I have to give myself to you.
What will happen to you ?
- Nothing.
See your friend Gilda ?
She’s just finding her former
face again. Her real face.
You’ve lost, Ingrid,
and you can feel it. Lost.
I love him.
We came too early.
First, it’s necessary to cure them.
They’re too seriously ill.
Ingrid !
Farewell.
Why does she escape the law ?
This is a privilege,
of the angels of the future.
Translation goupil66
Timing McDuck
January - March