No, no...
Look, over there!
Go home
and sleep it off.
Let me go! You're heavily drunk.
If you must throw up,
then it's into the drunk tank!
(Latin)"Now I clearly see
the destiny of Carthage!"
So speak Danish, man!
"Now I clearly see
the destiny of Carthage!"
STOLEN SPRING
Come in.
So ...
No, are you now lying
and working again!
Now you must stop
the disgusting habit, Edward.
A judge can't sit
and bite your fingernails in court.
What would the criminals think?
You must be careful
not to be cold, Edward.
Better turn off the light now ...
you must be rested for the party tomorrow.
- Yes, mother.
- Sleep well, my boy.
Good night, Mom.
AKSEL NIELSEN
Careers adviser
I know, Nikolaj isn't particular academic, -
- but he really wants to be
together with his comrades.
That I have understood.
The problem is, that his ...
... what shall we say ...
free manner to be -
- drag the class' level in a direction,
that isn't in nobody's interest.
We might explore the possibility
of some extra lessons!
Let's hold on
in our decision.
At a folk high school
Nikolaj can make his theater -
- and continue working at his poems.
We can't keep
him longer at the school.
- A judge Ellerstr?m  is waiting ...
- We are in fact finished.
- He has been sitting here for 35 years.
- Well ... and what has it turned to?
Come, come ...
Voila ...
This table is taken.
It's my table, gentlemen.
Can't you recognize us, Mogensen?
It's us ...
Ellerstr?m and Nielsen.
From the school!
The Black Hand.
Manus nigra ...
Edward Ellerstr?m.
How is it going
with the clarinet, Mr. Judge?
It was more the law.
And Aksel Nielsen. One has become
senior master at the old school ...
And the hair has fallen
of the literary man.
You know, you have an
anniversary this year ...
A kind of anniversary.
We must see the old boys again.
It would probably be
a sad sight.
Mikael, we'll
get you a dinner jacket.
We can't be without
you and your nasty cracks.
One isn't intended to play penguin.
Come on, boys!
Up the stairs ...
Ellerstr?m, Mogensen
and Nielsen in front.
The first step there ...
The rest stays like this!
And then Thygesen seems to stay here.
So there must be plenty of place.
Oh yes, we're missing Thygesen!
Well, Thygesen, was you
then get married in Bangkok?
Married! Rather two at 16
than one at the 32.
- Sorry.
- Not at all.
Yes?
What is it now? I don't care,
they have damn just to pay in time!
I've been grateful -
- for associate Blomme's
qualified latin teaching.
I remember him with gratitude.
One remember him
almost as sadist.
Sucking pieces of barley sugar day in and
day out, without he offering one a piece.
He took poison, right?
- God knows, what he did.
- Maybe he was poisoned.
Spicy thinking ...
One of us is perhaps a murderer.
Quite boring, we're damn not.
- A little more meat?
- One don't eat corpses.
- Thank you very much.
- More meat?
- Yes, finally.
A few days ago, there was spring
cleaning at home with us, -
- and what emerged
to the light:
My old student's cap.
I watched it,
and the memories rushed over me.
The Utopia of childhood.
The Lost Paradise.
When we stood like flowers
at the paradise meadows.
Ingemann.
And I thought of the old school
and all the wonderful memories.
Not at least, associate Blomme ...
Today we're sitting here
scattered for all winds.
Each of us fills
his place in the society -
- and probably no little place ...
But one thing binds us together, -
- and it's the memory
of our fine, old school.
Back in our youth, when the world
was bright and blue and pure, -
- then it was heaven on earth.
Oehlenschl?ger ... "The Golden Horns".
Then we learned discipline,
order and obedience,
- virtues that we again today
see the youth professes to.
Oh ...
We could evoke
this state forward again.
Could we force the nature.
Could we turn the worlds
large clock back, -
- could we turn
the flow of time.
Could we exorcise the universe.
Give us the childhood again.
Take us back to
Utopia of the childhood.
Nonsense! Mikael Mogensen
come with the fingers.
- Aksel Nielsen, may we hear?
- It wasn't, what we had got for homework.
You must learn your things!
I will ensure -
- that you end up as
shoemakers and road sweepers.
Ellerstr?m, will you please?
Excuse, it wasn't,
what we had got for homework.
One don't read, while one are eating, Edvard.
Then one have no use of the food.
You told me yesterday,
that you had learned it.
Hurry up, otherwise you're
getting too late again.
Come here.
So!
That's it!
- Aksel ...
- There was one left.
- Behave now properly.
- Yes yes.
Thank you.
When two secants intersect ...
What's the product? Come!
The product
of the one secant's side ...
... And it's outside the circle
lying piece is equal to the product -
- of the second secant and its
outside the circle lying piece, -
- and the tangent is mean proportional between
the secant and its outside circle intermediate piece.
It's pure logic, kid!
I don't understand, you can't learn it!
Jørgen!
Your lunch pack.
- Good morning.
... then sparkle may
the dull look, -
- the paled cheeks glow.
So we travel
to our homeland,
where the the day don't lie dormant, -
there stands a castle
so proud and great ...
If you got earlier out the door, Ellerstrøm,
then you didn't get all the slaps.
Good morning! Let me remind the responsibility
that rests on everyone's shoulders.
You are the flower of Danish youth,
selected to suck nourishment -
- of this school's teachings.
Therefore, it's expected,
that you all do your best, -
- so we again can achieve the highest
grade point average in the country.
It's a long time
for the examination, -
- but it's now,
the work has to be done.
I can be reached in the parliament
the rest of the day.
Water is running out.
Get on!
Hurry, get on!
Hurry!
Well, Thygesen,
have you potential enough to -
- to tell us about
the Second Punic War?
Get up, Thygesen,
you obese youth.
Open your mighty jaws,
you whale-fish, -
- and spit your excellent
knowledges out.
Don't be stingy or
parsimonious with your wisdom, -
- but let also the rest of us
be allowed to sun ourselves -
- in the dazzling light
of your intellect.
Yes ...
The Second Pu ... Punic War -
- began in the year 218 BC.
A crucial role
in this war was ...
... Ha... Ha...
Ha.. Ha ...
What is it,
that is so fun, Fatsen?
- Ha ... Hannibal's war elephants.
- Well, that is, what is so funny.
Curiously enough, that just you think,
elephants are funny.
You, even personally
reminds a lot of this heavy animal.
Wrong fanfare.
Sit down, lazy fat lump and sleep again.
If you continue in the way,
you will end up as candy boiler.
Maybe we could get Edward to
right the elephant outpourings?
Go ahead, Edward, you my firmly
support in this motley bunch.
You always can your stuff.
The Second Punic war
began in the year 218 BC.
A crucial role was
Hannibal's war elephants.
Hannibal led the army, 60.000 men
and 37 elephants, across the Pyrenees.
Then he went through Gaul, -
- and when the Gauls were put to
route, he came to the Alps.
Undaunted, he began
the dangerous march, -
- and after 14 days of effort,
he reached the Cisalpine Gaul.
There he defeated the two
consuls, Scipio and Sempronius.
Wonderful.
Come here, my own little pet.
- Come on, you can always your stuff.
- Stop it now.
Shouldn't it have changed water?
I don't want water in my pants!
Let go!
My mom gets upset!
No, no!
Ouch, don't!
Oh, woe!
I say it to my mom!
Come on, Marshy.
Can't you change it?
What is turtle named in latin?
Paddus.
Oh, woe ...
- What are you doing?.
- It's not your business, Thyggesen.
Beware, it's carnivorous.
The monkey is evil!
And that's one offered me!
Mogensen! Up to the blackboard.
Sit!
Your wretched rascal!
Who do you think, you are?
And this mess
dare you offer me!
Such a simple problem
solved completely wrong.
Do you know, what you are?
You're a saboteur!
You know very well,
how the problem must be solved.
It's so ridiculous logic!
You don't make a fool out of me.
Are we going to fetch your father again?
Then he might
beat some sense into you!
Look here!
P, Q, R, S. ...
And then we have given P Q -
- is 3 root 10 ...
Q R 6 ...
R S 2 ...
Rod 5 ...
P S 5 root 2 ...
Q S 4 ...
Root 5.
And then we prove,
that triangle P Q R ...
... is isosceles!
And what do we then do?
Well, you're stubborn.
You will not?
Scoundrel! Scoundrel! Scoundrel!
Down with you, Mogensen.
And Nielsen, up here!
Are we sitting and amuse us?
You may proceed.
Well!
3 root 10 multiply by 2 -
- root 5 equal to 4 -
- root 5 multiply by P R.
So the undefined terms in the equation!
How long is the line?
P R 6 multiply by 5 equals to 30 -
- root 2 plus 30 ...
root 2 multiply by P R.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
60 root 2, 4 root 5
multiply by P R.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
P R multiply by 3 root 10.
Is it true?
Yes.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
I've never seen anything like this!
Are you kidding me!
Well, you're stubborn!
You know very well,
how the problem must be solved!
It's so ridiculous logic!
Miserable scoundrel!
Your dad might
beat some sense into you!
Stop it.
He pulled it out of the wall.
Like this.
Hurry, give Axel the cake,
before he tears down the entire hut.
Majbritt, wake up now.
Are they really beaten you?
It's just
such a kind of ... tradition.
- Does he say anything to your father?
- My God, he doesn't.
- What if he does?
- We'll probably get the teachers.
We'll begin with him.
"The Merman"?
- He's then very nice.
- You will not take part?
Yes, yes ... For what?
The Black Hand.
We revive The Black Hand.
- What are you talking about?
- Talking?
There is no one,
who's talking here.
- Have you heard anyone talking?
- No.
Why must you always
make your clothes so dirty ...
It was Aksel,
who did it.
When I was your age, I could
beat all the others in the school.
I don't care, that
you always blame others.
- The wasn't me.
- Listen to your mom. One must meet ones responsibility!
This is also relevant in business.
Otherwise the company run down.
Don't lie.
Dishonesty is the worst thing of all.
Thygesen & Son.
Just a moment.
I'll call the director.
Director Thygesen,
there's a phonecall for you!
Yes, thank you.
Now I'll be there.
Director Thygesen here.
What can I do for you?
What?
We owe you money?
Just a moment, then I'll
contact the company's treasurer.
Then we'll get that little case
out of the world.
Miss Andersen, -
- will you write a check
to butcher Hermansen?
Yes ...
Yes, so it's executed.
Goodbye, goodbye.
I think, we should change butcher.
Herman's products are not,
what they have been.
Now make your homework.
Edward, I don't like, when you're playing.
Can't you let the clarinet be!
One can well be
musician without going under!
Thank you.
If you fail me,
I don't know, what to do.
I'm not so strong anymore,
as you might think.
So we're not talking more about that.
You would better
spend time doing homework, Edward.
I've done the most of it.
May I go over to Michael tonight?
We must read latin.
Yes, of course, my boy.
It's still here.
The Black Hand ...
The symbol of revenge and justice.
The struggle for the good against the evil.
It's time, that The Black Hand
waking from its hibernation.
The first victim is The Merman.
Agree?
We need two potatoes
and a carrot.
Come on!
I'll just blame.
I'll not be with you!
We dare not join in, Thygesen?
Into the closet with him.
He comes!
- Good afternoon.
Yes ...
Where was it, we came to?
- Nielsen?
- The internal secretion.
Yes, that's right.
The ... internal secretion ...
- Are we already reached to that point?
- We had to read on it today.
Okay ...
The internal secretion ...
There comes a time in your life,
not now of course -
- but for a few years, when
you have got your degree, -
- and has been
lawfully married, -
- where you must help, -
- ensuring the human
race against extinction.
It's your duty.
This is about "the internal secretions".
An excellent image of the
human reproduction, we see, -
- when the busy bee
gather nectar from flowers.
Are you not ashamed?
To belittle something
of the most beautiful here in life!
Be quiet!
Quiet!
- Let me out ...
- There are some rats in the closet.
I can't breathe.
Let me out.
Your nasty boy!
You're of course
one of the ringleaders behind this.
Then we might proceed.
What's going on here?
It's beautiful!
Beautiful!
Do I get to know, who is
the perpetrator of these perversions?
Was it you?
- Was it you?!
- No.
Good.
Who is head of the class order?
It's me.
Sit.
So tell me,
you obese Crassus ...
If you can overcome
your innate indolence, -
- so open your jaws and tell,
who's behind this mess!
- We have all been involved.
- Who is the creator?
I don't know.
We have all been involved.
It's the pure and
simple communism!
This vulgar method, to cover up
each others!
This misguided cronyism,
which has become fashionable in our time!
These bandits, who made
this, are bad companions, -
- as it's not worth
to cover up!
So tell me,
Mr. Jørgen Thygesen, -
- who is the creator?
Edward?
All leave the classroom,
but you three will stay.
- Can I do something?
- No, thank you. I'll handle this.
Many thanks.
Out!
I prefer to believe, that there
must be a misunderstanding, Edward.
I can't imagine,
you've helped, to do this.
It's not true, right?
It goes så well, Edward, right!
If you want good advice,
so stay away from these two.
It's not company for you.
Do you understand?
Look at me.
Do you understand, what I'm saying?
In the future there will be
watch very closely on you two!
Forward!
Forward, come on!
Hurry!
Come on, come on!
Yes, forward!
What the hell, Ellerstrøm! Are you raping the animal?
It's damn a male horse!
He thinks, it's Blomme.
Forward!
What's this chick ...
I can't take it anymore.
These kids drive me crazy.
Yes, one feel, one is
wasting the precious time.
It blocks any form
of research.
One must resign oneself to one's fate, -
to educate by the school's
tradition, is our duty.
We hold on a legacy.
There are also nice boys
between. Mikael Mogensen ...
I think, his father is engineer.
- And Ellerstrøm.
- Oh yes, Edward ...
There's something different with him,
orderly and well behaved.
- One must be over them.
- I just think ...
Just it don't ends up,
that the children are going to hate us.
As Caesar always said:
"Oderint, dum metuant."
"Let them just hate,
as long as they fear".
If there's anything, I can be met
in the parliament the rest of the day.
One doesn't leave, Edward.
Eat up now.
Well!
Shouldn't you have been to international
match with Michael and the others?
No, it didn't happen.
Uncle Børge would
also have liked to have you with.
He must stand and scream alone. It's
just before, one can hear him, right?
- Is it going well at school?
- Yes, we're so happy for it.
Let aunt hear a little of the
beautiful poems about Pyramus and Thisbe.
- Now let the boy be free.
- No, come on, Edward.
Is it not something as
Fistula Columbo ...?
(Latin) Fistula plumbo...
Scinditur et tenui stridente
foramine longas eiaculatur -
- aquas atque ictibus aera rumpit.
Isn't it beautiful?
He is no. 2 in his class.
That's fine.
And we agree, that the next time
you are no. 1. Right, Edward?
Yes.
What will you be?
It's really intended.
Edward must be a lawyer. Right, Edward?
Yes.
So it's "The Monkey's" turn.
And then Ejby ...
And Blomme ...
And then we'll have
Blomme's little darling.
I'm sorry for him.
- They're dead.
- I mean Edward ...
- I'm sorry for him.
- We don't need renegades.
Oops ...
Why the hellshould you always make scandal.
The order is lost!
You should at least have
given him an apology!
You're sitting here yet?
Good evening.
Oops ...
A poem.
So you write poems, Aksel ...
To Majbritt. I will lend you
a tiny bit. A day, an hour. -
I will be a whooshing
in your heart's conch, -
a breathe of air that brushes
your hair and mouth.
How beautiful, Aksel. Have you written
it yourself? Keep it up.
It doesn't hurt
with a little poetry.
It's damn
always better than him!
That kid can take over
a reputable construction company, -
- and then he sits
and fiddling with insects.
Do you know, what you shoud do?
You should read maths!
Shouldn't you
also go to bed?
What about that over there?
- What do you think, it is here?
- 1000.
It is 8. Isn't it funny?
Had it been the decimal system,
then would the digits have been -
- Ones, tens, hundreds and
thousands, and there would be 1011.
But now I've written it
in a binary system, so it is ...
And fours ...
... twos and ones!
Funny, right?
Let's look at the addition problem.
1 and 1 you would think was 2, -
- but it becomes 0 plus number carried.
It is funny ...
... a number carried, that falls
down here in the box, right?
Now we'll have
a truly masculine play.
Whoever stays inside the circle
the longest time, is the winner!
It's like in real life.
Can't you take part
in such a small Christmas-play?
Back with you!
That's good!
Yes, the devil ...
Just turn on!
Well done, boys.
Now it's dammit Christmas!
Come on, Ellerstrøm,
Give him back!
- Do you think, something has happened?
- Of course not ...
Mogensen, damn,
now see, what you've done!
Merry Christmas!
That garden,
Angels of God are flying in, -
Jesus will open for us; -
Heaven's King lives among us, -
Christmas joy he brings us, -
he embraces each child's soul on earth, -
and promise us angel wings!
The Christmas is the home's celebration.
Anyone, who has been hard-working, -
- can now rest a few days
with clear conscience.
Others can make up for lost time.
After the new year, I expect
extra diligence and punctuality.
Merry Christmas.
Peace on earth
and in the human's well-being.
I'll not know
of any kind of riots.
There will be crackdown
on troublemakers. Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas, Mogensen
... and Nielsen.
Happy New Year!
You can retrieve your grade book
at the rector's office.
I think, one stand for something
uncomfortable. Merry Christmas.
Christmas Peace has descended, right?
- Blomme has been killing us.
- I can sign them.
It will not work,
otherwise thank you very much.
- What would it be?.
- A few crullers ...
Do you the get beatings at home?
My father beats me simply to death.
We should then just ...
We just need to avenge it.
- We'll find on something.
- Come on, Aksel!
What ...
Are you never going in the cinema?
- At the cinema?
- Yes.
What do you say to
Roxy second Christmas Day?
- Are you going with?
- Yes ...
I'm afraid, I can't.
I've too much,
I must have been obtained.
Goodbye.
You're a glutton, -
- a real little glutton ...
I'll light.
The Black Hand ...
Is it one,
you got for Christmas?
Relax. He can't know, who it is,
if only you keep your mouth shut.
Have you heard, Kurt Hansen
has been thrown out?
By the way, before we split today, -
- I should just hear, if these gentlemen
have had a good Christmas?
Well thanks.
Has one got
some nice Christmas gifts?
Yes, thank you.
I got this, among other things ...
... black hand.
"Manus nigra".
There was no card -
- so I can't thank
the noble giver.
It's probably not escaped
the gentleman's attention, -
- that Kurt Hansen is no longer
frequents this school.
On this occasion
I have a little story.
In the period around the birth of Christ,
there was a brave, -
- but foolhardy slave
named Spartacus.
He started a slave revolt against
the Romans, but he made that mistake, -
- completely underestimating
his enemy's strength.
The slaves had to surrender.
All the insurgents were crucified and planted -
- along the Via Appia,
with Spartacus as the first.
A large flock of black birds
discovered the crucified, -
- and after a few hours was
all the slaves eyes chopped out.
Yes ... such is the way,
Gentlemen, -
- when ignorant slaves make a rebellion.
Have a continued good day!
Edward, wait a minute.
Sit down!
I want to talk with you.
Would you like a piece of candy?
Go ahead.
I'm extremely pleased
with your efforts, Edward.
It's guys like you, the community
must build its future on.
You'll know, that I
considering to set you up -
- to the school's special
prize for diligence.
What do you say to that?
Thanks ... many thanks.
That was, what I had to say.
One moment.
Is there something,
you would like to say?
About what?
You know it, if
there's something.
I can see it at you.
We two know each other
very well, right?
Tell me so.
Who owns this Manus Nigra?
I don't know anything about it ...
I don't know.
Well.
Then you can think about it.
If we two must preserve
our good relationship with each other, -
- then you're telling me,
who owns that hand ...
... tomorrow.
Is he too late?.
So he needs a slap!
I will not tolerate
any kind of noise and riots!
Why isn't you,
who is no. 1?
I still can't see,
that there's something wrong with you.
You don't have fever ...
How long have you been sick?
Ten days, but he
read extensively at home.
Surely it isn't girlfriend troubles?
He's only a child ...
Yes yes ...
- How are you in school?
- It goes very well.
Edward is almost
no. 1 in his class.
He is so glad of his school.
Isn't it right, Edward?
That's good. So we agree,
that you go to school tomorrow.
I think, you also need to
to get some fresh air.
Rector's coming!
Associate Professor Blomme is sick.
He suffered minor injuries
in a bus.
As a substitute, you'll get
Mr. lecturer ... Langhave.
I will not tolerate
noise and riots!
There will be cracked down
on troublemakers. Goodbye!
Goodbye.
Please sit down.
My name is Gunnar Langhave.
We should now talk about -
- the exception to the rule that words
ending with "is" is feminine.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
Good.
Has anyone a bid?
Yes ... and you're called?
- Thy ... Thygesen.
- Sorry?
His name is Thygesen!
- You must also have a first name.
- The Elephant.
The elephant? Well ...
So we're obviously related.
I welcome that. Gunnar ...
- Jørgen ...
- What is your bid?
- Amnis.
- Right.
Are there any other bids?
Callis.
- Aksel ...
- Right. More?
Edward. Sorry ...
Canalis.
Yes.
A word as "disciplina" ... how
do you inflect it in accusative?
Disciplinam.
- And in genitive?
- Disciplinae.
- Dative?
- Also disciplinae.
- Ablative?
- Disciplina.
Preservative?
- Torquis, torris...
- Ungvis, vectis, vermis.
And nougat-ice ...
Mrs. Svendsen, spit your
excellent knowledge out.
Let us be allowed to bask a little
by the light of your intellect.
Three cornets with it all!
Goodbye.
It's for you.
Thank you.
So, gentlemen ...
- So is served.
- Thanks.
- And it's my turn.
- Thank you.
Yes, excellent!
What is key in nominative?
- Mikael?
- Clavis.
- Let go.
- Clavem.
Clavis.
It's then not
in our curriculum.
- Come on, man!
- Clavi.
- Clave.
- Good, Jørgen.
What the hell!
Who has thrown the keys down here?
Sorry. I could hardly
make you throw them up here again?
-- If it's not too high ...
- Too high?!
Errare humanum est.
Translate.
- It's human to make mistakes.
- Fine.
One has learned
to be on time, right?
He comes now.
Today it's Langhave's birthday
hurray, hurray, hurray ...
he certainly become a gift,
as he has wished for this year ...
with lovely cho ...
What on earth
should this be?
Sit.
What's that?
A cake.
That has brushed my attention.
Is it you, having placed it there?
It's just a gift ...
It's nice, Thygesen.
It's bribery
of an official in function.
Take it away!
One observe, that Ellerstrøm
has risen himself from his sickbed.
It seems to me,
that his Apollo-face -
- has undergone a transformation ...
Now he's suddenly well enough -
- playing negro music in the latin-hour!
Are you become crazy?
Lay however that blowing horn,
your heinous pimple-infested kid!
Up to the blackboard.
Let's take his favorite poem
Pyramus and Thisbe.
Wake up and tell
your humble listening teacher, -
- how it relates
with the small mysterious word "an" -
- in the seventh line from above?
Did't you expected,
that Ovid would have used -
- "Utrum" or "ne" in the first part
of the disjunctive asking sentence?
Hadn't you?
Come on, Ellerstrøm! You maybe have
got pimples on your tongue?
Is your brain become one large
festering pimple? I wish you'd bother!
"An" is used in a dependent sentence,
whose first term is omitted.
Again! I didn't hear, what your
pimple-infested mouth said.
"An" is used in a dependent sentence,
whose first term is omitted.
- I can't hear.
- "An" is used in ...
Higher, Pimplepig!
Speak loudly and clearly.
- "An" is the first part ...
- Aha!
- "An" is the first part?
- No. I mean ...
"An" is used in a sentence,
whose first part ...
Nonsense, Ellerstrøm! You got
an incorrect clause, -
- when you feel up in the bag.
You guessed wrong!
Again!
I meant of course also ...
You must know!
I know you ... "Give him
just something, that idiot".
It's your method. Again!
Further, your wart hog!
What the devil! Are you standing and
throwing up and down at me?
Out!
Your pig, out!
Just wait for the exam! Wait for the spring!
I can't wait!
Thygesen,
remove that vomitus.
You can do it very good.
Again ...
... second part of the disjunctive
question, but also ...
- Hello!
- It's fucking Kurt Hansen.
Well ... come on.
When you're so industrious,
it will be good.
Beware, you don't get cold.
So ...
Mom ...
What is it, my boy?
Nothing.
Good night.
Here one have to teach -
- between the stinky gas taps
and chemical fumes!
ne have to be detectives to find
a place, where you can teach.
Open the window, so the smell
of gas can leak out. Sit down.
Let's now return
to the small word "an".
When do we use it?
Pimplepig! Speak -
- if you can open your mouth
without having to swim over by vomitus.
I'm waiting!
In the hottest hell ...
However, it's dammit, that you must
be disturbed by these sports freaks ...
Close that window!
A sad case, gentlemen.
Once an industrious
and nice student.
Now he even don't want
to open his mouth.
It shouldn't go up
like Hansen.
We're still waiting.
I've forgotten it.
There's nothing
to do with that.
- Nielsen?
- I think ...
Thanks, you just sit down
and relax.
Further, Nielsen!
Go ahead, Mr. Nielsen!
"An" isn't only used in the second part
of disjunctive questions -
- but also when one ask about
objections to the foregoing, -
- or when one oneself
to a question is adding the answer -
- in the form of a new question.
Excellent, Nielsen.
Absolutely brilliant.
Are you aware of, how
gravity the situation is for you?
I can't vote for
your promotion to the next class.
I don't dare to take the responsibility.
It's for your own best ...
I'm forced to
to sacrifice you, Edward, -
- although it makes me heartily sorry.
Yes ...
Well! I must get on.
STRYICHNINE
This knock-about life ... one
don't know, where one has ones issues.
Damn!
You thought,
I had forgotten them ...
You would almost have one, because
you haven't eaten them all.
Go ahead.
Just take. You can probably
need a refreshment.
We must continue!
It's so unbelievable, -
- that Associate Professor Blomme
is no longer among us.
So strangely, helpless
and poor, we're standing here -
- in this beautiful
Danish summerday.
Our thought can't hold it -
- our intellect
can't understand it.
We are faced to
the incomprehensible.
I will not know of the noise
in this serious moment!
There will be cracked down
on troublemakers.
All honour to his memory!
The students of this year
have now passed their exam -
- and is ready to
to go out in the life -
- to find their
place in the society.
We know, that we have
given them a ballast, -
- that always will be a part of them.
Before I go any further
with speech to this year's students, -
- it's my great pleasure
to be able to present -
- the school's annual prize
for diligence to ...
... Aksel Nielsen from 1. G.
He is No. 1 in his class
with an average of ug minus.
Let this be
a welcome proof of this, -
- that even son of a
carpenter will emerge -
- if he has the requisite abilities
and the requisite diligence.
Life is seriosness,
and the school must teach -
the child, that
each step isn't soft, -
the shoulder of the young
get burdens to bear, -
but when the faithful
have borned them steadily, -
trala lala lala
eja which tastes
then the rest sweet, -
trala lala lala
eja which tastes
then the rest sweet.
"Then we have
a truly masculine-play!"
"Those, who stay inside the circle
the longest time, is the winner!"
"Like in the real life!"
Camilla...
I've written a poem for you.
Will you hear it?
I will lend you
a tiny bit,
one day, one hour,
just one second,
I will be a whooshing
in your hearts' conch,
a breath of air to roam
your hair and your mouth.
It's for you.
My wife has been disgusting
for the male sperm.
So now she lies
in a double bed and drink liqueurs -
- and getting fatter and fatter.
- Why don't you substitute her with another?
- I can't so it in my position.
Cheers.
Well, Thygesen ... you probably sort
out the coolies out in Bangkok?
You can damned believe that.
It's damn gonna
be fashioned again!
Do you remember, when we
joked with the Merman?
- It was me, who planted the blackboard.
- I made the cord drive!
It was me, who killed Blomme.
Can you remember, when we came
a salted herring into the aquarium?
One would certainly wish,
that one had done it one self.
The world is young
and green and juicy.