Downloaded from
YTS.MX
(rain pattering)
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
(soft synth music)
♪ I was trembling with goose flesh ♪
♪ First time I prayed
to speak in tongues ♪
♪ I saw it comin' ♪
♪ And I tried to run ♪
♪ But now I make it up as I go along ♪
♪ I store my flaws in
other people's heads ♪
♪ Then I question what they know ♪
♪ The cloud of witnesses ♪
♪ Hover above you like a ♪
♪ A pillar of smoke ♪
♪ Singin' stories, whisperin' jokes ♪
- [Robert] From NPR News,
this is All Things Considered.
I'm Robert Siegel.
- And I'm Michele Norris.
David Bazan was once known as the first
cross-over Christian indie-rock musician.
His band, Pedro the Lion, sold hundreds
of thousands of records.
- [David] Hey, how's it going out there?
(people cheering)
- [Michele] Then Bazan
began questioning the God
he sang about, alienating
many of his fans.
Now, he has a new album
out under his own name,
and recently, he went on a solo tour,
playing in living rooms.
Clay Masters, from member
station, NET Radio,
caught up with Bazan on the road.
- [Clay] It took Bazan four years after
Pedro the Lion broke up to
write his first solo record.
In that time, it seems, he was overwhelmed
by his break up with God, and
he started drinking heavily.
The questioning of God
isn't something new for him,
it dates back to early
Pedro the Lion records.
Many music critics
called Curse Your Braches
Bazan's break up with God.
Bazan hopes people who buy it will respond
to his honestly regardless
of what he might believe.
For NPR News, I'm Clay Masters.
- [Ann] And so, there's two
games that are specialty , so.
But I think there's three or four games
that you'll be home for.
So that'll be cool.
- That's great.
Well when I'm home, I
wanna take him to the
batting cages a bunch.
- [Ann] Yeah.
Yeah, your dad said that he's
progressively getting better.
- Great.
- [Ann] Yeah.
- That's so great.
Okay, sorry, I'm turned around.
- [Ann] That's okay, I'll just let you go.
I don't know, it just feels like,
I'm so close to you, I'm
tellin' you I'm missing ya, so.
- I'm missin' you too.
- [Ann] Okay.
Love you.
- I love you.
- Bye.
♪ Other side ♪
♪ Of the road ♪
- Mara Liasson, NPR News, Washington.
As the Republican nominating battle
moved into the fall with
the two outsider candidates,
Donald Trump and Ben Carson,
still on top of the polls,
the frustration of the other
establishment candidates,
is growing.
- [Man] One of the many
surprises this election year
has been the support
Donald Trump has received
from conservative, evangelical
voters in the primaries.
To build on that support,
Donald Trump met with
hundreds of evangelical
leaders in Manhattan yesterday
and he suggested that they not pray for
the country's current leadership.
(soft music)
- I grew up in Phoenix, Arizona and
we lived a half a mile from the church
that we went to and that my dad worked at
and the school that I went
to was a part of that church.
Every single person in my...
- From like Kindergarten?
- Yeah.
Kindergarten to sixth grade.
- Okay.
- Every single person
in my extended family is
Christian and the same kind of Christian
that we were, Pentecostal,
Assemblies of God.
And certain kinds of evangelical
Christianity, specifically,
there's this push for your
faith to be integrated
in your person, in your identity,
and it's not some separate
ornament to your life.
It's like the fundamental thing, and so,
that was the mindset that
I kind of grew up with,
was that this is, it
just permeates everything
and I enjoyed that.
I mean, there's like a
feeling of fidelity to it
that just, you know,
just made you feel good.
(soft music)
(insects buzzing)
What's up?
Hey, how's it goin'?
- I'm Micah.
- Micah, how are you?
- [Micah] Yeah, I've seen
you up in Columbia before.
- Oh right.
- Big fan.
- [David] Thanks man.
- What's up man?
Brian.
- Brian.
- This is my house.
- Right on Brian.
- Thanks for playing.
- Thanks so much.
- [Brian] Do you want a beer or anything?
♪ Hello again ♪
♪ Oblivion ♪
♪ But it's no good to complain ♪
♪ Of fatigue and existential pain ♪
(soft acoustic music)
♪ On a six week solo drive ♪
♪ While your friends work nine to five ♪
♪ What really threw me off ♪
♪ Is that all these years I thought ♪
♪ I'd work it out ♪
♪ Did you sing it like it is ♪
♪ 'Cause you really thought
it would pack 'em in ♪
- [Man] You're so welcome.
Take care of the kiddos and yourself.
- [Brian] Thank you so much, dude.
Good luck on the rest of your tour.
- [Man] I can't believe he came, dude.
It's been a pleasure.
- Thank you so much.
These are the download cards.
And then there's seven inch packs.
- How much?
- 20 for the vinyl.
These are each 10, and then
the pack of seven inches in 35.
- Okay.
- [David] And I take
cards if that's helpful.
- Oh yeah?
And that is.
Then I'll take the vinyl and the seven.
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
- This is awesome.
- It was a great show.
(soft music)
- [David] Before inventing
house shows, you know,
I was at the pawn shop all the time
with my gear in pawn to make ends meet.
And once we got house shows figured out,
I had never went to the pawn shop again.
But all of a sudden, I'm on
the road all of the time.
I recently realized I was
gone two years and nine months
of my son's first five
years on Earth, over half.
And I've been right on
that line for too long.
Like, how much can my marriage withstand?
A couple of years ago it became clear
that our marriage really can't stand
this amount of time away.
And watching it crack and
seeing it could be over soon,
I gotta get home more.
(soft music)
- [Nils] What time is it for you?
- It's after midnight.
- [Eleanor] We're at 9:36 right now.
- I know, I'm at 12:36.
What are you doing, Nils?
Hi.
- [Eleanor] I hate him so much right now.
- He's just looking for love.
I'll be home in a minute.
- [Eleanor] In a minute?
In a minute?
- Mhm.
- I love you so much.
- I love you too.
I miss you guys.
- I miss you too, dad.
- How are dealing with all of that?
(laughs)
- [Ann] I'm gonna go.
- Pew, pew, pew, pew.
- All right, bye.
- I love you guys.
(soft music)
You have to be really
crafty about logistics
and how to make the day to day work
and where to shave things off, you know,
hotel rooms or staying with people.
You know, there are
just like a hundred ways
to figure out how to do it.
Being middle aged, having
kids, trying to justify
this weird choice that
you made when you were 19
and that all of your buddies
either got rich doing it,
or have given it up.
And so you're trying to
justify all this stuff
and it's easy to lose
faith, but if you're finding
that spark, if you're finding that thing
that made the White Album
just flip your chemistry
when you were in eighth grade.
And you're not Paul
McCartney or John Lennon,
but you're doing something that connects
your brain that same way,
then you can keep going
for a long time.
So that's the trick.
If Pedro had put out another
record and it was really good
and well received, that was the moment
where it was gonna change, you know?
There had been a string of close buddies
that had been in the band and were now
not in the band anymore.
There was some sort of failure
in each of those instances.
They didn't have enough
ownership or whatever.
It just didn't work, repeatedly.
All this was happening
during the realizations
I was having about Christianity
and the Christian narrative
and how it was all kind of falling apart.
I was, you know, just a
bundle of contradictions
and so I just thought,
well I just need to lean
into all those contradictions just
to be the mess that I am about this stuff.
I mean, Pedro the Lion was
a really beautiful thing
and it was really working for a time,
and when that couldn't
work, I just thought that
something is wrong,
something about the premise
of this thing is flawed
and you need to walk
away from that premise, whatever that is.
And to me, the name of that
premise was Pedro the Lion.
I couldn't write anything.
I didn't know why it wasn't working,
and I didn't know what I was doing wrong
and so I killed it, and along with it,
I effectively killed my livelihood,
I mean, my career basically,
to try to find out
why this was happening
and get some clarity.
Just driving around, playing solo shows,
trying to think through it and give myself
some time to figure it out
and then maybe by the time
I put out my first solo record,
I would be in a position
to have a band again.
For me to be allowed to
continue to do this work
of songwriting and interacting with people
and putting out records, while
I've been figuring this out,
really, really helped me.
(soft music)
Where is it?
Through here?
- [Yuuki] Third floor.
- With this method of
touring, people didn't know
what to expect and so, I
got to define what it was
and so it allowed me to
be myself more frequently.
It was grounding for me.
It was a pure form of the thing.
There's no lights, there's
no stage, there's no pomp.
You're right there, on the same scale.
If it was at a rock club, it
wouldn't work the same way,
but you're in this place
that you've never been,
they've never been before.
Everybody was just off
balance and open and so
that was when I started
seeing vulnerability
as the antidote to all this
anxiety and self loathing.
It was really helpful
to take the problem out
of my head to sort of
interact with that work
over and over again and the profound
and vulnerable way of singing.
What it does to your brain when you sing
something that you know and
that you love, it heals you.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
(audience applause)
I'm called Dave Bazan,
this is Yuuki Matthews.
Yeah, do y'all have any questions
at this point in the show?
It's kind of early,
but, maybe you curiosity
has already been stirred, who knows.
Okay well, we can talk later, also.
We have got a couple more
songs that we can play.
(laughing)
What is the definition
of what couple means?
- Two, right?
- Two?
- [Woman] Three.
- Or three.
- Isn't a few
three or more?
- Yeah but when I say go grab
couple me a couple of beers,
I do mean three.
(audience laughs)
- Are you surprised that
people who are religious
are still very big fans of you?
Does that bother you or--
- No.
I care about what happens
with Christianity.
I want it to get better.
I want it to quit shittin'
the bed so consistently.
So when I hear that, that
there are Christians whose
faith is of the sort that you can sit
and listen to me blabbing
on for nine minutes,
to me that is a good sign.
In regards to, whoever is
going to like this music
is gonna like it.
I can't stop it, and
I would never want to,
'cause I got a few in my family.
(audience laughs)
(soft music)
(people chattering)
I find myself interacting with people that
we have different worldviews,
but I'm trying to find
common ground and I say,
when you say God's kingdom,
what do you think about?
And they say, oh well
justice and these things,
and I was like, me too.
I think that's important too.
Let's join together and do that.
Because partially, you're
scared of burning in hell
for all eternity, me just 'cause
I think it's a great idea.
But let's do it, you know wat I'm saying?
The fruit on the tree, that's the thing.
People can claim all kinds of things,
but what's the fruit,
you know, in the end?
That's the myth of a powerful movement
like American Evangelical Christianity.
That there is one way
to think about a thing.
That the interpretation
that seems universal
is the real thing.
And so in the end, I realized that I was
challenging nothing more
than an institution.
(soft music)
I think my brain always was
kind of deconstructing things,
even as like a kid.
Seventh grade, I remember
we were at this church
in Lake Havasu City, Arizona,
and it was Fourth of July and my dad
was the music pastor
this church and they had
a color guard that came in and had flags
and I think fake guns,
walking up the aisle,
and we sang a bunch of patriotic songs.
And I remember thinking, like,
I think these guys are
getting some things mixed up.
I wouldn't have known the world conflate
but that you're conflating
two things with one another
that don't go, that aren't the same thing.
That day I mentioned it to my dad, like,
yeah, I don't think
those things go together.
His response was, "Oh, interesting.
"Tell me more about that."
(cars passing)
(tense music)
Yeah.
What did she do in that last race?
Was it an IM?
Did she do okay?
Two seconds?
Oh man, that's so great.
Oh, that's so good.
(drill whirring)
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
(soft acoustic music)
(audience applause)
You all wanna talk about anything
at this point in the show?
- [Woman] So the Whole EP
was one of the first albums
that I listened to by you.
It's a lot different.
- It is different.
- [Woman] Than what you
have recently produced.
What made you so bitter?
- Whoa, I'm not even a little bit bitter.
(audience laughs)
I changed a lot since the
time I was 18 until now
and I just did it in front of people.
- I have a question.
- Yep.
- [Audience Member] Are
you tired of talking
about Christianity?
- Oh no, it's so fascinating.
(audience members laugh)
Christianity is still
creating so many problems
all around us, like I'm
dying to talk about it.
Dying.
(laughing)
(soft acoustic music)
- Growing up in church,
listening to Christian rock
and this and that, or even somebody
who was like, within the church.
As soon as you found out that
somebody left the church,
you're done, I'm never
listening to your shit again.
- Yeah, right.
- I find, you seem to be
an anomaly, which is a positive thing.
That you do this and you
have this large majority
of your fan base are still young believers
that still continue to support you
and they're here tonight.
And you're the only person
that I think I can name
that has that type of support.
- What I hope is happening is that there
is a space, more of a middle ground,
for people to remain
Christian, and for their faith
to become faith and
not a militant sort of,
you're either with us or against,
like an othering kind
of thing where there's
a vulnerability to actual
faith that isn't just, like,
a club that you're beating people with.
- Right.
- Would you say that there's
stuff that's out there
that you've written and
that you used to believe in
that you don't believe in anymore?
- Yes.
- And, um, so people
find this music by you,
and they're like, oh
this is David Buzan, but,
is it really?
- It's David Buzan from
a certain point in time.
At any given point, it's
always been totally in earnest
so yeah, I changed my
mind about certain things,
but it was genuine at the time.
- That's understandable.
- Sure.
(woman laughs)
I think it's commendable.
- It's very commendable.
(soft acoustic rock music)
- [Justin] In the same way
that is often communicated
of you, this sort of like, departure.
- [David] Departure.
- Or stepping out.
- Yep.
- Those words don't connect emotionally
with what you believe or
feel like is a place for you
in a broader cultural context.
- I don't believe in the Resurrection,
I don't believe in the fall, I
don't believe in the trinity.
I don't know if there is God at all,
but I know that document pretty well
and I see a thread in
it that one could follow
and the fruit of one's
life and one's community
and everything would be
something really different
that what we see in America.
There is this thing that I think,
if we all pay a little closer attention,
could go better than it's
going and so if I can help,
then I'm gonna.
I am participating in a
larger Christian tradition.
That's what I was born into,
that's the language I know,
that's how I understand ethics.
I'm a son of Evangelical Christianity
and I'll never not be that.
(soft music)
In high school, God was church.
And then once I got out of high school,
I realized that I wanted to
take my faith more seriously
and for me, that meant having a
more regular devotional time.
Reading more and more books, praying more.
I would try to spend an
hour or two every day
reading the Bible, doing some
Bible study devotional book,
praying, and trying to sin less.
To do Christianity in the most devoted
and thorough way that I knew how.
I always thought that I was gonna be
a pastor when I was growing up.
It was just in my head,
eventually I'll probably
be a pastor, like start a
church or something like that.
♪ You came from heaven to earth ♪
♪ To show the way ♪
♪ From the earth to the cross ♪
♪ My debt to pay ♪
The first time I ever
played guitar in front of anybody,
I was leading the two and three year old
Sunday school class and like, you know,
if you're happy and you
know it, clap your hands.
And then shortly after
that, in 10th grade,
I started writing songs of my own.
And then when I started writing songs,
I thought that this is what I wanna do.
I just wanna write these songs
and drive around and sing 'em, you know?
Thanks for being here.
♪ And all the way to grandma's house ♪
♪ I stayed on the narrow path ♪
♪ My younger brother wandered off ♪
♪ Deep into the woods ♪
♪ Bitten twice by rattlesnakes ♪
♪ Tangled up in poison oak ♪
♪ He fell down and broke his legs ♪
♪ Into a great ravine ♪
♪ When I arrived at grandma's house ♪
♪ She had made us tea and cake ♪
♪ She asked me where my brother was ♪
♪ And I said I don't know and ate ♪
- [Man] NPR's Sarah McCammon reports
from Richmond, Virginia.
- [Sarah] Since the band's
inception, Pedro the Lion
has always towed the
line between indie rock
and Christian music.
One of the things that stands out to me
as I hear even some of
your very early work
as Pedro the Lion, a lot of these songs
are riddled with uncertainty and doubt
and criticism of religion.
And so this has been a
long process for you.
What do you think made the band
so successful in the early 2000s?
What is it that resonated with people?
- I don't totally know, but I can guess.
I think there is an
earnestness that I wrote with
and an openness with
which I sang about doubt
and faith at a time when I don't really
think that was going on much.
I think I did it in such
a way that it wasn't
slogans or trying to convert anybody.
It was just me trying to
process what was going on
inside my head, and I guess
that worked for some folks.
♪ When I get to heaven ♪
♪ I'll be greeted warmly ♪
♪ Surrounded by the angels ♪
♪ As Jesus takes my hand ♪
There was a sense early on that, like,
there's a version of Christianity that is
kind of pure and based on
scripture that the people
in the culture that I'm a part of
are just barely paying lip service to
and that was a lot to think
about forever until I was 28.
My thinking was more reform
the church, just be better.
(audience cheering)
Thanks a lot.
There's a lot of different
factors that come to play
and have caused a pretty
severe ghetto of thought
and creativity and artistic expression
in the Christian church.
We should be creating things
that are risky and new,
attempting to sloganize the gospel I think
degraded it to the point of
making it the most unprofound
thing that there is so I
just encourage you guys,
throw off the shackles
of Christian culture
and the Christian industry--
(audience cheers)
And attempt to do something
that's not down or whatever.
I wanted to be able to
be a band that was on
general market record
labels and Tower Records
and play in clubs.
Not play churches, not
have my records distributed
on a Christian label
and not having them sold
only in Christian bookstores.
I wanted out of that subculture...
musically.
I wanted to just sink or swim by my merits
if I was allowed to do
that in the world at large.
When It's Hard to Find a Friend came out,
that's exactly what happened.
It got critical acclaim
and got played on the radio
and played in rock clubs with bands who
we didn't know from church.
That's exactly what I wanted
was just to be allowed
to be out of the bubble and just be,
and just hock my wares the best I could.
(audience clapping)
Does anybody have any
questions at this point?
- [Man] How important is Jesus to you?
- That's like a private conversation.
- I'm sorry man.
- That's all right.
I'm gonna ask for a different one, yeah?
(soft, tinkling music)
It wasn't until after
high school that I really
had the bandwidth to start
to really take it seriously
and so then I went to Bible college
and just epiphany and
paradigm shift after epiphany.
And then some of these
deeper questions started
to come up where I had realized that I had
not ever evaluated the
fundamental truth claims
of Christianity and
that I was just sort of
rolling along with
these premises that were
un-sort-of-substantiated at the root
of my entire system of belief.
And I thought, well it makes
sense that if I'm gonna
really do this right, I
need to evaluate those.
The faithful response to them
is not to hide from them,
because these questions can't hurt God.
I certainly was reading the Bible a bunch,
like trying to read it like
I had never seen it before
where I didn't have a
bunch of assumptions.
But I was just like, really reading it,
and so as I mulled it over more and more,
it just seemed less
and less likely that...
That the picture of
God that I has accepted
from Christianity was true.
I think hell was one of
the first things to go,
and errancy followed pretty soon after.
Original sin came up pretty quick.
Moving from assuredness to anything else,
no matter what it is, is,
is pretty destabilizing.
At that point in time, the way
that my faith had developed
and the way that God
functioned in my brain,
it was the same as me.
I mean, it was like this
God was inside of me
and knew me intimately,
knew all of my thoughts.
I was losing this tremendous
resource, a friend,
a confidant, somebody who
made my identity what it was.
While I was doing all that processing
and falling away in kind of slow motion,
I would have the impulse to
like, pray to God about it.
And then other times,
I felt the strong need
to just guard myself against any kind
of sentimentality or God, really,
and so then I would do that.
Sometimes both things would
happen in the same day.
There were a few moments,
one of which I was in church
and it was Christmastime
and we were singing
all of these really rad,
old hymns, Christmas carols,
and I was doing the work.
Like, you know, one stanza of lyrics,
I would sing and I would think to myself,
I believe that, that's real.
And the next stanza,
you know I was doing like a line item veto
of these songs and really doing the work.
Just sitting there and
engaging and wrestling with it,
and it was cathartic and it felt like,
it felt right to me, and then I sat down
and the guy who was speaking
spoke and I hated him.
I hated every moment of, it
was just so unserious to me.
It was like pandery and
just was the epitome
of what I wasn't interested in.
I'm sort of wrestling with
this and then he says,
"Okay, now we're gonna take communion."
And I thought, I can't take communion.
I'm so not in community with this.
Like, I've just sat here
and judged it so negatively
for 30 minutes.
I hadn't been to church,
more or less, for years,
but I had never not taken communion.
And I had just, as they
started passing out the omens,
I just stood up and left.
I just, I can't.
I just told my wife, I was
like, "I'm gonna be in the car."
And what I did was I walked down to a bar
and had a shot and a beer and kind of had
my own little communion ceremony.
And then we went to lunch and I just,
I stayed in the car and just
sobbed for like 40 minutes
and then met them in lunch,
it was already going.
And I was devastated, I just thought,
it felt like...
Yeah, it was gradual, but
there were these moments
where there was big shifts.
And that was one.
(rock music)
♪ Wouldn't it be ♪
♪ So wonderful ♪
♪ If everything were ♪
♪ Meaningless ♪
♪ But everything is so ♪
♪ Meaningful ♪
♪ And most everything turns ♪
♪ To shit ♪
(rock music)
♪ Rejoice ♪
(wind blowing)
(soft music)
I think I continued to
kind of wrestle with it
for a long time, and in
some ways, I still do.
I mean, you know, God ridden me of God,
it's a powerful idea.
And was it just the false,
you know, deity that I was shedding,
and there's a real deity
that looks totally different in the
nooks and crannies somewhere?
In the dark matter, you know?
I don't know.
It feels impossible most of the time,
but sometimes, so yeah,
it was very painful.
The loss and the grieving
and all that stuff
were really pretty real and profound.
Particularly when I attempted to suspend
my belief that God
existed, I didn't know that
it was happening at the time,
but only could kind of put it together.
But man, that habit of drinking,
as much as we were,
was real bad.
It was a dissonance, I think, that my mind
just couldn't deal with.
I was just looking to
get, I was just looking
to lose time, I just wanted to,
to blackout for a while....
As confused as it was, even at the time,
my identity was still based a lot on
some form of my faith.
- [Marianne] Some of your
songs now that you talk about
as being more autobiographical,
talk about drinking.
How is that sort of path gone?
I mean, have you...
- Well, in Pedro the Lion...
Well, then let's talk about drinking.
- [Marianne] Yeah, maybe we should.
'Cause you've actually
made it a little bit
of a public issue.
But then you tend to make some of your
private stuff pretty public.
- Yeah.
- [Marianne] And, um...
- Mhm.
These habits that, at the time,
weren't particularly dark,
but they were, then,
it just was that habit
was a place when things did
kind of turn a little dark.
Then, you know, drinking
15 or 20 a day wasn't
an expression of all the good
things that we were feeling.
It turned into an expression of all of
the bad things that we were feeling.
(soft, melancholy music)
On that tour, I think,
was the moment when things
really started to shift.
My drinking was at kind of an apex.
We haven't checked in yet.
We're in the band Pedro the Lion,
we checking in right now.
- [Man] Oh man, this is crazy.
- [David] I can't believe that not even,
I mean, Cody's the only
one that's been here.
- I've never been here.
- You know I've never seen this one.
- And once we got onto
the festival grounds,
I switched to a jug that I had prepared,
poured like a third of the
water out of this gallon jug
and filled it up with vodka.
We had to be to the
festival grounds because
I had an interview and
it was with this guy,
Andrew Beaujon, who was writing a piece
for the Washington Post.
Whatever you want.
There's the uh, they're short
of the hospitality trait.
I mean, he's a grown person.
He could tell a drunk
person when he sees one,
and he also could tell
that I was drinking out of
a water jug that was a lot of vodka, so,
that was part of the texture
in his piece was that.
And so, later I think,
once the piece came out,
maybe a week or two later,
that was when Cornerstone
realized that I had been on the grounds
and I was hammered and
drinking on the grounds,
and that's expressly forbidden.
In a way, I have, I'm
living a double life.
I mean, I have these two
very different spheres
that I'm existing in
at almost equal times.
- [Ann] Who is that?
- Is it all the way zoomed?
- [Ann] Who is that Eleanor?
(Eleanor babbles)
- There was a lot of room for me out here,
especially if I'm on solo tours
and I'm staying in hotels.
You know, after the show is over,
after I've done my job for the day,
there's five or six hours that I just have
completely to myself,
and so that was a factor.
Like I would just go back to the hotel
with a bottle of booze
and a six pack of beer
and kind of say good
night while I was still
a little bit reasonable.
No one even knew about it.
(soft acoustic music)
♪ When I woke up the next morning ♪
♪ You looked right through me ♪
♪ Through your eyes, cryin'
I could finally see ♪
I would just keep on and keep on
until I just was passed
out and throwing up.
There was no voice in my head that said
it's time to stop tonight.
I had really crossed a line that made Ann
feel pretty unsafe.
She was scared for my safety and my life,
so she got really upset and
asked that I stop drinking
for a time or whatever.
And I was getting ready to leave on tour
and I remember it being really hard.
And I did call her and say,
"May I please just have one drink?"
♪ When I called you from Atlanta ♪
♪ You refused to speak ♪
♪ Not three days sober ♪
♪ Beggin' for a drink ♪
♪ I said please baby,
please baby, please ♪
♪ I said please baby, please ♪
♪ I said please baby,
please baby, please ♪
♪ I said please baby, please ♪
♪ Those two pairs of big, blue eyes ♪
♪ Stare me down, watch me fall ♪
♪ What makes a man realize ♪
♪ That he is about to lose it all ♪
Once I was able to kind
of make some peace with
leaving Christianity and just being myself
and owning my own thoughts,
the really intense,
sort of seed of that
compulsion to get blacked out
just kind of went away and then I was just
a guy with a drinking problem.
But it wasn't this hopeless
spiral that it had been.
And that's taken a lot of years to sort of
negotiate with, that, you
know, maybe somebody else
would've just stopped
drinking all together.
I did not do that, but yeah,
it's not a problem anymore.
(soft music)
- [Debbie] Who should decide
what the state flag is,
or is not.
Debbie Elliott, NPR News,
Jackson, Mississippi.
- [Woman] One of the
groups that helped push
Trump over the top in Indiana
was white evangelicals.
The question is, now that Kasich and Cruz
are out of the race, will
Republican evangelical voters
coalesce around Trump
in the general election?
- Hi.
- Hi again.
- Thanks for having me back.
- Yeah.
Thanks for comin' back.
♪ All the fallen leaves
should curse their branches ♪
♪ For not letting them decide
where they should fall ♪
♪ And not letting them
refuse to fall at all ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
(audience applause)
(cheering)
- [David] Hi, hi, hi.
You guys wanna talk about anything?
- I have a question.
- Yeah?
- [Woman] Do you realize
the amount of people
that are recovering evangelicals?
How do you feel about that,
that kind of follow you?
- And the answer to that
question could be kind
of loaded, like yeah, everybody needs to
stop being Christian or whatever, but,
I certainly don't feel that way.
So people who are allowed to sort of land
where their brains
really are in their life
and in their kind of view of the world,
it just makes me happy.
I feel like history, as
it's unfolding everyday,
it's forcing a lot of people to really
pay closer attention to
what's going on in the world.
And how their faith relates to that
and how their faith
relates or doesn't relate
to the teachings of the thing that they
ostensibly ave faith in.
(soft music)
I didn't want to write "Curse
Your Branches" like it was
but what came out was
all these tunes about
can the pot say to the potter,
why have you made me this way?
And it wasn't until people
started talking to me
about how they understood the record
that I realized what was really there.
You know, there were a lot more people
in that gray area than
I thought were there.
It was one of the 10 best
records in Christianity Today,
and I just, it blew my mind.
- Now I'm in my mid-30s
and I know that there
is a large generation for
which you spoke to that kind of
spiritual space that was hard
for many of us to express
really clearly and succinctly.
So I'm curious how you
recognize your place, kind of,
in that space in this
big transition that many
of us are going through.
And we find you on tour yet again.
- I sing these songs in people's houses
and at rock clubs and things and
officially that's what I have to offer,
and Twitter rants, you know.
(audience laughs)
Here's what I would say to that,
I feel like the little things that we do
that we don't think matter,
I think the evidence is
all around us, that
especially when we kind of
fudge those things, it matters, you guys.
How do collapses like the one
we're experiencing now
of judgment, happen?
It's those lapses in the little things.
You pee on the seat and you don't
wipe it up in a public space?
(audience laughs)
The aggregate is computing,
you know what I'm sayin'?
Everybody's still suffering.
Why so much suffering?
It's unnecessary.
We have the resources to not suffer
if we just wipe the seat.
(soft music)
(people chattering)
- I went from a solidly
Pat Robertson Christian
to a liberal, 'cause I'm
gay, I came out 10 years ago.
To an agnostic, to a
full on atheist humanist.
So, it's been a long journey.
- You're welcome.
- I miss church.
- Yeah.
- But I won't go back to
a church that tells me
that I have to believe in something
that's beyond nature or
that is condemning of things
that I know aren't bad.
- Right, are not bad, yeah.
- It was a spiritual nourishment,
and if I had this every week,
not necessarily from you.
- Yeah, right.
From various places.
- But just in general,
I would be a more invigorated human being.
- So then that's how you reconcile, like,
what you're doing with what you're doing,
is by touching people
and talking like this.
- [David] Yeah, yeah.
- [Man] Yeah, I'll be a
more active human being
because of what I experienced tonight.
- That's all I wanted.
Hey.
- Hey, thank you, thank you.
- Thank you so much, I
really appreciate it.
- Yeah, thank you for coming, cheers.
- Come back sometime.
- All right.
- You're doing good work.
- Thank you so much.
- [Man] I'm sure you know.
I hope you know.
(soft, tinkling music)
- [Nils] No, not exactly.
No, not exactly.
(David chuckles)
- [Ann] What is it then?
- Almost exactly.
- Measure it.
- Sometimes there's music in the world,
there's a lot of music
that when you hear it,
it's possible to think that everything
is okay with the world and I don't want my
music to be like that.
I feel like when you hear my music,
even if you really enjoy
it and are sort of like
lifted up by it, that there
should be some sense of like,
there's a wrinkle in
there that means, like,
it's the Men in Black, or whatever.
Until everything is okay with the world,
there's always gonna be
that wrinkle in there
that it's just not, it's not
okay to give the impression
that everything is fine, like half mast.
(soft, tinkling music)
The values that I think are what
makes Christianity worth while are missing
from the politics, it's just not there.
And that's compassion and care for poor
and people who can't care for themselves.
All of the minor Prophet
books and the Old Testament
are about God getting
mad at Israel because
they have forgotten their obligation
to the poor and to justice.
They're theoretically connected to this
source of power and wisdom and love that
would be able to help them come out on
the right side of a lot of this stuff.
On Jesus side of a lot of this stuff.
But it's not working, so.
And it's there, right
there, for people to see
if preachers were to preach that.
♪ Surprise, they took your money ♪
♪ They ate your kids ♪
♪ And they had their way
with your wife a little bit ♪
♪ While you wept on the porch ♪
♪ With your head in your hands ♪
♪ Cursin' taxes ♪
♪ And the immigrants ♪
♪ 'Cause you're a goddamned fool ♪
♪ You're a goddamned fool ♪
♪ And I love you ♪
♪ Of course I do ♪
(soft acoustic music)
♪ I love you ♪
♪ Yeah, I love you ♪
- [Woman] It was an election for the ages.
Donald Trump broke all the old rules
of presidential politics
and made an almost
clean sweep of the American rust belt.
A lot of different kinds of people
helped elect Donald Trump.
White working class voters, yes,
but also some Hispanics, white women,
and an overwhelming number of
white Evangelical Christians.
About 80% of white evangelicals voted
for President Donald Trump,
despite Trump's three marriages,
his anti-immigrant rhetoric,
and accusations of sexual harassment
and assault from multiple women.
The continued alignment of
many leading evangelicals
with Trump has caused some to question
whether their movement has lost its way.
- If there's any question that we've been
doing Christianity fundamentally wrong
in the United States
for our entire history,
I don't think that
there, if there ever was,
there just can't be none.
In the face of this cry
from the black population
that again, you guys, it isn't fixed yet.
And the response from
Christianity is Donald Trump?
It's, it's pure sadness.
(tense, dramatic music)
Until the election, I
was under the impression
that the white American
church was not a lost cause.
I thought I saw it maturing and evolving
and even if I couldn't
participate as a believer,
I wanted to be a helper in
that process if I could.
But the fruit that showed
up on the tree was,
for me, very much the
cut the damn thing down
and throw it in the fire kind of fruit.
It's not a pruning issue,
it's just the wrong seeds.
I've heard so many people say
that no matter what happens,
I'm not changing my mind.
It's all worth that Supreme Court seat.
It represents only abortion to them and
if somebody believes the
ends that they're going for
justify the means that
they're using to get there,
that is idolatry.
I mean, most of Christianity is apparently
cool with that way of thinking.
For everything Christians
claim to believe,
the election, I think, laid
bare what they actually believe.
They reliably work
against the best virtues
of their traditions.
The people that taught me
how to be a decent person are
losing their minds.
That's where I came from, and so it just
hit like another deconversion experience.
I don't totally know how to proceed still.
(tense, dramatic music)
♪ We turn to go ♪
♪ The angel shone ♪
♪ Said don't go back to Harod's throne ♪
♪ Take the long way ♪
♪ Around the sea ♪
(cars passing)
- Isn't it pretty?
- I like that.
It is just--
- I wanna get it framed.
- Well it's weird to figure
out, like, what it is.
- [Woman] Mhm.
It's cool.
- [David] It's really neat.
Beautiful brain that guy has.
(people chattering)
(soft music)
- [Jonah] So you have a new record.
- I do.
- I guess, do you feel
like you get something out of
making yourself vulnerable?
'Cause it seems like that's
the direction you're moving.
It's like, from a band and now it's just
you standing there, and now it's just you
sing songs about your family by yourself.
- Yeah, I think so, I mean
I think slowly I've been,
I've been looking for that because
there's a lot of emotional pain.
I wrote about it on the whole record.
So much of the drag in
my life that has hurt
my relationship with
my wife or just affects
on my career and my family,
and you know, myself.
That I don't, sorry...
(soft music)
♪ Somewhere else ♪
♪ I have kids who love
to splash in the waves ♪
♪ Who take the boardwalk by storm ♪
♪ And eat pizza all day ♪
♪ And digging in the sand ♪
♪ Shooting with straws ♪
♪ And rubber bands ♪
♪ I'm wishing you were here ♪
(audience applause)
Well thank you so much.
What's that?
- How are the kids?
- The kids are doing great.
Seven year old decided that last week
he'd ride a two wheeler by himself
without training wheels.
(audience cheers)
We waited a long time for that.
- [Woman] Were you there for that?
- Nope.
(audience laughs)
It's okay, here's my theory on that:
I just want it to happen.
I don't have to be there for it,
although it's important that
he knows how excited I am,
and I think he does.
(soft music)
- [Ann] Yeah it's feeling, um,
this one's feeling long to me.
- [David] Yeah.
- Like kind of, I don't
know if it's just 'cause,
I don't know if we're just tired.
We're gonna go up to Art
Darlington art show today.
Gloria's got stuff on display.
- Oh yeah, she's really
good at that stuff.
- [Ann] Well I'm gonna take them first.
- All right.
- [Woman] Talk to you later.
- I love you.
- Love you, bye.
(soft music)
(child chattering)
All right, shug, let's see you start here.
Yes.
(soft music)
Hurray.
How do you start?
Two hands.
There you go.
How do you start?
Leg over, uh huh.
Uh huh.
(soft music)
Now take off.
Okay, stay to the right.
Stay to the right, you got it.
(soft music)
- The sands are just racing
through the hourglass.
Eleanor, she lives in
our house for 18 years,
like she's two thirds of the way there.
And I've been gone for half
of it, and it's not okay.
It's not getting easier.
It's getting worse.
The cracks are showing all over.
I have to rework this whole thing.
And I'm looking at all this
time that I've put into
these musical relationships that I've had
with people that just haven't worked out
for one reason or another.
And honestly, with all
the good and all the
fun and joy that I
experienced with that stuff,
it feels like I'm trading
that fun and that joy
and whatever benefit that was for
the fun and joy that I could
have been having with my family
because if I just had
never invested in that,
I would be only out 75 days of the year.
I would've been able to
work with Nils on his
batting the first year that
he was in little league
where he didn't get a hit.
I could've helped more, but
I couldn't 'cause I was gone.
I didn't realize I was trading that for
driving my daughter to swim
every morning like I have
in certain summers where we just have
this really sweet time.
And her getting to kind of be herself.
You know, I'm out here on I-95 again
instead of doing that.
I like it out here, but not that much.
(soft, melancholy music)
My wife and I are growing old and we're
only growing old together half way.
That doesn't feel very good to me.
I wasn't all wrong, but
there was a miscalculation.
Yeah.
(soft, melancholy music)
(rain pattering)
(humming)
♪ A sinking feeling has
been lurking at your door ♪
♪ That it is real, you can't deny ♪
♪ You must ignore ♪
(humming)
You go to bed then.
You got you jim-jams on?
What'd you guys do today?
So did you do chapter three yet?
Well, I gotta finish packing up.
Love you too, kiddo.
Mwah.
♪ Sing like the angel ♪
♪ That you know you'll never be ♪
♪ And try to pin the blame on me ♪
Everybody have a good time?
Wish I was there.
It's scary to me because
I don't even feel like
I can take full
responsibility in what happens
at the show because there's just aspects
of my emotion that I can't modulate.
I can't come back from the
verge of tears feeling.
I don't know that I've
ever felt lower in my life.
♪ The heart that beats inside your chest ♪
♪ The awful need ♪
♪ It burns with holy fire ♪
♪ Righteousness and greed ♪
♪ Sing like the angel ♪
♪ That you know you'll never be ♪
♪ And try to pin the blame on me ♪
♪ Like the angel ♪
♪ That you know you'll never be ♪
♪ But you still try and pin the blame ♪
♪ On me ♪
(humming)
(people cheering)
(clapping)
(people chattering)
Watch the batter, bud.
Oh.
- [Eleanor] Hey dad, do you have money?
I'm gonna go get mom and pretzel and just
have a few bites of it 'cause I'm hungry.
- [David] You want a couple of corn nuts?
Are you doing all right?
- Not right now.
- All right, good.
- I have gum.
- [David] Great, good to hear it.
Get back over to your spot.
- [Child] Let me hear your music voice.
- [David] Okay, I'll play it right now.
- [Child] Okay.
- [David] On your mark, get set.
(child laughs)
Do you hear it?
- No.
- Oh man, it's so good.
(children laughing)
Hey, sit down you guys.
That was my fault coach, sorry.
(people chattering)
Almost.
(clapping)
Oh man.
- Good try, Nils.
- I love that guy.
He's always the last out
when the bases are loaded.
Poor guy.
(people chattering)
(water spraying)
(leaves rustling)
(laughing)
You ready?
(soft, upbeat piano music)
(birds chirping)
(Ann and David chattering)
(soft music)
- [Ann] Go ahead and go.
- When I stopped drinking, I started to be
able to see myself more clearly
and the things around me.
Right away, I was aware of a
very overwhelming loneliness
and I realized that my
native spot as a human
was behind the wheel of
a car, on an interstate,
somewhere in the United States, alone.
If you just picked any
moment in my life at random,
the odds were that that was
what I was going to be doing.
♪ I climb the rock ♪
♪ Still make my home ♪
That was the basic unit of my career.
It all reverted back to,
I play solo house shows.
And solo house shows were
amazing in the sense that
I could interact with
fans in a totally new way
and to continue to do this work
while I've been figuring this out.
(soft music)
And so I was looking
down the barrel of just
kind of doing the back half of my life
as a solo traveler primarily
and that killed me.
Sitting with that just
really brought me to my
lowest place that I had been.
I hit bottom, basically.
In 2016, I'm on tour playing
these club shows solo.
It just caused me to start
asking myself questions,
like okay, well then what's it gonna be?
Like, if you had a million bucks,
it's kind of like that question.
Like okay, if you could
anything, what would it be?
And it's like, I wanna be in a band.
That's what I've always wanted to do.
I love playing solo but that wasn't what
I set out to do.
You know, when I sat and
dreamt of what I wanted to do,
I didn't picture myself alone in a car.
I didn't picture myself alone on a stage.
It was drums and it was bass
and it was electric guitar
and that's what I wanted.
That's what I've always wanted to do.
(soft rock music)
I asked myself, what's the
way that you have access
to right now, to do the band thing?
And I realized when I
was a kid how I did it
was I wrote the drum
parts and the guitar parts
and the bass parts and I wrote the vocals
and I had people play them.
(soft rock music)
♪ I saw in your bedroom ♪
♪ The drawers had been emptied ♪
I had to return to the process that I knew
and that I had been
personally successful with.
That's where I had come
from and so I thought, okay,
I gotta find my way back to that.
And it was a revelation, it
was just like riding a bike.
It felt like home.
It also felt a lot like Pedro the Lion
and it occurred to me, oh, this is Pedro.
And as soon as that clicked,
it really felt like home.
Like a bunch of myself
just came right back to me.
(soft music)
Everything clicked into
place and I had a vision
for the future of the
way that the band sounded
and for the way that
the shows were gonna go.
I had people around who
were willing to do a band
like that with me.
Coincidentally, Pedro the Lion,
because it was a brand name
that I had developed for a
decade and that people knew,
would allow me to go out on
tour and play fewer shows
and make a similar living.
Instead of being six weeks on,
six weeks off all year round,
I could be three weeks on tour
and 10 weeks home and do
that four times in a year.
That would revolutionize my life
and my ability to connect with my family.
- [Man] A little less, check check.
That's fine.
- [Woman] Any questions?
Anyone have any questions?
Well thank you for being here, enjoy.
- [Audio Engineer And
Man] Five, four, three,
two, one.
- [Man] And roll out.
- It is 90.3 KEXP.
My name is Troy Nelson and we have some
Pacific Northwest legends in
the KEXP live room right now.
I am very, very pleased
to bring to all of you,
Pedro the Lion.
Thank you so much for
stopping by and doing this.
- Yeah, thank you for having us.
- Absolutely.
So you have reformed?
- Yeah.
- This is exciting.
- It's pretty fun.
- You're playing three nights in Seattle
at The Tractor.
You have a busy 2018 ahead of you,
and 19, and 20, and beyond, I'm sure.
- If the universe will, as they say.
- Well thanks for all
the years of great music
and looking forward to many more.
(acoustic music)
♪ I shut off the radio ♪
♪ To fix my eyes on the road ♪
♪ Pushed past the window glass ♪
♪ And let it flow ♪
♪ How wonderful, how strange ♪
♪ How invisible the change ♪
♪ Everything's staying the same ♪
♪ Except my brain ♪
(people chattering)
♪ All the way ♪
- Yeah, I got it.
(humming)
(soft acoustic music)
This is gonna be fun.
(people chattering)
Do you wanna come back?
- [Ann] No, I think I'll just right here.
We're just gonna park right here.
- [David] Sounds good.
- I love you.
- Love you.
(kissing)
(people chattering)
♪ Postpone the unavoidable ♪
♪ And prolong the pain of being alive ♪
Let's go.
(audience cheering)
(clapping)
Hello everybody.
(audience cheers)
Okay, so, we're called Pedro the Lion.
And this is very nearly the
20th anniversary of a show,
my very first club show ever in Seattle,
here at The Tractor, in 1997.
(audience cheers)
Any questions at this point in the show?
What's that?
- [Woman] Are you going to
do more living room shows?
- There will be more living room shows,
but it will be a minute
because we're trying to
do a thing where I make
a slightly better living
and stay home more also.
(audience cheers)
No, I only tell jokes from
stage when I'm blackout drunk,
and uh, not tonight.
(audience laughs)
I've done that for years
on end and that wasn't
as cool as this, I don't think.
- How do you like your band?
- For real.
What's this?
- How do you like you band?
How do you like playing with a band?
- Well, playing with a band
really feeds my soul, man.
All these shows sold real quick
and that was really fun for us,
because we didn't know
what was gonna happen.
And uh, thank you so much.
I'm really glad to be back playing
Pedro the Lion songs as Pedro.
And Sean Lane and Erik Walters,
we're all very grateful
that you came to the show.
(audience applause)
(rock music)
♪ All the way to grandma's house ♪
♪ I stayed on the narrow path ♪
♪ But my brother wandered off ♪
♪ Deep into the woods ♪
♪ Bitten twice by rattlesnakes ♪
♪ Tangled up in poison oak ♪
♪ He fell down and broke his legs ♪
♪ Into a great ravine ♪
♪ When I arrived at grandma's house ♪
♪ She had made us tea and cake ♪
♪ She asked me where my brother was ♪
♪ And I said I don't know ♪
♪ And ate ♪
(rock music)
(soft music)
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Cha cha cha ♪
(cheering)
I still find myself
reaching out for something.
It really doesn't feel
like my consciousness
is a closed system.
Things feel connected somehow.
And I don't know, I don't
know why or how come,
but I know what it feels
like and it doesn't
feel like a closed system.
So I don't know what that means.
At a certain point, I thought,
what if the divine is just
balance and harmony itself?
That in harmony, that's where
you experience transcendence.
Whatever metaphysical reality is that
is the thing that's
happening all around us.
Harmony is wanting to be had.
Ways of interacting with other humans
just waiting to be unlocked.
And in a way, crying out to be unlocked.
Justice just waiting to be balanced.
I've had impulses to put
a name on it at times
and I just thought, no man.
Not because I don't wanna arrive anywhere.
Not because I don't wanna understand.
But because it just
seems like that's where
you get into trouble. (chuckles)
(soft music)
You have that one cup of...
♪ It goes ♪
♪ On and on ♪
♪ It goes on ♪
♪ It goes ♪
♪ On and on ♪
♪ It goes on ♪
(rock music)
♪ Right here ♪
♪ I'll be ♪
♪ 'Til I can ♪
♪ No longer breathe ♪
(rock music)
(soft, tinkling music)
♪ You blew all your inheritance ♪
♪ And now you're trying
to pin the blame on me ♪
♪ I could write you off to easily ♪
♪ Except a hundred million
other people agree ♪
♪ So you kick and scream
to get your way again ♪
♪ But the writing is on the wall ♪
♪ Any minute you'll on to your reward ♪
♪ And someone else is
gonna make the call ♪
♪ In these strange negotiations ♪
♪ Man they really are getting me down ♪
♪ Strange negotiations ♪
♪ Feel like a stranger in my home town ♪
♪ You got me looking for a way around ♪
♪ All these strange negotiations ♪
(soft music)
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
(soft, tinkling music)