Commitment of Honor
(1949)
I'm going!
Haven't you heard
"ladies first"?
Are you in a hurry this morning, son?
Yes! Today's game
against the Beavers.
- They have a good scout.
- Do they?
Mom, have you seen my baseball cap?
No, dear.
You're not wearing it?
Mom!
I don't see him anywhere!
Oh!
Not again!
It can't be the first of the month already!
Bills, bills...
Dad, I wondered...
don't you think you could...
- No, I don't think so.
- No what?
I thought that if I had
a bicycle...
I want a
bike!
You can't ride yet!
Wait for your time!
Roddy, I told you not to
bother your father with this!
I know, Mom!
But I can't do without it!
I've seen a second-hand one.
It's beautiful!
It looks new!
- I could get it cheap!
- How much?
Well...
...28 sticks and 5 cents
for the license.
It might be enough for the license,
Roddy.
If I buy a girl,
we can put them both together!
A girl?
Not that one!
Forget everything!
Hey!
- I've got to go!
- You haven't finished your coffee!
I know, but I don't have time!
I have to train for the game!
- See you later, Dad. See you, Mom!
- See you, darling.
-See you, Mom!
- See you.
Where are you going?
- I'm going to train too.
- Yes?
I'll take care of the water!
I wish we could buy
the bike. You're out of your mind!
- Georgia, do you believe that...
- I don't believe it, that's what I know.
We can only face
basic expenses,
...pay for the house and the car,
and let's not talk about saving money.
We can't go on like this.
We have to do something.
But what?
Why don't you ask for more money?
It's worth much more than
they pay you!
I'm just an assistant accountant!
Yes, but even the auxiliaries and
their families have to live!
How do you expect us to live
with what you earn?
They are not responsible for
me having children.
Why don't you talk
with Mr. Jarvis?
Sam, why don't you ask
today?
- Okay, I'll see what I can do.
- Good!
Now I'm going or I'll be late.
JARVIS & HEARNE
INVESTMENT SECURITIES
Good morning, Mr. Austin.
-Good morning, Sam.
- Good morning, Ms. Vantay.
- Good morning.
- Ms. Vantay.
- Miss Vantay: Yes?
I'd like to...
I was wondering if I could see
Mr. Jarvis today.
I think you can see him now,
wait a moment.
Mr. Wilson wants to see you.
Can we do it now?
Yes, sir.
- Come in, Mr. Wilson.
- Oh, thank you.
I'm still a member.
Don't you want to discuss it reasonably?
There are other ways, I assure you!
Come in, Sam.
You've chosen a good day,
you're in an excellent mood!
Hello, Sam!
I wanted to see you because...
...I had to do that.
You see, I...
...my family can't cope
with my salary.
I'm sorry to bother you,
...but I think my work is worth more,
the cost of living has gone up,
...and many salaries with it.
Every month we are at zero.
I was hoping you'd
to give me...
...at least a moderate increase.
I didn't know you wanted to see me.
I told Ms. Vantay to
to come in and talk to you.
- Do you want to talk to me?
- Yes. Sit down.
I'm sorry to tell you that, Sam.
By the beginning of next month
we won't need your services.
Am I fired?
Yes.
Sir, if it's for the increase...
I'm sorry, you already know
the financial situation.
We can't go on like this,
we must cut spending.
I've been with the company for 12 years!
I was hoping to spend
the rest of my life here.
We didn't save much.
I know it's going to be difficult for you,
...but the company can't take it.
The company will recover!
It's just a matter of hanging in there!
- I could put money in your pocket!
- Money from my pocket?
How funny!
Do you know how much I have in the bank?
Zero!
- Maybe less!
- Mr. Hearne can do it!
We don't get along,
you know!
He'll put up money on the condition that I leave
without paying me anything!
He says the company
has no funds and is worthless!
And you're right.
He wants the name.
I told him not to talk about it!
I'm sorry, sir.
- I thought you were rich.
- Yes, everyone thinks so.
Just because I have a big house
and cars,
...but the fact is, we're ruined.
Hey, Sam!
Shall I drive you?
I'll stop by your house.
Thank you, sir!
And I want to talk to you.
I invite you for a drink!
Great!
I've been thinking.
Maybe there's a way out for both of us.
Let me tell you something
in confidence,
...something
that could benefit you greatly.
He loves his wife and children,
don't you, Sam?
Of course!
Enough to die for them,
no?
I feel that way about
my wife...
...and my son Sidney.
I would die for them.
Sam, I'm going to kill myself.
The...
No, you're kidding, Mr. Jarvis!
- You're...
- I'm not drunk. I'm not joking.
I'm planning to commit suicide.
I need your help.
Mr. Jarvis,
think about it twice!
Sam,
...I inherited 500,000 dollars
from my father.
There's not a penny left.
- But how?
- I'll get to that in a minute.
I can't walk away and leave
my family bankrupt.
I plan to leave them
as much as they left me.
I've been paying for life insurance
for years.
Three months ago
increased by another 200 thousand dollars.
But it's suicide!
- The insurance company wouldn't pay!
- That's it, Sam.
Then you enter.
I want you to make it
look like a murder.
Murder!
I planned everything.
I have a 38, nobody knows that.
I want you to come later...
and take it away.
Mr. Jarvis, I couldn't
do that!
I'll be in the library.
I'll leave the safe open.
With papers on the floor, like
it looks like a robbery.
Take the gun, get out and shoot
into the air once or twice.
I'll do my part in
my office.
I suggest you throw the gun into the sea.
You will be
completely out of danger...
...and I'll pay you 10 thousand dollars.
10,000 dollars?
Why don't you get your
business with it?
Sam, when you need half a million,
10,000 dollars is a trifle!
But that would be a lot of money for you.
No, Mr. Jarvis.
That money...
... it wouldn't do me any good.
You have to help me!
I can't trust anyone else!
I'll call you when
time.
I'll ask you for a report
of the ransom account.
The rescue account,
this will be the password.
When you hear that,
come and take care of everything.
I can't do that!
You shouldn't think about something like that.
Suicide is bad.
It doesn't solve anything!
I won't take part in it.
Okay, Sam.
I know that's your attitude,
I understand. Forget it!
Is that you, Sam?
Yes, dear.
Tonight is the
meeting at the church.
The girls will be here soon.
Sam, did you drink?
It's just that Mr. Jarvis...
Drinks with the boss!
You celebrated!
You got the raise!
Not exactly.
But he said there would be changes
that would affect.
A promotion! Even better!
You see? I was sure that
would be valued!
I wish I could stay
with you and celebrate!
Tell me all about it when I get back!
They're already there.
Your dinner's on the table.
You don't mind, dear?
Of course not.
I'll take these flowers to the altar,
are they pretty?
Did the kids have dinner?
They're with Freddy, watching
television.
George the Great,
fights El Monstro.
Don't worry, I'll be back as soon as I can,
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Goodbye, darling.
Hello?
Yes, I'm Sam.
Yes, Sam.
It's sooner than I thought,
but that's it.
Everything is ready here.
"I want a report
of the haggling account".
- But...
- From the ransom account, you know?
You mustn't, I told you!
"To the rescue, Sam."
Mr. Jarvis, don't do this!
Please wait!
I'll go and we'll talk!
Wait for it to arrive!
Hello?
Hello!
the happiness of my loved ones
IS IN YOUR HANDS. DON'T LET ME DOWN
SPORTS PORT
SPORT FISHING BOATS
BEERS
DANCE
Georgia?
Roddy!
- Good night, Sam!
- Good night, Bill!
- Is it still up?
- Yes.
- Have the kids arrived yet?
- Not yet.
- Did everything go well?
- Yes, it was great!
It was Mrs. Beamish and Sally.
I hadn't seen them for ages!
The bad thing is that I always
feel guilty!
Guilty?
And ashamed.
Of complaining about our little problems
when I hear real problems.
Tonight we're talking about the Parker family.
Sam, this woman keeps
two children at school...
...and her husband in the sanatorium with the
he earns cleaning!
Yes?
Yes, things could go
worse for us.
We have so much
to be grateful for...
A beautiful home...
...our children and us!
People like us should
give thanks every day.
Are you happy?
- Of course, he's very happy!
- But you're tired. Go to bed!
I'll go where Freddy is
to see the children.
All right, darling!
Mom, the newspaper!
I'm coming!
Go soon or you'll be late!
-Sam!
-Yes?
- Sam, come here!
- Good morning, darling.
I slept a lot!
And terrible, Sam!
They murdered Mr. Jarvis!
- Shot?
- Last night!
He was found in the library
and the police were called!
"Malcolm Jarvis was gunned down
in his Beverly Hills home...
by an unknown gunman".
"The motive is theft,
because there were papers all over the floor...
...and they had opened the safe".
Mrs. Jarvis was in her
beach house.
How awful!
And Sidney!
It's terrible.
Terrible.
Sam,
...we should go and see
Mrs. Jarvis.
Going to see her?
Georgia, I only worked for him!
We're not friends.
But you worked for him for 12 years!
And it's possible that we can
do something for her!
I suppose we could go,
...but I wouldn't feel comfortable
showing up at a time like this!
Jarvis was an important man.
We would be late for church.
There must be something we can
do.
I'll get dressed.
Drink your coffee.
- There will be police everywhere.
- We can offer them help!
That...
...what can I do to help them?
They will question everyone who
knew Mr. Jarvis,
...friends and work colleagues.
Don't they always?
Ask if anyone knows
enemies of the murdered man...
...or if someone was reprimanded
by him, things like that.
It's a case of theft, period.
At least the newspapers said
that.
They'll still ask questions.
That's for sure.
Did you want to see someone?
Yes, officer. My name is
is Wilson, Sam Wilson.
He was one of
of Mr. Jarvis.
My wife and I wanted to see
Mrs. Jarvis
...and see if we can help her.
I'll ask Lieutenant Webb.
He's in charge of the case,
according to the newspapers.
- You have a good reputation!
- Yes, I heard that.
Since Mr. Jarvis
so important,
...will leave no stone unturned until
they find the killer.
Lieutenant Webb said
that you can see Mrs. Jarvis.
And he wants to talk to you,
Mr. Wilson.
Hello, Mrs. Wilson, Mr. Wilson.
Would you like to come in?
Sidney,
...we're sorry about your father.
Thank you, Mrs. Wilson.
My mother sent the
to the beach house yesterday.
She also went last night.
Yes, we read that in the paper.
Are you here?
I'll tell her you're here.
- Mr. Hearne!
- How are you, Mr. Wilson?
- How's it going? Have you discovered anything?
- I'm afraid not yet.
It's terrible.
Mrs. Jarvis
is doing very well.
I'm glad!
I was telling the lieutenant that
we weren't very good friends.
He'll think I killed him,
I don't know why.
If it were for control of the
company,
... you already know how little you're worth.
The case is that you have to
find the killer.
It's your job.
Suspect you?
It's incredible!
Of course not.
He gave me a good reprimand.
I'm off.
See you tomorrow, Sam.
I told Mrs. Jarvis
that I'll be running the office at the moment.
I'm glad to see you, ma'am.
Goodbye, ma'am.
Now go downstairs.
Do you want to wait in the living room?
- Good morning, sir.
- Mrs. Jarvis.
- How are you, Mrs. Wilson?
Thank you so much for coming.
Mrs. Jarvis, we know that no one
can know what you feel,
...but if there's anything we can
do...
Thanks, but...
...I think everything is under control.
Sit down.
Is there anything
with business arrangements?
Thank you, Sam.
We can't plan anything.
They should do an investigation,
...but someone has to
take the office forward.
Mr. Hearne offered to
temporarily.
Frankly, I'd feel better
if you took care of it.
I would be happy to do whatever
was in my hands.
I have complete confidence
in Mr. Hearne.
I wish I could believe it,
but I don't.
Yes?
Lieutenant Webb wants to see
Mr. Wilson in the library.
I'm off. Excuse me.
Sam, I'll wait for you in the car.
Another thing:
could you get me a
financial report of the company?
Of course. I'll bring it tomorrow.
Thank you.
Come in, Mr. Wilson.
- I'm Lieutenant Webb.
- How do you do?
My assistant, Sergeant Cord.
Have a seat.
I understand you're an employee
of Mr. Jarvis.
Yes, sir.
Assistant accountant.
- I worked for him for 12 years.
- 12 years!
You must have known the murdered man
very well!
You know if he had enemies,
...already outside your company
or through personal relationships?
I don't believe it.
- I don't think I had any enemies.
- Didn't I?
And Timothy Hearne, his partner?
I couldn't call him an enemy.
They didn't always agree.
Mr. Wilson, be frank
with Jarvis and Hearne.
We'll find out eventually...
...and nobody goes to the
chamber.
I questioned Hearne.
It's not that there was much love
between them.
Mr. Hearne couldn't kill
Mr. Jarvis. He wouldn't kill anyone!
- No one is accusing him of murder yet!
- What did you discuss?
I believe that Mr. Hearne
wanted to run the company,
...make it more efficient,
profitable.
- The company was making losses.
- Losses?
That's not what Mrs. Jarvis
told me!
He said the business was very
profitable.
The company has lost 50,000 dollars
a year for the last four and a half years.
50,000 dollars,
these are major losses!
About 225,000 dollars,
today.
I'm sure that Mr. Hearne
is not a murderer!
That's great, you're sure!
Not me.
Hearne was alone at
last night.
He could have come and shot
Jarvis.
He admits to having a .38 revolver.
I sent a man after him.
I hadn't...
The autopsy report
reveals that he was shot with a 38...
...and we recovered two projectiles
in the bedroom wall.
Oh, yes, Mr. Wilson.
Right there.
What's up, Mr. Wilson?
that you knew exactly where to aim?
The newspapers said that
thrown out of the window.
Look for the holes in the
on the opposite wall!
Do you think there's something
tell us and help us?
Anything, not the press.
No, sir. Not a thing.
That's all, Mr. Wilson.
For now.
I'd like you to give us your
fingerprints, if you don't mind.
The fingerprints?
Yes. It won't hurt you.
They'll take it at the entrance!
Well, buddy.
Don't be shy, come with that hand.
Why would he be so nervous?
I wonder how I knew
the bullets were in that wall!
I don't know!
You won't believe that this
bunny killed anyone, do you?
Let them follow him.
Follow him? Are you kidding?
I said follow him.
Okay.
The phone is on the table.
Hey, Mom, Dad!
Do you know about Mr. Jarvis?
Have you read the papers? Have you been to church?
We didn't go to church,
we went to see Mrs. Jarvis.
Oh!
- It must be tough for her and Sidney!
- Yes, dear.
- Were there police?
- Yes, they were there.
- I spoke to Lieutenant Webb.
- Lieutenant Webb!
How exciting!
Do you know you were in the war?
He was behind the German lines.
He was wounded in the leg too.
Yes, he's certainly
a good man.
Look! It's like a modern
policeman!
Always get the bad guy!
He was also in T2.
Military intelligence, Dad.
Hey, get back to your soccer!
Mom, do you prefer Dick Powell
or Cary Grant?
Ask your father.
He wouldn't let me have any!
I swapped Cary Grant
for Dick Powell...
...at a wedding with Jane Greer.
I hope I haven't made a mistake.
I prefer Donald Duck.
Wait, Dad.
Oh. I'll give you the
section.
I don't care!
I'm reading about the murder.
Roddy, don't read that stuff!
It's morbid!
It's sensational!
I'm going to be a detective,
like Lieutenant Webb.
They say the police are after
the criminal's trail!
They know that, but he doesn't!
He knows
what they want you to know.
Sometimes they put lies
in the newspapers...
...to give him false clues.
- Roddy!
Surely Lieutenant Webb
has enough...
...to send him to the gas chamber!
Roddy!
I didn't know you were an expert
on police and crime!
It's because he reads detective stories.
If they let him,
he would catch the killer immediately,
...isn't that right, Roddy?
I'm going!
Hello, Sidney.
- Hello, is your father there?
-Yes!
It's Sidney Jarvis!
Sidney.
Tell him to come in!
Come in!
Sidney,
we're sorry about your father!
- Thank you, Roddy.
- Hello, Sidney.
- Good afternoon, Mrs. Wilson.
- Good afternoon, Sidney. Have a seat.
- Take this chair.
- Thank you.
Mr. Wilson, I want to talk to you...
in private,
to ask his advice.
Roddy, Hilda, upstairs!
Get ready for bed.
See you later, Sidney.
I...
You can talk to Mrs. Wilson.
She'll understand.
What is it, Sidney?
Mr. Wilson, my father loved
of you. That's why I'm here.
Thank you.
Also because you know
Mr. Hearne.
Dad didn't like him
and Mom thinks he's a thief...
...but I believe I know him and I don't
agree. What do you think?
I like him.
He didn't get on well with his father, but
I'm sure he's honest.
Me too!
Otherwise, I wouldn't be here.
You see, I saw Mr. Hearne
at our house last night.
Did you see Mr. Hearne
house last night?
He doesn't know I saw him,
but I did.
I had a date with Joan Martin.
When I left his house, I saw that I had
forgotten my wallet...
...and I went back to get it.
I didn't go to the entrance.
I left the car to one side and went upstairs.
When I came back, I saw Dad
and Mr. Hearne in the library.
Are you sure it was him?
Yes! I had a good look!
They were arguing and didn't see me.
What time was it, Sidney?
It should be half past eight,
not earlier.
Then we went to Joan's house.
Dad and Mr. Hearne
were home alone.
I went to dinner with Joan...
...and when I came back,
...I found him on the ground and called the
the police.
Did you tell them that
Hearne had been there?
They didn't ask, so
I didn't say.
I want them to catch Dad's killer
and I want to help the police,
...but I don't want to get an
in trouble.
I agree with you, Sidney.
It wouldn't look good...
...implicate an innocent man.
- Sam!
No, Sidney.
Don't say anything to Webb.
That's what I felt I had to do.
I'm glad you agree.
That's what Dad would have said,
...even if he and Hearne
didn't get along.
Thank you very much,
I'll take your advice.
I think I should go home,
I shouldn't leave my mother alone.
- Good evening and thank you very much.
- Good night, Sidney.
Sidney, I'm sure
you're doing the right thing.
- Good evening, Mr. Wilson.
- Good night, Mr. Wilson.
He's a good kid, isn't he?
Sam, I don't understand your attitude.
Darling, we usually agree
on almost everything,
...but I think you're
wrong about this!
The police must have
all possible information about the case...
...and that Mr. Hearne had gone last
night is very important.
And I don't think so,
...so I'm going to insist, Georgia,
forget about it.
It's not a question of implicating
Mr. Hearne.
Isn't it possible that you killed
Mr. Jarvis?
No, it's not possible,
I'm sure of it.
Sam, what's wrong with you?
It doesn't behave normally.
How can you be so sure?
Well, I know Mr. Hearne.
He behaves as if he knew
who it was. Do you?
What a silly question!
How can anyone know?
- Well... - Georgia, I don't want to
discuss this any further!
- What's your address?
- I don't know it.
Ms. Vantay!
- Good morning.
Here it is.
I didn't know if you were coming today!
Mr. Hearne
called a meeting.
They're waiting for you.
We'll talk about that in a moment.
- Oh, good morning, Sam.
- Good morning, sir.
- They're all there, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
I suppose many
wondering what's going to happen.
As for the immediate future,
...they can continue working,
that is, if they want to.
The company has no funds,
...but I personally will keep it
out of my pocket for three months,
...so don't be afraid,
they won't be on the street.
A delegation of
from the police.
It should be here soon.
They want to ask questions...
...and, of course, we must help them.
Well, that's all.
Just a minute, Sam.
Sit down!
Sam, I plan to put my
hands in the company.
That is, if you can make a
reasonable deal with Mrs. Jarvis.
That's great!
I'm sure you can do it, sir.
Thank you.
Where am I going with this?
Austin was fired
as head of accounts.
It takes months of discontent.
He knows about our situation and
another job.
He just told me.
- If you want his seat, it's yours.
- Austin's seat?
That's right.
I can't guarantee that it will be
permanent.
You pay 500 dollars a month...
...and I'd like you to stay.
Work hard.
What's most important:
he's honest and loyal.
Well, what do you say?
Mr. Hearne, you're very kind.
Yes, of course I will.
- Thank you, thank you very much.
- From now on you're the chief accountant.
I asked him to leave soon,
so he could start.
We'll meet when
the investigation is finished...
...and we'll discuss it in more detail.
- Yes, sir.
Roddy, what the hell are you looking for?
My baseball cap!
It's got to be somewhere!
Don't clutter up the closet
any more than it already is!
It seems to me that he's always
looking for him!
I'm looking because I can't find it!
Once I find him,
I'll stop looking for him!
Nobody uses it but you!
I'm not so sure about that!
It's funny how easy it is to
to lose a baseball cap!
I have a very important game today!
I can't...
Wow! I've found it!
Roddy, what have you done?
Did you hurt yourself?
No, I don't think so.
I'll take that.
No, no. Go on, get out!
I had to clean it anyway.
- Let's get to it.
- Be careful when you go down into the archives.
- Good morning, Lieutenant.
- Good morning, Mr. Hearne.
Sorry to disturb you, we won't make
more noise than necessary.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Webb, from the police.
You are in charge of the investigation
into the death of Mr. Jarvis.
I know they'll help you
you can.
To begin with, we want
your fingerprints.
Don't be alarmed,
it's a routine procedure.
We want to search
Jarvis' office and his files.
This way.
Well, friends.
I already have your fingerprints from yesterday.
Miss, if you want to come this way...
I had nothing to do
with Mr. Jarvis' death!
The police don't think
We just want your fingerprints.
If you don't mind.
Yes, I argued with Jarvis,
several times.
I didn't like him
personally...
...but that doesn't mean
that I killed him.
You wouldn't see Mr. Jarvis at his
Saturday night, would you?
Why, when I can see him
whenever I want at the office?
So the lieutenant
asks him why.
And I tell you
you had no reason to!
- Is that the last thing you have to say?
- Yes, it is.
- That's all right. That's all for now.
- Thank you very much.
I wonder what he's hiding.
That's the question of the million!
- And Jarvis' secretary?
- Miss Altanera?
I checked her out.
She was the boss's fiancée.
For Saturday night
you seem to have a good alibi.
She would be the first secretary
to get involved with a boss...
...whose devotion was so firm.
Hello? Yes!
Hello, Mac. I'm Webb.
Anything else?
Intriguing. Thank you, sir.
The bullet that killed Jarvis...
...it wasn't the same gun
that hit the wall.
That means they used
two weapons.
Maybe the secretary had
two revolvers.
Yes, or maybe there was a duel.
I only have one thing clear:
the murder was not
of a common thief.
Jarvis could have killed himself.
And get rid of both
weapons afterwards?
It's a good trick.
You can do it.
Frank, have you found anything?
They were right about the
financial situation.
They were on their last legs.
Debts of at least
250,000 dollars.
What about Jarvis' personal fortune?
None of that, it was broken.
Even his house
was mortgaged.
It looks like the typical
of suicide.
Yes.
Just a moment, Frank.
Tell Ms. Vantay to come here.
Ms. Vantay!
Close the door, will you?
Ms. Vantay, you know
that Mr. Jarvis had insurance.
Well...
...yes, I think I did!
Do you think so or did you?
Wasn't she your personal secretary?
Yes.
- Yes, I had insurance.
- With which company?
With Standard Life.
- I see, for how much?
- I don't know.
Why does the company know
not how much?
He only handled correspondence
relating to the policy,
not the policy itself.
Oh. Would Mr. Wilson know?
I doubt it.
You don't have that much responsibility!
I see.
And as for Mr. Wilson,
...they said they fired him
on the morning of the murder?
No.
Nobody mentioned it.
Thank you very much.
Ms. Vantay,
can you give me the phone number?
The insurance company.
Yes, sir.
Now we're getting
somewhere.
I thought you were going to ask
love life!
Yes!
Oh, I'm Lieutenant Webb,
from the police department.
I want information about a policy
in the name of Malcolm Jarvis.
Thank you.
She also thought he would ask
about her love life.
I'll do it, but I want to give you time
to come up with the answers.
Yes?
Malcolm Jarvis, that's it.
How much?
When?
Yes!
That's exactly
what you wanted to know.
Thank you very much!
What's next?
We're going to the house
and Wilson will come with us.
For a walk!
Sergeant,
I'm trying to shed some light on this case.
That's funny.
It's like a
defective...
...where the image inside
is not like the one on the box.
What do you mean, boss?
- To begin with, it wasn't theft.
- You don't believe me...
That Jarvis prepared
death?
That he hired someone to settle it
and so your family would collect?
Possibly.
There was very recently
a case in Kansas...
...in which one man paid another
to kill him...
...because his business was going very badly.
- Oh yes!
Of course, it's still
murder,
...and even if he did commit suicide
who would help him prepare for it...
would be an accomplice to crime:
hiding evidence.
That's right!
Are you coming with me, Mr. Wilson?
Wait here, Sergeant.
Oh, excuse me a moment.
Look at him.
I want to make him a little
nervous.
I'm sure there's something on his mind,
but I don't know what it is.
Peter Rabbit?
He's worried about getting home
with Mrs. Rabbit.
No, it's more than that.
If you get even more nervous
I might let something out.
If you get any more nervous, you'll explode!
Don't take your eye off him.
Well, Mr. Wilson.
Come in, Lieutenant.
Hello, sir.
Mrs. Jarvis, I'm sorry to disturb you
at a time like this,
...but something new happened
this morning.
Sit down, Lieutenant.
Mrs. Jarvis, what about the insurance?
Life insurance.
Do you know how much your husband
was insured for?
For about 50,000 dollars.
50,000 dollars? Is that all?
Yes.
Yes, as far as I know!
- Why?
- Do you know when you took out the insurance?
A long time ago.
Several years, I think.
Mrs. Jarvis, her husband
was insured for 250,000 dollars.
250.000?
Yes, 200,000 three months ago.
Lieutenant,
...if you mean that my father
killed himself for the insurance,
...bark on the wrong tree.
It's the insurance company that barks, not me!
If he was murdered, they will have to pay.
But if it was suicide, no.
They would save a few
thousands.
Dad wouldn't kill himself!
No?
I don't believe it either.
Finally, we're going.
Oh, another thing, Mrs. Jarvis.
Has Mr. Hearne been here?
Mr. Hearne hasn't
house for six months.
Six months? I see.
Well, thank you.
Goodbye, Mrs. Jarvis.
And now we're going to see Mr. Hearne
again.
- Mr. Hearne?
- He'll have left the office.
I forgot to tell you that:
he left the office.
I had him taken to the police station.
Now bring in Mr. Hearne.
Have a seat.
The Dawson case is closed.
- How much did you get?
- Twenty years.
- Lieutenant, do you think it's necessary
here when you question Hearne?
I told him what I know about the case.
I just want you to be here,
Mr. Wilson.
On the subject of investigations...
...the point is to contrast.
Contrasting one statement
with another, that's what it's all about.
Yes, and when something doesn't fit,
...someone is lying.
Then it would seem that Mr. Wilson
is not telling the truth.
Is it possible to have a pen
that writes?
Yes, boss.
Here, use mine.
The sergeant says...
...that when we meet someone
who has lied,
...the next step is to find out
why he lies!
So we got very close
to our man.
I want to know what this means!
If I'm under arrest,
I want to call my lawyer!
Arrested? He's no more trapped than
Mr. Wilson here.
I just told Hogan
to ask him to come.
It's a very persistent invitation.
Now that you've come, sit down.
He said to Mr. Wilson.
...that when we catch
someone lying...
...and we found out why,
you get very close to the solution.
Why do you think I'm lying?
He said he wasn't at Jarvis' house
on the night of his death.
He said he had no reason to go,
I could see him in the office.
But you were there, Mr. Hearne.
He left his fingerprints on the door
among other places.
Yes, yes, I was there.
- What unites you with Mrs. Jarvis?
- Mrs. Jarvis?
I didn't ask you!
What you suggest is crazy.
He hated me like poison!
But if it wasn't for Mr. Jarvis,
well, as I said,
...I could see him in the office,
it would be for his wife!
Okay.
I was there that night.
Do you want to sign a declaration or
want to call your lawyer?
Statement?
I didn't kill him!
- I was alive when I left.
- Why were you there?
I made another effort to convince him
to sell.
Why didn't you tell me
that you were there?
I don't know,
...but under the circumstances,
what would you have said?
Maybe not.
Did you ever hear Hearne
threaten to kill Jarvis?
Threaten?
Of course not!
Don't answer without thinking.
Did you know they argued?
Yes, of course, but...
...for business!
Have you heard?
I think so.
When?
The last time, for example!
Well...
...it was last Saturday
morning.
I came in to ask for a raise.
- And they fired him!
- We'll talk about that later.
I want to know what you heard
between Hearne and Jarvis that morning!
I didn't hear anything.
Nothing at all!
Mr. Hearne was leaving
when I heard him say...
...that if Mr. Jarvis didn't want to
reasonably discuss, there was...
Well?
Go ahead, Sam.
He said.
...there were other ways.
- But I'm sure it's not...
- That's enough, Mr. Wilson.
I want to talk to
Mr. Hearne alone.
You can go now.
It's Dad!
Dad!
Hi, Dad!
I wanted to see you!
- So what?
- What happened in the office?
- Have they found the killer?
- I don't think so.
- It was certainly full of policemen!
-Yes.
Hello, darling.
Dinner's ready.
Have a seat.
Lt. Webb
was with us all day.
Lieutenant Webb?
What a guy!
Now that I remember, can you
get me your autograph?
Dick Tracy is the best cop!
- I have your photo and your autograph.
- Movie cops!
Webb is for real!
Have you discovered anything, Dad?
I don't know, I don't think so.
The police think there is a
element in the case.
- It could be a good murder.
- There is no such thing as a good murder, Roddy.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I didn't mean good,
just exciting.
In any case, the newspapers say
that Webb already knows who he is...
...and he's going to throw down the gauntlet
at any moment.
You're giving him rope to
to hang himself.
Roddy, will you shut up?
Lord, we give thanks for the
food that we are going to consume...
...and for the blessings you shower
on our lives.
Amen.
How about some good news
for a change?
Austin left. They gave me his
as Head of Accounts.
Head of Accounts?
Is he the boss?
Yes. Mr. Hearne
plans to continue with the company...
...if you reach an agreement with
Mrs. Jarvis. I think I'll stay.
I wish I had
a Chief Accountant!
You'll see when I tell my friends
that my father is the boss!
I'm proud of you!
- I think your mother does too.
- Yes, Sam, it's wonderful!
In any case,
it will make things easier.
Yes, it's true!
And you did it as if nothing
happened!
Dad, you're very lucky!
Yes, very lucky!
What's the matter, darling?
I'm tired, I guess.
A difficult day.
I have the report prepared
for Mrs. Jarvis.
You should take him.
I'll drive.
Okay.
I'll put on my cape.
Sam, you know how much I love you.
I love you more than anything in the world,
no matter what I do...
...or have done!
You know that, don't you?
Yes, I know.
Why don't you tell me?
- It's an ugly story, Georgia.
- You'd better tell me.
You're afraid they'll arrest Mr. Hearne
for murder, aren't you?
Yes. Maybe they already have.
All that's missing is one word from me
to absolve him.
When I do...
...they're going to arrest me.
No, Sam, not you!
No, dear. He killed himself!
But I knew
and I got rid of the gun.
He paid me 10,000 dollars...
...so that his suicide
look like murder.
I know, I met them this morning.
I didn't want to stay with them.
I know you were going to give them back.
Tell me everything,
just like it happened!
Well...
...Saturday morning,
when I went to ask for a raise...
Go on, darling.
I'll wait here.
Come in, Sam.
Good evening.
I was waiting for you.
I made the report.
Let's go to the library.
- Sit down, Sam.
- No, thank you.
Mrs. Jarvis,
this report may surprise you.
The company has been losing money
for a long time.
I thought it was in that envelope.
This is something else, it's different.
I'm not sure that
wanted to know that.
I'd love to know.
I have something to tell you.
Something that will be a huge blow
for you.
Her husband was not murdered.
I don't understand!
- You didn't murder him?
- No, they didn't.
- He killed himself.
- Killed himself?
That's right, he committed suicide.
Why are you telling me now?
You have the right to know
how much I loved them.
To the point of taking
life.
I planned to give them these
10,000 dollars.
They belong to them.
- Have you told anyone about this?
- Not yet.
I'm going to the police to turn myself in.
I know how hard it is to lose
insurance money,
...but it's the only thing
I can do.
Sam, you're a coward.
A miserable coward!
The police have nothing.
If he'd kept quiet.
I would have won 10,000 dollars.
I knew your business!
Do you think you needed a report
to know it was ruined?
- Did you know?
- Of course you did!
I knew what I was planning
and I was proud!
I wanted to help him.
We sent the staff
to the beach house...
...and I told him I'd come later.
Sidney went out on Saturday nights.
Malcolm would be alone.
- Everything was perfect.
- Did you let him kill himself?
Not exactly.
I said goodbye...
at ten past eight.
At that moment I was convinced,
I saw it in his eyes.
But I knew him well.
As he left, he doubted that
Malcolm was going to kill himself.
That night or any other.
And with that doubt in my head,
I couldn't leave. Don't you see?
Everything depended on Malcolm!
And Malcolm was weak!
I couldn't risk it,
I had to be sure.
I heard him talking to you on the phone...
...and waited to hear the shot,
...but there was no shot.
I'd lost my nerve
again.
I had to do what he
didn't have the courage to do.
I think I knew...
...when he saw me standing there,
I was going to kill him!
And I remembered to change
the cartridge...
...so that they would think
it was suicide.
It had been suicide,
in a way!
He needed someone
to pull the trigger!
You killed him!
Yes.
Yes, I killed him!
So...
...I can't let you go
to the police.
He thinks that, having killed Malcolm
for 250,000 dollars,
...Can I let you ruin everything?
No!
The police won't listen to your story!
You will hear mine and that will be it:
came to my house and confessed
that she killed my husband...
...and stole 10,000 dollars
from his safe,
...and killed him with the same gun
you shot him with!
She's mad!
I'm not crazy!
I'm just a coward like
you and Malcolm!
I've always had money,
rich friends, position!
I can't face the future
without it!
That's why the police will find you
dead, with the gun in your hands!
I'm going to shoot, Sam!
What's in your story?
A man doesn't commit suicide
by shooting himself in the back!
You'll have to manage!
Do you think the police will believe
that I shot myself twice?
He had a shot and he used it!
I'll take care of it, Mrs. Jarvis.
Take her to the car.
It took me a while to get in,
Mr. Wilson.
-She was a bad shot!
- Yes.
Oh, you got it!
- He's lucky, just a scratch.
- Thanks to you, Lieutenant.
- It's part of the job.
- Sam!
Sam! I heard gunshots,
are you okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- You'd better see a doctor!
- A doctor? Sam, are you hurt?
- It's nothing.
- Nothing? How do you know?
- Take off your jacket!
Let me see.
Mrs. Jarvis is on her way.
Oh!
And you let me lose
all the blood!
Why did you have to shoot him?
Don't tell me he was trying to escape!
I know my husband better than you do.
I was going to face the facts...
Will you let me talk?
The lieutenant didn't shoot me.
It was Mrs. Jarvis.
- She killed Mr. Jarvis.
- Mrs. Jarvis!
That's right!
We suspected her, but Hearne
wouldn't admit it!
I can't believe it!
I don't understand,
...but I have to take you to a doctor.
- You forgot the police.
Are you under arrest?
How did they know you were coming?
We've been following you
since Sunday
You didn't know that, did you?
I'm glad that Mr. Hearne
is also acquitted.
And as for Jarvis' insurance,
they'll pay because it wasn't suicide.
Mrs. Jarvis won't see anything, of course.
The law does not allow a criminal to
profit from a crime.
Everything will go to your child.
I'm happy about that.
He said that Mr. Hearne
is also acquitted.
- You mean Sam...
- Yes!
- Take him away, Mrs. Wilson.
- Aren't you going to arrest me?
Why?
If Jarvis had killed himself,
he would have been implicated.
But it wasn't like that.
So much so that he's innocent!
But I got involved...
You won't be accused of anything,
Mr. Wilson.
And I think it's been
bad enough.
Take care of this, Sergeant.
And don't get him into trouble.
Oh, Sam.
Darling, I've made a terrible mistake!
But it won't happen again!
Oh, yes! Many times.
Not like this, of course,
...but he's a man
and men make mistakes!
Even women!
Sometimes!
Translation of subtitles:
PARENTE - SERGIPE - BRAZIL - 3