Question:
"Does stripping reveal
just the ﬂesh?"
The answer is "No."
It reveals one's personality,
individuality, and past...
In other words,
stripping reveals the soul.
One game wonderfully reveals all
of this.
It's name is...
Strip Mahjong!
Now it's time for Strip Mahjong.
I am your host, Kato.
And here's our commentator...
...Ranran Tachibana.
Pleeaased to meet you!
This game's cash prize is...
...10 Million Dollars! Nyah!
Then let's bring out
our contestants!
Ow, quit it!
What is this?
It's so bright!
Where am I?
Ah studio?
Ah mahjong parlor?
Who are these people?
Contestant #1:
Leader of the pop idol group
"Afterschool Expedition,"
and using her youth as her weapon,
it's teen idol Yuka Kashiwagi!
Let's call herYukarin!
Contestant #2:
She's won countless acquittals
for her clients,
it's the young, top-class lawyer
Aoi Onizuka!
Ah girl in glasses?
Exciting!
With odds of 2.4,
many are betting on you!
Contestant #3:
Uptown girl from Shirokanedai,
Misuzu Kaneda!
I wish I could live in Shirokanedai!
Actually, Misuzu is my type of girl.
Odds: 7.3, she's the dark horse!
Last, Contestant #4:
A freeter who works late
at the convenience store,
if she wins it's goodbye
to that life! It's Mirai Kisaragi!
Use that money well!
What?
Got to remember!
What the hell happened?
I remember! It was him!
That guy abducted me.
This program is brought to you live
via an exclusive channel
through pay-per-view fees
from you, our viewers.
It's live! It's liiive!
We'll do anything
for our customers!
Now, let's explain the rules!
Welcome to the 'World
of Strip Mahjong!
We ask everyone to play nice
and follow these rules.
Basic rules are mostly the same
as a normal Hanchan game,
a single two-round game
using Ari-Ari rules.
We'll use our own system
for Han points.
Instead of point sticks, players pay the winner
with "Strip Cards" and strip accordingly
Everyone starts with 7 points,
7 articles of clothing
Yakuman = 6 points
Sanbaiman = 5 points
Batman = 4 points
Haneman = 3 points
Mangan = 2 points
Anything less = 1 point
Strip Mahjong---?
By the way, any player
who goes bust,
that is, loses all
her "Strip Cards,"
faces a severe punishment.
Punishment...?
Objection! This is a blatant
case of wrongful imprisonment!
Objection overruled.
But I've got recorded evidence...
Yes, we're recording right now...
Let me out! Let me out of here!
The only one getting out
...is the winner!
Ha! That's just a toy.
You think we're stupid'?
Ah toy? Yes, but it does send
an electric shock. Zap! Zap!
Understand now? Please don't do
anything reckless.
You sure you don't want to strip?
OK, we get it, so stop!
We'll do it.
- I am glad to have your understanding.
- Fuck that!
I'll report you!
We're not some exhibition!
Shut up, bitches!
You still don't get it?
You're all good for nothing,
except for getting naked!
"Why are you here?"
You've all racked up
$5 million in debts...
but has that stopped your
obsessions with online mahjong?
You're here because you're
worthless human beings!
What!? You can't do this!
Please shut the fuck up!
May I finish?
None of you can pay off
your debts yourselves.
We're giving you the chance to
pay them off in full.
Everyone, please.
Strip down to the soul,
then win and pay off your debts!
Let's get up. Can you stand?
Please excuse my earlier rudeness.
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
'Win and you can leave.
- Wait, I don't have any de--
Everyone! Please be seated.
Let the Strip Mahjong begin!
Round 1 Hand 1
The Dora Indicator
is the 4 Circles tile.
The East Wind seat
and first dealer is Aoi Onizuka,
the South Wind seat
is Mirai Kisaragi,
the West 'Wind seat
is Misuzu Kaneda,
and North Wind seat
is Yuka Kashiwagi.
Turns will proceed in that order.
Ah nice starting hand...
This woman's named... Misuzu?
She's discarding all Simples.
She's the type
who relies on intuition.
And this would be Yuka.
Seems sure of herself.
And Aoi Shanpai,
maybe Tenpai-type?
Your turn.
Oh, sorry.
Ranran, you can see each
player's style...
Yes, each is fairly unique
We can see people for who they
are through Mahjong
Mirai has a cautious approach.
She's aware of what goes on
around her. She seems somewhat good.
She must've been quite the
lazy bitch to hone such skills.
She discarded the tile she just
drew... What's she waiting on?
Hey, it's your turn.
Sorry.
Can you try not to space out?
Le--let's all calm down a bit.
You first.
Look at your hand.
Reach
Mirai has declared a "Reach."
Let's pick a Strip Card
for your wager!
Outerwear
She's chosen "Outerwear!
If Mirai wins this hand, the losers
must remove their outerwear.
However, if Mirai loses,
she'll have to remove her own!
What? I didn't hear that rule!
Yeah, I didn't mention it.
Reach
TOP
The game is now afoot!
Aoi's wagered her "Top" card
It's getting interesting!
Mirai has secured a Mangan with
the possibility for a Batman,
but Aoi's hot in pursuit.
She too may have a Mangan.
The tiles I need have already
been discarded. I'll have to fold...
You're not supposed to say that
out loud.
Ron!
Reach All Simples No-Points Hand
Three Color Straight Dora 1
Haneman
You don't have to glare
at me like that...
"Hey, stop it!
The stripping time you've all
been waiting for has come!
Aoi will pay up
with three Strip Cards.
Two will be the "Outerwear" and
"Top" already on the table.
Our winner, Mirai, will choose
the remaining third card.
- Me?
- Those are the rules.
OK... "Socks."
"Socks" it is! In this case,
gartered stockings!
Hey, you! Cut it out!
Don't mind her. It's the game.
This woman... is married?
Aoi, please share
how you feel right now.
Th-- this is illegal!
Yes, it probably is.
Ok, I hear you.
I'll strip, I'll do it!
My my, such nice calves,
what you might call...
a guilty pleasure!
Next, off with the top!
Well then...
Wait a second.
No, I can't wait...
Aah! Stop! Stop! No! Stop! Stop!
It may be embarrassing, but...
What's this?
Ah tattoo of a peony tree!
Why'd you get something like that,
Aoi-chan?
Don't look at me!
Strip Time is over...
The next hand will start
with Misuzu! Nyan!
You won't forget this,
you little bitch...
Round 1 Hand 2
Aww, it seems that Aoi bears
a grudge against Mirai...
What kind of person
is this woman?
Uh, um, can't we all get along?
We have to think of how we're all
going to get out of here...
You let us know when you've
figured that one out.
Come on, hurry up!
Huh?
Misuzu, what appears
to be the problem?
I... won...
Closed Tsumo lipeiko
lipeiko! lipeiko! lipeiko!
It's an lipeiko!
I, I didn't mean to...
It's time for the three of you
to take off one item!
Misuzu, please choose
a Strip Card.
I'm sorry...
Bottom
Bottom it is! Haha,
who should it be...
First... Yukarin!
No way!
Hands off!
It's out! Her ex-delinquent ways
she learned when in a gang!
Seriously, I will kill you!
Tough girl, huh?
I think she tries too hard!
You sure you won't strip?
Even if I punish you...
Here they are! The bare legs of a
one-time delinquent, now a teen idol!
And next...
I-'moi!
Such beautiful, shapely legs...
and this time, she stripped
without fuss.
And last...
Mirai !
Do it!
Stop...
Make it stop already!
Got 'em! We got 'em off!
Hmph, that's what you get
for resisting.
Wasn't that what you did last time?
Round 1 Hand 3
Round 1 Hand 3. So far, Aoi
Nyah, Nyah!
Has been hostile to Yuka and Mirai.
Nyah, nyah!
They continue to fight without
any womanly code of honor. Nyan!
Reach
Bra
Oops, sorry.
Ha, now I'll get my payback!
Not going for Three Colors, she's
set a trap with the 5 Circles tile.
She's going after Mimi...
Mimi, you must spot the trap!
Oops, how clumsy of me.
Ah play for the B Circles tile...?
This isn't right!
Misuzu is giving hints to Mirai.
She got the hint?
Why is everyone after me?
Hmm, End of Round 1 Hand 3
Draw
Tenpai
You were all in Tenpai?
So close!
This means Yukarin's Bra card
is up for grabs in the next hand.
That was a close one
which anyone could've won.
Next is Round 1 Hand 3, but with
1 Bonus in Play. Misuzu is still the dealer.
Round 1 Hand 3 With 1 Bonus
Yuka had her Strip Card taken away.
She'll want to win this hand, even
with a cheap hand, to get it back...
Reach
Outerwear
Yukarin is in a rush, isn't she?
Here it comes...
She's also in Tenpai...
but I can still get her.
It's a trap, Misuzu. Be careful.
I'm no good.
I can't do anything now!
Tsumo!
Reach Closed Tsumo
Three Color Straight
Mangan
Congratulations! I return to you
your confiscated card.
Yes!
"Outerwear" is on the table, so
please choose one more card...
Ah, but Aoi is not wearing outerwear,
so choose two extra cards for her.
- Why for only me!?
- Shhhh!
Go ahead, Yukarin.
This one's for Mirai
(Socks)
and this is for Misuzu,
(TOP)
What's wrong, Misuzu?
Now, the cards for Aoi...
This... and this one!
(Bra) (Glasses)
Hoho! Scandalous! Yukarin had
no problems choosing for Aoi!
The cards for Aoi are "Bra" and "Glasses!"
Hey you! Knock it off!
Knock what off?
Let the Stripping Time begin!
Mirai, your outerwear
and socks, please.
No, now's not the time...
I have to focus on winning now.
The scent of fragrant olive...
Moving on, Misuzu, please.
It's OK... It can't be helped.
What's wrong, Misuzu?
You're acting strangely.
Wha--, what's this?
An S&M bustier!?
Amazing, but...
...unexpected! Not something
I'd expect a refined lady to wear...
Is this to please
your husband's tastes?
Things have suddenly gotten
more interesting!
Next, let's have Aoi remove
her bra and glasses!
The moment you've all been
waiting for! Mac Kato's...
Don't you mean "MC Kato's?"
...Lingerie Time!
This is when I use various items
to remove the clothing.
Aah! Stop it!
No, stop!
What are you doing?
Just, just quit it!
I'll catch you,
tuna fish!
Hey!
Got a bite!
Stop it! Stop it!
Hey! Knock it off, will you?
Stop it!
- No!
- Got 'em!
Caught myself one bra!
Regarding gifts to our viewers...
We offer the lewd she-lawyer's
glasses and...
her freshly-removed
and still warm brassiere!
We will then ship the prize
to the winner! Nyan!
Round 1 Hand 4
It's the 8th go around. The Dora Indicator
is the 2 Characters tile. The dealer is Aoi.
Since she lost her glasses,
Aoi's struggled to see the tiles.
Don't give up the will to win!
Go ahead, make fun of me...
I'm not.
I never thought something
like this would happen...
Listen, you have to focus now.
Ha, got it...
Secured myself 4 Dora!
Kan!
Well, hello!
Looks like she's out for blood.
Could it be...?
The same tile others
have discarded...
Pon!
Careful now;
if you step in now...
One short of Tenpai. Low chance on
a quad for the 8 Characters fife.
I've a concealed triplet on the 7
Characters tile. What should I do...
This will get he; but it may be dangerous for Misuzu.
She seems close to Mangan.
Huh!
Misuzu?
She can't see the table...
She's completely lost if.
South Wind is also a safe discard...
Wait! If she's got a double-sided wait...
She's given up Circles and Characters...
Her waits are concentrated on Bamboos...
But that's the same for Misuzu...
If my waits are good, I can discard
my draws until I get what I need...
I can then keep myself in Tenpai
with a double-side wait sequence.
She's giving this a Jot of thought.
Discarding Bamboos is dangerous, Misuzu.
Ron!
All Simples No-Points Hand
Three Closed Triplets Dora 7
Wow, "Sanbaiman!" Misuzu will
have to strip 5 items!
Three Closed Triplets with
a Closed Tsumo and a Dora of 7!
That's checkmate for you,
Misuzu. Boo hoo!
This is my fate...
I racked up so much debt
losing Mahjong,
I never had a chance winning here...
Wait! What's gonna happen
to her now?
OK, OK, I got it.
Just wait a second!
'Win, OK'? You have to live life
to its fullest.
You only get one life. Make
it count. Don't become like me.
But Misuzu, I...
It's OK, I know you can do it.
Let's go!
We're giving you a big punishment!
- Stop, stop...
- Wait!
You think it's fun to make
people suffer like this?
No, I think it's sad.
But these are the rules...
Misuzu!
So why are you wearing
a leather bustier?
I just have to strip off
5 items, right?
I asked you a question, why
are you wearing that bustier?
Stop, you don't have to
take everything off.
Huh?
Showing just your skin
means nothing...
I'm hereto see everything
laid bare, body and soul
My soul...?
Yes! Open your heart!
Out with it! Why the bustier!
It started a year ago, when I...
I found out my husband
was cheating on me...
Good!
Our relationship went cold...
I sought escape and passion...
You're a cheap whore!
Then, the partner I met
taught me S&M...
So that's how you got into it.
I just wanted my husband to love me...
more...
...to beloved more!
But, it wasn't going to happen.
That's it.
That's what I wanted to hear.
But I loved him...
I loved my husband!
Thank you for baring all to me.
I'll take these panties
off for you.
Aah! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop! No! Stop!
I can leave now, right?
Only the winner
of the game gets out.
Farewell, my love.
Instant death? That's
the Maximum Setting for you...
He's lying...
She can't be dead, right?
What's happened to Misuzu?
I'm sorry, but...
Wait! If we go bust, do we also...?
Yes.
What the fuck!
Hey, those are the rules.
Now, shall we continue?
Just a second.
And what is the matter, Mirai?
Give me her wedding ring
in exchange for this
Are you serious!?
You know you're just tightening
your own noose doing this?
I, I wasn't able to save Misuzu,
but if I get out of here alive,
I want to give her ring to her husband
I'm touched...
No problem, so long as you
exchange a Strip Card for the ring.
'Win, OK'? You have to live life
to its fullest.
You can do it
Now we've put that drama behind us,
let's get back into the game.
Let's introduce our
substitute player!
In our last match, she gave us
a wonderful fight to the death.
Behind the cute looks is a brain
trained for Mahjong since childhood.
Alias "Killer Mahjong Queen,"
it's Ranran Tachibana
Pleased to join the game! Nyan!
Ranran will start with 5 points,
what Misuzu had before going bust.
Round 2 Hand 1
I'm going to win!
Hey, Yukarin, guess what?
I'm going after you!
Huh?
It's cause you've
got the most clothes on...
When sleeping around for
recording contracts,
-these come right off, huh?
- I don't do that
Who is... this woman
I've no intention losing to you
Let's have a one-on-one side bet
for one extra article of clothing.
You're on!
You shouldn't provoke her.
Ah storm's been brewing since
Ranran entered the game!
PO", nyah!
How is she making the calls
and discards so fast? It's unreal!
It's no good,
loan'! read her at all...
Ron. Big Three Dragons, nyah
She's strong ...too strong
Nyan nyan
Wow! Ah yakuman from out of nowhere!
It's quick death for you, Yukarin!
Huh? Huhuhuhuh?
What's the matter, Yukarin?
No, I don't want to die!
Tough Yukarin is now groveling...
I am a sucker for women's tears...
-but it's Punishment 1'lme!
- Nyah
Well then...
Ooh, teenage years... nice
Stop... No! Stop!
What a wonderful scent...
- Let me to take it off... slowly!
- No no no no no...
You can't, you can't, you can't!
Isn't that a... swimsuit for school!?
Hold on a second!
I'll return to Yukarin what she
wagered on our side-bet.
Underwear
Now even Ranran's pulling
this sort of shit...?
Since she's an idol,
it should be a bikini...
- Butsurely, replacing a one-piece
with a two-piece item isn't fair...
Won't it be boring
to kill her off now though?
Alright! We take back
Yukarin as going bust!
Stop...
It's now two items. You're keeping
only the panties though.
- It's Mac Kato's--
- Don't you mean MC Kato's...
Lingerie Time!
What are you doing!? Cut it out!
Wow, it's turning
into a giant titty!
I'm scared! I'm scared! I'm scared!
Isn't this great, Yukarin?
You've been spared.
Round 2 Hand 2
Were you OK in there?
You're OK, right?
Nyan Nyan Nyan Nyan Nyan
She's got such composure! But I
can't let her put me on the ropes.
Got it! Others are discarding bamboos.
I should quietly wait it out...
Last go around, but I'll beat her.
...This tile's probably safe
to discard, nyah...
Ron, Haneman!
Half-Flush Dora 2
Bullseye! Ah Haneman
from out of nowhere!
Ranran, that'll cost you 3 items!
At last, I can cool down a bit,.
Nyan!
Other Bra Top
An interesting choice.
I'll be wearing just an apron?
Roger that!
Music, please!
She's not upset at all.
On the contrary, she enjoys iL..
Ah magnificent "nude apron" look!
I do it all for our viewers!
Round 2 Hand 3
Hey everyone, Let's try
and enjoy the game a bit more!
Are you fucked in the head? We
over here have our lives at stake.
It's the same for Ranran, too.
Boo hoo!
This is a battle of wits... Can 't
let her crazy talk trip me up.
Reach
Outerwear
Amazing, Ranran. That's our
mahjong fanatic in a maid outfit!
It's OK, stay cool...
Ah!
Sorryy...
Wait! That's a Chonbo penalty!
It wasn't on purpose. Forgive me...
We can't!
Yes, we can! I owe this woman
my life.
You can't take this
woman's side.
Ron!
Reach and a Straight, nyan!
How? My discard let her win?
Ranran won on a Hell Wait. Mirai,
that'll cost you one item!
I won this hand forjust one card.
So, Ranran, can you choose a card?
Nyan Nyan Nyan Nyan Nyan, bra!
Bra it is! Then let's begin...
the Stripping Time!
You're bad, too, you know.
What?
- You got into this helping a friend
with her mahjong gambling debts.
My friend begged me
and before I knew it...
You shouldn't so easily agree to
be someone's guarantor like that...
So how does it feel to get naked?
That concludes Lingerie Time!
Round 2 Hand 4
If she wins now those two
will end up like Misuzu...
I must beat her!
Tsumo!
Amazing! You won on a Hell Wait
for the North Wind tile again!?
Let's first choose the Strip
Card for Mirai.
Nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan
Other!
Other it is! That'd be...
Uh... the Cat Garter.
You can take that off later,
whatever.
More importantly, I'm sorry,
but Yukarin and Aoi...
You've gone bust!
Please, save me! Please!
Please!
Sorry, I play to win.
Wait, somethings not right...
With that hand, she should have
gotten sanmenchan...
Why win on a Single Pair Wait
for the North Wind tile?
And now, what you have all been
waiting for... Punishment Time!
I'm Yukarin.
And I'm Aoi. We're good friends.
I like you
I like you, too.
Ah...Ah...Ah...
What's this? My body feels hot
...with passion!
Come on! Do it like the dolls...
If you're going to kill us,
just kill us already!
You want to be spared, don't you?
I'll let you go if you dyke it out.
Ha, that's a lie!
I don't get to see that
sort of thing too often...
What are you doing!?
It might save our lives!
Knock it off!
Actually, I am a lesbian.
That's nothing I know about.
Really? I'm a lesbian? But why?
I've come to hate men.
nasty, perverted men
So you were sleeping around
for your career...
No, I was forced into doing that!
And why did I get a tattoo?
My boyfriend told me to...
He was a convicted yakuza member.
That's dangerous... getting
involved with the mob like that.
I wanted anyone who could made me
forget the pressures of my career...
He sought me out like a wild beast.
That's why I did it.
That's what I wanted to hear!
Baring both body and soul!
Everyone's really getting
into it, huh
Think! How'd she win like that?
Something's definitely strange...
Wait a minute, you cheated!
I did no such thing!
Stop lying!
People's lives are at stake!
You marked the Honor Tiles.
That's how you got the Big Three Dragons
and the Hell Wait on the North Wind tile.
I've been exposed, have I?
This match is invalid!
Quickly, let those two go!
I'm sorry, but I can't do that.
Why?
The match is already decided.
Even cheating must be forgiven if
it's discovered after the fact.
But that's...
That's the rules.
Let those two go!
Now why'd you go and do that,
Black Mask #13?
I was thinking of letting them go...
This isn't right, messing up like this!
We had another girl like you
before. Her name was Atsuko.
Atsuko...'?
She tried to expose my cheating.
That girl was a real pain...
sol killed her
Atsuko... I was her guarantor.
Always was a blunderer, a bit slam
and careless...
Mirai is declared the winner!
Congratulations.
Here's your $10,000,000 prize.
By the way, what will you use
the money for?
- For a match!
- H uh?
I am wagering it all to
challenge her to a death match.
Ho ho! Ah challenge from Mirai!
Yes, I accept her challenge!
I wager my outerwear. Nyan!
What beautiful breasts!
That wager is not a problem!
Let the final deathmatch begin!
This will be a one-on-one match using
only Bamboos, 1s, 9s, and Honors.
I, Mac Kato, will serve
as commentator:
Mirai, please tell us what you're
feeling now.
Don't bother me!
Ha! She's got some spirit!
Final Match
The die have been cast!
Last match for the panties begins.
Who will be the one to bare it all,
body and soul?
Good! My lucky Honor tiles are here...
But she's onto my marking
the tiles. I have to be careful.
Ah lot of bamboos here.
But why?
That bothers me.
Pon
She's quickly discarding Simples.
May be going for AH Honors, Little
Four Winds, or Thirteen Orphans...
In any case, I have to be first
out with a complete hand.
OK, I'll soon get these useless
tiles out of the way...
Pon
Ive got the West tile!
In Tenpai for Thirteen Orphans.
Just need the Red Dragon.
I'll discard this 2 Bamboos tile.
Pon
Whoa! That's the third time
Mirai's called "Pon!"
What should I do?
If I discard this, I can get
Tenpai for AH Greens.
No, I risk it all for this instead.
What was she puzzling over?
Ah, she knows since I'm cheating,
I'm aiming for Thirteen Orphans,
and so couldn't discard
a Green Dragon...
Maybe she's got...
No, I'll draw the Red Dragon
before a Green Dragon comes up...
This game is already decided.
Too bad for you.
HI win with Thirteen Orphans
before I discard a Green Dragon
You missed your chance, and now
you'll lose. Nyah!
Ron!
All Triplets only
Wonderful! Mirai narrowly won with a wait on the 1
Characters tile for an amazing All Triplets hand!
C Cup versus D Cup...
The winner is C cup!
How!?
How'd you win on a pair wait
for the 1 Characters tile'?
Thanks to you.
There's a scratch on the tile...
Eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth.
I did the same thing you did.
But, when!? When did you put
a scratch on the tile?
Mirai, please tell us what you're
feeling now.
Don't bother me!
You were too focused on my tits,
weren't you?
I had no idea you could tell
I have a breast fetish...
It was obvious.
You cheated! That's not allowed!
It is allowed! If it's uncovered
after the fact, right?
Those are the rules...
Atsuko... was always a blunderer,
a bit slow, and careless...
But she was my best friend!
Fucking bitch! That's a cheap
trick. It doesn't count!
Let's play one more time! One more time!
Freeze!
I've no need for sore losers.
It's Mac Kato's Lingerie Time!
Will the pencil snap first?
Or the panties rip first?...
Sorry!
Turn turn tum turn...
Hard a-port! Hard a-port!
Turn the helm! Turn the helm!
Turn left, turn left, turn left!
Ah! That's supposed to be "right!"
Turn turn tum turn...
Hard a-port! Hard a-port!
The penis mightier!
Mightier than the panties too!
It's over...
Our new champion is born!
Under provisional rules, we've
doubled your prize to $20 million.
Now, I'd like to proceed with
an interview with our heroine.
Congratulations, that was
cheating worthy a Mahjong Queen!
Give it back...
Everything you took from me...
Give it back!
What are you talking about?
By getting naked and baring all,
you've been reborn as a new you...
Yes, but you can't bring back
those people who died!
If you bear any grudge, hold it towards your
past self who wasted her life on petty things.
Saying goodbye to that past...
That's what Strip Mahjong is
all about!
What did you think of this
installment?
The next contestant might be you...
...on Strip Mahjong!
Until next week!
Thanks for the mammaries!
That's a wrap, Kato!
Good work, but your way of
talking is a bit shady...
Hurry up and let me out of here!
The exit is that way.
Strip Mahjong
Battle Royale