Well, well!
Come out!
Come out, we've been caught.
Do you not know that according to police regulation 17391 you're not allowed to sleep in public in vienna?
The Grand Hotel wouldn't take us im afraid.
Identification papers.
Here you go.
My diplomatic passport.
This is a military draft notice! I'll take you with me to the barracks.
Then we'll have to pass through Prater.
Piece of cake.
Let's go.
Ah, New Program Mr. Ebeseder!
Is she pretty?
Come on now, let's go, let's go
Good Morning Mr. Ebeseder.
Don't you have to enlist?
Mind your own business Mr. (unintelligible). The rehearsal started a while ago. If i was you i wouldn't have come at all
What would you do in my place? I have a sense of obligation.
If you could play the piano as good as you are cheeky,
you'd be the (name unintelligible)
Look, dont hurt yourself.
In the military you're going to be this small again.
So who was the new notes?
My sister Mizzi, now move along.
Good morning Mr.
So where are the new notes, Miss Mizzi?
Yes, I'm getting them Mr. Karl.
Thank you, little one.
You're Welcome.
The most important thing for me is the drum roll Mr. Conductor.
Yeah yeah i know already. (name)
So, and you Ms Mizzi?
What?
What about you?
Nothing.
What, you still haven't decided?
Decided.
I'll be decided alright.
If it was up to me..
But you already know.
Come on! Don't always tempt me like this.
But it's a pity.
A big pity.
God. You with your talent.
You must be very successful.
Yeah?
You think so?
Oh now you're starting again.
So, what do you say Mr. Pianist?
Such a sweet, pretty Girl. Not just because she's my sister.
She could have a baron on each finger,
but no, she's hanging on to a guy who is a nobody and has nothing.
Oh stop it already about Josef.
He's just not like that.
He's a thoroughly decent person.
You understand?
Josef.. yeah.
So only the architectural draftsmen are decent people..
Us artists are not.
There he goes again.
This is how it is,
He loves me and i love him and we're getting married.
So?
So!
And you can say whatever you want, it wont change anything!
You can turn yourself upside down, but it wont change anything either!
Let's go, my solo!
Because of an architectural draftsman i'll turn myself upside down.. I'll turn him upside down!
I could choke him!
I am a real viennese
from sunny Namur
full of humanity, i am
That's my nature
Yes?
Hard at work!
My god, Father!
Did something happen to mother?
What..
Nothing's wrong. I came because i wanna be there when you're accepted!
Sit down, father.
Yes.
My god!
When i think back to the time..
when i was called into draft.
And how the - whatchamacallit - called out, 'fit for service!'
That was a transcending moment.
How's mother?
Thank you. Good. And she says hello.
Thank you.
She's scared, that poor one.
That they're taking you to the military.
Theres people like that too.
She just doesn't know anything about life.
I was offered permanent employment for these construction plans yesterday.
Yeah? Congratulations.
Congratulations.
Very nice.
Very-
I don't understand any of it but..
very nice.
Mr. Father.
I do want to go to the military,
but-
Mizzi!
Oh oh.
She's a sweetie
Right?
A sweetie!
I'll go get her dad, okay?
Yes! Why not.
Mizzi!
Josef!
I've been waiting for you all day.
Yeah?
Yes
Come, i have something to tell you.
What is it?
My dad is here.
Oh dear.
I'm scared.
But he likes you.
Yeah because he doesn't know me.
But he just saw you at the window!
He has very good eyes.
Mizzi.
Today i'll tell him, that we both..
If he says yes i'll give him a huge kiss.
Really! I'll kiss him.
He'd like that.
But Josef.
Yes?
But..
Theres one more thing i want.
Yes?
Well..
The benefit..
I really want to perform there.
Oh please.
Just once.
Look, one time is no time. (Once wont hurt)
One time is a hundred times.
Mizzi we've discussed this.
Are you with them or are you with me?
with you.
Only with you.
Come. Let's go see my dad.
Yes.
Hello, Miss. I'm the father.
Well!
You don't have to be scared of me.
I'm just the father!
I..
I'm not scared.
I'm so happy to meet you.
The pleasure is all mine. 2x
I didn't think you were such go-getter.
Go-getter, dad?
I like her.
Well why are you telling me!
Why is he telling me? he should be telling you!
Am i right?
He tells me too.
Yeah? Look at that!
I always thought he's like.. he's.. he's like our mother.
Always working, always serious,
A young person needs to have a life! Do some partying!
A little umph!
You should've seen me when i was his age.
Oh my.
Oh look, how he's getting red.
Shy head over heels!
My little 'pepe' , when you have to leave to the military,
a small love affair like this is no sin.
What sin are you talking about father?
We want to get married.
Oh.
Well
Well..
First you have to focus on serving your three years.
The reason i came was because you're supposed to get assessed today.
I wasn't prepared for an engagement.
So there we have it.
He doesn't like me.
"He doesn't like me" on the contrary.
I like you very much, but..
it's about his mother.
Oh his mom?
Not to be henpecked.. but at the end of the day, she is the boss.
I was planning on writing her anyway,
to ask her to let Mizzi live in the house while i'm in the military.
What?
But theres still plenty of time..
until i know if they'll take me or not.
Hello, Hello gentlemen.
Hello, Franz.
What do you want now?
Oh please. Don't get so upset again.
You know it's bad for your beauty.
You have a new brooch, Sophie.
This one?
I've had this one for a while.
I dont know that brooch..
where did you get it?
Hello Ms. Director.
I'm picking up Franz, we're going to the barracks.
Let's go Franz.
That brooch..
is worth at least 12 Gulden.
Oh come on.
He's always so economical. Always calculating, always calculating.
But he got that from you Ms. Ebeseder, right?
You're the same way.
Wheres Mizzi?
A seam popped on her dress.
Where (else) would she be?
It's a misfortune, that love.
Mizzi is a true folksinger child.
This wont end well.
But it's her first love..
I think it's cute.
Come on Franz-y we have to go now. The generals must be waiting on us.
See you Ms. Director, we'll be back soon.
How did you get 12 Gulden?
Oh stop it already. Come.
Well, well.
I'll go now.
I'll wait for you..
I'll wait for you.. in the barracks.
At Rennweg (Street)
Rennweg, of course Rennweg.
What yard?
Yes, check which one you're in.
Probably the third.
Third yard.
I knew that.
940, yes.
See you.
What was that you said earlier? You want to send me to your mom?
Yes.
Why?
I won't leave you with your people.
They wont influence me.
But you know what they want to turn you into.
You have to understand.
They think as a folk singer i am somebody.
You're here for me,
and not for the guys your brother hangs around with.
If i come home with a folksinger for a wife..
People in the countryside won't understand.
If i have to join the military now..
Three years.
What then?
Then?
What do you think is gonna happen then?
You'll forget me.
Oh please.
Betray me.
Josef!
Look.
I won't forget you.
And i won't betray you.
And i love you.
661, 662, 663, 64, 65.
One ostrich feather please, they took him.
650!
My number mom!
651!
692, 693, 694, 695
696, 697, 698, 699
700!
Hey Miss!
What regiment are you with, hm?
You wan't something?
Come on, it was just a joke.
881 to 86.
Move it!
Don't get riled up Mr. Uncle.
Do i look like an uncle?
I'm Sorry.
Quiet. Get inside.
Bravo, Bravo.
Gotta be strict, gotta be strict.
We also had to ---
Why are you here? Are you a recruit too?
That'd be nice..
but where did the time go.
I'm here with my son, my boy.
Today.. He's joining today.
Yes.
Today you'll take him. Absolutely.
I myself served 12 years.
Yeah?
Active 12 years,
twenty six-er ---
Cigar?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
887 to 890.
Hello Ms.
Hello.
Your boy is going in too?
Yes. Yes.
Hopefully they take him.
They'll accept mine for sure.
A handsome boy. Two heads bigger than me!
Two heads!
And when you hear him speak..
you wouldn't even believe that he's my..
my son.
(unintelligible) The skin is so stubborn.
He grew up in Berlin.
17 Years, he was there (with his aunt?)
As child, she invited us once, so we drove there with my wife.
And she didn't let him leave. She made him study, and..
that's why he lost our dialect completely.
Completely.
But it's okay.
We'll teach him again, we'll.. we'll teach him again.
Look at that girl over there.
My word!
The pretty ones are always taken huh?
Sadly.
Your brother's coming.
Hello!
Here we are.
Always making himself important.
Like a rooster on a pile of dirt.
Oh please,
You and your problems with artists.
I really don't get it.
Artist.
Oh look the brother-in-law! Let's not even look at them.
Respect Mr. Oberleutnant.
Gentlemen.
Sophie!
Mr. Oberleutnant.
Thank you, thank you, thank you. Can i introduce you, Baron von Daffinger - these are the famous ---
Franz Ebeseder!
Yeah. So, you're scared already huh!
Scared! What should i be scared of! the military is my life!
Mr. Oberleiter. I brought you a program.
Our program for today, here you go.
You'll have a great time. Wonderful, Mr.
Maybe bring (the mayor?) along too.
Oh my, It's Mizzi!
I didn't even notice her!
Mr. Oberleiter we're singing a couplet.
'My old lady won't find out'
749, 750
So who's that girl?
That's my sister.
Is she also being drafted?
He's always joking!
That was a good one.
Who did she come here with?
Yeah if you dont mind, who's she with?
Well she's actually not here with anybody, that's just a friend.
Not even a friend it's just a distant relative.
Not even. More like barely a relative, really, nothing more.
Oh come on.
But pretty!
Very pretty!
But he's not pretty.
I was talking about her!
Oh her.
Very pretty, that one.
Yeah well she's my sister isn't she.
Is she performing too?
We're not sure yet.
If she'll be there we're going to have to come to the show for sure.
Mr. Oberleutnant, bring the whole reigment along. Would you do that?
We'll have seats ready for you.
You'll have a great-
You'll really have a great time. You'll see.
36, 37, 38, 39, 940.
940.
That's you. And..
Don't forget..
I'll always love you.
Bye.
So?
Mizzi.
I wanna introduce you to the Leutnant.
Why?
Don't even say anything.
He just told me he really likes you.
Yeah?
Are you scared of Josef again?
Nothing worse than a jealous man.
That's just how he is.
But that Leitner.. He's a fine guy.
Noble, rich, a baron.
He's everything.
And not to mention, he's Josef's superior.
Oh? Josef's?
Yes! That's why i'm telling you, he's the right one.
He already moved out.
But they didn't let him in.
If we have luck. Toi Toi.
I'm keeping my fingers crossed.
Yes?
Gentlemen.
This is my friend Mizzie.
Ladies.
Leutnant von Daffinger.
Ebeseder Mizzi
That name obliges.
Your brother told us that you're performing, dear Miss.
Me?
That's not true.
But!
But what are you saying!
She's just shy.
Come on.
Can we be there when you celebrate your debut?
No.
Why?
Yes.
She's just kidding.
You're stupid.
Unfit for the final time, because of Malnutrition.
So what is it? Are you fit for duty?
What were you laughing about with them?
Forget about them. Are you fit?
So! What is it? fit?
Dad, warm greetings to mom.
I'm fit.
You're fit..
Wonderful. Come here.
I knew it. I knew it all along.
Wait here, i have an ostrich feather for you.
So this is how it's going to be when im not here.
How. how. how does it look?
I saw the way he was looking at you, the officer.
How's that my fault! I cant prevent people from looking at me.
Don't be so childish.
Remember what i told you earlier?
You already forgot, huh?
Mizzi for my sake, please..
Go stay with my mom.
Stay at our place.
Come here.
I'm gonna buy one for me too.
Mizzi.
Go to my mom.
Well..
Fine.
I'll go.
Now i'm calm Mizzi.
Now i'll gladly become a soldier.
Hello Kids.
Come here with me.
I expect you all to have memorized the song by wednesday.
Go on now.
Go eat your lunch.
My spoon fell..
My spoon fell in.
How about that.
Well when we're done eating we'll find it.
Oh it has (milk?) i don't like that. No. I don't want that.
I don't like it with milk.
Why dont you make a.. a potato soup?
Hello.
Mother.
This is Mizzi.
Yes?
Sit down.
Give it to her.
Thank you.
Well..
Eat.
Go ahead.
All aboard!
Hey you.
I'm so..
Since today i have you..
I can't say it.
Get out.
Josef said to say hello, mother.
Wow.
My performance clothes.
My mom packed it for me.
Did you know i was supposed to perform once?
With the folksingers i mean.
Now ladies and gentlemen, our main attraction.
It's gotten fuller again. I'm happy that more of you came.
I'm happy that you all came.
Some of you have brought your wives, and others have brought something better.
Ladies and gentlemen, what does a real viennese need?
Money!
Yes money, we all need money.
But if he doesn't have it, what does he need to have more than ever?
Ladies and gentlemen, Humor!
That's why i dont have to say anything more to introduce..
Sophie Weidling and Franz Ebeseder. Viennas favorites.
Music!
Oh that's my job.
Theres no girl in love that doesn't envy me.
You've spoken to and broken the hearts of already almost a hundred.
But i belong to you, and i swear to you, that you are my world.
Because you are so -- today, as real viennese.
Oh Sophie, Oh Sophie, what are you doing to me.
I am just a man, who can't control himself.
Oh Sophie, Oh Sophie, prepare your mouth for a kiss.
You are like a passionate, a very passionate
You get involved with me
I have all i need.
Oh Sophie, Oh Sophie, what are you doing to me!
I am just a man, who can't control himself.
Oh Sophie, Oh Sophie, tell me how and when,
Sophie!
I am but only a man.
Too bad Mizzi is not here.
Oh please.
Oh, Mr. Baron.
It doesn't matter, she knows what's going on.
I'm sure she'll like you too.
You think so?
I could swear on it!
Yes..
When is she supposed to come back?
When is she supposed to come back, well..
Franz!
My utmost..
Respect, Mr. Oberleutnant.
Compliments, Mr. Baron.
Franz, how much longer is Mizzi supposed to wait outside?
3 Years.
3 Years?
Yes.
But we could get her back of course.
If you could do that..
We can, we can.
Well then let's do it.
You see, she wants to rejoice the baron by doing it, right?
Yes of course if i can gratify the baron, of course i could..
Of course i could. But you see if i leave here,
every day would cost me..
Atleast..
If not more.
Yes, colossal.
A piece of gold, because around here i'm colossally..
liked.
I am the.. And i..
What's..
She's coming.
I'm her brother after all.
A love song..
In the country, where flowers bloom
They sing longingly and with all their heart
The blackbirds from Lichtental
Did you hear them?
The kids are already singing along.
Mizzi.
Yes?
You.. You're here with upstanding farmers.
Not with a bunch of comedians.
but..
Go home.
The air is good here.
The food is good.
The people here are especially good, one could congratulate them.
Oh be quiet.
Josef wanted this.
Oh Josef?
Well..
He's more important to you than your art.
When a female artist has big success in vienna..
She'll have her own carriage within no time.
Everybody knows her and greets her.
Everyday theres something about her in the paper, she receives flowers.
Gentlemen kiss her hand.
But of course the air in Krems..
is a lot better.
Right?
So?
I'll drive with you.
I need to talk to Josef.
So, what up?
Was Josef reasonable?
I couldn't even ask the superiors to talk to Josef.
Well..
You know what?
You'll just write Josef tomorrow after you've performed. He wont be able to do anything then.
But he wont like that.
Oh so what, come on now.
Salute, continue.
Infantry Kernthaler!
Here!
Come clean Mr. Feldwebel's shoes with your brush.
Aye-Aye Sir.
Hand me that program.
..the performance of the nightingale from vienna, Mizzi Ebeseder
The Ebeseders are supposed to have a good program.
Look at that.
You can't even clean shoes.
And you claim to be an educated person?
Let's go.
Continue.
Let's go, go, go. Begin. Mariska is todays opening performance.
Miss Mariska, are you ready?
Don't annoy me. I'm always ready.
Go, Go.
Good Evening. Can he come in?
Of course! Walk right on in Mr. Baron.
I'm afraid you'll have to excuse me, i'm on duty.
Aw that's too bad.
Bye.
See you.
Can i go say hello?
Of course Mr. Baron.
Excuse me.
Oh please. Go on, go on.
This way Mr. Baron.
Mizzi, the Baron is here.
I dont know any Baron.
Come in.
Oh, it's you Mr. Leutant.
Goodbye! oh.
I just wanted to wish you luck!
Why?
For tonight.
Oh.
What do you mean, luck! Dear God.
My God. You're supposed to say break a leg.
Oh right.
You want anything?
You have to excuse me, i'm extremely nervous.
Oh please.
Why don't you sit- Sit down.
Yes, well.. Break a leg.
Oh please.
Thank you.
Miss Mizzi. I've been thinking about you a lot.
About me?
Don't you have anything else to worry about?
My bad, of course you don't have anything else to think about.
Tell me, Miss Mizzi,
Couldn't you like me just a little bit.
Of course! Why not.
Because i was thinking, if the both of us, you and me..
A profession of love?
Yes.
Well.. Break a leg.
Oh, pardon. I have to get changed.
Excuse me. I'm leaving already.
See you. And please don't be mad at me for acting this way.
I hope you'll enjoy the performance.
Come here, ladies and gentlemen!
You'll be amazed! You've never seen anything like this before!
Another bouquet for Mizzie from the Leutnant.
He's so rich.
But it's for nothing.
She's engaged!
They're raving!
A very fine and intelligent audience today.
Can you hear the thunder?
Come on let's go.
Shows over.
What a bunch of vermin.
Go on out! Let's keep going.
Sigh.
Hold this.
It can only go downhill after our performance,
watch how they'll tank.
Where's Mizzi?
You forgot to say Good Evening.
I want to know where Mizzi is.
She's staying here for now,
she still belongs here for now.
But i don't want to be with a folk singer who gets passed around.
What! Who get's passed around?
--- It's Mizzi i want to marry.
And she's supposed to stay good. She'll go rotten on me.
She's earning her money respectfully with a good family.
No one's rotten.
Well..
Now i look just like you.
Pretty, isn't she?
Well.. All she wants is a thank you
Adieu.
What's so bad about singing a few songs,
please let me.
Let me?
You know i love you.
Mizzi, i can't love you like this. Like..
Oh forget him. He doesn't understand, because he's not viennese.
What did you expect from a foreigner from Krems?
Mizzi i beg you.
Forget about the theatre, you'll go astray.
But Josef, am i not allowed to earn my own bread?
So why don't you pay her fee?
Then you can forbid her whatever you want.
A good person wouldn't hold on to a girl while he's being drafted.
Don't listen to him Josef. Look.
Mizzi i want to tell you something.
You won't perform here.
But it's too late-
Learn to work first.
How are you going to learn what work is in this place? from him?
The guy who's being taken advantage of by his lover?
How dare you. Say that again.
You cheeky bastard.
Out!
Or i'll choke you.
I've been waiting for this.
To get my hands on you.
Give it a rest!
Josef don't listen to him. Listen to me, Josef.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
As you know, today we are celebrating Mizzi Ebeseders first appearance.
She'll be singing and dancing a pretty marsh for you.
She's an artist now.
Yes. I'm an artist now.
Mizzi, for the last time.
Are you staying with me, or with them?
Of course with you..
With you, with you. Where to with you Josef?
It's not like i can live in the barracks with you.
Look Josef, please think about it. Theres no other way.
It's ringing already.
I swear on my love for you,
if you get on that stage now,
we're over.
What am i supposed to do Josef? I'm not made for the countryside.
Singing is all i know.
I have to work Josef. I have to earn my living somehow.
Well then.
Please.
Go then.
Go then!
Oh.
It's that easy for you?
Fine.
Mizzi stay here, stay here, or it's really all over.
It's over then.
Arguing and preaching, that's your love.
I won't let you torment me anymore.
And just so you know,
standing out there and singing is beautiful,
blissfully beautiful,
and theres nothing bad about it, and it's honest work.
It's just as honest to make people laugh,
as it is threshing corn on a field.
That's that.
Now i'm leaving.
Adieu, Josef.
Always pretty and cheerful,
with fists (?) and trumpets ---- marching
with fists and trumpets ---- marching
Just a little further
until the great fortune comes and makes life great again.
As long as the (?) marches to music,
the world can never end!
I respectfully ask to report myself.
Why?
Because i left the barracks illegaly.
(6 Weeks?) barracks-arrest.
You can step down.
Recruits!
At ease. (Step down.)
I have to talk to him.
Miss Mizzi!
You can't go in the barracks!
You.
Kernthaler. Please get Kernthaler for me.
Kernthaler, a lady here for you.
I have to talk to you.
Theres nothing left to talk about.
Scratch his eyes out if you want.
Silence!
What is it?
Let's make up.
Don't put on a show.
I have to talk to you Josef.
Can you send these guys away?
You don't have to tell me anything. I wont believe you anymore.
Look, Josef.
If i didn't love you so much, i wouldn't be here.
Please. Please, come tonight. Okay?
No.
Go on singing all you want,
getting flowers from all those guys.
You think i can bare it?
Having to think about it every night, how she has to be friendly with him just because he's a good guest.
While i have to sleep on hay, not able to leave the barracks.
I don't want it anymore.
But it's not like that, Josef.
Let me explain.
No no. You won't reel me in again.
Go back to where you came from.
You'll be just fine.
That's how it is with you.. you,
Folk singers.
One card please.
Yes.
Here you go.
Is it a futon chair?
Futon chair.
Front row?
Front row.
Can you see well?
Perfect.
Very good?
Good, how much is it?
80 Hella.
What's going on here, we want tickets too.
Move it. Move it.
Hold on. I wont let you rush me.
Is she going to be singing the --- song too?
Yes.
Yes?
Oh yes.
Because i composed it.
Oh!
Next one please.
Goodbye.
What's wrong.. Miss Mizzi?
Miss Mizzi..
What's wrong?
Oh come on. Everything's gonna be alright.
Come on.
You'll go on stage, and sing, and be happy again, and..
Come on!
and no stranger knows
i saw the light of the sun
in a small house.
I ordered a table at the wine press.
I hope Mizzi will show up.
Of course she'll come.
I know it.
Mizzi is performing.
You see! Can't be that much longer now.
in the early morning
i greet the young, radiant world,
with my melody.
If i had a secret,
and near or far, everyone likes to hear,
it.
The blackbirds, from Lichtental,
sing tri-li-li  and tra-la-la,
they sing, for the thousandth time,
They're chirping, a love song,
in the land, where flowers bloom
They sing longingly and with all their heart
The blackbirds, from Lichtental
Please.
A herring, but not too sweet please, okay?
Sit.
Well, Mizzi?
Well, Miss Mizz.
The teacher composed my song.
Oh really?
Yes.
Did you like it?
Yes, very beautiful. Very.
I came all the way from Krems to be here.
So.. What's new in Krems?
What could there be new in Krems.
The boys in my singing class still annoy me.
And on Wednesday there's the big concert from the men's choir.
I'll be conducting again.
Good Evening, Mr. Baron.
Good Evening.
Mr. Baron, do you have any wish?
Well, Miss Mizzi, what will it be?
What do you want to hear?
('My Mother'?) please.
My Mother.
Or no,
Play 'Die Amsel' (The Blackbird)
The Blackbird!
The Blackbird!, Mr. Baron. Very well.
The Blackbird!.
Cheers!
Sophie, something for the soul?
Of course something for the soul.
Stop.
Stop!
Over!
No sad songs.
No ones crying here.
Come here.
What's going on, Mizzi?
What's this!
Miss Mizzi.
Yes.
I'm alone with you for the first time today.
I want to be alone..
with you.
I already know.
You know a small place closeby.
We'll just drink a bit of wine.
You won't touch me, you just wanna look in my eyes.
And after an hour you promise to take me home.
Am i right?
Mr. von Daffinger
Then at least call me Fritz.
Yes?
I want us to remain good friends.
Fritz.
Franz!
Hello lads! Hello.
Come drink with us, on brotherhood.
May i introduce you to..
We already know each other Mr. Kernthaler!
So let's drink, the three of us.
Excuse me, one more liter please.
One liter please.
Cheers lads!
Cheers!
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
You go first, you go first.
Hold on.
Folk singer, huh?
What do you take me for?
He's taking you for a fool, Kernthaler!
Tell me, Kernthaler, did you hear my new couplet, 'My old lady won't find out'?
'My old- ..Yes. Mansfeld sang it.
My couplet?
Mansfeld.
But Kernthaler.
My couplet?
But she always performed as captain.
Like a colosseum.
No,
Over at ---street, up there.
I can't think of it at the moment. It's on the tip of my tongue, she performed as captain.
Those were seaman songs.
She mainly sang those.
Over there, i see
A riff.
Ship.
Riff.
Riff!
But it doesn't matter, ship or riff.
It does matter. It does!
A ship doesn't matter,
But a riff!
They'll shatter if they hit it.
Kernthaler is right. Kernthaler is right!
Cheers!
Wait!
This ones to..
To 'pepe' (Josef's nickname)
They locked him up!
Can't tell him nothing, that pepe.
Until they locked him in.
The wine is good.
I don't need a ---
If you don't have any rythm, as folk singer..
then i'm sorry for you!
that you don't have any rythm.
I have to leave.
It's only 3 o'clock!
My train leaves at 3:45.
You're scared of your old lady, huh!
I'm not scared, but.. but, i can't let her wait up.
She's still the boss after all.
Let her go beg if she's hungry. Come on Kernthaler, sit back down.
I have to go now.
---
You can take this with you.
This is unbelievable.
Where is this supposed to go when someone won't accept a bracelet with brilliants.
Where are we gonna go?
Who does she think she is?
You.
I already warned you.
I'm an upstanding person.
And i want to stay that way.
---
But Josef is right.
A slut's place. I don't belong here.
I'm going.
Godspeed, and greet Krems(?) for me.
Oh you'll see.
Now you'll really get to know me.
This is for Josef.
And this is for Daffinger.
I only like Josef.
I don't know how i'm gonna live without him.
Oh well.
It's always the first.
It's always
the first
who you can't forget.
That Daffinger.
He's a nice guy, but,
Josef,
i'd do anything for him.
Anything.
Oh Josef.
Kernthaler, Mr. Leutnant.
He's under barracks-arrest.
Theres no one else here.
Yeah, they all went out.
I'll send him right over to Mr. Leutnant.
Aye-aye Mr. Leutnant.
Daffinger is very despaired.
He would've loved to go out with you today.
What's wrong with him?
Well i.. uhm..
I don't know what it's called but, well..
Well, he's laying.
Why don't we go visit the poor guy?
Well, why not, right?
He'd be so happy.
Don't be upset but i don't go into appartments.
But..
But Mizzi, if he's sick..
Come on.
Of course!
If he sees you he'll get better for sure.
You think so?
Of course.
Well?
Why not.
I can assure you Mr. Feldwebel, our program is really first class.
I personally, Frank Ebeseder, am singing the famous and already well known couplet,
'My old lady won't find out'
first class. first class.
What about Mizzi?
She's not singing anymore?
Mizzi, Mr. Feldwebel, doesn't sing anymore,
but instead we have this new artist, and i can assure you,
she looks and acts like a.. like a venus, she looks! i'm not exaggerating.
I'll ask --- if he'll join us.
Very good Mr. Feldwebel, very good.
(Tomorrow your future begins?)
Oh, what an honor.
Brother in law, hm.
Now you did it. Now you can laugh at all us.
Leave me alone, okay?
Well, Mizzi moved in with you i assume.
What?
When you give up your job out of love to such a beautiful man..
What? What are you talking about?
Quit being so offended all the time.
We should be offended!
Her crazy love for you is what led to this.
Mizzi leaving her parents home and quitting her career.
Now we're ruined!
We're totally ruined.
Brother in law.
See you.
Mr. Feldwebel.
Yes?
I respectfully ask for a big favor.
Can i leave the barracks for one hour?
No way. You're on barracks-arrest.
Can't you give permission Mr. Feldwebel?
I need to talk to somebody.
I'm sorry, Kernthaler.
Set the table in the meantime.
But make it look nice.
You'll find everything you need in that drawer.
At your command Mr. Leutnant.
And when you're getting the wine, bring some nice flowers for the table too.
Yes Mr. Leutnant.
What do you do for work anyway?
Architectural draftsman, Mr. Leutnant.
Oh?
Why aren't you a one-year then? (military)
My folks are farmers, they don't think it's necessary.
Put your service revolver away, it doesn't belong here.
Because i'm expecting a lady.
A very beautiful one,  by the way.
I'm sure Mr. Leutnant has the right taste.
Well, it's not exactly easy with her.
And you? What about you?
Don't you have a girl?
Had, Mr. Leutnant.
But then things drifted apart,
and now i'd like to get her back.
Could i please respectfully ask Mr. Leutnant, to take a one hour break from my arrest.
Oh wee.
Okay, fine, I'll take responsibility.
Now go and get the wine,
you can come in later,
and then go get your girl.
Tell her i said hello.
I respectfully thank you, Mr. Leutnant.
It's okay.
Come on. Don't make a scene.
Mizzi!
He'll be so happy.
Walk on in, ladies.
There he is.
Oh, Miss Mizzi.
I'm so happy you came.
I knew right away that this was a hoax.
You're not even sick.
Yes he is!
He's sick with heartache.
Are you angry, Miss Mizzi?
No.
I'm leaving.
Oh no.
15 Minutes. Please.
I didn't expect this from you.
But we never had a chance to be alone.
Not even one minute!
As we shouldn't.
But i can't talk when others are there.
So i needed a little white lie!
You see.
Was it that bad?
Miss Mizzi, you have no idea how happy i am that you're here.
Come on, let's take off your coat.
No, i'm already leaving.
Look, i have to go.
But why!
Look, i cant stay.
But Mizzi.
No, i'm scared. Let me go
You can leave whenever you want.
You're a good guy, actually.
Mizzi, i like you so much
And i'm completely different from my friend Hfelmeyer.
And i know that you're different from Sophie.
So!
Tell me, Mizzi. Can't you like me just a little bit,
I don't know.
Maybe.
Yes?
Do you want to be my wife?
Me?
Why not!
Or are you with someone else?
No one anymore.
And here's our goods,
and here that window in the tower,
that's where i stay.
I always stay there on vacation.
This whole forrest belongs to us.
You even have cows.
Yes, they all belong to us too.
And this here is a hundred year old tree.
Here's a picture of the old bridge. It was destroyed by a big storm last year.
Now they're building a new, modern one.
In summer, when the corn is ripe, it's wonderful over there.
My father will be in for a surprise when you come.
Yes.
You'll have to get used to my mom though.
Josef!
Josef.. I..
Hello!
Why did Mizzi run away?
Didn't work out either huh?
Bad luck.
First you spend weeks trying to charm her and then she wont even let you kiss her.
You.
This girl is performing right now.
She's wonderful, i'm telling you, wonderful.
I ordered two tickets for us.
The bakery is really fantastic. fantastic.
Can i..
please ask to leave the barracks now.
Please.
Why are you running?
Because i was a pighead!
You.
Come in, let's drink together. I have someone over.
Thank you.
Leave me alone.
Give it a rest.
You men are all the same.
You don't even make an effort to try and understand.
I'm gonna be over you forever.
Go on.
Please.
Miss Ebeseder.
Miss Ebeseder.. I.. Is Mizzi here?
No no, I..
Well, where is she?
How should we know?
I thought she drove to you.
To Krems.
No no, i just saw her earlier.
If you don't know who else should?
We don't.
Where should i look for her then?
Try wherever you want.
But not here with us.
Mr. Kernthaler.
I know where Mizzi is.
Yes? Where!
In Hizing, with Sophie.
In Hitzing with Sophie.
Yes! If you hurry you can make the last (bus/train)
Mizzi!
Where is she?
She was just here, no?
Dear Josef.
I loved only..
you.
Mizzi.
Leave me alone!
What!
What the!
What in the!
She's gone crazy.
She'll do something to herself!
A bracelet with brilliants.
That's an unhappy love.
I don't want it anymore.
subs for kg by marshmellowv.