(light music)
- Roar.
(triumphal music)
(light music)
(ominous music)
(dramatic music)
(guns firing)
(cracking thunder)
(triumphal music)
- And that folks, is the story
of our very own, Sudsy Slim.
Now our little town Scratcher Pass
has grown quite a bit since Sudsy's time.
And there's even been stories about
a treasure of gold that Sudsy had hidden.
But to this day, it's never been found.
Any questions?
Yeah, go right on ahead.
- Can we still find gold here?
- Well, unfortunately the gold ran out
in the 1920s, but since
then the towns people
found something that is
just as exciting as gold.
Can you guess what it is?
- Diamonds?
- No, no, not diamonds.
- Rubies?
- Yeah, rubies would've been good.
But what the towns people
found was asbestos.
Yeah, this entire
mountain is covered in it.
Check out this cool asbestos rock.
Here kid, you can keep that as a souvenir.
Unfortunately for reasons
that we won't go into
asbestos isn't as sought after these days
as we would have hoped.
And now for even more fun.
My friend Wally here
will take you on a tour
of some of the actual asbestos mines
that used to be in production.
Now kids, if you're
good I'm sure that Wally
will let you use one of his pick axes
so you can do a little
asbestos mining of your own.
- Is this really safe?
- Oh yeah, Wally's been
doing it his whole life.
- Please follow me.
(funky music)
(groaning)
- [Burt] We made it!
Hurry up.
(dramatic music)
- [Old Woman] Help!
- Give it up, Ripper.
There's no way out.
- Have it your way.
But I'm adding another one to my list.
And this one's on you.
(dramatic music)
(guns firing)
(meowing)
- [Old Woman] He shot my cat!
(dramatic music)
- I need to catch my breath.
- What, god, we, we don't
have time for, come on.
I told you from the beginning
to work on your cardio.
- Last thing I wanted to do was toned up
and start looking
attractive in that place.
So now that we're out, what's
this big plan of yours?
You don't need to keep it secret anymore.
- It's simple.
We steal a car and we
drive to Canada, done.
- I like the plan.
- Great.
- It is simple.
- Don't care.
- What car do you wanna take?
- All right, new plan.
We hike 'til we find a car.
We steal that car and we drive to Canada.
It's a simple plan.
- Right.
- You're the one with the map!
- It's like breaking out of
prison with my sister's kids.
- There's actually roads
all over the place.
- Great, pick one.
- There's a city close by.
It's called Lidel Rock.
- Called what?
Little Rock?
- It's right here.
Yeah, you just take the 30 up to the 430
and it takes you right in.
- Little Rock's in.
Little Rock's in Arkansas!
We're in Alaska!
It doesn't, it doesn't matter.
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't need it now.
- We don't need a map.
We don't need a map.
The guards talk about a
little town in the mountains.
Simple, we hike to the
mountains, we find a car,
we steal that car, and we drive to Canada.
- What's the name of it?
- It doesn't matter
what the name of it is!
We hike to the mountains.
We find a car, we steal that car
and we drive to Canada.
- Okay.
- Simple.
(light music)
- Isn't Canada that way, Burt?
Wait up.
(funky music)
- It's clothes.
Let's hit that clothes line.
(rushing water)
(grunting)
Get, get something on.
What are you wearing?
- It's the only thing that fit me.
- You look like your mother.
- Thank you, Burt.
- Hey, get against the wall.
There's people, there's people.
Get against the wall.
Get against the wall!
- There's somebody over there.
- Hey!
(whistling)
It's a dummy.
(upbeat music)
- All right.
Over there is the house
of our current mayor and over here
we have the Scratcher Pass jail
with US Deputy Marshal James
M. Schuss standing guard.
We are currently working on getting
a grant for a more
masculine representation
of our marshal here but
until that time comes
the Mayor has generously
donated this from his, um
private collection, yeah.
It was actually right
here on this very street
that the famous gun battle took place.
Sudsy along with two of his gang members
were mortally wounded.
Of course, back in
Sudsy's day Scratcher Pass
wasn't quite as large.
There were fewer buildings
and there was just
a muddy road.
Do we have any questions?
- Uh, yes you in the
purple blouse, uh shirt.
- Thank you.
I was just wondering, this Sudsy guy
instead of getting into
a gunfight and dying,
wanted to drive to say, Canada.
Which direction would he go?
- Interesting, never
been asked that before.
- Smooth.
- Well seeing is how Scratcher Pass was
and still is off the road system,
and there were no cars around here
in the early 1900s, I'd
say Sudsy would have
to travel the 50 plus miles
by foot, horse, or dog sled
that direction to the
nearest town, Gangrene Gulch.
And then from there it's
another 200 miles to Canada.
But of course today he would just hop
on a plane and fly out.
Any other questions, no?
All right well let me just take
this opportunity to say thank you so much
for being part of the
Sudsy Slim experience.
May I remind you that our gift shop
is open until 6:00 and we are having
a two for one special
of Sudsy Slim lip balm
and asbestos oven mitts.
So check it out.
(light music)
- What are we gonna do, Burt?
- Shut up and follow me.
(light music)
- Hey look, I'm Sudsy Slim.
- Beat it, kid!
Or you'll end up on the
side of a milk carton.
I don't like people touching me.
(cackling)
- Oh no.
- Well Gladys that's the
last tour of the day.
I'm gonna go upstairs and change
and then head to the Slippery Nickel
and get something to eat.
- Sounds good, sweetheart.
I might see ya there later.
After I close up me and Hobart
are gonna go meet Snake Eyes and toss back
a couple boiler makers.
- All right, see ya there.
- Oh hey, real quick, one last question.
How often do those planes
come in and outta town here?
- Every four days.
- Right.
- Didn't they tell you guys that
when you flew in here?
- Oh I'm sure they did.
We were just sleeping.
- Mm.
(flashing camera)
- [Burt] Mountains.
(ominous music)
Quit touching, what?
- Look.
(ominous music)
- Say cheese.
(flashing camera)
- That'll be five dollars, please.
Uh, for you fellas it's
on the house today.
Have a good one.
(ominous music)
- That's right, you guys missed
the first part of the tour
featuring Sudsy himself.
- That thing gives me the willies.
- Woof, he's something all right.
- You're right about that.
Living, he was the town's worst enemy
but ironically dead, he's
the only thing keeping
this town alive.
His story and his corpse are
what bring in the tourists.
Without him, we'd be finished.
- So without this dried up mountain pirate
this whole down just--
- Pass away like a fart in the wind.
- Pretty much.
- Classy.
- Hey, where is his gun?
- It actually went missing
after the gun fight.
- Kate?
Can I borrow you for a second?
- Yeah, excuse me, gentlemen.
(dramatic music)
- Hey.
I know how we're getting outta here.
(dramatic music)
(ethereal music)
All right, like I said.
The plan is simple.
We steal Sudsy.
We ransom him for some cash
and then we catch the
next flight to Canada.
- Is it me or does he
seem a lot more menacing
than he did earlier?
- He just looks like a
bag of that jerky shoved
into a cowboy suit.
- Looks like his eyes are
following me wherever I go.
Not feeling to sure about this, Burt.
- Look, are we doing this or not?
We're doing it.
Glad we agree.
Help me pry this thing off of here.
(dramatic music)
What are you standing there for?
- I ain't touching him, he's dead.
- Grab him.
Afraid he's just gonna jump out
and eat your brains?
(screaming)
- Ow.
- That was close.
Almost over reacted.
- To me there's no wrong thing
you could put on a pizza.
- Except a Greek pizza.
- I am not a fan of anchovies.
I just really don't like the anchovies.
- What's the matter with you?
You don't like anchovies?
- [Gladys] I don't like
fish, I don't like seafood.
- [Hobart] That's what this place needs.
This place needs a good pizza joint.
- Oh that, yeah.
A nice thin crust pizza.
Son of a, I can't find the.
Hey, wait here just a second.
I think I left something
in the cash register.
I'll be right down.
- Well hurry up, I'm thirsty.
- I'm hurrying, I'm hurrying.
- Chicago style or New York style?
- For 100 year old dead
guy he is not light.
- [Gladys] Somethings wrong with me.
- [Snake Eyes] You get here
to the end of the world
and you have no life experience.
You don't even know what pizza is.
- [Hobart] Do I look lost, fella?
- [Snake Eyes] You've been
spending your time eating all
these gophers and stuff,
I mean look at ya.
- [Hobart] I've never had gopher.
- Now where did I?
I'm gonna check the.
(beeping)
Now where are you?
What, oh man.
(ominous music)
- What do we do?
- Cover his face.
- Oh.
(ominous music)
(screaming)
- Did you hear that?
Is that normal?
I don't really.
- For her?
(wailing)
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What is going on up there?
- Hey, hey, settle.
This ain't helping.
Settle down!
Now what happened?
- He assaulted me.
- Who, who assaulted you?
- Sudsy assaulted me.
- What?
- I saw him, he ran up the stairs.
I think he's trying to
escape out the back.
He assaulted me!
It was terrible.
- The dead guy assaulted you?
He's behind glass.
- All right, all right, all right.
Stay here with Hobart.
I'll go around back and check it out.
Honestly, god.
- Be careful, oh it was terrible.
- Breathe.
(heavy breathing)
(ominous music)
- Sudsy?
Come out, come out wherever you are.
What a crock.
- What are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do?
- Hold this, hold this.
I got an idea.
- What are you doing?
- We're going over.
- What?
(screaming)
- Did you hear that?
- It's probably nothing, move.
All right, you go over the rope.
I'll send the stuff after ya.
Look up!
Get over here and grab this body.
The one on top.
(grunting)
And the rope.
(dramatic music)
- My god, what happened?
Oh!
- Oh.
- Is that a finger in your eye?
- I'm gonna go get the Mayor.
(sobbing)
- All right, we're clear.
Shit, get in the, hide.
- Mr. Mayor!
- Son, I am so proud of you
for pulling out your own tooth.
- That's right.
Tonight you get to leave
it under your pillow
and while you're sleeping
the tooth fairy is gonna
come flying through
that window and leave
you something special.
- Hide!
(dramatic music)
- Oh, Mr. Mayor!
I gotta go get the Mayor,
I gotta get the Mayor.
- That was a freebie.
- What was a freebie?
- Get over here.
(dramatic music)
- Hey Burt, I can't.
- What, what?
- I just, it's too heavy.
- I'll help!
- It's too heavy.
- I'll help.
- Thank you, Burt.
- There, better?
- No.
- [Burt] Come on!
- Was he missing a finger
before we stole him?
- [Mayor] I beg you
madam, contain yourself.
What is the matter, what is?
Oh my, what happened to Snake Eyes?
- Sudsy bush whacked him.
- And he left this in my eyeball.
(light music)
- Holy zombie apocalypse.
(protestors clamoring)
- You don't have nine lives.
(protesters clamoring)
(phones ringing)
- [Receptionist] ABCD?
Yes, it's really a thing.
- Mark Hucksta for AKN News.
On the scene where an angry crowd
is protesting the tragic shooting
of a beloved cat named Mr. Tibbles.
The atmosphere is highly charged
with tension and the smell of Bengay.
Police have released the video footage
of the incident hoping to calm things down
but if anything, it has
only added fuel to the fire.
Watch.
We can see the ABCD agent pointing his gun
at Mr. Tibbles, his owner,
and an unidentified man
whom I assume is a family friend.
Wait, wait, we just got word
that the unidentified man might
have been a serial killer.
So he's either a family
friend or a serial killer.
(chuckling)
We've edited out the actual shooting
due to it's horrifying graphic nature
but we can see the aftermath
as the ABCD agent walks
over to inspect his victim.
That's just something you
never quite get used to seeing.
Things are getting pretty heated here
as you can hear in the background.
You get the sense that
with any slight provocation
anything could happen.
- [Protester] Fake news!
- Oh!
- Ha!
Grover, Grover.
- Do I come down to the bingo Parlor
and throw bricks at you?
- [Protester] You suck!
- Hey man, so you seen today's paper?
- Mr. Tibbles riots enter third day.
ABCD agent or heartless kitty assassin?
Are you kidding me?
(chuckling)
- Oh man.
- Can you believe this garbage?
The press is calling Mr.
Tibbles a kitten now.
That cat is over 14 years old
and lost it's tail to diabetes.
He was practically dead before I shot him.
Aside from grazing him, that stupid cat
is very much alive.
- Look, you caught a serial killer
that's been terrorizing
the city for weeks.
You did what you had to do.
There are a lot of
grateful people out there.
- [Protester] You suck!
- Well, maybe not out
there, but out there.
- It certainly doesn't feel like it.
- Sit down, I do have
some good news for you.
The review board came back
and declared your shooting
of the ripper as justified.
It's my privilege to
give you your gun back.
- That's good.
- I also have a case for you.
It appears to be a missing persons.
- We don't normally handle those.
Scratcher Pass.
You're sending us to Scratcher Pass?
- No, I'm sending you to Scratcher Pass.
Agent Grover will hold the fort
down here while you're gone.
I figured it's a good chance
to get you outta town for a little bit.
You know, until this
Tibbles thing blows over
and the cat ladies go home.
- I don't even know where this place is.
- It's off the road systems.
You'll be flying out.
The only info we have is
from a voice message left
by the town mayor.
The details are a bit scarce.
It seems a mudslide
took out the phone lines
and there's no cell
service up there, either.
You'll be flying out.
I booked you on a charter.
You have an hour to
get your stuff together
and head to the airport.
- [Protesters] Shame,
shame, shame on Sherman.
- Oh and Sherman, take your time
while you're out there to see the sights.
(splattering eggs)
Maybe do a little gold panning, fishing.
- [Protester] You suck!
- Why don't you grow some facial hair?
A lot of facial hair.
(splattering eggs)
(uplifting music)
- Wow, it's absolutely beautiful out here.
I bet you never get tired of the scenery.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
Uh, okay.
I can fly this.
No I can't, I can't fly this.
Don't be dead.
Wake up, wake up, wake up!
Please don't be dead!
- Be there in 10 minutes.
Wow, look at that scenery.
I never get tired of looking at that.
(ethereal music)
- Hello.
My name's Kate.
I wasn't expecting any tourists in today.
How was your flight?
- Uneventful, you know.
Aside from my pilot being Rip Van Winkle.
- Oh.
- Kate.
- Hey.
- Here's the mail for Froderick
and the newspaper that
I promised the Mayor.
- Perfect.
- Good to see ya again.
- Bye.
- Good flying with ya.
- I'm agent Sherman with
the Alaska Bureau of Criminal Detection.
We got a report of a missing persons.
- Oh, wonderful.
I knew the Mayor called for help
but I didn't realize
anyone got the message
because a mudslide took
out our phone lines
at about the same time.
- Here I am.
- Alaska Bureau of Criminal Detection.
Is that really a thing?
- Yes, it's really a
thing that I work for.
- Huh, never heard of it.
- We're getting a website.
So Kate, could you fill me
in on some of the details?
Who it is, the circumstances
of their disappearance?
- Well, the who is Sudsy Slim.
As far as the circumstances,
I think I better let the
Mayor fill you in on those.
Town is just two miles up the mountain.
(funky music)
Hello, Mayor.
- Oh.
- Here's you're newspaper.
Thanks for letting me
borrow the four wheeler.
I had to get the mail to Froderick.
And guess who I bumped
into at the air strip.
This is Agent Sherman.
- Holy rug!
- I beg your pardon.
- Your rug, it's got holes in it.
- It's a hard wood floor.
- Mayor, this is the gentlemen
that's gonna help us
with our little problem.
- Oh, Agent Sherman!
Thank you for coming so quickly.
We're terribly worried about our Sudsy.
Now some introductions are in order.
This is my assistant Hobart.
This is Mr. Snake Eyes he, he.
- I fix things.
- Yes.
- And this is Digger.
He's our local undertaker
and outhouse engineer.
- Outhouse engineer?
- I like digging holes.
It don't matter to me
what you fill 'em with.
Bodies or turds.
- Ah.
- Now, now, now please sit, sit, sit.
Now, Agent Sherman.
Have we met somewhere before?
- Uh, no, no reason we should have met.
- Ah, but your face is so familiar.
I just can't seem to put my finger on it.
- Nah, just one of those faces, I guess.
Can I borrow your newspaper.
I love the Sudoku puzzle.
- Yeah of course, help yourself.
- Thank you.
(meowing)
- Oh dear, oh I am so terribly sorry.
Can't imagine what's gotten into Higgins.
He's usually so well behaved.
He must know you're a cat person.
- Well, I do have a history with cats.
Um, anyway.
Mr. Mayor could you fill me in
on this missing persons case.
Kate said the man's name is Sudsy Slim?
- Yes, that's correct.
- Okay, and what makes you
think he's actually missing?
Did he not show up for
work the other day or what?
- He did not show up for
work, that is correct.
- And is it safe to assume this
is unusual behavior for him?
- Incredibly unusual,
he's just always there.
- Now is it possible that
there was foul play involved?
- Agent Sherman the thing
is, Sudsy just seems
to have run off into the woods one night.
- After he assaulted some people.
- Is Sudsy usually violent?
- Well, he does have
a history of violence.
Although it's been awhile.
- How long?
- Oh, about 100 years.
- Of course.
- Sherman, wait!
- When's the next plane out of here?
- Four days.
- Please, Sherman just listen to me.
We could really use your help.
- I catch armed robbers, serial killers,
really bad people.
I don't go chasing after people
that have been dead for over 100 years.
- It's not gonna work.
You see a mudslide took
out our phone lines and--
- Phone lines, yeah.
That's what I heard.
What about the cell tower?
- They were next to the phone lines.
Look, I'm sorry okay.
But I had to leave out a few small details
to get somebody up here.
If we told the whole truth no
one would have believed us.
- I'm still having a little trouble
with the believing part.
You know, because zombies.
- Okay.
At least let me buy you a drink.
It's not like you have
anywhere to go at the moment.
(funky music)
- There we go, cranberry juice for you.
Usual for you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Kate, you do know that this Sudsy thing
is pretty ridiculous, right?
I mean there's no way I
can help you with this.
- You know, the man was a real crap weasel
when he was alive.
I can only imagine what he's like undead.
But this town depends on him.
When he was alive Sudsy and his gang used
to make quite a living conning
and cheating, anyone
that came into this town.
- How'd he end up dying?
- Eventually the brought
in a deputy marshal
to restore law and order.
And things came to a head pretty quickly.
There was a cool spaghetti
western style shootout
on the main street leaving Sudsy
and a couple of his gang members dead.
- Ah ha.
- This town really needs him.
I mean we all dress the part to make
it fun for the visitors but at the end
of the day, it's Sudsy
that they're here to see.
- Can I get you anything else?
- Oh, no thank you Donka.
- Donka?
- Oh, it is gypsy.
By day I am bartender.
But by night I am the all seeing Donka.
Look, I have sign over there.
- Is your crystal ball a cantaloupe?
(ominous music)
(moaning)
- Bullets fly, guns blaze,
witnesses see through the haze.
The law man, the law man
falls lifeless to the ground.
His chest is still.
His breath, not a sound.
(crackling electricity)
Oh, there.
Small sample, enjoy.
- And you just met Donka.
- I didn't really notice
any other law men in town.
- Nope, you're the only one.
I mean she's picked a couple Superbowl's.
- Yeah, I think I'm gonna
turn in for the night.
- Wait Sherman, before you do
can you just come check
out the crime scene?
- Obviously the plexiglass
goes to Sudsy's coffin?
- Yes.
- Judging by the nails
I'd say Sudsy's side
is facing up.
Kate, were these scratches here before?
- No, they weren't.
- It looks like.
- Like he was trying to claw his way out?
Yeah, I know.
- Except a dead guy's not gonna
claw his way out and escape.
(dramatic music)
So, is this our suspect?
- That's him, that's the pervert.
Treating me like some sexy piece of meat.
Though you can't blame a guy for trying.
- Yuck.
- So you say you're some
kind of detective fella?
- Uh, yeah.
- Yes, Gladys this is Agent Sherman.
He's a member of the Alaska Bureau of,
I'm sorry what was it again?
- Alaska Bureau of Criminal Detection.
- He's an ABCD agent.
- Ha!
That sounds like some kind
of Sesame Street thing.
(chuckling)
- Gladys, can you fill me in
on the details of last night?
- Oh yeah, it was terrifying.
See I work here as a
cashier and I came back
late last night because I left
my vodka in cash register.
- Is that what's in your glass right now?
(chortle)
- Heaven's no, it's
way too early for that.
This is a martini.
- Okay, please continue.
- I was standing right
here behind the counter.
When suddenly I felt
like I was being watched
and the hairs on the
back of my neck started
to get all prickly.
So I went over to the
stairs to investigate
and that's when he jumped
at me and his tongue
was all hanging out.
I think he was trying to french me.
- Ugh.
- You know, and I'm not
that kind of a girl.
Well, not on the first date.
Well, or not the first 10 minutes
of the first date at least.
So, I screamed and I fell over backwards
and by the time I opened my eyes
I saw him go flying up the stairs
and that is when I ran out screaming.
- Okay, so Gladys was Sudsy
alone when he assaulted you?
- He was all alone and very lusty.
- Oh yeah, of course.
I mean he's been in a box for 100 years.
He's probably ready for a date night.
- All right, I think that's all we need.
Thank you so much for your time, Gladys.
- [Gladys] Now where's that tequila?
- Hello?
- Welcome to the Scratcher's
Inn and Post Office.
- Ah, I didn't see you there.
- My apologies.
I was tending to my crops.
- What crops?
- How may I help you today?
- I'm Agent Sherman.
I have a room reservation for here.
- Agent, real estate huh?
- Uh, no.
Alaska Bureau of Criminal Detection.
- ABCD, that's really a thing?
- It's really a thing.
- Do you ever feel kind of stupid
when you have to kick in a door
and scream, "Freeze, ABCD Agent!"
- Do you have my room key?
- Ah.
Room 1102, the annulment suite.
- What's with the orange thing?
- That's for if you drop
it into the outhouse.
You need to retrieve it.
- Okay, please tell me this is clean.
- What's clean?
- Did you say annulment suite?
- You'll understand when you see it.
- Okay, could you just
please show me to my room?
- Allow me to take your bag.
(ominous music)
(crackling thunder)
- [Donka Voiceover]
The lawman, the lawman.
- Bullets fly, guns blaze,
witnesses see through the haze.
- [Donka Voiceover]
The lawman, the lawman.
- The law man falls
lifeless to the ground.
His chest is still.
His breath, not a sound.
(maniacal laughing)
- Wanna spoon?
(wailing)
(light music)
- All right, I back
tracked, found his arm.
Also there's a cabin back there.
We must've passed it in the dark.
We can probably use it as a hideout.
- I don't like the way he's looking at me.
- He's also missing some more fingers
but you know, nothing important.
It's like keeping
together a jigsaw puzzle.
Here, give me that tape
from the gift shop.
The duct tape, from the.
I know, it's fine.
Yeah, that's right, whatever.
That's fine, I'll just do it.
Hopefully this, will keep him
from losing any more pieces.
- He just stares at me.
- Don't you think if
he was gonna come alive
he woulda done it before now?
Like when he was fresh?
- Yeah well, what about the mummy?
- What mummy?
- You know, a mummy.
Thousands of years old, the mummy's curse.
He returns from the dead
to claim his victims for
disturbing his rest, the mummy.
- You think that happened?
That that's real life?
All right, all right.
Okay.
Look at him.
He is against the trees.
He's in the grass.
He's hanging out with us.
Enjoying nature's bounty.
I like to believe that if
he came to life right now
he'd thank us for taking
him camping, right?
- No, he's angry.
- I'm ang!
Okay, exhaustion seems to
have made you a bit weird.
Why don't you come over
and grab your traveling companion
and we'll go back to that
cabin, get some rest.
And, and visit this anew tomorrow.
- Right.
- Yeah, okay.
(light music)
- Good morning.
This is your wake up call.
And I need to borrow a pair of your socks.
- Wake up call, socks?
The door was locked.
- The locks here don't actually work.
They serve as more of
a decorative function.
- What?
Why are you in here?
- I have a message from Kate.
Both here and Alex are awaiting
you at the Slippery Nickel.
Also, you're out of toilet paper.
And toothpaste.
- So, how's the food here?
- Best place to eat in town.
- What my sister fails to say
is that it's one of the
only places to eat in town.
Gosh, I'd kill for a McDonald's.
Well, not really kill.
Figuratively speaking because
that would be illegal, right?
- Last I checked.
Tell me, Alex.
What do you like to do for fun?
- I like to invent things, look!
I made this the other day.
I call it a shock bow.
- Is that a spork?
- Yeah!
- I wouldn't.
That thing is like a taser on steroids.
- Oh, very nice.
- Yeah, I shot my sister
in the leg the other day.
- Yeah, put a hole in my favorite jeans.
Although I could charge my
phone just by holding it
for the next couple of hours.
- You're welcome.
(triumphal music)
- Pardon the interruption.
We were hoping to speak with
Agent Sherman for a moment.
- By all means.
- Well, we're in a bit of a predicament.
You see our town relies heavily,
or should I say solely on tourism
for it's survival.
And the thing that sets our town apart
from other towns is that we
have Sudsy's, well corpse,
for people to see.
Now that Sudsy has disappeared things
have become rather desperate
and so we put our
contingency plan into effect
but it didn't work as
well as we had hoped.
- I put old man Peterson
in Sudsy's coffin.
- What?
- Don't worry, Peterson's been
dead at least three months.
- Isn't that awesome?
- Um, Alex why don't you wait outside.
We need to talk to the Mayor.
- Fine.
- Yes, good lad.
Yes, what Digger and
Hobart are trying to say
is that we put a substitute
body in Sudsy's place.
For tourists.
But as the body had been in the ground
for some months it had become
the home of several thousand worms
and when the body began to warm up it--
- He split open, like a birthday pinata.
- It's a bit of a PR nightmare.
- Yeah, and it's highly illegal.
- Oh we stuffed him back in his hole.
- Yeah, it's all good.
Plus we got a whole mess of fishing worms.
- Now the reason that I have come
is that I am putting together a team
of men to track down Sudsy.
But I need a person to lead the team.
A person of experience.
And I would like that person to be you.
- You want me to form a posse?
- Well, I like to think of
it more as a recovery team.
- I see.
- You are an experienced law man.
All we need you to do is to find Sudsy
and bring him back so we can put him back
on display where he belongs.
- And we'll probably
have to kill him again.
- What Hobart is trying to say
is that as Sudsy is already dead
why there's no crime in
leaving him in that state.
Even if you have to shoot him a few times
in the process.
- Your recovery team
is sounding a lot like
an assassination team.
- Oh you would have some
of the town's top men.
You will have some warm
bodies to fill out your team.
- We might be able to get a real bonafide
Indian guide and tracker.
(ethereal music)
- Hello.
- Raj could be our tracker.
- Did somebody order the pork vindaloo?
- Oh that would be me!
- Ah, my friend.
- Raj here runs the Indian food stand
at the end of the road.
What do you call that Raj?
- Ah yes, Kid Curries.
And I must say I am proud
to be farthest north
curry stand in the whole US.
- Yes, and he also moonlights
as a hiker and trail guide.
- Yes, yes.
I heard you mention tracker?
- We need a tracker.
Someone who can find things.
- I am more of a hiker, not a tracker.
- Are you kidding me, Raj.
Last week I lost my
keys, couldn't find them.
Looked everywhere, you
delivered my dum aloo
and found them right away.
- That's because I
found them in your door.
- Ah, but you also found my cat Higgins
when I told you he was
missing a few weeks back.
- No, no, no.
He was pooping in the
flower pot outside my stand.
Right okay, so I have found a few things
but I don't think that qualifies me
to go tracking down.
What is this you're tracking?
- Oh, we're gonna hunt down
Sudsy and bring him back.
- Okay, let me get this straight.
You want me help you track
down a 100 year old zombie
that goes leaping rooftop to rooftop
poking out random people's eyes?
- Yes, that's right.
- You know, in my culture
we put our dead in boats,
light them on fire, then
send them down the Ganges
so we don't have problems like this.
- That's funny, I never would
have figured you for a viking.
(sighing)
- I'm out.
- What?
- Well it's a shame about
your food stand, Raj.
- Pardon me?
- Well your lease is up
at the end of the month
and Duck Won has an
interest in establishing
a Korean food stand.
I understand that he makes
a kimchi that's to die for.
And we really need everyone
on board here, Raj.
- Fine, but I'm not going to like this.
- Excellent.
Now, Agent Sherman will you lead them?
- I have to admit I am interested
in seeing how this goes.
And I don't think it would hurt
to do a little poking around.
But, mostly to ensure that
there's no unnecessary
assassinating going on.
- Well, suit yourself.
As long as we get our Sudsy back.
Gear up, men!
You leave in an hour.
Thank you, Donka.
(dramatic music)
- All right, do we have everyone?
Looks like you're all loaded for bear.
What's this, no gun?
- I really don't like guns.
It's bear mace.
You know, for bear.
- More like hiker seasoning.
- Hey, I've used this once before
and it worked just fine, okay.
- Using it on a ground squirrel
that walked into your
food hut two weeks ago
doesn't really count.
- Oh that's where he got the
spicy curry special last week.
- That was good.
- [Raj] Thank you.
- Is this a flash grenade?
- It's better than a fly rod.
- You know what, I don't even
wanna know where you got it.
Just take it off and leave it here.
We can't take that with us.
Is that the pin?
- Oh sh..!
(explosion)
(light music)
(snoring)
(shouting)
- Sudsy, he was crawling right at me!
- He fell off the chair.
- I swear I saw him move.
- As he fell, Andrew.
- It looked like he was
reaching for me or something.
- That's what happens when
things fall, they move.
Have you slept?
(grunting)
Well.
You're getting a little delusional.
He's back in the chair now.
If you have another
nightmare, suck your thumb.
(light music)
- Look.
- Ah, what?
- An old gun.
Some ammo.
A newspaper.
It's from 1914.
And there's a story on Sudsy
and his gang conning a group of nuns
out of their rosary beads
and their sacramental wine.
And there's a picture.
- Neat.
Huh.
Hey.
SS.
- Do you think it was Sudsy
and his gang's hideout.
He was just there.
He was trying to reach for his gun, right?
- No, not right!
- He was trying to reach his gun.
That's what he was
doing, do you understand?
- Wrong, he's dead.
I've told you before.
Cowboy crypt keeper there ain't moving.
The dead don't crawl.
The dead don't jump.
The dead sit there and be dead.
- He jumped out.
- He didn't jump, he fell.
Additionally, we don't know
where this cabin came from.
We can't say this is Sudsy's cabin
or his gang's cabin, or
this is even his stuff.
It could just be some weird fan boy's
make believe playhouse.
You've seen the town.
You need a little bit more than an old gun
and some bullets in a cabin in Alaska
to prove to me that this is Sudsy's cabin.
- How about these rosary beads?
(dramatic music)
- We all seem to be recovering just fine.
Aside from Wally who was kind enough
to take the brunt of the blast.
He'll be sitting this one out.
Yeah, let's hit the road.
- What'd you say?
- [Snake Eyes] You're all right, Wally!
Walk it off!
- [Raj] This is going
to be a very long day.
(funky music)
- Well, one lock, one key right?
(chuckling)
Looks like Sudsy was one of
the original preppers here.
There we go.
Here, get the bag.
- Looks like we have some
100 year old clam pudding.
- Oh, neat.
Huh?
- Cool.
(funky music)
- So do you know where you're going?
- Eh, I like to put myself
in place of the undead.
100 year old zombie.
Fresh from the ground.
Really get into his mind.
And then I follow his fingers.
- What?
- His fingers.
I found these a few miles back
at the beginning of the trail.
And look, there's another one.
- You are good at finding things.
- It's a gift.
- Check it out, fingers.
- Ugh, too soon.
- What are you doing?
- What's it look like I'm doing?
That thing didn't fit.
I mean, there's some nice stuff in here.
Shame for it to go to waste.
Might as well put it on.
- You uh?
Here, let's see what else.
Well, put that on.
(light music)
Get this stuff bagged up.
Hey, think this used to be jerky?
- It's a little dry.
(light music)
- What's up, man?
Why'd you stop?
- Hey man, I'm peeing.
- Oh, ah yeah!
- The show's over.
- Yeah, yeah.
Let's go!
(dramatic music)
- I don't feel good.
- Well, you shouldn't have eaten
that 100 year old beef jerky.
- Ugh.
- Where'd we put that paper and pen?
I'm gonna write a ransom note.
- It's on the window sill.
- Hey Burt, wouldn't have been easier
and save more time if we just left
the ransom note at the scene
when we first took Sudsy?
- Shut up, Andrew!
This is my first kidnapping, all right.
I didn't have all the pieces previously
as we do now, all right?
- Right.
- Don't you worry about the thinking game.
- I've got it all.
It's also more dramatic this way.
- Right, right.
- He's rocking, you see that right?
- Yeah, I see it.
All right look, there's five
of us and only one of him.
- Yeah, but he's undead.
- I need you all to follow my lead
and just don't do anything stupid.
Sudsy!
Come out with your hands up.
We have you surrounded.
- Get down, get down!
Get Sudsy and get down!
Get down here.
- Did you see that?
Sudsy just jumped outta the chair.
- Go! ah!
- He's kicking out the windows!
- Hey, get out!
Take this!
(Andrew screaming)
- Get down!
(gunshot)
Open fire!
- Get him!
(guns firing)
- Come out and fight like a man you jerk!
(spraying)
- Ah god!
Not helping, not helping!
(guns firing)
- One of us is gonna make it!
- They're coming from over here.
(guns firing)
- Every man for himself.
- Hey you, get back, chicken!
(dramatic music)
- It's not working.
It's not working!
- Give it back!
- It's not working.
(guns firing)
- Why did he have to use a revolver?
- Whoa, that's it!
You're up.
- Oh jeez.
- Oh wait, oh crap I'm out.
- Yeah me, too.
(gun shot)
- Oh hey, guys.
- Sissy.
- Well what do we do now?
(ominous music)
- Shut up.
Stay down.
(dramatic music)
- Did you see Sudsy?
(gun firing)
(can hissing)
(explosion)
(screaming and coughing)
(thud)
(coughing)
- There's smoke.
There's smoke.
Come look.
You think he's dead?
- Head down the trail
I'll meet you in a minute.
(ominous music)
Upgrade.
(cracking thunder)
- [Donka Voiceover] Bullets fly, guns.
The law man.
The law man falls lifeless to the ground.
His chest is still.
- Sherman?
Sherman wake up.
Sherman!
(gasping)
- Kate, what are you doing here?
- All of your friends
from your little play date
came back running into town screaming
about Sudsy ambushing them
and taking you hostage.
So I formed a little search party
of my own to come and rescue
the damsel in distress.
- Search party?
- Well, yeah evidently word
has gotten around that my
parties stink so, I'm it.
(light music)
Plus, with a bunch of men
screaming like little girls
and smelling like they soiled themselves,
not too many people were too excited
to join in on the rescue.
- I didn't need rescue, I was doing fine.
- Oh, yeah I'm sure that taking
a nap in the dirt and
bleeding from your head
was all part of your grand
plan to capture Sudsy.
(light music)
- My gun, so you see my gun?
- No, actually I don't.
- After my head got hit, I
remember seeing Sudsy run
off into the woods.
Did he take my gun?
- We can get you another gun in town
but first we've gotta get you outta here.
(light music)
(dramatic music)
- Burt, did you notice something odd
just before the shooting
started at the cabin?
- What?
- They yelled Sudsy's name.
Like they were talking to him.
- [Burt] Yeah, I guess
they did, didn't they?
- [Andrew] Why would they do that?
- I don't know.
- Maybe they think Sudsy's alive.
- Well, that's stupid.
Unless.
When we took Sudsy, nobody saw us, right?
But they saw Sudsy, we
know they saw Sudsy.
- Okay, but that's not
what I'm talking about.
- That's weird, that would be weird.
- Yeah, I caught him
crawling at me this morning.
- No, no, and at the cabin they had
to have seen him through the window.
- I swear he keeps staring at me.
- What?
- I think Sudsy's alive!
Not alive per se, but not all dead.
(light music)
- We've been over this.
He's dead.
- Right.
- Listen!
I need you to get all
your duke in a duffel.
I know exactly how we're
gonna finish this ransom note.
I need you to stay here with Sudsy.
He is our only ticket outta here.
(ominous music)
(running water)
(clanging metal)
(moving shower curtain)
(dramatic music)
- Did you hear that, Higgins?
It sounded like it came from outside.
(dramatic music)
(chirping birds)
Hello?
(clanging metal)
(ominous music)
- Okay, Andy.
Keep it together.
Burt will be back.
(ominous music)
(chuckling)
Might come in handy.
(ominous music)
It's better than nothing.
- [Sudsy] Hey.
(ominous music)
Hey.
Wanna spoon?
(Andy Screaming)
(Sudsy cackling)
(Andy screaming)
- Oh god!
Find your happy place,
find your happy place.
(whimpering)
Find your happy place!
(screaming)
(light music)
- Hm, hepatitis again, Gladys.
- Sherman!
Sherman are you up?
- The door's unlocked.
- Sherman!
- I'll be fine.
A bump on the head isn't
gonna kill me in my sleep.
- The Mayor was attacked.
- By who?
- Sudsy, apparently.
- I'll grab my coat.
(dramatic music)
- Andy, it's done!
Andy!
Sudsy?
Where's the mine cart?
(sighing)
Andy!
Quit fooling around!
Is Sudsy okay?
So you mean, while I was gone, Sudsy
offers you a spoon?
- Yeah, but the way he said
it made me feel kind of dirty.
- And then, he proceeds to
chase you with the mine cart
and knock you off a cliff?
- Yes.
- You know it's occurring to me
that you have become a
bit more of a liability
than you are an asset.
I've got half a mind
to just leave you here.
- We could always go back.
- Go back where?
- To Moose Hump.
- To prison?
- Yeah, it's Gravy Wednesday
there, it'll be great!.
- The plan is simple.
We sneak into town, we make the drop.
If we do this right nobody even knows
we were here.
And then we take that money
and fly to Canada.
You could have gravy for days.
They put it on french
fries and call it poutine.
- I can't take much more of this, Burt.
- If you want me to leave you alone
and not haunt you for eternity
leave 50,000 dollars cash
at the old gold mill this evening.
Come alone.
So you're saying that when you opened
the door Sudsy whacked you
in the face with a shovel,
dropped this note, and then just ran away?
- Not necessarily.
I found the note stapled to his forehead
when I came to bring him
his usual morning order
of Caribou Curry.
- I told you he was
good at finding things.
- You were laying in the doorway
with your robe wide open.
Naked as a jay bird.
- Any who, where are we
going to find 50,000 dollars.
Plus we need him for the tourists.
He can't just quit and leave.
- [Raj] It is customary to
give at least two weeks notice.
- I have a plan.
- Should we gather the posse?
- Yeah, sure, let's gather the posse.
The same posse that just left me for dead.
- Oh yeah, good times, right.
- Not funny.
(light music)
- I see the drop zone, but no Sudsy.
- Hello!
(shouting)
- Where's the cash?
- Oh, I have it here.
We're a little light on actual cash
but we did make it up
with some other things.
- What's that smell?
- Oh, those are Raj's fresh curry rolls.
We were light on the ransom.
So he threw them in.
They're as good as cash.
- How come he didn't bring 'em himself?
- Oh he's sitting this one out.
Something about pet
sitting a neighbors ferret.
- How much cash is in here, exactly?
- 137 dollars and 47 cents.
- Are these coupons?
- Those would be Digger's.
He's what you might call
an extreme couponer.
- That represents a lot of savings there.
- Whatever, we're just gonna
have to make this work.
Mayor, take this.
Go around and leave it by that sign.
We'll keep an eye out for
Sudsy and if he appears
then we'll make our move.
- You two, go around
that side of the rock.
(light music)
- Do you see anything?
- If I saw something,
I would say something.
- Right, right.
- Hey, Mayor's coming
and he's got the bag.
- Finally.
- So far so good.
Well, why don't you go
ahead and move around back.
Make sure nobody's sneaking up behind us.
Keep watch.
Hey, it is very important
they think he's alive.
(dramatic music)
- Come on, Mayor walk back to us.
What's he doing?
Why is he just standing there?
- Is he not supposed to?
- No, he's supposed to drop the bag
so Sudsy can come get it.
Well that would have been a good detail
to know before we sent him
out there, don't you think?
(dramatic music)
- Why is he just standing there?
- No, don't look at us!
Don't look at us!
Look away.
No, stop, stop looking.
Stop it, stop looking.
- [Digger] Do you want me to shoot him?
- What is he looking at?
Do you see anybody?
- [Andy] I see nothing.
- Do you see anything?
- I don't see anything, Burt.
- Let me see if I can
move this idiot along.
(crashing)
- It's Sudsy.
What the?
(screaming)
- Leave the money and walk away.
You don't know the things I've seen.
- Something's not right.
Dang it, I don't have my gun.
Anybody have an extra?
- Here, you can use mine.
Laser sight.
(buzzing)
- Oh here, let me just turn
that down a little bit.
Sorry about that.
- Okay, cover me.
- With what?
Give me your gun or I'm
punching you in the throat.
- [Burt] You don't know where I've been!
I'm coming after you!
- [Mayor] Wake me up!
- Burt!
- [Burt] Go!
- [Mayor] Wake me up!
- Burt!
- Shoo, I'm gonna give
you to the count of 10.
- Burt, they're coming inside.
- [Mayor] Help, what are you.
- [Burt] To get your lying,
yellow, no good keister
of my property!
Before I pump your guts full of lead!
(mayor wailing)
One.
- [Mayor] There's a woman over there.
How long has it been
since you've had a woman?
Get her, leave me.
- [Burt] Two!
- Oh god, somebody!
Wake me up!
- 10!
(clanging metal)
(gunshot)
- [Mayor] What is going on!
- What the?
- Shoot him!
- What?
(guns firing)
What the?
Andy!
We gotta go!
- Stop!
(guns firing)
Stop that fire!
Hold your fire!
- Look.
- [Burt] Perfect.
(light music)
- Cease fire.
(gunshot)
Digger!
- Sorry, my bad.
(revving engine)
- Well that didn't go well.
- I know, I was there.
It's time we show these
bumpkins who's in charge.
Who's boss.
We are, we're in charge.
- Right, right.
- And where's Sudsy?
- What do you mean he's right.
(sighing)
(dramatic music)
- Now, I'm pretty sure
one of those guys saw us.
So if we're gonna get outta here
we gotta make it quick.
Would you get over here
and hold something?
- Uh-uh.
What's the new plan?
- I can't believe that Sudsy felt
he had to steal my four wheeler.
- Did you get a good look at him?
- Not really, but I do
remember seeing two Sudsy's.
- Excuse me?
- Well it's probably just
the blow to your head
had you seeing double.
- I understand that I've been getting hit
in the head a lot, but I swear I saw more
than one person on that four wheeler.
Now, I think it's possible
that Sudsy's got some outside help.
- The Dirty Bunch.
Sudsy must have dug up his old gang.
- The Dirty Bunch?
- Two of them died with
him in the shootout.
- Now we're dealing with more zombies.
- Sudsy's not a zombie.
- Oh yeah, well if he's not a zombie
than how come he's been running around
and knocking you out right and left?
- All right, all right, all right.
Now, Agent Sherman, I'm not saying
that I'm completely convinced
but let's say that you are correct
and there's more here going
on than we originally thought.
What's our next move?
- Well, I guess we could wait for them
to make contact again.
- When's that gonna be?
(screaming)
- Oh Digger, are you all right?
- All right, they got
the package, let's go.
- Wait.
- What?
- Do you mean this package?
- I thought you taped that to the?
Give me that!
I'll just do it myself.
- It's just a rock with a note on it.
- What does the note say?
- If you want Sudsy back have the money
in an airplane with a pilot
for us by noon tomorrow.
If you don't comply you'll
never see Sudsy again.
To show we're serious we are
including this little gift.
- So Sudsy really does have help.
- What's the gift, the rock?
(crashing)
(screaming)
- [Mayor] Oh for goodness sake!
Can't they aim for the same window pane?
- Got it.
Let's go, grab that bag of meat.
- I forgot the attachment
on the first rock.
(ominous music)
- What the?
- Is that a thumb?
- I don't see any finger nail.
- Huh.
I wouldn't have thought
that Sudsy was Jewish.
- Oh!
I want to thank you all
for joining me here.
I was running out of windows at my office.
- All right, how are we gonna get
a plane out here by noon tomorrow?
- Not to mention, we showed up
a little short on the ransom.
Ah, that reminds me, I have to make
a fresh batch of curry rolls.
- Do you guys realize that is just
a simple corpse napping, not a zombie.
- Uh, no.
- We need to get them out in the open.
No more quick glimpses.
That way we can figure out
who's finally behind this.
- Okay, how do you suggest
we make that happen?
(dramatic music)
- We'll get them their plane.
And I'm gonna need all
of you to make this work.
- Tell us what you want us to do.
(ethereal music)
- Well, the airplane's on the runway.
So far so good.
- Can you see if the pilot's there?
- Not from this angle.
- What about the money?
- It's probably in the plane.
We have to get a closer look.
- The place looks eerily quiet.
Do you see anyone?
- No.
I don't, whoa, wait a minute.
What the?
They just left the money
sitting in the middle of town.
Why didn't they put it next to the plane
like you told 'em in the note?
- Yeah.
The note.
- You didn't put that
in the note, did you?
- I was rushed.
- I don't like the looks of this.
We gotta go to the town to get the money?
- You got that dynamite
you found in the mine?
- Yeah.
It might be a trap.
- Yeah, but in this case
we have the advantage.
- How's that?
- We know it's a trap.
(dramatic music)
- Is everybody in position?
- [Snake Eyes] Cyclops
and Dirt Boy in position.
- Who?
- [Snake Eyes] Snake Eyes and Digger.
I thought you were
supposed to have call signs
when you're using these things.
- Kate and Hobart, do you copy?
- Kate-a-licious and the Hobman copy loud
and clear, Agent Sugarpants.
(sighing)
- No more call names, we're done.
Remember, nobody do anything until we know
what we're dealing with.
I don't want anybody getting hurt.
- Thanks for the vest, by the way.
You didn't have to do that.
- It wasn't really my color anyway.
(buzzing)
- Ow, man hey it's me.
Ow, oh that's painful.
- What are you doing in here, anyway?
- Well, I thought it would be safer
to hang out with the guy with the gun
and the fancy training, of course.
- All right, just be quiet okay?
- Although, you are
the one zombies do like
to hit in the head all the time.
Perhaps I didn't think this one through.
I should go.
(dramatic music)
(explosion)
(ethereal music)
- What was that?
- [Snake Eyes] It looks
like something blew up
on the far edge of town!
Digger and I are gonna
run over and check it out.
- Are we good?
- Yeah.
- Great.
(ominous music)
- [Sherman] Do you see anything?
- [Raj] No.
- Kate, do you see anything?
- No, I don't see anything.
(coughing)
- Come on.
It was an outhouse that exploded.
- That's unusual, right?
Cyclops and Dirt Boy are
heading back into position.
- It's awfully quiet out there.
- Yeah, almost too quiet, huh?
- Maybe our distraction worked.
- All right, everybody sit tight.
Let's see if something happens.
- We're getting that money
and we're going to Canada.
Let's go.
(dramatic music)
- [Sherman] Okay, something's happening.
They're coming out.
Everyone, hold your position.
- I don't like this, Burt.
- Shut up!
(dramatic music)
- Kate, your brother's out there.
- What, where is he?
- [Sherman] He's coming around
the corner of your building.
He's headed straight to the bad guy.
- Oh, Alex what are you thinking!
(dramatic music)
- Get up.
(chortle)
- Not good, not good.
- Go, go.
- [Sherman] Hey!
- This guy again.
- ABCD Agent!
(dramatic music)
- Wanna spork?
(screaming and electrical crackling)
(dramatic music)
- Why you little son of!
- Hey!
Drop the gun.
- [Hobart] Go.
- Drop the gun!
- No, man.
You drop your gun.
- They're not zombies.
They're just a couple of
desperate looking men with guns.
- You good?
(Electrical crackling)
Pick up Sudsy.
Hey!
(grunting)
Come one step closer and
I'm blowing his brains out.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- I mean it, man.
Sudsy will be history.
No pun intended.
- Look, let's just calm down.
- You calm down!
- Just stay calm.
Let the hostage go and
we can talk about this.
- I'm getting on that
plane, I'm taking Sudsy
and I'm going to Canada.
You can have him back when I'm done.
(meowing)
- We got you a plane.
Just leave Sudsy and go.
- I'm not doing anything until I see
that plane started up.
- Drop the gun and we'll
figure something out.
- Greetings, Wally.
- Hey, how's it going?
(crashing)
- Oh, it seems you've dropped your plane.
Wait a minute, that's
not a real plane, Wally.
- Oh no!
(gunshot)
(ethereal music)
- [Donka Voiceover] His
breath, not a sound.
(ricochet)
- I called it!
(dramatic music)
(gunshots)
- [Gladys] Ah, run!
(dramatic music)
- I ain't going back!
(guns firing)
Canada!
(purring)
(dramatic music)
(hissing cat)
- Higgins, no!
Higgins, oh!
(dramatic music)
- [Burt] Canada!
- Higgins, no!
(meowing)
- God, oh!
(coughing)
It got it in my mouth!
(spitting)
There's mummy dust in my
stinking eyes, Canada!
(grunting)
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
(meowing cat)
- Oh, thanks.
- Sorry about your cat, Mr. Mayor.
- Oh, I'm sure that after years
of therapy we'll both be fine.
- Ladies and gentlemen may
I present to you, Sudsy Slim
and his zombie gang.
And also his lost treasure.
- [Kate] How did that get in there?
- I think your grandpa
Sudsy didn't trust banks
and took to keistering his valuables.
- That would explain historical accounts
of how he jangled while he walked
but never wore spurs.
- Well come, good people.
All is well.
Higgins and our Sudsy
are both returned to us.
Let us away to the Slippery Nickel
for some celebration!
(uplifting music)
- Look at that.
What?
Hey, that's an eye for an eye.
It's in the Bible, you can look it up!
(triumphal music)
(funky music)
(light music)
(soft music)