SUKCES
Good day.
-Your tickets, please.
-Here you go.
-How can l identify you?
-That's me.
Take it off.
Haven't you heard
about Chernobyl?
-Radioactivity.
-Take it off.
lt's you. Here is your lD
and your ticket.
-Good bye.
-Thanks.
There is a time in a man's life
when every woman calls you
''my angel'' and wants to give you
her breast to suck.
lt never repeats itself
and later it's hard to find
even one volunteer.
Here they are.
The ones and only.
Just as pals from the army.
Marek...
Marek Late. Just a second.
My father.
Used to say l was a cute newborn
but they switched me in the ward.
l don't know if he was joking.
Things really started to happen
after l'd turned eight.
Wake up, sonny. Marek, wake up.
My mother. For her l was
the dearest
person on earth.
She let me believe
that for everything there was
a why and a wherefore.
That even an innocent event
could have irreversible
consequences.
Dear children,
let this holy water
remind you of your baptism.
Jesus will call upon you
to unite with Him.
This union
will occur fully
when for the first time, today
you'll receive
the Holy Communion.
-Do you renounce the evil spirit?
-Body of Christ.
Body of Christ.
Dear God! What about me?
But after all God
didn't forget about me.
And perhaps more out of pity
than real need he took interest
in my case.
Say cheese!
Hold on!
And the shoes.
From my childhood l remember
one day when l was going
home from school. l was ten.
For the first time l communicated
with my idol - God.
l'd never seen him,
but we had
good relations. But the Devil took
the shape of a small blonde.
Dear Lord...
That's me.
l've got a favour to ask.
Don't let them take me
to the blackboard.
Does it have to be now?
l'm talking to God.
-Which day of the month is it?
-The 23rd.
-Number 23.
-Please, God...
Marek Late,
come to the blackboard.
Tell me, please...
Why are you so scrawny?
So small? With such shiny eyes?
Cause right now
my mind is growing.
Dear God, you scared me.
l didn't pay attention.
-Why?
-Do you know what a woman is?
They were somehow wiser.
l wanted to be like them. And what?
A mistake.
The task has been accomplished.
We gathered... 30 kg
of waste paper.
Super! At the next meeting
you'll receive ''gatherer'' badges.
That's all.
-Can l do it next week?
-We're finished with this project.
But you can take
it to the purchasing centre
and get the ''thrifty'' badge.
What was l to do?
ln the paper mill where my father
worked they were short of paper.
l was pissed.
l'd always been the king of waste
paper, and now such a screwup.
But as it turned out it was all
a part of a Divine Plan.
My God came up with it for me.
Especially for me.
l didn't get the badge
and was thrown out of the scouts
for stealing books about Vinnetou,
but l had a new friend.
That was all that counted.
Carry them always on you.
Chief...
What is the most important
thing in life?
To be a chief.
What do you mean? Tell me!
What?!
Be a chief! Easy to say.
Be like Vinnetou, like famous
athlete, astronaut, boxer or pope.
Universe, Vatican...
Everything is taken.
They've been there, done that.
Weighted all, measured all.
And what of me?
Now what?
Come on.
l'd hoped that when l grew up
l'd better express my dreams.
''A ''.
''G''.
''Z''.
''B''.
''U''.
Skinny legs, pimples,
hair in strange places
and this part till now used only
for pissing, which'd taken
a new personality.
l spent long hours in the john,
urging him to fly.
l was flying...
We were flying together,
he was ahead, l followed.
Maciek... Wait up.
My soul hurts. l'm suffering.
Suffering.
Do you think about
who you want to become?
No.
-Where are you running to?
-Around.
l realised then
how difficult it was to find two
people thinking in the same way.
Help me.
How can l fulfil my ambitions?
l need something that will guide me.
-Here you go.
-Great. What am l to do with it?
You shoot, God carries the arrows.
O, my God!
Where's my armband?
l didn't want to go to school.
l didn't want to think.
-Move aside.
-l'm on strike.
-You're too young.
-Not at all.
What's the matter? Every year
you go to summer camp.
And away for the winter break.
Almost for free.
Let him rebel.
Medical care and vacations
almost for free.
You can study all you want,
provided you're gifted.
You can become an engineer,
What more do you want?
-Oranges.
-They are on their way from Cuba.
-Where is my fucking armband?
-Here.
Give it to me. l'm gonna go
and fight for your oranges.
l rebelled against my father,
he against the authorities.
He seemed such a great leader
that l had to follow him.
l'll never forget it.
A giant machine stops.
There is silence.
Father was sent to an internment
camp. Mother often visited him.
There was a crisis.
Meat was rationed,
and we were always hungry.
We needed meat.
l felt that something
was blocking me.
That something was deterring
my development.
Was coercing me.
Wrong word.
Was cramping my style.
That's right.
And then something happen.
Really something.
Alone! Ah, men!
And who of you,
divining my spirit,
grasps the meaning of its song?
Whose eye will see the radiance
of its shining?
Alas, who toils to sing
for men, toils long!
Shut the fuck up!
You...
savages!
You chickenshits!
You motherfuckers full of stink!
Shut the fuck up!
And that's that!
All of you! Stand up!
Give me
the rule of souls!
This lifless building
that common people call the world,
and praise,
l so despise that l have
never tested whether my word
has not the power to raze
and ruin it. But well l know
if through the portal
of air l swiftly shot my will
l might put out a hundred stars
and light a hundred still,
for l am immortal!
Chief!
Where are you!
-What's your problem?
-l'm looking for Vinnetou.
-That's me.
-Give me the rule of souls...
-What?
-l want to be an actor.
The amount of radiation poses
no real health threat.
Yes. lt was the big explosion
at Chernobyl.
And that man caused a great
eruption of dreams in my brain.
Oh, the great year 1 986.
The year of the big explosion.
At last l knew
what it meant to be a chief.
l took off to become a chief.
l left chaos behind. There was
a straight road in front of me.
l felt like a man.
lt's very manly to set a goal
and then to pursue it.
Thanks.
l'm travelling by train
for the first time.
l'm afraid too, chief.
l had a lot of experience,
l had a goal,
there was one straight road ahead.
One straight road.
Silence!
Please, be quiet!
l want to welcome you
to our school. Tom Burzynski alias
Thunder. l'm studying directing.
l'm here to take care of you.
What's the name of this school?
lt's a drama school.
30 people for one place.
So be humble. Over there
you see a list. You go
in alphabetical order.
Prepare your lines.
Concentrate, take two deep breaths,
and go in. ls that clear?
-l can't here you!
-Yes!
Thanks.
What have you prepared?
The Great lmprovisation.
Man... They all have that.
You have to be...
unique. Otherwise they won't
notice you. Want a smoke?
-lt's forbidden.
-Not for us.
l saw him smiling at you.
-Who?
-This one, on the stand.
You saw it?
He'd seen it. Really seen it.
l realised that next to me there
was someone like me. A friend.
What's your name?
-Marek Late.
-Gate?
Late.
Don't sweat it. My last name
also beginns with a ''p''. Wiktor.
Wiktor... my friend.
He suggested that we
should take the exam together.
He would play sour milk
and l would play a bottle.
Strange but very original.
lt's not easy to be
a believable bottle.
You've got to be sure
that you control what's inside.
That sour milk.
You've got to give it shape.
What would be sour milk
without a bottle?
A white spot.
You'll play the bottle,
l will be sour milk.
You are talented.
You'll make a career.
l've got other plans.
Come, l show you a real rehearsal
and a real actress.
-That's our task.
-And that we must do.
What's your answer?
-Martha.
-Go away.
My...
-You know.
-Leave me alone.
Love or power.
l have to choose between them.
Why can't l have everything?
After all l am a queen.
-l'm sorry...
-Well...
Very sorry.
-Am l awake?
-You're dreaming.
ls it a dream?
Will you stay?
Yes.
-Are you playing?
-No.
-So...
-Let the moment last.
-He pretends that he knows how to.
-And does he?
He'll say that he hasn't got
the right tools.
lf l had the right tools...
What the fuck?
What is she doing?
Pissing me off.
And what?
Drive.
How did you do it?
By magic.
ltching elbows,
buttertlies in the stomach,
runny brain, viral infection
of the thoughts. Only Martha.
Nobody, nothing. Just her.
She was everywhere.
Wherever l looked.
The streets were full of her.
Cars were humming. A light breeze
was murmuring in a cloud of fumes.
l thought then...
Now l know.
l know!
l know what it means to be a chief.
lt means to love.
Sure.
To love people and values.
And your goal.
But l'm in love.
l love her.
What's with your face? War paint?
We've been drafted.
How come?
What about Martha?
Drama school?
We flunked.
He was right. We flunked.
-As solders of the Polish Army...
-Not all of us. Wiktor passed.
-... guard the rule of the people...
-He was more convincing
- as a buttermilk that l as a bottle.
- ... in alliance with Soviet Army...
My bottle couldn't hold sour milk.
lt was brim-full with love.
... from imperialism.
Martha didn't have time to come
and see me swear my oath.
Am l do be disloyal
to my country, let me be punished
by the people's justice.
Attention! Right, march!
l wrote to her many letters.
She didn't reply but l was sure
she was thinking of me.
There is so quiet here at dusk.
Only the rustle of wind.
Up!
Down!
Get a fucking move on!
Up!
ls this ''down'' !
And such a warm wave comes
over me when l think of you.
Late, hurry up!
Down!
Move it!
Music exercises were my favourite.
l attended them all cause l wasn't
allowed to leave the base.
Dear God, that's me.
-Marek Late.
-Who?
l've not been in touch
but l have a request.
l want to leave here.
l'm in love, you know...
Love is everything.
-l have to get out of here.
-Then go.
l craved oranges.
Not stringy, Cuban
but rather Spanish, Moroccan
or Greek. Heaps of oranges.
Drink up. lt's on me.
But now we had to straighten
some things up.
We tried to do it
like seasoned actors.
You should get in now.
l'm well connected.
We'll see.
l don't want any favours.
You'll find out tomorrow.
Come now.
Tomorrow...
How is it between you two?
Tasty bread sticks.
Why don't you talk to me?
Salty.
Why haven't you written to me?
Not that much.
lt was sudden. l don't know you.
Don't you like beer?
How is it between you two?
Not particularly.
l like him. We are pals.
What about you?
Let's have it out straight.
l love it.
l love Martha. And you?
Really?
What about me?
Yeah.
What are your plans?
lt's all the same to me.
Don't spoil the fun.
We haven't reached an agreement.
There were two of us,
and only one of her.
Do you like convertibles?
l like other things.
We are going to the Caribbean.
-Want to go with us?
-Yeah.
l passed.
PRONUNClATlON
Count your teeth with your tongue.
Left to right and back.
Stretch all the face muscels.
Pretend to be a roe deer.
Wake up, girls.
You are roe deer.
And now take a deep breath,
open your mouth
and tighten your muscels.
Congratulations.
Remember that it is a calling
to be an actor.
An actor should set
an example for others.
He reins over people's souls.
Keeps guard over his native tongue.
You don't remember me
but you came to my high school
to recite poetry.
-Quite so...
-You won.
-Should l give you a lift?
-What do you drive?
The same car as 20 years ago.
-We'll walk.
-You should never give up.
You must perform.
You know it well, Martha.
You play in the theatre.
Yes, step by step.
-You should build your happiness.
-l've got something better for you.
Something better. A plan.
l thought it through
while you were away.
l prepared everything.
My uncle has a jewellery store.
At the front there are
cameras, alarms,
at the back nothing.
You go in, open the vault,
and you find a great loot.
Diamonds, gold...
Uncle is a collector. You fill
your rucksack and leave.
And you are a king of life!
Once l read in a john,
''Check your shit for diamonds''.
Everything is possible.
He told you about the heist?
From now on l only eat caviar.
Scram!
You can eat cheese if you wish.
What are you looking at?
You.
The tree is rustling.
Louder! l wanna hear it!
-Where is the second tree?
-What's your fucking hurry?
-Wiktor?
-Did you want to play alone?
Pear! Come on!
l wanna see pear on stage!
Get up!
Move it! Your lines.
l'm a pear and they are dwarfs.
Wiktor, now you!
Broader! We're in a theatre.
Broader. That's it!
Get up!
Don't destroy
the fucking branches.
What are you doing?
You're looking well.
You too.
How old are you?
-As old as everybody else.
-l need someone like you. Worn out.
-For a commercial.
-What?
-l want you for a commercial.
-OK.
One condition.
No smoking on the set.
l haven't really played
in anything.
Don't wanna end up as a detergent.
l'd rather play Hamlet.
Give me a ring.
Tomasz Burzynski,
director
Your tree was great.
The urinals are making music.
No! You can't be a whore.
As an actor and your teacher
l repeat, ''No!''.
You are to young and
too gifted to sell out.
Your calling is to play
in a theatre.
You have to choose:
art or commercials.
Thank you.
-l believe in myself again.
-Give it to me.
So it won't tempt the others.
Thanks. You've saved me.
Success, career...
This l can't decipher.
-l see a loaded man.
-Who is he?
-lt's not that simple.
-Do you know?
Someone very smart,
-with a sense of humour.
-l know who you're talking about.
Such people are a rarity.
Does he love me?
-l don't see it.
-Come on.
Look closely.
-l see an initial of his name.
-l know it.
-''W''
-''M''. The way l look at it.
A good one.
This is Martha. Leave a massage
after the beep.
l've always wanted to bring
you here. lt's my place.
Beautiful, isn't it?
-That's right.
-Everything is beneath you.
Beautiful.
You know what?
Forget about Martha.
You forget about her.
Why should you force yourself?
She's not a woman for you.
You're hopelessly in love.
Maybe there is hope.
And you're the one that's in love.
The other day in the bar you said
that it was all the same to you.
lt's not like that for me.
You know why you are here?
-You brought me.
-l didn't want to be in the army.
And you got in cause my mom
was one of the judges.
Don't act so surprised.
That was what you wanted.
Did you think
you were so talented?
Marek!
You can't even handle your hands.
Such a great actor.
You and Martha are alike.
You both come from small towns.
You think you're so special.
Shit!
Two knights were competing
for the hand of a princess.
She liked them both
and didn't know
how to choose between them.
Her father, the king, organised
a tournament,
which was supposed
to settle the matter.
- Greetings, noble sir.
- Greetings, spotless knight.
l swear on my honour that this
fight will be noble and beautiful.
My sentiments exactly.
To the death.
Stop, noble knights.
Before you draw first blood
let us talk about it peacefully.
The king should agree.
Let us talk.
Let us sit at a round table.
Thanks. lt's a wrap.
Great. They've bought it.
Don't be mad. l was drunk.
... the authorities
and the opposition.
They often knew each other
only from the newspapers.
ln a few minutes they'll appear
together on our TV screens.
People can come to an agreement.
Nothing is that difficult
that you have to fight over it.
We weren't enemies.
We were brothers,
accidentally standing
on opposite sides of a barricade.
lt must end well.
Go!
Wait a minute!
Marek,
-l'm not playing with you.
-Hold on!
When l was a kid l wanted
to eat my fill of oranges.
You know...
l used to say to my mom,
''l want oranges''.
And she replied, ''Sonny,
they are on their way from Cuba.
They will arrive in a three
weeks time''. And she smiled.
Do you remember green oranges?
Green, stringy and incredibly
sweet oranges.
-They were from Cuba. Remember?
-l remember parcels in the church.
There was detergent
and cheese inside.
Some cheese was orange in colour.
Marek!
Coming.
-Go ahead.
-l'm going.
l'll be right back.
Go if you want.
l'm going.
For the road.
-Check it out.
-What?
Oranges. Uncle Gierek is in town.
-Uncle Gierek...
-Eat.
-l'm full.
-What's the matter?
-l can't.
ls everything all right?
-Talk!
-lt's not.
Then take her. Understood?
You've fucking won.
-Devour her.
-God, you're stupid.
What have you done?
Am l bleeding?
Yeah...
Am l?
Nescafe, makes
you life colourtul.
Hi. That's me.
l can't talk.
Marek is at my place.
We moved in together.
She had a child but l didn't mind.
We loved each other.
Help me!
-Nobody will help you!
-Stop!
Don't move! Release
that beauty or...
-Or what?
-No!
-What's the matter?
-Why don't you talk?
-Why don't we.
-What about?
My saviour.
For the first time l was tasting
the every day aspect of love.
l had to make a living.
A beautiful woman needs
a beautiful frame.
l started working like a madman.
-What are you doing?
-l love you.
Wiktor prefers blondes
Wiktor's victory
You're late.
-What's that?
-Something stolen.
That's for you. Try them on.
Try them on?
Stockings?
-People are looking.
-Try them on.
They were very expensive.
OK.
Hurry up.
Marek, let's get away.
-Where to?
-Wherever.
-l'm suffocating here.
-What about Australia?
All right.
Please, think it over.
With you l'll go to the end
of the earth.
Let's stay.
With you l can stay.
Come here. Give me a kiss.
l love you.
Dear God?
Dear God? Can you hear me?
lt's me. Marek Late.
-l wanted to...
-This line is overloaded.
No wonder. Millions of worshippers
were praying,
focusing on themselves God's
attention. And l only
wanted to thank Him for her.
How is love?
Love?
-Chief, it's wonderful.
-Are you sure?
Yes. Even if it's not wonderful
it's wonderful.
These are the best moments
of my life.
Why are you lying?
Take your mark.
-lntroduce yourself.
-Marek Late.
- Agency?
- l'm an actor.
The sides.
Right side.
Left.
Show me joy.
Sadness.
Anger.
Absentmindedness.
Love.
-What kind of commercial is it?
-You'll find out if they choose you.
Thanks.
And do something
with those hands.
Your plans for the future?
l've got a few
but l don't want to jinx it
- by elaborating on them.
- And your private plans?
-l'm planing to go on a vacation.
-You can afford it.
You're a successful man.
lt's rare among your generation.
You know...
lt's a very complicated issue.
We, now in our thirties,
are in a difficult situation.
We were too young to fight
for freedom and now we're too old
to take advantage
of our European upbringing.
We have a special task.
We should not let anybody
call us ''the lost generation''.
Beautifully put. How about love?
Do women always
choose strong men with money?
That's a stereotype. Women
don't need money. They eat
like birds, drink very little
and don't spend
on lady friends.
-Go ahead.
-Shall we?
l mastered the hamburger.
Now you try it.
Yes...
What's up?
l'm all right.
Really.
OK.
l've go to go.
-l didn't hear you come in.
-Who was it?
-We have to pay the rent.
-Was it Wiktor?
Turn it off.
Yes, it was Wiktor.
He has a job for you.
What kind of a job?
Background in a commercial.
Cut!
Thanks a lot.
-Another take.
-l'll help you.
l can manage.
-Camera!
-Rolling.
Action!
l mastered the hamburger.
Now you try it. Yuck!
No!
l'm going out!
Martha?
Will you marry me?
Long or short answer?
Short.
l'll think about it.
Go.
This is Martha. Leave a massage
after the beep.
Let's go, son.
You've changed.
l'd changed. They remained
the same and l...
Why hadn't l noticed it before?
Why didn't anybody tell me?
End of the route!
-Why?
-lt doesn't pay to go further.
Late?
Marek Late?
Don't you recognise me?
l recognised you at once.
Everybody knows your face.
-Do l know you?
-Maciek. We used to jog together.
-You wore glasses.
-Had surgery.
Looking great, pal. You've made it
in Warsaw. Everybody envies you.
l've seen you in that commercial.
What a career.
-Can l give you a lift?
-l'd rather walk.
We have to celebrate our meeting.
What do you say? My treat.
Get in!
Will you eat something?
He got laid off
and for his severance pay
he bought a TV and a satellite
dish.
Now he switches between channels.
Sometimes he catches you.
You look the same as before.
You haven't changed.
But the world has.
l'm glad you're a success.
Marek?
-Where to?
-l'll be right back.
Let's have it out strait.
l don't wear a wedding band.
Business, you know.
l make balloons.
-l don't complain. Girls!
-Balloons...
- Get ready. We'll need a refill.
- Of the cream.
-Why are you so quiet?
-l'm talking the whole time.
l know all of you.
Everybody envies you here.
-Fuck off!
-What?
Pour.
And the ducks quack-quack-quack...
And the cow...
l looked into the eyes
of an actor from Warsaw.
Don't complain.
Come here!
Don't sweat it!
This is Martha.
Leave a massage after the beep.
Marek!
l'm done.
l've got my own.
You've left me. You've fled.
''The most important thing
is to be a chief!''
Pride! l don't have any pride?
Really!
l don't have any pride?
Dear God, and now what?
No!
Will you marry me?
Long or short answer?
Short.
l'll think about it.
There is a time in a man's life
that although he didn't die
he is born anew.
lt's a good time. The best.
Unless you are not you.
l won't need them any more.
-Did you say something?
-Rest.
Subtitles Ripped by chochosis