It's the Church of our Lady!
- Are you blind?
It's the cathedral.
- No, it's the Church of our Lady.
Two domes! Like tits!
Everybody knows it has two domes...
Why else would it be called
the Church of our Lady?
Nick? It's Jochen.
What's with the books?
I'm due two first editions.
You owe me 150 euros, too.
So come by.
Don't be shy.
Goodbye.
Nikita... it's me.
Call me, will you?
Don't you dare show up here. Ciao.
Hello Nick?
What's up?
Can I move back in?
Are you done painting?
Call me, will you?
It's really time you moved out! Bye.
Hi, Nick.
You're not returning calls again.
If you're hiding out
because you fucked up again,
we'll make you regret it.
Get me the money
or you'll be sorry. Bye.
Hey Nick, Lana here.
I got a tip, there's a villa
in Feldafing that's vacant.
You could hide out
there for a while.
But then we're even, okay?
Call me.
Bye.
We're going south...
What's that mountain range?
Yes, they're the Alps!
SUPEREGOS
Hello.
Rosa Ledig.
Nick.
I thought it was Franz.
Nick-Franz.
Friends call me Nick.
Yes.
Good that you're here.
I'm in a hurry.
Come in.
Yes.
Where did you meet Uli?
She only said you were friends.
Yes, we share common...
experiences.
Experiences.
- Yes, encounters and so on.
So, I'll show you the room.
It's delicate trusting someone
with your parents' house.
Absolutely.
I thought you'd be more conventional.
Anyway, I'm glad you're here
to look after the house.
Right... yes...
what else was there?
The sightseeing tour.
Come along.
The bathroom...
The subconscious
sends a signal to act.
This is sometimes
incorrectly executed,
and then, in retrospect,
our detective,
the consciousness,
defines this as our intention.
Stimulus... effect.
We're preparing a short film about you.
We want to feature your lecture
at the symposium.
Hence the next question:
will you speak
about the theory you just described,
or about other things?
I think I'll have to pursue...
a completely different... personal issue:
Oh, yes?
- I refer to the era of the Third Reich.
In this context,
Charles Steinbach once said
"Curt Ledig is one of the 20th century's
key psychologists and thinkers.
But unfortunately... he was a Nazi."
- How flattering.
Flattering?
Well, my writings
have indeed been influential...
but one of the most important
of the 20th century?
Who can say that?
But his accusations...
- Which?
That you were a Nazi.
Oh, yes, that...
Is the light bothering you?
- No.
Back then, as a young man,
your academic career...
was partly due to Goebbels' approval
of your early texts.
No, that is...
most complicated.
- Oops!
That was me. Sorry.
Time's up.
We have to go.
Can't we do another ten minutes?
- No, we've got to go.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
When is it being broadcasted?
- We don't know yet.
We'll let you know.
- Great.
By email or telephone?
Hello.
Papa, could you come here, please?
You know, I've changed my mind.
It's not a good idea, after all.
What?
- To leave the house now.
There's too much to do.
But you can work at our house.
- No, my office is here.
And all my things. I...
I have to...
prepare it here.
You could do that just as well at ours.
- No.
Come on, Papa. Don't be difficult.
What about Franz-Nick?
- Oh, he's no trouble.
Can you drive?
A manual, yes.
Manual?
It's decided.
You know what, Papa?
You're exhausting.
No really!
Stubborn as an ox.
That's just what I wanted to avoid.
My kids are waiting.
What shall I do with you both?
Can you even take care of him?
One condition:
danger money.
For you or for my father?
How do I know
you'll take good care of him?
Feminine intuition?
A little bit of respect and my father
is easy to handle. Get me?
He can do most things alone.
But you have to shop.
And he never cooks.
He has this kitchen-phobia.
This is all just temporary, of course.
Hello?
- Wait a moment, please.
Did you pay for the taxi, buddy?
Er, yes.
- Good.
We have something to discuss.
I just wanted...
- This really isn't the time.
You can go on to the house.
I'll be right there.
Good?
He'd better not be staying.
- He's just bringing my things.
Take good care, Franz-Nick.
- Don't you worry, now.
He'll be right there,
you can leave the meter running.
Franz...
unfortunately...
the situation has changed.
The old man is dead.
Oh!
I'm so sorry.
- Yes...
Very sad.
I'm here to tidy up his affairs.
But...
thanks for coming.
No really, thank you.
Too bad
you had to come all this way
for nothing.
Well then, goodbye.
Thanks again.
Give me that.
- Yes, thank you... Oh, boy.
What?
- Oh, nothing.
Shut that door!
"Concentration"?
You hit the nail on its sensitive head.
At the symposium I'll speak
about the darkest chapter
in my life.
It's...
just not that simple.
How do you make a living?
- Doing business.
Business.
- You have one?
Not exactly. I buy books
for two euros and sell them for ten.
I'm beginning to understand.
You love old books.
I took an interest
in old things once.
Now they are more like
a second skin to me.
Keep grubby mitts
off ancient lit!
One moment.
We have much to do.
Wednesdays at 11.
I get a massage.
Thursdays... Thursdays...
I visit my friend Hélène.
You'll have the opportunity to meet her.
Thursday?
- Huh? Yes.
Thursday is bad.
We'll manage.
'Night.
Well, I don't know.
Krazy Kat would be interesting,
but given the condition...
Nope, no.
The Plato is expensive
but it's worth it.
It's that great translation
by this humanist Agricola.
The Ferrari of Plato translations.
I'll stick with Atomic Eye.
It's more my thing.
But then we're even.
It wasn't exactly cheap.
Even?
Little shitter!
You're dreaming, son.
That hardly covers my costs.
Now you get a provisional fix
till you can deliver.
Let's hope it holds till then.
You're a bloody thief!
My comics will be buying your kids
a hybrid Hummer.
A what?
- A hybrid Hummer...
you bastard.
- See what I have to deal with?
I'm too kind, too benevolent...
let myself be exploited.
Open up, now.
There.
Wonderful.
So, now fingers here.
Good.
Now we wait till the mass hardens.
Then I'll be back.
We'll be right back.
Everything fine here?
- Yes.
Great.
One moment,
the mass just has to harden.
Gutlicht, you dog!
Oh shit!
Come out, you prick!
Bastard!
Wonderful.
Lacan... get lost!
You beast!
What time is it?
- It's after six already.
So late?
- Do you also make breakfast?
Can't you do that yourself?
No, the kitchen was my wife's domain.
lam excluded.
- Good excuse.
Three sugars and black, thanks.
Are you incapable or unwilling?
Of what?
Of entering the kitchen.
- Yes.
I'm prepared to go and get the paper.
What's your name?
Nick.
Fine, Nick...
The first foot.
Are you love sick?
Why, Professor?
You smell of oleander.
Lilac flowers.
The passion killer among the flowers!
It's not perfume, it's the massage oil.
Interesting...
You're the worst crossbreed
between a sewer rat and a book worm!
Thanks, sweet of you.
I have something for you.
Hey!
- That's where you belong.
What do you take me for?
A first edition of sentimental value;
spine broken, condition poor.
A mercy killing is what I'd recommend.
500... and the blouse.
Forget it.
Less than 3000 is a joke.
All right...
2900, the blouse and skirt.
750,
the blouse, the skirt,
and the boots.
and I get the panties, too.
Now strip
or I'll strangle you!
Entry one:
A new file on the man
living here with me.
Name and date...
unknown.
Where he's from is also unknown.
Too bad.
He's taken a work from my library.
Which precisely, I don't know,
but with the obvious intention
of concealing this from me.
Observations in his room...
Incredibly ugly.
Modern architecture?
- Yes, it's a villa.
It's a town house in the country. Vile!
It's functional, it's really pretty.
Functional!
It must be from the GDR.
Typical GDR.
This here was the GDR?
- In the style of the GDR.
It's obvious. They built it that way.
Without any taste.
I want to take a photo.
Andreas, be quiet. I have to concentrate!
Are you leaving the house today?
- I have to go into town.
You can take my car.
- Thanks.
Good.
I have to go into town, anyway.
But I'll be there all day.
- Excellent.
Sorry, I can't take you with me.
Then leave the car here.
Don't turn left here, drive straight on.
Watch the oncoming traffic.
It's heavy and fast because
they're coming from the highway.
So, then up there...
turn in right at the grey gate.
Well, I've got to go.
You can take a taxi home.
Will you give me the car keys?
We won't stay long.
If you please...
Thank you.
Hélène always has pretty companions.
I've known Ms. Tischmann
very long, let me tell you.
I think she's my oldest
living colleague and friend...
This is...
Hello, hello.
- Nick.
Have you had breakfast?
Careful.
Nick?
Nick, just dive in if you want.
I swim a few lengths every day.
I don't have trunks with me.
That doesn't...
-... matter.
Towels are over there.
Is this your... chaperon?
They hired him for me.
He's a not-uninteresting man.
A friendly drifter,
unruly, angry... full of passion.
Are you practicing again?
- No, no, no!
Under no circumstances.
She's not totally unerotic.
Neither of them are.
- No.
Look,
they're swimming together...
Are you French?
- Alsatian.
Alsatian...
An Alsatian
who won't enter the kitchen!
That's rare.
You'll have to tell me your name again.
Nick.
- Nick, Nick, Nick.
And where are you from?
The industrial zone.
From the Ruhr Area?
You don't like to talk about it.
I grew up in Linz.
The working man's part.
My mother was a cook.
Grew up in humble conditions,
father unknown,
mother a cook.
Shamefully anal,
latent Oedipal.
You feeling okay?
- Yes, yes.
Where should I drop you off?
Just keep driving.
Culture bulletin!
“Psychology in Transition“,
is the title of an Academy Symposium
being held in two weeks.
We particularly look forward to seeing
thinker and psychologist Curt Ledig,
who is to be the guest of honor.
Ledig's work on crowd psychology
made him famous.
He will speak on Saturday at 5:30 p.m.
with culture historian Bernd Wälzer.
How did you get this fine piece?
- Divine providence.
1060, it's all I have.
You get the rest when I've sold it, okay?
In a hurry, sweetie?
No romance without finance.
Shithead.
Wait here.
He divided up the money
and took only some of it with him.
There may be method to this.
He has been badly beaten
and looks in bad shape.
Get out!
What?
- Out! -Okay, okay!
Who is that?
- René.
He did this to you?
- Yes.
I owed Mother money.
Whom? Speak clearly.
- His boss.
I owed his boss money.
- Your mother?
She's not my mother.
- No?
No.
- Well?
She wanted more money.
So you gave her my car.
I wouldn't say I gave it to her.
She just took it!
Now how do you like that!
Professor, don't!
Prof...
Then get some help, use your head.
Yes, sure.
No, no way... Wait...
Well?
- A young man was just here.
He returned in a very bad condition.
And then my car was...
confiscated,
or rather, stolen.
Apparently on the orders of a lady...
known as Mother.
- You must be mistaken.
Hold on, I'll call you back.
Are you Mother?
- What is it you want?
I want my car back.
You have the keys.
- It was your car?
Bad luck.
Mother...
You hit people,
and they call you Mother.
Very interesting.
Sad.
Give me the keys, please.
You want a car?
Buy one.
An Astra...
Let's see... 2500 euros?
I won't pay for my own car.
- Now listen here...
your friend owes me over 15000.
And you're making a fuss
about an old Astra?
It's just a down-payment.
And the rest is due soon.
Tell that to your protégé.
Are you...
Now I'm mad.
René!
Let him have it!
Who let the old idiot in, anyway?
I shouldn't have let you go in there.
But you still have money.
Why didn't you pay more?
And what would I live from, then?
That's not how you do business.
I miscalculated slightly,
but you never completely pay back
these people or you're lost.
Where'd you get that idea from?
It's best not to borrow
in the first place.
And I don't like going to Mother
and getting beaten up.
You can believe me.
These are obviously repetitive patterns.
Cyclical, so to speak.
Now...
I'll play the role of the father.
Oh no... Papa!
Associate freely: spinning top.
No.
- Yes! Go.
Spinning top.
- Please spare me your psycho crap.
Try to visualize.
Enter into a dialogue.
I'll start again... spinning top.
No.
- Yes.
No!
- Go. Spinning top.
Will you stop with that shit!
Try to visualize...
I'll start again.
Spinning top.
Pain in the ass.
Backyard.
Blood-sucker.
Mother.
Cold dog.
Father.
Blue Danube.
Wavy locks.
- No, no, no!
Don't evade. Everything is fine.
Continue. You...
...nited states.
- The States.
Counties.
- Counties.
Communities.
Love.
- Shut up!
Easy now...
Imagine...
that you are a small tree
planted in stony soil.
I have to get out.
They broke my ribs.
Listen to me, stay with the image.
You are the tree.
Now someone builds a wall around you,
that shelters you from the wind
and protects the soil.
Stay with the image.
You develop...
and grow strong and tall.
Suddenly this wall
that has always protected you
becomes a corset
that makes breathing difficult.
Feel it.
You will try to break through that wall,
but if you fail...
you will stay where you are.
That's tough.
Just let it happen.
You made great progress.
You will notice it.
Hello.
There you are.
- Hello Fafa.
How unexpected.
- Well...
Hello.
Mr. Franz-Nick, right?
Fanny.
We haven't met,
but my sister told me about you.
I wasn't expecting you all.
We just got back
from San Francisco today,
and decided to visit you first
before going to the cabin.
Karina and the kids are here,
they're joining us for a few days.
But what happened to you?
Oh, it's a long story.
Well, come on in, then.
Look who's here.
Curt, hi, hey.
There he is... Morle!
How are you?
- I'm well.
Yes?
- Hello, Grandfather.
You, too.
Hello Curt.
- Hello, how are you?
Well, thanks.
- You're sweating.
Well, I think Curt looks frightful.
The house stinks,
that guy smoked everywhere.
We were in the garage,
the side window
is completely non-existent.
The car window is broken, Mama,
and shards are everywhere.
Won't you have something to eat?
Uh-huh.
Gladly.
Please...
Excuse me...
Thank you.
So what happened to you?
I had to pay money back.
And injured yourself doing so.
And my father?
He waited outside.
And got injured there? No!
No, sadly he got angry and decided
to speak to those people.
And then?
Then they got a little rough.
Just a little.
What?
Yes, he was really lucky.
It's not funny.
And you dare just tell us this?
This is entirely unacceptable.
I see what my father sees in you,
you're a not-uninteresting case,
but tomorrow we're taking father...
with us and will no longer need you.
May I leave the kitchen to you?
- Sure...
No problem.
He's gone.
Is anything missing?
I feel awful...
I...
I can't.
- Why not?
I can't go in there.
- You can't enter the kitchen?
No...
I don't know what's going on...
I had the weirdest dreams...
I was the old guy
and felt so horrible.
What old guy?
No... the... the...
Curt Ledig,
the guy I was living with.
The psychologist Curt Ledig?
You didn't mention that.
I can go into the other rooms...
All the others are okay...
But...
not this one.
Should I carry you over the threshold,
sweetie?
Let's give it a try.
Nick?
Am I in the bathroom or the kitchen?
Should I really tell you?
- No.
No...
That's great!
Help me!
You could start out smaller.
Try the Studiosa Model.
Studiosa?
The fucking Nazi!
What about Goebbels?
- Goebbels had my essay printed.
Yes.
Are they good?
- No.
That pleased me, back then, as a student.
That's true, yes.
It got me the teaching post
in Freiburg.
Isn't that right?
- Yes, that's how it was.
Sartre was right.
I'm nauseating.
Sartre never said you're nauseating.
Don't always contradict, Stephanie.
- I don't always contradict.
You've done it again.
Nauseating!
Do you know what Dr. Schwarz said
last time we saw him?
No, and I don't want to.
Well, he said you need our support
and shouldn't live alone anymore.
That's what he said.
Who said that?
Your family doctor.
This intermezzo with that Nick-Franz...
showed that this won't work.
We're not going back to Feldafing.
You'll live with Rosa now.
- That's enough, Stephanie!
Oh, mother mine!
The raving idiot!
Whom did he call thus?
"The Prince of Homburg,
clutching at the wreath."
Beloved, why do you recoil?
My Natalie!
"He snatches a glove
from the Princess' hand."
Heaven and earth!
What laid he hands on there?
The wreath?
Nick?
- You can't throw him out.
He'll be gone
before you can say "Kuala Lumpur".
Right, that's the worst thing...
you can't even throw him out.
I think we'll do it on Friday.
Saturday's okay, too...
Sometime...
Not for sale, not for sale, not for sale!
But they have price tags.
- Out. This is not a telephone booth!
Hello?
Yes.
- Listen, I was about to buy some books...
Why from the dentist's?
No!
No, I can't come.
What?
- She won't come.
Mrs. Proehl is ready in room one.
The waiting room is packed.
Oh, crap. I'll be right there.
He is me, the old guy.
But only partially.
The kitchen-thing, for example...
and the eye...
and anyway,
it's this general feeling...
How many sugars does he take?
- Very funny.
It's creepy...
and really sucks.
- Utterly, yes.
I'm busy, get to the point.
Are you nuts? There's no smoking here.
Give me that.
If you want to catch a tiger,
you have to enter its cave.
Mr. Sochurek, are you coming?
- Yes, I am.
Nick Gutlicht here. I'm not available.
- Hello, Mr. Nick?
Leave a message after the beep.
You're not there.
My situation is not good.
I cannot work here.
Please come here at once and pick...
get me out of here!
Tyrol,
August 23...
Cordially...
Ledig.
He's there!
- How did you find him?
I saw him from up there.
Grandfather...
Oh God! Grandfather!
He's freezing cold.
Anne, run quickly to Fanny.
Tell her to run a hot bath.
Fanny!
- And tell the others...
to come and help.
"The questions that torment me
will soon make me perfect...
...ly insane."
Oh!
"I must set this right."
What must you set right?
- Not me.
Curt.
What must you set right, Grandfather?
"I want to set right my motives,
I don't know
how much time I have left.
"Matsutake Titiku..."
Sorry, I can't read this...
"says:
'The morning... glory blooms
but an hour...
and yet it differs not at heart
from the... giant pine that lives
for a thousand years."'
"I'm cold, I want to get out."
Mu Tsi?
Look.
- What?
I've never seen him before.
- Nor have I.
Can you drive?
What do you think, can he cure me?
I think
you triggered something together...
and now you want to see it through.
I don't know...
It's always good if a therapeutic
process is not abruptly interrupted.
It'll definitely be interesting.
He hasn't practiced therapy in 50 years.
You!
Is that your car?
Hey kid...
What's the magic word?
- Thanks.
Nice tic!
That was your Nazi voodoo.
What?
Nazi what?
Your blitz therapy.
Remember? I'm your victim!
You look interesting.
I didn't recognize you at all.
I'm glad you're here.
We'll see about that.
Come home at once.
Yes, yes, yes.
Fanny!
Now let me work in peace, please.
Thanks.
Yes... See you soon.
Bye-bye.
They're coming.
All of them, I think.
Mama, Papa,
being silent is unhealthy!
You made me go gaga,
now make me normal again.
Is gaga a synonym
for the existential crisis
of a small-time crook?
No, this is gaga.
I can't go in the kitchen, either.
I feel like shit.
And... It's you who's the crook...
And I want to know
how you're going to fix me up now.
What did I do to you?
- Don't you remember?
All that shit with...
USA, county, community...
the association crap.
I never imagined
you'd react to it so well.
And you want to continue? Excellent.
How do we continue?
- I absolutely must prepare my lecture.
You'll never manage a lecture,
you wreck!
So forget it.
And either we start now,
or I'm taking you back
to your family at once.
Coffee would be nice.
- It'd be nice, yes.
I thought you couldn't go in the kitchen.
No, no!
You can keep that symptom for yourself.
This therapy, how long does it last?
Two years, two months...
that depends on you.
That's too long.
Then I'll have to invent
a blitz therapy.
But then you'll help me get in shape.
Bernie?
- I am here.
You won't believe the stuff
they've got lying around.
There's a complete
Encyclopaedia Britannica.
Yeah, I know.
Hello?
Curt?
Hello...
Jasper...
- Is anything missing?
Police? There's been a break-in
and we caught them red-handed.
No, they're escaping right now.
No idea.
- I'm at 10, Bergstrasse,
in Curt Ledig's house.
Someone might still be there.
Don't go too far.
Don't all go away.
We'll wait.
- Mama!
They should come!
- Are you coming?
No, we'll wait, but are you coming?
- Come here. I'm all alone here.
Mama!
- God, this is terrible.
Mama asked me where I had it from,
I told her I'd stolen it
and she slapped me.
She did what?
- Gave me a slap.
I had to take the chewing gum
back to the shop and say sorry,
even though
it was already in my mouth.
Pretty unpleasant.
And at the time
I didn't feel guilty at all.
Oh yes, guilt, guilt!
Egomaniacal
and with no conscience!
You think?
- Well...
Why?
I could have avoided that guilt.
We're talking about me.
- Yes, yes...
Let's speak about you.
Do you think... that I...
that I'm guilty?
Fitness is essential.
This will freshen you up.
Shit!
Well?
Where was the elephant,
little scoundrel?
Well, where's the elephant?
Ah.
And there's the other one!
You have the upper hand again.
Well...
Whale!
- Where was the whale?
I've become a stranger in my own past.
Deeper.
Easy for you to say.
Feel the weight of the shovel.
Accept it.
So.
These new sticks are really fantastic.
Where was I...
where was I?
Regardless...
You will see,
it's a successful transference.
You are developing.
We're digging towards the core.
What do you mean, "We"?
Hey, careful!
This is an established ascetic method...
as far as I know...
Since Claude Lévi-Strauss...
Like shamans
walking over hot coals. Only different.
Your symptoms will flee...
like birds from a scarecrow.
It might get hot.
Would you put your hat on my head?
Twenty minutes,
then you get me out of here.
Get me?
Twenty minutes!
I remember now, Nick.
You stole from me.
On first-name terms now, are we?
Don't be evasive now!
You stole from me.
Because
that's also your mode of dialogue.
I see it as a compliment.
Talk to...
the dead ant.
Dialogue bullshitter!
You're not ready yet.
We agreed on twenty minutes.
I want to get out now.
I need a pee.
You Nazi!
You Nazi bastard!
Shut your mouth!
You haven't a clue.
You old Nazi fag!
- Rhubarb, rhubarb, rhubarb.
Let me be!
You bastard!
Piss off.
Curt?
Curt, more light!
More light!
Curt!
Curt, more light!
What's wrong with you?
Why...
Why are you in the ground?
That's a good question.
You wanted to dig me out...
because
there was no point to this anymore.
Yes...
It's all pointless.
- No.
No, no, er...
Everything's fine.
It all went fine,
and digging me out now would be
the crowning glory, so to speak.
Don't you think, huh?
Curt?
I can't take any more... you sadist.
I can't take it anymore.
I can't feel my arms or legs anymore,
I can't breathe...
I don't want to die here.
Curt, hey, Curt!
I've started doing
my Far Eastern exercises again.
I sometimes feel
I should take patients again.
The conclusion of this experiment
remains unclear.
I can see clearly and remember more.
Perhaps the fresh air
is doing me good.
The young man
is doing well in his hole.
Dr. Schwarz would be pleased with me.
I can go into the kitchen!
I'm through.
I will have to cancel
the symposium.
Then I'll bring you home.
The children were right.
I'm old.
Straight ahead.
Then left to the parking lot.
You've made a step forwards
but you're not cured yet.
So, if you need me...
you know where to find me.
Yes.
Awful.
Don't let them get you down.
Take it easy.
Grandpa,
what are you doing in there?
Are you looking for something
in particular?
Yup.
Yes?
- I'm looking for Nick.
"Little Nicholas"? With the kids' books.
- No, our mutual friend.
Mother?
- That's why I'm here.
I can no longer stand to see Nick
suffer under the burden of his debts.
I've no idea what you're talking about.
- Give him my regards.
I'll be back in a week. One week.
Feedback is payback.
Get it?
Well...
This can't be the end.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I attempted to lead people astray...
and by so doing,
was misled myself.
There are...
areas of guilt...
Hello, how are you?
I was worried about you.
I woke up and suddenly
could see it all before me.
Now I know what must be said.
What are you doing?
Continuing our dialogue.
I still have a problem to resolve.
How bold!
My finest volumes.
For this you will bring me
to the symposium.
Curt?
Everything okay?
- Yes.
Hurry!
- Not so fast!
And at the end of the street
there's a manor.
That's where the symposium
is being held.
In the Liverpool Room.
Have you made a note of that?
Trousers!
One moment...
Yes?
Propaganda, Papageno. . .
- Not a castle, a manor.
A manor house.
And I have the goods, tell Mother that.
Jacket!
René...
I'll be in the eleventh row.
All right?
Yes. Bye.
Brown is just not my color.
This is better.
Ladies and gentlemen, please join me
in welcoming Professor Dr. Curt Ledig.
He holds the Charlemagne Prize,
belongs to the German Order of Merit...
and his honorary doctorates
are too numerous for me to list.
Professor Dr. Ledig,
you are here today because you've wished
to speak once more
about your own biography.
Both the specialist public and I myself
eagerly await insight
into your fascinating and varied life.
For me, this opportunity...
to speak about my own life
is of great importance.
The image of a person
in the public eye
never entirely corresponds to the truth.
It is, rather,
a collection of sources.
I would like to add my own truth
to this collection of sources.
That's all.
You mean the dispute
with Charles Steinbach?
What?
No!
That was in the 70s.
Back then I worked in California.
But that's not
the matter in question here.
I mean...
the Third Reich.
But your time as a regime-conform
academic has been described...
on many occasions
and at length... by you.
It has?
In your coming-to-terms
with a career in the Third Reich.
Yes.
And in your book...
"A Chance to Talk"
you describe yourself as
"a blinded young man"
and say it is...
a shameful thing...
that you kept your chair
for National Psychology throughout.
That cannot be!
Show me.
Hey, are you putting me on?
Where's the damn bag?
- I gave it to you.
It's not there...
Get it or you'll be sorry!
I...
Due to my age, I have...
forgotten many things.
My explanations
seem to me, today,
rather worthless.
What I would say today is...
that I regret what I did,
and that this guilt
will remain a visible part of me.
An outrage!
Stop him.
You're staying here!
Stop him!
- Yes.
I've got him!
Watch out! For God's sake...
Clear the area!
Everybody run!
- It's an emergency!
I've got him!
Clear the area!
- Ladies and gentlemen!
Baby, I love you!
I love you!
- Scram! Scram!
Look who's here!
- Well yes...
I said what I had to say.
But nobody listened.
Sorry, what?
What are you doing now?
- I'm going to kidnap you,
and demand 10,000 in ransom.
And if your family doesn't pay,
I'll turn you over to Israel.
Oh, I like it there.
What are you reading?
"A Chance to Talk".
Curt Ledig.
I'd read my own books, too.
You write?
BABELFISCH TRANSLATIONS