My dad said that ever since I was young,
I've had a dream for myself.
Having grown up, I still believe
that I will become a shining superstar.
My dream has to come true.
Like destiny!
Teacher!
The exam is coming soon.
ELEMENTS OF MUSIC - DURATION
What's wrong with him?
However, while waiting for your destiny,
you still have to do other things...
You guys study on your own today,
under my supervision.
Today, we're gonna talk about "Shining."
So, how does one shine?
Your voice?
Your attitude?
Or your wardrobe?
Yes, but not enough.
We need a heart filled with enthusiasm,
and a pure soul.
We need to hold
the audience's attention with our eyes,
and charm them with our singing.
Hey, Hoang.
Hey kid, slow down.
Tai, I said I'd meet you outside.
Hey. You out of your mind?
I can't get you in that show.
They're all A-list singers.
Where will I put an F-lister like you?
Call me again in three years.
Such a nuisance.
She's so annoying.
-Tai.
-Yes?
Remember to get me the best slot.
Yeah, I got you.
This is all I have.
And you will get all that you want.
I like you.
I like talented kids
who need one big break.
I hate those freeloaders
without any actual talent.
Just saying.
No joke or offense whatsoever.
Tonight is gonna be your night.
There's one door in your way.
You need to step over it.
Please step over. I need to talk to you.
You're an excellent teacher
and there's a chance for you
to shine even more.
Let me tell you something.
America is huge,
and their education system
is very developed.
Same with Japan.
Their infrastructure and education
are amazing.
And most importantly,
they need great teachers.
You mean... This is a surprise.
Right?
Can you see our beautiful
S-shaped country?
Look to the east of it.
Where the tiny dots are,
there's a special village
that needs a great teacher.
I think you are a great fit.
I'm exiled into wilderness?
There are people there.
It has a very fancy name.
Quy village.
But why me?
I can read people.
You have an enthusiastic heart,
and a pure soul.
You will shine.
No.
Swift as the wind.
Hey, you changed your mind?
I don't care who you are.
You pay your debt now,
and I'll be out of your hair.
You talked so fast he couldn't translate.
Why harass me every day
for a few hundred millions?
Soon you can take your money back in bags.
I'll pay all the interest too.
Learn Vietnamese.
If you don't pay,
I'll kill you.
TRIALS MAY NOT FAIL
Some day you guys will be proud of me.
And that day is today.
Mr. Nguyen.
Excuse me, you are...?
I'm Hoang.
I sent you some of my songs.
Hi Mr. Nguyen.
Hey, Huyen My.
-How are you?
-Good.
You thought about it?
It's okay.
See you later.
This number is up next.
Open the doors.
On behalf of V Heartbeat V Live,
we would like to thank you for coming.
Hope to see you again soon.
Have a great evening!
Thank you all.
Please let me go. I'm a nice person.
People are slandering me.
I'm not a fraud.
Please let me go.
Please.
Please. I'm telling the truth.
I did it because I was possessed.
Please, please officers.
Please let me go.
Hoang! I'm so sorry.
I got tricked so I had to trick people.
A showrunner named Tai
was just arrested for fraud.
As manager of a well-known dance group
scheduled to perform at a hit show,
Tai took money from young singers
to take them backstage,
promising them a chance to perform.
The organizer is confirmed
to not be involved in such a scam.
As years pass by, I ask myself
"What have I got?"
As days pass I am left with
a reminder of what I am not
How many more years do I get?
As days pass I am left with
A reminder of what I am not
How many more years do I get?
What's wrong?
I will be a famous singer.
Do what you want,
just don't quit teaching.
Because that was mom's last wish?
As years pass I ask myself
"What have I got?"
As days pass I am left with
A reminder of what I am not
I will always remember you.
TEACHER HOANG
Hello?
Why are you calling me so late?
I believe this is the right decision.
LET'S SHINE
Scream out loud declaring I'm an ocean guy
Breath in the stench
Looking like a crazy man
Meant to be, we meet where the oceans meet
Because you're a fish and I'm a shrimp
Trying to hold you
Gets me slapped in the face
Meant to be, we meet where the oceans meet
Because you're a fish and I'm a shrimp
Trying to hold you
Gets me slapped in the face
You're lucky today.
Usually, this road is covered by the sea.
It's opened up for you.
Normally you'd have to take the boat
and be throwing up from both ends.
Anyone here?
Anyone?
Hey.
Is a school near here?
Mr. Hoang.
I got it.
Got it.
That's not the crab.
Sorry.
Is it pinching you?
It is...
Is it?
That's really rare.
The first time a crab grabs a...
A crab grabs a willy.
You mean, mean crab.
What has the willy done to you?
You're a vasectomy surgeon?
Here he is.
Where's the claw?
Still on your thing.
It will let go tonight.
My name is Bung, the mayor.
Nickname is Weasel.
Let me take a pic for you.
Get photos right away.
It was my dad's. Very nice photos.
Let's try another one.
Damn, it's acting up again.
I'll fix it and take your photo later.
You're early.
Your boat wasn't ye lay.
Ye lay?
Like on a plane, you sometimes get ye lay.
Yeh, ye lay.
It's so unexpected
we only have enough time for an I ven.
What's that?
I ven is like... bar ty.
Oh, event.
-Event.
-Yeah, I ven.
Your pronunciation is weird.
Teaching primary school,
but you still need your English for today.
LUV YA
That's some serious moves there!
Dance! Dance!
Take a picture.
Onion stuck in your teeth.
I'd like to say something.
Hello everyone.
After everything I've seen,
I think Quy Village
is not as boring as I thought.
And...
you guys even made a stage
for me to shine.
Today I'll sing you all a song.
He's singing.
Oh, my attention
Has just been caught into your eyes
The audio is murdering my ears.
Then it started in my heart a golden fire
Fix the audio.
Act cool, but I was frozen for five secs
Does this doofus even know
how to control the mixer?
-What about these?
-These are not for volume.
Music on, dude!
GIVE ME A SHOULDER THAT I CAN LEAN ON
ENJOY YOUR HAPPY TIME.
SOMETHING TERRIBLE IS COMING.
I brought you water.
There's nothing to see. Can you leave?
Yep, nothing to see.
Get to know everything.
Here, life is not nearly
as fancy as the cities,
but it's very poor.
And in the class
you're lucky enough to teach,
there aren't a lot of kids,
but it's kinda empty.
Easier for you.
Also,
fresh water is very rare.
Very, very rare.
Luckily, there's the ocean.
All the salt water you need.
The kids here are amazing.
Cute and very civilized.
I'll introduce you sometime.
-Crap.
-Boohoo.
Hey, you evil kids!
Not everyone gets this treatment.
Only the people they like.
Hey, stop.
-Stop.
-Hey!
Think you're faster than me?
The little one is Cu.
The bigger one is Tinh, his dad.
They're the cutest ones.
Come here every morning to play chase.
Don't mind them.
Know what I'm most proud of
in this village?
The ladies.
They're so beautiful.
All the best qualities.
Plus, very gentle and sweet.
So cute.
Aren't you taking me to the school?
That's the school.
This is where I teach?
You wanna teach at the hospital?
And I live there?
Well, not me.
School's open.
Why didn't you get a Lion Dance team?
Oh yeah, I forgot.
After you.
Ooh, you guys dressed up.
This class has
more kids than the last one.
Only one class.
Ranging from Grade One to Five.
Kids, the ceremony.
DEARLY DEPARTED
A moment of remembrance.
Welcome here, teacher
We're very delighted
Our school is beautiful
Mr. Bung.
The teachers before me...
-they all died?
-Nonsense.
Who said they die?
I made up the song for the kids to sing,
so they remember
the teachers that were here.
Don't worry, you'll be there one day.
I almost forgot.
Let's take a pic of you.
Portrait.
Okay. The chorus.
The waves are singing a song
Are you blind?
That's the new teacher.
Couldn't you even say hello?
Do you want another pic?
It was blurry again.
What time are you coming in tomorrow?
I'll let the kids know.
Here's the previous class schedule.
Monday morning:
handwriting and math.
Afternoon: art.
Tuesday morning: handwriting, math.
Wednesday morning: handwriting, math.
Afternoon: art.
There's a change from Thursday.
Thursday morning: art.
Afternoon: handwriting, math.
Friday morning: art.
Saturday and Sunday off.
But if you're free you can teach them.
The view is very nice here.
We should go home, the crows are here.
Good morning teacher.
Can't you do it better?
Again.
Good morning teacher.
HOANG
Name?
-You go first.
-He asked you, fatty.
He asked your name.
Fine, there's lots of seafood here.
And I really like seafood.
You know that?
You're Snail, you're the monitor.
Yes, sir.
Shrimp, you're the study deputy.
OK.
But he's so stupid sir.
And has terrible hygiene.
Let me be that.
You're greedy.
You're dirty.
Never brushing your teeth.
You don't brush your teeth?
Shrimp, you'll be cleaning deputy.
MY TEACHER HOANG
-You're Clam.
-Yes, sir.
You're the discipline deputy.
But she cries a lot.
Scallop,
you're the art deputy.
-Yay!
-Couldn't be more wrong.
He can't do that, let me.
Listen to me.
From now on, when you come to class,
you have to brush your teeth,
wash your face,
clip and clean your nails.
And clean and iron your clothes.
What?
Teacher, the art deputy pooped his pants.
So stinky.
Unbelievable.
I'm so sorry.
Stop.
Cry.
She was a breech baby.
Next time if you're late,
don't bother coming in.
What's wrong with your foot?
Stepped on his shit bomb.
Knock it off. The teacher's mad.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
I'm... cleaning up.
Why didn't you draw the water?
I dropped the bucket,
so I had to jump down.
You went too far, Scallop.
Hey!
Why'd you scrub here?
Stop.
Cry.
I have to get out of here.
We've practiced this many times.
Today's the day.
Let's keep Teacher Hoang here,
whatever it takes.
-Ms. Tu.
-Present.
Today you're the rain master.
You're in charge of it. Go.
Teo.
-Are you ready?
-Yes.
The audio is okay, waiting for command.
-The content?
-Here.
I stayed up all night for this.
Good.
When I wave the hat,
-you start right away.
-Okay.
-Make it believable.
Try your best.
You'll get 2 kgs of longans.
Now give me one.
-Okay. Go.
-Yes, sir.
Hold on to your chickens and ducks.
Don't fight, okay?
Hey.
It's showtime, everybody move!
Let's go.
Teacher, where are you going?
Anywhere.
Anywhere but here.
Please don't mind Scallop.
He has an unhealthy gut.
I'll pick up after him.
There's no future in this village.
You can't go. A storm is coming.
I don't care.
You can't do that.
If you get on a boat,
the storm will sink everything.
The storm is here.
This is the weather forecast for today,
tomorrow, and all the days to come.
A storm is coming to our village.
There's rain somewhere
but we're not sure where.
Anywhere with the rain would know.
The sky looks clear,
but if you move it will rain.
You see?
It's weird here.
A storm comes even when it's sunny.
It's a thing.
Every time a storm comes,
the villagers have to go underground.
It's tough.
We have to take the animals too.
The winds are so strong
they could take houses.
You can't leave.
Gotta wait the storm out.
Understand? See how sad that is?
Get underground, quickly.
Look scared. Go down.
You see? Go underground!
Shit, he even fell.
Okay go, look scared. Expression.
Mr. Bung, Mr. Tu fell on my chicken.
This is not worth it.
Poor me!
The storm causes sustained wind.
Broken speaker.
It's storming everywhere.
It's hard to breathe.
What are you doing?
Watching a movie?
Leave, now.
So we can't know where it is.
There go my longans.
Why are you hiding there?
He caught us. Leave.
Go, go.
Ha, you can act now?
You think I'm a child?
Huh?
Show's over.
Boats are not allowed to leave shore.
Teacher.
Wait.
What?
Mr. Bung!
Are we done?
Let me down, it's hot up here.
Come down.
You're overacting for a buck.
You bastard!
Help!
Help me!
Crazy dude. Steal my bottle boat
to cross the ocean?
Who's up there?
I'm Sam. I'm kind of a gofer around here.
Don't you shower?
You smell like dried squid.
The mayor told me to come fix your roof.
That Weasel,
I'll beat him up.
Hey!
-Are you crazy?
-I dare you to hit my dad.
What? Weasel is dried squid's dad?
Hey!
Who changed my clothes?
You were soaking wet,
who's to blame if you're dead?
Did you do it?
My dad.
Oh, he said you seem tall but...
Never mind, I don't want you to feel bad.
HAPPY RELAXING
FROM A PRETTY GIRL
Thanks.
What does a gofer do?
Everything.
Houses, electricity, bikes, boats.
Why don't you fix your attitude?
Hey! Just like a dude.
Shrimp.
Listen to me.
You have eight apples.
I took five from you.
How many do you have?
Five.
Five, sir.
Count again.
One. Two. Three.
Four. Five. Six. Seven. Eight.
Taking away five,
how many do you have left?
One. Two. Three.
So what's eight minus five?
Uh... five, sir.
Focus.
Taking away five, we have?
One. Two. Three.
Okay, so what's eight minus five?
Hmm...
Not five.
Good, not five.
How many then?
Ah... It's okay.
I'm sorry.
Shrimp.
You didn't brush your teeth, did you?
They're my teeth, sir.
It is my business to brush them or not.
It concerns no other.
No other?
Hold out your hands.
Breathe out.
Stronger.
Palm your nose.
Concerned now?
Hey, don't you greet your teacher?
Name?
Cu.
Hey, hey.
I asked your name.
Cu.
His name is Cu.
If you're late again,
don't bother coming in.
I didn't yell at you.
Scallop, why are you so persistent?
I went too far.
Class is over.
Teacher.
It's not time yet.
The other teachers let us play soccer.
Soccer is over.
Let me go get that.
Would he leave again?
He doesn't like dirty and stupid people.
Scallop, it's your fault
the teacher doesn't like us.
Just poop all the poop at home.
I'm sick.
He will leave like everyone else anyway.
It's so poor here, not like the city.
How was school?
Good!
But the teacher doesn't like us.
That's not true. You're just naughty kids.
Try to study properly and he'll like you.
-Cu, bring food to the teacher.
-Yes.
I'll teach you English on the way.
Con meo is "the cat."
Con ga is "the chicken."
-What about con trau?
-Uh... I'm not sure.
Music Talent Show - Let's Shine
Deadline August 12th
AUGUST 12TH
Boss, the designer
has sent the stage plot.
We need something original.
Start from scratch.
Yes, boss.
Beautiful sun and clear blue sky
The wind brings a nice scent
The waves sing a lullaby
Oh ah oh ah oh ah
The sun's come out
Let's have fun and not worry
Life is not...
Anything else?
The sun's come out
Let's have fun and not worry
Let's live in the moment
Sailing downwind.
Don't give in to hardship
Keep sailing through rough waves
Crap.
Hey.
Cu, where are you?
I'm here, dad.
Where's my liquor?
I just got it, dad.
Good.
Here you go.
Cu.
Where did you get this?
Delicious.
Salty like salt and spicy like chili.
Just like your old man's life.
It's hot.
Fiery hot.
FOR MY DEAREST SON
You play?
Dear Producers of Let's Shine,
I'm Do Duc Hoang.
My dream is to shine on a music stage.
Today I'll sing an original song
that I wrote, called
The Fishing Song.
Beautiful sun and clear blue sky
The wind brings a nice scent
The waves sing a lullaby
Oh ah oh ah oh ah
How can I send this without service?
No clue how people live here.
Hoang.
-Let's go.
-Where?
Na is in labor.
-Na who?
-Mrs. Bay's daughter.
I know nothing about delivery.
Are you from the city?
-So what?
-City people know everything.
Cu, stop buying wine for your dad.
Use it to take a girl out.
Let's go.
Hurry up, teacher.
Someone is in labor
and you're taking a selfie.
Are you crazy?
There's no waves around here?
You're crazy? You're asking
if there's waves near the ocean?
There are sea waves everywhere.
I'm talking about phone service.
Oh, that?
Talk to Sam.
She's the only one who knows.
Who's this Na then?
The prettiest lady here,
so she keeps getting pregnant.
You'll see.
-That's Na?
-Isn't she pretty?
Of the two cows, this one is prettier.
I don't know how to deliver a calf.
Nothing is impossible. Get in.
No one here knows how to do it?
Yes, Cross-eyed Six.
But he's in the hospital.
Why?
He went to help a cow last week.
Accidentally walked in on a sick bull.
Got kicked, hospitalized, still there.
When you see the calf's legs,
you tie this around them,
then slowly pull it out. Okay?
Usually before you see the legs--
The water breaks.
Come on Hoang!
Such a beauty.
One more.
Hey, can we name your kid Hoang?
Hey.
Did you know how to do that?
I'm the mayor, I know everything.
Why did you make me do it?
You gotta learn.
What if I weren't here?
Can't rely on the mayor forever.
Thank you.
I'll teach you to deliver pigs
when we have time.
Much more fun.
Let's go eat.
There used to be
all kinds of services here.
Good ones too.
But after a few storms,
the cables went down.
Everything is broken.
Quy Village is very rich in sea resources.
Lots of seafood.
However, being so far from the mainland,
we face a lot of difficulties.
I'm not a tourist.
But you gotta know to teach the kids.
I don't teach. I'll be a famous singer.
Seems like no one here knows how to talk.
It's so sunny.
Yeah, clothes dry really fast here.
Where are you taking me?
The only place you can get service.
Very pretty.
It's called
The...
Very...
Far...
Away...
Place.
Still can't talk.
Don't think you're better than everyone.
People here call me Princess.
Princess?
Fine, why is there no Prince Charming
for our Dried Squid Princess?
'Cos I'm waiting for a prince
on a ship with scarlet sails.
People call this place the Wind Hill.
It's beautiful.
My dad is trying to keep you here.
But...
how could he?
Since your heart doesn't belong here.
This place needs a teacher so badly
that my dad always thinks his son-in-law
has to be a teacher.
Why can't I get service?
I lied.
Gotta go to the mainland.
What are you looking at? I saw your clip.
You won't get picked.
It's so boring.
So bad.
You...
-I what?
-Dried Squid.
Hello, teacher.
Where are you going so early?
I'm... going for a walk.
Ah, this.
I want to go to the mainland
for phone service.
So I can send an email.
I know.
You want to leave, don't you?
But I really want to learn.
This one is broken.
It doesn't work.
I'm not lying.
-Who's that?
-It's Cu.
He has a beautiful voice.
His mom was a singer.
Beautiful sun and clear blue sky
The wind brings a nice scent
I saw your clip.
It won't get picked.
So boring.
Looks like I gotta use the kids.
Today, we're not studying.
Just learning to sing. Agreed?
Yes sir.
I'll also make a movie about our island.
-You guys with me?
-Yes sir.
He's late again.
He has to take care of his dad.
Worried you'd kick him out,
he asked me for help.
It's okay, come in.
First of all, I want to hear you sing.
Let me go first.
Any song is fine.
Cool.
-Starting with Snail.
-Yes.
Hang on, I'm picking a song.
Oh, I got it.
There was once this little birdie
-Looking so...
-Definitely the work of Bung.
Whenever you're writing on the board
Chalk dust falls on you
Okay, good.
Yesterday, when I went to school
Mommy was holding my hands
My tiny school lies in the grapevine
My tiny teacher teaches me to sing
That's nonsense,
don't do that.
To be a good singer we need two things.
That's feeling and technique.
Feeling brings soul to your voice.
SOUL - FEELING - TECHNIQUE
It's hard...
to practice feeling.
But we can practice the technique.
Follow my lead.
Mi
Cu.
Why are you not singing?
Your beats are off.
Stand up.
You wanna talk beats with me?
Follow my lead.
Amazing!
Amazeballs!
Everyone ready? Camera rolling.
Action.
Beautiful sun and clear blue sky
The wind brings a nice scent
The waves sing a lullaby
Oh ah oh ah oh ah
The sun's come out, let's have fun
And not worry
Let's live in the moment
Sailing downwind
Don't give in to hardship
Keep sailing through rough waves
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through day and night
Come on, let's reach our dreams
They are out there waiting
Come on, let's go fish...
Hang on.
Go. Run.
Is it out yet?
Gotta wait for the singer to poop.
Lunch time.
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through day and night
Come on, let's reach our dreams
They are out there waiting
Stop, stop.
Did someone steal from you guys?
Are you going to a funeral?
Again.
Slow down so it's smoother.
Stop jerking back and forth.
I haven't eaten yet, dad.
Come on, come on.
Come on, let's go fishing
Stop, stop.
I told you to be happy, not crazy.
Be happy on the inside, understand? Again.
You're so weak, it keeps jerking.
You should eat less.
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through...
Stop, stop.
Let me down.
-What you doing here?
-Watching.
-You're in frame.
-Good.
How is it good!
My phone.
I wouldn't throw mine.
But the video...
Gotta start from scratch.
We're experienced now.
Lunch time.
There's no good angle here.
Hey.
Why are we shooting this at night?
Because seeing a teacher
teaching in a deserted place at night
will get more sympathy.
The power's out.
Then it's even more sympathetic.
A teacher teaching in a deserted place,
still teaching at night, without power.
But the power's out.
We can't shoot in the dark.
Can we use candles?
Nah, too cliché.
How about incense?
We get a bundle here and there,
there's light and smoke.
You're making no sense.
-I have an idea.
-What?
Firefly, firefly
Up the belly you light
Every summer night
Come out and play
From the bushes
To the sides of the ponds
From the high branches
To the grass down below
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through day and night
Come on, let's reach our dreams
They are out there waiting
Come on, come on, let's pull up the net!
The sun's come out
Let's have fun and not worry
Let's live in the moment
Sailing downwind
Don't give in to hardship
Keep sailing through rough waves
Come on, let's reach our dreams
They are out there waiting
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through
Day and night
Come on, let's reach our dreams
They are out there waiting
The boats sailing
Towards the sun
People diving
Into the sea
There's the fish
Come on
Let's go fishing
Our village sings through day and night
Come on, let's reach our dreams
They are waiting
Out there
They're out there
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through day and night
Come on, let's reach
Our dreams
They are out there waiting
Come on, come on, let's pull up the net!
Come on, come on
Let's pull up the net!
Come on!
That's good.
This contestant's phone
is always out of reach.
Address?
We have it, but very far.
Overseas?
No, in Vietnam.
Then it's not far.
We have enough good videos.
Let's continue.
I sent it.
I think a storm is coming.
Congratulations!
I think you'll get picked.
You don't seem very happy.
There will be other teachers for the kids.
There's nothing here
that can change your mind, right?
Shrimp quit school.
His parents made him go fishing.
Cu as well.
But they are just kids.
They have to study.
That's how it is here.
All done.
Hello teacher.
Hello everyone.
I'm Hoang.
He's gonna stay home from now on.
He did so badly in class.
Other teachers kept sending him home.
Boys in this village will go on boats
or work in this ice factory
when they're grown up.
But you have to know basic math
to do business.
Math?
Shrimp, tell me.
I give you 70,000 Dong.
I take 20,000 back. How much do you have?
50,000.
Good.
You see?
Okay, maybe she gave him an easy one.
Tell me. I give you 120,000 Dong.
I take 62,000. How much do you have left?
58,000.
See?
That's good enough. No need to study.
Yeah.
But...
Shrimp doesn't like this job.
He has passion and talent
for something else.
Shrimp.
-What do you want to do?
-I want to become Messi.
Messi?
Who's that?
-Is he an actor?
-No, a soccer player.
Gosh! You're too skinny.
Look at your legs.
They look like chopsticks.
You need legs like me
to be a soccer player.
Okay, try with that ball.
Wow!
It's the wind.
He got lucky.
What if someone held you back
from your dreams?
How would you feel?
He'd better have an education.
Let him go to school.
Come to class tomorrow.
Hello teacher.
Let him go to school.
Cu.
Yes?
Who was that?
My teacher.
Can he drink?
What was that for?
You get liquor for going to school?
For a singer,
breathing is very important.
Two.
Three.
You gotta eat more veggies and fruits.
That would help with your problem,
you know?
Yes sir.
And don't be afraid of the restroom.
To me, it's one of the most
relaxing places.
Stay there, I'll play you a melody.
I did it, teacher.
Today, we will review the last lesson.
It's calculating by
dividing numbers to their tenths.
Did you do the homework?
Yes sir.
Who will volunteer?
Shrimp.
Very nice.
82 sir.
158 sir.
Harder?
257 sir.
663 sir.
-Harder?
-Okay.
This is difficult,
so I'll let you think at your seat
for five minutes.
It's 2750 sir.
How are you so good today?
As long as you're not yelling at me.
Go, go.
Get it, teacher.
Okay, here we are.
Come on Shrimp.
Oh, so many people.
These people want to see you.
Hi, Hoang.
My name is An. This is Le,
the Music Director of
the talent show Let's Shine.
Hello.
We couldn't get a hold of you,
so here we are.
Your video is very impressive.
Awesome!
There are many great clips sent to us.
But to be honest,
our team was most impressed with yours.
You shot everything on a phone?
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Our team have decided
we would like... this boy
to be in the finale.
Come here.
What's your name?
Cu.
Your real name.
Yeah, Cu.
Cu?
Did you have singing lessons?
Yes, my mom taught me.
Could you please allow us
to test him a little?
If that's okay with you.
Go ahead.
Thank you. Come over here.
How old are you?
I'm nine.
Wait.
For the finale,
we have ten amazing performances.
So I think you guys should prepare
something really spectacular for him.
I trust you can do that.
Are you ready?
-Yes.
-Let's go to Saigon for the finale.
Okay.
Are you crazy?
I will never shine.
This stupid village will kill my dream.
My passion.
And you.
And your Weasel dad.
The kids.
That poorer than poor school.
I don't owe you anything.
No one wants to disappoint you.
You.
You will die alone on this island.
Because no stupid man will stay here.
You talk like that as a teacher?
Right.
There's nothing valuable here
to make you stay.
What are the kids to you?
And me...
I'll die alone with the dream
of changing life here.
My dad?
You think he's a liar?
Yes, he's a liar.
He sold his bike
to throw you that party.
He always tries
to hide all the difficulties here.
Hiding his sickness too.
All to make you feel welcome here.
Because the kids really need
a teacher who loves them.
That's my dad's last wish
that he has to do before he dies.
Probably not long from now.
LOVE YOU TEACHER
Teacher, are we still going to school?
Dad.
Dad, please.
Shut up.
How dare you disobey me?
Mom gave me that guitar.
Shut up.
I forbid you to sing.
You like singing like your mom.
She pursued singing and was corrupted.
She left you for some dude, don't you see?
You're lying.
She left because you hit her.
You're talking back now?
I want to be on the show
so mom can see me on TV.
The show?
If you wanna sing...
then get out of my house.
I forbid you.
You wanna sing?
Go follow your crazy mom.
You can't call her that.
-You!
-Don't call her that.
Get out of my house.
-Get out!
-You can't talk about her like that.
Cu!
Cu.
Cu...
Hoang.
Have you seen Cu?
He ran out of the house.
In this weather?
His dad hit him.
Let's go, let's go.
Let's spread out to find him.
Mr. Bay, go to the pineapple field.
You to the beach. The rest follow me.
Cu.
There he is!
Are you crazy? You can't swim.
Everyone stay here, it's dangerous!
Be careful!
Where are you going?
I gotta go find my mom.
She got him.
TEACHER HOANG IN QUY VILLAGE
Teacher...
We're here.
There's a boat to the mainland.
You should get going.
I'm sorry
for bothering you with our affairs.
About Cu...
His dad won't let him join the show.
LET'S SHINE INVITATION
What are you doing?
He's not going to school.
-Ouch.
-Teacher, please...
-Please don't.
-Does it hurt?
Of course.
How can a grown man like you
hit a child like him?
He's my kid.
So what?
I can teach him my way.
If you ever hit him again,
I will not let it slide.
Drinking all day...
Why don't you drown in it?
What kind of man hits women and children?
Coward.
Thank you.
I can't go to Saigon.
Why not?
I'm scared.
My dad always call me a loser.
I won't be anything when I grow up.
Anyone that says you can't do it,
don't believe them.
Why would you let someone
decide your dream?
But... the other kids are good.
Do you know why I didn't
graduate from music school?
What did you say? I'm not talented?
You're just not patient with me.
You'll never be a singer.
I'll prove you wrong.
I've always thought I was right.
Then I heard you sing
and realized they were right.
You have something that I don't.
It's called a gift.
Don't ever bury your dream
just because you're shy.
Let's prove to your dad
that he was wrong
not to let you follow your dream.
Don't be sad.
More than sad.
It is disappointment.
But now...
I'm proud of myself.
Now,
I can go to the graves of my parents
and tell them
I've tried really hard,
and I will keep trying...
to shine.
Maybe... not on a stage
but somewhere else.
My parents would be happy.
Okay.
Let's see who gets to the school first.
All of us will help you shine.
Will I be famous?
Of course.
-I'll write you a song about your mom.
-Really?
Dear Ms. Principal,
I have a favor to ask.
I need to borrow our school choir.
I've attached here the music
I'd like them to practice.
You'll understand what I'm doing.
I have to succeed this time.
Has anyone come by the school
looking for me?
If so, please tell them
I'm teaching in the States.
Thank you very much.
And one day,
just as in the prophecy and her belief,
the dream came true.
Assol was carried away by Prince Grey
on a ship with scarlet sails,
to all the villagers' astonishment.
From then on they lived
happily ever after.
Do they get to kiss?
For sure.
-Whoa, that's beautiful!
-What is it?
-It's so tall.
-I want to see, too.
-So handsome.
-This one is lower.
-Whoa.
-You too.
Look how tall the towers are.
-Go get ready.
-Yes.
You will shine.
Will my mom see me?
Of course.
-These go there.
-OK.
You never focus.
Millions of people are watching.
Help them, and I'll help you.
Remember, pull the sun up right away.
I know, you keep saying that.
Mr. Weasel,
are you okay?
Of course I am.
You forget that all the time.
Trust me.
I want to ask about your health.
I'm fine.
Guys like you have to live.
I'll take you to the hospital.
The conditions here are better.
What for?
I love you.
Did somene tell you I'm dying?
I told her to say that
so you would feel sorry for me.
You're very easy to trick.
Sir, should I submit
to the show next year?
You gotta love people.
Okay.
On a dreamy day
My heart wonders
All these emotions
Are as strong as waves
What was once a childish dream
Now becomes so real
Please don't be a dream
We were once together
Those days flew by
So many things to say
But all were unspoken
Tiny waves hanging by the shore
More gentle than ever before
Mom, do you know I'm missing you?
Mommy, don't forget to come home
How far is the horizon?
Please be here with me
And grow up with me
Mommy, what will be left behind
When everything has passed us by?
One morning I'll wake up to you
Cu sings so well.
We were once together
Those days flew by
So many things to say
But all were unspoken
Tiny waves hanging by the shore
More gentle than ever before
Mom, do you know
I'm missing you?
Mom, do you know I'm missing you?
Mommy, don't forget to come home
How far is the horizon?
Please be here with me
And grow up with me
Mommy, what will be left behind
When everything has passed us by
One morning I'll wake up to you
Mommy, don't forget to come home
How far is the horizon?
Please be here with me and grow up with me
Mommy, what will be left behind
When everything has passed us by?
One morning I'll wake up to you
One morning
I'll wake up to you
Mommy, mommy
You!
Don't forget to pay me, okay?
Come on, let's go fishing
Our village sings through day and night
Come on, let's reach...
Congratulations.
Can I talk to you?
I've listened to your songs.
We should collaborate.
Do you want the kid?
I want you.
Here's my name card.
Good luck.
Winner of Let's Shine:
"Mr. Hoang is my idol."
Talented Songwriter of VPOP
Top 5 Young Talented Songwriter in V-Pop
GOLDEN LIGHT AWARD BEST MUSIC COMPOSER
I'm very honored and happy as an artist
that my music is loved by so many people.
I really appreciate it.
I hope my new songs will be
as welcome as this one.
Princess Dried Squid.
-Teacher!
-Teacher is back!
Give me a moment.
You bought that?
So rich now.
No, just renting it.
Do you still need a teacher?
Isn't it better being an artist?
I only shine as a teacher.
You don't hate dried squid anymore?
Still do.
Hate it so much.
I'll dip it in wasabi
and eat it raw.
Stay here with us teacher!
Please stay,
I don't poop my pants anymore.
Stay and teach us how to sing!
Sam, can you ask him to stay?
Hey, answer them.
-You two make a good couple.
-This is so fun!
He agreed!
You guys should prepare for their wedding!
Get them!
-Why are you running so fast?
-Wait for us!
Let's go together!
We are!
We kids just tell the truth.
Life is not always the dream
we've been waiting for.
But every day is a new journey.
Don't worry.
Just keep going!
Thank you for listening to my story.
Invite others, the more the merrier.
I will tell it over and over again.
Good morning teacher.
Today, we'll write an essay.
Let's write about
what you like most on this island.
I like rain.
I like the boats.
I like the sun.
I like my mom.
I like the ocean.
I like the fish.
I like you.
Let's do this.
Everyone, we still have
another scene after the credits.
Hang in there and watch the credits.
It won't take long.
Security, close the doors.
Don't let anyone out.
That's all. Thank you everyone.