(Laughing)
Hows the writing going?
I can't escape it.
The ghosts of my former self come back to haunt me.
They follow me, as I write in peace
with the backdrop of so much pain...
Your'e one of the greatest
horror writers of our time.
... I was.
I have a new story to tell the world...
But even my ghost’s cast shadows.
Our Father, who art in heaven
hallowed be thy name
thy kingdom come
thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this our daily bread
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive them what trespass against us
And lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from evil
For thine is the kingdom
the power and the glory
forever and ever
Amen
Still a believer?
A man of faith cannot be a rational man...
You’ve had an early start to the day
Too early
as they say.
And you come all this way
just for me?
I’ve been walking by your side for quite sometime.
You must be exhausted.
Of all the places you thought of to hide from me
You are no recluse
even when in the company of strangers.
I thought I was familiar with this place.
But people move on
And boy, have you tried.
Shall this be over soon?
Am i to be silenced before i speak?
I’ve made a few amendments.
If I cannot inspire love
I will create fear.
and im far better at my job
than you are
I try to inspire people
how?
when you can’t even inspire yourself?
Your in my story now
and these
characters you write
there all mine now...
(laughing)
You a member?
Ahh of course..
Ten pound love
Thanks Dad!
Are you lost sweetheart?
Oh here for the...the Fright Night
Course you are.
I erm i got this sent in the post
Say no more
Your with the breakfast club over there
I was thinking of writing a thriller you know
a Stephen King type project you know what i mean?
Huh hi
Hiya your with us i think?
oh hi erm you must be erm
urghhh to tell you the truth i have know idea?
The writers thing
yes yes the write night
or what ever its called? Yes yes.
Sit
I got us a table
Erm not that its busy or anthing but erm..
Yes im Patrick my the way..
Oh Debbie nice to meet you
nice to meet you too yes.
So....
Your just another writer too
Oh well
I wouldn't say anyones just a writer
We are all just creaters after all
I think your in a world of your own love
Debbie ..this is Laura
Oh lovely to meet you
Of course it is
So Debbie what brings you here?
erm well ..the same as you two i imagine
And what do you know about it because
we know absolutely fuck all
I got sent this in the post
and it says
Ahh yes
Wednesday the 31st 6pm
The Old Familiar social club
Invite writers to showcase and pitch their..
Sorry can i just stop you there
Oh sure
Oh i got nothing to say
i just wanted to stop you there.
Laura be nice.
This is me being nice.
Its just harmless banter Patrick
Well has the youth say.
Well
this is
honestly
the first time ive ever been
in one of these social clubs
I find it quite homey
They got wine on tap.
Homey isnt exactly the word id use to discribe it
Speaking of which does any one want a drink?
Still time for ones pleasantries
before the others arrive.
How many are expected?
I dont know but there was a good turn out last year.
Huh people..
I thought this was the first year?
No no no there was one last year too.
oh did you come to that too?
no i was in the states
erm i was in New York
same time last year but erm
they go really big there
erm but its different since i've come here
Oh well
theres no trust in the neighbourhoods
anymore is there?
But still its mainly for the kids.
Yeah thats why Patrick likes it
To many knocks to the head init?
Oh are you a fighter?
No
No im not
Safer for me on the other side of the ropes
Oh like a sports writer?
yes
yes i live through the pages of my work
you know erm
i may not be in there
but im eye to eye
with a clenched fist
pen in my hand
3....2...1
Get back in the room
Well i thought that was lovely Patrick
truely insperational
Have you done horror stories before?
Well like i said i am a sports writer
same territory
Oh you didnt know?
We are in the presence
of the Stephen king of the boxing world
No no let us be the judge of that
That's me Gem
Goodnight love.
See you later Frank
huh hum
Another drink is that?
Sorry but can you please keep it on the plate.
Hey Birthday girl
What seems to be the problem this time Gem?
Well its just..
Its just nothing Gemma
May i surgest you present yourself behind the bar
where you belong.
Save your breath love closing time
Partys over.
Sorry to say sweety but
your mum has the worst taste in
selecting venues for her daughters
birthday surprise.
(whisper) He will come for you.
And i will make sure your father
hears all about this.
And ill make sure that my uncle brian
knows that you kid
has ruined his freshly varnised tables.
How do you like those toffee apples sweetheart?
(whisper) You have woken him up.
i think its time you leave
Preferably right now and preferably for good.
GEMMA HARTLEY
He'll come to collect you
don't be scared you'll fly away too.
Fly all the way up
to join them in the clouds.
I will not forget this
and i'll make sure you never will either.
(whisper) you've woken him up.
Hey mate you alright?
Come on lets go.
Come hide with me quick.
He'll come find you too.
(laughing)
Ready or not here i come.
(Scream)
(Laughter)
(laughing)
Surprise to see me Gemma?
You're at my party now.
Come to smile?
Are you laughing?
Save you're breath
The partys over.
Take out the bit with IT.
There won't be anything left.
i mean
the mum whos reading the book
Take it out.
Foreshadowing
to start the film
you always have all these little
facts in there you know.
Oh my god its him.
Who
The guy over there at the bar.
What. The demon Head Master?
I used to be his student in six form.
What lesson?
Writing for the screen
But the last i heard
he left his wife
and went over to europe.
anyway sorry
Its okay its faces from the past and all that.
He hasn't aged a day.
He must be one of the Judges.
well...those who can't do teach.
Complements from the mangement.
Is it just us three competing?
I wouldn't like to say sir.
Oh! What is in this?
Don't ask such things.
Have a good night
Gentlemen
and ladies.
You not a drinker?
well..i don't know
well your reaction didn't excactly sell it to me.
Go on it'll help you loosen up a bit.
Well its not just that its just...
Im on these pills.
Finally something we've got in common.
No i just don't want to take a chance.
They..
thin my blood.
not to give to much detail.
Well.....you just did.
Good evening class.
Mr Reivers
Debbie
how wonderful of you to except
my invitation
You rememberd my name?
Well
Can i just say
you don't look a day older
than the last time we met.
Care to join us?
That is of course
why i'm here.
So your'e one of the judges?
Jury and executioner
Yes Patrick.
It was i that invited the three of you here.
I hope you prepeared
Getting there.
You not drinking?
I never drink wine.
Patrick.
Not why im driving at least.
Thanks for the drinks anyway...
Here we go
red wine
mixed with
Jesus
The full tilt Boogie.
Know what im asking for now.
well
I'm not
gonna drink that.
No offence
So
are all three of you familiar
with each others work.
erm...well
We haven't really
gotten into that yet
i mean
We didn't know what to expect
we didn't know how many people would be here?
All Familiars
I can assure you of that.
So your a regular at this place?
Only when i need to be Patrick.
So
What have you been doing since teaching?
Well
It's like years ago
A lot of travelling Debbie.
Keeping things fresh.
Vary it up a bit.
Are you a gypo?
So
What have you brought
for me this evening Debbie?
Homework?
shall we call it?
Erm well
My love of film never really left me
oh i recall
you always was very fond of it.
remember back in the day
Well i always just
stayed with me
Quitely collecting dust
erm
anyway
The film that
i want to put forward this evening is erm
Its not really the style
i want to be remembered for making
i was very proud of it
at one point.
So what are you hoping to catch today then?
A shark.
A shark?
I don't think your nets big enough for a shark.
I'm gonna put it back silly.
Ahh well of course.
Besides
daddy hasn't got enough room
in his freezer for a full shark i don't think.
Why would you put a shark in the freezer?
we can put it in the fishtank with George.
Well sweetheart.
Whatever you find
mummy will be very proud of you anyway alright.
Becareful of sharks.
ROBERT!
Yes boss.
Phone call
said it's urgent
Right you soft lad whos next?
Nice stretches
Long night is it?
With you it never is.
Yes.
You know im on leave right?
okay okay
Tell lou i' ll get there as quick as i can.
Well why isn't he there yet?
Fine.
Well if you keep me talking im not gonna be
twenty minutes am i.
i'm hangin up now.
Bad timing?
With you it's never a good one.
Come on offer to clean the gym again tonight.
Come on what have you got to lose?
Tomorrow.
Tonight.
What if something else come up.
I'm counting on it.
Sorry sir, you can't come through here
it's a restricted area.
It's okay hes with me.
Sergeant. Its okay.
Thanks Lou.
It's okay hes new.
Good vacation?
Yeah it was alright.
What we got?
It's a mess.
we got a young girl
swept along from the resivour in the floods
ID?
No.
Jane doe.
She could be one of those girls
hanging up on the wall in the office.
Drowning?
eh?
Well it could be drowning.
we won't know till the autopsy boys
have had a go at her.
Looks like somebody already did.
Shes cute.
Fucksake Lou.
Hey.
Six foot
Blonde
beautiful.
You'd of nailed her.
Shit.
Well speaking of shit.
Whats that?
Sweethearts.
What?
You know the sweets?
I love you.
Be mine.
Yours forever.
They where stuffed in her throat.
Lou.
We need to talk.
In situations like this
i wonder what columbo would do.
ohh
ohh one more thing.
Lou
You never take anything serious.
Well as long as im this side of
the body bag
that's the way it's gonna stay
Ahh look
i can
feel bad
erm
What is it you wanted to say.
Her name
is Penny.
What? The girl in the body bag?
We went for a drink.
You went for a drink?
With the girl in the..When?
About six weeks ago.
Where did you meet her?
We met.
Now don't laugh.
We met on tinder.
Tinder.
Ohh.
Ahh that's beautiful...tinder.
ohh
Everything was fine we'd you know we'd
we'd talk for a while we'd
met up in a bar and erm
we...we had a few drinks.
i did the gentlemanly thing i tried to call her.
Call her a few time actually.
She never picked up my calls.
Not seen anything of her
she disapeared.
Untill now.
Correct.
The hand marks were they you?
No.
Use a condom?
Yeah of course.
You scared they are gonna find out?
No.
I'm scared my wife will find out.
Ahh.
Yes.
Still got the touch.
Yeah.
Your'e in trouble.
You forgot to fix the washer.
Jesus.
What have you been upto since i've been gone?
They for me?
This for you being home from the gym?
Again.
I'm sorry love but something came up at work.
I thought you was off this week?
So did I.
Oh poor you.
I know what you want.
That new place down the road.
Lets have a lovely evening dinner down there..
Maybe tomorrow
(Yawnning)
A bit tired are we?
Late night?
It was a late night again erm
i have had a word with the surperviser so
hopefully from next week i'll be on days.
But.
I still have to be at the Hospital in an hour.
There's pizza in the fridge
i really need to get ready for work.
Boss.
Where the fuck have you been?
You been broken in our something?
Yes because some fuckin idiot took the keys.
Look i told you i was gonna clean up last night
Oh yeah is this it?
Ehh..and did you?
Did you fucking leave something behind?
Ehh?
Robert.
You know this one as well?
When did you last see her?
Yesterday.
Yesterday?
The nurses outfit is this any
significance?
(Phone ringing)
My brother comes here.
Sorry love theres been an incedent at the gym.
What's going on mate?
There's about to be one at home to.
You not working tonight honey?
What are we going to do to you?
That's a rhetorical question
I'm really not expecting an answer.
It will take hours for that substance to wear off.
And by that time
I'll be the only one here.
Well i don't know.
You start off trying to conquer the world
and you end up six feet under it.
You've
been a very bad boy
Mr Faraday.
Be mine?
Well.
We tried that didn't we?
Guess who?
I wonder who that could possibly be?
The girl at the bar?
Maybe?
or
the girl at the gym?
Your Fucked.
Mr Tinder.
Is he still alive?
Depends on what you class as alive?
A see the knifes came in handy.
How many goes did you have at him?
Evidently not enough.
Daddy what a pop?
mmm no
I'll deal with the aftermath.
Did it make you sad Robert?
Knowing
that every year
from this date forward
I'll have your disapearance
to remember.
You was always to good for him.
You've got mail!!
Expecting it to rain, are we?
It's very peculiar here.
You’ve just figured that out.
Could i just have a water please?
I'm alright thanks.
What's that smell?
They had samples in the toilet.
Fuckin sunblock?
It's moisturiser.
I think I know what sun cream smells like.
Don’t be fooled by this pigment
It's the middle of fucking autumn.
Ahhh.
Here take a fresh one.
I'm sorry about that.
No don't worry about it.
I do apologise.
It’s fine, just a small cut.
What happened?
I’m fine, really.
Just a bit of a shock that's all.
Well
back to the main narrative of this evening then.
Care to invest a tale to this event Laura?
So anyway erm.
when you had it off with Denzel Washington right.
Come on hurry up and take the fuckin picture
Yeah of course.
You get there time in a minute.
Collecting flies the poor las.
Make her look pretty.
Alright sweetheart.
Here we go.
Chuck us a big smile.
Erm?
Can we try.
Just smile with your eyes.
Okay.
Just smile with your eyes
That's better.
Oh that's better.
Huhh..
Tacete! Canes!
What?
Shut up! You fuckin dogs!
You speak Latin?
Only when it’s convenient, apparently
And you thought
now
to be that time?
A dead language.
Reflecting what?
Your career?
Your anxiety?
Humour me.
They say you only die twice.
Once when your body fails and
twice when
your names spoken to for the last time
And in what order will that benefit you?
You have aspirations
on what you want to accomplish in this life.
Correct?
So why is it?
That this shoot
is dramatically put on hold
because you cannot keep your tongue pressed
firmly against those teeth?
Well your photographer...
One takes a picture of a rose,
regardless of the equipment or the skill
behind it.
It is still a rose.
Correct?
I’m sorry if I’ve insulted you in some way.
I just wanted some...
direction.
professionalism...
Direction?
Professionalism?
Mannequin?
Do you know what a mannequin is?
Yeah.
Mannequin does not talk,
you see, a mannequin
is a blank canvas
that one can showcase clothing
You are here to sell the items you are wearing,
not what is underneath them.
It doesn’t matter who we get,
the clothing sells itself.
A mannequin is for display purposes only,
you bring as much to this shoot
as a fucking clothes-horse.
You stop to ask for direction?
Can I ask you a question real quick?
Am I telling you how to do your job,
or are you telling me how to do mine?
Because we’re not doing the latter
ON MY FUCKING TIME!!!
Here
take one for the road.
Now get the fuck out of my studio.
Do i know you?
It's possible we met once before.
But.
as you've no recolletion.
Then collectively..
no.
Well you obviously
didn’t leave a good enough impression
did you.
We never do.
Come around.
I knew you’d be here
What would you do if I wasn’t?
Wait, you’d come eventually
I didn’t want to be alone tonight
But you are.
Let's begin
Don't shut it out.
Let it in.
Let if feed on your darkest thoughts,
and desires.
Your hatred.
It is bound to you,
as you are to it.
Come
let it out.
Let it breath
yes ..having to entertain these fucking models
your sending me.
Amateurs
all thinking they’re going to be the next Cara...
They'll only be good enough for toilet selfies
when i'm done with them.
Gumtree!
You insult me with Gumtree!
calling themselfs freelancers
They haven't even got the decency
to come through a proper agency.
I don't give a fuck who they
advertise themselfs as.
It's just Craigslist without the STI.
I know I know
just being facetious
Yep
Yep I got the delivery.
Yep.
Fucking Yank.
Tacete!
The last your name will be spoken.
Byron.
A warm welcome ladies and gentlemen
to The Old Familiar.
For a very special evening.
My names Archie.
I'm your announcer and your Bouncer
You can heckel but i'll kick your teeth in.
Hello.
Hello sweetheart.
Hello Shania.
I've shagged her.
Let herself go a little bit.
Haven't we all?
And now without further ado
Sorry i missed this one.
Each writer is going to come up
display his talents for you.
Please.
Show your appreciation to them.
We'll get on with the evening.
So...HAPPY HALLOWEEN!!
What you doing man?
What was that?
(laughing)
Relax.
Are screams not the soundtrack of halloween?
The very ambience of this evening?
They are merely gunshots to bonfire night.
The sounds that dwell
in familiarity of darkness.
Excactly.
So don't be scared Laura.
You won't feel a thing.
I promise you.
You see
I am really the ONLY writer in attendance
this evening.
You are my
my characters
my puppets
my pawns.
For me to do with what ever i wil.
Your not here to tell your stories.
YOU ARE THE STORIES.
SURPRISE!!!!
HAHAHAHA!!