This is Christy Colleran
for Satellite News Network
here in downtown Chicago,
covering stories
the world over
24 hours a day.
Here he comes.
CAMERAMAN: Rolling.
State's Attorney Roy Ridnitz
today announced that he would
challenge Governor Holt
in the upcoming
Democratic primary.
It's a matter
of public record
that these two men
haven't agreed on
almost any issue.
The campaign promises to be
a good old Chicago dogfight.
Yeah!
It's over, ma'am.
We got him.
The captain
just informed me
the police have finally
captured the infamous
Southside sniper.
(GUNSHOT)
We'll keep you informed.
Here you go, Christy.
It may look like rain
to the rest of you,
but on Lake Shore Drive
it's sunshine all the way.
Aah! That's right, Chicago!
Hit me! Beat me!
I love it!
This is Christy Colleran,
Satellite Network News.
MAN: Five, four,
three, two, one. Hit it!
It's 4:00 a.m.,
and here are
the fast-breaking stories
from around the world.
Today is a red-letter day
for the Chicago county jail.
Three hours after
the State Supreme Court
upheld the death sentence
of convicted cop killer
Ike Roscoe,
the authorities started
dusting off this old chair.
Chicago's first electrocution
in 27 years
is scheduled for July 15th
at midnight.
This man is
soft on crime.
He's soft
on the Soviets.
He's absolutely limp
on a voluntary
drug-testing system...
Limp? How can you
be limp on that?
Governor, please.
Gentlemen!
We're out of time.
I hate the Russians
as much as you.
Shit! Let's go.
So
that's what it's like
to roll a car
at the Cicero
stock car racetrack.
For SNN News,
this is Christy...
Christy...
What the hell
is my last name?
This just in.
At 12:00 noon today,
15,000 students
from all 50 states
will be joined
electronically
to play
Darktown Strutters' Ball
on the kazoo
for the President
of the United States.
(VOICE CRACKING)
The President is
a former kazoo player
and may wish to join in.
Hey, wait a minute!
We're doing a story
about 15,000 kazoo players
and the President
of the United States?
I can't believe...
I think my ex-wife
is cracking up.
What do you mean,
give her a vacation?
CHRISTY: Ha ha ha!
Give her a vacation.
Ha-ha!
Miss.
Ah-choo!
Oh! It's the fresh air.
Thank you.
Christy Colleran.
Bienvenue, Madame Colleran.
Oh, no!
That's Miss Colleran.
Mademoiselle Colleran.
We have a double bed.
Is that okay?
I don't care
what size... Oh!
Uh...
I'm--I'm very sorry.
No problem.
You were saying
s-something?
We have lots of things
here for you to do.
We have sailing.
Beautiful sailboats
for one or two.
Oh!
Need a lift?
Hi. Yes, please.
Hang on.
Here you go.
Grab my hand.
Aah!
Hi.
Canoes are
kind of tricky, huh?
Yeah.
I'll get you a towel.
Oh!
There you go.
Um... Do you mind
if I do my own hair?
Sure.
Well, uh, I guess
I owe you one.
How about
if I take you
to dinner?
Just be sure you keep
your credit card
in your pocket.
So...
What do you do
when you're not pulling
women out of the lake?
I run a sporting
goods company
in New York.
We make tennis balls,
gym equipment and...
Who cares?
God, your hair
looks amazing
in the moonlight.
So does yours.
Thank you.
Thanks, Henry.
We'll just be a minute.
Yes, sir.
She's here, Sully.
Oh. I'm up.
Sully!
What?
They're taking him
to the jail right now!
Hi, Abby.
Christy! Welcome back.
How was your vacation?
Incredible.
I brought someone back.
I'd like you
to meet Mr. Bingham.
Hi.
Where's the ayatollah?
In the pit.
I'll just be
10 minutes, Blaine.
Anything I can do to help?
I think after eight years
in a marriage,
I should tell him myself.
I'll just be
10 minutes.
I can't handle
being away from you for 10.
I'll make it five.
Uh, we haven't been apart
for the last...482 hours.
Yes, sir.
Stand back!
Late show's broadcasting
all week from the Summit
in Belgium.
How many people
are you sending?
One.
One?
Nothing happens
at summits.
No one knows where
the hell Belgium is.
Right. Call
on line two.
Ludlow!
Jesus, what an airhead!
Sully!
Yeah.
Christy, get downtown.
They just moved Roscoe
from the pen to the jail.
Three weeks in Canada,
and this is my welcome?
No! Welcome back!
Thank God you're back.
Get down to the jail.
I can't.
This is the story
of the century!
I've got news
of my own.
MAN ON TV: Get back!
The cameraman fell down!
We got a dog's
point of view!
And so, with the clang
of the cell doors,
and the hiss of 120,000 volts
of Illinois power
less than 12 hours away...
Nice image, Ludlow.
...now being led
to his lonely,
private vigil...
What a Twinkie!
...waiting, perhaps eagerly,
for his own
personal death knell
and deliverance.
For Satellite News Network,
I'm Karen Ludlow.
Chicago county jail, Chicago.
Dear God!
Save me from reporters
that have read a book.
Missed you.
Nobody to fight with.
I've never been happier.
You romantics think
divorce is a passport
to happiness.
If you're unhappy,
why didn't you contest
the divorce?
Because you didn't ask
for a dime,
and you accused me
of having an affair
with Margaret Thatcher.
You're lucky I didn't claim
the war in Afghanistan.
We've had great stories,
haven't we?
That's your problem.
Everything's a story to you.
There's never been a story
more important to me than you.
On our first anniversary,
you sent me to cover
the 10-second war
in Grenada.
Is it my fault
a volcano decided to erupt?
It's your fault
we had to go cover it.
We're in the news business.
You can't experience
lava indoors.
I'm quitting
the news business.
You're always quitting
Why is there a fire
on channel four,
and we don't have it?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
What?
Breakfast, boss,
and 24-hour ratings.
How are they?
They dropped two points,
but Christy's back now.
Oh. Ludlow's
not working out, huh?
Yes, she's working out.
It's not her fault
the news is lousy.
Same healthy breakfast,
I see.
Why don't you relieve
Ludlow at the jail?
I told you
I'm quitting.
Yeah.
I'm tired
of space shuttles
and trips to Bhopal.
Sure.
I'd like a nice, normal,
relaxed kind of life.
Oh. One other thing.
I'm getting married.
I can't leave you alone
for a minute.
Boss, I got a tape
of that fire you wanted!
I thought you were happy
with the divorce.
Who is he?
I met him
on vacation.
He's not in
the news business.
What are you
going to talk about?
Who needs to talk?
Yeah, right.
We're getting married
the day after tomorrow
in New York.
Jesus, why so soon?
I didn't feel like being
engaged for four years
and eight months again.
Blaine's
been married before.
What's his first name?
Blaine is his first name.
Blaine Bingham.
Siegenthaler!
Is he rich?
As a matter
of fact, yes.
Siegenthaler,
kick satellite 11.
How rich?
Well, he owns his own
building in New York
and he's the country's
largest supplier
of athletic equipment.
Athletic equipment?
Bowling balls
and baseball mitts?
Well!
That should make
for very snappy pillow talk.
Ha ha ha!
Again!
Perfect.
Blaine is a wonderful man.
He is decent
and kind and caring.
Sounds like someone
I should marry.
You're going to live
in an office building?
No. He has an apartment
at the UN Plaza,
house in Oyster Bay,
condo in Nice...
Ow!
Pinched nerve?
Yeah. Would you...
No.
You're going
to become gracious,
have power din-dins
with the yuppies
from the firm.
And lots of babies.
I could have given you
all the babies you wanted.
I could have had them
without your help,
aside from
your heavy chores
of conceiving.
Blaine wants
to nurture them.
No, he doesn't.
He wants to make them
into angry little lawyers.
Roscoe's behind bars.
What about Ludlow?
Keep her there.
No food and no water.
This will be
a big story.
Hmm.
You're giving up
the news business
to marry
a rowing-machine hustler?
No, just reporting.
I start as the new host
on AM Manhattan.
With the overweight
weatherman?
And the afternoons off.
Interviewing entertainers,
dregs of the world.
And a home life.
Gonna have it all, huh?
Gonna try.
If you want
to move to New York
and raise little suits,
I'm for it 1,000%.
You can fall in love
in three weeks.
Took us only two.
Was it that long
for you?
Oh!
Mmm!
I love it
when you're sincere.
It's completely transparent,
but it's kind of charming.
Well, Sully,
I'll see you.
Why don't I take
you and Brains to lunch?
Blaine.
Blaine. Tell him
to meet us.
We're on our way
to the airport.
The little rascal's
out there,
and you wouldn't
let me meet him?
Afraid of the comparison?
After you.
They filed for bankruptcy?
Sir!
Great!
Guess what, Abigail.
Hmm?
My principal competition
just collapsed.
Oh?
They got leveraged too high,
couldn't use a rollover,
so sharks got them.
Sign in, please, sir.
(WHISTLING)
Bingham,
John L. Sullivan IV.
(SPEAKING LOUDLY)
How are you?
I hear you're a terrific
racquetball player.
This is not him.
No?
That's him.
Hi.
Ha-ha! Sorry.
She said the guy
with the tic.
I've heard
a lot about you.
Christy, Rinehart Brothers
just went belly up.
Blaine, that's wonderful!
You own
this network?
No. He's a little guy,
looks like Hitler.
Sorry about
the hot weather, Bingham.
Glasses tied around your neck
in case a basketball game
breaks out?
You're marrying
a wonderful girl.
Yes, I know.
Don't let her reaction
to shellfish put you off.
A lot of people swell up,
get blotches all over.
I used to take lotion
and put it everywhere.
Anyway,
don't worry about it.
The scratching goes away
after a week or so.
This girl has
a great mouth.
Blaine knows everything
about me, Sully.
He does?
Even the, uh...
Just kidding.
You're a lucky man.
I mean that
in all sincerity.
Thanks. Know what she did
the third time we went out?
Do we ever.
Oh.
I wish you'd let me
take you two to lunch
as a kind of hail
and farewell.
We've got reservations
on a 4:00 flight.
Is the corporate jet down?
They're in Texas today.
Blaine, this is Chicago,
"Hog butcher to the world."
Planes leaving every
hour to New York.
It isn't often
a man meets the love
of his ex-wife's life.
Oh.
We were going to eat.
An hour wouldn't hurt.
Are you sure, darling?
Sure.
Me Sully,
you darling.
Blaine, I love
that jacket.
Oh, thanks.
If the lapels were
a little wider, it would
almost be too post-retro.
Look great
with my jodhpurs.
Oh, you ride?
Only at night!
What car are we taking?
The Rolls.
Sullivan, I love your town.
Did you know Chicago
means the smell
of wild onions?
New York just
means New York.
I left my computer.
I'll get it.
Siegenthaler!
Book every seat on every
airline going to New York
in the next 24 hours.
Sully, that'll take
all day.
Book the White Sox,
the Cubs,
every employee at ABC News.
I'll be at the restaurant.
Then put me
on the election.
This makes
the election look
like the opening
of Al Capone's vault.
I need someone with a strong
journalistic background...you!
Sully, I majored
in phys. ed.!
Perfect! You won't
run out of breath!
Sully, your table's ready.
Christy and I
will have the usual.
Two shooters,
wild turkey.
A Perrier with lime,
and hold the ice.
I'll have to send out for it.
Watch this guy.
Yeah!
Whew!
I love that fist.
Here you go, babe.
Joe, two shooters,
wild turkey!
Send out for a Perrier.
Sorry.
I thought you said
it was quiet.
It gets very quiet
between pitches.
So...
So you two
are getting married?
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Have the results
of the blood test yet?
Is there something
you've forgotten to tell me?
He's right.
Over the last
couple of years,
I've had 16 pints
of my blood frozen
and stored, just in case.
My God, 16 pints?
Day after tomorrow,
eight of those pints
are yours.
Aw.
I don't...
I think that's
so thoughtful of you.
What else have you got
saved up for a rainy day?
Sully, don't you think
that's enough?
The way you drink, maybe
he's got a spare liver
stored someplace.
Your Perrier's coming.
All right!
MAN: Go!
Come on! Four!
So you're what
a television newsman
looks like.
And you sell
jockstraps.
Seventeen million
worldwide this year alone.
If I'd invented
that little thing,
I'd be rich today.
Aren't you rich?
A multimillionaire?
What do you mean
by multi?
More than one.
Blaine, don't discuss
our finances with him.
Our?
Our.
Sully!
Pastrami's good.
Chicken salad.
You do
anything grilled?
You name it.
A little piece of fresh fish,
mesquite-grilled.
Put sauteed baby vegetables
on the side.
What did he say?
Three specials
and a pitcher of beer.
Hearty, but light.
You got it.
Blaine knows
everything about food.
That's important,
to know everything
about food.
Really.
Sully.
Yo.
Yeah?
American and United,
booked.
Working on TWA.
Hell of a reporter.
She'll get the Peabody
this year.
Talking about Ludlow.
What are you talking
about Ludlow for?
She's doing
a great job.
Where is he?
She gets over
400 fan letters a week,
three proposals
of marriage.
I'll call back
6:00 New York time.
Arrives this afternoon? Okay.
Fifty more.
Write it down.
I'm doing
the best I can!
Ludlow's filling
my shoes, huh?
Yes.
That Twinkie
couldn't fill my shoes
with an extra
pair of feet.
She's covering
Ike Roscoe's execution.
Who's Ike Roscoe?
BOTH: You don't know
who Ike Roscoe is?
His picture's been
in the paper every day
the last three months.
He's not in
the financial section.
He'll die for a crime
he should have committed.
Should have committed?
Ike Roscoe's son died
of a drug overdose.
He shot the dealer,
who was a cop.
Here you are.
They don't like it here
when you kill a cop.
That cop was supplying
dope for over half
the high schools.
The judge wouldn't allow
drug evidence
and sentenced Ike
to death.
He dies tonight
at 12:01.
Can't the governor
pardon him?
He could,
but we're talking politics.
Chicago politics.
In this town, rain
is a political deal.
Besides, the state attorney
that got the conviction
is running against
the governor. Excuse me.
Oh, yeah.
They're both trying
to out law-and-order
each other.
Can't something be done?
Yeah. I could
fire that hack Ludlow,
and your fiancee here
could do
one last interview.
Maybe it would be
so touching
that the governor
would change his mind.
Come off it, Sully.
It isn't fair to ask anyone
to postpone their wedding trip
to save a man's life.
Could Christy interviewing
Ike Roscoe really change
the governor's mind?
Yeah!
Thousand to one.
Ten to one.
Twelve to one.
You've got to, honey.
We'll take a later plane.
Don't you see
what he's doing?
He doesn't care
about Ike!
He wants a hot lead
on the 6:00!
If it means
it could save a man's life...
Do you see
what I'm marrying?
A decent human being.
It's a weird adjustment.
Do you really
want me to do it, darling?
Yes.
I got to stop.
Me Sully. He darling.
I'd never
forgive myself
if you didn't try.
How long will it take?
Two hours. You'll be
on a plane by 7:00.
No problem.
Three specials!
Fresh from
the microwave.
Perrier's coming!
This is light?
Cottage cheese, see?
I'll do the interview
on one condition.
You got it.
SNN needs a gym.
A what?
With the finest
Bingham equipment,
rowing machines,
bicycles...
Solarium, sauna.
Exercise
is bad for you!
More people die
from exercise
than from cancer.
That's not true.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Fill out
the order form.
This could cost
over $100,000.
Hundred and fifty.
A man's life,
Sully, remember?
Do you give, uh...
Discounts?
Never.
Okay. Where do I sign?
Well, thank you
very much. Pleasure.
Put down that sausage,
and get over to the jail!
Christy, I'll meet
you at the office
in an hour.
Good to have you back.
Don't forget, Blaine,
he pays.
Okay. Have fun.
(POLICE RADIO)
Jasper.
Christy,
how you doin'?
Fine.
What are
you up to?
Here to see the warden.
Hey, Eddie.
I can't let you
interview him
when I've turned down
everyone else.
Yes, you can.
Why?
I know about
those romantic visits
you arranged between prisoners
and their girlfriends
right in
your own office.
Now, who told you
about that?
True, isn't it?
You wouldn't understand,
being a girl.
A man needs
a little release.
Profitable release.
You charge inmates
200 bucks a visit.
All right, now just a minute.
That makes you a
pimp or a madam.
I'm not a pimp
or a madam!
In that case,
we can use this
on a new feature
we're doing on innovative
prison techniques tomorrow.
(GULP)
Unless I talk
to Ike Roscoe.
(COUGH)
BLAINE: Tell Bob
I want to order a gym
for Chicago right away.
That'll be great.
Hmm?
The whole thing.
Yeah. We're
just closing now.
It's a killer deal.
There's a pen
in my briefcase
if you need it.
What?
That's ridiculous!
They can't all be booked.
What's going on?
Uh-huh.
That's okay.
No problem.
We'll go to Plan B.
Yeah. Christy is
going to love it.
Wait till I tell her.
Siegenthaler!
Goodbye.
Have you booked
the, uh...
Bookings?
Just finished.
My girls can't talk.
(HOARSE VOICE)
Can we go home?
Please! Please!
God, you sound awful!
Thanks!
Good work, kids.
Take the day off.
See ya.
Bye.
Okay? Thanks a lot.
Every seat
on every flight
from Chicago to New York
is booked the next 24 hours.
The garbage strike
must be over.
Oh, thanks.
You'll leave
in the morning?
No. There's nothing
quite so romantic
as an overnight
train ride.
There's one tonight
at 11:00.
Yeah.
Beds are a little short,
but it's quaint.
Be back in a minute.
Oh!
Don't move!
Book every ticket
on the train to New York
for the next 24 hours!
Oh, is that all?
Boats, buses,
helicopters, too.
We can't!
The network's future
is at stake!
Get me the mail room.
We should buy
all the sneakers,
in case the guy
wants to jog
to New York.
I'm expecting
athletic equipment
from Bingham Industries.
Hit a couple
of exercise bikes
with a hammer
and ship the whole shebang
back as damaged goods.
Whose names do we use now?
Streets!
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
Yeah?
You did it, Christy!
I knew you could.
When are you
seeing him?
Not so fast. No interview
till you sign the deal.
I signed it!
I'd like to talk
to Blaine.
BLAINE: Hi, darling,
are you having fun?
Blaine,
did he sign it?
Sure did.
Not disappearing ink, is it?
He didn't date it 1888?
No.
No nicknames?
What do you mean?
Once he signed
a reporter's contract
"Peter Rabbit."
Ha ha!
No. It's all
completely legal, dear.
Sweetheart,
I do this every day.
Listen.
Do you mind?
Hmm?
Oh!
Darling, all the airlines
were booked,
but I've got us tickets
on the 11:00 train tonight.
It'll be just like
North by Northwest.
You already got tickets?
Yes.
You didn't tell me.
I didn't think
you'd be that interested.
Siegenthaler, cancel
what I just said!
What? Sully, you...
Okay.
Bye-bye.
She's going to make
a great little wife,
like another appendage,
an extra arm or leg.
She's real concerned
about my business, too.
After tomorrow,
she'll have half of it
and all that blood.
Like community
property? No, no.
Our relationship is
more profound than that.
We've both made
horrible, agonizing
mistakes before.
Sorry. No offense.
We don't want
to do it again.
But I love her
a staggering amount.
Very unusual for me.
(WHISTLING)
You make me
very nostalgic for her.
We just had a very
physical relationship.
Juices intermingling...
You know.
Hardly ever talked.
Sex,
sex...
sex.
I think she's happier
out of the cave.
Course she is!
You're right.
Marrying Christy will be
like having another leg.
Tell her that.
She'll love it!
I have got a great idea.
I'm going to get a picnic
for the train.
Champagne, caviar,
silver candlesticks.
We met
because of a candle.
Say, do you know
where I could get some?
Silver candlesticks?
Absolutely.
Great.
I know
a perfect place.
Siegenthaler,
I need you.
You are really
a good sport.
Christy warned me
about you.
Said you'd be a lot
different, not so nice.
I'm a hard guy to know.
Yo!
Where you been?
Take Mr. Bingham
to the silver store.
Where is one?
State of Illinois Tower.
The Tower has
a silver store?
That's the place.
Siegenthaler,
I'm very busy.
Sullivan, did you
actually sign
a reporter's contract
"Peter Rabbit"?
Yes.
What did
the reporter do?
Christy laughed her ass off.
Ha ha ha!
Can I ask you
a question?
Sure.
It's slightly
personal.
It's okay.
Do you streak
your hair?
Sure. Tried six
different colors.
I had Burnished Peaches,
but it was brassy.
Now it's
Mellow Sun Tone.
I think it works.
Works for me.
Me, too.
Bye.
Bye, guys.
Happy shopping.
Abigail!
Sir?
If that dildo
comes back,
search every orifice
he has.
Yes, sir!
Hey, everybody!
Hey!
Tell this guy,
if he delivers his ward,
he can be city sealer.
And his wife?
We'll put her in charge
of...a landmark.
$75,000 a year
is easy for her.
Oh. Oh, ho,
ho, yes.
I love it.
Hey, everybody,
I love these!
(APPLAUSE)
If we carry
the election,
I'll put
his whole family
in office.
The baby, too?
In charge of
parking violations.
Mr. Ridnitz!
What's so urgent?
It's Warden Terwilliger.
What does he
want, anyway?
Hey, Twig!
How are ya?
You did what?
(SIREN)
Hey, listen to me.
I spent two months
making sure
that nobody got an interview
with Ike Roscoe.
Now you're telling me
that you gave one to that...
Female reporter
on the night
of his execution?
I don't care what
she's got on you!
Call it off,
or you will not
be the warden of...
Understand?
Whatever you do, make sure
they don't catch you
on camera
refusing to be interviewed.
That's how Mike Wallace
got me last year.
No! Stop them!
He's changed his mind.
Let's roll tape.
We're rolling,
Terwilliger.
You're not trying
to prevent the public
from hearing
the final words
of a condemned man,
are you, Warden?
No. I was...
Trying to make sure
you got in okay.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Are you sure about this?
This is a vicious killer...
(SLAM)
Driven absolutely mad
with rage.
Hello, Ike.
Hi, Miss Colleran.
Thank you
for giving me
this interview.
I'd do anything for you.
You're the only one
who's been decent to me
except for Pamela.
Pamela Farbrother,
your lawyer?
How are they
treating you here, Ike?
I can't complain.
I mean, I never get to see
anybody but the guards,
but they're
pretty nice fellows.
Would you share
your thoughts, Ike?
Now I know what it's like
to be without hope.
All those months
I kept thinking,
"They're not going
to kill me."
All I wanted
was my boy back,
but now I know
they are going to kill me.
I know this is painful,
but would you go over
that horrible night
one more time?
Anthony was a quiet kid.
He didn't have
many friends.
He wanted to be
in the newspaper business.
What that man did
to him...
Needle marks along
his arm, inside his thigh.
He used to defecate in his bed.
That's what the drugs did.
He became a dealer
to--to keep his habit going.
That's how I found out
the name of the supplier.
Edward Kisinski.
What happened then?
January 18th...
Please, Ike.
Go on if you can.
On January 18th,
he--he went for a walk
completely zonked
and just fell off
the bridge.
I went downtown
to this shop off State Street
and bought a .38 special.
I went to Kisinski's house
and shot him over and over.
I ran out of bullets.
He was positively
the dealer?
I saw him sell Tony the stuff.
I didn't know he was a cop,
but I'm not sorry.
He killed Tony and who knows
how many other kids.
I--I did it for revenge
and nothing more.
Maybe I'm getting
what I deserve.
No. You're not.
You don't deserve
to be executed.
I'm gonna be.
You know what today is?
It's Houdini's birthday.
I used to practice tricks
when I was working
as a magician.
Anthony helped me with
the inverted water bottle.
Is there a favorite trick
of Anthony's
you could do here?
It's just a pen.
Very clever.
Terrific!
It's the simplest trick,
but it always fooled Tony.
Houdini would be proud.
Not even Houdini
could get out
of this place.
That's it.
Thank you, Ike.
Come on, Ike.
Let's go.
Thank you,
Miss Colleran.
I'll do
everything I can.
Come on, boys.
BLAINE: Some say it's
a monkey. Some say a poodle.
It's untitled,
but the contrast against
the vertical building
is really amazing.
I've got one
of those.
One of those?
No. A couple paintings.
It's a great town.
After New York,
Chicago is the best
in the country.
Yeah?
Hello.
Cute buns.
There's no pen
in my pen.
Hold it, Roscoe.
You know
the procedure.
(SLAM)
Okay. In you go.
Fred, you want
a coffee?
Yeah. Okay.
Anything on tonight?
I think the game's on.
All right.
What channel?
Uh, two?
Uh...
Wow.
It's huge.
So, where's Covalof's?
Seventeenth floor.
I can't go up there.
Okay. Tell you what.
Let me give you
my American Express card.
Get two candlesticks
for under two grand.
I couldn't, Mr. Bingham.
They check the signature
and the I.D.
Don't you want
to pick it yourself?
Yeah. Yeah.
(WHISTLING)
I can do it.
Aah!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop what?
Mr. Bingham.
Please! Stop it!
Stop it!
What's the matter,
Mr. Bingham?
Uh! Uh!
Mr. Bingham,
are you okay?
Is there something...
Uh! Uh!
Don't touch that!
Don't! Don't!
Ahh! Ahh!
That's the emergency button,
Mr. Bingham.
(ALARM RINGS)
Mommy! Mommy!
Help me!
Oh! Help me!
Dichotomy.
Egregious.
Shit!
So, Ludlow...
Karen.
Karen,
welcome to TV news.
What the hell
is she doing here?
Come on, guys.
We got action.
Colleran! Geez!
Come on, Bill.
(CHANTING)
Anybody got hamburger?
The zoo's out,
and the pandas
are hungry.
Christy! Christy!
What are you
doing here?
The governor's going
to pardon Ike.
You're kidding!
He's going to juice
the DA instead.
Beautiful pun.
Come on, Christy.
What were you doing?
Hey, how are you?
Weren't you
talking to Ike?
Did he say anything?
Who?
You don't win Emmys
for backstabbing.
That's exactly how
you win Emmys.
I'm through
with this business.
You, through
with the business?
Bullshit!
I'm off to the Big Apple
and a morning talk show.
An indoor job?
In two days, I will be
a happily married woman.
I thought you
were happily married.
Sully was
the miserable one!
Zaks, that's almost
as funny
as your series on
sexual harassment
in the supermarkets.
Low blow.
Nice shot.
I've got a tag waiting.
What's the tag?
Tune in at 6:00,
Tillinger.
She hasn't got anything.
All talk.
She didn't see him.
I'm going back
to the truck.
Yeah, me, too.
Whatever she tells me,
I'll tell you, okay?
I wish you guys
would stop following me.
Can she ever walk!
Hey! Let's take
the elevator.
Good idea.
You bastards!
Hi, Jessica.
Can I plug in here?
My desk is gone.
Christy!
How you doing?
Hey, beauty!
Welcome back
to reality.
What's your hurry?
Television's always
in a hurry.
Have no fear.
TV's here.
It's the mannequins
coming to find out
where the nonfiction is.
What have you got?
Where did you
get this?
I don't have
to look pretty.
I work for
a newspaper.
Nineteenth-century
journalism.
Yeah, Nancy.
Jack here.
Come on, Christy.
Dig up
your own dirt.
They couldn't dig up flowers.
For hard news,
they come here.
My TV's just
for my cat.
You'd drop your drawers
to be on TV.
I'd drop my drawers
to fart on overpaid
anchorpersons.
Ooh!
Now, that's a low blow.
Obie, can I use
your Xerox?
It's not a Xerox.
It's better.
25 cents.
It's nothing personal.
I know. I know.
Don't read it.
Just print it.
JESSICA: City press room.
Come on, Christy.
You interviewed him.
Who's going
to the
post-electrocution party?
You're sick.
Anyone interested
in an 82-year-old
heart attack victim
who drove through
a store window?
No!
Nothing here, Al.
They could postpone
this goddamn execution
until a decent hour.
Nobody watches
at 12:14.
Even Ted Koppel's asleep.
Isn't it 12:01?
10 minutes to fry him.
Three to get on TV.
You people have
no morals or integrity.
The conscience
of America.
You make jokes
while an undeserving man
gets electrocuted.
He's not undeserving.
You lost the case.
And the appeals!
Give up!
You lost.
He killed
a drug dealer.
Jury says
he killed a cop.
The four cops who swore
Kisinski was a dealer
got amnesia in court.
Ridnitz bribed
the witnesses.
I haven't heard that
since you lost.
Another point
you never proved.
He did bribe them!
If you weren't
preoccupied with eyeliner,
you might have
reported that.
You just cared about
book and TV deals.
I'm surprised
you didn't assume
we were sleeping together.
My God!
Were you?
No!
We usually save
that question for
presidential candidates.
A decent man
is going to die.
You're doing nothing
to prevent it.
Gentlemen of the press.
And that includes
you, Jessica.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
City press room.
Christy.
It's for you.
Line one.
Yes?
Yes, Siegenthaler.
What the hell
are you doing there?
What?
He won't let go.
The police can't
get him loose.
They can't
get him away from
the emergency button.
He's screaming
and kicking them.
Oh, for God's sake!
Tell him
I'll be right there.
It's a 555 number.
All right.
I'll hold.
Well?
She left the press room
20 minutes ago.
Then where the hell
is she?
Sully!
What?
Mr. Berger's
in your office.
Sully, we need more fires.
You got
a problem, Max?
Nothing some
visual action can't cure.
Family visual action.
No smut.
There's too much smut,
not enough fires.
Every day I got
a special unit
looking
for smutless fires.
You didn't
have one Thursday.
In Tokyo and London
they don't give a damn
about a Chicago fire.
People watch fires,
rapes, re-enacted murders,
overturned cars
in preference
to anything else,
except maybe a war
that's not too boring.
Those boring wars really cut
into the ratings.
Don't get sarcastic
with me now, Sully.
You're a good newsman,
but you've got contempt
for the public,
and your features
are running too long.
After a minute,
everyone switches channels.
Max, did you ever think
about running
for an office
like president?
And lose all my influence
in Washington?
You got a fire for me
tonight at 6:00?
I got something better.
(ALARM RINGS)
Christy!
What's he doing up here?
Buying you a present,
but there aren't any stores
on the 17th floor.
I don't know why Sully
sent him up here.
I do.
I'll sue. I'll sue.
Blaine.
Please, honey.
It's okay. It's me.
How are you?
They want me
to move, but I'm not moving.
What if I take off
all my clothes,
slip out
of my stockings,
so I was just
in my underwear.
Then you could
tear that off
with your teeth.
(ALARM STOPS)
I don't know.
Finally.
Oh, yes!
What the...
It worked on the plane.
Come on, Christy!
Fifteen minutes to air!
Ten minutes to air!
Where is she?
Come on, guys.
Come on.
Move it.
Take it to editing.
You take it.
I'll take it.
No time to edit.
I forgot.
You take it.
I have to deal with Sully.
I'm frisking you.
What are you
talking about?
I've gotta frisk you!
No, thanks. Never mind.
It's fine.
Where's Blaine?
Hurry, Christy.
Where the hell
you been?
Got the tape?
They're racking it up
now, you bastard.
How could you
do that to Blaine?
Who?
Thirty seconds to air!
How could you send him
in a glass elevator
when you know he's afraid
of heights?
How could I know?
He's so tall!
You!
What's the lead, Sully?
What's the lead, Christy?
Former reporter
slays ex-husband
in TV studio.
Twenty seconds.
I swear
I wouldn't hurt him.
How's the language?
I never use bad language,
you son of a bitch!
Ten seconds!
Go with it!
I've met some lowlifes
in this business.
Murderers, pimps,
but you are the worst!
You are
a ruthless, manipulative
bullying asshole...
Good evening.
This is Christy Colleran
with the SNN evening news.
And this is
Frank Chadman.
I'm gonna miss her.
She ain't gone yet.
Now for our top story
of the evening.
In an exclusive interview,
the first since
his appeal was denied,
cop killer dad Ike Roscoe
talked to me about the events
that tragic night in January
when his only son died
and he killed
an off-duty cop.
IKE: All those months
I kept thinking,
"They're not
going to kill me."
All I wanted
was my boy back,
but now I know
they are going to kill me.
CHRISTY: I know
this is painful,
but would you go back over
that horrible night
one more time?
He wanted to be
in the newspaper business.
Darling, please!
What that man
did to him...
Needle marks
along his arm,
inside his thigh.
He became a dealer
to--to keep his habit going.
That's how I found out
the name of the supplier.
(GIRLS SINGING)
Be quiet!
Aw!
Please, Ike.
Go on if you can.
Here. Have a piece
of pizza.
Quiet.
On January 18th...
Stop with that cat!
Anybody else
for Coke?
... he--he went for a walk
completely zonked...
I said quiet.
...and just
fell off the bridge.
Maybe I'm getting
what I deserve.
No. You're not.
You don't deserve
to be executed.
I'm gonna be.
Your Gatorade,
Governor.
Thank you.
You know what today is?
It's Houdini's birthday.
I used to practice tricks
when I was working
as a magician.
Anthony helped me with
the inverted water bottle.
Is there a favorite trick
of Anthony's
you could do here?
Not even Houdini
could get out
of this place.
That's it.
Thank you, Ike.
A journalist is
supposed to be objective.
There are some things
more important
than journalism.
Since this is
my final story,
I'll lay it
on the line.
Ike Roscoe
should not be executed.
He is being used
as a political Ping Pong ball
by a creep
of a state's attorney
and a weakling
of a governor.
What this state needs
is a chief executive
with the guts to forgive,
not just a macho hard-ass
because his polls
tell him to be.
Are you watching,
Springfield?
You've got
six hours, Governor.
If you pardon Ike Roscoe,
you could lose the election,
but you might
just regain your conscience.
This is Christy Colleran,
formerly of
Satellite News Network.
Thank you, Christy,
and welcome back.
The execution is planned
for 12:01 tonight.
Ahem. And as we promised,
we planned or expect
to have some victims
of previous executions
for you later on.
Should read, "witnesses
of previous executions
for you later on."
Christy! Christy!
You were beautiful.
"Hard-ass creep."
It was inspiring.
We could lose
our license.
Christy!
Blaine! Did you see it?
Did you?
No. I couldn't
get through security.
That...woman
frisked me.
I'm gonna kill you.
Who, me?
Boss!
(ALL GROANING)
Berger.
Yeah!
What did you expect her
to say, "the alleged creep"?
He's a creep!
Of course
I screened the tape
before I ran it.
Mr. Berger objects
to the use
of the word "ass."
He finds it smutty.
That's all he got
out of it?
That's all.
Shit! God!
God damn it!
Let me speak
to the governor.
I want him to free
that little Roscoe man,
or I'll blow up
the mansion.
Let him go, or every black man
will vote for Ridnitz.
You tell the governor
if he doesn't pardon him,
he is going to lose
the yuppie vote.
I wish I knew what to do.
Uh! God!
We've been discussing
this thing for months.
I think I'll pardon him.
Yeah.
Shouldn't I?
Well...
It depends...
I've had Wayne keep track
of your telephone calls.
Here are the numbers.
We have 367 to pardon
and two to kill.
Now I'm sure of it.
Right?
Shrewd.
Get me 15 minutes
of airtime at 8:00.
The viewers get mad
when you interrupt their
favorite shows like that.
Anyways, voters
don't watch primetime.
Voters watch the news.
11:00, sir.
I've got a much better idea.
Fifteen minutes at 11:00.
Good thinking.
And no leaks.
We don't want
the press to know
until the public does.
Good decision, Governor.
That's a winner.
Actually...
Yipes.
If I'm going to be
on television, I need sleep.
Crannock, you
handle the press.
Tell stations
we want the time,
but don't tell them why.
I don't agree
with this strategy.
Come on, let's move it.
There isn't much time.
Johnson, make sure
that makeup girl
is on time tonight.
Bryce, let's put him
in the blue suit.
Blue. Right.
Give me Ridnitz.
It's Crannock.
Yeah?
Oh, no.
When?
The Governor
is going to pardon him.
On the 11:00 news!
You know
what this means.
If that Roscoe twerp
doesn't fry,
I don't get elected.
And you all are
out of a job.
The governor is a...
Bad person.
Your families
will all starve.
What'll we do?
I hate bimbo...
Girl...
Television reporters.
Wait a minute.
Aah! Calm down, Roy.
You don't win billion-dollar
personal-injury lawsuits
by swearing at bleeding-heart
pantyhose reporters.
We're going
to kill him anyway.
Huh?
We're going to move up
the execution
because of the riots.
What riots?
The riots
and the bomb threats
scheduled for midnight
by the subversive,
anti-death penalty
left-wing terrorists.
Under advice
from Warden Terwilliger,
it is deemed necessary
to move the execution
up by two hours
in order to insure the safety
of the other mother...
Law-abiding prisoners.
Don't you need
a judge to do that?
I've got plenty of judges
in my pocket.
How do we keep this
from the media?
Invite them.
Invite them
to the execution?
The first televised
execution in history!
We're going to be
the lead
on every newscast
in this country.
Get down to the prison.
Get all the reporters
over there by 9:45.
Set up some refreshments.
The media is going
to love me for this!
Nobody out
law-and-orders Ridnitz.
Jim, Crannock here.
I need some time
on the 11:00 news. Yeah.
No, we can't elaborate now.
Is he still asleep?
The man could sleep
at a hockey game.
Check this speech.
Make sure
the press phone calls
come through me.
I love you, Christy!
Tomorrow, America
will love you.
They will name streets
after you.
Want a drink, Blaine?
Huh? No. No, thanks.
Not for me.
The switchboard
is lit up like Las Vegas!
(ALL CHEERING)
Here's to the greatest
news team since
Huntley and Brinkley.
Who, boss?
Never mind.
Okay.
Thank you.
Put that over there.
Maybe we
made the news.
Yeah!
Police are continuing
their investigation.
If we receive word,
we will bring it to you.
Chicago's O'Hare Airport
reports a record number
of no-shows
on flights to New York.
Apparently, 6,630 people
made reservations
and failed to show up.
Authorities suspect
a fraternity prank.
The tickets, too?
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
I'll get it!
Hello?
Yes, Crannock.
Say again. You got it!
Excuse me. The governor
would like 15 minutes
on television stations
at 11:00 across the state!
(ALL CHEERING)
Then he's going
to pardon him?
Why else would he
want the time?
You did it, Christy.
You did it!
You both did it!
Who's this?
Themistocles Berger.
He doesn't look
like Hitler.
You're fired.
That was
great journalism.
She's leaving us.
What?
I'm marrying this man.
He doesn't have a job.
What do you mean?
I fired him.
Time to go, dear.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
Hello! Yes, Morkum.
Bomb threats and riots?
What do you mean
the judge signed it?
A live execution?
Who's running
this state,
Pee-wee Herman?
What is it?
Ridnitz moved
the execution
up to 10:00.
No.
He's invited everybody
with an instamatic
to come tape it for posterity.
Siegenthaler, get me
the governor.
You're not going to tape
the electrocution, are you?
Yes, we are.
You people have
a hole in your hearts.
SIEGENTHALER:
Wake him up.
Maybe I won't
have to tape it.
The governor's unavailable.
He's taking a nap.
Something's starting
to stink here.
You're going to film
a man dying?
This is a news station,
not The Cosby Show.
That's right.
News is the most
important thing
in your life,
ahead of people, principles,
your own love life.
How do I change that?
Don't!
We have two hours
to save this man.
Get over
to Ridnitz's office!
We gotta get
to a train, thank you.
You'll never forgive yourself
if you don't do this.
No. That doesn't
work anymore!
Whoa, whoa! Time-out!
Let's calm down, okay?
I know this is exciting,
but we've got to be
in New York.
We made
all the plans, remember?
Yes, I know.
Okay.
If you want, tomorrow
I can have my PR guys
write a letter to The Times
condemning Ike's death
as an act of medieval barbarity,
but that's the bottom line.
Sweetheart, it's not
your life anymore. Remember?
I know.
Well, I have
a train to catch.
I don't want to miss it.
Goodbye, guys.
It's been hot
meeting you.
I always thought
newspaper people
were wimps, flakes,
and fruitcakes,
but it's not
that way at all.
I mean that from here.
(THUMPING CHEST)
Well, Sully,
I'll see you
when I see you.
Have a good life, Christina.
Forget about the girl.
Get the story.
The girl is the story.
Come on.
Keep moving.
Go ahead!
Quit shoving!
Take it easy!
Come on, come on!
Take it easy.
I'm Mrs. Kisinski.
Don't push me!
Slow down!
Hey, everybody, slow down!
Take it easy!
Clear the way, asshole!
Faster!
Move it!
Come on, pal,
move it!
They'll bring him
down the stairs.
I won't be able
to see a thing.
You don't have to.
You're a writer.
"...leadeth me in the paths
of righteousness.
"Yea, though I walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death,
"I will fear no evil
for thou art with me.
"Thou preparest
a table before me
"in the presence
of mine enemies."
I don't care!
Keep your god-damn
sound man out of my way!
Don't you have
something better to do?
I got better things to do
than listen to you.
Get your butt out of my face!
Gentlemen.
Gentlemen!
Hey!
Okay. Okay.
Now get down there.
Boys! Girls!
Are we rolling?
ALL: Yes, we're rolling.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to
the first execution
ever opened to our free
and uncensored press.
You would never see this
in the Soviet Union.
The State of Illinois
will be second to none
when it comes
to the protection
of victims.
Especially if
they're drug dealers.
Now,
all I ask of you,
gentlepersons of the media,
is that you be tasteful.
"...thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven."
GUARD: Ma'am! Ma'am!
Ike! Ike!
Oh, my God.
I love you.
I'll always love you.
Don't watch this.
It's not your fault.
You can't do this!
He's innocent!
Ike, please!
Say anything!
Last words! Ike!
JESSICA: Ike, talk to us!
What was your last meal?
Final thoughts?
Would you do it again?
Please, he is about to meet
his heavenly Father.
It's okay.
Beets. No.
Yes.
Only one of these
has the juice in it.
Please, let it be mine
"And may God have
mercy upon your soul.
"Our Father,
who art in heaven,
"hallowed be thy name.
"Thy kingdom come..."
Oh, darling.
I can't wait.
Oh, that poor man.
What?
That's the jail.
Well...
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
One,
two,
three.
Wait a minute!
Power feed's out!
"...lead us not
into temptation.
"For thine is
the kingdom..."
SOUND MAN: Okay, let's go!
"For ever and ever."
Okay.
One, two, three.
Go!
WOMAN: Aah!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Stop!
Oh!
(CROWD YELLING)
Will you calm down?
Don't panic. Don't panic!
Don't panic, anyone!
The perpetrator
is well-strapped down.
The warden here
is in complete control.
Find out
what the hell's
going on here!
Yes, sir!
Get the generator
working!
Get some light
in here!
Well, Warden,
I guess you forgot
to pay the light bill.
The TV stuff made
the electric blow.
JESSICA: He's gone!
BOTH: Who's gone?
Roscoe's gone!
Where is he?
He is gone!
He's not gone!
Let's find a phone.
Ike's escaped!
(CROWD YELLING)
What kind of a jail
are you running here?
What's burning?
Oh!
It's Ike!
Wait a minute!
Hey, wait!
We got a train to catch.
It's the last one!
I'll meet you
at the station.
Ike!
Okay, Henry.
Ya-aah!
Ike! Ike!
It's me,
Christy Colleran!
Oh!
Ya-aah!
(POLICE SIRENS)
Aah!
Shh!
Where are you going?
I don't know.
I don't even know
if I want to escape.
Yes, you do.
(POLICE SIRENS)
See that terrace
on the second floor?
Get there!
How?
You just escaped
from the electric chair,
and you're asking me?
Go! Move!
Hi.
Ollie, how you doing?
Hi, Christy.
Come on, Ike.
Come on.
Keep going. Good, good.
All right, you got it.
You got it.
Hi. Sully?
It's me.
I got Ike Roscoe
in the city press room.
He escaped from the chair.
What? Escaped? How?
Never mind.
I'll be right there.
She's got Ike!
Come on!
Hey, Sully!
We're losing the picture
on satellite 11.
Ow!
Son of a bitch.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Go! Go!
It was a miracle!
The TV equipment
blew the circuits.
How did you get away?
My pen?
Houdini's birthday?
From the chair?
(HELICOPTERS)
Oh!
We got to get you
out of here!
I'm so tired.
Here.
Ah!
All right,
this way.
Oh, my God!
Here they come!
Ha! In there.
Come back. Here!
Get in!
Get in! Go on!
Stay out of my way!
Excuse me!
JESSICA: Get out of my way!
Yeah. Boss?
Roscoe escaped!
No, from the chair!
Killed two guards!
Three guards!
Must know karate!
A gun!
There was
blood everywhere!
Two accomplices
came in!
Two unnamed
prison officials!
How many guys helped him?
One or two?
Three.
A reliable source
said three.
Four!
I saw it!
They were refrigerators!
Looked like
they played for the Bears!
Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah!
Can I borrow
your typewriter?
Sure.
I left my laptop
with...
Oh, my God! Blaine!
Give me that!
What's the number
for the train station?
Um...
Oh, let me help you.
Do you have
to do this now?
I must copy.
What about the heat?
I mean, the brown-outs.
You don't want to happen here
what happened at the jail.
These circuits
won't blow.
MAN OVER PA:
Broadway Limited,
service to New York,
now boarding on Track 12.
All aboard, please.
Uh, oh, ow.
Hey, what was that?
A lot
of hacks typing.
No. My machine,
it's groaning.
Must have read
your column.
Ha ha!
ROSCOE: Aah.
What was that?
What?
Who is doing
your hair now?
A new guy...
Eeh, aah.
Something ho-ho hilarious
going on here?
I'll fix it!
You? It's my baby.
Impressive.
How do you know
about copying machines?
Uh, Mother taught me.
See?
Aah!
Your mother, my ass.
RIDNITZ: Listen up!
Good news, boys.
I have an exclusive
for every one of you.
Bullshit, bullshit,
bullshit, Roy!
We know all about
your cockamamie exclusive.
You figured getting Ike
into the electric chair
on network television
would get you
the governor's chair.
Now, look. Killed
by your own ambition.
A laughingstock.
Hey, fellas.
I happen to know
where the prisoner is.
Exactly and precisely.
Really?
Get this!
The craven thug
was seen running
like a rotten,
spineless coward,
like a scared,
spineless jack rabbit...
Quit the editorial!
Where is he?
He took shots
at our brave police.
I knew
he had a gun.
Then, crossing an open field
on his yellow-bellied way,
he...
physically assaulted a woman
who was picking up
welfare checks
for her blind mother.
Oh!
Then...
Roy!
Welfare checks
at night?
Then, he was seen
stealthily climbing
onto this very terrace.
Here?
Wait.
Not here, but...
ALL: What?
One flight up.
I want to go
back to jail.
No. We'll get you
out of here.
Christy, do you know
where he is?
You're safe!
I thought I'd never
see you again.
Did they hurt you?
I just want
to hold you.
Are you safe?
Of course I'm safe.
Yes, I'm safe.
We gotta get him
out of here!
How about
my apartment?
Are you crazy?
That's the first place
they'll look.
RIDNITZ: You can quote me.
This is
a wily perpetrator.
He will be apprehended.
Uh-oh.
Get in!
Oh, no.
Get him in!
No, no.
Watch your head.
MAN: What do you mean,
was I rolling?
What a goddamn
waste of time.
A wild-goose chase!
We have
eyewitness reports.
Give it up.
I personally
am going to guarantee...
Get them a new poster.
We're going to take him
if we have to search
this entire building.
Pillage the area.
Follow me!
Come on, Zaks.
Zaks for bum-boy.
Ah-hmm.
Watch the hair.
What are you
doing here?
Where's Roscoe?
How should I know?
Why are you here?
To make sure
you tell the truth.
Not again.
This is wrong.
There were no guns.
You're making him
a monster.
We were there!
We know how
he escaped.
We... Oh.
Where's the camera?
Camera!
Roll 'em.
Okay, Roscoe! We know
you're in there.
Come on, boys.
Open it up.
Hey.
Follow me.
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh, you see.
He hasn't got a chance.
If you don't kill him,
Ridnitz will.
And the poor man
doesn't have a friend
in the world.
You never saw
the gentle side of him.
He likes to read.
He built the Eiffel Tower
out of toothpicks.
Ah-choo!
Hey!
Huh?
I won't let you do this!
You can't punish
the poor man anymore!
I won't let you,
even if I have to
give up my life.
Did you see that?
What did she do that for?
Is she dead?
She's...moving.
Call an ambulance.
What a night!
What a story!
Holy smokes!
Get out of my way!
Come on,
come on!
Roscoe's lawyer
tried to kill herself.
She threw herself
out the window.
There was blood everywhere!
Hey, Sully!
You missed
all the action.
Morsini,
what happened?
That ACLU broad
dumped herself
out the window,
busted the chandelier.
Ludlow!
Yes?
Interview that woman!
Me?
Don't you want
the story?
Yes! Come on, guys!
Yeah, let's go!
Hey, you guys, move!
Go, go, go!
What's your hurry?
She's not going anywhere.
Get the door.
Why?
Get the door!
Eric, shutters!
Come here, Ike.
She did it
for me!
We have
to get him out.
It's swarming
with cops out there.
Why did you do it?
Did it hurt?
What were you thinking
as you were falling?
Ha ha ha!
She's hysterical.
Are you
hysterical?
All aboard!
Porter!
In one of the most
violent prison breaks
in Chicago history...
...murderer Ike Roscoe escaped
his date with destiny.
Shortly after
his jailbreak...
...his attorney
and alleged lover,
Pamela Farbrother,
threw herself...
...from that window.
She suffered
massive hemorrhaging,
concussions...
...and contusions.
She escaped death
by a hair's-breadth.
This is a bizarre twist...
...in what will be hailed
as the most violent crime...
...of the last 10 days.
State's Attorney Ridnitz
has vowed to capture Roscoe...
...dead or alive.
He is armed
and decidedly dangerous.
This is Pamela Farbrother.
Pamela, give me
a break.
Help me,
this is important.
I've always been
there for you.
Pamela, we're women
in a man's world,
sisters.
CHRISTY: And then?
There was a buzz.
The lights went out.
What about
the buckles?
It was dark.
Don't set the scene.
Get the facts!
I am!
Okay.
You were in
the buckles...
Where was Ridnitz?
Where was the warden?
Do you want
to do this?
I haven't got any makeup on.
Well, it wouldn't help.
Please, don't fight.
BOTH: Well?
Well...
Well, it was easy.
You turn your fingers
and slip your wrist out.
Then I took that pen...
Sully!
Not now!
Someone's coming!
I'll take him
to the office.
Ridnitz will kill him
if he's found
in the copier.
He'll kill him anyway.
Hold on,
Mr. Sullivan.
What?
Will you take care
of Pamela?
Yes. If she lives,
I'll give her a job.
If she dies, I'll name
a foundation after her.
Thanks, Mr. Sullivan.
You're welcome.
Get down.
I felt like
Ted Koppel.
That broad doesn't know
how to jump
out of a window.
Wait till that bitch
reads my version.
Can we get rid
of the electronic parasites?
This is a newspaper office.
ZAKS: Up yours!
I love this machine.
I'd like to buy it.
Right now?
We don't have
a machine like this,
do we, Christy?
Oh, golly, no.
When Sully wants something,
there's no stopping him.
Listen to the price.
$22,000 new.
I'll give you
$20,000 for it.
Cash.
It's two years old.
An antique.
$20,500.
I'm not authorized
to sell this.
Besides, it's part of me.
Sentimental value, huh?
All right, another $500.
This is highway robbery,
I'm telling you.
I thought
you said cash.
Cash, IOU,
same thing.
Blaine!
Christy, you missed
the train.
There is no flight
till 3:00 a.m.
There's been
a new development.
Hi!
I've had it with you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I don't feel that way
about you.
What are you doing?
Sully just bought
a Xerox.
What did you
pay for it?
$20,000.
$21,000, but I'm not
authorized to sell it.
No way for 21 G's.
We bought six
88 Canon NP7550s.
$18,095 each,
brand-new.
Who are you?
It's this machine or nothing.
Don't be insane.
This is two years old.
Look at these insides.
Blaine!
Haven't you got
something to do?
We have to get
on a 3:00 a.m. flight.
I missed the train.
Don't blame yourself.
I blame you.
Oh.
Let's go.
Oh, oh, I can't...
We, uh...
Well, I have a...
She's in the middle
of a fast-breaking
news story.
You what?
My wife hates
the news business.
She feels oppressed
by it, right?
Right?
Well?
Christy, I want
to take you home.
I want to give you
a talk show,
and treat you
like a woman.
Come on.
Hard to turn
that one down.
My apartment overlooks
the goddamn United Nations!
What?
Come with me now,
or you're not coming!
Treat her rough.
She likes that.
I'm not usually
like this,
but I'm putting
my foot down!
Darling.
That's you.
Blaine.
Blaine,
true love is based
on mutual trust.
I'm just asking you
to trust me for five minutes.
I don't know.
And sex. It's based
on plenty of sex.
Five minutes starting now. Go.
I will not! This is my machine!
We bought it!
(YELLING)
I've changed
my mind!
Can I use this?
ALL: No!
Shitheads.
Whoa!
Wait a minute!
Want to work for me making
twice what you're making now?
Forget it.
He hates television.
Remember?
What would I do?
Gain some fat,
you'll be a movie critic.
I haven't seen movies in years.
Well, they haven't changed.
You like something,
you give it 10 bow ties.
If not, five.
I don't know.
Fifteen years of print.
Work for him and get
long, luxurious luncheons,
time to formulate
thoughtful opinions.
Millions blindly doing
what you ask.
They don't even
have to read.
See a movie tonight!
You'll be on tomorrow!
But it's so late.
Perfect. There's one
down the street.
CHRISTY:
Sure, go catch a porno,
or go watch cable.
Obregon, from now on,
you're our man in the dark.
Yes, sir!
Clean out your desk!
Right!
(SIREN)
ALL: He's in the copier.
Come on, guys.
Okay. Okay. Far enough.
Ladies, what's the problem?
Are you kidding?
The elevator!
Oh, shit.
Sullivan?
We'll take
the next one.
Where are you taking
this machine?
Getting it fixed.
During Roscoe's escape?
You're trying
to get that
out of here!
Hiding an escaped criminal?
That's it!
He's got Ike Roscoe
in there!
Okay, men,
get ready to fire.
Blow it open!
You gotta go through me!
Me, too!
Her, too.
REPORTERS: Roll 'em!
CAMERAMEN: Rolling!
Bastards.
Ha ha ha!
On the count of three!
One.
He won't do it.
Two.
And...
Boss!
It won't look good
if you waste
two news guys
on television.
Half of this country
will stand up and cheer.
No!
All right.
Get them out of there.
One, two, three!
That was very brave.
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
This is the outcome
when those amongst us
would defy law and order.
Geez, Roy,
there's nobody
in there!
Huh?
Probably in Indiana
by now!
Congratulations, Roy.
You just killed
a copy machine.
Wait! You can still make
the tail end of the news!
He's got to be
here somewhere.
Zaks, Tillinger, Carvalho!
What about my IOU?
I don't want that anymore.
It's got holes in it.
RIDNITZ: You guys, wait up!
I love you guys!
Ha ha ha!
Sully.
Sullivan!
Sully, you know where
he is, don't you?
I'm running out of time.
I don't know
where he is.
I swear on
Edward R. Murrow's grave.
Who?
Never mind.
Hey.
Aiding and abetting
is a serious offense.
You are going to jail.
And so is that...
Female!
I just watched
the 11:00 news!
The governor
didn't go on TV!
There's no pardon!
SULLY: No pardon?
The governor
didn't pardon him.
What are you
talking about?
How's he know
there was no pardon
unless he knew
there was a pardon
in the first place?
Pardon? He said,
"I beg your pardon."
This is
the politest warden
you'll ever meet.
You moved up the execution
because the governor
was going to pardon him!
Warden Terwilliger
moved it up
because he was concerned
about bombs and riots.
Me?
How does it feel
to be a patsy?
I see it now,
"Terwilliger charged
with obstruction of justice!"
"Distinguished warden
accused of murder!"
"Career in ashes!"
Aah! My chest!
We better
lie him down!
Here?
No. Here.
So you knew
about the pardon.
You lied about the riots!
And the bomb threats!
You'll go to the chair
for what this man did!
Or worse!
Life in prison with
your own prisoners!
Admit it! You knew
about the pardon.
(GASPING)
Don't try to speak.
Nod your head.
Ha!
Gotcha!
Ha ha!
You have got nothing.
Even if this man lives,
who cares?
It's your word
against mine.
You are amazing!
Isn't he amazing?
Amazing.
You'll be
the greatest governor
since Machiavelli.
The Italian
from New Jersey.
Right!
The way you make him
do everything you
want him to do.
Of course!
I worked very hard to get
Ike Roscoe electrocuted.
I'm not going to let
some pansy governor
keep me out
of that mansion!
(GASPING)
What?
The red light
on the camera.
RIDNITZ: Shut up! You'll be
lucky to be dogcatcher
after this.
TERWILLIGER: Camera...
Ridnitz, what asshole
shot the locks
off the doors?
Your Excellency...
Governor, have you
pardoned Ike?
I have.
It's time you two met.
Ike, come down.
You're a free man.
I don't believe it!
Here's
the persecuted man himself!
Thank God you're alive,
Mr. Roscoe!
That man needs help!
Saving the life
of the man
that was going
to fry him!
Is Pamela okay?
Yes. The only one
in trouble here is Ridnitz.
He's confessed to bribery,
attempted murder
and about
14 other charges.
What we have is a
state's attorney's word
against that
of a reporter person.
No! A state's attorney's word
against an Ampex tape,
which I want
on television
in 15 minutes!
See you in jail, Roy.
You're an accessory
after the fact,
and you're going to jail!
He's pardoned,
you're pardoned,
and you're not.
MAN: No visitors, Roy?
How can I
thank you two?
We were just
doing our job.
You're not much, Governor,
but you're all we got.
Siegenthaler!
Yeah?
You want this story?
Yeah!
You've got it, son.
Break their chops!
Yes, sir!
Ha ha ha!
Blaine!
Hello.
Blaine, I've got
something to tell you.
There's something
I've got to tell you.
It's pretty important.
Could you excuse us?
Sure.
I've been thinking,
and what we have here
is apples and oranges,
major apples and oranges.
I don't think this is
going to work out.
You don't?
Do you need
to sit down?
No. I'm okay.
You don't hate
the news.
You don't feel
oppressed by it.
You love it!
You'd be happier
here with him
than coming
to New York
with me.
Mind telling me why?
Well...because here
I make a difference.
Hmm.
I'm sorry
to have to hurt you,
but one day
you'll understand.
(POP)
I'm really
quite a complicated person.
Nice guy.
Wish I'd got
to know him better.
Sully!
Great taste
in champagne.
I've got his ring!
We'll hock it.
Pay for the honeymoon.
Oh, but we can't--
Did you say honeymoon?
Yes, I did. Don't worry.
We'll send the ring back
with the gym equipment.
Sully.
You're not going
to get sentimental
on me, are you?
Oh, no. No.
Say you love me
and that stuff?
Not unless you do.
I want to go someplace nice
this time, though.
Gorgeous.
And no news.
No news.
Where?
Excuse me.
Your drinks.
Hmm?
Oh!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Cheers.
Mmm!
I think we should
do this more often.
Yeah.
(BOOM)
What? You didn't?
Oh, come on. Please!
Ha ha ha!