A Vladimir Mashkov film
An Orphan of Kazan.
Dedicated to all moms and dads.
“Cold frost and sunshine…”
Well? Continue.
Why are you quiet? Cold frost and sunshine, then?
- Anastasya Pavlovna…
- What?
Have you ever been to Kazan?
No. Why?
Then why does my mom say you are an orphan of Kazan?
Well... You see...
That’s an expression. That’s what they say about a person who doesn’t have any relatives.
My mother died, and I don’t have anyone besides her.
Is your father dead as well?
- I don’t know. I’ve never seen him.
- How so?
Well, you see…
Listen, Demendeev, why are you here – to ask questions? Read the poem.
“Cold frost and sunshine:
Day...”
Right, what day is it?
- What day is it outside?
- 31st of December.
That’s the date, but the day? What day is it outside?
- A good one.
- That’s right, but not a good one – “of wonder”. Carry on.
- “But you…” do what?
- What?
“…my friend, are still in slumber”.
Just like you, Demendeev, but you’re not in slumber, just straight up asleep.
Did you learn it or not?
- I did.
- Then read it.
Right, let’s do it together.
“Wake up, my beauty, time belies”.
- Belies.
- “You dormant eyes, I beg you, broaden”.
- Broaden.
“Toward the northerly Aurora,
As though a northern star…” does what?
Pies.
- Arise!
- Arise.
See, you can do it when you want to.
Go make your parents happy, say I gave you a 3.
Also, wish them a Happy New Year from me.
- Put your hat on!
- Thank you!
Fyodor Mikhailovich, I’m out!
- Happy New Year!
- Thank you, likewise.
Anastasya Pavlovna, the key!
- Anastasya Pavlovna, you forgot your bag.
- Oh, thank you.
Happy New Year.
Happy New Year, Anastasya Pavlovna.
Nastya!
The carriage’s at the entrance, as they say. Why aren’t you dressed?
Why are we in a hurry?
Well, “why”?
We leave at five, it’ll be six when we arrive, also we need to get some gifts at seven.
It’ll be twelve before you know it.
Nastya! I’m thinking, should I put a tie on?
I took some from Fedya.
Kolya, maybe we should stay?
What do you mean? Are you out of your mind?
Don't be angry.
I’ve called up all the relatives to look at you, and you want to stay!
- What is there to look at me?
- What do you mean? Are you my fiancee or not?
- I am.
- Maybe you don’t want to marry me either?
- I do.
- Then let’s go!
Do you love me?
What does this have to do with it? Yeah, I do.
- And without the “yeah”?
- I do.
Then let's stay.
Let's.
Nastya, what are we going to do here?
The TV doesn’t work here, but over at my place, they’ve put up the tree, were setting up the table for three days straight.
And here? No champagne even.
I have a tree, although it’s plastic; I’ve bought champagne.
I see.
- That’s our first New Year, after all.
- So we will meet it together, like a family, and go visiting tomorrow.
Where are you going?
“Where”? To get champagne.
Wait!
Now you can go.
Look at that!
Kolya!
You’re here already? Come in.
Good evening.
Happy New Year.
Likewise.
This is for you.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Excuse me, who are you?
Didn’t I say?
No.
I... I came...
I came because of this letter in the newspaper.
I'm Pavel.
I forgot the money.
I said, I forgot the money.
Nikolay.
Pavel Ottovich Brumel.
My father.
Nastya, can I have you for a minute? For a minute.
Excuse me, I'll be back.
- Who's this?
- My father.
- Where did he come from?
- He’d read the letter.
- What letter?
- Mom’s letter, the unsent one.
- You told me it had no address.
- Kolya, I sent it to the newspaper and they’ve published it.
- Why?
- Don't you get it?
- Why? I get it.
- Kolya!
- It doesn’t even state his last name!
- Yes.
Just the name! "Pavel", so what? What does this prove?
- There are things in the letter that only…
- Did you see his passport?
There are things in the letter that only two people could’ve known.
Nastya!
He came here, you understand? That proves everything.
Wait!
More tea?
Yes. Thank you.
I better go.
Sorry.
I’ve… been waiting for you letter for so long.
Really?
I did write it.
As soon as I’ve read that letter in the paper.
Then I’ve read my letter and tore it.
I thought, why make up excuses after so many years?
Decided to come here.
I didn’t want to disturb you, I thought I’d just take a look and leave.
But then I saw you there near the school, and you look so much like Galya...
I realised I’m not leaving just like that.
Silly, isn't it?
No, it’s not silly at all.
If only you knew how worried I was! What if they wouldn’t publish it, or you wouldn’t read it,
or maybe you have a happy family, children…
Don’t worry, I don’t have anyone.
Imagine: Sochi, the palms, the sea.
I still remember it: I wore white sailor trousers, and a matching white jacket…
…that you tore when you were climbing over a fence to steal flowers.
How do you know?
The letter.
Has your mother really not told you anything about me?
When I was a child, she joked about finding me inside a cabbage.
When I grew up, she only once said: “Your father is a really good man. It just did not work out”.
Yes, it didn't.
For six days I was flying as if I had wings, doing incredible nonsense,
and then she just hopped on a train and left.
Didn’t even say goodbye. Usually men do that.
But on the other hand, what could I give her?
Become a wife of a circus performer? Live in a tiny van, move from town to town?
You’re a circus performer?
Yes, a magician.
A real one?
A real one. Although retired.
- Nikolay.
- My fiance.
Pavel, no need for the patronymic.
Nastya, I forgot the money.
I’ll go get champagne then, it’s not every day that fathers show up.
I mean, are found.
Well, arrive.
- I better go.
- Wait.
Now go.
We can go to my family in the district center. Huh?
You’ll get acquainted then. You’re the father, after all.
- So, should we?
- Well, it’s a bit awkward.
- What’s awkward?
- Don’t shout.
I’m not shouting. I see you two want to talk, after so many years.
Well, you’ll get enough of that soon, there’s a whole life ahead.
It’s New Year today. You said so yourself – “like a family”.
I’m not really dressed up for the occasion.
I’ll give you a tie. Got a dozen of these.
Are we going empty-handed?
Why empty-handed? You dress up and I’ll go to Fedya.
Let's go?
Let's.
FYODOR'S
Thank you.
I forgot how a properly ironed shirt looks like.
I’ve never learned how to tie a tie, after all.
You’re handsome either way.
What?
You are the second person in my life who'd said that.
Mother was the first one?
What’s wrong? Did I upset you?
Nothing, it’s just…
I’ve been waiting for you for so long.
Happy New Year.
- Is this house 11?
- 11.
- Are you Nastya?
- Nastya.
Well...
Hello, daughter.
We’ve met at last, as they say.
Were you not expecting me?
Or are you not happy?
And I went across half the country, so to say, straight from Kazakhstan.
First on a plane, then on a train, then two hitchhikes.
You probably haven't received my wire?
No.
These guys! Oh well, it’s New Year, after all.
This is for you.
Well, let’s get acquainted on the occasion.
Pavel Andreevich Koveshnikov, a cosmonaut, lieutenant colonel in retirement, Nastya’s father.
We can go straight to informal, I like it simple.
A colleague or a relative?
That's my father.
I don't get it.
There’s a little discrepancy.
What discrepancy?
- Are you Nastya?
- Nastya.
- Was it you who published this letter in the paper?
- Me.
- Asking for a reply?
- Yes.
- Gave your address?
So here I am.
Pavel Andreevich Koveshnikov, a cosmonaut, lieutenant colonel in retirement.
Your father.
Pavel?
Pavel.
My father?
Your father.
Hold up, there is a misunderstanding.
- Of course, you must be mistaken somewhere.
- No, first of all, stop with the informalities.
- Apologies.
- Second of all, I too am Pavel.
Pavel Ottovich Brumel. I am a magician, and also an honoured worker of art, by the way.
- Let's assume so.
- Third of all, I am not mistaken anywhere.
- 29 years ago… you are 29, right?
- Will be.
Will be.
So, 29 years ago, 14th of July, in a “Sunny” hotel,
I have met a charming woman named Galya, this girl’s mother.
We got along during breakfast in our canteen, then Galya and I had a romance, with Nastya appearing as a result,
the existence of whom I could not have known about all these years because Galya never knew my address.
- That’s all?
- That’s all.
Sit down, then.
Well, if you give me paperwork, I’ll reply with paperwork too.
Let’s open my military ID,
and read this entry on 2nd of July 1968. Let’s open it, c’mon.
Let’s read: “For the successful flight and the wit displayed in an unforeseen situation,
Captain Koveshnikov P.A. to be awarded with a Medal of Excellent Military- and Political Training,
and to be given an out of queue holiday of 3 weeks”.
And… and the signature, Colonel Dvoinikov. Here.
- So what?
- So that.
That on 4th of July, I was sitting on the balcony of the “Sunny” hotel in white sailor trousers and a matching jacket,
eating ice cream that cost 11 kopeeks, which was written down in my holiday book.
I can present it.
And in the evening of the same day, I was dancing tango with the most beautiful lady on the coast.
Her name was Galya.
Your mother.
- A husband?
- A fiance, Kolya.
Let’s say hi then, fiance.
Pavel Andreevich Koveshnikov, a cosmonaut, lieutenant colonel in retirement.
- Your future father-in-law, so to say.
- Who?
Father-in-law.
- What’s going on here?
- Kolya…
I’m Kolya alright, who is he?
That’s Pavel.
Another one.
- Put your coat on real quick.
- Kolya!
Put it on, I said.
- Kolya, just don’t get angry, I’ll explain everything.
- C’mon, I’m waiting.
You see, he’d read the letter too.
- And he also claims to be your father?
- Yes.
- And you believe him?
- Well… everything matches there as well.
- What everything?
- Everything!
Here, I’m showing you, it’s written very clearly: “Dear Pavel”, that’s me – one!
The “Sunny” hotel, that’s a no-brainer – two!
Then the promenade. Galya and I were walking there once, and a big sailing ship passed by – three!
The white Indian jacket that got stolen two years later – four!
The “Shroom” cafe and the milkshake – five!
Well? Give up?
By the way, I haven’t seen your documents yet.
Please understand, you can’t find a person just by his name.
It’s impossible to remember all the details after 30 years either!
- But they were in love.
- Who?
- Mother and father.
- 30 years have passed, do you understand that?
- Kolya.
- What?
Do you love me?
- What does it have to do with it? Yeah, I do.
- And without the “yeah”?
I do.
So if I don’t marry you, you won’t even remember me in 30 years’ time?
How you used to court me, how you entered my class through the window on the 3rd of September and kissed me while the kids cheered?
- That’s totally different.
- No it’s not, Kolya.
I don’t know which one is my father, but I feel that both of them are telling the truth!
- Nastya!
- I’m cold.
Kolya!
Hey, fathers! Stop that! Drop it!
- I’ll kill you!
- A fistfight is all I need now!
Roll outside and fight there!
- I’m not going anywhere!
- Me neither!
- Ah, maybe you need some help?
- Kolya, don't!
Be quiet!
Just you look at that, they won’t leave!
Who asked you to come in the first place?
Been gone for 30 years and now jumped out like two jacks in a box: “Here I am, love me!”
- Stop!
- What, am I wrong?
Why are you staring?
Kolya, be quiet.
Let him talk.
C’mon, finish me off, son.
You’re asking, who wanted me here?
Nastya wanted me here.
So it’s not up to you to judge me,
and not up to you to decide.
You were not even born
when I was playing volleyball with Yura Gagarin.
And if I wronged my daughter somewhere,
then it’s only when I’ve never received that letter 30 years ago.
Just say it, daughter,
and I'll leave.
May I?
Here I am!
I came from a kind tale, let’s have fun and not be stale!
Let’s all gather over there and have a wonderful New Year!
- I will give your moods a lift by bringing each of you a gift!
- Fedya, is that you?
Bourgeoise are saying oui!
They love some freckles and good beer!
And you sit up and look high up!
And you’ve got no appetite – better take some streptocite!
And this is for you.
Father?
You recognised me.
FYODOR'S
So that’s how it came about.
So, you didn’t even ask her last name?
Did you? I was looking into her eyes, not into her passport.
I have my doubts.
Listen, what’s your…. honestly, I-
To you, it’s Pavel Andreevich Koveshnikov, a cosmonaut, lieutenant colonel in retirement, I can show my documents.
- Why do I need your documents?
- Don’t pay attention to him.
- Why do you mean “don’t pay attention”?
Please don’t quarrel, I beg you.
So I hopped in a taxi and went back to the hotel,
said, you had a woman at your place, Galya!
And there’s this red-faced administrator, saying, we’re not an inquiry office here, sort it out yourself.
So I sorted him out.
Enlightened him straight in the face, but the police was there too,
they released me two days later.
And when I reached the port, they said that’s it, your white ship’s gone.
Well, you can guess what it’s like to miss your own ship.
So they wrote me off, that’s the story.
Then I became a cook on a seiner.
Didn’t Galya tell you anything about me?
I thought so.
She probably thought I just never showed up.
Demendeev, what do you want?
That’s for you. Mom told me to wish you a Happy New Year and thank you for that 3.
- What is this?
- A cake.
Although I fell over a little, it’s slippery out there.
Here are the candles to it.
They also say your pops arrived, so I came to take a look.
It’s interesting, after all.
So, which one is the pops?
Me!
I better come tomorrow.
Is the photo a match for you too, then?
Did you show them the photo?
No.
Do any of you have mother’s photo?
There we go!
We’re all here guessing, torturing ourselves. Why didn’t you say sooner?
C’mon, daughter, bring the photo in. Let’s sort it out.
- Bring it.
- I know I’m not thinking straight coming from the frost, but you two?
Just a moment.
Kolya, I completely forgot.
You took it with you.
Where did I take it?
To the district center.
Why?
To enlarge it to make mother’s portrait.
When?
Well, you know better when you took it. Hopped on your tractor and took it.
Remember?
Yeah.
Go there and bring it back, then.
What, right now?
Sure. It’s not far.
- Not far.
- So go get it, then.
- I'll go then?
- Go.
So you’re both Pavels?
And both decided that…
I don’t see anything funny.
I can't!
So you’re a cosmonaut?
I am, I am.
- And you went into space?
- I did.
- I don’t recite your name though, what year was that?
- Whichever it had to be.
By the way,
I ask you to stop with informalities.
You like it simple though, you told me yourself.
Your face seems familiar.
Was it you entertaining folks in a bar in Novorossiysk?
No, oh no.
I think you were showing tricks.
Brumel, you’re a magician! An honoured worker of art!
There are many magicians out there!
- Nastya, can I wash my face after the journey?
- Of course, I’ll give you a towel.
By the way, my dear, you were going on about documents, so here’s my document.
You can’t erase that one. Here’s the sea for you, and the palms, and Galya.
GAGRA-69 GALYA
Got it?
Hold up.
But it says “Gagra-69”.
So what?
So that! It wasn’t in Gagra, it was Sochi.
I met Galya in Sochi.
You maybe met her in Sochi, but I met her in Gagra.
And you?
Well?
Ah, here.
"From 4.07 to 24.07.1969, hotel “Sunny”,
city of Yalta".
I knew it.
I felt it. Felt it!
Nastya, do you believe me now?
Now you know who your father is?
It was in Sochi. I met your mother in Sochi.
She was in Sochi, was she?
I don't know.
I brought a little tree for you.
My god, Kolya, where’ve you been?
In the district center.
Where did you get so drunk?
In the photo studio.
You saent me there yourself… sent.
They said...
They said,
there’s no photo, but will be later.
Are you three free?
Can you walk past two houses over there with me?
I made a bet with Fedya that I have three fathers-in-law, but he doesn’t believe me.
I told him, c’mon, I’ll show you. So we can even make money from this.
- Kolya!
- What?
Go somewhere again? To the center?
And I almost believed you.
And you too, almost.
Your crying too, Ded Moroz, was pretty believable.
He usually never drinks.
You’re all good guys,
but two of you are lying.
Kolya, you don’t understand.
It’s important that they understood me.
Decided to make themselves a summer house here.
No wonder, what else do you need at this age? Right, fathers?
Kolya, get out, please get out. Get yourself sorted and put the tree back.
See!
She told none of you to leave, only me.
I'll leave alright.
But will I return?
That's the big question.
Do you also think that?
I think...
I think, how I am going to feed you all?
I've got nothing.
What do you mean, nothing?
So, your newspaper reached me all the way in Japan, in Yakagama.
Thanks to the guys, they bought me a ticket.
To Vladivostok by a plane, and then it was a question of details.
- Why are you wailing?
- The onions.
Not a drop from me, you know!
I've cried it all out!
I once did some math and gasped: in all my life, I have cleaned and chopped 17 tons of onions!
How much? 17 tons?
That’s the weight of the first stage of a launch vehicle.
You can lie, but don’t get lost in it.
Koveshnikov, keep wielding and stop eavesdropping.
Be like Brumel.
I have something too, by the way.
Space food.
Ukrainian borsch.
Beef Stroganoff.
Chicken Kiev.
Chocolate marmalade.
You can seal windows with this grease alright.
Today we have a festive menu.
Appetisers: chilled mussels in lemon sauce, bird fondue in pineapple and paprika sauce.
Main course: fish with bacon, South-French chicken, and the desert:
cocktail “Pineapple glaze”, and pancakes with orange syrup.
Any questions?
Since when do they feed you like that in the navy?
Since today, bros.
- Can I have the marmalade?
- Of course!
Nastya, I don’t recommend you eat that.
Listen, Brumel, why are you always butting in? Keep hanging up the baubles in peace.
- I am.
- You are. Splendid.
Eat, daughter, before that contraption is ready.
Is it really going to work?
You’re insulting me!
Of course it’s not the same as hanging up baubles, or chopping little onions,
but I’m old friends with tech.
Nastya, where’s salt in our house?
One moment.
Thank you.
- Nastya, where are the lights in our house?
- Ah, hold on.
- Do you need help?
- Please.
Nastya, where are the pliers in our house?
Oh, they were somewhere… wher- hold on.
Guys,
here's a proposal.
I propose to declare a truce till the morning.
If it wasn’t for Nastya, who knows where we would have been celebrating this New Year. Therefore I propose to drink after her.
Please cast your votes by cheering and drinking.
After Nastya.
Huh… Life sure has a peculiar sense of humour.
I thought nothing could surprise me anymore, I’ve seen it all.
I've accomplished something in my life, this and that – but then I’ve read the letter and…
felt like somebody poured boiling water over me.
You can’t lie to yourself – nothing was ever accomplished,
if I dropped everything like that and ran here.
My mother used to cook so well,
especially Ukrainian borsch.
I used to invite all my friends for that borsch, we had a giant flat, a big oak table in the dining room,
with a hanging fringed lampshade.
Why the past tense? Is the flat not there anymore?
The flat is there, but I’m not.
I’ve never had my own flat.
Here’s my flat.
There’s the bedroom, the living room, and the fringed lampshade, but I don’t regret it.
I don't.
I’ve read the letter and thought: huh.
Everything happens for a reason.
Where did the daughter go, I’ll go check.
- I’m with you.
- Me too.
- Nastya!
- Where have you been?
- We are worried.
Attention!
I'm turning it on.
It works!
Who is this?
That’s an announcement from the American president to the American people.
Satellite.
Is there anything in Russian?
Yeah...
Huh!
Kolya, where have you been? We’re all waiting for you!
Planted the tree, bought champagne, got cold.
- Please forgive me.
- Take your clothes off and go to bed!
- He’ll get ill.
- We need to rub him with alcohol, undress him.
- Quick!
- On the sofa.
- Careful.
- Take the shirt off, the boots too.
Careful.
Am I going to celebrate New Year naked?
Hold on, man, hold on.
Here, great!
- Maybe we should rub him with pee?
- What?
We were taught this in case of extreme temperatures.
- So what, does it help?
- It does.
- Rub him!
Nastya!
I understand you now.
Here's the New Year.
What are we waiting for?
Get the drinks!
- We'll be late.
- C'mon.
- Typical!
- C'mon, guys.
- Oh, thank god.
- For you too.
Happy New Year!
That’s not all!
Sit down!
Stop it!
So I’m standing there on someone’s balcony with just my pants on.
I realise I have to sing!
- What did you sing?
- What else could I do?
- What did you sing though?
- Tango.
"Tell me why".
- “Yesterday we’ve met…”
- Wait.
“Yesterday we’ve met by chance,
And you gazed at me,
I looked at you with hidden sadness.
It completely fogged my eyes!
Memories came down upon me,
The shadow of the past flickered in my eyes,
And a feeling of tender confession
Was revived in my memory!
Tell me, why,
Were we separated?
Why did you leave me at once?
I know you loved me
But you left, tell me, why?”.
- Don't sleep!
- I'm not.
Just thinking.
- Where are the dads?
- Smoking.
Arguing about who do I look like the most. Thank you.
- For what?
- For helping me with the photos.
That’s alright, I understand. But tomorrow…
Tomorrow will be tomorrow.
I'm telling you, wait! Nastya!
Do like this.
See!
Only Brumels could do this trick on the first try.
That proves nothing!
A problem and a question should be resolved on a genetic level.
For example, did you know that a good vestibular apparatus is inherited in the family?
- Nonsense!
- A fact!
- Nastya, come here!
- Pasha!
- Hold on. Hands! Feet shoulder width apart!
- Let's work, Nastya!
- What are you-
work work work work work work work
What did you do to her?
Are you thinking straight or what?
I just wanted...
That’s alright, it’ll pass.
Kolya, let’s get some fresh air.
Be back soon.
I would love to smack you right now.
Must be true what they say about you cosmonauts and your brains delayering on the centrifuge.
- So what?
- How is she?
- Bad, right?
You know who you are?
You're no fathers.
You know why?
Because you’re almost grandfathers.
Well, from this moment now on, the guys are only allowed to smoke outside.
And you should only be drinking juice.
I give a word to Nikolay, the father of our future grandchild.
- I would like a granddaughter.
- I would like you to keep quiet.
Please, Nikolay.
I don’t speak well,
I’ll just kiss her and she’ll understand.
And to you I want you say this: Fedya had lost the bet.
I do indeed have three fathers-in-law.
And all three are sitting at this table.
Well, it might be old-fashioned and all,
but I want to ask all three of you for your daughter’s hand. Yeah.
Well, fathers?
What are your thoughts?
This is a serious business.
We need to think.
Do you drink?
He doesn’t drink at all.
- Smoke?
- I do, but I can quit.
You'll have to.
Where are you going to live?
Here.
So you don’t have an apartment of your own.
Well, here for now, and then I want to build a house.
He is very good, you just don’t know him.
He left the city just for me, lives here alone on the edge of the village.
He’s been courting me for an entire year now, and I’ve been asking him to come live with me, but he says no, only after the wedding.
So what?
I’m not against it.
Me neither, actually.
But I’m totally… for.
One can get a heart attack like this.
- When’s the wedding?
- We were thinking about spring holidays.
Why stall? The groom is here, the bride is in stock, the table is full, a whole bunch of relatives are here.
Kiss!
Wait.
What about presents from the parents’ side? After me.
- Stop shaking.
- I'm not shaking.
Vitya! Let's go!
I'm coming!
God damn you.
That's not all.
Finally, I saw the station and began the docking procedure.
I feel we’re off.
I go left – it’s heeling.
I tried going straight – going straight, going straight, - I am straight.
We’re getting closer.
I see my speed is above the maximum, and the distance is this much – critical.
I turn the engine on, hit the brakes.
Suddenly, depressurization hits.
I get a knock on the illuminator, they show me the watch – that means time’s up, and…
Wait. Who knocked on your illuminator in outer space?
- Who knocked?
- I’m asking you. Who?
- Where?
- The illuminator.
- In space.
Did you fly or did you not?
Pasha, tell the truth.
We’re all reliable here.
Fine, I didn't.
But!
If they put me in the cabin even in my state right now,
I’d still fly the rocket with my eyes closed.
Right with your eyes closed?
Don't believe me?
Here.
Let's work. Work work work.
Attention. Attention attention attention.
All ready.
Here’s the button to contact the control center.
Here’s the link to the on-board power supply.
- And here?
- The oxygen adapter.
And that?
The cooling system.
And there?
Solar batteries and the docking station.
- And what's that?
- Don’t touch that, Kolya,
that’s the emergency release system.
Right...
And this little green button that I’ve just pressed?
Why did you do that?
You’ve started the first engine, you can’t stop it now.
What is this?
Vibrations, that's normal.
The ground power supply will shut down now.
Yes!
What are you doing?
Your fault. Don’t press buttons if you don’t know what they’re for.
Kolya, strap Nastya in your seat.
Follow my commands. Start.
- Where?
- Your left.
Turn on the oxygen supply.
- Turn what?
- Press the seventh button.
The first mast came off.
Start the countdown.
5, 4, 3, 2, 1...
Let's go.
Strap a whole antenna on top of it next time.
You, people of the dark. Have you ever heard of progress?
That’s a special float for night fishing.
- The bulb lights up when there’s a catch.
- It’s daytime.
- Who knows, maybe we’ll sit here till nighttime.
- Quiet, you’re going to scare all the fish away.
- I used to catch them in Japan with no floats at all.
- In a shop.
You're a shop.
That’s my place, I’ve fed them here.
A catch!
- Well, now untangle that.
- You’re no better. “A catch, a catch!”
- My bulb lit up.
- C’mon, untangle it.
- Give me your glasses.
- Carry your own.
Then let the magician untangle it, he’s used to it.
Quiet please, you’ll wake little Pavel up.
Wow, it did grow back.
Good day.
Seen each other already.
…and a cup of tea.
Three cups.