A Liberto Rabal film
SYNDROME: SET OF SYMPTOMS
THAT CHARACTERIZE AN ILLNESS
Well, Victor,
we have the test results.
And I called because
you wanted me to be
frank with you.
In the images
one can clearly see
the advanced growth
of the tumor.
Given its location,
the possibilities
for intervention, as we
discussed, are zero.
Under these conditions
you cannot expect to live
more than one or two months.
SYNDROME
See? See?
All right then.
ABSTINENCE SYNDROME:
SET OF SYMPTOMS CAUSED BY
THE DEPRIVATION OF THAT
TO WHICH ONE IS ADDICTED
What is it?
Really, what is it?
- AG-string.
- You knew... you idiot.
I didn't see a thing.
What colour is it?
What colour is it, or what
colour would I like it to be?
What colour.
You've got no idea.
Black.
You're an idiot.
Alex, you know you look
a lot like Dad?
No.
DEPENDENCE
I'll leave you
the keys, Alex?
Are you taking yours?
I can only see these.
Get a copy made.
Coca Cola and an apple.
And see if he's there, okay?
Just a second.
Ciao.
COMPULSION
Pull and m assage it, right?
Lock by lock since it's dry...
so it penetrates.
What are you doing?
- What are you laughing at?
- How should I know?
Is it nitwit's day today?
You're so cute,
we're hung up on you.
Yeah, right.
You're leaving?
- Yes.
- Give mea kiss.
- Will you do the till?
- okay.
Ciao.
Are you sure?
Don't worry,
just do me a favour.
Go and see if there's a guy
dressed in black, and tell me.
Ciao.
He wanted a shag or something.
He's funny, and sweet.
I've just got 4,000 pesetas,
but I want two pills.
Two pills and a Smiley.
- Hold on.
- You want some mushrooms?
Careful.
Shit, girl.
I'm going to clean the table.
I can't stand the smell, okay?
What? What?
I'm going to bed, Alex.
Tomorrow, we'll see, okay?
Good night.
Once upon a time
there was a boy and a girl,
a brother and a sister,
called Hansel and Gretel.
And they lived
with their parents,
until one day
their father went
to the forest to hunt...
and never returned.
So the two children,
Hansel and Gretel,
were left alone
with their mother.
But the mother
loved the father so much,
that she took no notice
of the children.
She gave them no water,
she gave them no food,
she didn't keep them warm
at night.
She didn't care for them,
she didn't read them stories.
And the children had to
love each other,
and take good care
of each other.
They got thinner and thinner,
and hungrier and hungrier,
and m ore and more
in need of affection,
so both of them decided
to leave home
and look for something
wonderful,
and someone to
give them the love
they weren't being given.
It's all right.
I'm not pregnant.
Show me you love me.
Look at me.
We've gone insane.
This can't happen.
It can't.
I don't want to follow you.
No.
I'm looking.
I'm looking at you.
Be yourself.
Whatever the cost,
above all else.
You won't lose
if you are yourself.
You will die when you want
Change is within.
Alone.
With fear...
and pain.
Open your eyes.
Wake up.
No.
I am a m an.
Here and now..
WANT
- I haven't got it now.
- Why?
Hang on.
Why?
Not now, I sold what I had.
That's a lie.
Your nose will grow.
No, really.
I don't have it.
Shall we take a walk?
Have a drink somewhere?
At home?
Do you fancy that?
Who's at home?
Nobody.
I'll have a glass of water
and then you can walk me.
Water?
Yes.
Okay, I've got some water
you're going to like.
I've never been up there,
have I, Willy?
What floor is it?
The fiirst.
So it's perfect for
failed suicides.
Yeah.
Is that your room?
Play the piano.
I'm hungry.
Chocolate.
Do you think I'm pretty?
Very,.
Yeah, and clever?
Not especially.
I can't help thinking
about that baby..
I did it yesterday,
and since then I've im agined
a baby the whole time.
And now, when I held you
in my arm s...
Can you imagine?
A baby that,
if it was still alive,
would be born, growup,
would one day be like you,
and I could hold it
in my arm s.
Shit, it's amazing,
one decision changes...
an entire life.
Worst thing is I can't cry...
I can't scream...
I can only piss
myself laughing,
laugh with pain.
Father... I'm sorry..
Everything I do is wrong.
Forgive me.
I love you.
ISOLATION
You want some water?
Do you?
Come, we won't let go
of each other.
Look, it's beautiful.
Hello, night.
Hello, night star.
As a child, walking
with Dad and with you,
I thought you could touch
the clouds,
and they'd be
like cotton balls.
I'm happy here with you,
and the night.
Call a taxi.
Hold on, it's okay..
Relax.
We're friends,
but you don't want to see me.
You only come when
you feel like it.
You want it?
Or not?
Ana.
Ana, talk to me.
Hey, are you all right?
Answer me.
Can you hear me?
He's gone.
Take it easy.
STOCKHOLM SYNDROME:
AN ILLNESS IN WHICH
THE KIDNAPPED PERSON
ENDS UP LOVING THE KIDNAPPER
FEAR
Do you want me to gag you?
- Yes or no?
- No.
Okay.
Don't scream.
Please, leave me
this hand free.
Do you know me or not?
Do you know who I am?
Do you?
Yes.
Please, leave me
this hand free.
I'll let you go.
I give you something
when you give me something.
- I'm suffocating.
- You understand?
I give you something
when you give me something.
What do you want?
You know nothing about
me since I left.
You know nothing.
We really hurt each other.
We both really hurt each other.
I'm so sorry I left.
You hurt me.
I have to sort this out.
Going to dinner, Alex?
No.
I let you go.
I let you go,
it's a show of trust.
I don't want you to touch me
or know. Anything about you!
I want to go!
You left me in a hospital
and split.
You didn't care about me.
Not at all!
I want to go to the only person
that cares about me.
He'll be worried -
for sure he'll be worried!
He thinks about me.
And he DOES love me!
And he DOES want me
to be happy!
Let me go!
No, please!
Let me put this on you.
No, I'll be good.
If you pass the test,
I'll take it off, or not.
You want me to tie you up?
No.
Let me do it.
Please...
Let me go,
you fucking nutcase!
Let me go.
You're crazy.
What, you think I'm kidding?
If you don't do as I say,
I'll smash your face in.
What a shame.
I'm going to cry,
I'll play the waif.
I'll play the baby girl,
the girl in need.
Huh?
Poor thing,
abandoned her whole life.
No daddy,
with that fag brother of hers.
Spit in my mouth, go on!
I like it.
Spit inside of me.
Please don't hurt me.
Please, let me go.
What do you want us to play?
Fine, try to leave.
Try to leave.
Go on.
Okay, fine.
- No, no, no!
- No?
No! No!
Take it.
Let me go, please.
Please.
Please!
Get in the corner and shut up
unless you want me
to hit you again.
Don't ask me to release you.
Don't ask me to let you go.
Don't ask me anything
you know I'll say no to.
Have you got that?
She was meant to be here
at 12, right?
Yes, but maybe she left
a message or something.
If she doesn't turn up,
we'll call the police,
though I think it's nothing.
NECESSITY
Your life is shit.
Say it.
"My life is shit".
I can't take it.
I can't.
Give me your wrist.
Please, tie them in front.
Please, I'm asking you.
Really, I'll do what you want.
I won't scream.
I beg you,
don't tie me up, please.
And how long can
this take to develop?
Yes, keep up the treatment.
All right, doctor.
Thanks a lot.
Bye.
I want to be all right.
I don't want to cry...
I will not cry,
I will not cry.
I will not cry,.
I will not -
Can you get me something
to calm me down?
Have you got money?
No.
Then what will I get
in exchange?
Am I making myself clear?
I accuse you
of being a menace.
A manipulator!
"Oh, I can't!"
You cry, a bit, and that's it.
I accuse you of being
a little girl
who has to be spanked.
Daddy has to spank
the little girl.
Huh?
She doesn't know. what to do.
She didn't have a daddy.
I condemn you to having a mirror
always in front of you.
I condemn you to judge yourself.
I condemn you to life.
I'm going out.
If you do what you shouldn't,
I'll tie you up.
I'll put a gag on you,
and you'll stay like that
till you explode.
I swear I won't.
They confirmed it to me.
This isn't a medicine that's...
alternative in the sense of -
one thing or another.
There are many factors
that in the end
may result in a cancer.
Has there been anything
emotional that might have...
had a great impact on you?
Some sort of loss?
My brother died three years ago.
He committed suicide.
He needed meand...
I feel like I couldn't...
be there for him, or...
Do you feel guilty?
If you decide to undergo
radiotherapy or chemotherapy,
we're all here to help you.
But you're the one
who has to take hold
of the reins of your life.
Can I use the bathroom
before I go?
OPPRESSION
Do what you have to do.
Victor?
Are you okay?
Yes.
You're a dick.
Water!
Give me some water!
Give me some water, please.
I will tame you.
If I tell you to do something,
you do it.
You don't want to see
what I'm capable of.
Can you understand
two things at the same time?
Yes!
Did I tell you to shout at me?
No.
The only thing you have to
put your energy into,
concentrate your thoughts on,
and the only thing you have to
put your whole being into
is in doing what I tell you.
I tell you to look at me,
and you look at me.
All the time.
Did I tell you to
stop looking at me?
No.
- Did I?
- No.
Mom, it's Alex.
Ana hasn't come home
in two days.
I've looked in her usual
places the past two nights
and I can't find her.
I don't know who else
can help me.
You've changed,
you're someone else.
Though in reality,
you're the same as ever.
A coward.
You left me like a cow ard
and now you have me here,
like a coward.
So let me go.
IMPOTENCE
Hope.
I love you.
I can't live without you.
I don't know how to tell you.
I'm in bad shape.
Look at me, please.
Don't take your eyes off me.
Don't take your eyes
off me, please.
Don't take your eyes off me.
Trust me, please.
Look at me.
Don't take your eyes off me.
Don't take your eyes
off me, please.
Please! Please!
Look at me!
Ana.
Ana, don't make me crazy.
Don't make me crazy.
I'm capable of any madness.
Don't do it,
for your own good.
Victor, please!
Let me go, please!
I'm dying
and you have no idea...
because you don't feel anything
and I feel everything
and I'm dying!
I don't want to die!
I have to rid myself of this.
I have to.
Let me go.
No! No!
Please!
Please, no.
Please.
I hate you.
I can't anymore.
He's not going to stop.
How do you stop?
Oh, God!
You want to stay tied up?
Yes, you do.
You want be tied up,
to be told how things are,
for them to fuck up your life
as much as possible, right?
Very, well.
Help me, please.
Come here.
I know...
I know l have to be better,
and I know
I have to change, but...
I don't know how
to do it alone.
Please help me.
Do what you have to do...
but I want to get out of this.
Please.
Please, come here.
I know I did everything wrong.
I do everything wrong,
but I want to do it right.
I want to live differently.
Victor...
Please, come, help me.
Please.
I don't feel I can do it,
and I'm really scared.
And so alone.
SUBMISSION
Victor, please, come here.
I'm so scared of being alone.
Don't leave me alone, please.
I don't want to be alone!
I'm always alone!
Come here, please.
Help me.
Come here.
You really don't remember
what happened to your father?
What happened?
I don't know how to remember.
Are you cold?
You have to give it up.
Your mother and father,
they turned their back on you.
And look at you.
You're chained up.
Look at them.
Tell them:
"Dad, Mum, thank you. "
I don't know how..
To them.
Dad, Mom...
thank you.
Victor, please help me.
It's your father.
He turns his back on you.
It's your mother.
Look at your mother, look.
Your mother is here.
She tums her back on you.
You tell them:
"I have come with you this far. "
Turn your back.
Victor, I think
you got me wrong.
I don't understand a thing,
I just want to get out of here.
You're not going now.
I have it all ready so that
you go when you have to.
When the time is right.
Everything I have is yours.
Do you understand?
The money I have left,
this place,
the shrouded furniture,
it's all yours.
When you have to go,
when you're ready,
when the time is right...
you'll go.
You're not ready yet.
But you're doing well.
I'm very proud of you.
Well done.
But there's work to be done...
hard work.
It's so painful loving you.
You have to live.
I have to die.
I loved tricking you.
I told you I turned around,
but I saw it all.
You sat down for a piss,
it dribbled at first,
but then it came out.
How it hit the water.
Then came the feces,
the crap.
The shame, the shame
I made you feel.
You squeezed softly,
very softly,
but I was there watching it all.
What are you doing?
I heard how your piss fell.
You're making me dizzy.
Move around a little.
Go on, yes, for yourself.
I'm not looking at you,
I don't care.
I'm not looking.
Why do you think you're here?
For me to look at?
Move a little.
I'll move around, too.
Move a little so I can
talk to you.
Do you want me to tell you
what's wrong with me?
Yes.
I have a tumor on the left
hemisphere of my head.
It began the size of a lentil,
and now it's a fist.
It's spreading through my head,
spreading through my head.
I feel my tumor
as a sixth sense.
I am a product of my tumor.
I see I am not capable of being
an artist as I wanted to be.
Don't touch me because if you do
I will pass my tumor onto you,
and you will become ill like me,
and see the light like me.
You WILL see the light and you
won't have to live in fear...
in fear...
Like Shit!
Cancer, how evil it is.
It kills us all.
Such fear!
Pneumonia, angina,
cardiac arrest...
Fear.
We are dating; how wonderful
that we are dating!
Oh, the love.
The love is wonderful.
What a feeling for life.
Wanting to live.
How I love to be with her.
How l love when she touches me.
How I love my life.
Let's dance, let's live.
I don't want it to end.
Let's not lose respect -
because if we lose respect,
what's left?
And you're blind.
You're going to see.
The truest thing in my life
is the tumor.
The tumor is true.
It's the only fucking dark,
painful thing I truly have.
It's the only thing of mine
that I have.
The only true thing I have.
It is the truth.
My brother came to see me.
He was in a bad way.
I couldn't see it.
He needed me there,
and I wasn't.
I was all he had.
The next time I saw him
he was dead.
It hurts me to look at you.
GIVING IN
I think if you hadn't come,
I would have simply thrown
myself to the ground,
and died.
Look...
I've spent almost a year
in a process of
getting myself off everything.
Incredible, terrifying,
a nightmare.
Really, you can't imagine.
Was it worth it?
Well, I'd like to think so.
Though for me,
almost nothing seems worth it.
You're worth it.
There's a writer who talks about
something called epic legend.
Things happen,
and in such a way,
but we tell a story,
and that is epic legend.
I think the story,
I tell myself...
is about a girl...
and the father
is evil because...
he hurts the girl.
And...
He touches her.
The girl only thought
and dreamt of
hurting this father,
until...
the father died,
but not how...
everyone thought,
from a sudden heart attack,
with no explanation.
Did you kill him?
I was always jealous
of your brother.
I want you to kiss me.
My love.
Stop, don't move.
Don't breathe.
Everything will be all right,
won't it?
Everything will be all right.
Not alone again.
You're not alone.
Death.
I'm going to come back.
Please.
Each time you
embrace me I feel you.
Each time getting smaller;
each time getting more fragile.
But with your death,
something new is born.
The necessity to live -
to live and leave behind
the guilt, the ghosts;
and the fear;
Forever.
I will miss you very much.