So you're stuck here.
You're lost.
I'm fed up with you.
Clare,
I'm sorry that
I'm straining you so much.
Sister Elma invited us
to go to Chiang Mai tomorrow.
We have already booked tickets to the USA...
On the same date as her.
Hey, wait,
You talked with a gynecologist ...
Which I advised you?
Yes mom.
What did he say?
Nothing.
You called a man from Angeles ...
Who deals with the adoption of Metis?
They called back.
And what did they say?
I'm not ready for adoption.
I do not understand you.
You help so many orphans ...
And she is not ready yet to adopt?
Because I want to help many orphans, not just one.
You know? Sister Elma is a very good healer.
I'll take you to her.
She can help you with infertility.
Mom, do not.
Tell your husband to stop by.
We will arrange a prayer service.
Maybe when you come back.
Here are your tickets and guide.
Here. "
You will fly Asia Pacific.
The flight leaves at 4.30 ...
Then you change to Chiang Mai, a flight at one o'clock in the afternoon.
Back to fly on Friday. So?
Thank you, Claire. You're a miracle.
We go.
When?
Right now.
All right, we'll wait for you.
Okay.
Bye Bye.
Okay bye.
You just need to check the balance of the book.
I'm sorry.
By the way, we need to go to the office.
48th
Mila called, I need to sign a check.
Then we can go to the consultant.
There is a problem?
Claire, I do not want to go to counseling anymore.
All the same from them there is no sense, nothing has changed.
Jeremiah,
You know, we need it ...
"I want to stop our relations in court."
Do you want a divorce?
It's only official, Claire.
Why not say it directly?
I know that you are unhappy with me.
I'm sorry.
You took the orphan from your wife.
I do not have a family.
I can not even give birth to a child.
I know that you do not
want a sad lonely old age.
Tell me this straight to your face ...
If you put a cross on us,
so that I have no hope left.
Claire, I do not understand
why you are against adoption.
"You do not even want to talk about it."
- Okay. Good.
This is progress.
"You do not need to wait for me."
- Claire.
I'm really sorry.
But this is actually the end.
I am your wife.
You do not even have enough
time to wait for my return home.
You really have to tell me this,
here in the car.
They have already taken Allan ...
To his grandfather in Cagayan De Oro.
Lalay and Tonting go to Bacolod, okay?
Lalina still does not have a ticket.
Does Elias really have such a big budget?
Five thousand only for gasoline?
Claire, gasoline prices have again risen.
Whom does he take with him?
That guy, Makoya.
From Paillatas.
Sandra and Elias will leave later today ...
To take him to Samar.
Wait, Sandra has not come yet.
She's still in Baguio.
Today she will not do it,
because she fell ill.
What did she have?
Heck.
You make me wait two days already.
I can not go on Sunday,
I need to go home to Pampanga.
My wife already complains.
It can cut ...
Me the content.
Hey, Elias, you can not smoke here.
Janice, can you go to Samar?
His papers are in order.
You just need to take the guy,
nothing more.
Oh no.
- We plan to take the children out ...
"Here you are, Mila.
This week.
It's June-June's birthday.
Now it's just Wednesday.
You can return on Friday
if you go right away.
Can not we wait for Sandra's return?
What if she has not been
discharged from the hospital yet?
And Elias will have
to go home for the weekend.
Janice, we must return as soon as possible.
I do not want to go on the
highway Kvirino at such an early time.
It is not safe.
Good afternoon, madam.
Where is the master?
He's behind.
Something is looking in the fridge.
I feel good with Sofitel.
Yes.
Separate room.
Yes, there will be no one with me.
Stop asking questions.
What are you doing?
Claire, let's go.
I'll stay at home with
my mother for the time being.
Claire, look at things realistically.
We have not ...
Do not be a prude!
I'm not blind.
What do you think about me?
These documents from your lawyer ...
Our property, our bills.
This is not an official divorce.
Clare.
Do not make me stupid.
Claire, it's not. I just wanted to ...
I will not steal your things and money.
You did not understand.
I did not think about it.
You made me believe.
You waited for a consultation.
Claire, please.
I thought you wanted to save our marriage.
Clare.
I thought you were preparing our future.
Claire, please?
Claire, please, wait.
Claire, please.
Claire, let's talk about this.
Go.
Where, madame?
Give me a minute.
Hello, Marie.
Heck.
Your things are heavier
than the child's luggage.
Leave, please, my things.
There's more here.
Here, all your stuff.
Heck.
What's in the bag? Your son?
You're still not used to it?
You know that I need to bring everything.
What happened?
Claire, did you forget something?
They are all gone.
Put your things.
I will take the child to Samar.
Why?
I'll just go crazy from the hotel walls.
- In the sense of a hotel?
- Hotel.
So who will take the child?
You or me?
What?
What a good suggestion.
I like it.
It's good that you came,
I can look after my son.
Jeremy is calling
Your mobile phone is ringing.
I'm not deaf.
Are you okay there?
Just drive.
You already can think of suicide.
Yes, what's the matter?
You're too annoying.
Sorry ...
If I'm irritable.
Have you traveled
to other provinces before?
Not yet.
Oh wait.
Have you heard of the Mayon volcano?
Does it ever erupt?
Erupt when heated.
Lava is flowing.
Do you know that
they take melamine for plastic?
1 missed call, 3 new messages
Do you want to take a picture?
Of course.
Smile.
Good.
Is this your job?
I am a volunteer...
Because I want to help.
A real work?
Guess.
I saw you in uniform.
Do you work in a store?
I am the manager of a travel agency.
What is it?
If you want to travel ...
You'll buy a ticket from me ...
And I'll take care of everything.
You do not have to worry.
You will only need to board the plane.
Aircraft?
I did not know that you were so cool.
Why are you doing this?
Because I want to be sure ...
That orphans like
you will find good families.
I'm happy about that.
A.
Look, I put instead of wallpaper.
Is not it nice?
Can I return to Manila?
Unknown.
Sir, you need to sign here.
Here?
Makoy, we have arrived.
Now we will go.
Do not forget to say thank you.
Poppy, look.
They seem to be good people.
And the house looks good.
Big.
I think it's sad.
Too quiet.
I think I do not want to live here.
You'll get used to it.
The important thing is that
you now have your own family ...
And you will not be alone any more.
Thank you, Miss Claire.
Hello, Mila.
Her cell phone is always off.
It seems that
she quarreled with her husband.
She will start to swear again.
Yes, we will go to Allen through Bicol.
We'll spend the night in Sorsogon.
Jeremy is calling
Are you okay?
Problems with her husband?
Jeremy is calling
Hey, Elias,
I never climbed into
your problems with my wife.
I do not bring my problems to work.
I'm not crying.
I do not sit quietly. I'm not sulking.
If you do not want to talk about your problems
- do not show them.
I'm sorry I broke up.
I'm not one to smile
when I'm ready to explode.
You know what, Claire,
Maybe I'm an asshole ...
But I'm still worried
about those with whom I work.
Jeremy left me.
Really?
We have already waited
for the marriage counselor.
I thought he wanted to save our marriage.
Then I learned that
he was talking to a lawyer ...
On the division
of property and accounts.
I feel like a fool.
It's just between us.
In the end, we are both from the shelter.
If you're going to
show yourself to your husband ...
Show yourself this.
Never let him see his weakness.
You already know this.
If only you do not have feelings left.
But I think,
He just wants to make a scene ...
To question your relationship ...
And take away from you
what you are ready to fight for.
Nonsense!
Where is he from?
There's nothing I can do.
So are you going back to Manila tomorrow?
Yes. My wife already
tried to commit suicide ...
And I'm afraid it can cut ...
My allowance.
Angela's things are collected.
I'll introduce you later, Claire.
With whom?
You did not talk to Sandra?
Oh no.
I only know that she is
in Bakuo and is ill with something.
I thought you called me here ...
due to...
Well, I spoke with Sandra on Sunday.
She took her child to Nauja ...
But said that she would return here.
You are doing a good deed.
The road was blocked ...
So Claire decided to stay the night.
Sister, what is your business with Sandra?
We decided to take an orphan.
We found a relative in Manila.
Her aunt is on the verge of ...
And wants us to take
Angela as soon as possible.
How old is Angelie?
In two days there will be 9 ...
Second of November.
Angeli ...
This is Miss Claire.
She will go with you
to Manila and talk to your aunt.
Hello, Angela.
Do not be shy.
Miss Claire is kind.
She has already helped many children.
Angelie.
She was always like this ...
Even when it first appeared here.
She peers ...
Although she has excellent eyesight.
Are your things ready?
Tomorrow you will go
with Miss Claire to Manila.
Jeremy is calling
Clare!
What?
I'm bored.
I'm going for a walk.
Where are you going?
I'll drink a little at the bar.
Do not drink much.
We leave early in the morning.
I do not for a long time.
I'll be back soon.
I'm just bored.
Battery low
Jeremy is calling
Janice did not
mean anything like that.
We are at work.
Well, you know,
her pipe is always off.
Wait.
Clare.
What?
Mila is calling.
Tell her I'm already asleep.
I'll call her back tomorrow.
She is already sleeping.
She'll call you back tomorrow.
I'm also going to.
I leave tomorrow morning.
Pssst ...
10 missed calls.
20 new messages.
What are you doing here?
I saw a man enter the room.
What?
Sister...
You are pissed.
O ...
Old age is not joy.
Pssst ...
Angela?
Angeli ...
You had a nightmare.
Angelie.
Angelie!
Stop it.
It was just a dream.
It's not really.
Jeremy came.
I did not know that you were leaving.
Janice did not tell me.
Mila, can we not
talk about this while I'm here?
Okay.
Till.
Baby, I got frost from your skin.
Sister...
You did not notice
anything strange in Angela?
For example?
I can not explain.
But...
At night she had a nightmare.
Her father died in an accident.
She was there when it happened ...
But she survived.
I'm sure it hurt her.
Jeremy is calling
Judging by the records,
you and your father traveled a lot.
First you lived in Bacold.
Then in Sagayan de Oro.
Then in Aklan.
397.
Then even in Samara.
How did your father go blind?
I, too, lost my parents as a child.
It's true.
I was five years old.
Mom and Dad went to Cebu.
They sailed on the ship ...
When the storm began.
Then no one survived.
Then I saw them for the last time.
I remember them
every time I look at the sea.
I pray for them.
Be careful, my dear.
Dad...
Look at this sink.
Do not touch.
Can bite.
Something moves inside.
Dad, look.
You can not take it from me, Gary.
Expensive!
Angelie!
Shall we sit here?
I'll rest first.
Are you cold?
Do you have a jacket in your bag?
Beautiful.
Did your father give you?
I'm sure you miss him.
But...
He said he would never leave me.
Surely he's looking out for you.
How do you know?
When I was a child...
I always felt ...
That my parents are
watching me and guarding me.
Do you want
to look at their photos?
Look.
You were plump
when you were a child.
Oh yeah.
Are they your parents?
Yes.
Now I know who you are so beautiful.
Your mother is very beautiful.
Jeremy is calling
I do not remember her at all.
Why do not you answer?
Jeremy is calling
- Jeremy calls
"Hey, Elias."
- Elias.
- What?
- Jeremy calls
"Please, look after the child."
Hello, Jeremy.
Claire, it's good
that you picked up the phone.
Why are you calling?
Where are you?
I'm worrying about you.
Really?
Why?
Can not the papers wait for my signature?
"Do you need this urgently?"
"Claire, please listen to me."
The fact that I want to get a divorce ...
Does not mean I'm not worried about you.
Please, stop calling me.
You wanted freedom, right?
Leave me alone?
Clare...
I've been feeling weird since you left.
Can we talk about this?
I do not have time to listen to you.
Angelie!
Hard to open.
Elias.
Elias, wake up.
477.
ABOUT.
Where is Angela?
I thought she was with you.
I asked you to look after her.
Where could she go?
She's here somewhere.
Come on, get up.
It is necessary to find
someone who will help her find it.
Something bad could happen to her.
Fast.
Pssst ...
Angela?
Have you found a child?
What?
Angela?
Angelie.
It's me.
Aunt Claire.
Where have you been?
What happened to you?
Where did you get this?
Who gave you this?
Angel, are you done?
Yes, madam. I am full.
Angeli ...
I want to ask you ...
About what happened on the ferry.
I saw how you talked to the woman.
Did she give you candy?
I do not remember any woman.
But I know...
That I was asleep.
I ran after butterflies.
I knew...
That I sleep.
When you woke me ...
I already had a candy.
Next...
If you do not know someone ...
Do not talk to him or go with him.
Dad taught me to
look people in the eye ...
To find out whether
they are good or bad.
How do you know who
is bad and who is good?
Dad said ...
If the reflection
in the eyes is reversed ...
Then the person is bad.
Heck!
What? What happened?
Nothing.
Hey!
Are these pigs?
Where did they come from?
A lot of pigs.
What is it?
What happened?
Brother!
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Nothing to worry about.
What happened to you?
Nothing.
Forget.
What happened to you last night?
I came to the bar,
and you were not there.
I had to drink alone.
What?
I did not go out last night.
And you?
Went out. I followed you.
I knocked at you at night ...
Because Mila wanted to talk to you ...
But you said that
you already went to bed.
Claire, are you okay?
I do not know what
you're talking about.
You're talking nonsense.
I'm sure you're doing this
to keep me from falling asleep.
How slowly can this truck go?
Elias, be careful!
Was it the same car as last night?
How did it happen?
Heck.
Hey, help me.
Here! Faster!
Where did the black car go?
We almost collided.
Let's check below,
they may still be alive.
We need to quickly,
until it exploded.
He is still stirring.
Let's carry him upstairs.
Slow.
Faster.
Hey!
What is it?
What are you doing there?
Who you are?
What you need?
Why?
Angeli ...
You noticed ...
What happens to us
a lot of strange things?
Like that woman on the ferry.
Why did your dad always tell you
to stay away from bad people?
In what sense - bad?
This can be important.
Hello, Mom?
Claire, where are you?
Jeremy came in ...
And spoke to me and your father.
I'm in the village, Mom.
I had to take the child.
And I'm on my way back.
Wait, my father wants to talk to you.
Mom, do not ...
Hello, Claire?
Where are you?
Dad.
We talked to Jeremy.
He told us what happened.
He's worried about you.
He shocked me, Dad.
604.
I know what you feel.
Please just go back home.
Let's talk about it.
Dad, do not worry about me.
With me, in fact, everything is fine.
I'll just finish it ...
And will return home.
Then, it's OK.
We love you.
Be careful.
And I love you, Dad.
Miss Claire ...
Was it your dad?
The one who adopted you?
In fact, he is my uncle.
My mother's brother.
But all my life
I treated him like my father.
You know?
They love me very much.
Do you think that the one who
will adopt me will also love me?
You are very easy to love.
You're lucky your aunt is kind.
I was not so lucky.
Elias, do not start.
Clare...
You can not tell a child ...
That life will always be happy.
Not all children
are lucky as you are.
I was almost killed
by my adoptive parents.
Elias, stop it.
Here, you need
to change the solenoid.
Here they are not for sale.
They are sold only in Manila.
So what are we waiting for ...
If we should be already on the bus.
I already asked around.
Buses here at this time do not go.
We can leave tomorrow.
We need your help. Faster!
What's going on here?
The man is wounded.
It seems that he was badly beaten.
Is he still alive?
There is no pulse.
Take him to the hospital.
I'll be damned.
Can we get lucky?
I'll sleep a little bit.
You, too, need to rest.
I'm scared.
Why?
They can take me.
Who are you talking about?
They are everywhere.
But we do not see them.
The ones you ask me about. It's them.
They are here?
They are always here.
Those who are hungry can have a snack.
Hello, Mila. Did not wake you?
Nothing.
Where are you?
I think we are already in Quezon.
Why did you call?
I tried to call you from last night.
I wanted to ask you
something about the baby.
What?
It's not easy for me.
I feel that something is wrong with her.
What?
Why?
Is her character ready?
And what? What happened?
We are waiting for you.
Hello, Claire?
Claire, hello.
Mila, I'll call you back.
680.
Yeah, we'll talk when I get back.
- Good.
- Of course.
Miss Claire!
Let's catch the bus.
What's happening?
Here's the money.
690.
Here, Elias.
I will first clarify.
Of course.
Sir, can I ask you something?
What?
Do you know where it is?
"Hey, no one will steal your bag."
- 308.
Third floor.
Climb the stairs to
the end of the corridor.
Thank you.
Of course.
"Hey, Elias ..."
- What was it?
Let's go to the third floor.
What is this call?
Hello, Mila.
We are already there.
Just arrived.
We are looking for an apartment
in which the child was taken.
Oh sure.
It's here?
We're still on the second floor.
Miss, do you know where is room 308?
This is the other side.
Thank you.
What did you say?
I asked, what do you have?
I did not eat.
That's 308.
Miss Pangitaon?
Are you with Angelica?
Come on. Come in.
Sit down please.
When will Miss Pangitaon return?
Oh, you do not know.
She told me that she would call.
Clear.
If it suits you,
you can leave Angela with me.
What? I can not leave the child.
In addition,
Miss Pangitaon must sign the papers.
Oh, yes, she also warned about it.
Well, Angela, now it's your house.
Do you want to look at your room?
I think she needs
time to get used to it.
I have to leave you.
I need to finish the costumes for Halloween.
I participate in the competition.
If you need anything,
I'll be in the next room.
By the way,
did not you hear your name?
I'm Tess.
Here's the key.
Make yourself at home.
I'll be back soon.
Thank you.
Heck.
Strange apartment.
As if the otherworldly.
Elias, this is not your house.
I want coffee.
I will go...
And I will finish something
important while you are here.
When will you be back?
I do not for a long time.
Angela, I'm leaving right now.
Do not hang your nose.
When will you come back for me?
I first need to go to the office,
withdraw money.
Then I'll buy spare parts for the car.
I can get stuck in a traffic jam.
Why not leave the baby with Tess?
We will return for papers tomorrow.
Leave the baby with her?
I do not even know her.
Sandra knows aunt.
Do not want to leave the child ...
Or just do not want
to solve problems with Jeremy?
When you get back to the office ...
Tell Mile to see what
characteristic Sandra gave to her aunt.
I'll tell Mila to call you.
Hey, Elias,
Come back for me, okay?
764.
Write to me,
or call me when you go back.
Of course.
Are you leaving already?
Go there.
So, in short, you do not have to go around.
And there is too long.
This is true?
Yes.
I do not like it here.
Dad told me that
someone wants to pick me up.
He said that they would
try to take me until I was 9.
What are you talking about?
You will not understand.
Since the moment I met you at the
orphanage and while we were traveling ...
Much has happened.
A lot of incomprehensible.
Are you afraid of Aunt Isabel?
Want to pogudyvat,
what does she look like?
She's got a nice apartment, is not she?
And the kitchen is big.
Do you think
she is fat or thin?
I think it's fat.
But you know what?
I think your aunt
is as beautiful as you.
You see, beauty is inherited.
Jeremy is calling
Jeremiah?
Claire, I'm so sorry.
I do not know what I did to you.
Us.
I thought this was what I wanted.
But when you left, I began to worry.
This led me to the idea that ...
I so wanted a divorce ...
Because I wanted
to know if I really love you.
And do you love me.
Now I know, Claire.
Now I know that
I still love you so much.
If there is something good in this ...
So this is what I now know.
I can not live without you, Claire.
Please come home.
I'm already in Manila.
I'm just waiting for someone.
Who is it?
I did not tell you that
I was taking a child to my aunt.
I'm waiting for my aunt.
I'll call when I'm ready.
Okay.
I'll be waiting for your call.
Of course.
Be careful.
I love you.
I need to go to the toilet.
What happened?
Is it locked?
Maybe there is a repair.
Angelie.
We'd better get out of here.
What?
I do not like it here.
Where are you going?
We go to the dining room.
Wait.
I'll go with you.
Please, take the money ...
- Well, there is not much here.
- No thanks. Miss Pangitaon asked me ...
- let you eat here.
"Now, you can eat now."
Delicious.
Seriously, normally.
Okay...
Thank you.
Eat while hot.
Delicious.
Angelie. Come on, eat it.
Domeng.
Oh, too hot.
You're right.
Let's take the instruments.
Wait here.
The guy is already gone?
Yes.
Why is she still here?
She's waiting for Madame.
She has papers for her signature.
Madame must sign it herself.
I could take a guy.
She could give me a woman.
Enough.
We are ordered not to harm these two.
By 7:30 ...
Miss Pangitaon still has not come ...
We with the child will go.
Hello.
Clare.
Mrs. Villamin?
God, Claire!
Get me out of here.
You have no idea
what's going on here.
In Thailand,
people take to the streets.
What?
They canceled all flights.
What happened?
How should I know?
I do not speak Thai.
I want to fly home,
but no flights.
Do something, Claire.
Mary, if only I could get there ...
I would already be there.
Can you at least
decide for yourself?
I'm already trying ...
Just can not find a flight to Manila.
Try to take her to Singapore ...
"Or in Kuala Lumpur."
"What about bills?"
Leave now.
They are going to take the child.
Let's talk about this later.
They're really going to pick you up.
Tess.
What?
I'm sorry.
She must be stuck in traffic.
I'm sure she's coming here.
If she does not arrive by 7:30 ...
We with the child will leave.
I already asked
someone to give us a ride.
You can call the office,
maybe she's still there.
Who are you writing to?
This is for you.
For me?
Let me have a look...
I will read.
It is too early.
I'll put it in the bag
until the right moment.
Not finished yet?
I think we should rest first.
So it will stay fresh
until your aunt returns.
She will come at any time.
Calling Elias
Angelie.
Where are you?
Angelie!
Jeremy is calling
Hello, Jeremy.
Where are you now?
I tried to call you.
We're still here.
Can I ask you?
Can you give us a ride?
Tess.
Faster Please.
I warned you.
You did not want to listen.
Excuse me...
Miss.
"Leave now ..."
- Miss.
It's not too late.
Where is Angela?
I do not know anything.
You're lying.
Where is the baby?
I already said, I do not know ...
And there's nothing you can do about it ...
Once she decided to go with them.
Hey.
Shut up fool.
Stop bothering guests.
I'm sorry, miss.
She's sick on her head.
Have you seen the girl who was with me?
It should be somewhere around here.
Maybe he plays with
the other children below.
Going fourth.
Answer our questions.
Spirit...
The spirit that
goes forth is the fourth.
Answer our questions.
Spirit...
The spirit that
goes forth is the fourth.
Answer our questions.
Children...
A!
Have you seen a little
girl in a black dress?
Black?
Yes.
Are you talking about Nenita?
It is black, does not wear black.
It is not local.
We did not see her.
Maybe it was already sold.
There's a full madhouse around here.
Children catch and cut ...
To sell their kidneys and liver.
Mila is calling
Hello...
Mila.
I found the characteristic.
I was at the bottom of the pile ...
Baby did not want to be found.
Sandra's characterization was negative.
What?
She suggested looking Aunt Angeli closer.
Where is Elias?
He should have come back.
He has not arrived yet?
He said he tried to get you through,
but without success.
I fell asleep.
He had to call longer to wake me up.
I'll call him back.
Okay.
We'll put your backpack
and your hair in order.
c
Angelie!
Oh sure.
Elias!
Elias.
Elias, stop!
Elias!
Angelie!
Angers ...
Miss Claire,
please do not leave me here.
I will not leave you.
Do not leave me.
You just slept.
I will not leave you.
It was just a dream.
I did not sleep, Miss Claire.
I know, it was actually.
It was just a dream.
The butterfly called me behind her.
We passed through
the walls of the rooms ...
Until they reached a beautiful place.
What place?
Everything there seemed expensive ...
As if the rich lived there.
I've never seen
anything like this before.
I heard a woman's voice ...
Who said that I should go with her.
But after...
Then what?
I remembered that I promised my father ...
That I will not go with them.
Angelie, listen.
It's not really.
"It was just a dream."
- It really is.
There is no butterfly.
- And there is no woman.
"It was not a dream."
You did not see a beautiful place.
- It really is.
-Actually...
It's real that I'm here, with you.
- I am real.
- It's real.
Stay here.
Clare!
Elias.
Get out of here...
now.
Tess.
Are you there?
Miss Claire.
What?
Miss Claire, they're coming.
We need to leave.
Miss Claire!
Angela, wait.
Angelie!
Tell me, who are they?
They are not like us.
What?
I do not understand you.
Tell me the truth, who are they?
Incanto.
Do not make me repeat ...
Because they will come closer.
Let's go to! Faster!
Angelie!
We have returned?
Why are we still here?
Angelie.
We must flee.
There.
Miss Claire!
Angelie!
Stupid.
Get up. Faster.
You did not want to believe me.
They left.
We are safe.
Faster, it's almost three o'clock.
I need to prepare
For what?
Do you want to return Angela?
Yes.
Hello, Angela.
The time has come.
Happy Birthday.
What are you doing?
We must save Angelica.
Her mother took it.
Her mother died a long time ago.
Anzheli's mother can not die.
Incanto immortal.
Angeli ...
Daughter of a mortal man and incanto.
The man fell in love with ...
Believe me, Claire.
I myself gave birth
to a child from one of them.
He took my daughter.
I could not do anything about it.
The child made a decision.
Decision?
What solution?
When a baby incanto
is born in the world of people ...
They need it before
her ninth or eighteenth birthday ...
Convince her to
go with them at her will.
They can not take a child by force.
But they can convince her with cunning.
In their world there is no true love.
They have no emotions.
They are callous.
They do not have souls.
They used you, Claire.
I brought her here.
Where's her bag?
Heck. She did not
have a bag when we took her.
There is.
We need it.
We need to destroy all of her
things so as not to cause suspicion.
It must be in the apartment.
Call Domenga.
Tell him to take the things.
Where are the things?
Things? Here.
Faster, it's almost midnight.
Three o'clock in the
morning is midnight for incanto.
We must return it while we have time.
This room?
Yes.
Take everything that we need.
I'll see.
"Dear Miss Claire,
if they come and take me ..."
Please come and find me.
Help me.
I honestly do not want to go with them.
With love, Angela. "
Mang Domeng is one of them?
Yes.
There are many,
so no one can be trusted.
We must hurry
until her birthday comes.
Good.
Well, where are you?
We need to go.
We may not succeed.
Maybe we can not return it.
We are late.
How are you going to get there?
We have already arrived.
Decisiveness can
sometimes lead to a goal.
Tess.
Did you bring all her things?
Where is Angela?
Follow me.
You know, Claire ...
I do not understand why
you can not let Angela go to heaven.
If I were you,
I would not count on it.
Why do not you join us?
Look, the holiday has just begun.
Rita...
What is it?
This is my daughter.
My child.
Dont touch me.
Don `t you remember me?
I'm your mother.
I brought you to this world
and raised you until they took you.
I do not have a mother.
Go away.
My child.
She's not your daughter.
Whatever you do,
she will not remember you.
She does not know another family ...
except us.
No.
I'll take her back.
Do not trust, Rita.
She chose to be incanto ...
And became one of us.
No.
Pssst.
My child, come with me.
I'll take you far.
I do not want to become like them.
I know why they are here.
Whatever you're up to, do not do it.
Who are you to take
the child away from your mother ...
If you are not your mother?
Angela asked me
to save her from you ...
Her father said so to her.
It was not easy for me
to leave your world.
We need people to have children ...
Then we take them back to our world.
My love, let's take
a picture with the child.
Like most people ...
Gary did not know about our existence ...
But even if we tried to hide ...
There are people whose
feelings are open, they feel us.
How can you say that?
She is my wife. We live together.
Once I gave life to
a being different from us.
Believe me, Gary,
Isabel is incanto.
"Gary, I'm telling the truth."
- Get out!
She is not a man,
Gary ...
Pssst ...
I thought...
For Gary it will be easy ...
To accept my death.
We preserve our earthly appearance ...
Until we give birth to a child.
Then we are called by the wind ...
And so we die ...
And we can return to our world.
Do not cry.
Leave this world.
"You're a demon!"
- What are you doing?
"I'm banishing you!"
"What are you doing with my wife?"
"Gary, you have to believe me."
- Get out! Leave us alone!
Look at your wife! Look at her!
My mission is not
complete until I get my baby.
Gary thought he could take it from me.
If he really loved Angela ...
He would not take her away from us,
in our world there is no sadness and problems.
Why are you so proud
of your hearts and souls ...
Because from them
only pain and suffering?
I want to see Angela.
I want to talk to her.
What for?
Because I know...
She needs to make a choice.
I want to know what she decided.
Then I'll leave.
We will see.
Happy birthday, Angela.
Happy Birthday!
You decided to become one of us ...
And turn away from the
people with whom you grew up?
Angelie.
In the letter you asked me to come.
You asked me not to give you to them,
whatever happened.
That's why I'm here.
I was wrong.
Here I am happy.
They will take care of me.
There I was lonely.
It is not true.
Do you remember Daddy?
You said that
he loved you very much.
He gave you a postcard
on your last birthday.
He said "I love you very much.
I want you to grow up
with a good heart and soul.
Please, remember me.
- "Remember me...
... everything I said and everything
I taught you, even when I was not around.
Happy Birthday!
With love, Dad "
There is no more love
than my love for you.
Even if your mother were alive ...
She could not have
dreamed of you the way I do ...
And wish you the same happiness.
And I hope you will always remember
that only the pope has good intentions.
I love you dad.
And even when I do not ...
Please remember
- I will always be there to protect you ...
And I'll watch that there
is someone who really loves you.
Why do you say that?
Angeli ...
Your cake.
Blow the candle, make a wish.
Oh yeah.
I want my dad's eyesight back ...
And I want, that we
always remained together.
You know what he sacrificed ...
To save you from this place.
Angelie, you're not alone.
I'm here.
I'll take care of you.
Me and Jeremy.
Just promise me ...
That we will go home.
I love you very much, Angela.
We'll always be together.
Nothing will separate us ...
Now that I understand that
fate has brought us together.
Miss Claire,
please take me home.
You have to choose, Claire:
Angela or the life of your husband?
What are you speaking about?
Did not you ask him to come here?
Jeremiah!
Choose.
Angela or your husband?
Do not touch her husband.
I'll go with you when I turn eighteen.
I promise.
But if you offend them,
I will never go with you.
The girl made the decision.
We can not resist it.
Miss Claire, let's go.
Faster, let's go.
Clare.
Rita, what's the matter?
My child.
1,291
I'll never go with you.
Let's go to!
I'll stay here.
Should I go if
I can not be with my child?
Leave.
Miss Claire.
Clare?
Clare!
Clare...
It's me, Jeremy.
This is Jeremy.
Jeremiah!
I've been looking everywhere for you.
What happened?
Long story.
Everything is fine.
Now I am here.
Go home.
Clare.
This is Angela.
She will live with us.
Angelie, come here.
This is your dad, Jeremy.
Come here.
"Hello, Mrs. Villamin?"
- Claire.
It's good that you are still awake.
This is the worst trip of my life.
Do you know where I am?
Where are you?
I'm in Laoag.
Your dorky assistant
did not book me a flight to Manila!
Now I need to wait another two hours ...
To fly away ...
God, Claire, that's too much!
You can forget about the gift.
I'll bring you Wigan sausages -
Angelie, are you ready?
Do you want me to go with you?
Not necessary.
I can do it myself.
Bye, Mom.
Kisses.
Bye, Daddy.
Have a rest.
What happened?
Hey, are you okay?
Why is she so pale?
Who is she?
She's our new classmate ...
From the province.
That's her?
Yes. Here is the call.
Hey, classmate. It's time.
- Oh my God!!
"I'm sorry, madam." I am so sorry.
"Next time, neater."
- I want to go home.
What?
Why?
Do not be afraid.
You are very welcome here.
Actually, I'm going to your class ...
To introduce you to your new teacher.
Oh, she's already here.
Miss Isabel,
meet your new apprentice, Angela.
Good morning,
Angelie.