To my mother, Dolores Maldonado Capado,
and Valverde del Camino (Huelva)
Forty years after the entry into force
of the Spanish Constitution
To date, the transsexual collective
still pursues its social inclusion
Public Institutions, in order to
the United Nations Charter,
TEXT: LORENA GUZMAN
must prevent this scourge through
effective laws and economic supports
For many years, transgender people
were engaged in prostitution
The labor doors are still closed
and persecutions and attacks continue
Children can´t choose their gender
due to social pressure and taboos
and this makes them suffer a lot
They loved your project!
You're the best. Take a few days off.
Thank you Carlos,
maybe some other time.
But now I prefer to finish
some work that is pending.
As you wish. We'll reward you soon.
Honey, what do you have to tell me
that is so important?
I've left some clients unattended.
Yes?
I can see it´s a boy
because of the genital organs.
- Do you like it?
- I love it mom.
- How beautiful will be my boy.
- How handsome he'll be!
I can´t wait to see him!
And how are you? Do you still vomit?
I don´t vomit anymore but he kicks me
at night and I can't sleep.
Oh! He´s like you!
You did the same!
Done!
Sleep, my little boy!
- Hello!
- Hi! I´m Pedro, your new neighbour.
This is a present for your baby!
Congratulations!
Oh, thank you! Please, come in.
- A doll? That´s not for boys, is it?
- Of course not.
I thought it was a girl.
Tomorrow I'll exchange it for another!
- Don´t worry, it´s very nice,
I'll keep it for me.
No! I'll change it.
Don´t worry!
Would you like another coffee?
Haven't you noticed something strange
about our neighbour?
- I'd say he's gay.
- Oh, come on honey.
-Well, and what if he's gay?
- I don´t want strange things
around our son. Maybe he's a problem.
-Oh, really? What kind of things?
THREE YEARS LATER
You are lovely, handsome.
-Handsome? Beautiful.
Have you heard that, love?
He said: not handsome, beautiful.
He said beautiful to you!
And what are you?
Handsome or beautiful?
Beautiful.
It´s time to go to bed.
Come on, sweethearts.
- Let´s go?
- Let´s go.
FIVE YEARS LATER
One, two and three. Boys to the right
and girls to the left.
Let´s go, 1... 2... and... 3!
Adam? What happens?
Choose one costume and get ready.
Come on, Adam.
Play with it.
When I grow up I'll be like you
and have the hair as long as you.
Oh yes? My little boy...
Don't get so angry.
Why don´t you play with someone? Gay!
Let me see that face! Oh, what a boy!
- How handsome you're. I love you!
- Me too, grandma!
Mom, why do you let
the kid do these nonsenses?
What nonsenses? Is this bad?
Take out that clothes,
you look like a clown.
Oh my god,
you are worst than you father!
What a girl, she´s young but...
Honey, are you okay?
Mummy, daddy, I´m a girl, don´t you see it?
Oh baby,
it´s a nightmare, don´t worry.
When am I going to be
who I really am?
- Come here, baby.
- Come, superhero.
- It's time for mental calculus. Ready?
- Yes!
If I have 25 sweets and I eat 15,
how many sweets are left?
- 15 sweets.
- Yes! Right!
I have 100 euros and spend 80.
How many are left Adriana?
- 20 euros.
- Right, very good.
Page 25 guys...
Adam, come here, let´s play.
Hello! Look Adam,
this is for your costume party!
- It´s a prince costume!
- It´s beautiful.
I don´t like it, I want a princess costume.
- Princess? Don´t talk nonsense!
- If he wants to be an actor...
He´s always with the same thing...
What´s wrong with this costume?
- I don´t like it.
- And which one do you want?
- Alberto, you're spoiling the boy.
You'll wear this costume!
We're leaving now,
so much nonsense about princess.
We demand to remove transsexuality
from mental illness manuals
and the right for trans people
to change their name on official documents
We concentrate after
the aggression to Lorena,
an act that incites hatred of diversity,
and that is why today we claim our rights.
We want the free
development of trans minors
their free self-determination
and choice of gender.
Silence is complicity.
For the rights of transsexuals!
Also the difficulty of
trans people to find a job.
We demand new policies to end
We demand new policies to end the
marginalization and discrimination.
We want to highlight the murders,
assaults and suicides
suffered by trans
people and their families.
And we point to the system as guilty.
You are so girly, you are a shame.
It´s enough, leave him alone!
What happens?
Children shouldn't be taken into account.
They change their minds quickly.
As a religion teacher,
I'll say children must be limited.
We can't let them do what they want to.
Adam, is in a difficult period.
Do not buy him girls things,
he´s not a girl.
You'll see he'll soon pass the whim.
- How did you get him that costume?
- I did, there's nothing more to talk about.
- You could have told me.
- We are not perfect. I made a mistake.
Adam, what happens?
Don´t you go to the toilet?
Adam is a complicated kid.
I don't know what's wrong with him.
I've never met a case like this
and I don't know what to do.
Sometimes the behavior of children
is due to problems at home.
There is no problem
that can affect him.
We'll make him an attention deficit test.
If you think it´s okay.
We´ll call you to sign the papers.
More things:
this drawing is from your son...
I have a lot of work tomorrow,
I will arrive late...
I waited for you at school today.
I'm having all the problems on my own.
Are you're saying
I don't care about my family?
You know what it's like to be
showing houses all day to earn a living.
You're so calm in your office.
Mommy, you have to ask me
the multiplication tables.
You study that at school!
Go to bed, I'm fed up with you.
I've finished my homework.
Am I handsome, eh?
I´m tired of this...
You are big enough for these games.
Adam!
Mommy, girls don´t have a pennis,
cut it please...
- Was it an accident?
- I´ve been beaten up...
- Why?
- Because I´m a trans person.
There're still people who don't understand
we live in another world.
Rosa, you can go in.
We've done several
medical tests and it's all right.
So, your son is very healthy.
-Rosa. -Hello Carlos.
You haven't come two
days and your phone's off.
What's the matter with you?
- I took Adam to the doctor.
- What about the Germans' project?
- I'll have it at the end of the day.
- I hope so.
I never wanted to wear girl's clothes,
nor to be a woman
I'm happy being a man.
What if your son is a transsexual?
Good night, I'm Sam the Giant.
I'm going to sing
a Spanish song called the Trinidad!
I stop because I want to
because the Spanish singers
have been shitting it for 40 years
saying Murillo and Rafael
and as a well-educated transsexual
in the Seville's Museum there's not
a single painting of Rafael
there's Juan de Valdés Leal,
so the song is
Right or not? How serious!
I´m singing culture
and people go out.
I´m explaining very well
the Valdés Leal thing.
Adam's case is complicated,
he's small but has clear his ideas.
We have to understand
that this can change as years go by.
You don't have to worry
and let him live as he feels.
Let´s meet in three months
to see his progress.
Honey, we are at home.
- What are all those clothes?
- Didn't you hear the psychologist?
Remember when you said
the most important was his happiness?
I love myself the way I am, as a man.
I'm not gay, but artistically
I dress as a woman.
I've been doing it since I was a kid
because it frees me up.
I don't dress up like a woman
everyday, just in occasional cases.
Silvia! One beer please.
Ana, do you think we're doing well?
Ana, if you see how happy he's
when she says she's Sophia.
That's not the case,
your son has a mental illness.
You have to get him
to a psychiatrist as soon as possible.
I know some very good ones.
Adam is a healthy boy.
The only problem
he's got is in his head.
You mustn't play along
because you're only hurting him.
Adam was born boy and what God creates
cannot be altered by man at his whim.
Do you want him to be
the school laughing boy?
Making fun of him all day?
You've lost your mind.
Alberto, how's it going?
I thought all this was going to be
a game, a passing joke...
but the situation is beyond me.
I've always had
everything under control
but I feel like I'm hitting a wall.
I just want everything to be normal.
I know,
but what's really normal, Alberto?
I want to know, too.
I want you to know
that I love my son very much.
I'm sure of that.
- Alberto Martinez!
- One second please!
Calm down.
Everything will be okay, darling.
You'll see everything will be okay.
He's out of gravity, he's bruising
but we don't care about it.
He's got a corneal tear,
his eyes'll be blindfolded
We´ll see how he evolves.
Can we see him?
He's sedated, you'll be able
to see him in half an hour.
Okay, thank you.
Don't cry, darling.
- Hi, daddy. I'm Sophia.
- Sophia?
- Sophia, your daughter!
- Have I got a daughter?
I can't remember,
I have a headache.
Honey, give dad a kiss
and let's get him rest.
I SAW A LIGHT SHINING,
I SAW MYSELF BEHIND, JUST AS I AM
LISTEN DAD, TAKE MY HAND,
YOU CAN SEE, EVEN IF YOU'RE BANDAGED
LOVE IS THE LIGHT
AND THERE IS NO NEED TO FEAR
EVEN THOUGH I'M DIFFERENT,
EVEN THOUGH I'M DIFFERENT...
LOVE IS THE LIGHT
AND THERE IS NO NEED TO FEAR
EVEN THOUGH I'M DIFFERENT,
EVEN THOUGH I'M DIFFERENT...
I SAW THE SUN RISE,
I SAW THE SUNRISE, WITH A HOPE
LISTEN, MOM, STAY BY MY SIDE
YOU KNOW WELL WHAT'S HAPPENED TO ME
LOVE IS THE LIGHT
AND THERE IS NO NEED TO FEAR
Go with dad, he's alone downstairs.
- Daddy, do you know who I am?
- Of course, honey.
AND EVEN IF THE MOON COMES UP
AND I CAN´T SEE YOU...
YOU LIGHT MY WAY
OH, YOU LIGHT MY WAY
BECAUSE YOU'RE MY LIFE
AND I´M LUCKY TO HAVE YOU
- What about transgender kids?
- Transgender kids know they are kids.
Like any other children,
they know that they are children.
The problem comes when what they are
faces what people say they are.
- And could this be a whim?
- No, it's not a whim, Rosa.
Transsexuality is not a choice,
you can't chose your sexual identity.
- Isn't it a disease either?
- No. That's why there is no treatment.
Each one is as he/she is and
each one is what he/she really feels.
If you really want to help Lucy,
you have to understand these issues.
Because that's important
to be able to help her in her process.
Now I want you to come with me
to see the place,
to get know about the dynamics
and to meet some transsexual families.
It was hard to assimilate what I was
'cause I didn't understand that world.
And I used to say my mum:
"I don't want to have that there."
I took the scissors. I didn't want...
I didn't feel as a boy.
I was always with girls and
I couldn't understand what I was.
When getting older, little by little
I understood what I was.
I was prescribed hormones
and I started with the treatment.
And it's a change very...
I feel really good now.
I know that he had a really hard time
and society is not ready for this.
It's hard, but she is happy.
And that's the most important.
And I get excited because she's now
what she really wanted to be.
You have to support her.
Even if you don't understand her.
Speak with her.
You'll understand her.
It'll be hard,
because you had a boy and now...
It's hard but you want
her happiness, don't you?
- Fifteen.
- Fifteen years old.
And, as you can see,
he's now very self-confident.
It's a great advance. He is very shy,
but as any child or adolescent can be.
To tell you the truth,
I see him very different.
I've lived a repressed transsexuality.
I didn't know what was wrong with me.
Until one day that I said it at home
because I couldn't stand it anymore.
I've suffered job discrimination.
I don't have the same opportunities
because I'm a transgender.
LIVE THE LIFE, LIVE THE LIFE
LIVE THE LIFE, LIVE THE LIFE,
And what shall we do now, Albert?
I'm very afraid about
what could happen to our son.
I'm afraid he might live
a lonely and miserable life.
I have a feeling whatever we'll do
we're going to do wrong.
Call your parents and your sister
and tell them to come.
It's eleven at night! Are you crazy?
It doesn't matter, call them.
Hurry up!
MY SOPHIE IS HAPPY, MY SOPHIE IS HAPPY,
- That's great!
- How happy she is!
- Grandma blows you a kiss.
- Muah!
Mommy, daddy,
today's been the best day of my life.
Little Adam, I carried you
for nine months in my womb,
you were born
and became the joy of the house.
But you started growing up
and your face stopped smiling.
I felt like a bad mother because
I was failing at something with you.
And I didn't know what it was.
Today, Adam, I want to say godbye
to you. Oh my god, I can't.
How hard it is!
Even though I know you're not anymore
and that you've never really been.
I cradled you, dressed you,
named you and loved you
like that beautiful child
I thought you were.
How difficult it is, Adam.
I'm trying to say goodbye to you
even though I'm seeing next to me
a beautiful girl named Sophia,
a girl who gives off the joy
that you should.
My little Adam, I want to tell you
that you'll always be in my heart.
Though my mind knows
you've never existed,
We are at life just to pass through
and to be happy.
Ok, we are now going to start
the project in the nature classroom.
But first, one question: what are
the human beings' vital functions?
- Who do I throw the ball at?
- Me!
Sophia! Take the ball.
Function of nutrition,
interaction and reproduction.
-Very good, right answer! -Very good.
Come on, start the research work.
This is for you. And you, let me see.
Ok, very good.
AMERICAN GUN, AMERICAN GUN,
IN, OUT, TURN AND JUMP
Once again.
AMERICAN GUN, AMERICAN GUN,
IN, OUT, TURN AND JUMP
You're a boy.
You will never be a girl.
You're annoying God
and he's going to punish you.
God loves me very much
because I'm very happy.
- We're going to the director!
- No! You're a bad person!
I just want that everything is normal.
He can come as a boy, as usual.
Why haven't they ask us and listen
before dressing him as a girl?
These parents are feminizing their son
and that's really serious.
I just want him to dress as a boy
inside the school.
Outside the school, he can dress
like he wants and do what he wants.
You can't turn a school and its values
upside down for a childish whim.
In my personal opinion,
these parents want to attract attention
and they are damaging the good climate
of coexistence of this centre.
I'm going to tell you
something that people
who know really well
these parents have told me:
These parents wanted to have
a girl instead of a boy.
Everything that is happening
is a whim of them
and they also want to design
their son's sexuality.
It doesn't surprise me, it's crazy.
And all they're getting is
our kids coming to school scared.
Despite all the nonsense I'm hearing,
I understand your concern
and that you're not prepared for this,
because we weren't either.
Now we're proud and happy
to have Sophia.
Sophia is a girl as yours
and we have to help her
to obtain the same rights
that your children have
and my daughter doesn't have yet.
- Your son is very dear to this school.
- Daughter!
I reject any kind of discrimination
but I will not allow my son
to be used as a guinea pig
in an integration experiment
that is not supported by medical,
psychological or judicial documents.
to be used as a guinea pig
in an integration experiment
that is not supported by medical,
psychological or judicial documents.
- We've had enough,
so let's get out of here.
- Yes.
- These people are all scoundrels.
You are all wrong.
I've prepared a document
to be submitted
to the Board of Directors
and the Inspection.
If you want to, you can
come and sign it.
- What's that? A boy or a girl?
- I don't know.
Don't you know
that sex is in the brain?
My mother says that it's a monster.
We are all humans.
Auntie, has it been many years
since you've been on a swing?
-Many. -A lot of them.
Auntie, has it been many years
since you've been on a swing?
-Many. -A lot of them.
Go hard! Now.
-How's school going, Sophia?
Very well auntie,
I'm getting very good marks.
Great! Do you want us
to go to the casino to see Grandpa?
Ok!
- Four.
- Three, it's three.
I'll be right back.
- Where is my grandfather Francisco?
- Who are you?
I'm Sophia, his granddaughter.
But Francisco didn't have
any granddaughters.
- I think he has a grandson.
- When he comes, ask him.
It seems to me
that it was a boy, doesn't it?
- I don't know Paco.
- It was a boy.
Francisco, your granddaughter
has come looking for you.
My granddaughter? What granddaughter?
Yes, a little girl has come asking
for her grandfather Francisco.
I don't have any granddaughter,
I just have two grandsons.
- I told it to you.
- But didn't Francisco have a...?
Francisco have a grandson,
not a granddaughter, ok?
Come on, let's continue.
You're my grandfather
and you're ashamed of me.
I'm a girl, your granddaughter Sophia.
And listen to this: I won't talk
to you again until you call me Sophia.
Carlos, I've finished the project
you asked me for. Look, I'll show you.
I come from a meeting
with the board of directors.
I don't like to tell you this but
we've decided that
you won't continue working with us.
-What?! -You're the best in the company but
your family situation
doesn't favor the company's policy.
Do you know what? My family situation
has helped me to know
which things are important in life
and who really worthwhile.
I'll come tomorrow
to pick up my stuff.
We've received a letter
parents of the school.
We have done as much as we could and more.
We've authorized him to come dressed
as a girl, to enter the girls toilet,
but we think we don't have to give
any more explanations at school
and even less to parents,
who are free to think what they want.
And they know what they want!
I have to recognize
that this situation
causes many problems to the school.
We're not prepared to face
problems like your son's.
Daughter! It's a girl
and her name is Sophia!
Sorry. We've decided that from now on
she cannot use the girls toilet.
- What?!
- Then, what toilet can she go into?
Don't worry, she can use the sink
in the toilet for her bowel movements.
No way! My daughter has
the same rights as everyone else,
so we're going to file a complaint
right now at the inspection.
You should maybe consider changing her
to a school where no one knows her.
Are we assassins, terrorists
or something else?
I've already spoken
with the director of a public school
and he totally agrees with the change.
Hi, honey! How was
your first day at the new school?
Very good, daddy. I'm very happy.
Mi teacher is very nice.
I love being with my classmates
and I've been made captain of a team.
- A communion with only two girls?
- What an outrage, God!
What are you doing, faggot?!
Hurry up, Sophia! You're going to be
late on your first date of institute!
My little girl,
you're already a little woman!
-Hello. -I'm Julia.
Hello, nice to meet you.
- Hello! Nice to meet you too.
- Hello.
My name is Rosa Gómez and this year
I'm going to be your biology teacher.
Let's not waste any more time.
I'm going to do a roll call
to get to know you better.
-Maite Álvarez? -Me.
-Julia Díaz? -Me.
-Daniela Fernández? -Me.
-Sara López? -Me.
Adam Martínez? Adam Martínez?
Hasn't Adam Martínez come?
Hasn't he come today?
Excuse me.
Sophia! Darling, they've called
from the institute.
I know what happened to you!
The teacher was new
and didn't realize it!
You can't give up! You have to fight!
To fight? I don't want to fight,
just to live in peace!
What do they need
to realize that I'm a woman?
How long does it take
to get my new ID card?
Hello, miss.
Could you give me your ID card?
Oh, your name is Adam.
There must be some mistake.
Yes, there is a mistake and it is
this society where we live in.
Indicating the characteristics
of each group of micro-organisms.
This is worth one point and a half.
Also, mention two differences...
- This isn't going to be in the exam.
- I think not.
I can see your package!
Come on, Sophia! We're late!
No!
Hi Sophia! How are you, darling?
I don't know. I'm afraid
the treatment won't go well.
You've just started a hormonal process
and you're very insecure now
about what could happen.
But this is a process
and it take time.
So don't worry. Everything's gonna
be fine little by little.
Do Adam have tits?
Do you want to see them?
Leave her alone! Go away!
Are you okay?
I forgot to tell you before.
Thanks for your help.
That's what classmates are for.
I suppose you mean good classmates,
not everyone is like you.
I really like you
even I don't know you.
And I still don't even know your name.
When I look at you,
I feel like I've met you before.
I have to tell you something.
You're so serious!
Do you have any secrets?
I'm Raúl.
Which Raúl?
- Your classmate.
- That monster who was all day...?
-Yes, that one. -I have to go.
-Wait. -I'm in a big hurry.
Sophia, please forgive me.
I know that I hurt you so much,
but I've changed. I promise you.
I'm totally different
and I really want to be with you.
Just think about it, ok?
- I'm going out.
- Where do you go so gorgeous?
- I'm going to a concert with a friend.
- That's nice!
- Are you sure she's a friend?
- Of course.
Well, okay. But if it's a boy
I have to meet him.
What things you say!
Sophia! Is it true what your father
says about a boy that you like?
No, how tiresome you are!
I'm very proud of our daughter.
Hey, do you want to play for a while?
Yoo-hoo!
Hey! You're so beautiful today.
What do you have? A date?
With your Prince Charming, right?
Listen: you are not a real woman
like me. I was born woman.
- Hey! Do you want
to have a drink with us?
-No, thanks Maite, some other time.
Are you coming inside?
- No, go ahead.
- Okay!
- Are you alone?
- Yes, but I'm waiting for a friend.
Aah. Then I'll see you inside now.
I was really looking forward
to this moment
and I want to introduce
my new single now,
which I dedicate,
of course, to my fan club.
I NO LONGER KNOW WHAT I FEEL FOR YOU
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE IN MY HEART
UH-HUH, FEEL IT
I WANT TO BE ALWAYS BY YOUR SIDE
I THINK ABOUT YOU
I FEEL YOU'RE ESPECIAL
MY OTHER HALF
HOW LONG DO I HAVE TO SCREAM
THAT I CAN'T FORGET YOU?
YOU KNOW I'M WILLING TO WAIT FOR YOU
I AM CRAZY
BECAUSE WITHOUT YOU I AM NOT MYSELF
SO LONG
LOOKING FOR YOU IN MY SOLITUDE
IN MY SOLITUDE
I WON'T GIVE UP WHATEVER IT TAKES
I KNOW YOU LIGHT MY DAWN
HEY, LOOK AT ME
HOW LONG DO I HAVE TO SCREAM
THAT I CAN'T FORGET YOU?
YOU KNOW I'M WILLING TO WAIT FOR YOU
YOU ARE EVERYTHING I ALWAYS DREAMED OF
YOU'RE PART OF ME
AND I KNOW
THAT MY DESTINY IS IN YOUR SKIN
YOU ARE MY LOVE
YOU CHANGE EVERYTHING INSIDE ME
WHEN THE SUN SPLITS IN HALF
WHEN NOTHING'S COLORED
YOU ARE MY LOVE
HOW LONG DO I HAVE TO SCREAM
THAT I CAN'T FORGET YOU?
YOU KNOW I'M WILLING TO WAIT FOR YOU
Come with me, Raúl.
I have to tell you something.
YOU ARE MY LOVE
Raul, I didn't know you were a sissy.
You like guys.
What are you saying?
I don't like guys.
You were dancing with a guy.
Dressed like a woman but with a good penis.
- She's not my girlfriend,
I'd be nasty to be with her.
Sophia, what I told you before
is not what I really feel.
I can't stand it anymore.
Don't do anything crazy.
Think about your family.
I can´t stand it anymore.
When you ignore those who laugh at
you in class, you taught everyone a lesson.
You're the bravest person I know.
Trust me, when we're together,
I don't care about anyone else.
We're going to practice
with PCES questions.
Let´s start.
Factors influencing enematic activity...
Who knows it?
Julia.
Inhibitors, temperature and Ph.
Names of bacteriophage life cycles...
- Lithium cycle and bisogenic cycle.
- Very good, Sophia.
- Phases of mitosis.
- Me!
You have to stop seeing that person
The whole world will point at you.
You're going to ruin your life
because of a whim of youth.
If you keep this up,
we will have to leave town.
Raúl, I forbid you to see Adam
or whatever his name is now.
Raúl! Raúl!
Did you get it?
More or less,
I look at it later at home, it's late.
- Ok! I can lend you my notes!
- Okay.
Hey, nothing, let it go.
Are you okey, Raúl?
- I came to talk to you.
- Of course, come up with me.
What happens?
I'm in love with Sophia.
We're doing very well
but I sometimes wonder what I am.
Do you understand me?
Yes and I know
you're questioning your identity.
But it's not a matter of labels,
it's a matter of feelings.
You're a great person because
you learned to value diversity.
That's why you fell in love
with Sophia. Calm down.
The best is
not to think more about that.
I already suffered a lot
when your father left us,
don't make me suffer again.
Your grandparents
really want to see you.
The number is not...
We're on the air in "Contigo a Diario"...
The most awaited moment has arrived...
We´re going to give the name of
the best student of this year...
The Director will give the details,
Castillo Ruiz...
I am the Director of
the Lebrija High School.
When I finish high school,
I want to study nursing.
- I'm Sophia Martinez,
I want to study biotechnology.
It's time to know who's the best student...
The lucky one, it's Sophia Martinez.
Let's hear it for Sophia!
Congratulations!
Congratulations Sophia!
Do you want to say something?
To be honest,
I don't like to take part in any contest.
I will gladly represent
our High School.
I would like to send a hug
to my classmates, who also deserve it.
I'll end by saying that I'm very proud
of being a transsexual girl.
The world will be better
when we accept ourselves
and we accept individual diversities.
Transsexual people
are like everyone else.
- What are you doing?
- It´s a surprise, trust me.
Traducción y subtitulado: Rosa María Espinosa
García y Claudia Fernández de la Poza