'Tales' could not have been made in 2012 if not
for the help and support of the Iranian cinema family
Shirin Dibaj
Tales
They were supposed to take us
with visas and work permits
Not just me, many others like me
I got the money for our house
from my mum...
I handed it over to him
-Want me to drive slower to get a good picture?
-No, it's fine
Do you have a lighter?
-Here you go
-Thanks
-Keep it
-I'll buy one
-Take it for now
-Thanks
Seems like it's not meant to be
Are you from overseas?
-Me?
-Yes
-No, why?
-You're filming the streets
That's how I observe
So...
-You paid them and they left
-I got into so much trouble
I lost everything
I thought, I did this and I'll fix it myself
I started a job, I messed up
at the first attempt
I lost all the drugs
I ran away from the dealers...
A few years
They'd chop me up if they found me
I'm still scared
-That's it
-This town is too crowded
On my way, yeah, I'm coming
Okay, I'll pick her up.
I said I would
Bye
She works three night shifts
for a tiny nursing wage
This poor thing is always
wandering around
My daughter, her name is Sarvenaz
God bless
Who takes care of her, then?
-My mother
-God bless her
You know what really upsets me?
The mother never complained once
I wish she'd slap me
I wish she'd do something
to hurt me back
When I got back I found out
she'd worked double shifts...
To pay for
my brother and sister's education
I have to get out here
-Sorry, I talked too much
-No, it was great
-I wish you'd filmed me too
-I would have if I'd known
-Here you go
-Be my guest
-Please
-Thanks
Bye
Hi Touba, how's my daughter?
Okay. Do you need anything?
Okay, bye
Where are you going?
-Where are you going?
-Wherever you decide
-What do you mean?
-You have your own place, right?
Get out
-Have some shame, get out
-He'll fall asleep
Get out
before I kick you out myself
Fine, my baby has a fever,
drop me off at the junction
Do you have any cigarettes?
-Where are you from?
-Why?
-Don't you have a brother to beat you?
-I've no brother, I'm not in the mood
-Pull over, I'll get out
-We had a girl in our neighbourhood
-Stop
-Since they moved to our area...
She got close to  my sister
Mahboubeh
My mother would braid their hair
Mahboubeh was jealous of Masoumeh
since she had thick hair
Her name was Masoumeh
-You didn't say where you're from?
-Pull over, I'll get out
Don't you need medicine for your son?
I was saying
They'd go to school together
Either Masoumeh was at ours
or Mahboubeh was at theirs
Masoumeh was such a nice girl
like yourself...
Unlike her junkie brother
Stop, I'll get out
Here, I don't have a lighter
When Masoumeh left
Mahboubeh got sick
She looked everywhere for her
Once she found her
but she went missing again
She hid something
at the back of her closet...
A long braided lock of hair...
That belonged to the girl
One night her stupid brother
picked on her for nothing
He hit her and cut her hair
Masoumeh left for good the next day
God!
Sit
-Hi
-I got so worried, why are you so late?
-I had a customer
-Did you have an accident?
-No, Touba
Ask Sarvenaz to come.
I'm tired, I want to go
She's asleep with an empty stomach
Let me take her, then
-Where's Mahboubeh?
-She stayed with her sister
-Did Hamideh argue with her husband again?
-No
Is there something wrong with Ali
that you're not telling me?
Well?
I'd do something if there was
I beg you, don't hide anything from me
I saw Masoumeh
Our Masoumeh? Zahra's daughter?
Yes
Where was she?
What was she doing?
What can I say?
Didn't you ask why she did this
to her poor mother?
She pretended she wasn't Masoumeh
You should've asked her for an address
so her mother could see her
It's better if she doesn't
Mothers should look for their kids
on the streets
-Here
-Thank you
You gave me the form.
You could've written my request too
Ask someone over there to do it for you
Who?
This is a staff announcement
Working hours are from 8:30 a.m.
till 15:30
Thank you for your cooperation
Hi
Could one of you please
write a letter for me?
Please, if you could
-What sort of letter?
-A request
I've written like ten now.
They say
you need to write one
to a circle, group,
an office or something
-Yes
-Sit down
What's your problem? Tell me
so I can tell you who to address
The company hasn't paid me
for nine months
I keep asking for help
but no one gets back to me
I got it
The Pensions' Support Allowance
To whom it may concern
Miss, your name is?
Were you official staff or a temp?
Can't we do an interview? I'm ready
and I'll get the license for it
I explained once, my documentary
is about problems regarding the clients
It has nothing to do with the staff
Turn on your camera, I'll connect it
-You know Mr Goudarzi
-Oh! I get it
Thanks for getting back to me so fast
I've been waiting for my turn all day
One moment, if you're not running late
we can have tea
No, I'm late, I was here to speak
to the clients, looks like I can't
Clients just moan and whinge
Everyone has problems
but the staff want to speak
People should find the solution
within themselves
Nice excuse, not my problem
Bye
Sir, will you please write
the rest of my letter, please?
I need something inside,
I'll be right back
Thanks
Okay
We'll get everything
Forget the watermelon,
I can't handle that
Why do I have two sons?
Send them
I've no car
It might be done by Saturday night,
I don't know
I don't know, bye
Look, sign these,
these have all been piled up
Who asked you to come in?
I was in the queue, I thought
It was my turn,
didn't you call my name?
What do you want?
This is the report
of what happened to me
I'm too busy to read all this.
You tell me
-Right, I'm Mohammad Javad Halimi
-Stand in your spot
-Is this good?
-Yes
Right, I'm Mohammad Javad Halimi
Retired office worker
How many hands do I have?
I worked for the government too
-I've been retired for 15 years now
-Sir
Yes
Is this the time for Bademjan?
No, how many hands do I have?
Fine, I'll be home for 4
Right, 3 months ago I faced a problem
I was sent to hospital
and had emergency surgery
Insurance covers my surgery
-I'll use a fingerprint
-Fine
But the problem is...
Because of the urgency, they sent me
to a hospital not covered by insurance
My surgery was performed
on a bank holiday
Therefore the case for insurance
was postponed to...
Hi, Jafar
What?
Jafar, I'm stuck Thursday, Friday
I'm busy
I need my car tomorrow,
thanks. Bye
-What do you need?
-I said
I'm covered by insurance,
I can't explain my problem
On the day of a holiday...
are you listening?
I got so sick
And the ambulance collected
my half dead body...
Went to a private hospital
I've had to pay from my own pocket
for the treatment
And I'm now in debt
When I applied for refunds, I was told
since I reported it a little late...
I was asked to go
for a second diagnosis
Sorry, but a check-up of
the same area...
-The private part I mentioned
-Speak clearly, sir
-Pick it up
-Just this one
I'll come to you, go
Go
Yes love, where were you
when I called?
The salon? Why there?
Blue black?
The type I liked?
I'll see you tomorrow
I love you
Okay
What a mess
-Are you leaving?
-Would you like to chat till the weekend?
Sir, I said what do you want?
Make it short
Sure, I'll put it in a telegram
I'm Halimi, retired,
three years and eight months experience
27 days ago, emergency surgery
Treatment payments, private debt
Loans from family and friends,
request for refund
Unethical request of organisation
for second diagnosis of special place
Oh, so it's the private area
-Get to the point, why take so long?
-What do you mean?
After 30 years of honest service,
do I have to pull my pants down
in front of strangers to prove my point?
Up to you, the laws are clear
-You should leave
-Where to?
I'm talking to you, sir
Should I stand here listening to reports
of your private areas?
I've been sat waiting here
the whole day
Now that it's my turn
you're leaving during working hours
What a mess
Send Nemat up
Who's there?
He's small, you can handle him yourself,
he's a nuisance
-Go on
-Watch your language, sir
I've not touched a penny
all these 30 years
Now I have to pull my pants down
and prove my point to people like you?
Let go, stop him, not me
-I have to come to a conclusion
-You'll pass out and get me in trouble
-I'll report you
-Don't make a fuss, sir
You think I don't know
what you're up to during work hours?
You're tending to your multiple wives
instead of doing your job
You're worried about blue black or chestnut hair?
How do you live with yourself?
I'll show you
-Stop it
-Where did they take him?
Stop the fuss
You have a camera
-Clear the tape
-We'll buy that
We're buying rope too
Just tie my hands tight
so I can't undo it
-It won't
-Then...
We need to hold a knife
-What if your husband comes home?
-Say hi if you see him
-What if he does?
-I said he's not been home for 2 months
-What if he decides to come?
-So what
-It's not his problem
-Really?
Tell me what else we need
Stop! They've no shame
This is the end, stop!
Is it him again?
-Yeah
-So he believed us
This means we've done a good job so far
How did he not recognise your voice?
We have your daughter.
You'll receive a video tonight
You'll send 30 million or you'll find
your daughter's dead body
He won't care
I got worried, how would he not care?
I callled him and said I'm not well,
I'm annoyed
-I want to leave this hell hole
-So he said safe trip
He said you decided to get married,
it's your own problem now
I said fine, I did get married
-Am I your daughter or not?
-Didn't he say he's forgotten about us?
He says it all the time to me
He's just afraid of losing his reputation
Kidnapped his daughter. I'm used to this
You're ruining my reputation, you don't understand
He's willing to pay 200 for his reputation
You remember how he embarrassed us last time
I'll break your legs, get out of this house
This isn't a cabaret
He deserves some druggie kids
He'd learn his lesson then
His entire problem is what to do
with his girlfriends
Not to lose them
He drove Mum away, now it's our turn
Why don't you visit Mum?
I don't feel well there
-It makes me sick how she's a pushover
-He's nice
-I swear, he's better than Dad
-Yeah
Poor Mum
You didn't tell Mum about
the mess you got into
What would I say?
You're right, what would you say?
-You're out of your mind, how are you a businessman?
-Here we go again
Look at me, you can't get yourself together
You write cheques now?
-"I've got to have money in two days"
-I was supposed to have it two months ago
Well done! Thanks
But if I could...
Bookselling, DVDs, music...
Cafe, Internet cafe...
Small movie screenings...
-Small bowls of soup
-You're mental
Get help from a doctor
People have no food on their table,
they're going bankrupt
Now you decide to start your own business
I was quite good though
We'l leave the video and tell you
where you can collect it
I did a good job
Our role here to help girls and women
who decide to quit
-Under the right circumstances
-Great
-Is it okay if I film it?
-If you've a license
-Hi
-Hi love, how are you, Kokab?
-If you've a license, sure
-Of course
Hi
You had a few phone calls
from the Sarallah Hospital doctor
A woman named Gilaneh
left a message
-God help me
-Dr Gabiri helps us voluntarily here
-Nice to meet you
-Good day
In the circumstances these women are under,
if their images are displayed
-They'll face problems
-Of course! I'm not here to make trouble
-I'm here to help
-Sorry
-Yes
-I'll call
Yes! I was waiting for your call
Help me, Doctor
Esmail is dying, Doctor
He's been unconscious since yesterday
I beg you to come here
The doctors here don't know him
You went to war together
Are they right saying he'll die?
What did you to yourself, son?
Are you okay, Doctor?
-Hi
-Come in
-Did I disturb you?
-No it's nothing
Sometimes I wish I'd lost my eyes
and ears instead of my arm
Why, Doctor?
-How are you?
-Good
-Are you on track?
-Yes
-Medication and tests
-Yeah
-Hi
-None for me, I'm leaving
-I'll send Samire in before you leave
-Okay
Don't forget to be at the hospital
on Monday at 7 for Dr Hosseini to see you
-Sure, thanks
-No problem
-Will you come here, Narges?
-Sure, I'm coming
Put out your cigarette,
Samira has missed you
-I thought she should come see you
-Sit down
I'll take the girls to the hospital. Bye
What's wrong?
-Pass it here
-Can you do it?
-Of course I can
-Kobra, you have a bad back
Move them into the storage
Why didn't you take the shopping down, Kobra?
Sara Hamed is waiting for you
Miss Monshi Zadeh,
I've got to go to Sarallah
I've written Samira's prescription,
she needs a painkiller
-She's not feeling well
-Thanks
-Hi
-I can give you a lift
-Thanks
-Your change
No we owe you money for some of the work
Keep the receipts, this is Kokab
and her daughter's results
-I almost die every time I open these
-I know
Take me outside Samira's dad's shop
when you come back
I have a student at 6
Can I come tomorrow?
-I'll go
-Sorry
-I just need the address
-Sure
We're going out, Maryam,
put out your cigarette
Pull your scarf forward.
Don't be noisy
-They stink of cigarettes
-Bye
-I told the hospital
-Hi Hamed
Come on guys, Hamed's time is valuable,
not like us
Sara, you have to use sarcasm
I didn't even say anything
Yes
-Ask Narges to come
-Who?
-Which Narges?
-Safarkhani, ask her to come
-You are?
Her husband asked her to come
Wait here
-Don't shut the door
-I'll open it again, wait here
Wait
-Is he right?
-How did he find her?
-He didn't know you worked here?
-He's made her life a misery
-Let her talk
-Sorry I didn't mention it
I ran away three months ago.
Didn't tell my kids, either
She slept at the mosque.
I felt sorry for her, brought her here
I've taken him to rehab multiple times
He beats me up in front of my son-in-laws
He won't leave
-He remembered he has a wife now
-Fine, stop the drama
Leave this in my room and bring the shopping down
-Shut the door, don't let the girls out
-See what he does?
-This is my life
-Fine
-Let's talk see what he wants
-He says he's sorry, come back
He'll beat me up if I say no
It's not his first time
The father of my kids died so I married him
Talk to him, he might calm down
-I'll kill myself if he tries to take me
-Don't say that, Narges
He'll annoy the neighbours
Get lost
What are you watching?
Get inside and shut the door
Why do you make trouble?
Why is she here? What is this place?
-I'll explain
-There is nothing, she abandoned me
I want to see what her problem is
I'm going in
-You can't come in
-What's this place?
-What is it?
-Sir, wait
You can't, don't!
-Ask her to come out
-Listen
-You can file a complaint
-I will
-I'll show you all
-Good
You're hiding my wife
-Don't hit yourself
-Why do you hide my wife?
Just calm down a second
-I'll go see what I can do
-Go
-I'll ask her to come out
Sit here, sit down
He's lost it because of the drugs,
he's hallucinating
He'll kill me some day
-No one listens to me
-I do
I won't let him take you
Listen
I won't put up with him
You're helping us here, I'm saying
I might be able to convince him to go to rehab
-He might get better
-Get better?
-You don't know my problems
-Don't cry
-Don't cry, darling
-I lied
-What?
-I lied about the explosion
And I was burnt
He burnt me with boiling water
He burnt me
-He swore if I didn't go take him to court, he'd stop
-Get out!
I got out of hospital and went to the rehab centre
They said he only lasted three days.
What is it?
Get out
-Why did you abandon me?
-Kill me
-Why did you leave?
-What do you want?
-I swear I'll beat you up
-Do it
-Move!
You think being a man is holding a knife?
Have you no morals?
See what you've done to her?
Here, look
Is this how you repay her
for not taking you to court?
You think you can do whatever you want
because you're her husband?
Go inside, Narges
Go inside
I swear I'm sorry, Narges
I've no one, Narges
Narges, I lost it
I swear, I got angry
I don't know what got into me, Narges
I'm sorry, Narges
Come back, Narges, please
I've no one else
Yes
I understand, yes
I'm fine with it if you're okay
I'll try to pay the loan till the end of the week
Yes, you're welcome. Bye
Right here it says your husband
has his own business
-Why do you need a loan?
-To pay for my daughter's baby shower
What's happened to your face?
-It was burnt
-What?
It burnt in an explosion
Okay, it has to be confirmed
-Come see Miss Rasouli next week
-I work
-Miss Monshizadeh is my guarantor
-She's a real lady
I hope they agree
-Thanks
-You're welcome
Yes ma'am
She pushed in while you were on the phone
Told her story
I've come all the way here
and have to get back now
To go ask for our wages
with some other miserable souls like myself
God help you with that
You might be able to help
-What can we do for you here?
-My son was arrested
They say for him to be bailed out
we need to pay
I've nothing to my name
or any rich relatives
-Help me
-What is his crime?
He's not a criminal, ma'am
-He's attended demonstrations
-He's being punished
-You should've stopped it
-He's done nothing wrong
He's not murdered anyone or stolen anything
I'm not the judge and we can't help you
Please help someone like me
Someone like me who doesn't own anything
has to lose her son?
Yes?
I checked the dates
Miss Rasouli, get her a glass of water, please
Yes sure
I wish you'd called earlier.
You're welcome
Hi
-Isn't there anyone else left?
-Whoever was supposed to be here, is here now
We can go, pray for the driver
Wait, sir, Touba
Come
Come, Touba
Don't rush her, she'll get run over
Touba
Excuse me! Move back a little, please
Thanks
-Hi Touba
-Hi
-Hi Touba, why were you late?
Hi
Hope we get what we came for
If you go through the motorway
we won't be stuck in traffic
There's no difference
-Give me some water
-Let me give Touba some water first
Once we get there and get out of the van
You stand in a corner if anyone asks
No one answer, got it?
We'll wait for our elder to speak.
That's Touba
Ali is good too, he reads the papers
He cries well too
Mehdi, don't get mad
-You'll get us into trouble
-Fine
I just mean don't say anything
so they have an excuse
-Got it?
-Nothing changed
A letter means nothing to a worker
The worker, the boss
-Talk
-We've been hiding
-Don't be nervous
-Don't interrupt him
I'm nervous because of the camera
I wanted to say I've been hiding
in the house like a thief
-I'm afraid of them finding me
-You know what?
They sold the company three months ago
and told no one about it
The new owner wants to demolish it
The owner changed three times.
Every time they fire the workers
Our boss says there's Chinese importation
I can't help it, control the borders
-Why should the worker pay for the loss?
-You did this last time
We need to take the legal route
We're not doing anything illegal right now
Here you go, director
-Will you put this on TV?
-I don't work for the TV
I had a job
My wife pays the expenses now
I need the money
I've not paid rent in four months.
What should I do?
Who should I ask for money?
He'll kick me out
Look at my hands, these are working hands
I swear I've worked hard
to earn my money all these years
But I can't put food on the table
Look sir, we sent letters
to all the different organisations
Who'll pay us? When?
We worked 17 years
and this is our life now
-What do we do now?
-You tell him, Touba, you can talk
-What can she say?
-Haven't they filmed us before?
It might work this time
-Touba, tell him please
-I will
Those in charge, ladies, gentlemen
Whoever, wherever you are,
I beg you to come see how we live
We were in debt when we had a job
Now that the company is shut down, it's worse
Some have to pay for the in-laws
and grandchildren
He just got married recently
He got this job with hopes and dreams
We're under so much debt, what else do I say?
We're careful not to get into trouble
We're paid 40 tomans every month.
Our own money
Thanks, but the prices have gone up like crazy
Water, electricity
If we'd told anyone else
they'd feel sorry for us by now
-That's why I'm saying don't talk
-Let her talk
-You know better than her?
-They arrested my son a year ago
I don't own a house or a piece of land
I will, I'l say it all
I worked hard and paid for his uni.
Now he's unemployed
He's willing to do any job available
They ask him for contacts
Don't make it political, please
I'm talking about my son.
how is that about politics?
-I'm sorry
-They say he has to have different memberships
Thank god he's not into drugs
You can see on the streets
how many innocent teenagers are into drugs
They use school kids to transport heroin
They always say it'll be fine, it won't
How will we survive?
I'm wandering around on the streets
for my son
I'm sure we'll all get into trouble for this
Who will you show these videos to?
Who'll see it?
Suppose they do see it
Where are you? What?
Why did you get back?
What?
-Why did they close the street off?
-Wait
We're on our way. Bye
He says they sent the buses back
and closed off the street
-Let's get back
-Why? Where?
-You shouldn't have come
-Should I turn back?
Keep going, you get paid to go
-He's right too
-You're scared of their bluffs?
We're so small we can't even defend ourselves now
You can go back if you want, I'll go stand there
until someone asks me why
Don't make a fuss
Don't get me into trouble, please
Don't say anything
Hi
Sure we'll move
Sure I'll go
-Hi good day
-Don't stop, move
Hi, good day
-He drove us here, we'll get off and he'll go back
-No
-You can't stand here
-We want to talk
Your representative can come talk later
Mo one gets off the bus
No one will see the rep.
Open the door
Ma'am, you're the wise one,
ask them to get back
You take responsibility for their families
and I'll send them back
-Open the door
Stop it, ma'am
Leave
I want to know who can stop me
-Let him drive you back, don't cause trouble
-What trouble?
Don't you believe in God?
We're workers here
-We're here for our money
-Once I arrest you, you'll see
Why do you say that?
We're talking
Open the door, where are you taking him?
You have to take me too
You're the worst one
I don't care, open the door
Where are you taking him?
Camera!
Get the camera man out
-Dad, a man wants to see Mum
-What?
Who is it? It's not the landlord, is it?
No, it's a classy man
Hi
-Hi
-I want to see Mrs Nobar Kordani
-I have to give her a letter
-What for?
A letter from Mr Rasoul Rahmani
I'm her husband
-What's the letter for?
-I'm Mr Rahmani's lawyer, it's about your wife
Do you understand? I'm her husband,
shouldn't I know what the letter is?
I didn't say you shouldn't,
I said I have to hand it to her
Nobar isn't home
-How dare he send letters for a married woman
-Sir don't get angry
I must make sure Mrs Nobar Kordani gets this
You're her husband, you give it to her
Here's my card
-Bye
-You forgot this
-What
-This
-Didn't I say not to touch it?
-Sorry
-Go away
Why did you leave the door open? Hi
Mum, come here
Dad is angry
Go do your homework
What's wrong?
Send the kid to Senobar
-What for?
-Farhad, go to your aunt's
He needs to do his homework
What's wrong?
Is this how you treat me?
-What do you mean?
-Was I a bad husband to you?
No
How long have you been
sending letters back and forth?
-To who?
What's the letter?
Was I wrong to have married you
after 8 years?
Look Reza, don't bring this subject up again
Tell me what's wrong, Reza
You were always unfaithful to me
I refused to see it
Did I break up with you?
Everyone made fun of me saying "Of course
she'd pick the rich old man over you"
-"Not you, who's a worker"
-To hell with them all
Would they support me and my siblings?
He lied to you
You've been looking down at me
since the day I arrived
-Was I wrong?
-Did I ask you to marry me?
-You decided
-God saved your dead wife
-Shut up
-Haj Rasoul's temporary wife
-I was
Now I'm your wife and the mother of your kids,
don't talk to me like that
It's fine for you to send letters
to your ex-husband
I swear I've no idea
whether the old man is dead or alive
What's this, then?
I don't know what it is
You don't? I felt sorry for you
when I married you
They used to say the old man
enjoyed his time with her
Once he had a stroke, his daughters kicked her out
and took their father abroad
-Read it, I want to know what it is
I don't know what it is
Do whatever you want
Don't do this, Reza
Why do you do this?
I'd never have to live under your roof
if I were lucky
-You're mental
-Yes, I am
Read it
I swear I'll kill you if you miss anything
-Dear Nobar
-God help me
"Dear Nobar"
I have to sit here hear love letters
someone else sent to my wife
Read!
I hope you're well
I know that
You've married a decent man
And you're living in peace
You've told him everything, right?
-Reza, I swear I didn't know
-Shut up
Just read it
I heard about your mother's death
in prison
God tests his favourite beings in this world
You were the most special angel
Angel! Look what he's calling you
Read!
My daughters tried to do me a favour
But they never knew
Happiness isn't something
people would see from the outside
Happiness is in people's hearts
No one ever knew that
Other than you
Let me go, I don't want my kids to hear
You'd never do this
if you cared about the kids
I didn't write to him
You probably thought I'm a miserable worker
He owns nothing in this world
If you knew me
You could tell I had no idea about him
Did your teacher give you
good comments on your work?
-Are you okay?
-Yes love
I'm fine, darling
My lady
Shirin has fallen out with you
Come here
Can you read this to me?
Don't read the first part
-The handwriting is bad
-You can read it
-Happiness is in the heart
-Not there, further on
By the time you get this letter
I may no longer be alive
I ask of you, Nobar,
to forgive me
No one other than me believes
-That... what's this?
-Read the rest
You've never cared about money
But let me
do this to die in peace
This is the smallest thing I wish for
A small house for you
I hope you accept this final request of mine
From someone who always prays
for your new life with your family
Spring 2012
In a place in this world that is not my home
We get a few a week like them
Why would a beautiful woman like yourself
want to commit suicide?
-You've a long life ahead of you
-Where's Sara?
-She'll come
-You'll be a bride
A mother, go up
Give her a lot of liquids
-You'll feel dizzy a few days too
-Thanks, ma'am
You're welcome
-Thank you
-Put it back in your purse, ma'am
Look after your friend
My mother had the same problem
She died in the same way
-Take care
-God rest her soul
Shall we go?
Sorry for the wait
Did I say something wrong?
You didn't have to, I can see for myself
-Miss Arshad called and said
-Miss Arshad is off
-Miss Monshizadeh, I meant
-I talked to her
-Do you want to lay down?
-No
I don't want any
Will it be okay if I don't talk?
-Since you're tired
-I'm not tired
-You're tired and agitated
-I'm neither
Talk if you want, but...
-Don't make fun of people
-When did I make fun of you?
-I was saying
-Don't read a book, Hamed, talk
It's good for you
-Don't pick on the way I talk
-Now you're talking
-You made me forget what I was saying
-You're not a lecturer of literature
-You were supposed to be a mechanical engineer
-Isn't that making fun of me?
-You're not?
-You never became one, did you?
No I didn't, you're right
I'm a taxi driver
-Are you in pain?
-I want to go to bed
I have a horrible headache
-Do you have any water?
-I gave it to you
Water, I need water, Hamed
-I'll stop and get some
-No need
There was a bottle under this seat
Let me see, sorry
If it has any water
I say
We're two people talking
There's no manifesto here
-You should let me speak, then
-Go on
-I said you're acting like an angel
-Oh man
You say let's talk, then use sarcasm
You call me Mother Teresa
I swear, sorry I shouldn't have
used the word angel
-My point is, travel from this side of town to the other
-What's the problem?
-It's very good
-Thanks, right
I told you, you're stressed
Look at your face right now
Do you know what this is about, Hamed?
-You think since you've stood by a great cause
-What great cause
You were a student at the best university
You said something and stood by it
-You were expelled
-When did I ever mention that?
The entire centre knows
-Then don't say not to use sarcasm
-Sorry
Since you've made a statement
You can't think no one else
does anything important
-No one else can do anything good
-It's not a competition
With the energy and time you invest
you can do something bigger
-You can do something more important
-It's all a manifesto
-Why?
-It is
-Why do you act like I'm talking nonsense
-You're not, but...
-You say beautiful sentences
-Is that a problem?
You tell me what I need to do for them so I can do it
It's very simple, I define help in a different way
I say think of a situation
where so many like Samira wouldn't be homeless
How many of them overdose a day?
Commit suicide and die?
-No one even notices
-We can't do the big thing, so we don't help her either
-I didn't say that
-You did
No I didn't
Hamed, let me just do my own thing
-Who's saying the beautiful stuff now?
-I am
You do the important stuff
If I do all this
-I do it for myself
-Fine!
One minute, let me ask this
-It makes you happy?
-Yes
-Do it, then
-Fine
I'm saying don't forget about yourself
-I'm not saying anything bad
-No, but it seems like it
-What can you see?
-The way you talk
-I need to smoke
Can I have your lighter?
You smoke a lot
We smoked once on our way here
and on the way back
Sorry for all the smoke and the blood in your car
Do it but don't attack me
Why don't you do something
related to your degree?
What's with the taxi?
Very good suggestion!
I wonder how I never thought of it myself
You talk like you don't live here
What job?
You studied for three years,
do something with that
Why do you think I've made a promise to myself?
Forget education, work as a taxi driver
or private tuition
Work at the centre once in a while
-To pay for my family
-But you like this educated taxi driver phase too
Why do you say that?
Don't say that
You've always lived the way you'd wished
Me and so many others lived the way we had to
The way I decided to live wasn't an easy way
I went wrong and I have to pay for it
Never said it was easy,
that's why you don't look like you should
What should I look like for it to suit me?
-I didn't say it had to be a certain way
-Actually you do
You think this is a strange place,
you're different, I've been here
-You could be too
-Thank god, I didn't
-You're so happy you weren't
-Should I be upset?
You've no image of being in rehab
-But I can understand
-What can you understand?
How can you?
I'm not saying I'm big because I quit.
They're doing a bigger thing
Everyone knows...
What an important thing you've done
You must've had a strong will
and not everyone can do it
Definitely not, there are many who want to quit
but can't because they don't have the support
That's my point, the support
Give me the chance to speak
Hamed, when I did this to myself
I had the luck of my mum being there
Took me to different clinics
and doctors till I quit
-Fine
-Sorry for the support I had
Since I had the support
I shouldn't help those who don't
Who said not to?
-The value for...
-Value! Hamed, what are you saying?
Value for what? Stop defining the values
My value is in quitting
You don't give me the chance to speak
We're there
"I quit, I quit" didn't you quit
to get back to normal life?
Live it, then
You keep talking about it
then tell me I give out manifestos
You're not willing to look around you
I think you haven't quit yet
You're still in rehab
-How can someone abandon herself like that?
-What's your point, Hamed?
-I am
-Say the main thing, we're almost there
-I am, I said
-Do you like me?
-Excuse me?
-What a question
-It's not odd, it's a yes or no. Do you like me?
-Don't be afraid, answer
-Why afraid?
If you can even say things like that
to someone like Sara
-You ask the question then answer it yourself
-You're right, go on
-Go on
-Fine, give me a moment
It's not an interrogation
Look, I don't know, maybe
-I was thinking
-If you have to think, then it's clear
Did you hear me tell her I like her?
You didn't say you didn't
-I didn't talk
-You don't talk, I made you say what you did
Sometimes in life we need answers...
that make things clear
Have you ever experienced this sort of thing?
It's clear to me
Suppose I'm in that position
You have to ask questions if you need answers
-I'll ask
-Ask
-What about you?
-What about me?
-I asked
-What about you isn't a question
I'm asking, have you ever thought of me?
No
-No means you've not thought of me
-No
You don't like me
No
Is it done?
I don't know, is it?
Done
-Look, it can't
-Look, Hamed
I dragged the conversation here
so you'd answer and I'd say this
and it'd all be clear to you
Thanks for making it all clear to me at once
-But I have questions
-I don't want to talk anymore
-I don't want to talk
-You have to, I have a question
The no you said, am I the problem?
-Or are you?
-What difference does it make?
It makes a difference, answer my question
If the problem is me, then I have nothing to say
Suppose I'm the problem
If you're the problem
-It's fine
-What is?
You think I've not thought about it?
To see whether it's possible...
If I can or not
Whether it's possible for us
I know
What do you know?
Sara, should I know more than
you can
You can tend to Samira's wounds
Who's a HIV positive patient without gloves?
Is it fine?
Yeah, no, that's over for now
They gave me the camera back.
No, it's fine
I'm used to it
Of course I'm still working
Listen
No movie has ever stayed hidden
It's screened somewhere somehow,
whether we're there or not
Yeah I know, I understand