February 9th, 1995
Seventh anniversary of
the death of Osamu Tezuka.
I started visiting him,
when I was only 15 years old.
It has been approximately 34 years.
It's a great honour for me
to have lived
the same age as Mr. Tezuka.
Mr. Tezuka traversed the Showa era
at lightning speed.
I regret that he didn't have longer
to work on his creation.
He's gone too soon.
Time absorbs all men
without distinction,
whether great or ordinary.
I felt it sorely.
The world of Manga is very empty
without Mr. Tezuka.
Haunted by memories of the past,
I could not stand it
and left the ceremony
before it was over.
I felt so tired.
The days of my youth
devoted to the passionate pursuit
of my dream of Gekiga
I miss sorely.
Three years after the end of war,
the sound of hammers echoed again
and Osaka finally seemed
to come back to life.
But for us ordinary people,
the lack of food was
a day-to-day routine.
I was born in Osaka,
in 1935.
At the end of the Second World War,
I was only 10 years old.
August 6th, 1971
Peace Park in Hiroshima
Get lost, Minister Satô!
Calm down!
Get off me!
It was raining that day.
A black rain ...
for 26 years,
black rain continues
to fall on my heart,
never letting me rest.
In 1945
August 6th
at 8:00 am,
an atomic bomb exploded
480 meters over Hiroshima
instantly turning the world into hell.
Appointed by the press service
of the Department of War
I was immediately sent to Hiroshima.
A black rain ...
Gloomy ...
The passengers were sitting quietly,
in the burned out tram.
As I got closer,
I realised they were burnt on site.
The powerful radiation of the bomb
had printed a human shadow
on the steps of a bank.
The shadow of a spiral staircase
engraved forever ...
I pressed the trigger
like one possessed.
I walked through the debris
to reach an alley where
a burned out house stood.
I discovered a sight so upsetting,
that I immediately
burst into tears.
On a wall,
two human shadows were printed clearly.
Probably a mother and her son?
The devoted son was massaging
his mother when the bomb
surprised them.
Sobbing,
I pressed the shutter button.
My eyes filled with tears,
I was blinded.
Does God not exist?
How can such things happen?
Not stopping to cry, I helped to carry
victims to a health centre.
I was completely numb when
I returned to the department.
Looking at the prints that night,
I burst into tears again.
Three days later, I returned to
the location of the photograph.
The wall on which the
shadows were printed
had disappeared.
Excuse me ...
Do you know who lived here?
It was the house of the Yamadas.
They lived here in pairs,
a mother and her son.
They were found burned, both.
My hunch was right ...
a devoted son massaging his mother.
Despite the smell of dozens
of thousands of corpses
burning all around,
the sight of the sunset
was incredibly beautiful.
Then the war ended.
Japan barely recovered,
signed the Treaty of Peace
in September 1951.
Journal Sanyô Maiasa
This photograph is exceptional.
It could move all of Japan ...
Who knows, even the world?
I'd like to sell it to you.
For over 6 years I kept it
without showing anyone.
Today, I need money.
Thanks to the treaty, we can finally
publish pictures of the bomb.
We offer you a good price.
The money I got for the photo
allowed me to feed my family
despite my unemployment.
But I was tortured
by the voice of my conscience.
Mom ... let me massage you!
What's gotten into you?
You're soaked in sweat!
A bad dream ...
A devoted son and his mother!
The moving shadows of the Yamadas
The photograph upset all of Japan.
The Maiasa published a series of
articles on the sacrificed mother and son.
The faces of the son Kiyoshi and his
mother Mado are finally revealed
Let's raise a fund to build
a statue in their memory.
Their image must live forever!
Poems and movies dedicated
to the devoted son
Another article calling you
a great photographer!
With the impact of my photography,
my guilt faded.
I even developed a secret pride.
Fantastic, right?
A famous sculptor created this statue.
The Maiasa decided to send him abroad
to represent our campaign
No More Hiroshima worldwide.
Mr. Koyanagi, take the lead
of our movement!
Me travelling the world?
I'll do my best.
I carry with me the memory
of the 200,000 victims of the bomb.
I'll spread No More Hiroshima
in the world!
We count on you, Mr. Koyanagi!
Every day, when the
limousine of the journal
came to pick me up with its flag,
I was carried in pride.
Rest in peace
Our mistakes will not be repeated
You are Mr. Koyanagi?
So you're the one who invited me here.
I'm in a hurry, tell me what you want.
Will you attend the inauguration
ceremony of the statue?
You became famous!
With nothing but a miserable picture.
What a charade.
The photo of a devoted son?
Takes a lot of nerve to pass a murder
for a simple massage.
What do you say?
That it was the image of a murder.
He was going to strangle her
when the bomb exploded.
What?
I have proof!
Who are you?
You're crazy!
Tell me who you are!
Don't you recognise this face?
Remember. I was in the newspaper!
I'm Kiyoshi Yamada.
The devoted son of the statue!
What are you talking about?
The mother and her son
were dead on the spot.
They were found burned!
They are on the list of victims.
There has been two deaths ...
but the boy was one of my friends.
I asked him to kill my mother.
On the day of the bomb,
I was mobilised in Kure
in a weapons factory.
My friend had to take care of
my mother during this time.
The bomb was dropped that morning.
I quickly returned to Hiroshima.
I saw the printed image,
the murder that I commissioned.
I rushed to tear down the wall.
The wall ...
It's true that it has been collapsed.
Yes,
it was I who destroyed it.
I thought I had cleared
all the evidence ...
But then your statue
and all the fuss.
That I didn't expect!
What do you think?
You have before you the devoted son
that makes people cry in their cottages!
Why kill your mother?
I wanted money ...
Sell the house ...
Money for my pleasure.
I had enough of labouring like a maniac.
But everything is screwed.
Now, here I'm deprived of identity,
forced to live hidden like a rat.
I can not believe it.
It's impossible.
This statue, would it be
the symbol of matricide?
NO MORE HIROSHIMA
Inauguration Ceremony
These two children,
bomb survivors,
will unveil the statue.
Are you okay, Mr. Koyanagi?
Call a doctor!
How is he, doctor?
Just a little anaemic.
He will be released soon.
A statue in honour of murder ...
I want money.
I want to have my share
of the funds collected.
I'm sick.
My lungs ...
In return, I'll keep the secret.
You'd be annoyed if
it came out now, right?
I count on you, Koyanagi.
I expect the money.
Is he okay?
He regained consciousness.
Thank you, Mr. Koyanagi.
Thanks to you, the pain of
the victims of the bomb
is known throughout the world.
Hold on!
Can I shake your hand?
One bomb was enough to
make more than 200,000 deaths.
More than 200,000!
One more ...
One more person added these 200,000 ...
It will not change anything.
Sorry for the delay, Koyanagi.
On this day ...
victims of the bomb came
here to find water.
A final walk.
Countless corpses floated here.
We still find bones.
You got the money?
I'll not give it to you, forget it.
This is donation money.
In this case,
I'll reveal the truth about the statue.
I don't have much longer.
I have nothing to lose.
Everyone will be disappointed, Koyanagi.
Your reputation will suffer.
Body recovered from the Motoyasu river
The statue?
The campaign has been canceled
by the management.
Apparently,
the son in question is still alive.
We have seen better as a devoted son.
He came to seek compensation
from the newspaper
yesterday during the day.
According to our survey, he does
appear in the records of deaths,
but it's him.
I saw hell
trapped in my own heart.
And for 20 years
I lived as if I was endlessly
travelling hell.
The penalty for this murder
is barred.
And yet ...
I can not find the courage
to confess my crime.
Lost in the crowd
gathered for the 25th Memorial of Peace,
I live alone
in the middle of hell.
Rest in peace
Our mistakes will not be repeated
After the war, the paper shortage
gives birth to rental libraries
lending 3 books for 5 Yen.
I was 12 when I started drawing Manga,
influenced by Yoshioki,
my elder brother,
two years older than me.
I worked diligently every
day on a long strip.
We named Yoshioki Okichan.
He had been admitted
to Toneyama hospital,
but our limited resources
had forced him to return,
aborting his treatment.
Because he could no longer go to school,
his attitude towards me
suddenly changed.
When I went out in the morning,
his gaze hardened,
and his eyes
seemed to me full of jealousy
and anger against me.
Sometimes he found an excuse
to hit me for no reason.
These days, I went to school
weeping bitterly.
It took me 40 minutes
of walking every day
to get to the College of Toyonaka 2.
We were six in the family,
but my father was rarely seen.
I'm hungry.
Wait for Dad before starting dinner.
No, start without him.
We will not wait for a guy that
you cannot be sure to return at all.
Mom ignores Dad completely
when he returns.
They are quarrelling.
Divorced under the same roof.
Divorced?
I'm exhausted!
Let me sleep.
Ahead, I'll send manuscripts everywhere!
Nothing can stop me!
Like being possessed,
I drew Manga every night,
that I sent to the magazines.
From 1949 on
new magazines
Manga for children
saw the day, one after the other.
BOOKS AND MANGA
I'm in!
My first publication.
The Korean War breaks in June 1950,
and Japan takes on the role
as a strategic base for the U.S. Army.
The revival of demand
allows the country to
rebuild its economy.
Excuse me, can you repeat that?
Yes, the Mainichi Newspaper.
Yoshihiro, it's incredible!
It was in 1950,
during the summer holidays.
A reporter from the Osaka Mainichi
paid us an unexpected visit.
Get changed quickly.
The gentleman of the
Mainichi is waiting.
Yes, but what does he want?
He writes an article about
the young geniuses of Manga.
A genius? Who?
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
This is Yoshihiro.
I'm delighted.
So it was you?
Thank you for the great
Manga you send to us.
This is me ...
In fact, I came today because
I'd like you to introduce
yourself to our readers.
Mainichi Journal
Relax yourself a little and smile!
Who is your favourite artist?
There is an author I adore
at the moment.
Who?
Osamu Tezuka!
I read all his Manga.
Would you like to meet him?
Unbelievable!
I'll meet Tezuka in person!
What a stately home!
This is where he lives.
I realised that up to this point
I had only drawn in order
to meet Mr. Tezuka.
Under my amazed eyes,
the feet, the hands,
the characters of Mr. Tezuka
came to life.
I still hold dear
this unforgettable memory.
This is the happiest day of my life.
Thank you.
You should attempt at long series.
I returned to the
silent house of Tezuka,
crept over by an unreal feeling.
I had the chance
to return several times,
but his huge amount of work
finally led Mr. Tezuka to Tokyo
for that he left Osaka.
I then realised that my mentor
was now far and out of reach.
Tokyo had kidnapped him.
I thought of nothing else,
but going there.
Habit is a horrible thing.
For me, always working
in the centre of noise,
silence seems to be the
most sinister of all there is.
When you have no intention to speak
any conversation seems pointless.
Machinery noise dominates,
and men each live in their own corner.
Men are more numerous,
the connections between them are fading
and their loneliness deepens.
Izumi Residence
My Castle of 9 square meters ...
It's only when I'm alone
when I finally feel less lonely.
My companion, Monkey.
For whatever reason,
he never dares to face me.
My girlfriend is next to me in my bed,
and my records
invigorate my manhood.
Here, the Vietnam War,
Okinawa, the disease of Minamata,
crossing the Pacific in a yacht
all these events seem unreal.
Suffice to say that the only
time I finally feel human
is when I'm with my monkey.
BLAM !
Do not push! The door will release!
Fuck!
While we suffocate,
these cows travel like princesses.
That morning, I was thrown
out by the masses,
forced to descend during the journey.
I had not been back to Ueno
since my arrival from the
countryside five years before.
Naturally I set myself
in motion, nostalgic.
It was 5 years ago
I arrived at Ueno my chest
swollen with aspiration.
I no longer had the strength to
commit myself to the factory work.
The zoo was less
frequented that morning
and it was as if
the animals observed the humans.
What do they have?
Looks like you are affecting them!
It was really funny.
The monkeys seemed troubled
by your presence.
This has encouraged me
to get to know you better.
Could we meet again?
I'm just a working man.
It does not matter.
Please.
My name is Reiko.
Call me when you are free.
Good-bye.
You've spent the day smiling.
Good news?
A girl?
I doubt it, but in any case, beware.
♫ ... soldiers on the way! ♫
♫ March together ♫
♫ Assemble ... ♫
Denouncement Request
Denouncement
Stop! Stop the machines!
The 3 Million Yen Dog
Boss.
Yoshida. You look good.
Here's your allowance. 300,000 Yen.
The company is in trouble.
Your carelessness will cost us dearly.
But don't worry too much. Rest well.
I forgot ...
Your denouncement has been accepted.
I missed you!
I knew you'd come.
Thank you for having called.
I'm a hostess here.
I'll make you a treatment.
You have money, right?
It's said that the workers
make a good living.
The Otowa plant is hiring:
10 men, 3 women
Difficult with this disability ...
Hiring employees, urgent
Looking for graduates, good pay
It's time to say goodbye, Monkey.
I can not keep you.
Forgive me, Monkey.
What are you afraid of?
They are like you.
Go with your new friends.
Stop it!
Monkey!
September 8th, 1951
Minister Shigeru Yoshida
signs the Treaty of Peace
in San Francisco.
Japan makes its first step
towards an independent country.
Pawnshop
Mom ...
My father didn't really took the effort
to support us.
If only ...
I had some money ...
This is too little.
I have to take a chance
with the short-time work tests.
We were poor
and I multiplied the shipments
hoping to win a prize.
Dad. Here I am ...
You're home very late,
aren't you?
A little ...
You have got mail.
Two registered mails and a letter.
Is this a prize?
A new 500 Yen note?
They have just been issued!
This is the first one I see.
You should not make yourself
so much trouble, Yoshihiro.
Thank you, that's nice.
Here I'm!
What happened to you, Mom?
Yoshihiro.
Forgive him.
I beg you. Do not be too hard.
What has he done?
Okichan had no chance.
He returned from the hospital
and he suddenly began
to tear up your plates.
He is desperate.
You have to understand.
My plates!
Why?
Bastard!
Stop, Yoshihiro, forgive him.
Yoshihiro!
I give up.
Never again ...
I'll never draw any more Manga!
My sadness passed over time.
Should I really give up
the fragile dream of
becoming an artist?
In 1954, I finally
published my first album
entitled Children's Island.
That's it! It's out!
Unbelievable!
I was intoxicated with the
sweet smell of fresh ink
emanating from the new book.
I often wondered
why I need drawing so much.
Of course, it was primarily a means
of earning a living,
but I knew that it wasn't the
only reason that pushed me
towards Manga.
At age 19, without a solid
guarantee for the future,
the only thing giving me the
energy to move forward
were my journeys into my imagination.
My daily life
was far from easy,
but I was still inhabited by
a feeling of abundance.
In 1956,
the post-war economic restrictions
draw to a close
and Japan quickly moves to its
period of large growth.
THE SPARROW INN
During the summer of 1956,
I moved into a small apartment
with three illustrators of the Hinomaru Edition
to work together on the
magazine Shadows.
It was a small room located
in the area of Tennôji, Osaka.
This is unbearable!
What a heat!
We are dying!
And if we are going to see a movie?
They play The Lady and the Tramp.
And the job?
We can complete it tonight,
as it's best.
You're right!
I could have fun all night
without hindrance,
with no one to stop me.
It was a sweet life and full
of aspiration, new to me.
The cinema is my mentor.
THE SPARROW INN
Of course, the young owner there
also prevented me from concentrating.
Look who's here!
Could you make me something to eat?
It's rare to see you alone.
Saichan has a date
and Macchan went to see his parents.
His parents?
The celibacy must pressure him.
A grill, would that suit you?
Perfect!
I want a drink.
Can I sit down?
Of course!
Is it good?
Can I have one?
Once this is done.
I want this one.
The sausage that you are chewing on.
Hurry!
But I've chewed it already ...
That is the one I want.
Give it to me.
Come on ...
Chirp!
I'm not a bird.
Me, I'm your little sparrow.
Make me eat.
The attitude of the owner
was no doubt a way of
expressing her affection,
this was my first experience
with a woman.
Within a month,
he'll be marked as senior and
will be buried by the company.
He could not bear the idea
of a boring retirement
accompanied by his old wife.
Section Manager
Already, nobody put any
papers on his desk anymore.
No employee spoke to him anymore
or called him director.
All the work was divided
between his successors
and everyone completely ignored him.
In brief, Saburô Hanayama
might as well not exist anymore.
Director.
Thank you for your dedication,
Miss Okawa.
Director?
You are very kind today.
He was touched.
Had he been a little younger,
and if she wanted,
he could love her
at the peril of his life.
If only I could sleep
with her just once,
I could die without regrets.
No, no.
I should not have these thoughts
on a woman so sweet and pure.
Miss Okawa,
forgive me.
Bank
Mr. Hanayama!
300,000 Yen.
The money I secretly saved.
I'll spend it during
my remaining months.
It should be 5 million.
Surely more.
Like so ... You're home.
We have not heard you.
Good evening!
You still calculate my retirement?
Do you never get tired?
This will be our only income
once you're retired.
Yes. And us too, we are counting on it.
His wife had never
cared about him.
This malevolent woman had
humiliated him for 30 years
gradually, never resigning
from her arrogance.
His only daughter
thought only of herself.
Her mother had arranged her marriage,
and Hanayama knew that his wife
had carnal relations
with her young son-in-law.
You're going to take a bath
or do you want dinner?
I'll take a bath.
He had not slept with his wife
for over 10 years.
Suddenly bottomless anger
filled his heart.
This is hell.
I'll never spend the rest
of my life cloistered
with such a monster!
Yasukuni Band of Brothers ...
You left at the right time.
Look at me.
My company abandoned me
and my wife has betrayed me.
I'm a walking corpse.
The gun enthroned in the
middle of the sanctuary
appeared to him majestic,
like the symbol for the virility
of his youth, forever buried.
Suddenly his blood boiled in his veins,
and a feeling of potent determination
invaded him there.
I'm still a man!
I'll show him that I can cheat on her!
I'm going to buy women
with my 300,000 Yen.
He decided to betray his wife
by cheating on her for the first time.
He thought that deceiving his
wife would grant him a retreat
from the visions of hell
present in her company.
It's rare to see a client
take a bath in a Turkish Bath.
What are they for then?
Well you know it ...
What would you like?
The clock is ticking.
A special or a double?
It's not enough to sleep
with a woman to be unfaithful.
It must be a real woman,
one I'm in love with.
Otherwise, it's not betrayal.
A rendezvous at night-time in Tokyo?
Meet a beauty!
Feeling lonely? Call me! Mika
Here is my registration fee of 3000 Yen.
What kind of girls are they?
They are all amateurs.
Good evening.
She is pretty.
I'm starving of hunger!
Let's go eat sushi.
That looks delicious!
I'd love to have dessert now!
This is sweet!
I'd like to sleep with you.
You are a nice girl.
What's your name?
Kazumi.
That's a pretty name.
Mister ...
What is it?
I'm starving.
Can I have eel before?
Please.
Having an affair with a woman
is not as simple as that.
Miss Okawa.
You look lonely, Sir.
No, why ...
Thank you.
I feel very lonely too.
Impossible ...
Someone as lovely as you.
If you agree,
we could have dinner tonight.
Really?
Go ahead, please.
I'm happy.
You're so nice to me.
He invited her to a luxury restaurant.
He was thrilled.
They walked through
the city hand in hand.
He felt like in a dream.
Miss Okawa ...
You should not drink so much.
It's okay. I want to be drunk.
Director ...
Today,
I have a broken heart.
My lover ...
married the daughter of a rich man.
The goddess he worshiped
laid in his arms.
His heart was about to burst,
but unlike his feelings, the
organ of his manhood refused
to respond to the excitement.
This can't be.
He panicked.
What is it, Sir?
He burst into tears.
And she wept as well.
Yet, their adventure had
liberated them from their grief.
In the Yasukuni Shrine,
the night was mournful.
He thought of suicide in front of
his comrades, but changed his mind.
My wife certainly awaits
my death with impatience.
When I die, she'll receive the
money from my life insurance.
I can not die.
I have to live long,
whatever happens.
This is the only way to avenge myself.
The barrel of the sanctuary stood there,
a black mass in the darkness.
He climbed onto the barrel
and urinated on it at length.
Maybe I'm impotent
facing life.
But look at you, canon.
You are as impotent as me.
In fact, you are the
symbol of impotence.
I'm a murderer? Lies!
After two months with Masahiko Matsumoto
and Takao Saito, I left the apartment
to devote myself to a long narration
Black Blizzard
My pencil slid easily
and I felt confident again.
So that's it, the pleasure of creation!
I didn't know!
I had never experienced it before!
Vulgar Manga on the rise
Parents of students are protesting
What is bothering you?
An article on the Manga rentals.
Another one!
It will not advance you
to pay attention to that.
We don't draw for children.
Parents are complaining
without even reading them.
Our readers are old enough
to understand.
They know that you bleed
when you are stabbed.
Our influence is not bad.
Yes, but our Manga are
on the same shelf as
the Manga for children.
Of course they are taken
for what they are not.
BLACK BLIZZARD
It's true what Okichan told me,
we should not call
Black Blizzard a Manga.
Our works are different from
the Manga for children.
Let's be clear on this.
Here, some new names.
Ryûdôga is too dark.
Setsuga is not bad ...
Let's proceed by elimination.
Gekiga
That sounds awfully good.
Yes, I also like Gekiga.
It has body and gives a dramatic nuance.
That is agreed. Go for Gekiga!
GEKIGA
Now, it must be ensured
that the term is spread.
How are you going to do this?
I'll take it to Tokyo!
This will be our banner!
Then you'll really go to ...
It has been decided.
We, the signees ...
... have decided to found Studio Gekiga.
We aim for a new kind of Manga ...
for adult readers, characterised
by a realistic drawing style
and psychologically nuanced narrations.
I must not forget that
I'm talking to adults.
Studio Gekiga Manifesto
I printed 150 postcards
and sent them to different
newspapers, editors and artists.
Without thinking,
I also sent one to master Osamu Tezuka.
In the book that he wrote later,
he acknowledged having been
perplexed by Gekiga,
and when this genre
experienced a great success
by having been pushed down the stairs,
having been struck with jealousy.
On April 1st, 1964
travels abroad are legalised.
The Dollar exchange rate
rises to 360 Yen and
everyone is allowed to take
500 Dollar abroad.
That does not work at all.
I should not have worked that much.
I have dizziness, nausea,
and a chronic colic.
It's worse in recent days.
I lost weight and my
body hurts everywhere.
Books for Children
Publishing Office
Are you done, Mr. Shimokawa?
Excuse me.
As I told you,
your series don't sell anymore.
You are at the lowest in the surveys.
I spend sleepless nights
trying to entertain the children.
That is the problem.
Children lead you to the cane.
An author must know how to guide
children where he wants them.
Anyway, the next episode
has to be the last one.
My head is going to explode.
Shit, look at me! Those fat dirty brats!
Give me back my health!
I should not have forced myself to eat.
I arrived too late
and vomited on the wall.
When I saw the obscene graffiti,
a violent nausea overcame me again.
For an artist as adherent to a
unique series as myself,
the last episode meant
the loss of my job.
I was exhausted.
After two days of resting in my bed,
I felt a little better.
Well, going for the last episode!
♫ A man must know how to
withdraw in style ... ♫
Do not let the children dominate you.
You take a drink?
I'll make you a treat.
You are more naive than you look.
You don't know why I asked
you to wipe my fingers?
I'll wipe them myself.
Excuse me.
Okay, tell me
you are quite something, yet ...
Little pervert.
It wasn't much.
She just excited me,
plucked me and threw me
out unceremoniously.
I suddenly wanted to see her again.
Only two days later,
the graffiti had already changed.
Someone had drawn them again,
after their removal.
I guess for the last episode,
that will do the trick.
Thank you for your cooperation so far.
I'll call you soon.
I knew he'd not do anything.
It was over.
My talent was gone.
Say there was a time when
I could not help but draw.
It's been more than 10 years
and I have not felt that urge since.
When I regained my senses,
I was already on the toilet.
The graffiti were all obscene
and repetitive.
I imagined the man who drew them.
At least he was tortured
by the desire to draw.
I felt evil, alone on the toilet
thinking such thoughts.
I laughed out loud.
The crowd rushes about outside,
but in here everything is quiet.
This is the place where I'm at best.
I sat at my desk,
but the inspiration would not come.
I was afraid to leave my desk,
but could not manage to concentrate.
What will I become?
The author of the graffiti,
didn't he draw only by
going to the toilet?
Or did he deliberately
went there to draw?
So you no longer work
on children's books?
That is good.
We thought of you for our magazine Play.
What do you say?
But Play is a magazine for adults.
Exactly.
You don't miss talent,
but you'll not draw for children.
So come to my office in an hour.
I'll be waiting for you.
Manga for adults?
I had never thought about this genre.
But thinking about it,
vibrant images crossed my mind.
I can do it!
This is the opportunity
I was waiting for!
It was as if I woke up from
a sleep of several years.
I freed you.
My body was boiling with excitement.
My heart beat so violently,
I could not sit still.
I have to draw!
This desire occupied all my mind.
The toilet walls were all clean.
The charwoman had made the
effort to clean them.
What ails you?
A pervert!
In the toilet!
There's a pervert in the toilet.
Call the police.
What is it?
A pervert?
Is it him?
Quick, call the police!
Like the hero of Occupied.
I had no other choice
than to publish
in monthly or weekly journals.
The stories you have seen
were all written in the seventies.
All my works from this period
are imbued with a deep malaise .
This was the period of
large growth in Japan
and many Japanese enjoyed that wealth.
I could not bear to see
all these euphoric and indecent people.
The wave of wealth didn't
caught on to us, neither to me
nor to the people surrounding me.
My anger against this state of affairs
concentrated in a black mass
at the bottom of my heart.
This is one explanation.
I devise my stories more and more
often in cafés close to me.
I attend
four different cafés
to work on my stories.
My wife was working
in one of those cafés.
We settled down together, of course.
I never knew anything besides drawing
and I lived just on my works.
Dealing with a white sheet,
a pencil in the hand
for drawing tirelessly,
is a hard and lonely work.
Once cured of his chest disease,
Okichan had no other choice
than to opt for an ordinary job
distant from Manga.
It has been very hard for him
with his health problems.
My greatest joy
is to invent stories.
It's an opportunity to rediscover and
glimpse into unknown worlds.
A Manga is 70% complete,
once the story is defined.
The remaining 30%, it's fun to draw.
But my ideal is not so much of
developing stories, but
passionately giving life to images,
gushing spontaneously from my mind.
Everything artificial resembles a lie.
Come!
Joe, come!
I'm coming, baby!
I love you, Mari. I love you so much.
We will get married, okay?
No worry, no worry.
I'm okay.
No, no. I'll marry you and
I'll take you back to America.
Again, the brats from next door.
Hey, you whore!
Beat it! Get the hell out of here!
Ouch!
Bitch!
Soldiers slut!
Mariko, are you okay?
What do you want, again?
Why talk like that
to your old father.
I just came to see my little darling.
I took the liberty to return.
You promised me not to come
back anymore.
A new client?
This is not the same sergeant as before.
How do you do?
I'm this girls father.
Father?
Yes, yes, papa.
Thank you very much.
Mariko, you allowed
yourself a nice big bed.
It's because these Americans are beefy!
What is with the money?
You came for that, right?
So take it and go away.
This is unfair.
Is this any way to treat a father
who came to see his daughter?
You are very ungrateful.
That does not work on me anymore.
The last time you pulled
that trick, my ring
was gone with your departure.
I know I'm a bad father.
Everything is my fault.
You, a father?
You steal the money I earn
from selling my body.
I don't think of you as a father.
I'm going.
And never come back!
Mari, your poor father is crying.
No, it's just theatre.
I'll not bother you anymore.
Take care of yourself.
Now, you are crying.
Poor thing.
Rotgut
Barkeeper, another one!
It's not my fault that we lost the war.
She thinks she's an American ...
Hey, you!
What are you looking at?
Hey! Leave us alone!
Stop drooling!
We are the dolls of the Yanks!
Learn that lesson!
Joe, let's drink.
I want to get drunk.
♫ I read my future ♫
♫ in the stream of stars ♫
You drink during the day?
Business must be good!
This season the rain
exceeded the limits.
How's the Yank ... Joe, right?
That bastard is back in America.
He fucked me.
He has a wife and children there.
So you drown your sorrows in alcohol?
Good-bye!
I don't care about the future!
All men are dirty perverts!
Mariko, stop!
You are hurting yourself.
Why do you interfere?
Do not play father now.
What are you doing, Mariko!
Stop it!
That is more like it.
I don't need a family.
This is just a man, like any other.
Good-bye.
I'm now 75 years old.
I don't know if I still have the energy
to give birth to numerous works,
but I'd like to draw new worlds, again.
Translated to English from the
French translation of Gaspard Kuentz
Original French Subtitles:
c.m.c. - Paris