Check it out!
Thirteen minutes and 54 seconds.
That's a new record.
Yeah!
Oh, my God what you gonna do.
with the girl but love her and pay her?
Give me my money. Give me my money.
You still owe me money.
Hey. Everybody,
shut the hell up for a second here.
As you know, today's
Belle's last day.
Aw!
And I'll tell you this.
You're the best man I've ever had.
Aw.
Aw, come on, now.
Look, look.
I just want you to know
I just stayed ahead of you
because I know you enjoyed
the view.
The view.
Anyway.
We're all real proud of you
for finally getting your taxi license.
Knowing that you're behind
the wheel of a taxi in our fair city
makes us want to move
to Albany.
Listen, I seen these sparkle in a window,
and I knew they had your name on them.
Come on, I thought they'd be perfect for you.
Check it out. You're gonna love 'em.
- Oh, wow.
- This is you, girl.
- Oh, my God.
- Ah? Ah?
- It's a titanium supercharger!
- Yeah!
- Oh, my God.
- That's gonna be some taxi, Belle.
- It's just my size too!
- That's right, Belle.
Please don't leave us.
Don't leave us.
All right. Time's up, man. Come on. Get your
hands off my girlfriend. Get off me, man.
- Hey, baby.
Oooh!
- Shut up! None of your business.
- Back to work. Let's go. Everybody.
I could have got the package there
with a horse and buggy. Back to work.
- What you doin' here?
- I called in a favor. They let me
take the rest of the day off.
- All right.
- Wait a minute.
- Wait a minute who you wearin' perfume for?
- What?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No, I cut through Macy's I got tagged.
- Uh-huh.
- Why, you like it? Is it me?
Look, let me tell you
something, baby.
- There's only one thing I like on you.
- What's that?
- And that's me.
- Mmm.
- And I got you a little somethin'
for your last day too.
- What?
Hold on now. You'll find out tonight.
After a mind-blowing romantic dinner.
Date.
And excit...
Ah, hell, no, B
Don't tell me you forgot.
What? No? Of course not.
No I didn't forget I can't wait, baby.
I know it may not be as exciting
as that titanium thing you got.
- My supercharger. You saw it?
- Yeah. Whatever, baby just trust me. All right?
I just got
a 4:00 appointment
at the Taxi and Limousine Commission
to pick up my hack license.
I'll be out of there by 4.30.
And then I'm all yours.
- B
- Aw.
BB
- Yeah?
- 4:00 was five minutes ago.
Oh, shoot!
- Yeah.
- All right. Love you, baby. Later, guys!
- Hey, lady! Come on!
- I got an appointment!
- No, no, no no cut.
- I got an appointment.
- Is everybody here with appointment, okay?
- What?
We take number like bakery.
Please go to the back.
I do not come here from Moscow
25 years for no bullshit.
Right here. Ticket.
Right there. Ticket.
Mm-hmm.
138?
Man.
Aw, he bought candles.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
I'll make it up to you, baby.
Oh! Hey! What the hell
is your problem?
- Come on. Let's go.
- What is wrong with you, man?
Cabbie, I need to get to.
JFK in 15 minutes.
One hundred bucks,
I make it.
Whoo! Done.
You jumped in
the right cab today.
Yeah.
I don't usually stop for white guys.
My way of balancing the universe.
That's 14 minutes.
Buckle up for safety,
motherfu...
Actually, if I miss this flight,
it wouldn't be the end of the world.
Oh, no. Don't worry. We'll be able to speed up
once we hit the highway.
Come on, man.
What'd I do?
Hey, look here, Hugo Boss.
You might want to hold on.
Nine minute, 28 seconds.
Damn, I'm good.
You know... Damn.
I'm good I am good.
Don't you scratch them,
you idiot.
Where's Frank, man?
Where's your friend at, man?
He'll be here.
It's all right.
Where is this guy?
He'll be here.
This is the guy?
Yeah, that's him.
Okay. Let's do this.
- It's cool, right?
- Right. It's cool.
Come on.
They're in.
It's no trouble,
Frankie.
You're going to fifth floor,
number 22. Okay?
A- And don't try nothin'
This is an easy bust, Washburn.
Don't do anything fancy.
We clear?
Yeah Nothing fancy.
That's cool.
Stick to the plan.
- It's okay. It's good.
- Got the money?
No, no. Wait, wait, wait.
I don't like it, okay?
You said these guys
are from Cuba like us.
- Tranquilo, chico.
- What's the matter?
- I'm not speaking to you, okay?
You're not from Cuba, okay?
- No, no, no.
Forget it. Forget it. Okay? You know what?
I don't like this. Okay, man? No.
- He don't like it.
- I don't like it. Okay, "mang"? I don't like it.
You don't like it?
Oh, do you no speak English?
I don't like it.
Read my lips. I smell something.
What do I smell, huh?
Huh? What do I smell?
Huh? I smell a setup.
What am I smelling here?
Huh? What do I smell?
Carnitas? Amigo? Pig!
Ah. Okay, "mang"?
- Don't do this. Don't do this.
- Okay?
You telling me
that you don't trust me?
That's what you're saying?
I'm only gonna
say this once, okay?
Your friend better come out
from behind that door. Okay?
Or I'm gonna put
a window... in him...
"mang"
Yeah.
Okay?
You're okay, man.
You're okay.
- What part of Cuba are you from?
- Huh?
- Havana.
- Havana?
- Oh!
- We're from Havana!
- Ah! Cigar!
Oh, I love this guy.
The three of us from there.
We must be brothers, eh? Who's your mother?
- I'll tell you something. You guys are ever... Hey.
- That's enough.
- You guys are ever in Havana, you give me a call.
- Let's go.
We'll have some tequila, cerveza. You know?
Okay? Mi casco es su casco.
He funny.
What part? What part?
- Uh, you ask me where I'm from?
- Yeah. What part?
- What part am I from?
- Yep.
- Uh, what part of Havana?
- Yeah.
You know, on the...
Uh, I live around the corner of, uh
uh, Castro Street.
You know?
So.
The show's over, pigs!
Aaah!
- Frank, are you all right?
- Goddamn it, Washburn!
How could there not be a Castro Street in Cuba?
That's insane.
- Shut up, Washburn.
- Right? Am I right?
Vàmonos! Vàmonos!
Hey! Stop!
They're gettin' away!
Come on. Let's go.
- You can't drive with your arm like that.
Give me the keys.
- No way.
- Come on!
- No, I insist.
Give me the keys!
Okay.
- Be careful, huh?
- Okay. All right.
Put my seat belt on.
Get my hands at 10:00 and 2:00
Okay, let's move the seat.
- Okay okay.
- Seat up. Like that. That's too close.
- Okay. Come on.
- Back more. Back more. Back more. Back more.
Back. Little back.
Back more.
That's good. All right. We'll have mirrors checked
and seat back. Can see side.
- Washburn, m-maybe...
- Ah!
I got it, dude! I got it, man.
Hand signal 'cause I'm comin' out.
- I'm comin' out.
- They're there. Go! Go!
Here we go. All right lets go.
Rock and roll, dude!
Washburn!
That's funny.
Get in here now.
I'm s... I'm sorry, Marta.
Lieutenant.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
Andy.
I know this is hard for you,
especially coming from me.
It kind of feels weird
calling you lieutenant.
Well, you may not have to much longer.
I mean, look at this
$40,000 in damages, Andy.
This is two lawsuits here.
I...
And this. Have you seen
your face on the cover?
- Oh, there's a better picture than that.
- Oh, shut up.
L... I'm sorry, Andy.
But this is just not easy for me.
Look, you're a good cop,
but you're a terrible driver. What is it with you?
Hey... Everyone has
their weaknesses, okay?
Superman has Kryptonite.
Indiana Jones, snakes.
You know Whitney Houston
has Bobby Brown.
Or vice versa.
I... I try to make the department look good,
try to make you look good.
You look great,
by the way.
I'm not saying you don't.
You're not like...
- You look... Ah!
- Right. Okay. Good. Enough.
- You look like a lieutenant.
- Shh.
- Beautiful. You're hot.
- Professional.
- Three cars you totaled.
Cop or no cop, that is 11 points on your license.
It's gone.
- No, don't take my license, please.
- It's gone.
Come on. Don't...
You're not gonna need it
for your next assignment.
I'm sorry, baby,
but that line at the T.L.C. was ridiculous.
- I cooked for hours.
- Come on. Look, look. All right.
Had wine, satin sheets.
I even bought candles.
Do you realize what I had to go through
to get that license?
- I won't be late.
- Yeah, well, you better not be
'Cause today I pulled out
all the stops.
Baby, I promise.
I promise I won't. For real.
5.00. At the restaurant.
All units, robbery in progress.
Manhattan Savings and Loan. Thirty-six
and Broadway. Suspects armed and dangerous.
Freeze! Police officer!
I'm gonna need your car for official...
I love you too. Bye.
Hi. Thirty-six and Broadway.
Manhattan Savings and Loan. And step on it.
- You know that's only two blocks...
- Yeah. Step on it. Thank you.
Okay.
Okay, that'll be 230
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, I'm not beat, man.
Now you owe me five
because I had to chase...
Get out of the way!
Freeze!
- You! We got a hot pursuit. Go.
- Do what?
- You still owe me five bucks.
- Maybe I didn't make myself clear.
I'm commandeering your vehicle.
Follow that car.
Don't worry about speed limits,
streetlights... nothin' You're with me.
Man.
All right.
But I'm still runnin' this meter.
Yo!
Hold this for me.
Hang on.
Whoa! Yo, man.
Be careful with that.
Careful don't bag the bad guys.
Here's the plan.
Fake like you're gonna go left,
then go right. Okay?
I'll lay a little suppressing fire down
from "pistolita" Hey.
- Oh, my goodness. Did you just...
- Drive!
Drive the car. Drive. Don't look at me.
Look at the road.
Come on.
Oh, what the... Oh, come on now.
Ah... Ah...
- Come on.
- What the hell are you doing?
Gotta get...
Watch it. You... The steering wheel.
Ah... Oh.
What the... Oh.
- Hey, why'd you stop?
- Hey, man. Watch that thing.
It's a dead end.
They ain't goin' nowhere.
- All right. Let's do this thing, baby. Get my burn on.
- You talking to me or your gun?
You better not be talking to me.
I know you ain't talking to me.
- Shot my...
- There's nowhere to run.
Damn.
Oh!
I know. They got away.
Damn!
- You shot my taxi.
- You calm down now, ma'am.
- Calm down, all right. No need to get upset.
- No need to get upset?
- Yeah.
- What? Are you outta your freakin' mind?
- Hey!
- Fool, I've been working on this car for five years.
- Who is gonna pay for that?
- Hey. See this?
This is a badge, okay? That means
you're not allowed to scream at me.
Come on, now. Give me the badge.
Hey.
Come on. Give it back.
Come on now. Give me it! Give me it!
- Hand it over, cabbie.
- Man, we cool.
- Nice and easy.
- All right, man. Damn. Be cool.
Be cool, huh? I had to flip and pull this
out of my ankle holster.
- Now, give me that and shush.
- Okay. Be cool.
- Shh.
- All right.
- Here. Take your badge.
- Mm-hmm. Yeah. Okay, now what?
- Uh...
How you like it being pointed at you?
I'm not givin' nothin' back.
Quick. Gimme, gimme.
Gimme it.
- Drop your weapon and put your hands in the air.
- Ooh.
- Freeze!
- It's okay I'm a police officer.
- Okay, slowly show me your badge.
- Uh, okay.
- Give me the badge.
- No.
Throw it over here.
Oh.
I can't.
She's got it.
- Freeze!
- Wai-Wait.
I said freeze scum... Washburn. Washburn.
He's such a loser.
Is he in there?
Washburn.
Washburn. You took a cab
to a bank robbery?
- You-You thought that was okay?
- Well, y-yeah.
Yeah I was the closest
to the scene.
If you hadn't of taken my wheels,
I would've nailed 'em.
I didn't take your wheels.
You drove your wheels through a bodega
and you killed.
Detective Manuel's parrot.
Det Manuel knew what he was risking
when he took the parrot on the stakeout.
- I can't believe you.
- So ridiculous.
Of all pets, I mean. It's the one that talks.
- What is that smell?
- L-I know I let you down.
- Mm-hmm.
- So, see what's happening?
- Mm-mmm.
- You're getting emotional
and taking it way too personally.
- Personally?
- Yeah.
I'm your lieutenant.
Of course I'm pissed off.
Come on, Marta.
That's not what I'm talking about.
You know what I'm talking about here.
I'm talking about... us.
- Us.
- What?
- Us I'm talking about us.
- You think.
- Shh.
- that I and you...
I got it. Got that.
I'm with you.
What? Mm-hmm.
Okay. Thank you.
I'll be right there.
The FBI's here.
I'm gonna do something
to you later.
Mm-hmm.
Washburn.
So, did you pay by the mile, or is there a flat rate
for chasing bank robbers?
Quiet.
Please give your attention to Agent Mullins.
FBI Armed Robbery Unit.
Thank you it's tape of this morning's robbery.
Watch close.
It goes by pretty fast.
Four cameras.
Four perfect shots.
In and out in 35 seconds.
Lieutenant, you have the witnesses' statements.
Miss Williams,
I'm Lieutenant Robbins.
This is Agent Mullins with the FBI
We want to ask you a few questions.
- Am I under arrest?
- Well, no.
Then I ain't answering no questions
until somebody tells me
who is paying for the damage on my cab
and when do I get it back?
Miss Williams, I'm afraid your vehicle's
physical evidence now.
- We have to run ballistics tests...
- Ballistics tests? On what?
We already know
who shot my cab.
It was that stupid idiot right there
with that dumb look on his face.
That's not fair.
Agent Mullins wasn't even on the scene.
- I was talkin' about you.
- Me?
You shot my back window out.
You could've shot me.
- You don't talk to me like that.
- I'll talk however I want.
- Get him out.
- Take his stinkin' ass out of here.
- All right, all right I'm sorry.
- Are you kidding me?
- I'm sorry.
- That is the FBI in there. You need to calm down.
Somebody better talk to him.
Sorry 'bout that, dude, um, sir.
The adrenaline's still pumping.
You know what I'm saying?
Had a crazy morning.
I'm a little out of line,
and I apologize.
Detective Washburn,
you were the first one on the scene, correct?
Yes, I was.
I was the first one on the scene.
My first instinct is to give you a shot
at leading this investigation.
- However, I spoke with your lieutenant.
You're off the case.
- Permanently.
- What?
Nice meeting you.
I know.
Y... Marta, you can't...
Lieutenant.
- You can't...
- Enough.
Now, go clock in.
You're late for your shift.
I already told you everything I know.
You can't hold me.
Now, I want my cab.
- Says here you did a year in juvenile hall.
- That's supposed to be sealed.
Joyriding. Graduated to reckless driving,
fleeing the scene of an accident...
look at this... moving violation,
moving violation, moving violation.
- Come on. Everybody got a few tickets.
- Not 75
And not on a bicycle,
Miss Williams.
Officers at the front desk will give you
the forms you need to fill out.
As far as your car's concerned, you'll get that back
when we're done. Two weeks, maybe longer.
Two weeks? Come on, man.
This is bullshit.
That's not just my car.
That is my job.
Wh-What am I supposed to do?
Give people piggyback rides to Newark Airport?
One more question.
Did you ever get close enough
to see the guy driving the car?
No, sir.
All I saw was their taillights.
Can I go now?
- Here we go again.
Didn't I say 5.00? Where are you?
- Jesse.
I feel like a damn fool, B,
thinking you'd actually be here on time.
- I tried.
- No, no, no no I'm tired of hearing excuses, okay?
I'm sittin' in my cab, right?
All of a sudden out of nowhere, this guy jumps...
Hello? Baby?
Jesse?
What the hell
could be so damn important?
- Freakin' day I had.
- Hey. Miss Williams.
- You again.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Go ahead. Talk.
- I just wanna talk.
- Talk then.
- I can get you your cab back.
Come on.
You gotta help me first.
Okay? Just hear me out.
They got five detectives on this case.
We gotta catch these guys first.
All I got to go on is
the MO, modus operandi.
- That's police jargon for...
- I know what it means.
- It's not police jargon. It's Latin.
- Right. Whatever. It's both.
They were pretty quick though.
They were in and out in, like, under a minute.
That's real pros. Witnesses
said they're either Spanish or Italian.
Nah, I think they're Brazilian.
They were speaking Portuguese.
- You sure?
- Confia em mim.
My first job was delivering food at...
Brazilian.
This is huge.
Hey, why are we not
doing this at the station?
Sometimes a good cop's got to bend the rules
so that laws don't get broken.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm not afraid to live outside the law.
You living outside of your mind.
That's where you live.
Well, the reports here say
that the man driving was about 5'10"
No no, no, no, no.
If that was a man, so am I
She looked like a model.
Tan, blondish hair.
All right. As I was saying.
It was a woman driving.
- and she was driving a Mercedes... an Au...
- No.
- Mm-mmm. No, no, no.
- She was driving... Definitely you saw her driving.
- a BMW?
- Right.
- Yeah, but not just a BMW. It was a 760
- Mm-hmm.
- But the engine sounded lighter.
- Light, yeah.
Now, with that much torque, she had to have
an inboard torsion damper system
with a push rod bell crank
and double wishbone arrangement.
Wait a minute.
You shot her tire out, didn't you?
Yeah. Standard OP
- That's police jargon for...
- But she kept on going
'cause she had run flats.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
She had "runs" flats on.
Armored tires. They seal themselves
with a gel when they're punctured.
Now, they're good,
but they only go for about 50 miles.
So, if she wants to drive that car again,
she's gonna have to get a new tire.
And there's only one place to get that tire
around here Lou's Garage in Secaucus.
- What are we waiting for? Let's hit it. Take my ride.
- All right.
There's my baby, right there.
- This is your unmarked car?
- We found her.
A Daewoo? Man, I know people.
I can't be seen in this thing.
Tsk. Open the door.
I don't wanna get Daewoo on my hands.
Buckle up for safety, everybody.
Hard to do it with my holster on.
Okay, we're good.
Good, wipers work
10:00 and 2:00
Mirrors work.
And here we go.
Oh, damn.
- Whoa! Sheesh, man.
- Little ding. Little ding.
- That's why you got bumpers.
- Can't you... What the hell?
- You trying to kill me?
- I'm not a perfect driving robot.
- I know. Oh! What are you doing?
- Here comes Junior.
- You can't... Oh, shit! Wait! Stop stop stop.
What the hell are you trying to do,
a 78-point turn?
- Can you get us out of this spot?
- Yes.
Everyone just chill out.
Be real cool about it.
God... damn!
Now, I'm turning the wheel.
Turning the wheel.
- Oh, my God! Wait wait.
- Shh. Everyone be cool.
No. Stop.
What? What? What do you...
What do you want?
- What's the problem here?
- Get over there.
- I got... I got shotgun.
- Get your ass over there.
You got insurance?
'Cause that's what I'm gonna need.
Daggone whiplash.
You got a driver's license?
Let me get my belt on.
Who the hell gave you a driver's license?
That's what I wanna know.
Okay, after I show you this place,
I'm gonna get my cab back?
- Deal.
- 'Cause I don't really trust you.
Soon as I know this is the place,
we'll go back to the station, I'll get your cab back.
- This is it?
- Yep.
If they gettin' that car fixed,
they-they gotta come here.
- So, what now?
- We wait.
You can open your eyes now.
I'm done.
You didn't see my nads, did you?
Man.
So, you got guy problems, huh?
Overheard you and your man on the phone.
Want a little bit
of wisdom from the man side?
I'll give it to you.
Men are like cats, you know?
Sure, we'll play with
the ball of yarn
unless you want us
to play with the ball of yarn.
Trick is,
hide the ball of yarn.
Don't hide it where you can't find it,
you know?
"Hey, what's the ball of yarn
doin' in the fridge?"
Whatever.
You know what I'm saying?
You know, cops are supposed
to talk to each other on stakeouts.
It helps the mission
go by faster.
- Would you please shut up?
- Okay. That's cool.
You wanna be quiet? That's cool.
No room for chitchat. That's fine.
I don't care I don't need...
I don't need to talk.
We'll just sit here
in silence.
So, are you into cars, or...
I mean, what got you into cars?
I mean, were you always into them?
Did you just, like, stumble upon them?
Damn. My grandpa.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
W- What?
He loved driving, or...
Yeah. He was a mechanic.
Taught me everything I know.
We used to live
next to a track.
You used to go to the track all day?
That's fun.
No. We didn't really go that much.
I mean, we went to a couple races.
But mostly, we would just listen
to the races together.
I could hear those cars.
Hear those engines.
I got good
l- I got to the point where.
I could tell who won the race
without even seeing it.
- Yeah. Driving NASCAR. That's my dream.
- Wow.
Wait. Let me ask you something.
Why would you take a taxi to a bank robbery?
I mean,
I've never seen that.
I got in a wreck in my last gig.
Bad guys got away.
My lieutenant flipped out.
Put me back on the beat.
No vehicle.
Aw, man.
What makes it worse,
me and my lieutenant used to date.
- Yeah. We went to Academy together.
- Okay.
She got promoted.
I didn't.
You can cut the sexual tension
with a knife.
Shh! Look.
There they are.
Oh, man. Yep.
That's her.
- Party time.
- Hey. So-So, what we gonna do now?
- I mean, we gonna call it in, right?
- Call it in?
By the time we get backup, that soup will be cold.
We go in now, baby. Now.
Shoot. Oh, my God.
Daewoo, please. I'm sorry.
I take back everything I said. Start for me.
Hi. Um, I'm not actually with him.
He's...
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Damn.
- What are they saying?
- The redhead is saying
she doesn't wanna kill a cop.
If we just play it cool,
then they'll leave us here tied up.
Okay okay I'll play it cool.
Play it real cool.
Okay. Hey,
what was that wink for?
- Shh. Hey, trust me.
- No, no, no, no, no, man. What was that about?
- Shh. Trust me. Trust me.
- Trust you?
- Yeah.
- Trust you? Hell no. Uh-uh. No way.
No, no, no. Uh-uh.
Hey. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Hey. Excuse me.
Don't mean to interrupt.
He's gonna do something.
He just winked at me.
- What's wrong with you?
- What's wrong with me?
- Yeah.
- I got a problem gettin' shot. Did you frisk him?
- Come on.
- Frisk his ass again.
He got at least one more gun on him.
- Cavity-search him.
- I do not I swear.
He got a gun, and he's gonna use it.
He's crazy.
- Whose side are you on?
- Mine.
Okay. You wanna strip search? Huh?
Is that what you want? Nothing up my sleeve here.
You wanna check my shoes there?
Ha!
Go!
All right,
you're all under...
Man, you're more dangerous
than they are.
Hey. What are you doing, man?
I'm evening
the playing field.
That's flammable gas. They won't be able to shoot.
This whole place will blow.
Man, we still
in this place, you jackass.
Turn that off,
and let's wait for the cops to come.
The real cops.
Oh, my G...
- Oh.
- Aw, man.
You smell that, ladies?
That's nitrous. One shot and boom!
Now, you wanna handle this
hand to hand, man to... chick?
Then we'll go home.
Hello. Hello?
Ace Dumbtura, they're gone.
They're gone.
Stay down. Stay down.
They're not there.
- Come on. We gotta go.
- Oh, damn.
This thing's jammed.
- Oh, man.
- Ohh.
Dumb ass.
You can't... You can't die
from nitrous oxide can you?
It's laughing gas, stupid.
I hate you, man.
- What's that?
- I hate your freakin' guts.
- Ow.
- You got to be the dumbest cop I've met.
- We gotta go. We gotta get out.
- Okay.
- We gotta get out.
- All right. Okay. Open the door.
Open the door, man.
Move.
You're stupid. All you had to do
was turn the freakin' knob.
Your car is on fire.
- No. Come on.
- Daewoo can't take a little heat?
Drop the weapon!
- Freeze!
- Oh.
Okay. This does not look good.
Here's the plan, all right?
Okay, when he comes by...
Or that. Hey! Hey!
Wait for me! Belle! Belle, wait up!
They've gone around the back side
of this building. We need to go.
I tell you what we do.
We go back to the station and search the files...
No, no... No. Hell no.
We ain't goin' nowhere.
You're comin' back to my house
with me to tell my boyfriend where I was
'Cause I had a man
when I went to work today.
Okay. That's the least.
I can do.
Damn straight. The most you could do
would be to get my cab back.
You'll get your cab back
when I catch these guys... girls, women.
Not before.
I'm getting a little seasick.
Swallowed it.
I don't know if this is gonna work,
so just hurry up and show him your badge, okay?
Because he's sensitive,
and he is pissed off.
All right. I got your back right here.
I owe you one.
What the hell?
Jesse. Baby, you home?
- Wait I can explain I was with this guy all night.
- Oh, really?
Then go home with him, Belle.
I'm tired of hearing your apologies.
First of all, don't take that tone with me.
I ain't apologizing.
Don't you be taking that tone.
I've been waiting here all night.
Hey, hey, hey I got this.
I can handle this. All right?
I can totally handle this.
What's up, bro? How you doin', man?
Yeah.
Here's the dilly, yo I know it seems weird
your girl hanging out
with the skinny,
pretty good-looking white dude.
But, hey,
I'm a cop.
The name's Detective Washburn.
- At least let me explain.
- Oh, no. Not again.
He's gonna give it back, right?
What's that sound?
Blowtorch.
Blo-Blo... Blowtorch.
Hey, Jesse.
Thank you.
Can I have my...
- At least let me explain.
- Ow. Man.
Damn!
Man.
- Always wanted a money clip.
- What the hell was that?
- It was my badge.
- You know what? Fine.
Forget it.
I'm just gonna let him cool off.
- Hey, wait up.
- I don't know you for seven hours, I lose my cab
my boyfriend
and my apartment.
- You battin' a thousand, you know?
- Yeah.
I mean, it's not enough you screw up
your own life, huh? This your place?
No I figured we'd stop here,
get something to eat.
You actually have a girlfriend?
Ma!
- Ma.
- Sweetheart.
I love you I love you I love you.
Ma, I brought company.
- Oh.
- Hi.
Nice catch.
Jungle fever.
- You know me.
- Excuse me.
I'm not his girlfriend.
I ain't even his friend.
Mom, uh, Belle here
is a cabdriver
and she witnessed a bank robbery...
- She needs a place to stay.
- Get in here! Come in.
Come in.
Oh, you must be starving.
I have got the number of a joint
that makes
a General Tso's chicken...
It'll knock you
on your goddamn ass.
- Whoo!
- Your mom's drunk, huh?
Always.
Where's my Daewoo?
Andy...
- did you do something to my car?
- Don't.
- You busted.
- Andy.
Look at me, darling. You didn't drive through
another bodega, did you?
- That was you?
- What? What?
That was you
on the cover of the post.
- You killed that parrot.
- No.
Mom, what'd I tell you about
talking official police business, all right?
- Sorry.
- He had the mustache.
I didn't recognize you at first.
See...
They took his license away.
There was the third car that he totaled.
He even wrecked
one of those big armored machines,
you know, with the battering ram?
Who the hell gave him
one of those?
He just mowed down three mailboxes like that.
That's a federal offense.
- Mom.
- Well, Andy is not a really strong driver.
See, he had a really bad
experience when, uh...
he had his first
driving lesson.
Driving lesson?
You call that a driving lesson?
- Mmm. Yes.
- Dad let go of the wheel and said
"You better steer or else
you're going to kill the whole family"
Yeah. It was good for you.
- We were going 90 I was six.
- That's right.
- And that's the way he taught you to swim.
- I can't swim either.
- Well...
- Can we drop it?
- Okay. Sure.
- Okay, Mom. Lock it.
Down your...
Down your brassiere it goes.
Oh. Mommy's getting
the spins.
Whoo. That's it for me.
- That's it.
- That's it for the kid.
Why don't you...
Take good care of this little girl.
- Daddy will be so proud of you.
- Mommy. Thank you. Come on.
- Good night, sweetheart.
- Good night, Mom.
- Nice to meet you.
- Oh, nice to meet you too.
- Yes yes.
- Oh, she'll be back.
- Where's my-my drink?
- There it is.
Don't forget that.
Mom, the bedroom's that way.
- Okay, sweetheart.
- Or are you just getting the blender?
- Oh, yeah.
- That's a... That's a 38-ounce blender.
You know, it is
getting late.
Do you wanna just crash at my place
until your dude cools off?
Like I have a choice.
Tsk. Stop playing.
You live next door to your moms?
Makes her feel safe.
She must not've
seen you in action, huh?
Oh, God, it feels good to lay down.
Good night.
What kind of grown-ass man
lives 10 feet away from his mama?
I wouldn't talk so much.
Isabelle "Precious" Williams.
- Who told you about my name?
- It's in your record.
Precious.
My. Precious.
Go ahead. Say it again.
Say it again, see what happens I dare you.
Precious.
Hey, you know, I was just thinking.
I remembered something.
The girls kept saying over and over again
to each other, "Nice 'dua rateeraros."
Mais duas retiradas?
Yeah. That's what they said.
That means,
"Two more withdrawals"
I want five cars on 14th and Broadway waitin',
and I want 'em now.
- Hey, I've made a major break...
- Get out.
- I made a major break in the case.
- Oh, really?
Does that explain why they found a car
registered to your mom.
- on fire in front of a shot-up...
- That's not important right now.
- What's important is
they're gonna rob another bank.
- First Financial
at Leonard and Church and they hit
two minutes ago and they're still inside.
So, I am busy.
Now, sit down and shut up.
Damn, man.
Car 10-70. Suspects are still in the bank.
- How would you like me to proceed? Over.
- Backup units are on their way.
- Do not let them leave.
- I don't think that's sexual tension
between you two.
I think that is genuine tension.
Like, she-gonna-fire-your-ass tension.
I can't stand this.
You know what's gonna happen?
They're gonna catch them,
and we're gonna miss the whole thing.
- Please. Ain't no cop gonna catch that woman.
- Oh, yeah, and you can, right?
If I had my taxi.
Right away.
And keep me informed.
Let's take a walk.
Find Washburn. Now.
Eddie B
"Washtub"
Hey, uh, I'm gonna need your help, man.
I gotta get the...
- The Crown Vic.
- Crown Vic.
Here. All I need are the signatures
of the two officers, man.
Two. Perfect. One, two.
You know Lieutenant Williams, right?
- Uh...
- Williams from SWAT?
- Oh oh.
- She's a jujitsu master.
Really?
She has her own dojo.
- Oh. Wow.
- You have any flyers?
No. Sure don't.
- Okay.
- Oh, man.
You gotta Friendster me, man.
I want a flyer.
- Hey, man. Got the, uh...
- Here you go.
Aha. Thanks, man.
Hold it right there.
Shots fired. Shots fired!
Officer needs assistance.
Suspects are headed north on. Third Avenue
towards the Queensboro Bridge.
What?
What are you doin'? We're gonna lose her.
Come on. Run lights.
- What are you doin'?
- Why would you take the East Side?
The Queensboro would be
a parking lot.
Oh, you bein' slick.
You headin' west.
You're drivin' the speed limit, okay?
You're driving the speed limit.
- We're not gonna catch...
- Oh, you think you slick, don't you?
You know 68th'll be gridlocked
'cause Hunter College's semester just started.
Unless you gonna drive
through the damn school.
Of course. She gonna take Fifth.
Hell, yeah.
There's plenty of room to maneuver
down the Museum Mile...
and I know your crazy ass ain't scared
to get up on that sidewalk.
That's what I would do.
Now, if I'm right...
which I believe.
I am...
she gonna come out
right
about here!
Oh!
Ooh!
- Ooh!
- Come on. Let's go! Get her!
I told you... too much torque, grandma!
Watch this.
Whoo!
Pull over! Police!
Pull over the car!
Pull over right now!
- What?
- My badge.
Now, pull over.
This means something.
It's your last chance.
Come on.
Okay. You tryin' to dent me?
Not gonna happen.
Damn.
Whoa!
We're gonna kaboom...
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Ha-ha!
Whoo!
- Oh...
- Shit.
Ah!
Aw.
Damn I was
on her ass too.
Let me just...
No B.M.W.'s have come through here.
A red BMW
cannot disappear twice.
Uh, I got a blue Beemer
on Morningside Avenue.
Good I'll take it.
Uh...
License and registration?
I'm gonna need you
to pop the trunk for me.
I gotta open it myself.
It's busted.
Shit.
Uh, pardon me, miss.
Thank you.
Uh, could you open the case?
Sure.
Here.
You ladies have a nice day.
Miss Williams, give me your license.
I'm taking it away from you.
- What?
- You heard me.
You're not driving
a taxi again. Let's go.
But I made her
pursue that car.
- Really?
- Hello?
Well, her taxicab is in
violation of 27 vehicle codes.
Did you make her do that too?
Yeah.
Yeah, I did.
- I, uh, ordered the modifications top to bottom.
- Top to bottom.
- Weeks ago.
- Mmm.
So there.
What kind of car is it?
- Ford.
- Ford. What model?
Crown... Crown... Vic...
- Ner-r-rvous...
- Excuse me?
"Roundville"
You're an idiot.
Give me... Give me the license.
- Crown Victoria.
- I don't know what that means.
Come on.
- Give...
- Well, but, see, it looks... It's the picture...
- It's actually a nice...
- Marta...
- "Lieutenant"
- All she's tryin' to do is help, okay?
Just do something?
- No.
- I stopped three BMW's this morning.
Let's take Miss Williams down so she can hear
the officer's testimony. Let's go.
Let's go.
- Let's go.
- Blue Beemer.
- This chick didn't even know
how to open the trunk.
- Chick?
- What chick?
- The driver.
Boy, she was a foxy little...
- Four women, and there was no money
in the car. I searched it.
- It's definitely possible.
- There's all kinds of paint...
- What are you two talking about?
Of course. It's a red BMW
You might as well drive an ice cream truck.
The girls drove a BMW,
so that's what we look for. Then they change it.
Wait a minute. You're saying that
all four robbers are women?
- Yeah.
- And you saw them?
Yeah.
Last night.
Damn it! When exactly were you gonna share
this information with the FBI, Washburn?
- I tried to tell... I tried to tell you this morn...
- Shut up.
Officer Preston,
come with me. Let's go.
You're fired. You're not suspended.
You're not on temporary leave.
You're fired.
Miss Williams, I'm giving this back to you
with a warning.
If I catch you driving that thing
in my city again, it is mine.
Andy, as a friend,
I'm sorry.
- I tried this morning I went into...
- Shh. Andy.
You've left me no choice.
Now, give me your badge.
What...
Whew.
Hey, wanna share a cab?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Turn over.
What? What? What?
- All I ever wanted to do
was just be a cop, you know?
I wanted to be like my dad, you know?
My dad was a cop.
You know, I let him down.
I let you down. You're screwed.
You can't drive this anymore.
She did not say that.
She said not to let the cops catch me.
I can see why you like
that lieutenant. She feisty.
You like us feisty girls,
don't you?
So what's up?
You gonna give that another shot?
Give it another shot?
She fired me.
So? Redeem yourself.
Catch these thieves.
Try and start this
for me, please.
Come on, baby. Come on.
Come on. That's... Yeah! Life!
Woo-hoo-hoo.
Wanna take it for a spin?
- Oh, no-no-no. No, I'm... No, thanks.
- Come on. You need the practice.
No I drive fine, and I don't wanna...
I'm not in the mood for a driving lesson.
Who said anything
about a drivin' lesson?
It's just me in the passenger seat
and you drivin'
It's not a driving lesson?
Okay. All right. All right,
buckle up your safety belts, kids.
- All right.
- Here comes Washburn.
Just a...
Just a leisurely stroll through the evening.
And here we go.
Whoa, engine's started. My bad. Uh, okay.
Turn... Light's here. Good. We have drive,
drive two... which is good, because.
- in case you need the second...
the sequel... to drive.
- Just chill out and drive, man.
Come on, now.
You just gotta relax just...
Come on. Let's relax just...
Y- Yea-a-ah.
I said relax,
not hyperventilate.
Don't... What you...
Look how tight you grippin'
the steering wheel. Damn.
I'm tryin' to get
in my mode here, all right?
- I'm tryin' to get in the game.
- Why don't you let the game come to you?
Dag. See, that's your problem.
You try too hard.
You always overthink things.
You be kickin' down doors that's already open.
You always tryin' to impress somebody:
Me, your dad, your ex.
Come on, now. If you ever gonna learn
how to drive, we gotta play to your strengths
and thinkin' ain't one of 'em.
So, don't think.
- Don't think. Don't think.
- Don't think. No.
- Mm-mmm.
- Just clear your mind. Relax.
- Okay. Relax.
- Listen to some music.
Oh, yeah!
- In the face!
- Oh, hell no. Hell, no.
- No, man.
- That was pretty good.
Hey, No, no! I like this one. Oh, yeah. Wait, wait.
- Natalie Cole, this one. Yeah.
- What you know about that?
That's one of my favorites I love this one.
This one, I used to...
Just a little kid, man,
I used to sing it in my mirror in my bedroom.
- All right.
- I mean, I was, you know... you know...
- Hey. Whatever works for you.
- under supervision and everything like that.
- Go ahead and sing sing along to it.
- Oh, you don't want me singin'
Aw, come on sing sing the song!
Okay. All right. There you go. There you go!
- All right, now, put it in drive.
- Okay.
Who said stop singin'? Sing.
Sing the song. Sing the damn song.
There we go.
Shoulders down.
Just relax. Yeah. There you go.
You got it! You got it, man!
- Whoo!
- Hold on to the wheel. There you go.
Thank you so much.
Oh, dude, you're drivin;
Um, wait. Jesse, baby, please.
Just stop buggin' for two minutes.
- Let me just explain what's...
- Shh, shh you okay, B? I been worried sick.
- Yeah.
- Come on, girl.
Um, baby, what are you doin' here?
You left your phone here. He called,
and I explained everything to him. And...
Belle, he's a dream.
- So, you're not mad at me no more?
- How could I be mad at you?
- You was mad at me.
- I wasn't that mad.
- Come here.
- Ohhh.
- I... mmm.
- Well, I missed you. Mmm.
- I missed you too, baby.
- Oh.
- Oh, my.
- This is like watching pay-per-view.
- Mother!
Ooh.
Mom, clear your throat.
- Uh, hi.
- Hi.
- Come on. Let's go home.
- Oh, no, no, no. You're not going anywhere.
- I made dinner.
- No, you didn't.
No, I didn't. But, I made margaritas.
We can order.
Oh, boy, can we order.
All right, look, let's be logical about this.
Let's go through the story one more time.
- Yeah.
- Okeydoke.
B.M. W. Pulls out in front, right?
Well, see, that's the amazing thing right there...
getting a parking space in Manhattan.
Yeah. Jesse's totally right.
Wait a sec.
How do you get a parkin' space in front
of a bank two days in a row? In Manhattan?
Yeah, 'cause the only places I ever find
are no-parkin' zones:
Loadin' zones, hospitals
or streets that are "no parking" for, uh...
- Garbage day.
- Yeah.
- The whole side of the street is a no-parkin' zone.
- Course!
So, they rob the bank early in the morning,
then they put the cash in the garbage can.
We chase the Beemer. The garbage truck
picks up the cash,
and they meet up later on.
So even if you do catch 'em,
that's why they ain't got the money on 'em.
The only thing they need to pull it off
is a garbage man.
- We gotta find that garbage man.
- Okay.
- Bye, Mom.
- Hold on. Where you goin'?
Bye, baby.
Wait, wait! Yo, whoa!
Yo, what do you want me to do with this?
We can't wait till the morning.
The FBI may have already caught them by then.
I mean... You know what I mean.
Just keep a lookout.
Hurry up.
Voilà!
Wait, wait, wait.
You don't think they have an alarm?
Come on. It's not Fort Knox.
It's the Department of Sanitation.
Ooh. Shh! Quiet down.
Plan "B" Plan "B"
Plan "B"
Police. We heard the alarm.
- What's... What's goin' on here? Everything cool?
- You all right?
- Officer, uh, uh, Mullins. This is Officer...
- Good snatch.
Hello, what do we have here? Uh-oh,
obvious "B and E" Perps might be still inside.
- Way to stay cool, dude. Way to stay cool.
- Yeah. Look!
They even left
their lock picks.
Surely they got
prints on these.
- Gotta... Gotta tag these. What's your name, sir?
- Verne.
- Earn?
- Verne!
- Yeah. Bern, where's the nearest...
- Verne?
- Verne.
Verne. Where's the nearest
computer, Verne?
The computers are inside.
Follow me.
All right. We find out who works 36th Street...
From Third to Broadway on Wednesday...
Leonard and Church on Thursday,
bang, we got our garbage man.
Okay. "personnel, '"
"Routes';! Here we go.
"Routes" All right
"36th," "Wednesday,"
- Boom, there we go. We got our man.
- "Anthony Scalia"
Yep. Same garbage man got both routes.
You see that?
"Three East 117th Street, Apartment 4R. '"
Yeah. Boom. Let's go.
I'm getting used
to your driving.
Okay. Here's the plan.
- I'm gonna need you to boost me up
to that fire escape...
- Cable!
Mr Scalia,
it's the police. Open up!
Thanks.
Stay back.
Damn.
Hello?
Shh.
One last pickup,
then you are free.
You bring us
the cash again
then, hey...
we let you go.
We... We let your wife go.
After I bring you the money,
how do I know what will happen then?
You don't.
But if you go to the police,
you do know what will happen.
Huh?
- So, that's the best way, over here.
- Mm-hmm.
We get in from here, and, uh.
I think the best way out is coming from here
so we can make it faster.
Your car, sir.
Okay, girls.
Time to go.
Don't transfer me again I need the route
of Anthony Scalia, okay? It's an emergency. Now!
Look. It was on the fridge. He works
midtown today, then he's off for two weeks.
- Oh, my God. It's gotta be today.
- Yep.
Get me Lieutenant Robbins.
This is Washburn Marta... Lieutenant, look...
Whatever you're gonna say,
I don't wanna get into this right now. I'm busy.
- I got FBI all over my ass.
- L-Lieutenant, with all due respect...
- I just can't hear you right...
- Shut up, Marta!
Now, look, they're usin' garbage trucks
to get the money out, okay?
Both robberies were on
the same garbage man's route.
We went to his house.
There's gonna be another robbery this morning.
I know I'm a hundred percent sure.
Please trust me, will you?
- What bank?
- It's gonna happen
somewhere between 23rd and 34th,
east of Fifth.
Down! Down!
Everybody down!
If I see anybody's eyes,
I shoot.
You! On the ground. Go.
Whoa, Whoa, Whoa.
Pull over. Stop, stop.
Pull over.
One squad car?
She didn't believe me.
So?
So, what we gonna do?
Fall back. Halt!
- Hey, grab somebody.
- Drop your weapons and step out of the car!
On the ground! Now!
In this skirt?
I don't think so.
Now, I'm going to drive away.
And if I see any cops, the kid dies.
- Okay, girls. Let's go.
- Wait wait, wait, wait.
Okay?
Can't let you take him.
- Look, take me. Okay?
- Robbins.
- Marta.
- It's okay.
Okay. Come here.
Get over here!
Spread 'em.
Let's make sure you're not wearing a wire.
Turn around.
Damn.
Oh, Jesus.
Would you take me too?
Okay.
Get in the car.
- Come on. Come on.
- Thanks.
Any cops follow me,
she dies.
Belle, we gotta
do somethin'
All units, all units.
Be on the lookout for a blue B.M.W...
headed north on Park Avenue.
This is Air Unit 1070. We lost 'em.
We have no visual
of the suspects.
Suspects last seen in the vicinity of 42nd
and Vanderbilt near Grand Central Station.
Washburn,
you stay out of this.
- All right? Whatever you got planned, don't do it.
- I don't got a plan.
- All units, all units.
Suspects still at large.
Last seen headed north on Third Avenue.
Callin' my own backup.
- Be on the lookout for a blue B.M.W.
- Hey.
Suspects are armed
and dangerous.
- Mario?
- Yo, Belle. What's goin' on?
Listen, listen, listen.
I need your help.
Mr Scalia,
I'm a police officer.
Come on, fellas who's got 'em? Who's got 'em?
We're still lookin'
We haven't seen anything yet.
I got 'em Fifty-seventh and Third, northbound.
- Damn! They're probably at...
- Sixty-fifth Street, heading north.
Damn! We don't have anybody up there.
We're gonna lose 'em.
I'm on my way.
- Hey. How you doin'? I got your money.
- Against the wall.
Oh, shit. You got a gun.
If they get past 125th,
we're gonna lose 'em.
Come here!
- Ha, ha you got punk'd.
- Sit down!
- You okay, Ms Scalia? It's okay. It's okay.
- Oh, help me.
It's okay. It's okay.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- Come on. Get out of here.
Oh! Thank God.
- Oh, my baby.
- Thank you.
Wow. That's a cool car.
You can have it.
Have fun.
They can chase him for a little while now.
Shit.
Oh, cool.
- Now, where's Marta?
- Who's Marta?
- Come on! Where'd they go?
- I don't know.
They never tell me anything I swear.
Oh, shit. Oh, my God Look at all this money.
Look, I'm just gonna take a couple thou'
for the damage to my cab
'cause ain't nobody payin' for that
quick enough.
Oh, my God. Shit.
- Hello?
- All right. Check it out.
They stopped at Marcus Garvey Avenue and 122nd.
Switchin' into two silver Beemers, M3's.
Put her on the phone.
Excuse me, ma.
- What?
- You got a phone call.
- Hello?
- Chasin' you around the city has been so much fun.
- And this tip, girl...
- W-What are you talkin' about?
- I'm talkin' 'bout your money.
- We got it! We got your money.
All of it! Hey, tell her.
- Tell her.
And that cop chasing you is not a real cop.
- Turns out... Ow! Ow!
- Shut up. Be quiet.
He is a real cop.
He just got fired.
What do you want, cabbie?
I'll tell you what I want.
What do I want?
- A trade A trade.
- I want a trade.
- The money for the girl.
Always wanted to say shit like that.
- Come on. Come on.
- Deal.
- Yeah, all right.
We make the exchange
on 125th Street and 12th Avenue.
- Three minutes. No tricks.
- Yeah. Three minutes. Whatever.
All right, let's get the rest of the money in a bag.
Yo, yo, my phone!
You heard her, Mullins. You got three minutes.
Now, haul ass and stay out of sight.
Don't worry. We'll have the roadblock all set up.
Don't wait for us.
Either backup is lyin' really low,
or they just not here yet.
What if she doesn't
take the bait?
Change of plans.
- I thought we had a deal.
- Never said I was stopping.
Follow me. We'll make the exchange on the go...
that's if you can keep up with that heap.
Washburn. Turn the car around.
Turn the car around!
"Don't wait for me" He must have thought
he sounded so cool sayin' that.
- Come on. What are we doin'? We need a plan.
- I'm workin' on it!
No more chitchat.
Give me the cash now, or I shoot the girl.
All right, all right.
Just calm down.
I got a plan.
But we need to stall.
- What?
- Start the transfer but don't complete it.
- Trust me.
- All right.
Too early! Not yet! Trust me.
Hey, these two big trucks comin' up...
is this part of your plan too?
- Get me in! Get me in!
- Come on!
Whoa!
- Gonna hit a truck!
- Too early! Get out. Get out of here!
- Get me in! Get me in!
- No, we gotta stall!
- What are you talking about?
- Hey! You got a car. You got a car coming!
- The exit's comin' up. We need to have 'em take it.
- This way. Less traffic.
Give me the cash.
No more games.
- Girl first.
- No. Girl first.
- No! We'll switch same time.
- On "three"
- One...
- Two...
- Three!
- Ah!
Brake!
Oi!
Yeah!
Die!
Oh, shoot.
Jesus.
You're hit.
- That skank shot me.
- We gotta get you to a hospital.
- Come on.
- Stay low.
- Watch out.
- Watch your head. Okay.
What are you doing? You... I should drive Andy...
- Come on.
- I got it Belle, hang in there.
- He's got it.
- No, he don't got it.
- You got it, don't you?
- Yeah.
I'm lettin' the game
come to me.
- Why are you singing? Why...
- Don't stop singing.
- You don't... Why is he singing?
- He sings. Don't stop him.
He sings?
Oh, yeah. Get me St Mary's emergency room.
- Whoo!
- Washburn, there's the exit!
The rooms are prepped for surgery.
Pull up to the ER entrance
and park in the white zone, but not...
Okay, let's get this woman to surgery!
Come on. Move it! And when
you get her there, prep her. Quickly!
Come on. Get this steppin; people.
There ain't nothin' for you to see here. Move it!
Welcome, NASCAR race fans.
We got a lot going on
this weekend.
Several NASCAR racing divisions
are represented here today.
And rookie driver.
Belle Williams...
with her new sponsor,
the banks of New York...
is taking to the track
for the first time ever...
to run practice
for her racing division.
The whole crew stands to make money
on this one 'cause we all bet on you.
You know where your money's good at.
All right, check the tires.
- Hey!
- Yo, you got visitors.
- Oh, my gosh. You look great. That's so cool.
- You look so cool! How are you?
- Hey!
- Wow. You look great.
- Hi.
- Oh, man.
- Wow I love it.
- How are you, Belle?
- Well, what do you think, huh?
- It's our latest undercover assignment:
Russian mafia.
- What?
Ah! Okay.
I'll buy it I'll buy it.
- So, how are your new sponsors treating you, huh?
- Oh, good. Check it out.
- They have hooked me up.
- This is unbelievable. It looks great.
I remember saving this one.
- Hey, Jesse.
- Hey, what's up, man?
All right. Don't tell me. What do you got here?
Probably a 358 CI, four-barrel carb.
720 horsepower,
8500 R.P.M.?
- I'm impressed.
- Oh, he's got it written on his hand.
- Mom!
- Come on.
She's wasted.
- He's stupid.
- Oh, Jesse.
Come on. Let's have
a cold one, okay?
- I'll be with you in a minute, all right?
- She really needs a cold one.
- Hey, watch your ass out there, baby.
- I will.
- 'Cause it's mine, all right?
- I will. Mm-hmm.
- Anyway... Oh, dude, we gotta split. Party time.
- Yeah.
- Good luck.
- Let's go. Bye.
- What are you d...
- I thought... Sorry.
I thought there was a moment there.
I'm s... Did you not... Are...
You keep giving me signals.
No signals.
There's no moment.
There will be others.
Hey, take care
of yourself, 5-0
And don't do nothin'
crazy or stupid, all right?
Crazy and stupid's
my style.
- Watch where you're goin'
- That yours?
- Oh, my God.
- That's your boy.
- That's your boy. You ready to do this or what?
- All right. Yeah.
All the cars are heading out to the track.
- Practice is now underway.
- Hey, come on, boys.
And we have a special
announcement on the Jumbotron...
for banks of New York driver.
Belle Williams from Jesse.
Ha, ha! Oh, my God!
Yes, yes, yes!
Of course I will.
- And we see NASCAR's
premier series driver, Jeff Gordon...
- returning to drive lead with the setup.
- Come on, boys!
- Congratulations, Belle.
- Thanks, Jeff.
You ready?
- Ready to try and smoke you.
- All right. Well, let's do this thing.
All right. Let's do it
''up, bro? How you doin'? Yeah.
Yeah?
Against
the car.
- Cut!
- I'm sorry I pinch her butt.
Mark!
- Whoa!
- All right.
Here we go.
Here comes Junior.
Oh.
Geez.
What the...
Wait! Oh, Lord.
What...
And... cut!
- Yeah, where in the car?
- Door panel on the left just pull it.
Say it.
Don't spray it.
- Think they're after computers?
- No, I think they're after your balls.
Yeah. They're after
the computers.
Next time you guys are in Havana,
you give me a call
and come over and play Playstation, you know,
and play, uh... you know, hang out.
You know, eat a gordita, you know,
which is a taco inside another taco...
soft inside of a hard one...
more beef, and then beans, and then more beef...
another taco,
and then into another one...
You must be starving,
little baby.
Oh!
- Door panel on the left.
- You make me mad, dude.
- You heard me?
- Door panel on the left.
- Yeah.
- Just pull it.
- All right? I'm tellin' you you could...
- Baby.
Be there.
- I don't know why I'm puttin' the phone here.
- Yeah.
- Maybe your shoulder has something to say.
- Okay. Yeah I don't know.
- Just pull it.
- Man.
- Just grab it.
- I know. No. Shh "Grab it" is better.
I can't believe this day.
- This is the worst day of my life.
- Yo.
I sound like Barry White's
illegitimate white grandson.
Hey, wait, wait.
I have an appointment.
I'm sorry I can't hear you because
of the sign that says we're "closed"
Aw, come on, man.
Give a sister a break.
I been workin' for this for five years.
Fillin' out these forms and taking these tests.
Waitin' in these lines.
I'd love to help you, but I'm sorry.
You know
a handsome man like you
should not have trouble getting a cab.
Mmm!
What is that scent you're wearing?
Could that be English Leather?
It is, huh?
Ooh, it's thick too. Ooh!
I bet you be having the ladies
in this office going crazy, huh?
I'll tell you something
and I know you gotta go
so I'm not gonna keep you too long
but I would pick you up anytime
every time and at all times
if I had my hack license.
Man.
Aw, he bought candles.
Tomorrow night's lows in the 50s.
Cool and breezy till Wednesday,
with a chance of rain...
Hmm. Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Baby.
Babe!
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
Mmm.
Now, where are you going?
Work.
It's only... 5:30?
Yeah, well, I had to get some extra shifts
so I could get last night off.
I'm sorry, baby, but that line
at the TLC was ridiculous.
Yeah. You know, it's always something, B
It's always something.
But I bet you had time to put on that damn,
uh, supercharger thing, didn't you?
Come on, baby I'm really sorry.
I'll make it up to you.
I'll make it up to you
soon as you get off.
- How?
- You tell me.
Mmm, okay. All right, baby.
You better be ready when I get back, girl.
All right? I'm...
Don't hurt yourself now.
I don't want no excuses later.
Tsk. Stop playing.
You live next door to your moms?
Makes her feel safe.
She must not've
seen you in action, huh?
Uhh...
Uh, it's a little messy, but, you know.
I've been working late so I haven't
had time to fix up the place.
I got some good artwork
on the way on eBay.
It's on the...
You know, I'm still bidding.
So make yourself at home, okay?
Enjoy yourself.
Okay. Ooh.
Nice. My hair.
Hey.
Okay, you're in luck.
I have two options.
You got the sleeping bag times
or the love capsule.
The love capsule.
"Dan"? Who is Dan?
It's supposed to say "danger"
You know how it is.
Nah, I don't know how it is.
Tattoos hurt.
You know, they stick needles in.
You know how tattoos happen?
They put needles in.
I think you better get that tattoo finished
as a warning to the rest of us.
Oh, God, it feels good to lay down.
Good night.
What kind of grown-ass man
lives 10 feet away from his mama?
I wouldn't talk so much.
Isabelle "Precious" Williams.
- Who told you about my name?
- It's in your record.
Precious.
My Precious.
Go ahead. Say it again.
Say it again, see what happens I dare you.
Precious.
What the hell?
Get your ass off of me!
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
- What you doin' down here?
- What's wrong with you?
- I should have warned you I'm sorry.
I roll when I sleep sometimes.
I move.
- I'm a restless sleeper.
- Yeah, you restless, all right.
I didn't know what was happening there,
but we... we spooned, okay?
We spooned a little bit.
At least we didn't fork.
We didn't... please, be nice.
Wait wait.
I just remembered something the girls
kept saying over and over to each other
"Nice 'dua rateeraros."
Mais duas retiradas?
Yeah. That's what they said.
That means,
"Two more withdrawals"
Two more withdrawals?
Let's go! Let's go!
You might want to change
your clothes, freak.
I want five cars on 14th and Broadway
waitin', and I want 'em now.
- Did she have an accent?
- Jersey.
Mmm.
- What size was her bust?
- What?
Her bosom.
Her hooters. Her headlights.
Her flesh pillows. Her fun bags.
Her knockers. Her rack. Her boobs.
Oh.
They were about like, uh...
Compared to mine. What?
Yeah. About like that, yeah.
34-C
All right, finish up, Officer.
- Four women, and there was no
money in the car. I searched it.
- It's definitely possible.
- There's all kinds of paint...
- What are you two talking about?
Of course. It's a red BMW. You might
as well drive a ice cream truck.
The girls drove a BMW, so that's what
we look for. Then they change it.
Wait a minute. You're saying
that all four robbers are women?
- Yeah.
- And you saw them?
Do you think they're after computers?
Verne!
You actu... Verne, crackheads!
Crackheads, Verne!
Crackheads.
Man, they'd do anything for the rock.
They'd bust you clean
'cross your head for that rock.
She's a sweet damned mistress.
Mysterious, like Atlantis.
Sunken crack whores.
- The bitch is crazy.
- Look, dude, about those
computers you're talking about...
The computers are inside. Follow me.
Yeah, I figured they were inside.
Okay, here's the plan.
All right. We find out who works 36th Street...
From Third to Broadway on Wednesday...
Leonard and Church on Thursday,
bang, we got our garbage man.
Okay. "personnel, '" "Routes';!
Here we go.
"Routes" All right
"36th," "Wednesday,"
- Boom, there we go. We got our man.
- "Anthony Scalia"
Yep. Same garbage man got both routes.
You see that?
"Three East 117th Street,
Apartment 4R. '" Yeah. Boom. Let's go.