(dramatic music)
>> No one took
the environment seriously,
until it was too late.
Food, water and air
were poisoned by
the years of pollution.
Most people died
of disease and hunger.
The rich people moved
underground, where it was safe.
Everyone else was left behind.
Killers and criminals
formed ruthless gangs.
When they weren't
fighting each other.
They were trying to
break into the underworld.
To steal our food and water.
That's where I come in.
I work for a TC Unit.
Tracker communicator.
An elite division of the
underworld security forces.
Our job was to
track the breakers.
To kick them out
or terminate them.
>> Jason, looks like
there's trouble
with the protective forcefield.
>> Shoot this Zoey and let's
get the hell out of here.
>> Copy. Stand by to record.
>> I had a laser decoder
a high voltage demobilizer.
And a rookie partner named
Zoey Kinsella.
>> Entrance granted, Unit 22.
>> Her father
helped form the underworld
before he was murdered.
I was sure she was going to
get my ass clipped,
but she was cool.
>> Man, is it hot up there
or what?
>> It's just one big
frying pan out there.
>> Hey, Henshaw, Dale.
>> You're late.
>> We're lucky we made
it here at all.
>> My heart bleeds.
Would you rather have
the night shift?
>> Aw geez, I don't know
what do you think, Jason?
>> Tough call.
Relaxing night off
or surface world at night.
>> Keep your eyes open guys.
>> Hey, it's a jungle out there.
>> Exit granted, Unit 99.
>> Let's hope
it's a quiet night.
>> Uh, what I'd give
for a cup of coffee
and a fresh doughnut about now.
>> Look out.
>> Yaah!
>> Control. Unit 99,
we're under attack.
Transition Gate 11.
Send back up.
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
>> Attention!
Code 3 Security alert.
Repeat!
Breaker attack in progress.
All available TC Units,
stand by.
>> Aw shit.
>> Yeah, so much for
a relaxing night off, huh.
>> Tell me about it.
>> Unit 22.
Security breach at Transition...
(dramatic music)
>> Yaah!
>> Aah!
>> Sparks, this is
Storm and Kinsella
we're tracking, let's go.
>> Yeah, let's do it.
>> Confirmed 22,
be careful out there.
You're outnumbered.
(dramatic music)
>> Look out behind you.
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
>> Aah!
>> Control. ETA
Transition Gate one minute.
(dramatic music)
>> Aah!
>> Fry 'em.
>> Entrance denied.
>> Go through the gate.
>> Jam it.
>> Entrance granted, Unit 99.
(dramatic music)
>> They're getting through
at Sub-level 3.
They must be getting through
at the food storage centres.
>> Sparks,
Storm and Kinsella here.
We're tracking 2 breakers into
Quadrant X17.
Request????
No back up required, yet.
(dramatic music)
>> TC Unit 22
this is Control.
What is your status, over?
>> Control Unit 22
We have requested X17, Y42
unit with slip solo.
>> Go that way.
>> I'll take the big guy.
>> Take care of
yourself partner.
>> You too.
>> Yah!
(grunting)
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
>> Yaah!
Yaah! Yaah! Yaah!
Oh shit.
(grunting)
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
>> Yaah!
Back to surface world
for you chump.
>> Unit 22,
Kinsella has breaker in custody.
>> Ditto partner. Now let's get
these breakers topside.
>> You got it.
>> Attention!
Return to Security status 6.
>> Hi.
>> Breakers have been
apprehended and contained.
(background chatter)
Please return
to Security status 6.
>> Hey Sparks.
>> Job's done Sparks.
>> Controller wants to
see you two. Nice work.
(beeping)
>> Thanks.
(heavy footsteps)
>> Bigelow, Bales out.
>> How the hell
did the breakers get in?
>> They used the dead bodies
of Dale and Henshaw.
>> Shit!
>> Man this shit is ridiculous.
>> You know, someone
is feeding the breakers
our exact schedules.
>> I know, it's bad,
but I'm looking into it,
personally.
Meanwhile, we've got to
keep our patrols up
or the breakers
will be all over us.
Sparks send him in here.
>> He's on his way, sir.
>> So what have you found today?
>> Well we recorded a variety
of topographical locations.
And when you match it to
Jason's gathering chips,
I think you just might find,
that Mother Nature's
working on a remedy
for the lack of ozone.
>> I wouldn't be
to sure about that.
Cameron,
I'd like you to meet
Zoey Kinsella
and Jason Storm.
The two best trackers
that we have.
Cameron Johnson.
>> We've met before.
>> How could I forget.
You spent a year putting word
viruses in my computer program.
Dr. Cameron was my Cybernetics,
Professor at the University.
until he left to go to
med school at what was it, 14?
>> So I suppose, he was
captain of the football team?
>> Well, we're on
the same team now.
Cameron is going to analyze
the data, that you bring me.
To see how it
interfaces with our new
TC project,
on surface world.
>> TC2000X's actually.
>> 2000X.
>> Yeah. Cybernetic trackers.
>> Uh-mmh!
>> Nice to know you can
always be replaced.
>> Well, I wouldn't
worry about that.
We haven't had a lot of
volunteers for this project.
>> Well if it means
moving to surface world
you won't find me signing up.
>> Oh that surveillance camera
at the Communications Centre
it just looks like
a standard bred camera
protect it's force field.
>> Thanks Zoey.
Sparks, scramble Unit 13.
Communication Center.
>> A pair of
surveillance cameras.
>> Aw fuck.
>> You little prick.
>> I doubt if you can
start days Lonnie,
>> Yeah, nice assignment.
Dale and Henshaw just got
fucking smoked
coming through that
Transition Gate.
>> Shit.
>> It's been really
scary out there.
>> Fucking Controller, someone
should ship his ass up there.
>> Watch what you say Trix.
>> Hey, the Controllers,
right hand man.
>> Hey.
>> Back off Bigelow.
>> See you in the gym, tracker.
>> All right, you two,
you know, the rules.
Our enemies are
the criminals of surface world
not each other.
When trackers and guards
have problems
they sort them out here
in the gym.
Anything goes.
>> Come on.
(colleagues yelling)
>> Jason. Come on Jason.
>> Yaah!
Yaah!
(colleagues yelling)
>> Aah!
>> Come on Jason,
you can do it.
>> Aah!
(grunting)
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Ooh!
(colleagues yelling)
>> Get him Jason.
>> Attention all tracker units
and guards.
Please report for night shift
detail at 19:00 hours.
(colleagues yelling)
>> Aah!
>> Come on.
>> Come on, break it up.
>> That's enough.
>> Come on, be brave.
>> Ooh, aah.
>> Take it easy.
>> Word is you took care
of Bigelow.
>> Yeah, I taught him
a thing or two.
He'd be out of commission
for a long time.
(Kinsella laughing)
>> Well I doubt the Controller's
going to be to happy about it.
>> Yeah, well I'm not to happy
with the Controller.
He shouldn't hire guards
like Bigelow.
>> You know,
I was just thinking.
>> Thinking.
Not about
the surface world again.
Quit playing with that thing
it's making me nervous, okay.
>> My dad said,
"Never to take it off."
>> But he never told you
what it was for.
>> Right.
>> So it must not be a key
to a buried treasure.
>> Maybe.
(jazz music)
What do you really think
is going on up there?
>> You know, you like this
every time we come back.
Can't you relax?
>> Look who's talking.
>> You keep fooling around
with that data crap
stuff's going to
get you in trouble.
>> You have to admit things
are starting to grow up there.
>> Yeah, for gangs.
>> Somebody could be
making it easier for them.
I think there's a leak
in the security system.
>> Zoey, leave it alone.
Try some of my mussel pasta.
>> No thanks.
I am going to go
and try to figure this out.
It's driving me crazy.
>> Well the Controller's
not stupid.
>> I know.
>> Be careful, okay.
>> I will.
Enjoy your dinner.
>> Thank you.
>> It looks really good.
>> I knew she was right.
Maybe the Controller was
keeping something from us,
could this go right to the top.
Our Overlord, seemed like
a decent leader.
But maybe he didn't know
anything about this.
>> Controller,
Master Sumai
has been located on
surface world, Monitor 7.
Should I dispatch
a tracking unit.
>> No that won't be
necessary, Sparks.
Sumai poses no immediate threat,
but keep me posted,
as to his whereabouts.
You keep killing yourself off
surface scum.
Less for me to do later.
(crowd cheering)
(dramatic music)
>> Aah! Aah!
(crowd cheering)
(dramatic music)
(crowd booing)
>> Aaah!
>> Welcome!
Friends. To my humble home.
We have much to celebrate.
Blade.
Let's hear some music.
(record spinning on turntable)
That's nice, that's nice.
Picasso, the time has come
for surface world to reclaim
what's rightfully ours.
And defeat
the underworld forces.
We may now penetrate their
underground sanctuaries,
with this a trackers PDR.
A gift from the enemy.
(crowd cheering)
So let's party boys.
>> Long live the Picasso.
>> TC Unit 13,
this is Control.
What is your status, over?
>> Control, Flannigan
and Zimicks here
we've reached
the Communications Centre.
The protected force field
surveillance camera
Section 6 & 7 tied.
The tech's working on
restoring power now.
>> What is your
ETR Unit 13, over?
>> Estimated completion
of repairs at 24:00 hours, over.
>> Ah, Zircon a shame to waste
a bottle of this great stuff
it would make
for a fine evening.
Sometimes I guess, we have to
make sacrifices, don't we.
Death to the under world.
>> Aah!
Aah!
>> We're under attack.
>> We're under attack. We need
back up. One man's down.
We're need
a MedEvac immediately.
(dramatic music)
>> Help!
Help me.
Somebody help me.
>> Yah!
(dramatic music)
>> Kiai!
(grunting)
(dramatic music)
Bring the bodies to
the Transition gate.
And be quick.
>> Come on, let's go.
(dramatic music)
>> You're mine tracker.
>> Entrance granted.
(explosion)
>> Aah!
>> Entrance denied.
>> Come on, bring the bodies
before they freeze the gates.
Hurry up, Blade
(warning signal beeping)
(computer keys clacking)
>> Security breach
Transition Gate 12.
(warning signal beeping)
>> Scramble Tracker Unit
7,10,22.
>> 7,10 and 22.
What does the monitor say?
>> Well, Niki Picasso.
>> Hello!
(tracker PDR beeping)
(dramatic music)
Come on.
our mission awaits us.
>> All right.
Let's get these guys.
(dramatic music)
>> Okay, Unit 2,
take tunnel 105
remember I'm behind you.
>> Good. Camera 45 Y14
and they definitely
know their way around.
>> Okay Unit 17 high side
Tunnel 104, right flank.
>> They're not headed
for the reservoir,
where are they going?
(warning signal beeping)
>> Calling for back up.
(background chatter)
(grunting)
(clapping)
>> Let's ask these gentlemen
to cool off the hijackers
and give us a hand.
>> Attention!
Code 1 Security alert.
>> They've breached
the tunnel access code
they're into Quadrant 13.
>> Alert the trackers.
>> Attention TC Units 7 and 22
this is Control.
Breakers have entered into
the main frame quadrant
they're into Quadrant 13.
>> God, they must have got
Unit 10.
>> It's the only way,
they could have gotten in, damn.
(panel beeping)
(dramatic music)
Control, they're heading
to the reservoir.
Correction, they've turned north
Quadrant 36.
>> They've got a plan.
>> What the hell
this is a dead end.
>> Wait!
What are they doing?
(dramatic music)
(glass panel shattering)
>> What is it?
>> Entry by unauthorized
personnel is...
>> Control this is
Storm and Kinsella.
>> ...forbidden, repeat.
we just chased the breakers into
what appears to be a dead end.
>> What the hell
is going on, Sparks?
>> My apologies 22,
we're working on it.
>> Additional trackers units
have been dispatched.
Please stand by.
(panel beeping)
>> There we are.
Follow me!
>> What are your
precise coordinates 22?
>> Okay Control.
We're at East 47, North 52.
>> North 52,
nobody's been there for years.
They're right under us.
Where's the Controller?
>> Anything I can help you with?
>> No! Proceed with caution.
>> No kidding, come on.
>> Attention!
This quadrant is restricted.
Entry by unauthorized personnel
is not permitted.
>> Something's wrong Zoey.
Why in the hell
would a breaker risk his life
to enter a dead zone?
>> Doesn't make any sense.
This place doesn't even
show up on our maps.
How do they know that
and yet we don't?
(grunting)
>> Trackers, looks like...
it's time to die.
>> It's time to get a new watch.
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
>> Aah!
>> Yaah! Yaah!
(yelling)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Ah, what a beauty
he didn't let me down.
(laughing cynically)
Surprise!
(gun firing)
>> Aah!
>> Shit!
>> Come on Zoey, let's go.
>> Get that gun,
let's get outta here.
>> I've got this.
(gun firing)
>> Unit 22, this is Control,
do you read?
>> Control this is
Storm and Kinsella
we're under fire,
send some back up.
(gun firing)
>> Control, he's shooting at us,
send back up.
(gun firing)
Repeat, send back up.
(alarm beeping)
Control, come in.
(gun firing)
(dramatic music)
We're trapped.
I have an idea.
(dramatic music)
(gun firing)
>> Noooo!
>> Aah!
(somber music)
>> Zoey.
>> It's okay.
They're bullets.
>> Zoey, Zoey hold on.
Don't talk, save your strength.
>> You lied to me Jason,
you said,
we'd be partners forever.
>> Zoey, we are partners,
partners forever.
Zoey.
Noo!
>> Why do you want her
at Terminal sStation anyway?
>> Never mind that,
just answer my question.
Can we program her
to do whatever I want?
>> Certainly, if you want her
to take on the Lifers at
the turning station,
she'll do it.
No questions asked.
She may require some assistance
but I can program her to be
very resourceful.
>> And they have to be dead?
>> Clinically, for the radical
neuro-restructuring.
>> Well do you
erase her memory?
>> To dangerous.
No one will figure out how to
access the memory.
>> No one!
(Cameron snickering)
Well it's not exactly what
the Overlord had in mind,
but what the hell.
Now let's see about
getting her partner back.
(dramatic music)
>> Remember, you're my woman
and I tell you what to do.
>> Let her go.
Get out of the way kid.
And when I say it,
you'll do a dance.
Come on.
(woman screaming)
You'll do as I say,
or I'll be...
(dramatic music)
You there,
interfere in my work
and I'll tear your head off.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Aah!
(giant yelling)
Come here you.
(grunting)
>> Yaah!
Yaah!
Bah!
(groaning)
>> Aah!
>> Yeeah!
Yeeah!
(laughing)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Yaah!
Yaah!
>> Aah!
(dramatic music)
(boy screaming)
>> Get outta here.
Just you and me.
>> Yaah!
>> Come on little man, I'll show
you who's big and tough
but it sure ain't you.
Come on get me,
come on and play my game.
>> Aah!
(wall shattering)
>> Enhance 3 times.
A PDR,
that's strictly TC issued.
Shit! They have an access code.
They had help from the inside.
Zoey, you were right.
They sold us out.
>> The soul is that we can
commit to the elements
the body of our sister
Zoey Kinsella dear departed.
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes
and dust to dust
but in sure and certain hope
of the Resurrection
to eternal life.
>> Sorry Jason.
>> We'll miss her.
>> My condolences.
>> Her father and I worked on
a lot of projects together
before we moved underground.
It seems like Zoey's always
been a part of my life.
If there's anything
I can do Jason?
>> I would like to see her
one more time if I can.
>> That's out of my hands.
Her body's the property of
the security council now.
>> That property used to be
my partner for 10 years.
>> Her chips, her access codes
they've all got to be removed.
Like all trackers
she is now listed
as classified information.
Well, that's fucked.
Breakers have access to
classified info and we don't.
>> What?
>> Zoey recorded our last run
the breakers had a PDR
with an access code on it.
>> Does anybody else
know about this?
>> No.
But I'm not sticking around to
see someone else, get greased.
>> You want to quit?
You want out?
Fine.
Report for total deprogramming.
Right now.
(dramatic music)
>> If you know
what's good for you,
get the hell out of here.
Prepare to remove his homing
system, directions finder
and access chips.
Cardiac monitor?
>> I'm running a cardiac doctor
but it can't be perceived.
ECG normal.
>> Blood pressure?
>> 130 over 70.
>> Set up for an art line.
>> Right away.
(coughing)
>> So many died.
>> What the hell,
Jason Storm is still alive?
Why didn't you take care of him
in the deprogramming room
like I told you?
>> There was
too many people around.
Besides, I can ruin my career.
Screw your career.
You work for me now.
Bigelow, you get
your boys on him
and don't you screw up.
(knocking on door)
>> Storm, Storm
we've got you now.
Storm, Storm open up.
(banging on door)
(door bursting open)
>> Yaah!
(glass shattering)
Yaah!
>> Aww!
>> Yaah!
>> There he is.
>> Oh shit!
>> Hey shit!
Damn man!
We're dead meat.
>> No, he's dead meat.
(grunting)
>> Attention!
Fugitive at large
in Sector 4.
Apprehend immediately.
Authorize and identify
all unsanctioned personnel.
(dramatic music)
>> Trackers, Jason Storm
has defected to
the surface world.
This poses
a significant security risk.
And I have
further information
that confirms Jason
orchestrated the break in
that resulted in
Zoey Kinsella's death.
>> Nah, he wouldn't do that.
>> Jason Storm is a traitor
and must be apprehended.
(dramatic music)
>> Do you want to
see the sights?
You've got to pay the price.
Give me your bag,
pretty boy.
And I'll let you live.
(laughing)
>> Back off, rat face.
I've had a hard day.
(dramatic music)
>> Yah!
>> Yaah!
(grunting)
Yaah!
(dramatic music)
>> Get up!
>> Yaah!
>> Come on.
>> Awwh!
>> Freeze him.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
(menacing growl)
(whimpering)
(heavy footsteps)
>> Members of the press,
we've always been committed
to the safety of those
who live here in underworld.
We are increasingly concerned by
the unrest and lawlessness
coming from above.
We are under attack.
And we must fight back.
I present to you
a scientific marvel
which will ensure
your protection
for the coming century.
80 percent human
20 percent machine
and 100 percent
dedicated to its mission.
Ladies and gentlemen
I give to you
the TC2000X.
(clapping)
>> Grand master.
(speaking in foreign language)
(fighting sequence)
(clapping and cheering)
>> Hey, look over here.
Are there anymore of you
where you come from?
>> Over here.
>> Get a close up shot.
>> Can you come this way please.
>> Hey TC,
who's the next model?
>> 2000, what 20 percent
of you is not human?
(cameras clicking)
>> Zoey, I have to kill you.
(gun firing)
>> Cybernetic Trackers.
Controller you're making
a mistake.
(murmuring)
You're the key Zoey.
(drums beating)
(people yelling)
(exotic music)
>> Hey big boy.
Looking for a good time?
(exotic music)
(background chatter)
>> The time for betting is over
the time for fighting is now.
>> Yeah!
>> Our challenger tonight
has the speed of the jaguar
the strength of the rhino
sting of the scorpion.
He's Zap!
(cheering)
He's known throughout
the territory
for his skills and cunning,
he's a survivour.
Master of all
who come before him
the reigning champion
Sumai!
(cheering)
(dramatic music)
It will be the greatest
prize we have to offer.
The two that have entered here
only one may leave.
Kari.
(cheering)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Yeah! Yeah!
(fighting sequence)
>> Look out Sumai
he's got a knife.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Yaah!
(gong clanging)
>> Come on, let's move.
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
(people yelling)
>> Miller, Basil,
what a surprise.
>> Yeah for you,
let's get
this traitor out of here.
>> Bah!
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
>> Forget about Sumai,
get me the girl.
>> Yaah!
>> I'll take care of this bitch.
Yaah!
>> Yaah!
>> Ooh!
Yaah!
>> Yaah!
>> Aah!
(fighting sequence)
>> Yaah!
>> Aah!
>> Stop!
Join us?
>> I thought you'd never ask.
(grunting)
(mellow music)
>> You have earned
my father's respect tracker
that is very rare.
>> Name is Jason.
He helps me, I help him.
Far as I'm concerned,
we're even.
He wishes to
thank you anyway.
>> How did you
end up with that?
That belongs to you, you know,
you would have won the fight.
But I accept something a little
more precious than water.
And that's information.
I'm looking for a guy
with a painting on his face.
>> Niki Picasso.
>> That sounds like
the man that fits his face.
>> There are very few who do not
know of Niki Picasso.
>> What of Niki?
>> He killed my partner
and that's why I'm here.
>> He has
terrorized us for years.
>> Why hasn't someone
stopped him?
Sumai, you're a great warrior,
why haven't you taken him on?
>> I am one man.
>> Niki's stand is many.
>> Well then,
let's go play his game.
Let's go round up some good
fighters and go kick his ass.
>> Only the Lifers will
stand up to Niki Picasso.
>> Let's go get the Lifers
and pay Niki a visit.
>> The Lifers are a brotherhood
of vicious criminals.
A closed society.
They protect,
Terminal Station.
>> Terminal Station.
>> Terminal Station is
a chemical warfare plant.
The population of the surface
world was to be eliminated
when the ozone layer
repaired itself.
>> That's insane.
>> So far,
it has been impenetrable.
There is some fear
that someone discovered
the key and activated it.
>> Picasso?
>> Niki Picasso's
very clever but.
>> Niki Picasso's going down
with you or without you.
>> Go by, day.
>> It's the only way to get
close to Niki's fortress.
He thinks no one is stupid
enough to go by day.
>> No one ever accused me
of being bright.
>> Now why should
I trust you?
You've been sent
by the Controller.
>> I've been programmed to
rescue surface world
at any cost.
And you will help us.
You have a great army
of warriors
You and the Picasso's are
the only fighters that can
defeat the protectors
of Terminal Station.
>> It's simple.
You get me safely to
the Terminal Station's door
and the Controller will get you
whatever you want.
>> The last time
I worked with the Controller
I almost got my ass shot.
>> Well this one, I will
personally guarantee it.
(wind blowing)
>> Sumai?
>> You're crazy to go alone.
>> Crazy to go together.
>> But much less crazy.
In day, the Picasso sleep.
>> Let's make our way
to the tower.
(wind blowing)
>> Niki Picasso down there,
very difficult.
>> No problem.
Tracker School 101.
So we have two choices Sumai,
either I lower you
or you lower me.
>> Don't forget to write.
>> Wise choice.
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
(heavy footsteps)
(ball bouncing)
(thump on table)
>> Where is it?
I know it's here, somewhere.
(dramatic music)
>> Yeah!
(spinning record on turn table)
Can you hear it honey?
(grunting)
>> Aah!
>> Go back.
I've waited a long time
for this moment
you killed my partner.
>> Killed who?
Oh no!
>> Don't screw with me,
you sack of shit.
>> Hey, hey don't kill
the messenger of good news.
(grunting)
She's still alive.
>> Bullshit!
How do you know?
>> I know
much more than you think.
Where do you think
I got this?
Does this look familiar to you?
Okay, okay
you want to see her?
Honey,
you got a visitor in here.
(dramatic music)
(heavy footsteps)
>> Zoey!
>> Easy boy.
She's a wild woman.
>> Partner!
>> Yaah!
(grunting)
Yaah!
(dramatic music)
>> Zoey, please.
>> Yaah!
Yaah!
>> Zoey, stop it.
>> Yaah!
(grunting)
Yaah!
Hey!
(grunting)
(dramatic music)
>> Zoey, stop it!
(Picasso laughing)
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
Yaah!
>> Come on Zoey.
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
>> Zoey, stop it!
(computer static)
>> Zoey, no I can't fight you.
>> What?
(computer static)
(gun firing)
What?
(computer override)
(laughing)
Yaah!
(grunting)
(computer override)
Yaah!
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
>> Bye, bye Jason.
>> Yaah!
(dramatic music)
>> What the hell happened Sumai?
>> TC2000X.
>> You've been unconscious
for a day now.
Much has happened.
What is the benefit
of this android?
>> She's no android.
Her name is Zoey.
She used to be my partner.
>> The Lifers
have encountered her.
>> Lifers, oh man.
If Niki gets her
to the Terminal Station
do you know what that means?
The end of surface world.
We got to get going.
>> Rest!
(dramatic music)
>> We'll make our move soon.
Lifers must be surprised
that they can be defeated.
>> Nobody has ever
defeated the Lifers.
>> But we will Niki,
we'll kill them all.
Enter Terminal Station
and all of surface world
will be ours.
>> Gentlemen!
>> All power will be yours.
>> What the hell is going on?
Why isn't she leading him back
to the Terminal Station?
>> She's merely
fulfilling my program.
Love takes time.
>> Did I ask you for an android
on hormone overdrive.
Your counter-programming
could jeopardize
this whole operation.
>> She's gotten
this far hasn't she.
>> This far,
is not good enough.
Now you,
get her back on track.
Before the Overlord finds out
that she's even
up there, all right.
(dramatic music)
(drums beating)
>> Is it true
the energy transfers
power through the objects?
Will you teach me?
>> Yes!
(dramatic music)
(Sumai yelling)
(watermelon smashing)
>> Sumai I can't remember
the last time I felt so great.
Feel like
I'm part of a team now.
I mean I'd be still
with Kinsella but...
>> Kinsella!
>> Zoey Kinsella,
what's up?
>> A man named Bertram Kinsella
built Terminal Station.
to replenish the atmosphere.
Instead, it became
the ultimate weapon of death.
>> Zoey's father.
>> My father often told me
of a young girl
who was the sunshine
of this brilliant man's life.
Before he was murdered.
>> Zoey's father,
Terminal Station.
How do you actually open up
the gate Sumai?
>> This is still a mystery.
>> It died with
Bertram Kinsella.
>> I don't think so.
Zoey's father
once gave her necklace.
>> What did it look like?
>> It was a child's hand
outstretched holding a...
>> A Key.
>> Bingo!
>> There it is Niki,
Terminal Station.
>> It's not going to be easy.
>> Nothing worth waiting for
should be easy.
>> You're learning to play
hardball aren't you?
>> And so do I.
Ooh!
>> I got this one Niki.
Yaah!
>> Aah!
>> We'll need all the Picassos
for this one.
(dog barking)
>> For crying out loud,
where is she going?
Why don't you stay focused?
>> All is working out,
I trust.
>> Fine.
Fine. Couldn't be better.
>> Good. Good, that's what
I like to hear.
The TC2000X,
everything's working out?
>> Like a charm.
Everything is going
completely according to plan.
>> Yes, I can see that.
Let's hope it stays that way.
(dramatic music)
(training sequence)
>> I think we're ready.
>> To soon.
Whether it's controlling Niki
or sealing up
the Terminal Station.
I'm not going to
sit around here watching.
Why don't you
guys join forces?
And try to squash
this little parasite.
>> There's a limit
to hospitality,
and you're coming
dangerously close.
>> Sumai.
What are you going to do?
>> Enough!
>> Sorry, I was pushy,
but your people need a leader.
And I think it's
your father's time.
>> You want all the answers?
The station my father knows,
the inside and out.
When they asked him
to come here,
it was to train guards to
protect military secrets
not guards
for instruments of death.
>> They lied to your father,
it wasn't his fault.
(heavy footsteps)
(machinery humming)
>> What the hell are you doing
out of the control room?
>> I had to take a dump
for crying out loud.
>> Well, you're the genius.
Figure out some way to do that
while you watch that monitor.
I'm not done with you yet.
If this thing screws up
you'll go down with me.
Do you have
a problem with that?
>> Yeah, I do.
I created the perfect protector
not the perfect killer.
>> It's the same thing,
other side of the coin, kid.
Anyway, I didn't
see you complaining
when you had Zoey Kinsella's
body to fondle in this project.
>> I suppose you figure no one
would notice one more boy,
that wasn't perfect.
You orchestrated it all
from the control room.
And that
bad team rushed in
and all of a sudden
she was on my table.
And you knew.
You knew no one
would ever realize
what had really killed her?
>> And what's that?
A bullet from a handgun, hmm.
A handgun, like this.
Wrong kid.
Guns don't kill people,
people kill people.
(gun firing)
(dramatic music)
Well, well, well.
You were closer to the truth
than you thought lover boy.
>> Lifers, guard
Terminal entrance here.
And we going to hide over here.
>> First, we need more fighters.
The Lifers are very tough.
>> Sumai, you're okay.
(dramatic music)
Listen, you people need to
get with the program.
Sumai said it all.
The time to act is now.
>> We trust Sumai,
but Niki's a killer.
>> The old guy
struts his stuff
and you're all ready to
drop to your knees.
Well go ahead
and let this little fossil
get you all killed.
If you're looking for a leader,
I'm right here.
This guy's a joke.
(crowd murmuring)
>> My time to lead.
(dramatic music)
(fighting sequence)
>> Who will join us
to fight Niki Picasso?
(dramatic music)
>> I vouch for these two.
(training sequence)
>> We've just
gotten word from Niki.
>> That's good Bigelow,
our plans are unfolding nicely.
So, we have a lot to do.
>> An extended coffee break,
I presume.
There's a little something
I want to discuss with you.
It concerns my
TC2000X.
>> Well, sir your
TC2000X, is just fine.
>> Really?
The TC2000X was conceived
to protect the people
in my quadrant,
that was her sole purpose.
I want you and your boys
to catch the next bus
to surface world
and I want my investment
back here, now.
(laughing)
>> Bigelow.
>> You wouldn't not here,
not now in front of everybody.
(groaning loudly)
>> Bigelow,
I think you're going to
like living on surface world.
(dramatic music)
(thunder rumbling)
(dog barking)
>> Guys are going to
protect Terminal Station
with their lives.
We'll just see about that.
>> Clancy, Blade
take out the guards.
Zircon, follow behind.
(dramatic music)
>> Yaah!
>> Ooh!
(dramatic music)
>> Death to the Lifers!
(gun firing)
(people screaming and yelling)
Done.
>> Shit!
>> Yaah! Yaah!
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Death to the Lifers!
(fighting sequence)
>> Looks like Niki Picasso
beat us to it.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
Let's let them
kill off the Lifers.
And then we make our move.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Well you got me to
the Terminal Station.
Now, let's just wait
for the Controller.
>> Let's party.
(dramatic music)
(can clinking)
Okay!
I got you your Citadel.
>> You've done
a soldier's job Niki.
And you'll get
everything I promised.
Guns, ammunition
and real food.
(people cheering)
>> And then what?
>> See then you will live
like Kings and Queens
here on the surface world.
You stay here,
we'll be right back.
>> Heh, No.
I'm going up too. I'm not
letting you out of my sight.
The key to her father's house.
And the key to my future.
Now it's time
for daddy's little girl
to get down on
her knees isn't it?
Because daddy's little girl
was much smaller
when he made this lock.
Would you?
(beeping)
>> Positive identification.
>> It is time.
(machines whirring loudly)
(door opening)
(people cheering)
Let's go!
>> Okay!
>> Attention Christmas shoppers.
The store is now closing.
>> Let's go!
(dramatic music)
>> You know, your father
was a brilliant man Zoey.
Unfortunately,
he was also a fool.
He thought he could
save the surface world.
He died before the full power of
Terminal Station was realized.
(machines whirring)
(footsteps running)
>> Come on, let's go.
(heavy footsteps)
>> The Kill Zone is only
accessible from the top floor.
So we'll cut through
the cook house here
under the stairs.
(men yelling)
>> Be careful.
(Sumai yelling)
(dramatic music)
>> Who the hell are they?
>> It's Jason Storm
and Master Sumai.
>> And what are they doing here?
>> Don't look at me.
Blade go help them, come on.
Move!
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Bitch!
Yaah!
(fighting sequence)
(laughing)
Yaah!
>> Ooh! Aah!
(laughing)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Stop!
Where's the Controller?
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> This way.
>> Any problems?
>> No problems.
>> Harold.
Kill Zone's
right through that door.
(Controller snickering)
Scott, guard the rear.
(footsteps running)
We won't be a minute.
>> I may start liking
surface world.
(jacket thudding on ground)
>> I'll check it out.
(dramatic music)
>> Ooh! Aah!
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
(heavy footsteps)
(key pad beeping)
(door opening)
>> Welcome to the Kill Zone.
>> Sumai!
Welcome home.
(Bigelow laughing)
(Sumai yelling)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> So why do you call this
the Kill Zone?
>> This was originally built to
replenish the atmosphere.
But a few modifications
have been made since then.
(Controller laughing)
>> I got us here.
>> Yes TC, you're finished.
Ironic isn't it.
Your program
and your father's program
both wind down in the same room.
(Controller laughing)
Come Niki, let me show you
what real power feels like.
(dramatic music)
>> It's my turn!
>> Aah!
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> This launcher contains
the chemicals,
individually they're inert
but you mix them together
it's as deadly as cyanide.
48 hours later
the effect dies out.
>> And you take over
surface world.
>> We take over
surface world Niki,
but let's talk about that later.
(lasers beaming)
(dramatic music)
>> Lasers, you idiot,
we're trapped.
>> No Niki, you're trapped.
(Controller laughing)
(panel beeping)
>> Attention!
The surface world cleansing
sequence has been activated.
All non-essential
personnel must report to
designated safety zones.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
(computer screen beeping)
Attention! The death launch
mechanism has been activated.
>> Zoey, take the elevator out.
Zoey, what's wrong with you?
Cameron's program
really fucked you up.
It's such a shame.
(missile launching)
(alarm beeping)
(explosion)
(Sumai yelling)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Attention all personnel!
You must follow
specified procedures
and report to
designated safety zones.
Death launch mechanism
has been activated.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> I'll show ya.
I got you.
>> Follow specified procedures
and report to
safety zones immediately.
Death launch mechanism
has been activated.
Surface world cleansing
has commenced.
>> They're destroying
the surface world.
>> I know.
>> Aah!
>> Last chance Zoey.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
(panel beeping)
(alarm beeping)
(flashbacks)
(missile launching)
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Attention! Sodium bromide
has been launched...
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
(man screaming
being electrocuted)
>> Beep, beep,
shut the damn machine down.
(missile launching)
(explosion)
>> Can't hear you Niki.
They love a blitz.
Insufficient time now exist to
travel to the safety zones.
If you have not reported to
your designated area
you must use
emergency precautions now.
High pressure chambers will...
3, 5 and 7.
Emergency supplies
will be within.
Repeat.
Insufficient time now exists
for travel to safety zones.
If you have not reported to
your designated area
you must use
emergency precautions now.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Aah!
Warning! Gaseous chemical will
be launched at 2 minute mark.
Layer 4 of the atmospheric gases
will be discharged.
Stage 4 of the surface world
cleansing will be complete.
(dramatic music)
>> Open the door.
(fighting sequence)
(dramatic music)
>> Aah!
(alarm beeping)
>> Live long Sumai!
You know the world's
falling apart.
>> Open the door.
>> Over my dead body.
(alarm beeping)
You were once
a great warrior Sumai.
But now,
you are nothing.
(Sumai yelling)
>> Aah!
>> Nice punch.
>> Come on.
>> Launched at 1 minute mark.
>> Damn!
>> All nucleic layers
will be replaced
and ready for chemical catalyst
1, 2 and 3.
Prepare for chemical fallout.
(dramatic music)
>> Aah! Goddamn!
>> I trusted you and you left me
down there to die.
>> We'll both die
if we don't get out of here.
>> You're going to die first.
>> No Niki,
I got the antidote
to the chemical.
No!
>> Thank you.
>> Niki! Aah! Please!
>> Aah!
(missile launching)
(explosion)
>> You're brilliant Sumai.
Deflect the laser
over to the right.
I'll take care of TC.
>> All death rays will be
launched in 2 minus 5 seconds.
(missile launching)
>> Zoey whatever happened
to partners forever?
(computer static)
>> Jason!
>> Zoey!
Jason.
>> Atmosphere glares are
in place...catalyst #2.
>> What the hell's going on?
>> Cameron put a virus in your
program to shut you down.
>> What?
>> Never mind!
We're in the Terminal Station
that your father built.
How do we stop this thing?
>> My father would have left
some sort of password
or something.
>> It's Zoey,
you're the key.
>> Yeah!
Of course, my necklace.
(computer beeping)
(missile launching)
>> I'll input Kinsella.
>> Execution of chemical...
>> Try Underworld.
>> Third and final catalyst
will be launched at Mark Zero .
Execution of all chemical
reactions will be complete.
And surface world
cleansing achieved.
Surface world cleansing will
commence at T minus 10 seconds.
10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4,
3, 2.
>> Life!
Zoey is Greek for Life.
You knew my father didn't you?
>> He told me.
>> Let's get the hell
out of here.
>> Niki come here.
Don't leave me up here.
Celebrate as the first.
Zoey save me,
save me, save me.
I've got the treatment.
>> Beautiful isn't it?
Mother Nature
really is healing herself.
>> This place, not so bad.
>> And the Controller
knew it all along.
>> Welcome home, partner.
Mother Nature
was healing herself.
And the Controller knew it.
It was people like him
that got us into this mess
in the first place.
But if the Earth
could start anew
perhaps so could we.
(dramatic music)
(drums beating)