If it gets on you,
just let me know, okay?
Really? Daichi has
started playing soccer?
Yes, but he's still a substitute.
Oh, I see. He's a substitute then.
Yes, but he's really enjoying it.
Being parents is not easy, right?
That's true.
Oh, Tamago, you're off to work now.
Be careful with the traffic, okay?
You've waited a long time.
I'm back, Chihiro.
Are you doing alright?
Good morning, Principal.
Good morning.
Amen.
Oh, Principal, welcome.
This taste is different from usual.
We switched to butter today.
So, the taste has changed a bit.
It's butter, huh?
Do you remember
the taste of our family's bread?
Yes, but it's not the same.
Due to rising ingredient prices,
we had to switch to cheaper materials.
But, well...
The previous taste was still better, right?
A long time ago, I told my family that...
Finally, I've made up my mind now.
I think it's time to close down this shop.
Well, um...
I've thought about it a lot.
I'm tired of it now.
Do you still remember when you...
You've mentioned the phrase
(shùnshuǐ tuīzhōu) to me before.
Yes, this phrase is not used
to describe going against the current.
The correct usage is when you
follow the direction of the river's flow.
You paddle with a bamboo pole
to increase the momentum of the water.
That's right.
Just now, you demonstrated "shùnshuǐ tuīzhōu" for me.
By the way, Principal...
Could you take a photo with me?
As a final memory,
I'd like to have a photo with you.
Oh, sure!
Impressive!
It's too close now.
Principal.
Today's weather is nice too, isn't it?
Hard to say.
How about playing a game?
Want to play a game?
Oh, I still have work to do.
Excuse me.
Look at how smug he is.
Still just like before,
really annoying.
What job does he have anyway?
I'm back.
Oh, you!
you are enough
That shop is closing.
This is the last chance.
This is...
What is this?
In French, it's called "roboket."
"把dikatiri"...
What are all these things?
Give it to Katie.
as…
Hey, hello!
Has it started?
Good morning.
Has Sora arrived?
Pay attention to it.
If you like it so much,
just keep it at your own home.
I'm considering it.
It's still in the process of dating.
I'm worried about these
potted plants all the time.
What if she pees on the potted plants?
Cats only go to specific places.
By the way, I saw a cat pooping
in the park not long ago.
Really? Did the cat run away?
No, it didn't.
So I kept watching it.
I heard that if a cat keeps pooping
while being observed by someone,
it means the cat doesn't fear that person.
Sora, come here.
Good boy.
Hey.
try pooping in front of me.
Shamisen: A traditional Japanese three-stringed musical instrument. There's a saying in Japan that shamisen used to be made with cat skin.
Look, I won't turn you into a shamisen.
(Imitating the sound of a shamisen)
Ping, ping, ping, ping.
Inside a cardboard box, the bodies of four
cats were found by the riverbank in Ogawa Town.
Here they come.
It's you.
I'm here again.
Hmm.
Didn't you have a lot of photographs?
You've never mentioned them to me.
Dealing with these hassles is
all part of working for the government.
Oh, you're back to photography again?
By someone's request.
Can I get you some coffee?
Ah, that reminds me.
I wanted to ask
you about this photograph.
When was it taken?
The school building's walls look strange.
It's from 1957 when
a dog was launched into
space aboard a Soviet rocket.
The dog was sent into space.
Only one dog?
Nowadays, animal welfare organizations
wouldn't stand by and do nothing.
But I think it's good.
Do you hate dogs?
No,
it's not that.
I mean, your photographs
I quite like them.
It's a way to document
the history of the streets and alleys.
I think you should get out more.
I'll go make some coffee.
Thank you.
Do you want anything in your coffee?
Only milk is an option.
Anything is fine.
Or, it doesn't matter.
Seems like you're not getting what I mean.
What? This gesture?
You're being too exaggerated.
I never said that.
Laika.
The first Earth creature to enter orbit
on the Soviet satellite Sputnik 2. The dog, Laika.
What?
Laika?
That's so cruel.
No one knows what
happened to that dog.
Oh, you mean
the Russian rocket incident.
What?
It was about the dog?
It's so confusing.
That's right,
that's it.
I brought this as a gift for Tamago.
Oh, I wonder if she'll like it.
It was even in the newspapers.
A cat was put into a box and
thrown into the river, drowning to death.
And there were four cats?
Really?
Yes, it's true. At that moment,
I thought of Tamago.
Here's this for you.
Ah, I never thought I'd have
to wear this kind of thing.
Times have truly changed.
Indeed.
Put it on the cat; that way,
I can feel more at ease.
Wouldn't it be great if it could
live freely as a stray cat?
His name,
in Russian, is Otdovich.
Is that interesting?
It sounds difficult to understand.
What's it about?
Well, this is a new translation
I've been working on recently.
A new translation?
Yes.
It's about a man born into serfdom.
Do you know what serfdom is?
I don't know.
Well,
serfs
were essentially
the lowest social class, peasants.
So, it's about a man from
the lowest rung of society.
A monk appears in his dreams,
a monk from Russia,
who says to him,
"One day, you will find enlightenment,
but before that, you will go through numerous
desperate situations and near-death experiences."
His prophecy comes true,
as the man's life is filled
with one cruel test after another.
In short, the story revolves
around the experiences of this man.
On his journey, he meets a duke
who asks
Are you an artist?
To which the man replies,
"Beauty is the pinnacle of creation.
For beauty, one wouldn't
hesitate to sacrifice oneself."
That's how he answered.
Ah.
Is the story interesting?
It's not a matter of whether
it's interesting or not.
So, do you find your
current work interesting?
I find it very intriguing.
Intriguing, you say?
Yes, well, that's good then.
Shh, be quiet.
Okay.
Tamako
watch out for cars!
One more time, one more time!
I'm back, Chihiro.
Sorry, I'm late.
It's wonderful, isn't it?
You have a home now, don't you?
Congratulations on your new home.
In today's English class,
we had a teacher
from Australia
named David.
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
Hey, sorry to keep you waiting.
You're really busy, huh?
I called you several times during the day,
but there was no answer.
Oh, it was the principal calling.
Is everything alright?
No,
it's just that the translation you asked me to do
isn't progressing smoothly.
What do you mean by that?
Exactly what it sounds like.
Hmm, I'll give you a mid-term report on it.
I'm amazed by you.
I never promised anything.
It's because you were bored
and asked me to translate that book.
Even if you complete it,
I'm not obligated to publish it, you know.
No, no, no. That's not what I meant.
I just wanted to make sure you
didn't forget about this task,
so I called you.
As long as you remember,
that's enough for me.
Alright,
don't focus too much on it either.
I'm afraid of having good intentions
but causing trouble, Principal.
You always have an
interesting way of speaking.
Alright, I understand.
By the way,
I've noticed something interesting
about Russian literature.
It's not categorized based on
the time before or after the revolution,
but rather, it's divided by the
19th and 20th centuries.
I've come to understand this recently.
Oh no, the watch stopped.
Good morning.
Let's take another picture.
I'm going to take it.
Oh, it worked! Impressive!
5 cm.
Wow, amazing!
Principal,
one more time,
just once more.
He smiled;
what a silly guy.
I'm back.
Oh,
where did you come in from?
What's up?
Do you have any objections to me?
Enough is enough.
Don't come any closer.
You annoying brat!
So that's it, it's "Nicheu-ōnie."
Just mutter something, mutter, mutter.
"Dī-kā-tī-rīkā."
Is that French?
Ouch!
Want me to do it?
I'm feeling motivated.
Sora probably won't come anymore.
Why?
Someone found a cat's body
by the river in Kogawa Town.
It was on the news.
Ah, here she comes.
Sora
Sora's roaming range is at most
only five hundred meters.
It's unlikely for she to go all the
way to Kogawa Town.
Why are you getting angry at me?
What's wrong, Sora?
The collar...
Oh, hello.
Long time no see,
Principal.
I'm sorry.
When I was fortunate enough to get into college,
I received your congratulatory note.
However, I was planning to return to school,
but things didn't go as smoothly as I hoped,
so
I haven't decided what to do next.
No, it's just that...
that
What about
Cat?
Are you talking about Sora?
Sora
is a stray cat living around here.
She hasn't changed a bit
and is still as arrogant as ever.
Is she dead?
She's alive, not dead.
It's okay; I'll take her to the hospital.
Shall we head to school?
Is that a small knife?
The blade is thin,
like a paper cutter.
Is she dead?
Although the wound is not deep,
there was a lot of bleeding.
She took medicine and is now resting.
Do you want to go see her?
No need.
Shogo, wake Grandma up.
Okay.
Grandma went to eat over there.
Here.
Unfortunately, we couldn't film
the Great Jade Jizo.
Please understand it through my face,
voice, and other elements
Well, let me take a look at the real thing first.
Wow, it's awe-inspiring!
How can I put it?
It's impressive.
Ah, it can't stand up anymore.
The photos are already developed.
Is the boss here?
Store Closure Notice
Thank you for your long-time patronage,
dear customers.
Thank you.
Freshly Baked Bakery
Lily.
Go a bit over there.
Stay a little further.
Look this way.
Hello there.
Yes.
I understand.
I'll be right there.
Grandma.
Inside.
I'm sorry.
Cat.
I'm allergic to cats.
Grandma, someone
has come to take you back.
Get up, Pamp.
Can you stand up?
watch your step.
Grandma, please don't
wander around.
Don't cause trouble for your caregivers.
I'm still at work.
Shuichi.
I'm Shogo.
Shuichi is my father.
I'm Grandma's grandson.
You even forgot your grandson's face.
Blaming her will only
make her more confused.
Then what should I do?
My dad won't be back until the evening.
I have a job too.
What's it to me?
Grandma, let me walk you.
She's gone.
Over there,
on the other side.
Please do not feed stray cats.
Some people feed stray cats, but this is a selfish and irresponsible behavior.
Please don't contribute to the increasing number of cats.
Wait a moment.
What are you doing?
Cats.
I'm a bit hungry too.
I'm hungry too
Yesterday's store promotion,
I bought a lot of stuff.
If you can,
please try some.
Hmm.
It's really delicious.
What's wrong?
The butter is different.
Um,
there's something I want to ask you.
There's something I just can't understand.
Teacher, the note you gave me,
I can't comprehend it no matter what.
It's this one.
I looked it up in the dictionary and asked others,
but I still couldn't figure it out.
It means "please do your best"
or "keep up the good work."
Have I done something?
I've been thinking that
way for a long time.
You can always say
"1, 2" and such things, right?
You're here.
Why?
Did you want to become a teacher?
Do you want to be a teacher too?
Not really.
I see.
As for me...
that is
I just go with the flow.
So
what did you want to be when you were a child?
Akato Suzunosuke.
That's a character from an anime, right?
No, it's from a TV drama.
How about you?
i can't remember.
I've been thinking about it since earlier.
Is there anything good
about being a teacher?
None.
Quick answer, huh?
After becoming the principal,
There's nothing.
Being a principal
seems quite challenging, huh?
When I was young,
I was happy.
No matter what child it was,
As long as I personally taught them,
there would be a change.
Humans are truly the most interesting.
Because that's still an obedient age,
And I am enthusiastic about it.
Even with personal guidance,
there are times when it's not possible.
Good morning.
Ah Tamago..
You're up early today.
Tamago.
Oh, Tamako, not going to take a nap?
And then the other person...
And then the other person, yes, yes.
Hurry up and disappear.
Quickly now.
That is...
No, be quick about it.
I won't open the door for you.
I've locked the kitchen window too.
Give up quickly, give up.
Go away.
Let me say this straight.
Every time you come here,
I'm reminded of my deceased wife.
Every day,
every day,
I'm fed up with it.
Don't come again.
I told you,
You're so annoying.
Listen to me.
It's not just our family.
You run around everywhere,
causing trouble,
And making misguided advances.
Do you think doing that will
make everyone pay attention to you?
I just can't stand your personality.
If it were only at my house,
that would be fine.
No, don't come to my house anymore.
Go to other places to please others.
I don't want to deal with you.
It's been a while.
It looks like it might rain.
The pronunciation of "tenkuu" (sky) is the same as "tenkuu" (rare encounter).
Look at the sky.
Mimi is here.
Come, come, come.
I've been waiting
for you for a long time.
What's wrong?
Nothing, it's fine.
It always comes around this time.
Because it also knows.
It knows the time.
Name: Sora A tricolor female cat Wearing a red collar around the neck The collar has a golden bell Not a domesticated cat, but often visits our store It hasn't appeared for about a week, and we are a bit worried
Welcome.
Principal.
Your wife used to take care
of our business regularly.
Long time no see,
Principal.
The flyers outside...
Ah, they're not ours, you know.
It's just that we can't
help but be concerned, right?
Is there something you need?
When did you last see it?
Didn't you say it's been a week?
Really?
Maybe someone adopted her.
That would be good.
We just want to confirm, right?
yes.
Principal,
is the cat here?
No.
That's suspicious.
What are its traits?
Traits?
It's quite aloof
and independent.
If you call its name,
it might respond to you.
Some people call it "Tamako,"
and others call it "Sora."
It's friendly with people around here,
but not with me.
May I ask, what breed is your cat?
Breed? It's just an aloof breed.
Specific characteristics?
It's a tricolor cat.
A tricolor cat.
Yes, an ordinary tricolor cat.
Where are the spots located?
Spots? Um,
they are similar to a crescent moon here.
Alright.
The colors are relatively light.
The area around the eyes is brown.
brown, right?
Yes, that's right.
Alright, I got it.
Principal...
Let's see.
How about taking a look?
That's incredible, isn't it?
Annoying.
Was it you who broke it, Mie.
Dad really likes this curtain, you know.
How can you not cherish it?
Ah, wait.
Thank you so much.
Goodbye.
Oh, Principal.
Do you want to see a cat?
What?
what did you say?
Do you want to see a cat?
Ah, a cat?
But I heard
that when cats die,
they hide themselves.
You idiot!
Are you alright?
By the way, teacher,
have you been to the health station?
Health station?
People from the Environmental Health Department said
that many cats were taken to the health station.
Then I'll go to the health station.
You can't get there by riding a bicycle.
It's far. Take the bus, it's five stops away.
Five stops?
Yes.
Five stops won't work either.
There's a bus stop over there.
Really?
No.
Fujimi-cho San-Chome Station.
Please take your belongings
and prepare to get off.
I need to get off.
Yesterday, the principal
came to look for the cat.
Really?
When?
Ah, it was just after noon.
That's interesting.
Why?
Why is it interesting?
Maybe he came to look for
the cat after seeing the flyers
the ladies at the hair salon made.
Flyers?
We're looking for a cat,
so we need to use photos.
Use photos?
Yes.
Then, let's put the photos like this, here.
- Write "Missing Cat
- Looking for this cat" on them.
Hello there.
Oh, Mayumi!
Long time no see, what's up?
Sora.
she said sora.
Do you know it?
I started feeding it a month ago.
I was worried it might get hit by a car,
but it didn't show up at the hospital.
Principal,
I've been looking for it everywhere,
even went to the health station.
So, we also want to
do whatever we can to help.
Indeed.
Many people may not like this child much,
but leaving it like this is just too pitiful.
Right.
I want to join too.
Let me participate.
After it went missing,
I realized that the time I spent feeding
it was essential to me.
So, please let me help you find it.
Alright, thank you. Sit here.
Thank you.
- Pass me the glue.
- Alright.
Glue, huh?
Looking for this cat.
Hello.
Hey, wait!
Ah, can I put this up here?
I'll be troubled if you do that.
How much was it, 70 yen? 70?
Then, how about here?
No.
100 yen?
105 yen?
Then, how about here?
No.
So, where do you want me to put it then?
You want me to put it here,
but you have this attitude?
I'm not doing charity here.
Why do you insist on putting
up these missing cat posters?
I thought you also cared about that cat.
I'm sorry.
Never mind.
Just leave it there.
I'll think about where to put it later.
Goodbye.
Mie, Sora, Tamago.
what are you doing?
i am looking for a cat.
A cat?
Is it your pet?
No,
it's a stray cat.
Hey.
Can I take a look at that?
Let me tell you a place
where you can put it up.
Sorry to bother you.
Kagawa Fujikawa.
Where is this cat from?
Ah, it's from Fujimi Town.
Cats are very cautious creatures.
I don't think it would cross
the river to come here.
There are also
people who don't like cats.
They put the cat in
a car and throw it far away.
But this cat is fearless of humans.
I'll lend you this.
A cage?
Put cat food and
its favorite things inside.
Maybe it'll come in.
If you want to take care of the cat,
this is necessary.
Alright.
People who feed
stray cats are like this.
They love and play with
the cat but don't take responsibility.
They never think about the cat itself.
Because of these people,
the number of stray cats keeps increasing.
Eventually, they end up in shelters.
Are you criticizing me?
of course.
I'm sorry for putting you in a place like this.
Anything is possible.
Stay here for now.
I'm leaving.
Thank you.
Let's put it up here.
Missing Cat Notice.
Grandma.
Is it tasty?
Have some.
Awesome, really awesome.
- How is it?
-Impressive.
Mie
Tamago.
Sora
Mie
Come here.
Tamago
Mie
Mie..
Are you okay?
Ah...
Did you drop something?
i'm looking for a cat.
A cat?
Am I that funny?
Anyway, would you like some?
Your meal.
i'm not a cat.
Cat allergies,
they can't be cured, right?
What's wrong?
I'd like to ask you to
help me find a good cat.
Because when my grandma
was here with that cat,
she was always very happy.
Mie, Mie, Mie.
Mie
what are you doing?
Come down from there.
Come down.
Can you hear me?
Come down from there.
If it's not a domestic cat,
can't you search for it?
The problem is, you can't wander
around busy streets late at night.
Maybe it's had an accident.
We have to find it.
But it's just a stray cat.
that kid saved my life.
Cats are nocturnal,
we can only search at night
Around here,
there might be a gathering of cats.
A gathering of cats?
I mean, what are you doing?
Uh, you know, this and that...
I've run out of options.
Sorry.
This time was supposed to be
for taking care of Dad and Grandma.
Let's go.
Alright, let's go.
It's really funny.
You...
I was asking the young girl.
Can you tell me where
the gathering of cats is?
Alright.
The principal just sits there,
looking dumbfounded.
So funny!
Hey, isn't this funny?
It's you!
I heard about this and
was wondering if it was you.
What?
Do you two know each other?
He scolded me once.
You, the principal?
Lately, I keep getting scolded.
Never mind, get in the car.
Thank you for your trouble.
The girl earlier said
that the cat saved her life.
I...
I've been bullied at school all the time,
and the teachers won't help me.
I can't tell my parents either.
I thought it would be better to just die.
So, I ran onto the main road.
At that moment,
I heard a cat meowing.
chihiro
Always
It stayed by my side,
That's why
this time,
I want to save Chihiro.
Tamago, it's time to eat.
Sora...
Doesn't seem to be here.
Or here.
Help me with the light.
Let's go to the next place.
Alright.
Tamago...
Sora...
Hey!
Is this where the cats are gathering?
I thought the cats were having
some kind of meeting together.
Let's split up and search.
I'll drive and check other gathering spots.
Don't get taken away by
the police again, okay?
Yeah, that's how it is.
Exactly.
Tamago...
Chihiro...
Mie.
Tamago...
Chihiro...
Mie.
Chihiro Chihiro.
Sora..
Chihiro.
Mie.
Mimi, Sora, Tamago.
Chihiro.
Tamago.
Mie,
Mie.
Chihiro.
Tamago.
Mie.
Tamago, Tamago.
Chihiro.
Tamago..
Sora..
Chihiro.
Tamago.
Mie.
Wait, wait.
Mie
Mie.
Tamago, Sora.
Come and have your meal.
Sora.
It's mealtime, come on.
small sky
Give the principal some barley tea.
Sure.
All I need to do is pamper it more.
I'm really frustrated with myself.
Every time the cat comes to my house,
it reminds me of my deceased wife.
That's why I drive it away
and tell it not to come back.
When it comes to say goodbye to my home,
I should let it bid farewell properly.
Until it's satisfied.
I don't want to think about it,
But I don't want to forget either.
Principal
You've changed.
You must have fallen for a kitty.
Want another drink?
Yes, please. Thanks.
Even if we find it,
we can't chase after it.
Then what should we do?
We can only wait.
Approach it slowly,
Give it cat food,
Keep calling it,
And keep waiting like this.
Even if we find it,
It might not be a good idea.
After going missing,
If it had a bad experience,
Its personality might change.
We need to be patient.
The principal,
I'm sure we can do it.
I'm starting to eat.
What's wrong?
ah
I CAN DO IT.
Is this a dad joke or something?
Hey, what are you talking about?
Nothing.
Stop right there!
I'll call the police if you run again!
It's late at night,
I can't just ignore it.
Ah, Principal, do you know this kid?
I only know he's not a cat.
Seriously...
When did you start coming here?
Let's stop here for today.
I have to take this kid back.
Alright, see you tomorrow.
Yeah,
See you tomorrow
Got it.
See you tomorrow.
Goodbye.
Come out quickly.
Where's your backpack?
Don't drag your backpack.
Principal.
Pack your backpack properly.
Principal!
Ah, it's you.
- Spare me, please.
- Yeah, right.
Don't be so dismissive.
I stopped looking for
the cat and went to look for you midway.
How many times have I called you?
Seriously...
I'm sorry. Anyway...
I thought I'd leave it at
that today after telling everyone.
So stubborn.
Who is everyone?
Ah, that...
Hello, good evening.
Good evening.
So, is everyone
also looking for the cat?
Yes
Me too.
Is that so? Thanks.
You're welcome.
Where have you been looking today?
I went to Fuji Ichome
and around the port area.
Is that so?
I heard the cats are having
a gathering around the port.
So I went there.
I thought a cat gathering
would be like a meeting,
but they were just sitting there.
Any other news?
Is Tamago not there?
No, it's not there.
i am allergic to cats.
I see.
Did you put up flyers around the port?
Yes, I did.
That's great.
- Are you hungry? Want one?
- Thank you.
There are also rice balls.
It's a shame I couldn't search with everyone.
What about tomorrow?
Will you continue tomorrow?
of course.
Then I'll join you.
Why are you looking for the cat?
Because it's important.
it's just a stray cat.
But that's also important.
is it still alive?
I don't know,
maybe it's already gone
Maybe it's already dead.
No matter what living creature it is,
they will all eventually die.
So, the remaining companions
will work hard to mediate their relationships.
I can go back alone.
Let's go together.
Today,
i don't want to be alone.
Principal, thank you so much.
I'm really sorry.
Honey.
The cat is here!
Hurry, come over here.
I don't know whose cat it is;
it might be a stray.
Even so, you really aren't afraid of people, huh?
Have you been getting food
from various places?
You're so lucky.
Does it look like the deceased mie?
Spare me, please.
I've had enough of cats.
Alright, alright.
If you dislike cats,
you won't understand one of life's great joys.
Come over every day from now on.
Stop it; let's leave cat alone.
Why?
They'll die anyway.
Of course, they will.
Aren't we going to die too?
But we will live longer than them.
Let it live its life on its own.
Don't be like this.
Don't be like this;
you might grow fond of it.
Isn't that nice too?
Darling.