This is the dream
grown young.
The dream so bravely tended
through a century of fears.
Through the years of working,
praying, striving, learning,
the dream become a beacon
brightly burning.
Black colleges are spaces
where black people are affirmed.
You could be yourself
and develop yourself
in this rich soil.
It's a space that is
an unapologetic black space.
These are places where there's
incredible freedom to explore.
Wade: We wanted
to better ourselves.
We wanted to have an institution
where there's people like us,
all wanted to be more
than the status quo.
Crenshaw: The question
for African Americans has
always been,
what is education's purpose?
Who controls it?
And what is the relationship
with education
to the broader aspirations
of our people?
♪ Well, I need more power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I didn't need more power ♪
♪ I need the everlasting power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
Marrs: "On every gate
around the stable
as on the plow handles,
you can see where I had
been trying to write
and every chance that offered
would be learning my ABCs" --
Elijah Marrs.
"There were some niggers
that wanted learnin' so bad,
they would study by the light
of lightwood torches,
but one thing sure --
They'd better not let no white
folks find out about it" --
William McWeather.
Slavery was more brutal
than we can imagine.
Brutality went with the system.
Gasman: But there's another
type of brutality that
took place during slavery,
and that was the brutality
of ignorance,
keeping intellectual thought,
keeping learning,
keeping reading,
knowledge from slaves.
The more that a system
denies you the chance
to read and to write,
the more that thing,
reading and writing,
becomes valuable,
becomes precious,
becomes a prize that
you must have.
"I had no schooling
whatsoever while I was a slave.
On several occasions, I went
as far as the schoolhouse door
with one of my young mistresses.
I had the feeling that
getting into that schoolhouse
would be the same
as getting into paradise,"
Booker T. Washington.
When they saw white people
reading, enslaved people
called that
"talking to books."
The idea that
this piece of paper
that someone was looking at,
they could actually
communicate with,
gave them a sense that this
was a kind of knowledge
that opened up all kinds
of opportunities.
A slaveholder could
do virtually anything
to his slave.
He could work a slave to death.
He could rape a slave.
He could sell a slave.
"It's my property,"
the argument was.
"So I can do whatever I want to
with my property,
except one thing I can't do
to my property --
I can't teach my property.
I can't teach my slave
how to read or write."
An educated black population
could not be an enslaved
black population.
The teaching of slaves to
read and write has a tendency
to excite dissatisfaction
in their minds.
any person or persons
who shall attempt to teach
any free person of color
or slave to spell...
if a white man or woman be fined
no less than $100 or imprisoned.
shall be whipped
at the discretion of the court
not exceeding 50 lashes...
The revised code
of the laws of Virginia.
The state of Alabama...
The laws of North Carolina.
Acts and resolutions
of the state of South Carolina.
It didn't just
happen in the South.
Some abolitionists wanted
to start a college
for black youth in New Haven,
where Yale University
is located.
Yale and the town officials
said,
"No, absolutely not.
That's not happening here."
This letter is from the mayor
of New Haven, Connecticut,
and it says, "The location
of a college of blacks here
would be totally ruinous
to the city,
whose certain effect..."
Whose certain effect
will be to lower the town's
public morals,
to drive from our city
its female schools,
its throngs of summer visitors.
The founding of colleges
for educating colored people
is unwarrantable
and dangerous interference
with the internal concerns
of the Southern states
and ought to be discouraged.
It's happening all
over the country,
this discrimination,
this repression,
this desire to make sure
that black people remain
subordinate to whites
is something that's national.
It's not just Southern, at all,
and I think that we sometimes
forget that.
Booker: "When I was
still quite a child,
I could hear the slaves
in our quarters
whispering that
something unusual
was about to take place,
and it meant their freedom.
There was not a single slave
on our plantation
that could read a line,
but in some way,
we were kept informed
of the progress of the law" --
Booker T. Washington.
Washington: As soon as
the war breaks out,
African Americans flee
the plantation,
and once they get
behind Union lines,
they call them contrabands.
The first thing they want to do
is to get an education,
so in the evening,
when they finished their labor,
they go to these
contraband schools,
and as the women say,
catch a lesson.
♪ One by one, two by two ♪
♪ Three by three
and a four by four ♪
Adams: "I is anxious
to learn how to read
so I can study and find out
about many things" --
William Adams.
"It is wonderful how a
people who have been
so long crushed to the earth
can have so greedy desire
for knowledge
and such a capability
for attaining it.
One old woman took her seat
among the little ones.
She was, at least,
60 years old" --
Charlotte Forten.
They feel that,
if they can get an education,
if they can get knowledge,
then other things will follow.
This is the beginning
of education in the South.
Booker: Suddenly, as if
at the sound of a trumpet,
a whole race that
had been slumbering
for centuries in barbarism
awoke and started off
one morning...
to school.
In the immediate years
after the war,
one of the first things that
formerly-enslaved people did
was to open schools.
Many of the people who
were so-called teachers
were really not capable,
knowledge-wise,
of being teachers.
They were simply teaching
what they knew.
If they knew up
to a 6th grade level,
then that's what
they would teach,
and so the first thing that had
to be done after the war
was to train people
to actually teach.
After the Civil War was over,
the South is devastated
in all kinds of ways.
The American
Missionary Association
recognizes the damage,
and they see an opportunity
to save the South.
They come down and set up
all these schools.
"We can now lift
them out of the pit.
Essential parts of the work
can only be done
by Northern voluntary
Christian organizations.
They can bring physical relief.
They can establish schools,
and they can bear the light
of the Gospel."
Washington: The large majority
of them were also dedicated
to the idea that
the enslaved people
needed to be "civilized."
One person termed it
"Yankee-fied,"
and they want to create
a kind of culture
that is, essentially,
a white culture,
and the AMA is the main
independent organization
that set this up --
first the schools
and then colleges
that are going to evolve
into the historically
black colleges.
The African Methodist Episcopal Church,
the AME,
start to say, "Wait a second.
We want to have
our own education system
in terms that we understand.
We have ideas here,
black ideas."
And so they start forming
their own colleges.
They wanted those schools
to be as free as possible
from paternalism,
from racism,
whether subtle or blatant.
"No man or community of men
can elevate another.
Elevation must come from within.
What the North and the South,
however,
can do is to cease
their injustice
and allow the Negro
to educate himself" --
Bishop Benjamin Tanner,
AME Church.
The federal government
also began creating separate
public black and white colleges
in the South.
By the late 1800s, there were
over 86 black colleges.
Many of them were created
by the AME Church, the AMA,
and the federal government.
The South's reaction was
one of incredible anxiety.
Southern planters elite
had an investment
in this certain kind
of workforce,
a workforce that they had been
able to keep docile.
Education was going
to turn that upside down,
and the planter elite said,
"That simply can't happen."
In Tuskegee, Alabama,
nearly every black school
that developed in the county
was destroyed,
or the teachers were run off.
One of the heartbreaking stories
is the lynching of a professor
at Talladega
because he was teaching
African-American students.
He wrote this very powerful
letter to his wife.
"My dear wife...
I die tonight.
It has been determined by those
that think I deserve it.
God only knows I have only
sought to educate the Negro.
God of mercy,
bless you and keep you,
dear wife and children.
Your William."
Alexander:
Between 1866 and 1872,
approximately 20,000 people
are killed,
blacks and whites in the South,
all because of
this perceived threat
that education will
unlock something.
Taylor: Despite the violence
and intimidation,
the shortage of
teachers and resources,
the black colleges
in the South survived.
They began to produce
their first graduates...
many of whom were
formerly enslaved.
Anderson: General O.O. Howard,
for whom
Howard University is named,
he was going around looking at
the plight of African Americans,
and he ran across students,
and he asked,
"What shall I tell
the people up North
about the plight
of the former slaves?"
And the 13-year-old
Richard Robert Wright rose
and said,
"Tell them we are rising."
"Although I had no
idea where it was
or how many miles away,
I remember only that
I was on fire constantly
with one ambition,
and that was to go
to Hampton" --
Booker T. Washington.
Booker T. Washington
hears about Hampton College,
and he works his way there,
walking across
the state of Virginia.
This is a dedication
to a vision for education.
The Hampton Institute
was founded
by a retired Yankee general
named Samuel Armstrong,
and his approach was
to teach the trades --
carpentry, laundry work,
farming --
to black youths.
Samuel Chapman Armstrong
was, without a doubt,
someone who believed in the
inferiority of black people,
no question about that.
He didn't believe
that black people were
capable of anything more than
an industrial arts education.
He just could not see
black people advancing
beyond that.
Booker T. Washington --
He's really taken in
by Armstrong,
becomes his right hand.
Armstrong says very clearly
that Washington
is his prize student.
Samuel Armstrong recommended
Booker T. Washington
to head the Tuskegee Institute,
making him one of
the few African Americans
to run a black college.
When Washington
goes to Tuskegee,
he starts the process
of building
Tuskegee Institute from scratch.
Gasman: It was a campus
dedicated to the idea
of industrial education.
Booker T. Washington
was, really,
one of the first masters
at marketing.
Using photography,
he's trying to communicate,
"This is the type of education
that, at Tuskegee,
we are giving to
African Americans."
Anderson: It appeals
to the white leaders
in the American South.
They don't see
pictures of lawyers.
They don't see pictures
of politicians.
of professionals
who they think they're
too good for hard work.
Medord: I think it was just that
Booker T. Washington felt
that black people were not,
at present,
capable of doing
anything more than that.
And as a consequence
of taking that perspective,
black people suffered,
so he did
a great deal of damage.
Booker T. Washington gave
one of the opening speeches
at the Atlanta Exposition,
and it was
incredibly significant
to have an African American
giving this speech.
Before he starts,
there are a lot of catcalls
on the part of whites
and hissing and so on.
"As we have proved our
loyalty to you in the past
in nursing your children,
watching by the sick bed
of your mothers and fathers,
we shall stand by you ready
to lay down our lives
if need be in defense of yours.
In all things that
are purely social,
we can be as separate
as the fingers,
yet one as the hand
in all things essential
to mutual progress."
What he was saying in that
speech to white people,
"We will be your laborers.
We will be the people who will
take care of your children.
We will be the people
who will do your menial work."
And then he says to black people
that you have to start
at the bottom
and work your way up,
and that's where
we were meant to begin.
By the time he finishes,
whites are crying.
white women are throwing
out their handkerchiefs
and throwing out
flowers and clapping.
They are so moved
by this speech.
He makes white people,
North and South, happy.
He makes capitalists
and plantation owners
in the South happy.
Everybody is happy 'cause
we now have a black person
who is saying,
"Let's compromise.
We won't agitate
for social equality,
political participation,
civil rights.
Forget all that stuff."
What he seemed to be suggesting
was a kind of neoslavery.
This is coming from
the college president
who happens to be
the most prominent
African American
in the South.
He's a rockstar.
He's a megastar.
This is somebody who is
going to be able
to dictate the terms of life
for black education.
He becomes the darling
of the white philanthropists.
We're talking about
the Rockefellers,
the Carnegies, the Peabodys,
these huge names in the country.
Booker T. Washington appealed
to Northern industrialists
for pragmatic reasons.
They were seeking
after a labor force,
and he basically offered
the proposition
of an educated
black labor force,
but not too educated
and not too pushy.
"History is to note
two Washingtons,
one white, the other black,
both fathers of their people" --
Andrew Carnegie.
Holloway: As his ideology
becomes the only ideology,
there's not enough room,
it seems,
for lots of different ideas
about how to save the race.
That becomes a problem
for other black leaders.
They want to have their voice
at the table, as well.
"There is among educated
and thoughtful colored men
in all parts of the land
a feeling of deep regret,
sorrow, and apprehension
at the wide currency
and ascendancy
which Mr. Washington's theories
have gained.
Mr. Washington's program
practically accepts
the alleged inferiority
of the Negro race" --
W.E.B. Du Bois.
W.E.B. Du Bois is, probably,
the most educated American,
black or white.
He has gone to Fisk University.
He has gone to Harvard
and then studied abroad
in Germany.
Du Bois believes with education,
you gain freedom.
You gain independence.
Du Bois' vision calls
for expensive high education
and for thousands
of African Americans
to go to college,
become educated,
and to be fighters
for freedom and equality.
Between Washington and Du Bois,
they were so fundamentally
different in terms of vision,
so fundamentally different
in terms of the purpose
of education,
that there was no way
to reconcile the two.
Du Bois: "We refuse to kiss
the hand that smites us,
but rather insist on striving
by all civilized methods
to gain every
right and privilege
open to free
American citizens" --
W.E.B. Du Bois.
Washington's ideology
begins to fade
the further you get
into the 20th century.
The notion of just having
a vocational education system
just doesn't make sense
in a changing U.S. society.
You see it in all of
the educational institutions
for black folk --
a shift away from
industrial education
to higher pursuits
for black people
and a new way of thinking
about how American society
ought to function and look.
Washington dies in 1915.
It is a moment in American
culture and society.
He is one of the last
generations of African Americans
born into slavery.
You can read that funeral
as a moment of bearing witness
to a change.
A change is coming.
Wolters: African Americans
loyally supported
the United States
during the First World War,
and then when they returned
to the United States,
they were determined to enjoy
a greater degree of democracy.
But whites were not prepared
for any changes here.
James: African American
returning veterans
were often beaten
at the train stops
when they arrived.
They were attacked
by their fellow veterans
who were white.
They were attack by civilians.
28 cities burned during
the famous Red Summer of 1919.
Although we refer to them
as race riots,
they were often small race wars.
The black veterans
were shooting back.
"Though far outnumbered,
let us show us brave
and for their thousand blows
deal one death blow.
What though before us
lies the open grave,
like men, we'll face
the murderous cowardly pack
pressed to the wall, dying,
but fighting back."
Holloway: The New Negro
has no fear is a reflection
of this changed sensibility.
It's a militant New Negro.
It's one that's going to
stand up for his or her rights
after all these black soldiers
had fought for those rights
and died for those rights
over in Europe.
And, by God,
they're going to get them.
Black colleges were
an interesting place.
Most of them, during
that period,
had white presidents,
and they were run in
a very Draconian kind of way,
with moral codes
and with lots of rules.
The white presidents were
completely ill equipped
as to what to do with
these African Americans
who now wanted to shape
their own destiny
and were very spirited
and were defiant.
McKenzie,
the Fisk University president,
is not the kind of person that
you would have expected
to come to Fisk.
He had worked out west
on Shoshone Indian reservations,
and he had
an extensive experience
with Native American-
white relations.
The board of trustees at Fisk
made no real distinction
between working with
Native Americans
and working with
African Americans.
His white secretary commented
that she didn't think
that he understood black people
and wasn't even sure
that he liked them.
President McKenzie comes in
with the notion
that he can make Fisk
more conservative,
that he can take
Fisk University students
and educate them
in a different direction.
So he starts to make changes.
He wouldn't let them have
any social organizations.
A bell told them
when to get up...
He took away the track team.
when to go to breakfast.
He took away the baseball team.
when to to go class.
Men and women could not
walk together.
He would make no compromise.
McKenzie said,
"I am as old-fashioned
as the Ten Commandments,"
because he believed that blacks
were particularly
sensuous beings
who needed more restraint.
What he was afraid of,
I think, was widespread...
He was afraid of sex, basically.
W.E.B. Du Bois heard about all
this from his daughter, Yolanda,
who was a student at Fisk,
and then, when Yolanda was
graduating in 1924,
Fisk invited Du Bois to speak.
"I have come to criticize.
In Fisk today,
discipline is choking freedom.
Ironclad rules,
suspicion are almost universal.
The Negro race needs colleges.
We need them today
as never before,
but we do not need
colleges so much
that we can sacrifice the ideals
of the Negro race" --
W.E.B. Du Bois.
Anderson: He's saying
to Fisk students, "Resist.
Resist this repression.
Rise up."
The Fisk students had
engaged in a tin-pan riot.
Shouts of "Du Bois! Du Bois!"
are heard.
They went about the campus
for a period of an hour or two.
They came back to their beds
and were asleep by 10:00,
when it was time
for the lights to go off.
Students awoke to find as many
as 80 Metro National Policemen
in full riot gear.
They treat the
students as criminals.
They handcuff the students.
They immediately place them
into these paddy wagons,
and they take them off to jail.
Some claim that
they heard gun shots.
Maybe the first shots fired ever
on a historically black campus,
but it certainly
wouldn't be the last.
The students were so angry
that they went on strike,
and for 10 weeks,
they refused to attend class.
The trustees essentially decided
that it was not possible
to continue to have a university
if they had no students.
"My dear Lambert,
if you have not already learned,
I've resigned as president
of Fisk University
and, probably, want to return
to the rank of teacher,
preferably in
the field of sociology,
including race relations.
Very truly yours,
Fayette McKenzie."
It's a victory because it
makes national headlines,
and students at other
black universities
across the country
are emboldened.
They are inspired.
They participate
in their own protests
in the weeks
and in the months and years
that followed the Fisk fight.
It shows that the modern
new Negro student, right,
it will no longer stand
for the Victorian atmosphere
of their predecessors.
Let black people understand
that they are the lovers
and the sons of warriors.
Let the world be a black poem,
and let all black people speak
this poem silently or loud.
♪ School days ♪
♪ Dear old golden rule days ♪
♪ Reading and writing
and 'rithmetic ♪
♪ Taught to the tune
of a hickory stick ♪
♪ You, my girl, in Calico ♪
In high school,
I was a good student.
That's why I guess the principle
is recommending me
to Wilson College.
The disappointment comes
when that person comes
from the college,
to interview me,
and then it was all downhill.
I have not forgotten
her words --
"Your grades are wonderful,
but we're a little concerned
because we don't know
with whom...
you would be paired
because we cater to a lot
of Southern gentlewomen,
and they room in suites.
Sorry, kid."
So I didn't get to Wilson.
I applied to Bennett
for a scholarship.
It was kind of special,
you know.
You kind of stick
your chest out.
I'm a Bennett gal.
During the 1930s and '40s,
black colleges are really
the only place that
an African-American student
can go,
and this created
this enormous incubator
for success and intellectual
thought and creativity.
The best and brightest
is going to black colleges.
These professors
were on a mission,
not just, say,
to teach classics
or French literature
or political science.
They are there to ensure
a vibrant black future.
They're going to encourage you
because they recognize
your full human capability
and possibility.
If a teacher saw you kind
of slipping or faltering,
there was a, "What's going on?
What's the matter?
Can I help?"
There was a watching over you
to see that you did
the best that you could.
Black colleges were
educating future doctors
and future lawyers
and future teachers
and nurses and judges,
and they were responsible
for lifting
African-Americans
out of poverty,
and they started to create
the black middle class
as we know it.
For a black child,
every teacher that you knew had
gone to a black college.
Every lawyer that you knew had
Every medical doctor
that treated you had gone
to a black college.
Black colleges were redefining
what it meant to be black
in America.
You weren't doing something
with your hands.
You were pursuing a career,
where education
and intellect mattered.
Black people were in charge.
Black people were in control.
Black people were
writing the checks.
I went out for the football team
when I got there
because the girls liked you.
They would really go for you
if you played football.
You'd get back at halftime,
and they'd call you, tell you,
"Listen! We're not playing
for no girls or nothing.
We're playing football.
We're playing to win.
Do you understand?"
Going to college was the best
decision that I ever made.
Anderson: There was
a football game.
It's not just
about the students.
It's really about
the whole state.
The whole communities
are engulfed
by those institutions.
This is the era of fraternities
and sororities.
You have a rich social
and cultural life.
We met in the registrar's office
at Fisk University.
I was in line to speak
to the registrar.
There was that young,
beautiful person
at the typewriter,
typing,
and it seemed as though
she was looking over toward me.
Something causes her
to bat her eye.
I got up to help him,
and he said,
"Did you wink at me?"
And I just kind of
smiled and...
That was enough of an invitation
for me to ask her out.
♪ I'll buy you a diamond ♪
♪ I'll buy you a diamond ring ♪
68 years ago,
we married.
It was a protective,
insulated environment
where they could talk.
They could exchange ideas.
They could be themselves,
and, at least,
for that time period,
for those moments,
they didn't have to deal
squarely with segregation
and inequality.
Once they left campus,
they were right back
into the kind of segregation,
the kind of humiliation,
and so it was a special place.
I don't recall it
crossing my mind.
There were some place
where you knew
you weren't supposed to go,
so you didn't go.
We didn't talk about it,
you know?
You just kind of accepted things
the way they were.
The plan to change
racial segregation
could only have found its seed
and borne fruit at
a black college,
like Howard University.
They had a commitment
around these issues
that even well-meaning
liberal whites
and white institutions
would not have developed.
This is an idea that
was cultivated and navigated
by black professors
and deans and black students.
This radical change,
I would think this affirmation
of the American ideal,
comes out of a black college
and black university.
With impressive
open-air ceremonies,
Howard University
of Washington, D.C.,
graduates several hundred.
The crowd listens avidly
to Johnson, president of Howard.
James: Mordecai Johnson was
the first black president
of Howard University.
He was going to, if he could,
try to work a revolution
of the Howard Law School.
And so Mordecai Johnson hires
Charles Hamilton Houston,
who, at the time,
is almost certainly the most
highly-educated African-American
lawyer in history --
graduate of Harvard Law School,
the first black member
of the Harvard Law Review.
Holloway: Houston had a plan
for this law school.
He's going to make it
a first-rate law school
that is all about breaking down
a whole system
of racial discrimination
and segregation.
That's what the Howard Law
School mission is going to be.
Howard Law School, at the time,
is an unaccredited law school.
It is almost entirely
a night school,
and many of its students
attend part-time
because they have to work.
It was referred to derisively
by some African-African
attorneys in Washington
as a dummy's retreat.
In 1930, Houston closes
the night school.
There is outcry among
the African-American lawyers,
not just in Washington, D.C.,
but nationwide.
They said this man is trying
to Harvard-ize Howard.
Enrollment plummets,
all the white professors quit.
They wanted to work
at their day-jobs.
This allowed Houston
to hire new faculty.
Now we've got
an all-black faculty,
and they're some
of the finest attorneys
who were working
in Washington, D.C.
Marshall:
Dean Charles H. Houston --
He used to tell us
in our first year
to look at the man
on your right,
and look at the man
on your left,
and bear in mind that two
of you will be here next year.
That sort of kept your feet
to the fire.
Thurgood Marshall was a
graduate of Lincoln University,
a black college where he was not
an exceptional student,
and, by all accounts,
this was from general
lack of interest in his studies.
Thurgood Marshall
was widely regarded
to be someone
who had a big personality,
and someone who could
persuade people by charm.
These are some of
the raw skills
that Charles Hamilton Houston
took and refined
and turned into one of
the most significant lawyers
of our generation.
Shortly after Thurgood
Marshall graduates
from Howard Law School,
he and Dean Houston
take a road trip,
and they head into the recesses
of the deep South.
They are charged by the NAACP
with documenting the conditions
in which black children
go to school
in the southern states.
Charles Hamilton Houston
was a big techie.
Anything that came out,
the new technology
that came out,
he wanted to have it,
and in Charles Hamilton
Houston's car,
they have a typewriter,
a camera, and a film camera.
This was their first exposure
to the conditions
deep in Georgia,
in Northern Florida,
and Alabama.
They had not seen that before.
Houston and Marshall
were able to film
white students on the buses
going to school.
And then they were
able to contrast that
by showing black students
walking to school.
There were not bathrooms.
There were not even outhouses
at some of these buildings.
Houston and Marshall
brought the film
back from the deep South
to NAACP Headquarters
in New York City.
The Constitution says that
the separation of the races
is okay
as long as that separation
is equal.
Houston has a plan.
It's an incredibly bold plan.
He's gonna attack segregation,
ironically, by supporting it.
So the strategy
that Houston devised
was that he was going to argue
that they needed to enforce
separate but equal,
by forcing the states to
actually make their facilities
that were already
separate equal.
In reality, it was impossible
to actually maintain
equal schools
that were separate.
It would be way too expensive.
The brilliant thing that
Charles Hamilton Houston
set in motion
was this was not going
to be a one-game struggle.
This wasn't going
to be a one case.
The idea was to build
a steady drumbeat
from one state to another,
establishing the principle
that separate was never equal.
Operating our educational system
is one of government's
most important jobs
because education is one thing
Oklahomans have
always believed in.
George McLaurin,
he was a 68-year-old teacher
with a master's degree.
He sought a PhD in education
at the University of Oklahoma.
University of Oklahoma
admitted him,
but they forced him to sit
outside the classroom.
Oklahoma was like,
"Okay, so this is equal,
but it's separate.
You said that
we could do separate
as long as it was equal.
So how about that?"
How about that?
Here we had a student who was
attending the same school,
hearing the same lecture
at the same time
as the white students,
but was sent aside,
stigmatized because
of his race.
He's not able to interact
with his fellow students.
with his professors.
This is clearly a circumstance
in which the separation itself,
even under conditions where
they're getting ostensibly
the same education
is not equal,
and that was, in fact,
a breakthrough moment
to be able to say,
"Segregation in and of itself
is an inequality."
Charles Hamilton
Houston died in 1950,
but his campaign that started
some 20 years earlier
at Howard Law School
came to fruition in 1954.
This is the group of lawyers
from all sections of the country
who are here
in the Supreme Court
for the purpose of arguing
the school segregation cases,
and we believe that
the proper place
for the issue of segregation
is in a court.
100 years after laws existed
that prevented African-Americans
from learning how to read,
it prevented white Americans
from teaching African-Americans
how to read --
100 years after that,
we have an integrated team
of lawyers,
led by an African-American,
arguing for the Supreme Court
of the United States
that separate but equal
is unconstitutional
in the field
of public education.
Crenshaw: The game changer
in the 20th century was
Brown v. Board of Education.
It took lawyers not
at an elite school
but at a law school
that was put together
by spit and glue and hard work
that that would be the space
that would create
a legal revolution
that all Americans
now benefit from.
This is an educational
institution at it's best,
not just creating knowledge
for the sake of having it,
but creating knowledge in order
to do something concrete
with that knowledge.
That's what Howard Law School
represents.
The decision opened the way
toward eliminating
racial discrimination
from American life,
but it did not bring into
reality immediate integration.
More than laws are required
to change long-established
attitudes and institutions.
I say that we will fight
to the last ditch
to prevent unwanted integration
against our great people.
You've got to keep the white
and the black separate.
We are determined, in Georgia...
As governor of the state
of Alabama...
we will maintain
separate schools
for the white
and the colored races.
What happens
to a dream deferred?
We don't want the niggers
going in this school.
It's a white school.
Does it dry up
like a raisin in the sun?
I think they should kept out
any way possible.
Or fester like a sore
and then run?
I think they should be separate.
Even the animals
choose their own breed.
Maybe it just sags
like a heavy load.
I'm for segregation
because it's biblical.
Or does it explode?
There was a famous man
who once said
"There's nothing
on Earth so powerful
as an idea who's time has come."
and I think the centuries of
discrimination and segregation
and ill treatment
and the lynchings,
I think the time had come
for the war to be waged
to end segregation.
We wanted freedom now...
not 25 years from now.
It was, "Damn it.
Are we going to keep talking,
or are we going to take action.
If not us, who?"
Nobody was doing anything.
There was no protest.
We decided we would sit in.
McCain: We came into this store
and sat in at the lunch counter,
which was not customary
or accepted
for African-Americans
at the time.
The New York Times
had this story on four students
who had actually sat in
at a Woolworth's store,
and that was absolutely
earthshaking.
Every one of us knew full well
that they were either
the bravest people in the world
or the craziest people
in the world.
McNeil: We sat for pretty close
to two hours.
The store manager said,
"You boys are going to
get in a lot of trouble.
I'm going to call the cops
if you don't get up and leave.
We can't serve you here.
We won'tserve you here."
So we sat until
the store manager
decided to close the lunchroom
for the rest of the day.
You know, why did you
fellows select
the five-and-dime
variety store lunch counters?
Why didn't you just walk
into a restaurant
if you wanted
to prove your point?
Woolworth's is open
to the public.
They should have
equal facilities,
not only restroom facilities,
but these facilities also.
A photographer from
the Associated Press,
Jack Moebes,
greeted us at the door.
He says, "You coming back?"
Well, we said, "Yes.
We're going to be back tomorrow,
and we're going
to keep coming back
until you guys serve us."
♪ Black and white together ♪
The Bennett girls became aware
of what we were doing
at the A&T,
and they couldn't be held
on the sidelines.
And so they joined it.
We deserve our rights,
and we are going to get them
one way or the other.
This was an opportunity
to make a difference,
We felt it was
incumbent upon us
because we were young people.
We were students,
and we had a responsibility,
and we were going to be
the future leaders,
so now was a good time
to begin to demonstrate
what good leaders
we could become.
Well, we started out
the first day with four,
the second day, 16,
the third day, 24,
then at 64,
then that Saturday occurred.
We had pretty close
to 1,000 students
demonstrating peacefully,
and it kept growing
until this thing just had
a life of its own.
Parham: It was being replicated
throughout the South,
and largely among
black college students.
A revolution had actually begun.
♪ Watch me ♪
♪ I've got it, hey! ♪
The targets of the students
were the lunch counters
of the city's two
largest department stores
and four variety stores,
and for the first time,
the community was confronted
with Negroes in places
where they had never been.
♪ And I'm super bad ♪
If you weren't out
there demonstrating,
then something had to be
wrong with your school.
♪ Unh! ♪
♪ Come on ♪
You sat and read your books
and caught up
with your homework
because you were students.
It was just a matter of,
you know,
reading this chapter
or whatever you had to do
before you got back
on the picket line.
During the weeks
after the sit-ins began,
opposition in
the white communities
of the South solidified,
and the first signs
of violence appeared.
We were called niggers.
We were spat on.
People came by
and threw cigarettes at you.
It was very difficult
not to fight back.
I spent a lot of time
on that picket line, crying,
because I could not retaliate.
♪ Freedom, freedom ♪
♪ Everybody wants freedom ♪
It's unusual for
someone to be singing
while they're getting arrested
because that arrest
is supposed to punish you.
It's supposed to be humiliating.
♪ Freedom ♪
But when you're singing
and dancing on your way to jail,
being put in the paddy wagon,
you retain the power.
♪ Freedom ♪
♪ Freedom, freedom ♪
Even when we had situations
that we didn't know what to do,
we had a song.
♪ I'm going to do
what the spirit says do ♪
♪ And what the spirit says do ♪
♪ I'm going to do, oh, Lord ♪
♪ I'm going to do
what the spirit says do ♪
Rich's Department Store
was the big kahuna.
They had stores
all over the South.
Dick Rich, who was the president
of Rich's at the time,
he told me that
if I brought my black ass
back into his store again,
he was going to put me in jail,
and I told him that,
"I'm coming back, Mr. Rich,
and I'm bringing thousands
with me,
and get your jails ready
because we going to be there."
Taitt-Magubane: We synchronized
watches and said,
"At 11:15, everyone was to enter
wherever they were assigned to."
It meant that they had to deal
with all of us at the same time.
King: We were able to cost
Rich's Department Store,
in 1960,
over the Christmas holidays,
$10 million in losses.
All of a sudden,
they wanted to talk,
and within six weeks,
they had signed an agreement
to desegregate
all that stuff downtown.
♪ I'm going to do
what the spirit says do ♪
♪ Well, I'm going to do
♪ And what the spirit says do
I'm going to do ♪
When I was finally
served at that counter,
I thought it was by far
one of the lousiest meals
I ever had,
and I asked myself the question,
"Is this what I put
my life on the line for?"
But, remember,
it wasn't about the food,
anyhow.
It was about being treated
as a fellow human being.
♪ Well, you better let my ♪
♪ Let my people go ♪
We want a black power
♪ Well, you better let my ♪
♪ Let my people go ♪
Black college campus
in the 1960s is getting
more and more complex.
They've been already trying
to change the world outside,
changing a society that was
about separation of the races.
You get to the late '60s
and early '70s,
that energy for change starts
to turn inward.
♪ Beep beep, bang bang ♪
♪ Ungawa, black power ♪
When a black person
looks at himself
in the context of America,
that's what he has to decide,
"Who am I?"
And when he finds out who he is,
then he knows
what he has to do.
Crenshaw: A lot of the conflict
that's starting to happen is
between the students
and the administrators,
students
and the boards of trustees.
They're wanting to see
themselves far more
than they have in the past.
And so that makes
for some pretty hot times
on black college campuses.
The present administration
are the children
of last generation.
We're the men and the women
of this generation,
and the generations to come.
Either they'll come with us
or be left behind.
Most likely,
they'll be left behind.
About 1,000 students here,
at Howard University,
have sat in and held control of
this administration building.
There are no classes.
The entire educational system
is shut down.
Many of us will stay in
the administration building
and be arrested.
There will be boycotts
until there is progress,
and we are prepared
to boycott until infinity.
It appears to me
that the attitudes
on the part
of the students suggest
that an explosion among them
is imminent.
And the question here
before us is, like,
who going to control
our education,
whether we going to let
white folks control
it or black people,
and the students at
Voorhees College
have taken a position
that black people going
to control our education.
You also start to see
the police being more vile
in their approach
to interacting with students.
President Nixon has urged
college officials
to be firm in dealing
with campus disorder,
and that's what
Dr. Potts was doing
when he agreed to the use
of the National Guard.
Black colleges were
particularly vulnerable
to police invasion
because white politicians
were quick to call in the police
and quick to look the other way
when police used deadly force.
When the bullets
were hitting the walls,
I was on the floor,
and there were a lot of people
on top of me,
and I don't know
what was happening.
All I know, I could just hear
the pounding against the windows
and glass popping everywhere.
Biondi: This kind of atmosphere
of policing and of crackdown
made students very,
very vulnerable.
I entered Southern University
in 1970.
Earth, Wind & Fire,
Barry White, Shaft --
That was the kind of music
we listened to.
Platform shoes
were in style, too.
and bell bottoms.
I hurt my feet,
and I had a head full of hair.
We was wearing afros.
We wore the little mini dresses.
We all had the little,
small figures
so it looked good on us.
My sister and my brother
had already entered
Southern University,
so I knew I should be next.
We wanted to go to Southern,
the black college.
I got on Southern's campus,
and there was, like,
10,000 students on campus,
and there were people
from Seattle, New York,
Chicago, Houston, Texas,
all these places --
It was amazing.
The mix of people
was one of the elements
that defined Southern.
It was an intellectual
and scholarly oasis that
I really, really wanted
to be a part of,
and all of it was there.
Southern University in
Louisiana was the largest
public black college
in the United States.
There was a black president
and black administrators,
but it was under the control
of the white elected officials
in Louisiana,
who only spent half
as much per pupil
as they did on
the predominantly white LSU.
My third or fourth week,
you could see that something
else was happening on campus.
You getting another vibe
that there was some students
that weren't happy
with what was going on.
They want to teach everything
the white-man way.
We're trying to break away
from this thing, you see.
Too long we've been listening
to white people and their ways.
We're developing our own ideas,
and we want adequate facilities
to be able to put them
into action.
We didn't feel that
we had enough professors.
Adequate classroom space.
Better funded.
More input into the curriculum.
And it started to build,
and it started to build.
And so we decided that
the best thing to do
was a very direct thing
and take this,
these matters, directly
to President Netterville.
Met with him,
and we thought that his response
was not a positive one,
and so we decided
to boycott classes.
We will not go back to class
until all of our demands
are met.
Power comes through unity.
Students at Southern
University's campuses
in Baton Rouge and New Orleans
began a series of marches
and demonstrations,
demanding the resignation
of the school's president
and control over
the administration.
For an entire month,
we boycotted classes,
and that had never been done.
Southern had a major
football tradition.
We knew that we could
have some impact
if we drew the attention
of people who attended
these games.
There were demonstrators
who went onto the football field
and stopped a football game.
That's when I was impressed.
I said, "This is really big.
Maybe the administration
is going to listen to them,
and something great
is going to happen here."
When they take the attitude
that they would walk out classes
unless they get their way
completely and instantly,
then it just becomes necessary
to let it be known
that that just cannot happen.
The call was go and
stand on campus,
stand around all day in uniform
in a show of force,
on the parking lots
and ride through the campus.
We started trailing
the students around
to see where they were going
or where they were holding
meetings off campus.
Everybody was on standby
in a high-alert situation.
Nobody knew what was
going to happen.
Well, of course,
I was not going to sit by
and allow them or anybody
to destroy public property
that didn't belong
to the students.
It belonged to the people
of the state.
And while I sympathized
with their complaints
and was willing
to address them,
I was not going to allow them
to destroy the university
or its buildings.
The student movement was,
indeed, a nonviolent movement.
There was not one incident
during that entire
period of time
that represented any violence,
certainly any violence
on the part of students.
At about somewheres between
2:00 and 3:00 in the morning,
I received a knock on my door,
which turned out to be
the police,
and they handed me
a warrant for my arrest.
I was scared.
I had never been to jail before.
I didn't know what to expect.
On the morning
of November 16th,
there were no police around.
It was a very serene day
on campus.
We did what we were
doing every day,
and that is that we were
rallying students
to leave the class.
Just that this day,
we informed them
that these four students
had been arrested
and that we were gonna go over
to President Netterville's
office
and ask him to go downtown
and get the students
out of jail.
He let us in his office,
and he said, "Yes,"
he will indeed do that,
and he said,
"You can stay here
until I return."
So we took him at his word.
He left the building.
The call that the sheriff's
office received
and who made the call
from Southern University,
I don't know, but it informed us
that Dr. Netterville
was being held hostage,
and he was in the
administration building
that had been taken over
by the students,
and we was ordered
to free the hostage.
We heard this noise outside
and looked out the window.
About 300 sheriff's
office deputies
and state police troopers
assembled on campus
to carry out Governor Edwards'
demand that order be maintained.
We immediately knew
that Netterville
had betrayed us.
M16s, shotguns, side arms --
You name it, they had it.
To our amazement,
there was a tank with them.
Big Bertha, they called it.
It was a big blue armored
personnel carrier
built out of steel.
It was there, in the front of
the administration building,
parked.
This thing was frightening.
We about to go to war?
Honore: We had every deputy
that could have a uniform on.
Some of them was new.
Some of them was reserve.
A lot of them wasn't trained.
Nobody knew what was
going to happen,
and a state police --
I was looking right at him --
leaned down and rolled
a tear gas canister
towards the crowd.
There was a Bobby Crow,
was the state police,
state trooper.
That was who rolled it.
I was looking right at him.
One of the students leaned down
and picked it up,
hurled it back over
to the deputies.
That's when hell broke loose.
Pandemonium, chaos --
It was something
that was quite surreal.
Big Bertha had some
portholes on the side of it,
and shots were
coming out of there rapidly.
You could see it rocking
from the vibrations
from shots being fired.
There were two people
left on the ground.
I thought that they had
been knocked down
by the rush of students
trying to get away.
But then I remember
this girl turning around
and started screaming.
Coming out of the
administration building,
what I noticed,
and what I'm sure
a lot of other people noticed,
was a pool of blood
with what looked like
brain matter
floating around in it.
We came out.
By that time,
the bodies was gone,
but we saw the markers
and the blood everywhere.
And we were weeping and crying
and going back to the dump.
They say, "You know that
was your brother, huh?"
I said, "What?"
I went numb.
There has been trouble
at Southern University
between black students
and authorities
for a couple of weeks,
and today, it ended in death.
And on the TV, sure enough,
they called his name.
20-year old Denver Smith...
Denver Smith and
Leonard Brown...
Smith-Jones: He was never a part
of the movement at all.
If I hadn't been involved,
my brother never would have
been there.
The accident would
not have happened at all
if they had not taken it
upon themselves
to occupy
the President's office.
That was the triggering
mechanism.
Had they just gone about
peacefully demonstrating
and agitating
and doing what they wanted to do
and had a right to do,
it never would have happened.
It came as a surprise to me
after we found out later
that afternoon
that Dr. Netterville
was not on campus
during the whole period of time
we were there,
at the administration building,
with the students,
that he was not
on campus at all.
I relived that moment
because I was one of the leaders
who led the students
to Netterville's office,
who believed
that he would go down
and get these students
out of jail,
and they trusted me.
Though I didn't pull
the trigger,
as a leader,
I may have been responsible.
They were exercising
their constitutional rights,
and they get killed for it.
They die for it.
Nobody sent their child
to school to die.
It just shouldn't have happened.
It shouldn't have happened.
♪ Lift every voice and sing
♪ Till Earth and heaven ring ♪
♪ Ring with harmonies ♪
♪ Of Liberty ♪
♪ Let our rejoicing rise ♪
♪ High as the listening skies ♪
♪ Let it resound loud ♪
♪ As the roaring seas ♪
My daughter's going to Spellman!
Yayyyy!
We're excited to keep
the bloodline going,
'cause our family bleeds
orange and green.
And this one's for you. Thank you.
The room is really small.
Don't know how all your stuff
is going to get in here.
At my high school,
I was the token black girl.
That was something
very hard for me.
You're either the ratchet
black, ghetto person,
or you're the exception.
You're the high-achieving,
excellent...
That's what you are,
and I'm tired of those boxes.
I don't want to be one thing
or the other.
I want to be me.
I want to have the opportunity
to discover myself.
I do believe that going
to an HBCU was going to be
a safe space,
somewhere where I can be free
to be completely myself.
I can be black.
I can have curly hair.
I can be smart.
I can be whatever I want to be.
When I walk on campus,
the excitement is unreal.
I love the stroll teams
that go around,
chanting for their dorms.
I love the step teams
that they have,
And they all look like you.
They all look like you.
It's so good.
And this moment marks
the beginning
of your journey.
This is the moment
where you part company
with your parents, your friends,
your loved ones.
You say goodbye.
There's something very different
about coming
into an environment
where you know that
everyone around you has
the same chance
of being successful as you are
without negative implications
associated with race.
What the black college
experience provides them
is a place to be, finally,
at some point,
in the majority.
They look around and see people
who share common experiences.
That is such a unique
and empowering experience.
My graduating class,
There weren't many
black students.
When I told my classmates
that I was going
to attend an HBCU,
none of them even knew
what an HBCU was.
Everyone was like, "Why?
Why do you want to go to FAMU?
Why don't you want to go to,
like, USF or, like,
somewhere else?"
I never even had, like,
a black teacher, ever,
from K through 12.
I remember, like, always talking
to my mom about it.
"When am I going to have
a black teacher?"
Like, "I want a black teacher."
On page 274,
we talked about hurdles
that you have
to get through.
I wanted to learn
from someone who looks like me
because I thought, maybe,
the learning experience
would be a little
bit different.
My freshman year was when I had
the African American
history class,
and that changed the world
for me.
Just knowing what my ancestors
went through
to learn how to read,
to get an education,
to be given the right
to sit in a classroom
that have good books,
and they worked so hard
for that.
It makes me want to be better,
and every day,
I just try to be great
just because of that.
It is our duty
to fight for our freedom.
It is our duty to
fight for our freedom.
I just wanted to be
more involved
in the movement
that was happening now.
We must love
and protect each other.
We must love and
protect each other.
We have nothing to lose
but our chains.
Movements are easily birthed
on HBCs campuses.
We're all going through
the same experience.
I just feel like I found myself
through being a student at FAMU.
I hope that the future of HBCUs
is a positive one
and one that will bring
a lot of experiences
to more people,
but I'm fearful that
it's not going to be that way.
Come on, Brown fans.
Sing it one more time
for Morris Brown.
The future for black colleges
is actually contested
at this point.
Many of them have not
been successful,
particularly over
the last 20 years.
This is a shell.
It's a shell
of a wonderful campus
that used to be 34 acres.
Fountain Hall, at one time,
housed the offices of
Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois.
In 2003, Morris Brown College
lost its accreditation.
It had 2,500 students
at that time,
to what you see now,
where we have
less than 50 students.
Wilson: Today, there are
over 100 black colleges.
Some are flourishing.
Some, like Morris Brown College,
established in 1881,
have all but closed.
Brown v. Topeka opened
the white colleges,
opened the field of choice
for black students
and black faculty,
often with a consequence that
black colleges lost enrollment,
and they lost some of
their most talented faculty.
There's a lot more competition.
What I think
successful colleges will do
will say, "If you come here,
you will find something
you won't find any place else."
So that's the kind of uniqueness
that you want to be able
to communicate
to your community.
I wanted to go home
because I felt like it
was too much to be here.
It's too hard.
And Dad gives me
this really long talk.
He said, "Calvin,
we want you to go to FAMU
because that is where you're
going to get the best experience
as a musician
and as a black man.
One, two, ready, and!
The university has pushed me
very, very hard
to become a self-standing,
strong, centered individual.
I've grown as a musician
and as a leader.
Three things I really want
from the university
are support and
education and love,
and since I've been here,
I've gotten just that.
Whoo!
I know I'm really gonna
miss this environment
because I know I couldn't
get it anywhere else.
This is my last home game.
It's my last year at FAM,
getting ready to graduate,
and the world is about
to get that much bigger.
Young people are
the engine of change.
They are the engine
of possibility.
They have a vision and a faith
in their own potential.
That spirit of being
at an HBCU is
very unique,
very different.
It's like you have a match,
and you want to start a fire,
but you have no fuel whatsoever.
All you have is that one match.
This HBCU experience has
shown me and taught me
that anything is possible as
long as you have that one spark.
♪ Alls my life, I has to fight ♪
♪ Alls my life I... ♪
♪ Hard times like, God ♪
♪ Bad trips like, yeah ♪
♪ Nazareth, ♪
♪ I'm... homey, you... up ♪
♪ But if God us then
we gon' to be all right ♪
♪ We gon' be all right ♪
♪ Do ya hear me? Do ya feel me?
We gon' be all right ♪
♪ We gon' be all right ♪
I got my degree, baby!
♪ Do ya hear me? Do ya feel me?
We gon' be all right ♪
♪ Unh! Now tell my mama I love
her, but this what I like ♪
♪ Lord knows, I can see
the evil, I can tell it ♪
♪ I know it's illegal,
I don't think about it ♪
♪ I deposit every other zero ♪
♪ Thinking of my partner,
put the candy ♪
♪ Paint it on the Regal,
digging in my pocket ♪
♪ Ain't a profit big enough
to feed you ♪
♪ Everyday my logic get another
dollar just to keep... ♪
Please rise!
♪ We gon' be all right ♪
Class of 2-0-16!
♪ Do ya hear me? Do ya feel me?
We gon' be all right ♪
♪ Tell the world,
I know it's too late ♪
♪ Boys and girls,
I think I gone cray ♪
♪ Drown inside my vices
all day ♪
♪ Won't you please believe
when I say... ♪
♪ Well, we'll need more power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I didn't need more power ♪
♪ I need heaven and power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I need the power
that save me ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I need the power
that saves me ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ We done talking about power ♪
♪ We done talking about
the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ Everlasting power ♪
♪ Get on your knees and cower ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I didn't rather have
the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I didn't rather have
the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ Wake up in the power ♪
♪ Did he follow in the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ Did he sing with the power ♪
♪ He done talking about
the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ I didn't rather the power ♪
♪ I didn't need the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ What you gonna do about
the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ What you gonna do about
the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ Well, now the captain's
got the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪
♪ Yeah, well,
now he got the power ♪
♪ Power, Lord ♪