It is said that the movements of
stars make or break a person's life.
Or, the day any star
takes a left turn above...
...then many new lives will
be born here, below, on earth.
Once, due to these
turns of the stars...
...in 1974, two children were born
on the same day at the same time.
Many other children too were
born but these two were different.
One was born in an ordinary
settlement of Mumbai...
...in a South Indian family.
Hey, what do you think
of yourself? Get out!
But neither did this child
want to learn the qualities...
...of a Brahmin nor the
South Indian simplicity.
Hey, Balu!
His style was different.
Mr. Shastri is coming!
His name was Balu.
- You think so end of yourself!
- What's the matter?
He plays cards with the
children, at school!
You always keep rebuking him!
Balu and his father
never saw eye to eye.
One day, Balu let his
father's lifetime efforts...
...go down the drain
Watch what I do to your now!
Get out of the house!
Our second artiste, who
was born along with Balu...
...was growing up.
Far away, across seven oceans.
This is London's Brighton
School. Rahul studies here.
The grandson of a millionaire
businessman Shambunath Mehta.
His only heir.
Grandpa!
- Rahul dear.
- Uncle Ramu, where is grandpa?
Son, grandpa has
gone out for 3-4 days.
This is uncle Ramu,
the loyal manager of this house.
The one who can empathize
with Rahul's sentiments.
Rahul acquired one too many things.
But these stars snatched away
his parents in childhood itself.
This music box gave him
company in his Ioneliness.
With which is associated,
a plethora of his parent's memories.
Many years elapsed.
Time taught and
showed many experiences.
Balu and Rahul went
on amassing dreams.
The time has come today
to fulfil those dreams.
Both of them have turned 21 today.
Come to wish them
on their birthday.
Hey! Who is it?
Happy birthday, dear brother.
How did that hoodlum come home?
How did he come home, huh?
Rascal, get up!
Wow! My father loves me so much!
He cradles me on my birthday.
He had done the same,
20 years ago, when I was a baby.
Am I cradling you?
Get up and get out!
He is your own son!
- Don't you understand, buddy?
- You call me buddy!
How can you be my son?
Despite being a Brahmin...
...you smoke, drink
and eat meat! Go to your room!
- Don't come here!
- Father!
Why shouldn't he? Have some shame.
It's our son's birthday today.
He has become 21 today. Won't
you wish him? You throw him out!
- You be quiet!
- Freshen up, son.
I'll feed you 'kheer' (sweet dish)
Watch, mother! Someday,
luck will shine on me too.
Really? I shall also
see how that happens!
You are not my father, Shastri!
- What did you say?
- Mother!
I think, the father
and son are fighting again.
My son's sleep has been disturbed.
Come on, son.
Get dressed soon.
- Happy birthday, brother!
- Hey, Paro!
- Here's your gift.
- Is this any gift? My cab key?!
It isn't only a key. There is also
a fantastic sports can with it. Look.
At least you gave me a gift.
Hey, drive some
sense to your father too!
There's no water.
Close the kitchen tap.
Shastri!
Where are you quietly hiding?
If you have the
guts, then come out!
- He is not at home.
- I know. Therefore I have come.
- Here's some 'kheer'.
- Wow! Paro, will you have some?
Get lost!
Don't spare that bloody Balu today!
Oh God! I'll be damned!
Paro, please save my skin
for the last time. Please!
- Who is it now?
- My creditors. Paro, get up!
Please! Will you have
some 'kheer'? It's delicious!
Paro! Can't you do this
much for your brother? Paro!
- Please, Paro!
- For the last time.
I swear, I shall
never do this again!
- We will surely catch Balu
today. - Let's go and see.
We won't spare him!
- Who are you?
- My name is Jaggu.
I am Dubai returned.
Is Balu at home?
Brother is not at home.
Hey, I am Charusingh.
Balu drives my taxi.
- Drive him out!
- We saw the taxi outside.
So we thought, he was at home.
Well, brother left his
taxi here and has gone out.
No problem, dear. My job
is to lend and take money.
This is my profession.
I only came to tell Balu that
he has hit a jackpot of Rs.5,000.
Have some 'kheer'.
Come out. We will feed
you to your hearts content!
Paro, sit in. I'll have
some sweets and come soon.
Hey, it's my birthday.
Let's talk amicably.
I shall feed you sweets!
- I told you, I'm full.
- Brother?
- Are you okay?
- They're feeding me sweets.
- Hey you!
- Hey, you'll have me killed.
Forget me. Catch him first.
He is escaping.
, Fix an appointment...
No, he will be there on time.
Happy birthday, Rahul dear.
Is it my birthday today?
Thank you, uncle Ramu.
You have turned 21 today.
Quickly freshen up.
We'll go to the temple.
Rahul dear, come on.
Grandpa must be waiting
for you for breakfast.
The managers have come to discuss
about the Japanese shipment.
- You may have to go to Japan.
- Really?
I hope, grandpa is
in a good mood today.
I will surely go to India this
year. Please explain to him, uncle.
He will never refuse you.
Good morning, grandpa.
Thank you, grandpa.
Rahul, did you
see your birthday gift?
No.
This is my third car, uncle Ramu.
You know, I don't want all this.
What is it that
you want from life?
Grandpa, I want to ask for
something else from you today.
If you permit me, then I will
get the answers to many questions.
These answers will
tell me my future, grandpa.
Balu's future. Pick.
Quickly come out
and save me from Balu.
That arrogant Shastri too
is here. Save me from him also.
Or both will be damned!
- Wow!
Listen to what the
astrologer says, father!
Wow! What a future this boy has!
Wow!
According to this, he is destined
for happiness, wealth... everything!
He will have a fleet of cars.
Money will fall on his lap!
He already has that.
He drives a taxi.
Taxi is not written,
in this. He will own cars!
Father, whenever I come here,
the parrot picks the same card!
- Suppose, all the cards are same,
then? - Certainly not! Pick up your card! ****
- It will be absolutely miserable!
- You said miserable, you demon?!
You have been drinking my
blood since the time you were born.
And even now, you ask for a debt.
That's why you bring me here.
Balu, I am not going to be
impressed with your card or parrot, Okay?! ****
Please consider, father!
It is the question of my future.
Your future?
Will a parrot tell you your future?
- My car! My money!
- Here's your future!
- Here goes your future!
- Father!
What is it that you want from life?
Grandpa, I only
wish to go to India.
I want Rs.20,000
to go to Dubai, father.
- To go to Dubai?
- Yes. I'm only asking for a debt.
I'll repay you within
a month, with interest.
I will not even give
you a penny! Get lost!
- What a father I have!
- Come ahead soon!
Here's one rupee!
Buy your bus ticket with it!
Stingy man! I asked
for 20,000, and he left in a bus...
...leaving me helpless!
But whenever I speak of going
to India, you ask me not to.
And that is the only
country which I want to go to.
Rahul, that is the
country which I detest.
That is the country,
where our factory...
...has been incurring
losses since 20 years.
That is the country with
which I wish to have no ties!
But we do, grandpa!
After all, we are Indians.
We were Indians; but aren't anymore.
Neither are you,
nor was your mother.
She was a fool to go to
India. And she never returned.
Today, you wish to repeat history?
Look Rahul, I have lost my daughter.
- I don't wish to lose you now.
- You won't lose me, grandpa.
You'll have me closer to you.
I promise. Please let me go.
Rahul, you are very stubborn...
just like your mother.
No. Just like my grandpa.
If I throw your bodies
from the seventh floor...
...then your corpses won't be
worthy of being eaten even by the dogs! ****
You know how we have bribed
the Labor Commissioner...
...and put this
factory under a lock out.
That's your problem, Mr. Mathur!
Mr. Kante, the task
will be simplified...
...because the power of attorney,
Mr. Rahul, is coming to India.
We have been hearing this
since the last 4 months.
The chairman's son is coming
to India. So what we do?
Don't worry, Mr. Kante.
Just keep watching.
Spare no efforts in
Mr. Rahul Mehta's welcome.
And keep the court
papers ready, understand?
Is a leader coming?
Our company's owner's son, Rahul
Mehta, is returning from London...
...to India for the first time.
What's written on the banner, Sir?
They mean to wish him
belatedly for his birthday.
I know! Even I know that
much of English! He talks big!
- Sir, when was his birthday?
- The day-before-yesterday.
The day-before-yesterday?!
What have you done?
You've broken my head!
Forget your head, Sir.
My luck is bad!
Do you know, it was my birthday
too on the 9th of October?
And look at me! I'm in this
rotten taxi, and that bloody fool...
I see!
Sir, please sit in my office
until your baggage arrives.
Your car too is parked there.
Your Vice-Chairman, Mr. Mathur,
has sent you this phone.
And has apologized for
not being able to reach on time.
You carry on. We'll come.
Uncle Ramu, why is
there a crowd outside?
To welcome you.
The son of such a great man is
coming to India for the 1st time.
So, his welcome
will be equally grand.
I know, son.
Go to the office and rest.
I'll bring the baggage, okay?
Who are you? Leave me!
Hey, I'm not Rahul
Mehta but Rahul Verma!
What! Give the garland back.
Yes, we need it.
Hey, where are you looking,
Ramsingh? Mirchandani is in front of you! ****
- Hey, you've become so fat!
- Not at all!
But how did you recognize me?
Mirchandani is the city's
greatest, private detective.
Why do you forget that?
Therefore, grandpa has hired me to
look after Rahul. Where's Rahul?
Hey, show me your license
and take the taxi out!
What!
Hey, show me your license and
take the taxi away from here.
I am!
What bad luck!
Hey! Hey you! Where are you going?
Look at him. He will book me!
Look at his face!
He can see Rs.100!
I'll give the money.
Please let's go!
Take the taxi out, or
I'll break your leg!
I beg of you to
please go from here!
- I'll break your other leg too!
- What's going on? Quiet!
Quiet!
Hey, stop honking!
Take away your taxi!
Wow! What a bomb!
Hey, Romeo! First, take your
taxi away or I'll break your leg!
He's breaking my leg, while he's
folding his hands... I'll leave!
Hey, stop!
Hurry! We are already late.
- Did you find out anything?
- I searched the whole airport.
But of no avail.
He left for the hotel.
No problem.
- Where do you want to go, Sir?
- I've to go to Hotel New Castle.
But first, take me around Mumbai.
Sir, when people come from
abroad, they are loaded with baggage.
But you have come empty handed.
That's because I haven't come from
abroad. I came to receive someone.
I see! That son of a rich father?
- Who?
- Rahul... Rahul Mehta.
Had you come to garland him?
Y... y... yes!
I had come to meet him.
How fortunate that bloody fool is!
Sir, do you know he and me share
the same birthday? - 9th October.
He is even born in
the same year - 1974!
The snafu created by
the Lord above is strange.
Snafu? What's that?
Snafu means a mix-up, confusion.
"Strange is your way,
strange is your play".
"You gave a silver
spoon in the mouth of a rat!"
My plight is similar.
God willed that rat to be born...
...in a millionaire's
home and me, in
What a miserable life!
Slog hard day and night,
but the outcome is the same.
But money isn't everything
in this world, my friend.
You possess a very
precious thing - freedom.
My foot! Freedom is fine
only up to the 15th of August!
I do not want freedom after that!
I want dough, hard cash!
A bungalow to reside,
in, a car to roam around...
...a retinue of people
all around, to salute you!
I have heard that the rich too
have their pot full of sorrows.
Then bestow me with all the sorrows!
Give me cancer, ulcer...
and I won't even whimper a protest.
But give me dough too,
which that swine has.
And in which he is rotting.
I swear, I too want to rot that way!
You are a very interesting
man, friend and extremely lovable.
Really, sir?
Hey, a cordless too?
That's real cool!
Why is the phone getting
disconnected every time?
Is it possible that he has
directly gone to the hotel?
Tell me something.
Where is St. Andrew's Church?
- Hey, that's very far from here.
- Take me there.
There's a 'paan' (betel leaf)
Shop on the way owned by Guruji.
The 'paan' there...
- 'Paan'? What's that?
- Don't you know what it is?
'Paan'? Let's go.
Good-day. How are you?
Prepare two 'paan' for us...
Sir, how do you want yours to be?
- Just like yours.
- Make both yummy? Add tobacco.
Forget about eating 'paan'.
You've been eating it for free since 2 months! ****
Pay first! Then you'll get 'paan'.
Hey, am I going to
run away? I will pay!
Respect me a little.
Sir is with me.
Don't call me sir. I am your
friend. Call me by my name - Rahul.
- How much is it?
- No, sir. Why should you pay?
My credit goes on.
Take this.
You con Balu? You indulge
in smuggling, wearing a suit?
Hey, since when did you
start this illegal business?
Did you print this note
at home huh? Smart lass!
You show a passport? Is it fake?
...And that too, a British passport?
Wow! An illegal
business, in London style!
I called such an affluent man, a rat!
He can buy me with
my taxi! What do I do?
Come on! I'll sit in the front.
Please do. It is
your taxi, Mr. Rahul.
Hey, Balu! Take the 'paan'.
But the next time, I will not
give it to you for free!
Thank you!
- Has Mr. Mehta come?
- Not yet. The press, too, await him.
What do I do now?
Do one thing. Tell him that
Mr. Mehta left directly for Delhi.
There is no need to tell anybody
anything for the time being.
You need not worry.
I'll just go and get rid of them.
- But Rahul?
- He too will come.
He has come from London, not from
a village, that he will get lost.
And don't forget,
Detective Mirchandani is with you.
I'll go and tackle them.
Hello, Ramsingh.
Did you reach safely?
- Yes, we did.
- Fine. Get Rahul on the line.
- Well, he is...
- Say that he is in the bathroom.
- He is in the bathroom.
- As soon as he comes out...
...have him talk to me.
- Okay.
- He is happy, isn't he?
- He is very happy.
Good. Have him talk to me soon.
You are unnecessarily getting
worried. Everything will be fine.
I'm here.
Wonder where Rahul is.
Mr. Rahul... no... buddy.
If my father were to give me
Rs.20,000, then I'd go to Dubai.
Earn 200,000 - 300,000 in 2 years
and have my own business in Mumbai.
Look here. I am trapped in a cobweb.
You are very fortunate, friend.
I wish, I were in your shoes.
If you were in my shoes, then
you'd have got a father like Shastri.
You would have committed
suicide in just two days!
At least, you have a father.
- Hello, Grandpa?
- Who is it?
- So you've come out?
- From where?
- From the bathroom. Where else?
- From the bathroom?
Yes. Ramsingh mentioned that
you were in the bathroom.
I see! So, you've
already spoken to him?
Yes. Didn't he mention it to you?
I had told him to ask
you to telephone me.
Yes. That's why I have called you.
- How did you like India?
- Hey, hang up!
- What's the matter?
- Grandpa, I've eaten 'paan'.
- It's very delicious.
- Delicious, my foot!
Immediately, spit if out. Until
then, give the phone to Ramsingh.
I will kill him.
How did he let you eat 'paan'?
Give him the phone immediately.
Where is that rascal?
Well... he is in the bathroom.
Knock on the door, thump it!
Whenever this city of Mumbai
gets on my nerves, I come here.
I swear, buddy,
I find immense peace.
Balu, do you know, I
was born here in Mumbai?
Really?
My parents died in an accident.
When I was only 2 years old.
My grandpa took me to London
from here, where I grew so big.
But my heart always
pined to come to India.
I wanted to see the house in
which my parents used to live.
And the cemetery
where they were buried.
Buried? Meaning?
Meaning, my mother was a Hindu
and my father, a Christian.
I am half Hindu and half
Christian. And you are a Brahmin.
Only for name sake. My father
considers me to be an untouchable since birth. ****
Therefore he doesn't let me
inside the house. I live separately.
He has given it to me
but I pay the rent.
One more thing. My grandpa
is a millionaire, not me.
I don't claim any
right over his money.
And yes! I do have some money.
Do you yet consider me your friend?
Buddy, you were only
a millionaire previously.
But now... you have become precious!
- Will come to my tiny house?
- Yes. - You can meet mother too.
- Let's go.
- Yes.
- Mother! Father!
- Where did you get this friend from?
- He is my friend Rahul.
- Where do you live?
- Pardon?
- Which caste do you belong to?
He's... a Hindu, a Brahmin. He
belongs to a higher caste than us.
Brahmin? I think,
your friend is very wealthy.
He was in Dubai for 2 years.
That's why he has minted money.
Had you also given me Rs.20,000,
I too would have been rich like him.
Don't talk about money.
I'll go and meet Ramnath.
- Have you eaten?
- No.
Balu, take him home.
I'll be back soon.
- How much one these?
- Rs.40 per dozen.
This is my area.
Afzal Tonda stays here.
He doesn't let any
chances slip out of his hand.
Khalid stays here. An absolute
trickster but he is my buddy.
- Hi, Khalidbhai! How are you?
- Absolutely cool!
And Pakhia's house is here.
He used to think, he was too smart!
But I whacked him,
and he wet his pants!
- Hey, trapped a new
guinea pig? - Hey Michael!
Who asked you to talk?
Get lost!
Shall I whack you?
He talks big!
Do one thing. You go.
There's a rotten tap ahead.
Four-five women will be fighting
there. Near it, is a rotten building.
I live there. Go there. I'll
settle the matters and come soon!
- Hey Balu!
- Don't let him escape!
- Where is Mr. Shastri's house?
- This is it.
- Sister, spare me!
- Quiet!
I've been teaching you
a tune since 2 months.
Let alone the tune, you couldn't
even learn to hold a violin!
- Wait!
- Please, sister!
Wait or you'll surely see me
flaring today. Don't harass me!
- Forgive me, sister.
- Wait.
Alas!
What's this Paro? What's wrong
with you? It's turmeric water!
Yes. The maid just left. I was
sprinkling water to sanctify...
...the house. I was throwing
the remaining water, when he came!
You should have at least
watched. The poor boy is drenched.
No problem.
He has been sanctified.
Look, Balu has come.
Go with him and change... Quiet!
Why did you lie
about me to your family?
I have to, buddy.
You don't know my father.
I can't understand how
to lie this. Please explain.
Wrap it around.
Tie a knot here.
And... take this...
and slip it inside!
Now watch what a fantastic
sacred thread I make for you...
...with the string used for kites...
...that all the girls
here will just stick to you.
You have a piano?
It may be a piano for you.
For me, it is a furniture.
It is in a bad state.
Does anyone keep a piano this way?
It isn't mine;
it belonged to the previous tenant.
He didn't pay. So Shastri
asked him to keep the piano back.
It's been here since then...
Beware of Shastri!
Here's your sacred
thread. Come here.
- Brother.
- Coming.
Come out and witness
the gaiety... Brother!
- I'm coming!
- Hurry!
That's enough! I'm going
to complain to the police.
Are you mad? Do you
want to put his life in danger?
In danger? Meaning?
If you complain to the
police, what will they do?
They will print Rahul's
picture in all the newspapers.
Flash it on all the T. V channels.
The underworld will learn of
it and they will capture Rahul.
So that they can deal
in millions with grandpa.
Hey, mother! There's
so much peace at home today.
Hey, Shastri is not at home!
- Shastri is not at home, indeed!
- You've made very tasty items today.
Hey, will you eat all
alone or feed your friend too?
Hey, what's in friendship?
Just attack!
Yes, son. Attack soon.
For, if he attacks, then there will
be nothing left for you, understand?
Take.
Mother, Rahul was saying that he
wanted to eat 'halwa' (sweetmeat).
So I said that the
halwa which my mother makes...
...is out of this world! Yummy!
You want to eat 'halwa',
and you take Rahul's name instead.
Actually, I have
prepared 'halwa' today.
Fine! Rahul was asking
for it, right? Take, Rahul.
- Eat some 'halwa'. Take, son.
- You are my mother...
...and he will eat 'halwa'?
- Rahul was saying so, son!
- Please give me, mother.
- Feed me with your hands, mother.
- Feed me!
- Take, son.
Brother, I've washed all his
clothes and removed the stains too.
Rahul, stay back for a day or two.
We'll roam around,
watch movies, huh?
Hey! Stay here for a day
or two. We'll have fun.
Yes.
Even I don't feel like going.
I've had food prepared by
a mother for the first time.
- Shall I stay back?
- No asking in friendship.
Just do it.
- No. Uncle Ramu will be worried.
- Then telephone him.
- Shall I talk to him?
- No, I will.
- Uncle Ramu?
- Rahul dear?
Rahul dear, I long
to hear your voice.
I know. I called, so that
you can sleep in peace.
How can I, when you
are not in front of me?
- Are you in trouble?
- No, uncle. I'm absolutely fine.
And I am really
enjoying wherever I am.
I have experienced what
life is, for the first time.
- So I won't be able to come.
- No, son. Don't do this.
There is a press
meeting at noon tomorrow.
The board meeting follows it.
Will you attend?
- Yes and no.
- Meaning?
Meaning, someone else will
attend the meeting instead of me.
Hey, have you gone mad? How can
someone else impersonate you?
He surely can. Look, other than
Mirchandani and yourself...
...nobody else knows who I am.
People will accept anyone whom
both of you present as Rahul Mehta.
And yes. Take care of yourself.
Are you mad?
How can I impersonate you?
- They'll hand me over to the
police. - They will not. I've spoken to them. ****
Now listen. Go straight to
the hotel and confidently say...
Then watch what a red
carpet welcome you receive!
And from where am I going
to get Rahul Mehta's confidence?
Look Balu, if you imagine
that you are Rahul Mehta...
...the sole heir to
72 factories and companies...
...across 16 countries, then
you'll gain confidence naturally.
I won't, buddy! You go.
These complications are beyond me.
You are too much!
Why are you scared? I'm with you.
Look, suppose you do become
a rich man tomorrow, then?
No, this cannot be.
This can't be.
Can I really become rich?
Why not? You surely can.
- Wow!
- If you wish. Do you want to?
- I do want to.
- Then your path is over there.
And yours?
- So, will you be staying there?
- No. Only for 2-3 days.
Have I ever stayed away from you?
I had banned you from coming
home. Why have you come?
I have not come to meet
you but to meet mother.
Forget it.
- Don't talk to strangers.
- I've already stopped doing it now.
- Take care of your things.
- Yes, I will!
- Taken everything you need?
- Yes, I have.
- Have your meals on time.
- There are many to take care of me.
- Look, do have milk at dusk.
- Milk at dusk? I will have.
- What kind of a job is yours?
- It is a very good job, mother.
I'll be interacting with big shots.
I have given up mixing
with such commoners.
Who will give you a job, huh?
He has failed in class X, 10 times!
You will get one job! This!
This is also an art!
What do you know?
Don't impede him when he is
leaving for work!
Hey, move aside!
Bye, Paro. Take care.
- Get lost!
- I am going!
- Hey, you left this, son.
- I'll eat it, mother.
Read further!
Who's it...
Brother, it's your phone.
Who's it? ...Mr. Kante?
What do I do about you, Mathus?
When we met...
...you had said that the chairman's
son would be coming to India.
- Has he come?
- Yes, he has, Mr. Kante.
- So what have you done?
- Two days later...
...there will be a Board of
Directors' meeting. We'll assemble there. **
I'll have the documents signed
as soon as I get a chance.
Mathus, you are so
foolish that I pity you!
Therefore, I spare you every time.
If you act smart this time, then
I will have you leave...
...this world, understand?
This is Mathus family's
promise to you.
After eating so much of our money,
you can't sign on one paper?
We had so many tenants vacate the
place because you wished so!
Remember one thing! Even if I
have to walk over your dead body...
...and build a building here,
I will not hesitate, understand?
Hit the bloody swine!
Stop!
- Hey, where are you going?
- Hey, look there!
- Excuse me.
- Hey, move aside!
This is all I could rattle!
That's the end of my confidence!
Sir, there's a man here. He says,
his name is Rahul Mehta.
- Should I send him upstairs?
- No!
We will come down to receive
him. He... he is our boss.
I'm extremely sorry, sir. I didn't
recognize you, and misbehaved.
It's all right, buddy!
I've got used to hearing this much.
I swear, if you say a word more,
then I'll break you right here!
Hey! What a groovy lass!
My my!
I swear, I should pack her
and take her home!
Impertinent loafer!
I think, he is Ramsingh.
Oh God! What specimen has
Rahul sent?
He looks a hoodlum.
What a snob!
Oh dear, where have you trapped me?
Hey, what a gorgeous room!
What fun it would be if Paro and
mother were here!
I swear, my life will be
made here!
Hey, it's great!
Hey, what are you doing?
Leave me!
How could you dare to
come here as Rahul?!
Answer truthfully, with which
here are you associated?
- Me?
- Yes.
- Your gang has how many more men?
- Gang?
Where have you kidnapped my boss?
Tell me soon where Rahul is or...
Hey! I have no gang!
And I am no hoodlum!
I haven't kidnapped your Rahul!
He's living there on his own volition.
And I'm not fond of staying here,
understand? Look there!
Who's it? Rahul?
Yes. There is no difference between
the man who is with you now, and myself. **
Because of him, I am
very happy today.
Uncle, if you get to know him
once, you will love him.
Rahul dear, I want to meet you.
Uncle, please! I want to stay
here for a few more days.
Fine. If you say so, then...
Order for some juice.
Not understanding?
Fool!
You understand English?
What's all this, Paro?
- What did you say your name was?
- Rahul.
Yes! Your father was a
very noble man.
So was your mother. She was a
very strong and understanding lady.
- Yes! Your mother was a Hindu.
- Yes.
Everybody was dead against
their marriage.
But they loved each other so much
that they silenced everybody.
And they got married in this Church.
Your father used to
play the piano very well.
He was very fond of
teaching children.
Sometimes, he would even begin
in the church itself.
Your father was my younger
brother's good friend.
He would often come to my house.
Therefore, I know about him.
Father, I wish to
visit their graves.
Their graves aren't here.
Perhaps, it is at Mahalaxmi.
Father Braganza will come after a
week. We'll find out from him.
Meet him. Okay?
Are you married?
No, father.
But you surely must be in love
with someone, huh?
My child, remember one thing.
Whatever you do in life,
do it ****
Like your parents. May your
parents' souls rest in peace.
Hold it like this... with this
hand and cut it.
You should hold it this way.
Just a minute...
What's your name?
- And yours?
- Eeshwarkumar Mirchandani. Why?
Aren't you ashamed?
You are named after Gods...
...and you eat food like
you are doing a post-mortem!
Hey, God's given 2 hands. Use it to
the fullest. I'll demonstrate.
Look.
- Balu, how are you?
- Hey, Rahul! How are you?
- First class!
- First class? You're learning!
Tell me, where are you calling from?
- Where are you?
- At the dining table.
I am in the taxi,
waiting at the red signal.
- Hey, I feel very sad hearing it.
- Certainly not! I'm enjoying.
- I am in love.
- You? In love? You're improving!
- Tell me, who is she?
- She is extremely lovely, buddy.
- Have you spoken to her?
- Not yet. - Why?
I'm very scared. It's first love.
I don't know how to tell her...
...from where to begin.
Take the Lord's name and buy her
some thing nice from your first pay.
Suppose she returns the gift, then?
Then it's your bad luck.
But if she accepts it...
...then the green signal will
turn on the line will be clear.
I'm speaking from my cordless.
I can't talk much. I'm very busy.
I am fed up with these meetings
and press conferences. Bye.
Look, think before you
talk in the press conference.
The reporters read a bit
too much between the lines.
- Please make way.
- Hey, shall I break your headlight?
Oh, photographs?
You clicked, then move aside.
Hey beardie, you click.
Wow, this is great!
This is no way. Sit properly!
Brother, our work
will become easier now.
Uncle Ramu, what are the traffic
police doing with this Mercedes?
Rahul dear, he's
Vidyacharan Mathur.
The vice-chairman
of General Products.
He is my younger brother
Shamcharan Mathur.
The company's general manager.
And he is my youngest brother.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Uncle Ramu, does this company
belong to Mehta or Mathur?
I think, grandpa has
employed them in dozens!
For a while, I thought my
name had become Rahul Mathur!
She's my daughter Pooja.
The company's
Public Relation Officer.
Daddy, I think I have
seen him somewhere.
He's coming to India for the first
time. You must have seen someone else.
For example, all the
taxis in Mumbai look alike.
Similarly, people too look alike.
Take your Mathur family, for
example. But you're an exception.
You are different.
- She'll take you around Mumbai.
- Implying, the meter is down!
125.
Sister, when I grow up, will
I also have to study so many books?
You just can't concentrate
on studies and you talk big!
At the speed with which you're
going, you'll end up at a grocer's shop. ****
Sister... I haven't seen
Uncle Pianist since yesterday.
He's very nice, isn't he?
He plays the piano so well.
Sister, here's Uncle Pianist.
I was going home...
I saw both of you.
I thought, even you were
going there. I'll reach you.
Let's go, sister.
Let's go.
Shall we go to eat an ice-cream?
Hey, you spilt all the milk!
Hey you! You park your
taxi in a No Entry lane?
Come out. Isn't this the same cab...
...that had broken the traffic
light at the airport the other day?
Come out. Show me your license.
Is this a license or a credit card?
- It is an international license.
- I know that.
First tell me, where would
you drive a taxi before this?
- In London.
- In which district is it?
- Is this a walkie talkie?
- No, a mobile phone.
Balu, do something. A traffic
cop is after my life. What do I do?
That's all? Give him
Rs.10-20 and close the matter.
- Hurry!
- Okay! Just a minute.
Amazing! I think he got
scared seeing the phone.
- Now speak.
- I'm thoroughly enjoying myself.
- And even I'm stuck in the traffic.
- Meaning. - Try and understand!
- I've met with an accident.
- With whom?
- There is someone.
- How does she look?
If you see her, you'll
go crazy. That latest model of 96!
But I'm scared
of going close to her.
- Scared? And that too, you?
- She's very posh, like you.
Now, you find a way which
will make my driving easy.
Fine, I'll tell you.
Listen intently.
Hey, you are a maestro, buddy.
I was planning to seek your advice.
But you turned the
tables on me. Okay, listen.
It's an everyday hassle!
Looks like all of Mumbai's water...
...is only in this tap!
Look, buddy. Listen carefully.
First of all, slowly
try to find out what she likes.
And do just that. Woo her in style!
Buy her flowers, clothes, jewelry...
And become exactly the
way she wants to see you.
That will be it, buddy!
The matter will click!
She'll go bonkers!
Assume, she is smitten, buddy!
She is smitten! To woo,
is beyond... your 'buddy'!
Because it isn't as
easy as he thinks it is!
Understand, Mr. Whoever-You-Are!
What do you think of yourself?
You ask others, how to woo me?
I didn't know that despite
studying at Oxford University...
...your standards would be so low!
Like an absolute
roadside vagrant! Good bye!
Pooja, where are you going?
Why are you getting so angry?
Rahul, get out of my way!
- Do you want to know?
- Yes, I do.
Before that, listen
to what I want to say.
Yes, I did ask my friend
how to win you because I...
I love you. I am Oxford
University educated.
But when it comes to love,
I am an absolutely illiterate!
You are backward to quite
an extent, let alone love.
This isn't backwardness but
an openness of the heart!
I had got many
proposals in London but...
...you are different.
Now, you teach this
illiterate boy about love.
And I spoke only with my friend;
I didn't make a noise about it!
Will you meet my friend?
He drives a taxi.
What to do now? I am...
Hey, why are you staring like this?
It's me. Didn't you recognize me?
I do recognize!
But I cannot fathom, how a man...
...who was a taxi
driver until yesterday...
...wears a suit,
jacket and boots today!
And the poor boy who
was a millionaire's son...
...roams around as a taxi driver!
I cannot fathom how the
tables have been turned!
- Should I fall unconscious?
- Hey, no!
It's all a matter of luck.
Who knows what will happen when?
Yes.
You just spoke about the stars.
So I'm thinking when
had luck will befall me...
...and the municipality
will break down my shop.
So, I am going
around with a beforehand.
Nothing will happen.
Don't worry.
Just make us 2 'paan'
filled with tobacco.
And make another 'paan'
filled with 'gulkhan'.
Who eats that?
Don't ask that. Just prepare it.
Okay!
I've fallen in love at first sight.
He is my friend Ra... Balu.
...She is Pooja.
He is a very good friend of mine.
- You had me frightened!
- Who is it, dear?
It's only Murli, mother.
I had asked me to bring tamarind
last Sunday. He hasn't yet got it.
The pianist has sent a letter.
He has called you
to the beach at five.
Murli, look how your sister
is trying to impress me.
Hey Paro, where are you going?
- Mr. Shastri, good-day.
- Greetings!
- You look very happy today.
- I am very happy today...
...because my daughter's
alliance has been fixed.
The boy is from an lyer
family and an engineer at PWD.
He has his own house
and hails from a devout family.
He visits the holy pilgrimage
in Tirupati every year.
So it is as good
as fixed, isn't it?
They will be coming the
day-after-tomorrow to see Paro.
Heartiest congratulations.
Don't forget to invite me.
Thank you. See you again.
Mother, what's the hurry?
Let's wait for a few days more.
Why, dear? You've completed your
B.A. You don't want to study further.
I want to study.
I want to do my M. A.
Enough of studying! All your
batch mates have got married.
You too get married
and go to your place.
Don't say that, mother.
I am your daughter.
That is your fault, Paro.
A daughter belongs to someone else.
The home where she is born,
is not her own.
Her home is where
her husband lives.
You are a guest in
this house, dear.
A guest who visits once in a while.
- Sister.
- Where is Rahul?
Paro, I'm very happy today.
Do you know, my parents live here?
I came to meet them.
You also come and meet them.
They'll be very glad to meet you.
What's wrong?
- Who are you?
- I'll tell you everything.
- First, come and meet them.
- No!
Paro, you are insulting my parents.
Come on.
Where have you come from? What
do you want? What's your name?
I am Rahul Mehta, the sole
heir to Mehta Industries.
I am a Christian,
I live in London.
My grandpa is a millionaire.
I have never lacked anything.
My parents are dead.
They reside here nowadays.
And I have come from London to
meet them. Any more questions?
What did my love lack,
that you hid so much from me?
Love? Some thing that gets shattered
in no time, isn't called love.
This is called love!
What my parents felt!
They loved and trusted each other.
They faced the troubles
of the world together.
When they left this world,
they were together even then.
This is love. People hold it
as an exemplar even today.
Your love?
I have seen your love!
Your love was short - lived!
What do you know, what love is?
Go! Go away from here!
You cannot be my Rahul.
- You cannot be my Rahul!
Have you gone to sleep?
I am not sleeping, Laxmi.
I am listening to music.
- What Melodious music!
- Our Rahul play sit.
I know it very well, Laxmi.
Sister, Uncle Pianist
has sent a letter.
How often have I asked
you not to go there?
We are indeed very happy
to meet all of you.
And we like your daughter a lot.
- Do you cook, dear?
- She cooks everything... very well!
- You too ask her.
- How much has she studied?
She is B.A. Passed,
with first division!
Let her also speak.
Is she mute?
No. She talks a lot.
But today, she is feeling shy.
You said that she plays
the violin very well?
Yes. She plays the violin as well
as teaches the children here.
Murli must be getting the violin.
Where the hell is he?
Murli, bring the violin.
What's the matter, dear?
At least, tell your mother.
No, dear! What are you doing?
This cannot be!
Sister has sent this.
Due to the export order of
the Japanese Company...
...Toshika Hara,
being cancelled...
...this is the state of our 25
year old Mehta & Mehta Industries.
Our company's chairman,
Mr. Shambunath Mehta...
...has given us orders
to shut this unit.
And to repay this company's
debt with the 200 million...
...that we'll get by
selling this land.
The court formalities are over.
Only one formality remains now.
For Mr. Rahul Mehta to give his
consent by signing on this document.
Hey, sit down!
Fantastic! He speaks very well!
Just a minute! What a
speech he's written! Wow!
Long live our revolution!
Down with Mr. Mathur!
Mr. Mathur.
- What's happening there?
- Nothing. He is a crazy worker...
...of our company Dattabhau. He's
been on a hunger strike since 9 days.
- He'll die!
- Forget it! It's a hunger strike.
The police will come, beat them
and they'll come to their senses.
- Come in.
- The man's been ***...
...since 9 days. Over it, the cops
will beat him! You should be ashamed!
Are you this company's
vice-chairman or... a butcher?!
- Shame on you!
- Hey, where are you going?
Long live our revolution!
Hey, brothers! Will you
please lower your volume?
- Hail Dattabhau!
- Hey, listen to me!
- Long live our revolution!
- Hey, open the lock!
- What can I do, sir?
- Open the lock!
- Hold this!
- Don't go out! They are dangerous!
- Long live our revolution!
Down with Mr. Mathur!
- Just a minute!
- Fulfil our demands!
My name is Rahul Mehta.
Who is Dattabhau?
I'll show you.
This a very dangerous situation
from the security point of view.
Dattabhau, Mr. Rahul Mehta has come.
I see! Rahul!
Mr. Shambunath's daughter's son!
How are you, son?
I'm fine, but what's all this?
You have not eaten since 9 days?!
At this rate, you will die!
No problem.
Maybe, they will heed us then.
The company is bankrupt.
For how long will they incur losses?
These have never been
any losses, son.
Mr. Mathur and his team
have always taken advantage.
And have always kept
your grandpa in the dark.
He was always kept in the dark!
All of them kept
looting the company.
And today, they are throwing it
in thrash like a sucked bone!
Since the last 6 months, 2,000
laborers have been unemployed!
And they are *** to death!
They are selling this
land for 200 million.
200 million?!
This place must be worth at
least a billion rupees!
They will *** mess up even this
deal! Or what's the need to sell?
Dattabhau, can the company
run on its own again?
Why not? It can!
But on a condition that the
management will be honest.
Then, let's decide today itself.
Come with me!
Hail Rahul Mehta!
Hail Dattabhau!
- Mr. Mathur, have the lock open!
- What are you saying?
I am saying what you
don't want to listen.
- This company will reopen.
- Impossible! It's been decided!
- We've signed the document.
- It does not have my signature!
- Have the lock open.
- Do you know its outcome?
- And the board of directors...
- Damn them! Get a hammer!
Mr. Mehta, what are you doing?
You don't know what will happen.
You are making a mistake.
- Hail Dattabhau!
- Hail Rahul Mehta!
Balu, there's no problem
for the machinery.
If you break this wall, then you'll
make place for it! It's done!
Careful. You'll get hurt.
There will be no wall,
no partition.
Break all of it!
Had you thought about the poor...
...then maybe, this company
would have progressed too!
After today, there will be
no boss and no employee.
All of us will be equal shareholders
of this company's profits.
Do you know who the girl is,
whom I love...
...and am going to marry?
- How do you know?
- Hey. O you think, I'm crazy?
Hey, it is written
all over your face!
Rascal!
My blessings are with you.
Go to sleep.
Brother has kept the room so untidy.
What will Rahul think?
Murli, hold it properly.
Hey, hold it properly!
Hey, I'm coming too!
How could you dare to
touch a Brahmin girl?
Hey, you tease a girl from our
colony! I'll teach you a lesson!
Don't hit him!
Leave my Rahul!
Leave him!
- Somebody save my Rahul!
- Hey, leave him!
If anyone even touches Rahul,
I'll break his hands and legs.
- Balu, don't...
- Get lost! - Don't interfere!
- What's happening?
- You are responsible for this, Shastri! *******
You consider yourself a devout, and
have sins committed in your house?
Guruji, the people here told me just
today that he is a Christian.
And I have witnessed
both of them embrace!
I've seen him visit the cemetery
for Catholics, many times.
His parents graves are there!
- You lied to me?
- He didn't, I did! And I made...
...him wear the sacred thread
so that he could gain entry at home!
You pretended to be Brahmin
despite being a Christian.
You deceived us by
wearing the sacred thread!
- Beat him so much that...
- Quiet!
If any man steps ahead,
I swear, I'll kill him!
He gave you a petty job,
and you have become his slave?
Didn't you think
anything about your sister?
I speak with the right of a brother!
And she has to marry somebody.
So, what does he lack?
Why is Rahul bad?
So what if he is a Christian?
Had I been so orthodox like you...
...then I'd have been starving to
death! And what have you given me?
No, Balu! Stop it!
They want to beat me? You want
to beat me? Please go ahead!
Why have you stopped? Beat me! Yes,
it's true, that I'm a Christian.
But it's also true that we love
each other and want to get married!
If you yet want to beat me,
then do go ahead!
But hear Paro say the truth
once, that she loves...
...and wants to
get married to me.
If this is my crime, then
beat me! Please kill me!
Paro, speak!
Tell them what the truth is.
Please tell them!
Please speak Paro!
Tell them!
Yes, I love Rahul!
I love him very much!
But...
I love my father also very much.
This marriage will take
place only with his consent!
Are you happy now, dear?
You have made your
father bow his head!
My Balu took away half of my life.
Why did you do this, huh?
Do you know that you are
the chief of the Brahmin's society?
Its very foundation could shake
with this decision of yours!
Foundation?
Which foundation?
The foundation of
this house has broken.
And you talk about
the foundation of the society?
My Balu - I threw
him out of the house.
He drives a taxi.
He could have become an engineer.
I did not do anything
for my children! Nothing!
If you wish, then this
marriage can take place but...
...only after
the boy is consecrated.
- Yes, he will do everything.
- You don't interfere.
- Rahul, did you hear?
- Yes, I did. I accept it.
The ritual of consecration
will be very difficult and long.
I accept everything.
The engagement will take
place a week before the wedding.
The decision to marry,
cannot be changed after that.
During this period, the girl
and the boy cannot see each other.
Do you accept?
Yes, I do.
Fine! With God's blessings and
under the auspices of the stars...
...and planets, I fix the wedding
for the 10th of the next month.
Sister, leave me!
- Wow! It's done!
- Hey, what's the matter?
- You appear very happy today.
- It's something to be happy about.
Firstly, you are not angry with me.
Secondly, my sister's
wedding has been fixed!
- Sister?
- And that too, with a...
...very good friend of mine.
Hey, but you had said
that you have no siblings.
And that, you are all alone. Where
did a sister come from suddenly?
I am alone.
But I look upon her as my sister.
- I see!
- Hey, how are you? Real cool, huh!
Hey, what are you doing?
Sit properly.
Do you know who sit this way?
The taxi drivers here.
Me, a taxi driver? Rubbish!
But hats off to your
observation! What... Wow!
- Let's have a 'paan' to that!
- 'Paan'? - Eat and see!
Hey Balu?
How are you?
Hey, you stare again!
Hey, your eyes will
fall off into the 'paan'.
Look here. My, my!
Isn't she very beautiful?
Do you know who she is?
She your daughter-in-law!
- How is she?
- Very lovely! Absolutely lovely!
A suit, a tie and boots,
in the first round!
In the second, a bride and a car!
And in the third round,
there will be a lovely baby!
Now, that depends on her!
- What do you think, darling?
- About what?
About what he is saying.
Hey, try and understand!
Hey, where are you going?
- Hey listen!
- What's wrong?
Mrs. Patel, this is Rahul
speaking from Mumbai. How are you?
- How is grandpa?
- Oh Rahul? Everything's fine.
Hey, I am going to get
married on the 10th next week.
I've called four times.
Why hasn't anyone informed grandpa?
Please do inform grandpa.
Rahul is so highly educated.
Why does he drive a taxi?
There's an advertisement
published for a good job.
The interview will be held
tomorrow. Ask him to go.
I'll go and meet the men
preparing the podium.
- Have you heard what I said?
- Yes, I have.
Hey, don't go in front of
him! It will be sacrilegious!
I won't.
Greetings! How are you?
How are your parents?
Won't you come in?
Won't you come in front of me?
Don't you desire to meet me?
Do you think of me?
How often?
Enough. Now tell me,
What brings you here?
Father...
I am going for my interview.
Where have you
brought me, Ramsingh?
Hey Paro, take care of the
children! Or else, throw them out!
How could you let Rahul
stay in such a deplorable colony?
It stinks everywhere.
Mirchandani, which house is it?
I'll inquire, Sir...
Which his Mr. Shasti's house?
- That vagrant, Balu's father?
- Yes.
Take a right, then a left.
It's the first house.
First right, then left.
Please come, Sir.
What an awful place
you've brought me to!
Wow, what an auspicious day!
I say, there cannot be
a better day than the tenth.
The stars favor this marriage.
If they get married in this period,
they'll lead a happy married life.
Who, amongst you,
is P.V.K. Shastri?
I am. What is the matter?
- He is Mr. Shambunath Mehta.
- London's eminent businessman.
So what am I to do?
- Rahul is my daughter's son.
- What! You are Rahul's grandpa?
Where is Rahul?
I'll take rent from you if you
stay in my room after marriage.
- Rascal!
- That I am. - The retinue is here.
Your grandpa has come from London.
- Where is he?
- At Balu's place. - Let's go.
I'm sorry, I didn't know
that you Rahul's grandpa sit.
- I have not come here to sit.
- Rahul must be on his way.
He is getting married to my
daughter the day-after-tomorrow.
- Grandpa! You?
- Are you displeased to see me?
What are you saying!
I knew, you would surely come.
I have not come here
to attend the wedding.
I have come here to
take you back to London.
Most of the arrangements are done.
Fine! Arvind, pay Mr. Shastri
for all the losses he has incurred.
I knew, this is precisely
what you would do.
After all, you are the son
of that father who was born...
...in this filth!
Grandpa, for God's sake,
do not speak ill about my parents.
Your mother was my daughter too.
There is no need
to talk too much here.
Mr. Shastri, this is for the loss
and the trouble you undertook.
Keep it.
You have no right to insult
anyone. Apologize to him.
You are not in
your senses right now.
The infamy I had to
endure because of you...
...is enough to last a lifetime.
Ramsingh, tell him that
all of us will be returning...
...by tomorrow's flight.
- Rahul dear...
- Uncle Ramu.
You have greatly
deceived me, Ramsingh.
Despite being an old, loyalist
of mine, you kept me in the dark.
Didn't you find anyone
else other than Rahul...
...to send, to that
deplorable colony?
You forgot your standing!
This** has proved, he is the
son of that father...
...whose life began from a dirty
slum and ended there too.
That's enough, Mr. Shambunath.
You may tell me anything.
But I won't tolerate even a word
spoken against my Rahul.
- You are not his father, Ramsingh!
- I know, I'm not his father.
But I have nurtured him
for 19 years.
Thanks for that!
But you have done no favor.
You were paid for this,
every month.
Wow! Wow, Shambunath!
You, eventually, did weigh years
of loyalty with money!
Driver, stop the car.
Shambunath, your
daughter left you.
Don't lose your son now, or you
will be left all alone.
Driver, start the car.
- Who are you? What you want?
- Quietly come with us!
Or I'll shoot you!
Come on!
Mr. Shambunath!
Mathus... what is all this?
We have to do this sometimes.
What do I do?
If we had amicably asked you to
transfer all the factories...
...of Mumbai, in our
names, would you have done so?
No, right? Therefore, we
kidnapped you.
Mathus, you have
always been foolish.
Your petty mind is
working over-time.
And you are committing a
folly again.
Mr. Mehta, Mr. Mathus has not been
so audacious, I have.
And I am not foolish.
Kante is my name.
Now, quietly sign it. Anyway, I'm
not fond of kids and old people.
I will. But it is futile.
Before coming to India, I had
transferred all my properties...
...businesses and bank
accounts in Rahul's name.
I told you, I am not foolish.
I have arranged for this too...
Call Rahul.
Look, I'm Rahul speaking...
His grandson Rahul Mehta.
Ask him to telephone me
as soon as he gets back.
Let's eat, son.
Balu will not come.
I think, Balu has come.
- Uncle Ramu!
- Grandpa has been kidnapped!
- What are you saying?
- The truth, son.
- It has to be his doing.
- Come with me.
Let's go.
- Is Mr. Mathus there?
- No. Brother is not here!
Swine! Tell me where my
grandpa is!
Hey, Rahul! He'll die!
At least ask him where
grandpa is.
His face reveals that this is his
doing! Answer, swine!
Tell me, where is grandpa?
Answer!
I told you, he is not Rahul.
Have you ever called me, your own
since childhood? Never!
Your lust to earn money made
you so crazy...
...that you never knew when
the ones your own, went away from you!
I do not want your wealth,
your luxuries! I don't!
Look! Despite death being so
close to you, you fail to understand!
You refuse to accept your Rahul?
What difference does my
signature make?
I was an orphan, I am
and will remain one!
Hey, resolve your family disputes
outside! Quietly sign now!
First, go and get the sign of the
man who wrote this on my hand!
Hey, where has it gone? Whose
signature did you want?
Oh, mine? You unnecessarily
wasted my time... Crazy man!
Let's go, grandpa.
Mathur's and Kante's men have
kidnapped grandpa.
Where are you now? I need your
help. Why aren't you talking?
You deceived Kante!
Tie the scoundrels!
- Who asked you to act smart?
- We had escaped.
Your name is Balu, huh?
You are Rahul's friend.
Now telephone him and call him.
Hey, I am Rahul's friend! I'll
die but won't call him! Get lost!
Hey you! The value of your
life has fallen down.
Quickly telephone Rahul or I'll
decrease the life span of your grandpa!
Hey Kante, you are a big fool!
He made his grandson's life, a hell.
He never loved him.
Is Rahul an ass, to risk his life...
...and save this stone-hearted man?
I am telling you, he will not come.
Do one thing. Rack your petty mind
and think of a new plan.
Then telephone me. We'll talk.
I'll leave now.
Stop your theatrics, or I shall
end your grandpa's life!
Telephone Rahul!
Quickly telephone him, or the
next bullet will come out...
...from your grandpa's brains!
Rahul, where are you now?
- No! Spare me!
- Spare him. He's my father-in-law!
Even I am!
Rahul, run!
Swine! You dared to touch
my grandpa!
Grandpa, forgive me. I behaved
impertinently with you.
For a while, I felt that I had
lost you forever, son.
No, grandpa. I'll take you to
the hospital.
No, I do not want to
go to the hospital.
I want to first attend my
grandson's wedding.
- First, come to the hospital.
- I said, I don't want to!
You are very stubborn.
You are right. Just like you.
Balu, come here.
- Balu.
- Yes?
Tell him that he is the cane
now of this lame man.
He can take me wherever he wants.
Let's go.
Mr. Shashi, now get Balu
also married quickly.
Who will marry him, Mr. Mehta?
- What's this?
- Marriage. - Marriage?
It is said that the
movement of stars...
...make or break a
person's life.
Someday, when a star up here taken a
left... I'm sorry, a right turn...
...then in the earth below...