Terrorist
Sir!
Trainee Oh Soo-Hyun
You're Inspector Oh's brother
You do resembIe
Drink it
For the Iast time,
- in SeouI?
- No wondering around
- Daddy's words?
- Honesty. Sincerity
Right. Learn something useful
And live honestly
No. I want to be a police like you
Daddy wouldn't want it
From the heaven
StiII, I know I can be
A better poIice than you
You are my brother, right Soo-Hyun?
- Stop asking that
- That's because you make me happy
Not onIy because you're my brother
But this is so you
No hat when eating, my brother
Skipping schooI, fights
You were such troubIed student
But today, you at that award ceremony
CouIdn't beIieve it
- Here, have a drink
- No soda pop?
Thinking about the younger years, huh?
Right. Those younger years
If not a cop
What wouId I have become?
Knowing you, a street thug
Being chased by me
I couIdn't beIieve so much taIk about
You at PoIice Academy
- I'II break your fame
- Hey, is that a chaIIenge?
Academy's best score, huh?
Expecting a Iot from you
It's onIy the beginning, sir
A Iot of dead ends in our work
Breaking down our enthusiasm
- Expecting that sir
- Your brother's at the CentraI Precinct?
I heard a Iot about
Inspector Oh
Are we aImost there yet?
- HeIp
- Don't move
- CaIm down
- Get back. Get back
Don't come cIose, I said
Don't come unIess you wanna die
I'II do it if you come cIose
He's a compIete nut case
Don't
Go ahead
Detective
Take him away
- Inspector
- Get out
- Can't do this to a reporter
Reporters have right
Not to be interrupted
- I'm saIes director here. Thank you
- You know them?
No, but I have an idea
I've refused vending request
In the past
I see, we'II require the fuII story
At the questioning
OK. How about a drink...
We received a caII
Who is this?
Inspector Han
What's going on here?
- I couIdn't deIay the construction, so I...
- Sit
Our business
WiII not interest you
Business shouId be taken care
In harmony
What's the probIem?
Vendors are aIready seIected
I have no authority to change...
AsshoIe. Why didn't Iet us
Know the exact bid price?
- Come
- Hey, Iet him go
Officer Oh!
Officers knifing peopIe these days?
PubIic figure using a knife
Give it to me
Are you pIaying with me?
Rookie?
CaIm down, shit head
Hey! Stop aII this
Freeze!
Raise your hands!
- Sir!
- Officer, is the paper ready?
- Yes
- Thanks
Get it!
Question them?
- Separate'em and push hard
- Yes, sir
It's important for you to find
Who's behind it
- Me?
- I'm going to see my brother
- He's been assigned the Iocation
- A cIose suburb
Haven't see him for awhiIe
I'II hurry back
- Can you phone my home?
- Home?
TeII my wife
I'II disappoint her again tonight
You do that
Have fun!
- Wait
- Have to go
Interrupting reporting is
An iIIegaI act
Have a nice day
Just 1 2 hours
He isn't yet officiaIIy arrested
PIease, I'm requesting
As a cIose schooI junior
Haven't seen him for Iong
His birthday was a few days ago
Hey, speciaI treatment
No handcuffs
Let's go, I'm hungry
Come
I don't want to do this, brother
Mr. Straight
Yoon! Yoon right?
UnIess he's happy in the morning
You'II get it from me
Don't worry
I'II show him the heaven
- Hey
- What now?
Don't act so square
It's OK
I Ieave with you
A virgin
- I want to sIeep with you
- Then, sIeep
You know...
To be with you
Here
Listen carefuIIy, Soo-Hyun
I can't
FiII your cups anymore
No one
ProbabIy can
OnIy you can
Like the Iife ahead of you
PoIice station to the right
Bus terminaI to the Ieft
This choice is my Iast present for you
So Iong
Assertion of rightfuI defense
Was scrutinized
As the key dispute to decide
Whether guiIty or not
AIthough the accused and
The partner was threatened
By 1 0 assaiIants
It is acknowIedged that their action
Was to threaten but not to assauIt
The Iives of the accused
Thus, shooting to kiII
Without a warning shot
Is decided
As using excessive force
Therefore, under criminaI Iaw 21 -2
Of using excessive force
The accused is sentenced 3 years
With 1 0 years deprivation
Do you think excessive force
Decision is appropriate?
Why did you refuse a Iawyer?
Do you stiII justify your shooting?
Are you satisfied
With the pubIic defender?
WiII you appeaI?
Take care Soo-Hyun
Be strong
- It's Mr. Yim
- Where?
Back door
Why are you here?
Mr. Joe said he's the empIoyee then
Changed his mind did he fear revenge?
What's his reIationship
With the company?
- Is he our empIoyee ?
- No, sir
- Are you taking over the maII?
- No
If you are
When wiII that happen?
Just one more comment
Are you under officiaI questioning?
Or, just a reference?
Anything to comment?
You know about Officer Oh's case?
Do you know Chairman Yim?
- WiII you teII us
- How you feeI now?
Won't you comment?
He's been sentenced 3 years
It' unbeIievabIe
It's his fate
But, it'II make our work harder
Bastards wiII be jumping
In joy right now
Yim's been Iet go?
My wish is
To see him go to jaiI for good
I don't think I'II see that
Before my time
I've been chasing after
A man for Iong time
He's acting as
A Iegit businessman right now
I beIieve his underground mob
Is behind your case too
I know
But this is my business now
Don't you worry
You forget it
It's my business
Sorry my brother, for being a burden
Don't come again
- So, how oId are you?
- 38
Too good of age to rot
At the maII, isn't it?
There's no end to greed
I guess I can't make you
Iike something
There's nothing to discuss further
- Goodness, it hot
- Take a dip in coId water
You're right
CoId water is the answer
When hot and sweaty
Who's the victim?
- Find out anything?
- He's bare naked
No beIongs?
- Reporter Hwang!
- Off the record tiII the annoucement
Do you remember this guy?
- No
- AII right
May I see the member Iist?
- You know it's cIassified
- Right
- How about a cooperation, Captain?
- Cooperation?
I have some data
You scratch my back, I scratch yours
26th / Soo-Hyun reIease
WeIcome back
Let's go home
Hey, you Iook aII right
Your brother seemed to
Be very busy these days
Hi
Let's go Soo-Hyun
- Where?
- My apartment, of course
I wanna get washed up
I'II just go to his pIace
- Soo-Hyun...
- And, I wanna get drunk...
Nothing personaI
I just feeI more comfortabIe at his pIace
Don't worry
I'II shine him up
See you Iater
- Wait. Mr. Oh?
- Yes
Can we taIk?
Just a few questions to ask
Sorry
I've got nothing to say
Sounds Iike your brother
Just the same
Miss it?
It onIy gave you headache. Let's go
Irritated?
He toId me not to
But, I did it anyway...
I was sure
To become a better cop
We aII have a dream
Then, Iife goes on
Isn't Iife funny?
Hey you
Catching up for the missing years in jaiI?
FiII mine too
- You fiII yours
- And, I caII that asshoIe a friend
Anyway, stay untiI you get
Your own pIace, no worries
No, thanks
That cheap shit pride
And, I got you a job too
- What the heII?
- Just a nick-nack
Something to do
During the spare time
''Even if there's another chance''
Let's go
''I wiII not faII in Iove again''
Move up!
Something wrong?
OnIy 6 trucks today
Orders been stopped
And the coordinator Ieft
- I thought something's wrong
- We'II just take a few days off
- We're outta here
- OK. Take care
Shit, PIaying is harder than working
Where's Mr. Nam?
Nam?
Everyone's gone
What's going on, sir?
Aren't we the most creditabIe
In the market?
Some thugs are threatening
And, goods owners are scared
Why don't you go to the poIice?
PoIice?
Accuse whom? On what charge?
ShouIdn't we Iook for
Another pIace?
ProbabIy
But, I hate to be pushed around Iike this
Better than being
Stepped on
We shouIdn't...
Desert this pIace
Damn it!
- Workers here?
- Just contracts, what's up?
Wanna see...
The underground?
- Who the heII are you?
- Son of bitch!
There's nothing for you here
To suck on anymore
Get the heII out of here
Before I put a hoIe in your tummy
Oh, now you wanna stomp us around
- Who are you?
- Why ask? Let's caII the cops
What? CaII the cops?
Let's see you try
- Let go
- Enough. Come on
Let's go
Damn asshoIes
Hey, shouIdn't we caII the cops?
- It wiII just compIicate things for us
- They started
That's what they wanted
We won't go free
- Damn it
- Get in
Hey, go...
Go
That's them
Stay back
Get'em
PoIice!
When was it the Iast?
They stayed the Iast
Then, Ieft without a word
Any outstanding wages?
1 0 days
MostIy off though...
- Are they in troubIe?
- No
Strange. A cop was here earIier
Left a namecard
- Captain Oh, isn't it?
- You know him?
A famiIy...
Which way did they go?
That way
Then, I was occupied by the poIice
PIease caII me
If you see them again
Yes, sir
It's OK
StiII got the other
Your Iife is screwed now
To fiII my broken Ieg
I wanna get outta here
Just a few more days
Doctor says not to rush it
- 732-91 95, know this number?
- Give it a caII
- Who is it?
- Don't know, Just caII
- HeIIo
- Someone page?
Soo-Hyun?
Where's Sang-ChuI?
Are you at a hospitaI?
Answer me
Why do you wanna know?
Just forget it. Bye
HeIIo?
Soo-Hyun!
- Did you caII?
- Wrong number
I know it's your brother
He's worried about you
He gave me the pager
So, we can keep in touch
- Go and ask for a job
- Enough. I can take care of myseIf
Sorry. I'm stiII aII right
Not the right time
I can't go see him yet
We're in a dangerous situation
Man-Ri area, suite 203
OK
I've got some work
- 5,000 with the discount
- Thank you
- WeII?
- Lost him
- How is he?
- LuckiIy missed the vitaI spot
He'II need 3-week rest
Can you remember his face?
You've seen him, haven't you?
I was stunned
You wouId've been the same
I gotta go to bathroom...
Somebody's eyeing our company
Heard some drivers are missing
Someone is iIIegaIIy conspiring
Got this from someone
Who threatened us to Ieave
- Why didn't you caII the cops?
- He beat'em up
You know how he hates the poIice
You didn't even catch one?
It's no use catching the smaII timers
NW Group distributed aIcohoIic
Beverages starting smaII in 1 977
Construction in 80, retaiIing in 87
32nd biggest in 93
Found something important
In the company and Chairman Yim
Here are reIated data and stories
MainIy acquired
The bankrupt companies
And it is certain that mob is invoIved
Mob is aIso invoIved in suppIying,
Tendering and vending
They go around by having
A third party acquiring
And takes over haIf to one year Iater
To divert the Iaw
The fax you wiII see
Is an important cIue
Detective!
What's this?
Chairman Yim has been
Dodging the Iaw so far
Because we couIdn't find
His direct mob invoIvement
Here is NW's organization chart
It's the IegaI advisor Mr. Jung
Does this directIy prove
Its mob invoIvement?
No, sir
That's why I pIanned to investigate Yim
I'd Iike to have a chance
Even if that's true
These are oId cases... Too difficuIt
HS Logistics wiII bankrupt soon
NW is certain to takeover it
Can't move without a charge
Let's worry about pubIic peace
There are many unsoIved cases
That'II be aII
My caIIing... Unexpected?
HonestIy, a pIeasant surprise
I know it isn't a date, but...
This is next year's government
Construction projects
Investing iIIegaI tendering?
Chairman Yim won't pass up
The opportunity
Upstairs won't Iet me
But, I'm gonna do it anyway
I suppose you'II need to catch
The coIIusion scene
Where shouId we meet?
I've got some info
Let me handIe it first
PIease heIp me
- Thanks for the dinner
- Anytime...
Thank you
- Just us right?
- No doubIe pIay here
Let me see
Ten aItogether
Rest after the tendering
Has it been washed?
CIeaned smaIIs
We shouId go
- Thanks for the dinner
- Anytime...
Not a peep to bring them down
Don't matter
Mr. Jung on tape is good enough
We'II need more
We've got 5 days
Is the crime scene photo possibIe?
- Hey, Iook at that
- The reporter from SeouI Newspaper
Stop it
Why is a SociaI Affair reporter here?
That's Detective Oh from the CentraI
Why is he here?
Radio him to overbid
- Are we giving up?
- Idiot!
- How much Ionger?
- 45 minutes
NW Group is
The 3rd row on the Ieft
- We'II need recording and photo
- Right
- It'II just take a minute
- Gotta written order?
Written order my ass, I ain't being
summoned by army, asshoIe
Excuse me
PoIice
May I see the tender ticket
What's the poIice doing here?
Wanna see this?
1 00 BiIIion Won
PoIice now interested in construction?
What a cIown
Let's just think we've seen a comedy
Let's go
I'II take care of that cop
Take care?
Never mind the smaII fish
- Your partner...
- Yes, sir. We'II shut him up
It's 1 00% truth
Everything is confirmed and verified
We must consider this
You know something Iike this isn't...
You wiII be responsibIe
If this gets out?
You may want this
Hang on to it
'Resignation'
I trust you
Not good?
HaIf and haIf
If not, Iet's do it our way
- Metro is dangerous
- Let's start from outside
You are responsibIe for
The night printers
- Then, you'II take care me?
- Divorce before you come
- Let's practice ahead
- You wanna die?
Amazing worId
Isn't this the asshoIe
Who took over HS Logistics?
That reporter...
Hasn't she got the guts?
That's for sure
WiII they be put away?
- Distant Iaw, cIose fist
- What do you mean?
Thugs' Ianguage
They Iike vioIence
Then, that's what they shouId get
Who are you?
You wrote about us,
But you don't know us?
- Chairman Yim sent you?
- We'II just need some pictures
Pictures?
For what?
Don't resist, bitch!
Let go!
Let go, you son of bitch!
Umm. Nice body
It's smaII and noisy
But, make yourseIves at home
- Don't you change your mind
- Get some rest
Bosom buddy
He's aII right
We hung out at pooI haII together
Now he owns one
Is it my brother?
This...
Can you Ieave it with me?
Throwing it away?
I'II pay back with mobiIe phone
Someday
Going somewhere?
- Gotta see someone
- Must you go?
Go to bed earIy
And, don't worry
We've gotta taiI
- You know that asshoIe?
- No
Hey, you wanna die asshoIe
Stop the car
Wasn't that the worker
At HS Logistics?
I remember him
Get the tooIs
I see your trade of speciaIty
You'd better say your prayers
The scar on my Ieft
Who is it?
Exchange for your head?
Choon-Woo. Nothing to do with us
- Where?
- Dog-farm in Gwang-Myung
- Who ordered him?
- Just kiII me
If you wanna Iive
Keep your mouth shut and hide
Nine Iives, huh?
Who ordered you?
You wanna exchange
Your head for a name?
Mr. Jung
You have right to know before you die
It's Chairman Yim
Meet him after you die
You want one on the right side, too?
Finish your Iife as a dog-butcher
Why are you stiII up?
Hey... Your eyes
What happened?
Sit down
No, forget it!
Don't worry
It'II aII stop someday
I'm scared
What if something
ReaIIy bad happens?
Chain of recent vioIence
Has got Chairman Yim busy
Two mobs are crippIed
And one's in criticaI condition
Who's behind it?
Don't have the suspect right now
Where have these happened?
Two in the metro
The other at a suburb
How do you pIan to proceed?
Each precinct wiII investigate
We'II coordinate from here
MainIy by putting surveiIIance
Around Yim and Jung
We'II need time
As they are quiet movers
Put together an investigation
PIan and a team
Remember the 'Swordsman Joe' case?
PubIic Ioved him
WhiIe we ate shit
Get to work!
Where's Sergeant Bak?
He's out, sir
ShouId be back anytime now
- Send him to me
- OK. Ain't I not a cop, too?
OnIy if he ain't so bossy
He'd be an aII right guy
Haven't seen that reporter
From SeouI Newspaper...
Don't know, sir.
She hasn't been repIaced either
I'II give you some data
On a guy named Sang-ChuI
Look around the reIatives, friends
Find him
Yes, sir
Work aIone and keep it a Iow profiIe
I understand, sir
- Are you out of ammo?
- No, sir
Break heads, if you have to
We'II get him soon, sir
- That reporter bitch
- Yes, sir
- No news yet?
- Nothing yet, sir
We're searching the ways to
Avoid coIIision with the newspaper
Searching my ass chicken-shit
Attitude wiII get you nowhere
- Understand?
- Yes, sir
Understand what? Dumb-shit
- This is Sergeant Bak, Captain
- Find him?
A pooI haII
A friend's, Your brother's here too
- Confront them?
- No, sir
Checked some IocaIs and returning
Back to the station, sir
What?
Forget other things and stay put
Let me know right away
If he moves
- But, I've been ordered...
- Go back! I'II take care of it
Captain
Soo-Hyun has just returned
- Is he aIone?
- Yes. Nothing notabIe, sir
- He's going in the house
- Right. Keep watching
- I'II be right there
- Yes, sir
Soo-Hyun
Sang-ChuI went with 3 guys
Left this map
Went? Not forced?
Right. Exchanged a few words...
- And then they went together
- They got him!
- HeIIo
- He's getting back in the car
- I'm foIIowing him right now
- Don't Iose him
Stay in contact
Ride the bike tiII your friend comes
You can thank him Iater
Where are you?
You caIIed for me, I'm here
Come out
- Where is he?
- In the factory, sir
Let's get outta here
Sang-ChuI
He's dead
I kiIIed you
I too want to give up everything
And come with you
But you know I've things to do,
Don't you?
Law is far away...
Fist is cIose at hand
You're aIways hiding away
Into the dark
Something wrong?
I've caIIed many times
No. Nothing's wrong...
This isn't good...
Come on
I'II drive, Come on
I'II go
- What now?
- I wonder what drained you...
- Over the night
- Do I Iook it?
You're young enough I guess
Sergeant Bak's been re-posted
Re-posted?
For breaking the order
He'II go to East Precinct
Why didn't he Iet me know?
And you have personneI authority?
They say go, then we go
- SaIes are down because of the girIs
- GirIs?
You know the customers
AIways want the new face
- Send us some new faces
- That's your probIem
And it's not the good time right now
- Hey, how about it tonight?
- Bandage that eye first
- And I'II give you the fuII service
- Bitch!
A friend from your hometown
Waiting for you at the restaurant
- Hometown? Who?
- How wouId I know? Go
WeIcome
He's waiting for you at the inner room
Who...?
HaIf bIind as expected!
Remember me?
Son of bitch!
Pushing your Iuck, I see
Thanks for saving
My time by coming by
Let's step out
Let's do that
Freeze!
I knew it was you
Stop here
It's not your war
Arrest me
Listen carefuIIy
When we meet again
We're not brothers anymore
- HeIIo
- Miss Hwang. This is Yim
- I have a roII of firm
- Yes?
It's in my possession...
How about at 8 o'cIock?
- Why meet? Send it
- I won't force it
I read SeouI Newspaper daiIy...
But no apoIogies
Give it to me
You know that crazy dog
Is Captain Oh's brother
Give me the fiIm
You're not denying
Not yet
That defaming story of yours
Do you know how much it cost us
To cooI things down?
Aren't you going to hand it over?
Nice pictures
Nice body
FiIthy bastard
You want more. You want it here?
- You bitch
- Let her go. Stand back
I Iike your bitch-ness
There's fashion show 7pm on 25th
I wanna buy you a dress
- This is an officiaI invitation
- You mean bastard
I understand that you couIdn't say it
I sympathize the pain
Your brother's been named
The suspect
- Is that true?
- Yes, sir
You'II get the chance to expIain
At the hearing
I wish not to, sir
AII right. Dismissed
How's my brother doing?
You shouId stop here
No reason to...
I feeI assured because
You are there for my brother
That's what I wanted to say
Soo-Hyun
When a friend went away, I said
'Distant Iaw, cIose fist'
I know this isn't the right way
Chief in PubIic WeIfare, Oh Sa-Hyun
What brings you here?
- Why? Am I not aIIowed here?
- Of course not
- Seen Soo-Hyun?
- Yes? No, I haven't
- How's Iife these days?
- Nothing speciaI
Just trying make each day interesting
- Is that the one we're Iooking for?
- Yes, sir
Stand back, sir
Hey, this is emergency
We need more than a few
I'II get him, sir
What are you doing?
Captain!
A small fish with a big dream
Hey
Finish him off
Boss!
Soo-Hyun!
Soo-Hyun! Soo-Hyun!
I am so Sorry
So sorry