NETFLIX PRESENTS
Every love story...
begins with the first meeting.
But my love story...
begins with my arranged marriage.
AMBARAWA, CENTRAL JAVA, EARLY 1998
You must be wondering why,
in this modern times,
there are still families
who arrange their daughter's marriage.
It's all because of my father.
He married a woman
who has now become my stepmother.
Mrs. Indah.
- Come, they're waiting at the garden.
- Right.
Let me take you there.
Come on, honey. Let's go, Yura.
Yura...
Yes.
Please sit down, Mrs. Indah.
If you will excuse me,
I'll go and call Mrs. Sadewo.
Thank you.
She is my father's wife.
He married her
a year after my mother passed away.
GERRY HAR
YOUTH'S FAVORITE SINGER
Why haven't I seen
this edition before, Dad?
Do you think they would let me have it?
Why do you need it?
Every magazine and newspaper clipping
about your father is kept in storage.
And this is my father, an ex-musician
who is not famous anymore.
Excuse me. There are two gentlemen
outside with flowers.
Did any of you order them?
- I don't think so.
- I ordered them, sir.
This way.
Here's your flower, miss.
Thank you.
And I've picked the ones
according to your favorite color.
Miss.
Here is the invoice.
Security, tell her to come in!
Ms. Yura, you've been asked to come in.
These two are my best friends.
They are the substitutes
for all that I have lost.
Is there anything else? Please go.
- No, we don't.
- We don't.
Please forgive me.
- Did you wait long?
- Mrs. Sadewo.
This is Nisa.
- Who is this?
- She is my biological daughter.
Mrs. Sadewo.
Gerry.
I am one of your biggest fans.
Yura. Come here, honey.
This is Yura.
She is my biological daughter.
She's beautiful.
Please have a seat.
Go on.
Be my guest.
Boby's two younger brothers are married.
Even Kevin, the youngest one,
is going to get engaged.
I don't want to see Boby
getting stepped over again.
This will never happen if my husband
doesn't support me, Mrs. Sadewo.
I really appreciate it, Gerry.
Hi, honey.
- How are you, sir?
- I'm fine.
Boby Sadewo.
Yura.
- Yura Diandra...
- Diandra Hartono?
And I'm sure Diandra
is your mother's name.
I'm just guessing.
Sir, we are going to do
a music recording soon.
We're going to do it together?
Mom, haven't you told him?
All right, please have a seat.
We'll talk about it now.
- Hi, Mrs. Indah.
- Boby.
Hi.
How is your new house, Bob?
I didn't choose
the wrong architect, did I?
In fact, I really like the design
of the recording studio...
You have your own recording studio?
Our recording studio,
to be precise, Mr. Gerry.
Are we going to record there?
While the instruments
are still brand-new. Why not?
Why don't you take Gerry
and Yura to see that place?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sadewo,
but I can't do it today.
- I am scheduled to perform today.
- You can cancel it, can't you?
This is more important.
Or maybe Yura can go in your place?
That's a good idea.
She used to go with his father
during recording sessions.
I don't mind.
If you both give us permission,
I'll be glad to take her there.
We wouldn't mind at all. Right, Gerry?
How about it, Yura?
Do you want to come?
Like every love story,
it's always beautiful in the beginning.
At a time like...
A FREE ADAPTATION
OF THE LEGENDARY TELEVISION SERIES
I'm looking at her and feeling sad
I saw that there's something there
Are you really
going to make an album for my father?
Why are you asking me that?
Who listens to old music nowadays?
I still listen to old music.
I still listen to The Beatles, Queen,
Koes Plus, the Indonesian band,
and I also listen to Aerosmith.
They're all legends, right?
Who knows? Maybe I am the one
who can turn your father into a legend.
At a time like yesterday
I was silent without saying a word
- Yes, right.
- Hey.
- What shall we do?
- What do you mean?
The music is lame and old.
- You want to leave?
- Let's just get out of here.
- Come on.
- Let's go.
Do you need a towel?
I'll get it myself in the bathroom.
Hiding with grief
In the empty stars
and the dark cloudy night sky
I'm waiting for her
To take me back again
Thank you.
That was the last song for all of you
who came here tonight.
Have a great night.
Thank you, sir.
Yura hasn't come home yet?
I think she stayed overnight.
Where did she stay?
At Boby's house, of course.
Here's your coffee.
Why aren't you concerned that Yura
spent the night at Boby's house?
Why do I need to be concerned?
She will soon be his wife anyway.
In fact, the sooner the better.
The sooner the wedding is held,
the sooner you can release your new album.
Isn't that right?
Come on, eat your breakfast.
Who could that be
this early in the morning?
Go and take a look.
Is it your friend?
Good morning, Mrs. Sadewo.
- Mrs. Sadewo.
- We didn't expect you to come so early.
- Please come in.
- That's not necessary.
I just want to give this back.
- That's for me. Have some manners.
- Wait, I just want to see it.
LETTER OF DEBT AGREEMENT
A letter of debt agreement?
Give it to me!
Careful! Don't tear out the letter!
It's very important!
Mrs. Sadewo, haven't we talked
about this yesterday?
The wedding is cancelled,
including the recording of Gerry's album.
You owe her five billion rupiah?
Why did we come to her house?
Please shut your mouth!
So you don't even know
the affairs of your own wife?
Mrs. Sadewo,
let's just talk this through, okay?
Seize the house.
- Go!
- Take the deed and all their belongings.
- Wait!
- Please, Mrs. Sadewo!
Please. I will take responsibility,
but please tell me what happened?
Hey!
Your daughter has robbed Boby.
And she left a scar on his face.
- Mrs. Sadewo!
- Hey!
Mrs. Sadewo!
- Yura is my daughter, not hers!
- Please, I will talk to Yura.
- I will talk to her!
- Yura is my daughter!
- She is my responsibility!
- Gerry!
She'll never do such a thing!
I will talk to her, Mrs. Sadewo!
That's enough!
I will give you a week.
If Yura doesn't come,
and you haven't paid your debt,
you must all leave this house!
Mrs. Sadewo.
Let's go!
Everything is ruined!
This never would've happened
if your daughter wasn't such a fool!
Watch your mouth!
It's you who owes her five billion!
If I don't borrow,
how can we pay the bills?
How can we pay for Yura's
and Nisa's education?
Gerry!
Just so you know, your songs
aren't worth anything anymore!
And now, your daughter
has ruined everything!
Including your own dream!
- Nisa, where do you think you're going?
- I'm going with Dad!
Nisa!
Where are you going to look for Yura, Dad?
As far as I know,
Yura only has two friends.
Yura is going to stay here for now
until she settles her problem.
Are you Oka, Yura's friend?
- Yes. What's the matter, sir?
- Where is she?
I'll tell you where she is.
Yura is my daughter!
- What right do you have on my daughter?
- You want me to strangle your child too?
- What is this?
- What's going on here?
- Who are you?
- I'm the owner of this boarding house.
- Who is she?
- She's my wife!
Why are you hitting my son?
I'm looking for my daughter, Yura.
Calm down, Dad.
Where is Yura?
- Where's Yura?
- Listen. Come here, Dad.
- Mr. Gerry is my friend's father.
- All right, go on.
- Okay.
- Her name is Yura.
- She left her house last night.
- You took a girl out of her house?
- You took her out of her house?
- Who is that?
- What's the matter?
- You raped her?
- No!
- What's going on?
- Then what?
- Just wait a second, Dad!
Hey, Oka! Where's Yura?
- You have to promise first...
- Promise what?
- Where is she?
- Hey, hold on a second.
You have to promise me
not to take her back to your house.
Yes, my dad agrees.
Please tell us where she is right now.
Sir.
There she is.
It's been a while
since you visited her, right?
What happened to you?
Talk to me.
What have you heard about me?
I don't want to hear it from other people.
I want to hear it from you.
Bob?
Hey. No.
What's wrong?
You don't trust me?
What difference does it make?
In the end,
we are still going to get married.
I think I should go home now.
I need to go home now.
Bob!
Your family owes my family a lot of money!
You are just collateral!
- Let me go!
- Shut up!
A week before we went
to Mrs. Sadewo's house,
I had told Tian and Oka about it.
I told them that I was
being arranged for marriage.
They insisted on looking out for me.
But I told them not to do that.
I'm sorry, Dad.
But I will never go back to your house.
All of this shouldn't have happened
if I wasn't like this.
I feel so helpless!
I already hit rock bottom.
All of this is just the beginning.
The start of my journey
that begins with the wound.
SPECIAL CUISINE TUMPANG KOYOR
DELICIOUSLY SPICY!
It's just that I didn't think
I would lose everything.
I've lost my mom before,
now I've lost my father.
All of my family.
- Oka!
- Yes, Dad?
Take the koyor out of the fridge.
Hold on, Dad.
I'm trying a new recipe.
Recipe?
You're just making instant noodles.
What?
Why are you making instant noodles?
You little monkey!
Now, just take out the koyor
from the fridge, okay?
I'll teach you how to cook.
- Hey, hold on a second!
- What?
Let me tell you something.
Your mother is a foreigner.
She can't cook tumpang koyor.
I will teach you how to cook it.
How to cook tumpang koyor!
Cook! Do you understand?
I'm not your only son.
Go and ask the others to do it.
Why do I have to do everything?
I want you to do it!
What's the matter with you?
That's not fair, Dad!
Why do I always have to do it?
Who's asking you to go to a fair,
like Jakarta Fair?
Mom, Dad called me a monkey!
Well, that's true, honey.
I told you so.
Here you go! Fried bananas, your favorite.
Come on, have some.
Yura, this is your favorite.
Why aren't you eating it?
Later, Ian. I'm making my life's
short and long-term goals.
Really?
I don't want to keep
on being a burden to Oka.
I need to finish my college degree.
I'm going to take a lot of classes
so I can graduate and work.
Oka and his family are happy
that you're here.
- I don't feel good about that.
- Why don't you feel good about it?
- I've stayed here too long...
- Tian! Yura!
Here it is, my new recipe!
What are you guys doing there?
Come here and try this.
- What is that?
- Just try it.
This is for Yura,
and this one is for Tian.
- Okay.
- What is it? Instant noodles?
Just try it.
Looks good.
- What do you think?
- I haven't tasted it yet!
Is it good?
- It's good, right?
- Yes, the sauce is very spicy.
So do you think I'm worthy
of being called a chef? Chef Oka Saputra.
Lunch is ready!
Please bring those plates over there.
And also the rice.
Come on, everybody! Eat!
- Oka, Cristian, Yura! Hurry!
- Tumpang koyor.
- Let's go.
So am I worthy or not?
- Hurry up!
- Gather up!
Where is it, Mrs. Somad?
Come here.
- I want some too.
- This is for you.
- Yura! Ian!
- I want some koyor.
What do you think?
You haven't answered my question.
Yes, you are worthy to be called a chef.
Only if you can make instant noodles
with a tumpang koyor flavor like this.
That's right!
How can I make instant noodles
with a tumpang koyor flavor?
Here you go.
I want some more.
- Have some more, okay?
- Okay, Mrs. Somad.
Mr. Burhan, my scholarship
is still in effect, right?
As long as your GPA is 3.5 or above,
it will be in effect until you graduate.
If you can graduate quickly,
that would benefit the university.
How about it?
Are you going to add extra classes
for this semester?
- Is there anything else?
- That would be all, Mr. Burhan.
- Thank you.
- Okay. You're welcome.
My fellow comrades who are well known
and who are unnoticed by the public,
who are courageous
and without ulterior motives,
who are selfless and who's given
all they have for others.
My fellow comrades, let us overthrow
this depravity of a regime!
The apprehension of activists,
the imprisonment and abductions...
NEPOTISM, POWER, AND CRONYISM
IN THE NEW ORDER GOVERNMENT
What is this?
There is no other option,
fight them or die!
Why are you reading this stuff?
Ian, when are you
going to propose to Yura?
What's the matter with you?
Why are you talking nonsense?
How long are you going
to keep it to yourself?
Let me tell you something.
Listen.
If you had proposed to her
in the beginning,
maybe she wouldn't
have ended up like this.
So easy to accept
an arranged marriage by her parents.
What's that got to do with it?
They had to put her in an arranged
marriage because of their debt.
It wouldn't matter
if I proposed to her or not.
You're ridiculous.
Ian, of course it would matter.
If you were already together,
things wouldn't be like this.
- Ian, listen to me.
- What is it?
Yura needs someone who will support her
in making her own choices.
- So?
- If you're with her,
she'll follow you wherever you go.
It's obvious!
That incident wouldn't have happened.
She almost got raped, you know?
Come on, Ian. Before anything else
happens to her, just propose to her.
Who's proposing? Who's the lucky girl?
Are you guys talking about me?
Ian wants to propose to you.
You want to propose to me?
That's right, Yura.
I've always wanted to propose to you.
Because you are the right person...
You are the right person
to become the Finance Manager
for our business.
What business, Oka?
That's right, Oka.
Please explain it to Yura.
This is all his idea.
I need to go to the bathroom.
- What are you doing?
- I need to go to the bathroom!
Yura, please come here. Just sit down.
Have a seat.
- Where were we? Right, business!
- What kind of business?
We are going to make
a profitable business that has a future.
What kind of business?
What are you guys going to make?
You know, a business of...
What is it called, Ian?
- That hurts!
- Business...
It's a business about...
- Instant noodles.
- That's right.
- Instant noodles?
- What? Yes, that's right.
You want to supply instant noodles?
- No, not a supplier.
- Not that.
We are planning to put up a store
that sells instant noodles.
- Like those kiosks near the sidewalks?
- No, it's different.
- It's different.
- Explain it.
We're going to make it a cool place
where young people can hang out.
- Excuse me, I want to ask something.
- Yes?
- Do you know Yura Diandra?
- Yura?
- She majors in Economics.
- Yura usually hangs out there.
- Really? Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Hold on a minute.
Why are you guys starting
a business like this all of a sudden?
What's going on?
And why are you asking me to join?
Here's the thing, Yura.
Actually, this is all Ian's idea.
Isn't that right, Ian?
Ian is planning all of this to help you.
Hopefully, this can help pay off
your parents' debt.
- Yura!
- Is it true, Ian?
Nisa?
Why aren't you at school?
What is it?
Didn't you see how panicked I looked?
But she looks more cheerful.
That's a good thing, right?
Oka, Ian.
- I'll be right back, okay?
- Sure.
Hey, why didn't you propose to her?
Are you crazy?
Next time you want to pull something
like that, you better tell me first!
But it turned out fine, right?
Didn't you see her face?
I also looked terrified! You imbecile!
The house, the car,
and our furniture have all been sold.
Well, they were only worth
two and a half billion rupiah.
Why was their worth so low?
What else can we do, Yura?
Mrs. Sadewo's goons
kept on terrorizing us.
And then?
How are we going to pay off
the rest of the debt?
Last night,
after Dad came back
from Mrs. Sadewo's house,
he suddenly collapsed.
The doctor said he had a stroke.
That's Dad's room.
What are you doing here?
Haven't you had enough?
Mom.
Calm down, Mom.
That's enough.
Do we have money to pay the hospital?
We can't even pay half of our rent.
But I will find a job, Yura.
What about your studies?
No.
You don't need to find a job.
- You must go to school.
- How do we pay for it?
That's none of your concern, Nisa.
You just need to go to school
until you graduate, okay?
And if you need anything,
you can find me at Oka's house.
I need to go now.
Yura.
This situation isn't fair to you.
Nisa.
I'm not looking for fairness.
I only seek acceptance.
You stay here and accompany Dad, okay?
Here it is.
Hey, go ahead. Try this.
Because of that act you did yesterday,
I couldn't sleep last night.
- Try it.
- Which one is spicy?
The one on the left.
I know what's good for a woman like you!
I don't have anybody else, Auntie!
Are you talking back to me? What is this?
Stop watching soap operas.
You need to eat first.
Hey, if you want to get married,
Hendra is waiting for you!
- You need to eat first!
- I can eat and watch at the same time.
This is good.
What did you use for seasoning?
That's a secret.
Here she comes.
- Yura, come here.
- Yura!
Come on. Here, try this out.
You need to try this.
This one is not spicy.
Instant noodles made by Oka.
- Try it, Yura.
- This time it's delicious.
Oka, it's so delicious! For someone
who doesn't like spicy food, this is good.
- It's good, right?
- We can start our business now.
Hey, hold on a second.
We're starting an instant noodle business,
but that doesn't mean
we'll put it up instantly.
Everything needs to be calculated.
We need to relax and slow down
so everything will go smoothly.
Right, Oka?
We need to check the materials
and a lot of other things.
- We need to plan everything.
- Let's do it now.
- Wait a minute.
- What do we need?
Stop it. Put this down for now.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Just relax, okay?
If we don't hurry,
others will beat us to it.
- Just relax.
- We need to be first.
You need to relax. Just trust me on this.
For the next five, ten years, Indonesians
will still love instant noodles.
- Especially with my recipe.
- Oka's recipe is delicious!
- Just relax for now.
- It's good, right?
Well, you guys are lucky.
You still have parents
who give you a monthly allowance.
What about me?
It's not like that, Yura. What I mean is...
If we do this slowly,
everything will be much better.
All right, you guys go ahead
and count slowly.
I'm going to look for a job.
Yura!
Aren't you going to give this
another thought?
WITHDRAWAL LETTER
This is very unfortunate.
Your GPA is above average.
I can't be selfish, Mr. Burhan.
I need to find a job.
Thank you.
What is going on anyway?
I've never used a dollar before.
I've been using rupiah
ever since I was a child.
People from Jakarta are very finicky.
I don't care about that kind of stuff.
I just want to sell newspapers
so my family can eat.
Everything's okay. That's it.
JOB VACANCIES
Honey!
It's lunchtime!
I made some very special tumpang koyor
that isn't spicy at all just for you.
- Thank you, Mrs. Somad.
- You have to eat it all.
- I made a lot, you know?
- Okay.
THE SADEWO FAMILY
SUSPECTED OF PLATINUM SCAM
- Just tell me what the issue is.
- It's okay.
Yura Diandra, please come in.
This way, miss.
This way, please.
Here's the thing.
We need to cancel the interview, okay?
Why is that?
Well, the situation in this office
is a little chaotic right now.
However, I will contact you again, okay?
You can go now.
The fall of the rupiah exchange rate
against the US dollar
will cause thousands of people
to become unemployed.
The number of unemployed will increase
by more than five million.
Several countries have also experienced
monetary crises. Countries like...
You have to eat, Dad.
Open your mouth.
Nisa, please help me.
When are your exams?
In three months.
- Which high school do you want to go to?
- How are we going to pay for it?
We can't even pay the hospital bills.
And we still need to pay off
our debt to the Sadewos.
You guys are dreaming.
Mom.
THE SADEWO FAMILY
SUSPECTED OF PLATINUM SCAM
Excuse me, Nurse.
Where is the patient in this room?
He was sent home this afternoon.
- Are you Yura?
- Yes.
Your sister, Nisa, left you a message.
Here you go.
Dad was allowed to go home, Yura.
I called Oka's house,
but they told me you weren't home yet.
If you can, please come by
our house, okay?
- Excuse me, ma'am.
- Yes?
Does Mr. Gerry live here?
- Yes, he does.
- Yes.
Here?
- Right.
Yura!
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
Come, Daddy's inside.
Hi, Yura.
You guys?
Why are you here?
Dad was able to go home because of Tian.
The menu for our business is all set.
Everything is ready.
The menu, the employees.
We just need to start.
Yura?
- Yura!
- Make way.
Yura?
Yura!
Yura, listen to me.
What's the matter with you?
What's the matter?
Did I do something wrong to you?
Didn't you tell us
not to take things slow?
Why are you acting like this?
I'm the selfish person here.
I am selfish, finicky,
disrespectful, and very arrogant...
I am...
Listen to me.
Everything has been taken care of.
What do you mean?
The hospital bills...
and your father's house rent
has all been taken care of.
My father's house rent?
I've paid in advance for two years.
How do you know
all of my family's problems?
I know it from Nisa.
She told me everything.
Don't blame Nisa. Do you hear me?
Don't blame her.
This has nothing to do with her.
She didn't do anything wrong.
In fact, because of her,
Oka and I became motivated
to start our business immediately.
Isn't that what you wanted?
That's what we all want, right?
So we can start our business
and develop it.
How did you get that much money, Ian?
- Where did you get it?
- That's not important.
It's not important where I got it from.
It's important to me.
Where did you get it?
You don't trust me?
Believe me,
I will never do something foolish.
I will never steal other people's money.
Okay.
Why are you doing all this?
What is your intention?
Oka is right.
He always told me...
"Tell her the truth, Ian.
Talk to her face to face."
But I always avoided it.
I never listened to him.
Because I wasn't ready, Yura.
I wasn't ready to be honest with you.
I...
I am doing this...
because...
Because I love you.
I love you, Yura.
I want to...
help you realize your dreams.
You're kidding, right?
You think I'm joking?
Why do you think I'm doing all this?
That it's all a lie? I'm lying to you?
You know that I'm not ready
to have a new relationship.
You know what happened
that night, don't you?
- I'm still not ready to trust...
- Yura.
I promise you...
I will never hurt your feelings.
I will try, Ian.
And I will wait for you.
But remember
all the money that you gave my family,
I consider it as debt.
Whatever.
It's up to you.
I only ask one thing from you.
I want you to trust me.
To be honest,
I'm already fed up with love.
Especially if it begins with pity.
Thank you.
Maybe I'm naive.
But I'm not selfish.
I'm grateful when people are good to me.
Especially to that person
who saved my life.
The sweet story
Just woke up from a dream...
- Instant noodles special with satay.
- Okay.
How can I help you? What's your order?
Yoi Mie? Come with me.
I want toppings...
One more with chicken satay.
In mother's embrace
Like a rose
So pretty and beautiful
How does it taste? Is it good?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
What do you guys think?
Did you like the noodles?
It's very delicious.
My friends really like it.
This is an ordinary instant noodle, right?
How can it taste this good?
That's what makes it special.
This is all in the secret recipe of...
Chef Oka!
Oka Saputra!
The beautiful story
It will be the reason
For this face to keep smiling...
- Two million, four hundred and...
- In just one day?
- Sixty-seven thousand?
- Sixty-seven?
Oka! Hey!
- Hey, stop playing!
- What is it?
- This is how much we got.
- How much?
Two million, four hundred and...
Sixty-seven thousand rupiah!
- Are you serious?
- Yes!
This is from Yura to pay for your school.
Please give my gratitude to my sister.
Sorry that we have to meet here.
I don't want Mom to know about it.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
- You're welcome.
One or two?
- We'll order two, please.
- All right.
Here you go!
This one is with a satay topping
and this is the chicken special.
Like a rose
So pretty and beautiful...
- Excuse me, sir.
- Yes?
- Can I talk to the owner of Yoi Mie?
- That's us.
I am from Kawula Muda.
Kawula Muda Magazine?
- The magazine?
- That's right.
- Really?
- How can we help you?
Dad, take a look at this.
My business with Oka and Cristian
was featured in a magazine.
Look, isn't this cool? That's me!
- My grades are good.
- Do you see it, Dad?
REPORT CARD
- Go and tell your father.
- Sure.
Dad.
- Hi!
- Yura?
Yura, take a look at this.
My grades are good.
Dad, look at this!
- You're such a smart kid!
- Thank you!
You should've cut your hair.
This ruined the picture.
Look, this is your right side
and this is your left.
- What is this?
- Hey, I haven't finished reading it!
- There's something more important.
- What is it?
Happy wedding anniversary, Mom and Dad!
Congratulations, Mr. and Mrs. Somad!
- Dad, open it.
- All right.
I'm opening it.
What is this, son?
- Is it a walkie-talkie?
- It's a cell phone, Dad.
- Cell phone? Where's the cable?
- Like this, Dad...
Modern telephones are like this.
Can I call the house with this?
You can call Mom too.
- Really?
- Because Mom also has one.
You both can call each other
with this cell phone.
Thank you, Ian.
For what?
For everything.
At first, I was hesitant
to go through all this.
You really are a nice guy, aren't you?
Yura.
What is it?
May I ask you something?
How do I say this? I've always wanted
to tell you this.
Ian, you've already told me
that you couldn't tell me
anything at all before, right?
That's right.
But this time is different.
Yura Diandra Hartono.
Will you marry me?
Ian.
I am not saying no.
But I'm not saying yes either.
Don't misunderstand.
It's not that I don't love you.
But I still don't know who you are, Ian.
And your family...
I haven't even met them.
You know that
I've always wanted
to have a normal family,
not just a relationship with you,
but also a relationship
between my family and yours.
Who are you looking for?
Young master!
Come.
Is this your house?
Are you like Batman?
I'll never forget your name,
Master Cristian.
You don't need to call me "Master."
Please come in.
Your mother is waiting. Come.
Come on, honey.
I'll just wait here.
You said you wanted to meet my parents.
This way.
Why didn't you tell me
you were coming home?
We could've picked you up.
Come on. I'm not like Robert, Mom.
- I don't like being treated like...
- Yes, I know that.
You don't want to be compared to him.
I know that.
Are you good and healthy?
- Who did you come here with?
- I came here with Yura.
Yura Diandra Hartono.
Yura Diandra Hartono?
Aren't you the daughter of...
What's his name?
That famous singer, right?
- Grace.
- Yes, ma'am?
Please take Cristian's friend here
to her room. Okay?
- All right, ma'am.
- Good.
Come, Ms. Yura.
We will have dinner together tonight.
I'm going to cook your favorite dish.
It's been a while, Mom.
Yura?
Honey, you're so beautiful.
Let's eat.
Grace.
Come and join us.
You have to try that fried rice.
It's very delicious.
You need to try it.
Is Robert going to join us as well?
According to our customs here,
you are not allowed to speak
before being given permission.
Sorry.
Not everyone is accustomed to our customs.
That's why it's important to choose
a partner with the same background as you.
Yura is not so different from me, Mom.
And I'm very certain
that she is willing to learn
our family customs.
Isn't that right, honey?
Here's the thing, honey.
Currently, Robert lives in America,
taking up his master's degree,
but he also has a business there.
His little brother should've gone
with him to America.
But you always wanted to do
something different.
Good evening, everyone!
Forgive me if I'm late.
Please have a seat.
Tian.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
It turns out that this rascal
is good at finding a girlfriend.
Come, let's eat.
Please serve your girlfriend first
before you serve yourself, okay?
Do you both attend the same university?
That's right, sir.
I mean, Mr. Salim.
Come on, please don't be shy.
Just like Tian, you can call me "Dad."
Well, Rachel has told me a lot
about your relationship.
And basically, I have no objection.
Tian is old enough.
He has been taking care of himself
since high school.
So whatever he decides,
I will support him.
No problem at all.
Isn't that right, honey?
There's absolutely no problem here.
Everything is settled.
But there's one thing
that I want you to do
before I can give you my blessings.
What is that, Dad?
It's your brother, Robert.
He was careless in managing
his business in Los Angeles.
So now his company
is experiencing bad credit.
I've sent my auditors from England,
but they also couldn't handle it.
I don't trust them.
And I will not give that to them.
So I want you to go there
and handle this problem.
But I don't know anything
about Robert's business.
Did you know anything about noodles
when you first started that business?
You didn't know, right?
That noodle thing
is just a small business.
It's as simple as that.
And I'm pretty sure you can handle it.
How long should I be there, Dad?
How long did it take for you to develop
your noodle business?
A week.
Right. That means
it's more or less the same thing.
But of course if you need more time,
and you need to stay longer,
then you could always ask your girlfriend
to catch up with you,
and you can get married there.
Why not?
Everything can be arranged.
Don't worry about your mother.
I'll talk to her later.
Son...
It's nothing.
Just finish your meal. Go on.
It seems that love
isn't just about being together
or merely just an expression,
but it's also a blessing in disguise
when we throw away all our desires.
I didn't expect your father
to be that kind.
Same here.
If you ask me
if this is the path for me,
maybe this will be my next choice.
For how long?
I don't know.
Please allow me to enjoy it first.
No, you can't. Close your eyes.
- All right.
- Don't peek. Close your eyes.
Now you can open your eyes.
I, Cristian Subagyo,
and the woman beside me...
Yura Diandra,
will be getting married in two months.
And one more thing.
Because tonight is a very special night,
I will be treating all of you here
to Yoi Mie. Free of charge!
So order anything you like.
Go ahead, but please
don't bring it home, okay?
Yura.
Why did you come here?
You're still not well, right?
He insisted on coming, Yura.
It was I who insisted.
Nisa didn't have the heart to say it.
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome...
Gerry Hartono!
Gerry!
Oh, where
Should I look for you
I am crying
All by myself
My heart
Is always longing to see you
Just for you
I will sing this song
To my dearest father
I want to sing this song
Even though
Tears stream down on my face
Father, please listen to me
I want to see you
Even though
It's only in my dreams
Just look...
All set.
Don't forget to come back.
- Okay?
- Sure.
Take care of Yura for me, okay?
I'd better go now, honey.
This is your mother's bracelet.
That's why I'm giving it to you.
Thank you.
Don't be sad. I won't be away for long.
Mr. and Mrs. Somad!
Have a safe flight!
Come back, okay?
Come on.
DEAR YURA, HOW ARE YOU?
LA FEELS A LOT COLDER WITHOUT YOU HERE.
MISSING YOU AND NOT SEEING YOU
IS LIKE COMPOSING A SONG
WHICH HAS NEVER BEEN SUNG.
Yura?
What's the matter?
I think I'm catching a cold.
I need to sleep.
Yura.
Mr. Burhan is missing.
What do you mean by missing?
He's missing. He never got home.
What do you mean?
They say there are a lot of activists
being abducted.
Abducted?
That's right. By the police.
The situation out there
is very terrifying.
Even college students have mobilized.
It's really scary out there...
- Oka!
- Yura?
- This is bad, right? Come here!
- What is it, Mom?
- This is bad, right?
- What are you talking about?
There are a lot of confusing words.
I don't understand this.
"Put forward..."
"Position..."
- What does that mean?
- I don't know. It's chaos out there.
I'll read it later.
PHARMACY
Reformation!
REFORMATION
BRING DOWN SOEHARTO'S REGIME!
CALL SHOP
The total is 1,000 rupiah.
Thank you very much.
Ian?
Where are you?
Are you okay?
Please call me back.
I want to tell you something important.
You're already here?
- Yes.
- Put it in the back.
Sure.
Yura?
Give me his phone number.
Let me try to call him.
Give it to me.
It's really bad.
Oh, my god!
What's that?
Oka!
Oka?
- Oka?
- Yes, Dad.
- Have you seen the news?
- No, I haven't. What's wrong?
Come here.
That's the situation in Jakarta
about an hour ago.
Allegedly, the riot was caused
by angry passengers
who didn't receive any explanation
from the airlines regarding their flights.
Several properties like computers,
telephones, tables, chairs, walls,
and even windows were smashed
all around the counters.
They burned it.
Where are you going, Yura?
To Jakarta.
Are you crazy?
Oka!
I want to know where Tian is right now!
I want to know what his parents will say!
But not like this, Yura!
Didn't you see the situation in Jakarta?
What am I supposed to do?
Sit here and do nothing?
Like a fool?
All right, let me take you there.
I'm going alone.
How do you plan to do that?
By plane or by train?
Didn't you see what was going on?
Let's go.
REFORMATION IS A MUST
THIS BELONGS TO THE NATIVES
- Turn left up here, Oka.
- Here?
There it is. That's the front gate.
Are you serious?
Is this really his house?
- Who is that?
- I don't know.
- Is this the house, Yura?
- Yes.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Yes?
- Can I help you?
- I'm Yura.
I'm Cristian's friend who came here
last time. Do you remember?
The young master has many friends,
especially girls.
- I agree.
- That's right!
- What's going on here?
- Grace!
What a coincidence.
I want to ask how Cristian is doing.
Who are you?
What?
I'm Yura, Cristian's would-be wife!
A week ago, a woman also came here
and claimed to be Cristian's wife.
What is this?
I've gotten used to handling
these kinds of dramas.
The family here moved to America
before the riots began.
So there's no one here.
If you really are Master Cristian's
would-be wife,
I'm sure you'll be in America by now,
because his wedding
will be held next week.
- Take care of this.
- Cristian...
What wedding, ma'am?
- She's his fiance.
- He already proposed!
- Ma'am!
- Go on now.
- Hey, you are trespassing!
- Out of my way!
- Mister!
- Just get out of here!
- Grace!
- Just leave at once!
Don't force your way in! Hey!
Listen to me!
If you want to be a con artist,
do it at home. Don't do it here!
Get out!
Let's go, Yura.
They're crazy.
NATIVE INDONESIANS
THIS BELONGS TO THE NATIVES
The most useless thing in life
is regretting a decision
and then seeing yourself
begging for hope.
THIS BELONGS TO THE NATIVES
Yura!
Yura, you haven't eaten yet, right?
Come on, let's eat.
Look, I made you some noodles.
Look, Yura. The egg is cooked over medium.
Look.
Can you tell Yura to come
and eat dinner, honey?
Sure, I'll do that.
Yura!
Let's eat.
Yura?
Let's have dinner.
Maybe she's sleeping.
Yura!
Yura?
Wake up, Yura!
Come and eat your breakfast.
We're going to have a guest from Jogja.
Yura?
Yura!
Mom! Dad!
Tian.
Please pick up.
- How is she, Doc?
- She's recovering, ma'am.
She lost a lot of blood,
but good thing she was brought here
just in time, so she will survive.
And thank God her baby is okay.
Baby?
Yes. Your daughter is two months pregnant.
Can I speak to her husband?
I'm her husband, Doc.
Come with me.
Is that true?
This is not like Ian.
I know him pretty well.
I don't believe
he has the heart to do this.
I'm sure this is all his parents' doing.
I'm sure of it.
Okay, that's enough.
What did the doctor say about Yura?
I don't believe that he's wicked.
What?
What did the doctor say?
He told me
Yura is having severe depression.
So I need to take care of her
and keep her emotions stable.
Come on. Wake up, Yura.
We are all here for you.
We all love you, Yura.
We are here for you.
Yura?
- Got you!
- Yura!
You better watch out!
I'm going to catch you!
I'm going to tickle you!
You are precious to me!
Mom.
Are you afraid of losing me?
I am so afraid of losing you.
Your mother Diandra and our father Gerry
both have this bracelet.
When you were born,
her bracelet was given to you.
Now, you can also have Dad's bracelet.
Please don't be sad anymore, Yura.
You're not alone, you know?
We're all here for you.
Sometimes...
when we really feel
we have lost everything,
the people we used to hate
and stay away from,
are the ones who will be there for us.
Yura.
May I speak to you for a minute?
When your father and I got married,
honestly,
I didn't know how to be a mother to you.
Maybe it's because
I've never had a child before.
That's why I didn't know what to do.
When Nisa was born,
I thought...
I could have a little experience
on how to deal with children.
But...
But it made me drift
even farther away from you.
I don't know why,
but you were like a nuisance to me...
especially when your father
wasn't successful anymore.
His album sold poorly on the market.
They didn't offer him opportunities
to perform anymore.
Meanwhile, our needs have increased.
And then I tried something else
to help our family.
I tried starting a business,
selling jewelry to wealthy people.
That's when I met Mrs. Sadewo, until...
That's why I...
Your fate should've been
much better than this, Yura.
This is all my fault.
I am the one who caused all of this.
I have accepted this fate.
You have to be happy, okay?
Whatever it takes,
I will atone for my sins.
Please forgive me.
Hi. It hasn't started yet?
It's going to start soon.
Mrs. Indah, my grandma wants me
to give this to Yura.
Akar fatimah.
What's that for?
Akar fatimah is very good
at inducing labor, Yura.
I'll boil it for her at home later.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
please sit on the available mat
in the middle.
- Wait here, okay?
- Okay.
Just walk slowly.
Yura, where is your husband?
- This is her husband, ma'am.
- Right.
Come on. It's all right.
- Please sit down, sir.
- Come on.
Just sit there.
So what are your plans
for the future, Yura?
Giving birth and raising this child.
Maybe I'll go to college again.
Isn't it cute
bringing my baby to class?
It's getting late. I need to go home now.
Give my regards to the little one.
Hey, handsome.
How much? One portion?
I think Oka is the perfect guy
to be your husband.
That's nonsense.
What's wrong with that?
You and Cristian
aren't officially married, right?
Yes, but that's just ridiculous.
Oka has been my friend
since the beginning.
Well, I don't want to burden him
with my problems.
Have you asked him about that?
I don't have to ask him.
I'm sure everyone understands that.
Yura, when a man has fallen in love,
I'm sure he'll sacrifice
just about anything.
She doesn't believe that?
Do you need proof?
No, I don't.
All right then, at least ask him, okay?
- Just ask him, okay?
- I don't want to.
Just ask him. It will be fine, okay?
I won't be asking him.
Mom!
- What's wrong, Yura?
- Her water broke.
Nisa, call a cab, okay?
Oka!
Yura, are you okay?
- Oka, her water just broke!
- What?
Come here! Quick!
Honey, please stay calm. Oka!
- Quickly, call a cab.
- What's wrong, Yura?
Come on.
Hello, Mom? Yes, she just went
into the operating room.
It might take two hours.
Mom, please bring Yura's clothes, okay?
Yes, and also her towel.
Bring a clean one, okay?
You can also bring a perfume.
Thank you.
Come on, just relax.
Yura is strong, you know?
The important thing
is she doesn't feel alone.
Yura's mother, please accompany
your daughter inside.
Can her husband come too?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
Only one person is allowed inside.
- Then her husband should go in.
- Why me?
- It has to be you.
- Why doesn't he want to go?
He wants to accompany her!
- Go! He's coming, Nurse.
- Okay, this way.
He really wants to go.
- Now.
- Why don't you?
Go on, it's okay.
He wants to accompany her, Nurse.
- Come on, just get inside!
- Let's go, sir. They're waiting for us.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Just relax, ma'am.
- First, I need to check it.
- Come on, sir.
The dilation is now nine centimeters.
Just relax.
Just relax, ma'am.
It's your first time, right?
Please come in, sir. Go ahead.
Take a deep breath.
Now, push.
- You can get close to her.
- Please help her out, okay?
Just a moment, sir.
You're almost there, ma'am.
Just a bit more.
Take another deep breath.
The baby's born, ma'am! It's a girl!
Is the baby born, Mom?
- Here you go!
- Thank you, Nisa.
- Here you go, Mr. Somad.
- Thank you.
And this is for you.
- Mom, can you help with this?
- Sure.
- I need to help Yura.
- All right, honey.
Please drink it.
Hello.
What are you going to call her?
You haven't given her a name
since we left the hospital.
That's right.
What are you going to call her?
A name is a parent's wish, Yura.
Isn't that right, Gerry?
Your cheeks are so chubby.
Hi. What is your name?
What do you think, Oka?
Why are you asking me?
You're her mother.
I can't give her a name.
You're good at choosing a name.
You're the one who named our stall.
- And it's very profitable.
- Hey.
Hold on a second.
How can you name this beautiful baby
like some stall?
- That's right! Don't do that.
- What do you mean by that?
All right then.
What's her name then?
Diandra...
Puspita.
Look, she smiled. Diandra Puspita.
What does it mean?
Diandra is the name of Yura's late mother.
It means elegant and strong.
This child will grow
to become a very beautiful girl,
and strong like her mother
and grandmother.
Diandra Puspita Hartono.
- It's a good name, right?
- Yes, it's good.
Diandra Puspita...
Saputra?
I know this will sound ridiculous.
But...
I can't deny my feelings anymore.
I want to have a happy family
like Mr. and Mrs. Somad...
who can give birth
to an amazing child like Oka.
I know this will sound very weird...
A woman...
A woman proposing to a man first.
But one thing's for sure...
I'm very happy to have a friend like you.
The person who I have chosen
to give my future to.
But if you refuse, I don't mind either.
I don't want you to think
that I'm giving my burden to you.
I don't know what to say, Yura.
You don't need to answer now, Oka.
I sincerely accept it.
I still consider you my best friend.
Hey, let's get out of here.
Why are we still here anyway?
We need to wait for Yura.
It's all done, right?
Yura's marriage has been set.
Whatever happens, she's still our friend.
We need to protect her.
- What if something happens to her?
- What will happen to her?
Well, anything can happen to her.
Why aren't you concerned at all?
All right, whatever.
Quickly, start the car!
- What happened?
- Just go now, Oka!
I promise you...
I will never hurt your feelings.
Yura! Mom!
I love you, Yura.
I accept it, Yura.
I accept that this child will be named
Diandra Puspita Saputra.
Come and give me a hug!
Finally, I have a granddaughter
from the Hartono family!
- Why are you crying, Dad?
- You made me cry!
Once again,
love isn't just about being together
or just an expression,
nor is it just a wish
for a blessing to come.
Love is all things.
There's also sacrifice in love.
There's always something to fight for.
Not just our desires alone,
but all the people
who sincerely helped us.
Will this be the ending of my love story?
I don't know yet.
Once again, please allow me
to enjoy it first.
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
I can take it from here.
Ian, what happened to your face?
Ian?