Records of the Iron Giant Project
Original Story by
Mitsuteru YOKO YAMA
Screenplay by Hiroshi SAITO
and Kota YAMADA
Screenplay by
Hiroshi SAITO and Kota YAMADA
In 1945...
Music by
Akira SENJU
the World War II was at the last stage.
Music by
Akira SENJU
With the sign of defeat looming large...
Visual Effects by
Hajime MATSUMOTO
Japan was secretly developing
the greatest revolutionary weapon...
Cast
as its savior.
Sousuke IKEMATSU
Yuu AOI
Hiroko YAKUSHIMARU
Teruyuki KAGAWA
However, as Japan lost the war...
Katsuo NAKAMURA
the plan vanished without a trace.
It was buried along with
the dark memories of the war.
Directed by
Shin TOGASHI
Dad...
Pay attention and draw.
No doodling.
Mr. Matsukawa!
Go to your seat!
Yes, ma'am.
Sorry, ma'am.
Mr. Kaneda, what are you drawing?
Didn't I tell you not to copy
pictures or illustrations?
I'm drawing what I see.
Wow! What's that?
That's cool.
Is this what you see?
It's just eating birdseed.
Don't lie, newcomer!
Hey!
I saw it flap its wings.
Yeah, for a split second!
He couldn't have seen the details.
Say, everyone, do you think
he can look this clear?
Class!
Come on! Stop that!
Quiet now!
Quiet!
The teacher said to be quiet!
Go back to your task!
If you can't decide,
go ahead and buy one.
It's the pleasures
of Japanese summer.
This one matches you.
Well... I'll take this!
Ah! You scared me!
- I'm home.
- Don't scare me like that!
I'm not a kid anymore.
Phew. I'm home.
- You're late.
- I'm sorry.
Hey, good job!
I'm certainly impressed.
Maybe I'll ask you
to do it every day.
Stop joking and get dinner ready.
I'm starving!
The fact you're starving
means you're in good health!
You silly boy,
wearing it inside out.
Shotaro drew a masterpiece again.
Everyone was saying
that drawing stinks.
Let them say what they want. Right?
Thank you for the food!
Teriyaki, again?
So? As long as it's tasty,
it should be fine.
Thank you for the food.
So, have you made new friends?
Not really.
I do feel bad.
I didn't think there'd be transfers
for jobs in cooking schools.
Don't make an ugly face.
That's why you can't make new friends.
Do you think you'll make it
in the new school?
I guess I'll just have to. Right?
I am standing in front of...
You sound just like your father.
Reiji Takumi's house...
the former president of
the computer company KOK.
Pass me the teriyaki.
The cause of this damage
is not clear...
but there are
several witnesses saying...
that they saw a giant arm-shaped
metallic object fly into the sky.
Reporting Live from the site
There is a big hole about
5 meters diameter in the roof...
and it appears that the words of
the witnesses do make sense.
Reporting live from the house of
Reiji Takumi, former KOK President
The police are investigating the case.
The police believe that Mr. Takumi,
who is currently missing...
might have something to do with it.
- We'll be on air soon with updates.
- Is something wrong?
Why did you turn it off?
Well, let's eat.
Hey, sit up straight.
Uh, Kaneda-kun.
Huh?
You like R/C model airplanes too?
Yeah.
You're really good at it.
Not that good.
I've dropped it so many times.
Um, listen...
What?
Not everyone in our school is mean.
Hey, I know a good joke.
Joke?
Do you know a clock that talks?
What's that?
Tick-tack, tick-tack, tic... talk!
That's dull!
Tick-tack, tick-tack...
Talk! Talk! Talk!
There's a wolf in the bathroom.
Tell me what it said.
There can't be a wolf in the bathroom!
"How'll" I do without toilet paper?
There's no way a giant iron arm bigger
than a dump truck can fly through the air!
There's so many people saying
they actually saw it.
Do you think that they'd all lie together?
I don't mean that, but...
Anyway, it's a huge basement.
Maybe they were playing soccer.
Do you wanna go out
for a drink after this?
I know a good place nearby.
- Mr. Murasame.
- Yes, ma'am.
You're fired!
Hey!
Did you find out anything?
There's a gym-size lab
in the basement...
and it seems that
the giant arm flew from there.
- What about Reiji Takumi?
- We haven't found him yet.
A giant arm. "All become Zero."
What's going on here?
Hey!
- "All become zero"?
- Zero?
"All become zero."
What could this mean?
At 3:47 this afternoon
for about 2 minutes...
the land broadcast system was hijacked
by an unidentified source...
and the mysterious message
was on air.
The police,
joined by all the TV stations...
Come here quickly,
we're celebrating.
I baked this at cooking school.
- Can I open it?
- Sure.
Whoa! Looks good!
Get the candles ready.
Where are they?
Oops. I forgot to buy them.
That's my mom.
What should we do?
Ah! I've got an idea.
Will this do?
Yeah, that'll do.
Birthday cakes won't do
without candles.
- Turn off the lights.
- Sure.
- Let's sing "Happy birthday".
- Mom...
There's... something
I want to ask you.
What is it?
I've been having weird dreams lately.
Weird dreams?
There's a small me
in a semi-dark, huge room...
and there's electric sparkles.
And then I see two giant poles
shaped like legs...
and someone is suddenly
staring at me angrily.
That someone is my dad.
He pushes me away and disappears.
Did this dream happen for real?
Why did my dad do that to me?
Did he hate me?
How could that be true?
Reiji Takumi's company, KOK,
was enormously big, wasn't it?
KOK was not just a company.
It was a kingdom. Takumi Kingdom.
Takumi was controlling
his computer business all by himself.
But that Takumi Kingdom was
shattered into pieces.
It was triggered by KOK's new computers
that repeatedly malfunctioned.
The media that praised Takumi had
suddenly turned their hands over him.
The sales of KOK's computer declined
and the value of stocks collapsed.
Takumi suddenly sold
the company three years ago...
and disappeared from the world.
And then, a big arm from his house?
I don't get it.
What are you grinning about?
You're creepy.
Well, I just thought
we're all alone right now.
We can see far away!
Hi, everyone. Here's the mascot
of Tokyo Tower.
Look, it's Noppon. Noppon!
- What's the matter?
- What's that?
Maybe it's some ad.
Takahashi, run. Hurry!
Hurry!
Megumi! Come on!
Bye-bye!
Amazing!
Everyone, please stop
what you're doing.
There was a big accident nearby
and an evacuation order was issued.
It's very dangerous here.
Please go home immediately.
It's a robot!
Run!
Mrs. Kaneda,
what are you doing? Hurry!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Mr. Furuta! Can you hear me?
Mom!
Mom...
You must be Shotaro.
She is just sleeping
from the medicine.
She had me worried there
for a while...
but the doctor said she just fractured
her leg and bruised her back.
Your mother...
She froze where she was
the minute she heard the word "robot."
Why didn't she run away?
Mr. Taura, the Tokyo Metropolitan
Police Commissioner, has arrived.
Is it true that the criminals
made the statement?
Have you identified the robot?
Please give us your comment!
Giant Robot Terrorism Task Force HQs
Later, okay?
Everyone, please be quiet.
Members of the media community!
Please step back.
- Good morning, sirs.
- Good morning!
Please be seated.
"All Become Zero."
"Black Ox will take over Tokyo
two weeks later."
"Good luck."
Someone hacked into the homepage
of the Metropolitan Police...
and a person who calls himself
"Zero" sent us this message.
Black Ox? In two weeks?
As you all may know...
the terrorist, Zero...
has sent a giant robot,
Black Ox already.
And has brought tremendous disaster
to the city of Tokyo.
- To warn of an attack in two weeks...
- Did you hear?
They're inviting a counter-terrorism
specialist to our department.
Really?
Supposed to be top-notch in
computer and robot technology at MIT.
It sucks! Sounds like we underlings
are not needed to solve the case.
Yeah, sort of.
Ah! Looks like he's already here.
I'm out of business cards right now.
Hello.
I'm Ejima of the Investigation Division.
I'm Murasame in the same division.
- I'm...
- Well, he's not the one.
He's Dr. Kawai, the assistant
to the specialist, Mami Tachibana.
I'm Kawai.
There she is.
Over here.
She's come upon our special request.
This is Ms. Mami Tachibana from MIT.
Oh, she is?
I'm Mami. Nice to meet you.
What a beautiful girl!
Let me get straight to the point.
Did you find out anything?
You smell like tobacco.
You'll die young.
What?
I think this is made by Reiji Takumi.
- What?
The very person that made Black Ox
must be Reiji Takumi.
There's no one else that can build
this kind of robot.
Then "Zero" is Reiji Takumi?
Who the heck is Takumi?
He's the world authority in
artificial intelligence research.
He is the genius of all geniuses.
Shoichiro Kaneda
Hello? Kaneda residence.
You must be Shotaro Kaneda.
Yes.
My name is Ayabe.
I want to meet with you to talk about
what he has left for you.
Pardon?
You must be Mr. Shotaro Kaneda.
Yes.
Step into the car, please.
Please.
I brought him, sir.
So you're Shotaro Kaneda.
You've grown.
Pardon?
I am Ayabe.
Please come.
I used to be...
an assistant for your grandfather...
Dr. Shogoro Kaneda...
and a guardian for your father,
Dr. Shoichiro Kaneda.
My life has always been
with the Kaneda family...
but I never thought I'd come
back here while I was alive.
This is your father's laboratory.
What?
Please, go on ahead.
You've been here before.
I have?
You remember now, don't you?
This is Tetsujin No. 28.
The first Tetsujin was made by
your grandfather for military use.
Then your father took over...
and remade it many times, wishing
it be used for peaceful purposes...
and finally completed
this 28th robot.
You must know where the device
to control this robot was put away.
That is the remote-controller
to operate Tetsujin.
You used your power as an eidetic...
and accurately recalled
your memories as a three-year-old.
"E-E-Eidetic"?
It's a person with the skills of inputting
what you see as you see it...
and recalling those memories
accurately anytime you wish.
You are going to use that skill
to operate Tetsujin.
Your father left Tetsujin for you.
What?
I don't believe that.
You'll understand soon enough.
Now, push the buttons.
That can't be.
Why should my father leave it to me?
You're a coward unlike your father!
Coward?
No way!
All units on patrol!
Black Ox has appeared in Kasumigaseki.
All vehicles to respond immediately!
All units on patrol!
There he is!
There he is! Ready?
Black Ox is coming this way!
Terrorist Zero's destroyer is about
to attack the town of Kasumigaseki!
Don't back down! Stay on!
Stay on!
Let's shoot it!
Open fire!
It's not working.
Huh? What is that?
Are you sure I'm the one to do this?
Of course.
Shotaro, what are you doing?
Quick! Make Tetsujin move.
Yes, sir!
That robot is fighting against Black Ox.
I can't do this!
Damn you!
Let's go.
- Hurry!
- Get in position!
Shotaro!
Don't take your hands off
the remote-controller!
What?
It's the only lifeline for Tetsujin.
Yes, sir.
Tetsujin...
Call an ambulance! Hurry!
Damn it!
This is unbelievable!
The Diet Building, the symbol of
the government for 68 years...
is going to be destroyed?!
You might have meant
to fight Black Ox...
but all you did
is cause more damage!
We don't want you bringing out
such a worthless robot without a permit!
Worthless robot?
You watch your mouth!
Call him the great Tetsujin No. 28.
I don't know if it's called Tetsujin
or whatever...
but what were you thinking,
letting that little boy control that thing?
Anyway, you've violated the law.
You'll certainly receive
harsh punishment. So be ready.
I'll be ready.
Hey, you, get off there. Quick!
I also have a lot of things to say to you.
Do you know
what'll happen to Tetsujin?
There's already an order
to destroy it immediately.
Hey, boy, come over here.
Never mind. Come on, old man.
We got to give you a hearing.
All right.
This way.
Come over here.
Are you the one
who was operating Tetsujin?
Yes.
You were terrible.
- Just as I thought.
- Let's destroy it.
No one can build a robot
that can withstand Black Ox.
My ideal world will not come true
unless everything is destroyed.
What's after Tokyo?
My greatest ideal world will be
controlled by my computers.
New York? Or London?
What's your wish?
That's what we call
"addicted to nicotine."
Oh, shut up.
We'll be transporting Tetsujin
to Mr. Ayabe's lab.
So you'll be demolishing it there?
We're not going to demolish him.
We'll rebuild him.
What the heck did you say?
We've obtained permission
from the office.
There's no question of responsibility
to you, Chief Ohtsuka!
What?
I'm going to make Tetsujin
strong enough to defeat Black Ox.
Won't you to help us, Mr. Ayabe?
Rebuild Tetsujin?
Really?
Can you check the knees?
Say, this is EMP, isn't it?
The one that Black Ox
exposed Tetsujin to.
EMP?
That's why Tetsujin's electric circuits
were damaged and couldn't be controlled.
I have to admit, Black Ox is powerful.
Well, but...
Tetsujin's head was not crushed
when Black Ox stepped on him.
These workmen
put their souls into Tetsujin.
I definitely wish...
to rebuild Tetsujin.
Any objection?
I'm looking forward
to working with you!
Tetsujin is awesome!
He's probably much stronger
than we imagine.
He lost the other day...
but if he really shows what he's got,
he'll definitely knock Black Ox down.
Don't you think so?
Tetsujin is the worst.
What?
Do you want to see Tetsujin?