LOVERS ON THE PONT-NEUF
It's Alex again!
Come on back, Alex! Come on!
Don't you talk to me like that!
Don't fuck with me!
Name's not Marie Asshole!
It's Madame JEAN.
Hey, Peanut! Wha' do I do?
How? Don't know.
Please come here, Lieutenant.
How about picking up the
empties...
bottles and bodies!
Yeah... All bashed up...
Come on, smartass...
Make an effort.
Shit!... Fed up doin' for you...
Third time you hit me!
Good Lord's gonna kill you.
That does it. Let's go.
See, Alex, do you good
to talk to me.
Gotta try to talk.
You don't want to?...
You got to!...
Gonna take you down south.
There's mywife, my kids...
We'll better be off there.
Just look at Paris...
Gotta go back to the bridge.
Look, you're like me.
Only live once.
Right?
Got one life and wanna live it.
You gotta choose, see?
Goin' back to the bridge.
Look, Alex...
think it over...
Take a minute to think it over.
A minute...
Cause it's too late.
CITY OF PARIS -
RESTORATION OF THE PONT-NEUF
PARIS' OLDEST BRIDGE,
IN HAZARDOUS CONDITION,
WILL BE CLOSED
TO VEHICLES AND PEDESTRIANS
REOPENING : SUMMER 1991
Hans,
it's me.
It's me.
I told you...
when you go nuts
you come to me... not the bottle!
What's that?
Bone's broke... It's gonna knit.
And that?
Fell.
Pass me my downer.
Cops pick you up?
Yeah.
-Been in the shelter?
-Yeah.
Asshole...
Here, go sleep.
Some guy's bedded down over
there.
Can't figure how he got in.
Tomorrow, out on his ass!
You! Come on...
Move it!
Pick up your shit!
And beat it!
Don't ever come back here! NEVER!
Miss!
Shit!
That me there?
That me?
Yes...
from memory.
Where'd you see me?
Took you for dead.
You give it to me?
No...
Really want it? Yes?...
Pose for me, right now.
And you got it.
A portrait.
Don't look at me...
over there...
Julian... Julian...
That's not me.
My Michele.
I'm so worried.
Howare you living? Where?
Your portraits ofJulian remain
here.
I look at them each night
and think ofyou.
Don't leave me without news.
I love you, Marion.
Night already...
Passed out, huh?
Was I drawing?
Yeah.
Louisiana...
You bring me here?
Yeah.
What about the old guy who...?
It's OK.
Want to eat?
Raw fish...
Iike in Japan.
Is it fresh?
They call it "sushi"...
"Wake up, little sushi, wake up!"
Have a name?
Alex.
One day, I'll draw you.
Got to sleep more.
Sure it's OK here?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Tomorrow, out on her ass!
Fish again!
Where's Saint-Cloud?
Saint-Cloud?
Waywest... in the rich suburbs...
Why you asking?
Nothing.
The girl... she's gotta stay here.
-Gotta stay.
-Hell, no!
Couple of days... she's sick.
Don't want her in my face!
Why?
DON'T WANT HER IN MY FACE!
GET IT?
Here, go sleep.
No!
Give me your hand.
The girl...
just a couple of days.
No drink! Not a drop!
Fix it so she's out of my face.
Fix it, right?
Just a couple of days.
Just a couple.
Michele?
Who's there?
What's it mean :
"First Love"?
Julian...
only one she loved...
"Love forever"...
Don't get it...
"First Love"...
Drew him, over and over,
only him...
He played music for her,
only her.
Then something happened.
Don't get it...
Fights...
sad...
Then...
he drops her.
She's waiting for him... so much...
That's why her eyes're so bad?
Can't forget him...
That why she loves him?
That why she's in the street?
Maybe looking for him?
Done a good job!
Gotta go to work.
Shit!...
Here
bought it for you.
Uh?... Thanks.
Don't have to go 'way
to get the news.
Gotta go work.
...city moves into high gear
for the 1789 Bicentennial...
My spot! See you again,
I bust your cords!
Beat it!
Hi...
See the guy playing the cello?
Wasn't a guy... a lady...
took the train...
It can't be.
A fat lady...
Who's there?
Michele.
You? How'd you find me?
Open up, Julian.
I don't see you.
Open up.
No, we have to forget each other
now.
I'm not asking for love.
No!
There's something
you don't know... about me.
Don't be cruel.
Move your finger...
I need to see you... one last time...
need to paint you.
No!
You can't refuse!
Love...
If you refuse, you'll see...
I'M THIRSTY TOO!
What's wrong?
You know?
Maybe... not sure...
Not sure... No matter...
We'll drink together,
but not your way...
Iike an old wino
I want to be drunk with you,
so I can see you laugh.
FIRECRACKERS... FIREWORKS!
Wait... wait...
Where'd you get that?
My dad's a colonel in the army.
Shit...
Take a look...
No bullet missing?
Yeah.
YEAH, WHAT?
No, none.
All there, sure? Still 15?
15, yeah.
Well, FINE!
Dying to shoot, me too!
Blow everything sky high.
Let's do it. 7 for
you, 7 for me.
Keep one for luck.
CATCH!
FIRE! GO ON!
City's full of music.
Want to join the crowd?
No. Better here.
SPEED OK?
CAN'T HEAR,
BUT YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL!
You OK, Louisiana?
Cat Egyptian?
Abyssinian.
A gift.
Dry me, boy.
Real good you're here.
Ready to drop right off.
Never with wet hair.
Here...
throw it over the side.
Gives you nightmares.
Dump it.
I'm zonked...
Wait for me...
Wake up, gotta sleep.
You pass me my downer?
A downer!
Can't find a snug fit?
Quick, need my downer.
Too much drink. Doesn't mix.
Yes... quick...
don't wanna be left alone.
No!
Go on!
BEAT IT!
Somebody loves you. If you say:
"The sky is white," he'll say:
"But the clouds are black."
Then we'll know we're in love.
Michele... Michele... Michele...
Go on up. Tryto sleep.
Can't.
Want your downer?
Too late.
Girl doesn't love me.
The girl doesn't WHAT?
Cause you... you want love?
Like the others?
Tenderness, like the others?
Look around...
No love here!
Love takes bedrooms,
not windy sidewalks!
Got no life for it!
So forget it.
FORGET IT!
The girl, she can't stay.
Got to go!
Leave me alone...
I'm hung over.
You have to go.
All you know how to say? Go?
Think I'd be here, if not for...
a goddam reason? Go where?
My eyes are going.
Listen to me...
When I try to paint,
this eye here
bulges out of my head,
like a snail.
At the museum over there,
I wanted to see a painting...
See it again... before I'm blind.
But a fucking neon
set the eye on fire,
it hurt like hell... I couldn't see.
Listen, maybe if you...
Go fuck yourself
with your "go"!
Look at this...
See that?
30 years a guard.
Factories, buildings,
cemeteries... It's all there.
One night, you and me,
we'll go to the museum.
I have the keys.
You'll be able to see your picture,
with a candle.
So, you weren't always...?
No.
Steady job... a home...
not bad-looking.
Ladies called me "Camembert".
Because of the smell?
No, because I was ripe and ready.
What was her name?
Florence.
Young, beautiful...
made life beautiful.
Always liked a drink...
high spirits...
But after our little girl died,
she downed more and more,
joyless.
How do you stop it?
Not that she didn't love me...
But the pain inched between us.
Couldn't look at me without tears.
One day she up and left.
For weeks I searched...
and I found her...
Wreckage!
Days in the streets,
nights in a train station.
I stuck with her...
followed her...
She died at 33...
and looked 50.
I threw her body in the river.
Yes, your Honor...
over there, near the barges she
loved.
Resembled you a bit...
not the nose.
That's why you can't stand me.
Look...
a woman who sleeps rough
gets beat up, raped,
periods don't come,
drinks to forget till she's numb!
Life outside,
it's right for me, for Alex.
But impossible for you!
You have to go
and... LIVE!
The sky is white today.
The sky is white.
But the clouds are black!
Say "Michele,"
Call me "Michele."
Stay with me .
Wait!
Got to be patient with me.
I'll tell you stuff one day...
about me.
We'll make love,
sure we will, but not yet...
Iater...
Wanna go walk?
Whole city's asleep...
Yeah, let's walk!
It's quick?
Real quick. Real powerful.
Take it often?
Can't sleep without it.
What's the taste?
No taste.
Got an idea.
No more swallowing this poison.
I'll teach you to sleep...
with me.
ANOTHER $ 150!
LET'S SPEND IT!
EVER SEEN THE SEA?
No, but...
THE HORIZON?
No need...
COME ON!
The sea! The sea!
It's wet!... It's wet!...
I'm about to drop off.
Didn't forget something?
Huh? Oh yeah...
Here.
Good night, Love.
I'm proud I taught you to sleep...
that it was me...
proof of our love.
I can't see the horizon...
My eye's too weak now.
But you... you only look at your
feet.
Wanna go back to the bridge.
Still asleep?
No.
My eye is worse.
Want an apple?
Not now.
You count it?
God, I'm stiff...
Gonna end up like an old bag!
Almost 2 thousand!
Think of what we can do!
Bridge's...
fine in summer, but winter...
We'll go under.
Stinks down there.
Oh! Hey! Peanut,
Where? Don't know.
Oh! Hey! Peanut!
The money?
NO!...
Fucking clumsy cunt!
BLIND!
I'm no good anymore.
Sorry, Alex.
First floor.
I know.
This way.
Stop saying "Shh!"
Stop... Shh!
Your shoes squeak...
You here?
Come on...
Take you back.
Michele...
It's there...
Turn that off.
Can't see.
Let's go!
Where are you? Where?
You're where?
HEY, YOU!
You OK?
Forget about me.
Just look.
Got to go back to the bridge.
Try not...
to suffer that way...
Want to be with you.
Really want to.
But you're so closed.
Got to open up!
NEVER DO THAT AGAIN!
We're gonna stick, you and me.
When it all goes black soon,
you'll be my last image,
Who else in your head?
Not many.
Who?
Faces in paintings...
my parents...
my old friend Marion...
my cat...
and then Hans...
and a boy whose name was Julian...
is Julian.
Must tell you sometime.
It'd be good.
You know,
I'm ready to live in the dark.
Because, right now,
the world's just a lot of...
blurry dancing flames...
and I'm sick of it!
You'll be there? My white cane?
My seeing-eye dog?
Playing dog?
Already can't see small things.
They're the most exciting.
A little smile's invisible.
Got to make it big...
Make it all big for me.
Wait.
Where you going?
What're you doing?
See me?
Michele?
I see you...
Clown...
Where are you?
Cops are checking. Don't like it.
Taking you back.
Whythe bum's rush?
Sorry...
Michele Stalens, missing for 6
months,
suffers from a rare eye disease.
Dr. Destouches'
new operation could save her
Every day counts!
See, Louisiana...
a loose wire...
Alex'll fix it.
Speak...
of the devil.
Hold me.
Radio's on the blink.
Got your coat on.
I got scared, Michele.
In the rain, had a bad dream.
Hold me.
It was night.
You weren't on the bridge...
but lost in the dark.
Couldn't find you in the dark...
But I'm here.
Hold me...
... Colonel Stalens' daughter,
24, 5'6", brown hair...
Michele's sight
can perhaps be saved...
Dr. Destouches' new operation...
Any information concerning her...
The radio!
You hear? Talking about me!
MY EYES!
A hope...
if ever...
Could it be?
The end of this nightmare...
Just think, Alex,
MY EYES!
Come,
let's share a bottle...
Another one?
Yeah...
Alex...
ALEX, NEVER LOVED YOU.
NOT REALLY.
FORGET ME. MICHELE
No one...
can teach me...
to forget.
Get up!
Come on!
You Alex Vogan?
Let's go...
Talk about a guy who fried.
TALK!
KID SAW YOU!
PIECE OF SHIT!
The defendant will rise!
The jury finds you guilty
of manslaughter...
and sentences you
to 3 years in prison.
VOGAN!
Call Vogan...
Nearly 2 years...
Knew it was me?
Want me to go?
Had to see you...
Wanted you to see me...
my eyes...
Not talking?
I like your face...
Strange to see you...
just like in my...
Thought I'd forgotten you.
But every night for weeks...
images of you.
That's why I'm here.
My dreams sent me.
People in dreams,
ought to call them when you wake.
Make life simpler.
"Hello, dreamed ofyou."
Love woke me.
You look at me.
Wonder who I was.
Don't know me.
But I imagined you in every
detail...
even your hair...
it's grown...
Same shining eyes as in my
dreams...
we were both running,
through cities,
valleys and plains...
And you didn't limp anymore.
Don't limp anymore.
What?
Don't limp.
You see,
nothing's... irremediable.
Went to the bridge last night...
All repaired.
Now it's solid.
Why'd you tryto forget me?
Never told you about me...
we led such a strange life...
Why'd you never come to see me?
I waited.
I'm afraid of us... at times
often...
You're weak...
No...
Can you love me?
Yeah, like before,
but not the same.
I'll visit you...
Never, not here.
I miss you.
so many things to fix...
inside me.
Want to be ready for you...
A new man...
When I get out...
Six months...
Christmas, yes...
Midnight on the bridge...
To do your portrait.
- With wine.
- Good wine!
No poison in it!
A room in a hotel. I have money.
Breakfast in bed... You'll see,
butter on our thighs,
jam on our bellies,
crumbs stuck to our...
DR. DESTOUCHES
EYE SURGEON
Louisiana...
I'm on your eyes.
I'm on your mouth...
Done!
I'll do better...
Like yourself?
Yes.
Yes yes or yes no?
Oh! Shit!
Clumsy! Take off your mitten.
No. It's OK.
YOU LOOK HAPPY!
YES!
LOADED... ON LOVE!
Know the happy man story?
Two guys in a bar...
really down... wonder
if they fuck enough to be happy.
So, the first one says,
"Me, I get it every two weeks."
The second one says,
"Me, once a month."
Not a hell of a lot...
But there's this third guy at the
bar,
all alone,
huge grin on his face... ear to ear.
Guys wonder... why's he so happy?
So...
not easy...
they ask how often he has sex.
The guy, beaming, says,
"My friends...
I make love every three years."
"What? Every three years?
So why're you so happy?"
And the third guy says,
"Because tonight's the night!"
Because tonight's the night...
Oh... my head hurts.
Tonight's the night...
3 o'clock?
Didn't hear 2.
Tonight's the night.
Alex, I have to go...
I'm dead...
Love, what's wrong?
It's not true.
What?
You're not tired.
Yes... I'm tired.
Little hotel nearby,
Louisiana, same as your cat.
I asked...
they serve breakfast in bed.
Love, have to go.
Where?
I'll tell you.
WHAT?
Don't shout!
Some things... take time...
Don't make me say, not tonight.
You're killing me.
Got to be patient with me.
No!
Lies...
LIES!
MICHELE!
Are you sand dealers?
We just haul it.
Our last trip.
Where're you bound?
All the way...
To the Atlantic.
The Atlantic...
We are too...
Right?
OK if we come along?
Can be arranged.
Oh! Hey! Peanut,
Oh! Hey! Don't know...
LET PARIS ROT!