[Wind howling]
[Water dripping]
[Doors squeaking]
Narrator:
Once upon a time,
There was a land where
the warm light of day
Was in perfect balance with
the cool darkness of night
And all lived
together as one.
To ensure that the perfect
harmony of this land
Was never disrupted, it was
arranged that king solter
Of the day would marry
princess dume of the night.
King solter, however, would not
accept an arranged marriage.
He would only marry for love.
And so he took the beautifully
luna to be his bride instead.
It seemed that things
couldn't be more perfect...
[Thunder]
Until princess dume appeared,
furious that king solter
Had chosen luna,
a common girl, over her.
No longer will
night and day live
in harmony as one.
From this day forward,
I, princess dume, shall
alone rule the night!
Narrator: As time passed so
did any hope that the day
And night worlds would
ever be reunited...
Until one day...
[Fanfare]
Look out! Look out!
Now the king is coming!
Did you hear?
I'm finally
a father!
[Yelling]
The king!
Make way for the king!
[Baby cooing]
Is... is this my child?
Your highness,
this is your daughter.
[Cooing]
Oh, she is beautiful.
This is also
your daughter.
Two daughters?
Luna, you've given me the two
most perfect children ever born.
What shall we name them?
Well, this one
is as calm and deep
As the silvery moon
on a summer's Eve.
This one is
as bright and lovely
As the golden
sun at dawn.
Eve and dawn.
Our daughters.
Make way! Make way!
The king is coming!
The king is...
Here.
[Laughter]
Cassy, meet the two
newest members of
our royal family.
Two?
Dawn and Eve.
Isn't it wonderful,
cassy?
Twins.
One from each world.
This has never
happened before.
It's an omen.
Perhaps these girls are
meant to bring balance
back to our world.
[Laughing] But
all that in good time.
Right now it's time
to give these girls
a birthday gift.
Huh?
Ok.
Mya mosca ariavi.
[Both giggling]
Ha! Ahem. It worked!
[Babies giggling]
It worked.
[Laughing]
Ah!
[Both gasp]
[Grunting]
[Laughter]
[People cheering]
* the night will turn to day
like it always does *
* nothing's gonna
stop us from being us *
* all we need's each other
* we'll find a way
to be together *
* the stars will shine as long
as you're here with me *
* you and me,
livin' out our destiny *
* all we need's each other
* we'll be ok
* we'll be together
* when I'm with you, I feel like
I'm floating through the sky *
* you're my better half and I'm
so glad you're by my side *
* every day's a gift because
I'm sharin' it with you *
* if you weren't around, I just
don't know what I would do *
* the night will to turn
to day like it always does *
* nothing's gonna
stop us from being us *
* all we need's each other
* we'll find a way
to be together *
* the stars will shine as long
as you're here with me *
* you and me,
livin' out our destiny *
* all we need's each other
* we'll be ok
if we're together *
[Babies squealing]
Narrator: Word of the
royal birth spread quickly
Across the land and
with it spread hope.
Perhaps the princess twins
were a sign that the worlds
Of day and night might
at last be reunited.
Of course, not all were
pleased with this prophecy.
[Wind howling]
Ah, strange.
[Babbling]
[Thunder]
[Yawning]
[All yawning]
Oh, dear,
oh, dear, oh, dear.
Maybe you'd like
to take a little nap
this afternoon, cassy.
Excellent idea, luna.
[Snoring]
I didn't mean right now.
[All snoring]
[Yawning]
I wouldn't mind
a nice nap myself.
[Thunder]
It's night.
* beautiful,
beautiful night *
Night!
[Gasps]
[Thunder throughout]
[Crying]
No!
Luna!
[Panting]
[Babies crying]
[Hisses]
Let go of my babies!
Uh!
[Babies crying]
Luna!
[Gasps]
Princess dawn
was in luna's arms.
She sheltered her
from the fall.
I'm sorry.
And princess Eve?
No sign of her,
your highness.
Find her,
cassy, please.
Find her.
Narrator: Desperate to find
his missing daughter,
King solter ordered every
member of his royal guard
To search the land
until they found her.
[Dogs howling]
They looked
throughout the land.
No stone was left unturned.
Until at last king solter
was forced to accept
The terrible truth...
princess Eve would
never be found.
Solter could not bear
the thought that dawn
Might someday hear
of the awful fate
Of her night world
mother and sister.
He believed the truth
would break her heart
Just as it had
broken his own.
And so the king passed
a decree forbidding anyone
In the kingdom to speak
of the night world again.
And all things of that world
were hidden from sight forever.
The hearts of day and
night will come together
in love no more.
[Birds chirping]
[Yipping]
Oh!
Did you find
them, sparks?
Uh-uh, no.
Ha ha. Oh,
that's ok, boy.
They're good at
hiding, but we're
better at seeking.
Hmm, we better
find them soon.
I was supposed to be
home hours ago.
[Yipping]
Oh, you're hot on the trail.
[Panting]
Ha ha!
Good job, sparks,
you found cammy.
No fair, you're my dragon.
You're not supposed
to be helping dawn.
[Laughing]
Hmph! You should
have found Gemma, not me.
Aah! But I love you anyway.
[Crunching]
[Giggling]
[Gasps]
[Laughter]
I found her!
You always find us, dawn.
Of course she does.
Dawn's the best
at finding stuff.
at everything.
Thank you, Gemma,
but I did have a little
help from sparks there.
Hey, you should get
a baby dragon
For your birthday, dawn.
Don't be silly, cammy.
Princess dawn doesn't
want a baby gift like
that for her birthday.
A dragon isn't
a baby gift.
Yes, it is.
Is not.
It is.
Is not, not, not.
Stop it, you two.
A dragon is a perfectly
lovely gift, cammy.
However, it isn't
really what I want for
my birthday this year.
What do you want, dawn?
Well, I'm not really sure.
You should get
a new dress with beads...
[Both talking at once]
Just one more
teensy game.
* I know that there's love
* I know that there's
more than what I see *
* I can feel it in the air
* something big is
out there for me *
* and the answers are clear
* it feels like I'm near
* and I won't stop until
they're in my reach *
* something tells me
there's a place *
* a whole new world
* that there's a better place
* because I don't believe
the sun just shines for me *
* one day I'll wake up
knowing everything *
* that's my dream
* something tells me
there's a place *
* a whole new world
* that there's a better place
* because I don't believe
the sun just shines for me *
* one day I'll wake up
knowing everything *
* that's my dream
Man: Dawn!
Whoa!
Hello, father.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry.
I was just...
You were supposed
to be home hours ago.
There's no need to yell.
I am not yelling.
[Yipping]
Ohh.
I'm sorry, dawn.
But I've told you many
times how dangerous it is
On the other side
of that wall.
Why can't I just
see for myself?
You'll see the world outside
these walls soon enough.
Please, father,
I have so many questions
About life outside
the castle, about my mother.
There is no one
more important to me
than you are, dawn.
I just want
to protect you.
I'm not a child anymore.
If you won't tell me
what I want to know,
I'll just have to go
and find out for myself.
Dawn, stop!
Come back here!
Cassy, follow her.
Take her to her room.
Lock her up
if you have to.
But don't let her leave
the castle again.
[Muttering]
Yes, your highness.
[Whispered]
We should go back.
No, we shouldn't.
Yes, we should.
We should not, should
not, should not.
Shh!
[Door closes]
[Door opens]
[Whispered]
This way, hurry.
I don't think
we should do this.
Besides,
the door is locked.
So, we'll just unlock it.
Cammy, you stole those!
I didn't steal them.
I just borrowed them
from cassy.
[Tapping]
[Gasps]
Sparks!
[Yipping]
[All sigh]
You stop sneaking up
on us like that.
Ohh. Ah?
[Door squeaking]
Hmm, we need some light.
Here, sparks.
[Yipping]
Come here.
Here, boy. Fetch.
[Yipping]
Good boy!
Hurray!
Ah, good dragon.
[Yipping
and panting]
Wow, look at all this stuff.
You can't play
with those, cammy.
Yes, I can.
Those things
aren't yours.
I'm not
going to hurt them.
They're still not yours.
[Gasps]
Wow!
Look at that!
[Gasps] Ohh.
She's beautiful.
She looks
like you, except
for the dark hair.
She really was
from the night world.
Shh!
Night world?
Uh, this sure is
a pretty necklace.
What do you mean, night world?
She didn't mean anything.
I'm not supposed
to talk about it.
Nobody is.
Tell me.
I thought you were my friends,
But friends don't
keep secrets from each other.
Do you promise not to
tell anyone we told you?
Cross your heart
and hope to find a
pixie in your shoe?
I promise.
People say that
a long, long time ago,
The sun would
only shine for a few
hours every day.
Then it would disappear and
everything would go dark.
That's when
the day creatures would
hide and the creatures
Of the night with their
glowing eyes and big,
Long teeth would come out
to terrorize the land.
My mother was one
of these horrible
night creatures?
That's what I heard.
Where did all
the night creatures go?
What happened to them?
I'm not sure.
But legend says that
they're still living
In a world nearby, a
world of total darkness.
Where?
Where is this world?
I don't know.
I don't think anyone
knows for sure.
Well then, it's time
that someone found out.
[Wolf and wind howling]
Where is that girl?!
Where is she?!
Look at my
poor sweet babies.
[Whining]
Oh, no, no, no, they're
practically starving.
Gee, they don't look
hungry to me.
Ohh!
I'll be the judge of that,
lieutenant ledem.
Of course,
your royalness.
Now, where is that girl?
I'm here, your royalness.
Yes, so you are.
Tell me, child,
do I not feed you,
Give you a place to sleep,
Allow you to do
chores for me?
Yes, your royalness.
Then, why can you
not do a simple task
Like feeding
my sweet babies?!
But I did feed them.
Then feed them again!
Foolish child!
[Whining]
I take such good care
of that child, ledem.
You do?
I mean, yes!
You do, you do!
You'd think she'd be more
grateful, wouldn't you?
Oh, yes, your royalness.
She should be singing
your praises... Like me.
* oh, I've been over
* I've been told
the heart of doom *
* is small and cold
* she is smart
and she is rich *
* some call her a wick...
Thank you.
That's quite
enough praise for now.
Go now!
And make sure
my babies are fed!
Yes, yes,
your royalness.
Right away,
[Sighs] Oh, it's so hard
to get good help these days.
What's this?
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Kylo!
[Gasps] Eve.
Are you
angry with me?
Oh, I cannot bear
to see you upset.
Come, bitter conduct,
come unsavory guide,
Thou desperate pilot,
thou at once run
On the dashing rocks thy
seasick weary bark.
[Horse neighs]
Don't worry, Eve.
I'm all right.
Juniper has come
to my rescue.
That's all well and good.
But who's going to rescue me
When dume sees those
nasty pictures you've
drawn on my walls?
Hmm, you're right.
She's going to be furious.
We should run away together.
What?
We can live in my cave.
Dume will never find us.
It will be our
secret hideaway.
Oh, I can't do that, kylo.
Why not?
You told me you dream
In your sleep about
a beautiful world without dume.
She's not really so bad.
She takes care of me
and she saved me
From those horrible
day creatures when
I was just a baby.
Horrible day creatures?
Who says they're horrible?
Have you ever met one?
No, but...
Come on, at least
go for a ride with me.
I...I don't think i...
You've got to stop dreaming
and start living, Eve.
But i... Ok,
just one short ride.
[Horse neighs]
* I close my eyes
so I can dream *
* 'cause in my dreams
* there is a beautiful
world waiting for me *
* where the stars are bright
and I never feel alone *
* and I know that I belong
* I'm home
* where are my wings
so I can fly? *
* I want to reach
the other side *
* these walls
around me can't be all *
* all there is
* there's got to be
more than this *
* I close my eyes
so I can dream *
* 'cause in my dreams
there is a beautiful
world waiting for me *
* where the stars are bright
and I never feel alone *
* 'cause I know
that I belong *
* I'm home
* I close my eyes
so I can dream *
* 'cause in my dreams there is a
beautiful world waiting for me *
* where the stars are bright
and I never feel alone *
* 'cause I know that I belong
* I'm home
Are you sure you
want to come back?
I have to.
This is the only home
I've ever known.
You better go now
before dume sees you.
Ok.
Parting is such sweet sorrow,
But I shall say good night
till it be morrow.
[Whistles]
Father!
Dawn, I know you're upset
about our conversation.
Oh, it's all right, father.
I don't mind being left
in the dark about everything.
Now, dawn, i...
[High-pitched squeaking]
Have you ever thought
about putting a painting
above that fireplace?
No. No,
I haven't.
Why would you
ask such a...
I've been thinking
about my birthday, father.
And I think I might
like some artwork.
Of course. Art makes
a wonderful gift.
And we
could certainly hang it
over the fireplace...
A portrait
of my beautiful
princess, perhaps.
Actually, I was thinking of
something with a moon on it.
You know, something
that shows the night world.
Night world?! What?!
Who told you
about the night world?
It should have been you!
Dawn!
You don't understand!
Then make me understand!
Talk to me, father!
My mother is dead,
but I'm not!
Go to your room,
young lady!
Fine!
Lock me away,
The same way you do everything
you don't want to deal with.
Cassy, you know I love her.
I... i just don't
understand her.
You can't
protect her forever.
She's becoming
a young lady and you
must respect that.
[Sighs]
Yes, I know.
I just don't
know what to do.
She's all I have.
She needs to know the truth,
your highness.
You need to tell her.
It's time.
[Sighs]
Of course, you're right.
Tomorrow, cassy.
I'll tell her the whole story
first thing tomorrow.
[Animal noises throughout]
[Shuddering]
How dare you
leave the castle
without my permission!
And with that
wretched little boy!
I-I'm sorry,
your royalness.
Silence!
You must be taught a lesson.
Hmm.
[Evil laughter]
[Panting]
Your royalness!
What is it?
I have urgent news.
[Whispers] There's been
a breach to the wall.
What?
[Whispers] I said...
There's been a breach
to the wall!
I heard you.
What do you mean,
there's been a breach?
An intruder from the day
world has broken through.
Come. There's
no time to waste.
I will deal with you later.
Hello there.
[Mutters]
Oh, you're cute.
[Giggles]
[Gibberish]
I didn't mean
to frighten you.
My name is dawn.
What's yours?
[Gibberish]
Hmm? [Giggles]
Uh, perhaps you want
to play hide and seek?
Very well.
One magic scepter,
two magic scepters,
Three magic scepters,
four magic scepters.
All right, here I come!
[Gibberish]
[Gasps]
[Giggles]
But I'm the one that's
supposed to find you.
[Chuckles]
Where I come from,
We don't have anyone
that looks quite like you.
[Gibberish]
Or sounds quite
like you either.
You certainly can gibber.
That's it! I'll
call you gibber.
[Gibberish]
Oh! [Giggles] Oh!
[Wolf howling]
[Gibberish]
Hey, wait! Gibber!
Where are you going?
[Growling]
Ah!
[Gibberish]
[Screaming]
[Howling]
[Gasps]
[Growling]
[Chuckles]
[Gibberish]
You idiot mongrel!
After her!
[Growling]
Aah! Gibber!
Oh!
Ah!
[Whining]
[Crying]
Aah!
Oh, gibber. Oh,
you're all right.
[Growling
and grunting]
[Gasps] Oh, no.
[Gibberish]
Unh!
We've got you now,
you little puny.
[Neighing]
Your shining knight
at your service, milady.
[Growling]
[Shuddering]
[Groaning]
[Neighs]
[Laughter]
Did you see the look
on that nippee's face
When I swooped in?
[Neighs]
I mean, when juniper
and I swooped in.
It was classic.
Dume must really
be mad to sic the night
beasts on you.
Hey! You're not Eve!
My name is dawn,
And I can't thank you
enough for rescuing me.
Uh... I'm sorry.
I don't know who you...
I'm kylo.
Are you
a night creature, kylo?
I guess you
could say that.
Boy, you sure do look
like my good friend Eve...
Same face, same eyes,
Except for that funny
day world colored hair.
[Wolves howling]
Come on, we better
get you inside.
Welcome to my home, dawn.
Kylo, this is amazing.
Ah, it's nothing really.
Do you live
here all alone?
Uh-huh.
I'm currently a bachelor.
[Gibberish]
Who is this?
That's Eve.
The girl
I was talking about.
The one that
looks just like you.
Does she live
around here?
She lives with dume.
Dume?
The one who sent the
night beasts after me?
Yes, but Eve isn't like dume.
Eve is wonderful.
Like a single star
on a moonless night.
Would you like
to meet her?
I could bring her here.
Are you sure you
can trust her?
Eve? I've known her forever.
I trust her with my life.
[Laughs]
Dawn?
Dawn, open this door.
Dawn, it's your father.
[Gasps]
She's not here, cassy.
I distinctly told her she
was not to leave this castle.
Wait a minute.
Hold it, you two.
Do you girls know
where the princess might be?
Princess?
What princess?
The last time we saw
her was yesterday
in the dungeon.
Shh.
Dawn was in the dungeon?
It's all my fault.
I stole the keys.
I just wanted to help dawn.
And then we went to the
dungeon, and it was dark,
And sparks lit a torch,
and we found this room.
And she asked us
all these questions
about the night world.
Cassy, she knows about luna.
What if she's gone looking
for the night world?
[Laughter echoing]
Eve?
[Gasps] Who's there?
It's ok, Eve,
it's just me.
Kylo.
Another bad dream?
Not bad really.
What's this?
Don't!
No wonder
you have nightmares.
[Men chanting]
There's no place
for her to hide.
We will search
and find our prey.
She won't live another day.
Searching hard
and searching wide.
There's no place
for her to hide.
You better go, kylo.
Dume's in a dreadful mood.
There was an intruder
in the night world.
Huh.
I know all about that.
She came here
from the day world.
It's a day creature?
Uh-huh. And you
won't believe this,
But she looks
exactly like you...
Except for the hair.
Me?
The intruder is a girl
and you let her get away?
Incompetence!
Someone helped her.
Who? Who helped her?
And you'd better
have an answer.
It was that little
friend of Eve's... the one
with the flying horse.
We must find that brat.
He'll tell us
where the intruder is.
No one knows
where the boy lives,
your royalness.
Eve knows.
Right.
Of course,
she'll never tell us.
No, she'll never tell.
I'll have to be
very clever about this.
Ooh!
I love it when
you're clever.
Ooh!
Quiet!
It's time we pay Eve
a little visit.
Come on, Eve.
You have to meet her.
She's waiting for us
back at my cave.
No, kylo. Day creatures
are dangerous.
That's what dume says,
But this girl doesn't
look dangerous to me.
[Footsteps]
[Gasps]
It's dume.
You'd better go,
kylo.
Hurry up!
[Indistinct]
I'll come back for you...
When dume is asleep.
Just go.
Oh, my dear, Eve.
Are you all right?
Yes, your royalness.
Thank goodness.
I was so worried.
An evil day creature
has invaded our world.
I... i heard there
was an intruder.
But are you sure
it's evil?
My poor innocent child,
it's a day creature.
Naturally, it's evil.
You see, a day creature
can take on any shape
to win your trust.
But sooner or later,
their true hideous
nature emerges.
Then creep
into your room
And snatch you...
[Gasps]
Right out of your bed
and carry you away!
Eve, dear, you
don't know anything
About this creature
who has invaded
our world, do you?
No. Of course you don't.
You would tell me
if you did, hmm?
You would never risk
someone being hurt
by such a dreadful beast.
Hurt?
No.
Then tell me what you know.
I...My friend, kylo,
he saw the creature.
She's in his cave.
Oh, dear.
I'm afraid your friend
is in grave danger.
Oh, I would love
to help him.
But I don't know
where he lives.
Oh, he lives in the grotto
behind the vesper waterfall.
Aren't you clever?
I knew I could count on you.
Lieutenant ledem!
Right!
Go find the boy!
And take care of him!
Permanently!
[Gasps]
It will be
my pleasure.
No!
[Gasps]
That amulet is no
concern of yours.
Lock her up!
She's served her purpose.
[Chuckles]
Uhh!
My father was right
not to tell me about
the night world, gibber.
I never should
have come here.
And I put you
and kylo in danger.
It's just that I was hoping
to find some answers here.
About the past...
My mother...
Everything.
Ooh.
[Splash]
Huh? Uh-oh.
What's wrong?
Is someone there?
Kylo?
Uh-oh.
[Gasps]
Well, what have we here?
A lovely day creature...
Trespassing into my kingdom!
But i...
Why are you here?
I don't see how
that's your business.
It's my world.
It's my business!
Now... Who sent you?
Was it that ridiculous
king solter?
I won't have you speak
of my father that way.
Your father?
Why, yes.
Oh, yes, of course.
I should have recognized
those eyes...
And what's this?
The other amulet.
[Laughs]
Oh! This is too perfect.
[Grunting]
Take her to the dungeon!
Let go of me!
[Grunting]
[Chatter]
What is taking so long?
We have to find dawn.
Your highness.
We must break through.
Uh!
[Gasps]
[Metal clanging]
[Chuckles]
Come on.
Ah! Come on!
Move it!
Uh!
[Growls]
Ah!
[Growling]
[Chuckles]
[Grunting]
That's for the night beasts.
[Water dripping]
[Clang]
Is someone there?
I don't understand.
I think I do
understand.
Dawn!
Kylo!
Stay away from her, dawn.
Eve's a traitor.
She told dume
where I live.
No, no, no, I'm not.
Dume tricked me.
It's not her fault, kylo.
Dume is evil.
Dume? Ha!
I told you, Eve.
[Dog barking]
It's dume.
No. Dume's gone.
She used your amulet
to enter the day world.
[Gasps] She's going
to harm my father.
Please, kylo, you have to
help us get out of here.
Leave it to me.
[Grunting]
Pull, juniper, pull!
[Neighs]
[Barking]
[Gasps]
Come on, juniper.
Hurry, kylo.
You can do it.
Pull, juniper, pull!
[Neighs]
Uh!
[Barking]
Oh, no.
[Both gasp]
[Grunting]
[Howling]
Kylo, where are you?
Uhh.
I'm good.
[Laughing]
You two take juniper.
Gibber and I will
take care of them.
[Gibberish]
Ahh. Maybe we better not.
[Neighing]
Oh, this bridal gown was
made for me 15 years ago
And I still
look fabulous in it.
Ha ha! Don't I?
You look amazing,
your royalness.
Hmm...
Although the decolletage
is a little deep.
Tsk-tsk.
And the trailing tendrils
are kind of left here.
Enough!
Oh!
Let's get
this wedding started.
Where's solter?
But it's bad luck
to see the groom
before the wedding.
[Grunting]
Get in here.
Ah, there's my groom.
Are you ready?
How do I know you
are telling the truth?
How do I know
my daughter is safe?
Your little brat
is perfectly safe
behind prison walls.
And she'll stay safe
as long as you say "I do."
[Neighs]
[Bell tolling]
[Whispers]
Gosh, Joseph, stop this.
Maybe if sparks
swallowed the amulets.
Huh?
Nice try,
flower girlies.
[Growling]
[Whistling]
[Clearing throat]
Now, let's see here.
Births, deaths,
sheep namings,
Pixie proms,
unicorn blessings,
Bar mitzvahs...
Hurry up!
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Here it is.
[Inhales]
Dearly beloved...
[Loud crying]
We are gathered here today.
The royal guard, the...
Just get to
the part where we
join our amulets.
Right, yes, of course.
Raise your amulets
into the air.
These amulets contain
the most powerful magic of all.
Queen dume,
repeat after me,
"This amulet I give you is
a sign of our abiding love."
This amulet
I give you as a sign
of our abiding love.
[Clears throat]
Your highness.
Yes.
This amulet I give you
as a sign of our...
Abiding love.
[Neighing]
Dawn!
Luna?
My name is Eve, sire.
[Gasps] Eve.
Come here, my child.
Father!
I'm sorry.
This was all my fault.
No, dawn, I was
the one at fault.
You showed great courage.
Had you not gone
into the night world,
You would never have
brought back your sister...
How quaint.
A family reunion.
Uh-huh. Uhh!
You, you devil!
You were supposed
to marry me.
Make me your queen.
You took my luna.
My life away from me!
My, my. Our first
lover's quarrel.
You monster!
Stay away from my family!
Uh!
[Laughing]
Father!
[Gasps]
Let go of him!
Oh, what a tangled web
we weave!
Look out!
[Laughing]
[Screaming]
Now the power of day
and night will be mine
and mine alone!
[Laughing]
Do something, cassy.
Dume will get
you powerful.
She has the amulets.
Uh... The power isn't
in the amulets.
It's in our hearts.
When the hearts
of day and night
Come together in love,
the world is one.
Dawn, Eve...
Together the power is yours.
Quickly, there's
not much time!
[Hissing]
Dearest solter, don't you
want to kiss your bride?
Uh!
No, stop!
You ungrateful little child!
I should have finished
you both off, along
with your mother...
The precious luna.
Never mention
our mother's name again.
Let our father go!
You want him?
You can have him!
No!
[Laughing]
Ah.
Now, to finish
what I started!
When the hearts
of day and night
come together,
The world is one!
What?
What's wrong now?
Why isn't it working?
Where is my power?
Where is my power?!
You have no power.
Ohh!
[Grunting]
I'm sorry
for you, dume.
I don't want your pity.
Dume, take my hand.
Eve, my sweet.
[Gasps]
[Shudders]
My sweet through all!
[Screaming]
[Laughter]
[Bells tolling]
Happy Birthday,
my daughters.
Princess dawn...
Princess Eve.
Citizens of
our fair land!
May I present to you
the princess twins!
[People shouting,
bells tolling]
Happy Birthday,
your royalness.
Ohh.
Oh.
Tell me again how
you fought off those terrible
night beasts, kylo.
Oh, well, uh...
Whoa, oh, oh!
[Gibberish]
Narrator: And from that day on,
the two worlds were reunited.
Never to be divided again.
* the night will turn to day
like it always does *
* nothing's gonna
stop us from being us *
* all we need's each other
* we'll find a way
to be together *
* the stars will shine as long
as you're here with me *
* you and me living
out our destiny *
* all we need's each other
* we'll be ok,
we'll be together *
* when I with you, I feel like
I'm floating through the sky *
* you're my better half and I'm
so glad you're by my side *
* every day's a gift because
I'm sharin' it with you *
* if you weren't around, I just
don't know what I would do *
* the night will turn
to day like it always does *
* nothing's gonna
stop us from being us *
* all we need's each other
* we'll find a way
to be together *
* the stars will shine as long
as you're here with me *
* you and me
living out our destiny *
* all we need's each other
* we'll be ok
if we're together *
* we'll be together
* together, together,
together, together *
* forever
* the night will turn to day
like it always does *
* nothing's gonna
stop us from being us *
* all we need's
each other *
* we'll find a way
to be together *
* the stars will shine as long
as you're here with me *
* you and me living out
our destiny *
* all we need's each other...