Here we go, folks.
Show's about to start.
We got multiple enemies! Get into 360!
Changing magazines! 360 security!
Hey, buddy!
We got a live one here.
735, come in, 735.
Umm, tracking something new here.
Yeah, it just lit up. What is that?
Weird.
Try to call them on 121.5 VHF.
Roger. Unidentified aircraft
40 miles west of Rollins field.
This is Rollins
tower, do you read me?
Please respond. What are
your intentions? Over.
Unidentified aircraft, now 35
miles west of Rollins Field.
You're entering controlled airspace.
Please identify.
Not responding.
Okay, call it in.
Roger that.
Albuquerque Center,
this is Rollins Tower.
This is Center, go ahead, Rollins.
We've got an unidentified
contact bearing 270 degrees,
20 miles, speed 600 knots;
appears to be descending fast.
You tracking a meteor, Rollins?
Negative, we've got visual on it,
definitely no meteor.
Stand by, Rollins.
Any ideas there, Jim?
Not sure, I'm switching to thermal.
Well, whatever it
is, it's going down.
Damn.
What the hell was that?
Whatever it was, it's
down for the count.
Rollins Tower...
Albuquerque Center, I'm
getting heavy interference,
say again?
Rollins Tower, please confirm...
Phone's dead,
try the radio on a
different frequency.
Any station, any station,
this is Rollins Tower on
Victor, anybody read me?
This is crazy. You gotta hear this.
What?
I'm gonna patch it through.
Okay, we are rollin' here
on another beautiful Arizona morning.
Oh!
Hey, Parker, buddy, I
see you're up at least!
Huh!
Hey, buddy!
Hey, good morning!
I know, buddy. I wish you could come, too.
I know, I know, don't
blame me, blame your mom.
She's the one that said there
wasn't enough room in the car.
I know, buddy. I call bullshit, too.
Here we go!
Morning, sunshines!
Collin! God!
Already with the camera?
Aw, wake up, guys!
I got a fun weekend planned for us!
Dude, I'll give you $50 if
you give us one more hour.
No, no can do, brother. Sorry.
As John Wayne once said,
we're burning daylight.
Let's do this.
- Fucker.
- Uh-huh.
For a hundred, I might reconsider.
- Fine, I'll write you a check.
- No, no, no. Cash money only.
Hey, Kimmy.
Time to wake up. Morning, baby.
Morning, hey.
What are you doing?
I'm watching you.
Am I totally creeping you out or what?
Pervert.
How long have you been filming me?
I don't know, 30, 40 minutes? Maybe less.
- So creepy.
- Uh-huh.
Hey, someone's camera-shy. Come on, baby.
Give it to me.
What? Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Give it.
- Easy. Oh!
See how you like it.
Oh... Now what?
Now that I've got you where I want you...
Oh, hello.
That what you wanna see,
you dirty little perv?
You know it. Please.
- Give it to me.
- No, not the camera.
Come on. No, no.
Easy, alright. Ah...
Okay.
Okay?
- Talk to me.
- Talk to you about?
Tell me what you're thinking.
I'm thinking...
...that I love you.
Aww, you're sweet.
And I think you're beautiful.
And...? What else?
I think you are the most...
...sexiest woman in the world.
Very nice. Keep going.
- The most intelligent.
- That's definitely true.
Hey, hey.
- Hands off the merchandise.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
No... tease! Total tease!
Hey.
You know I just love making you crazy.
Where you going? What're you doing?
I gotta pee.
Really?
She leaves me to fend for myself again.
Morning all!
Well, it is Friday, and
for many of you, that means
you have a fun and exciting
weekend to look forward to,
but I am working, and not
that I don't love what I do,
but seeing as how it is
"Full Disclosure Friday,"
I am not really feeling it today.
Oh, one cool thing, there was a report
of a meteor touching down near Hadly Hill.
And for those of you that don't know Hadly,
it's what we like to call a starter hill.
It's not too challenging of a climb,
but it's a beautiful hike,
it's perfect for those of you
that have small children with you.
Um, just don't get hit
by any falling meteors.
Um, now what some may
not know about meteors,
is that even though they look really
bright and beautiful in the sky,
what ends up touching down
is usually not that much
bigger than an acorn.
So it's kind of uneventful,
for the most part,
but it's always fun to investigate.
Ah, it's already cold. That's not good.
And it is later than I thought.
God, I hate when that happens.
Uh, okay!
This is Alice the park ranger, signing off.
As always, leave comments below,
click to subscribe to my channel.
You guys know the drill. Okay, bye!
Okay, here we are. First stop.
Casa de Duncan.
Hey, Dunk, what's up, buddy?
How're you doing today?
Alrightey.
Hope anybody's home.
Hello?
Oh, guess I'm breaking in.
- Hey, Janice, how're you doing?
- Hey.
Where's the old man?
- Where do you think?
- Alright.
See ya later.
Later.
So, uh, Duncan's got something
he wants to show you all.
- You live?
- Locked and loaded.
Got something I wanna show you.
What're you gonna show us
with that old hunk of junk?
Well, most folks look
at this, call it a scope.
But after a few of my modifications,
it is now known as the
Duncan Harvey original.
Shameless self-promoter!
You wanna see what it can do?
Yeah! Why the hell not?
- That's my mark.
- Alright, that ain't happening,
guess it'd have to be eyes on you.
Well?
What, you missed?
- How 'bout them apples?
- Shit!
No shit!
That's more like... 500 yards!
With this rig, I could
make the same at six.
Okay, alright, Duncan, you impressed me.
- Damn right.
- Well, but now how do I know
you didn't come out here and
take that shot an hour ago?
Nah, I made it last night
at ten yards, maybe twelve.
Yeah, I believe that, I believe that.
But seriously, that's
a bullseye at 450 yards.
I wish I could take credit,
but with this here hand-crafted,
and fully patented, Harvey scope,
hell, a brain dead stepchild
could make that shot.
Hey, whoa, man!
What the hell?
Some kind of weird ass bullshit TV...
Okay.
So you got the house and gate keys?
I think that should be it.
You can call me on the cellular
'til we get to the high country.
I got it. It's no problem.
- Guessing we're all set then.
- Daylight's a burnin'.
Yeah, guess it's time to shorten the road.
See ya Sunday.
Hey, bring me back a ten point!
I'll bring you back two ten points.
Alright.
Take it easy, Janice.
You're on driving duty, old man.
What'd you say?
Let the immortals ride again.
Okay, couldn't get the exact coordinates
on that meteor, but I'm
seeing some smoke up here.
Could be a brush fire,
and with the little rain fall we've
had this year, that could be bad,
really bad, considering
how dry everything is.
Not sure what's going on,
but I'm gonna let this run.
On my way to check out this meteor,
and my radio is doing all kinds of crazy...
At first nothing, but the
closer I get to my destination,
this weird sound is getting louder.
Okay,
on foot from here.
Okay, here we are down
at the old swimming hole,
April 2012.
There's my boy, Ryan, fishing.
Hey, Ryan, any biters?
- Not yet.
- Know why?
That...
...is a swimming hole! Not a fishing hole.
Yeah, yeah.
Whoa. This is where I
should be aiming my camera.
Say hey to the camera, girls!
- Hey, camera.
- Yeah, yeah.
You guys not getting
into the water or what?
Well, Ryan says we'll
scare off the fishies.
I'm sorry? What? I can't hear you.
- What the fuck just landed on me?!
- Whoa, whoa, hey, now.
- Be careful.
- "Hey now" is right.
- Just lost my PG rating.
- That totally freaked me out.
It was just a little bug!
There was nothing little about it.
If this ends up on
YouTube, I'm gonna kill you.
Wimpy, Wimpy, hey, Mr.
Skin, maybe, but you know...
- Shut up!
- You two, trust me, trust me.
I'm the filmmaker here.
I've found the source of the smoke, and...
Well, it can't be what it looks like.
Look at the size of this thing.
This is...
Holy shit...
What is this growing here?
322, come in.
What the hello?
Ahh!
Ugh, something just bit me.
Okay, that... really stings.
Okay, I'm out of here.
'Kay, whatever that was...
I-I've gotta get ahold of Poison Control.
Following protocol when
you don't know what bit you,
you're supposed to grab a sample,
but I am not touching whatever that was.
322, come in!
This is Range One calling
South Range dispatch.
What's this now? South Range dispatch?
322? Anyone?
Can anyone read me? Over.
Alright now, we're doing this
thing by camp rules, ain't we?
You really should know 'em by now,
but I'll repeat 'em for the record.
- Let's hear 'em.
- Rule number one...
- Don't shit where you eat.
- That's right.
I catch you pinching logs in my cabin,
and it'll be your head mounted on the wall.
Rule number one. When you
gotta go, you go outside.
And bury your own damn awful.
Nobody wants to step in it.
- Alright. Rule number two?
- Rule number two.
You're only allowed to eat what you kill.
You don't kill, you go
hungry. Simple as that.
And, uh, rule number three?
Don't jerk off where I can see ya.
That's right, Trevor,
added that one just for you.
Is that camera the heaviest
thing you're gonna lift today?
Alright.
Okay, I've gotta get this...
...recorded.
This is not like any
bite I've ever had before.
It's been...
...no more than 30 or...
...or 35 minutes since I was...
...stung by whatever that was.
This is really...
...hard to believe.
Ugh!
Ugh...
Following procedure to...
...the letter, I've
made several attempts at
contacting Poison Control, but
low and behold, my radios don't work.
Both in my truck and here at the office,
this is what I get.
So, I'm not able to get through to anybody,
not Poison Control,
not Central station...
No one.
To further complicate things, I...
I feel terrible,
and I-I can see that I
look just as bad as I feel.
I've pretty much done as
much as I can here by myself.
Simple first aid has been administered,
but something tells me
that's not gonna cut it.
Last reading was...
103.6.
That's not good.
Well, that's...
That's scary.
I am in no...
Excuse me.
I am in no condition to...
...operate a vehicle, and it is a...
It is a good, um...
...2.5 miles of rough terrain
to get down the mountain on foot.
Uh, all I can think now
is to...
...try smoke flairs.
And hope that somebody sees them.
It's all I can do.
It's all I can...
Wow, this is bad.
Okay.
I'm gonna have to sign off now.
Alright.
Just a quick rundown.
I'm totally out here doin'
the Francis Ford Coppola thing.
Got a GoPro Fully High Definition
Camera mounted to my head,
modded by myself for the true huntsmen,
gives me the option of going infrared.
Got a second one of these bad boys,
it's filming me talking to you right now.
Now, it works for a good backup,
but I can also strap it
to my chest strap here.
It gives a different field of vision.
Usually like to shoot 60p, ultra-wide.
That guy.
Now.
This is a truly Trevor original.
Hi-Fi scope camera.
Best angle for the kill shots to be sure.
Trev!
You done playin' with yourself?
Duncan, grouchy old codger as always.
Nah, Dunk, I'm just waiting for you
to come over here and finish me off.
Goddamn kids, no respect today.
Always bustin' balls.
You ready for this, old man?
Shit, boy,
you supposed to be an astronaut?
Laugh now, 20 bucks says I get first kill.
- Now you're dreamin'.
- Camera ain't gonna lie, buddy.
Same can't be said for you, though.
Alright, the game is on, folks.
This...
This can't be real.
Range One to South Range dispatch.
Anyone with ears on?
Anyone at all hearing me?
If anyone can hear me,
this is Alice Sumner,
park ranger number f...
4102.
I've been infected with some kind of toxin.
In need of immediate medical assistance.
Anyone...
Please!
Alright, here we are, folks, huh!
Outside camping.
How are you, guys? Huh? Everybody good?
- Good.
- Doing good, buddy.
Everybody hanging out
by the campfire, yeah.
Ahh, we're just hanging out, you know.
Alright, alright, alright, hey, ladies,
spread the love to the last true
hippie among us here, please.
Now that's what's up. Pass the pipe.
Lookin' out for you, my man.
Wait, wait, wait, that's not my pipe.
Well, yeah, it's not your smoke either.
- This is pure Cali Hydro.
- That good!
That good stuff.
Hey!
What are you doing in here?
- We're about to light the fire.
- Oh, yeah?
You can light my fire. That's cheesy, huh?
- You are so stoned.
- Yes, I am high.
I am, that Cali shit
is way better than mine.
Wait. Wait, wait.
I came in here for something.
Yeah, I'm right here.
- Not gonna happen.
- What? Why?
Sorry, no lovin' for you.
Really? It-It'll only take a second.
Isn't that the sad truth.
- Come here.
- No, wait, wait, not here.
Why? We always make love up here.
Our friends are right outside.
No, they're probably in their tent doing
the same thing that I'm trying to do.
You know...
Hello!
I spilled bong juice all over myself.
- You're so wasted!
- Yeah, and I'm so hungry!
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
This one.
Aww! My baby looks sad.
You're so sexy.
- You like?
- Oh, I like? Are you kidding me? I love.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, you silly, silly girl.
I'm not about to put
on a show for everybody.
Oh, modest and virtuous woman.
That's right, so camera off.
What the fuck?
This is too weird.
Something scared off the whole damn forest.
Where'd Duncan get to?
Okay, so, uh...
I'm gonna show you somethin' here.
I... I've never seen anything like this.
What in God's name did this?
Dunk?
Hey!
Man, what you think this was?
Judging by the size of
these rib bones, I'd say this
used to be a 10 to 12 point buck.
Probably a two to three hundred pounder.
No fucking way, man.
Can you believe this?
I'm seein', but I ain't.
Pod thing growing on it?
Holy cow.
Uh, just a quick note,
I've been hunting and fishing
in these woods all my life.
I've seen hundreds of animal carcasses.
I ain't never seen anything like this.
Never.
Never even heard of anything like this.
I mean, do you know anything
that might've caused this?
No.
Too weird.
Spooky.
Yeah.
Trev?
Still out there?
I don't know,
but we're moving on.
Yeah.
Thought I'd flip on here for a minute.
Got maybe a couple hours of daylight left,
so I've started to get a move on here
'cause I do not wanna get
caught here after dark.
Goddammit, it's been one weird ass day.
Hey, Dunk?
Duncan, I think we should
head back to the cabin.
I don't get it.
Let's pack it in, man.
You hear that?
No, what?
Nothing.
Not so much as a bird chirping
or a fly buzzin'.
Alright, I really think we
should, we should head back.
Probably so.
It's getting spooky,
man, there's nothing here.
No.
- What?
- Something's here.
It's definitely close.
Hey! Dunk!
- Where you going, man?
- Shit!
What? Hey, where...
Dunk, come back here, man!
Goddammit!
Jesus Christ!
- Fuck!
- Save me, boy!
Oh, man, what the hell did this to you?!
You're crazy, old man,
I ain't goin' nowhere.
Get the hell outta here, Trevor!
Jesus fucking Christ!
Here.
Put the pressure on there!
I gotta get you out-a here,
buddy, but I can't risk movin' ya.
Breaker, Breaker, on emergency channel!
Is anybody out there with ears on?
Goddammit.
Alright, buddy,
here's the situation, I can't...
I can't get anyone on the radio, must be
some kind of interference or something.
I gotta get to better
ground, so you just...
You just sit tight.
Goddammit!
Okay, okay.
Wait, wait.
Okay, now just keep one hand there.
Just keep it firm.
And keep that hand...
Right there, don't worry, buddy.
Alright, alright, buddy.
You just sit tight, I'll be back.
I'll be back!
Calling on emergency channel!
Breaker, Breaker! C.H.... C.H. 9,
in need of immediate
medical assistance! Over.
Sorry, folks, we're having
some technical difficulties,
but anyhow... let's see
what people are doing.
- Careful with the camera.
- I am!
God. Why does he treat
me like I'm retarded?
I know how to do this shit.
Okay, maybe not.
Fuck it.
Hey, Kim!
Collin, your fiancé has, like,
a totally rockin' pair of tits.
- Don't I know it.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Just joking!
Excuse me?
Thanks, but that's not really true.
It is true. Oh, yeah.
- Thank God for push-up bras, right?
- My God, such modesty!
- Hey, watch out.
- Hey, whoa!
You're supposed... You're
supposed to toast the marshmallow!
You're flamin' it!
I don't think there's exactly a set of
rules when it comes to the mellow, right?
Hey, guys, who has a scary story?
Kimberly? Any scary stories?
Fuck no, girl, I don't
got no scary stories.
Well, you got a scary story, baby, come on.
Come up with something.
Come up with something... baby,
you wanna put down the camera?
Join us, grab a beer, relax, please.
You guys have no respect for tradition.
Honey, I love you,
but it's tradition when you're 12.
Whatever. Tough crowd.
Uh, Ryan, you got anymore of that weed?
- Yes! That's communal! Let's smoke.
- Yes... No! No, no, no.
- Collin, you're up.
- I'm up?
Yup, scary story, and go!
- You want a scary story?
- Yup, go.
- Alright, I got a scary story.
- Hit me!
I got a super fuckin'
scary story, you ready?
- Let's hear it.
- No, not really, at all.
Alright.
Well, there once was this
talented young filmmaker...
- Ooh!
- ...that decided rather than to
follow the path to fame and fortune,
decided to teach Intro to Cinema
at the local community college.
Oh, that is super fucked up.
- You wanted scary, right?
- We got it.
And what's worse is
that most of his students
took his class to avoid being
challenged by a real teacher.
You're a really good teacher.
He's my favorite teacher.
Right, 'cause that's how they met.
- Hot for teacher.
- Hot for student.
Yup.
- That is illegal, though, right?
- Totally.
Yeah, but my baby's a rebel.
No, no, no, no, she was
over-age when we met,
and we didn't start dating
until after she graduated...
...college.
Whatever, man, save it for the judge.
You know what?
I'm guilty. I'm guilty, guilty as charged,
for being in love with the most
amazing woman on the planet, right?
Right?
Aw, thank you, sweetheart.
You guys are so sweet.
See, I... I just threw up
in my mouth a little bit.
- Ryan, you suck.
- Hey!
I'm kidding, alright? It is sweet, it is.
To Kim and Collin,
good friends, good couple,
good for each other.
I love you guys.
Here, here!
- Righty, baby?
- Yes, sir.
Ooh, right, okay. That
would be my cue to exit.
Alright, since you guys are so lame,
I'm gonna make my own scary story.
Once, there was a... tree.
Holly, yo. G-Give me the camera.
Why?
Man, no fun for Holly.
Shit, shit! H-Holly,
Holly, did you see that?
What? No, where?
- No... You're freaking me out.
- Look!
Right there!
Oh, shit, Collin, let's go.
Let's get the fuck outta here.
- Ry!
- Ryan! Baby!
- There's something in the woods.
- We saw something.
- Sasquatch?
- No, no, honestly, I think we should probably go.
- It's a creature or something.
- What?
There was some crea...
It jumped into the tree!
What was... It was an animal.
I'm too drunk and tired for this.
Ryan, Ryan, we need to go!
There's no animal that moves like that.
I think you're spazzing
out just a little bit.
I'm not spazzing out! You
didn't see we what we saw!
- I need to know what you saw.
- I don't know!
- I'm not moving, everybody.
- Ryan, I don't know what it was!
Okay, well, exactly, you
don't know what it was!
That's why we're not gonna leave here!
If he's gonna be a shit, make
him think we're leaving him.
Collin, this is kind of crazy.
We're just supposed to
leave all of our stuff here?
Honey, please, I'll play back the
tape so you can see for yourself.
Turn, turn the engine on.
No, wait, wait, Collin!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, stop!
Stop! Are you fucking serious?
Fucking get in the car, man!
This is fucking crazy! We're
really gonna fucking leave now?
Just come on, man, I'm
not gonna tell you again.
Okay, fine!
We're gonna sit here and
leave a fire burning like this?
Ryan, you asshole, get in the fucking car!
Holly, goddammit, no!
Ryan. Fuck.
Ryan...
Fuck!
It's coming closer!
- Slow down!
- I can't!
Use the brakes!
- He's dead, alright?!
- Holly, he's in pieces!
What the fuck was that?!
- Brake!
- Oh, my God!
Watch out, watch out!
I've been every which way
on every fucking channel,
I can't find...
What the hell?
Duncan?
Shit...
What the hell?
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa, buddy.
Oh, God.
You guys okay? You guys okay?
Oh, Jesus...
Oh, God.
Jesus, Kimmy.
Baby, baby, you okay?
Oh, God.
Baby, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Holly.
- Are you alright?
- I killed that guy...
No, nobody's dead, nobody's dead.
- I'm gonna go get Ryan.
- Nobody's dead.
Holly, stay in the car, stay in the car!
Stay in the car!
No, you didn't kill him! You
didn't kill anybody, okay?
Everybody's fine.
Stay in the car!
I'm gonna go check on
him. Just say in the car.
Stay in the car. Okay.
Hey, buddy? Buddy!
You okay?
What the f... What the fuck?
Hey!
- Where's Holly?
- Holly?
Where's... oh, God, we
gotta get outta here!
Babe, we gotta get outta here!
- Where's the car, eh?
- Holly!
Okay, baby, it's gonna
get real bright, okay?
Baby, I know, I know. It's okay...
Where's... Holly?!
Honey, where's...
Holly, Holly?
Ryan...
- Oh, we just left him...
- I know, I know, there was nothing...
Shut the fuck up! We just left him!
- Holly, there was nothing we could do, okay?!
- We have to go back!
There's no way he made it, okay?
- Whatever it was, it just tore him up.
- Shut up, shut up.
Hey, hey, hey, listen.
No! No!
Kimmy...
Baby, I know, just hold
still, okay? Please.
We gotta get help, we gotta get help.
Holly.
Try mine, try mine.
- G-Gotta go back and get Ryan.
- Anything?
Well, we can't stay here! Kim!
Holly, we gotta get her outta here.
Holly, we gotta get her outta here, okay?
Just help me with Kim for now.
We gotta move, baby, okay?
Fuck!
Holly, I can really use your help, okay?
Fuck, Holly! Help me!
Christ, Dunk, where the hell are ya, buddy?
Can anybody hear me?
Anybody out there?
Please!
Motherfucker! Mother fuck you!
You piece of fucking shit! Goddammit!
Oh, fuck.
Oh, fuck...
That was really smart, Trevor.
That's really fucking, that's
really gonna help your situation.
Duncan!
Shine the light over there.
- It's some sort of cabin.
- It's a house!
Come on, baby, just a little bit further.
Hope they have a phone and hope it works.
It's open.
Hello?
Hello? Anybody?
Hey, we need help!
Hello?
Okay, just rest, okay?
Alright. Okay.
- Do you hear that?
- What, baby? There's nothing.
- There's something scratching.
- Baby, I didn't hear anything.
- Okay?
- No, baby, don't.
Collin! Come up here! Come on!
- I'll be right back, okay?
- Did you hear that?
Just rest.
Collin? Collin, over here! Hurry!
You know how to work one of these?
How the fuck should I know?
- I've never even seen one before.
- Okay, well, it can't be hard.
Okay... Hello?
Hello? Can anybody hear me?
Anyone copy?
- Fucking thing doesn't even work.
- What? It's on, right?
It's on... I-I don't...
Try another knob. Try... get the volume.
Try the volume.
Anybody copy?
What's that?
T-Try another channel.
Try another channel!
Okay.
It's the same weird static
on every one of these.
I've never even heard of that before.
Holly, holy shit, look at this.
What the hell is that?
Are you crazy?! No!
Don't open that, Collin!
Collin!
Oh, God!
Kim, Kim, Kim!
Come on, come on!
Go, go!
Hurry up! Go, Kim, go, Kim! Go!
So, been a while since
we last saw each other.
I don't know why, but...
I just can't seem to get my bearings right.
I just...
What was that?
What the hell?! Shit!
Ahh! Oh, Goddammit!
I can't move!
I can't feel nothing!
My God!
- God, Holly, wait up!
- Keep up, guys!
She's got a concussion, alright?!
We can barely keep up. I need a break, too!
We've gotta stay together.
We gotta get back to the road.
How do you know where the road is?!
Collin, I don't know. I know
we just need to get back.
Kim!
Collin!
Hey! Hey!
Kim, is she... is she...
I don't know...
I don't know.
I can't... I can't find her.
She's gone!
She's fucking gone!
Kim!
Look, we're gonna find her,
we're gonna find her, just...
Kimmy!
Collin!
Collin, wait up!
Okay.
Shit.
Oh, shit.
It's quiet.
It's too quiet.
No way up.
No way down.
I've lost my fucking center of gravity.
Fuck, where the hell
did that old man get to?
Duncan!
Come on out now!
Come on out, fun's over!
I ain't seen him for hours, I...
You'll see him, he's...
He thinks it's fucking
funny to hide from me.
Fucking prick.
Ahh!
Okay, see, it goes like this.
Alright?
Alright, then they talk
to each other, like this.
Maybe it's like... this.
Fuck!
Nah, it's all fucking wrong.
It's all fucking wrong.
Just gotta start over,
just fucking start over.
And this time, you don't
get to fucking watch!
Kim?
Collin?
Stay calm.
- Kim?
- Holly?
Collin! You scared the shit outta me!
There's something not right here.
That's why I can't focus.
Wait, I hear it for a
second, and then it's gone.
What are you hearing?
I can't hear anything!
- Any sign of Kim?
- Shh, shh, shh.
Listen, did you hear that?
Listen!
I can't hear shit! C-Collin, come on.
Come on, you're freaking me out.
No! Collin!
Right here.
- They've come for their friend.
- Who's co...
Collin! No, come back here! Come back!
No, you can't leave me here, Collin!
Collin!
Collin? Where'd you go?
Collin?
Where'd you go?
This is zero hour for me.
I'm being tested.
My ring of fire.
I pass, and I live.
I fail...
Well, we've seen what this thing can do.
It's like the...
...Spartans,
Apaches,
and the Samurai
all rolled into one.
Everything...
My whole life...
...comes down to this moment right here,
right now.
Kill or be fucking killed.
Law of the jungle.
Simple as that.
Alright.
Hunts on, fuckers!
Okay, okay.
It's gonna be fine.
I'm gonna find a way out.
Oh, my God! A trailer!
Hello?
Hello!
Someone there?
That's weird.
One moment I'm hot. Another
one, I'm freezing cold.
The clock on my phone says 4:45,
so just another hour or so
until the sun should be start...
coming up..
I have no food and no water.
I'm so tired.
I'm so...
...thirsty.
It was...
It was more than three hours
ago since I last saw Collin.
I have this horrible feeling...
...like maybe the sun will
never come up, you know?
Whatever that thing was that attacked us...
Whatever... I can't...
I can't...
God.
My mind's real foggy.
It's like
I can't remember what I was
just thinking a second ago.
Ryan...
Oh, Ryan!
I love you.
I don't think I realized that until
now, but I really fucking love you.
If anybody...
...would find this...
Whatever happens...
To my Mom and Dad,
James and Margaret Powell
on thirty-five...
Fuck.
Thirty-five, twenty-five
East Pine Lane,
Jeffersonville, New York.
I love you both,
so, so much.
To Ryan's mom and stepdad...
To Kim and Collin's family...
I wish I could explain what's going on.
I wish I know something... I
can't, I can't, I don't know.
God said, "Let us make man in our image,
after our likeness,
and let him have dominion
over the fish of the sea,
and over the fowl of the air,
and over the cattle,
and over all the earth,
and over every creeping thing
that creepeth upon the earth."
Alright, now.
What I got to show you now is
something truly illuminating.
I know it don't look like much,
but this here...
...is a blood trail.
yeah, this here ain't nothing good.
Not natural.
Not bright like it should be.
It's black.
Like the blood from the heart,
but even darker still.
Dark blood of a dark prey.
You bring hell to me, demon,
and I'll bring it right back at
ya, you fucking night stalker.
I can hear you breathe.
I can hear your thoughts.
I'm inside you!
Look what we got here.
More tell-tells?
Oh, damn, you're gushin'
like a sieve, ain't ya, boy.
Whoa!
You're not who I'm lookin' for.
Hey, hey, hey there,
you don't look so mean.
You're alive, ain't you?
Can you talk?
What?
Damn it, you tryin' to say something?
What, what does that even fuckin' mean?
Hey!
No more pictures, you start talking!
What're you doing?! Ahh! Stop it!
Fucking stop it!
As you can see,
the sun is finally up.
I'm so thirsty.
That was my first priority,
gotta find some water.
I gotta find a way back home.
Collin!
Collin! Collin!
Hey.
Collin?
I need you to repeat what
you just said to me, okay?
Please, Collin.
You said you know something,
you-you been somewhere.
You know what's been going on here.
- You need to tell me!
- There was an accident.
What-What accident?
It wasn't supposed to happen.
None of this.
I... I don't understand.
I've seen things.
They told me things.
What... Who told you?
An accident.
Like a nuclear meltdown of the cosmos,
an outbreak.
But it's okay.
I'm safe now.
What? How?
They can't hurt me.
But they can still hurt you.
Gunshots!
They seem to be coming...
coming form there.
Oh, my God, whoever it
is, at least it's human.
Hello? Hey!
Hey, whoever you are, we need help!
Wait, Collin! Wait!
Help us!
Come on, fucker! Come out and play!
Plenty more where that came from!
Goddammit, where are you?!
Fuckers are everywhere!
Gotta get to better ground!
Oh, what have we here?
There ya are.
Yeah, ya thirsty?
Everybody gets thirsty.
God damn.
Another quiet one?
Shit, girl, I was sure you were one of 'em.
Hey, don't look at me like that.
Come on, get up! I-I didn't mean it!
Shit, come on!
You had the right idea, though.
That you, Duncan?!
Hey.
Hey!
Hey, I'm talkin' to you!
Hey, look, man, uh, I-I thought
I was the only one out here.
I'm pretty sure I just
iced your girlfriend.
It was a mistake. I didn't, I didn't...
What're you lookin' at
me like that for, huh?
Huh?!
Hell with you then.
Doctor Margo Thompson here with
a quick rundown of what we know.
We're still a long way from
making sense of all this.
I'm sending everything to
you on a coded frequency.
Got multiple enemies!
With all the variables that
we were dealing with here,
it seemed that containment
was our first priority.
What's even more of a puzzle
is our one known survivor.
A man who, for unexplained reasons,
has escaped contamination,
physically at least.
Psychological damage was extensive,
which makes communication a real challenge.
Today is Wednesday, the
fifth of June, 2014.
I'm here with Subject
31, Collin Dean Barstow.
Subject has been given
400 milligrams of Haldol
to stabilize his behavior.
He appears removed, but
has been more responsive
than in our previous attempts
to conduct this interview.
Mr. Barstow?
Collin?
I would really like you to
tell me what you remember.
What you remember?
Yes.
Anything? Anything at all?
Collin, I need to know what you saw.
Under hypnosis, you
mentioned to Dr. Brenner...
quite an amazing story.
You told her that, after your
friends and you were exposed,
that you were taken captive.
And that you were even able to
establish a method of communication
with those who abducted you.
That you were taken
out of the forest
and onto some kind of craft.
I said that?
I have a recording of it right here.
What about these?
Collin, can you tell me
about these drawings?
These symbols here?
My drawings...
Right.
What do they mean to you?
Are they representative
of something that you saw?
I'm gonna play you something here,
and I need you to
tell me what it means.
Please, Collin,
you said you know something.
You-You been somewhere.
You know what's been going on here.
- You need to tell me!
- There was an accident.
Wh-What accident?
It wasn't supposed to happen.
None of this.
I... I don't understand.
I've seen things.
They told me things.
What... Who told you?
And accident.
Like a nuclear meltdown of the cosmos,
an outbreak.
But it's okay.
I'm safe now.
What? How?
They can't hurt me.
Do you remember saying that?
Can you tell me what that means?
Why you?
What was it that made you safe?
Hey.
Come on now.
You gotta give me something here.
They wanted to...
Go on.
They wanted to try and find it.
To stop it.
Don't stop, Collin.
You're doing great.
Collin? Come on. Come
back to me, buddy.
Collin?
Let's try something else.
Hey, Kimmy!
Time to wake up. Morning, baby.
Morning, hey.
What are you doing?
I'm watching you.
Am I totally creeping you out or what?
Pervert.
How long have you been filming me?
I don't know, 30, 40 minutes? Maybe less.
- So creepy.
- Uh-huh.
Hey, someone's camera-shy. Come on, baby.
Give it to me.
What? Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Give it.
Kimmy...
Yes, let's start with Kimberly.
What happened to her?
I know this is hard, Collin.
It's also really important
that you tell me everything.
I need you to remember.
We need to go back to
that place in the forest.
Collin, what can you remember?
Everything.
Okay...
Hey, Kimmy?
Baby, can you come here for a sec?
- Yeah?
- Hey, sexy.
Who me?
Yeah, you.
Who else would I be talking about?
I don't know, maybe one of those little
freshmen that I always see you drooling over.
Aw, what? No.
Come on, you...
They've gotta know you
give out extra credit
- to the girl with the sweetest ass.
- Whatever!
- Am I right?
- You're crazy.
Really?
Yeah, you're crazy to think that I
would ever be checking out any other girl.
Oh, that's weird. I'm sorry.
What now?
There's something digging into my back.
Ow.
- Can you... Can you reach around...
- What is it?
I don't know what it
is. It's digging into me.
Is it a freshman?
I'm serious! I'm serious!
It's not. It's weird.
It's weird?
Ow.
And... Oh, I think you found it.
Wonder what that could be, huh?
Hey.
Kim?
- Well?
Come on, you're killing me.
This is how you ask?
Marry me.
Can I take that as a yes?
Yes!
Yeah?
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
You wanna see some crazy shit?
I'll show you some crazy shit.
That's some crazy shit.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com