## ["Nutcracker Suite"]
[mews]
Mm.
Mm, Linus.
What time is it, sugar?
Oh, shit!
## [rock]
Shit!
Shit.
Whoa! Shit.
Ow!
Shit, shit,
shitty, shit.
Oh, shit.
Poop.
Morning, George.
Morning, Mags.
I've been watching it
all night for you.
Thanks.
You're the best.
Later, gator.
While, crocodile.
# Lost inside
this angeltown #
# Lost like I could
not be found #
# No connections
of the heart #
# Love was glass
that broke apart #
# Give me faith in dreams #
# And someone to hold #
# Give me love 'cause
I'm out here in the cold #
# There are no secrets #
# No angels at my door #
Morning, Angus.
Hey, Mags.
I'll take the usual.
See you later.
# On a steeltown boulevard #
# Life's a promise
that doesn't last #
# Children come
and are gone so fast #
# So give me faith in love #
# Baby, tonight #
# Give me arms to hold you #
# Here so tight #
# There are no secrets #
# No angels at my door #
# And, oh... #
# When you touch my hand #
# I fall from grace #
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Come again.
[chuckling]
I've got a tardy treat.
You know, Mags,
if you'd learn how
to set an alarm clock,
you wouldn't have to
keep buttering me up.
But I like you buttery.
You know how I love
dairy products.
Ooh, look, Lettie.
I may have already
won $10 million.
Heh!
I've always found
Ed McMahon sexy.
Big hunk of a man.
[growling]
Okay, mildly disturbing.
Oh, great.
Another wedding
invitation.
I'm so not buying another
bridesmaid's dress.
Oh, good.
Jerry Logan.
Marrying
some supermodel,
no doubt.
I dated a Jerry Logan once.
Can't be the same one.
Nah.
So, you going?
Hell, no.
I mean, heck, no.
[yawns loudly]
Up all night
writing again?
You know, for a girl
who doesn't believe in love,
you sure write
a lot of fairy tales.
They're not fairy tales.
They're... fiction.
Which, okay, may include
an occasional prince
or damsel in distress,
but there's no fairies
in any of them.
That's just ridiculous.
Well, just remember
what Lettie says.
Paper can't love you back.
Love, schmove.
Besides, I'm a career-minded,
independent woman, remember?
I've no time for love.
Yeah, well,
this career-minded,
independent woman
is going to go home
and fix some breakfast
for her man.
Oh, tell Charlie
I'll be over
for poker on Tuesday.
And this time,
bringing my own cards.
Oh, you've got
to let Charlie cheat.
It's the only
reason he plays.
[bells tinkling]
## [rock]
# Take the last train
to Clarksville #
# And I'll meet you
at the station #
# You can be there by 4:30 #
# 'Cause I made
your reservation #
# Don't be slow #
# Oh, no, no, no #
# 'Cause I'm leavin'
in the morning #
[clock ticking]
# And I must
see you again #
[rings bell]
# We'll have one more
night together #
# 'Til the morning
brings my train #
# And I must go #
# Oh, no, no, no #
# And I don't know
if I'm ever coming home #
# Take the last train
to Clarksville #
# I'll be waiting
at the station #
# We'll have time
for coffee flavored kisses #
# And a bit of conversation #
# Oh... #
# Oh, no, no, no #
# Take the last train
to Clarksville #
I wish...
I wish for something.
Anything.
Ta-da.
All right,
this is just stupid.
[typing]
[Maggie narrating]
"The wind whipped
hard and strong
"along the jagged coastline.
"Suddenly, out of
seemingly nowhere,
"Prince Charming appears
"and sweeps the fair maiden
he loves so completely
"into his arms
and onto the back
"of his trustworthy steed.
They look deep into
each other's eyes and..."
## [country]
# She's 99 pounds
of dynamite #
# And, oh,
what a lovely sight #
# When she kisses
and holds me tight #
# She's like 99 pounds
of dynamite #
# A real package of TNT #
# When she squeezes
with all her might #
# She's like 99 pounds
of dynamite #
# I want the world to know
I love my baby so #
Hi.
Are you looking
for something?
A book.
[laughing]
Right, a book.
Well, you've come
to the right place.
[laughs]
Uh... we do actually
usually keep them
on the bookshelves, so...
Right!
[phone ringing]
The Book Nook.
How can I help you?
Magpie.
[Maggie]
Hey, sweet petite.
How's married life?
Oh, it's grand, Mags.
You should really try it.
Which brings me
to the reason I'm calling.
Okay, great segue.
And the answer is "no".
Six-foot...
sandy-blond,
the kind of butt
that fills out jeans,
but isn't bigger
than yours,
and get this, lawyer.
Okay, not a butt girl
and I'm not dating,
remember?
Spinster.
That's all I'm saying.
First of all,
this is not 1687
and we're not
in a Jane Austen novel.
And besides, working
on my best book yet.
This is the one.
[scoffs]
What one?
The one you're actually
going to let people read?
going to send to a publisher?
Okay, hangin' up now.
Don't be mad.
Oh, I'm officially mad.
How mad?
About a 72-hour mad.
Okay. I'll call you Friday.
X.O.
[rings bell]
Did you find what
you were looking for?
By golly, I did!
A first edition
of Great Expectations.
By golly, I didn't
know we had one.
[laughs]
Oh.
Oh, there's no price
in here and--
You know what?
We have this policy--
Ring me up
when you sort it out!
Wait!
I don't have your number!
## [rock]
# Yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah #
# I used to think
maybe you love me #
# Now, baby, I'm sure #
# And I just can't
wait till the day #
# When you knock
on my door #
[Man]
Boo.
You suck.
[Woman]
Boo!
[blowing raspberries]
For my next trick
I need a volunteer.
Oh!
[Magician]
Ah, yes.
You, young lady.
Please.
Hey, take your top off.
# I'm walkin' on sunshine #
# Whoa #
# And don't it feel good? #
# Hey #
# All right, now #
# And don't it feel good? #
# Walkin' on sunshine #
# I used to think
maybe you love me #
# Now I know
that it's true #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah #
# But I just can't
spend my whole life #
# Just a-waitin' for you #
You're not late.
What? I have to be late
to bring a pretty lady
some flowers?
Oh, well...
Keep 'em coming.
Don't stop there.
[giggling]
[baby talk]
You're so cute.
Mwah!
What's with you?
Oh, please tell me
you met a man.
Oh, I met a man,
all right.
Thank you, Jesus!
He wore a cape
and a top hat
and he sawed me
in half.
Is that some kind
of code for sex?
No, silly.
I went to a magic show
last night.
And you met a man there?
No man, just magic.
Well, once you find
real magic...
pulling bunnies out of hats
isn't going to cut it anymore.
Love, schmove.
Blueberry pie today.
Yummy.
You've got
to be kidding me.
[Man, radio]
This is SFO control.
Traffic continuing
toward east.
[Maggie]
Wow...
This is so cool!
[Man]
Isn't it glorious?
[Maggie]
It's amazing.
Hey, Gillis.
[humming]
Hey, hey.
Oh, Forelli!
The Magster.
How's it goin'?
You're lookin' good.
Hey, come on.
You hungry?
I bet you're starving.
Come over.
I made you lasagna,
your favorite
with the sausage.
Come on.
Ooh, yummies!
I have work to do,
though.
Typie, typie.
All work and no play.
All right,
I'll bring it over
in a Tupperware,
but, hey,
I want it back.
Don't forget.
I love those little guys.
Uh, and Mags?
Um, Maggie, uh...
I have to, uh--
You see, the thing is--
Wait.
You don't have to say
I'm late with the rent again.
Sorry.
I'll have it by Tuesday.
Promise.
Say no more, Magpie.
I'll go get you
that lasagna.
You're the best!
I don't know about that.
[singing]
Not today, Angus.
Hi!
It's your day off,
remember?
I know. I'm just
looking for something.
What are you
looking for, silly.
Well, it's-- it's a book,
but it's not really a book.
It's kind of like
what should be inside it
if-- if the lamp
was real.
Oh, you're just
talking crazy.
[sighs]
I mean, it's got
to be here, right?
You're supposed to get
three wishes, not two.
Wishes?
Have you seen that copy
of Great Expectations?
Oddly enough,
someone bought it
this morning.
Even odder, I didn't
even know we had it.
That had my
third wish in it.
What are you
talking about?
Well, the other day,
I was bored out of my wit,
so I kind of
rubbed this lamp
and I made a wish.
Lamp?
It sort of came true
and I got this
magic show ticket
and then I got to go
on an airplane ride.
Airplane?
And you know how much
I love magic and I've
always wanted to fly.
It was all in this
little book?
Yeah.
It was magic.
Magic?
Yeah... magic.
I don't know.
I just thought maybe...
...somebody up there
was listening
and thought I deserved
a little magic in my life.
You know?
Maybe so, dear.
[chuckling]
Oh, maybe so.
I hope your kids
know how lucky they are.
Not those devil children.
Mags, I've told you.
Charlie and I
have adopted you.
Yeah.
Where were you
when I was four?
Everything you
went through as a child
has made you
the strong girl
you are today.
Yeah.
Strong as an ox.
It just would have
been nice to have
a mom around to,
I don't know...
make me an Easter basket
or something.
Just call me
Little Orphan Maggie.
[chuckles softly]
I'm going to go.
Mags?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Strong... ox. See?
I'll see you
in the morning.
[sighs]
Oh, um, excuse me.
I bought this book
yesterday.
Yeah, we don't take returns.
Um, no, actually,
I didn't wish to return it.
I just wanted to--
You just what?
Don't test my patience.
Not today.
Excuse me,
but are you always
this rude, Ms. Malone?
Do I know you?
No.
Well, then,
how do you know my name?
Are you a Dickens fan?
What?
I mean, that's a little
cryptic, isn't it?
Oh, is that some sort
of British expression for--
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I don't know what
you're getting at, Mister,
but if that's some
sort of creepy,
weird sexual metaphor,
I'm not having it.
Who are you?
Well, I'm just
a, uh, messenger,
for lack of a better word.
Have you read this book?
Well, yeah.
I mean, not that
exact copy, but, yeah.
Yes, well,
you have a great deal
in common with Pip.
All right,
again with the cryptic.
Now you're just
getting on my nerves.
What in the Sam Hill
are you talking about?
You, Maggie Malone,
have a benefactor.
A what-efactor?
A benefactor.
Oh.
This is like
one of those--
those-- those setup,
joke thingies, right?
And-- and, oh, my God!
You're that
Jamie Kennedy guy
in disguise, right?
Am I being exed
right now?
Oh, my God,
where's the camera?
Um, no, no.
Ms. Malone, this is, uh--
This is very real.
All right.
Do I look like
I just fell off
a turnip truck to you?
I'm so sorry,
I don't follow.
I mean, do I look
like I have "sucker"
tattooed on my forehead?
Hmm?
Not unless it's written
very small.
I mean, do I seem
like an idiot to you?
Oh, idiot! Yes.
Um, no! Um--
Look, madam, I'm simply
trying to do my job.
There's really no need
for you to become hostile.
Doing your job, huh?
[chuckles]
Isn't, like, Santa Claus
or the Tooth Fairy upset
about you honing in
on their territory?
What?
[goofy laugh]
Oh! Oh, I see.
An attempt at humor.
No, I am actually
legal counsel
for your benefactor.
Okay.
Let say...
hypothetically,
that I believe you,
which I don't.
What would happen?
Well, uh, you get
to have anything
your heart desires.
Yeah.
Crazy talk.
Not buying it.
Well, those are the rules.
If you obtain the knowledge
of the identity
of your benefactor,
you will forfeit everything.
Is this the third wish.
I'm sorry. Wish?
Uh... nothing.
I'm just talking
to myself.
I do that.
Well, that sounds like
a matter for your therapist.
I'll leave you now
to ponder this
turn of events,
but as instructed,
I will be at your
home at 7 p.m.
to give you
a glimpse of your...
future life.
Hmm. Wrong Dickens book.
Another attempt at humor.
Yes. Jolly good.
All right.
Just hold on there,
four-eyes.
You know, you-- you can't
just waltz in off the street
and throw out some--
some fancy-schmancy words
with that phony
accent of yours
and expect anybody
in their right mind
to believe you, Mr...
Brandon.
Yeah, like that's
your real name.
I mean, how stupid
do you think I am?
Fine! Fine, Ms. Malone.
I will go back
to my employer
and tell him that
you simply weren't
interested in his offer
to make you incredibly rich.
Have a nice day.
Yeah, you do that.
Okay, let's not be hasty.
Oh, and...
wear something formal.
Wait!
You know where I live?
I mean, that's just
ridiculous, right?
What is all this nonsense?
I mean, he's just
getting my hopes up
in some mysterious
benefactor?
I mean, who in the Sam Hill
does he think he is?
Right, Linus?
Right?
[mews]
But I'm just going
to get ready, you know?
Just get ready.
Just in case--
Just in case it's not
all some big hoax.
Formal. Something formal.
Do I own "formal"?
What do you think,
Linus? Hmm?
[meows]
Oh, you're really
no help at all, are ya?
You've got
to be joking.
[groans, sighs]
Well, of course they
don't have a lift. No.
[sighs]
I'll just take the stairs.
[gasps]
[groans]
I've never seen
so many steps
in my life.
She couldn't live
in a bungalow.
[sighs]
Wow, you actually
showed up.
[breathing heavily]
Is this okay?
You look--
You look lovely.
Lovely is good.
I'll take lovely.
The-- The dress is very, uh--
Bridesmaid chic?
Yeah, I know.
I'm a trend-setter.
It's what I do.
[laughs]
[sighs]
Huh.
Not exactly the kind of car
I expected you to drive.
It's kinda like
the, uh, Batmobile.
Not that you don't bear
a striking resemblance
to Bruce Wayne.
Sorry, I have no idea
who this Wayne character
is, but uh--
The car doesn't suit me
because it's not mine.
It's yours.
[sighs]
Oh!
[whimpering]
Uh-huh.
Brandon, George.
George, Brandon.
Oh.
Hi!
Hello.
How are ya?
Nice to meet you.
[chuckling]
You hurt her, I'll kill ya.
I'm quite sure you would.
[laughing]
Bye!
Bye-bye, sweetheart.
[starting engine]
You kids have
a good time.
Yeah.
## [classical piano]
Do you think we could
go somewhere else?
Get a burger
or something?
Though the possibility
of mad cow disease
is appealing,
the answer is no;
these were my instructions.
Okay, just for the record,
I don't exactly fit in here.
Don't be ridiculous.
The only thing that
fits in here is money.
And now you have it!
Good evening.
Hi.
Um, your best table
for the special young lady.
Ah, yes. She's
obviously quite special.
Right this way.
[flaps]
[screams, laughs]
Sorry.
Hmm.
I'll send over
the sommelier, sir.
Excellent.
Is that the French
word for menu?
Uh, no, it's
the wine steward.
Right.
[chuckles]
Those "sawmilliaires"
sure come in handy.
Bonsoir, monsieur
et madame.
Bonsoir.
Hi.
Oh. I won't be
needing these.
Just thought I'd save
the dishwasher some work.
[normal American accent]
I'll be back to tell you
the specials.
What?
Well, you're, um--
[clearing throat]
You're quite odd.
Yeah?
Look who's talking,
Mr. Stiff Stiffy
Stiff Guy.
Are you quite finished?
Yeah, pretty much.
Look, just for the record,
I'm not exactly thrilled
with being your attendant.
It's not in my
job description,
so why don't we just
try and get through this
as quickly
and cordially as possible?
Cordially?
Sorry, I couldn't
help myself.
Do you think
I could at least know
a little something
about this
mysterious benefactor?
I mean, seriously,
the curiosity's kinda
killing me here.
No.
Come on!
Just a little hint?
A small, little,
miniscule--
I realize that you can't
relate, Miss Malone,
but I follow the rules.
"The rules," do you?
[laughs]
I'm sure you follow
"the rules," to a "T",
don't you, Brandon?
Pip-pip. Cheerio.
Jully good.
Excuse me, but I take
my job very seriously.
Besides, I would be dismissed
immediately if I said
the slightest thing
to you about my employer.
So, yes.
I follow the rules.
Rules, schmules.
Ah, biting wit.
Hmm.
That waiter
wasn't really French.
[engine revving]
[brakes screeching]
[turns off ignition]
Sorry.
I probably should have
warned you
that I've never actually
driven a real car.
Only the simulated kind
in Driver's Ed.
Oh, really.
I would never have guessed.
[chuckles]
Ow!
Um, I just--
I just wanted
to say thanks.
I just-- I had the--
[sighs]
I had the time
of my life.
And I owe it
all to you.
Well, thanks.
[laughs]
Get it?
Uh--
Oh, my God. Don't
tell me you've never
seen Dirty Dancing.
I--
Okay. How about
The Breakfast Club?
Come on.
You have to have seen
Footloose, right?
Afraid not.
"There is a time to laugh,
and a time to cry,
and oh, yes, there is
a time to dance."
Well, that sounds
quite inspirational.
Oh, you mock, because
you've never witnessed
the power of Kevin Bacon
in a pair of Levi's.
[chuckles]
Kevin Bacon?
Mm-hmm.
Come on. That's not
his real name.
No! Really?
Well, what's his
middle name? "Eggs 'n'?"
Eggs 'n' bacon.
Mm-hmm.
Wait a minute.
[coughs]
Pardon that outburst.
Mm-hmm.
There you go.
Wait, no. I told you.
This is your car.
What are you, insane?
I can't drive this thing.
I'm not gonna argue that.
Good. Pick me up
at 9:20.
Oh, well, actually,
I really can't. More, I--
Oh, and be on time.
I never like to be late.
Right.
Fine, splendid.
Uh, see you
tomorrow, then.
Typical nutty American.
Always wanting everything
for themselves.
It doesn't matter
that I've got a busy day.
[muttering]
[starts engine]
[continues chattering]
[Man]
How did it go?
Did she enjoy herself?
Oh, yes, well,
she seemed to, sir.
I must say, she's rather
a different sort.
Very unimpressed
by monetary things.
[laughs]
She's unimpressed
by $150,000 vehicles?
Well, yes, sir.
And I must add, she
befriends street people.
Street people?
Yes, sir.
Big, black ones.
I'm terribly sorry, sir,
but this really is
quite irregular.
My other duties for you
are far more important--
More important than what?
My priorities?
Or yours?
Sir, she's rude.
She's ill-mannered.
Enough!
You have your instructions.
Yes, sir.
[door opens, closes]
## [classical orchestra]
Mornin', George.
Oh, you're early.
Well, she's all ready
for you, huh?
No. Gettin' a ride today.
Ah.
Later, gator.
While, crocodile.
Him. I should have known.
Hanging with the homeless?
Don't be mean.
George is my friend.
Quite right.
Terribly sorry.
[sighs, clears throat]
Okay. Come on.
Let's go.
I don't like to be late.
Yes, I know.
You do realize you can quit
this bookstore nonsense now?
Don't be ridiculous.
Lettie needs me.
Fair enough.
But you must leave
early today.
[British accent]
Why must I, sir?
Please, tell me why?
[laughs]
That is uncanny.
Your accent's remarkable.
You could be
from my home town.
Really?
No.
[starts engine]
Thanks for the ride.
Ooh-whee,
what have we here?
A man
dropping you off?
A rich man, at that.
Not how it looks.
It looks pretty
good to me.
Well, it is pretty good.
But not in the way
you're thinking,
gutter mind.
He works for
my benefactor.
Your what-afactor?
Okay, brace yourself.
Do you remember the wishes?
Yeah, well, it turns out
that I have, for all
intents and purposes,
a fairy godmother,
or fairy godfather,
who wants to make
all my wishes come true.
Wow, that
sounds even weirder
saying it out loud.
All those Hail Marys
paid off.
I never thought
that'd work.
But that young man
is not your young man.
No, he's just
doing his job.
But wow. You barely
missed a beat.
This kinda stuff happen
every day in your world?
I believe
in miracles, honey.
Lettie, do you believe
that wishes can come true?
Well, I believe in miracles,
so sure I believe
wishes can come true.
I've always believed.
I think I'm starting
to believe, too.
I wish-- I wish--
I wish for
the afternoon off.
Oh, sh--
[laughing]
## [country]
Good afternoon.
We would like some help
with this
young lady's attire.
She has a very important
appointment this afternoon,
for which she must look--
Reasonably presentable?
Actually, I was going
to say, more beautiful
than she already does.
Why, of course.
I'll start pulling
some things in her size.
Good.
What are you?
About a size 26?
Actually, about a four.
European sizes, darling.
Right.
[chuckles]
That metric system
gets me every time.
Can we please leave?
Leave? Why?
I thought girls
loved shopping.
They don't like me, Brandon.
They're staring at me.
[sighs]
Well, that's because
you're stunning.
Thanks.
You're a liar,
but thanks.
[sighs]
Okay. Here we are.
Thank you.
Oh, wait.
Isn't this where I do that
"clothes-trying-on" montage
and that Roy Orbison song
plays in the background?
Get it?
Oh, just forget it.
## [country]
Thanks for
lettin' me get the hat.
Lettie's gonna love it.
Well, it's your money.
Right.
So, what next?
Right this way, madam.
This madam's pantyhose
are riding up.
Charming.
[dings]
Good afternoon.
May I help you
and the lovely lady?
Yes, we would like
to open an account
for a Miss Maggie Malone.
[softly]
That's me.
Maggie. That's lovely name.
Oh, thanks.
My friends call me Mags.
Good to meet ya.
Firm handshake.
Now just exactly
what kind of an account
would you like to open today?
A very large one.
Ah, my favorite.
[chuckles]
Please.
Can I have one of these?
Help yourself.
Now. Just exactly
how large an account
would you like to open?
Five million dollars.
[spits out pen]
Bye, Felix.
So, I'm a five
"millionairess," huh?
Ooh.
Pretty cool.
It was so nice of him
to let me have
all these pens.
Wow, these little purses
are just useless.
You're genuinely
more excited
about the pens
than the money, aren't you?
Guess I'm just a simple girl
with simple tastes.
Well, whoever told you
you were simple lied.
Lettie says
that I'm special.
And not like "I ride on
the short bus" special.
"The short bus."
I presume that's
another American thing.
Yes, it is.
Stick with me, kid.
I'll teach you all
you need to know about
smart-ass Americans.
Truly, you are too kind.
Out of order again.
Shocker!
## ['80s Rock]
[Woman]
Hey. Wait. Look.
I'm Debbie Gibson.
[laughing]
[Woman #2]
Debbie, meet Culture Club.
Oh, I love them.
The ruby slippers.
"There's no place like home."
[Woman #3]
It's frightening. Look at this
with the price tag still on it.
What is she thinking?
Not now. Girls,
she needs our help.
It's wrong.
Uh, hello? Oh,
who's calling? Maggie!
The '80s are on the phone.
They want their
entire collection back.
Ha, ha, ha.
Very funny.
Wow, Mags.
You look great.
Love your shoes,
and the hat!
You could really use
an amber scarf to offset
the whole thing,
but--
Yeah. Could you take a moment
from doing running commentary
on my wardrobe to tell me
what in the Sam Hill
is goin' on here?
We're going through
your clothes.
Yeah, I see that.
Why?
This is
an intervention.
A what?
What exactly are
you all saving me from?
Spinsterhood.
Ugh, again with
that archaic word.
What prompted you all
on this particular night
to leave your happily-married
husbands at home,
where you should be doing,
you know, happily-married
things together,
to come and
save your pathetic,
poorly-dressed friend.
Lettie called, and we don't
think you're pathetic.
Maybe a little.
And what, pray tell,
did Lettie have to say?
That some hottie rich guy
is interested in you,
and you're dissing him.
"Dissing him"?
What are you,
a rap star now?
Okay, whatever.
Blowing him off.
Kicking him to the curb.
Okay, did she include
the part about the fact that
he's not even remotely
interested, and that
it's just business?
Come on, Mags.
Tell us the gory details.
Uh, no.
Okay, secretive.
Can we at least discuss your
excessive overall collection?
Uh, please.
Door number two.
And, behind door number one,
all the shoes have
rubber soles, or--
have been dyed
to match taffeta.
You "smarty-pantses" will
be happy to know that
I went shopping today.
Is "pantses" a word?
Who cares?
What's in the bag?
# You blow my mind
Hey, Mickey #
# Hey, Mickey #
# So, Mickey, you're so fine #
# You're so fine
you blow my mind, hey Mickey #
# Hey, Mickey #
Mags? Maggie?
Maggie Malone?
Shh!
Not so loud.
Feels like there's
a thousand games of marbles
going on in my head.
Who's winning?
Who cares?
[chuckles]
Come here. Come here.
What?
What are you-- What--
Oh, oh, oh.
What are you doing?
I'm dolling you up.
Why?
Because that young man
is gonna be picking you up
in about... one minute.
Lettie, are you conspiring
behind my back again?
I told you.
No dates, no men.
Besides, what makes
you think he's even
interested in me?
Or better yet, what makes you
think I'm interested in him?
I mean, he's
not even my type.
So, what is your type?
Hi!
Hi.
This is awkward.
[clears throat]
You.
Um, no, um, you are--
Okay, I don't know
this game.
Lettie, would you
help us out?
She seems
to have a little--
Come here, sweetie. Okay.
Here you go, sweetie.
Here-- Here--
[sighs]
I just had a little--
Yeah.
Well, as much as
I'd like to draw
this magic moment out,
we really should
be going, so--
Chop-chop.
What chop-chop?
Where are we going?
You'll see.
I'm in the middle of work,
I can't just leave.
Have a lovely day, Lettie.
Bye-bye.
[Lettie chuckles]
Bye now.
Yes!
I can't keep taking
days off, you know.
I have a job.
Oh, pish-posh.
You're rich, remember?
So what is your type?
Excuse me?
Well, you said
I wasn't your type,
so I presume you have one.
A type, that is.
Mm. Yeah.
Not really.
I don't date.
Really? Why is that?
I don't believe in love.
Bloody hell.
That's a bit grim.
No, just--
I mean, the whole concept
just seems archaic,
doesn't it?
Two people spending
the rest of their
lives together?
What was this, a concept
that came into fashion
back when 15 was
considered middle-aged?
And how about all
those silly rituals?
Something old,
something new,
blah, blah, blah--
Oh, oh. The best one?
My favorite? The throwing
of the bouquet.
I mean, seriously.
What is the sense
in buying
a whole bunch
of stupid flowers,
just to have
to lug 'em around
the whole damn time--
And then to throw
'em mindlessly to
a bunch of losers,
who would fight each
other to the death to be
"the one" to catch it?
I mean, really.
So not a big fan
of marriage, then?
[chuckles]
What about children?
I'm sure your parents
would someday like to hear
the pitter-patter
of tiny feet?
I don't have parents.
Right. Oh.
I guess now
it's my turn to
feel awkward.
Don't worry. I'm not
gonna start sobbing
or anything.
My mom died
when I was four,
and my dad gave me up.
Only thing I remember
about him was that
he had this mustache,
and he used to do these
really bad magic tricks.
On Sundays, the nuns would
take us into town
and I would go up to
every guy with facial hair
and ask him
if he was my dad.
[chuckles]
How pathetic is that, right?
I'm sure I made
a lot of guys really nervous.
Anyway, he's probably
shaved it off by now,
and I don't really
like to talk about it.
Please don't look
at me that way.
What way?
Like you're pitying me.
I'm not. I was--
I was just wondering
why you told me that.
I don't know.
It must be the, uh--
the hangover.
Fair enough.
Well, I'm dreadfully sorry,
but I'm afraid
I'm going to have to
blindfold you now.
What? What kinda
segue is that?
All right. Bring it on.
But just for
the record, I'm not
really into kink, okay?
Yes. Course, I don't
believe you for a second,
you randy old goat.
Right. We're good.
Let us go.
Great.
Yes. Good?
Can you see?
Sure. No. Not at all.
[chuckles]
Oh! I never should
have agreed to this.
All right. But
we're almost there now.
Better be. I'm feeling
the quease factor.
All right, all right.
Bear with me. And--
Stop. Okay.
Are you ready?
Voila!
Wow.
[claps hands]
Cool!
[laughing]
Oh, this is beautiful!
Though I do find it
mildly disturbing
that you would blindfold
me to bring me up
to your apartment.
Little weird.
[chuckles]
Yeah. Yeah, I can
see why that would be
a little unsettling.
It's not actually
my apartment.
It is, in fact,
your penthouse.
Here at the Renaissance
Park 55, with a maid
and room service--
24/7-- I believe that's
how you Yanks say it.
Shut up.
I can't live here.
What would I do
with all my stuff?
You can't mean all that
old rubbish in your flat.
I-I did bring your cat--
Linus, I believe
he's called--
He should be around here
somewhere. And of course,
all of your papers
that were in
all of those boxes.
We're such
a privacy invader.
Oh, thank you.
Uh.
[sighs]
I can't live here.
Though it is really nice.
And they actually have
elevators that work.
And I guess I wouldn't
have to eat lima beans anymore.
Yes. It would be a terrible
shame to say good-bye
to the lima beans.
Do you think
they'd make me liver?
Foie gras?
For what?
Why are you speaking
French all of a sudden?
Do you think that
they'd make me liver?
I suppose.
Okay, then.
Linus and I will stay.
He's a big fan
of the liver.
Aren't we all?
What?
Nothing. Um,
I'm absolutely famished.
Shall I--
Shall I ring down
for room service?
Get them to bring us up
some afternoon tea?
Tea?
If you're hungry, order
a sandwich or something.
Oh, and get me one too.
[ringing]
And some aspirin.
[whispers]
I have a headache.
[ring]
## [Blue Danube]
They're so cute!
I almost feel guilty
eating one.
But I will.
Ohh! Ohhh...
too bad.
Do you think
you could refrain
from fingering
all of the sandwiches?
Why?
They are called
finger sandwiches,
aren't they?
[giggles]
I won't
even dignify that
with a retort.
Mmm, "retort."
My, we are
very upper-crusty,
aren't we?
What, are you
related to the Queen?
Don't be ridiculous.
Then, my uncle
is a duke.
Yeah.
Same difference.
All righty, Brandon.
Why don't you tell me
a little somethin'
about yourself?
Seems only fair
since you've,
you know,
taken over my life
and all.
Huh.
Well. Where
do I start? Um...
I went to Oxford.
And I graduated
near the top
of my class.
And, uh, then I worked
at the American Embassy
for a year,
which is where
I met my current
employer.
And then
I was uprooted
and moved
to this delightful spot
two weeks ago.
Hmm. That's nice.
But I didn't really
ask for your rsum.
Come on!
Tell me about yourself.
What do you like to do?
What are your hobbies?
Did you have a pet
growing up?
Oh, wait.
Don't tell me.
You had a dog,
didn't you?
Uh, uh, uh!
Saint Bernard.
No. No. Great Dane.
Oh, yeah.
Definitely
a Great Dane.
Actually,
I had a parakeet...
...named Trina.
I named her after a girl
I was madly in love with...
in, uh, in what
you refer to
as the third grade.
Hmm. Third grade.
You started young.
Yes.
Well, we-- we didn't
exactly date.
Though we did
ride the seesaw
every afternoon
for three days.
And then,
on the fourth day,
I came to the park...
and she was on the swings
with Nigel Wallingford.
The tramp.
Never quite recovered
from that betrayal.
How could you, really?
[chuckles] Yeah.
[laughs]
All right, Brandon.
Tomorrow,
it's my turn.
Your turn?
Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna show
your blue blood
how the other half
lives.
Oh. Well, thank you.
That's very sweet,
but, um,
I simply... cannot...
Oh, you so simply can.
## [Blue Danube]
What?!
What is this?
No, no, no.
This attire
just won't do.
Come on.
What? Pardon?
What won't do?
See you later,
Jimmy.
Well, this is
just embarrassing.
Oh, quit
your bitchin'.
Can you take this?
Thanks.
If you stop complaining,
you might actually have
some fun, you know.
Fun. Right. Yes.
This... looks
like a... hoot.
Ready?
As I'll ever be.
Well...
Ooh! Ooh!
Oh, Okay.
## [bouncy pop]
Oh, my God!
Wait! Wait!
Steer straight!
I can't quite
get my feet on.
# She's the kind of girl
that's not too shy #
Oh, my balance!
# And I can tell
I'm her kind of guy #
# 'Cause she danced
close to me #
# Like I hoped she would #
# She danced with me
like I hoped she would #
# Somethin' tells me #
# I'm into somethin' good #
# Somethin' tells me
I'm into somethin' #
# We only danced
for a minute or two #
# And then she stuck
close to me #
# The whole night through #
# Can I be quite in love? #
# She's everything
I've been dreamin' of #
I've been dreaming of #
# I walked her home,
and she held my hand #
# I knew it wouldn't be
just a one-night stand #
# So I asked
to see her next week #
# And she told me I could #
# I asked to see her,
and she told me I could #
# Somethin' tells me
I'm into something good #
I'm into something #
# Ah, something good,
something good #
You are so ill-mannered.
I'm sure the management
frowns on--
on littering.
Look around. Littering's
encouraged here.
Get off me.
Come on, do it.
Do it, do it.
No, I could not possibly,
no, no.
All right, fine.
All right, you want it?
Oh, my God!
I'm so sorry!
I'm-- I'm-- I'm--
I'm terribly sorry.
My first time
throwing nuts.
You're right.
That does feel
terribly liberating.
Told ya. See?
Life as a pauper
ain't so bad.
You know,
I have to say,
I-- I really have had
an enjoyable day.
I, uh, I don't think
I've had this much
physical activity
since Oxford--
first team cricket,
you know.
Oh, cricket.
Mm-hmm.
That's that cheap
imitation of baseball,
isn't it?
I beg your pardon!
Cricket came first.
At any rate,
what is the logic
with hitting a ball
with a cylinder?
A flat object makes
a lot more sense.
Oh. God forbid
something be illogical.
Mm-hmm-hmm.
Mm, nuts.
All right.
Come on, Mr. Logic.
Let's dance.
Well, there's--
there's no dance floor.
There is now.
All right.
## [Rock guitar]
Sorry.
[music stops]
All right, come on.
## [jazz piano]
## [saxophone]
Um...
You know, traditionally,
the man does lead.
Hmm, then stop
slacking off.
Oh.
# Oh, ne-- #
# Never #
# ...ver #
# Will I love again #
# Never #
# Will I give you pain #
# Ah #
# Never #
# Will my life
be the same #
# It's true #
# I wish
you'd leave my heart #
# Never #
[silence]
Ahem.
So then the monkey
gets off the bar stool
and says, "I don't
want a daiquiri.
I want a mai tai!"
That is the worst joke
I have ever heard.
I know. I read it
on a lolly stick.
Wow, look at that.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Uh, shall I walk you up?
Oh, sure.
Uh, I just usually
take the elevator,
though.
Oh.
'Cause it's
a lot of floors.
Well, I'll ride you
up there, then.
No, I mean
I'll ride on you up--
No! I--
Uh, I'll escort you
to your door.
Right. Great.
Well, here we are.
Yeah. This is my floor.
Right.
Um, thank you for a...
surprising day.
Mm. Did you have
the time of your life?
Oh, yeah.
Um... Okay, well,
it was really good
seeing you again.
Right. Uh, yeah.
Oh.
Ow!
Oh! Oh, I'm so sorry.
I'm Sorry. Really.
That's okay.
[elevator door dings]
Right. Um--
Uh--
Oh.
There you go.
Thanks.
Right.
Got 'em.
So I'm gonna go,
then.
Right.
To my room.
Yeah, well,
that would be where to go.
Okay, bye.
All right, bye.
Good night.
[ding]
Mags,
can you give me a hand?
Maggie.
I'm thinking
of leaving Charlie.
Mm-hmm.
'Cause I've been having
this tawdry affair
with the paper boy.
I like 'em young.
That's nice.
I'm also thinking
of having some lipo,
a boob job,
maybe even a butt lift.
What do you think,
Mags?
Uh...
that sounds good.
Maggie Malone, you haven't
heard one word I've said.
Oh. Sorry.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say you were in love.
Lookin' all doe-eyed.
What?
No.
Nuh-uh.
But you know, since you
brought it up, I mean...
in theory,
what would it... be like
if I was in love?
How would I know?
Well...
Listen to Mama.
When I met Charlie,
I didn't know at first.
I mean, I-- he was a friend
of my brother's,
and-- and I thought
he was kind of strange.
But strange in a good way,
you know?
Then one night,
when my brother wasn't home,
he came by,
and brought me some daisies.
He had on this--
this silly
second-hand yellow jacket...
and white
patent leather shoes.
And in that moment,
I fell for him.
That night,
I-- I couldn't sleep.
I kept thinking what it would
feel like to kiss him.
Good Lord, I just had
to see him again.
You have those kind
of feelings, sweetie?
I don't know. I don't know.
When it's real, you'll know.
Okay.
Let's say it was real.
Then what?
When you meet a man
who gives you
the warm fuzzies
all the way down
to your toes,
you look him
right in the eye
and kiss him.
Well, that's a little
forward, isn't it?
Damn right.
It's nothing
to be ashamed of
when you're in love.
You've got to go after
what you want, no apologies.
Go big or stay home.
That's what I say about it.
Why are you asking me
all these questions?
Um...
just research--
you know, for the--
for the new book.
Oh, of course. Research.
Of course I knew that.
You got any more
research questions,
you just come to me.
[chuckles]
You seem to be spending
more time with this girl
than originally discussed.
Yes! I know, sir.
It's just that, um--
well, she's--
she's quite fun.
What do you mean, fun?
Well, in an irritating
sort of way--
I want this kept business.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Good.
What about the manuscripts?
Oh, I had them removed
from the hotel this morning,
and everything's going
according to plan.
Good.
Have a good one.
Yes, sir.
[Maggie] Hi.
[Man] Hi.
[Maggie] Thanks.
Thank you. Okay!
Go big or stay home.
So next time I see him,
I'm just gonna kiss him.
Gonna kiss him
right on the lips.
Maybe even
a little tongue.
All right, Mags. Don't
get ahead of yourself.
Let's just see
how it goes.
Oh!
Gee-- hi. I'm--
[soft moan]
[moan]
Wow.
Oh, hello. [laughs]
Hi.
Um, I-I-I-I'm here
because I--
I wanted to surprise you.
Hm. Surprise!
Uh, what's the prize?
Uh, um-- well.
Moving right past the kiss
to the surprise. Okay.
Uh-- the surprise. Um...
uh... come in!
Uh... look around.
Do you, um-- do you
notice anything different?
Uh-- um-- hm.
Hmm...
Oh! Is this it?
No.
Thank God.
[laughs]
Okay...
Keep looking!
Okay okay okay!
New rug!
No! Wow! Not even close!
Wow! You're really
not good at this game!
Mm-hm.
Wow, that never gets old.
Come on! Just tell me!
What what what? I give up!
All right. You're all
out of guesses. Poor effort.
But all right.
Your life's work?
The manuscripts? Look around.
They're gone.
Is this... a joke?
No, no, no, no!
No joke, Miss Malone.
You are being published.
Well... I don't
know what to say.
Well, traditionally--
"Thank you, Brandon!"
would suffice.
Thank you.
How dare you?
[scoffing snort] What?
I mean-- how pathetic
do you think I am,
that-that-that you'd
have to--
buy that for me, too?
[groans]
Do you think maybe
I might wanna earn that?
You can't buy me
success!
No! Megan, no! No!
He and I thought that--
Oh, he! He! It's a he!
Who is he? Just-- come on!
Maggie-- I can't
tell you that!
Those were the rules!
You know that!
You know what?
Enough of the rules!
Okay? Maybe you should try
breaking the rules,
for once in your life.
[sighs]
Maggie-- I can't.
You can't, or you won't?
It-- [sighs]
Forget it.
Hey, wait. No.
Hang on a second!
[stammers] Wait, Maggie.
What about the kiss?
The kiss was a mistake, okay?
This whole thing has been
a mistake!
This is not my life--
Wait, Maggie--!
D-Don't...
[exhales hard]
[elevator rings, opens]
## [opera]
[Brandon]
So she insists on knowing.
I mean, just your name
would do, I'm sure.
What is that?
Is that a stain
in your tie?
Oh. Ketchup, sir.
Formed quite an addiction
to these hot dogs.
Will there be
anything else, sir?
No, Samuel. Thank you.
Very good, sir.
That will be all.
[Brandon]
I don't understand.
I mean--
it can't go on this way
forever. I myself am curious--
I don't pay you
to be curious.
It's not pertinent
to my interests.
And your interest,
by the way, is not
to compromise mine.
All right? It's to serve it!
I got 20 years of research
into this. Have you?
What do you think? I can
afford to lose her again?
'Cause you can't execute
a stupid lousy instruction!
News?
Hey, Samuel? Sit down!
I'm sorry. Could you go
to my closet
and get him a selection
of ties to try on? He's
got this stain, here.
Very good, sir.
## [pop --
"Daydream Believer"]
# Oh, I could hide #
# 'Neath the wings #
# Of the bluebird #
# As she sings #
[Man] Hey, Maggie.
I'll be right with ya.
# The 6:00 alarm #
# Would never ring #
# But it rings #
# And I rise #
# Wipe the sleep #
# Out of my eyes #
Hey, George.
I got something for ya.
What's this?
For years of--
exceptional--
bike-watching service.
See ya.
Wha--?
# To a daydream believer #
# And a homecoming... #
Ohh... [hits ground]
# Queen #
[Forelli]
Hey, Maggie!
You little canole!
How's it goin'?
Hey.
Oh, almost forgot.
Here's for all that
rent I owe you.
And that new roof
you've been wanting.
# Now you know
How happy #
# I can be #
# And our good times... #
[Maggie]
Did you ever think
I was scared?
I don't know--
fear of failure?
Fear of success. Whatever
those shrinks call it.
I don't know. I guess--
I just never thought
I was good enough
to be published.
The point is, you're
a published writer.
Yeah.
Only catch is,
I didn't earn it.
[rattling]
What the--?
[Brandon, outside]
Maggie!
[rocks on window]
Oh my God, it's him!
[squeaks]
[Brandon]
Maggie!
Please!
Come on!
Maggie, I must
talk to you!
How romantic.
Oh, he scores points.
Very Romeo and Juliet.
And that accent's sexy!
[giggling]
Get away! I don't want him
to know I'm in here!
[Brandon]
I know you're in there!
I saw your bicycle!
Damn it.
Go away!
Maggie, please!
[stammering]
I-I-I must talk to you!
I don't talk to liars!
I didn't lie! I-- omitted!
Same difference!
Don't be an idiot!
The man is fighting for you!
This knight-in-shining-
armor crap doesn't come by
too often.
## [rock -- "I Want
You to Want Me"]
[on stereo, outside]
Wait! Stop. Stay.
Don't move.
# I want you to want me #
# I need you to need me #
What are you doing?
[shouting]
I want you to know
that you've turned me
into a couch potato!
I rented every circa
1980's American film
to try to figure out
how to win you back!
I ran across this
terribly sappy gesture,
but I thought you'd
like it!
# I'd love you
to love me #
And if you don't,
I'll climb up the trellis!
Though I'd really
rather not. Looks
quite perilous.
Don't bother.
You might break
a nail or something.
Just take the stairs.
# Diddle-I diddle-l
Diddle-I see you cryin' #
Stairs?
Trellis would have
been easier.
[shuts off music]
[Bridgette]
This is so cool!
Oh, no no no no.
You're not watching
a blow-by-blow,
play-by-play whatever.
Go go go! Out out!
You are a terrible friend.
We are old married biddies,
and need to live
vicariously through you.
Yeah. Sorry to disappoint.
I'm a terrible friend.
Now go. Go! Out. Out.
[door opens]
Hello.
Hi!
Good luck.
[panting]
Um...
Ta-dah!
Very cute.
Now say whatever it is
you gotta say.
Okay. Warm welcome.
Well, I'll-- I'll just
get straight to it, then.
Umm...
See... the thing is...
all my life, I have
sort of thought of myself
as a bit...
passionless, for lack
of a better word.
Until... recently.
See... [sighs]
The truth is, Maggie...
I've... fallen for you.
I... I think about you
incessantly,
and, um, I think that I...
[sighs]...love you.
Now, I-I-I-I realize that
I have a lot to live up to,
what with you writing
about princes and whatnot.
And though I may not have
rode here on my white horse
-- I can't ride -- um,
I will do everything
in my power
to make you feel
like a princess,
every day,
for the rest of my life.
Any response to that?
Really, anything at all
will do.
Uh--
no.
I mean...
it doesn't really matter
what I feel,
or what I don't
feel for you.
The reality is,
I can't trust you.
You're right. I won't tell you
who the benefactor is.
See? I mean, I don't even
know why you came here--
I'll show you.
It doesn't even--
what?
I said I will show you
who your benefactor is.
You will lose
all of the money,
and I will be fined,
if not disbarred,
for breach of attorney/client
confidentiality. But, um...
for you, Miss Malone?
I'm prepared to break
the rules.
On one condition.
You let me finish
that kiss you started.
Hmm.
That's very sketchy
behavior.
Mm-hmm.
Trading kisses
for information.
Mmm.
Extortion. Blackmail,
some might say.
But...
But, alas, I seem
to have no choice.
[cooing, smooching]
[big sigh]
I've been, um...
thinking about you
incessantly, also.
Really.
Yeah.
Well, that works out well.
Mm-hm.
[chuckling]
[kissing, moaning]
Oh. I already spent
all the money.
Mm... good lord!
On what?
Umm... college.
A new roof.
And a security guard.
My God. Big spender!
I can't think of
anyone I'd rather
live in poverty with.
You say the sweetest things.
All right, enough about...
I am a man of my word,
and I still have to
pay out for that first kiss.
So, uh... let's bugger off.
Oh. My sweater.
Wait! I don't have
any shoes!
Don't... forget your shoes.
I'll go check the study.
Can't find him.
Who's that?
That's me.
[footsteps]
Daddy?
[church bells]
[soft chatter]
You must be proud.
Uh-huh!
[soft muttering]
Hey, hey. Shh.
Calm down.
I'm nervous.
[laughs]
## [church organ, loud]
## [wedding march]
Thanks.
Hi.
Hi!
[Man in back]
Wait!
Maggie?
Don't make me run.
I've got a bum knee.
You don't recall?
[panting]
Do you have any
recollections of us?
You don't recall
when Mommy died.
[bitter laugh]
You and I hit
the road, kid.
Like a pair of hobos.
Mom was a...
'Course, we ended up
in the street.
How was I gonna button
my own shirt, let alone
tell you a story?
I gave you to a church.
Just to get my head
straight, you know?
I come back after
a few months.
They deny me access.
Then I go back to
the church, to petition
the records.
The records are sealed.
I had to get permission.
You talk about humiliation.
Had to get permission
just to write.
So I wrote.
I wrote you a letter a month,
for 10 years, Mags.
You never answered.
I figured you just
threw 'em away.
A few weeks ago, I'm
in London. I get a call
from some woman named Lettie.
She says she found
the letters.
Why?
The letters just
came too late.
You know how many years
I looked for you?
I named my first kitten
"Daddy",
just so I could
say it out loud.
But I'll call you
Bernard, for now.
If that's okay.
That is your name,
isn't it?
Yeah.
[sniffles]
I gotta know
one thing, Bernard.
[sniffles]
Why the whole ruse?
You know, and
Great Expectations
and everything.
That was very creative.
Why not just call me up
and say,
"Hi. I'm your dad.
"Let's go to lunch."
I guess we get scared.
Right.
It's a common defect.
I would love nothing more
than to take you to lunch.
Well, you know,
I've kinda got a wedding
to finish in there.
Well...
Shall we?
We shall.
Otherwise, why
would he come?
Okay, let's go.
Come on, come on.
You take care of
my little girl.
I will, sir.
# Oh, when you
touch my hand #
[laughs]
# Oh, when you
reach for me #
# I fall from grace #
# I fall from grace, baby #
# Whenever I
touch your hand #
# I fall from grace, baby #