Thank you.
- Just these.
- Right.
- What train, sir?
- 7:55 to Nottingham.
- There's a reservation for Dr Radcliffe.
- Yes, sir.
'The 7:55 express
leaving platform 13
'will stop at Rugby, Leicester,
Nottingham and Sheffield.'
- Thank you very much indeed.
- Thank you, sir.
- All right?
- Yes, thank you.
Well, have a good holiday,
and Henderson will meet you.
- Yes. Yes.
- Right. Bye.
'... leaving platform 13
'will stop at Rugby, Leicester,
Nottingham and Sheffield.'
All aboard.
Dr Radcliffe, you forgot your camera?
Where's Dr Radcliffe?
Morning.
You should get up in the morning.
20 minutes late you are, you know.
- Anything new?
- It's all in the report.
And it's neat and tidy - unlike some.
You ought to remember
you're still in the army, boyo.
I'll tell you what, you remember for me.
9:45am, postal delivery.
The postman was your man Haggerty,
delivered two packets and four letters.
9:56am, the baker's van called.
Left two large brown and a sliced white.
They had an extra pint of milk
which either means there are more
people there or they're drinking more tea.
What are you doing here?
You're not due on for hours yet.
Ross wants you. So old muggins here
has to come down and relieve you.
- What does he want? Did he tell you?
- No.
Didn't he say anything?
Yes. I'm in his full confidence, I am.
Blast you and blast old Ross.
- You know what?
- No, what?
You've got some wiping to do -
that tape's still running. Good morning.
- Morning.
- Morning, sir.
- Thank you.
Come on, little pigeons.
Come in, Palmer.
- Sergeant Palmer reporting as ordered.
- Close the door.
And don't slouch into my office
like a pregnant camel. Stand to attention.
At ease.
Is that my B-107, sir?
As if you didn't know.
And it makes awful reading, Palmer.
You just love the army, don't you?
Oh, yes, sir. I just love the army, sir.
We may find you a better audience
for your jokes.
- I'm transferring you to Major Dalby.
- Oh. What will be my job, sir?
It could give your peculiar talents
more scope than observation duties.
- At least you won't be stuck in an attic.
- Er, is this a promotion, sir?
- Sort of.
- Any more money?
Let's see.
You're on 1300 pay and allowances.
Yes, sir.
- I'll try and get you 1400.
- Oh, thank you, sir.
- Now I can get that new infrared grill.
- Save your money.
You won't have much time for cooking.
Dalby works his men.
And he doesn't have
my sense of humour.
Yes, sir. I will miss that, sir.
All right, come on, I'll take you over.
Er, the B-107, must that go with us?
I'm afraid so.
Come along, Palmer.
...to take any old job...
...no, not weekends.
Oh. Good morning, sir.
The butler you asked for
is upstairs waiting to be interviewed.
Just go through the door,
along the passage and up the stairs.
- Got it?
- Er, yes, thank you.
Do you mind waiting?
Sir.
...I don't think I'm difficult,
it's just these jobs.
Well, I mean...
Good morning, Dalby.
- Good morning sir.
- I've just read your T-104.
I thought that might speed your arrival.
It did.
It's a pity you lost Radcliffe.
We were expecting something like that.
I hope you're not imputing negligence.
My dear chap,
there's no question of that.
Let me put you in the picture, Dalby.
The killing of Radcliffe's guard
has verified our suspicions.
For some time we've had a section
investigating the brain drain.
Too many government scientists
are leaving their jobs
at the peak of their careers -
they cease to function.
- You've checked on them, of course?
- Naturally. We checked on them all.
126 have left in the past two years.
107 had fair enough reasons to go -
better facilities, better pay.
Three defected to the other side.
- And the other 16?
- 17 with Radcliffe. 17 top men.
What defies probability
is that none of them
had a rational explanation for quitting.
But Radcliffe didn't quit.
- He was lifted.
- Exactly.
Now we think
we've got our first real lead.
And I want you to get Radcliffe back.
- I'll try, of course.
- That's not good enough.
If you don't get him back, the people
upstairs might have to close you down.
Now wait a minute.
This department was set up
for counterespionage
not security grade one surveillance
on people like Radcliffe.
Neither were Wilson's
or Roberts's departments
but I put them on S1 duties.
They were War Office, I'm Home Office.
I'm aware of that, Dalby.
I set you up, remember?
You have a very good job
for a passed-over major, haven't you?
Hm.
I've brought you
a replacement for Taylor.
Hm?
What's he like?
A little insubordinate but a good man.
Sergeant Palmer.
- That's it, Mrs Norman.
- It's not much.
After doing Lyons Corner House
you can't expect me to clean a pub.
- It's a good hotel.
- I don't know.
I'd do better at the labour exchange.
Yes, sir? You can go up now.
Good luck, Palmer.
And don't forget your mop.
- Good morning, sir.
- Morning.
Through the door,
along the passage and up the stairs.
Got it!
Shut the door.
It isn't usual to read a B-107
to its subject, Palmer,
but I'm going to put you straight.
"Insubordinate,
"insolent...
"and a trickster...
"perhaps with criminal tendencies. "
Yes, that's a pretty fair appraisal.
- Sir.
- Good.
That last quality might be useful.
But if I have any trouble with you,
I shall bite you, Palmer,
and I shall bite you so hard you'll go
right back to where Ross found you.
Come with me.
A word in your shell-like ear.
If there's anything
to be reported to Ross, I report it.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you for a wonderful evening.
Spare us the jokes, Palmer, I don't have
Colonel Ross's sense of humour.
Yes, I will miss that, sir.
The fella whose job I'm taking,
will he show me the ropes?
- Only if you're in touch with the spirits.
- I beg your pardon?
He was shot this morning.
- Good morning, sir.
- Morning.
Morning, sir.
Murray.
Palmer.
- Hi.
Give him your gun.
Issue him with a Colt. 32.
- Do you know how to use this?
- Colt. 32? Yes.
- I'd sooner have my automatic.
- Use the Colt.
I'll use the Colt.
- Morning, sir.
- Good morning.
Morning.
- Thank you.
- Here's the file on Bluejay, sir.
- You won't need that.
- No... Oh, come in, Palmer.
Yes, I understand. I see.
I'll be going down there.
Yes, if you will.
Oh, yes.
Excuse me.
Did you go over there last night?
How did it turn out?
This morning our S1, Radcliffe,
was lifted and Taylor killed.
It has been put to me
that if we don't get Radcliffe back,
this department will be closed down.
Message received and understood.
Palmer.
This is Palmer, Taylor's replacement.
Chilcott-Oakes.
- Hello.
- Carswell.
Gray, Edwards and Courtney.
You know Alice, of course. Now, then...
Oh, you may sit down.
There are only two people in Europe
operating on a scale large enough
to market Radcliffe.
One, codenamed Sparrow,
whom I've just been told by the French Sûreté,
was arrested two months ago
and they're still holding.
So, we are left with Erik Ashley Grantby,
codename Bluejay, born Albania 1918.
Thank you, Chico.
The one in the hat is Bluejay,
the bald one is his chief of staff,
codenamed Housemartin.
This was taken in Stockholm
two years ago.
Here is a more recent film of Bluejay
in Vienna last October.
Since then, it would appear,
he's been lying low.
Alice has done a breakdown of all
his known haunts in and around London.
I want them all checked.
- Jock, take these.
- Sir.
- Gray.
- Edwards.
- Sir.
- Chico.
- Thank you, sir.
Palmer.
Lastly, if Bluejay has Radcliffe,
he'll sell to the highest bidder
and that's got to be us.
Whoever contacts him must let him
know that we're in the market.
Right, get on with it.
Courtney, I'd like a word with you.
I say, er, my name's Harry.
- I'm Jock.
- Hi.
- Is that his bird?
- No!
Oh. That parade-ground manner of his
doesn't work with women.
- He gave you the treatment, eh?
- I'll say.
He does that to everyone.
Still, he's not a bad bloke really.
Go ahead.
This'll be your desk.
- Don't smoke a pipe, do you?
- No.
Mr Taylor was scared of cancer.
Combined clearing house reports,
your equipment requisitions,
expense allowance indent,
motor pool chit - yours is a blue Zodiac.
Log book, insurance,
civilian driving licence and form L-101.
What is form L-101?
Field report. You have
to make one out after every job.
It makes Dalby happy.
I've got to ask about Grantby
in 19 different places
and then make out 19 silly answers?
That's about it, laddie.
This job's nearly all legwork.
It may be Dalby's way of doing things
but it isn't mine.
- See you, Jock.
- Aye, cheerio.
I'm always doing you favours.
- We're mates.
- How about doing me a favour for once?
Sure, Pat. I'd do anything for you.
- Afternoon, Inspector.
- Afternoon.
- What's his name again?
- Erik Ashley Grantby.
- See what we've got.
- You've got a green card on him.
Won't take a moment, sir.
- Now...
- Yes?
That blonde bird
you was with the other evening.
- Rita?
- What's her phone number?
You dirty old man.
Well, you scratch my back
and I'll scratch hers.
- You ought to be locked up.
- I know.
- Here we are, sir.
- Thank you.
Ah... Grantby. A right master criminal.
Well, there you are, Harry.
Scrutinise that.
Three parking tickets.
Thurlow Gardens.
The last one only two weeks ago.
Ah! Registration number.
- Can I borrow that?
- Go ahead.
Four-one-seven...
F- L-U.
- Thank you, Pat.
- What about her telephone number?
Oh! Disconnected.
Get me Wilson's Metal Fatigue
And Stress Engineering.
Yes, certainly.
Mr Grantby?
Mr Grantby, we are looking for an
important piece of scientific equipment.
It was lost on a train.
We think that you might
be able to help us get it back.
Shh.
We would be willing to do a deal.
Call me, after six.
Operator, I'm getting unobtainable
on Knightsbridge 2149,
could you check it for me, please?
'That line is discontinued, caller. '
Grantby.
Right, gentlemen, sit down.
All right, let's hear what you have to say.
Carswell?
Er, no luck sir, I drew a blank.
- Chico?
- No joy at all. I'm awfully sorry, sir.
There's no use being sorry, is there?
Didn't anyone contact him?
Er, I did.
In the Science Museum library.
And?
All he gave me
was a discontinued telephone number.
- Did you follow him?
- Yes, and I lost him.
- You lost him?
- Yes.
You idiot. Let's see it.
All right, put it on your report.
I want your L-101 s as quickly as
possible, however feeble they may be.
And then you can all get out
and start looking for Grantby again.
Alice.
Don't worry, man, you were the only one
to come up with anything.
- He seemed very pleased.
- He's got a comical way of showing it.
- You know this is unauthorised?
- My mother gave it to me for Christmas.
You're supposed to be at work.
Oh, you are, of course?
Dalby likes to know about his new boys.
- Have you seen everything?
- Yes, thank you.
Then you know where the...
whisky is.
- Yes.
- Fix us both one, will you?
Thank you.
Cheers.
Do you like music?
- Yes.
- Why don't you put a record on?
Mozart.
Music to cook by!
What are you gonna tell Dalby
in your L-101?
That you like girls.
You got that right.
You're not the tearaway
he thinks you are.
You also like books, music, cooking.
I like birds best.
- How did you get into this game?
- My husband was in it.
He was killed in Tokyo.
I'm sorry.
So they gave me a job.
You were bailed out
of detention barracks.
Yes, I was.
- So what bailed you in?
- Er...
I was stationed in Berlin
and I was making rather a lot of money
out of the German army
and they insisted that the British army
made an example of me.
- What did you do?
- It's very complicated.
- It impressed Ross.
- It impressed me.
Boy, has he got me
by the short hairs for it.
Still, it's better than two years in the nick.
The food's terrible.
- You're very professional.
- Yeah, so are you.
Do you need all that?
It's as easy to cook for two
as it is for one.
I thought you might join me.
No, thanks. I'm not hungry.
- You got to have...
- You show me.
It's easy. Cut this first thing out
for a start.
Get that, will you?
- Forget it, we'll go to lunch.
- Right, in a minute.
- Duty officer, please.
- 'Who wants him? '
- Special Branch.
- Ah! Pat, it's Harry.
Hello! I think we might have
something for you.
Shoreditch have picked up a bloke
we're holding a red card on.
- Codename Housemartin.
- We'll be right down.
- Palmer.
- Mr Palmer's just left, sir.
He said he'd be back soon.
Would you like to wait?
Everything's under control, sir.
I'm Palmer.
Get the keys.
This way, sir.
Right, on your feet.
He's dead, sir.
Looks as if Bluejay beat us to it.
I want to see his charge sheet.
That's the one, sir.
"Charged with unlawful possession
of a suitcase."
- Where's the suitcase?
- The other gentleman took it.
- Did you see what was in it?
- Electrical equipment.
"Arrested near Sandersons."
What's Sandersons?
It's a disused factory, sir.
- Is that an outside phone?
- Yes, sir.
- 225 Wellington Street.
- Calling Dalby?
Up Dalby. I need a TX-82.
You'll never get it, man.
I did learn something working for Ross.
- Keightley.
- 'Hello, Pat.
- 'It's Harry Palmer.'
- What's up?
I want your help.
Housemartin's dead and I need a TX-82.
You need a 3H security clearance.
What's your authority?
Authority? CC1.
CC1?
All right, Harry, if you say so.
Give me the time and place.
2:30. They're late.
- Palmer?
- I'm Palmer.
All right, let's get on with it.
Come on, let's go.
- The men are in position.
- Get them away from the door.
Having fun, Inspector?
Did you call this TX-82?
- Yes, sir. I think Radcliffe's in there.
- Really? Get on with it, then.
Lose that door, will you?
All right, split up.
Get some light in here, will you?
- I wonder what sort of factory this was.
- Search me.
No one here, sir.
- Get the men out of here.
- Right, sir.
Get back in your cars. Come on, let's go.
Come on, get moving.
It looks as if all this
has been for nothing.
That's not good enough.
Come on, let's have you.
This operation was timed to start at 2:25,
you started at 2:35,
that's not good enough.
Good afternoon.
Thank you.
The next time you use CC1 authority,
just you make sure you have it.
You know, it's funny.
If Radcliffe had been here,
I'd have been...
a hero.
He wasn't and you're not.
Major.
This stove's still warm.
I found this in it.
A piece of recording tape.
- "Ipcress. "
- What?
It's got "Ipcress" written on it.
See what Chilcott-Oakes can make of it.
This might be something.
Yes, Palmer, it might.
- By the way, have you had lunch?
- No.
No, sir.
I'll buy you some.
And what do you make of that?
If I could have a bit more equipment,
I might be able to make something out.
Well, keep it within reason.
Well, it must mean something.
Hardly worth a TX-82 though, was it?
- Open a file on it.
- Right, sir.
- Chico, why...
- And we still have to find Radcliffe.
That means more legwork
and fewer hunches. Get on with it.
Oh. Good morning, sir.
"Champignons. "
You're paying ten pence more
for a fancy French label.
If you want mushrooms,
you'd get better value on the next shelf.
It's not just the label,
these do have a better flavour.
Of course.
You're quite a gourmet, aren't you?
Beefaroni? Extraordinary.
- I haven't seen you here before, sir.
- No, I don't...
really care for
these American shopping methods.
One has to move with the times,
I suppose. Hm?
- Yes, that's very nice.
- Is it really?
Mm.
- Settled down with Dalby, have you?
- Yes, sir.
- And the girl Courtney.
- You didn't come...
- Excuse me.
- Sorry.
You didn't come to talk about...
Oh, you men!
...button mushrooms and birds.
- Perceptive of you.
May I?
That, erm, tape. You must have
a pretty thick file on it now.
That's right.
That's baby food, sir.
- I want to see it.
- Why don't you...
Sorry.
Why don't you ask Dalby for it?
- I don't want Dalby to know about it.
- Why not, sir?
Don't be impertinent, Palmer.
- I want you to do a job for me.
- Have I any choice?
Frankly, no.
It's quite simple - I don't want the file,
I just want it microfilmed. Hm?
Sir.
- Stick that in my B-107.
- Very funny.
- Excuse me, please.
- Yes, of course. So sorry.
There are other people,
you know, Palmer.
Why don't you try them?
- Dalby's not to hear about this.
- You've already said that.
Or your past might catch up with you.
You'll find yourself in a military prison.
Good morning.
Thank you.
Champignons?
Nothing but the best for our Palmer.
You're working for Ross.
He sent you here.
Don't be silly. I'm working for Dalby.
You're working for Ross.
I'm working for Dalby,
you're working for...
Oh, what the hell?
Courtney, I am gonna cook you...
the best meal you've ever eaten.
That was the most delicious meal.
Good.
Do you always wear your glasses?
Yes.
Except in bed.
This is my itinerary for the weekend.
I want you to know where I am
in case you become desperate to see me.
- Considerate of you.
- If you spent it with me,
we would save ourselves
both a lot of bother.
Yours, I take it?
I'm sorry to spoil your weekend
but we're working tomorrow.
Saturday?
- Grantby's discontinued number?
- Turn it over.
- "The band of the Irish Guards. "
- And very good they are, too.
I think you'll find it most interesting.
I'll see you at the bandstand at...
three o'clock.
What's this called?
The Thin Red Line.
Good, patriotic stuff.
Got a proper rhythm to it.
Not quite your line, eh?
I prefer Bach or Mozart.
You're lucky, Mozart next.
Oh, really?
We are interested in a certain piece
of scientific equipment.
The proto-proton scattering device?
Quite so.
We understand that...
you hold the sole rights.
I wouldn't say that
I hold them personally.
A fine piece that.
Thank you. The band of the Irish Guards
would now like to play you
a light and classical overture,
this by Mozart - The Marriage Of Figaro.
There's a delicacy and precision
about Mozart's work.
Transcribes remarkably well
from the orchestra to the military band.
- Don't you agree?
- Oh, yes. Of course.
I might be able to arrange
those rights for you.
My principals are prepared to buy.
Shall we say 15,000?
My dear sir, this is not a clearance sale.
I can get a much better price than that.
20, then?
25.
- Agreed.
- Cash.
Here are the delivery arrangements.
Very neat.
Must we sit through any more
of this torture? I have things to do.
- I think they're playing very well.
- Tell me who wins.
Look out!
Congratulations, Palmer,
you've just killed an American agent.
The CIA should have let us know
they had a tail on Grantby.
Anyway, that'll teach them
not to poach on our preserve.
Tell me, Dalby, how is Radcliffe?
He doesn't remember being lifted.
Physically, he seems all right.
Just needs a few weeks rest.
- Keep the S1 surveillance on him.
- Mm-hm.
I'll put Palmer on him.
Do you think that's wise?
You know your own business best,
I suppose.
Ah. Very good tea.
Good morning.
Thank you.
Well, did you find it interesting?
Oh, yes.
Have you seen
the collection of portrait miniatures?
- No.
- No! Then we must go there tomorrow.
Yeah.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Palmer.
Bit of a rush but I think we'll make it.
- Out of breath, doctor?
- I'm all right.
In you go.
My dear fellow,
I'm delighted to see you looking so well.
- I'm sorry I'm late.
- Not at all.
- Shall we begin?
- Certainly.
I'll just say a few words
and then I'll leave it to you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you've probably all heard something
on our scientific bush telegraph
about Dr Radcliffe's
proto-proton scattering experiments.
It is largely due to Dr Radcliffe that
control of the fusion of hydrogen atoms,
and all that means in terms
of the world's energy resources,
is getting appreciably nearer every day.
So it is with great pleasure that I ask
Dr Radcliffe to give this symposium
his account
of the results of his latest work.
Thank you, Sir Robert.
Ladies and gentlemen...
today I shall be dealing with
a new meson production method...
which stems from the result...
...a new...
meson production...
A new...
meson production... method...
Dr Radcliffe, are you all right?
Hold it right there.
Over against the wall.
Right, now, don't move a muscle.
- I thought you British were subtle.
- Very subtle, like you.
- Trigger-happy, too.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm tailing you.
- Why?
Because you killed one of our men.
Uh-uh.
Open it.
- Why did you kill him?
- He came straight at me.
Yeah... that's what Dalby said.
- What do you know about Grantby?
- Nothing.
Now get this, I'm gonna tail you
till I know you're clean.
And if you're not clean...
I'm gonna kill you.
Ah, there you are, Dalby.
We'll lunch at my club -
we can walk there.
Good bit of lunch at your club, is it?
Not bad. The Dover sole's rather good.
Have you seen
the medical report on Radcliffe?
No.
The psychiatrist says he's suffering
from some form of amnesia.
Physically, he's perfectly normal
but he can no longer function
as a physicist.
Apparently, that part of his life
is a complete blank.
Scientist suddenly
becoming non-productive, eh?
Seems to fit in with
your brain-drain idea.
- Yes, exactly.
- What's our next move, then?
Grantby.
What sticks in my craw
is that he sold us damaged goods.
I've sent Palmer
to try and get the money back.
You don't think a man like Grantby
will do the right thing?
What shall I do? Pull him in, then?
No, I wouldn't advise that.
- Let's play him a little.
- It's dangerous.
- He could easily give us the slip.
- Oh, we'll take that risk.
If you say so.
- Incidentally...
- Hm?
...the Americans
have put a tail on Palmer.
How very tiresome of them.
If he's clean,
he's got nothing to worry about.
And if he isn't,
the Americans will take care of him -
save us a lot of bother.
- Good afternoon.
- Major Dalby sent me to see you.
- Indeed.
- Too tired to come himself?
- No.
It seems that you've been
slightly dishonest, Mr Grantby.
- The goods you sold us were damaged.
- I merely agreed to deliver him.
His condition is no concern of mine.
Nevertheless, we would like
our money back.
No. I am merely a pipeline.
You haven't been long
in this business but you'll learn.
Harry.
- What?
- Come here a minute.
What?
Round here,
I want to show you something.
"Induction of psychoneuroses
"by conditioned reflex under stress."
What does that mean?
It means I know why
17 scientists ceased to function.
- Yes?
- Look again, boy.
I-P-C-R-E-S-S.
Ipcress.
- Have you got your car outside?
- Yes.
I'm going to see Radcliffe.
I want to try a wee experiment.
Take a look at it while I'm away.
Be sure to lock it up after you.
Right.
Hello, Pat. This is Harry. What is it?
Yes.
Thank you.
Jock's dead.
He... He was shot in my car.
That American agent
must have thought it was me.
- You'd better move into my place.
- Yes.
I'll go and get my things.
Come on, I'll drop you off.
Palmer here, Major,
I must talk to you at once.
Very.
N... No, I can't talk on the telephone.
I must see you.
Yes. Yes, I know T108.
I hope this won't take too long.
I have an appointment for dinner.
All right. There's a dead
American agent in my flat.
- You killed him?
- Someone is trying to frame me.
Now, who would want to do
a thing like that?
Jock Carswell got somewhere with
the Ipcress file and he showed it to me.
I am being framed by whoever killed him.
- Can you prove any of this?
- The file was stolen from my desk.
By Grantby, of course.
No.
- Ross.
- Ross?
He once asked me
to microfilm the Ipcress file.
- Why didn't you tell me before?
- He'd have put me back in jail.
What time does
your cleaning woman arrive?
- About nine.
- Gives you exactly 12 hours.
Leave me to sort this out.
You, lose yourself.
Someone is trying to frame me,
you've got to help me.
But you're just too hot, Palmer.
Harry.
- They might be watching for you.
- I'll be watching for them.
I'll miss that train.
See you.
Colonel Ross, please.
'... leave platform 14
'will connect with
the transcontinental express for...
'... travelling via Prague,
Budapest and Belgrade.'
Thank you.
I'd like a word with you, sir.
Palmer's found a dead
American agent in his flat.
- Did he do it?
- He says not. Claims he's being framed.
- Where is he now?
- I don't know.
He also told me that you'd expressed
an interest in the Ipcress file.
Your department has developed
a remarkably high casualty rate.
- I wonder why.
- You better pick up Grantby.
I suggested that earlier.
Do it now, will you?
Billets.
- Yes?
- Tickets, please.
Hey!
Wait a minute.
- Who are you?
- I'm a doctor. Lie still, please.
What's wrong with these zombies?
Can't they speak?
You don't speak English in Albania.
- Albania?
- The land of my fathers.
This... starving and freezing...
won't work with me, Grantby.
- No?
- No.
I can resist it.
- I read the file.
- I know.
That's why you're here.
We'll give him two more days
then we'll start the treatment.
All right, zombie. All right.
How are you feeling?
- You're the doctor, you tell me.
- Do sit down.
He's ready.
The Gestapo and the MVD used to beat a
man for months to get him to this state.
But it's old-fashioned and crude.
And so slow.
Relax.
You are getting sleepy. Relax.
Quite relaxed.
'Listen to my voice. '
Nothing but my voice.
You will forget the Ipcress noise.
You will forget all about the Ipcress file.
'You will forget your name. '
Harry Palmer. My name is Harry Palmer.
You have no name.
No name.
'My name is Harry Palmer. Harry Palmer. '
My name is Harry Palmer.
He's using pain to distract himself.
Get him down.
Put padding on the straps next time.
- You want to make it easy for me?
- No. For me.
- He is difficult.
- He'll respond.
Intensify the treatment.
Every time he falls asleep,
wake him up and bring him here.
Ready.
Fit the rhythm of
the sound and vision to his brainwaves,
it'll make for a much deeper response.
Relax.
'Quite relaxed.
'Listen to my voice.
'Nothing but my voice.
'Relax. Relax'.
Quite relaxed.
You are getting sleepy.
Your eyelids are getting heavy.
Heavy as lead.
'Heavy as lead.
'You will try but
you can't open your eyes.
'You have forgotten the Ipcress noise.
'You have forgotten the Ipcress file. '
You have forgotten your name.
'What is your name? '
Now you will hear a voice say,
"Now listen to me. "
'You will always obey this voice. '
'Now, listen to me. Listen to me.
'You are here because you are a traitor.
'Listen to me.
'A traitor who killed
the agents of your allies.
'A traitor who stole the Ipcress file.
'A traitor who sold the Ipcress file
to an enemy of your country.
'Now, listen to me. Listen to me. '
Now repeat after me,
"Whenever I hear the voice say,
'Now, listen to me,' I will obey. "
"When I hear the voice say,
You will wake up when I count five.
You will forget what's happened to you
but you will remember your name.
One, two, three,
four...
five.
He's responding very well.
Aah!
Operator. CC1 exchange.
- Hello.
- This is Palmer.
Where are you?
In a call box at Austin's Wharf Lane.
Just a minute.
He's broken out.
- Is he programmed?
- I'd have preferred more treatments.
Try him.
Now, listen to me. Listen to me.
Are you listening?
- Yes.
- Phone Colonel Ross
and ask him to meet you
at the warehouse
then go back there yourself
and I will meet you there.
'Now, listen to me. Listen to me. '
Do it now, then hang up
and forget what I have just said.
Get those men
out of the warehouse immediately.
Palmer?
Stop, Major.
Don't say a word or I'll kill you.
Shut the door.
Don't say a word, not a word.
Right, over here.
There.
Get back to the wall, under the light.
Put it down.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Shut up.
Didn't tell me Dalby'd be here.
What has happened to you, Palmer?
One of you knows exactly
what has happened to me.
One of you is a double agent.
You're right, Palmer.
Who wanted you
to microfilm the Ipcress file?
I did that to test you.
Ross killed Carswell.
Don't be bloody ridiculous.
Ross couldn't have known that
Carswell had cracked the Ipcress file.
Courtney told him.
Jean was working for you?
Yes. I'd suspected this one
for some time.
It won't work, Ross.
You used Courtney
just as you've tried to use Palmer.
Ross killed the CIA man.
He framed you.
- You bastard.
- Oh dear!
You used to call me
a passed-over major.
Now, listen to me. Listen to me.
Shoot Ross.
Shoot the traitor... now.
I was counting on you being
an insubordinate bastard, Palmer.
You used me as a decoy.
I might have been killed
or driven stark, raving mad.
That's what you're paid for.
Thank you.