THE OTHER HALF
- Any relatives in Switzerland?
- No.
What kind of rep are you?
Hair products.
GENEVA
Hamid, look me in the eyes.
Can I still trust you?
Yes, of course.
Your papers, please.
Could I see your briefcase?
- What is this?
- A gift for a friend.
BRUSSELS
They checked my bag
on the train.
I hid the contents
in the toilet.
- Did you open the jar?
- Yes, of course.
You mustn't know
what you're carrying.
They were onto me
at the border
because of my passport.
They wouldn't have checked,
had you not opened the jar.
We'll talk about it
in my office tomorrow.
- Prayer?
- Yes, of course.
Hit me again, Anita!
Thanks.
I'd do her!
Say that again?
C'mon, say it again!
Say it!
Enough!
Leave him alone!
I didn't say anything!
Wait for me outside.
How was your day?
You look tired.
Did you bring me back anything?
No.
Not even cream
or shampoo samples?
What are we doing on Saturday?
Did you invite anybody over?
- Are you ashamed of me?
- Are you surprised?
The way you flaunt your ass
at work!
Are you jealous?
It bothers you that
men pay attention to me?
You're such a jealous man!
In a month, we'll be able
to apply for a passport.
- Then you can leave me.
- I won't.
You don't need anybody.
Drop it.
Come pick me up tonight?
Don't forget the samples!
Hello? Louis?
Louis who?
I have no brother.
Not interested.
Hello?
I don't know you.
I have no brother called Louis.
Stop pissing me off!
Take a seat.
Here, new name, new passport,
so you needn't worry.
The cops are watching me.
- Did they question you?
- They called.
To tell you,
"This is the police"?
It's not funny.
They pretended
to be someone else.
- Who?
- My brother.
- You have a brother?
- Yeah.
I haven't seen him in 30 years.
It must be a cop ruse.
It scares me.
Why wouldn't it be your brother?
He doesn't know where I am.
I should stop traveling
for a while.
You have a new passport,
you can take a little trip.
Nothing unusual.
Really?
I'm fed up of taking risks
for next to nothing.
I carry fortunes for EUR 500!
Risks? At worst,
they send you back to Algeria.
It's your country.
I doubt you'd be willing
to go back.
I'll pay you EUR 3,000
for this trip.
It's for financing
a school in Saudi Arabia.
It's a privilege.
Think of the community.
Why so quiet?
The community, the fight...
Two years in jail make you see
things differently.
Don't talk to me like that.
The community
didn't send you to jail!
At one point,
I thought you were watching me.
I'm busy now, come by tonight.
We can talk quietly.
I'm buying dinner, OK?
It's Louis, I mean Lunes.
Do whatever you want, Hamid,
but Mom's in the hospital.
It's pretty serious.
She'd like to see you.
I'll be at the Neuchâtel train
station bar tomorrow morning.
I'll wait till 10 AM.
If you don't come, don't worry,
you'll never hear from me again.
- You're early.
- Can I have some fruit juice?
Got your brother's message?
Why didn't you tell me
you had family in Switzerland?
I don't know anything about you.
It's as if you're hiding.
What are we doing on Saturday?
Did you invite anyone?
Wanna come have dinner
Saturday night?
- Leave him alone.
- What?
Nothing. He's my husband.
No luck.
Inviting people isn't my thing.
- What's that bag for?
- I gotta go.
When are you coming back?
You don't care about anything.
Me, you...
Hamid!
- Hello.
- Coffee, please.
- Hamid?
- Yes.
It's me, Louis! Lunes.
- Had a good trip?
- Yes.
No hug?
I've always dreamed of this.
- Shall we go?
- How did you find me?
- To find you?
- How'd you get my number?
It was in Mom's things.
She didn't know
I was in Brussels.
- She had your number in Algeria.
- She contacted me there?
Of course.
Shall I put some music on?
What do you like? Rock, blues...
What happened to her?
She was on her moped
and got hit by a truck.
- How come?
- That's what the police said.
I don't know her any more
than you do.
After your departure,
she left me with Grandma.
- I was 3.
- And I, 5.
She wanted to start over.
Her child was in the way.
I always pictured you living
happily with her in Switzerland.
Not at all.
- She wrote to me now and then.
- Really? What about?
That she wanted to come
to Algeria with you,
that she was thinking of me.
I'm about to see her
37 years later.
Can you believe it?
SWISS JURA
Did you talk to the doctor
since the accident?
Listen, the hospital called
this morning.
- Mom didn't make it.
- She died?
Why didn't you say so earlier?
- Drive me back to the station!
- It's a quick drive.
- Just see what my car's made of!
- Mom died and you talk cars?
Drive me back!
You can wait a bit.
We can get to know each other.
Drop me off anywhere.
I'll manage alone.
What's the rush? You can take
a memento from her house.
- I don't want one!
- It won't take long.
I said no!
We're almost there.
It's behind that hill.
Are you jerking me around?
You're insane!
OK.
I'll drive you back
after I call my girlfriend.
- Did you call your girlfriend?
- Yes.
- What's her name?
- Isabella.
She just called
on the other cell.
Spying on me?
She didn't pick up,
so I left her a message.
- Are you married?
- Yes.
Is she pretty?
When I was 5, Mom and I wanted
to come see you and Dad.
It was Christmastime.
I'd packed my suitcase.
We were in Grandma's kitchen
when Mom walked in.
She sat down at the table
and started to cry.
Grandma told me to go
to my room, to stay away.
I was scared.
Later, but much later,
she told me Dad had died.
- I gotta go back to Brussels.
- I tell you about Mom
- and you tell me about Dad.
- I've nothing to say.
I don't get it.
Aren't we brothers?
So? You want to make up
for 30 years in 5 minutes?
Yeah.
- Why are you driving so fast?
- Habit. I drive often.
I work for an art auction house
in Geneva.
I'm in charge of
security and shipping.
I also sell works of art:
Russian icons...
It's extra money.
Isa doesn't know anything.
- Shit!
- I told you, you were speeding.
Don't worry about it.
Hello.
- We were going a little fast.
- License and registration.
- We have a death in the family.
- Your papers?
- He's my brother.
- I don't drive.
- I'd like to see some ID.
- Why?
Don't argue.
I'll be right back.
They're such a pain.
- Follow us. We'll escort you.
- Why?
What is the problem? I'll pay
the ticket and we're good.
I asked you to follow us.
Got it?
No, but it's OK,
we'll follow you.
POLICE STATION
My name is Scherrer.
I'm with the Terrorist Squad.
- I'd like to talk to you.
- I have nothing to say.
I don't even know why I'm here.
- What do you do for a living?
- Hair products rep.
Really?
Why did you leave Algeria?
For no particular reason.
What about your 2-year stint in jail?
You had contact
with the Islamists.
You were once involved with ISF
and now with an illegal network.
You're a courier for the hawala.
Youssef Madani.
He's a friend.
We met at a wedding.
Brahim Khaffaf.
He owns a grocery store
in Geneva.
Isn't this you?
So?
I'm in front of a grocery store
talking to a grocer.
Three days ago,
you entered Switzerland
with a different passport
than the one you presented us.
We've been watching you
for a while now.
I don't understand.
The hawala is a system for
financing terrorist attacks.
People die because of you.
Do you even realize it?
I don't know who uses
the system. It's anonymous.
The hawala is the way
poor people transfer money.
Immigrants use it
to feed their families.
- Illegally.
- Your laws make it illegal.
You've everything.
We've nothing.
I'm asking you to collaborate,
not to make a political speech.
Otherwise, you'll be handcuffed
and sent to Algiers tomorrow.
- We don't want people like you.
- It's terrible there.
I want you to make a list of
everything you've delivered,
the names, addresses, codes
- and the amounts.
- You want me to betray friends?
I already told you,
it's an anonymous system.
Nobody knows what that money
is used for.
It's based on trust.
You don't have a Belgian
passport or refugee status,
collaborate or kiss
Europe goodbye.
No. I can't.
I couldn't live with myself.
Take him away.
What do they want?
- Wait!
- Why were you speeding?
- No talking for 24 hours.
- Hamid, I'll get you out.
Mr. Valence,
come into my office.
Your brother paid your bail.
He's waiting outside.
The examining judge
made this decision, not me.
Of course,
there's the funeral to attend.
You can't leave the country
and you have to provide us
with an address.
You will remain at the disposal
of the police 24 hours a day.
I expect to see you in my office
tomorrow at 8 AM.
Bring the list.
Hamid?
- Yes.
- I'm Isabella.
- Louis's girlfriend?
- Yes.
He went to get croissants.
Did you see that shop?
It's funny.
I wondered if I lived here,
what I'd pick
if I wanted to buy myself
a gift.
- What would you pick?
- I don't know!
Introduced yourselves yet?
Hamid, my brother.
Sounds funny.
- Were they a pain to you?
- Any idea where I was?
- What are you doing?
- I paid your bail.
The examining judge said
you have to be there at 8 AM.
- What do they want?
- Why did you pay my bail?
- You couldn't stay in jail.
- I would've been out in 2 days.
That's what you think.
Shall we?
They won't wait for us.
They said you worked for
the hawala, some kind of mafia.
I didn't even know it existed.
Ever heard of it?
Let's say you live in Brussels
and you want to transfer money.
You go to a hawala shop
or restaurant, give money,
and they give you a code.
You call your payee,
give him the code,
so he's able to receive money
in a shop in his country
that's involved in the hawala,
right?
Billions are transferred
this way every year.
Without paying taxes!
600 billion dollars
are transferred without a trace.
It drives the cops mad!
But there's a weak link:
the couriers.
If the police ID them,
they can dismantle the network.
You're a courier, right?
That takes a lot of courage.
Cut it out, Louis.
- How much was my bail?
- CHF 30,000.
- Where did you find the money?
- I managed.
- I don't like this.
- You could thank me.
I didn't ask you for anything.
What do you mean, "you managed"?
I managed!
It's none of your business.
Lord, please take
Marie-Rose Valence
who passed away.
Lord Jesus,
we entrust her to You,
Who will open the gates
to Your heavenly kingdom.
Amen.
This is it!
I'll leave you now.
- You're not staying?
- Burning a body is a sin.
- Really?
- Did she want to be incinerated
- or was it your decision?
- It was hers.
I would've liked to see her.
We're waiting for the urn.
This feels very funny.
Death helps us focus
on what is important.
I don't need your pity.
What makes you think it's pity?
What is it, then?
I don't know. You looked sad.
Shall we go?
I only saw her once a year,
at Christmas.
Now that she's dead,
it's as if she were a stranger.
You can sleep here, if you want.
Does it suit you?
Yes.
I've to go back to Geneva.
I'm teaching at 8 AM.
If she goes back,
we can spend time together.
- Relax. What's the matter?
- It feels so small now.
The bed used to be there!
This used to be our bedroom!
- Can I shower?
- Go ahead.
What do you want to do now?
For me, it's simple.
I feel as though I haven't lived
all that I wanted to live.
That's it.
What about you?
Think this is the right time
to discuss this?
Yes.
You want to stay in Geneva
in your apartment?
You want to live here?
What about us?
Do you want kids?
They'd have to be
5 or 6 years old at birth.
- I can't stand babies.
- Be serious.
- Do you want kids or not?
- Yes.
Stop it!
What's the matter?
Don't you love me?
We invited the neighbors
for drinks.
I hope it won't be awkward.
- Won't you help me?
- Yes.
- Are you married?
I was denied political asylum.
It was the only way
I could stay in Belgium.
How's that going?
It mustn't be easy?
No, it isn't.
Can I come to Geneva with you?
I have some friends there.
- What about Louis?
- I'll tell him
I'd rather go to Geneva.
- Want some?
- No, thanks.
You don't drink
because you're religious?
No, I just don't want any.
- Shall I put some music on?
- Yes.
I'm sure this music reminded her
of her husband and sons.
I can't stand it. Stop it.
What was Dad like?
Did he play with you,
teach you things?
Mom never talked about him.
I found this postcard
in Mom's things.
"Dear Marie-Rose,
I hope you're well.
"Hamid is in good health.
He's in first grade.
"I hope to see you by the end
of the year here in Algeria.
"All my love, your husband,"
"Areski."
"Hamid is in good health."
I don't exist.
- He never mentions me.
- Drop it, it's been a long time.
I wanna know what Dad was like!
What about Mom?
She was nothing.
She was invisible, fleeting.
She couldn't stay home with you.
She had to work.
You can't judge her.
Mom's things are downstairs,
if you wanna see them.
This is it!
I put everything that's left
in this trashcan.
You can pick what you want.
You were quick! You emptied
everything in one day.
The longer you wait,
the harder it is.
- Tell me more about Algeria.
- There's nothing to say.
You must still
have contacts there?
- Is there evidence against you?
- Scherrer's imagining things.
You fill bank accounts.
Remember?
We used to play with it.
I called your uncle. He said
he didn't know where you lived.
Did he raise you?
- Did you argue?
- Is this an interrogation?
No, I'm your brother.
What is a brother?
What?
Why are you asking me
all these questions?
- Don't you see it bothers me?
- I want to get to know you.
Fine, but how do I know
you're my brother?
Very well,
I'm not your brother.
The door is open, you can leave.
C'mon, scram!
Get lost!
Don't leave me alone
with the guests!
Tell him about his father.
He knows nothing about him.
- Am I early?
- It doesn't matter.
I live next door.
I knew Marie-Rose well.
This is Django, her cat.
I took him in after the crash.
He was lost,
but maybe you want him back?
It's best if you keep him.
- Good evening.
- Come in.
We worked together for 20 years
in the factory.
Of course, I'll miss her.
She was a good woman.
A really good woman.
- This is Hamid, Louis's brother.
- Hello.
I gotta go.
- Don't you wanna hear the rest?
- She was a good person.
That's all I need to know.
Bye!
- What are you doing?
- Why do you own a weapon?
- You're a cop?
- You looked through my stuff?
You're a cop!
Stop it!
Come back, Hamid!
Hamid!
- What's going on?
- We had a fight.
We'll leave you, then.
- Bye.
- Wait!
I wanted to hear more
about my parents.
How was my dad?
Your mother was very strong,
very brave.
We were happy to see him leave.
Why?
Did he drink?
Was he violent?
What happened with Hamid?
I'm tired of being
kept in the dark.
- Isa...
- I don't need to know, right?
How did you find the money
for the bail?
It's a scheme of mine.
I didn't come all the way here
to hear this.
I wanted us to get closer,
to talk.
You must think I'm a fool.
Isa, wait! I'll explain.
I sold an icon that was stolen.
I have to give back that money.
The cops are watching me.
- You can't leave me now.
- You did this for your brother?
Yes... No, but I'm gonna put
an end to this.
You lied to me.
That's all you do.
Constantly.
Isa, wait.
I'm heading back to Geneva.
Sorry, it's a little messy.
I rushed to meet Louis as soon
as I found out about his mom.
I was gone 3 days,
but it seems so far away.
Three days?
- When did she pass away?
- Three days ago.
- That's not what Louis told you?
- No.
He's a little twisted.
I don't get it.
- What would you like to drink?
- Some wine.
What kind of work do you do?
I work with children
who have pronunciation
and comprehension problems.
- What do you do with them?
- Exercises.
I tell a child, "go in the room
and take the scissors,"
but he doesn't understand
the word "scissors."
So?
I go in the room with the child
and I tell him,
"This is the room.
These are the scissors."
- Did you take anything else?
- No.
Anyway, nobody wanted it.
Why don't you like this music?
My dad listened to it
all the time.
- How old were you when he died?
- Seven.
I don't know if our parents
even wanted us.
Why not?
Your parents loved each other.
They were brave.
An Algerian man,
a Swiss woman...
- How old are your students?
- Wanna see them?
Isa, open up!
I know you're there.
We have to talk.
Not now. Go home.
- No, let me in!
- Stop screaming!
I'll stay on the landing,
but open the door.
- Are you with someone?
- I'm with Hamid.
- Hamid?
- Don't start fighting again.
Hamid, come with me.
I paid your bail.
How much did the cops pay you?
What?
What are you doing in there?
Go home now. It's enough.
Open up!
Hamid, I'm your brother.
You can't do this.
Muslim, my ass!
I have to go.
You don't have to feel guilty.
I used to have a friend there
when I was 7.
Whenever I'd go sleep over,
his mom would sit
on the edge of the bed
and tell me a story.
A normal thing
in a normal family.
It made me cry.
Can we talk a little?
It's 2 AM. Who are you?
Who is it?
It'd be better inside.
- Please.
- No.
Leave or I call the cops.
Where's Louis?
He owes us CHF 30,000.
Shit!
What's with this mess?
Isa?
Who were those 2 brutes?
They were looking for you.
Who were they?
I'll pay for the damages.
What did they want? Why didn't
the cop downstairs intervene?
I owe them money.
I'll pay it back.
- Everything will be like before.
- You disgust me.
I didn't want this.
What did you two do?
What did you do with my brother?
He fucked me and made me come.
Happy now? You can leave.
Leave!
I'd rather be alone.
- Stop it!
- I could kill you!
Louis!
- Gimme back my money, asshole!
- Buzz off!
Get up!
Buzz off!
Fast!
Clear off!
What's this about?
Who are these people?
I acted as a go-between for them
and a collector.
It was a stolen icon.
I kept their money.
- I used it to bail you out.
- You did that for me?
It's the last time I deal.
I'm gonna stop this.
Let's go get a drink.
- Whisky, as usual?
- Coffee.
- Get a whisky for once.
- No.
We fought against them together,
we can have the same drink.
- So take a coffee, then.
- Two coffees and 2 whiskies.
OK.
It's our first photo together.
What is Isa doing now?
I got it all wrong with her.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
- Two whiskies. Enjoy!
- Thanks.
Sometimes, when I was a kid,
at Grandma's, I wouldn't sleep.
I would think about you.
I'd tell myself you were doing
the same thing.
So I'd imagine all the silly
things we'd do together:
go to the movies, play soccer,
flirt with girls.
Things were different for me.
I thought you and Mom
were a lot luckier than I was.
Why did you stay there
after he died?
My uncle came to get me.
He took me in.
He wanted me
to have a Muslim education.
He was tyrannical.
I've only known people like
that all my life.
Was Dad like that too?
He was weak, fragile,
a weird man...
He liked gambling, showing off.
He tried to work
but never managed to keep a job.
So he went back.
I think I drank too much.
For the first time,
I feel like you're my brother.
It's moving.
Let's go to Algeria together,
so you can show me
your playground, your school.
I can't go back.
I'd end up in jail.
Scherrer'll send me back
if I don't collaborate.
And yet, I can't do it.
I decided to stop the hawala.
I made my decision in Brussels
before I left.
I was only doing it
for the money.
You're not going
to your appointment?
You'll lose your bail.
I don't care.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, how are you?
- OK.
I was wrong about you.
I thought you were working
for the cops.
I need to use the men's room.
The drinks
are making me nauseous.
- Why did you lie to me?
- What?
She died 3 days ago.
Why didn't you tell me anything
when you called me in Brussels?
Why did you tell me
she was in the hospital?
I had to meet you, to get you
to come to Switzerland.
If you don't tell me everything,
I'm leaving. It's over.
- Scherrer forced me to do this.
- Scherrer?
He gave me your address.
So Scherrer is behind the story
with the Russians too?
- He forced me.
- Why?
They came
so you'd buy the bail story.
They were cops, actually.
He told me you were dangerous,
that you were an Islamist
involved in the hawala.
That's why
they were watching you.
He said I could save lives.
What would you have done?
I didn't know you!
What I did was lame.
I messed up everything.
And yet,
I always dreamed of meeting you.
Don't come near me!
I could kill you.
I was facing charges
for trafficking.
My hands were tied.
I had to accept.
Why are you talking to me
in Arabic?
I was ready to trust you!
Screw other people, not me!
I never want to see you again!
- Hi, it's me.
- Hamid? Where are you?
In Geneva.
I have problems with the police
because of Algeria.
- I have to leave.
- Where are you gonna go?
- Want me to come along?
- No.
So I won't see you again?
I'll try to call,
I just wanted to say bye.
Thanks for all the things
you've done for me.
I'm sorry.
You deserved better.
I hope we'll meet again
some day.
Please forgive me.
Ciao.
So?
I was supposed to go to the
police this morning but didn't.
They're after you.
- They want to nab you.
- I know.
They blocked one of my accounts.
- What did you tell them?
- Nothing. They wanna deport me.
I have to leave Switzerland.
Can you help?
I spoke to Youssef on the phone.
You left without saying bye.
Did he tell you about the jars?
I did that to save your bacon.
I traveled a lot.
I know the network.
I won't rat you out,
even if you don't help me.
Calm down, Hamid.
I'll organize your trip
to Marseille.
- Need a new passport?
- Yes, fast.
Meet you at 5 at the hammam.
There's a hotel near the hammam,
if you want to rest.
Why not.
The owner is a friend.
I'll call him
and then get back to you.
By tonight, you'll be in France.
Yes, I'm here. Thanks.
This way.
We lost track of him
because of you.
You shook us off at 3 AM
and turned off your cell phone.
- We had an agreement.
- Yes, to bring him in
for questioning,
but you locked him up.
- You can't tell us what to do.
- What about the bail story
and the 2 Russians,
your men,
hired to lure my brother in?
That wasn't part of the deal,
and yet, I played along.
Did you get any info?
He didn't trust me
and he was right not to.
I'm stopping everything.
You didn't obtain any info
and you expect us to forget
your icon trafficking?
I did everything I could
and more, much more!
- It's gone too far.
- Not in these cases.
If he weren't dangerous,
he would've showed up at 8 AM.
Why did your 2 Russian cops
wreck my girlfriend's apartment?
'Cause he's dangerous?
I don't like your methods,
Mr. Scherrer.
You used me.
If you don't want to retract
the charges, I don't care.
I'm fed up and ashamed of this,
you understand?
I don't!
We're fighting terrorism
and you betrayed me!
Sir,
- we found him.
- Don't move, I'll be back.
He's in a hammam.
A hammam?
Rashid just called.
Your passport's ready.
He'll come with you
to Marseille.
Everything's OK.
You can relax.
There's only one hammam
in Geneva? What's the address?
Yes, I know the place. Thanks.
- This way.
- Thanks.
- Hamid?
- What are you doing here?
I'm here to help you.
Listen to me, Hamid.
Listen to me. Please, Hamid.
The cops know you're here.
Leave!
Wait! The clothes!
Let me go through.
Buzz off!!
Rashid, don't stay there.
Go get the car!
Hamid!
- Scram!
- Listen...
- Police! Stop!
- Get in!
- I can't leave him here.
Quick!
No!
- Get in!
- No!
- Are you gonna be OK?
- It's fine. It's nothing.
It's OK.
Do you have the keys?
In my pocket.
- I'll go get the car.
- Let's go together.
Police! Don't panic.
Don't move. Everything's fine.
Face against the wall!
The 3 men on the right.
Stand up.
Surround the car!
On the floor!
Against the wall! Fast!
Come forward. Against the wall.
Careful, he must be armed.
Search him! Go ahead.
CROIX-DE-ROZON CUSTOMS
It happened in December.
I was 7 years old.
I was coming home from school.
It was dark outside.
I found him in the kitchen.
He'd hanged himself.
He was just like you.
He was lawless.
Always short of money.
He wanted to be loved
but did everything he could
for us to hate him.
- Did you hate him?
- I was angry at him
because he brought me there.
- Are you still upset with him?
- No.
Are you upset with me?
No.
Translation: TV5 Québec Canada