[MUSIC PLAYING]
WOMAN: You stupid piece of shit.
You're not worth shit.
And if I ever catch you with your hands on my sister again,
so help me god.
MAN: You shut up, asshole.
Hey, no one tells me to shut the fuck up.
Hey, fuck you, man.
Fuck you, you little shit.
Yeah, love is in the air tonight.
Mm-hmm.
I guess.
Hey, it's 10 o'clock.
Don't you kids think you ought to be--
Fuck you, man.
Shut the fuck up.
[LAUGHS] Let me have the, uh, dog
with some mustard and relish.
What are you doing?
We got a call.
What am I doing?
I'm getting a hot dog.
What is it about you?
What are you doing, OK?
Every time I want to take a leap,
you say, what are you doing? What are you doing?
Hey, you've been sleeping alone too long.
Now, what you need is some serious trim.
Trim?
Yeah, baby.
Some wrap around hold on tight squeeze it
real right low down juicy trim.
[LAUGHS] You're coming on to me.
You want me, don't you? - No.
- No, I know you want me. - Uh-uh.
You do. I know what you mean.
Man, I haven't had a white boy since the high school football
team.
The whole football team?
The whole team.
[LAUGHS] Bunch of asshole.
MAN: Shut the fuck up!
WOMAN: Shut up?
I'm leaving, Vic.
I've had it with you.
I ain't staying here.
Do you hear me?
Yeah, I heard you and so the whole rest
of the fucking building, you whore.
Whore?
Now, I'm a whore?
Goddammit.
I had to listen to that kind of shit from you,
you stupid junkie. - Junkie?
You piece of shit.
Now, listen to me, child.
When I lay down and open up my legs--
You could just ask me.
I want a man, not some tight asshole white boy
who's going to be on you and then
in and out and out the door before you
get your panties down good.
Do your mommy know you talk like this?
Like what?
What are you going to do, cut me?
Are you going to cut me? - You piece of shit.
Go ahead. Try and cut me.
Try and cut me.
Come on.
[KNOCKING]
Can you just--
See what you did?
Cops are here.
MAN: Open the door.
[KNOCKING]
Police officer.
Open the door.
What the fuck, man?
You want to stand back.
Now, stand back.
Are you all right, ma'am?
[SOBBING]
What are you doing?
You're beating up on your woman here?
Hey, she's got a knife, man.
She's trying to kill me.
Huh.
You want to press charges?
Hey, she don't want to press nothing.
Yes, I do.
You son of a bitch, I'm going to press
you all the way to prison.
Yeah, why not?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Fuck you.
[GRUNTS]
MAN: Piece of shit.
Son of a bitch.
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
Wilma!
WOMAN: Oh, my god.
[GRUNTS] This motherfucker.
She's a bitch.
Jesus, Jackie.
You threw her out the fucking window.
What the hell was I supposed to do?
Restrain and subdue.
Well, from this point of view, she
looks pretty damn subdued, huh.
What a fucking night.
MAN: Open.
Close.
Tight enough?
It's fine.
Then we're ready.
Bobby?
Now is now.
Ready.
MAN: How are you today, Bobby?
I'm fine.
And thank you very much for the opportunity, Mr. Lawrence
You're very welcome, Bobby.
Do you have your lines now?
BOBBY: Yes, sir.
We've been rehearsing all morning.
Thank you very much.
I understand that you're nervous, Bobby.
We all are the first time.
Let me tell you about nerves.
It's your talent trying to come out.
It's all right to come out here.
Thank you, Mr. Lawrence.
Thank you.
Always check the gun to make sure it's safe.
OK, let's go for one.
Sweat him up.
And action.
You want to play?
You want to play, you smelly fucks?
OK, let's play.
You and me, let's play.
No, Bobby.
It's about the fear.
Play the fear.
You're about to pick up a gun, put it to your head
and pull the trigger.
Once more.
Action.
You want to play?
All right.
We got ourselves a game, man.
Let's play.
You and me, let's play this fucking thing.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Pick it up.
Let's play. Fuck you!
Fuck you! Come on.
Fuck you!
Fuck you, son of a bitch.
Fuck you. Fuck you!
[GRUNTS]
MAN: Pick it up.
Come on.
Yes, Bobby.
Ah!
[LAUGHING]
MR. LAWRENCE: Yes.
Do it.
Yes, pull it.
Pull the trigger.
Do it.
[GUNSHOT]
[CAMERA ROLLING]
[GAGS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Wake up.
Oh, great.
[SOBS] Thank you.
Thank you, Bobby.
That's the way it should've been shot originally.
Ugh.
Christmas.
Hollywood.
Present.
Come on.
WOMAN: If I had known he was married with two kids,
I would have--
Can I start over?
Mm-hmm.
WOMAN: Need a BLT, no mayo.
Extra cream cheese.
If I had known he was married with two kids,
I would have never gone out with him.
Never.
You just got to believe me.
Three kids.
Three?
And pregnant.
Does he know?
Ugh.
Wow.
W-O-W. You blew me away.
And when you said, does he know?
You had me believing that you really wanted to know.
So I wanted to know.
Do you know what I mean?
It's a really good movie script.
Yeah.
If the director doesn't fuck it up,
we could do some real numbers at the box office.
Now, tomorrow, you meet the director.
[GIGGLES]
MAN: Mm-hmm.
But honey, I want you to dress the part.
[VOCALIZING]
Mr. Jerry, that's an awful lot--
Honey, call me Latin Jerry.
Latin Jerry.
It's an awful lot of money.
Honey, I want you to get the best.
I want you to go to Trashy Lingerie on La Cienega.
And you just get the sexiest negligee you can find.
I don't know.
Honey, if you do this, this part is yours.
I guarantee it.
What about me?
Are you going to put me in your film, huh?
No shit.
It's Dick fucking Tracy.
Dick Tracy, yeah.
I bet you'd love some Dick Tracy, wouldn't you, huh?
What are you doing?
Are you having some soup?
Aw!
My god, excuse me.
Let me cool that off.
Motherfuck-- ah!
Shit.
JACK: Now, between you and me, where is she?
Check.
Fuck you!
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
No? No, you don't?
Where is she?
Goddammit, you tell me where she is now.
LATIN JERRY: I got her a gig at Blue Angel.
I'm going to fucking kill you.
Promise.
Look for it.
Get away from me.
Now.
Fuck you!
Sit down.
You know who that is?
His name's Latin Jerry.
He wants to represent me.
Sweetheart, that scum is a pimp.
You know what a pimp is?
A pornographer?
They take innocent little people like you
and turn you into granite in this town.
But he said--
Ah.
This town's based on, he said.
Look, do me a favor, your parents
a favor, yourself a favor.
Get the hell out of here, all right?
Go home to your little town.
Marry the boy next door.
Have babies before you become another hooker in a body bag,
all right?
Just get the hell out of here.
Right.
Look, if you need me, you call.
All right?
[SIGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
When I found out it was my sister's husband,
it just turn me on more.
The closer he got, the hotter I got.
I knew it was wrong but I couldn't help myself.
Oh, yeah, baby. It's big.
It's black. It's mine.
And now, it's yours.
It's inside you.
Yeah, touch it. Yeah, touch it.
Yeah. Ooh.
Oh. Yeah, baby.
Yeah. Oh, oh, oh.
Over, under, around you, inside you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Baby, I'm your blood.
I'm your-- hello?
Hello?
You cut me off.
You cut off the 16-minute, man.
Hey, take the boat back to Bangladesh, buddy.
Fuck you! - Excuse me.
Yeah, fuck you.
What the hell is going on in here?
Can I help you?
Yes, ma'am.
I was thinking maybe, uh, you guys could talk dirty to me.
You want me to talk dirty to you?
- Yeah. - That's what you want?
- Uh-huh. - Well, how about this?
Get the fuck out of here, cop.
Is that dirty enough for you?
We're legal here.
You're legal here?
Yeah.
What about back there, huh?
I said we're-- you can't go back there.
No?
Hey, you got a search warrant?
Hey, asshole!
Call my attorney now.
[MOANING]
MAN: Silly little bitch.
Silly little bitch.
Hey! Hey.
What are you doing with your-- - Now, here.
You like this stuff, huh?
That's for you.
Get the fuck out of here.
Get out of here.
What are you doing?
You told me you're going home.
Huh?
What's the matter with you?
I needed a little extra cash.
Here's some cash.
Why didn't you come to me, hmm?
Goddammit, Janet.
Get dressed.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Sara. SARA: Hey, Jack.
How are you?
I've been looking all over for you.
- Uh-huh? - Listen.
Do me a favor, will you? - Oh, no.
Oh, no.
Just type a report for me, please.
- No more, please. - Please.
Hey.
You still owe me dinner from the last time, right?
I took you to dinner.
Jack, McDonald's does not count.
I'm English.
I want something a little classy.
Look, help me out, all right?
I got to get this kid to the bus station.
Please.
What's it worth?
- You want dinner? - Yeah.
You want dinner?
Where?
Your house, at the beach, candlelight, soft music.
You're married, Sara.
So?
SARA: Well, since when did that stop you?
JACK: So you do this?
I'm going to need some notes though.
I got notes.
Here, let me take that.
Thank you.
- Oh, I got to work on this-- - Phone number.
Phone number. - Ugh.
You know, while we're at it, nicotine and caffeine,
something has to go.
How about this? - Thank you.
Um.
[PHONE RINGING]
Grace, what the hell are they doing?
Jack.
This is bullshit.
No, I have this whole thing covered.
- Jack, it's policy. - She doesn't need a shrink.
She doesn't need a shrink.
It will be fine.
She needs a--
Oh, god.
It's not going to be fine.
You know what she's going to want?
A second opinion. I know this guy.
Look, maybe we can persuade the doctor to-- to let her go.
You think I want to type out another report?
Talk a bit?
Listen, Delbert.
We got-- we're in a hurry.
We got to put her on a bus tonight.
I want a second opinion.
I want to ask Jackson.
Oh, what about my opinion?
Doesn't that count?
Listen, god-- goddammit, Delbert.
You know what Jackson's going to do?
He's going to commit her.
Now, you got a 16-year-old girl in there scared to death.
Let's just put her on a bus and get her the hell
out of here, all right?
And this is crap.
Listen, Jack.
Regardless what you may think, I'm here to help.
That girl's been through a hellish experience.
If she doesn't work through this now,
it's going to haunt her for the rest of her life.
She needs me right now.
Just like you might need me someday, Jack.
Oh.
Let me do my job.
Delbert, let me tell you something.
I'm never going to need you. Do you understand?
Now, I talked to this kid's parents.
They sent her money and a bus ticket.
I saw it.
I saw the tickets too.
I saw the tickets.
What is this, show and tell?
She wants to go home, Delbert.
Not a chance.
Hey, come on, doctor.
Let-- let him put her on the bus.
Let her go home.
If she comes back, god forbid, then-- then we'll pick her up
and we'll do it your way.
OK.
All right.
Have it your way.
I bet you any amount of money, she'll be back in two days.
She's all yours.
Where did they find him?
I need a word with her.
OK?
Yeah.
OK, young lady.
So you're going home.
You know, I've arranged for you to see a counselor twice
a week, someone just like me.
You, uh, promise you'll go?
I guess.
You know, uh, Jack's been really rooting for you.
And, uh, I don't want you to let him down.
And don't come back.
I won't.
Let's go.
Let's get out of here.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
You know, I grew up in these streets.
Hollywood.
It was a lot different back then.
JANET: What was it like?
Safe.
Clean.
Hell, it was even glamorous.
I actually saw Roy Rogers and Dale Evans riding their horses
right down this street.
JANET: Guess I was born 50 years too late.
50 years?
No, no, no.
It wasn't that long ago.
Thank you.
Huh.
Damn.
[SOBS]
[SIGHS]
Are you all right?
Yeah.
So what's in the envelope?
My items.
Your what?
My photos.
Yeah.
Can I see one?
[LAUGHS] That's beautiful.
Hmm.
Can I have an autograph, ma'am?
You sure can.
To my friend, Jack.
Thanks.
You're welcome, Janet.
[SIGHS] Come on, let's go.
No, Jack.
Believe me, I can get on the bus.
Trust me.
Yeah?
OK.
And goodbye.
Goodbye.
Thanks.
Get out of here, kid.
Go home.
Bye.
[SIGHS] You're done good, Jack.
It's a good thing.
A good thing.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
WOMAN: Don't move.
And don't make a sound.
All right.
Just relax.
Tell me what you want.
I got the gun.
I ask the questions.
Well, you do have a gun, don't you?
WOMAN: Drop everything.
Very good.
Now, little piggy, take your gun out and put it on the floor.
Do it.
All right.
Slowly.
Good boy.
Kick it over here.
Do I know you?
Johnny O.
Johnny who?
WOMAN: Come on, Jack.
You remember.
Johnny O. You put him away 16 months ago.
Guess what?
He hung himself last night in San Quentin.
He was my baby brother, you son of a bitch.
All right, lady.
Look, I'm-- I'm sorry about your brother.
But I had a long night.
And I got the shit kicked out of me.
So if you want to do me a favor, you just
pull the trigger, all right?
Come on, lady.
Put me out of my misery.
Pull the goddamn trigger.
Pull it.
Bang.
Where have you been, stranger?
Mm.
Around?
I think that's my shirt, isn't it?
Uh-huh.
Do you want it back?
Right now, yeah.
Now.
Better.
Excuse me.
I think that's my bra too, isn't it?
Uh-huh.
Mm-hmm.
You want it?
Uh-huh.
Mm.
She's back.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(SINGING) Billy West died last week
for those that did not know.
I buried Billy just at the beach about an hour ago.
And understands the [INAUDIBLE] screaming
at the top of her lungs.
I know they done wrong, but they poisoned one that
taught them how to use a gun.
JANET: Hello?
Oh, hi.
Hi.
Come on in.
Can I get you a cup of coffee?
JANET: Yeah, sure. - Good.
I just made it.
It's real delicious.
Would you like some, uh, cream and sugar, honey?
Oh, no.
Sweet'N Low?
No, black's fine.
Black it is.
A guy at the gas station told me I could
cash by bus ticket in here.
No, I'm afraid you got a real problem, miss.
You're going to have to go to Los Angeles for that.
[CLEARS THROAT] We stopped doing that about a month or so ago
with all the stolen tickets and trouble and everything.
So, is it always this slow?
Mm-hmm.
Do you know of any, uh, jobs in this town for a dancer?
[LAUGHS] Gosh, no.
I-- I don't know of any job for a dancer.
But I'll tell you something.
Down the road, over the recreation center,
every Saturday night after Bingo,
they usually have a dance.
No, I meant more like topless.
Oh.
You mean, uh--
Yeah.
No, heavens.
No.
Can I, uh, get you some, uh, not so something hot?
I'm not-- [GASPS]
MAN: Oh, wait a minute. What are you doing?
Wait. What's going on?
Motherfucker, shut up.
Motherfucker?
Oh, no, please.
If you ever run, I'm going to rip your tits off.
- No, please. - Shut up!
Shut up! MAN: No, what are you doing?
Oh, boy.
Oh, my--
Shut up!
[SCREAMS]
[GUNSHOTS]
[ENGINE STARTING]
Oh, my.
[MOANING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Mm.
Ah!
Jack.
[GIGGLES]
We've got five more minutes.
And I got my half an hour to do whatever my heart desires.
Yeah, all right. Sure.
That was the agreement.
Don't stop.
Uh.
- A deal's a deal, Jack. - All right.
All right. Just listen.
No rules, OK?
I've been tied up.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
MAN: You are so beautiful, Summer.
Is that your real name?
It is now.
[GIGGLES]
Where are you from?
Iowa.
What part of Iowa?
Des Moines.
What's it like there?
Cold.
MAN: Ooh, brr.
[GIGGLES]
MAN: How long have you been here?
Two weeks.
And what brought you here?
Movies.
Do you want to be an actress?
Or do you want to be a star?
Both.
Why don't we make you a star?
MAN: Knock, knock.
Look who's back.
Hello, Janet.
Hello, Mr. Lawrence.
Lovely to see you again.
Give us a minute.
How's your session going?
Fine.
Yeah?
Didn't I tell you it would?
Mm-hmm.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Just gone through my half hour.
Go down.
For half an hour?
Don't drown.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, she is so believable.
Brilliant.
[WATER RUNNING]
[GASPS] God, you asshole.
Uh.
I got to go.
Why?
Because I have to.
When are you coming back?
Whenever.
And when's that?
Soon.
[SCOFFS] OK.
Kiss me goodbye.
Don't go.
Bye.
[DOOR SHUTS]
Trouble.
[SIGHS]
[PHONE RINGING]
Well.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What?
No-- yeah.
No, I'll-- I'll be right there.
Yeah.
Shit.
How you doing, Jack?
Come on, over here.
[POLICE RADIO CHATTER]
DELBERT: Pick her up, Jack.
You said you'd pick her up.
And she came back.
Well, she's back, Jack.
I told you, didn't I?
Nobody believed me.
I seen it a hundred times.
I told you she'd be back.
Didn't I, Jack?
Yeah, Delbert, you told me, huh.
OK, I'm wrong.
You're right.
What do you want from me?
You know who that other girl is?
No.
DELBERT: You've never seen her before?
JACK: No.
DELBERT: Well, take a closer look, Jack.
I think she knows you.
How's that, Delbert?
I found your card in her purse.
Here you go.
What's it to you, Delbert?
Captain wants to see you.
No shit.
WOMAN: What are you doing back here?
I'm looking for a guy named Latin Jerry.
I don't know no Latin Jerry's.
Well, then you can't help me, can you?
So get away from me.
All right?
Get away from me.
[PHONE RINGING]
Knock, knock.
Mm.
Jack, I just heard.
I'm so sorry.
I know how much she meant to you.
Really?
She mean nothing.
Just another statistic in the LAPD homicide file, right?
Do not get emotionally involved.
I believe that's how the captain would put it, huh.
Did I quote him right?
Did I quote him good? - Jack.
Did I?
I feel just about as responsible as you do.
Hmm.
You know, her mother called.
She'd been down to the station.
Janet wasn't on the bus.
Did you talk to her?
I didn't-- I didn't know that Janet--
she's going to call you later.
I should have picked that son of a bitch Latin Jerry
up and thrown his ass in jail.
Now, listen to me.
But I thought--
I thought he was a small time pimp and a pornographer.
Jack, you won't know.
I should have known.
Oh.
Oh, Jack.
Hey, you know where I am if you need me.
Hmm?
I'm fine.
I know.
I know. - Hey.
Yeah?
Oh, well.
Thank you.
You want some?
[LAUGHS] Catch you later.
I think a little more hair in here.
Yeah.
And a stronger jaw.
That's right.
That's him.
Very good.
All right.
Thanks.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[WOMAN PANTING]
Yes.
Now, I can't even go outside.
I have never been arrested.
I've never gone to jail.
And I'll be damned I'm going to bend over, grab ankle, and make
a bulls out of my butt for cell block
fucking Z. Thank you very much.
Then take care of him.
What are you, brain dead?
You don't think if I kill this dick,
they're not going to put another dick on my case and up my ass?
Just because he saw you with the girl
doesn't mean you killed her.
Even if they pick you up, they still have
to try you in a court of law.
And that won't be easy.
Believe me.
You'll be out in no time.
No time?
Don't talk to me about time.
I don't want to be there in the first place.
OK? - OK.
LATIN JERRY: OK? - OK.
LATIN JERRY: OK? - OK, shut the fuck up!
Let's just forget about everything.
Oh, forget everything?
Great.
Terrif.
Poof, gone.
Fuck me.
I had a surprise for you.
Sit.
I finished the first five rolls of the film.
It's still rough.
There's no music yet.
No special effects.
And I need two more scenes.
I hate to show my films unfinished.
But since you're in such a bad mood--
Bad mood?
I thought it would cheer you up.
Do we have a title yet?
The Art of Dying.
Ugh.
Brilliant.
I know.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DELBERT: He's a filmmaker, Northcott.
What are you talking about, Delbert?
DELBERT: The murderer.
He's a pimp and he's a pornographer.
All right?
JANET: Listen, Jack.
You know, he films his victims while he's doing them.
The lab reports came back with traces of stage makeup
on both the male and the female.
You know, do you think you're right about the height
of that guy?
Yeah, I know I'm right about the height of the guy.
I don't think he murdered those two girls.
I think if you should bring him back alive
because he may be innocent.
Look, he was with Summer.
She's dead.
He was with Janet.
Yeah, but the downward stab of the knife
indicates the guy was at least 6 foot, 3.
I know what I'm talking about.
You know what you're--
you know what you're talking about?
Then why didn't you take it to the captain?
I did.
And?
And he told me to stay out of the lab.
Well, that's a great idea.
Stay the hell out of the lab.
You're going to be sorry, Northcott.
I know what I'm talking about.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[FILM ROLLING]
What the fuck, man?
That's not real, is it?
I know.
It looks scary.
[SCREAMING]
MAN: Get the fuck away from me.
Get the fuck away from me.
Beyond Pacino.
[SCREAMING]
Fuck.
HOLLY: Hi.
Well, hello.
What's cooking?
Well, chicken.
Where did you find a horse?
HOLLY: A friend.
A friend?
HOLLY: Yeah, a friend.
Let me get this straight.
You got another friend who lives down at the beach besides me.
And he owns horses.
Yeah.
JACK: Why don't you just turn around
and ride back in the sunset.
All right?
Because I'll tell you, I can't take this shit anymore.
I mean, I've been seeing you for six months.
I don't know your last name.
Christ, I don't know--
I don't know where you live.
Hell, lady.
I don't even know your area code.
818.
JACK: The Valley.
You see the problem is you come and you go whenever you want.
You know, I--
I don't know.
It's like, uh-- it's like-- it's like a one night
stand that never goes away.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
But that's the way I like it.
JACK: The way you like it.
What about the way I like it?
You don't like it?
I like it.
But--
HOLLY: It beats marriage.
Definitely beats marriage.
HOLLY: Then what's the problem, Jack?
The problem-- but the problem is we got nothing but problems.
I mean, I don't--
I don't even know who you are.
I got about an hour.
We can spend it out here fighting
or we can spend it inside fucking.
[SCOFFS] You see?
HOLLY: Personally, it doesn't matter to me.
I like them both.
JACK: You know, the only thing I got to say is, uh--
it's been really tough on men through the '70s and the '80s
when it comes to women.
And I'll tell you, if this is any indication
of what the '90s is going to be like, to hell with it.
I'll go gay.
I mean, I'll become some gay--
gay traffic officer passing out tickets on Santa Monica
Boulevard with a pink pen.
You hear me?
No, cuffs.
God, I mean, can't we just have straight sex
like normal people?
I mean, look.
Well, I got an idea.
I'll be on top.
How is that?
So what kind of movies do you make?
My dear, lawyers make movies.
I make films, films based on reality.
We live in a violent world.
We sit in front of our TV sets and our comfortable living
rooms waiting to catch a glimpse of a dead body
on the freeway or a drive-by shooting.
Directors dream of shooting such reality.
But do they?
Cimino real?
No.
De Palma real?
Hitchcock?
Did you ever see his TV show?
He was a clown.
Scorsese?
My dear, I am real.
Oh.
[WOMAN GASPING]
And cut.
Excellent, Donna.
Excellent.
DELBERT: These are pictures of the seven
most recent homicides.
They all seem to have several things in common.
Yeah?
Yeah.
DELBERT: Like, one, they're all between the ages of 16 and 22.
Two, they're all aspiring actors, actresses or models.
And three, none of them are native Californians.
I think this guy is filming people as he kills them.
You know that guy that was shot in the head?
"Deer Hunter."
Now, those two girls that were wrapped up in a shower curtain?
"Psycho."
"Psycho?"
Hmm.
Come on, Delbert.
Get to the point, will you?
I think we should check our acting classes, film schools,
you know, motion picture labs, and anybody
who's purchased a film camera.
Do you have any idea how many acting classes there
are in Hollywood alone, huh?
I got an idea.
Why don't you check out the acting classes?
What are you going to do?
Me, I'm going to hit the streets.
Sooner or later, that sick son of a bitch
is going to end up there.
Lehigh Mill.
And that, my friend, is the magic of film.
And my gift to my audience is the element of surprise.
[SCREAMING]
Slowly.
Yes.
[GAGS]
MR. LAWRENCE: Yes.
And cut.
Very good.
Ugh.
Hey.
Do you like it?
JACK: Yeah, it's very nice.
Very nice.
What's wrong, Jack?
Nothing.
I'm all right.
I'm just, uh--
I have a lot on my mind.
And, uh, hey, I haven't slept in a week.
Well, sleep is really the last thing on my mind.
No kidding.
Thank you.
For what, the gift?
You're welcome.
The gift.
This isn't a gift.
This is you dressing up your Barbie doll.
Great. You don't like it?
You don't like it?
Then I'll take it back, all right?
Well, sex toys and negligees really aren't
the most romantic gift ideas.
Well, excuse me, I thought you were into this kind of thing.
I wouldn't have bothered unless I thought that.
No, you're into this kind of thing.
Jesus Christ. What is it?
Is this PMS, huh?
Five days of hell?
I mean, what is it with women?
You can't please them.
I go out, I buy you something nice, you want something else.
What do you-- you want a box of chocolate?
Candy would be nice.
Candy, great.
How about a bunch of roses?
Long stem.
Long-stemmed roses in a goddamn vase and you
can mount them on your Harley.
All right?
This isn't about me.
And this isn't about women. - Right.
This is about you and your frustrations.
That's right. Yeah, yeah.
Throw it around. Turn it around.
Put it on me.
Just go find the guy you're really pissed off at
and take it out on him.
Why don't you shut the fuck up?
Oh, that's good.
Now, we're going to hit each other, huh.
You want-- do you want to be alone, hmm?
You want to spend the night alone?
Great. You spend the night alone.
I'm out of here.
Bastard.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MAN: If Jason calls you up and you are not at home,
you are not there, baby, you better hope
and you better pray that your machine is on.
They take a message.
Because you must returned his call.
All right.
You have to return his call.
And the number is in the book, baby.
So call him up today before it's too
late, too late to get off the path, a whoredom of pimpitude!
You.
Yes, you, brother.
You who are lying and murdering your way
through life without the fear.
For he will cast his darkness upon his brethren without the--
we would, uh-- thank you, brother because I'm parched.
Fire water!
Devil juice!
You better get right with the Lord, man.
If you're not bad, I think that it is.
You got to see the beast, man.
I'm Jason.
Get back here, baby.
I'm talking to you.
Where are you going, man?
Follow me.
We are all the people that believe
what the god has to say.
Come on home with me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
[CAR HONKING]
MAN: Hey, man, are you crazy?
It was a green light, man.
You ran right at the middle of the street.
Are you drunk?
Are you stupid?
Hey!
Where are you going?
[GASPS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Wake up.
Hi.
Hi, you.
I was outside trying to celebrate by myself.
But I didn't like it.
What are we celebrating?
Victory.
I nailed that son of a bitch Latin Jerry.
I nailed him real good.
HOLLY: [LAUGHS]
Well, that sounds a little bit more like revenge and victory.
I think you're right.
So is this some kind of statement that, uh,
tells me you that want to spend the night with me?
Yeah.
Aw.
Drink to that.
[GULPS]
Mm.
Now, how come I get this, uh, feeling that I'm
harboring a criminal, huh?
A criminal?
Yeah.
I mean, look at you.
You carry a gun.
You smoke dope.
You ride a bike that doesn't belong to you.
What did you do?
Did you make run on those plates?
Of course I did.
I'm a cop.
So, uh, what are you going to do?
Arrest me?
Maybe.
But then first, you'll have to interrogate me.
Do what?
Interrogate me.
I-- I could do that.
Then you'll have to strip search me.
Well, I-- I--
I could definitely do that, yes.
Cuff me.
[LAUGHS] Yeah.
And put me behind bars.
Ooh.
You think it would be all right if I, uh,
dusted your body for prints?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah?
Well, hell, I think I should arrest you.
Aw.
God.
I'm on top.
[GIGGLES]
You're right, captain.
He fucked up.
But he's a good man and a good cop
and the only cop that I know that still cares
after 15 years in the force.
You know, while you're out there with your fundraising
and your banquets, he's out there
in the streets with the kids.
I mean, come on, give him a break here.
You want to see me, captain?
CAPTAIN: I don't want to see here I
know you exist in this city until that case is closed.
You got that?
You're suspended without pay.
DELBERT: He's just doing his job, captain.
He killed the wrong man.
What the hell are you talking about?
Two more bodies, same memo.
And this guy's death is covered by the fact
that we were able to link him to three of the murder victims.
That's OK by me.
Got the mayor off my ass.
But if this headache waste one more wrong person,
I'll have an investigation team up my butt
in here from Washington, DC.
And I don't need that.
I've had it with you.
You got an officer of the law injured, a good cop.
Assistant.
A what?
That don't play well with me.
You're lucky you're not under the jail.
Did you not tell him to pick the man up for questioning?
Yeah.
You get the hell out of here before I
put my foot so deep up your ass, your breath
will smell like shoe polish.
What, you want me out of here, huh?
You want me out of here? - You deaf?
Yes.
I want you out.
And leave the gun and badge.
Around here is my way or the highway.
I run this show.
You're just a pony in my circus.
And you're a racist asshole.
What did you call me?
I called you a racist asshole.
[SCOFFS]
Did you hear that?
He called me a racist.
No, captain.
He called you a racist asshole.
He don't.
Here you go.
[CHUCKLES]
HOLLY: Jack.
Jack, there's somebody here to see you.
Tell him to go away.
It's a reporter.
Then tell him to fuck himself.
You tell him.
He's feeling a little down today.
Ugh.
May I ask you a question?
What?
Are you an actress?
[LAUGHS] No.
I'm not.
Why would you ask that?
You look awfully familiar.
Well, unless you saw a high school
production of "Joan of Arc" in Mendocino County in 1982,
I don't think so.
"Joan of Arc," really.
Burned at the stake.
Can you imagine?
Are you OK, sweetie?
Oh, yeah.
I'm fine.
Hi, I'm Ray Johnson from "The Times."
Yeah.
Sorry to intrude on you like this.
But I missed the press conference today.
I think I'll leave you two alone.
Yeah.
Can I get a drink?
HOLLY: Yeah.
Do you mind?
What do you want?
You have an impeccable taste in women.
She's very lovely.
Look, pal.
Uh, I'm not at liberty to talk about this case.
And besides, uh, I've been suspended.
All right?
Well, we don't have to talk about the case, Jack.
I interview people with dangerous occupations,
people who often come face to face with death.
For instance, stalking a killer.
You know, there's really not that much difference
between you and the killer.
- Oh, really? - Huh.
Yes.
I mean, you stalk the killer, the killer stalk someone else.
You catch the killer, you get a promotion.
He catches his prey and they're dead.
What does it feel like to kill someone, Jack?
Oh, come on.
I understand you send more people to the graveyard
than you do to jail.
All right, look, your time is up.
I'd like you to leave now.
All right?
Did you throw Latin Jerry in front of that car, detective?
You know, I've been--
I've been drinking all day.
But, uh, I sure as hell ain't that drunk.
And you tell me you didn't go to the press conference.
So how the hell do you know his name?
I saw it on the news.
You saw it on the news?
Why don't you take your camera, your news and your fat ass,
and you get the hell out of my house before I throw you out?
All right?
You don't have to get violent, Jack.
You don't want me to get violent?
Then you get the hell out of here.
OK, Jack.
Get the hell out of my house!
I'm on my way.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
JACK: Hey, Delbert.
It's Jack.
Listen, buddy.
I need a favor.
And what's that?
I want you to run a make on a license plate number for me.
Mm.
JACK: License number is 2HFJO6.
Jesus, Jack.
You're on suspension.
Just do it.
All right?
Yeah.
Well, yeah, OK.
Hold on.
Jack, you still there?
Yeah, I'm right here.
You sure that's the right number you gave me?
I'm sure.
All right, Jack.
That vehicle belongs to Francis Warner
at 6851 North 3rd Street.
6851?
6851 North 3rd Street.
OK.
Thanks a lot, Delbert.
I appreciate it.
Jack, what's this all about?
Well, I saw this, uh, beautiful blonde
in a black Bronco.
Thanks a lot, Delbert.
Bronco?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, man.
Please, please.
All right.
Son of a bitch.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MR. LAWRENCE: Hooray for Holly-wood.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on.
[RINGING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GRUNTING]
Get the fuck away from me.
[GRUNTS]
Yeah.
[SCREAMS]
Ride on.
[CHUCKLES]
[GRUNTS] You let go of me, you fucking asshole.
[CHUCKLING]
[SCREAMS]
[PANTING] Magnificent.
I can't wait to get you on film.
JACK: Holly?
Holly?
Oh, no.
No.
You son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MR. LAWRENCE: Welcome, Jack.
I was hoping you'd make a show of it.
For starters, why don't we lose the gun?
Are you all right?
Why don't we lose the gun now, Jack?
Just leave her alone.
It's between you and me.
Ah!
Damn it.
The gun.
All right.
Now, what? - Now, what?
Now, what?
Now, you sit.
Best seat in the house, front row center.
You like?
JACK: I like.
Officer Klein has been telling me all about you, Jack.
She's very open and honest after a little prodding.
Officer?
Are you a cop?
You're a goddamn cop?
MR. LAWRENCE: [LAUGHS]
JACK: All right, fella.
This has gone far enough.
Now, listen to me.
Nobody wants to hurt you anymore.
But you're sick and you need some help.
Sick?
Oh, no.
I'm way beyond sick.
[LAUGHS] Hell, Jack, I'm even beyond reality.
As you well know, I've been capturing
death on film for a long time.
[LAUGHS] But tonight, Jack, I've outdone myself.
And how is that?
How's that?
Two cameras.
One on your lady as she burns and one on her lover
as he watches.
Can you imagine?
What the hell's matter with you, huh?
She's got nothing to do with it.
She's innocent.
You killed my friend!
I loved him.
I understand.
And now, I'm going to kill your friend.
And you're going to watch.
No, not this.
Come on, Jack.
Give me some more. - You don't want to do this.
Give me more. - Damn it.
MR. LAWRENCE: Come on, Jack. - Don't you hurt her.
That's it. Come on, Jack.
- Don't you-- - Give me more.
Don't you hurt her!
MR. LAWRENCE: Yes, yes, yes!
Oh, yes.
Come on.
Ah!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Freeze, you son of a bitch.
[GUNSHOT]
Oh.
Stop shooting me.
Ugh.
Ah!
No.
Wait, please.
No, you don't understand.
Nobody's ever understood me.
Fuck you!
No, don't shoot.
Please don't shoot.
No, no, no.
No. - All right.
All right.
Now, calm down.
I understand.
You understand?
Oh.
All right.
Thank you.
[GRUNTS]
Ah!
I really understand.
[POLICE SIREN]
[POLICE RADIO CHATTER]
Officer Klein?
A cop?
I don't date cops.
Gretchen.
All right.
So, Gretchen what about this guy who lives
at the beach with a horse?
You're the only guy at the beach.
I rented the horse.
[CHUCKLES] And what about where you live, Gretchen Klein?
With you.
What, I got nothing to say about this, huh?
No.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Jack.
Yeah?
May I please move in with you?
Mother, may I?
Aw.
Yeah.
No.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Come on, Jerry.
Let's get out of here.