[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Excuse me.
I'm supposed to meet someone
here-- big white man,
speaks with an accent.
-Italian?
-Yeah.
-Upstairs.
-Thanks.
[GIGGLING]
-Dan.
Son of a bitch.
You haven't shown
up for two years.
Couldn't you have made it
two years and two minutes?
-Oh Renzo, you'll never change.
How are you?
-Better before you got there.
Oops.
-So how are we doing in Zaire?
-Dan, I'm going back to Italy.
-Renzo, you can't do that.
It took us two years
to plant you here.
-Don't worry.
I have the information you want.
-Now you're talking.
What have you got?
-There's a big shipment of
uranium going out of here.
-There's always uranium
going out of Zaire.
-Somebody paid double for this.
And in advance.
-Who made the deal?
-Listen.
I was promised a $10,000 bonus
if I came through for you guys.
-OK.
OK.
Don't you trust me?
-Sure I trust you.
I even love you.
But you mossad people still have
to pay me for the Uganda job,
remember?
I'm going back to my business.
You know where to find me.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Tell the bosses in your
mossad to test this.
-What is it?
-Uranium, yellowcake.
-Um, is it, uh, radioactive?
-You'll know when you blow up.
MEYER: Are you sure you
can trust this Italian?
DAN: Look, he's worked for
us three times already.
MEYER: But he wouldn't give
you the names of the buyers.
DAN: Not without cash.
MEYER: Why did we
choose this man
to plant in the uranium mines?
DAN: It was done before
you joined the mossad.
MEYER: I see.
DAN: Meyer, we owe
this man money.
MEYER: He's a bit of a
soldier of fortune, isn't he?
-Sort of.
-I never trust people who are
working for us just for money.
Well?
-Unfortunately,
it is yellowcake.
-Which means?
-It's a crude form of
uranium, generally used
in chemical
fertilizers, sometimes
the manufacture of paint.
-Is that all?
SCIENTIST: No.
There's another possibility.
Whoever puts those
200 tons of yellowcake
through an atomic reactor
will have enough plutonium
to make 25 to 30
atom bombs, each
the size that
devastated Hiroshima.
-When you get to Italy,
watch that money.
-Oh, I hate to carry
so much cash on me.
-Dan, be careful.
Operate through
your Italian friend.
He's our cover.
But remember, if he gets
smart, cut him loose.
Good luck.
Call me from Venice.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-$10,000?
-$10,000.
OK.
We delivered.
Now you deliver.
The name of the company
that bought the uranium?
-Asmara.
-Asmara?
RENZO: Yes.
It's a company in
Salzburg, in Austria.
I think it's a chemical plant.
-OK.
We'll have to go
and check it out.
-Who's we?
-You and me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[GERMAN] This is the place.
Strange.
She's the only one who's
been in our out all day.
I wonder if they do any
business at all here.
-Pretty, isn't she?
RENZO: One of us should
make contact with her.
-That's your department.
-I know.
It was in the contract.
I'll take her.
DAN: All right.
Get a move on.
Start earning your money.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[ITALIAN]
-You don't speak German?
How can you do a
crossword puzzle
if you don't speak German?
-I can't.
That's why I have to ask you.
HELGA: Well then, what
language do you speak?
-Well, uh, I speak,
uh, Italian of course.
And, uh, [FRENCH].
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
And, uh, a little
bit of English.
-OK.
A little bit of English then.
-Well, uh, my name is Renzo.
-Helga.
Well, you see, I'm Swedish.
My husband was French.
And we lived in Germany.
It just didn't work out.
So I left him.
I needed a job.
And this one came along.
-You don't seem
very happy with it.
-Oh, it's so boring.
I'm alone all day
in that big office.
-You mean you do all your
business by telephone?
-Not even that.
Hardly anyone calls,
only the baron.
-The baron?
-Look, aren't these beautiful?
-Yes, they are beautiful.
Is the baron your boss?
-In a way he is.
-I don't understand.
What kind of business is it?
-I didn't know
anything about it.
I've only been here
for three months.
Anyway, what are we
talking about my work for?
-You're right.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-It was a lovely afternoon.
-Yes.
Tell me, if you had
known me for a week,
you'd invite me to
come up, wouldn't you?
-If I'd known you for a week.
-We don't have a week.
We have just tonight,
maybe tomorrow.
-Who are you?
We didn't meet by accident.
You followed me.
-Never trust a Veneziano.
-Oh, you're from Venice.
-Uh huh.
-I love Venice.
-You know, for the
first time in my life
I think I'm going
to miss a woman.
-Then don't be afraid
to come back to her.
-Wait a moment.
I have a present for you.
Choose.
-This one.
-You have the salt.
And I have the pepper.
-You stole them
from the restaurant.
-I like beautiful things.
-Will you ever be back?
-I don't know.
-I hardly even know you.
-Maybe it's better this way.
-Well, what did you find out?
-What did you?
-Nothing.
I photographed all the
documents in that office.
There's no mention
of uranium anywhere.
-There's a man she
calls the baron.
He seems to be the boss.
-I saw his signature
on some of the papers.
He must be our man.
-If we can find him.
-You mean to tell
that your girlfriend
doesn't know where
her boss lives?
She's lying.
-She's not lying.
He runs the business
by telephone and telex.
-Huh, telex.
-I've heard of Asmara
potential, very
interested in your products.
Stop.
Please meet me
tomorrow at 3:00 PM
at the Golden [INAUDIBLE]
Hotel, Salzburg.
Awaiting confirmation at
the Hotel [INAUDIBLE] Paris.
Signed, Prince Abdul
Fuad of Saudi Arabia.
BARON (ON PHONE): Nothing else?
-[GERMAN]
BARON (ON PHONE): Send
a telex to the prince
confirming the meeting.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-Guten tag.
We are looking for His
Excellency Prince Abdul Fuad,
arriving from Paris.
Is he in yet?
-Just a moment.
No, but he is expected.
Are you with the baron.
-Yes, why?
-I have a message for you.
The prince was detained.
He'll be here at 4 o'clock.
He asked you to wait for him.
-Oh, thank you.
4 o'clock?
That's another hour.
-Doesn't matter.
We'll wait.
Where's your bar, please?
RECEPTIONIST: Right over there.
-Thank you.
-Please, it's OK.
[INAUDIBLE], this way, please.
Up.
Please, come in,
gentlemen, please.
Please, sit down.
[INAUDIBLE], take a
seat your excellency.
Sit down.
Your excellency, perhaps
I can offer you a drink.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
-Ha. [SPEAKING ARABIC]
-The prince only likes something
you don't have in Europe.
-Perhaps arak?
-Arak?
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-The prince would very much
like some arak. [INAUDIBLE].
--[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Very good arak.
In our business,
arak and vodka are
more important than
schnaps, even whisky.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-Toilette?
-Listen to this.
We are in receipt
of your bank check
for the amount of $12,500,
for which we thank you.
We take note of the arrival
of the yellowcake November 2
in Genova, and in
Milano November 4.
-And what is this, here?
-Wait a minute.
This is the contract for
the purchase of a ship.
[BARKING]
-It's very late.
Please tell the baron that
we'll contact him tomorrow.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN FRANTICALLY]
-Prince.
Prince.
If he was the prince,
I'm the [INAUDIBLE].
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-Ah, [GERMAN].
-There are two possibilities.
Either they're trying to
find out about the tank sale
to Saudi Arabia or
the yellowcake deal.
Either way, we've
got too much to lose.
We must find them.
But it has to be
handled quietly.
So use your heads, gentlemen.
The one thing our clients
can not afford is publicity.
-So, uh, where do we start?
-We have only one lead.
-What lead?
-The telex, [INAUDIBLE].
-The asmara chemical company,
which the baron controls,
bought a ship from
a Dutch company.
It's docked in
Amsterdam, getting
a new crew and a new
name, [INAUDIBLE].
-Another ship?
What for?
-Dan thinks the ship is
getting prepared to take
on a new cargo.
-The yellocake?
The same yellowcake
that is now on its way
from Zaire on the [INAUDIBLE]?
That doesn't make sense.
-What do you want to know?
-Did he ask you about
any kind of armaments,
planes, anything like that?
-No.
-What did he ask you?
-What was he interested in?
-I don't really remember.
-Tell me, did he ever
mention the word yellowcake?
-Yellowcake?
-It's an ore, a kind of uranium.
-Yes.
He did say something
once about uranium.
-Well, well, someone
is trying to nose
into our yellowcake deal.
Gentlemen--
-Looks like it.
-We are going to
Amsterdam immediately.
-Well?
-The yellowcake, which left
Zaire on board the [INAUDIBLE]
is apparently going to
Italy with a license issued
by [INAUDIBLE] to
a paint company
in Milano named Color Mi.
-What's an Italian
paint company going
to do with 560
barrels of uranium?
-And what's the [INAUDIBLE]
doing in Amsterdam?
-We'll soon now.
Dan's on his way to Milano.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Buongiorno.
-Do you speak English?
-A little.
-The factory, the
fabbrica, Color Mi.
-[ITALIAN].
-Yeah.
-It is closed five years.
-Five years?
-Go ahead, Dan.
-The paint factory is a phony.
It's a deserted place.
-I see.
Well, it looks like a cover.
Listen, Dan, I heard your
Italian friend is getting
involved with that
girl from Salzburg.
I don't like it.
-I don't like it either.
MEYER (ON PHONE):
Does she know you?
-No.
-If she finds out that
he's working for us,
if she ever exposes you, we'll
have to take care of her.
You understand?
-Yeah, yes.
MEYER (ON PHONE): All right.
Cool it.
Call me from Amsterdam when
you know more about that ship.
-OK.
Grazie.
-Hey, sailor?
-Yeah?
-When is the ship going out?
-Tomorrow night.
-And it's not loading yet?
-We're not loading here.
We're loaded in Antwerp.
-Antwerp?
-Yeah.
Why do you want to know?
-I'm looking for a job.
-Well, I think we got
a full crew already.
They were hiring yesterday
over at the shipping house.
Maybe there's still
something left.
You can try.
-I will, thanks.
SAILOR: Good luck.
-Keep an eye on the girl.
-Excuse me.
Where can I find a manager?
-Well, you find the
manager right over there.
-Oh, thank you very much.
-But I tell you I can cook.
-Maybe you can cook,
but you are not a cook.
-Ah, shit.
Oh, go to hell.
-Next.
-Are these all?
-These are all the
applicants we have
had during the past
three days, sir.
-Well?
-I don't see him.
-Excuse me, please.
-Of course, sir.
-I'm sure he was here.
CLERK: Next, please.
-Do you have anything
sailing tomorrow?
CLERK: [INAUDIBLE] but
it's already fully crewed.
RENZO: Oh.
-But, you must
fill in this form,
and return it with
a recent picture.
-Thanks.
-May I use your ladies room?
-Of course, madam.
I will show you the way.
-Wait a minute. [INAUDIBLE].
-Just take the second door to
the right hand, please, madame.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-[INAUDIBLE], get the girl.
-Oh, what are you doing here?
-Get out!
She's not there.
-Stay here.
-Next, please.
-Where the hell is the girl?
Did you fall asleep?
-She must have gone
out the other the.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN] and find her!
-Where is she?
-Other door.
[ARGUING IN GERMAN]
-Herr Baron, I think I just
saw the man we are looking for.
[CLANG]
[HURRIED FOOTSTEPS]
-No, leave me!
Renzo!
[GUNSHOTS]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-Leave me!
-[SCREAMING]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-Moving on to the next roof.
Come on.
-Jump.
-Oh.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[INAUDIBLE].
-OK.
-Hello?
Hello?
Anybody there?
Come on.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[INAUDIBLE].
[HONKING]
-Hey, look out!
-[SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-Hey, what are you doing?
Are you crazy?
-I like flowers.
I'm letting you off in a minute.
I want you to go to
the Western Church.
I'm supposed to meet my man
there at 12 o'clock exactly.
He'll be there no
more than 10 minutes.
So don't be late.
-How will I recognize him?
-He'll recognize you.
If I don't make it, tell
him the name of the ship
is the [INAUDIBLE].
You got that?
The [INAUDIBLE].
There.
See that little straw houseboat?
That's where you're
going to jump off.
You're going to jump now, Helga.
HELGA: Slow down, please.
RENZO: Don't worry.
Jump!
-[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-She jumped onto that houseboat.
You stay with the men.
[GUNSHOTS]
-Hurry, don't lose the boat!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GUNSHOTS]
-Get in the car.
Leave her to me.
[GUNSHOT]
-Oh my god.
[SCREAMING]
-[INAUDIBLE]
-[SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[GERMAN]
-OK.
You better come out.
Come out!
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
[CHURCH BELLS CHIMING]
-Are you Renzo's friend?
I have a message for you.
-What is it?
-The ship is called
the [INAUDIBLE].
It's sailing to Antwerp.
And it will load tomorrow night.
-Where's Renzo?
HELGA: I don't know.
He said he'd try to be here.
But they were after him.
Please.
Please, if you see him, tell him
that I'll be waiting for him.
I, I'll be waiting
for him in Salzburg.
[GUNSHOT]
-It's all clear now.
[INAUDIBLE] did not
enter the Mediterranean.
It's sailing to Antwerp.
-And the [INAUDIBLE]?
-Left Amsterdam on its
way to Antwerp, too.
They're going to transfer
the uranium in Antwerp.
-Looks that way.
Does he know about the girl?
-Yes.
He saw her get killed.
-Meyer, does he realize--
-No.
Let's get moving.
-Maybe it was a mistake.
-Maybe.
MAN: My whole
commando unit would
just love to go to Europe.
MEYER: 20 would do, but
choose them carefully.
-Are we having a war
I don't know about?
-Trying to avoid one.
-What is this?
Are we talking about piracy?
-And how do you call what
they're planning for us?
Genocide?
Let's cut the bullshit.
I'll need four of your best
boys to come with me to Antwerp.
The rest will fly
with you to Gibraltar.
How much longer will you be?
-Well, I'm not happy
with oxygen gauge.
-I see.
[INAUDIBLE], is
everything all right?
-Fine, great.
-How about you, Slow-mo?
-Well, if you want to blow
it up from five kilometers,
we need another
transmitter here.
-OK.
[INAUDIBLE], go down
and do some shopping
before they close
the stores, OK?
-Yeah.
-[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Don't slip.
Go.
MAN: Stop pushing.
Find a place below
decks to lock him up.
And keep an eye on him.
-Come on.
Go, go.
-Wait.
OK.
Where is Renzo?
-On th ship.
-On the ship?
So it was him.
-I don't know what happened.
-I should have listened
to my own instincts.
-He gave us all the
information we needed.
-Yeah?
And what did he give them?
-Oh come on.
MEYER: OK, back to work.
-What's going on?
-You're going home.
-Home?
-Mhmm.
Your job is finished.
-You're going to
blow up the ship.
-You just take off.
-You can't blow up the
ship with Renzo on board.
You know that.
-That's not your concerns.
-Meyer, we've got a
commitment to this guy.
-We better keep our
commitments where they belong.
Dan, you better go home.
Spend some time with
your wife, your family.
I'm You're losing
perspective, OK?
-Taxi.
-Look at these rotten,
stinking prices.
Just look at these
rotten, stinking prices.
Belgians have become so
rotten, stinking expensive.
Don't you think so, mate?
-Yeah.
-Hey, you're not a rotten
stinking Belgian by any chance,
are you?
-Yes, I am.
-Oh, I'm sorry, mate.
You know, I'm always putting
my rotten stinking foot
in my rotten stinking
mouth, you know.
-It's all right.
-No, I, I really
do love Belgium.
-Come up.
[GERMAN] Get a move on.
Come on.
-OK.
Who are you?
Who are you working for?
Just a moment.
-He was not on the plane.
-I see.
Call me in Gibraltar,
Hotel Riviera.
And let me know if
you don't track him.
-Good luck.
MAN: Bruno?
-Huh?
MAN: Everything OK?
-OK, OK, no problem.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
-Did it go all right?
-Yeah.
[SOFT SCREAM]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Everything OK, Bruno?
-OK, no problem.
-Hey, Bruno, come on.
Move it!
Get this boat in.
Bruno!
Hey, John, have you seen Bruno?
-Yeah, sure.
He was here a minute ago.
MAN: Bruno?
Bruno!
Come on.
Get the boat in,
and [INAUDIBLE].
-[ITALIAN]
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Si?
-What's the matter?
What's going on?
-One of my men is looking.
I'm going ashore
to look for him.
-Wait a moment.
You're not going anywhere.
We are leaving right now.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[ITALIAN]
-Renzo, Renzo, come on.
Get up.
Wake up.
It's me, Dan.
-Dan?
-We don't have much time.
Come on.
Are you hurt badly?
-No.
But I have a million
flies buzzing in my head.
DAN: Here, take this.
-Crazy bastard.
You didn't have
to do this for me.
-You're right.
I didn't.
-Help me.
Help me, Dan.
Did you see Helga?
-Huh, uh yeah.
Take this.
-Did she go back to Salzburg?
-Who?
-Helga?
Where did she go?
-Renzo, we must move fast.
Come on.
Let's go back.
-Dan!
Where is Helga?
-Listen, before we left
Antwerp, a commando team
placed charges on the
hull of this ship.
My people are planning
to blow it up.
-What?
Are you crazy?
-Let's go.
-Shit.
-Move!
-Don't move.
-Where's the captain?
-Hey, what the
hell's going on here.
What are you doing here?
-Shut up!
Where is the captain?
-The captain is in his cabin.
-Great.
I'm going to get the captain.
Will you be all right?
-All right.
-OK, take your hands off me.
And don't push.
-Take the wheel.
Same heading.
And no tricks.
-This is it.
The captain is fast asleep.
He'll kill you.
-You, get up!
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Tell him to shut up, and
get up, so he won't be hurt.
-Capitano--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Come on.
Come on.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Shut up!
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Frequency 4x0.
-All right.
-Quickly.
-OK.
-Move.
-I can't, I can't do it any
quicker than I can do it.
-Thank you.
-It's from Dan.
He's on the [INAUDIBLE].
-What?
Are you sure?
-Yes, it's his signature.
He's released his friend,
and seized the captain.
-He must be out of his mind.
Tell him to wait
for my instructions.
Let's go see the minister.
-Hi, [INAUDIBLE].
-Hi.
-How's it going?
-Good.
-You have the boat?
-Yeah.
-The others?
-They've all arrived.
-OK, let's go.
[YAWNING]
-How are you doing?
You want to get some sleep now?
-No, don't worry.
I'm doing fine.
-Hey, Tony.
Tony. [SPEAKING ITALIAN].
[KNOCKING]
MAN: [GERMAN]
-Yeah?
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[GERMAN]?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-The baron's coming.
-Don't move.
-[ITALIAN]?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-We need some men with guns.
Where are the guns?
[ITALIAN]?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]?
RENZO: Shut up!
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
--[INAUDIBLE], get
the transmitter
ready for the mines.
The ship will cross
in a couple of hours.
-OK.
MAN: You really think
we'll have to blow it up?
-Yes, I do.
-Meyer, Dan is on
board that ship.
-I don't know.
I'm not sure.
It's not certain.
-It is.
It was just confirmed.
-It says they're both on board,
and in control of the ship.
-Control of the ship?
-What's the matter?
-I don't know.
It smells fishy.
Anyway, let's get moving.
Where are the boys?
-Down below.
-Start the engines.
Hello.
MAN: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
MAN: Hey, wait a minute.
I ain't been paid
to get my ass-- oh.
-Anybody else want
to work against us?
Here, go ahead.
-Well?
DAN: Not a word.
They said they'd get back
to me by the morning.
-Hey you, hands up!
-Stop the engines.
-What?
-You heard me.
Shut off the engines.
-OK.
OK.
-What happened?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-They stopped the engines.
-Tell them to start the engines.
Move!
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Answer.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Tell him I'll blow
his head off if he
doesn't start the engines.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-He can't do anything.
-That's strange.
They're not moving.
-Maybe they've spotted us.
-No.
There's something
going on over there.
-Hey, you.
Listen.
You're completely surrounded.
I give you two more minutes
to come out of there.
Give them a hand.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Smoker flares.
-OK, throw them in.
Hey, sailor.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Will you stop that damn
[INAUDIBLE] do something.
They're going to wreck
the whole rotten--
-Get down.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-I'm out of bullets.
How about you?
-Me too.
Watch out!
You killed him.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Help me, someone, help me.
My god.
We're going to die.
Help!
-Come here, you.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Come on.
Tell them we give up.
-Don't shoot, please!
Don't shoot.
They're [INAUDIBLE].
Stop shooting.
-[ITALIAN]
-Let's kill them, just
shove them overboard.
-OK, him first.
Throw him overboard.
You heard him.
Get up.
-Wait a minute.
You're going to need him.
-Shut up!
-What do you mean, need him?
-This boat is loaded with mines.
The only thing keeping
us alive is him.
-I don't believe him.
-Captain, can we send
a man down to check.
-You son of a bitch.
-[INAUDIBLE].
Watch your leg.
--[SPEAKING ITALIAN] There are
mines down there, all right.
They're attached
to the stabilizers.
-Can we get them off?
-You try, and you'll
detonate them.
-He's right.
They're not the
electromagnetic kind.
Their clamps are booby-trapped.
If we touch them, they'll blow.
--[ITALIAN], quickly,
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
on the radio.
-Leave it to me.
OK, what is it?
-Well, it's a, it's a
message I don't understand.
Calling [INAUDIBLE],
request permission
as to stop the [INAUDIBLE].
-Where is it from?
-Well, they won't say.
They won't identify themselves.
-Hey, baldy, bring him over.
You sit down.
You get up.
Sit down.
What's this?
Don't look at me like that.
I know who you are.
Tell them everything
is all right now.
We're proceeding
according to plan.
And you read it.
-Aye aye, sir.
-Come on.
Do it.
[BEEPING]
-Something's wrong.
-What?
-It's not Dan's signature.
-What do you mean?
-Dan transmits at
a different speed.
But that could be Dan
trying to tell us something.
-Get me [INAUDIBLE], quick.
I'm changing plans before
they blow up the ship.
-I'm ready for your mines.
-They're moving again.
-Meyer.
-We're back to Plan A.
-Thank god.
-All right, pack the equipment.
Let's move.
-You're still
pissed off with me?
You prefer to be dead?
-Renzo, we're sitting on
25 potential atom bombs.
If this ship reaches
its destination,
it could mean the total
destruction of my country.
It could also mean that
tomorrow any group of terrorists
could get hold of an atom bomb.
Can you imagine what the
world would look like?
-I don't care about tomorrow.
I care about today.
And today your own
people will kill you.
You know that.
-Maybe.
BARON: Who are they?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Spanish Coast Guard.
-What do they want?
CAPTAIN: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Sorry, gentlemen.
Will you please move away?
Thank you.
-Tell them Captain Jesus
Villaverde of the Spanish Coast
Guard wants to come on board.
-Jesus Villaverde?
MAN: Rotten stinkers.
They want us to stop.
They want to come aboard.
-Ask them what for.
-Aye.
-What?
-They're asking why.
-Routine check.
-Those sons of bitches.
They say it's a
routine check up.
-How dare they.
-Gibraltar is an
international pass.
-Anyway, we're not in
their territorial waters.
-Well, what shall I do?
-Tell them to go to hell.
-OK.
Go--
-What did they say?
-Go to hell.
-Shoot one.
-They don't
understand my English.
[EXPLOSION]
-They do understand my English.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-I need some men with guns.
But keep them out of sight.
-And what about the prisoners?
-I'll take care of them.
Come out!
Come!
Quick!
Stop, this way.
Go in.
Go.
You, put it out.
Get out.
Pull it up.
See the dishes?
Start cleaning.
-What is this?
Prison with hard labor?
-Clean it.
Prisoner, we are going
to have visitors.
If you make one wrong
movement, just one,
I will empty this
into your stomach.
Understood?
MEYER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MAN: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-What's going on?
What do they want?
-They're looking for
an escaped killer.
They want to search the ship.
-Search the ship?
But we never anchored in Spain.
-You think the sons of
bitches don't know that?
[ITALIAN]
-I'm sorry, sir, but haven't
I seen you somewhere before?
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-I know I've seen
him somewhere before.
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]?
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-Oh, they want to know
what we're carrying.
-I thought you were looking
for man, not contraband?
-[SPANISH]?
-Oh, they, they're
just doing the cargo.
They've chartered our ship.
-[SPANISH]
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-[ITALIAN]
-Tell them it's
chemical fertilizer.
-What are you looking for?
It's just artificial shit.
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[LAUGHING]
-[SPANISH]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
CAPTAIN: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
-[SPANISH] OK, no problem.
[FRENCH] [SPANISH]
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-[ITALIAN]?
MAN: Go, go, go,
go, go, go, come on.
Come on.
Go, go.
CAPTAIN: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
MAN: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
[CLATTER]
-Hell, I know you, you
rotten stinking swine.
You're not Spanish.
You Speak English.
I saw you in that
shop in Antwerp.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
-[GERMAN]
--[GERMAN] The next
time, I won't miss you.
-Cover me.
But be careful.
I want him alive.
-Are you OK?
-Yeah, thanks.
MAN: Surrender, or
you're all dead.
-Ulrich, [INAUDIBLE],
where the hell are you?
-Lock him up.
There are some answers
he can give us.
-Does he know about Helga?
-No.
-Go and tell him.
Dan, Don't tell him everything.
-Well, we did it.
You come with me to Salzburg.
-Renzo, she's dead.
Helga is dead.
She was shot in the church.
[MUSIC PLAYING]