Leading Investment presents
in association
with SidusFNH-Benex Cinema Fund1
A Bidangil Pictures production
distributed by SidusFNH
Manchuria, battle against Ching
in 11th year of Joseon 's
King Gwang-hae-gun 's reign
General!
There are too many of them!
We must retreat, sir!
What? Retreat?
We must fight them off
until the main army gets here!
It's been 5 days, sir!
If they were coming...
What are you suggesting?
Sir!
Enough nonsense.
No one moves a step
until the main army gets here!
Damn it.
Are you okay, Do-young?
I'm fine.
This won't kill me.
Damn Ching bastards!
Why are there so many?
Oh shit!
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman
THE SHOWDOWN
Do-young!
Wake up!
Don't fall asleep!
If you do, you'll die!
Wake up! Open your eyes!
I can't... feel my left leg.
I'm sure it's fine.
It's probably from the cold.
If we warm up,
it'll get better.
So pull yourself together
and point the way home.
I wonder...
what happened to
the other Joseon soldiers.
Probably all died, right?
Weren't we all sent here
to die anyways?
Just go...
and all die.
I guess...
our army's duty
has been fulfilled.
Oh, not quite yet.
You and l... are still alive.
It's not funny.
Stop the nonsense.
You really think
I'm just joking?
At last,
I shall die because of you.
I don't understand you.
Isn't JANG Do-young your friend
whom you think of as a brother?
So...
When the So-beuk Clan and
his father were purged...
You desperately begged
to spare his life.
But why change the army list...
and insist on taking him?
Do-young often went to Ming
with his father
when he was young.
He knows the battle area well.
That's the only reason
I chose him as a section chief.
Really?
Is that so?
Yes, sir.
Do as you wish.
Think about it.
If you didn't tell me
to take the military examination...
I wouldn't be out here
to die like this.
What? Am I wrong?
Nonsense!
No one is going to die!
We can survive!
We'll surely live and step on
Joseon ground again!
I can't... Not like this...
Traitor, JANG Soo-in!
Seize him!
I can't just leave the bastards
and die like this.
Not without getting revenge.
How will I face my father?
Look, Do-young.
There's something
I must tell you.
It's been killing me.
The one you've been
searching for...
The one who accused
your father of treason...
That person...
That was me.
So? Have you made a decision?
But, sir...
He's like a father to me.
Your family belongs to
the Dae-beuk Clan like us!
How can you call the enemy that?
Ignorant fool.
So?
What will you do?
Die with him because
he was like a father to you?
Now that we have
His Majesty's trust...
It's only a matter of time
till we gain control of the court.
Is it not a heavenly opportunity
for you to join us?
Why you!
Leave him.
He wants to die with them.
You are dismissed!
I'll do it! I'll do it, sir!
Please give me the chance!
But, promise me one thing, sir.
I told you not to worry
about your future.
It's not that, sir.
Please...
Not him...
Please spare his life.
I beg you, sir!
I shouldn't have done it.
I'm sorry.
So sorry.
Please...
kill me.
Cold!
What the?
Damn it!
Do-young...
You...
Are you all right?
We should hurry.
Will you?
Why did I come down here?
Shit.
Why did they make
something like this?
What are they, mice?
I'm beat.
Someone's inside.
We're still in enemy territory.
Damn Ching bastard!
Are you a Joseon soldier?
Are you a Joseon soldier, too?
Yes!
Military rules are strict!
Anyone who dares runaway
from the battlefield
shall be beheaded!
How ever did you survive?
What a relief
meeting one of our men here.
Hey, Do-young!
Damn bastards.
Just my damn luck!
What's with the damn door!
The bastards don't move a finger.
I cleaned up like you said, sir.
Then I'll just...
It's been frozen good,
so it'll be okay to eat.
There's not much...
But it should last us
maybe two days or so, sir.
Why's this here?
Let's put it in the soup.
It's quite a big tavern.
Yes, sir.
Merchants who traveled between
Joseon and Ming stayed here.
Looks like they were done in
by bandits during the war.
Do you know this area?
Not much, Just a little, sir.
Joseon's three or four days away.
Really? Are you sure?
Damn sure!
I made money as a guide
to the merchants here.
You were a guide around here?
Then you can go to Joseon
with your eyes closed, right?
By the way,
were you in my unit?
You look familiar.
Damn hot!
No, sir.
I was...
in the central unit, sir!
Looks good, doesn't it?
Are you hungry, sir?
It's all ready to eat.
Smells great, doesn't it?
There's more, sir.
Let's give it a try.
Hey!
You think people can eat this?
Why? Isn't it good, sir?
It should be okay.
Let me try it, sir!
Get your filthy hand away!
Forget it.
It'll have to do.
Damn aristocrat bastards.
Complaining about food
at a time like this?
They should starve like hell
to appreciate my porridge,
and realize their mouths
aren't coated with gold!
Starve to death,
you damn bastards!
Shit.
Can't tell which way is which.
Bastards.
What? It's not this way?
Not this way, either?
Damn! I'll freeze to death.
Where have you been?
Just outside, sir.
I had to pee.
Then, why pull out your hatchet?
Planning on hacking someone?
Of course not, sir.
Just got a little startled.
I wouldn't dream of it.
It's really cold outside.
Look at this.
It's damn cold.
The fire has died down.
I'll put in more wood, sir!
Hey!
There's wood here, too.
Where are you going?
Ah, I left some broken
wood pieces in the room.
That fool's got something up
his sleeve.
Why?
Do you have
something to say to me?
Me?
No. Nothing.
Did he hear everything I said?
No.
If he did, he wouldn't
stay still like that.
Stop!
That's enough!
Not again!
Don't over do it!
You're always like this!
I'm sorry.
I pushed a little too far.
Must you go so far
to be damn satisfied?
I was too rough.
Forgive me.
Are you really sorry?
You're always like this.
Good swordsmanship
is important,
but do not neglect
your studies.
Remember,
books before the sword.
Yes, sir.
Thus, I am studying hard
at both, sir.
Good.
You've always been
gifted in both
Iiterature and martial arts.
The problem is you, Do-young.
Literature or martial arts...
You must make much effort
to catch up to Hun-myung.
You embarrass me, sir.
Yes, Father.
Of course you're right.
I shall try to do my best.
But no matter how hard I try,
I won't be able to
catch up to him.
He is a few years older and
born with natural talents.
Plus, he has a bad temper
not to lose to anyone.
No matter what I do,
how can I be as good as he?
So please, don't have
such high expectations on me.
You say we're only
3 days away from Joseon?
Yes, sir.
But it'll be hard
in this weather?
Yes... I reckon, sir.
I remembered
where I saw you.
You ran away
before the battle ended.
Didn't you?
That hand...
How should I take that?
Sir?
Do you dare?
I'm sorry, sir!
Please forgive me!
Please, General!
I was wrong!
Please forgive me, sir!
I know what you're
worried about.
But don't worry.
That won't happen.
Really, sir?
We already lost the battle.
Now, we must try to survive.
Thank you!
Thank you, General!
Thank you, sir!
Damn bastards.
Our dispatch rider isn't
lying dead here, is he?
I'm sorry.
Perhaps he got lost
in the fierce snowstorm.
Maybe he's stuck somewhere?
Let's hope so.
There's a tavern a day away
from here
by the Joseon border.
Shall we go there and look?
T omorrow...
We leave at the crack of dawn.
In weather like this?
What's the rush?
Sir? I reckon it'll be hard
in this weather.
I tried to go...
Not that I tried to leave.
Anyway, we could go
and freeze to death, sir.
If we stay, we'll eventually
starve or freeze to death.
You said
we're days from Joseon.
We'll take the remaining
food and firewood.
No matter how rough,
we should make it in 5 days.
But still...
Make the preparations.
Yes, sir.
That makes things difficult.
Why?
What do you mean, why?
I told you.
If we stayed here...
You asked me to kill you...
But now you want to live?
What...
do you mean?
How long are you going to pretend
you don't know?
Isn't that why
you're in a rush to go?
You think I should've died
in the snow field.
It was me.
Don't you?
You...
That's right.
I heard everything.
Thanks to that, I survived.
It woke me right up.
How could I die
with the traitor
I've been looking for
right here?
Well...
Since I'm like this,
I pretended not to hear and
waited for the chance...
But since you
insist on leaving,
you leave me with no choice.
Damn fool.
How can you eat that?
Though you're a simpleton
without much learning,
think with that
big head of yours!
Do you know
what kind of man he is?
You think he'd let you live?
We escaped from the battlefield.
That fool would sacrifice anything
for power and riches.
Look, Do-young.
He'll frame you with something
and say he had to chase you out.
Framing you is nothing to him.
That's what I'd do.
What do you think?
I guess my hunch was right.
Wasn't it?
Why? You want to kill me?
Oh, right. Of course you will.
Since he says he knows the way,
you won't be needing me.
If you knew,
you would've left me
out there to die.
You must really regret it.
Don't you?
That's enough.
Let's talk about that
when we get back to Joseon.
Joseon?
You really think you can
make it back alive?
You worthless dog!
You repay mercy with betrayal?
Though you passed
the court examination,
people still look negatively on
you and your family.
Though it is a low ranked position
in the country,
I struggled to even get you that.
Go down and come back
after a few years.
But, sir!
I passed the examination!
How can you send me
to a position like that?
I've backed away from things
I should have as you wished.
But not this time, sir.
Not this time?
Then what will you do?
You have no choice.
Sir!
Hun-myung...
This is a request.
Do as I say.
A request?
What do you mean?
If you cared for Do-young,
I hope you'll do this
for his future.
Actually...
our So-beuk Clan
has not been happy
with you two being close.
It's always been a burden
on me, too.
You and Do-young...
I mean, your family and ours...
we're in opposing parties.
We're different.
May I ask one thing, sir?
Is Do-young...
aware of this, too?
Why do you look
so happy, my friend?
You brought me out here,
Tell me.
Nothing gets by you.
Of course.
I survived this long
on my intuitions.
I...
Ianded a position in court.
But you didn't even
take the examination.
Special appointment?
Did your father arrange it?
Yes, I guess.
It's not like I want my father
to pull special favors for me.
If only I was gifted in literature
and martial arts like you...
Please.
That reminds me.
What about your test results?
Not good? I'm so sorry.
And I go on about getting in
on special appointment.
Anyway, I'm embarrassed.
By the way...
There is another
embarrassing matter.
What is it this time?
I'm arranged to be married.
At last...
you will marry Seo-hyun?
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman
Then you...
the soon to be son-in-law
of the governor,
are grumbling to me
who is an aristocrat in name only?
No, of course not.
Why would l?
I'm sorry.
How impertinent of me.
To say that in front of you.
Treating me
to this table won't do.
Let's drink all night, shall we?
Why sure!
I knew her since she was young.
I didn't have feelings for her.
But now...
I see she's grown
into a woman.
Hun-myung?
What do you think?
Well...
Oh, now I remember you...
Me? What?
Didn't you like Seo-hyun
since you were little?
What are you saying?
I did not.
Please... I was sure you did.
Nonsense! I never!
Don't get so excited.
I'm joking.
So silly.
I know what you are thinking.
Sir?
You want to kill me
and that fool.
Only then,
will you be rest assured.
No, sir! How dare l...
If you want to live,
it's unavoidable, isn't it?
Your only way to survive
is by killing him first.
Then, you'll have to kill me, too.
Am l...
wrong?
Well, I already gave up on life.
It doesn't matter.
But...
LEE Hun-myung...
I must kill him
with my own hands.
Do you know what I am saying?
He's set on leaving tomorrow.
So we must kill him tonight.
You and I can't beat him alone
the way we are now.
So...
Damn aristocrats
can't be trusted.
Just in case.
Treading out
in this snowstorm...
probably will be hard, right?
Yes, sir.
It's hard, but...
it'll be more dangerous.
You think we can take
someone with a bad leg with us?
- Do you have any family?
- Sir?
How many children do you have?
Four, sir.
Three boys and a girl.
Then, I guess you'll want to
make it back alive to see them.
If we make it back...
I shall owe you my life.
I promise I'll repay you.
Yes, sir!
Damn, stupid bastards.
Shit.
My master is not pleased.
What? Why...
As the county head,
there's a lot to spend money on.
But not enough money coming in.
I wonder where
we can get more money.
I should raise the taxes.
But, sir! No! Please!
No complaints.
Are we prepared
to leave tomorrow?
Yes, sir.
We'll be leaving early.
Get some sleep.
So...
Have you decided
what you'll do with me?
Will you kill me?
Or just leave me to die?
Since you're not
quick to answer,
I guess
you're set on killing me.
Where are you going?
I have to go pee, sir.
Stupid, wretched fools.
That's why they work to the bone
and complain all their lives.
He's supposed
to kill you with me.
There probably won't be
a chance after tonight.
Look, Do-young.
Oh, right.
Did you wheedle that simpleton
into killing me, too?
Of course you did.
You're more than capable
of something like that.
JANG Do-young!
Must you end it like this?
Now you show your true nature.
Must it come to this?
Why?
You expected me to just die?
Really, you have no dignity.
You killed my father...
And now you try to kill me.
I'm sorry.
But that's not happening.
I'll kill you first!
Fine.
If that's what you want,
I'll fight you!
Go to hell!
They're finely cut
pieces of glass!
I reckon it'll be hard to see!
I told you,
That bastard's life is mine!
Son of a bitch!
Who cares who kills him?
You're good
for a man who can't see!
You lowlife vulgar!
Think you can get away
with this?
This lowlife vulgar
must do this to survive!
You're dead anyways.
Go quietly!
Give it up!
I warned you! He's mine!
You son of a bitch!
Do-young! Do-young!
Must you do this?
What would you do
if you were me?
You gave me no choice!
Sir! Wait!
Wait!
Why are you doing this?
You didn't pay
your army tax for this month.
So you should go instead!
But I already paid!
Check the ledger, sir!
I paid!
- The ledger?
- Yes!
Well...
I don't know who you paid to...
But your name's not
in my ledger!
Get him!
Sir! Why are you doing this?
I offered up enough
to you officers, didn't l?
Then why are you doing this?
When did you ever
give me anything?
You always gave it
to other fools!
You should've paid me
long before.
- Take him.
- Sir!
You're too late.
You're already on the list
to go to war.
Take him away.
Sir! Please!
I beg you! Please!
Daddy!
Don't worry!
It's not the first time!
I'll be right back!
No!
Go on in!
Daddy!
Go on!
Going to this war
is just to build
better relations with Ming.
What can a handful of
Joseon soldiers do?
Just stand behind the Ming army
and pull out later.
If you distinguished yourself
in the battle, it would be nice.
War is a great opportunity for
a man from a weak background.
Yes, sir.
I'm very well aware.
Anyway, come back alive.
When you return from the war,
I'll make a position for you
in the court.
Sir?
What?
Do you have
something else to say?
I have another favor
to ask, sir.
What is it?
The former governor's daughter,
Seo-hyun, has become a slave.
I know. So?
Well...
You want me to give her to you?
Fine. As you wish.
Thank you, sir.
No need.
Anything for a man who gave up
everything to be on our side.
But...
Isn't that girl...
the one arranged
to marry JANG Do-young?
The wind is quite chilly.
Why? Angry?
Regretful?
Of course.
Fortune awaits
if you make it back to Joseon.
You must feel angry
it has to be this way.
Filthy bastard.
Ching soldiers!
They're here!
We must hide somewhere!
Let's go down there, sir!
This way, sir!
Grab the handle.
The handle, sir!
Pull up.
What are you doing?
Hurry! Or we'll all get killed
by the Ching soldiers!
Do-young! Hurry up!
I don't believe this.
Stop!
If he escapes,
he'll return with more troops.
Don't let him get away.
What happened?
Now, we're done for!
Sir...
We don't have time for this.
They'll be coming around
any minute!
Right, sir?
Look, Do-young.
Yes, I know.
I don't have any interest
in being in the court.
I should be happy just being alive
in the enemy clan's world.
Why don't you take
the military examination?
They won't care about that.
Not interested.
I'll just end up being
their dog.
That all depends.
You know how aristocrats with
no titles or assets live.
Look at me.
Take the examination.
How could you...
How...
Then let's make a bet.
If you last longer under water,
I'll do as you wish.
This isn't summer.
It's cold.
Don't take the examination then.
Living like this
isn't that terrible.
What?
Such hasty personality.
You change your mind
just due to cold water?
Watch it! I'll fall!
I want you to fall!
Wait!
Then let's go in together.
We're friends, aren't we?
How refreshing!
So refreshing!
How could you...
Hun-myung!
I have to live!
I can't live mixed up with you
aristocrats back in Joseon.
I'm sorry!
Just die! Will you!
Enough!
I said, that's enough!
Right!
You wanted to take
his life, right?
I almost lost
my wrist this time.
He's all yours.
For the last time...
Let me ask you one thing.
You'll die anyway.
So tell the truth.
In order for you to live...
did you have no other choice?
You had to do it?
Answer me.
Answer me!
Say it!
Kill him already!
Don't take all day!
You ignorant fool!
Stop meddling! You bastard!
Just stay damn put!
What did you say?
You son of a bitch!
Damn aristocrats!
I'll kill you both!
You son of a bitch!
He's practically dead.
So you don't need me, huh!
You're done with using me!
You know how I ended up
being dragged out here like this?
It's all cuz of
damn aristocrats like you!
You son of a bitch!
Still, I thought
I'd let you kill him
and kept patient!
I'll have to
kill both of you anyways!
It doesn't matter
who goes first! Does it?
You just know how to use people!
Damn aristocrats don't see
people like us as humans!
Die already! Die!
Damn annoying bastards!
Die! Die!
This can't be...
This can't be happening...
Gotcha!
No.
Oh no...
Gather around!
Follow me!
Do-young? Is that you?
Look, Do-young.
Must we really do this?
I had no idea that would
happen to your father.
If I did,
how could I have done it?
Yes, I was promised a future
by turning in your father!
I admit that! But!
I didn't do it
just for my benefit!
If it wasn't for me,
you would've ended up dead!
They would've killed you
like your father!
I actually ended up saving you!
Shut your mouth! You bastard!
Oh...
There you are.
Despicable bastard!
You worthless brute!
Shut your damn mouth!
After how my father
and I treated you,
you repay mercy with betrayal!
You call yourself a man!
Your father is already gone.
Killing me now
won't change that.
Let's just go back
to Joseon together.
I'm set to get
a court position.
I'll make a spot for you, too.
How about it?
After my father died...
my mother went mad from shock
and hung herself.
If you were me...
can you forgive?
Yes, it won't be easy.
You're right.
Of course you can't forgive.
But still,
I wanted to spare you.
That's why I let you live
all this time.
But I guess
it has to end this way.
Yes! So say it!
Confess everything!
Fine. I'll tell you.
You should know the truth
before you die!
Yes, I did it!
I went to them on my own
and denounced your father!
He's the one who informed us of
So-beuk Clan's plans for treas on.
I did it!
Tell the leader.
But promise me one thing, sir.
This involves betraying
a man who is like a father to me.
Thus, I deserve as much
in exchange.
I told you not to worry
about your future.
I'd like the party leader's
promise, sir!
- Why you!
- Enough!
Fine. I promise you.
Then, let's hear it.
What is it that you want?
Why?
Why did you do it?
Why, you ask?
Why did you repay mercy
with betrayal?
For what?
What? Mercy?
Your father treated me
like a son,
Then how...
If he thought of me as his son!
knowing how
I struggled through life!
How can he give my court position
to you and send me to the country?
How can he do that to me?
You call that a reason?
Even if it wasn't for me,
you can't land a court position.
What?
You worthless brute!
We took you in,
clothed you, and fed you.
How dare you!
A lowlife always acting proud
because you can swing a sword!
I should've seen how
vulgar and foul you really are.
If you had the chance,
you'd sell off anyone
to get what you want.
But, that's it?
Betraying your friend...
selling off my father...
and the opportunity
you gained...
was coming to fight in
a foreign land
to die like a dog!
It serves you right.
What do you know?
How can you say that?
What? It's the truth!
You don't know your place
and got used by
the Dae-beuk Clan!
What?
They told me to get rid of you!
You think I didn't know?
Why did you want to see me?
His Majesty ordered to restore the
So-beuk Clan and reinvestigate.
He reinstated
their positions in the court.
So what?
You want to make peace?
After everything?
That's politics.
Do anything to get what you need.
The same members can
fight for blood,
and gladly hold hands
with the enemy.
That is what politics is about.
You sirs can do damn politics
all you want.
We didn't fight
like market thugs.
We battled over power of the state.
If your father had the power,
I'd be the one dead.
It's just politics.
Nothing we can do.
So, what are you saying?
What do you want from me?
It's a gift.
I heard you're looking
for the one who betrayed you?
Everything involved in the case
is recorded there.
It says who informed us,
and how this all started.
I'll restore everything for you.
Get revenge for your father...
and let's forget the past.
You knew everything?
Then why...
I didn't believe it.
I couldn't believe it was you.
I thought the Dae-beuk Clan
was up to their tricks again.
I wanted...
to trust you till the end.
But you show your true,
despicable nature in the end.
That damn rat!
Do you get it now?
In the Ching's hands or mine...
you were sent here to die!
Shut up! I'm not dying!
Damn bastards!
I'll kill them all!
I'll kill every one of them!
Starting with you and that rat,
I'll kill them all!
You still don't get it!
They're not people you can face
with just your sword!
Do-young!
You dare mock me till the end!
You son of a bitch!
This all started
because of you!
If it wasn't for you,
if you didn't mock me so,
if your father
didn't do that to me,
none of this would've happened!
You bastards made me this way!
You're 3 years younger
but never showed respect!
Being older
doesn't give you the right!
Why you!
Shit!
Come here!
Where are you hiding?
Come out! You bastard!
I don't have time for this!
To go back to Joseon
and kill
the Dae-beuk Clan bastards...
you'll have to die first!
Come out here, now!
Do-young! Come out!
JANG Do-young
You're there.
Aren't you?
I know.
I can hear you breathe.
What...
What happened to us?
What happened...
I always did my best.
I would've done the same
ifl had to live my life again.
That was the only way for me.
Why did you...
Why did you tell me the truth?
Why not hide it from me
and ask me to trust you?
Why not...
If you were me,
what would you have done?
Would you have done differently?
Would you...?
I came back alive as you said.
Now it's your turn
to keep your promise, sir.
My eyes...
I can't see...
No!
We've checked everywhere.
He's the only Joseon man
we found.
So these men
killed our soldiers?
They were hiding...
and suddenly jumped out
and attacked.
I can't find any others.
It looks like they killed
each other.
What a brutal fight.
I must live...
Must go back...
Wretched fool.
Waking up
in a state like that.
He looks like
a Joseon general.
Should we seize him?
No, we have
enough prisoners of war.
We don't need him.
Must return...
Just leave him, sir?
He'll die anyway.
Leave him to die slowly.
It'll be more painful that way.
Why did Joseon send an army?
When they have no reason
to fight?
Joseon wanted to win
political favor with Ming.
Then what about
the Joseon soldiers
who died here?
They died like dogs
for nothing...
Just sent here to die.
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman