- [Promoter] The only
musical merry-go-round
between here and Onkaparinga!
Get back here, ride the
prancing white horses.
A free ride if you're over 60-
- [Promoter] What is he, what is he?
Is he man or is he woman?
It's amazing, it's
unbelievable, it's incredible!
No one under the age of 21.
(carnival music drowning out speakers)
Step right up for
entertainment for two bob.
It's titillating, tantalizing-
(ball thudding)
- Knock a dolly down!
Knock a dolly!
- It's easy, it's easy,
just roll the little ball
through the little hole,
that's how it's done!
(bell clanging)
(drumming music drowning out speakers)
- Now we're going to
introduce the fighters
in a few moments time, boys.
We've got to, hurry up there, pal,
you just take your turn, mate,
you'll get everyone fights here,
but we like to know
who you're gonna fight,
so we're going introduce
the fighters to you.
We've got Bob!
(crowd shouting)
- How about you, ma'am?
(airguns firing)
You, sir?
(people chattering loudly)
- [Promoter] Here she is, all
the way from darkest Africa!
(cheerful carnival music)
(people chattering loudly)
She's black and she's fair
as the day she was born.
- [Man] Young girl wins a prize!
Don't forget, back of the
stairs will win the lady
a cute, little doll or
a box of chocolates.
- [Man] Roll up, roll up!
(blows thudding)
(crowd shouting encouragement)
- I'll double up, do you wanna double up?
- Are you kidding?
The boy's getting the
snot knocked out of him.
(blow thudding)
- Uh!
(crowd shouting encouragement)
- Three to one.
(blow thudding)
(Tommy thudding to floor)
(crowd cheering)
- I can see my money, mate, where's yours?
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(blows thudding)
Hey, what's all this?
- (chuckles) He's getting his second wind.
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(blows thudding)
(blow thudding)
(fighter thudding to floor)
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(blow thudding)
(fighter thudding to floor)
(crowd cheering)
(blows thudding)
(crowd shouting encouragement)
- Watch him!
(blow thudding)
(Tommy thudding to floor)
- One, two, three,
(crowd shouting encouragement)
four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, out!
- That's mine and yours
better be here too.
(crowd booing)
What are you, lover boy,
he wants to have a go too.
- [Man] It's a swindle.
(crowd shouting rowdily)
- Oh, forgot my clothes.
(blows thudding)
- You never learn, do you?
(muffled announcer speaking)
(people chattering loudly)
(bag clattering)
- [Announcer] For the Grand Slam.
(bag thudding)
(background people chattering)
(cheerful jazz music)
(Jack coughing softly)
- [Tommy] Are you alright?
- [Jack] Oh, bit of a
cold, should be jake.
(cheerful jazz music)
(truck rumbling)
- Look, Jack, I'm sorry
about what happened
back there in the ring.
- Oh, it's alright.
No, it's bloody not, Tommy.
You always bugger things up, you know why?
Because you never pay attention,
that's why. (coughing)
- I was anxious, I thought
we'd make enough money
on them side bets to get a
little sideshow together,
you know, for ourselves.
- What, you die hard, mate.
Don't you ever listen to what I tell you?
- I still reckon we could
get ourselves a knock a dolly
or a shooting gallery
or something like that?
- You reckon?
- I mean, it's got everything,
regular income, no work to speak of,
get around the country,
see the local shows.
- Oh, I couldn't stand the excitement.
- You've got your freedom,
but you've still got
a roof over your head.
- I'm going to sleep.
(object tapping)
Look, for the last time, have a sideshow,
you've got to have a truck and equipment.
You have a shooting gallery,
you've got to have firearms,
rifles, that takes money, money
and that's something we
don't have plenty of.
- Oh, I don't know, reckon
we start it in a small way.
- Can't hear a thing you're saying.
(fire crackling)
(cicadas chirping)
- What about your tea?
(soft melodic music)
(Jack breathing heavily)
(Jack coughing)
(soft melodic music)
(Jack coughing softly)
(birds chirping)
(soft melodic music)
G'day, how you feeling?
- (coughing softly) Oh,
what the hell's this?
- Oh, I tossed them
over you after I got up.
Another night out in the open,
you'll end up with pneumonia.
When you feel better-
- I'll be alright.
(birds chirping)
(soft melodic music)
(car rumbling quietly)
(door opening)
- Oh, morning, Sergeant.
- Mrs. Lohan.
(birds chirping)
(background people chattering)
What's with out in the yard?
- Hm?
- About 25, looks like
she's been around a bit.
- Oh, just a blow-in the missus hired.
Help out in the kitchen, you know.
- She's a looker.
I just heard the shearers are staying out,
so I reckon you blokes
better think about moving on.
(man spitting)
Soon.
(men chattering)
- Who the hell does he
think he is anyway, ey?
I'm not moving, I'm staying,
bugger him, I'm staying.
(men chattering)
- Hey, Kearney.
(birds chirping)
Look.
(flies buzzing)
(Jack coughing softly)
(bags thudding)
(background men chattering)
- Hope you blokes are
just passing through?
- We're looking for work.
- Not around here, this lot
have been lying around for days
waiting for the strike to end.
They're running out of time too.
- He's not staying out again tonight.
(Jack coughing softly)
- Where is he gonna stay?
In the police station,
there's plenty of blankets.
Not scared to swing an
ax, you get breakfast.
- Jeez, thanks, Sarge, that's good of you.
- My missus is working on
the tea stall, Mrs. Crow,
tell her I sent you.
(dog barking)
(birds chirping)
- [Mrs. Lohan] I thought
I might give you a start
in the bar tonight.
- Oh, I'd like that.
- Hey,
that's nice.
Oh, it's only a maggot, isn't it?
- Present.
- Ooh, someone must be very fond of you.
- Hardly knew him.
(cockerel crowing)
(chickens clucking)
- You need some sleep, you
reckon you'll be able to sleep?
- Yeah, I'll be alright.
(dog barking)
(background people chattering)
- [Man] Hello, hello, get a go of this.
- Well, here she is.
Now you look after her.
- Ever worked behind a bar before?
- No.
- There's a knack to
pulling a beer properly,
you'd better keep an
eye on me for a while.
- And we'll keep an eye on her. (laughing)
Give the lady a drink, Lohan on me,
what'll you have, love?
Come on, we get a bit
sick of having nothing
but the boss' ugly face to drink with.
- No, thanks.
- Make it two then, if
the lady won't drink.
- Ta.
- Cheers.
- Joycie.
- Joycie?
I'm Keith, this is Dick.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Don't drink, ey?
No bad habits, Joycie, none at all?
Oh, sorry, did I hurt you?
Don't know my own strength, my trouble.
(glass tipping over)
- Oh!
(men laughing)
Look at this!
- Did I wet you, Dickie?
- Too right.
- Sorry about that, why don't
you take your mate's drink
and anything else he's got to offer?
You alright?
- Yes, thanks for the moment.
- [Man] Give me an old one anyday.
- Always gotta rush it, don't you?
Take a bit of time, we
could've been in there.
Only got to use your eyes, she's a goer,
it's written all over her.
- [Man] Well, what about
the Vanguard? That's a car.
- [Man] (laughing) Bloody Vanguard?
- [Man] At least you can
get a couple of Sheilas
in the back seat.
(dog barking)
(cicadas chirping)
(steps creaking quietly)
(soft melodic music)
(bottle clanking)
(door opening)
(door closing)
(Reggie burping)
- Wakey wakey, darling.
Reggie wants to play.
Cooee!
(Joycie screaming)
Stop it, stop it!
Stop it, Lohan, your boss.
- I can see who you are.
- Stop, stop!
- Get out!
(light clicking on)
- What are you doing?
(light clicking off)
You'll wake the wife.
(door opening)
- Go back to where you belong.
- I'm going, don't make a fuss.
(door slamming)
(door opening)
What about my pants?
- Get!
- Ow!
(door slamming)
(door locking)
(dogs barking)
- [Woman] (whistling)
Shut up, you mongrels!
(baby crying)
(footsteps ascending steps)
(dogs barking)
(door creaking open)
(door closing)
(Mrs. Lohan moaning softly)
- Oh, you randy, old goat, go to sleep.
(Reggie sighing)
(cow bellowing)
(water sloshing)
- Hey, did you get a
smell of that kitchen?
(chickens clucking)
Come on.
- [Annie] I'll keep doing it,
because it's my Christian duty,
but I don't have to like
cooking for the drunks
and no-hopers you bring into my kitchen.
(knocking on door)
- It's open.
(door opening)
- Morning.
(food sizzling)
(door closing)
- I think it's outrageous.
Police department's just taking advantage.
- [Keith] I get an allowance for it.
- Huh, not for my time
and effort, we don't.
If it wasn't for simple,
Christian charity.
- You don't need to bother.
- I wouldn't do it.
Suppose it's the cross I have to bear.
- Just sit down.
- Bringing people in off the streets
to make themselves at home in my kitchen.
My chair.
- Sorry.
- Oh, just stay there, it
doesn't matter where I sit.
- Should I move?
- Just sit down where you are.
- Bless us, our Lord in these times
by your bounty we're about to receive
through Christ our Lord, amen.
Imagine how much wood I'll get chopped.
(ax chopping)
- What about one of those
ring the bell things,
where a bloke hits a thing with a hammer,
a little thing flies
up and rings the bell?
(wood clattering)
- Keep chopping.
(ax chopping)
- It wouldn't cost that much, would it?
(chickens clucking)
I don't know what you've got
against sideshows, Kearney.
- Alright.
You've earned your keep.
(wood clattering)
- Next town's Marynong, 20 mile that way.
- Thanks for the tucker, Sarge.
- I'd appreciate it,
if you don't come back.
(birds chirping)
(dog barking)
- I like to travel.
- Around here, it's a big deal
just to go into Marynong to church,
look forward to it all week, some of them.
- Well, maybe they get, I don't
know, support from religion.
- Well, I'm not knocking religion.
I'm a Catholic myself, almost.
Lohan is.
There's a young Catholic
priest over at Marynong now.
He's a nice boy, he's the one that started
this free sandwiches and tea
for the men who couldn't find work.
- [Joycie] It's a nice idea.
- It is.
(door closing)
(birds chirping)
- Look at you, you're dead on your feet.
We ought to go back and see a quack.
- I'm alright.
- Oh yeah, you're great,
you old bull out to piss, couldn't you?
Where the hell you going now?
- I'm gonna have a spell, use your brains.
(bag clattering)
(bag thudding)
(birds chirping)
(Jack coughing softly)
(gate rattling)
(soft melodic music)
(gate screeching)
(cheerful jazz music)
(Jack coughing softly)
- Clean the place out a
bit, it won't be too bad.
What do you reckon?
- You get an agent's
commission or something?
(cheerful jazz music)
Well, if you're on the Titanic,
it doesn't matter if you're
travel first class or steerage.
(bed clattering)
- Bed an'all, ey?
(pots clattering)
Jeez!
Get out.
Go on.
Bloody thing.
(cheerful jazz music)
There's a bloody, big.
(firewood clattering quietly)
(cheerful jazz music)
I'm going into town.
I've got to get you something.
I won't be long, Jack.
(door creaking shut)
(birds chirping)
Cold as an Eskimo's out there tonight.
Evening, gents.
- What'll you have?
- I'll have a beer, thanks.
Hey, boss, what's a bottle of port
and a bottle of brandy worth?
- Oh, different prices, a couple of quid.
What, you feeling a bit crook, are you?
- It's my mate.
- Well, that'll fix him,
do you want them now?
- You haven't got any
half bottles, have you?
- Don't carry them, not the
way they drink around here.
- Yeah, well, I'll leave
it for a minute, alright.
- Your shout, mate.
- Here we go again.
I think I'll probably knock off.
- Yeah.
- Sorry.
(coins clanking)
(quiet background people chattering)
I was wondering if I could
buy a drink for the bar?
- [Man] Ey, one minute ago.
- [Man] You set them up,
mate, we'll drink them.
- [Man] You in the
casket or something, pal?
(men laughing)
(cicadas chirping)
(car rumbling quietly)
- You might just as well come with me.
- I'm going to the greasy spoon.
(car door opening)
(car door closing)
(car rumbling)
(melodic church organ music)
(coins clanking)
(hands thudding)
- No doubt about you, bloke,
I don't think I've won a toss.
- Same again for two bob?
- Well, how about we up the ante to say,
half a quid?
- I don't know.
- You've got to give a man a
chance to get his money back.
- You do a lot of this, do you?
- Do what?
- Set up suckers with a few little losses,
then jack up the ante.
- Hey look, we're playing
a nice, friendly game.
- Yeah, well,
don't think we haven't enjoyed it.
- If you bastards think
you can take a man-
- What did you call me?
- Hold you ba-
(hockey stick thudding loudly)
(glass shattering)
- I've never hit anyone
with this thing yet.
I usually just bar anyone
that wants to fight.
So you two, over there
and you, down here.
If you're after a quiet,
peaceful drink, you can have it,
- You tell them, Lohan.
- Otherwise.
(hockey stick thudding loudly)
- [Man] Piss off, Lohan,
you made me miss my shot.
♪ Mother of Christ ♪
♪ Star of the sea ♪
♪ Pray for the wanderer ♪
♪ Pray for me ♪
- It is what comes out of the person,
that makes him unclean,
poor from the inside.
From a man's heart come the ideas,
which lead him to do immoral things,
to rob, kill, commit adultery.
(cheerful melodic music)
(background people chattering)
- Is that all you drink?
The boys have got a couple
of bottles in the car,
I could borrow one.
- Could you?
- Well, buy one maybe.
- What for?
- Take down the river.
You've got a car, haven't you?
- Yeah, I've got a car.
- Want to?
- No.
- Scared of wifey?
Bet she's away somewhere,
else why would you be
eating dinner by yourself?
- Why don't you sit down?
(cheerful melodic music)
- I like men, boys know nothing.
- My wife's not away, she's at the church.
I'm waiting to take her
home to Cedar Creek.
I'm the Police Sergeant there.
- Whoops.
(background people chattering)
Goodnight, Sarge.
(all laughing)
(coins clanking)
- Hey, Lohan.
Let us know when it's charity
night again, will you, ey?
- Hey, aren't you gonna shift, Unger?
- Come on.
- [Man] Better make this the last game.
- Not exactly crash hot
as a conman, are you?
- I wasn't conning anyone.
- Sorry.
- (laughs) Oh, yeah?
- They were onto you all the time.
- I was a bit anxious, I
need to make a quid fast.
My mate's crook, I wanted to
get him some brandy and port.
- Some what?
- Port wine and brandy,
you mix a tod of each of them together.
- What's he got, for
God's sake, the mange?
- Flu, I think.
- What, are you trying to
put him down painlessly?
(Tommy laughing)
Look, I wouldn't worry about the port,
but the brandy might help.
- Drink up, gents, past time.
- Right, I'll have a bottle, thanks.
- Mr. Lohan, this gentleman
wants a bottle of brandy.
One for the road?
- Yeah.
- Hurry.
(glasses clinking)
- I spoke to you last
night, my name's Tommy,
Tommy Martin.
- Joycie.
- Just Joycie?
- Is that enough?
- You're a very pretty girl,
got a sort of look about you.
- Oh, yeah?
- You know,
ladylike.
- (laughs) Thanks, I think.
- It's just gone closing time,
I thought I might walk
you home or some way.
- You know what I think?
I think you'd better
get back to your mate.
(coins clanking)
- You're about halfway there,
it's 12 and six a bottle.
- Can I owe you the rest until-
- Give it to the missus.
Tell her to stick it back in stock.
Finish your drink, we're closing.
(coins clanking)
Alright, boys, come on, out you go.
(car rumbling)
- Nice service, was it?
- It was very moving.
Please don't do that, Keith.
- Yeah, ta.
(dog barking)
- How about one for the road?
- Thank you.
- Watch the bloody step.
- Whoa!
(men chattering)
(door closing)
♪ If I had the wings of an angel ♪
♪ Over these prison walls would I fly ♪
- [Man] Oh, shut your mouth, Sully,
you can't sing to save
yourself. (laughing)
- What are you doing here?
- I bought it from Mrs.
Lohan, you can owe me for it.
- That's very kind, but I couldn't.
- Don't be silly, if you mate's that sick.
- Well,
thanks.
You wouldn't come and have
a look at him, would you?
(soft melodic music)
You're a woman, you'd know what to do.
- Where have you got him?
- In a shack just outside of town.
(soft melodic music)
Thanks.
(lighter clicking)
(Jack moaning softly)
- You didn't say he was this
bad, he should have a doctor.
- Tell him that, he won't listen.
- And you in here drinking,
while he's freezing to death
out here in this rat hole.
- [Tommy] Well, I didn't know,
I had to get the brandy, didn't I?
- Get the fire going
and some water.
(pots clattering)
Got any rags?
- Rags?
Do you know what to do?
- I come from a big family.
(cork popping)
(water running)
(cicadas chirping)
- Oh, shit!
Bloody hell!
(water pouring)
- Come on, just a little bit more.
(water running)
(Jack breathing heavily)
(Jack shivery moaning softly)
(soft melodic music)
(bed creaking)
(firewood clattering quietly)
(fire crackling)
- [Tommy] Joycie?
- I left you a blanket.
He's warm enough, if you want another one.
- No, no, it's alright.
(soft melodic music)
(Keith snoring)
(bed creaking)
- Hm, g'day.
- It's been a long day, Keith,
I've just come back from church.
- What's that got to do with it?
- It's Lent, we should
all practice restraint,
- It's been Lent for three months.
Jesus Christ.
- And that's blasphemy.
Goodnight, Keith.
Keith?
- Goodnight.
(Jack breathing wheezily)
- Ssh, ssh, ssh!
Ssh, ssh, ssh!
You're alright.
(Jack breathing wheezily)
Ssh, ssh, ssh!
(birds chirping)
(water running)
(water sloshing)
Oh, you're awake.
- [Jack] Yeah.
- Feeling better?
- Yeah, fine, fit as a trout.
- Just not much here to eat.
Let me help.
(plate clattering)
How do you feel?
- Fine, slept pretty well.
- I know.
(birds chirping)
- Were you here all night?
- Most of it.
- Was I delirious last night?
- No, I wouldn't think so, why?
- Well, I had this sort of dream.
- Really?
Now you promise to stay in
bed till it warms up a bit,
later on, you can sit in the sun, right?
- Right.
- I'd better feed your mate.
By the way, I'm Joycie.
- Right.
- Tommy!
- I'm here.
- [Joycie] Breakfast's ready.
- I usually get my own.
- It's on the table.
I'm going down the
creek to clean up a bit.
- Yeah, I would.
- You've got a nice sense
of humor, you know that?
(birds chirping)
(firewood clattering to floor)
- (sniffs) Stew's burnt.
- No, it's okay.
- I reckoned you'd think so.
- What's biting you?
- Nothing, should there be?
- I don't know, is there?
- I'm bloody disgusted, that's all.
- What about?
- You,
man your age and a young girl like that,
(Jack laughing)
- Well, what do you know?
- You make me sick.
(sheep bleating)
(birds chirping)
- I'd better get to work.
- Oh, that's alright,
I can look after him.
I want to thank you for
helping him last night.
- Pleasure.
- I told him off, you
know, for taking advantage.
- Oh, yeah?
- He's just a bit delirious, you know?
I don't really think he
knew what he was doing.
- Right, I'll get my things.
Do you want to walk me back to town?
- Righto.
(tools clanging)
(background people chattering)
- Oh, thanks, darl.
- Please help yourselves
and here's a cup of tea.
- Great.
- [Man] Thank you, my love.
Thanks a lot.
Drop of milk.
- Would you like sugar?
- What do I owe you?
Kearney had a bit stashed
away in his camping kit.
(door opening)
- [Mrs. Lohan] He's
packed your bag, Joycie.
- Why?
- Well, he got all worked up,
when I told him about you
buying the bottle of brandy
for that young blood and then
when you didn't come home
last night, he jumped to conclusions.
- Well, his mate was sick,
I was looking after him.
- Oh, don't tell me, love,
it's none of my business.
All I know is Lohan's
got the knife into you
for some reason.
What happened?
Well, I could make a fuss,
tell him that he has to keep you on,
if that's what you want.
(car rumbling)
- Here you go, darling,
this is your lucky day.
(car engine idling)
(car door closing)
(car door opening)
(kick thudding)
(man thudding to ground)
(lively melodic music)
- You wanna try it?
I didn't think so.
- [Man] Come on, let's go.
(car doors closing)
(car rumbling)
(birds chirping)
- G'day.
(suitcase thudding)
- What a mess.
- Looks like she's moving in.
(pots clattering)
- Just for a couple of days.
- Where's she gonna sleep,
as if I didn't know?
- Look, what do you want me
to do, tell her to buzz off?
- No, just bloody well
behave yourself, that's all.
- You blokes old enough to be in here?
- [Man] Yes, sir.
- G'day, Sarge.
- Lohan, see you lost the new girl?
- Yeah, well, you heard
what she got up to?
Shacked up with those-
- I heard.
- Well, I had to let her go.
Can't have a tart behind the bar.
Can you?
Thanks.
- If she shows up again,
I want to know about it.
Or those two blokes she's with.
- Yeah, sure.
(fire crackling)
(soft melodic music)
(firewood clattering quietly)
- Why aren't you in the cot?
- Just thought I'd sit up for a while.
- End up bloody sick again, I suppose.
- He's right, we should all
be in bed, no arguments.
- Hey, fair go, shouldn't
you be doing that outside?
- He's not getting
undressed out in the cold.
- Haven't you two got any bloody modesty?
Ripping your clothes off like...
I'm going outside, give us a
yell, when you've finished.
(both laughing)
(gentle melodic music)
(Jack and Joycie laughing)
(Tommy coughing)
(door opening)
(soft melodic music)
Smart arse.
(water running)
(both laughing)
- Let me get him out.
(water splashing)
(birds chirping)
(water sloshing)
Here you are.
- You've got to get as much
mud out of them as you can.
Here, look at the size of that one.
(Joycie laughing)
- [Joycie] You know what I reckon?
Fruit picking would be the answer.
- Do you reckon you could handle it?
It's pretty tough,
physical work and dirty.
- There's worse
and dirtier.
- Yeah, I suppose there is.
- And I've done it.
You know what I've been?
A prostitute.
- I think I know everything,
that's important to
know about you, Joycie.
(water sloshing)
It's not what a person's been,
it's what you are that counts.
They say confession is good for the soul.
Don't you believe it, mostly
it's a pain in the arse.
(birds chirping)
I've been thinking,
there's a fair chance this is crown land.
More than likely we could stay
here as long as we wanted.
- Probably.
- Well, I was wondering how you'd feel,
if I was to ask Joycie to stay on too?
- What have you got in mind?
You're not thinking of taking
advantage of that girl,
are you, just because-
- Now, listen, Tommy,
all I'm saying is we'll
tell her she can stay,
if she wants to.
Alright, that's all.
- So long as that's all you're saying.
(soft melodic music)
- [Joycie] You beat me to it.
- [Tommy] Come in anyway.
- I think I'll just wait a little while.
- You're not gonna watch me wash, are you?
- Why not, are you shy?
- No.
Where's Jack?
- Resting, he still
needs building up a bit.
- Bit fond of him, aren't you?
- Yeah, I suppose I am.
He makes me laugh, that's pretty rare.
(water splashing)
(soft melodic music)
You're pretty, you know that?
- What?
- I said you're pretty.
(soft melodic music)
(birds chirping)
(fire crackling)
What have I done?
- I'll go and get some water.
- No, you stay here.
We want to say something, ask
you something. (clears throat)
We were saying that we all
seem to get along well together
and you think we're alright too,
we feel the same about you.
- It's okay to stay, if you want to.
- On one condition.
- You mean you will?
- The first sign of jealousy,
if you ever fight over me,
for whatever reason,
I go.
Alright?
- Right.
- Alright?
- Because I wouldn't want
you to change or anything
on account of me.
(lively melodic music)
- Got hold of it?
- Yeah.
(hammer tapping)
- How's that?
- Beauty, mate.
- Oh!
- "I wouldn't want you
to change or anything
on account of me."
(Tommy laughing)
(lively melodic music)
You bell end.
- Well, there's a few things
we need, kero, tea, sugar.
- We'll get anything you need.
- I'll get you some money.
- No.
- It's silly, if I've got
money, I ought to pay my share.
- No, Tommy's right, we
can't take your money.
But we might borrow a few bob for bait.
(shopping list rustling)
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
- [Tommy] How about a chance to get even,
up the stakes a bit?
- Oh, I don't know, I'm not
much of a player anyway.
- I'm not talking about a fortune.
(balls clicking)
Let's say, ah, say five bob a head?
- How about a quid a head?
- This is a private game.
- What do you reckon, Donno,
accept these blokes' challenge?
Us against them.
- Quid a head.
- You've gotta be joking, this
bloke can't play for peanuts.
- I beat you.
- Just keep it honest.
We'll have Lohan here hold the stakes.
(background people chattering)
- [Man] What about a water diviner?
- [Man] Bloody water diviner,
you blokes think it's drying out.
- These two seem a bit confident.
- Just think balls.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
Sorry, partner.
- Thank you, gentlemen.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
It's all yours.
- What do you reckon, what's on?
- It'll be closing time
in a couple of hours.
You want us to come back tomorrow?
(ball clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
- (laughs) How about that?
- [Tommy] Terrific play.
- What color's next?
- Any bloody color.
- How about the blue?
- Ah, look.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
- You're a real poker face, aren't you?
- You reckon?
(soft melodic music)
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
- Seven.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
13.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
14.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
19.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
20.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
27.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
28.
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
32.
(soft melodic music)
(balls clicking)
(potted ball thudding)
39.
(balls clattering)
- I take it you concede the game?
- Like bloody hell, you conned us.
(blow thudding)
Uh!
- Hey, hey, come on, come on!
(all shouting)
Calm down, calm down.
Calm down, come on!
- That'll do, break it up.
(man thudding into bar)
(glass shattering)
(man coughing)
- You're a lucky fella.
- Right, the rest of you
blokes can go home, go on.
- Fair go, Sarge.
(all complaining)
- Go on, move it!
- I haven't finished my beer.
- Go on, get!
- [Man] Alright, alright,
no need to kick a man.
- [Man] He's not a bloody dog.
- You two next.
You blokes don't move,
till they're out of town.
Shift it, Donno.
(dog barking)
(snooker cue clattering)
How much did they win?
- Two quid.
- Hardly enough to shout about.
Go on, give it to them.
(notes rustling)
- Thanks, Sergeant, a beer?
Three beers, one for yourself.
- I think you're trouble, Kearney.
- All we want is a fair go,
we've got this little place.
- I've heard about the place
and I know who's there.
What I want to know is how
you intend to live there?
- [Jack] If we could
get the work, we would.
- Times are tough around here.
The blokes out there want work,
but the farmers are having a bad season,
there's no love lost
between them at the moment.
It wouldn't take much to put
them at each other's throats,
just don't let it be you two who do it
or I'll come down hard, so hard
you won't know what hit you.
Thanks for the beer.
Lohan,
no more.
(men chattering)
- Good on you, mate.
- How much have we got left?
- Oh, three quid and a bit of silver.
- I'm gonna buy her a present.
- What are you two up to?
(gate closing)
(birds chirping)
What have you got there?
- Oh, just something we picked up in town.
- Let's set her up.
(metal clanging)
- What is it?
A gramophone?
- [Tommy] You like it?
- Does it work?
- Course, it's got batteries.
(bag rustling)
Got a record too.
Do you really like it?
- It's marvelous!
- That's good.
- What Tommy's trying to say
is it's a present from us to you.
- For me?
Thank you.
(soft melodic music)
- May I have the pleasure
of this dance, young lady?
(Tommy laughing)
(soft melodic music)
(melodic orchestral music)
(Joycie laughing)
(Jack laughing)
- Come on.
- Who, me? I can't dance.
- Oh, crikey, come on, we'll show him how.
(melodic orchestral music)
Just like Ginger Rogers.
(Joycie laughing)
Get your own, son.
(melodic orchestral music)
(Joycie laughing)
(all laughing)
Mine's prettier.
(both laughing)
- Whoa, hey!
- Oh!
(vinyl record scratching)
(wheels clattering)
(both laughing)
(cicadas chirping)
(women chattering)
(car rumbling)
- Morning, ladies.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, dear.
(cricketers shouting)
- [Man] LBW!
(door opening)
(bell dinging)
- Good morning.
- Morning.
(door closing)
It is, isn't it, lovely morning?
- You're the lass, who
was working for Mrs. Lohan
up at the hotel, aren't you?
- Well, I was, yeah.
These are nice.
- Oh, they're pure wool, very warm.
- I don't think I've got enough.
I've got enough for a pair.
- Ah.
- Though two wouldn't be
any use, I'd need three.
- Oh, they're very warm,
two will be plenty.
- No, it'd have to be three.
I was wondering if I paid for two now,
could you let me have
the other one, until-
- (laughs) Oh no, dear,
I'm sure you'll understand,
it's just, well, you are a stranger.
- Yeah, I understand.
- I can put them away for you.
- No, I'll have to
think of something else.
- Oh well.
(car rumbling quietly)
(car horn tooting)
(traffic rumbling quietly)
(cockerel crowing)
(men wolf whistling)
- There you go, Charlie.
(men laughing)
(cash register drawer closing)
- That was a quick change of heart.
- Yeah.
(bag rustling)
(background people chattering)
Thank you.
(bell dinging)
(cricketers shouting)
(dog barking)
(Mrs. Lohan humming)
(cheerful melodic music)
- For God's sake, what is it?
- A little present for the
sweetest girl in the world.
I sent off to Sydney for it,
that's a real gold nugget
and I thought later tonight maybe,
you might like to give
me a little present.
(face slapping)
- [Mrs. Lohan] God!
- Pure wool,
they'll be warm as toast.
- They're my present to you.
- They must've cost a fortune.
- The lady at the store, Mrs. Gansman
let me have them cheap.
- And why would she do that?
- [Joycie] Factory
seconds she called them.
- Never underestimate
the power of a woman.
- It was nice shopping
like the other women.
- You wouldn't want to do it
every day though, would you?
Be like being married.
- Dry up, Tommy.
- What did I say?
(water running)
(water sloshing)
- I think Tommy's shook on you.
- [Joycie] Is he?
What about you, Jack?
- Well, I'm a bit old for
that, bit past it, aren't I?
- [Joycie] Are you?
- I'm twice your age.
- What's age got to do with it?
- I don't know.
(water sloshing)
- Can I tell you something
without hurting you?
- I suppose so.
(soft melodic music)
- I'm very fond of Tommy.
- I think it's more than that.
- Maybe it is,
but you can't accept that
I could love you too.
You're very wise, Jack and very stupid.
- I don't want anyone
feeling sorry for me.
- Stupid.
(soft melodic music)
(birds chirping)
- Got you, you bastard!
- Hey!
- Oh, blood!
(flies buzzing)
- So help me, I found it
by the side of the road.
A car must've driven over it.
Dead it was.
- [Tommy] God, do you know
what they do to sheep stealers?
- Well, it's not yours.
Half of it.
- What?
- I'll give you a half of
it, if you shut up about it.
Didn't you, sneaking
around like a mad thing,
you'll scare a man to death.
- [Joycie] Jack, who's
gonna miss one sheep?
There's millions of them.
- I might've known you'd stick up for him.
Just a free bit of tucker, isn't it?
It doesn't matter where
the hell it comes from,
just like your blankets.
- What are you on about?
What about the bloody blankets?
- Tell him how you got
the blankets, Joycie.
- I bought them.
- I know you bought them.
Tell him how you got the money,
if you think I'm so bloody
innocent I don't know.
- What the hell are you on about?
What's he talking about?
- Forget it.
- No, I want to know
about the bloody blankets.
- It doesn't matter.
- No, you tell him.
He's trying to tell you
that I whored for them.
- He what?
(blow thudding)
- Uh!
(Jack thudding to ground)
- Did you?
- Well, what if I had?
I've done it before!
- Alright, you say you didn't.
We accept that.
- You accept it? You don't
believe it, but you'll accept it?
- I didn't mean that.
- I'm leaving this place,
I'm getting out of here now.
- [Tommy] Oh!
(cockerel crowing)
(horse hooves clopping)
(buggy rattling)
- [Keith] G'day, how you doing?
- Alright.
(Keith laughing)
- Are you? I got a good price
for my load, good price.
Wouldn't mind celebrating,
if you know what I mean?
- I have to see Lohan
to fix up about my room.
- [Keith] I'll come with you.
- No, you wait here.
I need five pounds.
- Five quid?
All right.
Alright.
(birds chirping)
- Oh look, I don't know.
I gave it away sort of.
- You gave it away?
- Well, I bought it,
do what I like with it.
- Is Mrs. Lohan about?
- Oh, listen, you don't
want to make trouble for me.
- [Joycie] I just want my room back.
- Well, we'll have to see about that.
- If you want your own room,
we'll build one for you.
We'd like you to come home.
(soft melodic music)
Please.
- Well, I'll be buggered.
(car rumbling)
- Just a moment.
Here's your money back.
- Hey, what's the matter, mate,
did he pinch your girlfriend?
- Girlfriend? She's a
prostitute, a bloody tart.
(men laughing)
- [Man] Few of those around
here, I can tell you.
- [Man] What are you talking
about, you can't afford it.
(traffic rumbling quietly)
- I heard him distinctly, the
woman's a common prostitute.
- I don't know about common,
not too many of them around here.
- [Annie] I don't think it's funny, Keith.
- Look, she probably is.
As long as there's no
trouble, what's it matter?
- Matter?
- Could be a good thing in a way,
keep the hot-blooded blokes
away from the decent girls.
- That is disgusting.
- And the scribes and the Pharisees
bring unto him a woman taken in adultery
and they set her in the
midst and said to him,
"Master, this woman was
even now taken in adultery.
Now Moses in the law commanded
us to stone such a one,
but what sayest thou?"
And this, they said tempting him,
that they might accuse him,
but Jesus bowing himself down
wrote with his finger on the ground
and when therefore they
continued asking him,
he lifted himself up and said to them,
"He that is without sin among you,
let him first cast a stone at her."
(traffic rumbling quietly)
(cheerful melodic music)
(blanket flapping)
(birds chirping)
- We're going into town.
- Yeah, we talked about it yesterday.
- Yeah, we're gonna get some work.
- Well, where, for God's
sake? There isn't any.
- Maybe that's why we're gonna try.
- Well, they can't blame us for looking.
- Well, wait for me, I'm coming too.
(gentle melodic music)
- What's the time?
(cheerful melodic music)
(traffic rumbling quietly)
(background people chattering)
- [Man] Give us a cuddle, love.
- Well?
- Better try Lohan, gotta start somewhere.
- I'll try the shop.
(dog barking)
- Get that thing out of it, it's crawling.
- I wanna know what
you're gonna do about it.
- Burn the bloody thing, if
you don't get it out of here.
- I found it shoved under
a rock near the shack.
It has to be them.
- Could've been anyone.
How do you know who put it there?
- Well, those two no-hopers at the shack.
- [Keith] Or those two.
- Sorry.
- Or if you knew of something?
- There's no work anywhere.
- It needn't be in town,
I've done some kitchen work.
- We know what you've done.
There's no work for the likes of you.
- I see.
Thank you.
- I'm sorry.
- Trollop.
- One of my lambs,
slaughtered it for meat.
- Oh, come off it, mate.
- Mr. Carter here reckons
he found the skin of a lamb-
- Reckons nothing, I found it.
- You can't blame us for
your own stock losses!
- You shut up too, you'll
get your chances later.
- Will we?
- Well, Crow, what are
you gonna do about it?
- Taking them down the
station for questioning.
(men complaining)
Well, what do you blokes
want me to do, hang them?
- Good idea!
(all grumbling)
(children singing in distance)
(background people chattering)
- [Man] Lock them up
and throw away the key.
- [Man] Fair go, what did they do, Sarge?
- [Man] Yeah, good for them there, mate,
eat the cockroaches.
Yeah, look like bread
and water for you blokes.
- What are you galahs looking at?
(dog barking)
- This bloke just gave you half a lamb
out of the goodness of his heart?
- Well, country people
are supposed to be famous
for their hospitality, could've been his.
- Well, let's just say I'm offering you
that famous country hospitality.
- You're locking us up?
- You know, I'm good and mine.
If I let you out of here,
I wouldn't be responsible for your safety.
- We'll worry about that.
- There's also the matter of my job.
I like it here, it's a good, little town,
as long as you don't upset the farmers.
- You weak sod.
- Well, you'll find out
how weak I am, come on.
(keys jangling)
(children playing)
(kick thudding)
- Congratulations, Tommy,
those few kind words improved
his humor quite a lot.
- Stuff him!
- You can't keep them here.
- Girly, in this town, I can
do just about what I like.
- So you could let them go?
- I could.
- Maybe I could talk you into it?
(lighter clicking)
(door opening)
- Sudden change of heart, isn't it?
- Don't push your luck.
Just be grateful.
(gate clanging)
- We're grateful.
- Oi.
(gate closing)
You're better off knowing,
so you leave town.
- Yeah, better for who?
- Everyone.
I'm telling you, you got two choices.
You can get out of town, I
won't be sorry to see you go.
You can stick close to
that shack of yours,
wait for the magistrate to come around.
- The sexual act is a
beautiful and a pleasant thing,
Mrs. Crow, designed by God to ensure
the continuation of the human race.
This repugnance you feel
towards your husband
is contrary to God's great plan.
Now you must give yourself
freely and in love,
oh, never in lust,
but in the knowledge that
even this can be a sacrifice
and a highly acceptable sacrifice too.
- I'll try, Father, I'll try.
If you only knew.
- Please, Mrs. Crow, please.
Go in peace, my child.
- You'd best go out the back way.
They're likely to see me around town.
- Don't worry.
- Here, hang on.
Give you some.
- I got what I bargained for.
- I know, I just want
to do the right thing.
(door opening)
(door closing)
(soft melodic music)
(traffic rumbling quietly)
(horse neighing)
(door unlocking)
(door closing)
(soft melodic music)
- Keith.
Keith,
it's me, I'm home.
You can make love.
- Not now, honey.
- It's all right.
I want to.
- Not now, I've had a
hard day, go to sleep.
- I want to, I want to, Keith, now.
- Annie, what's the matter?
You're behaving like a tart.
(Annie gasping)
Leave me alone.
I'm sorry, love, I didn't mean that.
- Don't touch me.
Don't touch me.
All these years.
- Annie.
- Having you touching me,
putting up with, once, just once.
(birds chirping)
(hammer tapping)
(dust blowing)
(hammer thudding)
(hand patting)
- Let me help.
- You've helped enough already.
- Fair go, mate, she did it
to get us out and you know it.
- What's gonna keep us out?
Unless of course you've
got a regular arrangement
with a copper.
- I'll say this for Crow,
he might be a copper, but he's honest,
which is more than I
can say for some people.
He took what he wanted and he paid for it
and at least he had the
grace to be ashamed.
- Did you?
(pot clattering)
- Where are you going?
- [Tommy] I'm going to
sort the bastard out!
- Crow?
- Crow.
(gate clanging)
Piss off!
- Shouldn't the police move her on?
I mean, your husband-
- My husband is very busy.
If you don't want to come,
any of you, just say so now.
- She's got two men with her,
we can't make them go away.
- We can talk to her as a
delegation, convince her to leave.
- And that's all we do?
Look, what if she refuses?
- We'll cross that bridge,
when we come to it.
I think it's time we got moving.
- Alright then, if you think so.
- Yes.
- Are you serious about this?
- I've had a gut full.
- She's a good girl, Tommy.
- I know.
Kearney.
- Yeah?
- Sometimes I wish we weren't mates.
(car rumbling quietly)
(soft melodic music)
(women speaking quietly)
(birds chirping)
(soft melodic music)
- [Joycie] Can I help you ladies?
- Yes, you can, you can leave our town.
We don't want prostitutes here.
You live here with two men
and you give yourself to both of them.
- Who do you think you're talking to?
Get out of here, all of
you, this is my home!
Leave that alone!
- [Annie] In the dirt, where they belong.
- Stop it!
- Oh!
(Annie thudding to ground)
- Annie, you'll hurt yourself.
- Why don't you let your
husband drive me out, Mrs. Crow?
He's the law around here.
- Argh!
(rock thudding)
(women exclaiming)
- Annie, stop it, Annie.
(all speaking at once)
- These things can go too!
(plates smashing)
(objects clattering)
- Get out of here, get out!
(both shouting)
You can't do this!
(bottle shattering)
(women shouting chaotically)
- Annie!
- What are you doing?
- Argh!
(women shouting chaotically)
(fire roaring)
- Get her away from here!
Get her away, Annie!
Annie!
(fire roaring)
(water sloshing)
- Uh, uh!
(pot clattering to floor)
(women shouting chaotically)
(fire roaring)
- Don't let her loose.
- Come on, get her away.
(fire roaring)
- Uh!
(women shouting chaotically)
- For God's sake, Annie!
(Joycie coughing)
- [Joycie] Uh!
- Never enough!
(women shouting chaotically)
- Uh, uh!
- Come away, come away!
- Come on, turn away.
- Burn in the fire!
(beam thudding to ground)
(Joycie screaming)
(fire roaring)
- Joycie, Joycie, it's too late, Joycie!
(Joycie breathing heavily)
(glass shattering)
(fire roaring loudly)
We never dreamed.
- It's nothing.
It's all gone.
- [Mrs. Gansman] Get away,
dear, it's for your own good.
- Leave me alone.
- Hey, you, Kearney.
- Look Evans, we're not after trouble.
We're looking for Crow.
- You're going the wrong way.
He's in the pub.
(car rumbling)
(soft melodic music)
(fire roaring)
(wood clattering)
(Joycie sobbing)
(soft melodic music)
(wood clattering)
- It was your lamb they
stole, do you wanna start?
- Yeah.
I'll take the old one.
(Jack scoffing)
- I thought you might.
- I'm warning you,
any fighting and whoever's
involved is barred.
- You'll have to bar every drinker
you've got in the pub, Lohan.
- Right.
(radio broadcasting quietly)
- Well, let's have a
drink before we're barred.
Set them up, Mr. Lohan.
- You're not gonna talk
your way out of this one.
- I say we beat the hell out of them.
- I know, but there's
no need to rush into it.
- Well, let's get it over.
- Come on.
(men scuffling)
(man thudding to floor)
- Hey, you're barred!
You're barred, you're all barred!
(blows thudding)
(men grunting)
- Whoa!
(man thudding to floor)
(glass shattering)
(blow thudding)
- Uh!
(blows thudding)
(men grunting)
(glass shattering)
- Uh!
- Get out, you're all barred!
(blow thudding)
Argh!
(blows thudding)
(men grunting)
- Having a bit of trouble, mate?
- You keep your nose out of this, sport.
(blow thudding)
- Uh!
(blows thudding)
(men grunting)
- Hey, who's who?
- Theirs!
- Come on, fellas!
(blows thudding)
(men shouting)
- Bastard!
(chair thudding)
- Uh!
(blows thudding)
(men grunting)
- Tommy, here, come on!
(blows thudding)
(men grunting)
Well, they all seem to
be introduced to each.
- Yeah, let's go.
- Hey, you!
(blow thudding)
Uh!
(radio sports commentator shouting)
(birds chirping)
(metal clattering)
- A man ought to go back and
thump the bloody lot of them.
- Well, that did us.
No, it's finished.
We'll move on.
- And where are we gonna go?
Do you think they're gonna treat us
any different somewhere else?
- No.
It's because of me.
- No, it's not you, it's us,
the three of us together.
They just can't take that.
They live in their
crummy, little community,
where everyone knows everyone.
They all toe the line, till
they get behind their own doors
and they can't take it,
because of what we've got,
had.
- What we had?
For God's sake, what do we have?
A bloody, ramshackle hut
and half a day's tucker.
- Is that all we had, Tommy?
- We'll have to split up.
- Us?
- No, Jack doesn't mean that, he means me.
I can't come with you.
- I'm not gonna leave you here.
They're not gonna change overnight,
they'll treat you like-
- Will they?
I know enough about them
and their precious cop,
that'd shut most of them up for life.
But you're lucky, I
saved a bit of your gear.
You'd better get going.
(soft melodic music)
- Well, we'll be off.
- Alright.
- We'll see you.
- Yeah.
- Meet you down the road.
- Goodbye, Tommy.
(soft melodic music)
(birds chirping)
- I hope you're bloody satisfied.
You buggered things up
this time, didn't you?
Well, I could cheerfully
flatten you, mate.
- I wouldn't try to fight you,
I might let you get away with it.
- Yeah, right?
Well, chuck your swag down
and let's settle it now.
- I wouldn't need to put it down.
- Put it down, bugger you!
- Don't try it, Kearney, you'll be sorry.
(birds chirping)
- Right then, there's a turn off up ahead.
But I want to say something.
She was the only beautiful
thing that ever happened to me.
Doesn't matter what she was.
To me, she was pure.
I suppose that means I love her.
- I know.
- Right then.
I'll see you.
- Yeah, good luck.
(birds chirping)
(men chattering)
- Oi, truck will take
you as far as Wolumla,
you've work there with a
bloke by the name of Johnson,
God help him.
(men cheering)
I don't know when I'll
see you back here now.
- What do you want with these, Sarge?
(men cheering)
(truck rumbling)
(man thudding to floor)
(dog barking)
(men shouting)
(footsteps running)
Who's paying for the beer, Sarge?
- You mean they didn't?
Jeez, you're getting slack, Lohan.
(truck rumbling)
(men laughing)
(birds chirping)
(footsteps running)
- Jack, what are you-
- I know I'm a lot older than you.
I won't ask anything
from you, I'll get a job,
we can settle down and
get married, if you like.
- You miserable, old bugger!
(pot thudding to ground)
You're too late, mate,
I've told Joycie I'm
gonna marry her already.
- Bloody fine mate you turned
out, a man's back's turned-
- What about yours, after running away
puffing and bloody wheezing
your old man's limp!
- I'll give you old man!
- Stop it!
Stop it!
I'm not marrying you, Jack.
- Yeah.
- Or you!
I'm not marrying anyone.
I tried to explain it to you,
but you're both too stupid to understand!
So thanks for the offers, but I'm leaving
by myself the way I came
and you're going together.
(soft melodic music)
(Tommy thudding to the ground)
- Uh!
- Look, now give us a go.
We're all in the same boat,
we can never go back to the way we were,
but, oh look, we've shared winnings,
we depend on each other,
we've, we've done things for each other.
Joycie.
(soft melodic music)
Look, it's the way it's got to be.
I mean, it's up to the both of
us to give you what you need.
- I don't need anything.
- You've admitted it to yourself,
that between the two of us,
we practically add up to one decent man,
well, that's the man that needs you.
- I, Jack does, same.
- There's no way I'm gonna
go tramping through the Bush
for the rest of my life with
a toothbrush and a blanket
and you said yourself,
no one's gonna let us settle anywhere.
- I've been thinking about that too.
- Oh, yeah?
- You can depend on Jack.
- I've always been keen on getting
a little carnival act together,
you know, like a sideshow.
- You what?
- Yes, it's great, you know,
the people you meet them,
they're open minded, they,
they mind their own business.
It's a good, clean life,
you see the country
and you've got some security.
- Hey, listen, I've been trying
to tell you that for years.
- Look, skip it-
- I don't know
anything about carnivals.
- You can't go wrong,
if you do what I tell you.
Now listen, you want a big
drum, boom, boom, boom.
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(bell dinging)
(blows thudding)
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(blow thudding)
(Tommy thudding to floor)
- Look, I'll double it,
do you want to double it?
- I'm not sure, my boyfriend's
taking a real beating.
- [Man] Look, I'll give
you odds, do you want odds?
- Three to one?
- Twos.
- You're on.
- Right, 10 quid to five.
- [Man] I'll have a tenner on that myself.
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(blows thudding)
- One, two, three,
four, five,
six, seven!
(blows thudding)
(crowd shouting encouragement)
(blow thudding)
(fighter thudding to floor)
(crowd cheering)
Two, three, four!
- [All] Five, six, seven,
eight, nine, 10!
(crowd cheering)
(cheerful melodic music)