You!
What are you doing?
No... no!
Oh, what awful weather!
It may be romantic,
mais très emmerdant, huh?
Mais oui.
Ireland is very beautiful
but it's raining all the time.
What a bore!
But it's the rain
that makes it so green and beautiful.
Yes, yes, I suppose you're right.
Where were you going?
Well, I thought that you were late
so I was going to do a little job.
Hm. Thank you for visiting, dear.
I didn't think you could get up
so early in the morning.
I could hardly believe it myself.
If I didn't know that my husband
was not in Dublin
I would have thought that he was
the author of such a miracle.
Now you're getting evil.
Perhaps, but I'm not playing
the role of the jealous wife.
- I know.
- Come on.
Here, put these parcels
in the boot of the car.
Er, perhaps it'd be better
to put them next to me, on the seat.
Yes, perhaps it's better.
But if you have something else to do,
I'll drive the car myself. Come on.
No, no, madam.
I beg your pardon,
but my business is not important.
It can wait.
- Where can I drop you?
- I have my own car, thanks.
Oh... Bien alors.
Mandel, stop first
at Trinity College, then.
Yes, madam.
Bernard!
Bernard, venez en voiture, chéri.
But... Bernard, what are you doing?
Come on, shoo!
Oh, my God!
What happened?
Let's call the police.
Yes, let's call the police.
Oh...
Hello? Hello, Jerry, it's you?
Oh, Jerry! Something horrible
has happened.
Yes. Yes, here in the embassy.
No, His Excellency is away as always.
He's in Switzerland.
- What are you doing?
- Jerry? It's me.
No, I came back last night. Listen,
you'd better come over right away.
As counsel of the embassy
you will have to look after this affair.
Yes.
I don't think there's any need for Bernard
to overhear this conversation.
- Ah, but it was he who discovered her.
- Well, exactly.
We must make him forget
what he has seen.
- Darling. Darling, go.
- Bernard.
- Go upstairs.
- Go to your room.
I, uh... I came back earlier
than I expected.
It never stopped raining in Davos.
Did you call on Marc?
No. No, I didn't stop over in Zürich.
Were you alone?
As always, my darling.
Now, when Jerry comes,
will you please tell him to get in touch
with the police immediately?
- Who are you?
- My name is Johnson. I'm the doctor.
Oh, I've called for him.
Well, have you written your report?
Yes, it's right here.
And... do you think it is possible
to recognize this person?
I would say it's impossible.
The murderer has done a perfect job.
A specialist, I would say.
Like me.
Inspector Lawrence.
Excuse me, sir.
- This letter is for you, sir.
- Thank you.
This must be the woman
who was in the boot of the Rolls-Royce.
Really? What, and nothing else?
Not even a letter?
What did you expect?
The murderer's name and address?
And an invitation to drop by for tea
between five and six?
- No, but... you never know.
- Get a move on.
According to this passport,
she was born in Holland.
- So?
- Well, it may be a coincidence,
but Mr Sobiesky,
before he came to Dublin,
was ambassador to The Hague.
We'd better call him in
for questioning.
For God's sake, man, wake up!
Do you think we're enough to call
an ambassador in for questioning?
It will be a lot if we get permission
to question the members of his staff.
I'd like to see him try and stop us.
He can do it quite easily.
I'll have to get onto the Foreign Ministry
if I'm to get to the bottom of this enquiry.
- Will they give us permission?
- Let's hope so but it won't be much use.
At the most, all we can do it is
to get him declared persona non grata.
While we wait for the bloody bureaucrats
to make up their minds
our boy will have time to slit
three or four other throats.
Is there nothing else we can do?
Don't worry, Johnson.
I'll go on making my enquiries
all the same.
And I couldn't care less
if I am accused of being unorthodox.
- Get me?
- But how?
You'll find out.
Give her a good rub down.
Your Excellency,
Inspector Lawrence is here to see you.
Why didn't you tell me this before?
He arrived without warning.
He's in the library.
Inspector Lawrence
of the Homicide Squad, Your Excellency.
He insisted on speaking to you.
- Hello, Inspector. Please.
- How do you do, Your Excellency?
Oh, uh...
Matches.
I'm sorry to trouble you,
Mr Ambassador,
but I find myself in a particularly...
embarrassing position.
I quite understand.
And I'm going to collaborate
with the police.
Naturally, I expect this investigation
to be carried out
- with the utmost discretion.
- Yes, Mr Ambassador.
There's a question
I should like to ask you.
Did you know that woman?
- Which woman?
- I meant the one... the one that was in...
Oh, the one who was
in the luggage boot of my car?
Well, I might tell you, Inspector,
after one glance and...
quite frankly I didn't feel
like taking a second one,
the lady seemed to me
utterly unrecognizable.
Because of that, do you think
the man who killed her...
Or woman.
What makes you think
the murderer might be a woman?
Well, why not? It's just a thought.
After all, as far as I can see,
there's no evidence
one way or the other.
You spoke of the man
who committed the murder.
I seem to suggest
that it might have been a woman.
Why? Isn't it possible?
Certainly, it is possible.
The use of vitriol
does suggest a woman's hand.
Or a colored person's.
They're expert at such things.
I'm grateful for your suggestion.
Don't rely too much on the words
of a diplomat, Inspector.
Remember we are all professional liars.
We may do it with a certain amount
of style and elegance
but... we are still liars.
So you have no idea who might
have put that corpse in your car?
Or why?
No. No, I haven't the faintest idea.
However, if it's any use to you,
I might suggest that this could be
an attempt to create a big scandal,
which would compromise relations
between our two countries
which right now
happen to be excellent.
Yes, I suppose so.
You're most kind, Your Excellency.
- I don't know how to...
- Oh, not at all. It's my duty
to collaborate with the authorities
of the country of which I'm a guest.
It's a matter of courtesy, hmm?
Would you allow me to question
some members of the embassy staff?
Yes, of course.
But not here.
Call them to the police station, will you?
Whom do you want to see?
For the moment, it will be enough
to talk to the chauffeur.
And the governess.
Later, perhaps...
Well, let's hope
the matter will end there.
It will be so much better for all of us.
I'll take you to your car.
- No, don't worry.
- No, it's a pleasure.
- Maggie?
- You are here too.
Yes. Who is it they're questioning
in there now?
Mandel, the chauffeur.
Listen, Maggie, there is one thing
I would like to ask.
You can be sure, Miss,
I know what I have to say
and what I haven't.
I'm not so stupid
as to tell the police
everything about
the ambassador's private life.
That would be quite useless
to the police
and dangerous for me.
- So...
- What do you want me to say?
You've been making questions now
for two hours
and I don't know what I can tell you
that I haven't already told you.
You haven't told me much.
I'm sorry. I suffer from conjunctivitis.
I can't bear the light.
Rather inconvenient
for your kind of job.
- Yes, it is.
- You haven't replied.
I've told you everything.
That night I went out as usual.
To go to the pictures, wasn't it?
Yes, to the pictures,
even if I can't prove it.
You can take your glasses off now.
There's not too much light in here.
It was almost midnight.
I got home. I put the car in the garage
and locked the doors.
Yes, you told us that.
I'm telling you
for the hundredth time.
Take it easy.
We're just asking questions.
But you ask questions
like you suspect that I'm guilty.
That's your opinion.
He only wants to know
if you've forgotten some detail
that might be important to us.
I do not forget anything.
All this means, therefore,
is that when you got back
to the embassy,
somebody else could have put
the corpse in the boot of the car.
That's what I say, and the next morning
I brought the car around
and was waiting for Mrs Sobiesky
to come down.
That's not what the governess said.
Why? What the hell did she...?
That stupid...
- And so?
- A lot.
She said that when she came out
of the embassy with Mrs Sobiesky
it looked as if you were in a hurry
to go somewhere
and that you only reversed the car
because you saw them coming out.
Well, I didn't think
that was worth mentioning.
Why did you take the car out?
Well, that morning
I thought they would come out late
so I thought I would dash up
to the cleaners.
Are these the cleaners?
- Yes, that's the place.
- What was so urgent?
Did you have a shirt
that was dirtier than usual?
I don't know what you mean.
I'm only telling you the facts.
We appreciate that, even if sometimes
your facts are incomplete.
It's a question of distraction.
Then what?
That's all, nothing else.
Very well.
If in the future you should happen
to remember something else,
some detail
that you think is unimportant,
instead of keeping it to yourself,
you might let us know.
You can go now.
You can tell the ambassador
that so far as you are concerned
the investigation is over.
I won't see him again.
The ambassador has left.
- And besides...
- Besides?
Nothing.
Take it, but remember
this is the last time.
Now, get out and stay out.
Hmm. Is that all he gave you?
He gets tighter every day,
the old bastard.
I gave him what he asked for,
but it's the last time. I'm fed up.
All right, I agreed to keep your son,
but there's a limit to everything.
But... you could have let me
speak to him. Maybe...
No! No, this is the only way.
The sooner he goes back to Switzerland,
the better it is for all of us.
You frightened me, sweetheart.
You scare easily, don't you?
How did you manage to get in?
It doesn't require much imagination
to find a back entrance.
Guess who's here tonight.
I don't care.
How much?
Once when you offered
to give me money, as I recall,
you offered it with a certain flair.
And you too, when you asked for it.
I'm going to need more.
How much, then?
A lot.
And if I refuse?
I wouldn't do that, if I were you.
Can you give me change
for the phone?
Sure.
Where did he go?
I don't know,
and I don't care.
- Mr Jones. Mr Jones!
- What's the problem?
Is that new singer.
She's dead in her dressing room.
Excuse me, I'm a doctor.
Maybe I can help.
No, I think it's too late.
Anyway, you'd better come with me.
All right, go back.
There's nothing to see.
No.
Wilhelm, go to the door,
don't let anybody out and call the police.
Move back, please, everyone.
Come on now, move back.
Go back to the bar.
Go on, now.
All right, everybody,
keep calm now. It's only a fuse.
Please stay where you are.
Stay calm.
No one is to leave the premises, please.
We must wait until the Guards get here.
You're showing
a fine turn of speed there, Miss.
Getting a bit stuffy, wasn't it?
Are you running for your car?
No. I was with a friend.
We came in a taxi.
Ah. Well, never mind.
I'll give you a lift.
- Here, you'll need this.
- But I thought you had a car.
Oh, the only car you're going to see
around here is the paddy wagon.
- You mean the police?
- That's right,
only we call them the Guards.
Now, get your finger out and hop on.
- Who is your friend?
- A friend.
Would it be enough to say thank you
in return for your kindness?
Oh, there's no need for thanks.
All this trouble for nothing?
I didn't exactly say that.
Are you making for the airport?
No, I live outside Dublin.
You know the Manors?
- Uh-huh.
- You do?
Then to the Manors. Do you always take
advantage of disasters to pick girls up?
Well,
I wouldn't consider it a habit now.
- Do you have a name?
- Of course.
- Well, what is it?
- Helen.
Do you want to hear my life story too?
Turn in there.
Well, now, my fleet-footed filly,
are we going to have it off
in the bushes or on the bike?
Hmm. It's damp in the bushes.
You could have asked me
in a roundabout way
for a scotch or a cup of tea.
You know, I'm a great believer
in formality.
Like you.
Mm, you have
a nice turn of phrase too.
Here, now, as long as you're going
to keep me standing outside.
- Isn't this the place they found the...?
- That they found a corpse? Yes.
Curious, isn't it?
You picked me up in a club
where they found another corpse.
Funny it doesn't seem
to worry you very much.
Why should it?
I'm not the murderer.
Do you work here?
As the ambassador's daughter.
Shall we go in? You coming?
- Oh! Hello, Mandel.
- Good evening, Miss.
You look so strange.
Aren't your eyes better?
Much better, thank you.
- Good evening, sir.
- Hi. Good night.
Let's go upstairs
and have that whisky we talked about.
Well, now that's a good start.
Thank you.
Helen?
Would you come here for a moment?
That's my father.
I hope he's in a good mood.
By the way,
if he asks me who you are...?
Well, now, I've washed dishes,
swept the streets
and done a little gun-running.
If he waits a couple of years, he can
read the book I'm writing about my life.
Oh, that's my father.
He won't smoke any other brand.
But I've never known him
to finish one yet.
Would you like one?
Oh, no, I can't stand the things myself.
Shall we go
and hear some nice records?
- Aha! Would you call that diplomacy?
- Oh, don't be silly.
The bushes were never like this.
If you want anything,
help yourself.
Who are you calling?
Oh, there you are.
That's the way I like you.
Let's go.
Mother, the telephone.
Mother!
For pity's sake, it's the phone!
- Oh, Mother!
- Now, eat your dinner.
- Come on now, be a good pussy cat.
- Hello? Yes, it's himself.
Eat it up.
- Yes.
- Yes, you're a good pussy cat.
- Hello, Daddy. Hi, Granny!
- Sweetheart.
Find Granny's glasses
and put them on her, for the love of God.
Go on, pussy, eat it.
Eat it. Come on.
Now, where the devil
have they got to?
- All right, then.
- What is it, Sacha?
Come on. Not hungry?
- OK.
- Come on, now.
Oh, dear.
Give Granny a kiss, dear.
Oh... Thanks, dear.
Granny, why didn't you keep
your glasses on?
Daddy got angry
because you didn't as usual.
But I can't see anything.
And if I can't see
how can I find my glasses?
Anyway, if you didn't go out all the time,
you could answer the phone.
Hmm!
There, I've collected all the clippings
on those two murders
and I think I know who the killer is.
- Did you say something?
- What do you want me to say?
If you don't put on your glasses,
you'll never hear it. Keep 'em on a string.
- And didn't I tell you...?
- I just gave them to her!
Now, then... All right, Mother.
Hm...
Who is it, then?
You're pulling my leg.
Why, it never crossed my mind, Mother!
Oh, yes, you are. I know it.
You think because I'm old
and never go out
that I can't find out
who committed a crime
just by studying the facts of the case.
But you remember that old woman
in the Agatha Christie books?
You know I don't like detective stories.
That's another of your defects.
You read too little.
Dare say. Now,
who do you think is the killer?
Hold on to your seat, Daddy,
while Granny tells you.
As for you, young lady,
just you remember your place!
Now, then, Mother,
don't go changing the subject.
Come on, now.
Out with it, Miss Marple.
- Who is it?
- Are you listening?
- Well?
- Mmm-hmm.
It's the son of the ambassador.
- The son of the ambassador?
- Mmm-hmm.
No, no, no, no!
You'll be saying next
it's Father O'Connor.
Well!
- Daddy!
- What is it?
Daddy, where are you going?
Secret mission.
All right, now, get 'em up.
And don't you move.
Now, let's take a look
at your ugly mug.
God help...!
Like a whisky, John?
How, with these things on?
Take those handcuffs off him.
I told you I was going to use
unorthodox methods in this case.
He's my unorthodox method.
You might have told me that you...
that I'd find your unorthodox friend...
in that flat.
- It would have saved my chin.
- If you went there,
you went there on your own initiative.
Too much zeal sometimes
gets a man into trouble.
Go on.
Good luck.
- You were too hard on those two.
- Hmm.
They weren't exactly kidding either.
You haven't changed since...
You mean, since when I was
in your place, Lawrence?
'All right, then.
'I said, "Talk!"
'Talk!
'Talk! Talk!
'Talk! Damn you!'
'I know you did it! Talk!
'No, you don't.
'No!'
Why do you act this way?
I don't even know myself.
Could be the memory
of my wife's murder,
the thought that every criminal I meet
might be the killer.
When I saw your sergeant walk in,
my mind went suddenly haywire
because I thought he might be the one
that I've been looking for.
Thanks.
You know, I remember once in Brazil
I stepped on an iguana
hidden among the jungle foliage.
This murderer too
is certainly living amongst us,
perhaps under our very eyes.
You know, the iguana is clever
at disguising itself.
The only difference is that the iguana,
though horrible, is harmless,
while our murderer is probably
pleasant to look at
but he cuts throats
and uses vitriol.
It's his tongue of fire, you might say.
Now, then, about that girl.
Come off it.
Don't play the fool.
You know what I mean.
The ambassador's daughter.
Cultivate her. It could be useful.
It's the only discreet way we have
of finding out
what the ambassador is up to.
All right,
if you want.
Hell, what is she? Just another bird.
Try not to get into too much trouble.
You know the risk I took
giving you this job.
- I won't forget it.
- Where are you going now?
To the hospital,
to get myself sewn up.
Doctor, there's a man here
who needs your help.
- Well, then, sit him down.
- Come along.
Sit yourself down here.
I won't need your help for this job.
You may go.
Switch off the light, please.
It's rather a deep wound.
A fight?
You might say, yeah.
I'll have to... inform the police.
Oh, don't worry.
They were there at the time.
Don't move.
Do you think that they will find
the embassy murderer?
I wouldn't have any idea
and I couldn't care less.
The police will never find him.
Never.
He's too clever.
Much too clever.
Ow!
Good evening, sir.
Oh, Norton...
A bow of homage to the man
who took my girl from under my eyes.
And how is it you know my name?
Who doesn't know the name
of Inspector Norton?
Or should I say of ex-Inspector Norton,
known as "the brute"?
Doesn't it ever occur to you
that sooner or later
one of your victims
might try to do you?
Do you call that a threat?
No, only a little bit of advice.
Then here is a bit of advice
for you, my boy.
Don't run into me again.
Madam, I...
- Oh, hello.
- I'm sorry to be disturbing you.
No, you don't disturb me at all.
Helen won't be long.
Please sit down.
- Thank you.
- No, here. Here, beside me.
I was hoping, you see,
that I would be lucky enough
to have a little chat with your husband.
I mean, of course, His Excellency.
I am sorry, you are not lucky at all.
His Excellency has gone back
to Switzerland. I am alone.
As always.
The way you're saying it, I...
How do you expect me to say it?
It's the truth.
Behind... this facade
you are looking at
there is the most terrible,
unbelievable emptiness.
Between me and my children,
between me and...
...my husband.
It's what I suppose
they call nowadays uncommunicability.
Yes, uncommunicability!
Je suis formidable, formidable.
♪ L'amour est un oiseau rebelle
♪ Que nul ne peut apprivoiser ♪
But you see,
the terrible thing
is that I can't fire up.
At least not as I did before.
I'm no longer young.
But I'm not for the rubbish heap yet.
You shouldn't be talking like that.
You're a very beautiful woman.
You are sweet
but I know you don't mean it.
No, no, no, don't try to deny it.
I know you don't mean it.
Anyhow, it's very nice
to hear it said by...
such an attractive and charming man.
That's a marvelous fine lighter you have.
From Cartier.
I would willingly give it to you,
but I can't.
It was a present
from my first husband.
Yes.
When I married His Excellency
I had already two children,
Helen and Marc.
Bernard, the little boy, was born
from my second marriage.
Now I only have memories.
And pleasure I can get from these.
One of the few advantages I can get
from being the wife of an ambassador.
No police, no search warrant, nothing.
Poor Mr Norton.
I hope you haven't bothered him
too much, Mummy.
Not a bit of it. Your mother
has been delightful company.
Another lie.
You know, Helen,
this gentleman,
he's quite... quite charming.
He's a charmeur.
- Where did you find him?
- Between one corpse and another.
Oh, mon dieu!
Quelle façon de causer.
What a horrible thing to say!
Well, I think I...
Well, it was very nice
to chat with you.
- Yes, thank you. Goodbye.
- Hope to see you soon.
À bientôt.
This friend of yours
is rather becoming a pain in the arse.
I don't know why you're talking like that.
He's such a charming man.
And not at all... boring.
I'm beginning to get
a little worried about you.
You know, what little mind you had
has been eaten up by those drugs.
You are going too far,
Excellency de merde.
I'm merely trying
to lower myself to your level.
I am there at the place
where I picked you up,
remember?
Mon chou, how can I forget it?
It's one of the most lovely
souvenirs of my life.
But I don't know
what you are bragging about.
You only got to this rank just because
you've been bowing and scraping
to one minister after another.
How dare you speak to me like that?
You can order your servants around
or your whores.
And from now on
you can go out with them
to your boring reception
and your official appearances.
- Do you want me to break your neck?
- Don't try to raise one finger to me.
Ah, you have no idea
how far I can go.
You bitch.
You fucking bitch!
You bitch! Bitch! Bitch!
Your place?
Fabulous. What time?
Yes, five. See you then.
Well, then, I fixed the party for tonight.
Sort of an all-male affair.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you can count me out.
I have a date with Helen
and I don't want to lose her.
Count me out too.
I have something else on myself
for tonight.
You can't!
I've arranged everything.
Ah, come on, Jerry.
Don't get your knickers in a twist.
- You can't just...?
- Oh, no?
Why should we do what you want?
You take it easy.
Don't try pushing me too far. I warn you,
it wouldn't take much before I...
Oh, what a roar!
Well, lion, what would you do?
Tell me, or shall I knock your face in?
John, why don't you come with me
to Switzerland?
It's out of the question.
Will you tell me something, Helen?
Did you know your father was having
an affair with that girl found in the car?
No, of course not.
He was going
with the one in the club too.
What I'm saying doesn't seem
to astonish you a bit.
- Now, why is that?
- Why should it astonish me?
My father has always been a collector.
He happens to collect women.
Now, why all these questions,
Inspector Norton?
- You know who I am?
- I have known from the start,
ever since that evening
you drove me home.
My father recognized you.
Then Walter confirmed it.
I see. So that's why
he called you into the library
and you had that argument.
I don't remember having an argument
with my father that evening.
Then I'd say you had an unusual way
of conversing.
Well, it's true, Father,
that is stepfather,
can be a little original
in his behavior at times.
But he's just like that.
It's not important.
But tell me,
why did you leave the police?
I'd rather not go into it.
What is the matter?
- Can't say I care for that customer.
- Oh?
What do the papers say?
Oh, there's a lot of speculation
on Sobiesky's role in this affair.
The usual things
to arouse readers' interest.
They're only agreed on one thing.
That we are incompetent
and inefficient.
- Hello, Joe.
- Norton.
Will you give me a pint
of the black stuff?
We've got something
that's been waiting for you.
You have?
Letter.
My precious pussy.
You go down to the kitchen
and have some food.
That's right, my pussy.
Go on, down you go.
That's my puss.
Who's there?
It's me, Mother.
Is this your razor?
Yes, it's mine.
I thought I might shave
the old way again for a while
but I found out I was a bit wobbly.
You see?
I see there's been a new murder.
And I suppose
you already know who did it.
And I suppose your suspicions
are on the ambassador's wife
because you found her lighter
at the scene of the crime.
But you're not listening!
Oh, for crying out loud!
Of course I'm listening, go on.
No, no, no!
A criminal on this level
would never be so stupid
as to leave such obvious clues behind.
Somebody has done that
to fool the police.
That shows the murderer
is an intelligent person,
even if a bit infantile.
If you've never read anything
but the story of Tom Thumb,
you must know that.
So? Go on.
The murderer is the little boy.
The little monster. Believe me.
Hi, Granny. Hello, Daddy.
I'm going to the kitchen.
I'm hungry.
Erin, what is it?
- Er, Miss Sobiesky, please.
- If you go through there,
you'll find the young lady in the bar,
first door on the right.
Have you got a pen and paper?
Thank you.
Would you perhaps be kind enough
to see that this reaches her?
Of course.
Her boyfriends
even follow her out here!
What a surprise.
I could of... missed you,
you know?
A bad sign, hmm?
By the way, who are
those two fellas you were with?
You're jealous, huh?
Could be.
One is my brother Marc
and the other one is a friend of his.
I was hoping to have a word
with your father.
Is it very urgent?
More or less.
You'll find him over at the bobsleds.
He spends all his time there.
Uh, there's my father's bobsled.
Oh!
Do you mind if I sit down?
Please.
I'm fully aware of the reason
for your visit.
And I can assure that I intend to take
full advantage of my diplomatic immunity
to refuse any further comment
on an unfortunate incident
or in any of the others
which followed it.
Now, if that is quite clear, Norton,
then maybe I can offer you a drink.
Or a cigar.
Thanks.
Would you believe I flew
all the way to Switzerland
for the purpose of finding out
what brand of cigar you smoke?
And now you know.
- There was something else.
- I thought we had finished.
It seems I was expecting too much
from a policeman.
Are you aware
that your bobsled was sabotaged?
Somebody was trying to kill you.
Oh well, that's really very good news.
I thought it was my fault.
Well, in any case,
you send your report
to the federal police.
Um, why don't you stay on
another day or two?
No, I have to get back.
Why didn't you tell me
you'd rented that place in Dalkey?
I rented nothing in Dalkey.
Are you out of your mind?
Listen, the time is long past
when I used to enjoy solving riddles.
So if you're hiding something from me,
it's better for you that you tell me now.
But I swear to you,
I don't even know where Dalkey is.
It took a while
but I tracked down the solicitor
for the woman
who owns the house.
I saw the lease.
It had your name on it, Helen,
in nice clear letters.
Some of your dresses were hanging
in the bedroom closet.
And one other thing.
There was a guest in the house
when I got there.
A very dead one.
And he wasn't in the closet, though.
He was in your bed.
Look, if this is a joke,
it's in very bad taste.
No, it's no joke.
The dead house guest
was your old pal, Walter.
You haven't forgotten him too,
have you?
How horrible.
It's terrible.
I can't believe it.
It can't be true.
It's true, Helen.
They're all facts, like the fact
I also found a lighter in the room.
A very special one,
a Cartier lighter.
Then there's the fact that...
that Walter's body
was covered with flowers.
I've no idea why,
possibly to hide the ugly gash across...
...across the poor devil's throat.
Now will you tell me the truth?
I've told you the truth already.
I don't know what you're talking about.
It's all so shocking, so awful, and...
...and after all you've just told me,
you found my mother's lighter.
If that's true, why didn't you
immediately go to her,
instead of torturing me
with these silly accusations?
That's just what I'm going to do
the minute I arrive back in Dublin.
I want that killer,
and embassy or no embassy, I'll get him.
- Good day.
- Something terrible has happened.
Thank goodness you're here, sir.
Madam was trying to kill herself
in the... in the bathroom.
She is still alive.
Will you call an ambulance?
Mandel.
Inspector.
I was waiting for you.
I want to speak with you.
Have a beer?
The ambassador didn't need you
any longer?
So you know too?
Almost three weeks ago
he said with my conjunctivitis
I couldn't drive anymore.
Mmm-hmm?
Only, he has to pay me
what he owes me.
He thinks he can take advantage of me
because he's a diplomat on foreign soil.
But he doesn't know the likes of me.
I will knock his block off
even if they put me inside for it!
And...
That fucking bastard!
And why didn't they give you
a month's notice?
I... I don't know.
It was twenty days ago.
That's why I'm sitting here,
free as the air and without a penny
in my pocket, you know?
Twenty days ago...
That'd be right after the murder, then?
Yes...
Yes, you are right,
now that I think of it.
- You smoke?
- Uh-uh.
No, I don't.
Oh... they got broken
when I got off the bus.
Some bastard gave me a shove,
you know?
Uh, I heard the crack
but I didn't take any notice at the time
and, uh, when...
- When are you pulling out?
- Why?
Nothing.
I might just want to have another word
with you, you never know.
I'm sorry you're broke, you know?
I'll take these with me
and have them fixed.
Why did you do it?
I...
I didn't try to commit suicide.
Someone tried to kill me.
Who?
Who was it?
I'm sorry, sir,
but you'd better go now.
Well, then, Hobbs, what's your opinion?
There's no doubt about it, Inspector.
This piece came from those glasses.
Very well, you can go now.
Mmm...
You don't seem sure.
What doesn't fit in
according to you?
I don't know. It just doesn't fit.
We'll discuss your misgivings later.
This is Jack Mandel's address.
Bring him here.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Go on.
All right, what is it that doesn't fit in
according to you?
Does it surprise you that a murderer
should leave such obvious clues?
Lawrence, if you had a mother
like my mother
you'd know what it means
to have misgivings.
We just have to wait for a few minutes
and then we'll know the answer.
Hello? Inspector Norton, please.
Yes, put him through.
It's for you.
- 'Hello? Inspector Norton?'
- Yes, go ahead.
- 'Listen, I went to get my money.'
- It's Mandel.
I heard Mrs Sobiesky shouting
and if I hadn't come in at that moment,
she would have ended up
like the other victims.
No! I saw the person
who was trying to kill her.
Yeah.
'I cannot tell you who it was because...
'because I'm scared, you understand?
'But it was not me, right?'
Yes, I know that, for God's sake.
Who was it?
I... I'm sure you've already got
an idea about who it is
since from the beginning...
Argh! No!
Mandel!
Just a moment.
I'm not deaf!
I'm coming.
The lady wants to talk to Mr Norton.
I said he wasn't in, but...
I'm Helen Sobiesky,
I'm a friend of your son.
I know everything about you.
- Everything?
- Yes.
- May I come in and wait for him?
- Of course.
Now, thank you, Guard.
Thank you.
I seem such a prisoner
with these policemen
but my son wanted it.
He said we're safer
but it's such a bore.
- Will he be very late?
- Oh, I don't think so.
But please sit down.
I'll get you some coffee.
- Do you like coffee?
- Yes, but don't bother.
It's no bother.
Here you are, Miss Sobiesky.
You must think I'm terribly rude
but John has talked so much
about you and Erin...
That's his daughter's name, I believe?
...that I felt a desire to see his home.
You're a woman. I'm sure
you understand my curiosity.
Of course I understand,
but don't worry.
- Come and have some coffee.
- Thank you.
No, two, five.
Yes, thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Hello?
Who do you want to speak to?
Hello? This is Inspector Norton
calling from Dublin.
I want to speak
to Mr Marc Sobiesky.
I'll go and see if he's in.
- Who is it?
- Shh.
I'm sorry, Mr Sobiesky is out.
If you leave your number,
I'll have him call you when he gets back.
No, don't bother.
You're very kind, but I'm afraid
I can't wait any longer.
Please excuse me, and would you
tell your son that I'll call him later?
Of course I will.
And I do hope
you'll come again very soon.
Thank you, I will.
- Goodbye.
You frightened the life out of me.
When will you learn
that if you don't wear your glasses
you can't hear anything?
Somebody could come in and kill you
like they did the cat.
With that policeman out there
that's not possible.
- Well, you could bolt the door.
- What?
You could bolt the door!
Taxi.
Taxi, over here!
Taxi!
Oh!
Help!
Help me, somebody!
Help me!
Help!
Do you think we...
we should inform the police?
There's time for that later.
Right now
we don't know what it was.
An accident?
Attempted murder?
Maybe she wanted to kill herself.
The only thing we do know
is that you fished her out of the river
in a state of shock.
Do you think
she's one of them junkies?
Maybe.
But it's strange.
She has some bruises on her forearm.
I don't know exactly
what caused them.
For the moment, the only thing to do
is to let her sleep.
It's all clear now.
Oh...
Oh, dear.
Are you using his sun lamp again?
Well, I hope it isn't your father.
Oh, too stiff these bolts.
Ah, Helen, my dear!
Do come in.
My son isn't here, but this time
I won't let you go till he comes back.
And this time you must have
a cup of my excellent coffee.
Please, sit down.
I'll just put the kettle on.
Oh, dear, I should have put on
a saucepan instead of a kettle,
but it's too late to worry.
Help! Granny!
Help!
Granny!
No! Let me go!
Granny, help!
Help! Granny!
Help me, Granny!
Granny! Help me!
What are you...?
- Hello, William.
- Huh?
I'll be in for the rest of the night.
You can go.
That's very good of you, sir.
Thanks.
Anything new in the papers?
There's nothing
the politicians won't solve, sir.
Good night.
Daddy! Help!
Erin!
- Erin...
- She's got Granny!
Helen. Helen!
You're crazy!
You're...
You're her brother!
For God's sake!
I'll kill you like all the others!
I'll kill you!
Mother!
Daddy!
Look out!
Marc had always
been perverted, sick.
He hated us.
Oh, I think he hated everyone
whom he thought was
happy, beautiful, lucky.
Yes, he really tried to destroy us.
He tried to make us look responsible.
All those murders.
Mandel, the chauffeur, found out the truth
and was trying to blackmail him.
Well, the rest you know.
Anyway,
my career is quite over.
At least, I shall have time
to try and forget.
And what's happened
with Helen?
She's in Paris. She'll join us later.
Anyway, I hope so.
It's all a bit pathetic, isn't it?
You'd have put the handcuffs on him
quick enough.
Yes, because...
...it was he who killed the girl
they found in the car.
That was what touched off
Marc's wild spree.
Why didn't you tell me this before?
It would have been useless.
You wouldn't have been able
to do anything.
Anyway, when he arrives back
in his own country
he'll be in
for an unpleasant surprise.
He won't have
his diplomatic immunity then.
And this time,
he won't screw the police.
I'm for a drink.