Subtitled by Victoria Sánchez Mayo
I have never been alone.
Neither do they.
The three of them always together.
18:00.
When they call on the switchboard,
my mother without answering
she tells me that Valentin is already here.
Before leaving I give him a kiss.
Walking down the stairs I run into the neighbor's
the neighbor's dog.
On Valentin Street
is kicking the ball.
And when he sees me he says:
"What's up, sucker!".
And we walked away from the portal.
And I don't want to look
towards my terrace.
I don't want to look,
but I always end up doing it.
And I see my mother leaning out
waving "goodbye" to me.
And I feel like yelling at her:
"Mom, I'm already 15 years old."
But in the end I say nothing.
And I also say goodbye.
And Valentin sees me and laughs.
(Door)
Hello.
Do you mind if I smoke?
I don't.
But you can't smoke here.
Do you know
when the lawyers arrive?
Aren't you Ramón Fortuna?
The door closes and in peace.
We are not going to stand here
talking in a dry way.
The first thing you
you told the police
was that you had killed the man.
It was unintentional.
Well, I don't see the point.
Depending on how you look at it.
It's not funny
that a person has died.
But it's funny
that the person in charge says
who did it unintentionally.
I am only presumed.
The alleged.
It is the truth. It was unintentional.
We will see what the truth is.
I want you to tell me
everything you did that afternoon.
From what time?
Since lunchtime,
for example.
The three of us ate together.
It was the day of the Pilar
and my sister was not working.
My mother and sister
got ready to go to the movies
to see one of Harrison Ford.
What did you do?
My mother had given me
a movie, "Natural Born Killers".
and had arranged to meet Valentin
to go see her at home.
I almost never bring friends.
Why?
Because my mother
and my sister are there.
And since I don't have
no room to myself.
That you sent them
to the movies to get them off your back.
Have you seen
any of Harrison Ford's movies?
Yes.
Doesn't it seem more normal to you that she
see that one instead of
of "Natural Born Killers"?
And don't you think
is not an appropriate film
for her to give you as a gift?
She didn't choose it.
It was recommended to her by the guy at the video store.
So that afternoon
you met your friend Valentin.
What happened is that when I arrived
to the bank where we always meet,
was giving himself
the beating with an aunt as a sophomore.
He told me he was coming with us.
And you were upset?
Of course. What a plan.
They keep going on and on and on and on and on and on
watching the movie like an idiot.
How do you get along with Valentin?
Well, that's good.
I get along with everyone.
Do you know what I'm doing here, Ramón?
He is a lawyer.
No.
I am not a lawyer. I am your lawyer.
It means that I will
defend you even if you are guilty.
It means that
you have to speak clearly to me.
I'm going to decide what you have
to say about what you have done.
But it is important that you tell me
the whole truth.
Valentin has had it up to here with me.
He is my best friend...
But I have the feeling
that he is taking advantage of me.
To ask for my notes.
To ask me
money every now and then.
To come home
to make out with the girls.
57, 58, 59, 60...
61, 62, 63, 64, 65...
I'm coming!
Hey! The blond guy is
behind the red car!
-Because of Pablo!
-It's no good! He's snitched!
What a bastard!
No, it's a lie. I saw you.
What's with the T-shirt?
We have made it
for the end-of-year trip.
Do you like it?
If you behave yourself,
I'll show you the back.
Get something to eat,
I'm hungry as hell.
When you want beer,
here it is.
If his mother were here
I would have taken some panchitos out of us by now,
some cortecitas...
You don't know how cool
this one's mother is.
You just panchitos and crusts,
you spend three days burping.
That's enough, man. Don't overdo it.
Come on, don't get mad,
If not, Jessi says "Fuck you".
She says, "Fuck you." (LAUGHS)
(Car horn)
Hey, you! Let's see if you stick
your dick up your ass.
-Can't you see they've locked me in?
-What the hell do I care?
Stop now if you don't want it to go down.
Do you want to go inside
and let people live?
The one you're going to get inside
you're the one who's going to get a milk.
Fuck, close it there,
don't be a party pooper.
Don't mess with Ramón,
he'll throw us out on the street.
Yes, yes, go on.
Keep on banging on, go on.
Why don't you open
the can of cockles?
Do you open it or not?
Fuck, that donkey meat
does not show through. (LAUGHS)
Damn, you're a blanket, aren't you?
And who is this guy in the photo?
He is my father.
But this photo is old,
How old is he now?
He is now dead.
Okay, son,
it's not my fault...
But let's see, what about that can?
I'm going to have to go myself in the end.
As always.
What the hell are you doing?
I'll open it while I'm at home.
Okay, but if it falls again,
I don't duck.
Come on, open it now, dammit.
(Cough)
What's up?
But, man, what have you done?
Have you cut his throat
for a can?
He cut her throat!
He cut her throat
for a can!
What's the matter, girl?
His throat has been cut
for a can.
What have you done, you bastard?
Calm down,
I haven't done anything.
If you come any closer, I'll shoot.
Son of a bitch, leave the girl,
I'm coming over there and I'll kill you.
Please be still.
Release the girl.
(SCREAMS)
(Shouting)
Call the ambulance.
Valentin, man.
You don't scare me, motherfucker.
Let me pass,
I haven't done anything.
I must wait
for my mother to come.
You're going to kill her in a heartbeat.
A father who would give you two smackers
was needed.
Let me go.
This way I'll have you
until they come to arrest you.
(barking)
Ramón, what is it, Ramón?
Shut up.
(barking)
(Melancholic music)
Fuck, Ramón...
All day together.
They will end up burying us
in a mass grave.
You and me, there alone.
Underground.
What have you done to him?
(THEY SPEAK AT THE SAME TIME)
Where are you going?
To the Fortuna's house.
It is in 4ºA.
Thank you very much.
Good night.
Who is it?
I am Marcelo, the lawyer.
Marcelo...
but what do you mean, the lawyer?
My goodness,
how like your father you are.
And how handsome you look.
Come in, come in.
Thank goodness you're back.
What would we have done?
If we are desperate
for all of this.
Hello, Marcelo.
Gloria?
I don't know if I would have been able
to recognize you.
You wouldn't have recognized her,
it's been so long since you've seen each other...
We remember you and your parents
of you and your parents.
That's why we don't think of anyone else
when we were told that Ramón
needed a lawyer.
You don't know how hard we had it
until we found you.
The worst thing is
the neighbor across the street.
Every time I meet his wife
his wife on the street,
I don't know where to look.
When will they let me come to see you?
You can go whenever you want.
There are no bars,
no call shops.
It is more like a school.
Yes, but there is nothing
like a mother's house.
What do we have to do now?
Be patient.
I already told your daughter on the phone
that juvenile trials
are fast,
but the judge has to
to review the prosecutor's report
and you have to wait
for the girl and the friend to talk.
Poor Valentine.
I have come alone
to keep her quiet.
And to make them think a little
if they really want to
to take care of Ramon.
I have just arrived in Madrid.
So far, I have only dealt with
money matters.
I have spoken to the public defender
who accompanied them with the prosecutor
and he could take it forward
without any problems.
We do not want it to be handled by
a public defender,
we want you to be helped by
someone you trust.
Don't worry about anything.
I have to go now.
Already?
But aren't you staying for dinner?
Thank you very much,
but it's late and my wife and child
are waiting for me.
A child, how old?
One and a half years.
And your parents without seeing it...
Oh, how life is...
It's a good thing Ramón's father
didn't see what happened to him.
Okay, Mom, that's enough.
Let him go, he's in a hurry.
Don't be heavy.
It's not being heavy.
Before you go
I want to give you a present.
It's a picture of your father
and my husband.
I've had it in storage for years,
but it's you who should have it.
You'll see how handsome he looks.
If I were alive, I would be proud of you.
So many years of work
for you to study,
and now you are a full-fledged lawyer.
Why don't you take out the album?
I'm sure we'll find more photos.
That he has said he is leaving.
Another day.
Well, I'm going to look for them
and by the time you get back,
I'll have them out of the way.
Thank you very much.
Thanks to you.
Forgive her, these days
her head is a little off.
She is much more cautious.
Don't worry.
Goodbye.
Marcelo,
I just wanted to tell you
don't forget Ramon
and thank you again.
This boy was in no hurry to leave the neighborhood.
to leave the neighborhood.
Why is that?
Well, I don't know.
And to Barcelona, no less.
And his father here alone.
After all
what you did for him...
Sometimes children are very unfair.
So much effort, so much work...
everything for them.
Even if we are sometimes wrong.
Do you remember this box?
I'm going to bed.
Do you like cats,
Sir?
There are people in the neighborhood
who do not like animals
and they see it as wrong for me to feed
cats,
but of course,
as I am already 85 years old,
I don't care what they think of me.
I feed the cats, that's all.
the cats, that's all.
Well, then... goodbye, sir.
Good night.
Marcelo, I'm a little scared,
Jaime is 38 and he won't stop coughing and crying.
and crying.
There is no way to get it down,
I don't know what to do.
Please do not delay.
It's me again. The child is better.
Where are you?
Keep on sleeping.
-Let's go!
-Hey, come on, let's go!
You are Ramón Fortuna, aren't you?
Yes.
Says the Perico...
Do you know the Perico?
No.
It is one that is here.
He says you've killed
a guy
and that your friend is dying.
And why did you kill that guy?
I didn't kill anyone.
Just knowing that your friend
you didn't want to kill him is enough for me.
It's bad for me to sleep with a guy
who wanted to kill his friend.
I didn't mean to kill him,
I cut his throat unintentionally.
Don't you brush your teeth?
Is it mandatory?
No, you brush them
if you want, look at my teeth.
What do you notice?
That they are clean.
And what else?
I don't know, nothing.
The two paddles
above are false, man.
Can't you tell?
No, it doesn't.
I had them fitted last week.
I have been waiting for them for a year.
One year of Vicente's work in Social Security
in Social Security.
Do you know Vicente?
No.
Vicente is the assistant.
One year for the guy to get
to get my teeth for free
and the dentist said to me:
"Let's see what you do now."
Every night, every night
with the brush for five minutes.
Damn, that's good.
I have been called the nicked one.
Mellado here, Mellado there.
Now I've cut them off.
If they talk to you about the nicked one,
they talk about me.
But of course, I'm not a nicked man anymore.
Fuck them.
What did your mother say?
About what?
That you have killed many people.
That I haven't killed anyone.
That you are here,
what did he say?
I'll see if I get out soon.
What a rush your mother is in.
Mine said the longer I'm here, the better for the world.
I'm here, the better for the world.
For the world in general.
And what have you done?
I don't remember.
I've been here for a long time.
Last year I was catching
horse in the Blackfeet
and that's where I got busted. But the horse
was not for me, I don't get on it.
And who was it for?
I'm going to tell you.
I didn't tell the prosecutor, with that....
(Door)
I'm sure it's Vicente. Enter.
Hello, Ramón, how are you? How are you?
How is it going to be? Fucking great.
I'm asking him.
Thank you.
But tell him you are Vicente.
I am Vicente.
The assistant.
Come on, Aníbal, please,
it's very late, huh?
And let him sleep.
Why don't you stay a while?
Until 23:30.
Because I am very tired.
Most of all
of listening to you all day long.
Did you take the pills?
Yes.
All of them?
Yes, man.
Well, go to sleep
and let the others sleep.
Tomorrow you have to take me
to the eye doctor, don't forget.
But how can I forget?
If I live for you.
Come on, if you need anything,
I'm just down the hall
at the last door
on the left, right?
If you need anything, I am here.
Oh, right.
You know, you ask him, right?
See you tomorrow.
Would you like to?
No, thank you.
You know what Chino told me,
man? He told me to be careful with you
because you had been searched
your bag and you had a knife.
It's a lie.
I know that.
I registered it for you later,
but I didn't do it for gossip.
I did it to sleep peacefully.
That Chinese guy is
a motherfucker, man, be careful.
You know, I better
think you've taken out four of them.
You tell him six, let him be scared.
I'm glad you didn't
you didn't kill anyone.
I've seen dead people, man.
I saw one who stayed like this.
With the beak on,
it was a dead man who looked like a living man.
But of course, it's not the same
sleeping with a murderer.
If I saw you and said:
"This one didn't kill anyone".
And your father, what did he say?
My father is dead.
Is he dead now too?
No, he died many years ago.
What a scare, man. That would
that would have been a real pain in the ass.
I haven't seen mine
since I've been here.
It was not my fault.
I know that.
They have done very well bringing you here.
Now they will be able to say that:
"If this kid had had a father.
a father.
What would I have been like
if I'd had you?
If I had lived?
I would have scared away that pair of women
that haven't let you breathe.
That night
I would have beaten you up.
I would have been wrong
and now you would be hating me.
This is impossible.
Nothing is impossible, son.
What's wrong with this kid,
Why is he so thin?
Take a lot of pills.
I think he is sick.
Poor thing.
His father hasn't been
to see him for a whole year.
God gives bread to the one who
has no teeth, son.
Where are you going?
Well, where am I going to go? Well, home.
My goodness, how you have grown.
How old are you?
15.
15 years,
what a barbarity.
Why don't you want
to be a railroader like me?
I just don't like it.
I want to be a computer technician.
Computer Scientist?
What nonsense,
but it has no future.
A lifetime.
You only live once.
What about this one?
It's Mom.
It is necessary to know that this life...
How old she is.
It is that little is fixed.
Well, I don't like it anymore.
How old she has become.
But, Dad, he's 60 years old.
I have never liked
old women like that.
It's a good thing I'm dead, so
I don't have to sleep with her.
(Prayer)
But she doesn't know how to talk,
she howls because she is very lonely.
Sometimes, the acute hearing
of their adoptive species
listens to his call.
My child.
No boyfriend?
He had one some time ago.
But I think he left her.
Everything is so changed.
I should have been back much earlier.
The drum, "rum, pon, pon".
Yes.
That one?
The clock, "tick, tick, tick".
"Pa?
Are you still angry?
No.
Yeah, you never get angry, do you?
I never get angry, no.
The boy asked me
to go see his mother.
And you didn't hear my messages?
The child had a fever,
I was scared.
Sara, I couldn't leave him there.
Dad?
Come on, let's have breakfast.
Have you told him yet?
Does this mean that
you're going to take over the case?
Yes.
Well, it's a change.
Yes, but just now
we have just arrived.
With the house unassembled,
the office work.
I would have liked to
I would have liked to take it easier.
Marcelo, you want to help
those people, don't you?
Of course.
That's it then.
Don't give it any more thought.
Have you spoken to the prosecutor?
Yes.
¿Y?
When he questioned the boy,
he could barely get anything coherent out of him.
In addition, with all the fuss that was made
with the press and television,
the boy was very nervous.
That's why I sent him to the center.
He seems convinced
that it was all an accident.
How was the boy?
Fine, he seemed calm.
Almost too much.
What about your mother?
She is a stronger woman
than she looks.
Poor thing, it must have been very hard.
And how have you seen the neighborhood?
They brought the sofa, didn't they?
Of course they brought
the sofa, otherwise I wouldn't be here.
You always do that to me, huh?
I asked you
if your neighborhood has changed much.
It was nighttime.
The boy told me
that after the accidents
had gone to a park.
That before going
to see his mother, he went there.
When I was little,
when I got out of school,
I was always going to play
soccer in that area
and there was no park.
That was the end of the neighborhood.
In the spring, the women
would go with chairs to sew.
And the grass grew so tall
that it covered us completely.
I have remembered
that place many times.
Help me.
Ten.
What are you going to do today?
Now come the movers
and this afternoon
take the child to the pediatrician.
I will accompany you.
Not if we're going to live here,
I have to manage on my own.
You don't know what Madrid is like
on a weekday and by car.
What are you talking about?
Look, we do one thing.
You go to work
in a cab, I take my car
and when you leave the pediatrician,
we pick you up.
I think it's a hassle,
but whatever you say.
(Phone)
I'll take it, it will be my mother.
Hi, I knew it was you.
(SPEAKS IN CATALAN)
Would you have liked
your father had lived?
When he died, I was two years old.
So it's like
I've never met him before.
Is it possible to miss
miss a stranger?
I don't know,
is what I want you to tell me.
I have my mother,
my sister, my friends.
Above all, Valentin.
I have known him for many years.
We are very close friends.
Is there anything about you that you don't like?
Don't like it?
Well, like everyone else, right?
I just don't think
it's not important.
What you tell me is important.
Yeah, but it doesn't seem normal to me
to tell anyone that...
The situation
in which we find ourselves
is not very normal,
don't you think so, Ramón?
Maybe I'd like to have
I'd like to have some beard already.
I would also like to be thinner.
No pimples.
I would also like to be blond.
Do you find it hard to talk about yourself?
A little, actually.
You still haven't answered
the question from before.
Which one?
If you miss your father.
No, I already told you that he died
when I was two years old.
So it's like
I've never met him before.
How's your hand?
Well, it doesn't hurt anymore.
I brought you
a change of clothes and socks.
This morning we also
we have been given here.
But these are yours.
I brought you some flan.
Thank you.
And also this book.
I guess you'll have time to read here.
you will have time to read.
Yes.
Have you met anyone?
Who are you going to meet here?
Just my roommate.
Now in the morning
they are all in high school.
I have also been talking
with the psychologist.
With the psychologist?
And what did he tell you?
If I may ask.
To tell him about me,
what I liked and what I didn't like.
Of what you liked and not what?
About me.
And what will that matter to her?
Mom, it's her job.
What an ugly job, to go around
meddling in people's lives.
They could have found a nicer one.
Besides, you don't
you don't need a psychologist.
What you need
is the love of your mother and sister.
Has he asked you anything about us?
No, not from you, from dad.
From daddy?
My poor darling.
13 years dead
and still they do not leave him alone.
What, how are you doing?
Good.
What about you?
Are we still like this?
Fuck, you don't have
you have no nerve or anything.
Hey, he's better at writing
in a notebook than talking.
Let's see.
Yes, sir, this is Ramón.
What about you?
Have you already introduced yourself?
No? Ramón, this is Antonio.
He has undergone surgery for angina
and has been unable to speak for several days.
But since the doctor
said that she is already well,
day after tomorrow, right?
How was your day?
Well, this morning
I talked to the psychologist
and then my mother and sister
my mother and my sister came to see me.
Well, that's good, isn't it?
Yes.
I have not killed anyone.
You're such an ass.
Antoñito.
Do you like to read?
My sister brought me a book.
Which one?
History of time.
I couldn't finish it.
But I think
that you are going to like it very much.
Your sister has done well to bring you
one, because I don't know if
what you are going to find here
is very interesting.
To read other things
you have a public library.
Vicente, I'm leaving,
I'll call you on the phone.
Ramón,
don't pay any attention to the nonsense
they have said about you.
You don't have to lock yourself in,
but keep in mind that
sooner or later
you have to go back to school.
If you don't like yours, it doesn't matter.
You can come to one we have here.
(Door)
You are the one from Vallecas, right?
Yes, but I haven't killed anyone.
I don't care about that.
If you want, keep it,
I haven't seen anything.
But maybe something about you is coming.
Don't let Vicente see it,
he'll get upset.
And if he catches it,
don't say I gave it to you.
(Door)
Come on, man, do you read the newspaper?
How about this?
Mine.
But weren't you from Vallecas?
And what does that have to do with it?
I have not read a newspaper.
They are the leaves that the Parakeet passes.
This was given to you by Perico, wasn't it?
I don't know who Perico is.
I'm sure he gave it to you,
he reads the newspaper every day.
If you find something from someone
who is here, he gives it to you.
He says he wants to be a librarian.
It seems to me that not even he
knows what that means.
Have you found anything?
No, not yet.
Search well, if he has given it to you....
But man, don't be a pain.
Have you had your snack yet?
I'm so hungry I can't see.
I'm going to pee
and we're going to have a snack together.
I'm going to bed.
Have you gone to sleep yet?
Aren't you cold?
Is this Ramon's file?
Yes.
Have you talked to your boss yet?
¿Y?
There is no problem.
I hope it will be fast.
It would be different
if I were of legal age.
And the family
of the deceased has not filed a complaint.
The boy says it was an accident.
Yes.
And you believe him?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
If you help him,
you should trust him.
And shouldn't it be the other way around?
He's a kid.
You have to earn it first.
You were right this morning.
What's that?
Well, I got lost
on my way from the pediatrician to your office.
And we've been driving around
in the car from traffic jam to traffic jam.
I got a little nervous.
It had been a long time
since something like this had happened to me.
Of not knowing where you are,
or where you have to go.
Not that I was afraid, but....
I don't know.
I felt...
Shall we go?
Yes.
What is this?
It's your father, isn't it?
Yes.
And the one next to him
is Ramón's.
Did they know each other?
They worked together.
They became friends
in the underground union.
You had not told me about him.
"Everyone wants to know
where that terrible failure was
that was feeding
a murderous and vengeful personality
and vengeful personality.
At what moment
that harmonious personality
unfolded and grew up,
in the secrets,
to another RFM
who lacked any mercy whatsoever".
This morning I met
Gordo's wife.
I was walking on the other sidewalk
and he stared at me.
Hasn't he said anything to you?
Not a peep.
He wanted to say something,
but he didn't say anything.
I haven't told your sister anything
and don't go and tell her,
I'm sure he'll tell me off.
Lately there is no one who can stand her.
This is already cured.
I brought you some fruit.
There is a little bit of everything.
One is ready to eat
and the other is a little harder.
This way it does not spoil.
You leave it in your room
and you'll see how good it gets.
I have already told you
that I have everything.
Fruit is never left over.
Sorry.
Do you have to watch TV
now that Ramón has a visitor?
-Let him be, if the boy doesn't bother.
-If it's not just for that.
You have other things to do,
don't you?
In five minutes
I want to see you in your room.
(Door)
Come on, open it.
No, look, tell him not to come.
It just gets really heavy.
Give him a kiss for me, okay?
See you later.
What are you looking at, nicked?
I have an answering machine
fucking great
for those who want it.
And what do we want that for?
When you don't want to pick up the phone.
-To send you messages.
-But what phone?
Is someone calling you?
You're hung up, man.
-Where did you get it?
-From the Corte Inglés.
From an exhibition,
in front of a watchman.
And don't let Vicente know about it.
-You could have caught something else.
-Come on, he's talking.
-Better than you 20 times.
-Since when do you speak?
How does it feel to not talk?
-It's fucking great.
-Yes, man. Fucking great.
My grandfather called
and I didn't talk to him.
I would write to Vicente
what he wanted to say and read it.
What a drag
Vicente finding out everything.
-Of course, talking to your grandfather....
-Vicente!
(LAUGHING)
What a fool you are.
Screw you guys.
Here.
But what are you looking for?
Have you ever seen a giant peanut?
Something like this.
A what?
It's all the same, let it go.
Do not leave anything in the room.
Patricio steals anything he can find
he can find.
He snatched a thousand bucks from my drawer.
Well, I don't know if it was him.
Poor Patricio, man.
He's going to eat the answering machine.
Does your mother have one?
No, why not?
You could have given it to him,
since he comes to see you
every other day.
What luck.
We're going to be stiff.
So don't smoke.
Will you let me see
what Perico has given you?
Is it ok?
I don't know.
But it's almost half a page.
And that's all about you?
Almost everything.
That has not even happened to the Chinese.
You always talk about Chino.
You have to be careful with him,
because he'll do it to you right away.
According to you, anyone can do it for you.
Do you know its history?
A few months ago,
he had a crush on an aunt in high school.
I would pick her up after school every day.
class every day.
Until one day, it occurs to him,
suddenly, he decides to open a car.
So he opens it and goes to look for
the girl to show off.
They mess up, they mess up
and end up in Portugal.
And along the way
opening more cars.
Until, on the fourth day, they were caught.
They even took pictures of them.
To the girl at home,
with some teddy bears,
and the Chinese
entering the prosecutor's office.
And Vicente insisted.
"That you put on a hood."
As if he were an ETA member.
And I told him no,
that I wanted my picture.
And so I leave.
When I'm like this, I laugh,
they take my picture
and I come out laughing my head off, of course.
And that Vicente said he had a bad prognosis.
that he had a bad prognosis.
Have you seen my picture?
No.
But there are no photos here.
I just don't care for this
doesn't say anything to me.
If there are no photos, it's business as usual.
Fuck, he tells us the fucking story
every day.
Don't you go to high school?
No, not yet.
Antonio says that your mother
always comes and brings things,
but if you need anything,
you ask me for it
and I bring it to you.
Anything at a bargain price.
Thank you.
This guy doesn't look to me
he could have killed anyone.
Well, you trust and you will see.
"Dear friend:
I read your article
and I was impressed.
He says that I am a victim
of the culture of violence
that leads innocent, ignorant people to crime.
ignorant people to crime.
I'm glad you believe in my innocence,
but I would like to tell you something.
He says I tried to imitate
the violence
of the video film.
But with what happened,
I couldn't even start it.
I wanted a kilo of plums
and one kiwi.
I am not violent.
I have always been quiet.
My mother was always worried
that I would come back with a bump
and said I had to defend myself,
But that's the way I am,
what can I do".
"I am not ignorant.
I don't know if it's okay for me to say it.
I am one of the best readers
in my class.
Now I am reading 'History of time'.
My sister says
that something will stay with me.
Anyway, the article
I loved it.
Look, really, Ramón,
don't be an asshole.
That guy doesn't care
what happens to you or not.
Forget about newspapers.
Don't read them
or even think of responding.
Can't you see that this is serious?
I just wanted to tell you...
You don't have to say anything.
They brought you
so they wouldn't bother you.
To avoid talking nonsense
to journalists.
So be quiet.
For your sake. Is that clear?
Yes.
I'm going to tell Vicente
that we are going for a drink.
Where are you going?
To have a drink with my lawyer.
Are you going out?
But you never go out.
Today you do.
Can I come?
No.
Do you want something?
I can ask Vicente to come.
Yes, tell him to come.
What do you want to drink, Ramón,
that you're gone.
One Coca-Cola
and, if you don't mind lending me
money,
I would like to
to eat something for a snack.
When we get back to the center
I'll give it back to you.
Come on, man, ask for whatever you want.
You look better with a side parting.
How is it going with your mother?
Fine.
No, not good.
You told Gloria
not to go every day.
I told him not to go
because he won't let me...
He arrives, starts to cry and I...
Is it bad for your mother to worry?
He means well,
but he makes a fool of me.
You are made a fool of by them all.
No, not everyone.
Not you, for example.
I'm giving you a piece of my mind now.
But you don't treat me like a child.
Try to understand your mother.
Did he tell you to talk to me?
No, man.
I do it because I believe
I have to do it.
Did you know my father?
Yes.
I used to see him on Sundays when he would meet
with mine for a ride.
Sometimes your sister would come.
They were good friends
and I was very fond of him
because...
I wanted to ask you a question.
I just don't know where I have to spend
Christmas.
You don't have to
stay in the center.
You can go home.
You have time to think about it.
I just don't want to go home.
I am fine where I am.
It would be very sad
for your mother if you did not go.
It would also be sad for me to go
and for her to be always crying.
My sister consoling her
and me not knowing what to do.
You can tell him that it's better
that I stay in the center.
That is nonsense.
Come on, please!
Have you finished it yet?
Almost.
What a guy! And what is it about?
Well, of time in general.
Since the beginning of the world.
I like that science fiction stuff.
No, this is just science.
It's about the formation
of the earth and that.
Not anymore. For me, thinking
about space makes me nervous.
I prefer that God arrived,
on Monday he created the sea,
on Tuesday the rivers
and on Wednesday the animals.
But thinking about the universe
for the sake of it, I don't like it.
Neither did my mother.
One day I told him that man comes from the monkey and all that
comes from the monkey and all that,
and slapped me.
I think it's broken.
But man, don't be handy!
Did you hear about Antonio? He's leaving.
To live with his grandfather.
It has been seen and not seen.
Hannibal, what?
What?
What do you mean? That the teeth
are not brushed here. Let's go to the bathroom.
Ramón, you have a call.
I just got off the phone
with Valentin's mother.
He has finally testified
at the hospital and agrees with you.
From now on
everything will be much easier.
(Crickets)
Again uncle.
We don't have
enough of our own
that on top of that we have
to organize it for them.
-Some will go home, won't they?
-Yes, yes.
Like the Chinese last year
on Christmas Eve.
His father almost killed him
by a beating for a silly thing.
It's because Chino
is a special case.
See, that's what pisses me off.
He believes that, so do we
and in the end he doesn't raise his head.
What are you going to do?
You too
with the little question of the balls.
I don't know, man.
Because if they don't show up
Hannibal's parents
and I hope they don't show up.
He will ask me to stay
at least on Christmas Eve.
And who says no?
How are you doing?
It is still below 200.
But come on, it's fine.
It's pretty good.
If it were not Hannibal, it would be someone else.
Yeah, but it's Hannibal.
You didn't see him when he arrived.
You don't know how bad it was.
And what it has cost us
to get it off the ground.
(Phone)
Take it so they don't wake up.
Yes?
But do you know what time it is?
About Valentin?
I found out last night after I saw you.
Your sister has already called you, hasn't she?
Besides, I have
other things to do.
I don't know if you know
that I don't live off this case.
I work every day
and on Saturdays I like to rest.
Then go see him.
I think you should too.
Have Gloria or the social worker
or the social worker.
The best thing would be for you to go
with your lawyer
and two bodyguards.
Does your psychologist already let you
your conscience?
Okay, I'll pick you up...
I'll pick you up...
At 11:00?
Okay. See you later.
What's wrong with you and that boy?
Why?
I don't know.
You take him out for a snack, you meet up with him
with him on a Saturday morning...
Ramón, I am leaving.
Aníbal told me yesterday.
Good luck to you.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
-If you need anything, you know.
-Yes.
-Chao, thank you.
-I'd be delighted.
I have brought you this book.
I hope you like it.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. We will surely see each other
at the hospital,
I have to take Hannibal.
Well, he didn't tell me anything.
Look there's Marcelo.
Is it a gift for Valentine?
What is it?
The book.
No. This was a gift from Vicente.
J.D. Salinger.
The Catcher in the Rye.
Alianza editorial.
Have you read it?
I've heard of it. But I haven't.
Do you think I should bring him something?
Do you want to bring him something?
Wait a moment.
Don't worry. Everything is fine.
Valentin has been very serious.
I know.
He says you did it unintentionally.
It's true it was unintentional.
Do you know how long he was
on the ground
with no one to help him?
Almost an hour.
It's just that I thought I was...
I thought I couldn't do
anything for him.
He lost a lot of blood. And he had
an infection that almost died on me.
I just want you to tell me one thing.
I don't want an answer from
your lawyer or my son.
I want you to tell me.
And looking me in the eyes.
Was it a fight?
No, I swear.
Can I believe you when you say
that you didn't do it on purpose?
Of course I didn't do it
by the way, Rosa.
I have only come
to thank Valentin.
And to tell you
that I am very sorry.
Come in and talk to him.
What's up, sucker?
How are you?
Very bad, but better.
You gave me a great cut, man.
I saw it for the first time the other day
in the mirror and I almost fell down.
I turned white as a door.
My mother can't quite believe
that it was unintentional.
But I would say to her:
"Mom, if you already know Ramon."
Don't laugh, man.
You almost sent me to the other neighborhood.
Good thing you hit me in the neck.
If you hit me
in the face, I'll kill myself.
I could not bear to go
with a cracked face
as if it were a quince.
My mother says
you're in a reform school.
Well, it's like a school.
They made such a fuss
that they wanted to get me out of the way.
If I continue well, next week
I can go see Jessi,
who is in maxillofacial.
They had to
put a new chin on it.
As far as I'm concerned, as long as I still have
the same ass as always...
I get so bored that I read
"Interview with the vampire".
And I will leave it because I dream that
Tom Cruise comes
and takes a bite out of my neck.
When are you coming home?
I don't know.
They won't let you?
Yes, but I don't know. Do you?
No fucking idea.
Well, I'm off.
Get well and thank you, really.
What are you doing not thanking me?
I saved you from the slammer.
Have you already told them
about Christmas?
I will talk to them on Monday.
Ramón.
Are you coming home for lunch?
Do you like flan?
A lot.
You are lucky,
there is flan for dessert
and Sara makes them like no one else.
Thank you.
I have never seen
a house as beautiful as this one.
Thank you.
You are also from Vallecas, right?
Yes.
We have always lived there.
My house is very small,
there is almost no room to move.
But here... It's good that you have
the garden nearby.
Yes, it was necessary for the child.
When I look out the window, I see the neighbor's living room,
I see the neighbor's living room.
Here they are.
Marcelo, why didn't you
you have not put them on plates?
Do you want a plate?
No, I don't.
My sister also
likes to make flan a lot
and also complains because
we don't put them on plates.
Neither my mother nor I can wait.
It's the same for me.
And how old is your sister?
29.
He will turn 30 in February.
So you knew her, didn't you?
Yes, when I was a child.
My mother showed me the photo
that you have in Luis' bar.
Gloria still goes with my mother
every Sunday for lunch.
Well, now I don't know.
Because, apparently, it hardly ever comes out.
When I went to your house I stopped by.
It is as usual.
The cockles are delicious.
Although I don't know if I'm going to be able
to eat them for a long time.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
What are you doing here, huh?
Do you also want to?
By yourself?
Let's see,
Coffee, anyone?
Me.
Ramon?
No, not me, thank you.
And he came back from the kitchen with coffee
and those chocolates
that are so good.
This is mind-blowing.
When I found it
here on top of it I freaked out.
Weren't you this morning
at the hospital with Vicente?
Yes, I went to see my doctor.
And what did he say?
How nice, as always.
Would you like a puff?
In short,
his wife is hot.
If that guy wasn't going
be with just anyone.
Yes?
-Downs?
-No.
Why?
I have been punished by my parents.
I can't hear you, why don't you come down?
That I have been punished.
Tell your mother
if she'll let you out for ten minutes.
No, it does not.
Then go talk to your father.
No, they don't want to. They are very angry.
Hi, Carmen, how are you?
I left my keys behind
and my parents are not here.
Don't worry.
Would you like to have a drink?
-Come on, give me a coffee with milk.
-Hi, Carmen, how are you doing?
-Well, how are you doing?
-Very well, as always.
What a surprise.
I came to see you, but no one was there.
Is something wrong?
No, no.
I wanted to tell you
about Ramon's Christmas.
Do you know he was with Valentin?
Yes, he told me yesterday.
He also said that
he had eaten at your house.
(LAUGHS) Yes.
He was very happy.
Would you like to have a drink?
Sure.
Hello.
Hello, what's up?
Luis, give me a cane.
Do you know who it is?
The fact is that before
when he entered
his face has rang a bell,
but I don't get it.
Román's son.
The mother who bore me.
(LAUGHS) Román's son. Sole, look
who is here,
Román's son.
Marcelo? Yes, I was just saying
I thought I knew his face.
That's why I've been watching you.
Maybe you thought
I wanted to flirt with you.
You are as handsome as your father.
It's been a long time
since you've been here, hasn't it?
Maybe you were annoyed
that I told you...
No, not at all, don't worry.
I just knew he was going to be happy.
He remembers a lot
of our parents.
Something like that will never
ever happen to me.
As I have not left here.
It's already happened to you.
When?
When I saw you
in your house for the first time.
I told you that on the street
I wouldn't have recognized you.
(LAUGHTER) It's true.
I still remembered you as a child.
The last time we
last time we saw each other we were very young.
Last time
you had just started college.
What do you say?
Yes.
We went for an aperitif
at your parents' house.
It was hot, don't you remember?
No.
That was the day that I
my first long skirt.
Of flowers.
And a blouse that left me
all my back in the air.
My father didn't want me
to wear it,
but I got stubborn.
He was very strict.
Although with me
always ended up giving in.
You showed me
your record collection.
I have never seen
so many records together in my life.
You were very fond of music.
I remember
that I thought you were taking me
to your room to entertain me.
Like when
when we were kids we used to come to this bar
and on the way
you held my hand
while our parents
chatted without paying any attention to us.
That was the last time.
And then Barcelona.
Lawyer.
You got what you wanted, didn't you?
On the other hand, I have let myself go
and the days have gone by
days and days.
Gloria.
And now we are here again,
in this bar.
How did you get it?
But, Marcelo,
I've told you a thousand times.
So tell me one more time.
Good.
Summer, on the beach,
I was still nine years old.
My mother sent my brothers
to buy a bottle of soda.
But they sent me.
That's why you were the little one.
That's why I was the little one.
And as I ran back
with the bottle, I fell.
And what did your mother tell you?
He scolded me for running.
What mothers are like.
Have you noticed that
scars can be read?
Like a book.
You got this one when you fell
off a fence.
Yes.
Do you see how I do remember
everything you tell me?
You had never told me
about Ramon's sister.
Gloria?
Yes.
Well, I don't know her very well.
I had almost forgotten it.
Until he called me
by phone to the office
for me to
to take care of his brother.
Do you miss
having some family?
No, that's nonsense.
Besides,
these things cannot be invented.
I just don't have it.
The other day I asked you
a question and you didn't answer me.
Which one?
What's wrong with Ramón?
I have never seen you
so interested in anyone's life.
I don't know, you're usually colder.
I am not cold to you.
No.
No, not even with the child.
It's with the rest, you don't get involved
in people's lives.
In Barcelona, for example.
You had coworkers,
customers
of those of whom you have been
affairs for years
and you never got
intimate with them.
This is the first time
you are interested in character.
Don't say that.
This is not the first time.
Everything that
there was before I met you,
I can't help but feel
it was another life.
I never had any attachment to my neighborhood.
We lived in a corrala,
Do you know what that is?
The neighbors knew what
were cooking in the house next door
because the smell
was getting everywhere.
And not just the smell.
Some recount their childhood memories
of their childhood with a smile,
well, as far as I'm concerned, let them stay
in childhood and never come back.
All those Sundays in the neighborhood,
studying in a room
from which I heard
my parents' TV,
the neighbor's radio,
the shouts from upstairs.
I didn't want a life like that,
I didn't want a life
like my parents'.
Every thing I did, every step I took
I took was to get away from there.
When my mother died,
my father
did not want to leave the house.
During his last two years,
we hardly saw each other.
He did not want to leave Madrid
and I didn't like
to go back to the neighborhood.
So he died alone.
Then I realized that,
with him, I was losing all my past.
And then I met you.
Payment?
In a house, in a street
can be a whole life.
I don't have any of that.
What little my parents had
disappeared with them.
There is no one who was with me
with me during my childhood.
And it is so difficult
to recount a memory.
(Melancholic music)
Vicente.
What's up?
I wanted to ask you a question.
Yeah, man, don't be such a pain.
Just like a dog.
I have already told you that
you can't smoke.
It's not that,
it's whether you're going to stay or not.
Let's see, what day is today?
December 15th.
It seems to me that
Christmas Eve is a long way off.
As soon as you get careless, the day comes
and I wanted to know what you are going to do.
What are you going to do?
What do you care?
I do care.
I have to get used to the idea
to the idea in case you don't stay.
You're going with your mother, aren't you?
No, I'm staying.
So there are more of us.
Better,
the more we are the more we laugh.
That one is an asshole.
And what are you doing tonight?
Let's go to Barcelona.
What about New Year's Eve?
On New Year's Eve
Sara's parents will come to see us.
Gloria Fortuna
wants to talk to you.
Put the call through to my office.
He's not on the phone, he's here.
It seems that they already dared
to testify in favor of Ramón.
When the prosecutor passes the report
we will talk to the judge.
And if it goes well after Christmas
it will all be over,
we have been very lucky.
Ramón does not want to return home.
Well, I told you
that he was going to stay
this Christmas at the center.
He has made a good friend there.
Ramón is stronger
than he looks
and it's holding up
much better than we thought.
It's just that Ramón
doesn't want to go home anymore.
What nonsense, did he tell you?
He didn't tell me anything, but I know.
I know this better than anyone.
Well, at 15 years old,
you tell me where he's going to go.
There is no reason
for it to remain there.
For Ramón this
has changed his life.
But, woman, don't exaggerate, for God's sake.
Ramón will return home
and they will look at him with curiosity.
But in time, everything will pass.
He went downtown for a few days
and has been here for a month and a half.
This is Ramon's
Ramon's birth certificate.
I got pregnant when I was 14 years old,
my parents took me out of the house.
They got an apartment in Tetuan,
so that no one
in the neighborhood would see me.
When I came back, the baby came
home in my mother's arms.
I thought the neighbors would know
the truth from the beginning.
This lie
has been growing day by day.
I have been living with her for 15 years.
And now, what are you going to do?
Having the courage to be his mother.
I don't want him to return
to a place that was not his home.
I will find a way
for him to live in another neighborhood.
I don't care if my mother bangs her
banging her head against the walls.
She did not decide about my life.
I will decide about my child's.
I don't know what to say.
But I think that
if you want to tell Ramon,
maybe the best thing to do is to
wait until after Christmas.
To having arrived home
and for all of you to be
a little calmer.
I guess I don't have to tell you
to tell you, but...
is going to be a difficult situation.
If you need help,
you can count on me.
I'm glad to have found you
you again,
even if it was for this.
You have behaved
like a true friend.
But, well, what happened to you
in your heads?
No, no, you look very handsome,
really, huh?
Very funny. You look
just as ugly as you are every day.
(LAUGHING)
Well, kids, today
because it's Christmas Eve,
we have a special menu.
We would prefer that you do not end up
too light.
The hors d'oeuvre cannot be used
as throwing weapons
let alone the three prawns
that are going to be on each plate, OK?
Well, enjoy your dinner.
I hope that next year
you have abandoned this
and we can go
with our girlfriends.
Enjoy.
Hand me a piece of nougat.
-Take it.
-Thank you.
Let Chino tell
about Portugal
-I still don't know it.
-No, not again.
Then let Ramón
tell about the dead.
Antonio, don't be too smart.
We always have to be
always have to be talking and he shuts up.
Well, if you tell your stuff
it's because you feel like it.
I'll tell you again:
let's have the party in peace.
Did you know that next quarter
they are going to open a new workshop school
and that whoever studies there
will be able to live in the apartments
that they have built next door?
-And what is being studied?
A lot of things:
computers, electronics...
carving and wood, bookbinding.
Abel, what do you have in mind
for next year?
Well...
I'm going to keep training.
And, when I'm ready, I'm going to ask the cop's manager
the cop's manager for proof.
I talked to a guy who works
at El Velero
and he told me that the cop's manager
the cop's manager goes by
and that since he is no longer
or to hit his mother...
who is looking for a kid
to represent.
I have given the bar staff
the center's phone number
and I have been promised
that if the manager comes back,
that they are going to give it to him.
I don't like boxing,
but if you fight, I'll go.
When I get out of here
I'm going to my grandmother's
to the charcuterie
in Cuenca.
-Wasn't it a butcher shop?
-No, a deli.
You told me a butcher shop.
As you say
that my grandmother is a butcher,
I'll cut your balls off.
-Hey.
I still have to clean
the school for a year.
So next time,
you think about it,
before destroying three classes.
That's not something that everyone is
to everyone.
Javier broke I don't know how many booths
and has not had to pay.
You are going to be an example
for all of Spain.
As I seem to be doing well in this course,
I'm going to see if I can take a course
of these librarian courses
or some other move.
I'm going to set up a tavern
with Francis.
A little joint in Entrevías
with a colleague
who is now of legal age.
We work hard
and then we give him the dough.
And we cheated you on the accounts.
I don't think I'm going back
to high school this year.
I don't know, the truth is that I haven't
I haven't thought about it yet.
You are staying here with me
until next year.
Be careful, kid, this one
he'll give you some of what he's got.
What's the matter? I didn't say anything.
The only thing I have told you
is to be careful.
Ask for forgiveness.
Who, Ramón?
Don't be too smart,
ask Hannibal for forgiveness.
Fuck this kid...
on top of the fact that whenever he is taking
takes out a cigarette paper...
And I am always by his side,
as if nothing had happened.
Ask for forgiveness!
Ask for forgiveness.
That it doesn't matter, really,
that it doesn't matter.
Fuck, Vicente,
if I haven't said anything.
Go ahead, ask for forgiveness.
If I only said that...
Go to your room, you cunt!
I hope you die next year.
Let him go, Ramon.
Let him go, please.
It almost killed me. It almost killed me, I swear.
(Door)
Ten.
Take this and lie down.
Yesterday was great.
I've been dreaming for a year
of someone doing that to him.
As long as you're here, he won't dare
to mess with me,
but when you leave...
I still don't know what I'm going to do.
You went berserk.
Even Silvester was freaking out.
And the guy starts:
"It kills me, it kills me."
Don't you care that I'm sick?
that I'm sick?
Me? Of course not, man.
And do you know what I'm sick of?
Yes.
The doctor says that they no longer die
as they used to,
that it is no longer the same.
Of course it is not the same.
Well, my father knows it too
and he hasn't come to see me.
Come on, man, we're late.
Look, man.
Fuck.
The one that is rare is Vicente.
When he seems to be on your side,
the guy who goes and takes the other guy's side.
the other guy's side.
He told me that Chino deserved
more compassion than me.
Let's go. That bully.
What, are you improved or not?
What the hell is wrong with you now?
I've never been
to a Chinese restaurant, you know?
Well, the truth is that I've never
been to a restaurant.
To bars, yes, to many.
In the end, we always end up
eating some tapas in a bar.
We have to transfer here.
When we lived with grandma
it was different,
we always ate at home.
But when he died,
my brother Lexis and I
went back to my parents.
Last Christmas
we spent in a bar.
We were my parents,
my brother Lexis and me.
My parents told us
that we could ask for
of everything we would like.
After a while, they told us that they had to leave for a moment.
they had to leave for a moment,
but that they would be right back,
that we would wait there.
But when people left,
my parents didn't arrive.
We were there, waiting.
I didn't know what to do.
The owner of the bar
gave us Coca-Colas
and some tortilla skewers.
We were there for at least two more hours,
two more hours,
while those at the bar
finished eating.
I watched a whole movie on TV,
one of a slave who does not want
to be a gladiator
and rebels against the Romans.
It was very long.
In the end, the bar owner
called the police
and that night they took us
to a place to sleep.
And then to a residence.
I haven't seen Ulises for three years
I haven't seen him,
because some gentlemen adopted him.
When my parents came
I lived with them for two years.
All that time, I don't know what I did.
Waiting.
When my parents showed up, it was
to put on and go to sleep right away.
In the end, not to be alone,
I ended up accompanying them
to catch them in the village,
and one day when my father was ill, he
sick, he sent me.
When I had already bought it
and was on my way home,
The police showed up and caught me.
They asked me about my parents,
but I have never snitched
and I didn't say anything.
My mother appeared from time to time
in the center,
but he hasn't been here for a long time.
I haven't seen my father since.
I thought that if Ulysses
is still with that family
maybe one day she'll come looking for me.
That's my sister.
Hello.
This is my friend Aníbal.
Hello, Hannibal.
Bring it here, child.
Don't get a cold in your throat
and get sick.
This is impossible.
I'm checked by the doctor twice a month
a month
and tells me
that I am getting stronger every day.
Twice a month? That's a lot of crap.
They do take good care of you, yes.
And I just got new teeth.
new teeth.
And look how I have them, look.
It's great that you're so happy with your
so happy with your teeth,
that you don't know what a nuisance they are.
I used to have a hole here in the middle,
but Vicente managed
to fix it for me.
He also had a bad ear.
What have you not gone through, child?
What have you done to your hair?
Well, I've put on some hair gel.
You look very handsome.
And you too.
Do you want to show Hannibal
where you live?
It's just a moment.
And then you can do whatever you want.
Of course it is.
And you have to take the box
with the photos for Marcelo,
who will stop by the school tomorrow
and I promised him
that I would have them ready for him.
Come on, let's go.
Look, I live very comfortably
in this street,
but if it had trees,
I would like it a lot more.
And where is your house?
It is right here.
-Hello, how are you?
-Hello.
-What? Is the boy coming back already?
-Yes, in no time.
Let's see how you behave,
your mother is very sorry for you.
How are you going to behave?
Well, as usual.
Woman, that's an understatement.
I lived with my parents
in a boarding house.
That's good, so your mother
didn't have to clean up.
She wasn't around much.
Neither was my father.
Most of the time we spent most of the time
my brother and I alone.
And why were you left alone?
Too much work?
Yes.
Have you seen how hot it is?
Sit there on the couch
and put whatever you want.
Gloria, cut some nougat for the kids.
for the kids.
With everything that has happened, this year
we haven't even split it yet.
Christmas is going by
that we are not even aware of it.
Let's see if next year
things get better,
because this is no life.
Mom, don't start.
Can you help me?
I don't say anything anymore. Every time
I say something, you tell me to shut up.
I don't know what I have done
4The other day I went to high school.
The director told me that
January 8 you can come back.
If you feel like it.
It's just that everyone
is going to ask me.
But we can look for another solution.
I don't mind if you lose a course.
You can spend it on other things.
I'll have to know what mom says first, won't I?
what mom says, right?
Mom has to be given it done.
To dwell on it will only complicate things
will only complicate things.
He would start wailing,
and cry and...
I can't stand it anymore.
If it's okay with you, I'll come see you
next week and we'll talk.
I went to the institute
to prepare the ground for you,
in case you wanted to come back.
You can really do
whatever you want, Ramón.
You should not stay there any longer
there, you are not a delinquent.
Neither does Hannibal.
But Hannibal has no family.
It has nothing,
don't compare yourself.
Why don't you go to the movies?
They show an adventure movie
that they say is very good.
Take money from my purse.
The one with the beard married last year
with one of the TV news,
but he at night
and she in the morning
and that marriage will never be seen.
So they don't fight.
(LAUGHTER) Well, you're right too.
(Melancholic music)
And Ramon?
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Where is Ramón?
Ramón is sick, with the flu.
He told me to come
here to wait for him
and I've been there for three quarters of an hour.
Well, I'm going to your room.
Better not.
He told me
that his head hurts a lot
and says he doesn't want to talk
to anyone. He knows what Ramón is like,
when he says he doesn't talk,
is that he does not speak.
It was for him.
You can share it.
Shall I open it now?
No, in your room.
And tell Ramon
that when he feels better
to call me.
Ramon gave me this for you.
He told me, when I see him,
to call him.
And I say it to you.
I do what I am told.
(Melancholic music)
I came across this by chance.
"I just want to know if it's true
and if you knew it."
"I'll be all afternoon
waiting for your call. Ramon."
And he didn't tell you anything else?
Yes, to call him.
That sweater is old, isn't it?
If someday you want my cap.
I'll leave it with you.
Isn't it fucking great?
Who is my father?
I can't tell you.
I have a right to know, don't I?
That I can't.
What difference does it make. I never saw him again.
He was not my boyfriend.
Ramón, I was only 14 years old.
I just want to know a name.
To know how you knew him.
Please tell me who it was.
One night, my friend Luisa and I
we went out with three guys
from high school.
First we went to La isla bar
to have a few beers
and when we were all loaded up, we went to the park,
we went to the park.
There we smoked a few joints.
I liked one of the boys,
but I started with another one.
Then I went on to the one I liked.
Shall I tell you that I did it with all three?
Well, I can't tell you,
because I don't remember.
I do not remember
and I have no regrets.
How can I regret something that happened
that happened 16 years ago?
I just want you to know that I would never,
I never thought that you could
have killed anyone.
At the worst moment.
When we came back from the movies
and everybody was talking about you,
as of someone
who had gone mad.
So I ask you not to think
that I was a whore.
Because it wasn't.
There are so many things
that are done at that age
without thinking about the consequences.
I have never wanted to talk
to anyone about all this.
I don't know how you will feel
not knowing who your father is,
but I only feel shame.
Ramón,
you have to learn
to understand and forgive.
And you can't say
that you lacked affection,
because you've got some left over.
Son,
son,
I know you are angry with me.
I am not your son.
But that doesn't change the affection
I had for you.
Why didn't you tell me this before?
You've been fooling me for a long time.
But you wouldn't have believed me.
You would have been angry
and you wouldn't have let me come back.
Don't talk nonsense.
You can't get angry
with a dead man.
If you want me to leave
forever.
I can no longer change anything.
We dead people can't fix our mistakes
our mistakes.
And what shall I call you
from now on?
I don't want to call you dad
like I used to.
Well, Grandpa, I don't want you to call me.
And I don't like my name either.
Your mother insisted on putting it
in the niche and I didn't like it.
Call me Fortuna.
Fortuna?
You were the best son
a father could ever wish for.
I have a belly like a drum.
I can't sleep either.
Well, we are off to a good start this year.
No, man, no, please.
Well, this relaxes me.
You lie down like this, on your back
and it's as if you were
in the countryside.
Do not open the window.
Hey, are you going to sign up for the
to the school-workshop?
What about you?
I guess so.
We'll have to get out of here sometime, won't we?
have to get out of here, don't we?
Already.
The thing is that I don't know
if I want to leave so soon.
I'm sure Vicente
misses me.
And, what does your family say?
Well, they still don't know,
but I don't think they think it's wrong.
Anyway, since it's fine with me, I'll do it.
it's fine with me, I'm going to do it.
Well, if you are so sure.
Of course. You have three months
to decide
and when we are there, we can
continue to live together in the apartment.
And what can I do?
I don't know, any of
of those things that Vicente said.
Computers, wood carving,
bookbinding...
Look, and this way you can fix the book
that you broke.
I have never read
a book in my life.
You don't have to read it
if you don't want to.
Hello, did you find the street well?
Yes.
Jaime, do you remember Ramón?
But how great you are!
We were watering. Come in, come in.
They are going to make a report
for television about the workshop.
Vicente called me and told me
that I should not go out.
Because I am not very representative.
I'm not a waif
and all that.
But of course...
Nobody knows the truth.
And what are you going to do in the end?
I'm committed and I'm going out.
They say that we won't be able to see well
and our face will be blurry.
Do you want to go out?
Me? Why?
How you helped me.
But I didn't do anything.
Besides, my thing
not about chorizo.
I help the fat cats
not to pay taxes.
(Phone)
This is the sweater you gave me.
And you've been wearing
with the label on?
The truth is that I haven't had
many opportunities to wear it.
But it's very nice. It really is.
I would like to invite you to dinner,
but we are going out with some of Sara's friends
Sara's friends who are coming from Barcelona.
It doesn't matter.
Sorry. It was Begoña,
who can't stay with the child.
You go. I'll stay with him.
No. Alone I don't feel like it.
If you want, I can stay.
You tell me what to do
and I wait until you come.
It's a good idea, isn't it?
Can you come here for a moment?
Come! Where are you going?
What's up?
Do you think it's a good idea
to leave the child with Ramón?
Yes, they do, don't they?
I'm sure they get along well.
In addition, Ramón is very affectionate.
Do you think I'm crazy enough
to leave my son in the hands
of a child
I don't know what's in his head?
You told me I should trust him.
trust him. Don't you remember?
We are not going to argue about that.
If you don't want him to stay
it doesn't stay.
But the kid is not crazy.
What interest do you have
in continuing with this?
You have already done everything you could
for him and his family.
They are the only thing
I have left from my past.
With them I have the opportunity
to get it back
and I'm going to take advantage of it.
But what past do you
do you want to recover, Marcelo?
It's just that...
It's hard for me to talk about it.
It makes me sad.
It makes you sad
because you don't talk about it with anyone.
And the one who feels it is me
who am here with you.
Do you love me?
What's that all about now?
No, really. Do you love me?
I have the feeling that
you are with me because I take care of you.
Because I am here.
For what I love you.
Please, this is absurd.
Of course I love you.
Sara...
Sara is very fearful
with the child.
He has had very high fevers and...
It's all right.
I'm going to leave.
Stay a little longer.
I heard some of what he was saying.
Don't think that...
No. If I understand it...
There is something I want to tell you.
I lied to you when I told you
how things had happened.
I killed Gordo.
He had me by the neck
and only let me go
when I kicked him.
He stood cowering on the stairs.
And he looked at me.
I realized
that I was waiting
to grab me again.
So I gave it another kick
and he fell down.
I think there is no difference
between having kicked him or not
because it was going
was going to fall.
But there is.
And the fact is that since then
I have not been able to stop thinking
that I killed that man.
I'll call you one day
and we'll meet for lunch.
You take me to one
one of those restaurants you know.
Of course it is.
See you later.
Goodbye.
Ramón.
Don't think about what happened.
You have nothing pending.
(Music)