1961 Arts Festival Entry
A Takarazuka Pictures Production
The End of Summer
Produced by Sanezumi Fujimoto...
...Masakatsu Kaneko,
and Tadahiro Teramoto
Screenplay by Kogo Noda...
...and Yasujiro Ozu
Cinematography by Asakazu Nakai
Art Direction by
Tomoo Shimogawara
Original Music by Toshiro Mayuzumi
Sound by Koichi Nakagawa
and Hisashi Shimonaga
Film Editing by Koichi Iwashita
Assistant Director Jyukichi Takemae
Production Design by Okamura
Tamondo
Set Decoration by Kitagawa
The Cast
Setsuko Hara
Yoko Tsukasa
Michiyo Aramata
Keiju Kobayashi
Akira Takarada
Daisuke Kato
Reiko Dan
Yumi Shirakawa
Kyu Sazanka
Yu Fujiki
Haruko Sugimura
Yuko Mochizuki
Chieko Naniwa
Chishu Ryu
Haruko Togo
Michiyo Tamaki
Masahiko Shimazu
Tatsuo Endo
Tomoo Uchida
Kyoji Hayakawa
Hisaya Morishige
Ganjiro Nakamura
Directed by Yasujiro Ozu
The City of Osaka
So meticulous.
Let me see that.
Hey, does my eye look strange today?
Looks the same to me.
Someone got you a nice gift.
I bought it myself.
He's here.
- Welcome.
- Good evening.
You came alone?
She'll be here soon.
I told her to come at seven.
I'll have a whiskey on the rocks.
She said she had to deliver a
painting before coming here.
I see.
Listen. You say she's a real catch.
I hope you know what I'm looking for.
Oh, I'm well aware.
Your late wife was very pretty...
...and when we went
to Arima this past spring....
No need to mention that.
There's a slight catch though.
What's that?
She had a son with her late husband.
I don't mind.
I'm in the same situation.
What did her former husband do?
- He taught at Osaka University.
- A professor, huh?
He didn't run a sake brewery?
He said the family
business wasn't for him.
A professor's widow....
A member of the intelligentsia.
She should be here any minute.
Wouldn't it be better if I
wasn't sitting here?
- Oh?
- I'll stay out of sight for now.
When she arrives, I'll act
like I ran into you by chance.
- Where will you be?
- Just right over there. Okay?
- It's a great idea.
- Hey, Mr. Isomura.
If you like her, give me a signal.
Okay, I'll rub my nose.
Here you go.
Where did he go?
- What's all this about signals?
- We were just talking baseball.
Right over here.
- Welcome.
- Sorry to keep you waiting.
Please have a seat.
Would you like anything?
I'm fine, thank you.
- Maybe later.
- Enjoy your stay.
Thanks for coming out here tonight.
Not at all.
What did you wish to discuss?
Well, I haven't seen you in ages, and
the anniversary of Mother's death is soon.
I just wanted to catch up.
Hello there.
- Hello, Kitagawa.
- It's been awhile.
Yeah, not since Rokko.
Please, have a seat. Please.
Just for a little while, then.
- Who's this?
- She's from my wife's family.
- The Kohayagawas.
- I see.
I've heard about your family.
From around Midosuji right?
I work at my friend's art gallery.
I see. That's great.
Here's my card.
I run a small steel mill
over by Sakaigawa.
Mr. Isomura has always helped me out.
It's very nice to meet you.
Your job seems very elegant.
I suppose so....
Do you have any paintings of
oxen at your gallery?
- Sorry?
- You know, cows.
I collect cow related things.
You see, I was born in the year of the ox.
This is a cow too.
If you had a cow painting lying around,
I'd love to take a look at it.
A Japanese painting?
Or perhaps a different style?
What do you think?
Should I leave it up to her?
- Good idea.
- I'll leave it up to you.
I'll look for one.
I think that Noriko may be visiting today.
Please excuse me while I use the phone.
Is there a phone?
- What do you think?
- Looks good. Very good.
- Wonderful.
- She's great.
You do know my tastes.
She's the right age too.
- Hey, I'm counting on you.
- Oh?
We should grab dinner.
First, let's have a drink. Hey.
Gin fizz sounds good right?
Three gin fizzes.
- This is great. This is better than great.
- Glad to hear it.
This calls for a celebration. A toast.
I'm home.
- Welcome back.
- Hi.
I'm sorry I kept you waiting.
I was invited out,
but I declined and hurried home.
Does this look correct?
Try again.
This goes here, right?
So this won't work this way.
Think it over.
What did you want to discuss?
Well?
I was told to meet with
a prospective husband again.
Again? You're so popular.
Not like that one. This one is serious.
Even Fumiko is encouraging me.
What's he like?
His father is the president of a bank...
...but he works for a beer company.
Sounds good.
- It's not that easy. I'm stuck.
- What do you mean?
I don't really want to get married yet.
You'll have to eventually though.
- Why don't you meet him, at least?
- But....
If you don't like him, just say no.
Neither Father nor Fumiko will force you
into something that you don't want to do.
- You think so?
- Of course.
The thing is,
the store isn't doing so well...
...so Father really wants me to marry him.
I understand.
I have to go.
Is it that late?
If you hurry you can...
...catch the train that
leaves at 16 past the hour.
I'll come again some other time.
Thanks for talking to me, Noriko.
You're welcome, anytime.
Oh, I bought some sweets.
I'll have some the next time I visit.
- See you later, Minoru.
- Goodbye.
You should hurry.
I'll see you later.
Take care.
Bye.
I heard that Okaden is going to
merge with Katsura Masamune.
Oh? I heard that rumor.
Who'd you hear the news from?
Do you know Kaneko?
- From Katsura Masamune.
- Yeah, I know him.
I ran into him yesterday,
and he mentioned it.
So I got him drunk to get some details.
Hello? Yes, he's here.
It's your wife, sir.
- Any response from Mr. Yamayoshi?
- Not yet.
Hello? Hello?
Yeah, it's me.
What do you need?
My uncle from Osaka just arrived.
If you have some time,
I wanted you to stop by.
Okay, see you then.
- He said he'll be right over.
- I see.
So, how do they feel about the situation?
He met her 2 or 3 days ago.
- Seemed very interested.
- I see.
What has Akiko said?
Well, I haven't explained it to Akiko yet.
So Akiko met her prospective
husband without even knowing it?
- That's right.
- That's not going to work.
Do you think Akiko will like him?
I think it's a pretty good match.
What do you think?
Hopefully she'll find him attractive.
Thing is, he's not a scholar like Koichi.
I'm worried about that.
He runs a steel mill.
That might not bother her too much.
Agreed.
That's for her to decide.
He's home.
Welcome.
- It's good to see you again.
- Good to see you.
It's been awhile.
Yanosuke has a
prospective husband for Akiko.
- I see.
- I think it's a good opportunity.
I see.
We've also got Noriko to deal with.
If they both got married,
it would be ideal.
Indeed.
- See how Akiko feels about this.
- And you, Father?
Well, I'll certainly encourage her...
...but do talk to her.
- Where are you off to?
- I forgot an errand.
If you're going out, I'll tag along.
Don't bother. Relax and stay awhile.
I guess he's busy too.
I don't know what he's up to,
but he's been going out often lately.
I see. It's good to see him
up and about.
Did Noriko decide
to meet with her suitor?
Yes, over at the New Osaka Hotel.
That's good news. I'm glad to hear it.
It's going to be a scorcher.
Yes. Yes. Where?
From six, right? I'll go.
I'll invite her too.
Are you free tonight?
I am. Why?
Mr. Teramoto is leaving
in the next 2 or 3 days.
- For Sapporo?
- Yeah, so everyone's going out tonight.
I see. So it's finalized now.
I see.
So he's leaving....
Cheers.
- To your health.
- And happiness.
Thank you, everybody.
- So you're really going, eh?
- Do you get a raise?
Nothing big.
You'd be surprised how little
teaching assistants make.
But you could become an
assistant professor.
Not much better.
Anyway, you should all
come up to ski sometime.
I want to, but the train fare
to Sapporo is so expensive.
In honor of you, we'll at
least make it to Mount Ibuki.
How can I say it?
You do not know
How my love for you burns within me
Like the blazes of wormwood on Ibuki
Are you flirting with us now?
That was fun.
Hanging out with everybody
makes it hard to leave.
How long are you going to be gone?
They told me 4 or 5 years,
but who knows.
If you can, you should
come visit me sometime.
I'm serious.
Tonight was fun. It made me happy.
I'll write you some letters.
I hope you'll do the same.
- I will.
- I'm serious.
What a fun night.
I don't want to leave.
Add these up.
The total is 33,455 yen.
- And you?
- The same.
- How much?
- 33,455 yen.
33,455 yen.
It's even worse than I thought.
There's nothing we can do. Smaller
companies can't compete these days.
- You think?
- Let me see the sales slip.
- This one?
- No, the earlier one.
This is the one.
How's it going? Mighty hot today.
Where is Hisao?
He left a minute ago.
Know where he went?
- To Katsura Masamune.
- I see. I'll go over there too.
Take care.
He's been going out a lot lately.
He does leave often.
One wonders where he goes.
Hey, listen.
You know how he's been
going out? I think it's a bit fishy.
His family is worried about him too.
So I want you to go....
- To his home?
- No, no. Just follow him.
- Right now?
- Yes, I want you to see where he goes.
- Hey, Roku!
- Hello.
Where are you off to?
Come join me for a minute.
Have a seat. Sit.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
You want anything?
- Anything's fine.
- Shiratama sound good?
Sounds great.
Add a shiratama to my order.
Quite a coincidence, running into you.
I'm out collecting some debts.
I see. A hard worker.
It's hot today.
Yes, the summer refuses to end.
Where are you headed?
Who are you collecting from today?
Oh, here and there....
Hey....
- Do you have any cigarettes?
- Yes.
- Let me have one.
- Please.
"Peace," huh?
You're smoking the good stuff.
Sorry.
Listen....
- I already know.
- What do you mean?
Don't worry.
Hey....
Hisao sent you, didn't he?
No, sir, not at all.
That's not the case at all.
I see.
So who asked you to do it?
The debts.
Oh, the debts. I'm never told to do it.
I just get up and go.
I see. That's very impressive.
Hey, is that shiratama ready yet?
He's busy. He has to collect debts all day.
- Hurry, will you?
- Coming right up, sir.
You really are a hard worker, Roku.
Anybody home?
Hello there.
How good of you to visit, despite the heat.
Please, come in.
Don't mind if I do.
By all means.
- It's so hot this year.
- I'll say.
Is the store busy these days?
Actually, this is the slowest time of year.
Sake shops can't make
money without new rice crops.
- Something funny happened just now.
- What's that?
Our store manager was following me.
- Why?
- I've been coming here recently, right?
My family's worried about me.
So, just now...
...I pulled the manager into a nearby cafe.
He had "Peace" cigarettes
on him, so I took one...
...but he was so nervous...
...that he ended up paying for
the shiratama I got him.
Is that so? Good for you.
- Did you want sugar in your barley tea?
- Don't worry about it.
- Strange, isn't it?
- What is?
If I hadn't taken that exact train
on that day in Mukoumachi...
...I wouldn't have seen you.
It's true. That's destiny for you.
Yes, destiny is a strange thing.
- It's been 19 years.
- And of all places.
We've both changed so much.
On the way home from
a bicycle race, no less.
Like life and the flow of water....
Indeed. The world has changed
so much around us.
- It's not much of a world anymore.
- I miss the old days.
- Remember the cafe at Uji?
- Yes. Hanayashiki.
We used to go there often.
It was such fun to have you
take me out on long vacations.
Yes, going to see the snow...
...chasing fireflies....
Do you remember that night,
when the moon was beautiful?
How could I forget?
It's the night
you turned me into a woman.
- We've known each other forever.
- Indeed.
Yuriko is going to turn 21.
How times flies.
We should go visit Uji again.
Just the two of us.
Sounds good. I'd be delighted.
- Care for some sake?
- Sounds good.
- I'm home.
- Welcome back.
Your father is here.
Oh yeah?
Welcome back.
Hi, Father. When did you get here?
Have a seat.
I have to leave again. I forgot something.
But stay awhile.
You're going out again?
Yep. I'll see you later. Bye.
Bye.
Father, when are you going to get me
that mink stole you promised me?
Oh, that thing?
It's still too hot for a scarf.
Well if I don't start asking now....
Oh I know, I know.
That girl is full of energy.
Oh, hello.
Nice to see you.
Good afternoon.
Yuriko, George is waiting for you.
Hurry up now.
I'm going, Mother.
Don't stay out too late.
- Who was that?
- An American. He works in Kobe.
That's who she dates?
She's a typist. Sometimes she
brings home strange things.
I see. It's not a big deal?
Things are different from
when we were young.
These days, kids take care of themselves.
Try one of these black things.
- What is it?
- Yuriko brought it home.
She said they're shark eggs.
Shark eggs, huh?
Pretty small for a shark.
I think so too.
Take those home, if you like.
We have plenty more.
Thanks.
Tastes good.
Let's have a drink.
Thank you.
So what did you do?
Not to worry.
He thought he had lost me,
but I followed him the whole time.
Where did he go?
It looked like an inn.
The lanterns said "Sasaki."
- Sasaki?
- You know them?
Continue your story.
What was the woman like?
She was slender, maybe
in her early forties.
A bit older, no? 47 or 48.
- You know her?
- Never mind.
I hoped their relationship would be
another casualty of the war.
Tell me more.
Mr. Yamaguchi.... Did he have a
daughter with that woman?
- A daughter?
- Twenty-one years old, very pretty.
- No.
- But she was calling him "Father."
He's the only one who believes
that she is his daughter.
Anything else?
I heard a shamisen playing for about 30
minutes, accompanied by his singing.
He was singing a nagauta.
No, no. That's a hauta, not a nagauta.
- That song, right?
- Yes, that's the one.
I knew it.
That's all he ever sings.
Who is that woman?
- From Gion?
- Nope.
- From Minami?
- She's not a Geisha.
- She's an old flame.
- An old flame?
Mr. Kohayagawa used to
be a carefree man.
Even his parents had to
deal with that woman.
I see.
Just when I thought things were calming
down, we've got another headache.
- I'm putting your clothes here.
- Thanks.
Welcome back.
What is it you need?
The postcard from Mr. Yamayoshi.
Here it is.
Hey, Father's at it again.
She supposedly lives in Kyoto.
Where in Kyoto?
- She's called Sasaki.
- Sasaki?
Tsune Sasaki.
She's the woman that Father
used to see in Osaka.
- That's the one.
- I see.
I was still young back then...
...but I remember her bringing
Father home late at night...
...and Mother crying because of it.
Yeah. That's her.
The old flame is flaring up.
I wish Father would act
appropriately for his age.
I wonder if he even
worries about the store.
Now I wish he was just wasting his
money at the bicycle races.
One thing after another.
Unbelievable.
Just be sure that you don't
interrogate Father over this.
- Why not?
- Well, of course it's better to keep quiet...
- ...unless it comes up.
- No, I'm going to speak to him.
No, no. He's an old man.
Well, then he should act like one.
You know how he is.
What are you saying?
Is that an excuse
to do as you please?
That's not what I mean.
But at this point, Father's
personality isn't going to change.
I'll yell at him until it does.
Don't bother. You'll just
make a mess of things.
That was a good bath.
Hey, listen to this.
I was thinking while taking a bath...
...that for the anniversary of
your mother's death...
...we should stop by her grave, and then
have lunch over at Arashiyama.
We did the formal ceremony last year.
Yes, that sounds good.
Mother really liked Arashiyama.
What do you think?
Arashiyama in Kyoto, right?
Of course it's in Kyoto.
Mother liked Kyoto, but you
really seem to love it there.
What do you mean?
You seem to be going there often. Is
something captivating your attention?
What?
- Listen--
- Be quiet. I said be quiet!
Father...
...are you going to do the same thing
that made Mother cry so long ago?
What? What do you mean?
I already know everything.
Know what?
Why can't we go to Arashiyama?
Who knows what you
mean by "Arashiyama."
Hey. Hey, look at me.
You two suspect me of doing something?
- Right?
- No, not at all.
Having Roku follow after me?
Is there something that you
wouldn't want him to see?
What?
The reason I've been
going to Kyoto often...
...is to discuss the store's affairs
with an old friend of mine.
Watch what you say.
Who's this old friend?
Give me a name.
Let me guess. Is it Sasaki?
No. It's Yamada.
- You know.
- Never heard of him.
That's your problem.
I've asked him for various favors
concerning the store.
Since you can't seem to keep it in order.
- Well, then....
- That's enough.
No, it's not. Be quiet.
- Tell me, Father....
- What?
Are you really worried about the store?
- Of course!
- If it's that serious...
...why don't you go over there again?
- What?
- Hurry up and get ready.
There's no need to go today.
I spoke with him yesterday.
No, these things should be
taken care of immediately.
You should leave right away.
Not today.
I've already taken my bath.
I'll prepare another.
Go ahead, Father.
Go and ask for his help.
So you guys don't believe me, huh?
Fine, I'll go!
If you're so suspicious...
...be sure to have Roku follow me!
Ridiculous!
It's sad that you can't trust your father.
Hey, I'm going.
Be sure to follow me!
Make sure to see where I go!
I'm leaving! Let's go!
Here I go! Watch me!
Fools. This is nonsense.
Should we let him go?
Will he be okay?
He'll be fine. He didn't
even take his wallet.
He'll wander around the
block and come home.
You think?
- I hope so....
- He needs the exercise.
You're in the way.
Mother, is that man really my father?
- Why do you ask?
- I was just thinking...
...when I was small, wasn't
it somebody else?
I feel like I called him "Father" as well.
Is that so?
Perhaps.
So which one is my real father?
Why does it matter?
It's up to you.
You don't know?
I mean, I guess I don't mind either one.
I was born and here I am.
That's all that matters.
Yes, that's right.
Think of it that way.
- Hey.
- What?
Is this father rich?
I'm sure he is. He owns a sake brewery.
I see. He still hasn't
gotten me the mink stole.
It's in the way that you ask.
It's all in how you ask.
I see. Well he's certainly my father until
he gets me that mink stole.
That sounds good.
I'm here. I came back.
Well, hello.
Hi, Father.
Cleaning the floors?
Staying at home today, eh?
Here, let me do that.
I'm part of the family, after all.
Father, you have to take off your
tabi if you're going to do that.
You're right. Very observant.
I forgot my wallet at home, so I
was wandering around broke.
The cigarette shop lent me 1,000 yen.
I'll get you some shiratama.
I don't want any shiratama.
Father...
...won't you buy me that mink stole?
I'll get it for you.
You're good at that, Father.
Hello.
Good to see you.
I'm sorry about the other night.
Don't worry about it.
Were you able to find
any ox paintings?
I'm still trying....
He's quite amusing, isn't he?
He's an interesting fellow.
Did Fumiko speak with you?
I see. What do you think?
It's very sudden.
I would like some time to think it over.
Yes, certainly. Please do.
Your father is very worried about you.
I'm sorry to trouble everyone.
Not at all.
Would you like to meet with him again?
He would really like to.
What do you think?
He was disheartened
after you left early the other day.
I hear that you're going to Arashiyama
for Mother's memorial service.
Yes, that's what I heard.
You're going, right?
It should be beautiful there
at this time of year.
Pass that to me.
- Hisao?
- Oh, I'm fine, thank you.
- You don't drink much?
- Beer fills me up rather quickly.
Say, brother, I'm surprised
at how fast the moss grew.
The moss?
The gravestone was covered with moss.
Indeed it was.
They do say "until the moss grows."
It was rather quick.
Time flies, doesn't it?
It's already been six years since
Koichi died and Akiko became a widow.
Where is Akiko?
She went out with Noriko.
I see.
About Akiko....
Her suitor seems very interested.
He has two children.
A girl and a younger boy.
He's glad that Akiko also has a child.
That's good. What do you think?
That's good to hear.
The issue is how Akiko
feels about the situation.
You know,
feelings can't determine everything.
Akiko is still young.
She has a future.
Is she going to stay single forever?
That would be unfortunate.
I suppose so.
Akiko is one thing, but how
is Noriko feeling about her situation?
She's already met her suitor.
Fumiko, have you asked her?
Yes, I did speak with her.
What did she say?
She was being rather ambiguous.
She's still unsure.
I see.
She needs to decide soon.
I think it's a great match.
Especially if her suitor is interested.
I agree, but my wife says that
you must not rush into these things.
No, she should hurry.
Don't you think so, Fumiko?
Brother?
Well, I suppose it can't hurt.
With so many captains,
this ship will end up in the mountains.
You all need to listen to how she feels.
Father, don't you need to go
somewhere now that we're in Kyoto?
Excuse me?
- Another?
- Thank you.
There they are.
Really? And then what?
He ate everything
that they put in front of him.
Then he loosened his belt!
He ate so much.
He must have been famished.
I suppose.
After the dinner at the hotel,
we were walking through Nakanoshima--
You two were alone?
Yes, everyone insisted.
I see. What happened?
He asked me
if I disliked Western cuisine.
So I said, "What about you?"
And after eating all that food,
he said that he isn't too fond of it!
Such a peculiar man!
He sounds entertaining.
What happened next?
He saw that nobody was around,
so he grabbed my hand and squeezed it.
And what did you do?
- I squeezed right back.
- And then?
He said that my hand
was cold and wouldn't let go.
His hand was warm.
But when we were near other people,
he would try to let go in a hurry.
So I wouldn't let go
of his hand on purpose.
And then?
Oh, Akiko, you're making me
do all the talking!
How are things?
What do you mean?
The suitor that Uncle Yanosuke set up.
Oh, I'm already an old lady....
That'll be 100 yen.
What?
You promised me that you'd give me
100 yen each time you called yourself old.
Oh, you're right!
- Here you go, 100 yen.
- Why, thank you.
Masao, be careful.
Minoru, please keep an eye on him.
So how do you feel about your proposal?
I mean, I'm just....
I haven't said anything yet!
I jumped the gun.
Such gorgeous weather.
Today was quite fun indeed.
It's nice to go on excursions like that.
- Yes, we should do it more often.
- Certainly.
It was such a nice day too.
Yes, it was. Don't you agree, Fumiko?
Yes, but I feel bad for Father.
- Why?
- We made it all the way to Kyoto.
This again? You're so stubborn.
Father, would you like to get some rest?
Sounds like a good idea.
The time is right.
Noriko, please help him.
Good night.
Did you have to bring it up?
He was in such a good mood.
It's better that I said something.
I should have said more.
I should probably leave as well.
It's still early.
Yes, but....
Minoru, we should get going.
We're going, dear.
You should stay a while.
Oh, I know, but....
It's Father!
- What?
- He's collapsed!
Father?
- Father!
- Father.
Noriko, call a doctor.
Father.
Hello, 30-1051, please.
How does he look?
He should be okay,
barring another attack.
You know, he's rather old though.
Hello, Aunt Teruko.
- What happened?
- What's going on?
He looked fine this afternoon.
We came home,
and all of a sudden....
How does he look?
It was a heart attack.
The doctor said he should be okay
if nothing worsens overnight.
I see.
Have you told everyone?
Yes, I sent out a telegram.
I see. Let's go see him.
It was so sudden.
Very much so.
I wasn't expecting it.
Did he have heart problems before?
No, a bad liver.
Who is the man who just arrived?
His younger brother.
- From Nagoya?
- No, he's from Tokyo.
The woman who came here earlier today
is from Nagoya. She's his younger sister.
So she's the older sister of the....
No, no. Listen up.
The woman from Nagoya and the wife
of the gentleman from Osaka--
Wait, now I'm confused.
Okay, the wife of the man
from Osaka is Mr. Kohayagawa's--
He was an orphan, you know.
Is his dead wife's younger sister.
I see.
Very complicated.
The Kohayagawa family
is complicated indeed.
Auntie, you must be tired.
Would you care to rest?
Oh, no. I'm fine.
What about you?
I'm fine.
Are you sure? You must be exhausted
from riding the train all night.
No, I'm fine.
Have you been busy lately?
Yes, relatively.
And you?
Busy as usual.
How's he doing?
He's sound asleep for now.
That's a good sign.
He needs to recover.
This must be difficult for you, Hisao.
Such a critical time.
Yes, it's hard.
I think he's through the worst of it.
He seems to be stable.
Yes.
I hope so.
It's already 5.
If he's okay,
I'd like to return to Nagoya.
I left things unattended.
Same here.
- Are you busy?
- Yes.
I have a large meeting to attend.
You too, Auntie?
Yes.
I suppose I could stay...
...but we're building a new factory.
I do wish that both of you would stay.
Everything's up in the air right now.
Yes, I agree. You never know....
What's wrong?
What is it?
Father!
Father?
Are you okay?
Should you be up?
I slept quite well.
I have to use the bathroom.
What happened?
Is he all right?
I tried to stop him.
Well, this is a good sign.
I'm so glad that he's okay.
I'm so relieved.
Father has all of his energy back.
Yes.
I can't believe how worried we were.
You throw like a girl, Grandpa!
Just give me one more chance!
Where is Minoru?
- On a hiking trip.
- Where to?
Mount Rokko.
I wish I could spend my Sunday
doing that.
He invited me, but I didn't want
to ruin the kid's fun...
...being so....
- What?
- One hundred yen.
I didn't say it.
Oh, come on!
Would you like some help?
No, this is the last of it.
Can you hand that to me?
This?
Even on a Sunday,
Hisao is quite busy.
Yes, with this and that.
He says that smaller companies
just can't make it these days.
But Father is against a merger.
It must be difficult.
Okaden was in a similar situation.
I'm sure we'll follow suit eventually.
It's hard to beat big companies.
He wants to hold off while Father is still
healthy, but who knows what will happen.
That was fun.
Great exercise.
It's good to see you so energized.
Yes, I had everybody terribly worried.
But I'm fine now.
See?
Father.
What is it?
I wanted to apologize.
- About what?
- I was being very hard on you.
Don't worry about it.
I'm used to it.
Don't say that.
I would have been
devastated if you had died.
Don't be silly.
I won't die so easily.
I have too many things to think about,
including Akiko and Noriko's situation.
I'm sorry...
...to have worried you.
Still undecided, eh?
Oh, can you sew this?
Are you tired, Grandpa?
- Not at all.
- Then let's play hide-and-seek!
Hide-and-seek, eh?
- Okay, wait one minute.
- Oh, hurry up.
One second.
Hurry!
Am I intruding?
What are you doing?
Writing a letter.
To whom?
I can't say.
I know.
What?
To whom you're sending it.
It's to the man who eats a lot.
No, no.
How are things going with him?
Nothing new.
I'm supposed to give him a response.
What do you think?
I don't have a single reason
to decline.
Then you should just do it.
That's easy for you to say.
Why? He seemed like a nice person.
If I did marry him, I know that
everyone would be relieved.
But I can't.
You're in love with someone, aren't you?
Yes, you are. I knew it.
Who is he?
What is he like?
Remember when I went skiing at
Mount Ibuki with Takako and the others?
Is that the one?
I think I met him
at the Hankyu department store. Right?
That's him, isn't it?
Have you been meeting with him?
No, he lives in Sapporo.
Sapporo?
That's quite far.
So that letter is for him?
I'm just replying.
Oh, sure, sure.
Just a reply.
I don't know how Father
and the others feel...
...but the important thing
is to marry without regret.
You're the one who has to live with it.
That's what I think too.
Anyone would find it
to be a difficult decision.
Is that including you?
I was happy. I had no regrets.
Despite all the worrying everyone does
on my behalf, I'm still quite happy.
So are you planning
on staying single forever?
I'm still considering...
...whether or not I can maintain this life.
Grandpa, you're it!
Oh, no! Again?
I'm pretty tired now.
I think it's time to quit.
Oh, come on!
I just remembered
that I had an errand to run.
No, you're it!
Close your eyes!
Okay, I give up. This is it though.
You better not peek!
You're peeking!
Okay, okay.
Face that way.
What are you doing?
Hide-and-seek. I'm it.
Are you ready?
I'm ready!
I don't know how young people
feel about things these days...
...but I think it's stifling to live
with someone who has no character.
In my case, as an example...
...if a man was a little wild before I
married him, I wouldn't be too bothered...
...but I would never marry
a man who lacks character.
You can alter behavior,
but you can't alter character.
You're right.
What is it?
Where's Grandpa?
I don't know.
You haven't seen him?
What are you doing?
Hide-and-seek.
Grandpa didn't come this way?
Nope.
I wonder where he went.
I can't find him anywhere.
Oh, yeah?
Hey!
There's Grandpa!
Well, that's too bad.
Should've bet on the other one.
Yes. I was thinking
that it might be a 3-2 finish.
Well, that's that.
Regret won't get us anywhere.
Shall we go to Osaka to eat?
How does udonsuki sound?
Let's go home to take
a bath and have a drink.
No, no. Let's go to Osaka.
To Osaka!
She's taking forever!
Yes, she is.
Is that all you have to say?
I wonder what happened.
"I wonder what happened."
That's what I want to ask you.
What happened indeed.
I wonder why she's late.
She said that she would try to come.
Try? Why didn't you say so earlier?
She said, "I'll try"?
Aren't we being a bit ambiguous?
Don't you think so?
First of all, this is something...
...that you brought upon me, am I right?
That's right.
Then why don't you show
some responsibility, huh?
I wish I hadn't met her,
if this was the case.
Why did you introduce us
in the first place?
A man falling in....
A man falling in love with a woman
at first sight is serious stuff, you know?
Am I right?
Well?
Am I talking nonsense here?
Am I wrong?
This stinks.
Let's get a drink somewhere else.
Well, wait....
Let's wait a bit longer.
She said she had the cow painting.
A bit longer?
We've already waited for 2 hours!
Painting be damned.
- Let's go.
- One more drink.
No, no. I'm full of alcohol already.
"I'll try to."
Give me a break.
She's not coming.
This is terrible.
Look on the bright side.
It means he's healthy.
I suppose.
I just wish he'd say something
to us before disappearing.
That's true.
He's a merry fellow, that's for sure.
This morning he claimed that
he had knocked on the gates of heaven.
What shall we do with him...?
The phone's ringing.
Hello. Yes, this is she.
What was that?
We'll be right over.
Noriko!
Who was that?
- Father is ill.
- Who called?
The Sasakis in Kyoto. They said to
rush over. It was a young woman's voice.
What could it be?
I'm not sure, but she said
Father had collapsed again.
Sounds serious.
We must go.
Who called?
Father is ill again. Get ready
and head over there with your brother.
Let's go.
They're taking so long.
They should be here soon.
You know...
...I really lost out today.
How's that?
My mink stole is gone.
Had I known, I would have
had him buy it for me sooner.
I saw a gorgeous one in Kawaramachi.
Have George buy one for you.
George can't afford it.
The best he can do is a purse.
Someone's here.
Good evening.
- Hello, Yuri.
- Hello.
Oh, it's just George.
It's not George.
Tonight it's Harry.
I'll see you later.
Come home early tonight.
I suppose you promised him
you'd go out.
I'll be home early.
Bye, Mother.
Hello.
What a day it was....
We shouldn't have gone out today.
I guess today wasn't
as good a day as you thought it'd be.
So unfortunate....
And it was so hot.
Is anybody home?
Good evening.
My name is Kohayagawa.
Please, do come inside.
How is he doing?
Please come in.
It happened so suddenly.
The time was 8:23.
He looks so peaceful.
I'm not sure what time he came over,
but we went out together.
He insisted on going to Osaka,
but I managed to convince him otherwise.
I was washing my hands over there,
and he was sitting over here...
...and I thought he looked rather ill,
when he suddenly grabbed his chest.
I see.
I had a doctor come right away...
...but it was too late.
I see.
He was in such pain.
Did he have any final words?
"Is this it? Is this really it?"
He said that twice.
I see.
It was so sudden.
Life is so fragile.
Do you think there are more
crows than usual today?
Yes, there are.
Think someone died?
Perhaps.
But there's no smoke coming from
the chimney of the crematorium.
Yes, you're right.
Are you tired, Fumiko?
No, not too tired.
You have much to deal with
as well, Hisao.
What is the company going to do?
I've been thinking it over,
but it just makes my head hurt.
A merger?
I think it may be inevitable.
What can you do...?
Father was worried about it.
I think the best thing would be
to merge with a large company...
...and continue to work under them.
A salaried man, eh?
Yes, it's an option.
Father was always so undependable...
...but it seems
that he was the only thing...
...keeping the Kohayagawas afloat.
I feel bad for Hisao.
I was really hoping...
...that Father would be with us
until you were married.
I was up all night
thinking about what to do...
...and I think that I should do
what makes me happy.
What are you saying?
With Father dead, I feel like I should marry
the suitor that everyone picked for me.
But I don't think I could live with that.
Doing that might be beneficial
to the Kohayagawa household...
...but I think I'll regret it
if I'm not honest about my feelings.
It's a hard decision.
What are you going to do?
I think....
Yes?
I think I should go to Sapporo.
I see.
I personally thought
that it would be best to do so.
Really?
You're young. I want you
to be as happy as possible.
- Have you checked the calendar?
- Yes.
Then let's make the funeral
the day after tomorrow. The obituary?
It'll be in tomorrow's paper.
I see. So that's done.
Oh, what about lunch?
Yes, I called about that too.
Should we get cars?
It's across the river,
so we'd have to make a detour.
It's close enough to walk.
You can accompany them.
Eight people, right?
No, it's nine.
Hey, it's the madam from Nagoya.
Hello, ma'am.
Right over there, please.
Thank you.
Auntie.
Please....
This is quite a shock.
What happened?
Was it his heart?
Yes, it was very sudden.
I suppose it's better than being
bedridden, just wasting away.
Yes, that's true.
So he had no final words?
He said:
"Is this it? Is this really it?"
That's all?
How happy-go-lucky.
After doing as he pleased for
all those years, that's all he had to say?
What a silly man.
I'm sure he wanted to go on like that
forever, but you can't be too greedy.
Yes, I've heard that before.
Oh, hello.
Hello.
We humans can't come to terms
with death until it's too late.
Even people like my brother
who did as he pleased.
On his deathbed,
even Toyotomi Hideyoshi said:
"It's as if my glorious life
was but a dream within a dream."
Indeed he did.
Where's your uncle from Tokyo?
I haven't seen him.
He must be very busy.
If this was the case, he should have just
died when we were all gathered earlier.
He did as he pleased his whole life,
sold the family heirlooms...
...spent all of his money, and angered me
with his irresponsibility...
...but he was also quite happy.
It's a rarity these days.
Not that it matters much...
...once you're dead.
Hey, look.
Somebody did die.
There's smoke now.
Indeed there is.
It's not a big deal if an elderly person
were to have died...
...but it would be tragic
if it were somebody young.
Yes, but no matter how many die...
...new lives will be born
to take their place.
You're right.
It's the cycle of life.
It'll be lonely here without you.
Sister...
...once I go to Sapporo,
I want you to visit.
I would like to see you.
Of course I'll come visit.
It's so far....
What are you going to do now?
Me?
I'm happy as I am.
Minoru's still growing up.
I think this would be best for him.
That sounds like something you'd say.
I don't know about that.
Let's catch up.
We shouldn't be too late.