(slow tense music)
(helicopter whirs)
(weapons fire)
(men chatter)
(Deacon groans)
(soldiers chatter
in foreign language)
(weapons fire)
(soldier screams)
(soldier yells)
(mid-tempo lively music)
(water gurgles)
(kettle whistles)
(Deacon groans)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
- [Elaine] Deac?
- Elaine, how are you?
How's that washed-up
husband of yours doing?
- [Elaine] Marty, well,
that's what I was
calling about, Deac.
I just don't know what to do.
Marty had an accident, he's--
- What is it?
- [Elaine] Dead,
Deac, a car wreck.
- A car wreck, when?
- [Elaine] Two weeks ago.
That's what the sheriff's
calling it, a car wreck.
I just don't know.
I didn't know if you knew.
- No, no, I'm
sorry to hear that.
- [Elaine] I've been
running the bar by myself,
and all I can do--
- Well, don't worry about it,
I'll, uh, I'll come up
there this afternoon.
- [Elaine] Oh, thanks, but you
must have things to do and--
- No, no, it's no problem.
I've got, I've got
not urgent business.
I'll be up there today.
- [Elaine] You're a good
friend, Deac, thanks very much.
- Okay.
(phone tone beeps)
(mid-tempo serious music)
- Fill it up, will ya?
- Hey, Audrey.
Let's leave town
for the weekend, eh?
- Just a second.
Three bucks.
- Put it on my tab.
- You at least gonna
bring the bottles back?
(engine revs)
(tires screech)
(bottle clangs)
What do you want?
- Well, tell me
you're not married
and the mother of three kids.
- I'm not.
- That and a tank of
gas, I'll be a happy man.
- How many more of you
guys are gonna show up?
- How many more of me
you think you can handle?
- That'll get you
to the next town.
- Well, I'm not going
- Don't you guys ever get
tired of making life miserable?
- Nevermind.
Lady, if you could tell me
how to get to the Forty
Niners Bar and Grill,
I'd appreciate it.
Keep the change.
- Up there to the right.
- Thank you.
- Uh, are you Elaine's friend?
- Yeah.
- Uh, um, I'm sorry,
I thought you were
somebody else (laughs).
Welcome to town.
- I'll accept your
apology over dinner.
- [Audrey] Okay (laughs).
- What's your name?
- Audrey (laughs).
- [Deacon] Deacon Porter.
- [Audrey] Hi.
(slow piano music)
- I didn't expect you so soon.
Take a look at that picture.
Marty sent me that just
before you guys left Nam.
- I remember the day
we took this picture.
♪ Tell me what you see
- Seems like a long time ago.
Shame to go through
all that combat,
and then to buy it in
a lousy car accident.
- If it was a car accident.
- Marty was too good a driver,
and he knew these
roads too well.
That was no accident, Deac.
- Who'd wanna kill--
(door thuds)
- Elaine.
This the new help?
- [Elaine] Deacon
Porter, Clay Marsh.
- Hi.
- [Clay] Expect, we'll
get to know each other.
- [Elaine] Deac fought
with Marty in Vietnam.
- Vietnam.
Porter, let me give
it to you straight.
We don't take to outsiders
in King's Ransom.
Outsiders usually mean trouble.
And I don't need trouble.
- I'm just here
to help a friend.
- See to it that you
keep it that way.
Elaine.
- He always this friendly?
- He has a problem
with the growers.
They've taken over the valley
for their marijuana business.
- [Jerry] Come on, come here,
I wanna show you
something, come on.
- [Linda] What?
- I'll show ya.
- [Linda] Huh?
- Ta dah!
- Oh, wow, we drove right
past here last night,
and we didn't even see it.
- It was too dark.
It could've been anything.
Look!
- There's more
growing over there.
- I knew you'd like
California better than Canada.
(both laugh)
- Oh, it's harvest time.
- Right.
(gun fires)
(tense dramatic music)
Run, run, dammit.
- What's going on?
- [Jerry] Hurry.
This way.
- [Man In Stripped
Shirt] Over there!
- [Jerry] You head
for the highway,
I'll try to draw their fire.
- No, no!
- [Jerry] Don't argue,
please Linda, do it, go!
- [Linda] Jerry!
(gun fires)
- [Man In Tan Jacket]
Come on, this way!
- [Man] Relax, they'll get him.
- [Man In Tan Jacket] Come
on, don't let him get away,
shoot him.
(guns fire)
(Jerry grunts)
- [Man On Left]
There's our turkey.
(men laugh)
(gun fires)
(Linda screams)
(slow unsettling music)
(Linda grunts)
- Why you no good!
- Come on, let's go.
- (laughs) in it goes, boys!
Woo hoo!
(lively country music)
- Have a beer, Deac.
- [Deacon] Don't mind if I do.
- This is my friend, Jim.
- Hey.
- [Deacon] How you
doin' there, Jim.
- Looks like Jim's
gettin' pretty friendly
with Porter over there.
- [Man On Right] Yeah.
- This here is my
partner, this is Deac.
- How are you?
Nice to meet you.
Excuse me just a minute.
- Hi.
- [Man On Right] Let's do it.
(upbeat country music)
- [Man In Green]
Doing some talking?
What'd you tell that guy?
Huh, what'd you tell him?
- [Jim] I think you got--
- [Man In Green] Big mouth!
I'll teach you to keep
your big mouth shut.
(woman screams)
(man in green grunts)
- Lock him up, I'll
press charges later.
- Come on, let's
take a little walk.
- [Carey] I thought you
and I had an agreement.
- I had no choice.
The whole place
saw what happened.
If Porter hadn't stopped
that goon of yours,
he would have beat
that guy to death.
- He was just a little
excitable, that's all.
You can let him out,
he's cooled down by now.
- Can't do it.
This time is different,
Porter's pressing charges.
- Don't worry about
it, I'll handle Porter.
Everything's okay.
Here's a little something
called bail money.
- I gotta turn you
down on this one Carey.
- Have it your way.
But remember one
thing, I give the word,
my boys will bury you
in your hick town.
Now you better think real hard,
and see if you can't recall
just who it is that's
been keeping you
in business around here.
- Hawkins!
- Sheriff?
Yeah?
- Release the prisoner.
- Okay, Sheriff.
- As usual, it's a pleasure
doing business with you sheriff.
(door thuds)
(slow unsettling music)
- [Man In Vest] I
was at that party.
I knew Marty pretty well.
But you're talking
to the wrong guy.
I gotta go.
- Excuse me sir,
I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to ask you to leave,
right now.
- Thank you.
(uptempo peppy music)
- So how do you like rural life?
- [Deacon] Seems everyone's
too scared to talk to me.
- [Man In Hat] Come on.
- Damn growers, they
think they own the town.
- What about your sheriff?
- I think they own him too.
- I have an idea, why
don't I take you for a ride
through the countryside.
- That's the best
offer I've had yet.
- Yeah, okay.
(mellow country music)
- Well, Audrey, don't
you look pretty tonight.
You really didn't have to get
all dolled up on my account.
- Ready?
- [Audrey] Yeah.
- Pardon me, I didn't realize
you two were together.
Aren't you gonna introduce
me to your friend?
- Deacon Porter, John Carey.
- Welcome to King's
Ransom, Deacon Porter.
- Thank you.
- [Carey] I hope you find
our town to your liking.
- You know what, Carey,
it's not your town.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
(door thuds)
(tense dramatic music)
(cars thud)
(tires screech)
- [Man] Son of a bitch!
Come on, come on, get out.
- Let's get him.
(men groan and grunt)
- [Man] Come on.
- [Man] Grab hold
of him, I got him!
- Reese.
(Deacon grunts)
(punches thud)
- Come on, Carey,
you gotta stop 'em!
- [Reese] Listen, Porter,
we own everything in this town.
(punch thuds)
- [Audrey] Come on, they're
gonna kill him, please!
- Your boyfriend is just
not a reasonable man.
- Nobody owns me.
- Please, stop it.
(punches thud)
- You want him, take him.
Okay, boys, let him go.
- I'm gonna try
something else on this.
Just a second.
I think this is more the way to.
(slow gentle music)
Deac?
- I gotta go.
- Okay.
- It was an accident.
He had a few drinks,
lost it on the curve,
went over the cliff.
- Doesn't sound like
Marty to drink and drive.
- Well, people change,
they get careless.
- Went through six years
of combat with that man.
He kept people alive
because he wasn't careless.
- Hey, Porter, I'm
trying to be nice to you.
- Don't be.
I'll find out what
happened to Marty
with or without your help.
I wanna see that
coroner's report.
- I don't have to
show you anything.
- I'll be back
with a court order.
- [Man With Rifle] Go
right ahead, sheriff,
you know the way.
(men chatter)
- We gotta talk.
- [Carey] What's on your mind?
- That guy Porter's
threatening to open up
the investigation in
Marcus Darien's death.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah, I think he means it.
That's one guy you
shouldn't have messed with.
- Let him investigate.
What's he gonna find out?
- Maybe nothing.
But if that coroner you
paid off decides to talk,
we're all in a lotta trouble.
- He won't talk.
- I think Porter can
be pretty persuasive.
- Get on back to town,
I'll figure something out.
- [Clay] Yeah.
(slow suspenseful music)
(gasoline sloshes)
- Let's see how they like this.
- Yeah.
(tense gripping music)
- [Man] Yee haw!
(coughs)
- [Deacon] Elaine!
Elaine!
(Elaine screams)
(glass shattering)
- [Man In Blue] Damn!
(explosions rumble)
(gun fires)
- [Man In Flannel]
Bob, what you think?
- Come on!
- [Man In Plaid]
Got him (laughs).
- [Man With Dark
Hair] That's one guy
won't be causing
anymore trouble.
- [Man In Plaid] Yeah,
you can say that again.
(both chuckle)
- [Man With Dark Hair] Come
on, let's get outta here.
(slow somber music)
- 16 bucks.
- Nice and peaceful
around here, huh?
Too bad about your boyfriend.
(Clay chuckles)
♪ I'm in the mood
(hums and vocalizes)
This isn't very
sociable of you, Audrey.
- I should kill you right
now, you son of a bitch.
- Hysterical again?
- Get out.
- [Carey] Get outta here.
- Or I'll shoot your ass off.
(lips smack)
(slow gentle music)
- Hey, Deac.
- Spence?
- This is it?
- [Deacon] You bet.
- Come on, Deac, you
were lucky the last time.
You go back up there again,
they're gonna kill you for sure.
- Gotta go back.
- Why?
- Just something I
gotta do, that's all.
- Will you knock off
the John Wayne shit
for a minute and be realistic?
- Did you bring the stuff?
- Yeah.
Listen, you know I'm the best
electronics specialist
in the business.
Now I've been doing
it for 20 years,
I can do it in my sleep.
You think you can
learn everything from
a book overnight?
Forget it Deac, it's hopeless.
You can't do it by yourself.
I guess you're just gonna
have to take me along.
- It's not your fight, Spence.
- Goddammit, Marty
was my CO too.
- I'm not taking you,
now that's final.
- [Spencer] Fine,
I'm gonna help you
whether you like it or not.
- [Bartlett] You
have my word on it.
- This is a rather
expensive order.
I feel my partners
will require something
a little more substantial
than your word.
- I see your point.
Perhaps the deed to
my boat will suffice.
- I think my
partners will agree.
- I'll have the papers
for you this afternoon.
- Half down, the
balance on delivery,
including the return of
your collateral, of course.
- Of course.
- Salam, Mr. Bartlett.
- See you around,
greaseball.
- You never change, do you?
- Hey, Jesus, it's
been a long time, man,
long time.
- I just looked for you
over at the yacht club,
they told me I'd
find you out here.
Nice boat (chuckles).
- Hell, Art, this isn't my boat.
That's my bucket over there.
- (chuckles) You snake.
- Look, uh, buddy, I know that-
- I just thought
I'd drop by to see
if I could get you
to change your mind
about going with
me to help Deac.
- I can't do it.
I can't go with
you, I'm past it.
- Come on.
- You know what I do now?
I keep the rich Arabs
supplied with pop guns.
It's a real nice arrangement.
Now what can you say to me to
make me wanna fuck that up?
- You got a friend
who needs your help.
- I'll tell you what I'll do,
I'll put together
a package for you.
It'll be good, all you need.
But I can't go with you.
- Call me when it's ready.
(uptempo energetic music)
(crowd chatters)
- You on?
Go, woo!
Take it.
Yah!
- [Man With No Shirt] Whoo.
- All right, come on, come on.
Okay, come on.
Cheese.
Hey, rat, check this out.
Want some balls, come on.
(men grunt and groan)
All right, come on chop suey.
Chow mein time,
brother (grunts).
- Hey, the winner, yeah!
(coins jingle)
- [All] Cheater!
- [Ox] Go, run, move it!
(gun fires)
- Get in!
- [Ox] Spence, you saved my ass!
(knocking on door)
- Yeah?
I'm coming.
(knocking on door)
Who is it?
- [Ox] Where do you think
you're going without me, mofo?
- Ox?
- Ah, (chuckles) yeah, Deac!
- [Keith] I'm telling you,
there's a lifetime
supply up here.
- [Student In Hat] Eh, far out.
- [Keith] Come on, up here.
- [Student In Hat]
(laughs) Where man?
- [Keith] Shh,
just wait a minute.
- [Student In Hat]
Yoo hoo, marijuana!
- [Keith] Hey, you
gotta be serious here.
- [Arnold] Where is this stuff?
- [Student In Hat]
Oh, look at that, man.
- [Arnold] Oh my god.
Wow, more, more.
Hey, I'll get the sack.
- [Student In Hat]
Yeah, Arnold, get it.
- [Keith] What do ya think?
Mother Nature at its best.
- [Student In Hat] True,
man, Keith, you said it.
- Not bad, huh?
- [Student In Hat]
Too green, man.
Uh, look at that?
- This sprig is a
little you know--
(weapon fires)
(student in hat grunts)
(tense suspenseful music)
- Hey, I think you got one.
- [Man In Hat] Check it out, eh.
Only a college kid.
(weapon fires)
- [Keith] Arnold, shit.
Huh?
(gun fires)
- [Barbara] Mornin'
Sheriff, how are ya'?
- Barbara, good.
- [Barbara] Good (chuckles).
- [Reese] I'm worried about
those kids, they went bonkers.
Howdy, Miss Barbara.
- Hi, Reese.
- [Reese] You look
mighty fine today.
- [Barbara] Why, thanks.
- [Reese] Well, look
who's here, mornin'.
- How's the sheriff business?
- There's three kids missing
from college over at Oak Hill.
- Maybe they took off
on spring vacation.
- Maybe they didn't.
Look, Carey, two campers
disappeared from the east.
That coulda happened anywhere.
It's a big, wide country.
I'm talkin' about
local kids now.
(Carey sighs)
And I'm not the only
one that's talking.
- Well, then you better
come up with some answers.
- Don't push me.
- What do you want?
More money?
- No more killings.
- When I do a job, I
do what the job needs.
You're in too deep to tell
me to do anything else.
(slow ominous music)
(thunder crackles)
(knocking on door)
(slow gentle music)
- My uncle closed
this place years ago.
Nobody comes around, I doubt
Carey even knows about it.
- Looks solid, boss.
- This place checks
out just fine.
- All right, let's
go get the gear.
- Let's start a war, all right!
- Better get back
to the gas station.
I don't want you gettin' hurt.
- I'll keep an eye
on things, okay?
- Let's just torch
the sons of bitches.
- They'd be back in business
again in two months.
No, I wanna take these bastards
apart one piece at a time.
- You gotta be realistic, Ox,
a little selective sabotage.
- Look it, we're gonna
fight a goddamn war,
let's fight a
goddamn war, do it.
- We are, our way.
(tense dramatic music)
Look at this set up.
Come on, take a closer look.
- Hey!
(man grunts)
(man screams)
- You still draw like a chicken.
- Thanks.
- [Man] Why'd you start?
- [Man] Yeah, hear
the whole thing,
you want me to tell
you the whole thing?
- [Man] Yeah, starting
from the very top.
- [Man] Tell me about
this chick, man,
it's incredible, all right.
Couldn't believe it myself.
- [Man] So did you get any?
- [Man] What you
mean did I get any?
Come on, who you talkin' to.
(both laugh)
- What's up?
- You pick up some
of my boy last night?
- Now why would I do that?
- Maybe you started to
feel like a sheriff.
Just answer me, Marsh.
- Hey, I didn't pick anybody up.
Jesus, you act like
it was the first time
these punks took off on ya.
- Not three at once.
- Maybe they took
a spring vacation.
- And maybe some
other grower decided
I had three men too many.
- Hey, it's a tough business.
- This is my territory.
I pay you to keep it that way.
- Well, it ain't much, Spence,
but it's all we've got.
- Yeah, Bart never came through.
But it should be interesting.
- I wish I had a bazooka.
- Ox!
- Oh!
- Always complaining.
- [Ox] You dickhead.
You are a couple a.
(mid-tempo rock music)
(mellow country music)
- Check out his car.
- Here you are.
- [Man In Hat] Just
passing through, are you?
- Yeah, something like that.
- What sorta business you in?
- Minding my own.
- Where you staying at?
- A motel down the road.
- [Man In Hat] Uh huh.
- Roach motel.
- Shit.
- Cam Thompson, there is
cat hair in your armature.
- [Boy] I'm sorry, Miss King.
- Well, you know I
usually get $35 an hour
for this kind of work.
Okay, half a piece
of Double Bubble
and a kiss from a future
Monte Carlo winner.
- [Bartlett] Hey, hey, somebody!
- [Man] Come on, shit
head, get your ass in here.
(tense dramatic music)
(explosions boom)
(weapons fire)
- [Spencer] Yahoo!
- Spence, jeep!
- Yeehaw!
(Ox screams)
(weapons fire)
(gun fires)
Bulls.
- [Man On Radio] Boss,
they hit both trucks,
and blew the whole
shipment up in smoke.
- Repeat that.
- [Man On Radio]
The convoy is gone.
Plus, we just caught a stranger
with a van full of guns.
- Shit.
Reese, they took the convoy.
- Jesus, I doubled the security.
- Obviously, it wasn't enough.
If it's a war they
want, I'll give 'em one.
(punches thud)
(Bartlett groans)
Who you workin' for?
- Builder's Emporium.
I'm in the lumbar department.
- All you gotta do is
tell us who sent you here.
- Why don't you go
buy yourself a dress.
(punch thuds)
(Bartlett grunts)
- You think it's
worth dying for?
(Bartlett spits)
(punches thud)
(Bartlett groans)
The guy's hardcore.
Bring some boys into town.
Chances are, he's
not on his own.
When he talks, I'll
be over at the cafe.
(Bartlett grunts)
(punches thud)
- Carey's boys picked up a guy
at Jake's Diner
couple hours ago.
Jake said he had a whole van
full of guns, military stuff.
- Bartlett.
Where?
- Jail, I think.
(tense suspenseful music)
- Oh, Jesus.
(men grunts)
(Hawkins groans)
- Ah ah!
- [Deacon] Just stay real quiet.
(keys clang)
- [Hawkins] Hey, I'm
going, I'm going.
- [Ox] Move it, come on,
you wienie, get in there.
- Hey, sleeping on
the job, again, huh?
(Bartlett groans)
Come on.
- [Ox] Okay, in, dickhead.
Pissant, punk.
- [Man In Cell] What the fuck.
You won't get away
with this (moans).
- [Ox] Hey, Deac, my lunch.
- [Man In Cell] Hey, man,
don't eat the fucking key.
- [Man In Cell] We'll cut
that key out of your fat gut.
- Son of a bitch.
- [Ox] Delicious (laughs).
- Porter!
- [Deacon] Stay
out of it, Marsh.
(slow riveting music)
- [Bartlett] Guess you know
how to throw a welcome party.
(all laugh)
- Woo hoo!
- [Ox] All right, we
got that Jack Daniels.
All right.
- [Spencer] Woo, yeah!
- Hey, have a little Jack
Daniels there, buddy.
Good to see ya,
how ya been, huh?
- [Bartlett] Thanks, brother.
- I knew you'd make it.
- Been on ya, huh?
Looks like they got you
going there a little, huh?
Pretty good lookin', huh?
- I just got the
crap beat outta me.
(all laugh)
- No prob, good to see you.
What the fuck, you know?
- Good to see you too, man.
Good to see you too.
- [Ox] Ooh, you sweetie, mm.
(metal scrapes and clangs)
- [Carey] Let's nail
that son of a bitch.
- [Audrey] Reese get your
goddamn hands off me!
You pig, let me go!
- So you ride at his side, huh?
Throw her in the car.
- [Audrey] Carey, get your
goddamn mercenaries off me.
- [Carey] She's gonna take
us to see her boyfriend.
- [Audrey] Goddammit!
- Blow it!
(car tires screech)
(weapon fires)
(explosion booms)
- All right, let's go.
- Go in!
- [Man] Come on, get
it in gear, move out.
- [Man] Let's take
care of these shits,
come on let's shoot
'em, let's go.
- [Man In Hat] Come on,
let's get these jerks.
- Come on.
- Yeah.
(slow uneasy music)
- Reese, move out over there.
The rest of you, follow me.
(explosion booms)
(tense dramatic music)
(weapons fire)
- [Bartlett] Scramble
or we'll never make it.
- Blow the son of
a bitch up, Spence.
- Move out!
- Let's go!
- They can't get far.
Take the boys, track 'em.
Reese, no prisoners.
- [Reese] Let's go, guys.
(tense dramatic music)
Okay, let's go.
Come on.
- [Man In Hat] Come on,
get the goddamn lead out.
(men grunt and groan)
(weapon fires)
(Ox yells)
- You, okay?
- Yeah, just a little rusty.
- [Clay] Where's Carey?
- [Man In Hat] Inside.
(men laugh)
- Carey.
- Get her inside.
- [Man] Come on, come on.
- You and Porter can blow
yourselves up all I care,
but you let her go.
- You're pressing your luck.
- Hey, this stuff's
gonna stop right here.
I'm bringing in
the state police.
- I wouldn't do
that if I were you.
- I mean it.
- So do I.
Reese.
(tense dramatic music)
(weapons fire)
- Boys, let's get him backed up.
- [Man] Get the fuck outta here!
- [Man] Who the?
- Thanks.
- Save it, sheriff.
- [Reese] Delta
one, do you read me?
Come in, this is Delta four.
Delta one, come
in, do you read me?
- [Man in White] They got
at least four of my men.
They're all over the place.
- [Man In Hat]
(coughs) Forget it man,
these guys are too good,
let's get outta here.
- No, we regroup and
hit 'em again tonight.
I'll call for more of the guys.
(mid-tempo gripping music)
(whistles)
(grunting)
(man in hat groans)
(weapons fire)
(men scream)
- [Man In Tree]
Hey, hey, help me!
Don't leave me, let
me go and help, ah!
- Hey, I don't expect
you to believe me.
I want that viper
as much as you do.
- We don't need this
dickhead, shoot him.
- Hey, bog brain, you're
not gonna shoot anybody.
I know of another way in there.
- Ox.
- You guys go barging in there,
Audrey's gonna be the
first one to get it.
I know Carey's escape route.
You'll never find it.
You gotta take me along.
- All right, sheriff, deal.
But you make one
move to cross me,
I'll blow your fucking head off.
(tense dramatic music)
(metal clanks)
- Shh!
- All right, Ox,
there's your field.
You torch it.
You guys see the
fire, blow the bridge.
- What if you're not back yet?
- You blow it.
- Okay.
- Hey, Ox!
That weed starts to burn,
don't breathe too deep, huh?
- [Ox] (inhales) All right,
biggest joint in
the world (laughs)!
(tense dramatic music)
♪ A hunting we will go
(vocalizes)
Oh, baby, the ganja (laughs)
Ooh, yeah (laughs), delicious.
- You might need this, Marsh.
(Ox yells)
(weapons fire)
- Mwah, stay right
there (laughs).
Smoke, all we need
is a little match.
Beep (laughs).
(alarm blares)
(tense dramatic music)
(men chatter)
- [Man] What is it?
- The outfield's been torched.
The field's on fire.
- Shotgun, get it right.
Alert the outposts,
nobody in, nobody out.
- [Man On Right]
Come on, Henley.
- [Spencer] That's one.
- [Man] All right,
let's go, come on.
- [Man] Come on,
let's go get 'em.
- [Man] Come on let's go.
- [Bartlett] Come on.
(weapon fires)
- [Ox] (laughs) I love the
smell of dope in the morning.
(men chatter)
(weapon fires)
- [Ox] Mm, (laughs) okay,
let's take one of these.
Oh, hello baby, yeah.
(speaks faintly)
Now let's kill some
sons of bitches.
Ah, nice!
- [Reese] Drop it, Porter.
(Audrey groans)
- Let her go, Reese.
- [Reese] I said drop it.
(weapon clatters)
- It ain't worth dying for, boy.
Let her go.
- Now the handgun.
Real easy!
(gun fires)
(Audrey screams)
- [Clay] Come on let's go.
Stay down, stay down.
(weapons fire)
- Quick, get out now.
- [Man] Keep firing.
- [Man] Son of a bitch.
- Now shoot him.
- Shoot him, come on.
- [Ox] Ah, ha ha (laughs)!
- [Man] Come on, we gotta stop
that fat son of a
bitch, he's crazy.
(weapon fires)
- [Bartlett] Spence!
- [Man] There he is.
(Ox screams)
- [Bartlett] Go on, take off!
Go, go, go!
(tense dramatic music)
(weapon fires)
(Bartlett screams)
(slow unsettling music)
- Blow it, goddammit!
Blow it!
(water rumbles)
- Deac!
(slow somber music)
(moves into tense
dramatic music)