How am I going to hold this pose
if you make cracks like that?
You ought to see the
crack I've made in you.
Then how about my taking a look?
- Nothing doing.
You can admire yourself later.
I wanted to see if you had
carved your initials in me.
I should have given you
a general anaesthetic.
I didn't think you'd mind a little
thing like an appendectomy ..
After all the crack-ups
you've been through.
What do you mean "all the crack-ups"?
I haven't had a crack-up since you froze
the controls as I taught you how to fly.
How do you want this,
hem-stitched or buttonholed?
No zippers?
What kind of a hospital is this?
You know.
I had a yen once to become a doctor.
All I can repair is an aeroplane motor.
You can repair people.
You've built up a great name, Jim.
I think the patient
is getting delirious.
I guess I am.
Well, that is a neat piece of
embroidery if I do say so myself.
Now take good care
of this guy, will you.
No matter how much he hollers.
Don't feed him steaks.
Yes, Dr Stanton.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Barbara!
Well, it is about time you gave
your lord and master a break.
Hey.
Wait a minute.
I am your bride-to-be.
But don't forget there
is still a "to be".
Overwhelmed.
Not bad for an overworked doctor.
Time out for repairs.
Beautiful.
- Of course.
What are you doing in the big city?
- Shopping.
Getting a trousseau for our benefit.
Say, I'm a wreck.
If you're ready to leave
I'll drive you home.
Oh, I'm sorry. I've got too much
work to do here. I can't make it.
Well, I guess if I'm going to be a
doctor's wife I must get used to it.
Don't rush off.
We've got time for a cigarette.
I got a surprise for you.
I was talking to the contractor today.
And he tells me we can move
into the new house by the 1st.
That is if we can make up our
mind about that dining room.
Come in.
There is a Mr Grey
to see you, Dr Stanton.
Grey?
Well, show him in.
Out, wench.
He might be a spy from
the Junior League.
Dr Stanton?
- Yes.
I'm inspector Grey from the
Department of Commerce.
Oh yes?
A complaint has been made
against you for reckless flying.
Reckless flying?
Haven't you made some mistake?
- No chance of that.
The complaining party gave
us the number of your plane.
You've been charged with
diving at a residence.
Why that is absurd.
I fly a lot but I've never
dived at any houses.
I value my neck too much for that.
Who made the charge?
Well.
The complaint was made by
your father, Dr Stanton Senior.
Ah.
So father is playing tattle-tail again.
If there's any more of this stunting ..
Your transport licence
will be cancelled.
Hello?
See if you can get me my father.
Yeah. I think he is in Ward B.
Thanks.
Alright, Barbara. He has gone.
What is the matter with you?
You look as if your inkwell bit you.
- It's worse than that.
Dad has turned informer.
He called the Department of
Commerce to stop me from flying.
I think that is a swell idea.
I'm doing my work here. Why would anyone
care what I do outside the hospital?
You can't seem to realize who you are.
You are a Stanton.
The fifth in a long line
of illustrious doctors.
Yeah.
If you keep on flying you are liable to
break your neck and your father's heart.
Should I travel on a horse just
because the first Dr Stanton did?
Don't take it so seriously, darling.
- It is serious.
And I won't stand for interference.
If I don't get started I'll
be caught in the traffic jam.
Hello, Dr Stanton.
Don't let me drive you away, my dear.
I really must be going.
Remember your best
bedside manners, dear.
Alright, darling.
Dad, a Department of Commerce
inspector was just here.
Did he beat any sense into your head?
Don't you think it is just about time
you let me handle my own affairs?
I'm out of rompers you know.
- Mentally, you are not.
We've been through this before.
Yes, and we are going into
it again. Once and for all.
I like to fly and I am going to fly.
Flying is only a part of it, Jim.
You are running around too much.
It's time you got over
this youthful exuberance.
You are a doctor now.
Besides, you have got
Barbara to think about.
I know it, Dad. I love Barbara. I'd not
do anything in the world to hurt her.
Dad, I am trying to make myself
as great a surgeon as you and ..
Grandfather, great grandfather and
all the rest of the Stantons but if I ..
Jim.
I am going to keep after you and
the Department of Commerce.
Until you learn to
behave like a Stanton.
If I want to have a
little fun on the side.
Or relaxation it's nobody's
business but my own.
I've got an appointment
tonight in Philadelphia.
I am flying there whether
you like it or not.
But I must get to Philadelphia tonight.
- I'm sorry, ma'am. I've told you.
All transport planes are grounded
because of the weather.
Jim Stanton.
Helen.
What are you doing out
on a night like this?
Jim. I have got to get
to Philadelphia tonight.
You know everybody around here.
Couldn't you prevail on
somebody here to take me?
I fly to Philadelphia in a few minutes
but I won't take you in this weather.
Not without written permission
from your husband.
Tom knows all about it.
I'm going to visit mother.
She hasn't been well.
That's funny.
I examined her a couple of days ago
and she seemed in perfect health.
Jim Stanton, are you trying
to tell me I am lying?
No, but ..
Even at the pigtail age Helen
you had a good imagination.
Had another fight with Tom?
- Don't be silly. I said mother is sick.
I must get there, Jim.
I don't know whether you
are telling the truth or not.
But I guess it is your business.
Come along.
Thanks.
Doctor James Stanton Junior.
Well, gentlemen. I am all ready to
go through this dirty mess again.
Get your microscopes adjusted
and watch me squirm.
Dr Stanton.
This board has been convened
for the purpose of ..
The purpose of helping the newspapers
make a sensational story out of nothing.
Running off with another man's
wife can hardly be called nothing.
I was flying to Philadelphia.
And by accident a woman was killed.
You know how much I regret that.
You know all my testimony.
We know the medical profession has been
dragged into a very distasteful scandal.
Jim, I warned you.
When you became a physician.
Did you understand the
meaning of the oath you took?
The oath of Hippocrates which says ..
"Guiltless and hallowed I will
keep my life and mine art."
I understand that oath
very well, gentlemen.
And I also remember a part
of it which most of you ..
Particularly Dr Smythe,
seem to have forgotten.
It requires a man to be honorable and
just in dealings with his fellow men.
Jim.
You are taking the wrong attitude, boy.
This whole matter
isn't important enough.
It is important.
It is important to me to find
out that my .. colleagues.
My brothers in medicine.
Have so little faith in me as to refuse
to believe my sworn testimony.
For years all I have heard from
my family is how honorable ..
Understanding and loyal to one another
are the men in the medical profession.
I believed it.
I put men like you up on a pedestal.
I was proud to be one of you.
Well gentlemen, you have
been vastly overrated.
Dr Stanton.
Your attitude is unpardonable.
That is exactly what I think of yours.
We could ask for your
resignation, Dr Stanton.
However for your father's sake.
We'll ignore your actions and abide
by the original verdict of this board.
You are hereby adjudged guilty
of unprofessional conduct.
And you are placed on probation in
this hospital until further notice.
Jim.
You made a fool of yourself.
If that is being a fool then I
was born wearing a dunce-cap.
You are disgracing our
name in the profession.
As far as I am concerned the
profession is disgracing our name.
You should have known
before asking that woman ..
Helen Richards was my friend.
And I thought Tom was too.
Perhaps his definition of friendship
didn't include giving you his wife.
Dad.
I was sure you would believe me.
But no. You wouldn't take a chance of
losing a bit of the reputation of yours.
A man in the medical profession ..
Must be a proud, respected,
high-handed hypocrite.
If that is the way you feel about it.
Why don't you get out of here?
That's just exactly what I Intend to do.
Good evening, Dr Stanton.
- Good evening, Mary.
Is Miss Reed home?
Yes, she is. Come right in.
I'll call her.
Thank you.
Barbara.
Why, Jim.
You look as if you just came
from murdering somebody.
Was it anyone I know?
I've just come from the medical board.
Oh? How are all the longbeards?
Be serious, Barbara. This is important.
They have put me on probation and I ..
- Jim ..
You cannot expect to get
involved in these scandals.
And come out untouched.
You should have thought about me.
And about your name.
You still think I was trying to
run away with Helen Richards?
Well, do you?
We aren't children, Jim.
Barbara, I know the whole town hovers
over me like a bunch of vultures but ..
I was sure I could count on you.
Of course you can, Jim.
Although I can't say
I like the publicity.
But those things soon blow over.
But they don't.
Barbara, I am leaving town
and I'm taking you with me.
You can't walk out on your
practice and on your father.
I already have.
Where are you going?
Some small town.
Erase the blackboard clean and ..
Start all over again?
- That's right.
I'm going to pick out some place where I
can hang my shingle on a frame house.
And do the things I like.
Build up a practice.
And forget that I am Doctor
James Stanton, society doctor.
It will be tough at first because
I haven't much money left but ..
But I know we could
make a go of it together.
We get married and take a train tonight.
Jim.
It sounds great.
But it wouldn't work.
You're thinking about struggling
upward side by side.
And dashing off heroically in the mid of
night to save lives of little children.
It may be wonderful.
But I just can't see it.
I am thinking about doing our washing.
Wearing cotton stockings.
Eating cheap food.
What if it were that way at first?
If we love each other.
I am sorry, Jim.
I can't do it.
I promised to marry Dr James
Stanton of Park Avenue.
I am not interested in country doctors.
I was counting on you, Barbara.
I suppose I should have known better.
"All aboard."
"Pittsburgh, Cleveland
Chicago, Kansas City."
Hey. Could you give me a lift, mister?
Hop in young fellow.
You look pretty tired.
I guess I am.
Where you heading for?
I don't know. California, I guess.
California.
I've been wanting to go to
California for forty years.
What's holding you?
Too many people depending on me.
Getting sick and having babies.
And dying.
I am a doctor, you know.
Yes, I've been practising
around here for forty years.
Forty years.
Yes. Forty full, fine years.
That I wouldn't change for a trip
to California or around the world.
You wouldn't understand, young man.
But there is something about the
medical profession that pays dividends.
Spiritual dividends.
There is something inside that makes
up for all the worry and lack of money.
They certainly did a good job when they
pumped you full of high-sounding ideals.
And you are still not wise to them.
Well, you can have my share.
I'll take California.
Well, young man.
I have got to turn off here.
Thanks for the ride, doctor.
Give my regards to Hippocrates.
I don't know.
This cold weather irks me.
I'm for hopping the
next freight out of here.
No. That's the gypsy in you.
Where you going?
Hey, I've been thinking that out too.
California.
Palm Springs looks good to me.
There is too many fleas.
At them desert layouts.
It looks like you don't
have to make the trip.
Here. Pick out your own resort.
There is Santa Barbara,
Catalina. Coronado.
Palm Springs.
The resort of the elite.
Beautiful women.
Tennis.
Badminton.
There is nothing so good like ..
Oh .. meals included.
Sounds swell. Let's go.
Deal me out.
Don't you want to improve
your social standing?
Positively.
But when I get to California,
no Palm Springs for mine.
I'm going to Lake Arrowhead
where they have snow.
I spent last winter in a boxcar
at Lake Placid, New York.
Summer sports for summer.
Winter for winter.
What you trying to do?
Break up a beautiful friendship?
I'll leave it to Close-mouth.
If you was us, where would you go?
To the mountains or the desert?
Why not compromise
and go to Los Angeles?
A lot of our best people go there.
That's an idea.
I got an uncle that lives there.
Under a bridge.
Well, your uncle is going
to have company.
Coming along, Close-mouth?
Sure. Why not?
Well, they tell me there is no welcome
there for our fraternity in Los Angeles.
They can't jug you just for
crossing the state line.
Why no. It's an infringement
of your civil rights.
He is right.
They can't toss us in jail ..
Just because we think
working is unethical.
On to California!
Right.
Welcome to Los Angeles, vagrants.
Guests in our fair city always have
a variety of things to choose from.
Winter sports.
Boating, bathing and badminton.
Quiet. Or I will have you
put out of this courtroom.
I mean it. Shut up.
I am going to treat you all as guests.
To give you the privilege of
choosing 60 days in jail ..
Or 30 days on the city projects.
Sign up with the clerk.
There is a bit of rat in that guy.
Who said California?
How come I got to dangle on the
end of one of these muck sticks?
When all that tramp has to do is
wave a pretty little red flag.
Why didn't you hold
out for winter sports?
Ain't you got the courage
of your own convictions?
Hey!
What are you trying to do?
Attack the barricade?
Jim.
Go on, start moving.
You are blocking the highway.
Jim Stanton, what are you doing here?
Working. And minding my own business.
Gee, it's great to see you again.
I guess this meeting is a
sort of a shock to both of us.
I won't ask you any
more questions but ..
How much time do you
expect to spend here?
Oh, thirty days.
Then I got a reservation
on a freight train.
I'm going to do something
about those thirty days ..
And change the train reservation.
- I don't want you to.
We'll talk about it later.
Well, there you are.
The story of my misspent life.
What about Barbara Reed?
I thought you were engaged to her.
We postponed it.
You got a bad case of
chipmunks on your roof.
Dick, when I heaved my medical
books out of the window ..
I heaved out everything else with them.
All that bunk about tradition.
All father's highfalutin notions
about how I should run my life.
Dick, I'm fed up.
Yeah, but you can't stay on with
the pick-and-shovel brigade.
Why not?
- Because you can't.
I'm a transport pilot.
And I stand in pretty good with
the boss. Roberts is his name.
He is a good guy and he'll
take you on if I say so.
Doing what?
Doc, we got a hospital unit.
A flying ambulance fully equipped
for any kind of an emergency.
Now just a minute, Dick.
I've told you I was
through with medicine.
That's too bad.
You'd have been in a swell spot.
Well doc, I'll find you
some sort of a job.
Alright. I guess it would be
better than manicuring roads.
But I don't want anybody to know
that I have ever been a doctor.
So don't call me "Doc".
And don't call me "Stanton."
The name is ..
Jones, from here in.
Whatever you say.
Come on, we'll visit Roberts.
Only, we'll detour by
way of the locker room.
Hiya, Alice.
- Hello, Dick.
I don't want him to think
I'm bringing in King Kong.
Well, I don't know. We ..
We haven't any openings right now.
But Jones here can tune a motor
until it sings a symphony.
And besides, he's a good friend of mine.
Well, that is no recommendation.
But if this fellow's half as good as you
say I may be able to find work for him.
As a mechanic. Is that alright with you?
Sure.
Yes, sir.
Well, you report to Williams.
He has charge of the hangar.
Thank you, Mr Roberts.
Thank you, sir.
Now get out of here. I'm busy.
Now you've got a job, such as it is.
- Yeah.
Anyhow, it is better than
doing what you were.
Thanks for the sales talk, Dick.
- I was selling a good commodity.
Hello Dick.
Hiya Doris. How is my little girl today?
I am not your little girl.
Now that we've had our morning greeting.
I'd like you to meet Jim Jones.
Hello.
How do you do.
This is Doris King.
The pride and joy of the ambulance unit.
But we love her just the same.
And Dick is our lying, flying fool.
I'll see you later.
- Alright.
Who is the high hat and monocle?
He's a friend of mine.
Just signed on as a mechanic.
I thought he at least owned the
company. What's eating him?
Nothing. He just isn't
interested in women.
I think he saves stamps.
Now, don't flutter our eyelashes at him.
It is wasted motion.
I shall flutter them into a dither.
Alright. If you wear him out
don't say I didn't warn you.
I can always buy more.
Hey, mystery man.
What's the matter with you?
I've been staying awake nights
trying to figure out if you are ..
An escaped criminal, an international
spy or a prince in disguise.
Try counting sheep.
That will put you to sleep.
I did and made a tidy little fortune.
Catching them and selling their wool.
I'm not commercial minded.
Just the same, I am on your trail.
Let's say goodbye here.
It's a crossroads.
Anyway, I warn you.
You got caught in the
downdraught, didn't you.
The dogfight has just begun.
That big nut-and-bolt man
intrigues my analytical mind.
Listen. If you are tired of
minding your own business.
Try minding mine.
And leave him alone.
This Jones man is fresh material.
He is the strong, silent type.
Maybe he just hasn't anything to say.
A smart girl could make the Sphinx
propose a weekend in the mountains.
Hello.
- Hello.
Coffee and doughnuts please.
You are Jones the new man, aren't you?
Yeah. Why?
I'm Watson. A reporter. On the news.
The boys all call me "Nosy".
Where are you from?
- The east.
Always been a mechanic?
Maybe.
Thanks, chatterbox.
Hello, Nosy.
Hello Doris. How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
Hello Doris. Sit down here?
No thanks.
Is this seat taken?
Yes.
Dick tells me you've done lot of flying.
- Does he?
Ah, you talk your head off, don't you.
No.
You know, I've been wondering about
you. You aren't the mechanic type.
You don't act like one, you don't
talk like one. And your hands are ..
Did you come in here to eat
or to keep me from eating?
I came in just to keep you company.
You looked lonesome.
A cup of coffee.
And two doughnuts for the lady.
- I don't want doughnuts.
Doughnuts.
- Why doughnuts?
When you mouth is full
you won't be able to talk.
Hello Dick.
- HI, Eddie.
Hiya, Mack.
Hello Dick. You want a seat?
- No thanks. I'm looking for Jones.
Well, he is not looking for you.
Well, the dirty bachelor.
Pardon me, is this woman annoying you?
Why, not at all. She is a
charming conversationalist.
And her table manners are superb.
Wait a minute. Your cap.
Thank you.
Coffee please.
So how goes the battle?
The enemy is weakening.
I made him laugh.
He is a nice guy underneath.
Way underneath.
Where did you meet him?
I taught him to fly.
What has been doing since then?
What?
Say, is this the third degree?
How about minding your own business?
I am going into town for a while.
You know where you can reach me.
Give her my love.
- What?
Coffee and doughnuts. 15 cents.
- Mr Jones left his check for you.
He said you owed it to
him for entertaining you.
"Attention. Emergency."
"Castle, Miller. Doris King."
"Report to Mr Roberts."
"Ground crews."
"Get ambulance plane
ready for immediate take-off."
"Emergency."
"Castle, Miller. Doris King."
"Report immediately."
Have you seen Castle and Miller?
- No.
If you see them tell them to report
to the old man. He is primed.
Doris, you are to pick
up a very sick man.
If I can find one of my pilots.
- Yes, sir.
Hello?
What?
Alright .. alright.
That was Castle.
He's in home in bed with the flu.
Where is Dick Miller?
- Dick is off duty.
I know it. I've looked
high and low for him.
Doris, he is the only man available.
Say. You know all of his hangouts.
Find him.
By the time I find Dick, our patient
will able to walk here.
You will bring Miller here if you
have to drag the rivers for him.
He doesn't take off on his
usual run until 9 o'clock.
It gives him time to
make this hop for me.
Here is a report on the
case and your orders.
Get busy.
I'll find a pilot for you.
Jones.
Get ready. We're taking the
ship and picking up a patient.
What do you mean, "we"?
Just what I said. Castle is
sick and we can't find Dick.
Where do I come in? I'm a mechanic.
- You are also a pilot, aren't you?
Sure, but ..
- No buts.
It's an emergency case.
We've got to get to him.
That's your job, not mine.
It is your job to take
orders from Roberts.
Well, how does he know
I can handle the ship?
Dick told him. Said that he taught you.
You are wasting time.
Come on, Jim. Hurry.
Alright. What are we standing
around arguing for?
He's been in terrific pain.
I gave him a hypodermic.
That should keep him quiet on the trip.
Well, goodbye, Dr Farrell.
- Goodbye, Miss King.
All set?
- All set.
I can't stand it.
It's alright. Get back down ..
- Let me go!
I want to get out that door.
- Get back.
Jim!
- Let me go.
- Let me go!
Easy does it.
Are you hurt?
I'm alright. I've got to
do something for him.
Give him a quarter grain of morphine.
Hurry.
You'd better let me do that.
You are shaking pretty badly.
I'm alright now. I'll take care of him.
A nice quiet trip, wasn't it.
How do you like piloting?
- I enjoyed it. A great feeling.
I'm glad you liked it.
Maybe you won't like it so well
after Roberts gets through with you.
So, while Doris was battling
with him I was flying the plane.
The first I knew of the whole business
was when she opened the cabin door.
You are saying that little girl put that
guy out of the way without your help?
Sure she did. She's dynamite.
Sounds kinda screwy to me.
Haven't you ever heard of Ju-jutsu?
Japanese wrestling.
And how.
A little bit of a guy threw
me out of a bar once.
Yeah, well that's what she used.
- Ju-jutsu?
What a story.
I'll spread that all over the
front pages before noon.
See you later. I'm going
to grab pictures of the ship.
And the kid herself.
- Hey, Nosy.
Doris may try to give you another
story but don't believe her.
She's just modest.
Don't worry. Nobody ever
fooled Nosy Watson.
Yeah.
Alright, Jim. That's for the newspapers.
Now what really happened?
- Just what I told Nosy.
That Doris is a handful
of angry crazy wildcat.
I get it. She did it
with her little hands.
What I am wondering is, why did
Roberts send you on that hop at all?
Doris knew where to reach me.
She did?
Well I might have known our
little politician cooked it up.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Well Doris.
You seem to have taken the management
of this airport into your own hands.
Why did you disobey my orders and let a
mechanic fly a plane in this emergency?
Who is running this airport, you or me?
You are, sir.
Didn't I tell you to find
Dick Miller last night?
Well, you said that
it was an emergency ..
And I knew that Dick was
pretty far away out on a date ..
Doris, you didn't even look for Dick.
I know it, Mr Roberts.
Well, why didn't you?
I ought to fire you right on the spot.
You can do it but you will be sorry.
Jim Jones is the kind
of man we need here.
He is meant for something
better than a mechanic's job.
I watched him day after day.
I've tried to get him to open
up without much success but ..
I do know this.
You couldn't find a better pilot.
You should have seen
him handle that plane ..
And take care of my patient
when he got out of hand.
Mr Roberts, you have got
to make Jim Jones a pilot.
Young lady, I had you come in
here to give you a good talking to.
And I can't have you turn discipline
sessions into your own triumphs.
What are you trying to do,
wind me around your finger?
That wouldn't be a bad idea either.
If I hadn't met Jim.
Get out of here before you try to talk
me into resigning in favor of Mr Jones.
Does he stay on as a pilot?
- That is none of your business.
Get Jim Jones.
I'll get him. I know just where he is.
Don't get Jones.
Morning, boys.
The mighty, mighty.
With her mighty rags.
Where is Jones?
Oh, he is hiding.
He is afraid you will
pop him on the smeller.
Good morning.
Not with you around.
Thanks for putting me in
newspaper headlines.
That's alright.
I bought two copies
for wrapping packages.
Jones, for a man who
doesn't talk much ..
You certainly delivered
a long lecture to Nosy.
Just wanted to beat you to the punch.
Everybody around here
knows what really happened.
Why don't you take
credit when it's yours?
I'm not interested.
- You ought to be.
Or is it your ambition to stay
a grease-monkey forever?
Never mind my ambitions.
- Don't be an idiot.
I'm not trying to inspire you.
I'm just trying to talk a little sense.
Why do you always fight me off?
I haven't any designs on you.
I don't know why I
even bother about you.
Well, I wish you wouldn't
bother about me.
Alright, Jones.
If that's the way you want it.
Try and get it.
I almost forgot.
Roberts wants to see you right away.
I guess you fixed that too?
A little more help from you
and I'll be out altogether.
Yes, Mr Roberts.
We're looking for Mr Jones.
Oh.
That guy sure handles
himself like he was somebody.
Say. Who is he, anyway?
I mean .. really.
- Him?
Why that is Jim Jones.
From the east.
Thanks. We'll get out and extra.
You weren't supposed to fly that ship.
You and Doris endangered
the life of her patient.
Yes. And you took a chance on wrecking
the reputation of this company.
I might have known it was
one of her bright ideas.
You think I'd have flown
the ship if I knew that?
You didn't use your head.
If anything had gone wrong we'd
have had a nice lawsuit on our hands.
And this company wouldn't get
another nickel's worth of business.
If that's the way you feel about it.
Oh no. You don't get a chance to quit.
You are fired.
It's alright with me.
- Now wait a minute.
Take it easy.
If anything had gone wrong you and
Doris would have been responsible.
But since her judgement was vindicated.
I am going to take full advantage of it.
Jones, I am firing you as a mechanic.
And hiring you as a pilot.
Is your license in order?
I haven't renewed it yet.
So, you'd better over to the Department
of Commerce and take care of it.
But I .. I don't want the job, sir.
You are not letting King down, are you?
King?
- Sure.
She has been bullying me
for days to give you a chance.
Jones, that girl has got a
lot of confidence in you.
To have Doris like you is the biggest
break a man can get at this airport.
Well, I guess that includes
all the airports.
I'll take the job, sir. Thanks a lot.
Good luck.
- Thank you.
If you want to know more about
Jones, why don't you ask Jones?
Call Mr Evans at the
Department of Commerce.
Tell him one of our boys is coming
over to have his license renewed.
Ask him to take care
of it for me, will you.
Yes, sir.
So Roberts is making a pilot
of Jim Jones from the east.
Sure. Doris King was in here
all day raving about him.
Jim Jones from the east.
It sounds to me like a phony
name for a hotel register.
It couldn't be a phony.
Not if he has a license from
the Department of Commerce.
That is just what I was thinking.
You are going to get your nose caught
in a lawnmower one of these days.
When I do you will read
about it in my paper.
Exclusive.
And with pictures.
How are you going to get your license
renewed under the name of Jim Jones?
I'm not. I am renewing
it as James Stanton.
Nobody else has to know that.
It seems to me you are
jumping feet first into a bear trap.
If the Flying Board inspectors check up.
Roberts will find out all about you.
Sure he will, but by that time I
hope to have the job sewn up.
I can't let Doris down.
I am with you, Doc.
Oh. So Doris took care of the
patient but you get the promotion.
What are you trying to do,
confuse the press?
How about giving me a story?
Sure, Nosy.
Once upon a time there
was three bears ..
There you are, Stanton.
You are all set for another six months.
Thanks again, sir.
See you around, Inspector.
- Right.
Hiya, Nosy.
How is the peeping-tom business?
- It strains my eyes.
I just saw a guy outside I
haven't seen in a long while.
He just came out of
here with Dick Miller.
I don't remember his last name but
I think we used to call him "Doc".
Doc?
- Yeah.
Was it Dr Stanton?
Yeah.
Dr Stanton, that's it.
He just had his license renewed.
He is from Boston, isn't he?
No. New York.
Oh .. I remember.
He is the Dr Stanton who
was in that society scandal.
He cracked up his plane.
Yeah. He is the one.
The Department investigated
the crash. It wasn't his fault.
Too bad the woman was killed.
Doris.
I have a story that
will knock your hat off.
Where is Jim Jones? I've got to see him.
I don't know. What's all the excitement?
- Do you know who Jones really is?
Santa Claus.
No .. seriously.
It will drop you through a trap door.
Now let me see. Peter Pan?
Did you ever hear of Doctor
James Stanton, senior or junior?
Of course. Who hasn't?
Jim Jones is Dr James Stanton junior.
The one who was engaged to Barbara Reed.
That high-society dame.
But why all the secrecy?
What is he doing as Jim Jones?
That's what I am going to find out.
I will squeeze every bit of story out of
him if I have to use a meat grinder.
Nosy, you can't print that.
The biggest story of the year.
And you say I can't print it?
Why?
- Because ..
There is some reason why he
is Jim Jones and a mechanic.
I've got a hunch if we find
out what is behind all this.
It will be the biggest scoop
you have ever come across.
If you print that story now,
he will run away.
But I had my yarn practically written.
But with him gone it will
only make a ripple.
I know you will get a smash story.
One that will make you famous.
If you just give me a chance with him.
I promise you I will find out
what is behind all this.
And you will be the first to know.
Just give me a few days.
Alright, Doris.
If you say so, I'll hold the story back.
You always did have
the Indian sign on me.
That's what I get for mixing
women and business.
Mr Roberts.
Have you any confidence in me?
Why .. of course.
Then assign Jim Jones to
pilot the ambulance ship.
Haven't you enough to do as a nurse
without running the whole airport?
Please, Mr Roberts.
It means a lot to me.
I ..
I'd like to have you look over
the list of our executives.
There might be another position
you'd rather have for Mr Jones.
Mr Roberts, you need a regular
an on the ambulance ship.
Look what happened when Castle was sick.
Dick Miller is kept busy on his
transport run and so is McClintock.
You know you can use another pilot.
And Jim Jones is the
one to fly the ambulance.
You seem to know
more about it than I do.
You may be right at that.
You are making history.
Hey, watch for air parking.
We're taking you home to wash your face.
And to put on your best bib and
tucker. We're celebrating.
Jim's probationary period is over.
Roberts is going to let him fly.
Gee, that's swell. Let me down.
Jim, you get a kiss for this.
Hey.
Don't forget that stuff
about a woman scorned.
Are you becoming acutely conscious
of a wheezing concertina?
I like it. It is so romantic.
Splendid. I will have it removed.
Say, Officer. Would you send this
wandering minstrel on his way.
Kick him back into the 15th Century.
Isn't he a friend of yours?
Never saw before in our lives.
Hey, wait a minute.
On our way or I'll run you in.
You can't arrest me.
Can't you leave these folks be?
Anybody could see they want to be alone.
Do we?
- What?
Want to be alone.
Uhuh.
You know, Jim. You are lucky.
Being a flyer is just about the
finest job a man can have.
Except one.
And what is that?
Being a doctor.
Well, I wouldn't touch the medical
profession with a banana stalk.
It is full of stuffed shirts.
My father was a doctor.
I wanted to be one too.
You are doing alright as a nurse.
Sometimes I want to be a lion
tamer or something else.
And then ..
Along comes an interesting
case and I am a nurse again.
Let's talk about you.
You know, you'd have made a fine doctor.
What makes you say that?
I don't know. I guess
it's just because ..
You always seem to me as though
you were diagnosing my case.
You're letting your imagination
run away with you.
Flying is good enough for me.
I am glad you are satisfied.
When I first met you ..
You reminded me of a little
Scottie I had once seen.
He'd just been run over.
He didn't bark or whine but ..
I could see the hurt in his eyes.
Just as I could in yours.
When I tried to draw you out you
said it was none of my business.
It wasn't.
But I wanted to help you.
I just think I went about
it in the wrong way.
You talk too much.
Did you know it was raining?
Seen Jim yet?
- No.
But according to the bulletin board he
has been assigned to the hospital unit.
I wonder how he is going to take it.
Why shouldn't it be alright?
Why did you frame me into that ambulance
job? I told you I didn't want it.
Now wait a minute.
- I talked Roberts into it.
Why? Why should you take it
on yourself to change my job?
Because I love you.
I did it for your sake.
To snap you out of your shell.
Maybe I like that shell.
I'm seeing Roberts about this.
Jim, you can't back out now.
This is your chance.
Now try to get this into
your head, will you.
I am not flying any ambulance ship.
And I don't want you meddling.
You ran from the medical board.
You ran out of town and you've
been running away ever since.
Yes. I know you are Dr Stanton.
I know all about you.
But get this into your head.
Every time you run away, you're bound
to run right smack up against yourself.
And the next time you do, take
a good look. You won't like it.
Are you through?
Certainly I'm through. In every way.
So pick up your marbles
and run home little boy.
The game is too tough for you.
Thanks.
You certainly handed it to him.
- I had to, Dick.
I had to make him realize that
he is hurting himself and me.
I guess you are all
washed up with him now?
Oh, no I'm not. I've got an
idea and I need your help.
Doris King.
- Seat 12.
Hiya, Jim.
Dick, I am sorry I ..
Skip it.
Alright.
Going somewhere?
- Yeah.
I'm going to lift my anchor.
Fine.
Sad to see you go.
Now that you and Doris are gone.
I have time to mend my socks.
But I am going to miss old Doris.
Miss Doris? What are you talking about?
She has gone.
She put her freight on
the afternoon plane.
But there is no sense in her leaving.
I guess she got tired
of you sneering at her.
Well, she'll come back as soon
as she hears I'm out of her way.
Sure, sure.
As soon as she has a chance to
figure out what a mouse you are.
She was only in love with the
guy she used to think you were.
Maybe you are right.
Listen.
I am having my appendicitis
scar painted over.
Because it reminds me of you.
And where do you think you are going?
I'm going to make my run to El Paso.
I want to get plastered down there.
You can't fly in that condition.
I can't, can't I?
Who is going to stop me?
I am.
Hello. Get me the
Roberts Airline please.
Hello. I want to speak to Mr Roberts.
Jim Jones calling.
Hello, Mr Roberts?
Well Dick Miller is over here
and he is .. he is pretty sick.
Ptomaine poisoning I think.
He can't make that trip to El Paso.
But I'll take it if you
are short of pilots.
Alright, sir. I'll be right over.
Hello? General Hospital?
Dr Stanton please.
Hello, Dr Stanton?
This is Doris King, a nurse.
I've just came from your son.
You came from Jim? Is he alright?
What is he up to?
Is he practising medicine?
No, he isn't.
He is working at our airport.
Oh, he is, is he?
That's all I wanted to know.
Hello?
Dr Stanton?
[ Buzzer ]
Is Miss Reed in?
- Who is calling please?
Miss Doris King. Just say it
is about James Stanton.
That's alright, Mary.
Did you say you wanted to talk
to me about Jim Stanton?
That's the idea.
I am Doris King, a nurse
at the Los Angeles airport.
Miss King: Mr Howard Dennis, my fiance.
How do you do.
- How do you do.
Please sit down.
Cigarette?
- No thank you.
I guess you are wondering
what brings me here.
Yes, I am.
You surely aren't Jim's kindly old aunt
come to patch things up between us.
I've come here to ask for help for Jim.
He is in a critical spot
working around the airport.
I've tried to get him
back where he belongs.
He is a doctor at heart
and he has got to be one.
Admitting that you love Jim and
he is in some kind of a spot ..
Why should he come back into my life
considering that he's already out of it?
I have tried to see his father.
I am sure he could influence Jim.
But Dr Stanton is as
bull-headed as his boy.
He won't even talk to you.
That is where you come in.
You've got to make him listen to me.
It is very amusing.
Don't you know that woman number one
is supposed to hate woman number two?
Rather than accompany the other?
I am sorry. I knew there wasn't much
chance of you helping me but ..
But .. well I was clutching
at any straws in sight.
And I guess I end up with no straws.
Wait a moment.
I love Howard now.
Then you will help me?
- Sure.
Can you get my coat, Howard?
I think we had better go now.
I tell you something funny, Miss King.
Sometimes, I still catch
myself thinking of Jim.
Don't worry. Jim and I could
never get together again.
Maybe if I got him definitely married
to you I could forget him myself.
Here you are.
Wait for me, Howard. I will be back.
The keys.
Hello, Barbara.
Hello doctor. Been waiting long?
When an elderly man accepts a rendezvous
with a beautiful young girl ..
He is prepared to wait
as long as is necessary.
Correction please.
Two beautiful young girls.
I want you to meet Miss King.
- How do you do.
How do you do.
- Won't you sit down?
I have ordered two
steak dinners for you.
A typical Stanton gesture.
Everybody has to eat what he orders.
- I know what is best for you.
Waiter.
- Yes, sir?
Two steak dinners please.
Now, what is this so-important business
that drags me out of the hospital?
It is Jim. Miss King has
just come from him.
Barbara, I'd never have thought that ..
- Sit down, doctor.
It's about time you and I started
listening and hearing about ourselves.
In doing what we can to bring Jim
out of the muddle we drove him into.
I have done nothing to be ashamed of.
When Doris starts talking
you may change your mind.
Please, Barbara.
Nothing can change my mind.
Doris. Tell him what you told me.
Dr Stanton, I have come
a long way for this.
Hey, what is the idea?
Have you been dodging me?
I've been looking for you for two days.
Ever since you got back from El Paso.
Jim, I want to thank you.
- Ah, forget it.
I guess I have been enough to
drive you and Doris both to drink.
Been checking up on yourself, huh?
I had plenty of time to
think up in that plane.
I could hear all the names you and
Doris called me in alphabetical order.
Did you agree with them?
And then some.
But the 'running away' part
doesn't hold anymore.
Then you are going to stick it out, huh?
Sure.
There is always a chance
Doris will come back.
I'll have coffee and doughnuts on that.
Hey, Marie.
Coffee and ..
You've outsmarted me again, young lady.
I just called your bluff.
You know Doris, I have been thinking.
I came away on a sudden wave of emotion.
Now that it has passed.
I can't help wondering if
this isn't a wild goose chase.
Jim won't listen to me.
- I have tried everything else.
Hello, Ed.
Dispatcher's office. Joe speaking.
Number 19 just went
through Pine Forks on time.
Alright, Joe.
Hello.
Got it.
Which number 19?
Number 19 Express.
Alright.
Give me the office.
Joe. The mainline switch is stuck.
Can you stop number 19?
But I can't, Joe. It's stuck!
Number 19 is wrecked.
Send help as fast as you can.
"Miller. Jones."
"Report to Mr Roberts'
office immediately."
"Emergency!"
"Ground crews. Get transport
W8 and hospital unit ready."
Alright. Let me know
if they need anything else.
There's been a bad train wreck in the
mountains. 20 miles west of Pine Forks.
No town near there for us to get doctors
and supplies to them, so it is up to us.
Dick. The hospital is rushing
some doctors over here.
When they arrive you must take
them in your plane to the wreck.
Jones, I depend on you to fly the
ambulance ship with the nurses.
They are waiting for you.
Now get going just as soon as possible.
Yes, sir.
I'll be there before you get
your wheels off the ground.
Doctor.
We've found another man.
He is in pretty bad shape.
I'll be right with you.
I've done all I can.
Keep him well covered.
Come on, Doris.
Getting close.
We should be able to see the wreck soon.
Doctor. Will you come?
I am not the doctor. The plane with
the doctors will be here any moment.
Come along anyway.
We need all the help we can get.
Thank goodness you've come.
I tell you there is nothing
we can do for this child.
0nly an emergency
operation can save him.
We came in ambulance plane.
It is completely equipped.
Get everything ready.
The doctor is preparing
for an operation.
You two had better leave.
We'll stay here.
They want you too, pilot.
I can't help them.
I know how you feel, son.
How do you feel, John?
Better.
But if it hadn't been for
that doctor I'd have ..
He is a great guy.
I saw him a few minutes ago.
He looked as if he needed
a doctor himself.
I am sure glad it isn't me
he is going to work on.
You should be.
The doctor is too far gone
to tackle an operation.
He'd probably fold up
in the middle of it.
Nurse, get me gown and gloves.
Jim!
That's alright, nurse.
Doris, gloves please.
A crushing injury to the
frontal area of the skull.
I've stopped the haemorrhage.
But the pressure must
be relived immediately.
The boy is going to be alright.
How did you two ever get together?
Doris brought me out, Jim.
Doctor, the other plane
hasn't arrived yet.
And some of those people
need immediate attention.
I'll right with you.
You take it easy, Dad.
We'll go.
Alright.
Doctor Stanton.
=(sd)=