Yeah, there's a
little shade here.
An architectural masterpiece
of urban planning.
Fresh from the drawing board:
the theory of an urban district.
Guess they're going
to call this "Europacity."
Europe is certainly
deserving of that.
Should I turn it up?
We don't have power anymore.
We need power.
NOTICE OF TERMINATION
Things can't stay as they are.
Things aren't allowed
to stay as they are.
Let's assume the
three of us live here.
We live a makeshift life.
Our bags are always half packed,
we're on the go.
Freedom is important to us. We
have no bonds and don't want any.
- Take care. Good luck!
- Bye!
Hello!
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Give that here.
- Camera.
Our goals are short term.
The main objective
is to make ourselves happy.
is to make ourselves happy?
My film's about self-optimized
individuals and collective consciousness.
I wanted to know what you're
aspiring to at the moment.
What is your ideal aim?
You mean for my future?
Yes, for your future
but also more generally.
These things prove the arbitrariness
of economic principles.
These shoes were
new and had a price.
They're still new, but the price
is now a fraction of what it was.
All the same, no one wants them.
Is this all without value?
When does it have a value? Right
now it's clearly superfluous.
This is broken and worthless now.
I put it back together and
it's Jeff Koons' "Balloon Dog."
It was once worth 10,000 dollars.
- Excuse me?
- Yes?
Can I give you
10,000 dollars for this?
No, you don't need to pay.
You can just have it.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Thanks.
- Hello, Mr. Felsch.
- Hello.
Mr. Felsch I read your book. It
inspired me to do the film I'm making.
I was wondering where we are today. Have
we entered a "long winter of theory"?
Because that combination
of theory, reading and political
revolt no longer exists in that way.
Firstly, we have an entirely
different reading culture.
You can really see
that at universities.
- You work at a university.
- I do, that's right.
I teach cultural studies
at Humboldt University.
I believe the people who
were part of the 1968 generation
were, above all
else, gifted readers.
As has been noted repeatedly
that generation itself
didn't really produce very
many high-level theoreticians.
- They...
- That's interesting.
As if one can't read and write
at the same time.
That's sort of the
point I wanted to make.
Lots of figures
from the 1968 political scene
read a whole lot and got
books and texts in circulation.
Like the founders of little left-wing
publishing houses, such as Merve.
When you look around
universities today
it's actually
virtually the reverse.
That is, we are all
constantly writing something.
People write a lot more
during their studies.
Cyberculture has greatly reduced
inhibitions about producing writing.
Without having to go to any fuss
you can get publicity in some form.
There's probably a lot more
resistance with a typewriter.
With a typewriter what
you've written is only on paper,
no one reads it.
There are a lot more ways
to get publicity today.
Peer-to-peer culture encourages
writing. It's very empowering.
You have to wonder if all
that's written is getting read.
Yes, mathematically
that can't be.
So how is it as a historian?
Can you research
the future as well?
- Is the future relevant to an historian?
- I think that's a pretty important point.
The long summer of theory,
the reason it was
so long and so hot
was because they were theories that
ventured to predict the future.
The blueprint for
that was Marxism
or the philosophy of history,
which goes back roughly to Hegel.
Theories that don't just
describe things in the now
but that also make a claim to know
how history will develop going forward
and that always project towards some
objective at the end of history.
I don't think we can go back
to those grand, optimistic
teleological narratives
that tell us what direction
things are heading in,
what direction history is moving,
it's meaning.
Yet, at the same time, I see,
in and outside of universities, things
like the Anthropocene discussion.
They show there's obviously
a desire for that again.
That after these 20 years
of postmodernism
there's a desire to
return to something,
to develop a theory of history
that can somehow or other give us a
sense of how the story will go on.
I think it's clear
that has resurfaced.
I'll sleep with you.
Yes, I'll sleep with you.
Now that we've been
married for a day.
Yesterday,
on April 29, 1945,
we got married.
My name is now "Eva Hitler."
My hair has turned
brown in the bunker.
Like my old name.
"Eva Braun."
Braun. You have to roll the R,
that's what they did back then.
What kind of a text is it anyway?
I'm no longer pretty.
My powder boxes are empty.
My silk stockings have runs.
Runs.
And tomorrow...
Tomorrow we'll all be dead.
But I'm going to
fuck you before then.
I think that's good.
Yeah, I reinterpreted the text.
No one can perform this crap.
- And then?
- "And then" what?
What happened then?
Then another girl
came and she did it.
Bye-bye German Film Award.
- You'd have given him a blow job?
- I'd do anything for a lead role.
Besides, let's be honest.
What's the deal with humanizing a monster?
Am I supposed to empathize with Eva Braun?
"Sentimental drama
in the Führer's bunker."
Nazis had human emotions too.
Justification of the past is the
new genre with "good Nazis."
Justification of the past?
I have a different theory
I think those films are so well-loved
because of the female parts.
Back then women
were still beautiful, seductive,
and, most importantly,
submissive.
You know, that brings back
memories of the good old days,
when a man was still a man
and a woman was still a woman.
Frau.
- Frau!
- The woman from bygone days.
At least your part had a name.
Recent movies hardly
ever pass the Bechdel test.
- What test?
- The Bechdel test.
It indicates if a
film is misogynistic.
A film isn't that if it has
at least two female parts.
And they have to talk to each
other about a topic besides men.
- What else do you want to talk about?
- Yeah, that's right.
- What else would we talk about?
- That's about it, really.
This isn't going to be misogynistic,
but it won't be very kind to men either.
Okay, read it.
"Dear, etc... I find
your movie title,
"The Long Journey
from Collective Consciousness
"to Self-Optimized Individual -
We become I..."
- Cumbersome?
- "Romantic.
"You swoon over the past.
"Nostalgia oozes forth
like lukewarm gravy..."
If your theory is labeled "romantic"
you can take it to an emotional level.
You have to do that in every
screenplay. It's about identification.
This is a total Hollywood independent
film expert speaking, right?
I don't want
a character to identify with.
Why not?
It imposes foreign emotions on you
and I don't want to be manipulated.
- I mean I'm really hungry.
- Yes, I'll be there in a sec.
What kind of a
character is Detlef?
Detlef has always been here
in this apartment.
Yeah, when we moved in
he always slept in the bathtub.
- Until we got him the sofa.
- Thanks.
Detlef has seen the
entire recent past.
He basically holds 30 years of history
inside him and now he mostly keeps silent.
- So the silent past?
- That's enough for me.
I don't want to sit here later
and have done nothing.
Can you convey
that to the viewer?
It's not entertainment.
Nola is making a political film.
- And it's about freedom.
- Freedom sounds a bit romantic, right?
- Replenishments.
- Finally!
Freedom isn't
romantic, it's existential.
We'll notice that when it's gone.
Where are your doors?
- They were in bad need of refurbishment.
- Yeah, that's right.
Yes, they urgently had to be
fitted with gilded doorknobs.
- The hypothesis is: What should we do?
- That's no hypothesis.
Sure, we just have to scream
it out: "What should we do?!"
That's all been done.
It's how Baader and Meinhof sat
at the table planning abductions.
Nonsense! First they set fire to
a department store in Frankfurt.
Yeah, but we're talking
about not reenacting the past.
Not reenacting it
but processing it.
Or as inspiration.
But still the question remains:
What to do?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Is something going
on with you guys?
Nothing at all is going on.
Work, earning a living,
a livelihood.
And we're not any further ahead.
The low-wage sector is still
primarily occupied by women.
More and more so.
A growing number of women
are working in low-wage jobs
like caregiving,
cleaning.
And then the neoliberal blather
about how emancipating it is when
a woman can provide for herself.
She has to provide for herself.
All that does is provide
capitalism with cheap labor.
And women end up doing
the same jobs as always.
I toil for my independence.
That's a contradiction in terms.
You know what, Nola,
sometimes I'd like
to have it like that too.
Someone who helps me put my coat
on, who holds the door open for me
or who escorts me to the table.
And who reads the menu to you.
An older man who fumbles to get
his reading glasses out. Oh, Katja!
You know what I mean.
But, you know,
as long as the tourists come
and pay their 25
euros a head per night
and are happy with that
everything's dandy.
At least someone invented
the washing machine.
Yeah, what are we
complaining about?
- I think we should go in for the audio.
- Sounds good.
Can you explain
the term "state feminism" to me?
That's the title of our book and
it's actually meant a bit ironically.
About ten years
ago it was a surprise
to see established politicians
turn feminist.
They gave passionate speeches about
the importance of women's independence.
Then came a series of reforms.
The parental allowance
was introduced,
day care was expanded
and "mini-jobs" were introduced.
Ultimately it was clear
that the main aim of that reform
was to get well-educated women
to have lots of kids
and to get them to return to work as
quickly as possible after childbirth.
Once you realized
that it's primarily women
who take care
of small children and old people
it turned out that it was ultimately
the intensification of a double burden.
As far as we know that has never
been the aim of a feminist movement.
We don't know
anybody who wants that.
So the burden on women
has actually increased
thanks to prevailing ideas
of motherhood?
Yes.
But you can't view
that independently
from the other laws
that have changed as well.
The Hartz IV reforms to unemployment
and social welfare were implemented,
so were mini-jobs
and part-time jobs.
And all those things led to
a lot more women
being in employment.
The labor force
participation rate for women
has increased from 2003 to today
to over 70 percent.
And back then it was 55 percent.
That's something that
makes you wonder:
How did that happen?
Why has the state discovered
feminism all of a sudden
and why do we now have so many
women with children who are working?
So it's really about creating
a more productive society,
about incentives
to make society more productive.
- That's how I see it.
- And to preserve the capitalist system.
- Actually.
- Yes, to preserve it...
- Or even to...
- To optimize it.
Yes, to optimize it.
So that... Yes, you really can say
that. What does it mean for society?
Well-educated women
who are then supposed to be...
After having spent all of 20
years going to school and studying
they're supposed to put all their
effort into raising one or two children?
As far as the state's concerned
that's a huge waste,
from a capitalist standpoint
it is as well.
Basically those women
are supposed to continue
to make their productivity
available to the market.
Nowadays most women have to work. Lots
of women had to do that before too.
But in this day and age
there are more demands.
Women are expected to have
immensely successful careers
while at the same time, and
we haven't yet talked about this,
lofty demands are being put
on mothers and fathers.
You can't just raise
a kid nowadays,
they have to be very gifted
and you have to foster
your children as
much as possible.
I insist upon my
right to laziness.
Like other people insist
upon their right to work.
I've always been
a flop on the job market.
Whatever.
I had a job as a
corpse in the theater.
In this play
that was like three hours long.
I died ten minutes into it.
I lay there, me with
my weak bladder.
I couldn't hold it anymore
after 40 minutes.
And I had to decide if I was going
to pee onstage or go to the toilet.
I chose the toilet.
I got up, went to the toilet,
came back
and lay down in the same place.
No one really noticed.
But the director
totally blew his top.
He was so hot-tempered
he fired me on the spot.
It's absurd, as if anyone
really believed you were dead.
- Yeah!
- That's an idea.
Theater with real corpses.
Maybe with volunteers who want
to live out their final rush.
Yeah, like GG Allin.
He died in front of his audience.
He did it.
Even as a corpse in a theater
you still have no
right to laziness.
Come on.
You coming?
Hey, come on!
That's good. One, two...
three!
Towards me. That's right.
We're nearly done.
Oh yeah, this is...
I don't even know
what his name is.
- Time for a Sexy Lamp Test.
- Oh, you're mean!
We'll take the part out of the script
and replace it with a decorative lamp.
If the story doesn't
change, it's a fail.
Two against one, so...
Man, you guys are so mean!
The guy is really nice,
and a great actor to boot.
- Hello.
Hi. Nice lamp.
- Can we borrow your bike again?
- Yeah.
- Do the Chinese guys still need it?
- The Chinese guys don't need a bike.
Yes, you can take it.
- Have you found a new apartment?
- Mom says we won't with all the dogs.
- What'll you do then?
- Grandma has a yard.
Do we know where
we're going to move yet?
"My husband is my home."
That's what my grandma said.
I mean, what are we doing here
anyway? I mean in the here and now.
Are we different
or are the times different?
We're sitting at a dumb hand-me-down
table with all our old crap.
And all we own is
the cup in our hands.
Wouldn't the situation
be totally different
if we were sitting
in a cozy little garden?
Like in the community
garden Bornholm II?
We're different
people in this situation.
We'd read a Friedrich
Kittler text totally differently.
We may even
interpret it differently,
take the opposing position,
not an affirmative one.
I doubt I'd read it at all. These
brats would have me at my wit's end.
The situation could
be totally different.
Imagine it, we're
sitting in the salon
of a 200-square-meter pre-WWII
apartment on Pariser Strasse.
The nanny
has already put the brats to bed.
Or we didn't have any to begin
with. Right? You not here at all!
Wow! I never thought your
imagination was so bourgeois.
To be honest I find it pretty
strenuous to keep my bearing all day.
I mean, bearing in what sense?
- Towards what?
- I imagine it being quite fun.
You know, when you really get
into it and get a feel for it.
But then it'd be the
only life you have.
Thank you.
We could do
something totally normal.
Yes.
An occupation we never would've
chosen of our own free will.
Right, this is for you.
You can read through it.
Well, if I had to sit here
at my desk every day
I think I'd try to find happiness
in the evenings and on weekends.
- I think that makes lots of things easier.
- I couldn't do it.
But if I had to
maybe then I could.
Maybe you have to have to
to be able to.
And then it makes sense
to rebel against all this crap.
You're right about that, everything
here really is total crap.
We're going on about parallel
worlds. We could do this forever.
Yet it doesn't get us any further
along, and we never go far enough.
A coffee picker in Bali,
a seamstress in Bangladesh,
we jump from one
extreme to the other.
The more extreme we get
the more we neutralize ourselves.
Neutralize?
Yeah.
We always revert
to being ourselves.
Yeah.
Damn!
Yeah, you have
to position yourself.
To find a position.
But within or without?
Do I think from the inside out or
do I see myself from the outside?
I would actually
rather do the latter.
But I fear there is
no "outside" anymore.
The individual has greedily
absorbed that within.
But what you dream
of, or what you mean,
is that everyone is outside.
That no one follows
any rules or any laws anymore.
And that brings us back
to the Red Army Faction.
No, that's baloney.
Even if I were allowed to break laws I
don't know which laws I'd want to break,
let alone demolish.
I can think of one or two things
that one could demolish.
Yes, you as an individualist.
But, in all honesty,
we're all totally sedated
and stupefied
with little gifts and rewards.
And no one voluntarily demolishes
their little reward.
That's a primal instinct.
Sure, but I'm not even that far
along. It's not relevant to me.
Right now I don't have any
possessions that I could defend.
All right then, I'll explain
the entry area to you now.
As you can see it's a prestigious
space, gloriously awash in light.
You could call this room
the centerpiece of the apartment.
Look how the wonderful features of
this old structure are brought to bear.
- Cool, eh?
- That's right, I want to hear a "whoop!"
Yes, now I'll show
you the bathroom units.
You can have them converted and made into
a designer bath and sanitary facilities.
- Hello, Ms. Jaeggi.
- Hello, Nola.
How do you define
the term "forms of life"?
I'll tell you the formula
and then explain it.
They are something akin to inert bundles
or ensembles of social practices.
That alludes to some things that
are key to the term "forms of life."
One is that they
are social practices,
things that people do and that they
do with certain behavioral patterns
that are social in that they are
socially shaped and defined.
When discussing forms of life people
argue about what practices to include.
Is a family still a family if the members
no longer talk or eat dinner together?
- Lots of fighting.
- Interesting.
Is it a city
if it no longer has public places
where people can meet up without
making a date and without paying?
You could say that
contradicts the idea of a city,
or of how we construe the city as a
form of life if such spots are gone.
In the film we dream ourselves
away into other scenarios.
So we're actually a little bit
weary of our existing form of life,
or of existence in general.
So we dream about how it would be
if we had a bourgeois family
or if we had jobs that didn't
allow us so much time to think,
jobs that are a lot
more structured.
But in the end we realize
no matter where we dream ourselves away
to we always revert back to ourselves.
What do you think about that?
I mean, would that change me?
Or, what does a form of life
do with me, as an individual?
The idea that I as an individual am
here and the form or life is here,
like it's some kind of armor
that you slip into,
or as if your form or life were some
kind of a cabin that you walk into
but can also walk back out of
and be yourself.
Yes, that is not
the notion that I...
That isn't the notion
that guides me or that...
I don't assume that,
I basically assume that you...
I assume that getting out of that
socially determined behavioral...
What I mean is that you
can't escape interpretations
of how you see your
life and what you are.
That is, you can't
just step out of them.
When you step out of them you're
still referring back to them.
- A good way to explain that may be...
- There is no neutral space?
- Exactly.
- I'm always in a form of life.
I can't step out into a vacuum
with no form of life
and step into a new one.
But you can still consciously
plan collective forms of life.
Artists living together precariously is
a conscious attempt at a form of life.
One could call
that a form of life
that takes the fluid
or the transitional...
It institutionalizes
the transitional phase.
We were talking about our lack of
bonds, which we actually quite like.
I wanted jump to the way the New Right
interprets what it means to have no bonds.
It sees reviving ties to family and
homeland as the way to save humanity.
So they basically see a lack of
bonds as the plague of humanity.
How do you see that?
Something like that quite crude
notion of homeland and family,
the idea of something you're born
into that is steadfast and undying,
is something that is meant to give us the
guidance we are all allegedly missing.
I think that is a very, very
disastrous interpretation
and a very disastrous diagnosis
that seems to cover a lot of things.
It's why the New Right
call themselves "identitarians."
I think it's important to realize
that a lack of relationships, an
indifference towards the world,
oneself and others
is a real problem.
But that cannot be correlated
to pre-existing,
given and developed
identities and ideas of homeland.
My assumption is
actually the opposite.
I believe that overemphasis, or
that emphasis on what is given,
the emphasis on homeland and
traditional family structures,
is something that
has to do with the fact
that people feel powerless in
the circumstances they live in.
- That they can't shape them...
- Out of fear?
Yes, it's a...
- A realization of impracticability.
- Yes.
That's just how we grew up.
Politics are for politicians
and we, we do something else.
It's established,
like the division of labor.
If we're political at all
then we're the opposition.
That's not really true anymore.
We were the opposition.
Now Pegida, the AfD, right-wingers
and identitarians are the opposition.
So now we're
the opposition to the opposition.
Or we...
Or we work hand-in-hand
with politicians.
With the government.
A cabinet of horrors.
But we want to be the opposition,
that's our role.
Oh, guys, opposition aside.
Don't we want to do something?
Make political films
or films in general?
I've seen quite a few political films
that were just political thrillers.
They were about big names
and big-time topics.
I'm definitely going to revolt.
The only question is when?
Whether I'll do it before or
after the Nazis have seized power.
Somehow we have to create
entirely new structures.
To reinvent politics.
Like reinventing the wheel.
We have to start there,
by creating a new -ismus.
- One that doesn't exist yet.
- Yeah, and what should it be?
Empathism, perhaps.
What's that supposed
to be? Rousseau?
Should we start over
from the beginning?
Empathy as a value
anchored in the legal framework.
Not before I've pushed through the right
to earn money with your eyes closed.
Am I the only pragmatic person
in this room or what?
It's not like the refrigerator
fills up overnight on its own.
Well, in a certain
sense it does do that.
Really? How does a
refrigerator fill itself?
Well, Katja managed to crack the lock
to an empty apartment in this building
and to use it as a
nice Airbnb lodging.
- In order to feed the family.
- Let's move beyond the food issue.
We really should
open up our eyes.
Do we really want to see this?
It is high treason
against the German people.
We categorically say no
to expanding immigration
to allow third-country nationals.
It would overstrain our
country's integration capacity.
Lying press!
What does the German oak care
if a warthog rubs against it?
So you'll eventually only get
stale bread and water.
Because that's
what is just for you.
Deport!
Deport! Deport!
- I'm going to make an announcement.
- Yeah?
Listen here, everyone.
Zip them!
As you know this is
our last Wednesday dinner.
We're going to be thrown out
in three days.
Today we sit together, then we
party and then it's over and done.
So I propose that we all
raise our glasses again.
- To a new start.
- Did someone ring?
What's that?
- What is that?
- An ulcer remedy.
Do you have an ulcer
or do you mean us?
Oh, come on.
- Hassan.
- That's a bit mean.
- What's he doing over there?
- Dishes.
- Boy, you guys suck.
- Hey, have a burger to add to your halo.
He's an actor, like we are.
But he fell out with all the
directors and his agency dumped him.
Yeah, and so we
help him with his rent.
He wants to work for it,
so he does dishes.
I saw you on TV
playing a Lebanese drug boss.
Na, dude, don't start.
I'm done with those roles.
Screw stereotypes!
I want to play normal people.
We work, we've been living
here for years. What the hell!
Then play yourself, write your
dialogs. I have a low-budget project.
- What do you say?
- With deferred payment?
- No, I said low-budget, not no-budget.
- Oh, okay.
Dog, don't get me wrong. I have
to do my job. I get a set rate.
- I got you.
- My hourly wage drops the longer we talk.
- Okay.
- That's straight talk.
The art crisis.
The real question is: Does
art always have to be unpaid?
It's more that we differentiate.
We say "no-budget" is art.
If something's
paid it's commercial.
- It's either-or, that causes poverty.
- I make art and my punishment is no money.
For me making loads of dough
doing it would be a disaster.
I don't think he wants that
either, that's why he's here.
So you don't want to be whores,
but what if you love your clients?
If you made really awesome money
doing things that you love?
Paradise.
Yeah, but the market is made up of
people and people desire things.
Do you think people really desire
what they see? Or that it...
- I'd say audiences, the masses...
- Bye.
Bye.
They watch what's shown to them.
The problem we're facing right now is
that critical art is what's in demand.
I don't need money, just burgers.
22/6, first take.
Clapper.
Go ahead.
- Hello, Mr. Hegemann.
- Hello.
Nice to see you.
We are now here...
What if a movie didn't create an
illusion? Would that not be cinema?
When making art in general
and when making political art
you have no choice but to
peek at what's behind the façade.
And no matter how bad it is you
have to concern yourself with it.
That would be a
kind of enlightenment.
But you have to be fully aware
that the audience
always feels it has
been duped then,
because audiences go to
the cinema for that illusion.
But a film that employs
those mechanisms of illusion
to present a successful revolution
or a strong socially critical plot
without breaking the illusion is
perhaps not all that political.
- According to Brecht...
- Then it's more manipulative?
Yes.
It's probably without effect.
You watch it, are moved and maybe
you shed a tear and that's that.
Brecht said people
are lulled into the illusion
and no longer construe
the world as alterable.
You can only construe it is as alterable
when you free yourself from the illusion.
That doesn't exist anywhere else,
it only exists on this stage.
That a grown person can claim they
are the King of Denmark or similar.
And that is interesting,
because if you were to do that in
real life, if you were to dress up...
That great suit you're wearing
is borderline.
- It's almost a costume.
- Yeah.
- If you walk around in that...
- I get stared at walking around the city.
As Hamlet I'd probably be...
If I said I was Hamlet
I'd be put in a psychiatric ward.
Or if you were to put on a tie
and stick a moustache on
and claim to be a man.
Wearing a glued on moustache in
the theater is no problem at all.
People believe it, people accept
that kind of mixing of identities.
But mixing up life with a theater
stage, that can be really dangerous.
It is simply extremely liberating
when you can say what you think.
A colleague
who is your age recently told me
she didn't know anyone
among her acquaintances
who still says what they think.
People can't afford
to do that anymore.
But what kind of a society,
what kind of life is it
when you only ever say what's
suitable in a given moment
and the other
person does that too?
Then you live in a
totally illusory world,
then the theater of social roles
is truly detached from the people.
- And that's why it's so liberating and...
- Then we're all zombies.
We can say that this stage is
exemplary because people here,
where others stay objective and cool
when they try to lodge a tiny objection,
people here yell, that's
why there's so much yelling.
That's because here people can use their
voice to express authentic thoughts.
And that truth and seriousness, you
really can't act as if it were so.
It seems you can only do that onstage,
where it's not forbidden to yell.
In my script it says
we ride Bobby Cars now.
If it say so, we have to do it.
I doubt it's conducive
to self-optimization.
- This is chic too.
- I think it makes you look old somehow.
- The fur, not you.
- Um-hm.
Yeah. Or maybe
a two-piece outfit...
"This rapidly changing city
"that made its flaw of a lack of
tradition into a sign of modernity."
That sounds like it
could be from now.
But it was written
by Robert Walser in 1908.
"Makeshift
existence suits Berlin,
"where people are eager for anything
new, quickly pass over yesterday
"and nothing stays as it was."
That's still true today too.
"To Robert Walser Berlin is a body,
a dream populated by Berlin's women.
"He wants them all, the
naive, voluptuous violent lady
"and the good little girl
from Kurfürstendamm."
- Button it up, right?
- Yeah.
"Berlin is a giant lady.
"Contemporaries continually stress
the analogy of Berlin and its women
"Robert Musil, Carl Zuckmayer...
"These quotes have
"a striking mix of incredulous
adulation, erotic attraction
"and restrained aggression that they
use to describe the city and its women."
This is still the 1920s.
"The spry and firm big-city girls
"with their insatiable
open mouths grow annoyed
"when my eyes settle too long
on their gliding shoulders
"and floating cheeks."
A certain Franz Hessel.
More "Berlin as woman."
"The 'rubble woman.'
"Youthful beauty contrasts
with the rubble she sorts.
"In the mid-1980s Helmut Newton shot
his 'boardinghouse photos' in Berlin."
That sounds good.
"Fräulein Petra."
"Ten years later, Jürgen Teller.
"Cloudy puddles, rusty iron doors,
barred windows, dismal trees,
"garbage, construction cranes.
"Teller's Berlin photos
look like a hastily opened gift
"whose contents disappointed
and were cast aside.
"He photographs flawed female
bodies that don't fit any ideal:
"thighs adorned with red spots,
lips ripped open, elbows too raw."
Heroin chic?
Me again.
"He reacts to the dematerialization
of existence with vulnerable bodies
"that tell stories.
"In Berlin he seeks phenomena that
open themselves up to narratives.
"The girl in the sweater
with Hölderlin in her pocket,
"as Harold Nicholsen
described in 1929,
"had become a junkie after 1961."
I'm the girl in the sweater. I
have Hölderlin in my pocket too.
The City and Its Bodies.
The City of Women.
No, that was another film.
And behind that façade
lurks an immense void.
- Hello, Ms. Allmendinger.
- Hello, Nola.
I interviewed students for my
film and what stood out to me
was most of them answered the questions
in relation to their own futures
but never in the context
of society as a whole.
And I was wondering if it was
due to my questioning technique
that it always went in
that individualistic direction.
People naturally start
talking about themselves.
We know that, and so we
have to resort to measures
to make them move on to talking
about society of their own accord,
or to get them to extrapolate from
themselves to their social circle
or to what they think
about society and the world.
So you can of course do that by
sitting in a bar for a long time
drinking beer with them
and you'll get that in what
we call a "narrative interview."
But you don't get anything
representative with that.
We start with just what
you were criticizing.
We want people
focused on themselves,
so they notice how they feel.
And that they begin
with themselves alone.
And we do that
by trying to shut down cognition.
They shouldn't think.
And then we give them these
surfaces. This is a kind of mat.
This is rough, this is glass,
this is corrugated cardboard.
- And we say...
- And it works. You immediately...
- You feel...
- We ask, "How does your life feel today?
- "Just tell me how life feels today."
- Yeah.
What the media tells them, what they
read in books is immediately gone.
Think about how your life feels.
You can do it differently.
I can have you smell this.
How does your
life smell? Like this?
Or does life smell like this?
And voilà! You forget what
people have been telling you.
We don't want that.
We can read that in the paper.
We're interested in your opinion.
When we have them at a point
where they've attained inner peace
and have forgotten all else,
then we get started.
Then we ask, "How important is
a feeling of togetherness to you?
"How important is that to you?"
And then you can answer that
question on that very pure level.
Those are preliminary questions,
then we move on to the real ones.
What do you desire
for the coming generation?
What do you wish to pass on to
your kids? What'd be your legacy?
We've already moved a step from a
focus on "me" to a focus on society.
And then if we then
take a third step and ask,
"And what do you think?
How will society actually be?"
Those steps get us
something utterly different
than going right to
that third level does.
You're absolutely right, then people
stay in their own little lives.
If you were given carte blanche what
would you change in our society?
What we see is that income is important
and, of course, so is education.
There's no doubt about that.
But when we consider
which people have visions,
which people see life as an opportunity
to shape the things around them
and see life as worth shaping.
Increasingly those are people
with true circles of friends.
And not lots of friends
who are all from the same place,
as was once perhaps
the case for me,
but friends from different countries
and from a diverse array of backgrounds.
People of varying ages
and sexual orientations.
And that can be facilitated.
That's something I think
society does less and less.
We've noticed that those various groups
are increasingly staying among themselves.
And so what I would recommend
is a mandatory social year.
That there's a kind of
mandatory exchange
with people in other countries.
We have to introduce people,
young people, to that
so that we don't stay in one little
spot in Germany our entire lives.
So we want to open up and have
to open up to the wider world.
You can't force that on people,
they have to want it.
And the will to do that comes with
one-to-one contact, with experience.
People with a broader focus?
Pessimistic people say, "The
feeling of togetherness is lovely,
"but it's going down the drain."
Those are people who haven't
experienced a feeling of otherness.
- Yes.
- Yet you can create that.
You can do that politically,
socially with incentives
and by supporting that.
To create the possibility of having
those diverse social contacts.
Not by doing the opposite
with urban planning,
that is, keeping people among
their own, in their own schools.
Or, on the other hand, by having
schools that are so diverse
that there's no longer
a common thread.
Thank you so much.
We're waiting for one
little screw then it's done.
It looks pretty good already.
Nola.
- How's your film coming along?
- Nearly done.
- I just need a really good final scene.
- Do you already have a resolution?
I'm not deluding myself.
My film won't change the world
or kick-start a revolt.
It's more of a stocktaking.
I asked questions and everyone
has to find their own answers.
I'm going.
A package for Pit.
So? Sexy lamp?
"You can't do a thing
there anymore," so they said
It's like a museum,
all it does is look good
And that's why we're moving on
To shut down the next city
Ownership
Our ownership
Own
Own and everything
Ownership
Our own and everything
- Hello, Mr. Groys.
- Hello.
- Nice to see you.
- I'm glad you're here.
We've chosen
this very futuristic location.
Do you feel
like you're in the future here?
Yes, perhaps, inasmuch
as this place reminds me of
how I imagined the future
when I was a child.
When I read books and saw movies
this is more or less
how I imagined it.
It seems to me that for a period,
in the 19th century,
at the start of the 20th century
and into the 1960s and 1970s,
people still thought
a lot about the future.
And people had the feeling
that they could shape the future.
That you could push a project through,
develop a vision, so to speak,
and then realize it.
There was this idea
of a sort of human omnipotence.
But now, more and more,
the future is becoming
an event to us.
An event
that's new to us.
We're not really prepared.
It often comes as
something unexpected.
And we have the feeling
that we should constantly adapt.
I believe that our
strategic behavior
has increasingly become a strategy
of adapting to the future.
I sometimes call
that "self-updating."
In one of your texts
you talk about film and say
film contains a paradox between
vita contemplativa and vita activa.
That screen heroes
are hyperactive.
They shoot, they jump,
they have to achieve heroic aims,
and the viewer
automatically becomes passive
because he or she sits statically
in a chair in a theater seat.
How can you become capable of
acting in the face of that paradox?
Or how can you induce
the viewer to become active?
By getting the viewer
to internally identify with
the movie's heroic character.
What you described
as internal movement of thought?
- Not movement of thought.
- No?
No.
Neither the hero can think...
- The hero can't think?
- He can't think.
The hero has to act heroically.
And when you act heroically
you don't think.
And the viewer
isn't supposed to think either.
The thinking viewer
was a big mistake of Brecht's.
The viewer should identify...
The viewer should
identify with the movie.
identify with the hero.
And if that hero
is a revolutionary
the viewer will try to adopt the
same position, the same attitude.
But via identification,
Brecht was anti-identification.
Yes, but I'd say
via identification.
Ultimately...
you have to...
You become revolutionary
when you feel like you're
in a movie in real life.
- Yeah?
- That's the premise. You have to...
- Like you're in a movie in real life?
- Yes.
Or like you're in a novel.
The true revolutionary is
romantic. What does that mean?
It means life is
like a novel to him.
If, just for a moment,
he crashed back down
into reality, so to speak,
then the revolution
and the romanticism is over.
That means that only
as long as I live in that...
Only as long as I live in
that totally artificial reality,
which is more real
to me than any reality,
am I capable of
inciting a revolution.
The moment that reality becomes
a kind of quotidian misery...
When I perceive reality
as quotidian misery
- When I surrender to that misery.
- Yeah, then I just want to go to sleep.
That is, and everyone said this,
Mayakovsky and others said it.
The daily grind destroys revolution,
the misery of the everyday.
- But still...
- The boredom.
The boredom of life.
Life is fundamentally boring.
Fundamentally.
And you can't have any kind
of revolution against boredom.
Disgust and luxury.
Luxury and disgust,
shell and content.
You throw concepts into the ring
that go beyond the world of shopping
and refer to capitalist society.
It's the bland, dull husk
that luxury leaves behind
when the expensive
veneer is peeled away.
It's immanent, and
thus wickedly genuine.
The luxury item in the glossy bag
turns into a monster.
Money is of no use.
An illness that can't be cured with
all the plastic surgery in the world.
Yes.
Ms. Schöne-Radunski.
Marvelous name, by the way.
Yes, you have huge potential.
Debunking the hype machine behind
the linking of fashion and art
in a clever and
rebellious manner.
You really make
me feel pissed off,
and like I genuinely don't want
to play along with this.
Which is all the more attractive.
What I can't have is all the sexier.
That type of thing
can escalate into an obsession.
You know what I think of all the
pseudo-rebellious young women
who walk in like sluts
and do totally conformist art.
That's where things
come full circle.
Those drug-addict role models have to
be the faces of those luxury brands.
I could really imagine something
with you, marketing you.
We'll stage your art in public,
crash cultural events, disrupt,
we'll be all over the media.
No, you know what?
Screw that.
Right.
We'll shoot this
without cuts, okay?
Right.
Just read them aloud
one after the other.
What is this? Improvisation?
Please start.
I'll start.
I won't say anything about this
cart as a container for goods.
That would be too obvious.
It's about the value of things.
I just bought this
thing for a euro.
Are you stupid? I
had a plastic token.
Think about what it cost. It must've
cost 200 or 300 euros to make.
And who pays for that?
The supermarket?
Initially, yes, but the supermarket
has you, the shopper, pay for it.
Yeah, exactly.
It's like a truck toll.
Huh.
- Huh?
- Or like paying taxes.
Yes, it's paid for by
the general public.
Uh-huh, but who does it
belong to? The supermarket?
Me, because I put a euro in it.
No, you're the holder
but not the proprietor.
Come on, let's not get
into terminologies again.
Yeah, the thing about taxes
is much more interesting.
Huh? Why are taxes interesting?
He means the general public, the
general public needs such things.
The question remains whether this
thing is ours because we paid for it.
If it is ours then we want to
have a say in what happens to it.
Yes, that's right.
Exactly, we'd better go get the drinks
with it or we won't get anywhere.
End of scene.
That's written here.
Welcome!
When do you have to go?
Where will you go?
I think they're putting
a fitness studio in here.
There can never be enough love.
We need loads
of love in politics.
I was thinking about all the empty vaults
in cemeteries that no one looks after.
You could make
hostels out of them.
That's funny,
I was thinking that yesterday.
Really?
I'd like to live in
a public space.
- A public space?
- Yeah, the circle line.
A theoretician called that
"depopulation." I think it's a good term.
The zombie city!
If you have love inside you
because you know how it feels
theoretically you can...
But we can't afford
romanticism anymore.
I think we need empathetic
politics, that'd be key.
I recently saw a couple
having sex on a public subway.
That's private. Sex in
the subway is privatization.
But isn't that just the problem?
Like the Internet, where
everyone writes their beliefs
and makes a public space private.
It's not a belief
it's sexual relief.
Can't anyone write
that kind of love poem now?
Lots of people think
people don't work anymore
but I think that people would...
Where's the incentive?
We're flying!
We're flying right out of here!
Bye!