Time don't march, or walk.
Or even move in a straight line.
It skips around like a pinball.
Last year...
ten years ago...
yesterday.
It's all now.
Listen, that all was ten years ago.
I don't know what I can tell you now.
Just anything at all
would be real helpful.
Well that sort of thing
never happened around here.
Uriah and the misses...
them bodies.
Hell, it was a god damn mess.
I didn't know the, the wife too well.
I knew Uriah though, he was
a decent man far as I knew.
What did he do it for
if he was so decent?
I heard he had a sister?
Next county over...
still there as far as I know.
What about the farmhands?
Migrants mostly.
They move on after the harvest is done...
except for one, and he lives downtown.
How do I find him?
Well, I could get you an address...
but I think you might be
wasting your time.
The man's become some kind of recluse...
from what I hear,
completely shut himself up.
People bring him things to fix.
Things to fix?
Hello, misses Taylor...
my name is Ruth young.
I'd really like to talk to you
about your brother...
if you don't mind.
I'm sorry, it's a little hard
to explain over the phone.
Can you call me, please?
I'm looking for a Miller, Lee.
Am I at the right address?
What do you want?
Well I was wondering
if I could talk to you.
Well, ain't you?
Well, it's a little involved.
There somewhere we could sit down?
I, I tried calling,
you got no phone apparently.
I, I think you mighta know someone.
Her name was Gale.
You work on the Taylor
farm some years back?
I talked to the sheriff this morning.
Then you heard all there is to know.
All right, but I thought
since you work there, and all...
It was... some time ago.
Yes, sir.
See, I just wanted to...
Wanted to know what she was like.
No, I can't help you.
Well, I could... I could leave you
my number in case...
All right.
Quiet.
Mister Taylor?
What do you want?
I heard you're hiring for the season.
You know, a month or two is fine
for me if you got something.
You ever worked tobacco before?
No sir, but I got no
problem with hard work.
Besides that, I can fix most any
mechanical thing you got around here.
That so?
Think you can get that thing running?
I can take a look at it.
Why don't you, and come on back here...
tell me what's wrong with it.
Yes, sir.
Hey, put it in your pocket.
Take the damn thing off
and put it in your pocket.
I told you guys, nothing
that can catch in the machine.
Go home.
Needs a new starter.
You'll need 'em for
the oil on the leaves.
You can return 'em when you get your own.
Be here at five tomorrow morning...
fix the tractor, put
you out in the fields.
Pay's at the end of the week.
At least I'll get a few days outta you...
before you run off and drink it all.
I ain't like that.
I said I ain't like that, sir.
You drop that sir
bullshit, you know my name.
Mine's, Miller.
I guess you know what I'm here for.
Owner' got himself pretty worked up
at this point.
Says I bring it to him today,
or he'll come get it himself.
Well hell...
let me see it at least,
I got to tell him something.
Well...
it's coming along.
Fine work, like always.
Well, god damn it, how
long do I tell him?
A week.
I think week.
- You're killing me here.
You do the work, you keep on living here.
You don't, you can get the hell out.
I ain't running a charity.
I paid 100 for materials.
Can you cover me?
- Christ all mighty!
I come for the furniture
I leave empty handed...
and $100 lighter?
Ain't that just wonderful?
You keep the place this neat...
gotta have a girl around somewhere.
I just like things a certain way, is all.
Well, Becky says
you being all by yourself...
is the worst thing that
can happen for a man.
I'm all right.
Says in prison they put a man
in solitary just to torture him.
I mean, go figure that.
A man would rather spend his days...
with killers and psychopaths
than be by himself.
I guess that explains marriage too,
don't it?
You got that cash on ya?
All right, yeah.
Hundred...
I shouldn't be giving you this.
Well, you're in luck.
There it is, $100, don't say
I never did nothing for ya.
This thing...
there's no reason that...
You've got to pull through for me,
you understand?
I'm a man of my word,
I've given this guy my word.
He's given us a lot of
business, you know he has.
I've already gone back
to him to him twice.
I'm going back one more time and see
if I can buy you two or
three days, but that's it.
After that, you have got to...
Dance with me.
Don't you know how to dance?
I was in the neighborhood.
There ain't but one neighborhood
in this town.
Right.
Sir, I'm just asking you...
Look I told you...
because I seen it, on your face.
When I said her name you knew her.
I know what that man did to here.
I just, I wanna know why.
You worked on that farm,
you gotta have some idea.
What's it matter to you?
I'm her daughter.
An interesting place.
What was it, a factory?
Abattoir.
A slaughter house...
- I know what an abattoir is.
No, don't touch it.
Is it valuable?
How'd you come by it?
A rich family bought a
plantation outside of town.
I'm restoring every piece of it.
I heard you don't get out much.
How come you don't talk to no one?
What for?
It's just one.
Ain't he lonely?
No, he's all right.
They say fish got no memory, anyhow.
Now how'd anyone know if that's true?
What you staring for?
I seen that smile before.
My grandma died a month back.
She raised me like I was her daughter.
I thought I was... 'til now.
I found these letters.
It's my real mama trying to explain to me
why she ran off...
after I was born.
I ain't looking to stir nothing' up.
I just wanna know, is all.
Where you come from?
Out near Asheville.
Gale never said nothing about us?
She sent this, in one of her letters.
She's real beautiful.
Can you just tell me something about her?
Just any old thing?
We harvest from the bottom up.
We passed through this field twice,
all ready.
Every pass we pick from the lowest level.
It's been empty since I bought it.
Thought I'd convert it into apartments...
but the historical commission got word.
Told me I wasn't changing a damn thing.
Place sits abandoned for 40 years and...
suddenly it's a land mark.
The water work?
Yup, just gotta turn it on for ya?
How long ya thinking?
Well...
a few months, I guess.
Where's that go?
Downstairs.
Back in the day,
they brought the cows down there.
Kept them all in the big room
just below us...
killed them in another room
on the other side.
Look, like I said...
I can't do nothing to spruce the place up.
So you want it, or don't ya?
Uriah, hey, how you been?
I'm doing fine.
Mighty nice to see you.
Oh yeah, I haven't seen you all year.
Did you crop that late?
Well, what's been happening?
- Quality crop, it's B1.
No way, I can't go B1, this is not B1.
You know that, look at it,
it's too much green,
too much brown, it's not clean enough.
That's B1 if it's anything.
It's B2.
- Look, that's all I got.
B2's the best I can do, I'm sorry.
Well, how much?
213 a pound, that's pretty good.
You're stealing my tobacco,
you know that?
It's as good a quality
as any you got here.
Right, look, take it or leave it.
That's all I've got.
Hey, come here.
What?
Don't touch me.
Give it to me. Give it to me.
What the hell you keep this for?
- Give it to me, Uriah.
I know about that ring.
It was her daddy's wedding band.
He died when she was ten.
She said in her letters that was all
that she had left of him.
I was hoping better things
mighta come her way.
Mama, well her mama,
she got married again...
a couple years after, and there I came.
I guess Gale and my daddy
never got along too well.
Can you tell me more about her?
Ma'am, I'm sorry to trouble you.
Who are you?
Name's Miller.
I'm working for your...
Well, he gave me these
until I could get my own.
So... I'm returning them.
I'll be sure he gets 'em.
I'd appreciate that.
Well?
I...
I know it ain't my business, but
I saw what happened this morning.
Well, I was just wondering
if you were okay.
You were right the first time.
It ain't your business.
I saw you at my house.
My wife...
ain't none of your concern.
That clear?
I'm sorry about your loss.
It's late.
All right.
Well, I'll be going then.
Hey, maybe I come by again,
if that's all right.
There ain't no reason to.
I done what I can for you.
You know anything
about working on a farm?
Don't look like it!
You cost me 100 a day!
Jesus Christ.
Get the hell off my farm!
All you fuckers!
I said get!
Hey! God damn it, wait a minute!
- I've had my fill of this!
To hell with you!
All right, maybe I lost
my composure a little bit.
You done good...
I'm grateful to ya.
Come on, now. It's late.
How 'bout you come on,
have supper with us.
I reckon I owe you that.
Don't you want more?
- No.
Thank you, ma'am.
So, where you going after season's out?
South.
Like what, Florida?
No, way down, Brazil, Argentina.
What for?
No reason, I just want to.
I seen a lot pass through here, drifting.
Don't own nothing but their clothes...
and most of 'em
are running from something.
You ever done time?
Well, shit... I have.
Banker man, right here on my property...
telling me he's gonna take this farm.
He's talking and talking, I just watched...
his jaw move until I
couldn't stand it no more.
I cracked his skull...
busted his eye socket in.
Looked more like a cut of meat
than a man.
And Gale here, she's screaming at me...
even turned the hose on me
like I was some kind of rabbit dog.
Didn't ya darling?
God's sake, Uriah, you
gotta tell that story?
I did three years for that.
I got no regrets.
A man can't defend his home...
he ain't worth shit.
Who's that?
That looks like Jimmy.
Jimmy, come on in.
- Hey, Uriah.
Hope I didn't interrupt nothing.
You're okay.
What's up?
- Well, I'm on that construction job...
they're doing up on route 70.
Could use a man to run the paver.
Yeah, starting when?
Well, tomorrow.
You serious?
I can ask Frank if you can't.
I just thought I'd come to you first.
Don't bother about it.
You want another beer, or something?
No, I'm fine.
The place is real nice.
You think so?
How long you two been married?
Now, why you wanna know that?
Well?
They need someone
for that highway project...
union wage.
How long?
A few days.
Got another job, or something?
You think anyone's making
a living from farming?
Listen, I got to have that
crop done before the frost.
Looks like I'm a bit short handed
at the moment still...
I appreciate you sticking around a bit longer.
I guess I could.
I need you to go into town tomorrow,
round up some help for the field.
Think you can do that?
All right.
Miller? I know you're there.
I ain't going nowhere.
Are you deaf?
I brought you coffee.
I thought you might like some.
I'll just stay a little while.
Look, I don't wanna do this.
- Do what?
We're just talking.
What if I help you, then?
Like how?
Well, there's gotta be something.
I got two hands, don't I?
Hold it steady, now.
Come on, you doing this, or not?
- I'm doing it.
Some things don't change.
How's that?
When I was just a girl,
my daddy never let me do anything.
I was always just holding stuff...
a flashlight, a screwdriver,
hold this, hold that.
Well, that's called apprenticeship.
It's called boring.
When'd you see him last?
A while, I guess.
How come?
Something happen to him?
I don't mean to be...
I just don't know
if that's any of your concern, is all.
Ain't none of is my concern.
You're the one that come here
asking questions.
Hell, my old man...
he beat on me, I mean good.
I grew up trying to be invisible,
hiding, you know.
I was five years old...
he knocked me out cold.
Hey, hand me that knife, would ya?
That looks pretty painful.
How it is, you know.
Old man up and died some years back.
Funny thing though...
I'm sorry about it.
Now I just wanna see him.
What for?
I'd just like to know him, is all.
More of a man than what he done
when he was too young to know better.
Say he don't act the same,
or think the same.
Watch your fingers!
After a few years,
not a single piece of you...
is what it was, you know that?
Well, it's a fact.
Every cell in your body,
every hair on your head, it's all dying...
and replaced by something new.
You shed your skin...
a hundred times.
What you done...
well... you can't shed that.
I started having dreams.
Dreams?
Things I'm seeing when I'm just a baby.
Saw same face in the picture,
but she's just a girl.
She's staring at me...
like she needs to tell me something.
Her mouth opens but she don't have
a voice to speak.
In my dream I'm...
I'm wondering...
what's she done to make my daddy
punish her like that.
She was just fourteen when she had me.
Hey Miller?
Why did he do it?
Miller!
They'll be hanging around
Montgomery street, get three.
Yeah, all right.
I'm back on Friday.
All the north fields done by then, right?
All righty then.
Same time tomorrow.
- Yep.
Y'all good with that?
Yep.
I'm gonna drop the keys off.
- Okay.
Have a good night.
We're done for the day.
Something else you need?
I saw you looking for it.
A little big for you, ain't it?
Well, it...
All this about you going south.
How come?
You running?
That Uriah's take on it?
He thinks you're kinda strange.
- Well...
that's mutual.
So?
I'm just curious to see
something in this world.
Ain't you?
I'm all right where I am.
Just 'cause somewhere's different
don't make it better.
Well...
you might look around a bit first,
before you decide.
I heard the state fair is in town.
What about it?
- Nothing.
Just I ain't never seen one before.
It's funny working alongside of you.
It's like you don't even know
the time's passing.
What goes through your mind,
all these days you're alone?
I can see her sometimes...
when I look at you.
It's nice if that were true.
I know it ain't.
She's much prettier than I'll ever be.
For you.
You giving this to me?
If, if you want it.
Thank you.
You know, you think you know yourself...
who you are, where you came from.
I ain't got a clue no more.
Can you understand that?
I guess it's late.
Suppose I should go.
All right.
I was thinking about what you said.
You...
you think people can change?
I think if you do good,
you can be good...
no matter what you done before.
Good night, Miller.
Well... like I told you,
ain't much to see.
Looks like time stood still.
They kept cows here?
So I'm told.
Pretty sparse.
Well... they're just here to die.
They don't need much else.
They killed 'em in there.
Hung 'em up to bleed out...
and then they'd freeze 'em,
store 'em in here.
Do you think they knew
they were gonna get killed?
Well now, there's a question.
Jesus, look at that old relic.
Does it work?
I ain't tried it.
Moment of truth.
Don't you know how to dance?
Well, all right, I'll show you.
Hang on, I'll make it easy for you.
Jesus...
What time is it?
About five.
He'll be back soon.
Don't play with me now, I gotta go.
- Don't go.
I'm serious.
- So am I.
You're crazy.
Come on Miller, let go.
- You could come with me.
What?
- I said you could come with me.
I take you so far from here...
you wouldn't ever have to come back.
You don't know much, do you?
Ain't no simple thing,
a wife leaving her husband.
Come on now, let me go.
Take from someone what's his, well...
you best think twice about that.
Comes a time, though,
you can't see past what you want.
Desire...
Can't feel nothing else.
Like stepping into a river.
Water rushing.
Your feet leaving the earth.
I never made love to no one before.
Just had men take what they want.
Ain't the same thing.
When you go...
I'd go with you.
If you still want me to.
Do you, still?
Where you been?
I didn't know you were back.
I woulda made you something.
Come here.
Asked you a question.
Where you been?
Nowhere...
just walking.
Walking where?
I said walking where?
I told you, just walking.
You wouldn't make a
fool out of me, would ya?
You ever did...
I don't know what I'd do.
Uriah, please.
You're so pretty.
Take your dress off.
Take it off.
Do it!
Keep going.
Shoulda harvested like two weeks ago.
I want you to.
I'll get him.
I promise I will.
I dream I walk through this door...
and you're there.
Same as you were...
same as I was.
Time...
everything played out different.
Ma'am, my name is Ruth Young.
I left you a message already
about your brother, Uriah.
You please call me?
My number is 9...
Hey Ruth.
He speaks my name.
What's that?
They told me this was the good stuff.
What do you think?
- Well...
we'll find out.
I guess you think this is
some kind of tactic.
Get you drunk, get the truth outta you.
I hope you're a happy drunk.
I can't get drunk no more.
Drink don't make me feel nothing,
one way or the other.
I tried it often enough.
God help you.
Well hey, look at that.
This looks god damn amazing.
Yeah?
Are you kidding?
It's great.
Wow, beautiful.
Did you... go through the night
to get this done?
Something like that.
Look, I'm grateful to ya.
What for?
You bought me a little piece,
for one night at least.
Well...
now how about we celebrate.
Pour me another.
Don't go getting all stupid on me, now.
Oh, don't you worry about me.
I'm tougher than you think.
Are ya?
Hell yes, I am.
Hey, Miller.
I gotta ask you one more thing.
What's that?
You tell me about her last day?
Please?
Just everything you remember.
Well, what good's that gonna do?
- Oh, just tell me, please.
Just tell me, and I won't ever ask you
for nothing else.
You know, you're something.
Coming here asking all these questions...
like I oughta, bare my sole to you,
like I owe you something?
I never said that!
- But you ain't told me a whole lot.
How 'bout you talk some?
- About what?
I suppose you tell me why she'd
just up and leave her daughter behind.
She didn't seem the type to me.
- I don't know.
Oh, you don't know?
- How should I?
Well I wonder, there's something
in that strange family of yours,
you musta given it some thought.
I bet you got a pretty
good idea, actually.
You're a real bastard, you know that?
Am I?
Who are you to judge?
Mommy, mommy.
How come daddy
doesn't love me just like Gale?
What are you talking about, honey?
He loves you just the same.
How come daddy doesn't kiss me
just like Gale?
What'd you just say?
I didn't want to mama, he made me!
He made me!
- You're own father!
He ain't my father.
He's just some asshole
you let into our home.
You get the hell out!
If I go, I'm taking her with me.
Like hell you will!
You leave her be, Gale.
I mean it.
How's a little tramp like you...
with a baby.
You can go to hell, mama.
She'd a kept her secrets to stay with us...
but I brought it all to light.
I made her go.
There's something I want you to know.
I did my best to...
care for her.
I want you to know that.
Care for her?
Why would you?
I wanted...
I wanted more than anything
to be the man that was good to her.
I wanted to be the one
that treated her kind.
I did her no harm.
She was real to me.
She's all that ever was.
Is that why he killed my mama?
Is that why you never said nothing
about you and her?
God damn it, tell me!
What's it matter now?
- 'Cause it does, 'cause it's the truth.
Oh, like that's some precious thing.
What do you think?
That I'm some little girl,
you gotta shield my eyes?
You're the one
all caged up in here hiding.
You're the one scared!
You tell me why he did it.
Tell me! Was it 'cause of you?
Is that why she's dead?
- Watch your mouth.
That's why he killed her, ain't it?
Because you fucked her!
I'm sorry, Ruth.
I didn't mean that.
Jesus, we were so careful.
We were so god damn careful.
I told her, don't be scared.
I said I'd take care of her.
She said I'd be scared too if I knew him.
He'll come looking.
I know he will.
She said we oughta wait
'til he goes off again...
on another highway job.
But each day seemed like forever.
I was going crazy thinking of her
sleeping in the same bed as him.
But Uriah, well, he needed me then...
just to get through the season.
But his mind was gone in all directions,
and all of them crooked.
Suspicious of everything.
What do you do when you're
down there in town, at night?
There ain't too much going on.
You got yourself a girl there?
I'm just passing through.
That's right.
I forgot.
Time was getting short.
I knew that much.
Something was gonna happen.
God damn it.
Jesus.
Thing went out of it's god damn mind.
Came right at me.
I think it's back is broken.
God damn dogs, you trust 'em...
and they turn on ya.
Help me bury it?
Next day he got called away again
to work on the highway, just for a day.
And I told her that was as good
as it was gonna get for us.
So that was that.
We was gonna go.
Where you going?
Nowhere.
Nowhere?
I love you, girl.
Don't you know that?
Don't ya?
Yes.
What do you wanna leave me for?
I don't.
Hurts me when you lie like that.
You know how much?
- Uriah.
He beat her bad enough to kill a man.
Broke her neck before he shot himself.
I wondered ever since
how that must've been.
Her last breath.
That pain.
Police carried her body out
in a white sheet...
stained red.
Where the hell was I?
Where in the hell was I?
I can see her dying,
I can see her eyes staring at me...
and I ain't man enough to save her.
God damn it, where was I?
You'd have done something for her
if you could.
I know you would have.
Tomorrow...
you and me, we're gonna walk outta here.
We're gonna leave it all behind us.
It ain't as easy as all that.
Well it ain't impossible neither.
I'll help you.
I'm sorry.
Every damn day of my life I'm sorry.
I wanna come home.
- Ruth.
Hello?
Yes, thank you for calling.
Well I was hoping...
Well how far from the city are you?
Won't you sit down?
I'm awful sorry about her.
My brother loved her deeply.
I don't know what you came here for
exactly, but...
I found these for you.
I thought you'd like to have 'em.
I remember when she showed up.
Uriah took her in
like some kind of lost kitten.
She looked like one too.
Skinny, broke...
run away from somewhere.
He told me once...
that he knew she was too pretty to keep.
Well, he went and married her
all the same.
Too pretty.
Young and wild is what she was.
I apologize for saying that.
I don't mean anything against her.
For two days I got no answer
on Uriah's phone.
I told the neighbors to go by
and check the house.
They called me a few hours later,
told me what they found.
I drove right over.
Police didn't want me in.
Said it'd be more than I can take...
to see it.
Uriah was just a farm boy.
Maybe he wasn't a genius,
but I never knew him to be cruel.
Never once.
Not to dogs neither.
What?
People change, ma'am.
You think so?
To do what he did?
What do you think he did?
I know what he did.
None of you knew my brother.
If you knew him at all...
you would know he wasn't capable.
Well if that's true,
then what did he do time for?
Time, Uriah never did time.
Maybe you didn't know your brother
as much as you thought.
You think I don't know my own brother.
I love you Miller.
Miller.
What are you doing here?
I thought...
I got everything packed up,
I was coming for ya.
I can't no more.
What do you mean?
I love you, Miller...
I truly do.
I ain't going with you...
I can't.
Miller?
He do something to you?
Well then...
then what?
I'm expecting.
Do you hear what I said?
Well...
Well so you are, that don't change
nothing between you and me.
It changes everything.
But, baby, I'm not the kind of man...
who's just gonna run away on you.
You know that, don't you?
No, you got good intentions.
But...
it ain't yours.
Well, wait a minute, you don't know that.
No, this don't make no sense, you can't.
Is it 'cause you're still fucking him?
Are you still fucking him?
- He's my husband.
There's no way you love that man.
Look, we'll go...
and we'll find some place to settle.
- Like where?
Like somewhere, I don't know,
we'll figure it out.
I'll take care of you, I swear I will.
You're a good man...
you are.
One thing I know...
a man won't ever
love another man's child.
Gale, you...
You hush your head.
You know me, you know
I ain't the kind of man...
It's decided, Miller.
Who says it is?
Stop, please!
Wait, you can't go.
Gale, wait...
God damn it, I said wait!
You down here?
Miller?
You came back.
You scared me.
You been gone so long.
I... I left you a note.
I been to see Uriah's sister.
How come you went there?
She called me.
Well what did she want?
Nothing.
Nothing?
She... I mean,
she's all confused.
She said they found
my mama's body some days after.
That ain't right though, 'cause...
you'd known right away
something happened to her.
You wouldn't have left her there
like that.
You wouldn't have.
I got something for ya.
That's hers.
It's for you.
I found it for you.
How'd you get it?
Take it.
Uriah's sister?
She said he couldn't have done them things.
I was thinking about what you said,
about the dog.
Miller you...
you got them scars.
No, he did it.
God damn it, he did all of it.
She loved me, she came
here to tell me, she...
She loved me.
Where, Miller?
Where was she?
Was she here?
In this room?
Where!
There.
She was standing right there.
What happened then?
What happened then!
I took hold of her.
I just wanted her to see sense.
She hit me, hard, and...
I...
I'm somewhere else.
There's blood spreading out
around her head like a halo.
I had to stop her blood from spilling.
I... I couldn't stop it.
I loved her.
I loved her so much, I...
No, it's all wrong I did not do that!
No, she couldn't have been bleeding here.
I mean, why would she do that?
No, she was bleeding up there,
at that house.
Up there where her husband killed her.
He did it!
The fucking killer!
The fucking murderer!
He's gonna pay for what he done.
What did he do?
Damn it, Miller! What did he do!
- He took her.
He took her away f...
He took her.
Gale.
Gale?
Oh, Jesus.
Gale.
All this time.
You let everyone believe.
I ain't that man, I...
I ain't.
It ain't me no more.
It ain't me not more.
Don't be scared of me.
D... don't be scared of me.
She ain't dead.
She's here.
She's right her, I see her.
What are you doing, where you going?
Y... you said we was gonna
go away, you said that.
You stay away form me!
- What, you wanna leave me?
You bastard, you god damn bastard!
You said you was gonna help me.
- Oh god.
That what you want?
You gonna leave me?
Answer me, Gale.
Answer me!
I don't.
I swear, I don't.
Please, Miller.
Please!
I wanna stay.
I'll stay...
with you.
I want to.
I'm begging you to forgive me.
Please?
Forgive me.
I love you, Miller.
I truly do.
Where are you, girl?
Baby, where'd you go?
Don't go, Gale.
Gale, don't go.
Gale, please don't go.
Lord, I've gotten old.
I'm retiring this year, you know.
My wife says she want's
to see Alaska while we can still walk.
She sure has put up with
a lot over these years.
As far as this situation,
you can go on like you please.
I guess you got what you came for.
I don't really feel that way.
What if I never showed up here?
I mean...
what if he'd just gone on living there,
keeping to himself?
Well, I don't know.
That sound like justice to you?