THE GOSPEL
ACCORDING TO ST MATTHEW
To the dear, joyous familiar
memory of Pope John XXIII
Joseph, fear not to take Mary
as your wife...
...for she has conceived by the
power of the Holy Ghost.
She will bear a son whom you
will call Jesus...
...for he is to save his people
from their sins.
The virgin shall be with child...
...and shall bear a son...
...and they shall call him Emmanuel,
meaning God with us.
Where has the king of the Jews
been born?
We have seen his star in the east,
and have come to worship him.
Where will Christ be born?
At Bethlehem in Juda, the prophet
wrote:
And you, Bethlehem, in the land
of Juda...
...art far from the least
among the princes of Juda.
For out of you will arise a leader...
...who is to be the shepherd
of my people Israel"
Seek the child, and when you
have found him...
...bring me word so I too may come
and worship him.
Take the child and his mother...
...flee to Egypt and remain there
until I give you word.
For Herod will soon search for
the child, to destroy him.
I called my son out of Egypt.
A voice was heard in Rama,
lamentation and great mourning.
Rachel wept for her children...
...she would not be comforted,
for none is left.
Take the child and his mother
and return to Israel...
...for those who sought the
child's life are dead.
Repent, the kingdom of heaven
is at hand.
It was of him that the prophet
Isaias spoke when he said:
There is a voice of one crying
in the wilderness
Prepare the way of the Lord...
...straighten out his paths.
Brood of vipers! Who taught you to
flee the vengeance that draws near?
Yield the acceptable fruit
of repentance.
Do not presume to say in your hearts:
We have Abraham for our father.
God has power to raise up children
to Abraham out of these very stones.
Already the axe has been put
to the root of the trees...
...so that every tree that
does not show good fruit...
...will be hewn down
and cast into the fire.
I am baptizing you with water,
for your repentance...
...but one is to come after me
who is mightier than I...
...so that I am not worthy even
to carry his shoes for him.
He will baptize you...
...with the Holy Ghost and with fire.
He holds his winnowing fan to sweep
his threshing-floor clean.
He will gather the wheat
into his barn...
...but the chaff he will consume
in unquenchable fire
It is I that ought to be
baptized by you.
Do you come to me?
Let it be so for the present,
to fulfil due observance
This is my beloved Son...
...in whom I am well pleased.
If you are the Son of God,
turn these stones into bread.
Man cannot live by bread alone...
...but by all the words which
proceed from the mouth of God.
If you are the Son of God, cast yourself
down to earth. For it is written:
He has charged angels to watch over
you lest you should trip on a stone.
It is further written: You shall not put
the Lord your God to the proof.
I will give you all these, If you
will fall down and worship me.
Away with you, Satan!
It is written: You shall worship the
Lord your God, and serve none but him.
The people that abode in darkness
have seen a great light.
For men living in a land where death
overshadowed them, light has dawned.
Repent, the kingdom of heaven
is at hand.
Peter.
Andrew.
Come and follow me; I will
make you fishers of men.
James and John, sons of Zebedee,
come with me.
The harvest is plentiful,
but the labourers are few.
Ask the Lord whose harvest it is
to send labourers for the harvesting.
Peter...Andrew...
...James...John...Philip...
Thomas.
Simon.
Bartholomew.
Thaddaeus.
James, son of Alphaeus.
Matthew.
Judas Iscariot.
You shall be labourers for
the harvesting.
I am sending you to be
like sheep among wolves.
You must be wary as serpents,
yet innocent as doves
Do not put your trust in men.
They will deliver you to courts and
scourge you in their synagogues.
On my account you will bear witness
before governors, kings and Gentiles.
When you are given into their hands
do not fear what to say.
Words will be given you
when the time comes.
It is not you who speak, it is your
Father's Spirit that speaks in you.
You will be hated by all men
because you bear my name.
Fear not those who kill the body but
have no means of killing the soul.
Fear him more who has the power
to ruin body and soul in hell.
Are not sparrows sold
two for a penny?
Yet not one of them may fall to the
ground without your Father's will.
Every hair of your head...
...he takes into his reckoning.
Fear not, you count more than
a host of sparrows.
Do not imagine I have come
to bring peace to the earth.
I have come to bring a sword,
not peace.
I have come to set man at variance
with his father...
...and the daughter with her mother.
A man's enemies will be
the people of his own house
He is not worthy of me, that loves
father or mother more.
He who secures his own life
will lose it.
It is the man who loses his life for
my sake that will secure it.
Lord, If you will, make me clean.
It is my will, be made clean.
Tell no man, rather go and
show yourself to the priest..
...and offer the gift which
Moses ordained...
...to make the truth be known to them.
Blessed are the poor in spirit;
the kingdom of heaven is theirs.
Blessed are those who mourn;
they shall be comforted.
Blessed are the patient;
they shall inherit the land.
Blessed are those who hunger for
holiness; they shall have their fill.
Blessed are the merciful;
they shall obtain mercy.
Blessed are the clean of heart;
they shall see God.
Blessed are the peace-makers; they
shall be counted the children of God.
Those persecuted in right's cause;
the kingdom of heaven is theirs.
Blessed are you, when men revile
you and persecute you...
...and speak all manner of evil
against you falsely, because of me.
Be glad and light-hearted, a rich
reward awaits you in heaven.
So it was they persecuted the
prophets who went before you.
If your son asks for bread,
will you give him a stone?
If he asks for a fish,
will you give him a serpent?
If you, evil as you are, know
what is good for your children...
...will not your Father in heaven give
more good gifts to those who ask?
Do to other men all that you
would have them do to you.
That is the law and the prophets.
Do not think I have come to set aside
the law and the prophets.
I have come to bring them
to perfection.
You are the salt of the earth; if salt
loses salinity, what can restore it?
Nothing can be done with it but
throw it out to be trodden underfoot
You are the light of the world.
A city on a mountain top
cannot be hidden.
A lamp is not placed under a bushel...
...it is put where it will
light the house
Do not lay up treasure on earth...
...where moth and rust consume it,
thieves break in and steal it.
Lay up treasure for yourselves
in heaven...
...where there is no moth or rust,
no thieves steal it.
A man cannot serve two masters.
He will hate one and love the other,
devote himself to one, scorn the other.
You may serve God or money;
you cannot serve both.
When giving alms, let not your left
hand know what your right is doing...
...so secret is your almsgiving to be.
Then your Father, who sees what is
done in secret, will reward you.
You have heard it said: An eye for
an eye, a tooth for a tooth.
I tell you, do not offer resistance.
If a man strikes you on your
right cheek, turn the other.
You have heard it said: Love your
neighbour and hate your enemy.
I tell you: Love your enemies,
pray for those who persecute you...
...so that you may be true sons of
your Father in heaven...
...who makes his sun rise on the evil
and on the good...
...his rain fall on the just
and on the unjust.
Do not judge others, or you
yourselves will be judged.
As you have judged, so you will
be judged, by the same rule.
Award shall be made to you
as you have made award.
How is it you see the speck
of dirt in your brother's eye...
...and are not aware of the beam
which is in your own?
When you pray, do not use many
phrases, like the heathen...
...who think to make themselves
heard by their eloquence.
You are not to be like them.
Your Father knows well what your
needs are before you ask him.
This, then, is to be your prayer:
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses, as we
forgive them that trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Do not fret over your life, how to
support it with food and drink
Over your body, how to
keep it clothed.
is not life itself a greater gift
than food, the body than clothing?
See the birds of the air never sow,
or reap, or gather grain into barns...
...and yet your heavenly Father
feeds them.
Have you not an excellence
beyond theirs?
Can anyone of you add a cubit's
growth to his height?
And why should you be anxious
over clothing?
See how the lilies grow,
they do not toil or spin.
And yet I tell you that even Solomon
in all his glory...
...was not arrayed like one of these.
If God so clothes the grasses
of the field...
...which today live and will feed
the oven tomorrow...
...will he not be much more ready to
clothe you, men of little faith?
Do not fret then, asking what you
will eat or drink or wear.
It is for the heathen to busy
themselves over such things.
You have a Father in heaven who knows
that you need them all.
Make it your first care to find the
kingdom of God, and his approval...
...and all these things shall be
yours without the asking.
Do not fret over tomorrow, leave it
to fret over its own needs.
For today, today's troubles
are enough.
Make your way in by the narrow gate.
It is a broad gate and a wide road
that leads to perdition...
...and those who go that way
are many indeed.
How small the gate, how narrow
the road that leads to life...
...and how few there are that find it.
Father, Lord of heaven and earth,
I give you praise...
...that you have hidden this from the
wise and revealed it to children.
My Father has entrusted everything
into my hands.
None knows the Son truly
except the Father.
None knows the Father truly
except the Son...
...and those to whom it is
the Son's pleasure to reveal him.
Come to me all you that labour and
are burdened; I will give you rest.
Take my yoke upon yourselves
and learn from me.
I am gentle and humble of heart;
you shall find rest for your souls.
For my yoke is easy
and my burden is light.
Your disciples are doing
what is not lawful on the Sabbath.
Have you never read what David did,
when he and his followers hungered?
How he went into the tabernacle,
and ate the loaves set out there...
...although neither he nor anyone but
the priest had the right to eat them?
Have you not read in the law...
...that priests violate the Sabbath
rest in the temple; none blames them?
I tell you, there is one standing
here who is greater than the temple.
If you understood the words:
I desire mercy, not sacrifice...
...you would not condemn
the guiltless.
The Son of Man has even
the Sabbath at his disposal.
is it lawful to heal on the Sabbath?
If one of your sheep fell
into a pit...
...would you not pull it out
on a Sabbath?
What is a sheep compared to a man?
Mercy is not unlawful on the Sabbath.
Throw away your crutches.
Tell no man that you have
been healed...
...so that the word spoken by
Isaias may be fulfilled.
Behold my servant, my chosen,
with whom my soul is well pleased.
I will lay my spirit on him, he shall
proclaim my rule among Gentiles.
He will not protest and cry out; none
shall hear his voice in the streets.
He will not break a bruised reed
or quench a smouldering wick...
...until the time comes when he
crowns his judgement with victory.
We must find a way to make a way
with him.
It is past the accustomed hour.
Let the multitudes buy food
in the villages.
It is for you to give them food.
We have only five loaves and
two fishes.
Bring them to me.
I am going to pray. Take ship
and cross to the other side.
It is an apparition.
Take courage, it is myself.
Do not be afraid.
Lord, if it is you, bid me
to come to you over the water.
Why did you hesitate,
man of little faith?
is it his coming that was foretold...
...or are we yet waiting for
some other?
John has sent us to ask if it is
your coming that was foretold.
Go and tell John what your own
ears and eyes have witnessed.
How the blind see, the lame walk,
lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear...
...the dead are raised to life, the
poor have the gospel preached to them.
Blessed is the man who
does not lose confidence in me.
What did you expect to see when
you went into the wilderness?
A reed trembling in the wind?
A man clad in silk?
You must look in kings' palaces
for men clad in silk.
Did you go to see a prophet?
Yes, and something more.
This is the man of whom it was
written:
I am sending before you that angel of
mine who is to prepare the way.
God has raised up no greater son of
woman than John the Baptist.
Yet to be least in the kingdom of
heaven is to be greater than he.
Ever since John the Baptist's time...
...the kingdom of heaven
has opened to force...
...whereas all the prophets and the
law, before John's time...
...spoke only of things
that were to come.
He is that Elias whose coming
was prophesied.
As fort his generation,
to what shall I compare it?
It reminds me of those children
who complain to their companions:
You would not dance when we
piped to you.
John would not eat or drink,
and they say he is possessed.
The Son of Man came, ate and drank...
...and they call him a glutton,
friend of publicans and sinners.
It is by her own children
that wisdom is vindicated.
Woe to you, cities where I did
miracles and you have not repented.
If Tyre and Sidon had witnessed
such miracles...
...they would have repented in
sackcloth and ashes long ago.
I say it shall go less hard
with Tyre and Sidon...
...than with you at judgement day.
Capharnaum, do you hope to be lifted
to heaven? You shall fall low as hell.
Can this be the Son of David?
It is only through the power of
Beelzebub that he casts devils out.
He who is not with me, is against me.
There is pardon...
...for all the other
sins and blasphemies of men...
...but not for blasphemy
against the Holy Spirit.
Master, may we see a sign from you?
Wicked and unfaithful generation,
the only sign that will be given...
...is the sign of the prophet Jonas.
Jonas was three days and nights
in the belly of the sea-beast.
The Son of Man will be three days
and nights in the earth.
The men of Nineveh will condemn this
generation on judgement day...
...for they did penance to Jonas,
and a greater than Jonas is here.
The queen of the south will
condemn this generation...
...for she came from the ends of the
earth to hear Solomon's wisdom.
And, behold, a greater than Solomon
is here.
Your mother and brethren are here,
looking for you.
When an unclean spirit...
...leaves a man to find another
dwelling, yet finds none...
...it says: I will go back to
my own dwelling.
It finds it empty, neatly swept, and
It brings seven worse spirits...
...and they enter and settle down.
So the last state of that man
is worse than the first.
So shall it fare with
this wicked generation.
Your mother and brethren are here.
Who is a mother, who are brethren,
to me?
Here are my mother and my brethren!
If anyone does the will of
my Father in heaven...
...he is my brother, and sister,
and mother.
How did he come by this wisdom,
and these strange powers?
is his mother not Mary...
...and his brethren James,
Joseph, Simon and Judas?
And do not his sisters live near us?
How has all this come to him?
is not this the carpenter's son?
Only in his own country, his own home,
a prophet goes unhonoured.
Master, what good must I do
to win eternal life?
Why ask me of goodness?
God is good, and he only.
If you want to enter into life,
keep the commandments.
Do no murder, commit no adultery,
do not steal, bear no false witness..
...honour your father and mother,
love your neighbour as yourself.
I have kept these;
where am I still wanting?
To be perfect, sell your possessions
and give to the poor...
...so your treasure shall be
in heaven; then follow me.
Believe me...
...a rich man will not enter
God's kingdom easily.
It is easier for a camel to pass
through a needle's eye...
...than for a rich man to enter
the kingdom of heaven.
Christ, bless our children.
Leave the Lord in peace.
Let the children be,
do not keep them from me.
The kingdom of heaven
belongs to such as these.
Your dance has pleased me;
I will grant whatever you wish.
Give me the head of John the Baptist,
onadish.
Her wish be granted.
Let us withdraw into desert country,
to be alone.
Come, let us cross to the other side.
Lord, give me leave to go home
and bury my father.
Follow me, and leave the dead
to bury their dead.
Master, I will follow you
wherever you are going.
Foxes have holes and birds their
nesting places.
The Son of Man has nowhere
to lay his head.
Howl, O gate; cry, O city.
Thou, whole Palestina, art dissolved,
for a smoke shall come from the north.
in their streets they shall
gird themselves with sackcloth.
On the tops of their houses, and in their
streets everyone shall weep abundantly.
Who do men say is the Son of Man?
Some say John the Baptist.
Others Elias.
Others Jeremy.
Or one of the prophets.
- What do you say that I am?
You are the Christ, the Son
of the living God.
Blessed are you, Simon son of Jona.
It is not flesh and blood, it is my
Father that has revealed this to you.
And I tell you that you are Peter.
And it is upon this rock
that I will build my church...
...and the gates of hell shall not
prevail against it.
I will give you the keys
of the kingdom of heaven.
And whatever you shall bind on earth
shall be bound in heaven.
And whatever you shall loose on earth
shall be loosed in heaven.
You are to tell no one
that I am the Christ.
I must go up to Jerusalem...
...and there, with ill-usage from the
chief priests, elders and scribes..
...must be put to death.
Never, Lord; no such thing
shall befall you.
Back, Satan! For these thoughts of
yours are men's, not God's.
If any man has a mind to
come my way...
...let him renounce self, rake up
his cross, and follow me.
The Son of Man is to be given
into the hands of men.
They will put him to death, and he
will rise again on the third day.
Who is the greatest in the
kingdom of heaven?
Unless you become like
little children again...
...you shall not enter
the kingdom of heaven.
He is greatest in heaven who will
abase himself like this little child.
He who welcomes such a child,
welcomes me.
If anyone hurts the conscience of
one of these little ones...
...he had better have drowned
in the sea...
...with a mill-stone hung about
his neck.
Woe to the world, for the hurt
done to conscience
Such hurt must come, but woe to the
man through whom it comes.
If your hand or foot is an occasion
of failing to you...
...cut it off and cast it away
from you.
Better to enter into life
crippled or lame...
...than to have hands and feet when
you are cast into eternal fire
If a man has a hundred sheep
and one has strayed...
...does he not leave the ninety-nine
and go to look for the stray?
If, by good fortune, he finds it...
...he rejoices more over that one
than over those that did not stray.
So it is not your Father's pleasure
that one of these little ones be lost.
How often must I see my brother do
me wrong and still forgive him?
As much as seven times?
Forgive not seven wrongs,
but seventy times seven.
Now we are going up to Jerusalem.
The Son of Man will be given up into the
hands of the chief priests and the scribes
Who will condemn him to death.
And these will give him up into the
hands of the Gentiles, to be mocked...
...scourged and crucified...
...but on the third day
he will rise again.
in that village you will find
tethered a she-ass and her foal.
Go and bring them to me.
If anyone asks...
...say that the Lord needs them,
and he will let you have them.
It is Jesus, son of David.
It is written: My house
shall be a house of prayer.
You have made it a den of thieves.
Hosanna to the Son of David!
Do you hear them?
Have you never read the words:
Thou hast made the lips of children
vocal with praise?
Let no fruit grow on you hereafter.
How suddenly it has withered.
If you have faith and do not hesitate
you will be able to do more.
If you say to this mountain:
Be cast into the sea, it will come about.
Every gift you ask for in prayer
will be granted.
By what authority do you do
these things?
Who gave you this authority?
I too have a question to ask.
If you can answer I will tell you
what is my authority.
Whence did John's baptism come,
from heaven or from men?
If we tell him it was from heaven,
he will ask:
Then why did you not believe him?
If we say from men, we have reason
to fear the people...
...for they all look upon John
as a prophet.
We cannot tell.
And you will not learn from me
of my authority.
Tell me what you think:
A man had two sons...
...and he asked the first to work
in his vineyard that day.
The son refused, but relented
afterwards and went.
He asked his second son to work
in the vineyard.
The son said he would go,
but did not go.
Which of the two
did his father's will?
The second.
The publicans and harlots are further
on the road to God's kingdom than you.
John came among you following all due
observance, but won no belief from you.
The publicans believed him,
and the harlots...
...but even when you saw that...
...you would not relent,
and believe him.
Listen to another parable.
A rich man planted a vineyard.
He walled it, dug a wine-press,
and let it to vine-dressers.
Then he went on his travels.
At vintage-time he sent his servants
to claim its revenues.
The vine-dressers beat his servants
killed one and stoned another.
The man sent even more servants,
but they were used no better.
Then he sent his son,
thinking he would be respected.
But the vine-dressers,
seeing the man's heir...
...thought to kill him
and seize his inheritance.
They thrust him from the vineyard
and killed him.
What will the man do to
those vine-dressers?
He will bring those wretches
to a wretched end...
...and will let the vineyard to
others who will pay him his due.
Have you never read these words
in the scriptures:
The stone which the builders rejected
has become the corner-stone...
...this is the Lord's doing, and it
is marvellous in our eyes?
I tell you the kingdom of God
will be taken away from you...
...and given to a people which yields
the revenues that belong to it.
When a man falls against the stone,
he will break his bones.
When it falls on him, it will
scatter him like chaff.
Many are called, but few are chosen.
Master, we know well that you
are sincere...
...and teach in all sincerity
the ways of God.
You hold no one in awe, making no
distinction between man and man.
Tell us, then, is it right
to pay tribute to Caesar, or not?
Hypocrites, why test me thus?
Show me the coinage in which
the tribute is paid.
Whose likeness, whose name
is inscribed on it?
Give unto Caesar what is Caesar's,
to God what is God's.
Moses told us: If a man leaves
no children when he dies...
...his brother shall marry the widow
by right of kinship...
...and beget children in the
dead brother's name.
We had seven brothers in our country,
of whom the first died...
...a married man without issue,
bequeathing his wife to the second.
He died, bequeathing her to
the third...
...and finally she had been every
brother's wife, dying last of all.
When the dead rise again, which
brother will be her husband?
You do not understand the scriptures,
or what is the power of God.
When the dead rise again, there is
no marrying or giving in marriage.
They are as the angels in heaven are.
Have you never read what God himself
said of the resurrection?
I am the God of Abraham, of Isaac,
and of Jacob.
Yet it is of living men, not dead men,
that he is God.
Master, which commandment in the law
is the greatest?
Thou shalt love the Lord thy God
with thy whole heart...
...thy whole soul and thy whole mind.
This is the greatest of the
commandments, and the first.
And the second, its like:
Thou shalt love thy neighbour
as thyself.
The scribes and Pharisees sit
in the chair of Moses.
Do what they tell you,
observe what they tell you...
...but do not imitate their actions,
they do not practise what they preach.
They bind unbearable packs
and lay them on men's shoulders.
They will not stir a finger
to lift them.
They act...
...to be a mark for men's eyes,
with rich clothes and fine books.
They love the first seats at table
and in the synagogue..
...and salutations, and being
called Rabbi.
You are not to claim the title of
Rabbi; you have but one Master...
...and you are all brethren.
Nor are you to call any man on earth
your father; you have one Father...
...and he is in heaven.
Nor are you to be called teachers;
you have one teacher, Christ.
The greatest of all
is to be the servant of all.
The man who exalts himself
will be humbled.
The man who humbles himself
will be exalted.
Woe upon you, scribes and Pharisees,
you hypocrites...
...that shut the door of the kingdom
of heaven in men's faces.
You will not enter, nor let others
enter when they would.
Woe upon you, scribes and Pharisees,
you hypocrites...
...that encompass sea and land
to gain a single proselyte...
...then make him twice as worthy
of damnation as yourselves.
Woe upon you, blind leaders, who say:
If a man swears by the temple,
It goes for nothing.
If he swears by the gold in
the temple, his oath stands.
Which is greater, the gold, or the
temple that consecrates the gold?
And again: If a man swears by
the altar, it goes for nothing.
If he swears by the gift on the altar,
his oath stands.
Blind fools, which is greater, the
gift, or the consecrating altar?
A man who swears by the altar
swears by all that is on it.
He who swears by the temple, swears
by him who has made it his dwelling.
The man who swears by heaven...
...swears not only by God's throne,
but by him who sits upon it.
Woe upon you, scribes and Pharisees,
you hypocrites...
...that will award God his tithe,
belt mint or dill or cumin...
...and have forgotten the
weightier commandments of the law...
...justice, mercy and honour.
You did ill to forget one duty
while you performed the other.
Blind leaders, that have a strainer
for the gnat, then swallow the camel.
Woe upon you, scribes and Pharisees,
you hypocrites...
...that scour the outward part
of a cup and dish...
...while all within is running
with avarice and incontinence.
Scour the inside of the cup
and dish first...
...so that the outside, too,
may become clean.
Woe upon you, scribes and Pharisees,
you hypocrites...
...that are like whitened sepulchres,
fair in outward show...
...when they are full of dead men's
bones and corruption within.
You may seem exact over your duties,
outwardly, to men's eyes...
...while there is nothing within
but hypocrisy and iniquity.
Woe upon you, scribes and Pharisees,
you hypocrites...
...that build tombs of prophets
and engrave monuments to the just.
You say: If we had lived in
our fathers' time...
...we would not have murdered
the prophets.
You thus witness your ancestry;
your fathers slaughtered the prophets.
It is for you to complete
your fathers' reckoning.
Brood of vipers, how should you
escape from the award of hell?
Now, behold, I am sending wise men
and prophets to preach to you.
Some you will put to death
and crucify...
...some you will scourge
in your synagogues...
...and persecute them from city
to city...
...so you will become answerable for
all the blood of just men...
...from the blood of the just Abel
to the blood of Zacharias...
...whom you slew between
the temple and the altar.
Believe me, this generation shall be
held answerable for all of it.
Jerusalem, still murdering prophets
and stoning messengers sent to you...
...how often have I been ready
to gather your children together...
...as a hen gathers her chickens
under her wings...
...and you refused it.
Behold, your house is left to you,
uninhabited.
You shall see no more of me until
the time when you will be saying:
Blessed is he that comes
in the name of the Lord.
Do you see all this?
There will not be a stone left on
another, it will all be thrown down.
It is time to bring Jesus
into our power.
By cunning... and put him to death.
Not on the day of the feast...
...or perhaps there will be
an uproar among the people.
Why this waste? It could be sold at
great price, to give alms to the poor.
Why do you vex the woman?
She did well to treat me so.
You have the poor among you always;
I am not always among you.
When she poured ointment over my body
It was to prepare me for burial.
Wherever the gospel is preached,
this deed shall preserve her memory.
What will you pay me for
handing him over to you?
Thirty pieces of silver.
Believe me, one of you
is to betray me.
Lord, is it I?
The man who has put his hand into
the dish with me will betray me.
The Son of Man goes his way,
as the scripture foretells...
...but woe upon that man by whom
the Son of Man is betrayed.
Better for that man if
he had never been born.
Master, is it I?
Your own lips have said it.
Take, eat, this is my body.
Drink...
...for this is my blood,
of the new testament...
...shed for many, for the remission
of sins.
I shall not drink of this fruit
of the vine again...
...until I drink it with you, new
wine, in the kingdom of my Father.
Tonight you will all lose courage
over me.
For it has been written:
I will smite the shepherd, and the
sheep of his flock will be scattered.
But when I have risen, I will go on
before you into Galilee.
Though all else should lose courage
over you, I never shall.
This night, before the cock crows,
you will thrice disown me.
I will never disown you, though
I lay down my life with you.
Sit down here, while I go and pray.
Peter, and you two, James and John,
come with me.
My soul is ready to die with sorrow.
Abide here and watch with me.
My father, if it be possible,
let this chalice pass me by.
Only as thy will is, not as mine is.
Had you not strength to watch with me
even for an hour?
Watch and pray, that you may not
enter into temptation.
The spirit is willing enough,
but the flesh is weak
My father, if this chalice may not
pass me by, but I must drink of it...
...then let thy will be done.
Put back the sword! Those who rake
the sword will perish by the sword!
Do you doubt that if I call
upon my Father...
..he will send more than twelve
legions of angels to my side?
You come to arrest me with swords
and clubs, as if I were a robber.
Yet day after day I sat teaching
in the temple...
...and you never laid hands on me.
Friend, on what errand have you come?
He said: I can destroy the temple
and raise it in three days.
I, too, heard him say those things.
Have you no answer to make
to these accusations?
I adjure you by the living God...
...to tell us whether you are Christ,
the Son of God.
Your own lips have said it.
And you will see the Son of God
again...
...when he is seated on the right
hand of God's power...
...and comes on the clouds of heaven.
- He has blasphemed!
What further need have we
of witnesses?
You have heard his blasphemy
for yourselves.
What is your finding?
The penalty is death.
You were with Jesus.
I do not know what you mean.
This man was with Jesus.
I know nothing of the man.
You are one of them;
even your speech betrays you.
in the name of the living God,
I know nothing of the man.
He must die.
Give him up to Pontius Pilate.
I have sinned...
...in betraying innocent blood.
What is that to us?
It concerns you only.
It must not be put into the treasury;
It is the price of blood.
We will use it to buy the
potter's field...
...as a burial place for strangers;
to be known as the field of blood.
Do you not hear the testimony
against you?
It is the paschal feast.
As is customary, I wish to
release a prisoner...
...according to your choice.
Whom shall I release? Barabbas,
or Jesus who is called Christ?
What wrong has he done?
Let him be crucified!
I have no part in the death
of this innocent man.
It concerns you only.
His blood be upon us,
and upon our children!
Hail, king of the Jews!
Carry this cross!
You will listen, but for you
there is no understanding.
You will watch, but for you
there is no perceiving.
The heart of this people
has become dull.
Their ears are slow to listen,
they keep their eyes shut.
So they may never see with those
eyes, or hear with those ears.
My God, why hast thou forsaken me?
He is calling upon Elias.
Wait, let us see if Elias
is to come and save him.
I know you have come to look
for Jesus, who was crucified.
He is not here; he has risen,
as he told you.
Tell his disciples you shall
have sight of him in Galilee.
All authority in heaven and earth
has been given to me.
Make disciples of all nations...
...baptizing them in the name of
the Father, Son and Holy Ghost...
...teaching them to obey all the
commandments I have given you.
Behold, I am with you always,
unto the end of the world.