Hero
"A person who has accomplished
an extraordinary deed..."
"...and exhibits qualities like honor
and valor."
"Tupac Amaru:"
"Fought the Spaniards who were treating
the Indians like slaves in the mines..."
"...and they were dying of asthma."
"Then they caught him and tortured him."
"They tied his arms and legs
to four horses."
"They scared the horses so they
would pull his arms and legs."
Like a Barbie doll.
"But Tupac Amaru was so strong
that he wouldn't come apart."
"And so they had to come with
a machete and chop his head off."
Did it hurt when you died?
My chest always hurts during gym class.
"Jose Olaya:"
"He was a poor fisherman,
but he was a very good swimmer."
"He had to swim through the night
to deliver all the secret letters..."
"...but he was betrayed."
"And right before he was caught,
he ate the letters and refused to talk."
"They pulled out his fingernails,
one by one..."
"They cut his throat, then he was
shot by a firing squad."
I'm going to be a hero... like you.
"Miguel Grau:"
"He won a couple of battles
against Chile..."
"...but his boat was so tiny that it
was surrounded and bombed..."
"...at the Battle of Angamos."
"The only thing that remains is his
boot, which can be seen at the museum."
"We celebrate the Battle of Angamos
on October 8th..."
That means that we don't have
to go to school.
Why is it a holiday
if we always lose the battles?
I don't know...
...but we won the War of Independence.
Have you realized that in most of the
parks and plazas of our city...
...there are statues of military heroes
on horseback?
Yes...
And did you know that when the horse'
two front legs are in the air...
...it means that the soldier
died in the battlefield?
Guess what it means if the horse'
two front legs are on the ground.
He didn't die in the battle.
Correct.
But if he didn't die in the battle,
he can't be a hero.
You're wrong, Cayetana.
And what happens if the horse has one
leg on the ground and one in the air
It means that the hero was wounded
in the battle... but survived.
And what happened to the horses?
Girls... bomb threat.
Time to evacuate.
Not again... Quickly, girls.
Hey, that' my lunchbox.
What am I going to eat now?
I have a banana if you want.
Doesn't she know another song?
Sit down, de los Heros.
Listen, girls. I think that I'm going
to be really good at sports...
...because I heard Lupe tell Alicia
that I had athlete' foot...
...so one day, I'll be a champion.
What about your asthma?
And when you get married, who will
take you to the altar...
...your father or step-father?
I'll go alone.
Did you hear about Martita' dad?
Last week they went abroad,
because her dad was a narc.
Abroad?
- What' a narc?
- I don't know.
Are you on the right or the left?
Your mom is coming back tomorrow, right?
Her hair must be so long!
Did you know that if you stare at
someone for 5 minutes without blinking...
...they go crazy?
I've missed her so much.
I haven't seen her in so long.
Cayetana de los Heros...
Bye, Jimena. I have to go.
Bye.
Excuse me... Here I am, Ms. Cayetana.
If you keep carrying that bag,
you'll become a hunchback.
You crashed.
Yes, Ms. Cayetana. I crashed.
Any change, Miss?
No
lt' for food... nothing to eat.
No, I don't have anything.
I threw everything in the toilet.
But I have these pills...
They're for asthma but when I take
them my hunger goes away.
Please, Ms. Cayetana.
Roll up the window and lock the door.
This neighborhood is dangerous.
My country makes me sad.
The only thing people care about...
...is soccer.
What difference does it make,
if we never win?
Final score: Peru 6, Brazil 0.
It must be a mistake.
Why aren't you eating anything,
Cayetana?
Ok. Get some rest.
"I would die 1000 deaths before
betraying my comrades or my country."
Your mother won't even recognize you.
Have you taken your pills?
No, I forgot. Can I have some
lemonade so I can take them?
No lemonade. Just drink some water.
Besides, there' no lemons.
Let' go outside, they'll
be here any minute.
Perfect.
No lemons, huh?
Are you sick?
What' that thing on your beak?
Don't worry, I'll save you.
I'll make you better.
Cayetana, they've arrived!
You're not getting out?
She won't want to see me.
Don't worry, Ines.
I told you to take your pills.
Damn pills...
Mrs. Ines, how good to see you.
You look so pretty.
How are things, Lupe?
Good.
Can I have a glass of water?
Yes, of course.
Welcome back, ma'am.
Go and say hi to your mom.
Cayetana?
And how was your trip, ma'am?
Good.
You must be tired after
such a long trip.
Classes ended yesterday and I went
straight to the airport.
I barely slept on the airplane.
Where is Cayetana?
Sometimes I had nightmares,
thinking that I had forgotten your face.
Don't be silly, it hasn't been that long.
What happens when you have to go back?
I don't want to think about that.
Maybe we can put Cayetana in a suitcase.
If I am reflected in her eyes,
she only has eyes for me.
Cayetana...
...here' a present for you.
This is also for you.
You don't have this one do you?
Yes, I already have it.
Well... you can pretend
they're twin sisters.
Ohh... how pretty!
For my dolls?
No, it' even better than that.
You're going to have a baby brother.
Congratulations, ma'am.
When are you due?
May 2nd.
A little brother, Cayetana.
You're so lucky!
Why such a sad face?
Aren't you happy about the news?
Cayetana...
I'll never do anything for her again.
I'll never sing with her again.
May 2nd... May 2nd.
They want a new baby.
Why?
What happens to the old one?
Lt' no good because it has asthma?
A new one is born...
...and the other is thrown away?
May 2nd...
That day...
...is the day I am going to die.
"Mother..."
"Those wrinkles were formed..."
"Death to traitors..."
"Maoist triumph..."
You're so quiet today, Ms. Cayetana.
I have something to tell you.
My eyesight is getting worse
and I'll probably have to stop working.
I've thought about it a lot and...
...I want to be a master cobbler.
Do you know what that is?
Yes, the one who fixes shoes.
No, the master cobbler
is the one who fixes...
...and prolongs the life of the shoes.
In other countries, when something
gets old it' thrown out.
Yes, I know.
When my brother is born,
they won't be able to throw me out...
...because I'll already be dead.
No... think of it,
you'll be the older sister.
Look Miss... where you see the
key stand.
That' where I want to have my shop.
It will be a gold mine, right Miss?
If I count to three...
...my father will come.
One... two... three.
If I fall, I would die like a hero.
What is this?
A pumpkin.
Ramon Solari.
Why do you always come in 3rd place?
Cayetana de los Heros.
Why don't you say hi to your mom?
Well... 3rd isn't so bad.
At least they give you a trophy.
4th place... they give you nothing.
When are we going to have a telephone?
Soon...
We don't have a line yet...
but look, we have a phone.
Someone will forget about me
if I don't call.
Ok guys, this is it... exactly like this.
Let' go, get to work.
- Got it?
- Yes, yes.
We're building a swimming pool,
just like this one.
It' going to take time and energy.
Esweeeming puuul?
Very good, my friend.
I know some words in English.
Oh, that' good...
A swimming pool is like
an upside down house.
Can I borrow the ladder?
Lt' very important.
Sure, Miss... go ahead.
So how does it feel to know
that you're pregnant?
It all happened very quickly...
...kind of a surprise.
And how did Ramon react?
He was pretty relaxed about it.
Cayetana, leave them alone.
You don't even know them.
Of course I know them.
They're my neighbors.
Maybe you can make that
wall higher.
How do you know you're pregnant?
What if it' a tumor?
I... didn't even come into the kitchen.
That canary has died from sadness.
It couldn't take being alone.
Can animals die from sadness?
Yes, of course.
And people?
Yes, I think so.
Mothers and fathers who get divorced...
...will not go to Heaven.
Raise your hands
if your parents are divorced.
Ok. If they were good, perhaps...
But if they get remarried... Hell.
Or some kind of long purgatory...
Mom...
I have bad news...
...you're going to Hell.
Mom...
Don't be sad but...
...you're going to Hell.
Mom...
...you're not going to Heaven...
...you're going to Hell.
Cayetana... what are you doing?
Nothing.
You've thrown out your food again.
No, I didn't throw away anything.
Hang on...
Are you going to tell my mom?
No, I won't tell her. But what was it?
Soup. You open it and it stinks.
Want some?
No.
Cayetana... I have some extra bread.
Do you want it?
Ok.
Are you cutting class?
Yes, Religion.
Listen, Jimena...
The religion teacher says that divorced
people who remarry won't go to Heaven.
Do you think they go to Hell?
No, Cayetana!
Those things don't exist.
You're so dramatic...
I can't tell my mom.
But if she gets divorced again...
maybe she'll be saved.
And you... are you cutting class?
I had to go to the nurse' office.
I almost fainted.
You almost fainted for real?
Oh well... I pretend to faint so that
they carry me like a princess.
I faint for real.
Sometimes for real, but
usually you fake it, right?
You usually fake it, right?
Yes, almost always.
Do you want to play?
Let' do "terrorist."
Ok.
"Terror-terror-terrorists..."
Less cement, more sand...
I'm getting nowhere.
I don't know, the soil is terrible.
So, gentlemen...
How is the project coming along?
Miss, we have work to do.
Cayetana, we're going to Mass.
I can't, I have asthma.
So you're staying with us this Sunday?
No. I'm spending the day with my father.
The only way to call your father is if
you come with me and call from town...
...which means that you're coming to
Mass, whether you like it or not.
I hate waking up early.
I hate going to Mass.
I hate you.
Several electrical towers were knocked
down, causing a blackout...
Under cover of darkness, the
terrorists attacked private property...
... burned shops and harassed vendors.
You're not going to Mass?
The thing is at Mass there' a guy
who looks just like Dracula.
During the peace-be-with-you part,
he always tries to hug me.
There' also these fat women
with sweaty hands.
I'm leaving in 30 seconds.
Cain told his brother Abel...
Let' go into the field...
And when they were in the field...
Cain attacked Abel...
...and killed him.
God asked Cain...
"What have you done?"
"Your brother' blood is crying out."
"From now on you will be cursed."
"You'll live far from this fertile land, which
is coated with your brother' blood..."
"...blood that stains your hands."
We must have compassion for our
brothers who have lost their way.
I have to go.
Mass is ending and there must be
a line for the telephone.
Cayetana, you're not going anywhere.
Please rise.
May peace be with you...
And with you...
Let us hug in peace.
Dad?
Are you sleeping?
So at what time, then?
At 1:30?
So late?
Ok, fine. At 1:30.
But at 1:30, ok?
Bye.
May I have 1/2 kilo of rice...
...1/2 kilo of sugar...
...and 25 candles, please.
Make that 50 candles.
Grey, grey, grey, grey, grey, grey...
Cayetana, come inside.
The sun is too strong.
No.
Lunch is ready, let' go!
I'm going to eat with my dad.
Cayetana, please come in.
Don't get me in trouble with your mom.
You know your mom doesn't like it when
you're out here. It' too dangerous.
Alicia. Leave it to me.
Go serve lunch, please.
Yes, ma'am.
Cayetana, what are you doing?
Nothing, waiting for the ice cream man.
What kind of ice cream man will come
here? We're two hours away from the city.
He' not going to come.
Didn't he forget you last Sunday?
Didn't he say he was coming at 1?
No. Now that I think about it,
he said he was coming at 2 or 2:30.
No, he said he was coming at 1.
Perhaps there was a lot of traffic.
Yes, of course.
Since there are so many cars...
Cayetana, you've been
waiting for two hours.
Why don't we eat lunch?
No, I'm not hungry.
Besides I want to eat with my dad.
I don't understand why you're
so obsessed with your dad.
He doesn't even behave like one.
Do you know who pays for school?
No.
Do you know who pays for your doctors?
Well, just so you know, Ramon pays
for everything, not your father.
Look a grey car!
Don't forget to take your pills at 5!
Hey kiddo what' up?
Hi
Just this once, get in the backseat ok?
If you want, I'll get in the back...
No, don't worry about it...
Ok, Cayetana. Let' go, get in.
Hey kiddo, how have you been?
Wow, you've gotten so tall...
This is Andrea.
Hi, Cayetana. You're so pretty...
Hi.
Look...
...this is Cayetana' first tooth.
- What a lovely tooth...
- Why didn't you come last Sunday?
Because you didn't call.
But there' still no telephone.
Oh come on, just give me a hug.
Where' Maria?
No, Maria and I broke up.
What about Pilar?
What are you getting at, kiddo?
Oh, nothing. But why do I have
to learn all these names...
...if you're never going
to see them again...
...and I'm never going
to see them again.
Well, someone' in a bad mood...
...so let' turn on the radio and go.
Here we go, here we go...
Grab your tickets, grab your tickets...
Let' go, the guinea pig is getting dizzy...
...round and round, getting dizzy...
Let' see who wins... Here we go!
Dad... mom never lets me eat this.
She says it causes cancer.
Relax... Your mom is so uptight.
Don't worry, you're with me...
We won't say anything to your mom.
You want to bet?
No
Pardon me
Do you want to get out?
Look if one of you climbs on the other...
...you'll be able to get over the wall.
I'll save you.
Run
You're going to die.
Tomorrow you'll wake up in a kettle.
We're leaving in 15 minutes.
Hi, Grandma Carmela.
What are you doing?
Waiting for death to come get me.
Death is coming?
What are you reading?
Cayetana!
Death!
Here' your milk, Cayetana...
The one you like so much... warm milk.
Cayetana!
Here I am. Don't step on that.
Take your milk, little girl.
You don't like it?
Cayetana, let' go.
Bye, Herminia. My time is up.
Bye, Grandma Carmela.
What' that fire?
I don't know.
They must be burning trash.
I've seen that symbol before.
It' the hammer and sickle.
Are the terrorists coming to kill us?
What are you talking about kiddo?
Are you ready for me to win again?
I'm winning 4-1... and I know this song!
"Lt' my life..."
"What can I do... she chose me..."
"lt' my life...
"lt' not Hell...
"lt' not Paradise either..."
Dad, are you going to pick me
up next Sunday?
Kiddo...
I have to take a trip...
...I just remembered.
But I'll be back soon ok?
And since I'll be back
before Christmas...
...maybe we can go to Disneyland...
...and I'll buy you the doll you need...
the one with red hair.
No, I have that one already.
I need the one in the wheelchair.
Ok.
Give me a hug.
I'll fight until I fire my last bullet.
And we lost right when
he fired his last bullet.
Where' Isaac?
He' at the doctor, he'll
pick you up after school.
Isaac is acting strange.
Don't worry, he' fine.
He' old but he' strong.
It' really late.
If the traffic lights worked like they do in
any other city, this wouldn't be happening.
Sorry, I'm turning here...
It' one way!
There are fewer cars!
Besides, don't you have assembly
first thing in the morning?
Yes...
So they're going to sing the whole
national anthem. We have time...
Shut up, jerk!
Are you ok?
Yes.
I help addicts. And you?
I run them over.
- Castro...
- Present.
- Cisneros...
De los Heros...
Cayetana, pass me one of my pills.
They're in the glove compartment.
Va-li-um...
They're for anxiety.
Cayetana... give me your hand. I think I felt it kick.
Can you feel it?
I don't feel anything...
...has it died?
Are you ok?
Yes
47 minutes late.
A new record. Run, run!
Cayetana de los Heros...
"Oppressed..."
"Chains..."
"Condemned..."
"Servitude..."
While Bolivar was liberating
Ecuador from the North...
...San Martin was liberating Argentina
and Chile from the South.
The problem arises when they both want
to declare the independence of Peru.
That' where we get the famous
phrase from Bolivar to San Martin:
"Two suns cannot shine in one sky."
So, Miss Cayetana. How was your day?
Look, Isaac. Today my dog was put to sleep
because it was vomiting green blood.
And I have asthma, a
migraine and anxiety.
So don't talk to me.
Today there another bomb threat.
We missed math class.
That' great, huh?
Do you want a piece of gum?
No, thank you.
If you insist...
Oh dear god...
Why me, dear god?
Don't get out, Miss.
Does it hurt to die?
Of course it does, Miss.
Ma-ssa-cre.
Med-io-cre.
Ramon is mediocre.
Yesterday there was a
massacre in Ayacucho.
Cayetana, are you done?
Not yet...
Come help me in the kitchen
when you're done.
It' for the baby...
Money for the baby...
There you go...
Do you want to practice the song
we're playing tonight?
Ok.
Lift your guitar up.
How does it go?
You have to stir the batter,
so that there are no lumps.
You see?
Lupe, can you make me a
lemonade please?
One for me, too.
Dont' be scared.
They're fireworks.
Alicia... lt' time to prepare the
bread with valium for the dogs.
Yes, ma'am.
Those pills again?
You know how nervous they get
in these situations.
Puppy! Dog! Don't eat that!
So, Miss. Where are you spending
Christmas Eve?
At my aunt' house.
Ready guys?
All done.
Well, it' not here.
What the hell am I going
to pay the workers with?
Lupe can you come here please?
Did you look in your study?
Do you know anything about the
money that was in this drawer?
No, sir.
Lupe, call Alicia.
Cayetana, you took the money
that was in my room.
No.
Alicia...
It must have been you.
You're the only one who
cleans the rooms.
No ma'am. I swear it wasn't me.
Alicia, I'm losing patience.
If the money doesn't appear in 15
minutes, we're going to the police station.
Ma'am...
If you want you can check in my room.
I have nothing to hide.
Go get your things.
I want you out of here right now.
Please, bear with me...
I'll pay you first thing Monday morning.
But you said today.
I have plans tonight...
Merry Christmas, guys.
Lupe!
Can you give me a hand, please?
What are you doing here?
It was you, wasn't it?
You're in trouble, little girl.
You're in trouble.
Your daughter is a thief.
What will happen 10 years from now?
That's enough, Ramon.
Tonight is Christmas Eve.
And no one can be punished
on Christmas Eve.
Cayetana isn't a delinquent.
She's only 8 years old.
What should we do?
Don't worry, Ines...
They'll see...
They'll be sorry...
This would be the perfect place...
...to entrench and defend ourselves.
The Heroes!
Olaya!
Gentlemen...
...but the idea isn't to hide.
I'm not moving until I
fire my last shot.
Does it hurt to die?
It only hurts in the beginning.
What do you have to do
to become a hero?
We're under attack! The Royalists
have discovered us!
Lt' not the Royalists,
it' the terrorists.
Oh, Uncle Ramon. Buy something else.
You've finally arrived!
What a cute baby!
He looks like you.
No, he looks like his father.
Let' keep singing...
I don't know what else to do with her.
That girl has been alone
for a long time.
Why don't you leave her with me
for a few months?
We're going to the beach tomorrow.
It will be good for Cayetana.
Kill it!
No.
Then open the window and let it go.
"Flies live for 24 hours."
Cayetana...
Mathematics...
They always place bombs at that time.
Also, my dad bought me
a scientific calculator.
Listen, Jimena... why don't we...
...count the number of tombstones
on the highway?
Or why don't we count
red beetle Volkswagens?
Pretty boring...
...unless you have to hold your breath
until you see one.
That' a wonderful rule!
We'd turn purple from asphyxia!
Look at all the dead animals...
Why is the sky always white in Lima?
The sky in Lima is always
covered by a white veil.
It always looks like
it' going to rain...
...but it never rains.
Is it blood?
Yes.
Well... it' fake blood. My father
couldn't buy the real thing.
One never knows when there
will be a tragedy.
With the Barbies?
Let' go!
Fly away. But now you're lost...
...and you'll never see
your family again.
Listen, Jimena...
...pretend that you're in a canoe and a
volcano has just erupted.
So, the water is getting hot...
...and in the canoe it' you,
your father and your mother...
...and you have to kick someone out.
Who would you kick out?
My father because he' a good swimmer.
No... when you kick someone out...
...the piranhas wake up.
Who would you kick out?
My mom.
But she' going to float with
such a big belly.
Then my dad...
...even though I think he went to
live in Disneyland.
Every year I come and say
I'll climb the sand mountain...
...but I can't.
We have to try.
If we get to the top, we'll be heroes...
Or athletes.
Don't be silly, Cayetana...
...l'm sure there' just
an old fisherman' hut.
Old fisherman' hut?
Let' find out.
Jimena! Cayetana!
Come down immediately!
You know that you can't
exert so much energy.
Finland...
Massacre...
Did you hear about the
massacre in Finland?
Finland...
Sweetie, it' not in the newspaper.
Where did you hear that?
Oh... nowhere.
Hello.
When I die...
When I die... l'll come visit you.
When I die... l'll visit you every day.
Every day?
What? Does it scare you?
How about...
...once a week.
How about every birthday?
No, I've got it... every time you say...
..."Resurrection."
You're don't bleed?
So you're a vampire!
Lt' because your stick isn't sharp.
Look at mine.
Ouch...
Cayetana! Jimena! Dinner time!
Let' go.
Guess who came to visit.
What do they do?
They kill everyone.
I think they've killed almost
all the policemen.
Jimena... pretend the terrorists tell you that you
can use the letter "J" 100 more times...
...and then they kill you.
What would you do?
Because your name starts with "J."
Cayetana?
The beach is full, there' no room.
It' because it' Sunday.
They look like ants.
Let' hope that the captain
sees the towel.
Why does he need to see the towel?
It means that he has to
prepare the boat.
We're going on the boat!
The sharks are going to eat us.
Everyone stay together.
Be careful
Come here, Cayetana
Help me, Panchano.
Excuse me, kids...
And how is the glass business?
I can't complain. With all the bombs...
business is booming.
Business in the provinces has tripled...
now we're making bulletproof windows.
A neighbor has a candle factory...
...with all the blackouts, his
business is exploding.
Either you pay them off, or you
get rich because of their attacks.
They've threatened Ramon several times.
What is "paying off?"
And when is the baby due?
Soon...
It' kicking and moving a lot.
- What is "paying off?"
- The birth is scheduled for May 2nd.
On a holiday?
Cayetana, you must be happy that
you're going to have a little brother.
But you'll have a little brother
who will take care of you.
How is he going to take care
of me, if I'll always be older?
Pardon me.
Be careful Cayetana.
It' great in here, right?
Yes, no one can bother us.
Are you ok?
Are you scared?
Sometimes... when I don't feel well.
What scares you?
That it' going to hurt?
Listen, Jimena...
Do you want me to tell you a secret?
What is it?
When the baby is born...
I'm going to die.
You're so silly Cayetana!
Those things don't happen.
You'll see that you'll love him...
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la.
...and you won't feel so alone.
You too, Jimena?
You want that baby too.
Cayetana, wait for me.
I'm walking slowly...
Jimena?
Are you ok?
Cayetana!
Cayetana I'm leaving today...
Come say goodbye.
Say goodbye from me, ok?
Machete...
Disease...
- Do you have the car keys? -
Yes, right here.
I'm going to get the elevator.
Can you get up, Jimena?
Yes.
We'll be back soon.
Intensive Care?
Ok Mrs. Amalia.
Ok. Goodbye Mrs. Amalia.
Jimena is still at the hospital.
They still have to run some tests.
You are not going to take Jimena.
You can take me if you want...
Better yet, my Grandma Carmela...
...who is waiting for death
to come for her.
Do dead people float?
Only for a while...
Afterwards, the sharks eat them.
I can't see anything...
In the Nanay River...
In the jungle...
The water is so muddy...
That as time passes,
fish are born blind.
No, thank you.
If I reach the top...
Jimena will be fine.
If I don't make it...
You take Grandma Carmela.
Mr...
Are you the guardian of Heaven?
Are you a member?
Do you have ID?
You have to attack now,
they can't see you.
But we can't see them either.
We have to wait.
I have to keep going. Let' go...
I don't have a stick.
You always forget your things...
I always get the stick that' not sharp.
Your time is up!
Blood.
You're bleeding?
So you are not a vampire?
You're a hero.
I will always take care of you.
I will always look after you.
Is there anyone home?
Cayetana...
Here, in the study.
The swines took everything, Cayetana.
They took your trophies.
But you still have your paintings...
Yes...
Why do you think they left them?
I'm sure they had no more room
in their bags.
Don't worry...
They'll come back for them another day.
Did you say hi to your mother?
No, where is she?
Locked in her room.
Why is she locked in?
Do you want to bring this too, ma'am?
What am I going to do with this child?
I never learn.
What am I going to do with this baby...
...if I can barely take care of myself...
Everything will be ok, you'll see...
Someone left them at the door...
...some of them are dead.
Poor little guys...
I'll save you, little kittens.
Close my eyes... close my eyes...
open my eyes... open my eyes...
What' going on?
They just want you to be afraid of them.
Are you afraid of them?
Yes.
But it' important to pray.
So that this doesn't get worse.
And why do you pray so much
if you're going to Hell anyway?
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing.
When you are in a dark room...
...and you can't see anything...
Do you open or close your eyes?
What?
In a river with muddy water...
...fish are born blind because they
don't use their eye muscles.
Who told you that story?
Panchano Zapata.
Well I think that...
...we need to open our eyes...
...because there is always
something to see.
Are you going to leave again?
I don't know...
I think it' Isaac.
Cayetana, don't play with the candles.
No, we still don't know where it was...
It felt like it was near.
Do you guys have electricity?
Tell me... how is Jimena doing?
Does she recognize you?
Yes, tomorrow.
I'll talk to you later.
Ramon might be trying to call.
Ok. Take care.
When will I be able to visit Jimena?
Not yet, Cayetana.
Jimena is very sick.
She is in Intensive Care.
Ma'am.
The attacks were close by, in Nana.
Hello?
Ramon!
Are you coming soon?
Why don't you stay there.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Your brother' birth was complicated.
He has a disease. He is deformed.
Do you want to see him?
No, thank you.
There is only one way to save him.
A blood relative like you...
...must donate their heart,
lungs and eyes.
Your parents have agreed.
They have already signed the papers.
- No, Doctor.
Besides, I'm adopted.
My organs won't work.
Cayetana...
Your brother is about to be born...
stay here with Lupe ok?
You'll come and see us tomorrow.
Hello?
Hi, Grandpa...
May I speak with Jimena?
Cayetana!
The nurses just finished bathing her
and are putting her to bed.
How are you doing?
Fine...
Where is abroad?
Lt' a huge country, why?
Some of my friends
moved there forever...
...because their parents were narcs.
Narcs?
Hello Cayetana? Lt' Grandma.
Ramon called...
The baby is going to be born tonight.
I'll pick you up tomorrow morning, ok?
Two suns...
...cannot shine...
...in one sky.
Ouch!
I died...
No... not yet.
If I am alive...
...it means that the baby is...
...dead.
The baby is cute...
A little purple...
He got wrapped in the umbilical cord,
but he' fine now.
Do you like the design of his room?
Do you like it?
You can't act like nothing is happening...
The time has come.
You are so ugly.
You know what?
I don't love you.
And I'll never love you.
Are you scared of vampires?
I am a vampire.
Look.
I brought you a tarantula...
I am not invisible...
Well... did you see him?
Yes, we've met.
No, that' not him.
He' in another room.
What would you name him?
Who is that?
Come on, let' go.
Hello...
Hi, Amalia.
Sit down...
Have you seen Ines?
No, she is in a very bad mood.
She doesn't want visitors.
She is breast feeding.
What did the doctors say
about Jimena, is there any news?
No, nothing. Only that it is serious.
Hi!
Hello!
Flowers?
For Ines...
Hello?
Hello Francisco. It' Cayetana.
Hey kiddo!
How was your vacation?
They were ok. But they were in the summer.
You went to Disneyland, right?
No...
Things got complicated at work...
I have a question...
Is Grandma Carmela breathing?
What?
I need to know...
...if Grandma Carmela is dead...
No... Why?
And why are you calling me Francisco?
Please insert coins to continue...
What year are we in?
Who is the current president?
Ok...
I want you to touch the tip of
your nose with your left hand.
Don't worry. I'll be back, ok?
Jimena!
How are you?
I'm fine too.
You know, I climbed to the
top of the sand mountain...
And guess what I found?
Just what you said!
An old fisherman in a small hut!
Lupe found some kittens...
...but I've already given them some milk.
What else?
My mom said you have a disease that
goes away with time...
Look at my new inhaler!
I don't have to take
those big pills anymore.
And I can breathe easily.
My brother was born...
...and look, I'm still alive.
Brother...
Jimena...
You are my favorite person
in the world.
You have to get better quickly, ok?
I'll be right back.
Poor Tupac Amaru...
They've quartered him...
We're running low on ammunition.
Quiet, please...
we don't want to be caught.
I must protect these letters.
I have to find a way out.
How can we defeat an enemy
that is five times bigger than us?
You don't know what happened, do you?
Is this supposed to be me?
We lost...
We have experience in battles...
...in losing them all.
What are we going to do now?
If you want you can stay in my house...
I have a pool.
Let' go gentlemen.
It' time to face our destiny.
Are you coming with us?
No, I can't.
I have to meet my brother.
There is no time to lose.
It' time to attack.
From one defeat to the other...
Victory will be ours.
No, don't go yet...
I can't. I have to go with them.
Yes, I know, but... where are the letters?
No...
...I ate them.
Yes, I know you ate them. But...
Did you read them before eating them?
What did they say?
That it was time to attack?
Retreat?
Surrender?
Or were they so wet that
you couldn't understand anything?
No, no... It' not that.
So what is it?
I don't know how to read.
Two suns cannot shine in one sky...
Breathe baby...
Breathe baby, breathe.
Come on, breathe...
You can't be in here!
Go on...
It' a sedative...
You'll feel better with this.
Get some rest...
Cayetana...
What' that smell outside?
Are there flowers?
Yes, a lot...
But I'll throw them in the trash,
just the way you would.
Thank you.
You know how much I hate those things.
Have you seen him?
Yes...
Come here...
Cayetana, come closer.
Come closer... sit down.
Look at this cut on your finger...
And your kittens?
They are ok...
What can we do
to make you smile more often?
Cayetana...
Isaac...
Are you Miss Cayetana?
I am Justino...
Your new driver and bodyguard.
Why is everything so dark?
They're the new tinted windows
that Mr. Ramon had installed.
They are bullet-proof, bomb-proof
and kidnapping-proof...
They look like mirrors
from the outside...
...they can't see you.
They can't see me?
Where is Isaac?
Is he still sick?
I think...
...the old man died.
Poor old man...
Don't cry Cayetana...
You hate Isaac...
I am not invisble!