Xi'an Film Studio
This is a legendary story
According to the old folks,
when Haige came to Double Flag Town,
it was still a vast desert
Some say it was eighty-one years ago,
others say it was seventy-one
Either way, it's a thrilling story
of the Chinese West
"The swordsman in double flag town"
Screenwriter: Yang Zhengguang, He Ping
Photographer: Ma Delin
Art Designer: Qian Yunxuan
Music: Tao Long
Recording: Wei Jia, Hong Yi
Editing: Yuan Hong
Starring: Gao Wei as Haige
Zhao Mana as Haomei
Chang Jiang as Lame Man, Sun Haiying as
Lethal Swordsman, Wang Gang as Desert Eagle
Producer: Zhao Wanmin
Director: He Ping
Have you seen the Lethal Swordsman?
Shit, are you trying to scare me?
That horse is foaming at the mouth.
Do you want it to die of thirst?
Do you have any dry food?
You seem intelligent
Do you know who I am?
For five hundred miles around,
there isn't anyone who hasn't heard of me.
I am Desert Eagle, a knight-errant
Well, don't you know?
Don't be in such a hurry!
Cold water will choke you and break your lungs!
First time traveling, right?
- Where are you going?
- To Double Flag Town
Double Flag Town? Alone?
That's no place for a boy on his own
I am going to get a wife
Ah, a child like you...
...speaks of getting a wife?
What does she look like?
I have never seen her
Well, we are going the same way.
Just follow me
With this flying sandsword, I travel all over...
...to weed out the wicked and help the poor
I bet you can't find another
man like me in the Northwest
Hey, can you lend me some money?
I am saving it for the wedding
Then it's ok
Look, this road leads to Double Flag Town
Hey, knight-errant!
I think you're a good man.
Here is half my money
If you run into any trouble,
come to Dry Straw to find me
I need a saddle in two days!
- Who is that on horseback?
- Is he a swordsman?
Fire!
We have aged wine and
specially tenderized horsemeat
Let's go and look
What are they doing?
Have you seen the Lethal Swordsman?
Hi! Are you two from the West?
Let me do it
Come in, please
Little Pigtail, what are you here for?
I am here to fetch my wife
The Little Pigtail! The Little Pigtail!
Brother Chang, busy?
Whose daughter? What is her name?
I don't know her name.
My father arranged for me when I was a boy
She has a mole on her butt
On his deathbed, my father told me that...
...my would-be-father-in-law is a lame man
Do you know him?
What does he do?
No, there is no lame man in this town
My memory is bad? Not in this town maybe?
My dad couldn't speak clearly at his death
No food for you! Go elsewhere!
Haomei, who are you talking to?
A dirty kid with a pigtail
He dared to knock on our door at midnight
Pretending to be a swordsman...
...with two rags on his legs
Where are you from, you bastard?
- Stop!
- Dad, beat him hard!
What have you done?!
Stop!
Stop! You wild rat!
I'll beat you to death!
Kowtow to my father-in-law
The Lethal Swordsman is coming!
I've been looking for you for seven years
Pull out your sword
My leg was injured in a swordfight
I couldn't fight with your father any more
I quit my wandering life many years ago
I opened this restaurant to make a living
I am not the man I used to be
My father sent me here to find my bride
Stay here, we can discuss it later
Haomei
Come and see your big uncle's son
I never want to see him
Never!
Where does this uncle come from?
When his father was alive,
I betrothed my daughter to his son
to protect her
But now, I have only one leg,
and the whole world is a mess
Besides, that child has
neither skills with a sword nor common sense
If something happens to me,
how can I leave Haomei in his hands?
Such a young kid yet he practices
Midnight Emptiness Kung fu?
From this day on, you'll work here
In this town, you must remember three virtues
The hand virtue, the foot virtue
and the eye virtue
There are also these rules
Never be inquisitive,
and never talk with strangers
Too many people come here to seek their revenge
One slip of the tongue can kill a man
Haige
Pick the bones out of this carcass for cooking
At work, never carry your daggers
Take them off!
My dad said that if my head is on my shoulders,
my swords stays on my body
I doubt if he knows Kung fu
What a shame to carry the daggers
How stupid!
Look how much lean meat you're wasting!
Watch!
Watch! Did you see?
Eye virtue!
Lame Big Brother!
It was said that your son-in-law has come
He's my brother's child. My nephew
Oh? Folks are talking...
It's none of your business!
What's the big deal?
The art of your father's swordsmanship
has never been seen in books
In the past years he defeated
countless famous swordsmen
He was well recognized in the Northwest
His swordart absorbed the essence
of fist and palm boxing
To laymen, his technique looked very simple
It had neither fancy maneuvers
nor a life-threatening whistle
But a professional swordsman
understand its deadly strokes
Most important part is when he unsheathes
his sword for his last deadly stroke
The sword carries his breathing strength,
which in turn pushes the sword
You can't tell when the sword
is out of the sheathe,
and when its tip stabs into the enemy's flesh
This swiftness all depends on
one's breathing strength
Without it, it is impossible
to perform this maneuver
Even if you want to learn,
you are not able to
Haomei, Haige.
Tomorrow you go out and walk the horses
- I don't want to go with him
- Haomei!
Look, the Little Pigtail
Look!
The Little Pigtail without little tail
Good Little Sister is walking with a Little Pigtail
without a little tail!
Good Little Sister!
Good Little Sister is walking with
a Little Pigtail
without a little tail!
Good Little Sister is going to marry!
We don't want him!
Tell him to leave! We don't want him!
Tell him to leave!
Little Pigtail! Tell him to leave!
We don't want him! Tell him to leave!
Little Pigtail!
I am afraid the weather is going to change
Stay up late tonight,
and put some wood in the stove
Don't let the fire die out
Haomei
Let me tell you the truth
Haige came here...
...to take you home as his bride
But he's not the one I'm satisfied with
Go to sleep. I won't allow this marriage
When the knife cuts into the flesh, go along
the bone. Don't use sheer animal strength
You father should have taught you this...
...if he taught you martial arts. Did he?
Everything about him is marvelous except
that he doesn't have common sense
Haomei, you go and take the leather on
our backyard fence to Uncle Tanner
- Did you hear?
- Yes, Daddy
Let's go
Watch, let me show you
If you really want to learn skills,
you should watch, ask and practice
Let me try
When my father was alive,
a big man carrying a sword said to him that...
...he could cut a very thick tree trunk
in two with the back of his sword
My father said that...
...he could do it with his hand
How thick was the tree trunk?
This thick
There was a large crowd around the backyard
After a roar from my father...
Did he cut it in two?
No. He only made a twenty-inch crack
For this my father lost five acres of land
I say your father is not a loser,
cracking should be counted as breaking
Later my dad told me that...
...at the time he farted,
losing some of his energy
Otherwise, he could have cut it in two
- Haomei
- Yes?
Your butt...
Is there a mole on your butt?
My dad said the girl
whose butt has a mole is my bride
What are you talking about? Nonsense!
Haomei!
Haomei! Stop!
Hold on a second !
I taught you to have the eye virtue!
Never look at what you're not supposed to!
I wanted to see if her butt has a mole!
Dad
Stand aside!
Watch, today I will spank him
like he'll never forget!
Dad. Please stop
I bet this!
Come on! Come on!
You lose!
- Man, more wine!
- I am coming!
- Lame Man!
- Yes
Lame Man » where is your pretty daughter?
She is sick and at home in bed
Lame Man, go ahead and feed my horse
Yes, sir. It will be well attended
Let's see what happens
What are you doing?
- Come on, let me touch!
- Let me go! Let me go!
Daddy! Let me go!
Let me go!
Daddy! Daddy!
Help me!
After you feed the horse,
come to the hall and help
Daddy! Help me!
- Haomei!
- Daddy! Help me!
- Second Big Brother!
Daddy! Help me!
Second Big Brother, please don't!
Stop!
- Daddy!
- Haomei!
You little bastard! Pull out your sword!
She is my bride!
Your bride?
This pretty girl?
You sleep with her? You sleep with
a little pretty lady Budhlsattva?
A little shit like you should have
this pretty lady fortune?
Second Big Brother has been killed!
It wasn't me
I didn't do it. I don't know
The Little Pigtail killed him!
You think the Lethal Swordsman
is easy to deal with?
The kid killed his second brother
The bastard will certainly
create a blood bath in our town
The Lethal Swordsman has been well known
in the Northwest for more than twenty years
He always kills with one deadly stroke
If your father was still alive,
maybe he could have dealt with him
But now...
Haomei
From today on, you are his woman
He lives, you live.
He dies, you die
Haige, Haomei is yours now
You must treat her well from now on
Get up
Pack. Leave at daybreak
The Lethal Swordsman and his men
will be here in three days
If you can't get out of the desert, you'll die
If you see a little swordsman here,
let him stay!
Quick!
This is...
You...
You, little brother
we Double Flag Town folks beg you
You can't leave
Since you killed Lethal Swordsman's brother,
he will come
What can we do without you?
Big Lame Brother, he must not leave
If you don't stay, we'll be
on our knees till we die
But he is only a child
Little Swordsman, your Kung fu is outstanding
If you can do away with this bully,
you are the hero of the people
of Double Flag Town
You can't leave!
The people are right
They are right
We should face the catastrophe...
...that we created
Come on. Go on eating
Floating sand stirring wind! I got it!
Be careful on your way
- Go quickly and be back soon
- I will
The Little Pigtail is running away!
He can't leave!
You coward!
Are you trying to let him escape?
No, no
Stop dreaming! You can't get away!
You can't go away!
If you run away, whom should we turn to?
I'm not drunk
My feet haven't turned red yet.
Don't try to fool us!
Everybody,
he is going to find the Desert Eagle for help
The Desert Eagle?
I know him. This man is marvelous
I made horseshoes for him.
Maybe he's the man to fight the Lethal Swordsman
He asks for big money! Will he come?
Haige helped him once.
He will certainly come
How can we trust you?
You can't depend on a promise
What if the Little Pigtail doesn't come back?
- I guarantee he will
- How can you guarantee that?
I allowed him to marry Haomei,
so he is my son-in-law
If he won't return,
me and Haomei will wait
for the Lethal Swordsman to claim our heads
Yes, he should hurry up to get there
I'll be back
More wine
You owe me money. How dare you act rude here?
I owe you money?
Yes, I owe you money. I won't deny it
Desert Eagle helps the poor
and give tyrants their due
I deserve more and you know it
I just owe you a little money
I admitted that. Why worry?
Watch. It's silver
Although my brother
is not a first class swordsman,
his sword art is outstanding
His swordsmanship must be extraordinary
Tell everyone we will meet at Double Flag Town
Are you having trouble with the Lethal Swordsman?
I killed his little brother
I wanted to leave town with my bride,
but the townspeople wouldn't let me leave
They all said that the Lethal Swordsman
would come for revenge
I've come here for help
With or without you, sooner or later.
I would've cut him in two
Well, eat
Don't worry.
Death is fast approaching for the Lethal Swordsman
- Do you have any money?
- Yes. This is all I have
Fuck! I still owe that woman for the hotel bill
If you are able to help,
my father-in-law will pay you well
I'm always easy to bargain with. Eat!
When will the Lethal Swordsman arrive?
In two days
Well, I'll see you the day after tomorrow,
at high noon
Haven't you seen that boy's rolling eyes?
You can tell he's a bastard
He wouldn't leave his bride here, would he?
Women are men's foot-rags.
You can go anywhere to pick them up
We may witness a bloody drama
Wait for death.
The Lethal Swordsman is coming tomorrow
Wait for death! Wait for death!
The Little Pigtail will come back
It's hard to say
We are folks. How can he cheat us?
She's coming
Why hasn't the Little Pigtail come back?
He never knew the Desert Eagle in the first place!
He never knew him! You lied!
You go bring him back!
Bring him back!
Come on now. Leave him alone
The Lame Brother is not that sort of man
He will by no means abandon us
It's still broad daylight. We must have patience!
Let's wait!
Haige!
Haige did it! He persuaded
the Desert Eagle to come and help us
Let's toast to him
I can't drink
You're our hero!
Drink!
The Lethal Swordsman
isn't the rival of Desert Eagle
We're going to see some action!
The Desert Eagle fights the Lethal Swordsman
Saaaa, floating sand stirring wind
Shoooooo, a swimming snake shaking its tail
Huaaaa, a hand rising and sword falling
Yeeee, blood splashing
Who do you think will win?
I say the Lethal Swordsman
The Desert Eagle is also a hero
Let's bet!
- No problem! I bet one goat!
- One goat!
Whoever regrets is a son of a bitch!
- Settled!
- OK! A goat!
Drink
Haomei, do you have a mole on your butt?
Haven't you seen it?
The door fell down before I saw it
Set a fire!
Do you want to die?
He hasn't shown up
Daddy!
Stay here!
- Daddy! Come back!
- Don't go!
Daddy!
Daddy! Come back!
I killed your brother!
It has nothing to do with the others!
Go ahead, draw your sword!
Daddy! Let me go!
Daddy!
Haomei
- Come back!
- Daddy!
Daddy! Wake up!
Stop!
He's only a child
If you want revenge,
it won't be too late when he grows up
It's not decent for a swordsman
like you to kill a child!
Floating sand stirring wind
A swimming snake shaking its tail
Wake up. Drink
Who says that the Desert Eagle hasn't shown up?
I am the Desert Eagle
I haven't drunk too much
Look at my feet. They're not red
From who did you learn the sword art?
Floating sand stirring the wind!
Where is the Lethal Swordsman?
Quit crying!
I already knew he wasn't your match
My money! Didn't we have a deal?
My dear nephew?
My dear nephew!
I didn't get the worst of it.
This sword has a gold handle
You cheated me
You are not grateful, but I can't be unkind
If you need me,
I'll be at Dry Straw