Why are you staring?
Aren't your ears firm?
- Test it!
And what about yours?
- What's your name?
- Grishka!
I'm Anton, Antonina.
- Ha! Are you a girl?
- Aha!
- You look like a boy.
- Do I?
Do you know who's my father? The earl!
The famous inventor Markoni!
- Do you know the wireless telegraphy?
- No.
- It's my dad's. He is Italian.
- Italian?
What? My nose is bulbous?
It is from my mom.
She is Russian.
- Does she type, too?
- She tiptoes!
- What for?
- For being ballerina.
Do you know Kseshinskaya?
- Well, I do.
So, when dad stopped loving her,
she plunged into the water.
Wow!
The divers were looking for her
for 3 days and never found.
Why?
When it's because of the unhappy
love-it is impossible to find.
And my dad, too...
- Drowned himself?
- No... he was...
- The Earl?
- Yeah!
- What was his surname?
- Damaskin.
Zamazkin! The earls don't have
such surnames.
Well, he was a kind of earl.
He served as a coachman at merchant.
- As who?
- As a coachman.
The 1 st guild's coachman.
Grigory Chernikh, 16 years old, his father...
It's difficult to read.
I don't have father. And I never had.
Mother is a laundress,
he gave up school.
And he is suspected of the
burglary of Shuster's haberdashery.
- At first prove that!
- Sit down, sit down!
I can slander you, too.
Besides, Grigory Chernikh...
is an orderly, careful, polite guy.
- And he doen't smoke, I think.
- Exactly!
- A humanist!
- It is noticeable.
Well, who is ready
to accept Grigory Chernikh?
No, no, I'm fed up.
I have a hundred of such humanists.
And I have a lot of such junk.
I can offer it as well.
But otherwise we
should send him to jail.
All right, in what subjects
did he make progress?
- In drawing.
And they even complimented me for one time.
- Fine fellow!
- The painters would prove useful to us.
- You take him!
- No, wait!
- Wait a little!
- Send him now!
I accept him if these things
are given out:2 pairs of trousers.
2 beddings,
Upright bolts and screws
accordingly.
And nails won't be superfluous.
And sugar!
And sugar.
- One-two, one-two... left!
One-two, one-two... pull up!
Grisha! Grisha!
Here it is... about love.
Well, don't think about it...
I'll come to you,
swear that you will come, too!
I swear...
Juvenile depravity!
What a disgrace!
I'll never forget you! Never!
You are my only one!
I don't have anybody!
I love you!
Carry this sugar to her and be back immediately!
Good, finish changing
your clothes!
- Is the breakfast ready?
- It's been cooking!
The first breakfast!
Wonderful!
- What's the smell?
- It's the sealskin oil. The deficit.
So, listen:
cook 60 helpings.
Oh, but we have
only 16 kiddies.
No matter! Let them be full.
Ella Andreevna!
Be quite! Quite!
Kiddies are asleep!
Ella Andreevna!
Are you ready?
It's high time!
Wait, don't be nervous!
Marta! Marta!
Marta, where are you?
Wonderful! Wonderful.
The inconceivable architecture.
Marta! Damn it!
I've nearly got lost!
In this house there are places
where the human foot didn't step.
Don't be nervous.
It is the premiere today.
The curtain will soon rise.
Yes.
Marta! Marta!
Who is this personality?
Hey, who is this personality?
Now, Goga, ride him
on the bicycle!
I'll do it!
Yankel is here! A Jew!
A typical blond Jew!
Who do you look like?
A typical brunet Gypsy!
A horse-thief! Let me tell fortunes,
let me know your destiny!
Well done, Yankel!
You've guessed him right!
Hey, you!
Why do you pester Yankel?
- I'm not Yankel.
- You are Yankel! And I am Sparrow!
Don't be afraid of him,
he fears Kupets himself!
- Do I fear?
- You do!
- Do I fear? Do I?
Don't you hear the bell?
The breakfast is waiting for you!
Everything is getting cool!
Put the beds to their places
and go for breakfast, quickly!
Put the bed to it's place!
Make the bed!
Why he is sleeping?
Where is the person on duty?
- Who is on duty?
- Nobody!
You are on duty now!
Take it and wake him up.
Ofenbah, stand up!
Stand up, Ofenbah!
Okay, what time is it?
Five past ten.
- Well, I stand up.
Move it! Move it!
When I studied in military school,
I caused Kuzmich to go deaf.
When he was awaking me,
I hit right upon his ear!
Upon his ear-drum!
How ingeniously!
If you are not at the table in 5 minutes,
you'll have your breakfast at supper!
Listen, what's going on to him?
Is he offended?
Oh, I am...
- Hungry?
- Yes.
Goga! You've been appointed
person on duty! Bring!
Just a minute!
Food!!
Not enough salt!
Just a minute, kiddy, just a minute...
Eat, kiddies!
Kiddies, where are you?
Give me some.
The prog is enough for a
hundred of paunches!
Finish your breakfast and make...
Where are they?
Meftahutdin!
Meftahutdin! Who has...
Why you didn't detain them?
Bandits! You see...
they snatched out the keys!
And they tossed it to that tree!
Bandits!
They've got the keys!
Penetrating guys!
Where from the firewood? Hey?
It looks like it's from forest...
The fathers are sawing...
And I will take it for heating!
What a frau! O dear!
Would you like to have these lovely,
not much used boots?
Oh!
Allow me!
Wow! You have cooked
the scum for all the Europe!
Oh, kiddies!
Oh, oh, oh!
Well, today is not
the best day we could have.
The roses are yet to come.
And roses can't exist without the thorns.
Oh!!
Well, don't cry, don't cry!
A teacher is a fighter above all!
Stop that, stop that!
How could you become so spoiled
in the face of the foster children?
How do you look like?
What a hair-do! Tidy youself up!
It's all your fault! You allowed
them to get out of hand! You!
Calm down! A prim young lady!
- Oh!
- Take it easy!
Our stallion is neighing!
A sacristan's voice!
Half-assed Shalyapin! Ha!
You chewed it!
And this fellow is bawling!
Let's have a talk with him!
Hush!
Stand up!
Ha-ha-ha! Rhinos!
Move it!
If you're late for breakfast...
you'll have it at supper!
Vilmgentel, free gunner!
Dirty guys are not admitted
to the breakfast!
The next one!
- This way!
- The next one!
Here he is!
- What has happened to them
today? -Back your hands!
A roll-call!
Gromonostsev! Gromonostsev is absent.
- Delay his helping.
- I'm here!
- Japaridze!
- Chernikh!
- I'm here!
- Kosorov!
- Yonin!
- I'm here!
I'm here!
- Golubkov!
- Pilnikov!
- I'm here!
Start eating!
From this day everything
will be in another, organized way.
Guys, we start the new life.
We won't be waiting
for the new school year!
The lessons will start after the
breakfast, from morning till night!
You all are the pupils of the school
Of individual upbringing,
named in honour of Dostoevsky.
- SCID! - What?
What did you say?
SCID! Shortly, in a Soviet way...
SChool In honour of Dostoevsky.
Yes. Are you Gromonostsev?
Depending on the level
of your knowledge,
You are divided into 4 companies
like in the army.
Now I'm going to introduce
the teaching staff.
My name is
Victor Nikolaevich Sorokin.
VicNikSor!
Gromonostsev! The first
remark is the last one!
My deputy... teacher of German.
Ella Andreevna Lumberg.
- EIAnLum!
Get out! Stand up!!
You'll have your breakfast at supper!
Sorry.
A teacher of history... Al Nik... well,
Alexander Nikolaevich Popov.
AINikPop!
Chernikh! The first remark.
A teacher of gymnastics.
Wow! A hefty chap!
A knacker from the slaughter-house!
A beefcake!
Konstantin Alexandrovich Mednikov!
KonstAIMed!
Chernikh, you'll have your breakfast at supper!
But what have I done?
What have I done?
Don't be naughty!
Change your clothes! Be quick!
Oh, kiddies!
My name is Amalia Skuratova.
- AmaSku!
What?
American Skunk!
No, the underwear is not American.
It's our, domestic, from institute.
What do you give out?
Hey, American skunk!
Let's establish the order!
Old woman! Give us the trousers!
Just a minute, kiddy...
- We go to city!
- What?
- We go to city!!
- But nobody comes to city!
That'll do!
Now you are all go to lessons!
You are the pupils of the 4th senior company,
you have a lesson of literature.
I wish.
- Well, how do you find him?
- What?
Do you like him?
No. And you?
You know, guys, the revolution
made all the people equal.
But your teachers,
so to say.
Don't want to have
equal rights with you.
- They wake us in morning!
- They make us wash ourselves!
They make me do the same!
- It seems to me we'll get on well!
- But can you sing?
Imagine that I can!
And even not bad.
If you can... sing now!
- Should I sing? But what
about the lesson?
There is still time!
It's never too late to learn!
Well, what can I do, hooligans.
Can somebody stand at the door?
Goga, be a jigger guy!
Everything is okay.
Come on!
You sing for 2 weeks!
You must remember that you are
A teacher of literature above all.
Undoubtedly. That's why there are
Russian classical literature
And city folklore in my vocal repertory.
Sit down.
What did you say?
City folklore.
Don't marry students
of industrial schools?
They are fat like sausage?
They are fat like sausage...
What do you teach?
I teach Great Russian literature,
but I introduce a new method,
Which deeply differs from yours,
which is of old regime.
Do you really beleive it's new?
Absolutely!
Yes. We won't get on well with you.
Now you can...
Don't leave us! Come back!
- Pavel Ivanovich, come back!
Farewell, friends, I couldn't do
many things that I had conceived!
Excursions to opera, and free
reading of Russian literature, and...
- Hurray, herculeses!
- Hurray!
Hooligans! Let's kick up a row, such
as the world has never seen before!
Victor Nikolaevich, let him sing
instead of this outrage...
It may be better if we take him
back for a period of probation.
- That's it!
- Indeed!
- Liberals!
I dismissed him and I don't intend
to change my mind!
I propose to create the government
of our hooligan State.
And I propose as a chairman
of Council of Ministers...
With dictatorial authorities!
I propose Kupets the Brilliant!
Hurray!
We declare war to teachers!
Henceforth we call them Chaldeans!
Appoint me as a Minister of the row!
The total mobilization!
Hooligans! Let's make posters!
- Propose him Minister of press!
- Hurray!
Go to classes! Friends!
Hooligans!
Hello, kiddies!
It's strange that you...
Don't be naughty!
All right! Wonderful!
The Chaldeans accept a challenge!
The school is declared to be
in a siege! Nobody will come out!
The war will last
till the final victory!
- Beat the Chaldeans!
- Hurray!!
Oh God! How terrible!
I'll show them what's what!
No, no, not this!
- But...
- No!
One, two, three!
Sigh the capitulation!
Goga! Bring the sulfur from
the chemical safe!
These are the mountebanks!
Should I call for Police?
No! On no account!
We'll overcome them ourselves!
- We burn!
Meftahutdin, wait a little!
The armistice!
Do you know, guys, that you
make a row not because of Arikov!
Because of him!
Because of him?
Who is your ringleader?
We are not the rabble!
We have a chairman
of Council of Ministers!
- Who?
- He, Kupets!
Kupets the Brilliant!
- And are you all the Ministers?
- Yes we are!
Well, let's make the acquaintance.
So, you make a row
because of Pavel Ivanovich.
And take out your
hands from the pockets.
- What did he teach you?
Many things.
Then, many things, you say.
What exactly?
- He knew well how to...
- What? How to sing?
Yeah! About sausage!
Yes! You grew fond of that
impostor for his sausage!
You are smart guys with
a great life experience.
How you could do that?
You like music. You scratched
an indecent word upon the piano.
- Our song!
- A thievish song!
Why it is thievish?
At our place Lipovka
a pickpocket stole some beer.
Ha! It's Gaudeamus!
- Right you are, Ionin, it's Gaudeamus!
A longstanding student hymn.
It's Latin language.
- And what's the Russian translation?
- Translate!
- Here it is: we are cheerful...
- As long as we are young!
But is the translation necessary?
Make up your own hymn
You have the State,
but you don't have hymn.
No.
Take this melody of Gaudeamus
and who will write the words?
You!
It'll be great!
Why not? Some time I wrote poems,
and they were not so bad.
Imagine... even Alexander Blok
was envious of my poems.
- It was he, who wrote
"The twelve"? -Yes. Yes.
- Could he really be envious?
- Well, imagine!
Of course, it was
during the certain period
Of our creative work, when we were
sitting at the same school sits.
- But I've lost my ability
to write poems. -Me too!
And who composed "The rebel"?
Very interesting and
critical newspaper.
I did!
To tell the truth, it slightly
reminds the yellow press.
But I didn't compose it myself.
Jap helped me.
Well, fine. Let's compose
the hymn together.
- Let's sing again.
- Yes!
It's interesting to see
a sunflower here.
It's the State Emblem.
This is a symbol!
Each republic has it's own State
Emblem and ours must have one.
- Indeed!
- The implication is like this.
Our school consists of pupils
just as the sunflower consists of seeds
- Do you see?
- Yes.
You know that learning is light. The
sunflower reaches for the light, too.
The principal inventor of
our emblem is Chernikh.
- Wow, brainy Yankel!
- Long live press department!
Well done, Grisha! Well done!
Long live the newspaper
and People's commitee!
We are the sunflower seeds
and Victor nibbles us!
Victor Nikolaevich!
Guys, guys!
- She's arrived!
- Who?
- A fiancee!
- A typical blond fiance!
- Kick her out from our commitee!
- Let's make herself scarce!
It's not my fault,
she comes as she likes!
- Turn her out! Turn her out!
- Immediately!
Goga! Run and tell her to clear off!
That's right, Yankel!
Just so!
- Do you need Grisha?
- Yes!
Grisha asked you to kiss off!
Good riddance to bad rubbish!
Go lay an egg!
Farewell and be hanged!
Hey, boy!
Stop!
- Is it you?
- Me!
Wait a little!
Leave me alone!
Here we are at last.
How are you doing, Vitenka,
my dear sonny!
My dear, my dear
blue-eyed boy!
I'm so happy I can admire
you before my death.
Let's go, mom. Let's go!
You are my little blue-eyed kitten!
Guys, Vicniksor is mother's son!
- Come on, come on...
- Be careful, mom!
- How do you do!
- Let's go!
- Welcome!
- Mom, it's Ella Andreevna!
- Who?
- Ella Andreevna!
Oh, Ella Andreevna! I see.
Vicniksor's mother is as
deaf as a post!
Exactly!
Guys, I forgot to introduce
A new pupil... Alexey Panteleev.
By the way, he is a future
writer, he writes poems.
Accept him properly.
We are all experts in poems!
We compose hymns!
Can you swallow the swords?
Maybe you can cycle?
We'll teach you. Goga,
it's a grammar-school boy!
They study here for nothing!
I have changed Vitya's piano
Who will cook him real pancakes?
Okay!
Who will feed him with real pancakes?
My little kitten! Blue-eyed!
Oh, Marta, if you only knew
what poems he wrote
when he was small!
My little blue-eyed kitten.
In short panties!
I smell the cabbage soup, which
is made of fresh cod-liver oil!
It's not our sealskin oil!
What are you doing?
It's a famine, do you see!
Vicniksor's mother is
blind as a mole!
Eat, Vitenka! My little
blue-eyed kitten. Eat!
Thank you, mother!
We've snatched it!
- Marta! Marta!
- She is here, she is here!
Ella Andreevna! Where are you?
You don't like it?
You have missed it, gawk!
Why you didn't steal a pancake?
Chase yourself...
What? Why do you
banish us? Hey?
Because it's mean... to rob
the blind old woman!
Meanness, meanness, meanness!
Go and denounce us to Vitenka!
; of SCID! An unprecedented event in our republic':
An angelic person has
appeared in our ranks!
Idiot!
What? Guys, does somebody
have a pancake?
- A pancake!
- I have!
Eat! Eat!
- Grasp him!
- Grasp!
Eat! I say eat!
You hit my tongue! Beat him!!
- Beat him in the dark!!
- Vermin!
Bump him off!
Come with me.
- It's the end. He'll denounce us.
- Indeed!
We shouldn't have cramed
that pancake into his mouth.
Of course he will denounce!
It serves you right!
Panteleev is not like me.
He won't lick your boots.
Guys! A shocking incident
has happened in our school!
Old and weak woman was offended.
I didn't want to discuss this case
While it concerned myself
personally. But...
Later I witnessed more abominable
And aggressive incident.
Guys, I understand and
even share your indignation
About your classmate's act
But even if Panteleev acted
so basely
You didn't have the right to show your
resentment in such a barbaric way
And by Lynch law! You didn't have the right!
It means that Panteleev
didn't denounce us.
Panteleev! Lyosha!
Are you sleeping?
He's sleeping.
Go to hell! You don't let me sleep.
He isn't sleeping!
Are you hungry?
- He is!
Here we have collected something
to eat for you! Do you hear?
- We'll push it under the door!
- Come on!
Don't be angry, it was a mistake.
It's Greek to me...
- So, what is our school?
- A reformatory school!
A labour settlement!
Unhappy country, suffering from
the Chaldean's yoke!
SCID republic!
- Right you are! A republic!
- Rather monarchy, then the republic!
The Monarchy!
So, our school is a republic!
But Victor Nikolaevich, in republic
the power belongs to people!
- Ha! He'll give you a thrashing!
- Ionin is right! I agree.
I suggest to give people
the power in our school.
- That's splendid!
- I offer the self-government!
Don't beleive him!
Now we elect the monitors! Of the
groups, dining-hall and cloakroom!
And who will be weighting the bread?
Don't warry, Ionin, the bread will be
distributed by SCID-citizen!
- That's right, Victor Nikolaevich!
- Well done, Vicniksor!
What a brainy man!
A brainy man!
The Council of the monitors
will settle all the questions.
You say "all the questions?"
Nuts to you!
- I will invite the monitors
to the Pedagogical meeting.
As the full members.
start the elections! The first post is the kitchen mo
- Who do you offer?
- Yankel! Chernikh!
We'll do without blonds!
Without blonds!
- Cry for me!
- Let Gromonostsev be in the kitchen!
We'll do without horse-thiefs!
Without horse-thiefs!
Vote for Gypsy!
Guys, nevertheless, but we must
have a parliament, not a mob.
I open the debate with selection of
candidates! Gromonostsev and Chernikh.
Hey, Gypsy, tell them
few words! Come on!
Gromonostsev!
SCID citizens! Dear voters!
I won't offend you, pals!
I'll give the crusts to the
senior company.
And I won't offend the
junior company, too!
The cod-liver oil must be on our tables!
The sealskin oil must be taken away!
A plenty of grub!
Panteleev!
Say, Panteleev!
Guys, we have the famine now.
We count each piece of bread.
In short, Gromonostsev
won't do here.
- We want the justice! - The honest
monitor must be in the kitchen!
Down with the horse-thief!
In my opinion Yankel is the
justest guy! I mean Chernikh.
Chernikh must be electee!
Yankel must be in the kitchen!
Down with the blonds! Down with the blonds!
Who votes for Gromonostsev?
Let your hands down.
Who votes for Chennikh?
A majority vote!
s conceived the idea of smoking? Does anybody wa
I warn:
I'll cancel both the vacations
and walks for discipline breakers.
The monitor of the cloakroom
will take their clothes off.
Oh, the great people of SCID!
You've been given the parliament,
but you've got the servitude!
I offer to choose Ionin as the
monitor of the cloakroom!
Long live the self-government!
Long live the President
of the democratic republic
Victor Nikolaevich Sorokin!
- Vivat to President! Vicniksor... hurray!
- Congratulations!
- Kapustin!
- I'm here!
- Nesterenkov!
- Rodionov!
- I'm here!
- Polunin!
- Kuzmin!
- I'm here!
- Sloyonov
- Hey, newcomer!
- Yes! I'm here!
- Savin!
- I'm here!
Start to eat.
You have bad food here.
We eat only frozen potatoes.
That's bad.
Maybe you would like to eat pancakes,
cooked with the cod-liver oil?
- Eat up your bread quickly!
- I have no wish to eat.
- Are you replete?
- A kind of.
- Give us, we'll eat it together!
- Why together? I asked first!
And I was second!
Shame on you!
That's not good.
I'll eat it myself.
On the lesson.
Finish the breakfast.
Stand up!
Wait!
Here it is! Eat! You'll give it
back to me at lunch.
How do you like that! At lunch
they give us the quaters,
But you're foisting the eighth of it now!
- It's up to you. I don't force you.
- Wait! I agree!
Thanks! Good boy.
- Give me a bit!
- Where is yours?
- I owe the newcomer.
- What for?
Please, give me some.
Fancy that!
Lend till the supper.
Then you'll give me back 2 helpings!
At supper and at breakfast!
Lend me too!
- Then you'll give me back the
whole quarter. - All right.
Hey, newcomer, give me too!
- And for me too!
- And for me!
You will all give me back
the whole quarters!
Thank you.
You are so slender!
- Rokfeller! Swine!
- Rotshild!
Purishkevich!
What are you looking here?
It's not a junior company.
I thought...
What did you think?
I thought you were hungry.
- Here it is, guys!
- Do you have more?
Of course, I don't grudge it!
No more!
- Oh! Give me!
- Leave him alone!
Ah! If we had some sugar
...and tea!
Help yourselves!
Wait a little! Hey, slaves!
Give, give!
Eat! And bring the boiling
water! Be quick!
What are you doing?
I'll smash his mug!
- Smash!
- It's impossible!
He eats three helpings every lunch!
I'm hardly able to drag my feet along.
Eat these crumbs!
Eat, guys! I don't grudge
anything for good friends!
If someone offends you... tell him!
- I wish I had some tea now...
- And sugar.
Are you drinking tea?
Bon appetit!
Thanks!
I stored up some sugar for you.
Merci!
You bribe the senior company!
You, skunk!
I'd whip you, rotten usurer!
- Let's fry him up!
- That's right! Open the oven!
Welcome!
Oh, don't! Oh, don't!
You'll all kick the bucket from hunger!
Hey, guys! They elect the new
monitors in dining-hall! Let's go!
Konstantin Alexandrovich! May we
do some more exersises?
All right! Repeat
the combination!
Have a rest!
- Give me the key!
- I'll give you what for!
- You are not the monitor anymore!
- And who is?
Savin... according to the majority
of the votes and the constitution.
Your time is expired! They
have elected the other one.
Madam, you owe
me only 250 million.
- Ah, blood-sucker!
- Merci!
- A notebook!
Here it is!
Konstantin Alexandrovich! Has
Kosorov been in dining-hall today?
No!
But there is a note that
he has got his helping.
I told you that it was
something wrong in the kitchen.
- And has Pilnikov been there?
- No.
- And Bessovestin?
- He is in a hospital.
- And Starlinsky?
- He is at his parents.
This is the result of your
self-government, Victor Nikolaevich.
Don't be naughty!
This is awful!
The shabbiest act is
To steal the last slice
Of your friend's bread!
- To leave the little ones hungry.
- It's vile and base.
Savin is dismissed!
Victor Nikolaevich! Why?
I... I didn't want!
Who received the bread instead
of the absent pupils?
- Who did it?
I'll demand for
The expulsion of Savin!
- But... where will I go?
- To cell for the time being!
Konstantin Alexandrovich!
Take him!
Let me go, I won't go to cell,
I won't, Chaldeans!
Who owes Sloyonov?
Raise your hands!
- Me!
Everybody!
- Do you all have your helpings?
- We do.
- Eat!
- But he can call for elders!
- Never mind! Let him do that.
"I guess life is a great delusion,
But I don't complain, my
soul doesn't suffer
From the grief and wounds,
because nobody helps!"
- Pay the debt!
- Ask Fedor Mikhailovich.
- Who is Fedor Mikhailovich?
Dostoevsky.
Here is the new rule: if we
owe you... you are fool!
So, you are dishonest!
All right, wait a little!
- What a mess will be now...
- What? Come what may!
It's he!
I asked to pay the debt
But he sent me to Dostoevsky!
But who do you think we are for you?
Are we your body-guards? Hey!
If you poke your nose one more time,
I'll give you a sock on the jaw!
Wait! Gypsy! Wait!
Yankel!
They put a yoke on yourself!
That's dishonest!
I didn't beat you!
- Oh, it's painful!
- Beat this skunk!
The slavery is abolished!
Victor Nikolaevich!
Release Savin!
It's impossible.
Victor Nikolaevich,
come out for a minute!
Victor Nikolaevich, we have
a self-government just now!
- You really beleive us!
- I beleive you.
Savin is not guilty.
Is it you, Ptashlya?
No! He wouldn't have hit!
It was me! Personally!
- Where did they took you?
- In Crimea.
- Have you been on resort?
- Yes.
All our pupils have hobbies.
And what about you?
The illustration of Chernikh.
- Yes, Chernikh. Are you an artist?
- Nope.
- Oh, I see... you are a musician!
Nope!
- Well, what about your
balalaika? - It's beautiful!
- Do you appreciate the beauty?
- Nope!
Is it Dostoevsky?
It is Dostoevsky.
Did you read Dostoevsky?
I read "Crime and punishment".
And do you like reading? Nope?
- Nope...
- Well.
- But do you have a dream?
- A dream?
A dream.
To eat my fill.
Mother, make fresh
carrot tea for us.
I understand you want to eat.
Well, would you like else?
I'd like to snatch this table-cloth
and make a red shirt!
- Cool?
Cool! Is that all?
I want to escape from here!
That's my dream!
It's fresh and hot! Drink,
kiddy, drink!
Mother, thanks.
Well, maybe I'll live
here for some days.
Come here, here is a place at the window!
Sprechen sie Deutsch?
(Do you speak English?)
- What?
- Do you speak German a little?
- I speak very nice!
- Wow!
- Gut. Sprechen sie.
- What?
Speak!
In German... that's abracadabra,
in Russian it means the sandwich!
Is that all?
Ofenbah, concern yourself with him.
Panteleev, go to the blackboard!
Are you hungry?
Oh, my mommy,
who is not hungry now?
Hmm, mommy...
I can't give you more
then one million.
Are you crasy?
Eat! I say eat!
- Who touches mommy... I'll kill him!
- Ha! Mommy!
- But I wanted to call him Cyclop!
- A real Cyclop! Wow!
You are a Cyclop!
I'll squash you!
Look what a loony! Okay, you
are Mommy! As you like!
- What is it?
- That's the hall door.
Do you like the handle?
- Nope! And what's that?
- A clock. Do you like it?
Nope!
- What's that?
- A mixer.
- Do you like it?
- Nope!
- I do!
When they executed my
dad near Kakhovka,
His American boots were
given to me, do you see?
Hey! Mommy!
Are you sleeping?
He's sleeping.
Look out, Kostya Fedotov.
Let me help you.
Take care.
You have stolen the last
trousers of your friends.
The trousers were school property.
They can give the other pair.
You say the"other!" They won't give
the other! There is no other pair!
Soviet Government sewed these
trousers for the last money!
Go away.
And take it.
Take.
And give it back.
Or else guys will know...
they will... you see.
And go away. We don't
need such pupils.
Kupets!
Let me smoke!
You've been cought by Vicniksor.
You turned to be a scoundrel,
Kostya Fedotov.
Kupets!
May I come in?
How will we celebrate this holiday
If we don't take
the solemn supper?
- We'll dance till one drops!
- The performance!
- What a performance, Jap?
- , Let's arrange the cabaret.
Let's invite Poddubny!
We can also invite clowns!
We can stage "War and peace"
with SCID's help.
- And we can present "Three sisters"
- I will play sisters!
And me!
Classical literature is beautiful.
But would you like to stage
anything modern? Revolutionary?
For example, "The twelve"?
We can really take it.
Great! Who wants to
take part in performance?
I can dap-dance!
I can move my ears!
I know a song!
It's very plaintive!
- Bravo!
- Well done!
A new singer appeared!
Mommy won't do!
He can slip away.
I want to be a singer! I dream of it!
I'll be damned if I escape!
I'm not sure.
Who's here?
Come here!
What?
You see, my mother feels bad.
I see!
Can you run to the drugstore
and buy an oxygen bag?
- Yes, I can!
- Will you remember?
Yes.
Here is money and the prescription.
- And the pass?
Here.
Okay.
- Say the address!
- The address is on the prescription.
Fedotov, wait! Stop!
You should put on the coat!
We are a short of time!
Wait!
Keep balalaika! They gave 40
million for it on goods market!
I'll be soon!
Stop!
Wow! Who do I see!
Ha! Kostya! Plaice!
Boatswain!
- Let's go!
- Splendid!
- Let's warm ourselves!
Let's drink!
Guys, I must go.
I'm late, guys!
Let me go, do you hear me?
Come on, come on!
Guys, I'm late! Let
me go, please!
Here we are!
Look what a dandy!
- He was going to his girlfriend!
Give it back!
What are you doing, scums?
- Oh, hooligans!
- Give me that!
Why! 2 million
and that is all!
And what's this?
She looks like nun.
- For Vitya from his mom".
- Don't touch the picture!
Let me go, they are
waiting for me!
- Madams, give us some seeds!
- Pay money!
Can we have it for nothing?
She looked at me!
And then she smiled!
- And what about you?
- Am I fool?
I smiled her like a horse!
Too early.
Why?
The less we care about a woman,
the easier to touch her heart.
Maybe I should slick my hair down?
- No, it won't help.
Close the window!
Guys, I don't like it.
Does it make any difference for you?
- Yes!
Come here.
Finally, bring your friends
here, to school.
- We doubt you'll allow that!
- Why not?
Well, swear on your mother!
As a Presinent of SCID's
republic, I announce officially:
You may come with your girlfriends
to our May-Day-holiday.
AII!
Hurray!
Hey, brunet, what do you want?
- I'm looking for Tonya! Markoni.
Tonya! Tonya, a fop
has come to you!
What? Why are you yelling?
What do you want?
Tonya, hi! Do you recognize me?
Tonya, I didn't forget my vow.
Let's go to our May-Day-holiday.
And what about you, do you
remember your vow?
- I don't.
- Why!
You told me about your dad who
was the famous American inventor.
Tonya! Tonya!
It's time to open the library!
Wait.
Look here, you,
coachman of the 1 st guild!
Good riddance to bad rubbish!
- What? Why? For good?
- For good.
- But what about the vow?
- You have recollected too late.
Good bye.
Tonya! Tonya! Do you hear?
It's time to open the library!
You exchanged us for a woman!
Long live the World's Revolution!
Hurray!
- A sister!
- How do you do!
- Come in, please!
- A cousin!
- I'm very glad.
A pretty madam.
- A second cousin.
- How do you do!
- How do you do! I'm Masha.
- Masha, come in, please!
What a pretty girl!
A glimpse of perfect womanhood!
- Is she a second cousin?
- Yes.
- She resembles you very much.
- How do you do!
What are they doing?
They smash their mugs or
they distribute the food.
Nope! They are dancing.
Hey! Do you have a light?
Mommy! Mommy!!
Super dull drummer!
Hey, bare-legged!
Half-assed scouts!
Hey, bare-legged, you'll
lose your tambourine!
- What's up? Get down from
the window-sill immediately!
Victor Nikolaevich, come here!
There are half-assed scouts!
Stop that!
These are not scouts!
These are the pioneers!
- What pioneers?
- What are these pioneers for?
Guys, the pioneers' community
Is recently established children's
communist organization.
But why should we be
scapegoats? Let's organize it too!
- Indeed!
- I'll play the pipe!
I'll play the drum!
Don't fly into a passion.
I'll make inquiries tomorrow.
They stole the table-cloth.
Teacher on duty!
Yakushka, wait, he'll
make a tie for me!
Yes!
Savushka, make a little
tie for me, please!
mat's enough. You have cut all the table-cloth to piec
Do you already have a supper?
What's new,
Victor Nikolaevich?
Guys, don't worry.
Hurry up,
Victor Nikolaevich!
They didn't permit us
to organise
both pioneer and
comsomol community.
- Why? -Why?
Because our school is
a prison-kind school.
But we don't make
a row anymore!
It's forbidden till the complete
reform of the pupil.
It's not provided in the
regulation, you see.
- Then... our faces kept
us from it.
Password!
Your money will be ours!
Response!
There's a nasty mouse
in every house! Go!
Password!
Your money will be ours!
Response!
When I came nearer
I saw the light!
We don't have the right to
organize the legal community
And so we organize the illegal one.
Bandits!
- Now, the vow! Who's first?
- Me!
I swear to serve for our
common cause
to the last drop of blood.
If I betray my organization
may the public
contempt find me!
And may my friends
condemn me.
The disgrace may be
wiped out with the blood.
Your hand!
One, two, three, four.
The inevitable has occurred!
I feel good!
The inscription on
our flag must run:
People's association, in which
the free evolution of each man...
Is a condition of the free evolution of everyone!
Karl Marks wrote this
in his manifesto.
- Go to bed.
- But...
Don't tell anybody!
I don't understand anything.
Jap! Why you don't bathe?
Merci! But who will prepare?
I have a secluded nook here.
Today at 12 o'clock as usual
we have a lesson on the garret.
Keep your eyes open!
Give the signal!
Yes!
Right face!
Follow me! Quick march!
One, two, three...
Why you are sticking here?
Beat it!
Are you deaf-and-dumb?
- Guys! Pioneers beat our people!
- Pioneers beat Jap!
SCID, forward!!
Beat the bare-legged!
Otekhnikin!
It's disgraceful!
Are they yours?
Mine.
Please, excuse me.
How could they entrust
the orphan riff-raffs to this woman!
Stand to line!
A sin and a shame!
You may be taken only
to the uninhabited island.
Orphan rats! Scums!
NAP-man! Blood-sucker!
What a disgrace!
You disgrace me!
We... we are not guilty!
The orphan kids...
What orphan kids?
What old-regime words you are using?
Okay - Dostoevsky's kids!
Hey you! Red collars!
What are you doing here?
Hey, feeble!
Play the pipe!
- Sit here or I'll put out your eyes!
- It serves him right!
Repeat! Say! Come on!
I'm a turkey cock,
red sluggard in red collar!
That's it! Repeat!
Now, abjure your
red collar, scoundrel!
It serves these pioneer
scums right!
What are you doing, dregs?
Who is this shrimp?
I ask why do you
scoff at this boy?
- Come here, sucker!
- Climb to the box for company!
Well, I'll give you what's for!
- You, single-eyed frog! You...
- Beat him! He must be pioneer, too!
Get it, pioneer's defender!
Oh my! Men, what are you doing?
You'll kill him! Oh!
Homeless Konstantin Fedotov
Wasn't scared of the
brutal drunk merchants,
He defended the young pioneer
And he didn't retreat,
until he lost consciousness.
Pals, that's our Mommy!
Thanks. Thank you! It's
the only picture of my mother.
It's not my fault.
They didn't let me go. Boatswain.
They took away your purse!
It's not my fault!
Stop that! I know it's not your fault!
You'll tell that later.
We say "hurray for Kostya Fedotov"
from all the pioneers!
Hurray!
- Mommy, make the speech!
- Hey, you'll lose your tambourine!
Guys! Stop being awake in nights!
No more secrets!
From this day
Your organization of young
Communards becomes legal!
Great!
Did they really allow
to do that?
No, they didn't.
- It means...
- Right you are!
Are you out of your mind?
I'll do it!
If I need... I'll go to
Felix Dzerzhinsky.