Good boy, come on.
Come on.
Good, good.
Whoa, stand.
There's a girl.
Good boy, good.
Steady, girl. (Horse neighs)
Come on!
Let's go!
Before they all get
out there and spread it.
Thank you, Father.
This is a splendid present.
(clock ticks) (gentle music)
Now.
(dramatic music)
(man shouts)
(wagon rattles)
(chugging music)
Just like flying.
(dramatic music)
(man groans)
(wagon rattles)
(glass shatters)
(ducks honk)
(men chatter)
[Townsman] Whoa,
whoa, whoa, steady.
Steady there, whoa!
(people chattering)
- What should we do?
- My father.
- You've cut your arm.
- Is he all right?
- [Townswoman]
- He's only cut his arm.
- What about his father?
Someone should fetch the doctor.
- No, he's all right.
- Where's my father?
[Townswoman] They
say his neck is broken.
[Townsman] What
about his father?
[Townsman] The
bloody man was driving.
[Townsman] Rich and
dangerous, that's their trouble.
- Try rich and stupid.
- It's my birthday.
Happy birthday.
(chickens cluck)
Yes?
There's been an accident.
[Woman] How bad?
Very bad, Your Ladyship.
My son?
He's not badly hurt.
My husband?
(sombre, graceful music)
(thunder booms)
(rain patters) (sombre music)
(clock ticks)
Why do I not recover?
(thunder booms)
The arm's infected.
I'll unwrap it and
change the bandages.
Then we'll see
what's to be done.
Get off, get out!
Go away!
A little attention to
cleanliness would help.
(thunder rumbles)
[Harry] Are they
talking in the town?
Yes, they talk.
They wonder how such a
thing could have happened
to such a fine reinsman.
I've wondered the
same thing myself.
There, is that better?
Where's Mother?
She should read to me.
I should think
the mating fence.
(fire sizzles)
The mating fence.
The never-ending fences.
Why hasn't he recovered?
What I...(sigh)
His father was the same.
The least cut would
suppurate, leave a scar.
I know that.
And then there's the climate.
So many factors
could contribute.
Mumbo jumbo.
Might as well employ a witch.
He's not strong
enough. Not only in body,
but in mind, as well.
He's still too much of the boy.
You seem to manage very well.
[Woman] One thing I can't do.
What's that?
I cannot sire an heir.
You have an
heir, he's upstairs.
Useless!
(hooves squish)
(children shout)
Jonathan, get off that table!
[Man] Matthew!
(children chatter)
Quiet!
Get off that table.
[Townsman] Would you
come here this minute?
- [Townswoman]
- Give me that pillow!
Get over here.
[Townsman] Get down
from there, come on.
(person coughs)
(children giggle)
(door slams)
Well?
Is it to do with his
wasting disease?
Perhaps.
Now, this won't hurt a bit.
(people chattering)
White gangrene
has set into his wound.
Michelangelo
couldn't do it better.
Where's he live?
So quickly?
The two must be connected.
Where, in the swamp, does he?
They may be, but
I need more proof.
Sometimes, Sarah, you
jump too quickly to conclusions.
Does he?
Did you tell him
what must happen?
No, I couldn't
bring myself to.
Can I go?
Then I'll tell him.
I'd prefer that.
- I know.
- Can I?
Yes!
Here.
(person coughing)
(townspeople chattering)
(children teasing)
[Townsman] Matthew!
Matthew!
(townspeople chattering)
Your mother
said to tidy you up.
Take off your boots, damn you.
You're making the floor shake.
(dish rattles)
Tidy the room and
leave me alone.
(sombre music)
Every movement hurts it.
It can be stopped.
By cutting it off?
I've stolen your thunder,
and I know very well
how much you hate that.
The horses, who'll
exercise the horses?
I won't be able.
When?
Tomorrow.
No.
Do it now.
I'm not frightened.
I'm glad.
Glad?
Oh, Harry.
My father.
It was my fault.
It wasn't an accident.
I fainted, I lost control.
Harry, it wasn't your fault.
But sometimes, sometimes
I can't convince myself
that it was just an accident.
Because I don't believe there
are such things as accidents.
Harry.
(tender music)
How can you bear to do that?
I just close my
eyes and pretend.
Pretend that you
are still pretty.
(tender, soft music)
This faintness, has
it happened before?
(sombre music)
(saw grinds)
(bone snaps)
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
Perhaps now he
won't be able to do
the things that exhaust him.
Cricket,
horses,
hunting,
the foolish racing.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
(Harry screams)
(hooves thunder)
(dramatic music)
(wagon rattles)
(percussive music)
Get up, get up!
(hooves thunder)
Get up, let's go!
(people chattering)
(people laugh)
[Passenger] Say,
are you all right?
(people laugh)
(people chatter)
(hooves clomp)
(percussive music)
Get up!
(wagon rattles)
(percussive music)
Get up!
(wagon rattles)
(percussive music)
(people chattering)
[Townsman] Come to
the church on Sunday.
[Child] Move it, I
want to get through here.
(people chattering)
[Townsman] Ah, let's go.
Harry.
(children chattering)
How's it all going, eh?
(people chattering)
[Townswoman] Hello,
Mr. Laney, how nice to see you.
(children shouting)
(people chattering)
[Townsman] Hear
the word of the Lord!
(children chattering)
Don't be stupid, Harry.
These people have
memories like elephants.
Even if you could cope,
it would be madness
to be seen driving here.
Harry, Sam will drive.
- [Townswoman] Here, Mrs.
- Row, let me help you with that.
How long are you staying?
(wagon creaks)
Jesus, man, will
you watch the road?
Mother, the man's an oaf.
He can't handle
horses of this calibre.
I thought he was
doing rather nicely
now he's cut down their food.
No, I only cut down their feed
so that he could handle them.
This is no way to treat horses!
It's only a temporary solution.
I won't have them
worked like this.
Perhaps we ought to sell them
before they lose
condition completely.
Don't fiddle.
That girl gets a lot of post.
She sends for things.
[Mother] Does she?
Yes.
I suppose this means
a stop on the way home.
Yes.
(wagon creaks)
Mother.
Yes, Harry?
Her father wants a
sample of my urine.
I'm sure he has good reason.
(chuckles) He wants
to taste it. (Chuckles)
How extreme.
Shall you let him?
Harry.
What?
Self-pity is never attractive.
(wagon creaks)
Pass the butter.
You're not eating.
[Harry] No.
You should.
Well, obviously I should.
The food is disgusting.
[Mother] I know that.
Nevertheless, you
ought to make the effort.
[Harry] I know.
Hey.
It seems, Harry, we
have reached an impasse.
Mother, I think I found
the right man for my horses.
Please, Harry!
I would appreciate it
if, just for a moment,
you could think, talk,
about something else
other than your horses!
We need a maid, Harry,
housekeeper, butler,
a cook or two, a footman.
Gold, it's like a disease.
Well, you never know
what might turn up.
Well, I do know, Harry.
That's the discouraging part.
They come, they go,
they drink, they fight,
they frighten the horses.
In short, Harry,
it's not like home.
At least your father
talked about it,
which was a comfort.
(sighs) Damn it, Harry.
Why do you think I do it?
Why do you think I
struggle so to make
something out of nothing?
You enjoy it, Mother.
That's hardly
the word I'd use.
Oh, what is the word?
One day, I'll tell you.
[Harry] You
confuse me, Mother.
(sighs) I know.
(gentle music)
(people chattering)
(people singing)
♪ Life is but a dream ♪
(people chattering)
(people singing)
(man chuckles)
(people chattering)
(people singing)
I came here to talk to you.
I need someone.
Someone I won't want to throttle
every time I see his
hands on the reins.
I think you love horses,
and you drive
as I would myself.
To do so, I would give you
twice your present wages,
board and lodging
into the bargain,
and a team second to none.
- No.
- As many men
as you want to work under you.
You'd be a fool to refuse me.
(man laughs)
The Leviathan's finished.
The steam train will
replace it within the year.
(people chattering)
So um,
what do you think?
I told you, no.
Why?
Well, sir, my lord, this
way, I'm my own master.
[Harry] Oh, really?
Well, to the extent
that any working man is.
I do my job, and
they leave me alone.
From what I've heard about you,
it wouldn't be like that.
I'd be at your beck and call.
Or at your mother's
beck and call.
I don't wanna be owned.
Well, you wouldn't be owned.
You'd just have the
best team on the road.
Can't you see it?
[Ned] Yes, I
can see it, all right.
Well then.
Don't worry, I'd see you right.
I'd look after you.
I don't need you or your
job or any other bugger.
Oh, yes, you do.
You just don't know it yet.
Well, you make
me laugh, I'll say that.
Shall we have another?
Why ever not?
(woman laughs)
(people chattering)
[Townsman] Rick says
he can't hold his liquor.
[Townsman] On the
count of three, one, two.
(people laugh)
See the bugger in the afternoon.
(men chatter)
(birds warbling)
My God.
I think we might pursue it.
[Sarah] What have
you been up to, Harry?
Nothing.
Just been drinking, that's all.
Harry, listen to me,
this was more than drink.
You must know that.
I'd not dismiss the drink
so lightly, if I were you.
I'm so thirsty.
I know.
But, first, you'll pass
water for Father.
I can't move.
You won't have to.
(water gurgles)
(urine filling jar)
[Doctor] Reading
at the table, Sarah.
Your mother would
never permit it.
I know.
Just as well she's dead.
Sarah.
Sorry, my mind was elsewhere.
Really, I am. I don't
think sometimes.
You won't like to hear it,
but you're very like her, very.
Well, let's be glad
for that, then, shall we?
I am, every day.
There's no future in
the relationship, Sarah,
and you know it, no matter
how serious his intentions.
He hasn't spoken of it.
But he will, and then?
I love him.
[Doctor] I need
hardly point out
to you the consequences of that.
No.
For that woman to yearn
for an heir as she does
is, in my opinion,
selfish and wicked.
I love him.
That will pass.
I hope so.
I hope for that more than
anything else in this world.
(gentle music)
It's so sweet.
So we're agreed
about the diagnosis?
(gentle music)
(people chattering)
[Child] Hey, come on!
Yay!
(children shouting)
(people chattering)
[Driver] Come on, hop down.
[Child] Please, take
me to Sydney with you.
Get down.
(children chattering)
(horn honks)
Get up there, come on, yah!
(wagon rattles)
(children shouting)
(horn honking)
(birds tweet)
(horn honks)
(hooves clomp)
(wagon rattles)
(dramatic music)
Get up!
Do the horn, Ray.
(horn honks)
Get off the road!
- [Man On Horse]
- Pull over, you idiot!
(tense music)
Get off the road, you madman!
You (indistinct).
Keep it straight, lads!
(tense music)
Watch your heads.
(glass shatters)
(tense, dramatic music)
Get up, get up!
Pull over, you idiot, pull over!
(exciting music)
Steady, now, steady.
Steady, now, whoa, steady.
(chickens cluck)
(dramatic music)
Now come here!
Wait till I get you home
and I tell your father.
(people chattering)
Come back here!
(horn honks)
Steady.
(train chugs)
(horn honks)
(children shouting)
Good morning, Scott.
[Passenger] Who's
in charge here?
- [Passenger] What happened?
- What the hell happened?
Why don't you listen to me?
Why don't you ask
me what happened?
No one seems to
be congratulating us
for keeping this bloody
thing on its wheels
or the horses on their feet!
Anyone else driving
and you would have had
a proper accident on your hands.
[Passenger] The driver
must take responsibility.
It was reckless
driving in the extreme.
[Passenger] You're lucky
you didn't lose any lives.
(people chattering)
And as for that idiot.
If he brings any action,
then the bloody company
can answer for me,
but I'm not leaving a
forwarding address.
- You wanna keep this job?
- I'm saving you the trouble.
Damn your job and
damn the company!
(people chattering)
The Leviathan's finished!
The steam train will
replace it in a year!
(people chattering)
(horn honks)
(hounds bark)
[Hunter] Tally ho!
(sheep bleat) (birds tweet)
(Ned knocks)
Come.
Yes?
I'm the coachman, if you-
- [Harry] Huh?
If you remember, my Lord.
Oh, yes, I remember,
on the Leviathan, as I recall.
Is that it?
Not any longer.
Oh, why is that?
Well, it's a long story.
(Harry laughs)
Ned, I don't need your story.
It's enough to have you here.
I'm overjoyed to see you,
and I'll make you glad
of it, too. See if I won't.
Come on!
I haven't agreed
to anything yet.
Sam, Sam!
Ah, there you are,
fetch the horses.
(chickens cluck)
(water roars)
(hounds bay)
Ah, here they are.
Look at them, they're
a perfect match.
They were my father's.
This is Nightingale.
Come here, come here, come here.
- She's very free.
- And difficult.
I find her perfectly
manageable.
Using a lot of tact, that is.
That's Apollo.
He was injured
during my accident,
and I was too ill
to look after him.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy there.
We should get them
out as soon as possible,
assess his condition, and, well,
I'll leave it
entirely up to you,
should you take the job.
There is one more thing.
(graceful music)
It's a cobweb.
A cobweb on wheels.
(laughs) I knew it.
I knew you were my man.
(horn honks)
(hunters chatter)
Hello, Mother.
Perhaps you'd like to have
a word with Mr. Devine.
He's our new coachman.
Not now, Harry.
We expect our servants
to take baths, Mr. Devine,
once a fortnight.
Did Harry tell you that?
All over, not just
the extremities.
(hunters chattering)
Shall we go up to the house?
I'd like to finalise
our arrangement.
Is it agreed?
It is.
(hunters chattering)
One more, Sam.
[Hunter] Hear, hear.
(hunters chattering)
(wagon rattles)
(exciting music)
See?
It's just like flying.
(exciting music)
I'd like your opinion.
I'm trying to
tempt his appetite.
I don't know.
I certainly don't.
Dare say you've found
a name for it by now.
Your father's been
hinting as much,
but the man can
spit nothing out.
Diabetes.
And is it fatal?
Often.
They say they're not
ready till you can eat
them with a spoon.
And it's in the blood?
We think so.
Time does not exhaust it?
No.
(graceful music)
Go on, go on. Please, say yes!
Why?
Sarah must meet Ned,
and Ned must meet Sarah.
[Mother] He's
a servant, Harry.
Well, I know he's a
servant but just at the mo...
Listen, Mother, at the moment,
Ned and Sarah are the most
important people in my life.
Apart from you, of course.
And I wanna show
them off to each other,
and I need the carriage.
Surely, you don't
need it for just one day!
You exhaust me, Harry.
Please, say yes!
Yes.
(soft music)
He'll be home soon.
Tomorrow morning, then.
(soft music)
My sleeve is empty,
but my hand, it reaches out,
touches you.
And you feel nothing.
(soft music)
How wrong you are.
(wagon rattles)
Get up, Busy, come on.
(laughing)
Come on, ready.
Ready?
Come on.
Ready.
Right.
(ball thumps)
I've been practising. (Chuckles)
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking it's worth taking
a good deal of
care in this life.
Not to get shot at or maimed.
Or hanged.
[Mother] Have you no work?
Get up.
(wagon rattles)
I'm sorry, mother,
we were delayed.
Daisy threw a shoe.
[Mother] Daisy threw a shoe?
She did.
Where, pray,
did Daisy throw it?
Over the windmill,
perhaps, over the moon?
Mother, I fear-
- Don't lie, Harry,
you're not good at it.
As you see, we have a visitor.
Oh, are you ill, Mother?
Not yet, Harry.
The doctor was, what
were you doing, Doctor?
Repaying the compliment.
May I put it like that?
You may put it how you like.
I must go.
What compliment?
The compliment
of your calls, Harry.
Those you've been paying him
in the afternoons
while he's out.
I see.
I'm glad of that, Harry.
It'll make my task
in pointing out to you
that these visits must
cease so much the simpler.
Wait!
You'll not be happy not
hear it, but there's more.
It seems, Harry,
the impetuous Sarah
has confided to her
father that she loves you.
What?
Sarah has confided to
her father that she loves you.
Under the circumstances,
Harry, I find the pleasure
you take in what I just told
you quite beside the point!
No. Under the
circumstances, Mother,
it is the only point.
Don't mimic me, Harry!
You aren't a parrot.
What you are is a fool!
Why, why a fool, because
I'm happy someone loves me?
I love her, too, Mother.
You grow more
foolish by the minute!
What is wrong with Sarah?
It is not what is
wrong with Sarah.
It is what is wrong with you.
What?
What is wrong?
(sombre music)
(Mother weeps)
My childhood illness?
I feel I'm over it.
Just lately, I've
never felt better.
My arm.
I'm practising, Mother,
I'm practising learning
to live without it.
You should see what I can do.
I'll show you.
Now I've got Ned, I...
(Mother weeps)
(solemn music)
Mother, please.
(crickets chirping)
(gentle music)
(woman sighs)
I came here to talk to you,
because it seemed so silly.
I've talked to father about you
and your mother about you but,
never to you about you.
Harry.
Harry!
I do.
Do what?
Love you.
I do love you.
You're not listening, are you?
No.
Please, Sarah... No, you please.
Please listen!
If it's about my
mother, I don't,
my mother can go to hell.
She hates you, so
she can go to hell!
She's worried, Harry.
No, she's,
desolate.
Desolate, I don't...
Sarah.
I love you so much,
but I'm afraid.
I'm afraid our talking
will spoil things.
Why do you say that?
You might say something
that you can't take back.
I see.
But I must.
(pot clatters)
I mean, do you
know what I think?
No, but I would like to.
All right, well I'll tell you.
It is interesting, I suppose.
Interesting that you enjoy I,
talking behind my back.
Mother and you, you and Mother!
You're the two black
announcers at my death.
(crickets chirping)
(clock ticking)
(eerie music)
[Man] Now.
(ominous music)
I wish we could run away.
I wish we could marry,
and live in a cave.
How did you get in?
I flew.
Round the roof, and
down the chimney.
(tender music)
This low, hectic
fever never leaves me.
It's you, Sarah.
(gentle piano music)
(birds chirping)
(rooster crows)
(cockatoos squawking)
(hooves clopping)
(coach rattling)
Don't say it, Father,
don't say anything.
I wasn't going
to say anything.
Would you like some tea?
Yes, please.
But I do worry,
in silence, that is.
You needn't.
(hooves clopping)
I'm happy, Father.
I can't help it.
And should you help it?
Perhaps.
Because of Harry.
Your happiness or otherwise
can't make any
difference to him.
There's nothing you can do.
But there is.
Just today, on the Leviathan,
I'm expecting the latest
book on his condition-
- Sarah, it'll take more
than a book to cure Harry.
It's impossible.
I despise your
relentless pessimism.
I'm a realist, that's all.
I agree there are
things that may
aid his recovery
this time, but after.
Anyway,
Harry's as much a
pessimist as you think I am.
For once, his
mother's powerless.
She's watching
her dreams crumble
with the death of
the Ironminster name.
How ridiculous
she is, so selfish.
[Father] Yes.
To mourn the death of a name.
Have you discussed
these things with Harry?
No.
Then how do you know that
Harry doesn't mourn with her?
I don't.
(people chattering)
- Hello.
Good.
That's very good, violet head.
They drove as
careful as they could.
(coach rattling)
(hooves clopping)
Steady.
(birds chirping)
It's my fault.
I shouldn't have sent for him.
He was for Harry.
I thought we could train
it to do things for him.
Be his right hand.
Well, it was a good idea.
But unkind.
Poor little thing.
Here, let me take him.
I'll bury him for you.
Oh no,
I'll find a use for him.
Well, if there's
nothing I can do,
then I'll be getting back.
Ned?
Sarah?
Do you mind working for Harry?
No, not Harry.
I was thinking, what with
the fly and everything,
seeing how it takes
his energy, well,
I thought that you
might resent it in a way.
And me with it.
No.
I'm grateful to you.
His only real pleasure
is what you do for him.
Well, then I'm glad.
(Sarah sighs)
And as for this, it
must remain our secret.
I won't have Harry
getting morbid over it.
(hooves clomp)
Steady, girls, walk.
Walk.
Hold steady, girl.
You should marry Sarah.
No, I can't.
She loves you. Marry her.
No, her father's against it.
Why?
Well, he knows I
couldn't make her happy.
Well, her father's wrong.
She wants you, doesn't she?
So to have you
will make her happy.
It's a simple thing.
Marry Sarah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Harry] You go and get
her and I'll hunt out Mother.
Get up.
(wagon rattles)
(birds cry)
(Ned knocks)
[Sarah] Is it Harry?
There's nothing wrong?
No, nothing.
The opposite, in fact.
You're to come to the house.
- The house?
- Mm hmm.
Well, you are mysterious.
You won't tell me, will you?
Uh uh.
Then I won't ask.
It's marvellous, isn't it?
It's been a wonderful
study for me.
This is very like
our own, you know?
(gentle music)
Well, I won't keep you waiting.
No, I don't mind.
He'll keep.
It's wonderful.
I've never understood
Harry's passion for this,
but now I do.
Can we go faster?
We can, but we won't.
The road's not good enough.
Well, can't we go somewhere
where we can go faster?
No, the horses are tired.
Oh.
(gentle music)
Sometimes it doesn't
hurt to stretch them a bit.
Get up!
(wagon rattles)
(dramatic music)
Get up, get up!
Get up!
(dramatic music)
Go!
(hand smacks)
Come on, Ned, tell me.
(Sarah chuckles)
I understand that you...
Well, Ned said...
Well, he didn't say, but
he hinted of some surprise.
Harry?
Come, Sarah, not a surprise.
Surely you expected
this proposal?
Proposal?
There's been no proposal.
I'm sorry, I should've
asked you before I...
Ned said-
- Ned?
Yes, Ned.
He said-
- I have no desire to
know what Ned had to say.
Wait, I-
- I have no desire to know
what anyone has to say.
Rather, I shall have my say,
and the subject will be closed.
You yourself told
me that any children
my son might have
would more than likely
carry his disease in their turn.
Now, Sarah, with your
outlook and upbringing,
surely it is not your intention
to produce a sickly child.
You would take steps to
avoid this, would you not?
That is none of your business.
I'm making it my business.
Why, in these rather
dismal circumstances,
have you encouraged my
son to want to marry you?
I have not encouraged him.
But I do want to marry him.
Then I can take him to London,
where there's a man,
an expert on diabetes.
The function of
marriage, Sarah,
is not to further
medical research.
It is to produce children.
Sons to inherit and
carry on the line.
Marriage is something I
have longed for for Harry,
but it cannot be.
(door slams)
Harry-
- Mother is right.
She's right.
(door slams)
I want you to
take me home, Ned.
I would've thought Harry
would want to do that.
Well, he doesn't.
What's happened?
There'll be no marriage.
And, Ned, you shouldn't
have suggested it.
It's embarrassed me.
Well, I didn't
mean to do that.
I saw you leaving the
house one morning,
and, well, I just thought...
Well, you must've expected it.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have.
Wouldn't have?
Wouldn't have what?
I see.
Well, Ned, an
expectation of marriage
played no part in my action.
I love him.
I'll have the carriage
around the front of the house
directly, Miss Redbridge.
Thank you, Ned, but I
have changed my mind
and I will walk.
(chickens cluck)
(peacocks cry)
I can't believe the hurt I feel.
This marriage would
not have been perfect,
as a marriage between
us should've been.
It would've been
unnatural to avoid children.
'Tis not a matter
of unnaturalness.
It's a matter of common sense.
I don't have time
for common sense.
And, Sarah,
I've come to realise
that it is only through his
children a man goes on living.
Wait!
I will not.
I love you.
[Sarah] And love
conquers all, is that it?
I don't know.
It might.
Yes, it might.
(sombre music)
(Harry sighs)
One by one, the stars go out,
and I'm left alone.
You understand,
don't you, Father?
(Harry splashes)
(birds tweet)
Mother loves the world.
She's made a great
investment in it,
which dies with me.
Then don't die.
So much of this is up to you.
It's inevitable.
All death is inevitable.
Is that really
all you can say?
It is inevitable, but
it may be postponed.
And you're brave, Harry,
even strong in your way.
Don't, Doctor.
Your sudden good
opinion of me tires me.
It all tires me.
That will pass.
This time.
This time, yes.
And, after that, a few
simple precautions, that's all.
A meat diet, for example.
You know. I've never really
cared for it much, this world.
Life is mother's
passion, not mine.
I know that, Harry.
I recognised it in you long ago.
Recognised it?
I recognise it, I do
not in the least admire it.
Over the years, I've
come to understand
that the man who despises
the world and all those in it
is likely to despise
himself even more.
And that this same
man, will do his best
to make those that love
him as unhappy as he is.
(gentle, sombre music)
Sarah will visit
you this afternoon.
(Harry snorts)
Doctor.
Would you tell Mother
I'll join her for dinner?
You shouldn't.
And ask Ned to come.
Would you?
Thank you.
(water gurgles)
[Sarah] Sometimes, it's
so hard to think of death,
the darkness of death.
Then don't, it's not natural.
A passion for
naturalness is something
that you and Harry both share.
I wouldn't know about that.
Do you like children, Ned?
Well, everyone likes children.
Sometimes, I get a
little frightened of Harry.
Oh.
And, other times, I
need someone more.
A friend.
I was so glad when you came
because I thought we might
be friends. The three of us.
I can't be your
friend, I'm a servant.
I'm his servant.
Ned, it's all right.
Ned, I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
It won't happen again
because if's wrong.
(insects chirrup)
(clock ticks)
Harry?
Would you like to talk
about your horses?
Do you miss Father?
Yes, I do.
That morning.
We were going to
go faster than ever.
A race against time, he said.
But we never did.
I know this is complicated,
but it's come down to this.
We never finished that race.
Ned is going to help me do it.
That's what we were
talking about this afternoon.
I suppose that's
why he came, really.
You may not understand, Mother,
but it'll be my own small stab
at this immortality of yours.
Not much, I know.
Certainly not what
you had in mind.
But, for the time
being, it's all I can do.
(insects chirrup)
Conditions are perfect.
I rode the course
this afternoon.
[Harry] Mm hmm.
And the horses
will never be fitter.
Neither, I dare
say, will I. (Chuckles)
I thought you'd be pleased.
I am. I am, Ned.
It's just, I'm
tired, that's all.
Tomorrow morning, then.
Would you like the horses, Ned?
Hmm?
They're more yours than
mine, really, aren't they?
I couldn't accept such
a gift, you know that.
No, I don't.
Don't be so coy.
Do you want the horses?
Is there anything you need?
Well.
'Night, Ned.
Goodnight, Harry.
(exciting music)
Next time, we'll do it,
we'll have your time.
(exciting music)
(wagon rattles)
Steady, steady, steady.
Why did you do that?
Because...
Because it's meaningless.
(thunder rumbles) (rain patters)
Hello. We're not open yet.
He says you're to come.
He says it's time.
Come where?
You're supposed to know.
He said you would.
(rain patters)
(thunder booms)
Now that such things
have no meaning,
you'll not be
needing my services.
Which is, perhaps, a good thing.
It has become
difficult here for me.
Difficult?
Is it my illness?
The extra service it involves?
No, and you should
know it's not that!
[Harry] Well, damn it, man,
will you tell me what it is?
[Ned] I can't.
Perhaps I can guess.
Perhaps.
Is it that you desire Sarah?
And is it.. She
desires you in return?
She loves you.
I can't love her as
she should be loved.
[Sarah] Harry!
Over here.
Our cave, Sarah.
The one you wanted to live in.
Ned is thinking of leaving us.
We must think of something
that will change his mind.
I have a longing to be well.
It's like a pin
through my heart.
But I'm ill, and I
always have been.
You see, I've been a great
disappointment to Mother.
She wanted someone
strong, someone reliable.
Someone who could see to
things after she got too old.
And then she got me.
You know, she talks
about immortality,
but you know what
she really wants?
Just someone to remind her.
Ned.
From the beginning,
I've felt, between us,
a likeness of spirit that I
haven't found in any other man.
A likeness of spirit I
should have hoped
to share with my child.
And, when I die, I won't mind,
because you'll be there
to be everything I
ever wanted to be.
Sarah will be there, being
everything I ever wanted to have.
A child, Ned, yours and Sarah's.
It could be mine, as well.
A likeness of all our spirits.
Will you do this for me?
It would give me
the courage I need.
(gentle music)
(Sarah moans)
(soft music)
[Sarah] What's that?
Tennyson.
It's yours, look,
you wrote in it.
"Sarah Redbridge, her book."
I suppose you brought it up here
one day and forgot about it.
What are you doing?
[Sarah] I think I should
stay like this for a while
to encourage the
fusion of sperm and ova.
Oh, right.
I love you, Sarah.
First of all, I love you.
Promise me you'll
never forget that.
"Concerning diabetes. I have,
"in the course of
my medical life,
"seen a good many instances
of this formidable disease.
"Of late years, a considerable
proportion of such cases
"have got well under my care
"or have had their symptoms
very much mitigated.”
Considerable proportion.
It's not all.
No, not all, Harry,
but there is hope.
(delicate music)
Sarah, wait a moment.
Tell me, Sarah. Are you
quite well, quite happy?
Yes.
I only asked because
my son has confided
to me that he, too,
is in a similar mood.
He tells me he's happy,
which is rare for him.
He says it's due to you.
So, Sarah, if that's the case,
no matter what has passed
between us, I'm grateful.
[Sarah] It is not
solely due to me.
You're too modest, Sarah.
I was thinking of Ned.
[Doctor] Does that hurt?
[Harry] Nope.
- There?
- Nope.
No.
(Harry groans)
That hurts.
[Doctor] Yes,
well, it's caused
by the infection in
your foot, but it will pass.
[Harry] Good.
I'll increase the opium
dosage to make sure that it does.
Five grains, three times a day.
(gentle music)
I'm in love with you, Sarah.
[Doctor] I'm exhausted.
Father?
[Doctor] Hmm?
I'm going to have a baby.
You will look
after her, won't you?
If she'll allow it.
I shall do my best.
Though sometimes her pious
optimism sets my teeth on edge.
Mother?
Yes?
Would you read to me?
(Mother sighs)
You shall marry her,
Harry, I will see to that.
Dearly beloved, we
are gathered together
in the sight of
God to join together
this man and this
woman in holy matrimony,
which is an honourable
estate, instituted of God
in the days of man's innocence,
and recalling unto
us the mystical union
which is betwixt
Christ and his church,
which holy estate
Christ born and beatified
with his presence
and first miracle
(speaker fades
out). (Grand music)
(person knocks)
She says you're
to come to the house.
(Harry breathing)
Harry.
It's your foot.
It's all right,
Mother. It's all right.
(man whistling)
(birds tweeting)
Give me a death I can bear.
(birds tweet)
(hooves clomp) (wagon rattles)
(sombre music)
Get up!
(dramatic music)
(Harry laughing)
It's just like flying!
(dramatic music)
(birds cry)
(wagons rattle)
I'll not mourn him.
I will not.
(soft music)
Yes, yes, I know, Ned,
but you must go.
(sombre music)
(train horn whistles)
(train chugs)
(steam hisses)
Steady, girl.
Come on.
(steam hisses)
(boy whistles)
(train chugs)
(melancholic, graceful music)