You're here for the convention?
Biggest damn one we've ever had.
I'm not here for any convention.
What line of work you in?
I work for the government.
Auditing.
Ooh...taxes!
Well, I wouldn't worry.
I only review large companies.
Well, there's only one company around here
worth a shit...
Turnbull Chemicals.
You hear about our little tragedy last week?
No.
Bank manager, 20-year man.
Couldn't sleep, so he gets up and shoots his
neighbor's dog.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And the owner goes to take a
look out.
And he shoots him, too.
He shot the owner?
Dead.
Then his wife comes to the window and
she gets plugged.
People saying she's the stupid one.
[Laughs]
Welcome to Walton.
Hartwell. Hartwell...Hartwell...
Nope, we gave your room up.
Uh, you gave it up?
Thanks, Marge.
I don't think you understand.
My room was confirmed.
Well there's nothing I can do about it now
because we're all full up.
Look.I'm very tired, and I'm sure it's just
some sort of mix up.
So why not just give me any room for tonight
and I'll straighten it up with the manager tomorrow.
I am manager.
Oh.
So aloha, Bub!
[Drunken chatter]
- Hello?...
- Hello, Operator.
Yes. I'm new in town and I need you
to connect me with a with a hotel.
- Well just use the yellow pages. .
Yes, I would. But there isn't any phonebook
here.
- Well where is it?
Well, I don't know. Like someone just ripped
it up.
- Ripped it up?
Well...again, if you could hook me up with
uh...with uh...
Will you excuse me a moment?
Hey guys, if you just wait quietly and I'll
be finished in one minute.
[Rowdy laughter]
Hey, Alex!
Need hand with those bags? Say, how did you
know my name?
Say, how did you know my name?
Read it on your luggage tag.
Aha.
Aha. All the regular hotels be booked up on
account of the the convention.
But I think it just might know a place.
Well, come morning, you go up two blocks,
cross one, talk to Mrs. Haggerty.
Tell her Ernie sent you.
Buenos Noches Amigo!
I beg your pardon?
That's Mexican for, "Hey there, stranger!"
Oh.
Coffee?
Thanks.
You look like a sad old dog with no bone to gnaw.
It's been a long day.
What is that on your shirt?
Oh, my God.
Must have been from that palm tree.
There's a john downstairs.
Do you mind watching my bags for me?
Sure.
Oh, and flush hard, 'cause it's a long way to the government.
[Laughs]
What's the matter?
Uh,my hotel gave up my room and this this cab
driver, Ernie
He said that you might have a have a place.
Well then
I guess we're going to have to show Mr. Hartwell his room.
I wouldn't have a thing if it weren't for
Mrs. Henderson dying last night.
Dead as a bucket, just like that.
And here's the kitchen.
You mean the last person that lived here just died?
Oh, does that bother you?
Oh, well, I mean, she wasn't shot by her bank
manager, was she?
Oh, heaven's no!
Brain hemorrhage. Oh,
Oh my. That's right where it happened.
What?
They say that just before she died, she
vomited.
Oh.
I tried shampooing, but it just keeps coming back.
Uh huh.
Your keys
Good Morning.
I'm the auditor, I think you were expecting me.
We have been expecting you.
Alex Hartwell.
Sorry I'm late.
I'm Mr. Abernathy.
This is your desk.
Ok.
I'll pull some files to get you started.
Great.
You want one?
No, I'm fine.
Where are you staying?
Michelle apartments.
Haggerty's, place?.
Yes.
Why?
There's something funny about those two.
Funny?
Funny. Like they're related.
Well, they are married, aren't they?
Oh, no. I mean, they're related.
You know?
Well, they do have baby.
Did you see the baby?
I'm sorry.
I didn't see anyone.
Excuse me.
Nice lamp.
To bad it's broken.
I guess you'll have to fix it.
I guess I will
You know, a little porcelain cement will fix that
up in no time.
I'll remember that.
Listen, honey, I've got a stain on my shirt
and I need to know how to get it out.
Well, I'm not sure what it is, it seems to be
something sticky.
Right? Yeah.
Yeah, I know, I know, I mean, I wish I could
be there to help you out.
Listen, honey, I didn't get too much sleep
last night, so I'm really tired, OK?
Uhhuh. Yeah, me too.
Yeah. Yeah.
Bye.
Oh, yes, Mr. Hartwell.
I'm sorry, did I wake the baby?
Oh, you know, babies.
Anything little thing just sets them right off
Well, I hope it's OK.
It just have to get used to the new
surroundings.
[Baby Cries]
- What is it, Jellyroll?
Mr. Hartwell at the door again, Jules.
What can we help you with?
Well, there seems to be a problem with the
plumbing.
[Offscreen thump. Baby stops crying].
The plumbing?
Yes, it's making a lot of noise.
I had some trouble sleeping last night.
Oh, well, Jules will look at that today,
won't you, Jules?
Sure.
These things do have a habit of getting
worse, don't they?
Yes, they do.
Thank you.
- Mr. Abernathy.
- Yes.
It seems to be a bit of a discrepancy.
Discrepancy?
There's three hundred and fifty thousand in
the environmental contingency and only
thirty one dollars in the interest.
Sounds like a possible journal entry error.
I'll need a copy of the bank statements, just to be sure.
The bank statements aren't kept here.
I'll have to phone up for them.
That'll be fine.
It's Abernathy.
Mr. Hartwell is asking questions about the
environmental contingency fund.
He wants to see a bank statement.
Copy machine is down right now.
They'll have them brought over here by tomorrow.
[Phone rings].
Yes. Mr.
Mr. Hartwell.
That was Mr Turnbull.
He'd like to see you in his office.
As soon as possible.
Human excrement.
That's what the son of a bitch threw on at
this time.
One day I'll catch the little fucker.
And pinch his head off...like a bug.
Probably just some kid.
So how do you like our little hamlet?
Well, I've never been any place quite like it.
This is the peak season.
Name your poison.
Nothing. Thanks.
My father said never trust a man who doesn't drink.
It's a bit early for me.
My father was also an asshole.
So where are you staying?
The Michelle Apartments.
Must be hard. Being in a strange town, not
knowing anybody.
You a family man, Alex?
I'm engaged.
Left the little woman at home, eh?
I know some people that would see that as an
opportunity.
Mr Turnbull, is there something specific you
wanted to discuss with me?
What is it?
Looks like a turkey.
You're right.
Can you believe it? And there isn't a stitch
of turkey meat in the whole damn thing.
[Laughs]
Wie geht es! Guten Abend!
That's German for, "How's it hanging?"
Ahah.
I got some news for you.
- Dumplings.
- Dumplings?
und Wienerschnitzel!
Oh, I Don't know, I'm not very big on exotic
food.
That's not exotic.
It's German.
Mama made it!.
Mm hmm.
That's the spirit.
Thanks.
You planning to eat here?
Oh, Hi.
Yes. I just ordered.
I think.
Bert's been giving you the B.S. about his mama?
There you go.
Wow!
How about you, good looking?
Just two packs of the usual Bert.
I keep telling her to eat more and smoke less.
Those things will kill you!
Not any faster than my mama's schnitzel.
Shh! Don't let mama hear you say that
You survived!
Survived?
Bert's cooking.
I hope so.
Did you get your lamp fixed?
Why?
I meant to ask you earlier.
Maybe you want to give me a hand with it?
Sure. If you'd like.
Are you good with your hands?
Yes, actually. And lamps are my specialty.
Really?
Thanks.
It's always so hot in here.
It's probably the heat.
From the, uh, dryer.
Where's Flo?
- Flo...
Flo , it's me!
Excuse me. There's nobody in there.
What are you doing here?
Flo!
Oh, do you mean Mrs. Henderson?
It's me, Dirk!
Listen. Dirk.
I'm the new tenant here.
Mrs. Henderson is dead.
Dead?
A few days ago,
What happened?
Me and Flo, we had a date!
Well, I guess she won't be going on any more
dates.
That isn't funny, pal!
You make fun of the dead and the dead will be
making fun of you.
Oh!
Oh no no no.
Living the bachelor life, huh?
You want to get yourself a little lady to do
that for you.
That's a good idea.
[Machine stops]
Washing's done.
Right! [Ahem]
So then I guess I should be getting back.
Mr. Harwell, what a surprise.
[Baby Cries]
I hope I'm not disturbing you, but it's about the noise.
Yes.
Now there's a stain on the ceiling.
Oh, my.
What's up, Jellyroll?
Mr. Hartwell says that there's a stain on the
ceiling.
I didn't see no stain when I was up there.
Oh, well, Jules, maybe you should go
to Mr. Hartwell's room and take a closer look.
Sure. Anything else on your mind?
Well, there is one thing.
It seems that some of my laundry got mixed up
with someone else's.
Oh, don't say.
Yes. When I was sorting my laundry, I
discovered an extra sock.
Oh, dear, you're certainly have your fair
share of problems.
I believe it belongs to a young
woman, brunette, about so tall.
Oh, dear. Excuse me.
Listen, why don't you go get the sock and I'll take care of it.
Well I'd really rather return it myself, if that's OK.
[Off Screen]
Jules, I think there's something wrong with the baby!
Just a second, Jellyroll.
Ok, I know you're busy, so why not just tell
me what apartment she's in?
Ok, pal. She's in 303.
[Off screen]
Jules!.
Hi!
What do you want?
I think some of your laundry got mixed up
with mine.
I brought it to you.
It's in the bag.
Who's this, Maddie?
Our new neighbor.
He says some of his laundry got mixed up with
ours.
Is that right?
We have some of your laundry?
No, I do. You see, I was doing laundry with
your wife and uh...
...we weren't doing it together.
And she left and I did mine.
And then there was something in the dryer
that got mixed up with my load.
Your load.
Yes, it's Pretty common, really.
People's laundry gets mixed up all the time.
I didn't know that, did you know that Maddie?
You see, Maddy does all our laundry.
Is that what's in the bag?
Yes.
Thank you.
That was a downright neighborly thing for you
to do.
It's nothing really.
Maddy, have we got enough of that home cooked
chili of yours for a good neighbor here?
I can't stay.
I have work to do.
Maddie makes some kind of hot chili.
Don't you, hon!
Well he says he can't stay.
Sure he can.
No, really. I can't.
Come on! There's lots of food.
Oh, I couldn't.
We feel insulted if you didn't join us.
Sorry.
It's OK.
To good neighbors.
So what aprtment you in?
203.
203...didn't some old lady live there?
Yes, she died, actually.
Is that right?
Not too long ago.
I wouldn't want to live in a place where the
last person died.
It doesn't really bother me.
You must be a pretty brave guy.
Mmm, this is great chili.
Matty, you're not eating.
I told you I'm not hungry.
Open up.
Choo choo choo choo...
Wooo, woooo...
Here comes the big train.
Woo! woo! Coming into the tunnel...open up.
Atta girl.
Big train doesn't think you can get in there
unless the tunnel gets a little wider.Woo,
woo, woo!
Choo-choo-choo-choo.
Lick.
There that wasn't so bad, was it?
And she wonders why she's skin and bone.
I have to go.
I've got work to do.
Hey. You haven't finished.
What about dessert?
I bet Maddie's cooked up a big surprise for us.
She's full of surprises.
Good morning, Mr. Hartwell.
Good morning.
Had the bank statements arrived yet?
Sorry, Mr. Hartwell, the copier is still down.
I was told I would have them on my desk this
morning.
I said perhaps they would be on your desk
this morning.
It's been two days!
Well, I can't have that now, can I, Mr. Hartwell?
I'd like to see them on my desk this afternoon
Or would you rather be served with a court order.
I don't see any need for that.
You have them as soon as possible.
See that I do.
I'd like a bacon and tomato on whole wheat.
Ah, so sorry, no can do.
It's Chinese night.
Couldn't you make an exception?
Well, I wouldn't mind, but mama makes the
rules.
Your mama?
Who's mama do you think?
I don't know you...you tell me!
How about some nice chow mein with sweet and
sour pork?
Yeah. All right, that'll be fine.
Gong my fat chow, baby.
Yeah!
I got your seat right right here, darlin.
You want some of my barbecue pork?.
[Laughter]
You never learn, do you?
What?
Bert's cooking is a slow death.
Is that right?
Are you inviting me for dinner again?
I think you invited yourself.
Hmm? You probably think I leave my panties
around for other people to find.
Oh,scavenger hunt.
Lost lobster panties!
Ok, OK. Keep your voice down.
Ok. I'm sorry.
Dean thinks there's something going on
between us.
Well, what are you doing here talking to me?
I guess I like you.
Yeah, but I mean, what if he sees us?
There's always that chance.
How did you ever get together with a guy like Dean?
I got pregnant. Then he went to prison.
What for?
He killed some people.
Staying for dinner, good looking?
Just here for a smoke, Bert.
[Rock Music starts]
I love this song.
Are you crazy: Sit down!
People are watching.
Want to dance?
Oh, no thanks. I'm eating.
Woiuld you please sit down?
Oh, come on. Maybe I can teach you something.
I used to be a professional.
Shake it baby! Oh ho!
[Music continues]
And you gonna stand there all night or wait
for the next one
Going down?
Uh,actually uh...no.
Hard day at the office?
Sort of.
Yeah, me too. I'm heading out for a couple of beers.
We'll see you later.
Yeah. Have a good night.
Hey!
Want to join me?
Oh, no thanks.
I insist.
No, I've got work.
Ah!
You tried that the other night.
I'm beginning to think I can't trust you, Alex.
You can trust me. Lots of people trust me.
The government trusts me.
Well come on. I drive, you pay.
Come on!
This baby sure motors.
Three hundred fucking horses.
Hey!
Remember these?
Uh, I don't...I don't know.
Take a look. There's a stain on them.
Got any idea what that might be?
Well, if these were the ones that were mixed
up with my laundry, then I think it's a vomit stain
You're fucking kidding.
I know. They fell on the carpet where Mrs.
Henderson vomited just before she died.
And know I accidentally stepped on them.
Mrs. Haggerty said said she tried shampooing,
but it just keeps coming back.
Whoo-hoo! Whoo-hoo!
Slicing badly!
Just got her out of the shop.
Whole front end was smashed to hell.
Really?
Fuck!
What happened?
I hit a fucking station wagon.
Anybody hurt?
Fucking whore.
Fucking whore!
[Mad laughter].
Come on, lighten up
Fucking bull's eye!
Whoo-hoo!
Got an old lady, Alex?
Fiancee, and we're getting married next month.
What's she like?
Gosh, she's uh...normal.
Is she good in bed?
Yeah, she's good.
How about Maddie?
What do you mean?
Maddy's fantastic.
Well, that's good.
You want to fuck my wife?
What do you have to think about? I'm asking
you whether you want to fuck my wife and you
have to think about it?
I'll fuck herfor you buddy. Ten bucks.
Get your fucking hands off my car, asshole.
Get out.
[Screeching tires]
[Dean & Maddy argue]
Talk to me!
just talk to me.
tell me!
What do you want?
I see what you do.
I see what's going on. What do you mean? What
are you talking about?
I see what you do.
Don't you think I see what you do? I go
around, and what, I cant see?
Just behave!
[Slam!]
I just went out with your dad for a while!
[Argument continues]
Get off me! You're not hitting me anymore!
[Knock on door]
Let him go!
Get off of him!
Pigs! Oh shit...oh Dean!
[Emergency alarm]
Code Red. Code Red...Containment slash bravo...
[Loudspeaker]
Move along. Move along. Move along.
Morning, Alex.
You look like hell.
Thank you.
Not getting any sleep?
No, no, no, I feel fine.
How about I pick you up a nice hot cup of coffee
and a Danish from the cafeteria?
Sure.
- Where's Abernathy?
- I don't know.
But if he shows up.
Tell him I went for a leak. Alright?
Alright.
Turns out she'd screw he own grandmother if
she thought there was something in it for her
Yes, sir, I understand.
Nothing too big.
Just enough to shut her up.
How about the turkey grant?
Turkey grant turkey balls, I don't give a shit.
Yes, sir.
Have you given any thought About
the discrepancy sir?
Fuck the discrepancy.
I think it could be pretty important.
Trust me. I know what's important.
203.
That'll be fine.
[Knock at door]
- Hi.
- Hi, are you OK?
Dean's in jail.
I know I saw them and take them away.
I bought some porcelain cement.
I just called a cab.
Maybe you could call it back.
And if you hold the bottom of the top.
Like this?
Yes. It's great.
Oh, you have flowers.
They're nice.
They're not really mine.
Are you taking care of them?
They're starting to wilt.
Oh is this you?
Yes, that's me and my...sister.
You must be very close.
And
We're. Done.
That was quick.
Thanks.
I got some lipstick on you.
It doesn't matter.
[Knock on door]
That would be my cab.
Forget about it. Kiss me.
[Knock at door]
Hey, Alex. Open up.
[Whispering]
It's Dean!
I thought you said he was in jail.
[Whispering]
He was.
Open the door. I've got something for you.
Dean. Hi.
Alex.
You busy?
Yeah, I was just, uh...packing.
Where are you going?
I'm moving on.
I hope you're not leaving because of me.
Oh, of course not, no.
There's a stain on the ceiling..
Jesus...
What fuck is that?
I don't know, it just kind of appeared one night.
Oh, by the way...
Some guy...Abernathy?
He was at the front door today.
He didn't he didn't know the part when you were in.
So I told him that I'd get this to you.
Thanks.
At least I could do. After last night.
Right. Well, thanks for dropping this off.
Fuck!
Things got pretty wild last night.
Yeah, it looks like it.
Got any beer?
I just called the cab, but I'll check.
Hey.
Hey. This here, a picture of your fiancee.
Yeah.
Well, it looks like I'm out of beer.
Maybe some other time.
Say you know anything About Maddie doing some
kind of wild dance last night at the diner?
No, I ate there last night, but I didn't see Maddie.
What time would that have been?
Around dinner time.
Listen, why don't we go out and pick up a couple of beer?
I thought you said you had a cab coming.
That's right. But it's no problem.
Hey. Maddie's got a hat just like this,
Really?
Just got that from my fiancee.
This..Looks like Madeleine's hair.
No, that's not Madeleine's hair.
How the fuck would you know, asshole?
uh, I don't.
I mean, uh, I don't know.
This is definitely Maddie's hat.
Alright then, um...I'll tell you the truth.
She gave it to me.
Maddie?
Maddie gave you her hat?
Um... to give to my fiancee.
Why? Why would she do that?
I don't know!
Well, then come up with something fast!
Ok. Hey!
- You fucked my wife, didnt you?
- I didn't, I swear!
- Liar. You liar!
- No, I'm not lying!
Liar!
Jesus.
He's out.
- Wha...what are you doing?
- I tell you what I'm doing.
I'm getting the hell out of here.
You can't you can't leave.
Really? Sorry about everything. But I'm out of here.
If I were you, I'd be thinking about getting a divorce.
Oh, my God.
Is he dead?
What are we going to do?
We have to call police.
Are you out of your mind?
How do you think this looks?
- How does what look?
- Don't be a fool.
I'm in your apartment.
Dean comes looking for me.
And he winds up dead?
It was an accident.
Think about it.
Have you ever been to prison, Alex?
We have to work together.
He was going to kill, you know that, don't you?
And I'm the only one who can save you, aren't I?
Yes..
Do you know what we have to do?
Do you.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yeah.
We have to get rid of the body.
Yes.
Ye...
What?
[Out of breath]
I can't get him in.
Stand him up!
!
We're going up!
Just relax, will you?
We're going down.
Where are you taking that rug?
I'm taking the rug...
to get it cleaned. There's a stain on it.
Oh.
You want a hand? That looks kind of heavy.
I'm sure we can handle it.
Have a good night.
Oh, my God.
I can't go through this.
Just relax, OK?
Jules don't know shit.
[Muffled Moan]
What was that?
[Moan continues]
It's Dean!
Stop the car.
He's alive!
Stop the car!
We have to get them to a hospital quick.
Madeleine?
What are you doing?
He's alive!
Get him out of the car.
This is no good.
What are you talking about?
I have to go to the police.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. And while we're there, we can give
your fiancee a call,
hmm?
It happened in your apartment.
Jules saw you with the carpet.
Your prints are all over this car.
Now get off your lying little butt and get
him out.
Don't just stand there...
Sink him!
He's stuck.
What in hell happened to you?
Oh, that's a nasty bump.
Why don't you sit down?
When I didn't hear from you, I came round to check.
Honey, will you bring a glass of water?
The door was open.
I hope you don't mind.
[Pipes banging]
Thanks, Hon. And could you get Mr. Hartwell his packet, please?
I understand you two have met.
Now...my man Abernathy, has prepared an audit
on your behalf.
Should be everything you need to make your report.
Go on, open it.
And we threw in a little extra bonus for you
and the little woman.
Sort of a honeymoon donation.
So now what do you have to say?
Dean is dead.
She killed him.
What the fuck is he talking about?
Where's Dean?
Beats me.
She hit him in the head with a golf club.
What kind of shit you trying to pull
Hartwell?
Hartwell? What's the deal here?
[Knock at the door]
Oh, excuse me. Sorry to interrupt, Mr. Hartwell
but I thought I should take a look at that stain you mentioned.
Wow. You weren't shittin'.
Maybe you could come back a bit later.
If you don't mind.
Actually, I do mind.
Now, what the hell is this?
Dean is dead.
What?
My boy's dead?
What about the baby?
You really think I would have had it if it was yours?
Shoot him.
Just..just like that?
Honey, I love you and everything, but you really
got to start showing some initiative.
Ok, OK.
Ok, get down on the floor.
Piss off you little shit.
Get out of here.
I mean it, man, get down the floor.
Oh, for God's sake.
[Shots firing]
You got him!.
Now what?
Mr. Hartwell kills himself.
! Ok.