- Hi, I'm Taylor.
I'm 22 years old.
I'm from Miami, Florida.
I think that I'm more
than perfect for the show
because I'm cute, I'm
spunky, I'm spontaneous.
I'll try anything once.
Who can so no to me?
- What's up guys?
I'm Shawn.
There's really only three things
you need to know about me.
I'm young, I'm dumb,
and I'm full of surprises.
- Hi, my name is Ashley.
I live on a farm outside of Charleston.
- My name's Derrick.
I'm 24 years old.
I'm competitive and I'm a winner.
- The name's Adam.
I am 20 years old.
I think I'd be good
for your survival show.
- And you know cast me in the show.
Maybe it'll raise your
production value a little bit.
- Hey there.
I'm Derrick.
- Ashley.
- I'm guessing you're here for the show.
- Yeah.
It's where the e-mail I got said to be.
- Same here.
- Hey guys.
I'm Taylor.
- Adam.
- Ashley.
- Derrick.
- Is this it?
- The e-mail I got said
that we should all be
- Whoo!
Let's get this party started.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm Shawn.
I'm the winner.
Hey, Shawn, I'm the winner.
- Cocky much?
- I'm just stating the facts, baby girl.
- Okay, on that note,
you guys all got the same e-mail, right?
- Blah, blah, blah,
grand prize of $50,000.
- Wait a minute, is that an iPod?
- Yeah.
- Why do you have an iPod?
- Well they said
that we could each bring
one item of our own.
- And you decided to bring an iPod?
- You do know those
things need charge, right?
- And what did you bring, your pom poms?
- What?
This complexion doesn't come naturally.
- I don't think you're gonna need
any help with that out here.
- But if you need any help
applying it, I got your back.
- Well, I brought this.
My fiance gave it to me
on our second anniversary.
It was a really, really nice--
- Did any of you guys bring
anything that's actually useful?
- Since you're the expert,
why don't you educate us, survivor man!
- Bug spray?
- Yeah.
Have any of you guys actually
ever seen one of these shows?
All the contestants are
covered from head to toe
in mosquito bites by the
end of the first night.
- Did you bring a night light too?
- Well what'd you bring?
Muscle milk?
- I got everything I need right here.
- Welcome to reality TV.
- Hey guys.
- Are you here for us?
- Throw a line, tie her up.
- Are you sure this thing is safe?
- Tell me this thing is just for the show.
So where are you taking us?
- Is it just me or does it feel like
these trees are watching us?
- I'm a little more worried
about this floating death trap.
- Wouldn't wanna get that iPod wet.
- Honestly I think I'd rather be swimming.
- In that case, I'll
just throw you overboard.
- Stop it.
- Guys, be careful with
any sudden movement.
This thing may capsize.
- They say war flanked these hills
years before the white man settled.
Tribes butchered tribes for nothing more
than land and crops.
Blood seeped through the ground
and cried out for retribution.
What crawled out of the womb of the Earth
was a force neither man
nor God could shackle.
When settlers finally came
their eyes played witness
to unimaginable horrors.
What was one a place of life
was now a gallery of death.
Bodies littered the
earth, consumed the trees,
yet the forest seems as
if it feeds day and night
on the souls of men.
Its hunger for flesh remains unsatisfied.
Its thirst for blood remains unquenched.
Beware all mortal souls
who enter these woods.
None shall return.
- Bravo, bravo!
Now that, ladies and gents
is quality entertainment.
Coulda gone with a few more
fireworks and explosions
but overall not too bad.
- At least he looks the part.
- And he sure is cotton
pickin' good at it.
- Hey now.
- Guys, it's usually
not a good idea to make
fun of a man with a gun.
- Come on, it's not real.
All show it is.
It's just in case the Union soldiers
happen to come marching
through these here parts.
- Hey, you mind if I borrow some chew?
I hear cancer's making a comeback.
- Oh that's so disgusting.
- What?
You mean to tell me you don't
wanna play tonsil hockey
with Jed Clampett over there?
- That's it, I resign.
Dry land.
Thank God, I never thought being stranded
would look so good.
- Wouldn't want you to hurt yourself.
- Where is everyone?
- Yeah, shouldn't there be
some kinda host or camera crew?
- Hey, is this it?
- Is it really just us?
It's a Sony Handycam.
- Are you serious?
What year did they steal that thing from?
Jesus, it still
uses mini DV tapes.
Mini what?
- Guys, am I the only one
concerned that nobody is out here?
- You guys are so naive.
They probably have this whole
forest rigged with cameras.
They've probably been
watching this whole time.
I'm sure they're watching us right now.
And this, thank you,
is for our POV footage.
You know for our diary shots and stuff.
- All right, let's say you're right.
So what do we do now?
- How about we just walk into the woods
until we find a good spot?
- Wait a minute, I think we gotta be
a little bit more strategic than that.
- You got a map there, Marco Polo?
- No, but I got a little
bit of common sense.
- Why don't we just follow the river
and maybe it'll lead to
a large source of water.
- You know what, how about
we just follow the river.
I'm sure it'll lead to a
larger source of water.
- Let the journey begin.
Journey begins.
So ladies, why don't
you tell us about yourselves.
- What would you like to know?
What do you like to do for fun?
- The usual.
Sleepovers, pillow
fights in our underwear.
Mm, what do you say, Ashley?
Is that accurate?
- I prefer horseback riding,
going to the theater,
hanging out with my fiance, Brad.
So you like movies?
- No, like musical theater.
You know plays?
Yeah, that's boring.
Well as you ladies know,
the 50,000 big ones
will only be awarded to
the last man standing.
Of course man standing, obviously.
And since there's no question
that I'll go the distance,
which many females can attest to,
my question is this, who do you think
will be the first person
to leave the island?
- I'd say Adam.
Interesting.
Why Adam?
- I know his type.
Unless he can turn that hoodie of his
into a fully functional RV,
I don't think he'll stand a chance.
Oh I like that.
It would appear the kitten has claws.
- So who do you think
will be the first to go?
My money's on
Lieutenant Dan back there.
Hey Lieutenant Dan, you
want some ice cream?
Not one of us girls?
Oh don't get me wrong, ladies.
I'm going to win.
But if I had to choose,
I'd rather get stuck
out here with you two.
Who knows what might happen.
- Dreaming, lover boy.
- Who knows what may happen.
- Oh, what the hell?
What is that?
- That's so gross.
- Anybody have any idea
what type of animal this is?
Or was.
Could be a wild boar.
- It was a snare.
- A what?
- Hunters used 'em to catch animals.
My guess, poor guy tried to get loose.
And something came along
before the hunter could.
- Who would be hunting out here?
- It doesn't look that fresh,
so it's probably been a while.
- Thanks for the science lesson, Bill Nye.
I'm gonna go.
- Hey, do you need us to stop
and take a break for a second?
- Why would you ask that?
- I just noticed you were
having a hard time keeping up.
- I'm fine.
Look at me, I'm doing my part.
No, now I'm itching.
Ow, ow.
Yeah, get that fly.
That's what I do.
Pick up sticks.
Oh look, another stick.
How 'bout that.
Hmm, okay no.
You don't understand
it's more than a choice.
It's a lifestyle.
I'm just too close-minded
to understand though.
Being a furry isn't just about sex.
Well, it is for me though.
I'm bored.
Oh yeah, yeah put on some lotion.
Yeah, just spray though.
Just rub, oh right there,
yes down the thigh.
And lay back, lay back.
Yeah oh nice, nice
rotation towards camera.
Oh I love it.
I love it.
Oh just bask in all your glory.
Oh my god.
Man, can I get a hand?
- I was just thinking the same thing.
I would, but you seem
to be doing a great job.
Wouldn't wanna steal all your glory.
Harry Potter.
Keep an eye on this for me.
- I really hope if you have a girlfriend
that you actually treat
her with more respect.
You know or boyfriend, or whatever.
- You think I'm gay?
- No, I just didn't wanna
jump to any conclusions.
I'm not judging you or anything.
I just, there's this guy
in my women's studies class
and he was so--
- I'm just messing with you.
And I don't have a girlfriend.
If you haven't noticed
I don't exactly have the
most inviting personality.
- Well that's not true.
- Seriously?
- I mean yeah, just 'cause
you're not an uber extrovert
doesn't mean you're not
worth getting to know.
- Try telling that to the other
eight and a half million
people in New York.
- Come on, I'm sure you
have somebody back home.
- Actually I just got out
of being in a pretty serious relationship.
- What was their name?
- Her name was Brittney.
She had this knack for making me feel like
I could actually accomplish
something with my life.
But in the end I guess you could say
we had a difference in opinion.
- What about?
- I saw us being exclusive and she didn't.
- I'm sorry.
You're probably better off without her.
- What about you?
How did you meet your wonderful boyfriend?
- Fiance.
Brad and I actually grew up together.
But it wasn't until I went away to college
that he finally mustered up
the courage to ask me out.
I turned him down at first.
You know, 'cause a long
distance relationship.
Not really a good idea.
But every time I came home from school,
every time, he brought me a dozen roses
and asked me to dinner, like without fail.
After a year and a
half, I finally said yes
and I don't know, I've never
regretted it, ever since.
- Wow.
That's a nice story.
You should sell the rights
to the Hallmark Channel.
- I know it sounds cheesy.
But it's our story.
- I don't mind the pain of the betrayal.
Helps make me a better artist.
- Well everyone's got their own rosebud.
- Yeah.
- You know, it's much nicer in here.
- Is that a fact?
- How about you come in and find out?
- Really?
- Promise to keep you safe.
Oh my god it's cold in here.
And that's for getting me wet.
- Are you sure you know what you're doing?
- I've done this a couple times.
- My father taught me
how to fend for myself
growing up on the farm.
Did your father teach you to do this?
- I don't have a father.
- Oh.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to--
- What about you?
What are you doing here?
- What do you mean?
- You seem like you
got a pretty good life.
Good head on your shoulders.
So, why do you want to be on reality TV?
- I guess I could say
the same thing to you.
You did it!
Yes!
What do we have here?
- It's day one in the
wilderness and Derrick here
has created fire out
of practically nothing.
- It's beautiful out here.
- Yes, it is.
- Do you think they're watching us?
What was that?
- It was probably an animal or something.
It's the woods.
- We haven't seen a single
animal since we got here.
- So what?
You think a curse haunts them there hills?
- No, kind of creepy though.
What?
Shawn?
Shawn!
Shawn.
You're an asshole!
- It was a joke.
- It wasn't funny.
I really thought that you--
- The Loch Ness monster got us?
- You're such a dick!
- Do you think it's edible?
- Oh it's edible.
Question is will you eat it?
- Oh well I was hungry.
- Hmm, it's a bit chewy.
Not that bad.
- Ugh, I'm gonna be sick.
- Are you sure you guys don't want any?
I'm sure there's more around.
- He's got the right idea though.
We do need to start thinking about food.
And bugs are a great source of protein.
- If that's our only option,
I definitely just became a vegetarian.
- All right, you say that now,
give it two days.
I bet that grub over there
start looking like Big Mac.
- No way.
- The good news is I bet
there are plenty of fish,
frogs and small animals we can eat.
If we set traps maybe we
can catch bigger game.
Whoever set that snare back there
obviously had some success.
- Could we possible carve some spears?
- I really don't know how I feel
about sharp objects around this group.
- At least we have a fire.
And that's one of the
biggest hurdles out here.
- Thanks to you.
- What if it rains?
- That would be good.
That way we don't have to worry
about filtering our drinking water.
- What was that?
- What happened?
- Take a look, Rambo.
- What the hell is that?
Better question is
what would do a thing like that?
It was probably
a wolf or something.
- You know last I checked
wolves don't drag their prey up a tree.
- What do you think we
should do, detective?
Interrogate the victim?
- We need to stick together.
There are animals out here
that know this terrain
a lot better than we do.
And the last thing I want
is any of us getting hurt.
- Thanks Dad.
But I think I'll manage.
I mean, after all, it is
every man for himself.
- It's chilly out here.
Thank God we have a fire.
- After what we saw today
I'm just glad we're not in the dark.
- What are you so scared of?
You know most animals
are more afraid of us
than we are of them.
- Let's just hope
whatever it was, it's full
and far away from any of us.
- Don't worry, if it shows up again
I'll turn it inside out
and make a rug out of it.
- Guys, you know what, I really
hate to be a buzz kill here,
but don't forget, this is a game.
- What do you mean?
- My point is, eventually
there won't be no more
of this buddy buddy stuff.
I wish it wasn't the case,
but some of us are gonna be going home.
It's a competition with
50 grand on the line here.
- So what you're saying is that eventually
we all have to stab
each other in the back?
- I'm not saying that.
But like it or not
there's gonna come a time
when we gotta fend for ourselves
and forget about everybody else.
- There's nothing wrong
with sticking together.
If somebody wants to
leave then they can leave.
- I'm trying to be realistic here.
At the end of the day there
can only be one winner.
- If we're being realistic.
I think we all know
who that's going to be.
- I'm not trying to start an argument.
All I'm saying is--
- What Derrick is trying to say
is that while it's convenient
to stick with the group now,
when push comes to shove, he'll
do anything for the money.
Am I wrong?
Why don't you tell us what
you need it for so badly?
- Well I know what I plan
on using the money for.
As you guys know I'm
due to get married soon.
I was planning on using
the money to help pay
for the wedding and honeymoon.
- Where are you planning on going?
- Well we had a couple places in mind,
but I really wanna take this train
through the mountains in Canada.
And stop at all these sweet
little towns along the way.
- Sounds like a blast.
I thought you said
your parents are paying for your wedding.
- They are, but Brad and
I wanted to help out.
- Doesn't Mr. Perfect have a day job?
- Well yeah, but he's
already done so much for me.
I just...
- Well I'm just going to get a boob job.
- No shit?
- My plan is for the show
to be a stepping stone
for something greater.
I know it might seem shallow,
but I really wanna be famous.
- So your goal is to be a reality star?
- What and you're going to
cure cancer with 50 grand?
- Damn.
Now I'm thinking about
throwing in the towel.
What kinda after market
parts are we talking here?
C, D?
- I was thinking--
- I think you look just
fine just the way you are.
- No it's fine, I know it's superficial,
but I really don't mind talking about it.
- Why would you put
yourself through all that
for a bunch of guys who
aren't worth your time?
- Dammit woman, you're
killing my boner over here.
- Look, there's a difference between
being beautiful and being remembered.
Beauty is for pageants and princesses.
But the rest of us, we have
to claw our way to the top.
- I just think you should
do what makes you happy
and not what makes everybody else happy.
- I'll sign the petition.
You with me Derrick?
- It's your body.
I'd say just be sure
that's what you wanna do
before you go under knife.
- Oh gees, you sound just like my parents.
- You've actually talked
to your parents about this?
- Well when this airs I won't have to.
- So Adam, you said you're an artist.
But you never said what kind.
- I'm in this band.
We play a lotta local gigs.
But we haven't really taken off.
- What are you gonna do
with the money if you win?
- I'd like to find some dedicated members,
spruce up our gear and hopefully
record a kick ass demo.
- That's actually really cool.
What kinda music is it?
- It's kinda like, melodic hard core
meets Viking death metal.
With a touch of folk
and classical mixed in.
- Well that's nice.
Brad plays a little bit on the guitar.
- Oh my god.
- What?
- So what's the name of your band?
- I've been toying with
a few different names.
- Well what do you got?
- Nothing that great.
- Come on, let us be the judge of that.
- Yeah come on.
- Let's hear it.
- We were thinking Bloody Skyscrapers.
Or Bumper Planes.
The Fold-up Chairs.
Or The Liquid Shitters.
What?
- No, those, those are great man.
Just make sure you save
us a seat at the Grammys.
- Hey, we can't fault
you on the originality.
- Whatever.
It's not like it matters.
- Hey, don't give up hope.
Even a blind squirrel gets
a nut every once in a while.
- Speaking from experience?
- More than Brad.
- So what are your big plans?
I mean you are the winner, right?
- Isn't it obvious?
Take my winnings, move to New York or LA.
Jumpstart my modeling career.
- No surprises there.
- Come on, body like this.
Be a crime not to show it to the world.
- I'm sure you'll fit right in.
- I always do.
- I'll give you the 50k
if you can go five minutes
without making another sexual reference.
- So?
Last but not least.
What about you?
- Oh you know, I'll buy myself a new ride.
- Please, do you think we're stupid?
- Come on dude.
We may all want this money,
but you, you need it.
The question is why?
- It's not important.
- Well if it's not important,
what's the big deal?
- It's personal.
- More personal than a boob job?
- I played football in high school.
My auntie, she really pushed me hard.
Wanted me to actually go places.
When I graduated
I landed a couple of
different scholarships.
I was even given a full ride
as long as I kept my grades up.
They always say you
should have a backup plan.
So I went for communications.
Played ball for two years.
Everything was going great.
Until this one game,
it was close to the end of the season.
Playoffs on the line.
I was running this hitch route.
Defensive end came around the corner
with a little bit too much momentum.
Cut me off at my knee.
Jacked up my ACL in my left leg.
Doctors did everything they could I guess.
I had a lotta complications.
But I was determined.
I was gonna work hard and go to rehab
every single day.
But in the end it just wasn't enough.
They took away my scholarship.
And before I knew it, I
was $30,000 in the hole
with a semester left and no prospects.
So that's why I'm here.
I'ma get outta debt, I'ma finish school
and I'ma get my life back on track.
- I'm sorry that happened to you.
- It is what it is.
- So what are you gonna do if you lose?
- I don't allow myself to
consider failure as an option.
What the fuck is that?
- I think Brad's balls just dropped.
- Maybe one of us should stay up?
Who wants first watch?
Guys!
Morning.
- Have you seen Adam?
- It's too early to be up.
Did you hear
anything weird last night?
- Other than The Liquid Shitters?
- Adam's gone.
- Maybe Rainman went into the woods.
Had to take a piss or something.
- What's going on?
- So nobody's seen Adam?
- Who cares.
- Let's not jump to conclusions.
He most likely woke up and
decided to take a walk.
- She's right.
There's nothing wrong.
I'm sure he just went off
to have some alone time.
It's day two out here in the wilderness.
And I've decided to take some time
out of my busy schedule
to demonstrate survival tactic number one.
Create a deadly weapon
with your bare hands.
Now I know what you're thinking
and yes, may bare hands
are deadly weapons.
But for those less fortunate,
search your surroundings
for a suitable object
capable of mass destruction.
My weapon of choice?
This stick, which with a little work
could be the difference
between winning and...
What was that word again?
I'm having a hard time remembering.
- Hey.
I hate to break it to you
but unless you're hunting caterpillars,
that thing isn't big
enough to do you any good.
- I wouldn't just to
conclusions if I were you.
- You need something much bigger.
- I'm impressed.
You really don't seem to be
afraid to get your hands dirty.
- Well I didn't have much of
a choice growing up on a farm.
- Sorry, I just find
it hard to picture you
as a farm hand.
- Why do you say that?
- You seem too dainty.
- Please, when was the last
time you touched a shovel?
- I used to do landscaping.
So I've had my share of splinters.
- I have a hard time picturing
you performing manual labor.
- Yeah well I didn't
have much of a choice.
- Sorry, I didn't realize--
- No, it's fine.
I grew up on the wrong side of the tracks.
My mom left before my sixth birthday
and my dad started drinking.
As a kid I used to walk
up to the pawn shop
and steal DVDs outta the cases.
And one day I got caught.
My dad had to pay the store
back for everything I stole.
So did I.
But you know I deserved it.
- So, modeling.
- Actually I,
I kinda wanna be an actor.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Not a lotta people make it
out from where I'm from.
I mean hey, if you shoot for the stars,
even if you don't make it
at least you won't be where you are now.
- Well I'm impressed.
- Well maybe you shouldn't
judge a book by its cover.
Even when that cover's so
hard to look away from.
- Still no sign of him, huh?
- Not yet.
- So strange.
It's been several hours now.
I don't know where he could be.
- Maybe he gave up.
- Hey, you mind giving
me a hand with these?
- I guess.
What do you want me to do?
- Until we find a source of protein,
this is gonna be our
best best for sustenance.
We just have to separate the
good ones from the bad ones.
- What's the difference?
- It's not that difficult.
You see these?
These are extremely poisonous.
- Well then why would you pick them?
- Because I wanted you guys to know
which ones to stay away from.
- So are any of them edible?
- Yeah.
Look, these are okay to eat.
You see how they look like tiny clusters
of even smaller berries?
You want some, don't you?
- What happened to fending for ourselves?
- Well, maybe I couldn't
resist those puppy dog eyes.
- What are you guys munching on over here?
- Berries.
- Are there any left?
- Yeah.
Come on, help yourself.
- I'm not sure I trust
your berry picking skills.
- Your loss.
- Guys, I'm really starting
to worry about Adam.
- Yeah, it's been way too long.
- One down, three to go.
- Really?
You're gonna do that now?
- It's really past the
point of joking around.
- Only the strong survive.
- All right, you know what, that's it.
We're gonna go looking for him.
Now.
- Mm hmm, definitely.
- Seriously?
You guys are gonna follow Mr. Clean?
Okay yeah, all right, I'm coming.
And this is what happens
when furries go missing.
Hang onto your pets, folks,
because if they run away you
should just let 'em run away.
Well we're in a forest,
what do you expect?
This is what we signed up for.
And there's the winning ticket.
Wow.
Ladies and gentlemen, you
cannot get enough of that.
Adam!
I hope he's all right.
I really don't
see what the big deal is.
- What if he's hurt?
I'm telling you,
this is a waste of time.
- No, Ashley's right.
We've seen some really
weird shit out here.
Starting to believe that old man.
- What do you mean?
On the boat.
The old perv was going on
about some legend out here.
- This is getting outta control.
What if he just gave up?
We all knew it was gonna
happen at some point.
- Yeah, but where'd he go?
It's not like he can just walk home.
- You guys can go back.
I'ma keep looking.
- I thought you were the one that said
we needed to stick together.
- This is a waste of time.
I'm headed back.
- Shh.
- What?
♪ Imagination in mind ♪
- You hear that?
- I don't hear any--
- Shut it up.
♪ You can spend your life ♪
What is that?
- It sounds like music.
- Where's it coming from?
- Sounds like over there.
- No.
We need to call for help.
- Everybody calm down.
We don't know what happened here.
- What, are you blind?
Something serious has happened.
- How do you know,
because we found his iPod
with some blood on it?
I'm sure it's not even real blood.
- Gosh you can't be this stupid.
Fake blood?
You think that's fake blood?
- Haven't you seen those
Scared Straight shows?
That's all this is.
They want you to think it's
real, but it's all fake.
I mean let's look at the facts.
Adam goes missing during the night
while we're all asleep.
Nobody knows what happened to him
and the next day we find his iPod.
That's it.
I've said it a thousand times.
It's all a part of the show.
- I don't see how making
us think he's dead
is a part of the show.
- I'm telling you, we're being pranked.
That's all.
- Or somebody's trying to cover it up.
- What?
- The way I see it, there's
been one person stalling us
this entire time.
- What are you trying to say?
- Adam's been gone all day.
Everybody else here is
concerned except you.
And you keep bringing this stupid camera.
- You think I had something to do with it?
- I'm not ruling it out.
- You outta your fucking mind?
- I don't know, you tell me.
- If anybody has something
to gain, it's you.
We all heard your sob story last night.
Maybe you couldn't wait any longer
so you decided to balance
the odds in your favor.
- Now what you talking 'bout?
- Couldn't handle the competition.
So you decided to start
picking us off one by one.
Am I right?
- No, stop it.
- You seem a little upset
for someone who's innocent.
- You see any blood on my hands?
- You see any on mine?
- It doesn't matter, okay?
We just need to keep looking.
- You know what?
You're right.
You wanna play CSI?
I'm down.
But I vote we split up
to cover more ground.
- Are you sure that's a good idea?
- Fine.
We'll split up.
We'll circle the lake and
we'll meet back at the camp.
- Sounds good to me.
- I'll go with him.
- You be safe.
We'll see you back at camp.
- What a fucking dick.
It's so painfully obvious
it's all part of the show.
He's gonna feel like a real
jackass when he finds out.
- Let's give them something to edit out.
You know I had
nothing to do with this, right?
- Yeah, of course I do.
You think something bad really happened?
- Honestly I don't know.
If something bad did happen,
we need to be prepared.
Nobody gonna help us out here.
- Hey, why don't we stop for a minute?
- No, I'm good.
Let's keep going.
- It's not a problem.
- I said I'm fine.
- Why do you get so hostile
when people try to help you?
- I keep telling you the
same thing, I'm okay.
- You're not okay.
You've been grabbing your
knee ever since we got here.
What is it with you guys
every time a woman offers you
help you think you're weak?
Are you really that narrow minded?
Why did I come out here?
I mean look at me, I'm filthy,
I'm sweaty and for what?
50 grand?
I could be at home
right now riding horses.
But no, I just had to come out here.
- Look, I know you said why you're here.
But it's not just about
the money for you, is it?
- You wanna know what it is?
Pride.
Brad takes care of me.
He always has.
Anything I ever needed he would handle it.
That may sound nice, but after a while
you start to feel pretty worthless.
Like you can't even brush your teeth
without somebody there to help.
- So you're here to prove to yourself
that you can stand on your own two feet?
When I got hurt,
I had to go through
multiple knee surgeries.
I couldn't even walk.
My auntie, she had to
do everything for me.
She helped me get dressed,
get in and out of the car,
she even had to help me take a shower.
Man was I miserable.
So now, anytime somebody tries to help me,
it just takes me back to
that place and that time.
I couldn't do anything for myself.
So you not wanting to
rely on other people,
I can understand that.
Come on man.
Don't you go crying on me or nothing.
- You look relaxed.
- Eh.
- Where are you going?
- Gotta take a piss.
- Thanks for sharing.
- Thanks for asking.
Taylor!
Taylor hold on!
There's no
way that that is true.
- I swear to you it is.
- Nope, there's no way they switched
your medical chart with another person.
- Yep.
Apparently it happens all the time.
- No way.
- Can you believe that?
- No!
That's like wrong.
Shawn.
- What the hell?
- We have to leave right now.
- Dude, where's Taylor?
- I don't know, it happened so fast
I didn't have time to do anything.
- We can't help you until
you tell us what happened.
- We have to leave right now.
- Why?
- Where's Taylor?
- I don't know.
Something got her.
I turned away for a second
and the next thing I knew
she was gone.
- What do you mean something got her?
- What happened to your leg?
We have to go get help.
- Who's gonna help us?
- Well nobody if we stay here.
- So she just disappeared, huh?
- Yeah, that's what I said.
- Just like Adam, right?
- Yeah, I guess.
- Seems kinda odd, doesn't it?
- Really, you wanna do this again?
- You're the one standing
here with blood on your hands.
- Yeah, my own fucking blood.
- All of it?
- Hey fuck you.
This is bullshit.
- No one is accusing anybody here.
Okay?
We just, we need to go
back to where you were
and see if we can find some answers.
Take us there, Shawn.
- It doesn't matter.
I'm sure we're already dead anyway.
- Hey,
this place isn't safe anymore.
- Anymore?
- I think it might be a good
idea for you to head back.
- Where am I supposed to go?
- Just head back the way we came.
Try to get to the river
and flag somebody down.
- Seriously?
You think it would be safer
for me out there by myself?
Where'd you get that?
- I found it this morning while
I was out looking for food.
Look, I don't know what
we're about to walk into.
And I'm not so sure I can protect you
if something were to happen.
- I'll take my chances.
- I don't think you understand.
No one is coming to help us.
- How do you know that?
- I don't.
But based on everything that's happened,
I'm not counting on it.
- They wouldn't just
send us out here to die.
- We don't know that.
- And our families, they
have to know where we are.
Right?
- It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna make it outta here.
Somehow.
It's right over here.
- Remember,
if anything happens, you run.
- This is where it happened.
This isn't a fucking game anymore.
We need to make our way back to the river.
Hopefully we can find some help.
- Let's give them something to edit out.
- Where is she?
- What?
- What did you do?
- This isn't helping.
- You don't know what he is, what he did.
What'd I do?
Fuck off me.
What'd you do, Shawn?
- Guys.
Guys!
There's something out there.
What?
Come on.
No Derrick!
No, Derrick, wait!
Derrick wait.
- No no no, come on.
Come on.
No, no!
No, no, no, no.
- Go.
Do you think someone's in there?
- I don't see anybody.
- Wait.
Are you sure it's safe?
Shawn.
- What?
What is this?
I don't know.
- Hold on, you don't think this is--
- I don't know what it is.
I just don't think we need to be in here.
- Is this some kinda cult shit?
None of this was ever a fucking game.
- What are those?
Oh my god.
- Oh my god.
Wait.
No!
- Oh my god we're gonna die.
We're gonna die.
- No, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
We're gonna make our
way back to the river.
We're gonna leave this place.
We'll find out, okay?
You can't just hide.
- Come on, okay?
After I open the door, make
your way back to the river.
No matter what don't look back.
Okay?
- Shawn help me please, help me, help me.
Ashley, Ashley!
Ashley no!
- Shawn please help me.
Shawn!
- We quell the beast with this sacrifice.
May the blood of these
lambs bring fulfillment.
- Ashley.
Ashley wake up.
Ashley.
- Shawn?
- Ashley, I'm right here.
- Shawn what?
What happened?
- I don't know.
Try to get your hands free.
- I can't, I can't.
Shawn you have to help me, please.
Please help me Shawn, please?
I can't feel my fingers.
Help me.
Please.
- Hey, hey, I got you, okay?
- Okay.
- Try to get the rope over.
Help me please.
He's coming.
He's coming Shawn, help me.
- Hold tight.
- Please, please.
I can't, I can't.
- All right, come on.
- Don't please.
- Almost, almost, almost.
- Shawn, he's coming.
He's coming.
Ow!
Shawn, Shawn, Shawn.
Please help me.
- I'm sorry, I really am.
- No, I don't wanna die.
Shawn please, please.
No, no, no, no!