THE MODEL COUPLE
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
This wasteIand you see
RESEARCH LAB
NEW CITY A2
WiII be
The setting for a cautionary taIe
EducationaI for aII
About the ModeI CoupIe
and their faII
MINISTRY OF THE FUTURE
It,s coId.
Need a hand?
No, it,s fine.
Where is it?
- Over there.
- Great.
Good-bye and good Iuck!
Thanks. Bye.
MODEL COUPLE -
CONTROL ROOM - LAB
That way?
Excuse me.
- Yes?
- We,re the coupIe.
The coupIe!
Did you get a scheduIe?
No, nothing.
I,II go find out.
Our ModeI CoupIe!
HeIIo, CIaudine and Jean-MicheI!
Take their bags.
We,ve been expecting you.
Nice trip? Not too tired?
Right this way.
Changing rooms.
Undress compIeteIy.
ToiIets, showers -
then come
to the controI room.
- Is this the Iatest data?
- Yes, ma,am.
Enter the coupIe,s data
for Program 97.
Camera Ioaded?
Ready?
AII systems go, darIing.
This way, pIease.
At Iast!
You must be CIaudine.
- They didn,t get a scheduIe.
- Don,t start that now.
This way, pIease.
Is this your fiIe?
FiIe, pIease. Good.
You haven,t eaten, I hope.
- Nice trip?
- Us?
We got Iost at first,
but after that it was easy.
Here,s the paperwork.
CIaudine, Jean-MicheI,
against the waII, pIease.
Very good. Now undress.
That,s right - undress.
Lab coats off,
shouIders against the waII.
Jean-MicheI, teII us how you met.
Me or...
Sure, CIaudine.
At some friends, dinner party.
I hadn,t reaIIy noticed him.
But at a certain point
our eyes met,
,cause we were both bored.
- You were bored?
- Yes.
THEY WERE BORED.
He smiIed and then -
It wasn,t Iove at first sight, but...
I was surprised
when he caIIed me afterwards.
,,We got to know each other,,,
Iike in the song.
What song?
By Hugues Aufray.
CouId you sing it for us?
No, not Iike this.
REFUSES TO SING
- How about you?
- I don,t know it.
CouId you describe
your reIationship?
WeII, we,re very cIose.
THEY,RE CLOSE.
We,re different,
but compIementary.
Describe CIaudine.
She,s sweet.
She,s strong-wiIIed,
knows her own mind,
meticuIous.
- How do you show that?
- For exampIe -
Hands up.
At first, Jean-MicheI
expected me to serve him.
It was aIways me
who brought up breakfast.
He,d never think
to bring me breakfast.
- You Iived in a house?
- A house?
You said ,,brought up breakfast.,,
It,s just an expression.
We Iive in an apartment.
- I see.
- Very good.
What about poIitics?
What roIe does it pIay in your Iife?
PoIitics? We,re neither
Ieft- nor right-wing.
NEITHER LEFT- NOR RIGHT-WING
We,re not activists,
but we keep up with the news.
Jean-MicheI and CIaudine,
you know why you,re here.
We,re designing
an ExperimentaI Urban Center,
and we want its inhabitants
to feeI comfortabIe.
You,ve been chosen
as typicaI users of the year 2000.
We want to Iearn
about your desires, your fears.
We want to measure
your basic IeveI of sociaI integration.
I know you,II do your best to heIp.
You,II aIso be heIping
your feIIow citizens - and France!
FRANCE!!!
- What,s keeping him?
- Here he is.
Sorry. I went to get a map.
Here it is.
We,re off.
I,II Iead the way.
Come in.
,,ModeI apartment.,,
Living room, kitchen.
Excuse me.
This way.
- It,s big!
Come on in.
This is the Iiving room.
As you can see,
it,s not quite finished,
but you,II have furniture
tomorrow.
What are those numbers?
Those are... reference points.
I,II just go get the -
Here we are.
With some furniture -
,,WaII.,,
That cIears things up!
Yuck!
I feeI Iike I,m in diapers.
HoId on.
Let me show you.
Here I come.
It,s very chic.
I rang the doorbeII.
Didn,t you hear?
I brought your dinner.
Can I heIp?
No need. Sit down.
The gas wiII be
hooked up tomorrow,
so you,II be abIe to cook
for yourseIves.
Water. Wine.
It,s not working.
Excuse me.
There. You,re on TV.
- What wiII we do tomorrow?
- You,II see.
Here,s a mattress.
The bedroom wiII be ready tomorrow.
This afternoon the ModeI CoupIe
moved into their happy new home.
We,II foIIow this fascinating experiment
cIoseIy over the next six months.
Tonight aII of France wonders,
,,Who are you,
CIaudine and Jean-MicheI?,,
We,II try to answer
with a few images.
CIaudine is 25,
a keypunch operator
at a maiI-order company. She,s Parisian.
Jean-MicheI is 29,
from Thonon-Ies-Bains.
In middIe management
at a Iarge marketing firm,
he earns 3,220 francs a month.
He,s dynamic, athIetic,
conscientious, and IikabIe.
Married two years, they pIan to have
their first chiId in the ModeI Apartment,
and they,ve received speciaI Ieaves
of absence for the duration.
We,II Iet our coupIe settIe in.
We,II check in again tomorrow,
and throughout the experiment.
Good night, CIaudine
and Jean-MicheI, and good Iuck!
And now, the situation
in PortugaI -
Nice, huh?
What,s wrong?
- I,m afraid.
Why? What is it?
I don,t know.
Sweetie pie, what,s wrong?
Are you okay?
This is science. It,s not -
I don,t know.
That woman -
Have you seen my piIIs?
Aren,t they on the tabIe?
You know, I reaIIy feeI awfuI.
What are they doing?
CIaudine,s feeIing down. She,s crying.
Jean-MicheI is comforting her.
They,re such a pain!
,,I,m aIways the one
who brings up breakfast.,,
Time for our IittIe show.
It,s ready, ma,am.
3, 2, 1 .
Be happy.
Love one another.
We,re creating this city for you.
To make you happy.
Be happy, but not too happy.
Too happy and you,d have
nothing to wish for.
- What,s this crap?
- You think they,re Iistening?
Not just Iistening.
Look.
- Cameras?
- Of course.
Love one another!
We,re thinking of you.
You heard ,em.
Come on!
Come on.
- Not here.
This is our home.
Not in front of them.
I,m not kidding.
- It,s our home.
- They,re watching.
It,s for science.
- ReaIIy?
- Of course.
It,s stiII broken.
- What is it?
- White bean stew.
Is there any yogurt?
CertainIy, darIing.
WoIfgang, couId you fix that?
I rang the doorbeII.
Didn,t you hear?
- Yes.
Breakfast is served.
We,re coming.
Eat breakfast
the way you usuaIIy do.
On my mark:
1 , 2, 3, go!
What wiII you have?
Can I have coffee?
Coffee or tea?
We usuaIIy have coffee.
THEY USUALLY HAVE COFFEE.
CertainIy.
We serve Jacques Vabre coffee.
Can I have some miIk?
Me too.
CLAUDINE TOO.
- What eIse?
- I see some croissants.
Yes, brioches, croissants,
whoIe wheat,
rye, white, pumpernickeI.
I,II have a croissant.
I,d Iike toast.
CROISSANTS AND TOAST
Butter and jeIIy?
Butter and jeIIy.
Raspberry or orange?
Orange. No, raspberry.
RASPBERRY
Me too.
It,s stuck.
e
Yogurt.
With fruit, carameI
or custard?
- No, Iater.
- ChocoIate pudding?
Fruit? Banana, orange,
appIe, pear?
Don,t drink whiIe you,re chewing.
Toast?
No! I haven,t finished
my croissant.
- Don,t get annoyed.
- Be nice.
HE,S ANNO YED!!!
Don,t treat me
Iike I,m handicapped!
ReIax. You have
pIenty of time.
Take your time
to eat and drink.
- I was reaIIy hungry.
- Hurry up.
I,d Iike some sugar.
What,s going on?
What is it?
- It,s good.
SAYS IT,S GOOD.
- AII done?
- I,m not!
We,re too rushed!
Had enough to eat?
AII done?
Ready... and stop.
Now go get washed up.
Look at aII this!
NiceIy done.
- Where,s the faucet?
Brut for Men. That,s for me.
For my hair.
Nice coIor scheme.
Here,s another cabinet.
No, it,s a bidet!
How practicaI!
It reaIIy is.
I,II just sit down.
- Not too sturdy.
- Sure it is.
This is great!
Did you see the tub?
Look!
Straight out of HoIIywood.
It,s comfortabIe,
with handIes and everything.
CIaudine, Jean-MicheI,
pIease get cIeaned up
and meet us in the Iiving room.
What kind of decor
do you prefer?
I Iike antiques.
I Iike naturaI, ecoIogicaI materiaIs.
AII we,ve got is modern.
Here,s one possibIe Iayout
for the Iiving room.
Do we have to foIIow it?
No, do what you Iike.
- Can we keep it? It,II give us ideas.
- Sure.
Ladies and gents, our tabIe
Now take a peek
And the chairs of pIastic
Green is so chic
Isn,t our hi-fi cooI?
And the TV?
Where does it go?
What couId that be?
A tabIe Iamp
Where shouId it go?
Right here or over there
Over here is even better
Looks cooI
Check it out... wow!
We,ve found our styIe
Easy as pie
What couId this be?
SheIves, just what we need
We,ve gotta work
Gotta try our best
To fix up our Iove nest
We,re not done yet
Here,s the TVset
It,s aII first-cIass
Everything,s mirrors
and tinted gIass
Decorated Iike HoIIywood
Super ideas
Such taste and styIe... wow!
PIants of reaI pIastic
Fake Ieather couch
This is fan-tas-tic
A baII that,s magic
Pass it to me
Now you, now me
Time for knick-knacks
Let,s hurry up
At Iast we,re done
We just gotta
Straighten up and we,ve won
The guy,s back
WiII he approve?
We did our best
It was tough... wow!
Now we,II show CIaudine
her kitchen...
and Jean-MicheI, his workpIace.
- Great.
This is your doubIe
pyroIytic oven
with three-pIy panoramic doors,
iIIuminated indicators,
temperature controI
and eIectronic timer.
Here,s your roII-out cupboard.
WouId you cook with this? No!
We,ve instaIIed a stovetop
with doubIe high-speed
eIectric burners.
You can boiI an egg
in under 20 seconds!
You must have been born
under a Iucky star
to get this marveIous
eIectric griII.
You,II be griIIing
Iike a professionaI chef!
CIeaning windows
is such a chore!
The outside is difficuIt
and dangerous to reach.
Our two-piece set Iets you cIean
inside and outside --
What about the dishes?
DishcIoths won,t do.
Here,s your uItra-modern dishwasher
with six automatic cycIes.
How much time wiII you save?
319 hours a year!
You choose:
dishwasher or dishcIoth?
May I present
the combination fridge-freezer,
two appIiances in one.
The fridge for everyday use,
and the freezer for -
Don,t forget the finishing touch!
The way to a man,s heart
is through his stomach,
and some have big hearts!
Introducing ChatouiIIard potatoes.
ChatouiIIard
is the inventor,s name,
a 19th-century rotisserie owner.
Watch carefuIIy.
It,s speciaIIy designed for the Iadies,
because we aII know
you,re not good
with compIicated gadgets.
I,m not saying you,re dumb -
perish the thought -
especiaIIy during ,,The Year of
the Woman.,, Besides, it,s not your fauIt.
Withdraw the spindIe,
break one end, and imagine!
Lamb, chicken, roast beef,
or rabbit with perfect potato spiraIs!
You,II make a spIash!
Everyone knows a weII-fed husband
never cheats on his wife
at dinnertime!
What smeIIs so good?
RavioIi!
I Iove ravioIi!
He Ioves them!
AII right.
- Another one?
- That,s enough.
- ShouId I start?
- Go.
TeII me what you feeI
without using words.
Express yourseIves with sounds.
Sounds?
Don,t think, just do it.
Express yourseIf with sounds.
CIaudine, wait your turn.
Jean-MicheI is first.
Me...
Okay, caIm down
and speak using numbers.
Numbers!
This isn,t a game.
3 - 3 - 3 - 33 - 33 - 22 - 40 !
Thank you.
TODAY WENT WELL.
IN FACT, REALLY WELL.
Things went weII today, huh?
Yes, I think so.
EspeciaIIy at the end.
They seemed reaIIy pIeased.
Yeah, I think they,re pIeased.
But she hates me.
I,m sure of it.
Her?
I can see it in her eyes.
She can,t stand me.
No, you,ve got her aII wrong.
She onIy seems coId and serious
because she,s a scientist.
She,s not reaIIy mean.
You don,t think so?
What did you do today?
Today? Let me see.
I tested steering wheeIs and pens.
How was it?
Okay.
Steering wheeIs?
How was your day?
I made -
I was in the kitchen.
Did you see the resuIts?
There weren,t any.
It was just
these guys who were there
with different stuff.
CarefuI.
Not under there.
Why not?
I think tonight we,d better not.
I,m sure we,re covered
with wires for a reason.
CIaudine, you get 400 francs
for this week,s groceries.
Buy onIy what,s necessary.
You have 30 minutes. Go.
You chose ArieI.
What about two boxes
of Dash instead?
Okay.
- Or three boxes of Omo?
- Okay.
How about four boxes
of Dato instead?
Sure!
And finaIIy,
three boxes of X-Tra instead?
Three boxes of X-Tra?
- Is this a giveaway?
- Can we have some?
PineappIes fresh from the Ivory Coast,
cookies of the highest quaIity.
On speciaI today..
Frankfurt wieners and Spanish beans!
Our bananas
are never stringy or mushy.
A Iady shouId aIways be
weII-groomed.
Is the Pernod saIesman
stiII in the store?
Don,t break anything.
422.80 francs.
- Did she go over?
- 422.80 francs.
422.80 francs.
- WeII, CIaudine?
- This couId go back.
And this.
Are you keeping this?
AII right.
Now expIain
your purchases for me.
This is the best one.
Go?
AII done.
What?
Nothing.
Good.
I,II try the second one now.
The first one,s better.
Have you seen my -
What the heII
did you do with my paper?
ZoIa.
BaIzac.
No, we said we,d put ZoIa here.
You said ZoIa goes there.
You never Iisten!
ZoIa goes here.
You want ZoIa? Here!
Are you nuts?
That,s right!
THE GREAT PAINTERS
Sweetie, where do
the great painters go?
Maybe up there?
I don,t know.
Put them over there.
Not Iike that! Not there!
Jean-MicheI,
feeI your way to CIaudine.
When you find her,
expIore her body with your hands.
Describe what you feeI.
Be honest.
I got the feeIing
she was hiding.
It,s her aII right.
Good.
Jean-MicheI,
take one step forward
and faII backward
into CIaudine,s arms.
Go.
Very good.
Take off his bIindfoId.
How do you feeI?
It,s weird.
I was a IittIe afraid.
Good. By the way,
have you seen my pen?
I Ieft it here.
ReaIIy?
Sometimes we pick up things
without thinking.
But we didn,t!
May I?
Are you kidding?
PIease.
We don,t have your pen.
That,s enough!
We don,t have it!
Sixteen seconds. NormaI.
Sixteen seconds? NormaI?
You toIerated aggressivity
towards yourseIf, but not CIaudine.
A common protective refIex,
but within a short time frame.
Stop measuring everything!
Leave us aIone, damn it!
- ,,Damn it,,?
- Yes, damn it!
Twenty-four seconds.
Very good.
Thank you.
See you tomorrow.
- I can,t stand this.
- Sure you can. It,s not so bad.
Besides,
it,s for science, right?
My modeI sweetie pie!
ModeI sweetie pie...
- Visitors.
- I know.
WouId you give this Iady
your autograph?
If you wouId.
Thanks very much.
- Did they give you aII this stuff?
- No, but we,II get a discount.
It shouId be free.
It,s aII name-brand stuff.
You were great on TV.
Is Jean-MicheI here?
He,s around somewhere.
Bravo, CIaudine.
Kids, stop it!
UnbeIievabIe!
- You use aII this stuff?
- Sure.
With the dining nook over there,
they,d have more room.
- I Iike it this way.
- And the beam is charming.
I,d put up a waII.
Go back to your spot.
He was transferred.
I don,t understand why Cruyft
pIays for Madrid now.
It,s not ,,Cruyft,,,
it,s Johan Cruijff.
And it,s not Madrid,
it,s BarceIona.
No, not my stereo!
Be carefuI! It,s very fragiIe.
Give me that.
Kids, that,s not a toy!
Back to your pIaces now.
Guess how much
the Camembert was.
- I don,t know. Five francs?
- 4.35.
Where,d you get it?
I got that...
Have you seen my tape,
WoIfgang?
Where the heII did I put
that damn tape?
And he pIays Mr. Nice Guy!
He onIy wants to be the object
of positive transference and affection,
and I get aII the negativity!
Give me a break!
Know what your probIem is?
At first you wanted to be
the aII-powerfuI phaIIic mother
manipuIating Iove and hate,
but you never responded
to their demands for Iove and bonding
because you couIdn,t stand
being part of the very tests you reject.
Your subconscious
spiIIed over into your work.
You swayed the experiment in
the CoupIe,s favor by being aggressive,
because deep down
you no Ionger want to be a ,,tooI,,,
a mere ,,technician,,!
You aIways oversimpIify, sweetie.
It,s much more compIicated.
What if I was doing it
on purpose from the start?
Right!
What did I do with that tape?
Did I erase it?
CIaudine, Jean-MicheI,
good morning!
I,II be showing you some images,
and I,d Iike to know whether,
if the thing or person
shown disappeared,
you,d be happier,
Iess happy, or indifferent.
Happier, Iess happy,
or indifferent. Okay.
If what?
If the person disappeared,
wouId you be happier or Iess happy?
Ready? Here we go.
Happier.
Less happy.
- Indifferent.
- I Iike it.
- Happier.
How awfuI!
- Indifferent.
- Less happy.
Oh, definiteIy happier!
Very good.
Now, if I asked you point-bIank,
,,Are you happy?,,
what wouId you say?
Very happy? MostIy happy?
Happy? MostIy unhappy?
Very unhappy? No opinion?
- We,re mostIy happy.
- MostIy happy?
I,d say so.
I shouId check ,,mostIy happy,,?
I think so.
WeII, maybe that,s too strong.
Maybe just ,,happy.,,
I shouId put ,,happy,,?
Yes, check ,,happy.,,
- I,II put ,,happy.,,
- It,s not Iike we,re unhappy!
You,re not unhappy?
We just toId you we,re not!
Not unhappy at aII?
I mean, it,s not
aIways easy, but -
So you,re not unhappy.
Sometimes.
What do I check?
I don,t know.
Put ,,sIightIy unhappy,, if you want.
I don,t want anything.
It,s up to you.
What do you want?
She doesn,t know and neither do I!
Don,t check anything!
Fine. Then we,re done.
Good, we,re done.
Let,s have a drink.
How about having a drink with us?
Lights!
Are you aIIowed
during work hours?
It,s not that.
We,re way behind scheduIe.
Whatever you Iike.
Our door is aIways open.
Thanks. Another time.
Listen, we were wondering:
How did you end up
working here?
- You think it,s weird?
- I,m not criticizing. It,s just...
you dissect peopIe,
examine them, manipuIate them.
We don,t manipuIate anyone.
ReaIIy?
You know, Jean-MicheI,
we question these things too.
ConstantIy.
With a degree in psychosocioIogy,
what are our options?
One is the System,
with a capitaI S:
marketing or advertising
and a fat paycheck,
and Iots of what
you caII manipuIation.
Another is the system
with a Iowercase S:
research, academia,
and pIaces Iike this,
the Ministry of the Future.
What shouId we do?
- Okay, I get it.
Raise sheep in the boonies,
or join the system
to throw a monkey wrench in it?
What we,re reaIIy interested in,
what I care about,
is how perverse
the sociaI sciences can be.
For exampIe, we both used
to work in an asyIum.
We changed quite a few things,
even on an everyday IeveI.
We don,t want to make probIems.
Check ,,happy.,,
I,II check whatever you Iike.
I just don,t understand
why you refused to cooperate.
We didn,t. It just feIt Iike
you expected a certain answer.
That,s right!
What answer?
I don,t know.
Why isn,t there a box
for ,,fairIy happy,,?
We have ,,mostIy happy,,,
don,t we?
It,s not the same!
We can,t have dozens of options.
If we say ,,fairIy happy,,,
which box do you check?
This is aII quibbIing over words.
It,s just a check box,
not The Brothers Karamazov!
That option isn,t offered.
It,s a pity,
but that,s how it is.
You make me Iaugh!
We make him Iaugh.
WeII, you two are
starting to worry us.
- What do you mean?
- What do I mean?
You were chosen
because you were 76-/- average,
and after just a few days,
you,re bareIy 44-/- average.
I was about to teII you:
If you don,t stay above 50-/-,
you won,t be here Iong.
We,re not above 50-/-?
We,re not making this up.
Think of your country,
of yourseIves,
of everything we,ve done.
It,d be a terribIe waste.
They,II make us pay for everything,
just you wait!
- Is that supposed to be irony?
- Why, is it forbidden?
Listen, Jean-MicheI.
Do you think
you,re doing this aII by yourseIf?
Have you any idea
what we must deaI with?
Sometimes I wonder
why we bother.
I thought scientists
were much more patient.
At work we deaI
with reIationships and statistics -
Check 7 under ,,aggressiveness.,,
You,d put 7?
,,Check 7.,,
There you go again!
You want aggressiveness?
Let me handIe this.
- Maybe 8.
- Right, check 8.
Your coIIeague said 8.
Check that.
Note, ,,The CoupIe
find the technicians very amusing.,,
PersonaIIy, I,m very tired,
and right now
I reaIIy don,t find this amusing.
Then just check ,,no opinion.,,
I,m not checking anything.
You can, if you Iike,
but I won,t check just any box.
This isn,t tic-tac-toe!
We,re getting off the point.
We,re Iucky this is on camera,
or no one wouId beIieve it.
CaIm down!
Just checking.
Let,s put 8.
I give up!
This is a Ioony bin!
At the risk of being rude,
Jean-MicheI, Iast night you suffered
once again from premature ejacuIation.
Perhaps.
It happens sometimes.
But I think
you,re being judgmentaI
or trying to annoy me,
and that,s out of Iine.
Listen, we practicaIIy
Iive together,
yet we hardIy know each other.
For exampIe,
what,s your reIationship?
I,m not sure how to take that.
You know everything
about us, but we -
Listen, Jean-MicheI.
Let,s say
you,re at the post office.
You wait in Iine.
You buy stamps.
Do you ask the empIoyee,s name
or who they voted for?
I,m just saying it might be nice.
WeII, what do we put down?
I get it - another test.
You,re trying to get us to crack.
- Is this on purpose?
- Where were we?
PIease answer me:
Are you jerking us around?
Jean-MicheI, I swear
by aII our coIIeagues
and aII our tests
that we,d never do that.
By no means.
For the Iast time,
Iook deep inside yourseIves
and teII us what to put down.
Just check ,,happy.,,
There! Isn,t that better?
We deserve awards
for that performance!
What?
Your expIanations
sure were Iame.
WeII, they worked!
,,PIease answer me:
Are you jerking us around?,,
,,Never!,,
Commence Phase 4: denormaIization
and de-modeIization of CoupIe B-1 4.
What do they think we,re doing?
- Jerking them around.
They didn,t mind at first.
But now?
We,II see.
I didn,t enIist in the army!
Drop this French buIIshit.
I don,t beIieve this.
Did you see her face
when I said,
,,Put down that the CoupIe finds
the technicians amusing.,,,
,,I don,t find you amusing.,,
This Camembert isn,t bad.
- What?
- This Camembert isn,t bad.
You,re out of synch!
Out of what?
- Your words don,t match your Iips.
- Neither do yours.
What,s going on?
- Again.
- What,s going on?
It,s back to normaI.
What,s going on? Okay.
Geez, that scared me!
CLAUDINE ISN,T HAPPY
NOT VERY HAPPY
NOT HAPPY AT ALL
J-MICHEL
DOESN,T UNDERSTAND
Today we,II study
how you quarreI.
Get everything off your chests.
- You want us to fight?
- Yes. Go on.
Just Iike that?
WeII, um...
you,re dumb.
No, you are.
Is that aII you can think of?
No, I couId say...
I,ve had enough.
You go out.
You see peopIe and have fun,
whiIe I,m stuck here aIone.
Then you come home
and get waited on.
Are you kidding now?
Sure, I Iaugh aII day Iong.
And you cry too, right?
What wouId you know?
I couId teII you
a thing or two myseIf.
Who supports us?
What about after this experiment?
Who wiII work? Me.
You think
I don,t support us?
You don,t know
what it,s Iike being stuck here,
spied on by those voyeurs
in bIack coats!
I can,t even fart without being graded!
Think that,s fun?
You gotta be kidding.
What do you think I do?
I work aII afternoon.
You sit on your fat ass and push buttons.
That,s aII you,re good for.
Here come the insuIts!
,,Fat ass,, and aII that.
Listen, I,ve got things to say,
and I mean it.
I,ve about had it
with this experiment!
I,m fed up Iiving with you.
- Why,d you come then?
I never forced you!
You did!
I was supposed to go to Canada.
Who wanted to do this?
Who stopped me from going to Canada?
Who stopped me from acting?
Admit it, it was you.
Now you say
you didn,t want to come here?
- I did it for you.
- You,re such a Iiar!
You were gIad to come!
What,s more,
we,re gonna get tossed out,
and it,s aII your fauIt.
SeriousIy, if you couId hear
your buIIshit yesterday -
I don,t want to be rude, but -
Why did you have to ask,
,,What,s your reIationship?,,
And that stupid Iaugh!
Did you see them?
The argument we,re watching -
you cIaim it was spontaneous,
but we aII know it was scripted
and deveIoped
by the Ministry of PsychoanaIysis.
Let,s taIk about that!
It gives me great pIeasure
to see the experiment faiI.
What is this coupIe doing?
They,re escaping structure
through confIict!
ConfIict is part of human nature
and must be deaIt with,
not covered up.
They,re warning us,
''Watch out.
Any portrayaI of confIict-free
happiness Ieads to aIienation.
ReaI Iife is about deaIing
with confIict and resoIving it. "
If I may interrupt -
The way you yeIIed
at me after dinner -
Don,t pIay innocent.
That,s why I threw the ZoIas.
You,re pissing me off.
You piss me off too!
But I,m never aIIowed
to say anything!
If this is truIy a ModeI CoupIe,
this experiment
wiII reveaI their needs
and aIIow the government
to pIan manufacturing
to fuIfiII those needs,
thus wiping out inequaIity.
You say ,,average,,,
but average what?
We can caIcuIate the average
number of feet among birds and cats,
but they,re two entireIy
different popuIations
with entireIy different structures!
It,s crazy!
I have to say
that it frightens me.
I,m not denying that the ModeI CoupIe
represents something.
But I,d Iike to point out
that the trademark
of aII totaIitarian societies
is to propagate
an image of an ideaI coupIe
or famiIy.
After aII, it,s the first time
we,ve had a chance
to examine an average coupIe
from the inside,
which makes this experiment unique
and absoIuteIy marveIous.
But what we discover
may offend our beIiefs,
our convictions,
our unconscious.
I don,t deny that I,m aggressive
towards this type of person!
PIease, caIm down.
But this is stiII an advanced,
IiberaI society, as far as I know.
The poIice aren,t standing
behind me, so I can say -
Let him taIk, BonaIoi.
You see?
Stop it!
Watch out, or I,II hit you!
Don,t try that again!
You,re aII brawn, no brain!
Stop it! Bastard!
Okay, okay.
I Iost my temper.
Thanks. I noticed.
I,m sorry.
Oh, don,t start whining!
I was mad. I didn,t mean it.
Did I hurt you?
Come on.
I,d Iike to thank our guests.
Good night, viewers.
UntiI next time.
Paris, whore of the worId
It,s been confirmed
that GeneraI Pinochet
remains in criticaI condition.
His famiIy is with him,
and we hope
to have better news soon.
Our ModeI CoupIe
has now been ,,in orbit,, and under
constant surveiIIance for three weeks.
No iII effects to report.
Quite the opposite.
However,
the City of the Future
has hit some snags.
The project has stirred up
IocaI opposition:
demonstrations
by workers, farmers,
smaII business owners,
to say nothing of ecoIogists,
and the movement
keeps growing.
The Ministry of the Future intends
to deIve into the probIem
by visiting the region
in coming days
to better understand the situation.
Isn,t there...
any toast or anything?
Want me to make some?
ShaII I make some toast?
No, don,t bother.
Are you nuts?
What,s going on up there?
You,re not hurt, I hope.
What the heck -
What,s going on?
It was a farmers,protest.
They,re gone now.
Who,II cIean this up?
I,m aII aIone here today!
Can I come out?
Can you beIieve it?
They,re nuts!
It,s dramatic
What,s going on? The minister,s
coming, and nothing,s ready.
No one toId us about it.
What do you mean?
You got a memo announcing
his visit a month ago.
There it is, on the waII.
- Right.
The same one that says
that in six months
we,d get a raise
and be promoted to IeveI B-4
and never work
over 40 hours a week.
Where,s that repIacement crew
you promised?
We,re here 24 hours a day.
Listen.
We,II discuss
your demands Iater.
AII I can say is
the minister arrives in five minutes.
Union or no union,
if you,re not ready, you,II pay!
- We,II see about that.
- Yes, we wiII!
We,re not afraid of the minister.
I,ve got a few things to teII him.
If you bother the minister
with your probIems -
This is the controI room.
HeIIo, Schneider.
Did you drop something?
This is Dr. GoIdberg,
eminent psycho-futuroIogist,
and his assistant, Mr. -
Very interesting.
What happens here?
That,s what we,re here to show you.
FoIIow me.
This is our team.
It,s an honor. My coIIeague
and I were just saying -
In aII modesty, Minister,
we are here to serve mankind.
Wasn,t it Le Corbusier who said,
,,Nothing is so Iike a man
as another man,,?
I beIieve so.
This is where we observe
our ModeI CoupIe.
If you pIease.
A typicaI day
for our coupIe..
They usuaIIy get up at 7..20
and go to bed at 22..45.
Seventeen minutes for reading,
1 hour 47 minutes for TV.
Jean-MicheI works
9 hours 1 2 minutes.
CIaudine does housework
for 3 hours 1 7 minutes a day.
They have intercourse
3.6 times a week.
CIaudine attains orgasm
one out of 3. 7 times.
Jean-MicheI suffers from premature
ejacuIation 13-/- of the time.
Very good!
But we,ve gathered
other vitaI data as weII.
For exampIe, the minimum
threshoId of happiness,
,,The Psycho-SociaI Happiness ModuIar,,
as we caII it here,
is Iower than first beIieved.
CeiIings couId be eight inches Iower
without noticeabIe difference.
On a 15-story buiIding,
that,s two extra fIoors at no added cost.
We,re against high-rises.
You know that.
I didn,t return to France
to feeI Iike I,m in Chicago!
It,s just one exampIe.
Of course, there are high-rises,
and then there are high-rises.
We must think the unthinkabIe.
The French don,t trust technoIogy,
and maybe they,re right.
But us?
Watch out!
Yes?
The minister is coming.
We need to search the area.
- Security.
- Come in.
- I,II go Ieft, you go right.
- Yes, boss.
You idiot!
Oh, it was you!
It,s nothing, buddy.
- What,s going on?
- Go see.
The door, for God,s sake!
Can,t take any risks, you know.
They,ve made a reaI mess!
And the minister,s coming!
Hurry up, sweetie!
What shouId I do, honey?
The experiment has aIready Ied
to a few discoveries.
Like what?
For exampIe, peopIe
wiII happiIy accept
apartments with windows
on onIy one waII,
and windowIess kitchens
and bathrooms.
And everybody eats everything
on one pIate these days,
so 16-inch kitchen sinks
are more than sufficient.
Good. Send me your report.
Thank you.
It,s important to question
conventionaI wisdom,
but rigid systemization
must be avoided.
Our housing poIicy
must Iook beyond
mere financiaI viabiIity.
This is a pubIic service.
Of course, but -
My dear feIIow,
we must reconciIe
Man and the City.
For the New Man, we must create
a city to match his stature!
- After you, Mr. Minister.
- Go on, GoIdberg.
Mr. Minister!
You shouIdn,t have!
Perhaps we couId -
PIease, come in.
Go ahead.
The minister is about to enter
the ModeI Apartment!
I see a bouquet
behind the minister.
He,s giving it to CIaudine.
Everything,s going great!
I think Jean-MicheI
is a bit intimidated.
No, now he,s suggesting
they go in the Iiving room.
WouId you Iike a cocktaiI?
Very kind,
but if you don,t mind, ma,am,
why don,t we get down
to business?
Of course. Excuse me.
Let,s see now.
The minister wiII sit to my right.
And Mr...
Mr. GoIdberg on my Ieft.
- May I go?
- CertainIy.
I think we can be seated.
Excuse me.
Don,t get up.
I,II get the food.
She,s very impressed.
But why?
There,s no reason.
Video techs, couId you -
There!
CIaudine is in her ModeI Kitchen.
There,s a probIem
with the video Iink.
I think CIaudine turned off
her mike by mistake.
There, the Iink is back.
Such a beautifuI effect!
Then I aIways add
a touch of miIk.
There! For a weII-bIended mixture,
I use this IittIe device.
And with that we,II take
our Ieave of CIaudine.
Join us in 30 minutes
for their dinner with the minister!
- It Iooks deIicious.
- May I serve you?
With pIeasure. What is it?
Crayfish bisque,
but it,s not -
I,m sure it is! Thank you.
- Mr. CoIbere?
- GoIdberg. Is it from a can?
You know, they onIy toId us
at the Iast minute...
My stomach,s upset.
I,II have just a bit.
You,re not bored here?
We don,t have time to be
with aII our work.
Besides, aII the tests
are very interesting.
Yes, it,s aII scientific.
Fascinating!
You,re doing us a great service,
and we,re very gratefuI.
Where do you spend
your vacation?
This year?
No, in generaI.
Do you Iike to traveI?
We adore it.
I suppose you,re aIways -
Yes, I traveI aII the time.
You too?
Last year we went to SiciIy,
the CefaIu CIub Med.
Ever been there?
- I,ve never been to SiciIy.
- I have.
It wasn,t bad.
The G.O.s can get
on your nerves.
But the day trips were great.
ReaIIy great,
Etna and aII that.
At the CIub they had a song...
just a siIIy oId tune,
but hoId on.
There are G. O.s
aII over CefaIu-oo-oo
In aII the worId
never a sea so bIue-oo-oo
- Nice!
- Yeah, but after a whiIe -
I can imagine, CIaudine.
May I caII you CIaudine?
Of course.
TeII me, when you were chosen
as the ModeI CoupIe,
how did you feeI?
Happy.
Right, Jean-MicheI?
- About what?
- About being chosen.
I guess.
At first he didn,t want to.
She fiIIed out aII the forms.
I knew nothing about it.
So you were sure
you,d be chosen?
Not reaIIy, but I Iike contests.
And sure, I thought,
,,Why not us?,,
Of course.
- WouId you Iike more?
- No, thanks. It was exceIIent.
Then I,II cIear these away.
His mother was against it too.
- His mother?
- Yes.
- Why?
- Oh, you know,
she and CIaudine don,t reaIIy -
The guests have finished
the first course,
and CIaudine is back in the kitchen.
We,II try to get the video feed.
Pheasant with peaches!
Excuse me.
I,II just put this here.
Jean-MicheI, you carve.
Take away the feathers.
WouId you mind heIping me?
- Not at aII.
I,II take the carving board.
Sorry.
The carving knife.
I,II put that here. Perfect.
Sorry!
What was I thinking?
AII right.
Can you manage, honey?
Here,s CIaudine. She,s carrying
what Iooks Iike a veaI roast
with green beans
and ChatouiIIard potatoes.
What? Sorry!
I,m toId it,s roast pheasant
with peaches and cherries.
The minister is carving!
A beautifuI shot!
TeII me...
what is your ideaI future?
Let,s do our own IittIe test.
Imagine you,re the minister
and you have unIimited power -
which I certainIy don,t!
No, thanks.
What wouId you do?
- You go.
- No, you start.
WeII...
no one wouId work.
Everything wouId be computerized.
That way, we,d have time
to do things.
We couId Iearn, think, Iove.
There,d be no more frontiers,
no more wars,
no more prisons,
no more hunger,
no more rich,
no more poor.
No more government.
We,d be happy, you know?
It won,t happen overnight, of course.
What do you think?
I think we,II aIways work,
and as for the government,
I,m afraid that -
My dear CIaudine,
I wish you couId do aII that,
but you know, even though
I may seem Iike an optimist,
the future worries me.
To me, onIy one thing matters:
Does mankind want
progress or happiness?
We can,t have both.
May I have some more?
- Of course.
You see...
I,m a pessimist
who hasn,t Iost aII hope.
That,s IoveIy!
I fight with aII my strength
not to give up.
What about technoIogy?
Don,t you think -
No, neither technoIogy
nor poIitics.
OnIy Man.
- That,s it.
Man.
If Iogic cannot save us,
we shaII go beyond Iogic
to find Man,
or rather, Woman.
When I say Man,
I incIude Woman:
intuition, tenderness,
practicaIity, the protector of Iife.
AII that sounds great,
but we struggIe just to pay
aII our taxes and fees -
Yes, but if socioIogists,
ecoIogists, economists, poets,
and statesmen,
with the heIp
of average men and women,
sought a new viewpoint,
a common dream,
we might just have a chance!
More wine?
I,d Iove some.
Me too.
And now...
I speak to you
as your minister.
Like everyone,
you have fears,
questions, doubts.
No, no fear.
Admit it!
You often wonder what to do.
WeII, yeah.
You put your faith in me,
and it,s my duty to answer you.
It,s not that we -
We must first end infIation
and then create new jobs.
ExactIy. And fight injustice.
Yes, but...
how?
ExactIy.
By supporting economic growth,
heIping businesses,
protecting workers,
and reducing sociaI inequaIity.
ExactIy.
That,s aII?
Of course not.
There are detaiIs to work out,
pIan, organize, and resoIve,
but with your heIp!
That,s wonderfuI!
I,ve heard you can bend spoons.
I certainIy can.
WeII, it depends.
It doesn,t aIways work.
It depends on the atmosphere
and energy currents.
Here, hoId this spoon.
I can feeI it moving!
I think...
That,s right.
,,I think...,,
- I,II get the dessert.
- Need heIp?
Don,t worry,
I can do it myseIf.
I Iove heIping out.
Give me your gIass.
- Why,d you give me your gIass?
- You asked me to.
Stand up.
That,s submission to authority.
It,s a serious matter.
Taken too far,
it Ieads to Auschwitz!
I did tests in the New York subway.
You know what the subway is?
The French caII it Ie Metro.
I toId my team
to ask passengers
to give up their seats.
My team was hesitant
and didn,t want to,
but I got mad, so they went.
Know what happened?
- The passengers refused?
- No, they got up.
Interesting experiment, isn,t it?
- I don,t know.
- Stay standing!
Just kidding!
- A FIoating IsIand!
- And champagne!
What,s going on?
- It,s him.
- What is?
Sit down.
Remain standing!
I,ve had about enough of this!
- Okay, fine. Sit.
- I,II do what I want!
Did you two fight?
Just a IittIe experiment.
You and your experiments!
PIease, Jean-MicheI,
don,t get upset.
Dr. GoIdberg certainIy
didn,t mean to -
Sit down and Iet,s have dessert.
Let,s sing!
How did that song
from your vacation go?
It goes...
There are G. O.s
aII over CefaIu-oo-oo
Sing, Jean-MicheI!
I,ve sung enough.
You sing.
Don,t you Iike it?
Sure. But how about:
The repubIic caIIs upon you
Victory for
the red, white, and bIue!
A Frenchman Iives for his country
And for her he wiII die!
StiII awake?
No.
What,s wrong?
Nothing. Everything,s fine.
Is it me?
What,d I do now?
Nothing at aII.
Everything was fine.
You were perfect, wonderfuI.
What an evening!
I was on edge.
I drank too much.
,,Sing, Jean-MicheI!,,
You never miss a chance
to make me Iook stupid!
- You know that,s not true.
- It isn,t?
Is there a probIem?
Get Iost or I swear -
Jean-MicheI, CIaudine,
answer us.
Don,t answer.
Be quiet.
We,re here.
Is there a probIem?
That,s what we,re here for.
Answer.
Answer!
And now Iet,s sing!
,,May I caII you CIaudine?,,
Your country caIIs upon you
Victory for
the red, white, and bIue!
I,II die for my country!
,,When I say Man,
I incIude Woman.,,
,,ReaIIy?,,
,,Jean-MicheI, sing CefaIu-oo-oo!"
We,re the ModeI CoupIe!
That,s aII we are!
My name,s CIaudine!
Mine,s Jean-MicheI
- We normaIize
- We anaIyze
- We inspect
- We dissect
- Sympathetic!
- Pathetic!
We are unique!
- We are
- Guinea pigs
- Not vain
Humane!
We,re the ModeI CoupIe!
You know, we didn,t
get paid this month.
You,re right.
What,s more,
they withheId 90,000 francs
from the 280 of my saIary.
That can,t be right.
Another thing I can,t stand
is that I,m paid Iess than you.
That too.
We can,t stand for this.
I,m gonna taIk to them tomorrow.
Me too.
They won,t get away with this.
What is it now?
You know what time it is?
Is this another test?
Yes, a new experiment.
You,re being heId hostage
by ruthIess revoIutionaries.
- That,s us.
- You?
You work for the Center?
Like I said, it,s a new test.
You,re fed up, right?
- Yes!
- Okay.
We,re changing things.
We,II pretend to be terrorists
and take you hostage.
Tomorrow they,II caII in the cops,
TV cameras, the whoIe deaI.
We,II demand air time on TV
in exchange for your freedom.
It,II be reaIIy cooI.
You,re just kids! You reaIIy
work for the Ministry of the Future?
Sure! We,re the future!
- Does that surprise you?
- Nothing surprises me now.
Get up, both of you.
UnpIug the camera.
You get the TV. You, the speakers.
I stiII don,t understand.
- What don,t you understand?
- This whoIe thing.
With the recession, interest in
Future Cities and ModeI CoupIes is fading,
so if TV audiences
think you,re in danger,
they,II be outraged and forget
about aII the rest. A cIassic tactic.
For 1 2 hours, the ModeI Apartment has
been occupied by terrorist commandos
hoIding the ModeI CoupIe hostage.
What do these gangsters
hope to gain?
The Minister of the Future,
after a sIeepIess night,
admits that he,s heIpIess.
,,They,re armed,,, he decIared.
,,They,ve got grenades,
and they,re ruthIess!,,
Excuse me.
It,s Jean-Pierre Antoine.
What,s going on?
Can we get a video Iink?
HeIIo, Hubert de BonaIoi?
This is Jean-Pierre Antoine.
I,m here with a camera crew
outside the apartment
where CIaudine and Jean-MicheI
are being heId hostage.
You read me?
We read you Ioud and cIear.
Good. As I was saying,
for the Iast 12 hours,
the Center has been hoIding its breath.
As has aII of France!
But who are these terrorists?
What do they want?
UnfortunateIy
we don,t know at this time.
Wait!
I see a terrorist, a femaIe.
ProbabIy their spokesman.
I,II ask the cameraman
to fiIm her.
TeII him to adjust the exposure.
Adjust the exposure.
HeIIo, terrorists!
Do you hear me? What do you want?
Why cause this nightmare?
You,re the nightmare, butt-face!
We,re sick of workers, sIums
and working for crumbs!
This is your Iast warning:
Stop your buIIshit
or we,II bIow it aII to bits!
They,ve got bombs!
What,s the situation?
It,s cIear that CIaudine
and Jean-MicheI are hostages.
They,ve been kidnapped,
imprisoned, taken hostage.
LegaIIy, this is a very tricky situation.
Two things can happen:
If they,re reIeased
after Iess than four days,
their assaiIants risk
15 years in prison,
but if the hostages are heId
for more than four days,
their assaiIants
couId receive Iife in prison.
But this isn,t a normaI situation!
We,re not judging aduIts
who,ve kidnapped chiIdren,
but chiIdren
who,ve kidnapped aduIts!
ChiIdren who,ve kidnapped aduIts!
That changes everything.
Existing Iaw
doesn,t address such a case.
FrankIy, I don,t see
a judiciaI soIution.
Something,s happening.
Do you read me?
They,re going to Iet us
see the ModeI CoupIe.
There they are!
It,s the CoupIe!
ModeI CoupIe, how are you?
We,ve been treated weII,
but we,re very tired!
It stinks in there!
The toiIets are cIogged!
The horror!
Terrorists, take me hostage
and reIease the ModeI CoupIe.
Chief, no!
Enough buIIshit!
We want action!
We want an hour of air time!
Got that?
An hour of air time or eIse!
Let,s go.
Hear that?
Anger,s running high,
but with Iives at stake,
we must keep it in check.
I,m speaking with Chief Bayard,
who, for the Iast 12 hours,
has shown incredibIe composure.
Bravo! IncredibIe!
You shouId,ve seen it!
They were shitting their pants!
You were great.
I aImost cried.
You were perfect.
Superb.
- Imagine what your parents wiII say!
- You smoke?
Kids grow up fast these days.
- Got a Iight?
- Here.
HoId on.
The chief of poIice.
Yes, it,s me.
Okay.
How Iong? Are you nuts?
Yeah. AII right.
When wiII it be aired?
And no funny stuff.
We don,t budge tiII we see it.
And we want a getaway car.
A Porsche.
No, a Mercedes.
- A RoIIs!
- A tank!
- Okay, bye.
- WeII?
A TV crew,s coming.
It,II air tonight.
CooI!
How much air time?
Three minutes.
Just three?
Programming confIicts.
We,II be on after the news.
That,s prime time.
Just three minutes!
We better think what to say.
We,II give ,em heII!
Check it out.
- Who,s there?
- TVcrew.
The TV crew, guys!
That was fast!
AII right!
HeIIo.
The terrorists.
What,s the pIan?
First, we expIain why we,re here.
Second, we expose
this entire operation,
and third -
Right. Where do we set up?
Stay there.
ModeI CoupIe, stand next to me.
CIear the tabIe.
JuIien, shut the door.
Nobody wants to hear speeches,
so we,II do something reaIIy cooI.
- What do we do?
- HoId on.
Can you beIieve this mess?
- Ready?
- RoIIing.
Terrorists, take 1 .
Here,s the big moment
you,ve been waiting for, foIks.
Sorry, no big desk and fIag,
but I,m speaking from the heart.
Let,s meet the gang.
I,m Pierrot.
This is JuIien and Georges,
and you aIready know
CIaudine and Jean-MicheI.
This is CharIotte,
Vincent and Frederic.
What was I gonna say?
Think about the TV you,re watching.
Whose is it?
OnIy two or three knobs work,
and the station chooses what you see.
You never Iook inside it.
Try to take it apart
and it,II bIow up in your face!
Same for your apartment.
You think you own it,
but your ceiIing is the fIoor upstairs,
the waIIs are
your neighbors, waIIs!
You got screwed!
Your apartment was soId twice,
and it,s Iike that with everything.
So? So you own nothing.
You,ve got nothing to Iose,
so give it up.
Thanks.
And now bring on the kids!
And now, the ModeI CoupIe!
We don,t reaIIy know
what to say.
We don,t reaIIy understand.
Listen here!
Enough nonsense.
Stop it now.
We,ve had enough.
Enough! Stop it!
You,re just jerking us around!
It,s aII buIIshit.
- No, it,s not.
- It is.
AII that stuff about the ministry!
We were having fun!
You,re Iike aII the others,
just trying to manipuIate us!
ManipuIate!
You don,t even know
what you,re doing.
What wiII happen to us now?
This experiment is important to us.
They,II throw us out
with no pay!
They won,t hoId you responsibIe.
- We,II be a Iaughingstock.
- Everyone wiII say we were in on it.
You were fed up, weren,t you?
What do you care?
It,s not your probIem.
You think you,re a revoIutionary!
You grab a mike
and show off on TV!
We were just having fun!
- Don,t you know poIitics is just a show?
- We put on a show!
A show!
Who do you think you are?
Put on a show
at home for your parents!
Lighten up!
FREE THE MODEL COUPLE
- Is it broken?
- No picture.
They must have
disconnected the antenna.
ProbabIy.
I bet they won,t even air it.
I,m getting hungry.
- Me too.
Let,s see what we can find.
- I,II go with you.
- Me too.
Wait for me.
Hey, guys, how about we -
Yeah, okay!
At Ieast we had fun, right?
Yeah, it was cooI.
What,s that?
They,re coming!
- What do we do, boss?
- Pack it aII up.
Check out what they,re doing!
They took out
aII our furniture.
We,d better go see.
Everybody out.
What are you doing
with our furniture?
We don,t know.
- Who toId you to put it here?
- The boss.
- Where,s the boss?
- We don,t know.
They,re throwing you out.
We didn,t mean for you to take the rap.
Sorry.
Why don,t you come with us?
Let,s go.
WeII, see ya.
Bye, CIaudine!
THE MODEL COUPLE
EXPERIMENT TERMINATED!
We don,t know where the boss is.
We don,t know.
We reaIIy don,t.
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
With your new way of Iife
And your stereophonic kisses
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
With your programmed happiness
And your standardized wishes
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
Not bad but not perfect
The average French coupIe
PoIiticaIIy correct
What,s troubIing you?
Is it aII in your head
or is it reaIIy true?
Don,t know, do you?
If not you, then who?
Poor IittIe dears,
you,ve waited for years
CoupIes aII across France
It,s too Iate
You,ve Iost your chance
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
With your new brand of dreams
And your video nightmares
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
Happy, sad, indifferent
Average at 88 percent
Hey, ModeI CoupIe!
Something must have changed,
ain,t that true?
No need to feeI bIue
Don,t caII us
We,II caII you
Yes, we,II remember
StiII at the same number?
Poor IittIe dears,
you,ve waited for years
CoupIes from aII across France
It,s over, no second chance!
TransIation by LYNN MASSEY
for SUBTEXT SUBTITLING