KOM EL NAHL (Bees Nest)
- Good morning.
- Welcome.
Is this Kom El Nahl?
I mean, how do I get there?
- I'm the new postmaster.
- Welcome, sir.
- Thank you.
- The village is down there.
- Is it far?
- No, only 2 kilometers.
Not bad.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
THE POSTMAN
Shukry Sarhan
Zizi Mustafa
Directed by Hussein Kamal
Out of my way.
Move it, now.
Scram.
Come here.
Where's the mayor's house?
It's this way.
Beat it.
Hello.
Good morning to you.
Isn't this the mayor's house?
Yes.
I need him.
Where's the mayor?
At mister Salameh's.
I am Abbas Hussein, the postmaster.
Welcome. Glad you made it.
You, boy.
Tell the mayor the postmaster's here.
Please.
Please sit.
You must be tired.
Mohammad.
Make us some tea.
It's a bad harvest.
- Is this the whole alfalfa harvest?
- Yes.
Two boxes only?
You father used to get
at least 10 per harvest.
The bees are abandoning me.
They're going elsewhere.
- Mister mayor.
- What is it?
The new postmaster is here.
Is he with you?
He's in your house with the deputy.
- Are you staying here?
- I'll come with you.
Today, in Asyut, the grand opening...
of the new American school...
for girls, free of charge...
for reading...
and writing...
and sewing, and cooking...
and many other skills...
What is this fellow going on about?
You should meet mister Car-Tar...
Hey, you there.
The mayor wants a word.
- Where are you from?
- Asyut.
- What are you shouting about?
- About a school, sir.
A new school...
with boarding for girls.
School?
For girls?
In Asyut.
Who would have thought?
And how do you get in?
If a girl is 16, can she go?
Yes, she can.
- If she can read and write.
- Of course she can.
You want to send your girl to school?
Have you no shame?
She's a young woman now.
Asyut boy, you leave this place now,
and don't let me catch you again.
Yes, sir.
Here's the flier.
- It has the address and the details.
- Scram.
Don't go for this modern nonsense.
Keep your daughter safe in her house.
Why shouldn't I send her?
The flier says she'll be
very well supervised.
She'll be with other young girls.
Times have changed, mayor.
It's not like the old days.
You know how things are now.
It will do us good.
She might marry a clerk...
and work as a teacher...
for extra income.
- You want her to work, too?
- Yes.
This is none of my business anyway.
Let's go see the postmaster.
- Yes, let's go.
- I'll need to discuss a matter...
Welcome, welcome.
Thank you.
We got word two weeks ago
that you were coming.
Sit down, deputy.
It took me a while to arrange the move.
Are you married?
No, I am not.
I support my mother and sisters.
My father is gone.
So you're single?
- Yes.
- And how will you live here?
Pardon me for intruding.
Like others.
I'll try to find a small place to stay.
Here?
In Kom El Nahl?
You won't.
This is the countryside. The only
way to get a house is to build one.
Besides, folks don't like
to rent out to single men.
What then? Where will I live?
You'll have to live in Asyut.
- And commute everyday?
- Yes.
Two hours by train from here to there.
2 hours?
Plus 2 kilometers walking...
both ways everyday?
No way. Impossible.
- Where is Smedah?
- He is staying in Bani Hussein tonight.
Smedah is quite a fellow.
He has the keys to the post office.
He's gone to Bani Hussein.
His second wife lives there.
He should be here in the morning.
I don't know.
Before starting work, I need
to know where I'll stay.
Asyut will not work out.
Don't you worry, my friend.
I'll find a suitable solution for you.
Tell me, mayor.
There's your old house...
How about it?
Indeed.
I was thinking of that.
Let's eat first and then go see it.
Or maybe...
we should go and see it before sunset.
We will send Jamilah to school in Asyut.
We'll do as you say.
But...
Will she commute to Asyut everyday?
No, she will stay there.
Really?
Away from her folks?
So what?
It's a boarding school.
It's run by priests and nuns.
She will be closely supervised.
When will she go?
She will leave tomorrow.
I'll take her.
I'll drop her off.
I won't leave her...
until I am sure she'll be safe there.
You're going to Asyut.
You're leaving tomorrow.
Your father decided.
Get me the rent contract.
Let's go.
Please come in.
This...
is where the mayor used to
live before he was mayor.
It's a very good house.
It's very solid.
Please, it's too much, don't exaggerate.
It does not compare to city homes.
But it will do here.
Tell me...
What's your name?
- Abbas Hussein.
- Tell me, mister Abbas...
Have you brought any furniture with you?
How much is it for?
40 pennies only.
Here's the contract.
This...
It's a room full of junk.
I have the key.
You won't need it.
Why would you need 2 rooms?
Congratulations.
You pay me when you can.
There's no rush.
Let me know if you need anything.
Goodbye now.
Goodbye.
Mariam, my heart is beating fast.
That's normal.
This is the first time you go away.
Soon you will be very happy.
Dear me.
I wish I could leave this place.
Can you take me with you?
I wish I could.
I'm afraid to go alone.
Mariam.
Are you done?
Go make her some food for the journey.
Yes.
This trip is making me nervous.
God help me.
You're a big girl, you'll behave well.
Were you afraid something bad happened?
That's how peasants are.
They're upset that they didn't
slaughter it before she died.
It's a big loss.
They can't use her meat now.
That would be a sin.
Although some of them don't care.
Someone will sell it to a butcher.
But everyone saw it's dead.
You're right, but some don't care.
The postman's here!
Get out of the way.
Hello, sir. Glad you made it.
I am sorry I am late.
It seems your new wife lives far away.
They've told you?
The mayor can't keep a secret.
The keys stay with me.
From now on, you come on time.
It is too early for this hassle.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
I said nothing.
What's all this?
A cow too?
How very nice.
A great start.
Go tend to her.
Does she need stamps?
Or is she mailing a letter?
What are you looking at?
Go get it out of here.
Send it back to its owner now.
Got it?
And what's this?
A little extra income in my free time.
What free time?
Your commute time to Bani Hussein?
Between the old and new wife?
Tell me, is this a post office...
or a stable?
What do you think?
It's always been like this.
It's not my place.
No, it isn't.
It's the government's place.
The government pays you to
keep it clean and tidy...
not to sell tomatoes in it, dear fellow.
Don't 'dear fellow' me.
I'm the mayor's relative.
I won't have you mocking me.
How very impressive.
So you're related.
Listen, mister relative.
I will write a report on
you and send it to Cairo.
If you don't wise up, I'll
demand your transfer.
Go tell your relative.
Now, mister relative...
Get a broom, and clean this mess up.
- How long have these been here?
- About a month.
Since they fired the old postmaster.
I got rid of him.
I ruined him.
I have money orders.
I want to keep them here.
- Where's the money order file?
- The police confiscated it.
Open a new one.
You see, the old postmaster
was a modern fellow, just like you.
He thought the village was backward,
and hated it.
- Can you come tomorrow?
- Sure, why not?
He started to drink and gamble...
with the accountant and
the station agent.
- That's when he began embezzling.
- What are these tales?
Better start working.
I don't want to hear such talk again.
I'm going to deliver the mail.
You better make this place
suitable for human beings.
Got it?
Hello.
- Welcome.
- Give me some pastrami.
- We're out.
- Give me some sardines.
- No.
- How about some cheese?
- No one buys such things.
- Just take some salmon.
Hello, mister agent.
I don't like salmon.
Once, I had some, and I got sick.
Then you need to stop by
the butcher for some meat.
Come with me.
- Where are you staying?
- The mayor's old house.
Watch out, that man is a snake.
This whole place is bad.
- You know...
- Yes?
I have mail for Izz Abou Kfour.
- You must know where that is.
- It took me 3 years of misery...
But I now know all of it. Show me.
Alright.
You go this way.
The villages are left and right.
They're separated by 2 kilometers.
How did you end up in this dump?
A promotion.
From a clerk in Cairo...
to a postmaster here.
In this dump, as you say.
- Yes, Khalil?
- Restroom, sir.
- What?
- Restroom.
Restroom again? What is this?
Enough. Sit down.
Please sir, this is the last time.
Fine.
Write it down.
Khalil, stop this nonsense.
- I have news from our cousin.
- Is that why you're here?
I know why you're here, you naughty boy.
- Isn't this your friend?
- Yes, it's Jamilah. What do you want?
Nothing. Just say hi.
- Come here.
- Fine.
Leave, before the principal sees you.
Don't forget to write to our cousin.
I'm leaving.
Send my regards.
Are you asleep?
I can't.
Wasn't that Khalil earlier?
Yes, my brother Khalil.
- Who did you think it was?
- I didn't think. I just got scared.
He had news from our cousin.
You run away every time.
- Why don't you talk to him?
- And say what?
I don't know.
Anything.
I think he likes you.
Hello, Darwish.
How are you?
Impossible.
Don't mention it again.
Abbas effendi, be reasonable.
The agricultural agent
needs a place to stay.
You have no use for that room anyway.
He can stay there.
- It makes sense.
- You want to rent it twice?
- No way.
- I am appealing to your good sense.
You better not go against me.
- What is this? A threat?
- Not at all.
- Remember that I rule this place.
- You rule?
That's right, I rule.
I rule.
We'll see, postmaster.
Time will tell. Go.
God damn this place.
I was about to leave.
- What is it?
- That owl of a mayor.
He has another renter.
He takes 40 pennies, and
he's got a room locked up.
Today he told me he wants to rent it.
What insolence.
And he threatened me.
Why did you stop visiting me?
You live far away.
The road is muddy, and dark at night.
- I travel enough by day.
- Hello.
Greetings, Aziz effendi.
Hello, Abbas effendi.
How are you?
See how he greets me?
Put in a good word in for me.
I will.
Be nice to Faltas effendi,
he's quite the fellow.
What is it now?
Why are you always after me?
I don't gamble, and I don't drink.
I only drink coffee and tea.
I am no good for you.
Give it up.
You do not do me justice at all.
I will not force you into anything.
In any case, you are welcome
to my place whenever you want.
Look there.
Here he is.
Eyes and ears wide open.
He wishes I'd stop by your place.
I'll drink, and gamble,
and he'll report me.
He wants me gone.
The mayor's relative, and
the village's private detective.
You're exaggerating.
You should relax. You're paranoid.
Loosen up.
I'll give you a good gift.
A piece of cloth, to make a gown from.
- Better than this stifling suit.
- A gown?
Me, in a gown?
You want to put me in a gown?
Like them?
Never mind him.
He's arrogant.
Only time will humble him.
- Humble me?
- I'm done here. I am leaving.
Humble me, you ignorant beast?
That will never happen.
By god, I will tame this place.
Take this, you might need this.
You're in quite a critical state.
Today, we go to the park.
We will study outdoors.
- Understood?
- Understood, mister Carter.
I want order.
Attention.
What's wrong, Jamilah?
Are you sad you're going back home?
Rejoice, vacation is near.
Sometimes you're heartless.
- I will miss you so much.
- You must come and visit me in Nekhilah.
How about it?
Father will say no.
Don't you have an aunt in our town?
Yes, but I can't visit her on my own.
- Either mother or father must come.
- So, you won't visit?
I don't have relatives in your village.
There's only a distant
relative, called Faltas.
We are not close.
Abbas Effendi, happy holidays.
I will see you soon.
Must you leave? I was hoping you'd stay.
- I need someone to talk to.
- Why don't you go visit your folks?
I wish I could, but I can't.
It would cost 3 pounds.
I don't have it.
It's going to be a bad break.
- Goodbye.
- Take care.
Daughter.
Hello.
Welcome back, dear.
You've changed a lot.
She looks so pretty. Look at her hairdo.
- Did you cut it?
- No, I just braided it.
Everyone does it in Asyut.
Why have you lost weight?
Mariam.
Make her some chicken.
- Yes, mam.
- Listen...
Go to your room and rest a while.
I will join you soon.
- I want to hear all about school.
- Yes, mother.
How are you?
Hello, sir.
No, sir. Please, don't.
Please, spare me.
Don't be scared.
I want to visit Nekhilah.
- Hush now, don't talk nonsense.
- I miss my aunt, I want to see her.
I said hush, I don't want to discuss it.
I will ask father to take me with him.
Your father?
- Welcome back, daughter.
- Thank you, father.
- Father...
- Yes?
I want to visit my aunt in Nekhilah.
You just came back home.
You haven't been here a day.
Please, father.
I miss her so much. Plus,
it's the holidays.
When I travel to Asyut, I'll
drop you off in Nekhilah.
Thank you, father.
Happy holidays indeed.
Where are you from?
From around here.
- And where are you from?
- Cairo.
The center of the world.
I want to talk to you.
Talk to me?
- Talk about what?
- Many things.
How about it?
Where do you live?
In the mayor's old home.
That little man was right.
It came in handy.
Girl, you're good.
Better than Badia Masabni.
I can't believe my eyes.
Tell me, have you ever seen Badia dance?
And how?
Le me tell you.
We used to go every month...
my friends and I...
We'd spend the whole night.
God. Those were good times.
The music... The dance... The wine...
and the people.
Not like this hellhole here.
Those were the days. You
shouldn't remind me of them.
Tell me...
Do you miss Cairo?
Do I miss it?
I long for it, I burn for it.
Come here.
Why don't you come here?
Am I awake or dreaming?
This city man has come here to soil us.
Are we going to stand for it?
The postmaster is a bastard.
He has a woman with him in there.
Is that right?
My god.
Get out, woman.
- You can't do this in the mayor's home.
- You shut up, you senile idiot.
Show me some respect.
Take your men and leave now.
I have no women here.
No. There are women.
So be it. I do as I please.
You better mend your
ways before the mayor hears about this.
Are you threatening me?
You can both go to hell.
Go tell him.
I won't open.
What are you going to do about it?
Calm down, effendi.
Let me leave. We'll meet later.
- Are you frightened? Stay here.
- They're unforgiving, effendi.
I know them well.
They'll wait until I come out.
And if I don't, they'll ruin me.
Why is your hair undone, woman?
What were you doing in there?
Will show us a good time too?
My house is near. Wanna come with me?
Is he better than us?
Did he pay you?
- Damn you.
- Let me touch this white marble.
God help me.
Are you Abbas effendi?
Yes, sir.
I am the police chief.
- Welcome.
- May I have a word?
Of course. Please come inside.
The mayor has reported you, and
demands you vacate his house.
The deputy and other eye witnesses...
Caught him, red-handed,
during the holidays...
in the company of a woman of ill-repute...
and since... etc etc.
- What do you think?
- Me?
I think that the mayor...
- is a greedy man, and a criminal.
- I sympathize with you.
- I know you have your issues.
- It's all because of the house.
An old house. A dump.
It is not worth a dime.
- Let's go and reconcile you.
- Me, go there?
That criminal?
He should be the mayor of cattle...
- not people.
- Mister postmaster...
Put this in my account.
Still saving up money, are you?
- Why don't you spend it instead?
- I am not doing anything illegal.
Here's 10 pennies.
Don't follow your family's desires;
It will ruin you. How much is it now?
Almost there.
He is starving himself to save.
You know why?
To buy a gun and avenge his father.
Everyone knows.
Even the dead know.
Goodbye.
- And you do nothing?
- What can we do?
This crime of revenge will happen, just
like thousands before it.
And I'll question, and investigate...
and even the dead man's family
will cover for the murderer.
They'll avenge him themselves.
A vicious circle of ignorance.
There is nothing to do.
They're not to blame;
They live in the dark.
Ever since I came here...
- I can't stand it.
- I tried hard to get transferred.
Petitions, and letters...
I was just like you.
But the days passed.
I have been here 6 years.
I forced myself to be content.
And little by little...
I got to recognize the good in the bad.
One must not...
wallow in anger and despair forever.
Send my lunch over.
I will stay there.
Yes.
- Good morning, aunt.
- Good morning, dear.
Aren't we going?
Be reasonable, dear.
Your father would not approve.
He said you should stay home.
But it's a short trip,
and you're coming with me.
- I can't go out either.
- Please aunt, I beg you.
Sheir is my best friend.
We go to school together.
You'll meet her mother.
- Stop badgering me.
- Please aunt, say yes.
Uncle won't be back until nightfall.
He's busy.
Sit down.
After I deliver his lunch...
- We'll go together to meet your friend.
- Thank you, aunt.
- Welcome.
- Thank you for having us.
- Is this your school friend?
- Yes, mother.
And I'm the aunt she dragged with her.
We are honored by your visit.
I've heard so much about you.
I've been looking forward to meeting you.
- I've been bedridden so long.
- You must stay strong.
God willing.
Welcome to Nekhilah, Jamilah.
Thank you, mam.
Sheir holds you in such high esteem.
- I'll show Jamilah the garden.
- Don't be late.
Of course.
God bless them.
Sheir is a good girl.
I'm in Nekhilah.
I can't believe it.
I'm so happy.
So very happy.
Let's talk.
I feel like flying.
My heart is beating so fast. Feel it.
It's going to burst.
- I thought you were never coming.
- It was hard.
I had to pester my aunt for a long time.
- She finally said yes.
- Good girl. I'll show you the ruins.
- Will we be late?
- No. Let's go.
You stay here and wait for me, got it?
You scared us. What are you doing here?
- I've come looking for you.
- Looking for me, or for someone else?
How are you, Jamilah?
Welcome to Nekhilah.
Thank you.
Did you tour the ruins?
- It's just rocks. I don't get it.
- It used to be huge castle.
Shall I tell you the story?
- This was a castle?
- Yes.
About 2 acres. A long time ago.
Before the demons took over.
Stop teasing.
I tell the truth.
Jamilah, are you scared?
Don't be scared.
I'll protect you.
Tell us the story.
It was a huge castle.
The king had a daughter...
who was beautiful...
All the princes wanted her hand.
But the king said no.
He wanted to marry her to another king.
But the daughter fell in
love with a servant.
The king found out.
He built this castle.
It was secluded and well guarded.
She was held prisoner in here.
The castle was full of gold, and jewels...
and other wonders.
But all she wanted was her love.
She would write to him, on stones.
- Are you fooling us?
- Don't believe me? I'll show you.
Come.
- Should I read it?
- That's a letter?
- It's a drawing.
- Yes, silly. They used drawings.
And then what?
Finish the story.
What happened to her?
Her?
Yes.
She wrote many letters.
And then...
they eloped.
- They traveled to another kingdom.
- What's wrong?
What can I say?
- You want to talk in English?
- Yes, teach us.
Khalil speaks English very well.
Show her your pen.
Mister Carter gave it to him...
because he speaks English so well.
Naughty girl.
Show me.
What are doing after graduation?
Find a job.
A job where?
I don't know.
My brother-in-law will help me find one.
I already wrote him.
He lives in Alexandria.
- You'll move there?
- Yes.
And they traveled to another kingdom...
- But it is so far away.
- Yes, it is.
But it is a beautiful place.
Don't you want to stay here
and take care of your land?
I didn't study to be a peasant.
I want to travel and
live in the big cities.
Why so sad, Jamilah?
What to say?
Let's play hide-and-seek.
Yes, let's do it.
I'll count.
And they traveled to another kingdom...
- I've been waiting for hours.
- Here we are.
- Is the boss here?
- No, in Nekhilah.
- I wanted to discuss it with him.
- What's there to discuss?
Get to the point.
Say what's on your mind.
We want to know who it was.
I don't know, and I don't want
to involve my husband in this.
- Fine.
- Call her.
Listen.
You take her and deal with her elsewhere.
Use your judgment.
Do what is best for your name.
Yes?
Yes.
Mariam.
Your folks are here.
Your brother and uncle.
Are you going to make them wait?
Uncle? Brother?
- Welcome.
- We've missed you a lot.
You're coming to Luxor with us.
Why? What happened?
People have been talking.
Serious things.
I am innocent. Have mercy.
Why are you crying?
- It is too late now.
- God damn you. You know I'm innocent.
Dear me, Khalil...
- What are you doing?
- I must talk to you.
- I travel tomorrow.
- Travel?
- Travel where?
- Alexandria.
My brother-in-law wrote back.
He said to come.
I want to see you. Can I come up?
No, please don't.
Stay there.
I'll come down.
Are you leaving me?
Don't leave me, I beg you.
Don't be silly.
You're always in my heart.
I won't be long.
After my first paycheck, I'll
come and ask for your hand.
I'm in your hands...
to do as you please.
Are you scared?
No, but I don't know how I'll wait.
Whenever you think of
me, write me a letter.
Here's the address. Save it.
Write me every day.
And when I get there, I'll write to you.
Why did you rip it?
I will never forget it. Don't worry.
- Welcome. We've not seen you around.
- I have not been feeling good.
I didn't go to work.
- Honestly, I am fed up.
- By the way...
You got a package by train.
What package?
It must be some magazines I ordered.
I was expecting them.
Your mail doesn't go
through the post office.
Better by train than through the post.
Excuse me.
- Take care.
- Goodbye.
I'll see you all later, at home.
Instead of staring, make me some tea.
Any mail for 'Awaden Mahrous?
- Is that you?
- No.
- Where is he?
- Don't know.
Animals...
Here.
Listen, I'm out delivering mail.
You stay here.
Come see. See what has become of us.
I'll show you. Come.
What is it?
This is a real woman, you mules.
My god.
By god, those we married are not women.
Unbelievable.
Where are their gowns?
- It must be drawings.
- Drawings, you idiots?
They're photographs, like in
posters in the town hall.
They're not like these pictures.
This is something else.
Abbas effendi is a sly fox.
He knows these women.
They send him pictures.
He'll send word for the one he likes.
Yes.
These women are coming here?
Ever since the dancer incident...
he's changed.
I tried my best to make a
drawing of my heart...
with a picture of you inside.
I am back home, but you're still
in my heart. I miss you, my love.
Once you receive this letter, please
write me to Oum Ahmad's address.
I've attached the address.
Everyone knows Oum Ahmad here.
She'll help us.
Rest assured she'll deliver your letters.
- She can keep a secret...
- Tell me, aunt.
- What is Jamilah doing?
- She's upstairs.
I will go and check on her.
Fine.
Do you want to see my fabrics?
They're beautiful.
Here's the letter. Please mail it soon.
Please don't tell anyone.
I beg you.
Silly girl. Your secret is safe with me.
Come here.
- Deliver this to the train.
- Yes.
Go.
And don't ride the donkey.
Out of here, scum.
How are you, Abbas effendi?
I feel like garbage.
Here I come.
What's wrong?
There is not one person I can talk to.
Not even to joke with.
It's awful.
All the town's secrets are with you.
Its coming and goings are
all in these letters.
Comings and goings?
These were not written by humans.
I think that these people...
aren't humans.
You know, I envy you.
You work far away.
Take it easy. Calm down.
It's just like other towns.
They'll all backward.
I need to catch the train.
Goodbye.
Here are the vaunted letters.
Same old stories.
Never ending drudgery.
A pile of disgusting
missives, coming and going.
Cairo to Kom El Nahl...
Kom El Nahl to Mahatta...
To be delivered by hand to recipient...
Urgent, urgent, urgent...
You stamp it...
throw it in a bag, then the train...
Two days later, you get the answer.
You will end me with your hands.
You will mock me to my grave.
I want to know how you live.
What goes on in your skulls?
Comings... Goings...
You sons of...
I got you now.
From now on, I'm watching you.
I'll crawl under your skins.
What's wrong with him? He must
come in person to take his wife...
It's shameful.
We resolved the problem...
We inspected the well on Wednesday...
All was good at the end...
Another pound, that makes six...
Your mother is coming...
Fatma, once you receive the
money, open an account...
Save some aside...
Send my greetings to all the relatives...
When I come back, you better not...
The buffalo costs two pounds to feed...
I will only pay one
pound, and that's all...
Nothing for me today?
Why are you angry? What have I done?
Name?
Your servant, Oum Ahmad.
Nothing today.
Try again tomorrow.
Yes, I will try tomorrow.
God bless you, and help
you, and smile upon you.
Hello my love...
My warmest kisses and passion to you...
This old hag...
still gets kisses? And passion?
My love, I must tell you that...
I am sorry I haven't written in a while...
I have been so busy...
I think of you night and day...
The position that my
brother-in-law promised me...
is on hold.
I was in despair...
I did not want to burden you with this.
But I have found...
another position in Cairo...
I will start soon, god willing.
Therefore, my love...
my darling, my sun...
do not write to this address anymore...
as I am traveling today to Cairo.
I have so much more to tell you...
once I get settled in Cairo...
I await your reply with
burning impatience...
Please write to me to
this temporary address...
Khalil Effendi Saad...
Impossible. It can't be.
There's a secret.
Is this Oum Ahmad...
moonlighting as a postwoman?
She's delivering letters.
- You little...
- Hello, sir.
Anything today?
Hello. Just in time.
You have one letter.
- Sign here.
- I need a favor.
I forgot my stamp. Can
I use my fingerprint?
Sure. Just for you.
Don't forget it again.
My guardian angel...
I received the letter I have been
waiting for so feverishly...
My love...
Ever since we left Nekhilah,
my soul is with you...
I am so happy that you found a job...
I pray to god to keep you safe.
My love...
My sister has visited me...
Mother could not come...
We went to the zoo...
We saw the lion, and the tiger, and
the elephant. She was very pleased.
How I wish you were here with me.
My love, I write to you everyday...
All I do is think of you...
You write every fortnight.
I suffer while I wait...
My love, have you forgotten me?
Has Cairo made you forget me?
If you love me, write me more often.
My dearest love...
How can you say I forgot you?
I have good news for you.
I am coming to you soon.
I will come to your home and
ask for your hand in marriage.
Mother, I can't believe it. I can't wait.
Let's see what your father thinks.
Please god...
Welcome.
- You honor my house.
- The honor is ours.
- Please rest.
- Here you go.
Thank you.
- Khalil wants to discuss a matter.
- Welcome, mister Khalil.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Speak, man.
Don't be bashful. Fine, I'll speak.
Mister Khalil wants to get married.
- He asks for your daughter's hand.
- I'm honored.
- Tell me about yourself.
- Mister Khalil...
is the son of Saad Abou Ragheb...
god rest his soul, from Nekhilah.
You must know him.
He and his sister own land there.
And what's more, he works in Cairo.
- You said Nekhilah?
- Yes, sir.
My mother is sorry she couldn't make it.
- She is ill.
- I understand.
My uncle represents her.
Khalil is family to me.
His late father...
was my father's cousin.
- Welcome.
- Thank you, sir.
- We're going to be relatives.
- Slow down a little.
- So you're from Nekhilah?
- Yes, sir.
My sister is Jamilah's friend.
- They're in the same class.
- You know her name?
Did she visit you?
Yes, she visited my sister once.
- So it's like that.
- What do you say, sir? Do you agree?
I think it's too early for this.
She's still too young.
- But...
- Later.
We'll talk later, when she
finishes her studies.
- But that will take years.
- So what?
You must be reasonable.
- We might not come back.
- As you wish.
She won't marry.
As you wish, sir.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
You say she was in Nekhilah?
And you know her name, too?
Yes, sir.
Men coming. This way.
Goodbye.
Why did he change his mind?
What a mule. I told you not to bother.
What are you doing? He might see you.
He knows you? You're
friends with his sister?
Where did you meet? Speak.
You bring me shame and dishonor.
I've deprived you of nothing.
Is this how you pay me back?
You think you're so smart?
You see him behind my back?
From now on, no school for you.
You stay home.
He said no, mother. He said no.
Woe is me.
I am ruined, as good as dead.
Why did he say no? What's
wrong with Khalil?
Daughter.
What is it?
Mother, you must help me.
I beg you.
What have you done?
What a disaster.
God help us. A scandal.
- Help me. Convince father.
- Convince him?
Him, break his word? After all this?
You know how he is.
I will marry her, despite his wishes.
- You'll see. I'll do it.
- As you wish.
It will be hard.
My love, I have not heard
from you in so long...
If only you knew... I
am a captive in my house...
I'm so distraught, I can't sleep...
It's starting to show...
My mother found out...
Oh no.
I should go early.
I must mail her letter by nine.
This is serious.
Since you left, I'm hiding in my room...
hoping father does not notice.
Time is passing, my belly is
growing, and he will soon find out.
Please find a way, I beg you.
Take me from this place...
I'll be forever grateful.
I can no longer hide...
You idiots.
What have you done?
When did it happen?
Once he finds out...
he'll find a way.
Take these to the train.
But I just came back. Why not wait?
I said now. Move it.
Good. It will make it.
Unless the idiot goes elsewhere.
Dearest angel...
I am in agony over my
encounter with your father.
I have received a message
from my brother-in-law...
saying that the original job is ready.
I was very happy.
I was busy moving.
That is why I have not written yet.
I am sorry I have neglected you.
I am writing you from Alexandria,
where I started my job.
Please write me to my Alexandria address.
He is no longer in Cairo.
He won't get her letter.
As for the marriage, rest
assured that I will find a way.
I can't picture us apart.
I am looking for an apartment for us.
I will write in more detail soon.
If your father persists...
you should elope, and we'll get married.
If you agree, please write me.
Finally, my warmest kisses to you.
God help them.
Poor creatures.
He knows she's suffering.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
- How much this time?
- No.
- I want my money.
- Why?
- Changed your mind about the gun?
- Stay out of it.
- I want my 10 pounds and 80 pennies now.
- You can't have it.
- It has to go through the main office.
- What main office?
- The office in Cairo, my friend.
- I do not care.
- I want my money.
- Didn't you understand?
- Hello, mister postmaster.
- Hello.
- I need a word with you.
- What is it?
- The mayor wants you to leave his home.
- Again?
Always the house. Won't you quit?
I swear to god...
and to you, and the mayor,
and this hell hole...
I am not leaving. Got it?
Don't come here again.
Scram and go tell your mayor.
Is that so? Me, scram?
- We'll see.
- Mister deputy.
- Please help me.
- You scram too.
I'm going to report you to the mayor.
Wait, deputy. I'm coming with you.
Unbelievable.
What's this?
I knew something bad was going to happen.
What to do?
It's tainted. I can't deliver it.
It's hopeless.
She won't know he's in Alexandria.
So what? They're in love...
They'll find a way.
But she's pregnant.
He'll write another letter.
He will surely write again.
Nothing.
- Maybe this evening.
- Thank you. I will try this evening.
God help them.
I should have stayed out of this.
- Why did I interfere?
- To the station, I'll follow you.
- Yes?
- How's your daughter?
- She's in bed. She's feeling better.
- I am traveling.
If she steps out of the house...
- I'll cut both your throats.
- You know, dear...
mister Khalil is from a good
family, and he has a good job.
I don't want to hear this.
God help us all.
Who is it?
It's Jamilah.
Welcome. Come in.
Please come in.
Sit.
- I'm sorry for the mess. I'm traveling.
- Traveling?
For a little while. I
am going to a wedding.
My cousin's.
I'll stay for a week.
I know you're worried about the letters.
I check everyday.
Honestly, dear...
I must tell you...
I think he maybe got
discouraged by your father.
He hasn't written since.
You're crying?
Did something happen?
It's like that?
Why didn't you say anything?
Please, tell me what to do.
Don't worry.
I'll be away for a week.
When I'm back, I'll help you fix this.
He wrote again.
Oum Ahmad has not stopped by lately.
Come here.
Take this to Oum Ahmad.
- Who?
- The old lady who dyes her hair red.
I noticed that you are fond of her.
- You should stay away from such people.
- You shut up.
- Deliver the letter.
- I don't deliver letters.
She must pick it up herself.
You know the rules.
I'll be outside.
Damn you.
My dear, I can't bear our separation.
I found an apartment.
The view is breathtaking.
I feverishly await your arrival.
Or have you changed your mind?
I am surprised you haven't written.
I beg you, my darling,
to write to me again.
That will make me so happy.
Tell me when you're coming, and I will
wait for you at the station.
Great.
She'll find out he's back in Alexandria.
Where's Oum Ahmad?
You there.
Go inside.
- You'll delivering it?
- I said inside.
Where's Oum Ahmad?
Where does she live?
Do you know where Jamilah lives?
Where can she be?
- I want to know.
- No.
Mister deputy, come here.
You there.
Take two policemen, and go
round up those girls.
Deputy, come.
He'll show you the way.
Write this down:
On this date, etc...
To the police commissioner:
An employee at the post-office...
informed me...
that the postmaster, Abbas Hussein...
assaulted a young girl
on her way to market.
Moreover, the aforementioned...
tried to assault another girl on the
same day, and she escaped.
This occurred on the main road.
Neither girl agreed to testify...
for fear of gossip and scandal.
Signed by the mayor. Hand
it over, I'll stamp it.
I attacked you?
Speak.
You too.
I'm going mad.
I swear...
I swear I've never seen them before.
- All this for a house?
- Calm down, please.
Watch it. Your father is here.
Mother, please help me.
Oh god.
Who's here? Darwish?
You're here? Thank you.
I've slept a lot.
I have to go to work.
I have to see what happened.
If I hadn't interfered...
they'd be together.
She'd be safe.
I ruined them.
In Cairo, I wouldn't have cared.
But here, I fear for her.
They'll kill her.
They're animals.
I know them.
If only I could find her.
If something happens to
her, I'm responsible.
I'd feel like I killed her myself.
Please, I beg you, don't.
Khalil, save me.
Khalil.
Tell me, Khalil.
What did the king's daughter do?
The daughter...
She eloped.
They went to another kingdom.
Another kingdom.
The End
Subtitles by Kanafani