All similarities with real persons
and occurrences are intentional.
"The Blueberry War"
No problem. Off course you can make
that money in Sweden.
It was my cousin Jerzy from Poland
who called me. I told him I would help.
We'll sort it out. Come up to Sweden
and we get you that money.
And here we are, in the middle of the
Swedish wilderness.
I already started to regret what I
had promised.
Wake up Stefan. There is someone at
our place.
I'm sleeping.
It's just a moose.
It is the chinese pack. They saw our
car at the road.
Sorry, we didn't see any sign this
was your place.
In Sweden there is a law they call
"All mens right".
This is Kongo-Rolle. He's the bodyguard
to one of the local berry buyers.
Nadja, the Russian, who mostly deals
with the Ukrainian pickers.
He did what?
Today... where are you?
What did he say?
Sedvallson?
Tell him to go to hell
if he comes back!
That asshole Sedvallson has been at
the Ukraine's and scared them.
Said that the immigration authority
will take their visa
If they don't sell to him.
Can he do that? He's just a runner
for the Berry king.
They have to. He has their
passports and documents.
He is worse than Stalin.
Fucking Blueberry Stalin!
I don't think you should
throw dirt on Stalin.
He made the Sovjet Union
a superpower.
You're stupid.
Stalin did nothing good!
Are you thinking like a baby?
Two other important characters in this story,
Ullabritten, the local EU business manager
And Svante Sedvallsson, the local dealer,
who's also involved in the berry trade.
This is big business, the last thing
we need is trouble with poles.
There is no problem with the poles.
It's the other pickers that makes fuss.
The Berry king is involved and his freezing
company in Poland... Polzamar...
Polzamarzac.
Ain't this cosy?
When my job get too intense,
I use to go out here and wash the car.
All tensions lose up.
It's like fucking in the Jacuzzi.
What is it, Svante?
I only have a shower at home.
They tell me you are a fixer.
You will help me with this, won't you?
It smells like curry, maybe they are
stealing hens somewhere.
That barrel is almost what
they have taken from us.
Rice with curry.
What about the rice?
No!
Have you got any berries, lads?
Just a few buckets, those fucking
chinks picked all our berries.
Stefan! They are here with our
blueberries.
Stop fighting for some lousy
litres of blueberries.
They have been a pain in the ass
the whole week.
Take it easy! Sit down while
I settle up with the others.
How many kilo, Monika?
138.
We want money. Money, real money, no
paper!
Much blueberry, much work,
much paper, much money.
Monika, could you drive them
back to the camp?
They think I am some sort of cash
machine, but they like stamps.
Well boys, what can I do for you?
We have some berries to sell.
Forget the blueberries.
I have a real job for you.
Young, strong guys like you
shouldn't pick blueberries.
What about a real job.
Ten thousand. Black.
Black?
What did he say?
He has a good job, no tax.
A real job.
You'll do it in a week, ten days.
Wait, I'll show you.
He might cheat us.
We need the money, don't we?
What was that about no tax?
Come on, how was it with your sister?
Without contract and receipt he can
cheat us.
We have to raise the value of the building.
Water in the pool, repair the illuminated track...
Someone?
Most important is to get rid of the
loss from the last bankruptcy.
There must be some department with a profit
that can use the loss in their tax planning.
The dump is the only section with a
profit.
But they take the loss from
the theatre and the museum.
Did we pay the fire insurance this
year?
Yes, we did.
Good.
Further.
I've hired some carpenters for you.
Do you have a permit?
Molle will take care of it.
Do you know someone who can
put this place on fire?
I thought the Poles were going to buy
it?
I'm not sure we can fraud them to
invest in such a rats nest.
What about the contribution from EU?
We'll see what happens.
Börje!
Remember to talk to Molle about the
permit.
Listen now. When I was in Poland they invited
me on a hunting trip. I shot a wild boar.
When that polish tourist attaché arrives,
I have promised him a moose hunt.
What?
Ullabritten, no way! It's three weeks
before our hunting season starts.
Börje, we're trying to sell a tourist resort
that has been bankrupted four times.
And slowly is eaten by mould,
termites and bad bank loans.
But moose hunting is serious matters.
Who's in charge of that?
The County council of course.
I guess it's guarded by some nature
freak.
Who is the boss for the County
council?
Well... it's the County governor, of
course...
Börje, who is the County governor?
I am.
Then who's in charge of the moose
hunting?
Do you know someone who can find a
moose, Svante?
It was all about Jurek's younger sister.
She needed an eye surgery.
I had told Jurek that's an easy thing
in Sweden.
Lots of Polish doctors work in Sweden.
I know one that surely can help you.
Don't worry. We will take care of this,
I told him.
Well done, lads. The inspector was pleased.
Just some more nails in the roofbeams.
Have a look at this.
Beware of him. He's the head of the
construction board. Politician, politruk.
Hide if you see this guy or his car,
ok?
Now you can start working.
Nobody has died of a little rain.
Think about the money, boys.
What car was he driving?
A blue Volvo.
What the hell, it was a red Saab.
I told you...
Take it easy, Sedvallson.
GLH 231, red Saab...
You can't make jokes about
such a serious thing.
I get into trouble if they find you.
Maybe it's better if
you work in the night.
Think about the money, boys!
Ten thousand, he said.
Ten thousand, no receipt and he will
do the surgery.
Health care is free in Sweden.
Maybe for the swedes.
But this fucking doctor is polish.
And earning a good buck here in
Sweden.
What will happen if she don't
get that surgery?
She will be blind.
They say it will take half a year
and then she can't see anymore.
We finish this job and
you have the money.
Remember what he said:
"Think about the money, boys."
Maybe it's the inspector?
Politicians don't run around
in the forest at night.
This is Sweden.
Not even here they do.
Have you seen any moose?
Moose...elk?
Nail?
Both Sedvallson and Nadja were minor
buyers compared to the Berry king.
Wholesale dealer, owned the freeze house,
bribed the officials at the immigration office.
Take that once again.
My polish freezing company buy half
of the ski resort from the County council
And pay with shares in the company.
The County council will own half of my freezing business
and I will own half of their mouldering tourist resort.
If we estimate, each part has a
stock value of 25 millions
Then we can get 50 millions as EU
contribution for interregional co-operation.
Understand?
Yes.
Good.
The polish tourist association takes
care of the polish stock.
But...
...the swedish company need a
swindler.
Some one who signs the company papers and get
a 25 million dept when the company has been stripped.
Pretty much.
You'll take care of that, won't you
Svante?
You have to explain what you want
from me...
This is big business.
You can get a piece of the cake...
What should I do to get that
opportunity?
The Berry king is buying the ski
resort from the County council.
And pay with shares from the company.
Fifty, fifty, and then...
...it will be possible to raise the
same amount from the interregional EU-fund.
The higher price, the more you get.
And the polish company?
A junk yard, freon and poison.
Run, for God's sake!
And what's my part?
Signing the swedish firm taking over
the shares in the freeze company.
5% of the EU contribution. And a
grant that all the debts are taken care of.
5%! That would be millions. The only thing
you need to do is signing some papers.
Two?
Four.
Typical!
I'll see what I can do.
It really looks nice, Svante. Very
good job.
Just a little crack in the window
panel.
We will take care of that later.
Hello, and welcome!
Champagne for everyone. And for me of
course.
Come on!
These are the boys that helped me.
They are so skilled.
I need to get a refill. I'll be back
later.
The police! They stopped down at the road.
We must get out of here fast as hell.
You have the key.
You had it last, when you bought
nails.
I gave it to you.
I don't have any key.
Sedvallson was with them!
He was there with the police.
Showing them were are tent was.
I put in on the left front wheel.
We had been cheated. He always did
like that.
When the job was done he reported you as illegal
workers. You had to leave without any payment.
Ullis sad that she paid him 80 000
for the job.
Ullis who?
The lady with the house, Ullabritten.
She paid him 80 000 for the job.
"Ullis"?
He offered us 10 000.
It doesn't matter.
Now he has cheated us anyway.
Hurry up!
Hello!
Seen anything?
Should it be a bull moose?
A big one. With huge horns that the
tourist clown can bring back to Poland.
Are you sure it's ok with
the County council?
Yes. It was the County governor
himself who gave the permit.
You know, there is millions in
EU contribution on stake.
What do you think?
Then we take one from the research centre,
they have radio transmitter. Easier to find.
You haven't seen any red polish car
around?
See you!
Could you follow me, please?
Do you need any help, darling?
No, I'm fine.
He owns us at least 40 000.
These are worth less than
the paper it's written on.
Shouldn't we buy them back?
We will sort it out with him later.
What the hell are you doing?
Are you insane?
Where the hell is our money?
You can't pay with only papers and stamps!
I will call the police!
POLICE, understand?
Just call the police then!
Then we will tell them.
Just call the police! Come on!
Let's push this crap down.
Come on! Let's go!
You will regret this!
The police! Yes, that's right...
We were lucky that you were out on
the road this early.
Have a taste.
I've put sugar in it,
I think it should be sweets for the sweet.
Little but tasty.
Nothing happens here.
Well, we're coming back soon.
Pet him!
He like women.
He can smell when they're near.
Horny like a baboon.
They are on their way.
Just passing Finnfallet.
Can you move the cart a little
forward?
Roadblock, reverse to the dirt road.
Do you need any more help?
I can follow you with the tractor?
You don't have to. Just move that
fucking pig.
Yes, yes.
Go away. We will take care of it.
Where is the key?
Damn it!
How much berries was it?
Many tons of berries, worth at least
100 000.
That's what happens if you try to be nice
and give them a chance to earn some money.
They haven't given up. They will be here
in ten minutes. We have to move on.
She will be blind. Where am I going
to find the money? You screw it all up.
We have to go on.
The police are after us. What are we
doing here Stefan?
Driving around in the forest like fools with a ton
of stolen blueberries in the middle of nowhere.
We can sell them to that Russian
buyer and then you'll have money to bribe that doc
You can't bribe anyone with thousand
litres of rotten blueberries.
How's your foot?
It hurts. We'll have to do something
about it.
How's it going, Geronimo?
They've been here. Someone stepped
in the blueberries.
Let's give up.
We better go back to the station. We just
get into trouble if we keep on working too much.
This is the bus, you can tell from
the wheelbase. The tires are smaller, you know.
Is it still warm?
Warm?
What are you talking about?
I better drive, maybe we can speed up
a bit.
What the hell, Jörgen! We have been
working since 4 am.
For christ's sake, Jörgen!
We were one millimitre from crashing
into that fucking moose.
Take it easy, it wasn't even close.
Let's quit. Stop. Finito!
What's your problem? Have you never
been in a car with a real rally driver?
Annika!
Annika, can you put up the warning
triangle? It may...
...someone might come...
Just for some fucking litres of
blueberries!
Is there any sign of life out in
space?
You haven't seen a moose by any
chance?
That damn Jörgen was two millimetres
from crashing into one just a moment ago.
A bull moose, with huge horns? Almost
black?
Something like that.
I'll drive.
Stop, it's your colleague!
He can walk home. Bloody idiot!
What a luck that you were here
Mäntyranta.
You can thank my stupid sister for picking you up.
I thought of leaving you as food for the wolves.
I understood we had to do something about
Jurek's foot so we went to the polish doctor.
If the police were after us we could explain
everything to him. At least he was polish.
I told you he would help you.
Did he say anything about your
sister's eye surgery?
He still wants ten thousand for putting
her on the waiting list.
He is an asshole, I know.
Stefan, you said we would earn money here in Swede
Pick blueberries and do carpentry.
Where shall I get the money?
I have to pay him ten grand for my sister
and twenty for the plaster.
Twenty thousand?
Otherwise he will report me to the
authority.
He must be crazy.
I have to pay him in a month, or
else...
Or else what?
He know some people who can break the
foot again.
How's your foot?
Not so good.
Listen.
Call that russian lady.
Yes, I know. I saw it on TV.
Stay were you are.
I will contact you tomorrow.
Have you seen Sedvallson?
I think he is with the other
boys in the sauna.
No. it's because they have such red
eyes...
Is it Rotary meeting?
Are you cold, boys?
Is Sedvallson here?
Not even in the sauna you can
be alone from the women.
Don't be silly Svante. You have to
leave DNA for the paternity case.
What do you want?
The moose has crossed the county
border.
Isn't there any other around?
Not with such big horns. Not with
transmitter.
Couldn't you call him back?
Empty. No one could live like this.
The papers are only a few days old.
I'll see if we can sleep on the
attic.
Hello!
Hey! Hello! Sorry if we bother you.
What did he say?
Where is Ivar?
There is a naked man in the potato
field.
Give me the blanket.
Is he weird?
Guess he is a bit crazy.
But no more than any one else
out here in the forest.
It's against the rheumatism.
It's great for the body.
The whole body...
Get on your horses!
He knows a few words in polish.
A lady from Ukraine or Belarus
stayed here a couple of years ago.
Could you bring get some blueberries?
I heard about you on the radio.
I'm the maid from the local
government.
It smelled of yeast. Something was
fermenting...
A top modern high-tec moonshine
factory in the crazy man's barn.
What is it?
Look!
They were transported to the airport were they
are waiting for a flight back to Thailand.
Soon this group will be sent out of the country.
As you can see there's a lot of emotions involved.
Where the stolen blueberries are
hidden is still a mystery.
That's right. We have to show those hooligans that
they can't come here and do anything they want.
Can I have some more?
Stop that, you old horny stud!
Keep quite about things you don't know.
They start with blueberries and cars.
Then money and antiques.
Robbing old people in the countryside.
I've read about in the papers.
It's only Mäntyranta.
Is Ivar at home?
Sorry. He happens to be at
the opening of the Opera tonight.
Later on it was a cocktail party at
the Spybar.
Heard that he's been naked the whole
week.
Is it Väinämöinens daughter, Marketta
with the red skirt?
Who wanted a man with a rapier.
One with a sword and one with money.
Wicked on his shoes came a villain
splashing in the mud and slush...
One that had to take what was left,
choose among what had been rejected.
Can I borrow the stilts?
Will it be inspection?
In the end of the week.
They are out in the barn.
One of the polish boys can help you.
What was that?
Kalevala.
Oh.. poetry reading?
We're training for a local play.
What are you going to do with the blueberries?
The russian lady are coming to get
them.
You can come with me if you want?
What's the point with this?
Compensation from the authority.
Didn't the moose eat enough this
year?
He didn't eat at all.
The forest owners put out carrots
in the forest for the hunting season.
Quite! What was that?
He was just standing there watching
us.
Go away! Just let us do the whole job,
you non-loyal sucker.
Where have you been?
Picking up the new car.
Look!
Rolls with cheese...
And fresh Danish.
I kiss each millimetre of your skin.
Give you massage with etheric oils.
Rub you with my magic cat skin.
Chafe you naked in my
Granny's squirrel fur coat.
Give you a bath in milk and myrrh.
Brush your naked body with my marten
brush.
Stop that. I didn't write anything
about how you made a fool of yourself.
Get the coffee.
Here you are.
And then you can empty the dish washer,
clean the sewer at the shower room,
Bring the garbage out,
and clean the floor at the loo.
You forgot the milk in the coffee.
Oh, I'm sorry...
What was that you suggested
with the squirrel fur coat?
How's it going with the terrorist hunt?
Any new leads?
First, they are no terrorists.
They borrowed a car and took back some
blueberries they didn't get paid for.
That fucking Sedvallson cheated them
as always.
What would've happened if one of
the Tamils had killed himself?
Hung himself in his shoe laces?
They were Thai, not Tamils, and all
were sandals.
But I can give you a tip.
How much does it cost?
That is a later subject. But it might bring honour
and fame to your little narrow-minded world.
I know where they hide.
Who?
"The Blueberry terrorists."
Would you like to know?
How much?
Jörgen has a list of suitable bribes.
There was something about a squirrel
fur coat.
Can't you show him how to do it?
Where's Ivar?
Out in the potato field.
Too much rotten berries.
I can't use them.
What should we do with them?
Throw them away.
No that's me. He is the chemist.
Here I am.
I thought you were a farmer.
Guess I am in a way, but the money
comes from the University.
International economics.
Without books?
Easier this way. Doesn't collect as
much dust.
I have the password for almost
all archives on the net.
Ivar said you have a potato machine.
I don't know how it works.
Or if it can be used, but here it is.
Are you sure it was here?
Yes, she said so.
Let's look in the barn.
Stop, stay there!
Shit man, they must be crazy.
Those can't be legal?
I don't know.
The car seems to be in here.
Why are you whispering? Is it an old
VW bus?
Yes. Run the camera when I open the
door!
No, wait. Let's do it like this.
I open the door and you follow with the camera.
It can be problematic with the light,
but I'll try.
One, two, one, two... ok?
It's ok, I start the pan from the
junk yard, start talking at the harvester, ok?
Yes, yes, yes!
Ok, action.
We got an anonymous tip that they were hiding
here. A deserted farm far out in the forest.
We haven't found anything so far,
they might have continued already.
But it seems like they have left one
of the stolen cars. Let's have a look...
Oh, what the fuck!
Great, what a take!
Stop filming and help me get down.
I have a fucking pike trap in my
hand.
It's some sort of elevator. I haven't
the slightest idea how it works. Here!
Hurry up!
Put something under.
Help me down, God damn it!
What the fuck!
My nails like burn from viper.
My palms as poison snake.
I raise a fence of iron...
...around my simple house.
Tied up with viper roap...
...wicker braided out of lizards.
He must be crazy!
Must have escaped from a mental
institution.
The tripod!
Don't bother, just drive!
What a take. Cool!
If that rope would've taken my neck,
I would've been dead right now.
"Wicker braided out of lizards."
Did you see any blueberries?
I can help you sharpen the knifes, boys.
You'll have potato flour enough.
I'll bee back tonight to see how you
manage.
Thank you.
Be careful with the knifes,
they can easily cut off a finger.
Wouldn't it have been easier
to buy it?
Can you buy potato flour in the
store?
Of course.
But Ivar said you have to do like
this.
He just fools you around.
He only wanted to know if it works.
And make a painting of it.
We used to do like this when I was a
kid.
When it dries you become white.
Have you understood that it's
just a scam?
Ryszard said it's just a bookkeeping
issue.
You'll have a 25 million debt
when they've robbed the company.
But still you've signed
for the swedish company?
I take the chance.
If we can keep our companies going,
we can take in on them.
But we have to co-operate.
Are you with me?
I just thought this business was an excuse
for Ryzsard to fuck that swedish bimbo.
It might be that way.
But why couldn't we take advantage
of the situation?
Hohoo, anyone at home?
You got it started!
We did the same when we were kids.
Where's Ivar?
In the potato field.
I spoke to Fors. He will be here at 2
am.
The russian lady and Jurek were up to something.
They made tests and some chemical analysis.
I didn't know their plans but we needed money
to pay for the plaster and the eye surgery.
This is also some kind of life.
It's a life for the leftovers.
Those who can't live among normal people.
A mix of wackos and witches.
How much?
Two or three cubic metre.
Do you know were his place is?
Yes, no problems.
Hi Ivar, are you awake in
the middle of the night?
Production development. Damn!
Damn!
Be blessed noble maiden, divinity
of early morning haze. Golden Diana...
...with the deadly weapon
resting in your soft hands.
Stop the fuzz, Ivar. Are you going to
help us call for the moose?
Mäntyranta suggests that you wait
at the lookout.
Darling, I'll wait in the car.
Dear Madame.
Come with me. An early walk in the
forest.
The freshness of the dew, the satiation
of the air will make your blood rush
Colour your cheek and sharpen your
emotions.
The fields, the forests and us.
Sure Franciszca darling. Just follow
Tarzan's grandpa tracking down the wild animals.
Shut up!
No. Not a single hit.
We could keep doing this all day.
Hello. Alright, he passed.
Stop filming and help me get down.
I have a fucking pike trap in my
hand.
What do you think? Is it use of a
deadly weapon or preventing journalistic works?
You are watching to much TV.
If that rope would've reached my neck
I could've been strangled.
You shouldn't have been there.
It's his private area.
You weren't doing anything so we
wanted to reveal where they were hiding.
We don't need any help. We know
where they are hiding.
And still you don't do anything?
The berries are back. There's no
case.
The local police has informed us that
the case...
The case with the stolen...
The affair with the stolen
blueberries is dismissed.
We've heard that all the berries
were delivered this morning and...
What did you say that the police had
said?
I spoke to that police chick, you know.
She said the berries were back.
I haven't seen any. They must be
rotten now anyway.
Here are lots of them.
That is what I bought yesterday.
Are we going to do anything?
No you're not. I can give you some
coffee.
You can pack up.
Stop! Don't open!
I think I can help you with
a very special story.
Did the guy with the milk tank work
it out?
Yes, I think so. He filled up
through the ventilation tube. Great.
Is it spelled like this, Medyczny
Uni...?
Remove the S and write C and Z.
Excuse me.
How many do you need?
I think I have twenty-four...
I think he is on the right track. He
have to hurry up.
We are right in the scent.
If he catch our scent, he might turn.
We better swim to that island. Hurry
up!
He is just behind those pine bushes.
That was the ruttish call, he might get angry
when he finds out that we cheated him.
What the...?
You better hurry up!
We've checked the bookkeeping
for the tourist resort.
And right now there is a bank and a
construction company demanding millions.
If the loan is not paid next month the bank
will bankrupt the whole place.
There is no problem, we have a solid
buyer...
The health authority has condemned
the kitchen
Was that a ruttish call?
No, it was just a mating call.
What's the difference?
You can tell from the words.
And all that about the scent?
It was a bluff, to allure you
to come with me here.
We didn't even ask what it would be good for.
We just carried those frozen sheep down the sloop.
We had picked them up at the cold storage
of the Berry king.
They are getting a bit old. Try to get
the inspection as fast as possible.
They are getting a bit old. Try to
get the inspection as fast as possible.
I'll call them tonight,
then they'll be here tomorrow.
They want them on the Norwegian side
next week.
Are you cold? In the middle of the
summer?
Do you have marks and tong?
What is she going to do with them?
The "Wolf damage fund".
What do you earn from it?
15%. Normal tax.
What are you doing?
A wolf. A real wolf. First time I've
seen one.
Now you're in a fine mess!
Excuse me, there's a limit.
That polish tourist clown wounded
that fucking moose.
What moose?
The one you permitted Ullabritten to
shoot.
I haven't given any permit. There
must be some misunderstanding.
The TV-crew videotaped the whole
thing.
That reporter has been trough the
bookkeeping.
They know the whole fix with the
company and the EU contribution.
You'll take care of this in a proper way,
do you understand?
And tell Ullabritten to start
thinking with her head.
And also make sure they quit my
options in that company, right now!
The polish blueberry thieves filled
my camper with blueberry jam.
Don't you have any sense of humour?
Humour? It was five ton blueberries
worth 14 SEK per kilo.
You've never paid. At least you have
the jam.
Yes, thanks! Fine. Thank you, bye!
It's obvious. Both the swedish tourist resort
and the polish freeze factory are fake.
The board in both companies has
bought options
So they can put the money from EU
in their own pockets.
This is your business manager.
These pictures should absolutely not
be shown. I know Janne.
I'll talk to your boss!
Janne and me are really close. Get lost!
The County governor is coming, you can talk to him
Believe me, they are on the wrong track.
They told me they just would check some
information about the local companies.
You are chief for the news desk.
You are responsible for everything you broadcast.
It is a matter of hundreds of jobs in
the region.
Wolfs! There are wolfs out in the jogging track.
Totally crazy! They were going for Börje.
I think they took him!
Oh my God!
For the constitut... constutit...,
hat the hell!
Constituent assembly.
A toast for..
Wait, wait...
A toast for the board in
the vodka company Sagolandet.
Wait a minute.
You did a great job with the company.
We have a special gift for you.
Great work!
Let's make that toast.
To Jerzy and Sagolandet.
I hope you understand that I can't
make any public comments
Before we've had a closer look
at this information.
When do you think...?
Impossible to say. I will contact
you.
You don't think...?
And this is the complete material?
Superintendent Brandtzek.
They think the County governor has
been killed by a pack of wolfs.
Up in the illuminated track at the
tourist resort.
Don't be hysterical Ullabritten.
It's a natural step in the food
chain.
Instead you should delete my name
from that options list.
Did you hear about the County
governor?
Yes, it's insane.
Father! Look what I found in the
illuminated track, can I keep it?
What are you doing here?
They think he surprised the wolf pack eating booty
a wounded animal or something.
It must bee that moose the tourist
boss shot.
What moose?
We've got it on tape when he shot it.
He and that lady from the EU-office.
Ullabritten!
We have decided to wait with
broadcasting that material.
It's a lot of jobs. You know how it
is...
When the contract is signed, you can
have as much information as you want.
Do you think the poles would buy a resort
were wolfs eat people in the illuminated track?
Could you...?
Not even think about it.
Another thing, what about those
options?
How many did you sign for?
Three thousand. You'll cancel them,
right?
You know that I always try to help
you.
The polish tourist attaché wounded the moose,
and it fell on the illuminated track.
Then the County governor comes jogging
right into the pack eating the carcass.
So they had him as a starter...
Or main course maybe.
How many bottles do we have?
25-30 litres I think.
What are you aiming at?
Will there be many journalists reporting
about the eaten County governor?
TV will drag down all extreme hunters and
wild animal freaks and broadcast for weeks.
This is our big chance!
Is it true that you get blue teeth?
Ivar says it goes away in a couple of
days.
Have you thought about that you
and I together own all the shares.
If we can avoid the bankruptcy, we can
get the whole EU contribution.
Should we take the money or invest
them?
Maybe this company, Sagolandet, would
do.
Why not. They seem to be particular
potent.
You mean potential?
That as well.
That company was a failure.
Not so bad. I make a purchase on
that new company.
But all the blueberries?
Much better when you can
use them in a proper way.
What do you mean?
I buy better and cheaper berries from
Russia.
But I have to buy 10% swedish berries to
print "Swedish Berries" on the jar.
So I buy 10% and bring them to the dump.
Now you can make vodka from them.
I love you.
What does the formula mean?
50 million. Probably more.
We sent the blueberry vodka to Kiev
for an analyze.
Everybody I know in Ukraine would drink
the vodka and don't care about the analyze.
Not this guy.
Becoming Nobel prize-winner.
He found out that this type of alcohol extracts
the same substance as they use in medicine.
It's only in the scandinavian
blueberries.
An Italian company sells such medicine
for hundred million a year.
Euro.
Then we have a gold mine out in the
old barn.
It's about my sisters eye.
When can she have her surgery?
What is this?
A copy of your exam at the medical
school.
If you look at the bottom of the first page.
It says 'Not approved'.
That line is missing in the papers
at the hospital archive.
Where did you get this paper?
I know someone who's good at
searching the web.
Will September 18th be ok?
That will do.
...that the company Sagolandet is given
exclusive right selling liquor...
...at the new reconstructed
tourist resort Vargklämman
...and that Sedvallsons bär have the obligation
to deliver 10 tons of blueberry each year
...at the lowest daily price.
Didn't the police wreck that
investigation?
Maybe you want to see the tape where
the police chief receive the material?
Don't bother!
It's a good start at my new job as
a County governor to inaugurate a project
Where local production and industrial
innovation can work together
In an international and
interregional investment.
This is just the kind of spirit
I've worked on in Brussels.
I know you need it out here.. out
here in...
The bush!
...in the thinly populated area.
Good luck and congratulations to the biggest
EU contribution ever paid to this region.
Who is that guy next to the russian?
New business partner.
Drug company from Milan.
I'm taking a group picture.
OK, here we go. Are you ready?
Cheers.
No, I don't know what's wrong with the car.
I'll be late.
Somebody else could go there and cut the ribbon.
I don't know when I'll be back.
No problem.
Ain't the factory owners coming down
for some coffee?
A strange country.
A Sagoland.
No problems. No problems.