Alright. Go on.
Let's have it.
Can you go through with it?
Have you got the guts for it?
Or have they knocked it out of you?
Have they made you yellow?
Carry out this bag? Coming right in.
Take it.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry.
- That's alright.
The 16th Precinct.
Is that the police Station on 5th?
- Yep.
Where's Tobin?
Who?
Inspector Tobin. Toby.
His office is down on 7th Street.
Don't give me that.
He's been here since he was a rookie.
Where is he?
- You're so smart, you find him.
Keep an eye on these.
I don't want them hooked.
You call me.
You're Inspector Tobin, huh?
- Uhuh.
Head of Homicide?
- Yep.
Why did you state Louis'
death was accidental?
Louis? You mean Louis Lepetino?
- Yeah.
Because it was.
A lot of malarkey.
Who are you, mister?
- John McKittrick.
Now I got you.
You're old Chris's boy.
Glad to see you. Sit down.
I, uh ..
Used to work for your father
in the old East Side days.
Too bad he left the force.
He might still be with us.
I've an opinion that getting into
big money don't do anyone any good.
Your opinion.
Let's stop cutting up the apple cake.
I'm here to find out about Louis.
A friend of yours?
- Since we were kids.
You know that.
Where you been hiding out?
- Yeah, you weren't at the church.
Louis had a swell funeral.
I've been on a ranch in
Arizona, taking a rest.
From Spain?
I heard about that.
I didn't know about Louis until
I read it in a newspaper.
I caught the next train.
- Uhuh.
You know Louis didn't kill himself.
I didn't say that.
I said it was an accident.
The toughest cop on the
force falls from a window?
Don't give me that. I knew him.
Maybe you're playing Dude on an
Arizona ranch you've got out of touch.
Or maybe you didn't know Louis got mixed
up with a crowd. Your kind of crowd.
Park Avenue and a couple of refugee
princes. What do you think of that?
I don't like this.
I don't like any of it.
You know Louis didn't fall out a window.
What's the angle?
- No angle.
Or maybe you think you know more
than the whole of Homicide Squad.
Maybe you got psychic
on that Dude ranch?
Listen.
Arizona may let you guys play
cowboys as long as you pay for it.
But I'm hanged if New York will let you
play detective if you're Mr McKittrick.
So run along and forget it. You'll have
more fun uptown where you belong.
Alright, sweetheart.
Let's leave it straight.
I'll find what happened
and why you're covering.
Run along, son.
And don't get a headache.
Oh.
Louis got me a permit to carry a gun.
His 'accident' doesn't shelve that?
Good for a year.
Why did you want to carry a gun?
To shoot people with, sweetheart.
Mama. Mama Lepetino.
Kit. It is Kit. Papa, it is Kit.
Kit.
We knew you would come, Kit.
Always, big boy.
When he was a boy ..
When he was in trouble, you would come.
Now.
We're alone and I want you.
My boy, Louis. My boy.
Can you find out, Kit?
Yeah, I'll find out.
I know it wasn't an accident.
No.
You got any ideas, Papa?
- No.
We not see Louis for a
long time before he die.
He goes around with these people.
- What people?
These very swell people.
Inspector Tobin says it was an accident.
- Yes.
Why did he say that?
- I don't know.
He was a good boy.
A great guy.
Will you stay for supper, Kit?
- No I can't, I've got to run but ..
I'll come down in a couple of days
and we'll have a real visit, huh?
Arrivederci.
You'll find out, Kit?
- You bet I'll find out.
We'll see you again.
Good luck, Kit.
Hello Ab.
- Kit.
Come in. What you doing back?
This is really good news.
I thought I'd had enough.
Mind if I bunk with you a few days?
Try going anywhere else. The man
will unpack you when he gets back.
You have the place to yourself though.
I've got to go to Washington tonight.
Come on in, I want to get a good
look at you. How are you, anyway?
I'm okay .. I'm fine.
You look it. I guess the
ranch was the right answer.
I guess so.
- Great to have you back, Kit.
Thanks Ab.
- And you're okay?
Yeah.
- Sure?
Yeah .. I never felt better in my life.
Scars all healed. Weigh what
I should. Eat well, sleep well.
Steady as a rock.
- No more noises?
No.
- Swell.
This calls for a celebration.
How about a drink?
Sure, thanks.
What are you doing all dressed up?
- Going to the Tavitons.
Barby is giving a party for some
refugees. That's her latest craze.
Why not come along, Kit?
You won't have to dress.
I don't mind.
Wasn't Barby the reason you
rushed back to New York?
No, not exactly.
Was it because of Louis Lepetino?
What do you know about it, Ab?
Nothing much. I wasn't
there when it happened.
One of Barby's parties.
Louis falls from the top-floor window.
That's the way they tell it.
- Who?
All of them.
You'll meet most of them tonight.
Louis got you out of Spain .. didn't he?
How do you know that?
- A guess.
Can you talk about it now?
I .. I tell you I'm okay.
I know you are, Kit.
Will you tell me about it?
I'd like to know. I've got a reason.
What is this, a test?
- You know better than that.
What do you want to know?
How it was in Spain when
they held you prisoner.
When you came back before
you wouldn't talk of it.
Yeah, but I can now.
It was pretty tough.
First, you didn't think
you could take it.
Then you did.
It was if somebody stuffed you
in a bottle and put the cork in.
Dark .. hot ..
You live mostly by sounds.
You knew it was morning
when you heard the birds.
You knew it was Sunday
when the bells rang.
In the dark there, you got to
know everything by the sounds.
Like the padding in the corridor.
That would be the ..
The footsteps of .. a peasant.
Or the .. boots of a Nazi guard.
Sometimes the .. screams ..
Of some of the other prisoners.
A key turning in a lock
with a squeaky hinge.
Water dripping in the hall.
I remember that, on the left.
That was bad because ..
We didn't get much to drink.
We got pretty good on the
sounds and they helped.
Except when you knew it was
long enough between times.
Then you'd just wait for the boots
to come and the drag of that foot.
When that came, you knew they'd
come in and take you upstairs and ..
Beat you up and do their little tricks.
Maybe it was only a little
while between times.
You hear the drag of that foot.
You'd try to hide
against the wall and ..
Crawl into a hole, only there
wasn't a hole to crawl in.
Try to hide in a corner and ..
You feel like a dog that's
been whipped and cut.
You tell them it's been too soon.
Those filthy rats. It was too soon.
They knew it was too soon.
I couldn't stand any more.
They didn't want me to die.
They couldn't let me die.
I couldn't take it anymore.
I have to tell ..
Take it easy, Kit.
Well.
That's the way it was.
Over and over again.
You hear the sound
of a limp in the hall.
I never saw him. The one that limped.
The others would come
down and take me upstairs.
And go to work on me.
Between times, they
thought of new ideas.
The sadistic swine.
Then they'd throw me
back in the cell and ..
Go on, all over again.
Well, how am I doing?
I'm sorry Kit, I didn't mean
to bring it back to you.
That's alright.
I've licked it. I can talk about it.
Louis got you out of all that.
Yeah .. Louis Lepetino.
Is that my room?
- Yeah.
I'll clean up now.
Good evening, Mr Parker.
- Hello Robert.
Good evening, Mr McKittrick.
- Hello, Robert.
Sounds like a binge.
- Exactly, sir.
Here is Miss Taviton.
- Kit.
Hello, Barby.
Darling.
Kit, you look wonderful.
- Thanks. So do you.
This is marvelous.
Well, why all the reserve?
So many people. I'll see you later.
Hello, Ab.
Ever since Ab called
I've been in a whirl.
Come on in.
There's people I want you to meet.
They were just talking about you.
Coming, Ab?
- In a moment.
Kit. Good heavens, look at the man.
Doctor Skaas, may I
present John McKittrick.
How do you do.
And this is Otto Skaas.
Mr McKittrick.
Miss Taviton told us that
you fought in Spain.
I was there for a while.
- I'm very interested, Mr McKittrick.
You see, at present I'm engaged
in a work having to do with ..
The cruelties of men towards other men.
Your opinion would be invaluable.
Could an old invalid impose
on you to visit him someday?
Glad to be of service.
I was just frightening these people.
I was comparing
modern scientific torture.
With the methods of the ancients.
Shall I continue?
- Go ahead.
Thank you.
Would someone please close that door?
I was saying ..
That the ancients were far too violent.
They concerned themselves ..
With a purely physical torture.
Primitive ideas.
Because release by death,
comes too quickly.
The ancient Asiatics
on the other hand ..
Displayed far greater cunning.
For now is conceived the idea ..
Of combining mental torture.
With the purely physical.
For instance, the old practice ..
Of dripping water.
Drop by drop.
On the forehead of the victim.
Drop by drop .. for hour after hour.
Day after day.
Until the weight of each drop.
The shock of it.
Mounts and becomes unbearable.
Then.
Here is the principle
of all modern torture.
Release is given.
The dripping is stopped.
The victim revived.
Just at the borderline of sanity.
Then.
Then comes an interval.
In which the victim tortures himself.
Waiting.
Knowing the operation will be repeated.
And it is repeated most assuredly.
With perhaps several new variations.
You see the point?
How perfectly ghastly.
You see the beauty of the idea?
Mental torture.
In which the victim
actively collaborates.
I could tell you many, many
more ingenious methods.
Barby, come on. We'd better get started.
It's after nine now.
- Alright.
We really should be going.
Come on, Kit.
We're off to the refugee dinner.
Don't bother about dressing.
A great bunch, what?
Who are the Skaas's?
- Refugee friends of Barby's.
The doctor is a famous
Norwegian historian.
He escaped from Norway
just before the Nazis got in.
Who's the blond wolf?
- Otto?
He's too interested in Barby.
Maybe you'd better smack him down.
Who is he?
- The nephew.
They're both friends of
Prince François de Namur.
They live in the same house.
The Prince is great with the refugees.
The old Skaas seems to be okay.
He's been pretty well identified.
What about Otto?
He's taken on his uncle's word.
He got out by underground.
Automatically, that puts
him on the prescribed list.
You believe all that?
Do you mind if I don't?
- No. Not at all.
Were the Skaas's at the party
when Louis had his 'accident'?
Yeah.
Kit, talk to Whitney about the Skaas's.
Whitney?
- The 'Imp'. My cousin.
She's here tonight, talk to her.
She was at the party.
[ Singing ]
She's improved, hasn't she?
- Who?
Whitney. That's Whitney Parker.
- Oh, that's 'The Imp'.
She's a big girl now.
She sings professionally at Club 50.
Society stuff.
- Not so much. She's on her own.
Her father wouldn't have it.
Threw her out.
[ Singing ]
I don't like to watch people dance.
Take me back to my table please.
- Yes, sir.
Who's that girl?
- The one with Otto?
Yeah.
The prince's granddaughter.
Prince Françoise?
- Yes. How did you know?
I get around.
You've got a roving eye, Kit.
That's something new.
What's the matter, Kit?
- How?
You seem almost indifferent.
When I kissed you tonight, I thought ..
I don't know.
- You're spoiled.
What is it, Kit?
Maybe I haven't big ideas any more.
Maybe I'm just a mug.
Don't get tough with me, darling.
When I came back from Spain and
you came to see me in the hospital.
I thought I got the brush-off then.
You looked so awful.
- Yeah.
I know.
Kit, Otto and I are going to
Franconia Lodge for some skiing.
Why don't you come along?
- No thanks.
Kit, please.
I can't, I have to stay in town.
But I'll see you when you get back.
Don't sit on me, you'll mess my dress.
I was going to suggest you
go home and put one on.
It's nice to have you back, Kit.
You're looking fine.
And you. Your hair done
and braces off your teeth ..
You almost look grown up.
Stop it. Didn't Ab tell you about me?
No.
A dog of a cousin he turned out to be.
Why don't we go someplace
and have a real drink?
I'll go, Kit. But I have to be
at the club by midnight.
Come on over there.
- Ab?
I can't, Kit. I've got to leave
for Washington in an hour.
He's a working man now.
Come on, The Imp. Let's go.
- Kit.
Take it easy until you hear from me.
- Sure.
We're going now. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Is this alright?
- Fine, thank you.
They won't serve you a drink, Imp.
They will but I don't want one.
I'll have some brandy. Bring the bottle.
- Yes, sir.
Are you going to howl?
- No.
There is a solution. Ask Ab.
What's Ab doing in Washington?
- Working for the government. Decoding.
But he's on his own.
About the Skaas's, I mean.
Who is Otto Skaas?
- He could be an agent.
How about Doctor Skaas?
- He could be another one.
What makes you think so?
- I'm smart.
I can smell phonies.
What do you know about Louis Lepetino?
- That's why you came back, isn't it?
They're waiting for you.
- Who?
The Lepetinos.
I work for Jake, Louis' brother.
He runs this place.
You were there that night
at Barby's, weren't you?
Yes.
- What happened to Louis?
I don't know, Kit.
Only Toni Donne saw him fall.
Who's Toni Donne?
The girl you were ogling at the ball.
The dark-haired one.
Uhuh.
The Prince de Namur's granddaughter.
Alright, stop making me guess.
Now you put it together.
It was .. one of Barby's big parties.
Everyone was packed in the playroom
upstairs to hear Anton and me.
Doing that song you heard tonight.
Both the Skaas's were there.
They were staying at Barby's then.
Barby, of course. Louis, and Toni Donne.
Yeah, go on.
I was just finishing the last chorus
where I start to build to the climax ..
When suddenly she screamed.
- Toni Donne?
Yes. She said she felt faint. She'd gone
across the hall to the library in front.
She said she was across the room and
saw Louis fall or jump from the window.
Where were the Skaas's?
Doctor Skaas was sitting next to me.
- How about Otto?
Otto was upstairs in his room.
A waiter spilled wine on his
shirt and he'd gone to change.
A perfect alibi.
Alibis have to be perfect, don't they?
And the prince?
He wasn't there.
He is too feeble to go out.
How do you know so much
about these people, Imp?
Anton. My accompanist.
Where does Anton fit?
He's alright.
Look, he's just a lunk-head musician.
He knows the prince and Toni. That's it.
Let him alone and stick to Toni Donne.
I've got to go change.
Will I see you after the show?
No. But I'll call you.
Goodnight.
- Night.
Waiter.
Tell Jake I want to see him, will you.
- Yes, sir.
Hello, McKittrick.
- Hello, Jake.
We thought you didn't care, Kit.
You took so long to come.
I didn't hear about it for a month.
I was over to see Mama this afternoon.
Your health is regained?
- Yeah.
Who got Louis?
If I knew ..
It was no grudge. It was no hood.
I found that out.
Louis liked women, Jake.
Beautiful women.
He wouldn't jump out of a window and
wouldn't let a guy get him in a spot.
Someone pushed him.
And it had to be a dame.
A beautiful dame.
- Yeah.
How did he get mixed
up in a society mob?
I don't know.
Does Toni Donne come around here?
I know so few by name, Kit.
Barby Taviton comes here.
That makes two dames.
Toni Donne and Barby.
Where'd you get that pianist?
- Whitney brought him in.
What about him?
A musician.
He's kind-of funny.
- How do you mean?
He hangs around with a funny crowd.
You're bad for me.
Maybe there are three dames.
Mr Parker told you to expect me?
- Mr McKittrick?
Yeah.
- Yes, sir.
You're new here, aren't you?
- I'm substituting for Henry, sir.
I'm Roman. Come this way, please.
I've unpacked for you, sir.
Except for the small case.
That was locked.
- Fine.
Thanks.
- Very good, sir.
[ Foot-dragging sounds ]
[ Water dripping noise ]
Good morning, Monsieur.
Good morning.
Hats?
Pardon?
I said 'hats'.
You have them here, don't you?
Yes, of course.
Do they come out on the
hour like a cuckoo clock?
Our trade is mostly custom, sir.
My name is McKittrick. John McKittrick.
How do you do.
Didn't I see you at the
refugee dinner last night?
Yes.
I thought you were the most
beautiful woman in the room.
Thank you.
But you are interested
in hats, Mr McKittrick.
Vaguely.
What time do you go to lunch?
- I don't go to lunch.
I saw you on the train
yesterday, didn't I?
Yes.
If we keep running into each other
we might as well be friends.
The Plaza is only a few blocks ..
- I do not go out to lunch.
Good morning.
Miss Donne.
Is that why you came here?
To meet me?
- Yes.
Why?
- I'd like to know about you.
And I'd like to know
about Prince Françoise.
You can read about the
prince in any library.
I can't about you.
Is he really your grandfather?
- Of course.
I doubt it.
Good morning, Mr McKittrick.
Monsieur.
I'd like to see some hats.
- Yes, Monsieur.
Can the young lady show them to me?
- Certainly, Monsieur.
Not bad.
Not bad at all as a matter of fact.
Very nice.
Let's see some more.
More.
I don't know.. I don't know.
You do not want a hat.
I really want to eat some lunch.
I told you. I do not go out to lunch.
Alright. Let's see some more hats, babe.
And do not call me 'babe' again.
I should push your teeth down your
throat. Even as a kid you were a liar.
What are you talking about?
- Drink?
In there.
What are you talking about?
Giving me that junk about Toni Donne.
- What junk?
How could she heave a guy
like Louis out of a window?
I didn't say she did.
- The only thing you didn't say.
What is it?
Trying to get her in trouble?
She's competition for Anton?
You get out of here.
- The only way it sets up.
It had to be a dame. Not Toni.
She couldn't push around 170 lbs.
Besides .. it isn't in her face.
For heaven's sake. Now it's you.
You look into a pair of
baby eyes and start drooling.
Anton goes for her too. Huh?
That's it.
You get out of here.
When I'm ready. Who's Anton?
Where'd you meet?
Where does anyone meet?
I'm a singer. He's a musician.
A superb musician.
That's all he cares about: his music.
Where did you meet him?
- At an audition.
How does he know the Skaas's?
In Europe, I suppose. I don't know.
I don't know everything.
You have to do some work yourself.
Long distance?
This is Plaza 32099.
I'd like to speak to Mr Ab Parker in
Washington DC. The Jefferson Park hotel.
Yep. That's right.
Mind if I use your phone?
- Help yourself.
I have to go to rehearsal.
Put the key in my mailbox.
Hello?
Never mind. Cancel it.
[ Foot-dragging sounds ]
You don't hear it. It isn't there.
It's in your head, like the Doc said.
Alright. Suppose it is there?
What are you afraid of?
You're in New York now.
This isn't Spain.
You've got to find out.
Got to get hold of yourself.
What did you come back for?
To hide because you hear the sound?
[ Rapping at window ]
Are you crazy?
You're drunk?
- No.
Kit.
- Shush.
What's the idea?
I'm looking for a man who
came in this building.
You are drunk.
- I was. Not now.
Who is the man?
- I don't know.
Look Kit, I'm tired.
I've worked all night.
I don't want to play anymore.
Go home will you.
I'm looking for a man who
drags one foot when he walks.
He came into this building.
Know anyone like that?
- No.
No.
[ Buzzer ]
Go on, answer it. Answer it, I said.
It's the police.
Fine. Ask them up. I'll see if I can
dig up a few more toothbrushes.
He says he saw someone
come up the fire-escape.
Nobody came in here.
No.
Hear any disturbance?
- No.
We didn't hear anything, officer.
It must have been another floor.
Thanks very much, Miss.
You're alright?
- Yes, Anton. I'm alright, thank you.
I did not know you had company.
- Goodnight, Anton.
That's just lovely. Anton will
have a beautiful picture of me.
I didn't know your playmate was here.
Kit, please believe me.
He's not my playmate.
He has the rear apartment.
Handy for rehearsals.
When did he arrive in this country?
- About a year ago.
Ever seen a man who walks with a limp?
- No.
He came in this house tonight.
I saw him.
If he don't live here, who did he visit?
- I don't know.
Are you sure you saw him, Kit?
Did you know why I was a prisoner for
two years after the war was over?
No. We heard you were dead.
Then you returned.
I escaped.
And you never talked about it.
- I couldn't.
Ever wonder why I was so important?
Ab did. We all tried to
guess but no-one knew.
Louis knew. He helped me escape.
With some old country relatives.
That's why he was killed.
Because he helped me. I'm sure of that.
He was the greatest guy I ever knew.
He would have gone
to hell and back for me.
Do you understand?
- Yes.
Why were you so important, Kit?
They wanted something I got.
They haven't given up.
Somebody squealed on Louis.
That's why the guy with the bad
foot is here. Because I'm here.
Who is it?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
He flew in from Berlin once a month.
I'd hear him in the hall.
After every visit they worked
on me all over again.
Listen.
What?
What, Kit?
- Listen. Hear it?
No.
Do you hear the drag of a foot?
No, Kit.
You'll be back at the ranch
if you keep on like this.
Don't you think you'd
better see your doctor?
I did.
He said, rest and quiet.
And freedom from anxiety.
[ Door knocks ]
Yeah?
A Miss Toni Donne on the phone, sir.
- Thanks.
Hello, Toni Donne.
Hello.
I called to thank you for the roses.
They're very, very lovely.
I'm glad you liked them.
Is that all?
Well.
You're forgiven.
Can we go on from there?
How about tonight? Have dinner with me?
Alright, then. Dinner.
Great. Eight o'clock?
Yes.
Will you call for me at the house?
I'd like you to meet Prince Françoise.
I'd like to meet the prince.
Alright then .. tonight .. goodbye.
Bye.
Good evening, Mr McKittrick.
Hello.
- Come in.
I'm afraid my grandfather
is in a bad mood.
He's very old.
Please be careful not to anger him.
I'll be very careful.
Presuming to set themselves
above the anointed.
Just consider the state of
the world they have erected.
Yes?
Your Highness.
May I present Mr McKittrick.
- I'm honoured, sir.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
- Mr McKittrick.
Just who are you, young man?
No-one in particular, sir.
Hardly that, Mr McKittrick.
A man of exceptional merit I should say.
A man of adventure, Your Highness.
A fighting man.
Perhaps you can tell
me, Mr McKittrick ..
Just what you found to fight for ..
In a world of imposters and pretenders
and bourgeois tradesmen?
Perhaps I just wanted a fight.
Something of an idealist, Your Highness.
Oh .. an idealist.
Come.
I will show you.
The Standards of the House of St Jerome.
My house, Monsieur.
There is a living history.
Something you can't
buy or steal or invent.
Something to fight for.
They represent the honour and
glory of a hundred generations.
A known treasure.
You have trouble understanding
this, Mr McKittrick?
What a simple banner can mean?
Perhaps this will help.
You see these ashes?
This was once a Battle Standard.
A flag of a revolutionist who
assassinated an ancestor of mine.
They thought to burn it.
To prevent its capture.
They thought so.
But it is here now.
The honour of the house is secured.
I see.
Now we'll have wine, Anton.
There things are difficult to
understand for an American, huh?
No, not for me.
Splendid. You see, Your Highness.
As I said .. a man of exceptional merit.
Your experiences taught you something
of the traditions of the old world.
Something.
Beautiful goblets, aren't they?
You observe the medallions?
The Lion of St Raphael, isn't it?
- Exactly.
The Lion of St Raphael.
They originated in Spain,
as you might suppose.
They travelled to Italy and came into
the possession of the prince's family.
In His Highness's veins flows
the blood of the Borgias.
Probably held .. poison in its time?
Undoubtedly.
We'll drink to Mr McKittrick.
Just an old Borgia custom, doctor.
To America, Your Highness.
Finally, here's to us.
What is it you really want of me?
A girl who looks like you shouldn't
ask that question. You know why.
No.
When you stared at me
at the refugee dinner.
That wasn't just the way
a man looks at a woman.
You went out of your way to find
out who I was and where I worked.
You came to the hat shop only to see me.
You didn't ask me out tonight just
because your lady's out of town.
What is it you want?
In school, did you ever talk
about what you wanted to be?
Of course.
I always wanted to be the boy who
chased the beautiful adventuress.
You're not serious.
- Absolutely.
Now it's my turn. You be as frank.
Did you come with me tonight because you
wanted to or because you were told to?
Told to?
- Uhuh.
What kind of a girl
are you really, Toni?
Was Louis Lepetino in love with you?
I only knew him for a short time.
- That didn't matter.
Louis always fell in love easily.
With you, he'd be in
love before he started.
He like beautiful things.
He was kind to me.
He was kind to you?
So you pushed him out of a window.
- No, no. That's not true.
I think you'd better take me home.
Toni .. let's dance.
No, please.
- You can't make a scene.
Think of the prince.
Think of those hundreds of generations.
Don't you know the beautiful adventuress
never fights when she's kissed?
I don't understand you.
You can be a gentleman or a ..
- Or a mug.
I was raised that way.
I was a mug until I was fourteen.
Then they made me a gentleman.
Then some of the boys
made me a mug again.
Why are you doing this to me, Kit?
I don't know.
Maybe because I'm fighting too.
I meant it when I said it would
be easy to fall in love with you.
I came out with you tonight
because I wanted to.
Because in the shop, even
through your insolence I felt ..
I know.
- You didn't let me finish.
You didn't have to.
Where did you get Louis' wallet?
He gave it to me.
It wasn't that night.
It was the day before.
He showed me a picture of the
two of you when you were boys.
He forgot it when he left.
That's a honey.
- You can believe it or not.
You dropped it in my pocket
on the train, didn't you?
Yes.
- Why?
To warn you.
I didn't want any more trouble.
I liked you because of what
Louis said about you.
How'd you know I'd be on that train?
Don't you know you've been watched
ever since you set foot in New York?
I've seen many pictures of you.
Pictures you don't know exist.
I had access to information that
told me what train you'd be on.
I could be killed for
what I've just said.
I told you everything I know.
Or everything I can.
Believe me.
I'd like to.
Let's drop it.
Let's have some fun.
I can use a big slice of the stuff.
So could I.
Come on. Let's see the town.
We're not good for each other, Kit.
- Aren't we?
No. There are many reasons, but ..
I'd like you to believe in me.
It's possible we may be
of help to each other.
Goodnight.
Alright Danny. To the apartment.
- Okay.
Come on.
Talk.
I'm sorry. You surprised me.
I surprised you? That's swell.
I was searching your apartment.
- Don't give me that.
It is true.
Now.
Let's have it.
It's no good you hitting me.
I'll only tell you what I please.
Come on, let's have it.
You're the one who should know.
That a man cannot be made to talk.
It would mean my death.
As it would have meant yours.
You know, no matter what happened.
If you talked, you would be killed.
Is it not so?
That's why they allowed you to escape.
Allowed me to ..?
Yes.
It was so.
They permitted you to send the letter.
They allowed you to steal the Luger.
You were watched as you crawled through
the swamps and slept in dung-heaps.
Every minute, you were watched.
So they let me go, huh?
I should have thought of that.
They didn't beat it out of me
and they couldn't kill me.
So they'd wait.
Is that it?
Alright.
They don't have the Standard.
I do, and I'll keep it. Tell them that.
You can tell the little
man in Berlin that.
You can tell them this.
They watched, maybe.
But they slipped up.
Because they didn't see my ..
- Then it isn't in this country?
Get out of here.
Out.
Come on. Come on, you.
Alright.
Get out and stay out.
That's not the way. Drinking won't help.
It's you yourself who's got to do it.
You almost flunked it tonight.
Like you flunked it at Whitney's.
You have to fight it out yourself.
Face it.
Find the man and kill him.
You've got to do it quickly.
[ Gunshot! ]
Hello?
Whitney? Kit.
I want you to come right
over here. Ab's apartment.
What is it, Kit?
- Come in.
Listen, Imp. Can you stand a shock?
What is it?
Ab is dead. He was shot. Here.
A few minutes before I phoned you.
No.
Where is he?
Come on.
Ab .. Ab.
Don't touch anything.
How, Kit?
How?
- I don't know.
I found him just as he is.
Kit .. you didn't do it?
Whitney. Stop it.
You know better than that.
But he didn't do it himself.
He couldn't.
No. We both know that.
Whoever did it made one mistake.
Come on.
Why did he go to Washington?
I don't know.
He was working for the government.
That's all he told me.
Could it have been because of you?
Maybe.
Give me five minutes.
Call Tobin. Inspector Tobin.
16th Precinct Headquarters.
Tell him what happened. I'll be back in
an hour. Tell him it all. Understand?
You afraid?
- Uhuh.
Good kid.
Lock the doors after me.
I'll leave the hall door unlatched.
Hello, Mama? Mama Lepetino?
This is Kit.
Yeah, Mama. Did Louis ever show you
any souvenirs I sent him from Spain?
Souvenirs, Kit? Like some seashells?
Yeah. That's right. You got them?
Yes, Kit. I have them.
That's fine. I'll be right down.
I was to keep them and say nothing
about them until you asked.
Louis put them here.
That's it.
You can throw the rest out, Mama.
I don't want them.
Kit.
- Yeah?
You know who killed Louis?
I .. I think so. I'll find him.
I'm McKittrick.
Where is Tobin?
- In the kitchen. Quizzing the butler.
He's back, is he?
- Yeah, he's back.
Tell Tobin I want to see him.
- Yeah.
Are you kidding?
Are you alright, Imp?
- Yes.
I told them everything.
I'm sorry the way I broke it.
I had a reason.
Hello McKittrick.
- Hello.
No-one here but you?
- Right.
Tell me.
It was about 6 o'clock. I heard a shot.
I got my own gun and went out.
That door was locked.
- Why?
I locked it. Any objections?
- No.
Let me see your gun.
Got any ideas?
- Yeah.
I have something somebody else wants.
Some guy is after me. I don't know who.
That's why it sounds phony.
All I know is that he limps.
What's this got to do
with Parker's suicide?
It wasn't a suicide.
- You start that again?
Didn't you tell them?
- I did.
As a kid, his brother played with
a gun and it went off in his face.
After that, just looking at a gun
gave Parker the willies. I heard.
He couldn't possibly handle a gun.
I know that.
Funny you claim that.
It puts your own pants
right on the hot seat.
Ab didn't kill himself.
The Parkers are an important family.
I wouldn't take a chance on calling
a murder a suicide unless I was sure.
Then the Lepetinos aren't so important.
Is that it?
You think this is tied up with Louis?
- Of course I do.
Ab suspected a man named Otto Skaas
who was at the party when Louis got it.
I think Ab was doing some investigating.
Otto Skaas was at Franconia
Lodge earlier this month.
This lame guy you're talking about.
Why is he after you?
He's after something I have.
A Battle Standard.
A what?
A Battle Standard. A pennant. A flag.
Where did you get this .. flag?
In Spain. It belonged to my brigade.
For crying out loud.
You expect me to believe
you let a guy gun for you.
You let your friends be bumped off one
after another for a dopey pennant?
Let him alone.
- Take it easy.
Take it easy. It's alright.
You wouldn't know, Tobin.
Sure, it's a dopey flag.
You could buy one like it for ten bucks.
But you couldn't buy this one.
I've got it, I've kept it and
I'm going to keep it.
Well.
Do you think Parker was bumped off as he
knew something of this pennant of yours?
He never heard of it.
- For the love of ..
So why was he wiped out
by this gang of yours?
Because he was after the Skaas's.
Because Louis was after them.
But he got bumped off.
- Nobody bumped off Louis.
Don't you think the department
takes care of its own?
Not well.
Listen.
We checked on the Skaas's. So has
Washington and the refugee committee.
They are okay.
- Anton, the piano player?
He was here last night and
saw me when I came in.
No, Kit.
Yeah?
I threw him out early this morning.
You threw out the butler.
- I had to.
Not what he says.
He says he heard you yell.
Looked in the room.
You were alone, yelling at nobody.
Then you threw him out.
You think I'm nuts. Is that it?
Look.
Louis told me you were in bad shape
when you came back from Spain.
Maybe you're not yourself yet.
Just forget about flags and people who
aren't here and people being murdered.
Who are you covering, Tobin?
If you think they're after you
I'll assign a man to you.
No thanks.
He'd probably fall out of a window or
shoot himself with a gun he didn't have.
Okay, sweetheart.
You work your way and I'll work mine.
But if I commit suicide
you'll know it's a phony.
Even if you watch me
write the farewell note.
If you go around yelling Parker was
murdered, you'll be in the hot seat.
Fatheaded, stupid ..
What is that, Kit?
I've seen that design before.
- On the prince's cups.
That's why they're on
exhibition for me to see.
Is this from the Standard?
Yeah.
You don't believe me?
Yes, Kit. Of course I do.
- No. Or else you're covering too.
Why does everyone dummy up on me?
What's the angle? They think I'm nuts?
Kit, please.
You believe Anton was here last night?
But he can't have killed Ab. He was
at my apartment at three this morning.
He seemed frightened. I made him coffee.
We talked until you phoned.
You're a great bunch.
You and Barby and Toni.
You're a walking string of alibis.
Anton can't have shot Ab.
He was with you.
He can't have killed Louis.
He was playing your accompaniment.
Otto couldn't have shot Ab.
He was at Franconia with Barby.
He wasn't in the room when Louis died.
Dr Skaas can't have killed Louis as ..
He was sat in a wheelchair next to you.
And the prince never leaves his nest.
And when Ab was shot we'll find Toni was
sitting in Skaas's lap playing checkers.
Maybe the boys did commit suicide.
- No, Kit.
Listen.
Get on the phone.
Call Barby at Franconia. Have her
meet me at 8 o'clock in Jake's office.
Tell her to bring Otto.
You come along too. Get Toni to come.
Tell them it's important.
Don't mention this.
It's going to lead me
to the man who limps.
Kit. Miss Taviton and young
Skaas are in the office.
Greetings.
This is ghastly about Ab.
It can't have happened.
It seems real to me. Hello Skaas.
I'm terribly sorry, Mr McKittrick.
Ab couldn't kill himself.
You think that?
We know how he felt about guns.
- We do.
Otto thinks he may have been
killed by foreign agents.
A bright boy, Otto.
What can we do, Kit?
Can we find out what he was working on?
If you went through his papers we
could at least find a starting point.
Otto can help.
I have some understanding
of ciphers, Mr McKittrick.
If there should be any
among Mr Parker's papers.
This gives me a chance to be
of service to my own country.
A lot of your people made
their own opportunities.
Yes. This is true, but my
uncle is a helpless cripple.
I do not feel I can leave him.
I'm grateful for this chance
to do some little thing.
Kit, where is everybody?
Is Whitney coming?
She should be here now.
Otto, see if you can find her.
- Certainly.
Come on, beautiful. Let's dance.
- Kit.
Sure. We'll dance on Ab's coffin.
Why not? Ab liked people to have fun.
You've been drinking too much.
- You're a hypocrite.
You like anything that's
wrong and you know it.
You're a pagan and always have been.
Don't talk like that.
- There's only one way to talk to you.
I have to tell you, Kit.
Ab and I were engaged.
Wonderful.
After you came back he
didn't want to hold me to it.
But I had to pretend.
I couldn't hurt him again.
- And Otto?
You were so indifferent.
You should have been
in Spain, sweetheart.
Why?
- Anything for a thrill.
Is that why you went?
- Why not?
We're sort-of alike.
Greetings.
Hello, Toni.
We.
We've been waiting for you.
In a manner of speaking.
Hello, Barby.
- Hello, dear.
Hello, Whitney.
- Hello.
Let's all have a drink.
No thank you. I'd rather not.
Why did you ask us to come here, Kit?
You heard about Ab?
Yes, I'm terribly sorry.
He shot himself with
a gun he didn't have.
At least that's what the police say.
Bright boys, aren't they.
Otto here, had a different idea.
He thought they might be Nazis.
Me, I don't know.
I had a hunch and thought I may
be able to tell you something.
But it didn't work. I'm sorry.
Then there's nothing you want us for?
I guess not, except ..
The most beautiful thing I own
to the most beautiful girl.
Where did you get that?
I picked it up in Spain.
It's sort-of a medallion
that hung on a Standard.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Like Toni.
They go together.
I thought of that today.
So I had it set.
Will you wear it for me, Toni?
I'm sorry. I can't accept this.
You've got to, Toni.
- No.
You mustn't refuse it, Toni.
The prince would not
object to your accepting it.
Wear it for me, Toni.
I'm going.
Please take me home, Kit.
Glad to.
I said I was sorry.
It was a false alarm.
My apologies.
You can drop the act now.
- Thanks.
Kit, why did you do this?
So they could all see it of course.
You know what it can mean.
You want to be killed?
I don't intend to get killed.
I'm going to find the man
who limps when he walks.
This won't help you find him.
- Don't lie to me.
Kit, I can't wear this.
Please take it back.
Stop it.
Believe me, I want you to wear it.
I want you to keep it.
When I said you're the most beautiful
thing I'd ever seen I meant it.
I could have said more.
- Please, Kit.
I've meant everything
I ever said to you.
So have I, Kit.
[ German language ]
No. I cannot. I will not.
Yes.
Yes, sir?
- Hello.
You catered a party for
Miss Barby Taviton?
On the 17th of last month.
Remember, there was an
'accident' there that night?
Yes, sir.
- Well.
I'd like to get the name
of the waiter you sent.
The one who spilt wine on
the shirt of one of the guests.
Are you from the police?
- No. Why?
They asked about it before.
- When?
The next morning. The name of
the waiter was Luigi Covantelli.
But for further information,
you'd better go to the police.
They arrested him.
The next morning?
- Yes, sir.
You understand, sir. That we ..
- That's okay. Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
I guess we've both
been doing this wrong.
You want to tell me about it now?
- What do you want to know?
Louis didn't fall from a
window in the Taviton library.
No.
Why didn't you tell me before?
- You were spoiling for a fight.
Besides, I don't like wise guys
telling me how to do my job.
That's not enough.
Alright. I knew what you
went through in Spain.
But didn't know if you'd come out of it.
I couldn't take a chance
on you breaking.
I figured if I got you mad enough
and you had what your father had ..
It would come out.
Why tell me now?
You weren't fooling.
I put a man on you the day you got back.
I go down for four.
- Holy month ..
Then.
You knew Anton was in
my apartment that night?
Yeah. But Anton didn't come back.
- Who did?
I don't know.
What happened to the waiter, Luigi?
We got him on an old
rap until we want him.
You want to give me the rest of it now?
Want some coffee?
Thanks.
Louis was working for the government.
He was working out of here as a blind.
He was after an espionage ring.
We think Louis was pushed through a
window on the floor above the library.
From the room old Skaas had.
We know Otto was in the next
room changing his shirt.
But we haven't got the gun that
fired the slug between Louis' eyes.
It was a 0.45 automatic.
Maybe they think we'd not do an autopsy
on a man who'd taken that kind of fall.
It isn't easy to do.
But we have the bullet.
What about Ab?
I didn't know he was working on it.
I found out when I talked to Washington.
So you don't know how Ab got it?
- No, I don't.
Mind if I use your phone?
- Help yourself.
Say, about that flag or yours?
Is that on the level?
Yeah.
I know it's hard to understand.
You talked to the Federals about it?
- No. They wouldn't be interested.
It's a personal matter between
me and a little man in Berlin.
The brigade I was in took
out one of his generals.
An old pal of his since
the beerhall days.
They knocked off the mug
and the whole battalion.
He swore he'd have every
last man in our outfit and ..
The Standard to hang in Berchtesgaden.
I swore he wouldn't.
Hello? McKittrick. Any messages for me?
Toni Donne? Thanks.
Have you any idea what brought
Louis to Skaas's room that night?
Yeah, he was after some papers.
We heard he got the tip from
your girlfriend Toni Donne.
Hello?
Hello, Tony.
Yeah.
Kit, I must see you right away.
Important?
- Yes. Please come now.
Yeah. I'll be right there.
Do me a favor, Toby.
Call off your dogs for 24 hours.
I'll wind this thing up if you do that.
Otherwise there might be a slip.
They've got too many mice.
What will you do?
The guy I'm after. The guy who got
Louis and Ab is the man who limps.
He can open up to me.
I'm going to force him to.
Listen, McKittrick. If you go plugging
anyone, you'll answer for it.
24 hours, Toby?
I'm a sap.
Thanks.
The medallion did its job.
I guess I'm marked up like Louis and Ab.
- Kit.
Listen, Toni.
We've a lot to say to each other.
No need for lies between us.
I won't lie to you, Kit.
If I can't answer, I won't lie.
You didn't see Louis Lepetino
fall from the library window.
He was in Dr Skaas's room
when he was murdered.
Yes.
And you helped kill him.
- No.
I didn't know what was going to happen.
I was told to go into the library as
soon as Whitney started to sing.
To open the window and wait there.
I've got to do what I'm told.
- Why?
There's a hold over me.
That's all I can tell you.
- Then what?
I opened the window and ..
I saw the body fall past and I screamed.
- You knew who it was?
Yes.
Later, they told me he
fell from the room above.
It was Otto that shot Louis but it
wasn't Otto that got Ab. Who did?
I don't know.
Why were they killed?
I think they were getting
too near the truth.
What truth?
Louis was killed because of me.
I'm the one they want
because I have the Standard.
You do have it?
- Yes.
Please give it up, Kit.
No.
I can't stand this any longer.
I'm sick to death at the thought
of what might happen to you.
I'm afraid, Kit.
Terribly afraid for you.
- Don't, Toni.
Last night.
All night I lay awake
in bed trying to think.
Why men act the way they
do about little things.
I tried to understand but I can't.
What earthly good do you
think it does you to hold out?
Do you think it's heroic?
Well, it isn't.
It's senseless. It's childish.
Think, Kit.
- Listen ..
No. Don't answer now.
Think what it is.
Just a .. little piece of cloth.
A dirty rag you wouldn't stop to
pick up if you saw it in the street.
And you're willing to ..?
Kit.
You're out of that world now.
Please give it up.
Perhaps we'll be able to find a
way to get away from all this.
The two of us.
Please, Kit. Darling.
Maybe I can't tell it
so you'll understand.
It's mixed up and hard to tell.
But I'll try because I want you to know.
I want you to know how it is.
More than anyone, I want you to know.
First it was something a kid would do.
A kid who had ideas and ideals.
Hold out on the dirty sadists.
Then it meant my life holding out
because if I gave in they'd kill me.
Then it began to mean something more.
Can you understand that?
Some things you have to do.
It don't matter what you think.
Nor how afraid you are.
You just have to do it.
What else makes a man stand up against
a tank with only a rifle in his hand?
Why do they hide out in the
hills after their army has gone?
Keep plugging away.
When they know as sure
as God's in heaven.
That their people will be
knocked out in retaliation.
Do you suppose they think?
I don't think so. They know.
Deep down inside they
know they have to do it.
It's something they can't help.
That's the way it is with me.
I know I have to hold out.
Maybe because the thing is a symbol.
A symbol of 3,000 men
who were my friends.
3,000 guys who were ..
Shot down around me.
Maybe it's something more than that.
Maybe it's everything that people
all over the world are fighting for.
I don't know.
I just know before I let that little man
put his filthy hands on that Standard ..
I will burn in hell.
I'm sorry, Kit.
You don't think I can win?
I know you can't.
They've got you. Is that it, Toni?
Or they've broken you. Don't let them.
You belong with me. Come with me.
- I can't, Kit.
I know what you're fighting for.
I've loved peace all my life.
I love life's little things.
Things that were important to me.
The house we had in the village.
The old dog.
I loved watching the children grow up.
I've lost all of that now.
I love you too, Kit.
Toni.
- No.
Listen to me. You must make a
choice now before it's too late.
I can't choose now.
- You must.
Will you come to the house tonight?
There will be a crowd.
It's a party for the doctor.
- You choose that?
Yes.
Will you arrange .. to get me out ..
So I can have a look
at Dr Skaas's rooms?
I don't expect to find anything
more than Louis did.
I know the man that
limps will come along.
When I meet him ..
I'm going to kill him.
You can tell him that.
I don't know him, Kit.
He'll come, alright.
Suppose he doesn't?
Then I'll burn the Standard.
They won't get the ashes either.
I'll throw them out over the bay.
Alright, Kit.
Okay, Danny?
- Okay, pal.
We got both Otto and
our ex-butler at Jake's.
On ice. They won't bother you.
Nice going. Riverside Drive.
- Hop in.
Hello darling.
- Hello Kit.
You're lovely.
I will do as you ask.
- Good.
My grandfather isn't here. They took
him to hospital this afternoon.
Serious?
- No. He just needs rest.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Kit, you can't stay here.
- Why not?
Nothing I know. Something you feel.
Something that's here that's
wicked and vicious and awful.
I don't know. But I feel it's so real.
Like a blanket smothering me.
Go to Jake's.
I'll meet you in a few minutes.
You promise me?
- Sure.
Mr McKittrick, you're
not thinking of leaving?
No, not at all.
Too bad the prince isn't here.
I shall have to play host.
I'll make a sorry host I think.
But perhaps we'll have our talk.
A long talk. If you would be so kind.
About tortures?
How we shall get along.
Come .. let's have something to drink.
Toni.
In your honour, my dear friend.
The prince was very flattered
that you admired his goblets.
Now, a toast.
Just an old Borgia custom, doctor.
Oh yes.
Your joke.
And now a toast.
To us.
Success in the New World.
The old Borgia custom.
We talked this afternoon.
The prince and I.
About poisons and drugs.
He had just been given an
injection of Scoloradine.
You are familiar with its
properties, Mr McKittrick?
I believe not.
The ancients.
They knew some remarkable drugs.
But it has remained for modern science.
To produce Scoloradine.
Which kills 'will'.
'Will'?
Yes, 'Will'.
The will to resistance in any form.
Particularly where speech is concerned.
That's why your American papers.
Have called it a truth serum.
But I'm boring you, I'm afraid.
Hardly.
We must see the dance.
Do you like gypsy music, Mr McKittrick?
- Very much.
Toni. Please.
Up these stairs.
The first door on the left.
You'll find it unlocked.
Please hurry.
[ Foot-dragging sounds ]
Why do you not shoot, Mr McKittrick?
You have a gun.
Yes.
Why do you not shoot?
I will tell you .. Mr McKittrick.
It will please you to know.
Because you cannot.
You haven't the courage.
You sent me a message:
'When I meet him, I shall kill him'.
Very brave .. very brutal.
But it's not possible for you
to carry out your threat.
Is it, Mr McKittrick?
No.
We have broken you.
When you came back to New York.
You thought you were a man again.
You thought you could face the one
you're after and shoot it out.
But you're not a man.
You're only a relic of a man.
Look at you now.
You're trembling.
I'm not afraid of you, doctor.
Seeing you was .. all I needed.
But you will not shoot.
No.
Neither of us will do any killing.
I cannot kill you because you
have information I must obtain.
You cannot kill me.
Because you lack the brutality
to kill in cold blood.
And now.
Now, we'll have our talk.
By all means.
Otto killed Louis Lepetino.
Yes, it was Otto.
He does pretty well what he's told.
Who shot Ab Parker?
I shall be very nice
to you and tell you.
I did.
I sent him a telegram
signed with your name.
But he did not come at
the time we expected.
So I remained hidden while you
had your little talk with Anton.
Then you went to bed.
I waited for your friend.
It was childishly simple.
At the sight of the gun ..
He was frozen.
I placed it against his temple.
And fired.
Then I went as I have come.
By the rear entrance prepared
for me by Roman the butler.
Why did you shoot Ab?
Why? Why?
He had become something of a nuisance.
With his investigations.
It was also my purpose
to dispose of your friends.
Until such time as you chose
to see our point of view.
But you forced the issue.
Well.
There are other means by which you can
be made to tell us what we wish to know.
Tonight, I mentioned Scoloradine.
You know.
The drug that destroys the will.
You will talk to us, Mr McKittrick.
Believe me.
Don't worry about the time.
I took care of your gunman, Otto.
He won't be here.
- Yes, I know.
That is not why I look at my watch.
It is about time the
drug has taken effect.
The drug that was in the
goblet, Mr McKittrick.
Yes. You were very clever
when you exchanged them.
But you made one fatal mistake.
You underrated your opponent.
I had counted on you doing just that.
The drug was in my goblet.
No ..
Don't give me that.
Try to raise your hand.
You dirty .. sadistic .. swine.
[ Foot-dragging sounds ]
Danny.
Danny!
Do you feel okay?
Yeah.
I'm alright.
You called Tobin?
- He's on his way.
Sure you can make it?
- Yeah.
Come on downstairs with me.
If Anton makes a run for it, beat him.
Only Anton, you understand?
- Okay.
I just killed Dr Skaas.
You sent him up to get me.
- No.
You knew it was a trap. I knew you knew.
I had faith in you, Kit.
- Where does the prince fit in all this?
He's senile.
He thinks they're going to
make him King of France.
He's dying in the hospital.
He's not your grandfather?
No.
I had to do as I was told.
- Why?
I married the real Otto Skaas.
He died in a concentration camp.
The one here is a Nazi.
I have a daughter, three years old.
She's in Germany, held as a hostage.
You said you loved me.
Did you mean that?
Yes. But it's no use, Kit.
There's nothing for us.
We'll get her out of their hands.
There's ways, underground ways.
I won't risk her, Kit.
I'll fix it here.
You haven't been to blame.
You acted under compulsion.
Come with me, Toni.
We'll have our own life together.
No, Kit.
It would always be between us.
There would come a day when
one of us would have to choose.
How do I know which I'd choose?
I have other relatives there.
I couldn't trust myself.
You couldn't trust me.
I'm unlike your men in the hills who see
their people slaughtered and carry on.
I'm not brave, Kit.
I love and ..
I do for those I love what I can.
Do you love me?
Yes, Kit. But ..
I'm afraid.
I can't risk my daughter.
You're not afraid.
It's what they drilled into you.
Let me show you the way out.
I'll help you. I love you, Toni.
You'll have time to forget
me when I'm gone.
If you'd let me go.
[ Police sirens ]
You have to make a choice now.
The police came. You've only minutes.
Please let me go.
- Listen to me.
No harm will come to your daughter.
Believe in me. Trust me.
Can I?
- You must.
Go tonight to Chicago. Use a new name.
Stay at the West Side hotel.
I'll square it here.
When it's safe, I'll join you.
Bless you, Kit.
Tobin. Upstairs. First door to the left.
Take a look.
- You two stay here.
Hey, are you alright?
- Sure. I shot him.
Maybe self-defense. Maybe not.
I wanted to kill him.
I didn't when the time came
but I had to to save myself.
That's up to the Federals.
He's head of an espionage ring.
He wasn't Dr Skaas.
There's papers in his desk that help.
You got Anton?
Yes. He has a sort-of dent in his head.
You can pick up Otto and
that butler of mine at Jake's.
He has them both on ice.
What about the girl?
- She got away.
Yeah?
Let it go, Toby.
She helped me.
Do you think this will stop
with the ones we've got?
What about that flag?
- It's hidden in Lisbon.
If I don't stand trial, I'll go to get
it and hand it over to the boys.
Who can use it.
There will be brigades forming again.
Are you sure about that girl?
I don't know .. but ..
Maybe we could ..
She was going to meet you in Chicago.
So she takes the Lisbon clipper.
You go back to them.
How'd you get your passport
permits for the Clipper?
I had to do it this way, Kit.
Believe me.
I must go back and find my little girl.
I wish there were a little girl, Toni.
I wish you'd told me the truth.
You got your passport and permit for
the Clipper from the German Consul.
Please trust in me.
Come on.
No, you can't.
Sorry, Kit.
According to how you look at it.
Another sparrow fell.
So long.
..t-g..