We are closing. The public
is kindly requested to leave.
Last call.
We are closing. 777B public
is kindly requested to leave.
- Wait, I'll help you.
- Yes... Thanks.
- Good day, Doctor.
- Hello Kurt.
- Dr. Schwarz.
- Hello.
- Doctor.
- Hi Miller.
Good evening, Dr. Krader.
How is your symphony for
orchestra and animals coming along?
Pretty good.
- The work is slow-going.
- You work too much.
You're Dr. Schwarz, right?
Yes, it's me. Have you
come up with a title?
Yes, I was thinking about
something like "Nature Weeps".
- You like it?
- "Nature Weeps"...
Don't you think it's a
little creepy as a title?
- Bye.
- Have fun.
Good evening.
Go, Brek.
- Watch out!
- Oh, my God! What's the matter?
Careful.
These new cages are a drag.
- Excuse me, Fritz, will you open it?
- At your service, Doctor.
And kill that damn siren.
- You're free to go.
- Thanks.
Look who's coming.
Hey Gladis... Be a good girl. Stay calm.
Calm down. You don't
like being pricked, right?
That's it. Be good, girl.
"Good girl, good girl."
You're real good. Walk over
there. Wait for me, huh? Good...
Go! Pass me the syringe.
Alright, are you ready, Gladis?
Come on, easy.
With that big fur of yours,
you won't feel a thing.
That's it... Be good,
Gladis... Easy... Easy.
Here we go. You see?
You didn't even feel it.
- Feeling better now, Miss?
- Yes.
Danger's over.
- Take your picture now, Laura.
- Yes!
Be quick. And there she goes...
Five seconds to go.
What's wrong with her? Does she feel bad?
Rip!
No, she's alright.
It's a normal reaction.
She's taking a nice trip
to the land of dreams.
He's bitten her nipples bloody.
That's why she behaved so crazy.
- Crazy indeed, she ate her babies.
- Well, luckily not all of them.
There's still this little witch
here. Listen to how she growls.
The little bastard...
You want to see her?
Look who bit her mother
instead of sucking the milk.
- Easy does it.
- Take her to the second ward.
A little higher.
What a little beast!
Look how she bites.
Don't do that.
Alright, I'll see you at the lab.
Just a moment, I'm coming!
It's 7:30 a. m. I left you some
hamburgers in the kitchen.
I'm coming! One moment!
Take a shower, but don't
flood the entire house, alright?
Put on the striped
jeans because didn't...
Dr. Schwarz, it's 6:30 pm. This
is the last bulletin from solitude.
Helga's out. I'm putting on
my jeans, and will leave as well.
I'm going to dancing lessons with Tommy.
Hear that ringing? Will you
stop that noise? I'm coming!
I listened to your message.
Thank you so much for reminding
me to eat, to dress, to wash...
Mom, ł just wouldn't know
what I'd do without you.
But where the hell did
you stash my Ba-Ba-Ba?
Here he is.
Malta called from the newspaper.
She wanted... Yes, she basically
wants you to call her before 5:00 pm.
But since it's already past 6:00 pm...
Oh well, like I said, we're used to it.
End of message. Signed,
your daughter Susy.
That girl with the brown curls, remember?
I'm coming, you ball-buster!
Come on, move, Brek.
You're strange tonight. What's up?
Don't make me drag you. Will you
walk? What's gotten into you, Brek?
Brek! Walk! What did you see tonight?
Brek! Come on, walk!
Be good. Be good!
Come on, let's go!
- What's wrong?
- Did you see that guy?
- I don't know, I had a strange feeling.
- Come on...
Don't tell me a guy like him worries you.
He's just blind. What's
he supposed to do?
Come back down. I'd like to
tell you a story only I know about.
You're so stupid!
- Does your story have a happy ending?
- Yes, very happy...
So let's begin with the end.
I think it's a story like any other.
- You want to know how it ends?
- Oh yes, please...
She's not home. She could have at
least turned on the answering machine.
- She does that on purpose.
- But no, she's probably just forgotten.
I don't think so.
That plague doesn't do
anything without a reason.
- I'm telling you, she did it on purpose.
- You know her better than I do.
She's your daughter. Honey
Pie, is your colic better?
You're good - unlike the lady's daughter.
Thanks for the "lady".
Who wrote that children are aliens
who come from another world...
to destroy the one of their
parents? Aldrich? Huh?
An insinuation?
You too were at war
with your mother, huh?
Don't you know that mothers
have to be respected?
Mothers are dangerous, very dangerous.
The company of the
owls doesn't become you.
- You hear that?
- You're snippy like them.
- You're not snippy.
- According to you, I'm a bad mother?
- You're good.
- I have to clear up the situation.
You know what I'll do?
Congress or not, I'll
pick her up at school.
- The time has come for a long chat.
- The mothers...
Speaking of which, hers would have
eaten her if we hadn't been there in time.
If we hadn't removed her, we'd
have another mom guilty of infanticide.
The mothers have decided
to stop being mommies...
and only think about their jobs.
Is it my fault that I don't
have enough time for her?
I have to earn our bread and butter.
Become mine, doll, make me happy, and
you won't have to worry about anything.
And become your private whore, doctor?
And also your secretary
and your cook, right?
And God knows what else
you got in your macho mind.
Well, little miss, why are you
so bad to your mother, huh?
Because her cannibal
mother ate her siblings.
Kidding aside, isn't it strange? From
a naturalistic perspective, I mean.
The survival of the species
and the maternal instinct...
Once upon a time maybe.
But not these days - strange things
have happened around here lately.
Well, why did you stop?
Keep talking. This day
might not be wasted after all.
I might be a failure as a mother...
but as a journalist I could
write a most interesting article.
What would you say if I'd call the article
"The dangerous madness of the zoo"?
Can you imagine? Or maybe I could
steal the title of Krader's symphony.
It's very impressive: "Nature Weeps".
Not like that, it hurts.
- Did you hear? What was that?
- What do you mean?
Now come on...
No...
- They're rats! Rats! Belt!
- Wait!
- Help me, Belt, do something!
- Let me see!
- Let's get out! Help!
- No, don't open it!
- There are thousands out there!
- Do something! Please do something!
No!
- Go away! Get lost!
- Go, get out!
No, help! Belt, help me! No!
- At 7:00 pm. then.
- Alright.
Thanks a lot.
Oh, Rip, you're as stubborn,
ponderous and lazy as a sloth.
Don't you want to change your mind?
Impossible, I want to
finish that taxidermy work.
And you know that I
can't stand these meetings.
I'm a doer, Laura,
not a thinker like you.
All those strange intellectual
acrobatics on Darwin, Lamark...
and other "holy fossils" shorten my life.
Well, I wouldn't want to
taint myself with such a crime.
- Bye, you "doer".
- Hey, didn't you forget something?
Goodb...
Hey, with another kiss like
that you will shorten my life.
I suggest you take a
nice cold shower, tiger.
- Didn't you feel like you were on fire?
- No, I just smelled the stink of Gladis.
Laura? Will you come
to my place tomorrow?
Everything's possible.
But I'll call you first.
I count on it, huh!
Queen of Hearts... Here we go!
It's all over, you're finished.
Over and out, grandpa!
How could I concentrate on the
game with all that noise in my ears?
My dear grandpa, live and let live.
Bullshit! That's just bullshit!
It's all useless gimmicks. Just
rubbish like that stuff over here.
Big buttons, small buttons, big levers,
small levers, lights and little lights.
Automation, they
call it. I call it bullshit!
It's only good to rid
people of their jobs!
But which jobs? What people do you mean?
There's never enough
staff around here anyway.
Where are you going now?
Trying to find Kurt and Miller.
They're better off than I am.
At least they have animals as friends.
Bye-bye.
Speaking of animals... Look
here. Check out this pretty piggy.
- Nice teats.
- What the hell is that?
- It's in section 4.
- The cat area!
But what the hell happened?
It's the tiger cages.
Look at their movements.
Maybe an earthquake.
They're acting strange.
But here everything's okay.
They say animals sense
them long before we do.
I'll take a look at it.
- Have you seen my torch?
- It's on the table.
It looks like someone's
trying to open the cages.
Hey pascha! What's wrong?
Are you crazy, pascha? Stay calm.
Behave! Behave! Behave!
Strange...
Are all of you in a bad mood tonight?
I don't get it.
It is an earthquake.
Oh, Christ!
Now everything's blowing up!
What the fuck?
Damn it!
Hello!
Who else could it be
but my beloved inspector?
You're the only one who
calls when I'm taking a shower.
What's that?
What? Rats?
- Rats?
- Yes, you got that right.
- Rats! Rats! Rats! Thousands of rats!
- What have you got to do With rats?
They attacked two kids in their car.
They killed them, massacred them.
Fire rats? They killed them?
You have to see how they
mangled them. It's horrible.
What kind of rats are they.?
Normal ones, sewer rats.?
Rats, sewer rats, brown rats...
What the hell are they called?
They come out of the drains in thousands.
Where are you.?
WernerstraBe. In that quarter
under construction, near Barnum.
I'm asking myself What
caused it. Maybe a gas leak.
Hey, hello! Hello Natl
Are you still there.?
Yeah, yeah, I'm still here.
You should see what I'm seeing.
- The exterminators showed up.
- I'll be right with you.
Well, doctor, don't you think
this might be your department?
Isn't it strange.? Aren't you interested?
Of course I'm interested!
So stop talking to the phone,
move it, and get over here.
- Relax, IVat, I'm half-naked
- Rip, I need you. Hurry up.
I'll race down there.
But if they fine me.?
Quite the novelty...
I'll take care of it, as usual,
speed devil. Now move it.
Put up a barrier!
2nd squad over here!
Increase the pressure!
Hans! Wolfgang!
Oh, my God... Miller...
Wolfgang!
Watch out!
No! No!
No!
Go away! Go!
So, can nature go crazy?
Can animal madness and violence
create monstrous assassins?
Yet another question:
Can nature strike back?
The answer is: Yes.
Yes, the monsters
from our darkest fears...
and ancestral nightmares
are becoming a reality.
We arrived at a time when we have to
tolerate injustice, infamy, mutilations...
ecological and biological
horrors. We have no intention...
- Miss, there's a call waiting for you.
- For me? Thank you.
On our nature is pure madness.
We kill and destroy...
- Excuse me.
- No problem.
We kill and destroy our nature
because we don't know any better.
- Silence.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Do you know where the phones are?
- Yes, thank you.
We have to obey our genetic heritage
and to laws that are stronger than we are.
We have contaminated our atmosphere,
and the cancer we introduced...
There's a phone call for me, right?
Thank you.
Hello? Yes?
Susy is daughter of Laura.
They say Laura is mother of Susy.
Also, Susy worries from
afar about her mother Laura.
Have you eaten, Laura?
Have you washed, Laura?
That's not funny. Cut it out.
Blow your nose if you
have a cold. Behave.
If you have something to tell me, do so.
In any case, I'll pick you up at 7:00 pm.
The tape is running out.
Susy is fine, Laura is fine.
Susy will wait for
Laura. That's all for Susy.
Goodbye, doctor.
One of these days, I
will strangle this girl.
That's it. That's the way.
- Go to the second hydrant!
- Drive them to the sewers.
Direct the flamethrower to
the sewers! Scorch them away!
I have seen some crazy
animals lately, but never like these.
I can't explain it.
I'm pretty certain there's
a gas leak in the drains.
That doesn't explain their
aggressiveness, of course.
You wouldn't have
achieved much with water.
And with poison you would've
contaminated half the neighborhood.
Fire is the only way to kill them.
Leave some of them alive, please.
Nat, they're probably rabid...
but to make sure, I'll have to
analyze their saliva in the lab, okay?
Help!
It's like they're possessed!
They're going crazy!
Help me! Help! They bit me! Help!
- Turn around! Turn around!
- Help me up! Help me up!
- Yeah, like that!
- Do something!
They're still all over me!
- Where's the special unit?
- Here! Come here!
- It's Masterson, they got him!
- Crush them! Crush them!
They're afraid of nothing! Look
what they've done to the boot!
They jumped at me from the ground.
- Did they bite you too?
- No, I'm fine.
Take that boy to the
hospital for a rabies shot.
- When do you think you'll know something?
- No idea.
Send the other samples to the pasteur,
they're better equipped for these tests.
- I'll catch up with you as soon as I can.
- Okay.
Bye.
Brek.
Brek! What's the matter with you?
Behave, Brek, behave!
Brek!
Fritz! Hans!
What happened?
Damn it.
Wolfgang!
Impossible...
police?
Yes, my name is Berner, Rip Berner.
I'm the veterinarian of the
Strand Zoo in Michelstraße.
No, I'm not sure what
happened. Something terrible.
There's a dead body, one of the guards.
The animals have escaped.
- Yes, they're very dangerous.
- Attention, attention...
all mobile units. Dangerous animals...
Attention, all units. Attention,
all units. Top priority! Code 16...
Block the streets according
to code 16. I repeat: code 16.
Unit 30, 31, 32 and 34 of district 20...
authorizing cordon of
sector D, quadrants 1 and 2.
Unit 30 and subsequents, join unit 18.
Let's see what the
hell got into these rats.
There's no doubt, they don't have rabies.
The pH of the blood indicates acidity.
Just a moment, Nat.
Matthaus, mobilize everyone.
I need some more analyses.
Repeat the blood and saliva
tests, and prepare me a Coleman.
Send all the samples to the Pasteur.
I want their opinion.
Nat, would you call the
bikers for the transport?
- They're here in two minutes.
- Listen, Rip...
Berger is sick, and Struhler
has some personal problems.
I don't give a damn!
Sickness, personal problems...
I want them all here - even if we
have to send the police to pick them up.
Where the hell are the cartridges?
If the Coleman result is
negative, try a Wurmser.
Now where are those damned cartridges?
- Hello?
- Rip, finally!
- Laura!
- Can you tell me what's going on?
Did you hear about the
escape of the zoo animals?
Yes, I heard it on the radio.
But the radio didn't say that the
guards are dead - they massacred them.
Sorry, I have to hang
up. Catch you later.?
Sure.
I forgot that you don't have your car.
No, it's okay, the
subway is pretty close.
See you later, Laura.
Excuse me, would you listen for a minute?
Hello? Hello?
Have you seen all that
chaos? It's incredible.
It seems that they've spotted lions at
Brumerallee and panthers at Kurtenplatz.
How could that happen? Hello?
Hello? Hello Klaus, run to the newspaper.
Of course, at once. When else?
Hello? The police closed
down the Struttwage quarter.
- Hold the line.
- One moment. Hello?
- Would you take the third?
- Sure, with my feet...
Block the first page. We'll
exchange column 5 and 6.
There's now a curfew for
the quarters west of the Rhein.
Fire state of emergency
has stopped all life in the city.
Fire authorities do not try to hide the
exceptional gravity of what has happened
It has been established
that no less than 30
beasts, 4 Indian and
3 African elephants...
have escaped the Strand
Zoo in Michelstraße.
A cordon of police and military forces...
No! Help! My God, it's horrible!
Start the car! Start the car! Quick!
- Quick!
- It won't start! It won't start!
That fuckin' thing is dead!
No! No! Help! Help!
Stay calm!
Close the windows!
Close them! Close them!
It doesn't work! It doesn't work!
Help... Help...
No!
Get lost! No!
Alfred! Alfred!
Help me! Alfred!
Unit 8, unit 8 for
King. 8 for King. Over.
- I hear you, K.
- It seems there's a tiger at Gartenplatz.
K for King, K for King. Code 20. Code 20.
- Unit 8 for King. Unit 8 for King.
- Receiving, 8. Authorization to proceed.
- Central calling F. Freddy.
- Freddy to Central, copy.
Listen, Freddy, you need to
go to zone Kurt Schumacher.
An emergency.
There's an animal there, a
predator, possibly a leopard
We don't know for sure, but
the call was legit. I repeat.'
Zone Kurt Schumacher. That's
between Bower- and Lipstraße.
Alright, Central, copy that.
Are you sure your soporific really works?
Sure it works. Relax.
It knocks out a rhino in seconds.
You worry about your driving, huh?
"That was 'Silver Moon" by Mutilati'.
Hey, do you know why someone
With just one leg has a short life.?
Because he already has one
foot in the grave! Macabre, huh.?
777/5 is Sun Radio 5!
- Oh, no!
- Fire station that's all about politics.
Now here's a brand-new piece of music
for you: "Clap, Clap, Clap" by Simba!
- Is she crazy?
- Look, she's not crazy!
She's chased by Cheetah! I recognize her!
Oh, Christ!
Hurry!
- Hurry! Turn around!
- That's what I'm doing!
- I'll run over that beast!
- No good, you won't make it!
I'll try to get as close as possible.
Can't you take her out with
that syringe gun of yours?
No, no, impossible under
these circumstances.
Use my gun. It's in
the glove compartment.
- There it is!
- Yes, yes, I got it!
Hurry up!
The car's not steady enough!
I'm afraid I might shoot the girl!
No!
Damn, is she crazy?
Hurry up, we must stop her!
Come on, Nat, we must stop her!
Watch out, it's red!
Stop! You won't make it!
Nat, you take care of the animal!
There's nothing we can do for him.
Nat, Nat, bring the extinguisher!
Oh, my God.
Nat!
I missed the beast!
Forget it, that poor guy's dead.
- How is she?
- She can still make it! Stay with her!
No, Rip, are you crazy?
The tank could explode!
- I can't make it!
- Come on, give me a hand.
Move it. Quick, take her away from here.
- I'll call an ambulance.
- Get down!
Yes, another car was
destroyed at Normenplatz.
777ere are four dead and one badly
wounded No, no trace of the elephants.
A witness claims to have seen
them heading down Williamstraße.
Another witness, a woman, has seen them
entering a parking lot
at Katharinenstraße.
- Maybe...
- This is inspector Weber.
What do you mean, there's
no trace of the elephants?
You know what elephants are?
They're elephants, not lice! Elephants!
Now go find them, Jesus! Move it!
- Now what are you doing, Susy?
- "The Dying Swan".
Looks more like a dying lame duck.
Alright, let's go to work, kids.
Tommy! Hanna! Helga! Come on.
All together now.
One, and two, and three, and four.
One, and two...
Savanna Alpha Savanna. Landing
coordinates: 12 and 14 Beta.
Quadrants 3-2-1.
Pamela Alpha Marina.
Loop altitude: 2,000.
Alignment radio beacon Omega.
Savanna Alpha Savanna. Everything's okay.
Alignment completed.
- Burma Elisa Alpha. Wait for coordinates.
- Tango Alpha Charlie 6-3-2, okay.
- Runway 8 is clear.
- Copy.
Heading for coordinate 16-1.
Slowing down.
I repeat: Heading for coordinate 16-1.
Tango Alpha Charlie
6-3-2. Okay, runway 8.
I'll bring Oscar, and
you will bring Jill.
It would be perfect to do
something together tonight.
My boyfriend calls me in
my room every day at 9 pm.
No problem. I'll see you
in your room then, huh?
Forget it!
Easy, easy, nobody
will steal it from you.
Look at you... Look what you did.
How do you get yourself so dirty
all the time? I'm at my wits' end.
- You're always a problem.
- She's only little.
- Am I going crazy?
- Elephants!
- There's something on the runway.
- What?
I can't tell what it is.
Emergency! Emergency!
There are ele... mobile obstacles!
Mobile obstacles on
the runway! Watch out!
Elephants...?
- Elephants!
- Flap twenty!
Maximum thrust! We need
to bring her up, for God's sake!
We're stalling! We won't
make it! I'll try to land!
Go faster! It's too
short! Maximum reverse!
Come on, baby, you gotta make it! Quick!
Come on!
- What happened?
- No idea!
Always the same old story...
Not again...
Nothing works in this city.
- Dear God, I hope it's not a blackout.
- What are you saying?
It's nothing. Don't worry, honey.
If you really want to know, the
problem is that nobody gives a damn!
Everybody wants everything!
Air conditioning, heating...
washing machines, electric cookers...
Of course everything
blows! It's a total mess!
Nobody understands anything anymore!
- May I ask for your name?
- Hers? Carol.
But I prefer calling her "The Pest".
What was that?
Did you hear that too?
God, I don't understand...
What's going on?
I'm the monster from the
black hole of the galaxy!
I came to eat you all!
Silence! Be a little quiet!
Susy, there should be some flashlights
in the closet next to the door.
Tommy, would you help her?
- The lights are off.
- Well, we're quite aware of that.
I have to check the fuses. There's
no water or telephone either.
- Nothing works in this damn shack.
- May I go get a drink?
Yes, go.
- The last one won't get a drink!
- I'm thirsty too!
- Want some water?
- No, thanks, I'll have a coke.
Come on, throw the ball. Come on!
- Did you hear that?
- Mommy!
- Be quiet!
- What is it? What is it?
What is that? There! Look!
Somebody raise the alarm!
Come on, quick! Do something!
Stand back, stand back!
Mommy! Mommy!
No! Help! Help me! No! Help!
Break open the doors!
Oh, my God!
Watch out for the girl, you'll crush
her! Watch out for the little girl!
- The doors! The doors!
- Mommy! Mommy!
Carol! Carol!
- Go, go!
- Move it, quick!
Pick her up! Somebody pick her up, quick!
- Out of the way!
- Hurry!
Oh, my God!
Mommy!
- Mommy!
- Come on, quick! Come here.
- Don't look.
- Where's my mommy?
I'll take you to your mommy.
- Be still, please!
- Where's my mommy?
We'll find her, you'll see. It's okay...
Stay calm... Stay calm!
- Mommy!
- We'll find her. We'll find your mommy!
I don't get it. Really,
I just don't get it.
Well, I'm asking myself how
this could possibly happen.
At least the blackout
only affects two quarters.
I'm not thinking about the
blackout, but about the animals, Nat.
They are so ferocious,
so incredibly aggressive.
It was Cheetah, an animal
that never attacks anybody.
I know her very well, she's shy. She's
startled by a leaf falling from a tree.
I don't understand the animals' behavior.
They all seem to be
hit by the same virus.
- How can you eat all this stuff?
- What stuff?
Ah, it's a habit.
Attention all units! Code R! Code R!
An unknown number of
animals attacked a tube wagon.
F. Freddy, F. Freddy, do you
read me.? Do you read me.?
- Here's Freddy, I'm listening.
- A message for Dr. Berner.
Go immediately to the
station and join a special squad
It seems the reported animals are tigers.
F. for Freddy. You're
the closest to the spot.
Go to the Kurt Schumacher
station immediately. Over.
Copy.
Inspector, here's Berner. Is there any
news from the Pasteur or my lab? Over.
Nothing yet, doctor, but I'm in
constant contact with both laboratories.
As soon as I know
something, I'll let you know.
Calm down, honey, calm down.
I can't go on...
Oh, my God...!
Susy! Susy!
This is great, Tommy!
Can you do a lion, Tommy?
Come on, Tommy!
Tommy, stop it, I'm scared.
Did you hit her?
Give me the rifle.
Go get her now. She's
not dangerous any more.
Laura! What are you doing here?
Rip, it's like a miracle
to see you again.
- Relax, now everything...
- Carol! Carol!
- Mommy!
- Oh, Carol!
- Stay calm, madam.
- Oh, my Carol!
- Mommy!
- It's okay now!
- Don't worry.
Mommy!
- I called her Susy.
- What?
I ran, I ran towards that
light. But I could never reach it.
It was a nightmare.
- I will never forget it.
- But it had a happy ending.
You'll need medical attention, Laura.
The officers will take you to the station.
- I've arranged an emergency ward there.
- No, I'm fine, I'm fine.
Refresh your makeup at least,
so you won't embarrass me.
Always in the mood
for a joke, aren't you?
- What should we do with the animal?
- Don't shoot her, I need her alive.
I want to find out what happened.
She'll be asleep in a few seconds.
As you wish, doctor.
The chain... and the stick.
Now surround her. Go slowly, slowly.
It's Gladis! It's Gladis.
Do you recognize me?
Gladis, hey...
You're totally plastered,
huh? Gladis, look here.
It's okay now, huh?
Be good... be good.
- Be careful, doctor!
- No, there's no danger.
She can hardly stand on her feet.
Be good... It's alright, Gladis, alright.
Behave...
Here we go! Let's go home now, huh?
Be ready with the net. Spread it wide.
Tighter! Tighter! It has
to be tighter! A little more!
Now!
That's it!
Come on, be nice.
- Do you enjoy the show, inspector?
- You really are completely crazy.
- Come on, quick!
- Hurry up! Come on!
I tried to call the school at
least a hundred times now...
but the line's always busy.
The class should be over in half
an hour. I really have to pick her up.
- Nat, can't you go faster?
- The lines are overloaded.
Everyone's on the phone
trying to find out what's going on.
It's always like that.
Help! Help! Help me!
Don't leave me here alone!
- Help!
- I'm coming.
Natalia!
Stop shouting, or it
will hear us. Got it?
Come on.
Come here. Come here. I'll carry you.
Go, go, hurry! Come on!
- Susy!
- What's up?
Listen, I'm going to
the kitchen. Wait here.
But why?
Take it, for self-defense. Come on, run!
- Tommy!
- Don't stop! Run! Run!
- Go, go! Tommy and Susy, where are they?
- We don't know!
- Wait!
- Here they are!
- Where were you?
- In the kitchen.
I got some knives, for self-defense.
Here, if you see him,
you throw it at him.
Help!
- I'm scared! I'm scared!
- Don't scream! Don't scream! Listen!
In there.
- Help! There he is!
- The key. Which one is it?
I can't find it.
I'll get it.
Don't you move. Don't move!
Come on, quick. Hurry.
Get in. Get in! Hurry!
Just what I thought.
They're reacting to the
injection, unfortunately.
What kind of reaction? What do you mean?
I'm not 100% sure, but if what I think is
true, it's incredible,
basically impossible.
There's phenol in the
blood. Phenol chlorate.
Matthaus, check if it's cyclical.
Laura, are you coming?
The entrance is full of journalists.
I can't hold them back anymore.
They want to come in.
- Talk to you, take photos.
- No way.
- Anyway, here's the chlorate.
- Don't worry, I'll take care of them.
- It's 3%.
- Perfect. Let's proceed with the alkalis.
Rip, whatever it is,
to make them drink it,
someone must have
put it in their troughs.
- But who would? Only a crazy person...
- I don't think it's the work of a madman.
The solution has to be the water.
It's the only element all
animals have in common.
How could've anyone put
the same amount of phenol...
into all their troughs?
Can you tell me that?
Listen, do you know someone
in the city's water department?
I don't think so...
Wait a moment! Berthros!
I could ask him. He works for the city.
I guess I know what you're thinking.
- Doctor.
- Excuse me, doctor, do you have a minute?
- What is it now?
- Come with us. You have to see it.
Excuse me.
Dr. Berthros? Hi, I'm Laura Schwarz.
I'm calling you from the zoo.
Yes, doctor. And I think
soon you'll be involved, too.
- Where the hell are they going?
- Oh, God, I think they're crazy!
Where do they come from?
Oh, God, I hope they
won't climb the stairs!
- Look how they run!
- But where are they heading?
Hey, it's hundreds of them!
Go, go! Let's get away from here! Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry! No...
Let's go over there! Run!
Look, there they are!
They're smashing the glass!
Go, go, go!
Go! Go!
They calmed down all of a sudden.
They were screaming
and growling like crazy.
- Now they're quiet.
- Ah, yes?
You see?
- Don't give them anything to drink.
- Sure, they notified us.
- Look at Toto. He was furious, but now...
- Hey Toto, want some apple?
Come on, take it. Open your mouth.
- Now he's an angel.
- Yeah, true. He's back to normal.
Look here. Come on.
Now, Toto, take it. Come on.
- Does he eat a lot?
- Now he's eating quite a lot.
Good. Very good. Here you are.
You got over it, huh? Come on, take it.
Give him lots of fresh vegetables, yes?
Could you please repeat that?
Hey, it's Berthros.
Nothing unusual in the main tanks.
- And in the aqueduct?
- Ah, I see. And in the aqueduct?
Nothing.
Doctor, it's phencyclidine alright. Look.
Okay, thank you.
You can reach me at home.
You got the number, right? Yes.
- See you soon.
- My God, it's incredible, crazy...
The guys from the water department,
the police, the firemen are all...
- What's that?
- PCP.
- Incredible.
- It's dynamite.
Junkies call that stuff "Angel
Dust", "Peace Pills", "Zombie Dust".
Also "Jet Fuel" and "Busy Bee".
A thousandth of a gram
to go totally bonkers.
- But that's absurd!
- I thought they only smoke it.
You can smoke it...
sniff it, shoot it, eat it, drink it.
- The worst of all drugs.
- Are you sure?
I'll take it.
Hello? Yes, it's me. It's Gustav
Sorensen, the health minister.
Yes, of course I can
confirm Dr. Schwarz' report.
Now I can even be more precise:
It's phencyclidine hydrochloride.
- Phencyclidine hydrochloride?
- Yes, yes, phencyclidine.
What you just told me is truly
incredible. You're quite certain?
I imagine that you know that
phencyclidine hydrochloride is a drug.
Exactly, PCP.
I have the reports from the central
in Ipswage, and they're all negative.
- Your discovery seems impossible to me.
- What do you mean, "impossible"?
- Can you send me some samples?
- Sure! Where do you want them?
Good. Do you want me to send
someone to pick up those famous samples?
No, that won't be necessary.
I have a police officer
here with me in the lab.
Goodbye, sir.
He wants the samples we analyzed.
Matthaus, get them ready. I'll take
them there. You're coming, Nat?
Doctor, do with me whatever you want.
Susy's school is on
the way to the pasteur.
We'll pick her up and then carry on.
Ah, so that's why you went out earlier.
At least it's not PCP.
- You know what I was thinking?
- What?
That the best lawyers and
insurers will have a lot to do...
in order to unravel
this tragic confusion.
I think that millions and millions won't
be enough to recover the damages.
Have you told
headquarters that the drug's
effects should have worn off by now, Nat?
Sure.
The lights! It's a
miracle, they're back on!
My God, this nightmare is finally over.
I'll go in and get
Susy. I'll be right back.
Wait here, Nat, I'll go with her.
- Hey, look!
- What is it?
What are you doing here, pompeo? Pompeo!
- Pompeo? Who the hell is pompeo?
- It's him over there. Look!
Pompeo, old beast,
what are you doing here?
- Don't get too close.
- Oh no, he's a good boy.
- Pompeo has always been my buddy.
- Maybe...
- Right, pompeo?
- Step aside.
It's all good, don't worry.
Pompeo, how did you get here?
Watch out!
What are you doing, huh? Pompeo!
Hey! Why don't you
behave? Huh, Pompeo? Huh?
- What's up, fatty? Come on.
- Now take a look at this loony...
Well now, are you my friend
or not? Come on, let's go?
I'll call the special unit, Rip.
Don't let the kids out until
Pompeo is back in his cage...
- and with his trainer.
- Alright, alright!
Hey Nat, come here.
Pompeo wants to meet you.
Tell him I'm busy.
Mrs. Vogner?
Susy?
Blue is the sky, green is the grass.
Close... close... close
your eyes so you...
so you... so you...
Close your eyes so you won't see.
Close your mouth so you won't talk.
Close your mouth so you won't
scream. So you won't scream.
Won't scream.
Susy...
Mommy! Mommy, they're
crazy! They're all crazy!
Take me away from here,
mommy! They will kill us!
They have knives,
mommy! They have knives!
And then, the lights,
mommy... The lights were gone!
It was Tommy! They didn't do anything!
Tommy came closer,
mommy! And then... then...
- She screamed and they laughed, mommy!
- Lady...
Beautiful lady, come and play with us.
It's wonderful. Please,
why aren't you coming?
They are evil, mommy,
take me away from here!
Alright...
Alright, I'll play with you. But...
But tell me what game
you want to play, Tommy.
A beautiful one. A game you will like.
She liked it too, see?
Play... Play with us, beautiful lady.
Susy!
No! No!
- Here they come!
- Calm down, honey!
They can't get out! I locked it!
Calm down!
Calm down, you hear me? Calm down!
You're save with me! You're save!
Laura!
Calm down, Susy, I'm
begging you! Calm down!
My God...!
Oh, God, please help us.
Help us!