Who killed Brother Zhang?
The Masked Avengers.
They stop at no evil.
We've spent over half a year's time,
but still can't find anything about them.
Brother Zhang, have you heard anything?
I...
Nothing at all.
No.
There's some news.
Brother Zhang went to investigate
the Masked Avengers,
he fled after being attacked.
He found out that
they are based in Jingyang Town.
Jingyang Town?
It'd take just a few days
to reach there, let's...
They work under a Chief,
and wear masks when they're killing.
The Chief's mask is golden,
and uses a golden trident.
Chicken blood? That's dull.
I'll give you another type of blood.
Du Gang, you always claim to be brave,
what's the matter with you now?
You thieves raided on me,
and killed my family of twenty eight.
As long as there's one of us left,
he will kill you all for revenge.
Wait a minute, I know that your family
has twenty nine people in total,
why did you say twenty eight?
Did your brother Du Meng get away?
He'll come back and revenge for you?
That's right.
Yes.
Eldest brother...
Second brother.
How could we let anyone escape?
Let me be clear;
We were paid by your enemies
to get rid of the twenty nine of you.
I could use it all now.
Alright, everyone got your share,
let's do our job.
Let's get rid of the Du Family!
Your whole family's dead.
There's no hope left, and you can die now.
I can never die in peace.
That's what I'm hoping for.
Chief, Jingyang Town.
That's all we know.
Jingyang Town?
Doesn't Ling Yunzhi live there?
He's from a well-known family there,
we could find him and investigate.
Ling Yunzhi?
What's going on?
There's someone here
who would like to see the master.
His name is Zeng Jun.
Send him in, I'll go outside to greet him.
Yes.
Send for Master Zeng,
our master will greet him.
Please.
The inn's full, sorry.
Goodbye.
"Chang An Inn"
Sorry, there's a private function.
We're all paying customers here,
how could you?
They all have some backgrounds,
I just worry about your inconvenience.
Sorry.
This is not a good inn.
Ling Yunzhi is a rich man,
why don't we stay at his residence?
There aren't that many
martial arts experts here,
since we know that
the Masked Avengers are based here.
I get it, you suspect Ling Yunzhi
to be the Chief.
Watch it! Don't break my stuff.
I didn't say that.
Welcome.
Qi Shanyun.
The Eight-armed Nazha.
You've made a name at such a young age.
Welcome to our small town!
But why would you
be staying at such a lowly inn?
Come stay at my place,
there's plenty of guest rooms.
Brother Ling, did Zeng Jun tell you
why we're here?
Yes. But it's strange that
despite my family being here
for generations, I've never heard that
the Masked Avengers are based here.
They are very secretive and
come and go like ghosts.
We need to take our time
in this investigation.
You're from a prominent family,
I'm afraid it'd be a bother
if we stay with you.
I think we better put up in an inn.
Nonsense! If this gets out,
people will think of me
as a terrible host.
Don't listen to Qi Shanyun, follow me.
We've already lost several men
dealing with the Masked Avengers.
We must be extra careful.
We've all taken oaths before,
no one would act alone.
Very well, I'm the host.
Maybe we could sit down and have a chat?
Certainly.
The food in this inn is awful,
go home and get the kitchen to
prepare something good.
Yes.
Let's drink.
Cheers.
How did you know that
the Masked Avengers are based here?
I've introduced them to you briefly, but
I'm not sure whether you can
remember so many of us.
You know of Loyang's Long Family
and Jizhou's Han Family?
Of course.
Although the eldest Master Long is dead,
but his eldest son, Long Congfeng,
has grown into a famous young man,
and his brothers
are well known as
the Four Greats of Long Family.
Old Master Han, the Whirlwind Blade,
is also a famous expert.
These are two of the Long brothers.
Long Congyu, Long Congjiang.
And Han Family's son,
Han Yanzhang "Little Whirlwind"
I'm sure they can tell you the details.
It happened about a month ago.
My family and the Han family
had a wedding to plan.
My eldest brother Congfang
and my fifth brother Conghai
escorted 4th sister Xianer
to be married to Yanzhang.
They were besieged by
Masked Avengers outside the town.
Help!
Eldest brother...
Third brother Congjiang & I
were with Yanzhang in town,
about to greet the bridal party.
As we rushed there,
eldest brother was about to die.
Eldest brother...
It's the Masked Avengers.
They took Xianer and Conghai with them.
Eldest brother...
And then the group of us
went out and tried to investigate
in that area.
A friend, Zhang Cheng
found out of the Masked Avengers
being based in Jingyang Town.
Unfortunately he had sustained
serious injuries,
and died before he could tell us more.
You brought us the heated wine,
why are you still here?
Leave now, we've business to discuss here.
The cook is a bit strange,
not sure what he's up to.
Come on, let's eat.
I'm sure he's up to something.
Maybe not.
But it seems that he knows martial arts.
Xiaoyang pushed him just now,
it looked as if he fell.
In fact he pretended to fall,
he wasn't being pushed down.
If that's the case,
we must keep an eye on him.
Strange indeed, he looks very familiar.
Brother Ling, let me drink to you again.
I can't drink anymore.
I think I should sleep here tonight.
Master, this isn't a place to sleep.
I like to sleep wherever I please.
It's not your call.
Why do you think
Ling Yunzhi's staying here tonight?
He likes to be pampered,
and is very particular
about his meals and lodgings.
Why would he be interested
to sleep in this dump?
And it didn't seem like he's drunk.
Surely something's up.
Wang Zhenlin,
you're sleeping next door to him,
stay alert.
Watch out for
anything out of the ordinary.
Fang Ying,
since Ling Yunzhi's staying here,
sneak in his house and take a look.
See if you could find anything.
Write properly, pay more attention.
Got it.
And now, turn the pages,
and repeat after me.
Zhao, Qian, Sun, Li...
Zhou, Wu, Zheng, Wang;
Feng, Chen, Zhu, Wei;
Jiang, Shen, Han, Yang; Zhu, Qin, You, Xu
Why aren't you writing?
Where are you going?
I'm thirsty, I want water.
Very well, I'll go with you.
Get up! Why are you lying at the entrance?
Impressive! No wonder Zeng Jun said
you know kung-fu.
Looks like you've taken some lessons.
But I'd really like to find out
how good you are.
What are you two doing here?
Thirsty, just want some water.
Me too.
I don't believe that he can fight.
What was that move
when you were dodging Xiaoyang?
I have no idea.
You are...
The cook of the inn.
Sorry to disturb your sleep.
It's better to be awake.
There's nothing strange
about the Ling residence.
I was attacked by the Chief.
Golden mask, golden trident,
none of the Ling family members knew.
Go upstairs and check
whether Ling Yunzhi is asleep.
Slowly, don't make a sound.
Checking on Ling Yunzhi?
What happened? What's going on?
Shut up! It's my turn!
Stop!
Thank you.
I don't understand what you're saying.
See if you know any of them.
Sure.
No...
No
Fang Ying, Wang Zhenlin was killed.
And where's Ling Yunzhi?
He's been sleeping there
the whole evening.
Guess he's got nothing to do
with the Masked Avengers.
Take the bodies out.
The Masked Avengers attacked us
in the kitchen.
Zeng Jun and the others killed them.
Do you know this person?
No.
Please have a seat.
Brother Ling, do you know who could be
involved with the Masked Avengers?
There's one in Jingyang Town.
His name is Fang Zuguang;
a very skilled chap.
But then, everyone knows of us as foes.
This might sound like
I'm trying to frame him.
Please, could you just tell us more.
Fang Zuguang likes to help others
from time to time,
but he does things according to his moods.
He has a lot of martial arts experts
working for him.
And to prevent others from
finding out their base,
it must be set in some big house.
Other than my residence,
the Fang Residence is the biggest here.
Fang Zuguang.
Master Fang...
Master Fang
Please.
Master Fang. Welcome...
Here's the wine.
Fang Zuguang has gone in.
Going to the market?
Yes. Don't run around like a
piglet awaiting slaughter.
In order to find the butcher,
the piglet must take its chances.
Not afraid to die?
Looking for the butcher is risky.
Tell me how a piglet can find
the butcher.
Answer me.
I don't know, I'm like a piglet myself.
The butcher looking for me,
and I searching the butcher.
I'm going to the market, wanna come along?
Certainly...
What are we cooking today?
Braised fish head,
a platter of appetizers, and this.
Light the fire.
Me?
Aren't you a bit harsh on me?
If I can, why can't you?
We see each other everyday,
I still don't know your name.
Just consider me as a nobody.
I'm Zeng Jun.
I don't know your background,
but I can tell you are a hot-blooded man.
You think? I'm cold-blooded.
Please step aside
if you can't light the fire.
What's the fun to be a cook?
Beware being burnt to death
without the fire being lit
You're saying that
the Masked Avengers will kill us?
Though I don't know
how to light a fire, I can cook.
You want to be a chivalrous man?
Who doesn't?
True.
But don't get yourself killed
in the process.
Even so, it's better than trying to evade.
Why can't you leave me alone
like the rest of them?
I want to help you.
Very well, light the fire.
I don't believe you're cold-blooded.
I think you don't believe that yourself.
Ling Yunzhi said you seem familiar.
A man must be upright.
If you evade, you might as well be dead.
Impressive! That would really hurt.
It's too late, I saw that.
What are you hiding from?
Light the fire.
Sure.
Don't cry, let me buy you a toy.
One please.
Don't cry, isn't this fun?
Take a look.
Xiaoyang, Yang Qingbiao.
Hurry! Move aside.
Come on everyone! I made all these!
What are you looking at? Eat up!
Just the few of us?
Where's Xiaoyang and the rest?
Why aren't they back?
They're keeping an eye on
Fang Zuguang at the teahouse,
Chen Shengkang and Yanzhang are outside.
I guess Fang Zuguang hasn't left,
hence neither could they.
Yang Qingbiao must be eating
with Brother Xu right now.
So what?
Do you think any restaurant
could make better dishes than me?
Come on! Eat up!
Eat up!
Come on!
Yang Qingbiao is...
...unlucky.
Yang Qingbiao is really unlucky.
They killed Yang Qingbiao,
he was killed by a Chief
who used golden trident.
What are you doing here? Get out!
Another piglet's been slaughtered
by the butcher.
What are you talking about?
Liang Rong, don't be mad.
What he just said,
wasn't what you think he meant.
What does he mean then?
Enough, come over.
I don't trust him.
Fang Zuguang isn't the Chief.
When Yang Qingbiao was killed,
we were in the teahouse.
Fang Zuguang isn't the Chief
and neither is Ling Yunzhi.
Then who is?
Have you thought of something?
Neither of them is,
and it could also be said
they could both be.
We only know that they have a Chief,
but there could be more than one.
We kept an eye on one,
while the other's free to kill.
That's why Ling Yunzhi and Fang Zuguang,
they both could be.
What are we waiting for?
Let's invite both Ling Yunzhi
and Fang Zuguang,
and see what happens.
Alright.
Invite Fang Zuguang tomorrow
at Ling Yunzhi's home,
Zeng Jun's with me.
The rest will keep an eye
outside the Ling Residence.
If Fang Zuguang leaves,
Chen Shengkang will follow him.
Alright.
We've been looking all over for you.
That's very smart of you to hide here.
But then, we could still find you.
What are you two talking about?
You just came from a temple fair?
I didn't know there's one.
You can act.
Yes. Show him what he's hiding,
and then he can't act any longer.
You have something to say?
Your turn.
Fine, my turn.
Even if the piglet is hiding,
the butcher would come looking.
You saw them?
What do you want?
You're on our side,
only that you use a different plan.
You plan to infiltrate them?
But the mask and the trident
is that of a Chief.
You can't handle the
whole organization by yourself.
How about?
What keeps you from thinking that
I'm a Chief myself?
I should slap you for saying that.
I take you as a friend and
you treat yourself as an ass.
Sorry, maybe I was out of line.
Maybe you don't want to mix with us.
Hold on.
You've asked my name several times.
Let me tell you now, my name is Gao Yao.
Master Fang's here.
You've the nerve to show up?
Why not?
But I didn't invite you.
I've two friends who'd like to see you.
Qi Shanyun.
Zeng Jun.
I've heard of you.
Must have been a tough journey here.
And I think you've followed me
on the streets before.
As for Brother Qi,
if you've any misunderstanding,
please say so.
We're here to investigate
the base of Masked Avengers.
So I've heard.
And you've already lost some men
because of it.
I don't know who's your source,
so as to prompt you to
come looking for their base.
If that's true,
I guess
only Master Ling would know about it.
I honestly don't, but I guess you do.
Both of you are known for your good work,
I'm sure you'll help to get rid of them.
Of course.
Since I'm the host,
I've prepared some wine,
let's talk this over.
Come on.
You...
Chen Shengkang's dead.
He's got a golden mask in his hand,
he must have been killed by the Chief.
Before he died,
he snatched the Chief's mask.
In that case, he knew his identity.
Too bad he couldn't tell us.
So the Chief is...
I know who the Chief is.
He's been close to us all this time!
It's him!
That's nonsense!
Let's go back first.
Liang Rong, don't be rash.
Move aside.
I'm sure I can find something here.
Even so, what can you prove?
Zeng Jun, what are you trying to say?
What's going on?
Brother Qi,
I've found two strange items,
he hid them away before.
I've changed the hiding place
after I found them.
These are the items.
I think the cook is the Chief.
No, Gao Yao isn't the Chief.
He wants to get rid of
Masked Avengers as much as us!
He has the items
so that he could infiltrate their group.
Zeng Jun, take a closer look.
This weapon is the same
which killed Chen Shengkang.
What's going on?
Why are you protecting him?
My friend.
The night when the Masked Avengers
raided the inn;
If it wasn't for him,
Yang Qingbiao, Chen Shengkang and I
would all be dead.
That's just your opinion.
Now that Yang Qingbiao and
Chen Shengkang are dead,
who could prove that?
A Chief.
How could he be?
Think about all the robberies
by the Masked Avengers,
with all that money.
And the Chief is not going out
and having a good time,
instead he's working here as a cook?
I'm sure he is.
We're still trying to find the suspect,
but the Masked Avengers
keep killing our brothers.
When Chen Shengkang died,
were you with Ling Yunzhi
and Fang Zuguang?
Calm down everyone!
Look! He's here!
Brother Ling, what are you doing here?
And how about you?
Checking on someone to see
if he's indeed an old buddy.
If the person you're referring to
is a cook,
I've met him before,
and he seemed like an old friend.
Brother Fang, please.
Brother Ling, please.
Who would have thought?
The person we've tried so hard to find,
is right under our nose.
Life is full of surprises.
My friend,
I can see that you're very skilled.
This is highly unusual.
Are you somehow connected
to the Masked Avengers?
Over the years they have committed
too many crimes,
you should know
'what comes around goes around'.
I am aware of that.
A man will take his chances
and face the consequences.
If you're a member,
please show us the trident.
I've sworn not to
use the trident
unless on a Masked Avenger.
Brother Qi, why don't you fight?
I think he has back up.
Hide now! It's not a good time.
They will understand sooner or later.
Go! I await your return.
Brother Qi, you ask him.
What does he mean by letting a Chief go?
If he's a Chief, I'll fight him.
That must be him.
Brother Qi, do you believe me?
Of course.
And I believe that
no matter who Gao Yao is,
he seems to be a good person.
Excellent.
As long as you give him
a chance to explain
I'll find Gao Yao back!
You know where he's headed?
No, but I've promised him to wait here.
I treat him as a friend, and so does he.
He wouldn't take off just like this.
Very well.
Who are you?
You're not permitted to come here.
You can't disturb
the Zen lesson in process.
Third Chief.
Chief, now that we know
each other's identity,
we no longer require our masks.
From now on, let's team up.
Sure.
What? Your friend isn't back yet?
I've told you, he's a Chief.
He leads a team of criminals.
You have gone nuts to treat him
as a friend!
Shut up!
Have you thought of something?
I suddenly realise that
you've mastered
the skills of using a trident.
I'm a Deputy Chief,
of course I would have mastered it.
What are you kidding about?
I'm not kidding.
You! I've offended Brother Qi
and the rest.
So I was wrong about you.
You can't be!
I am!
I was a Deputy Chief
of the Masked Avengers.
Do you still remember
when you arrived at the inn?
I heard Long Congyu talk of
his eldest brother's death
and the kidnapping of
his younger siblings.
I was there at the scene.
The Masked Avengers are based
in a deserted temple.
Fifth brother...
Please don't cry, sister. We're tough.
A young boy claiming to be tough.
Fifth brother...
This girl...
Should we reward this girl to our members?
Good idea.
Go.
Wait.
What is it? Is the Deputy Head interested?
We've killed many,
that's because we've been given
large sums to do so.
The dowry we've robbed
isn't much this time,
and we've killed
a famous swordsman Long Congfeng.
And Long Conghai was just a kid.
How can we hurt a woman now?
We kill anyone it takes,
what's the big deal to hurt a woman?
Go.
Deputy Chief, where are you off to?
Stand still or I take you as a rebel.
Rebel? Alright. I quit now,
and I'll no longer have
anything to do with you.
Aren't you scared that we'll look for you?
We've always worn masks,
and we don't know each other's identity.
I'll use my way to hide,
and you can use your way to find me.
So you refused to associate with them,
you've left the organization.
I was right about you after all.
You've been hiding in the small inn.
Yes. Because they would never expect that
I'll have the nerve to
stay in Jingyang Town.
And being here,
I can find out who's the Chief
and the Third Chief.
They are?
The Chief is Ling Yunzhi.
The Third Chief is Fang Zuguang.
Just as I thought.
This isn't right!
When Chen Shengkang died,
Ling Yunzhi and Fang Zuguang were with me.
Chen Shengkang grabbed a golden mask
used by a Chief.
That's right.
Within six months after I left,
there's a new Deputy Chief.
Are you the new Deputy Chief?
Yes, I am.
Do you have the order?
Yes.
Who did you kill?
Under the Chief's order, Cui Liang,
the young master of
White Tiger Clan was killed.
Please check.
It's Cui Liang.
A reward of 100 gold taels
for killing Cui Liang.
Half of it to the organization
and half to Deputy Chief.
Thank you, Chief.
You're the Deputy Chief now, have a seat.
Deputy Chief.
Twenty taels of gold
for everyone to split.
Who's the new Deputy?
I've no idea,
I tried but couldn't find out.
Gao Yao, what do you plan to do now?
Go afar.
Stop hiding! Join us
against the Masked Avengers!
Trust me.
Your friends don't trust me at all.
They will come around sooner or later.
You've uncovered the identities
of the Chief
and Third Chief.
Go back and tell Qi Shanyun,
get more manpower.
You thought that the base
must be in some big residence.
But in fact, it's in a deserted temple.
All you have to do is wait,
you can nab them all in one go
when they assemble.
You should head back.
Gao Yao.
Didn't see that coming?
You thought I didn't notice,
but I heard you.
So? You've changed your mind? I guess so.
What are you doing?
Very well! The three of you here!
I deserve such attention!
I'm so silly not to see it.
You don't dress the same as Gao Yao.
You're Fang Zuguang, the Third Chief.
I know who you are.
Ling Yunzhi, the Chief.
That's right, and now you can die.
The Deputy Chief is...
Honestly, I don't know who you are.
Now I know.
So it's really you! I was right.
Looks like they've already found out
our identities except for Liang Rong's.
They know about us.
Brother Fang, please summon everyone,
Liang Rong could then
lure them to our base.
It's my treat this time.
Stop pulling me!
Forget it! Let's go!
What's going on?
The kid's almost dead.
We should report it.
Stay out of it!
Can't you see the tridents on him?
It's got pinned him on the tree.
So scary!
Zeng Jun.
Deputy Chief?
Liang Rong.
"Chang Ann Inn"
Add some water.
Thanks.
Brother Qi, I think we should send someone
to where Gao Yao was last night.
Yes.
And we should send someone on the streets.
But whenever our members went alone,
they were attacked.
We must also send someone else
for back-up.
Congyu,
you go with Yanzhang
to where Gao Yao was last night.
The place where your brother was killed.
I know.
Weifang and Congjiang shall
stay on the streets.
Yes.
Be careful, everyone.
"Warrant"
Hide!
What would you like to buy?
A mat.
Zeng Jun is still not back.
I'm worried.
I don't think we can trust him;
And he said that Chief's a good man,
and he treats him as a friend.
Liang Rong, Zeng Jun is our brother.
A brother? Then why does he take
a Chief as his friend?
I think Zeng Jun...
Do you want to know where Zeng Jun is?
That's him! He's the Chief.
Brother Qi, Zeng Jun's your buddy.
You should be able to
recognise his outfit.
It looked like he was hurt by a trident.
Yes.
Brother Qi, the murderer is here.
Let's avenge for Brother Zeng.
Wait for me to finish.
You've nothing more to say.
Qi Shanyun, if you won't hear me out,
all your friends
would have died for nothing.
Let him finish.
He has a golden trident,
he's a Chief for sure.
Zeng Jun and I said goodbye,
three Chiefs appeared after I left.
The three attacked him.
He fought his best, one against three.
And he's found out their identities.
Why are you listening to his bullshit?
Shut up and let him finish.
I don't know why we should;
After all, he did kill Zeng Jun
and is talking nonsense here.
Let him finish.
I know who the Chief
and the Third Chief are.
Who?
The Chief is Ling Yunzhi.
The Third Chief is Fang Zuguang.
What about the Deputy Chief?
It's him.
You've said quite enough,
but who would believe you?
You don't?
Brother Qi, you must not believe him.
Zeng Jun's dead, who could back you up?
He can say anything he wants.
I never said Zeng Jun's dead.
Why are you so certain...
that he's dead?
He got pierced by a trident,
of course he'd die.
And how did you know that?
Brother Zeng... please come here.
Earlier you said that
Liang Rong is the Deputy Chief,
and he escaped.
Now that the truth is revealed,
he has nowhere to go.
He can't run anymore.
Now you will believe me.
I had my suspicions
when he became restless earlier.
But it'd be impossible to prove this
if Brother Zeng's dead.
Zeng Jun is indeed dead.
When I got there,
all he could utter was Liang Rong's name.
If not for this,
Liang Rong wouldn't blow his cover.
Zeng Jun?
Brother Zeng's killed.
At least we've a Masked Avenger
in our hands,
we could ask him about the Chief.
He killed himself.
So there's no one alive.
Don't worry, we've known
the identities of the Chiefs.
Ling Yunahi, Fang Zuguang, and Liang Rong.
Liang Rong too?
He was holding this
when we caught the masked avenger earlier.
This is an order to assemble them
to meet at the base.
The base is in a deserted temple,
I know where.
I'm sure Liang Rong's there now.
Let's go there!
We can get rid of them all!
Sister.
Xianer.
Xianer, what's wrong?
Sister...
Forget about tracking us down.
From now on, the Long and
Han families no longer exist.
Gao Yao has revealed our identities,
he's now with Qi Shanyun and the lot.
Gao Yao knows this place,
they'll get here any time.
Let's go to the back hall.
These two...
Keep them alive.
They can tell them that
we've gone to the back.
As long as Qi Shanyun &
Gao Yao have gone there,
they can't leave.
Brother Yanzhang, Second brother.
They've gone towards the back.
Second brother.
Brother Yanzhang.
The door is behind the Buddha statue.
Brother Yanzhang,
There's a trap besides the door.
Go in! Hurry!