"The Ball"
I am mayor of the city of Horn.
Hans Rasch.
Er. Yes, it's carnival season now,
that's the only time of the year
that happiness and laughter prevail.
Laughing is healthy, people are doing
serious labor day in, day out.
So they shall be happy once a year.
And that is why I welcome the carnival season.
I like going to the ball,
because I am always glad
to meet good friends with
whom I can be funny.
I have a lot of work all year,
lots of trouble.
And laughing sets people free.
Please be careful now.
This is delicate.
We must cooperate now,
or else it will go wrong.
If we are to the front,
or relatively far to the front,
a bit further up front than now,
yes, mind the distances
when we are an little bit
more to the front than now,
the ladies shake hands, yes, so we
have a slight cohesion between the rows ...
I am the director of the Federal
Secondary School Horn.
My name: Privy councilor Otto Mayer.
My attitude towards the
Horner students' ball is positive.
I welcome the realization
of this traditional ball,
a youth celebration ball that's a
highlight of the Carnival of Horner.
Its uniqueness lies in the party
and the whole ambiance.
The opening polonaise of the
committee of the bachelors
and bachelorettes is magisterially
conducted by Prof. Hagel.
It always constitutes the
festive prelude to the festival.
In this ambiance,
it is understandable that
that for the Horner youth in general,
this is the first ball they visit.
What is more, the Horner
ball is a stomping ground
for former students,
even whole classes.
This needs to be so,
sooo precise, that they,
Reagan and his cronies
would lick their fingers.
It needs to be very precise.
And over there the gentlemen, please:
everyone pulls a lady, aren't they
young, lean, feather weighty beings.
It's no hardship.
Some do as with a piece of furniture,
pull it around, don't they?
I personally visit the ball
usually in tandem
with my wife and we always enjoy
the colorful image of the youth.
We're pleased to chat when we dance,
so to me it's also a highlight
of the Carnival of Horner.
My name is Dr. Heinz Sommer.
I've been at the Federal High School
since 1967 as a school doctor.
Regarding the ball; the upcoming one,
I'd like to make the following statement:
I'm always pleased to
participate in a student ball,
since I do have the opportunity
to see what has become of them,
the students that left school,
what professions they took.
And also the happiness of the youth
to participate in this event here.
There is always a casual,
relaxed companionship.
And for me as an senior,
it's always very enjoyable
to participate in this event
with the youth.
My name is Dr. Franz Hochhinaus.
I am a lawyer here in Horn,
in Lower Austria, in the Forrest District.
As you know Horn is a small town,
notably a school city with a secondary
school and a high school.
I am also chairman of the Parents'
Association of the secondary school in Horn.
As such, I especially like
to visit the students' ball.
Now for the question:
Why go to a small town to a ball?
I think it's essential to
distinguish why people go to balls
in cities and why in a small town,
where you know each other.
The ball as a social event
facilitates being together,
I would say, and not any, for any
other reason, as it might be the case
in a big city, where you
go to see and be seen.
Song: "Gonna Take A Sentimental Journey"
Yes, this is my first ball
and I want it to be a kind of romantic event.
But not as one used to say,
more like "High Society",
but we dance polonaise,
because I think that this should
be an unforgettable event for me.
All women will look around
at what whom is wearing
and how often they have already
been wearing it and whether
they go with the same dress
for two or three years.
No matter at what table,
everybody comments.
In any case it's being discussed
who flirts with whom.
Yes, after all, my business
is specifically aimed at women
and I can imagine, that I,
if I get a man to dance at the ball,
and the lady is sitting next to me,
and might be a customer of mine,
she probably won't be too pleased.
Is it pleasing? Very subtle. Yes.
You only need to change the dress
and you can go dancing. Thank you.
Song: "... Sentimental Journey ..."
Well, I like to go to the ball,
so, because I, I go to the ball
because I like to have a chat,
because I like to dance.
And I, so if I'm there,
I dance with everyone,
so, who asks me.
I don't care, whether I,
whether he's a child of
a professor's or a doctor,
or whether he descends
from a worker's family.
So, unlike others,
I know some that say,
I'm not gonna dance with
this or that guy,
so to me it doesn't matter.
So, I want to just enjoy it.
And hope that I can dance,
with whom asks me to,
I hope it's just a lot of dancing.
Song: "... Seven, that's the time we leave ..."
Yes, that is a fact that bothers
me quite a bit at a ball.
One experiences, well actually
you'll experience it anywhere, that...
that there are sometimes women,
especially women,
who don't quite know how to
actually dress for a festive ball.
There are those that race around in rags.
That are supposed to be
something of a dress.
That is, thrown around towels,
and then, well, I think ladies
should observe certain rules.
Well why I go to a ball.
I try to do at a ball
what I like to do: namely dance.
And to meet friends.
And to get to know them privately,
which is easily possible at the ball.
And above all I am very
happy to go dancing.
While you're dancing you only
have to watch out what you do,
what you say, how you go,
how you stand,
and especially how long you
dance with a particular person,
without somebody else seeing it.
It's impossible to dance all night
with somebody you like to dance with,
because you meet the people
from the ball all year through.
And, yes, you've got to stand it
and it is not just pleasant,
if you hear that he dates her,
well, still and again ...
And I try to solve this by
dancing with other men also
And, uh, I nonetheless like
to go to the ball, to dance;
also to dance with others.
Song: "Take my lips ..."
I go to the ball to dance,
since I can dance here with like-minded,
with people who also like to dance.
And I love to dance,
that I may be a bit of an actor,
a bit in the limelight,
to be as I want to be,
which is very rare.
The climax of the ball is
to me the polonaise,
because then I can be best actor,
dance the most,
I'm very much in the limelight then.
A coat? 40 Austrian Schillings.
-Two, please!
-2 adults? 160
- Do you have a tenner?
Well, I would not go alone to a ball,
no. I'd never do that.
I don't know, it feels odd.
I wouldn't know where to sit.
Almost everybody is in pairs.
Even in circles, they are always 2,4,6,8
always double;
one would feel superfluous,
to sit at a table as seventh
or ninth, or as a fifth,
nobody's gonna pick you up. There must
always be a couple to remain seated.
If you're a circle of five at a ball
there will never four of them be
dancing at once, but only two.
The other two would not dare to,
because they think
they need to remain seated,
since they included me as a fifth person.
Well, I think that men
also have opportunities
to shape their bodies and to
manifest their inner expression.
There is the possibility
to wear a vest or none.
And there is the possibility
of a black or a red bow tie.
A very black or a
rather dark gray one.
A pin-striped suit or none.
And there is the possibility
of choosing the shirt.
- Keep still!
- Scandale Grande!
- Cheese!
- Smile, smile, baby.
Well, if I find somebody
to push me right,
push me politically, then I
might be able to...
enter the clique of
the Opera Ball dancers.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I thank you very warmly for your applause
for the opening by the committee
of the bachelors and bachelorettes
and now ask the Director of the
Federal Secondary Schools of Horner,
privy councilor Otto Meyer
to open the ball.
Distinguished guests.
Dear youth. First, I'd like
to express my joy
about this year's numerous
followings of our invitation to our ball.
With exceptional pleasure
I welcome the patrons of our ball,
the members of the
Lower Austrian Landtag,
Kurt Puchinger and
economist John Steinböck.
I also warmly welcome Dr. Wagner
from the District Commission Horn,
who comes in place of
the deputy district chief.
We are particularly pleased,
that our dear Mr. Mayor, councilor
Hans Rasch, is in our midst today.
To you, and to you all,
I wish a beautiful, fun ball night.
And to our organizer,
the successful volleyball team
under the leadership of Professor
Pavlicek, I not only thank,
but also wish a financially
successful night.
In this sense and in the hope
that all my wishes come true,
I open the the ball of the Horner
Federal Secondary Schools of 1982.
And!
The sound was good ... Hahaha!
So to me a ball is a success,
when I more or less danced
with all the other polonaise ladies.
And then from midnight danced
with all the ladies that lie in my heart.
Well, that's women who
dance relatively well.
Or, ladies, I just know, who
thereby are seated to other tables,
and they are invited to dance,
and then you chance it
whether you dance in step.
And if the first dance passes off
more or less without complaint
then you continue dancing some more.
If you'll give me the opportunity
to address the questions asked,
I must first introduce myself:
my name is Dr. Richard Straub,
lawyer by profession in Horn,
in my political function,
I am vice-mayor.
I suppose this function is the
primary reason for your visit.
Now to your questions: my comment
on the ball happening in Horn,
respectively the importance
of the ball in Horn.
This question I must answer
from two viewpoints.
Once again from my
position of vice-mayor,
and then the importance
I personally attribute to the ball.
I consider the ball to be very
essential for the town of Horn,
to be very important from the social
point of view, from the cultural standpoint,
from an economic standpoint, etc.
Since television crept into the families,
and predominates leisure time at home,
social life in small towns
faded into the background
So it is very welcome and beneficial,
especially during carnival
but also throughout the year
if any kind of social events take place.
To the ball itself -
Singing voice: "In the party. In the party.
My father was in the party.
My mother was in the party.
My brother was in the party,
my sister was in the party... "
It's always very embarrassing
if a woman has to turn men down.
People then might say she's arrogant,
or snooty, or something like that,
so it's easy for a man to
relieve her from that choice,
to say "no" or "later" or "no, thanks".
These are decisions I have to relieve her from.
Since I'm supposed to know my partner
I should know which men
she dislikes, might be interested in
for professional or business reasons,
or thinks to be completely uninteresting.
And relieve her from saying 'no',
thank God man can decide that.
I also tell myself that it was not
the woman who turned me down,
but her partner,
who thinks I'm too handsome.
But probably his lady would like me.
It's not like the woman turns you down directly.
So, I repeat the announcement:
from half past ten cards, slips of paper
are handed out with hearts on them.
Whoever has the most hearts
and slips is queen of the ball.
There are ladies wearing bright red gloves
and keeping their hands quite far up,
so they are particularly noticeable.
They of course engage a lot of attention.
The ball in a small town is a representative event.
And as a professor of the local school
I enjoy that the youth is taking an active part.
The only danger is that,
and I now speak as a psychologist,
that there may be a little "ball shock"
with girls not being picked up for a while.
Lots of them come to the ball as couples already,
and if a young man doesn't find somebody,
and in his solitude gets carried away a little,
that could be a certain danger, no?
Apart from that the ball is
always very well attended,
many graduates come,
and then it's always very nice.
Song: "Let's dance Charleston ..."
Now you imagine, that it pleased
us at that time in our youth,
to raise a lady's ball gown up to the ruff to potter
around underneath it in this stuffy, hot atmosphere.
- Where it is probably as wet as out here.
- Well, we didn't get that far back then.
Song: "He who was born in April,
get up, get up ... drink up ... "
My name is Peter Berger.
I am a shareholder of the
Printing Company Berger.
We employ 200 people.
Incidentally, I am a councilor in Horn.
For me, a ball in the countryside
is an ideal means of communication.
You get to know people you've
only seen passing on the street.
You can participate in conversations
in a relaxed atmosphere.
One gets to know people,
their problems, their attitude.
And I personally go to
Horner balls to get entertained.
To spend a harmonious evening with my wife
and if it ends different than planned,
by making a new acquaintance,
then it is surely the end
of a successful evening ball.
Song: "drink up, drink up, drink up ..."
My name is Dr. Robert Seiner.
I am a notary by profession.
And the umpire of OEVP Balls.
Today as any year the ball
of the ÖVP Horn takes place.
The ball of the ÖVP Horn is certainly
of great importance to the city of Horn.
This ball is the highlight of the Horner Carnival.
At the ball all classes of population meet,
teachers as well as the medical profession,
civil servants, business,
and of course dependent workers.
Moreover, this ball is visited
by many foreign visitors.