If the story you
are about to see
were the product
of a writer’s imagination,
you might
label it unbelievable.
But these events
actually took place
on the streets and alleys
and the tenements
where we filmed them -
in the shadow
of the bridge.
[Dramatic music]
(Lawyer)
What did you do
after he fell down?
(Defendant)
I hit him.
(Lawyer)
What did you
have in your hand
when you hit him?
(Defendant)
A piece of wood.
(Lawyer)
And this piece of wood
you had in your hand,
what was on it?
(Defendant)
What do you mean?
(Lawyer)
On the end
of piece of wood,
what was there?
(Defendant)
I don't remember.
(Lawyer)
Please, speak up
so we can hear you.
(Defendant)
I don't remember.
(Lawyer)
What was your answer:
Please, let the court hear it.
Objection!
Are you trying to make
a fool of me?
Your honor, I cannot
complete my examination
if this idiot goes
on interrupting...
That is not
a proper remark
in reference
to counsel.
(Judge pounds gavel)
Gentlemen.
Your remarks are discourteous
not only to one another
but to this court
as well.
I realize everyone
is very tired.
Let's just confine ourselves
to questions and answers.
Get away from me!
Don't lay a hand on me.
Your honor, this man
wants to assault me.
Your honor,
I did not assault him.
Take the defendants
out of here.
I demand police protection
from the prosecution.
This court will
be in order at once!
This trial stands adjourned
until 4 o’clock
the jury
will be advised...
Judge...
May I have
just a moment?
Get that
man out of here!
...can I just
say something...
(Policemen)
...Get him out,
get him out...
What did I do?
All right,
stand there.
Lean forward and put your
hands up against the wall
and freeze there.
Where's
the weapon?
Weapon?
It's a Bible.
Maybe there's
a gun in it.
Who do you work for,
the gangs?
Ahh, it's just a Bible,
where's the gun?
I don't
have a gun.
I'm a minister.
Those are my
ordination papers.
You always carry ordination
papers with you?
What are you
tryin' a hide?
David Wilkerson.
That your name?
Yes.
What are you
doing here?
I'm trying to get
permission from the judge
to help those kids.
With what,
new evidence?
All right, stand up, now.
Watch him.
I'll go see what the judge
wants to do about him.
How do you think
you can help those kids?
I've got a whole church full
of people praying for them
back in Philipsburg,
Pennsylvania.
[Laughter]
They better be praying
for a miracle
because the D.A. will
burn those creeps.
(Policeman)
Give him back
his Bible.
Alright, the judge said
he won’t press any charges
if you agree not
to come back here anymore.
Now what do you say?
What the hell.
These kids aren't
of your faith.
(Reporter)
Hey, reverend, what's that book
you got in your hand?
The Bible?
You ashamed
of it?
Of course not.
Stop hiding it then.
Hold it up where we can see it.
(Court personnel)
...All rise, hear ye,
hear ye, hear ye...
What can you do,
what can you say?
Where do you start
to begin, begin
you gotta face the fact that
you're just one guy,
but, on the other hand
the fact is you've got to try.
There's a dude sleeping
in the backseat.
I dig.
What if he
wakes up?
He look bad?
He don't look
too bad -
but, he don't look
too good either.
You chokin' up,
baby?
How we goin'
about this?
Now look.
When he comes out of the car,
you grab him like this.
You hold on to him
and I'll grab his wallet.
You like that?
Yeah.
That's nice.
Okay, when he come out,
we just get on him, dig?
Get his wallet.
Watch out! He's fast.
Hey, Bottlecap,
cool it.
Turn loose
that cat.
You're the cat from
the trial, ain't ya?
Yes.
Lay it on me, baby.
Don't wrestle with me.
Just lay in the sky.
That's it.
Look here.
This is the cat that went
after the judge in the
Egyptian king trial.
Right, baby?
Well, in away
I went after him.
I'm David Wilkerson.
Little Bo-peep, Davey baby.
You can call me 'Bo',
and the dude that tried
to slice ya,
that's my man
'Bottlecap.'
Hi, Bottlecap.
Hey, you niggers.
Bring that junk back here!
Come on! You want me
to whale tail on you?
You fools coppin;
From my man.
Get yourselves
together.
That's a real fine pair
o' shoes you got there.
Sure wish I had me a fine
pair o' shoes like that.
Thanks.
Hey do you know that gang,
the Egyptian Kings?
Yeah, they pretty bad,
but they ain't the heaviest.
Like they wouldn’t mess with
the Mau Maus or the Bishops.
I took these shoes
off of a wino.
He must a had athlete's
feet or something,
'cause I'm always itching.
Mau Maus, huh?
Sure would like
to meet them.
Is that
you're gang?
What I need a gang for?
I run alone.
I got no use
for jitterbuggin,
and getting messed up
and cuttin' cats.
Ain't no bread in it.
Bo, do you
believe in God?
I don't worry
about him.
I just worry about
the pigs and hustlin' bread.
Easy for you
to talk about God...
A rich man like you
with that bad car
and those
fine shoes.
God worries
about you.
You're on his
mind right now.
You better tell him
to think a little harder,
'cause he ain't
comin' through.
What's the gag?
You keep belly achin'
about shoes, put 'em on.
I don't want your
stinking shoes, man.
Don't make a thing of it.
Just put them on.
What you
gonna wear?
I've got another
pair at home.
Where’s that?
Philipsburg,
Pennsylvania.
Oh, beautiful, baby.
Give me five.
So you want to see the gang.
I'll show you the gang.
Let's get this chariot
together, Davey baby.
I'll take you to see
some real boppers.
Only don’t go laying none
of that God stuff on them
cause they'll cut you
so full of holes
that you could sprinkle
the grass
in which-em-a-call-it,
Pennsylvania,
just by drinking
a glass of water.
This turf belongs
to the A.A.A.G.P.
They got a peace treaty with
the Bishops and the Mau Maus.
They don't rumble anyhow,
they just freak out.
What's
the A.A.A.G.P.?
That's the American Association
for the Advancement
of Gangs and Pot!
You better
park here.
This is about as close
as you're going to get
and still keep
your car.
I think you’re gonna
wish you still had your shoes.
Music
it’s water.
We were lucky.
Hey, Angela!
Angie, it's me Bo.
Hello,
where you been?
I haven't seen you around
in along time.
You don't
know him.
You just seen his picture
in the paper.
This is the preacher that
got himself busted
at the Egyptian Kings trial.
Oh...
(Bo)
Leave him alone.
That's his thing.
And don't go tryin' to turn
a trick on him.
He popped that same smile
on me an' Bottlecap.
Hey, he wants to meet
the gang.
Why don't you
take him inside?
I can't.
The Mau Maus waitin' for a war
council with the Bishops.
My brother's inside.
That's all right, Bo,
we'll go in.
Oh, now wait a minute.
Maybe it's better if I don't.
Like I said,
I'm loner.
I just run dispatches
for one gang or another,
but if I was to just walk
right in the clubhouse,
they might not
like it.
You're just afraid
they might cut you.
Oh, go on.
Take him in.
Uh huh. I ain't gonna
get bawled out-
unless you give me
five dollars.
Go on, you can turn him loose
just inside the door.
Five dollars
is my price.
Let's cool it,
Davey baby.
Five bucks is this
chick's top price.
For that you get two
joints of marijuana,
her body,
and two bits change.
Should I give her
some money?
Two bucks tops.
You better
make it three.
You don't wanna
insult her pride.
That cat could
only swing two.
Come on.
Later,
Davey baby.
I'm gonna go steal
me some breakfast.
All right, Bo.
Thanks.
Hey, Rosa
can I come in?
Your brother
wouldn't think so.
I brought
a friend.
Hey man.
The tennis club
is down the block.
You're stumblin'
around in my turf.
He's okay,
chance.
He's the preacher they
dragged out and beat up
for trying to help
the Egyptian Kings.
Yeah?
That's cool,
cool, man.
Smoke my peace pipe?
I will.
Have my
peace pipe.
Have a piece
of my pipe.
Have a...
What are you doing
with that joint?
I like it.
It makes me feel sexy.
Do you want me to embarrass
you by slapping your face?
Will you quit acting
like you own me!
Get out of here.
Hey, man,
don't walk on that grass.
That's genuine
Kentucky Blue.
Go home!
I wanna stay!
I want to be a deb.
I keep telling you that
I want to be a deb!
Look
look at 'em.
You want to be
like them?
You want to do what
they're doing?
I gotta start
doing it sometime,
why can't I start
doing it now?
Tell the man
we have arrived.
We are the chosen people.
We are the Bishops.
Big Cat's the name,
and jitterbuggin's my game.
Now let's get this
thing together, ace-
time and place.
Okay, Mr. Cool.
Mr. Cool.
I like that.
Israel,
President,
and I say the park.
The turf under dispute-
symbolic to boot.
Monday.
It'll be at eight, baby.
Don't be late.
Not at night man.
You can't see these
cats at night.
My man, the War Lord,
Abdullah,
he say the night
time's no good.
Too many pigs
out at night.
High noon then so that
the schools ain't out.
Yeah, right on, cat,
I like that.
If the pigs come,
then we join forces
and fight 'em together,
you dig it?
Agreed.
What weapons?
My War Lord,
Abdullah.
Make it light
on yourself.
My War Lord,
Nicky.
Zips, blades, straights,
chains, clubs. Anything goes.
That's the way
we like it too.
Wait a minute.
No zips.
The cops don't like shooting.
Even from a homemade job.
You chicken?
You go one-on-one
with me
and you'll find out
who's chicken, fat lip!
Oh, wait
a minute now.
You gonna insult
my War Lord
we gonna get this
thing on right now.
[Brief argument]
Cool it man.
I told you you
could use the place
but leave it standing, dig?
Okay. No zips.
No guns at all.
We just use blades,
chains and baseball bats.
[Laughing]
Blades, chains
and baseball bats...
Can I... can I
say something?
Well, I don't know,
dude, can you?
L... uh... I just want to say
that there's somebody
who cares
about you people.
He cares about you
very much...
In fact, he loves you
just like you are.
Keep talkin'
about me, baby.
He knows about
the drinking, marijuana...
[Laughing]
La cucaracha...
He knows what you're looking
for when you play with sex.
We're looking
to make love, not war.
(Big Cat)
All right, all right,
everybody quiet, now.
Okay, dude,
you go ahead and rap.
Anybody give you steam,
I'll pound 'em into cream.
He wants you to have what
you're looking for.
Groovy.
Where's his turf?
What she mean,
dude,
the big man in the sky
eludes the naked eye.
He is dere,
but where?
You guys talk
about gettin' high.
God'll get ya high.
But he won't
let you down.
What God you talkin'
about - Allah
tell me, preach.
This God of yours,
does he rumble?
Yeah, yeah,
he rumbles.
He's fighting for you
right now.
Whose side
is he fightin' on?
Is he with the Bishops?
Or is he with
the Mau Maus?
He's with
both of you.
That's why I'm here.
God sent me.
Look I'm scared.
I know you guys
could kill me.
That's why I know
God's on your side
because he's making
me do what I'm doing.
Big Cat, Mr. President,
I'd like to shake your hand.
Nicky, Mr. War Lord,
how 'bout it.
I've got one thing
to say to you,
God loves you.
Oh yeah,
now I dig it.
You dragged this dude
in here to pacify us.
You thought maybe you
was goin' change our minds.
The only thing we gonna
change is your lip...
We gonna push
it up into your nose!
[Brief argument]
Alright, alright, it's bats,
blades and chains...
And when all your worstest
plans are made,
you best sign up
for medicaid!
You better forget
about medicaid
and start saving
for your tomb!
[Brief argument]
This God of yours preach,
is he on my side, too?
What's he gonna
do for me?
I'm a mainliner.
You know, the hard stuff,
heroin -
a whole mountain
of snow white.
That's heaven.
You just don't know what
heaven's like, preach.
What da ya got
for me, huh?
I don't have any
magic cure.
Then what did ya
come here for?
Where is your good life
nobody knows . Do, do, do...
Did they dig ya,
Davey baby?
You say that love
will change the world someday,
how come it doesn’t
happen right away?
Where is the magic?
I like to see.
Where is your
good life,
aren't you coming on
strong with me?
Hey,
look at this!
Can you play
with that?
Sure I can
swing with it.
I used to play
in the Y.M.C.A.
Drum and Bugle Corps-
'till they kicked me out.
Why'd they kick
ya out?
They found out
I was a girl.
Bo...
[Singing in the background]
Wait a minute.
Is that a church?
[Singing]
You are David!
We have all been
praying for you!
You have?
This is the preacher
in the newspaper.
This is
David Wilkerson.
I am Hector Gomez.
I am pastor here.
We have been practicing
for the service.
And this is my wife,
Graziella.
This is Isaac, Ruth,
Israel, Samuel.
Oh go on,
shake his hand.
Hello...
So, where are
you staying?
Well... it took
all the bread money
in my congregation
to get me here.
The cat sleeps
in his car.
Oh no, you
mustn't do that.
That's very
dangerous.
You must come and stay
with us, Mr. Wilkerson.
Oh no, I... although it would be
awfully nice on my back
be nice to be near a phone too,
I'm having a baby.
My wife’s
having a baby.
[Laughter]
So while you are living in
the city, this is your home.
Thank you.
Where do you live?
Oh, he's got his car
parked in my parlor.
You don't
have a home.
Yeah,
I got a home.
And I got ten
brothers and sisters.
Better in the streets.
More room and a lot
more quieter.
So you will live
with us, too.
What is it?
What miracle brings
such a fine young man
to our troubled streets?
Miracle?
I was beginning to think
it was pure insanity.
But you people,
you make me feel that maybe
it was... something good.
[Dramatic music]
[Police sirens]
[Whistle blows]
[Dramatic music]
[Gunshot!]
Norma!
Nicky?
Yeah, yeah,
it's us.
It's back here.
How did it go?
Great. For us
it went great!
We burned
'em good.
Did you get hurt?
Nahh-we're
doing great.
We don't
get hurt, baby.
We hurt them.
Hey, anybody
else been here?
Just Mingo.
The Cheer Leader.
Will the others
be coming soon?
If they make it.
You got your watch?
Yeah.
Okay. Listen.
You give 'em one
more hour, see?
No more.
Anybody comes
in that time,
you give 'em their rags and tell
'em where the new hideout is.
Okay, I dig.
When the hour's up, you stash
the rest of the rags and split.
Okay.
[Horn music]
"Onward Christian Soldiers"
what do you think
you're doing?
I'm going
to preach.
You're not preaching here.
We got enough trouble.
Okay, everybody.
The circus is over.
You can all go
home now. Go on.
Officer, don't I have
a constitutional right
to speak on any street
corner in America?
Only under
an American flag.
Okay, you people
move on.
You're blocking
traffic.
Come on now.
Does anybody
have an American flag?
I can't speak
without a flag.
You get outta here, buddy,
or I'll run you in.
[People booing]
Here's a flag.
[People cheering]
That's no flag.
You can't speak
under that.
What do you mean
that ain't a flag?
What is it then?
That's a toy.
Get down from there.
What's going on?
Oh hello Sergeant.
This fellow is trying
to make a speech
and he's pawning off
that toy as a flag.
What's
your pitch?
I just want to tell these people
that somebody loves them.
That'll be a novel
experience for them.
But that's no flag -
that's a toy!
That looks like
a flag to me.
Go ahead.
You talk to them.
Thank you.
[People cheering]
I'm just a country preacher,
300 miles from home.
But I've got
a message for you.
Hey! I've got
a message for you!
[Sputtering tongue]
[Laughter]
Is there anything in your
life you'd like you change?
Yeah! Yeah, I'd like to make
the rich poor and me rich!
We got no love,
we got no bread.
We try to call out
but the line was dead.
Look at that.
Hey, man.
That's their president.
And he's
all alone.
Cool it, man.
Look.
(Big Cat)
What's the matter, preach,
you forget your lines?
[Laughter]
I don't know much
of what's goin' on around here.
But I do know that some
of you are so blind
that you're heading for a ditch
and you don't even know it.
I've seen you walk around
like you own the world.
You don't even know how much
danger you're really in.
Now you can't live too long
around here on luck.
Because somebody could
put a knife in your back
in the next minute.
In fact, for some of you time
may be running out right now.
The Bible says
"how can you escape if
you neglect your soul?"
Now that's one thing
you can't run away from.
Come on.
Let's go.
No, wait
a second.
...I can see the hate sticking
out of your eyes - some of you.
I don't know who
put it there,
but I do know who
can take it out.
Some of you strutting
like a big man,
but it's all
a front.
I can see right
through ya.
Will you
come on?
You wanna go?
Go.
I wanna listen
a minute.
You pretend you don't want
anybody to touch you.
But inside you're
crying out for love.
Now I know there's some pretty
tough guys in this crowd.
You wouldn't be afraid
to shake hands
with a skinny preacher,
would ya?
Will you,
big cat?
What do you
want me to do, man?
Pray with me.
Pray with me right now
that the Holy Spirit
will come into your heart
and make you a new man.
I ain't
ready, man.
Hey, don't let it
bug ya.
You're coming
through.
[Spits]
[Crowd in awe]
God loves
you, Nicky.
You come near me
and I'll kill you.
Yeah,
you can do that.
You could cut me up into
a thousand pieces
and lay 'em in
the street...
And every piece will
still love you.
Sergeant Delano.
Am I glad to meet you.
Burn 'em...
Did we ever burn 'em.
You should have seen 'em
when they hit the trees.
They were tumbling over
the wires and knocking
each other down
like ten-pins.
And then when they
trapped us in the alley
and they were blasting
us with fire-bombs.
I picked up this
garbage can, see.
And I was running up the fire
escape with the bricks...
Hey, Nicky, hey,
I thought you got busted.
I didn't see you get
outta the alley.
Next time look over your
shoulder when you run.
Hey, man,
you're kidding, right?
I fought out there
like a maniac.
I don't see
a scratch on ya.
Oh, you're
kidding, man.
Look at this.
Look, look at that.
You got that falling
over a garbage can.
Are you calling
me a liar?
I'm calling you
a liar and a chicken!
Line up.
Come on, get off your butts.
Let's go. Come on.
Come on.
Let's go.
Get your belts
and leave room to swing.
Nicky, honest.
Now you gonna
run through,
or do I have to come
over there and drag you?
You holdin'
an election?
Mingo
was chicken.
Israel, I swear.
I fought the biggest,
blackest jigs you ever saw-
three of 'em...
With bats and bayonets.
What are you trying
to do behind my back?
Make an ass
out of me?
You done that
pretty good already.
When?
Hangin' around
that phony preacher!
Keep your
voice down.
Did you get down on your
knees and sing hallelujah!
We rapped
for awhile.
About what?
How to bring all your
lost sheep into the fold!
Why do you
let that guy bug you?
Because
I hate him!
He's just a nice guy with a lot
of guts trying to help people.
He wants to break up
the gang!
What the hell do you think
he's in the neighborhood for?
- To be our chaplain!
He wants to bust us!
What's the
matter with me!?
Why does he have
to pick on me?
Because you're
the worst,
craziest bastard
there is.
If he can reach you,
he can reach anybody.
No!
[Dramatic music]
[Ahhhhhh...]
[Screams]
Somebody get
an ambulance!
Who won?
What?
Who gets the park?
I don't know.
[Dreaming]
Mingo... Mingo...
Mingo was chicken... ahhh...
[Knock at the door]
Who's there?
[Knocking continues]
Hi, Nick.
Can I come in?
You gotta
be kidding!
I just had
to come by
and try to make you understand
that God loves you.
You woke me
up to tell me that?
Can we
talk awhile?
Listen,
you crazy witch.
I told you to
stay away from me.
I didn't think
you really meant that.
Tell me
what I meant!
I'll kill you!
I'm not afraid
of you Nicky.
You better be...
You talk tough,
but inside you're just like
all the rest of us;
you're scared.
There are a lot of guys
with scars from Nicky
that know
different.
Aren't you sick
of hating people?
I like
to hurt people.
Aren't you
lonely, Nick?
You...
Damn you!
Love is only a word to me
a word you use
when you're not to sure
of what to say...
Don’t sit down.
I'm meeting someone.
Oh, Norma?
Well I'll just sit here till
she comes, then I'll split.
How’d the rumble go,
huh?
Great.
And how
have you been?
Great.
I been just great.
Do you think you could
let me have some money?
Ten bucks.
Come on, baby.
It’s not for stuff.
It’s for food.
Order a soda.
I'll pay for it.
Don’t tease me,
Nicky.
Then don't try to kid
the kidder, baby.
I can see that
look in your eyes.
You're sweating
out you next fix.
Ten bucks.
Trust me, Nicky.
Just until tomorrow.
I wouldn't trust
you till yesterday.
Remember when you used
to do everything for me?
I got a secret.
I know a deb is supposed
to belong to the whole gang
but I only really ever
belonged to you, Nick.
Now it isn't a secret
anymore, is it, baby?
With all the other guys
it was boring.
But with you, Nicky,
I really dug it.
Write it
in my yearbook
I loved you, Nicky.
And I was good for you.
Now you love the needle
and you're good for nothing.
Please, Nicky.
Please what?
Give me the money.
You're really
desperate, huh?
Like I'm down.
You know what I mean?
You want me
to straighten you, huh?
Oh Nicky, would you?
Would you?
What do you think
of the preacher?
He's okay.
He wants to help people.
No! He wants
to break up the gang.
Why would he
want to do that?
Because
he's a fanatic!
Because he's got
a one-track mind.
He's gotta convert
everybody.
So where does that
leave you, huh?
Without any gangs
to mooch from
you'd have to whore
for your habit.
Think how boring
that'd be.
What do you
want me to do?
I want you to get
rid of the preacher.
How?
However.
Kill 'im, scare 'im,
ball 'im, I don't care.
Nicky, no.
With him out
of the way,
you have nothing
to worry about.
I'll see to it.
Nicky, you're
teasing me.
You can have all
the junk you ever want.
You can even be
my girl again.
Oh my God, Nicky,
what a mess we're in.
You gonna do it?
Yeah, but
straighten me first.
Uh huh.
Do the job first.
Then I'll straighten you.
I can't.
I need to get fixed.
I'm shakin' so I can't
even hold a knife.
Okay, baby,
forget it.
Oh no, gimme the knife, Nicky.
I'll do it.
What do you think
the stuff is worth?
Few bucks.
We should da clobbered the guy
and searched the whole pad.
I bet he had tons
of bread
hidden in them closets
in his shoes.
Or in his
yarmalke.
Hey!
Look at this.
It was in his
jewel box.
The guy's
a catholic!
This worth
anything?
We gotta
take it back.
Take it back?
It's bad luck
to steal a crucifix.
Yeah, 'cause ya can't
get nothin' for it.
You shut
your mouth!
Maybe we could take it
to the hospital
and give it
to Mingo.
Are you crazy?
He doesn't
even see us.
How is he going
to see this thing?
He can feel
what it is.
He don't
feel nothin'.
Yeah,
that's right.
He still in a... coma?
A komona?
Mingo's in a komona?
Hey, Israel,
Mingo's in a komona!
What?
Somebody's
in the clubroom.
I'll go.
It’s Nicky.
What's he doin'?
How should I know?
What am I, his mudder?
What do you call these?
Tostones.
Hmm.
These are delicious.
We don't have anything
like this in Philipsburg.
Maybe we should
open a mission there.
Seriously, David.
You have done wonders already
with the kids in the street.
You've been working with
a bad bunch of apples
and you got 'em
smilin'.
I didn't
see Nicky smilin'.
Nicky!
Do you know what
you're dealing with
when you're dealing
with Nicky?
Yeah, but none
of them are breaking.
I get to the point where I think
I'm really getting through,
they turn me off.
They turn you off
because they're afraid
of being
called chicken.
Being the gang, fighting,
stealing, shooting dope
is their way of proving
that they are a man.
Yeah.
Maybe if I could just get 'em
all together in on big place -
get them to really
commit themselves
right in front of their friends
so they couldn't turn back.
You mean
like a rally?
Yeah, a rally.
A gang rally with all
the beeboppers, jitterbuggers
and everybody.
Now wait
a minute.
You can't tackle a hoard
of the toughest gangs
in New York
with a Bible.
They're liable
to crucify you.
Where could
we get a hall?
I think you just
lost an argument.
What kind
of a hall?
A big one, big enough
for every gang member
and junkie
in New York.
That don't
take a hall.
That takes
the Grand Canyon.
Well, I could
get you a hall.
Will it be
expensive?
Never mind
about that.
If you're crazy
enough to go in
with those fuzzy
faced killers,
I'll find somebody crazy
enough to pay the bill.
What's
the matter?
Nothin'.
I felt like
being by myself.
Bugged about
Mingo, eh?
Yeah I know.
It gets to me, too.
I just want
to know one thing.
How can you take
a guy like that?
A guy like what?
What do you mean,
Mingo?
I mean
the preacher.
Are you still
thinkin' about him?
What'd you rap about
that was so interesting?
When?
The other day,
by the school.
How do I know.
I don't even remember.
God loves me...
Crap like that.
You know...
He came to my place
at 3 o’clock in the morning
just to tell
me that.
I almost had
a heart attack
if he wasn't right on my
doorstep, I'd a killed him.
So you know
what I done?
I sent Rosa over
to kill him.
I gave her the knife
and everything.
No kidding. Hey, you
think she done it?
If she did,
it'd be the first thing
she done right since
she's been on the stuff.
[Door buzzer]
I'll get it.
Vacation time
is the best time.
You know some of these
kids do go to school.
So Thanksgiving vacation
would be the time.
Right.
[Phone rings]
You know, we're gonna have
to get a bus to move these kids.
They're not gonna cross
each others turfs.
Hadn't thought
about that?
(Mrs. Gomez)
David.
For me?
Thank you.
Hello.
Hi Gwen!
It's my wife.
[Door buzzer]
Rosa! Come in,
come in.
Is the
preacher in?
What is the
matter with you?
You know
what's the matter.
You've seen
it before.
I'm sorry.
You got ten bucks?
You know the
answer to that,
you've asked before.
...here with the Gomezes
and Sergeant Delano.
I had a wonderful meal.
Listen honey,
we had a great idea!
We're gonna have
a big rally -
a lot of the gangs
are going to be there...
Hector...
Oh Rosa poor baby.
Where's
the preacher?
(Hector)
Why do you
want to see David?
What is this-
a police station?!
I want to give
him something!
...yeah but honey,
it has to be vacation time,
it's the only time we
can get the gangs out.
(David)
...What?
I want
to see you.
Please, I gotta
see you now.
Yeah, okay...
Gwen, I know it's time
for the baby,
but aren’t babies
usually late?
Please?
Sit down.
Would you like
something to eat?
No!
Uh, Gwen, honey, can I call you
back in just a few minutes?
I’ve got
an emergency here.
Oh honey, it'll be soon,
I promise. Bye.
I... I love...
I want to see you,
preach.
I gotta talk to you-
alone.
Use the chapel.
Okay.
(Sergeant Delano)
Who was that?
It was a girl
in the neighborhood.
She's on heroin.
Glad to see you again,
Rosa.
Glad?
Oh sure, why?
Sit down.
Why are you glad
to see me, huh? Why?
Because I've thought
a lot about you
since the last
time we met.
You know I love Nicky,
don't you?
No, I didn't
know that.
He's like
it for me.
Now he don't give two
pops what happens to me.
You know why?
I think I do,
but you tell me.
He says you're trying
to break up the gang.
Break up
the gangs?
I'm trying to grab
them with something
that will
wake 'em up!
You don't care who
you hurt, do ya?
Take it easy,
Rosa.
Liar!
Lend me ten bucks.
Don't touch me!
I don't have
ten bucks to lend you.
I need a fix!
Oh, can’t you
understand that?
A fix!
I need it
twice a day.
And I haven't had any
since last night.
So give me some bread,
man, I gotta score.
Rosa, I'm
no easy touch.
I'm a man of God.
I'm not going to help
you kill yourself.
You're a filthy fink,
that's what you are!
You want to scare people
into believing in God.
Oh, what am I going
to do without Nicky?
But you didn't think
about that did you?
Rosa, if you
really want Nicky,
you better get
yourself clean.
I want ten bucks!
And you're going
to give it to me.
Or I'll cut
it out of you!
Rosa, you
don't need that.
Rosa...
Help!
Don't come near me!
He's trying to...
Step back...
I'm gonna to cut
my throat.
I'm gonna stick
myself like a pig
and you're all
gonna watch!
Don't throw your
life away, Rosa.
You're too young.
God needs you.
He sent you here
for help.
God wants David
to help you.
But there’s
no way out for me.
I'm hooked.
There's no way out.
I'm in hell!
We are here,
just for you.
Why don't you give us
a chance with you?
If there's just a chance,
just the smallest chance
that we might succeed,
isn't that worth
a try?
Be still, Rosa.
Just let your
body relax.
Let your arms
hang loose, easy;
just let your mind...
That's it, Rosa...
We'll take care of you.
Cover my ground
with fleecy white snow
cover my floor with dust
cover my walls
with spidery webs
[Rosa cries out]
Cover my mind
with drugs
I won’t be
needing sympathy
I'll never know
you cried for me
I'll love another
chance and then
why do the same
damn thing again?
I'm feeling cold
hey, look at that!
I wish he were in
that box instead of Mingo.
Yeah,
poor Mingo.
Boy, that mother's
really got guts!
[Dramatic music]
[Whistle blows]
It's the pigs...
[Dramatic music]
Hey, Nicky.
What's the matter,
you get hurt?
Hey, Nicky.
It's me, Little Bo.
I sometimes run
for your gang.
Do you want me to get
help or somethin'?
(David)
Need some
help, friend?
I'll be
all right.
We gotta get
you to a doctor.
Get away from me.
Bo said you
wanted to see me.
You outta
your mind?
Nicky, I gotta say
two things to you.
Yeah, Jesus loves me
and you love me.
I heard it before.
This is important.
Hey, man,
no kidding, look.
I got a leak in my chest
and my head is busted.
Go away, huh?
Can't you give
a poor spik a break?
Can't you see
I'm dying?
How can I just
walk away and leave you?
With you feet.
Just leave, man.
Tip! Blow!
Someday you're gonna
stop running, Nicky.
When you do, I'll
be there waiting.
Should I help him?
He won't
listen to me.
Yeah, go ahead.
Tag along, Bo.
I can do
it alone, Bo.
I don't
mind helping.
Go away, please!
Go on,
get out of here.
Go on, beat it!
Nick, I'm clean.
I went through
it an I'm clean.
You deaf
or somethin'?
I said beat it!
What's the
matter, Nick.
You said if I stopped
using the stuff that...
Stopped?
What do you mean, stopped?
Nobody stops.
I know.
But I did.
Oh Nicky, look at me.
I kicked.
It was the preacher
and the Gomez family...
Get out of here.
Is it because
of the preacher?
Get outta here!
All right.
I'll go.
But just
tell me.
Is it because
of the preacher?
The preacher,
the preacher,
all I ever hear
on this turf,
all I ever see
is the preacher!
But he and his friends
brought me through.
So what!
What do you want,
a shrine named after you?
You gonna go on
television and tell 'em
how you got saved?
I thought you'd
be happy, Nicky.
You thought wrong!
When you went
on the hard stuff,
you died as far
as I was concerned.
Now you got religion
and you're deader than ever!
I liked you
better as a junkie.
I seen junkies before.
You're the first religious
freak to come out a this turf.
Cover my ground
with fleecy white snow
cover my floor with dust
cover my walls
with spidery webs
cover my mind
with drugs
I won’t be
needing sympathy
I'll never know
you cried for me
just turn your head
and look away
there's nothing else
for you to say
I'll love another
chance and then
I do the same
damn thing again?
I've turned around
Hugo? Hey, about
a taste, huh?
Beat it.
It's scarce.
Oh just a drop!
Bitch!
You made me
spill it!
[Doorbell rings]
Hey, Rosa,
where have you been?
I tried to kick
you poor doll.
By yourself?
No, with
the preacher.
Oh... boy,
he messed you up good.
You look terrible.
Oh, it wasn't
so bad.
That guy's
a phony.
I can spot 'em.
He's been messing with
a lot of my clients.
Well, anyway,
I'm back
don't feel bad.
Nobody can kick it.
Even the big
doctors say so.
It's in the papers
every day.
I don't
have any money.
No problem.
First one's always
on the house.
Gee, it's good
to have you back.
I don't
have any fixins.
No problem.
The first one
comes with fixins.
Whenever a steady
customer doesn't show up
for a few days,
it worries me.
You know, like maybe I hurt
their feelings or something.
I can't
make it work!
Relax.
Just call for
room service.
We bone it...
(Singing)...
Saute it...
(Humming and whistling)...
Wash the silverware...
(Humming)...
Fill the sugar tip...
(Humming and whistling)
And serve it
with a smile.
[Whistling]
That's it baby.
Let it out.
Let all the bad
run out.
Nothing in there now
but the cool, cool snow.
Now let your
head drift off,
drift off into that
purple-violet-squish.
You cut it!
Ssh, ssh.
Don't fight it.
You're selling
garbage!
I didn't sell
you nothing, baby!
I gave it,
and it's the best.
Put it on
your tongue.
Taste it.
You taste quinine?
Do you taste sugar?
No sir, baby,
you taste pure junk.
I don't
feel the same.
It’s like a bad drink
or a tranquilizer.
I've seen 'em trying
to get a free taster before
but baby,
you're the best.
The second one's
no freebee, baby,
it's ten bucks and so
is the third, the fourth
and the four thousandth!
Get yourself out
in the street, baby
and you better learn to turn
a sweet trick or two
because you gonna have to bring
your tail in here more often
and it better be waggin'
up ten dollar bills
'cause you're already
behind by one!
And stay away from
that preacher!
Somebody's messin'
with your head!
I know what
you're thinking.
Nothing but
good niks out there.
(David)
All I see
is empty seats.
Yeah.
Maybe I'm the reason
they're not coming.
The gangs know
there's a cop around.
They may think it's
a trap or something.
You think so?
It's a
thought anyway.
I won't show up
tomorrow.
They'll see there's no
squad cars parked outside.
We just won't hang
around at all.
That is if you think
you can handle them.
I don't see much fight
in those empty seats.
[Dramatic music]
You dudes trampled
my man's grave.
Yeah, baby.
So what's the beef?
Hey.
I'll talk
yeah, a few of the people
got out of hand.
You saying
you're sorry?
I don't
apologize!
And I don't
talk to seconds.
I'm talkin',
Nick.
My people
want blood.
Well then,
blood there'll be, baby.
When?
Whenever.
Tonight.
Where?
The park.
Stick the park.
We had the park!
Clam up!
I'm talkin'.
Well, what
did it prove?
We trample some grass
and jitterbug around a bonfire
and whose
turf is it?
I say we have it out
once and for all.
Winners get the turf.
Right, baby.
But whose winners?
What do we do, count cuts,
bruises and broken bones?
Last man standin',
that's winners.
How you gonna
do that?
Soon as we get it on,
everybody runs
all over the city.
We get it on
where they can't run.
What the hell
are you talkin' about?
The youth rally.
Man, there's
fuzz all over the place.
Not tonight.
Words around that
the fuzz is laying off
to give the come-on
to us gangs.
So?
So we come
on with all we got.
The cool gangs
seal off the doors.
Nobody gets in or out.
Then we have it on.
Last man standing,
his gang's got the turf.
First time I ever hear
a white cat say something good.
Man, didn't I say
you were to lay back?
I'm on.
We got the time and place...
The hardware.
Bats.
Blades.
Chains.
Spikes.
Zips.
Yeah, baby, but none
of that store bought stuff.
Hey, preach!
Look at this!
I brought my whole
Bible class with me!
Hey, Dave.
I think you're
making it.
Oh, oh, this
is the first time
I don't want no soul brothers
comin' to my party.
[Bickering back and forth]
I don't like the look
of the whole thing.
We'll let
Mary sing.
Maybe that'll
cool 'em down.
Someday a bright new wave
will break upon the shore
and there will be
no sickness,
no more crying
no more war
little children never
will go hungry anymore
and there'll be a bright
new morning over there
there'll be a bright
new world for us to share
someday there'll be
an end to unkind words
and the man who says there is
no God will know he is a fool
[crowd rowdy and cheering]
And peace will be the way
of life and the only rule
and there'll be a bright
new morning over there,
there'll be a bright new road
for us to share
someday, we know not when
life will be strong
and everyone from every
land will all become as one...
[Crying]
[Crowd booing and chanting]
I... I’m going to try
something different tonight.
...anything will be
an improvement...
I'm going to take up
an offering.
[Crowd boos]
And I'm going to ask some
of you gang members to do it.
Can I have
four volunteers.
[Crowd cheers]
Nick, Augie...
Abdullah, Pete.
[Crowd laughs]
All right now, when you
finished collecting,
take the money through
that back stage door
and bring it to me.
Okay.
Music
hey, dig it,
man.
Do we split it now or do we
put it together in a bundle
and the winner takes all
in the rumble.
Know what?
That dude is so
cock-sure of himself,
he knows that everybody
in this place
expects us to cop
this bread.
I bet he's going to pop some
stupid sermon about honesty.
I say we cross him up,
and take all the bread
and we give it to
that stupid preacher.
That's cool,
man.
Here's your money,
preacher.
Yeah,
every cent of it.
Thanks, Abdullah.
Thanks, Nicky.
[Crowd rumbles
about giving money]
You know, we all like to put
tags on people, don't we?
Try to make 'em
like everybody else.
I'll bet you thought that askin'
those guys to collect the money
was like askin' a junkie
to guard a drug store.
[Laughter]
Right?
But they fooled you,
didn't they?
They wouldn't
wear your tags.
They shook free.
(Shout from the audience)
They did it because
they were suckers!
[Laughter]
There's nobody in this
world that can tag you
'cause nobody knows how
you really feel inside.
No friend, no gang
member, no deb
or ditty bopper or preacher
or priest or rabbi,
or social worker
or psychiatrist, nobody!
'Cause your mind,
your feelings, your spirit
are so fantastic it would
take a mind bigger
than the whole world
to understand you.
That's why I don't
preach religion.
I preach about a man.
The only one who knows
why you do the things you do.
what's bugging you,
what's eating you.
And the only one who has the
power to do anything about it.
Now I want every ditty bop off
and I want you to listen to me.
Go on, take 'em off.
Don't be looking around
at somebody else
to see what everybody
else is doing.
Have the guts to be different.
To listen for once.
Now I'm makin' this
God's house right now.
And this is a pulpit.
And I'm gonna talk and if you've
go the guts - you'll listen.
I'm gonna talk
about a man.
And I'm gonna
talk about love.
That's right, love!
The word that bugs you.
It's a sissy word
to most of you.
You're going to see tonight
that love is the gutsiest word
in the English
language.
I've got to try and make you
understand the meaning of love.
Love isn't just
something you feel.
Love is something
you do.
It's got nothing to do with weak
knees or a fluttering heart.
Love is the gutsiest act
that you'll ever do.
Because love is turning
away from hate.
That takes guts!
Now this book says
"God is love".
God looked at the sins
in our heart.
All our hearts-
yours, mine, everybody's.
And he hated those sins.
But God turned away
from his own hate
and sent his only son into
the world to love us.
Jesus was a package
of pure love.
Sweet, straight love.
For you and for me.
I don't care
who you've cut.
I don't care what you've
been smoking' or shooting,
I don't care who you
been layin' around with,
God loves
you anyway.
I know each one
of you here
knows about
the Ten Commandments.
Most of you have broken
every one of 'em.
God knows about that too.
He knows about your angers,
you fears, your frustrations.
He knows that most
of you have fought.
Some of you have
even killed.
But God also knows what you
can be like in the future.
Not just what you've
been in the past.
Jesus said there is just
one great commandment.
That you love God with
all you heart, your soul,
your mind and your
neighbor as yourself.
He said, "a new commandment
I give unto you
that you love
one another.'
I'm gonna ask God right now
for a miracle.
Father, I'm askin'
you now for a miracle,
that in this next moment
these live will be changed.
I'm asking you Mau Maus
to turn away from hating
your black
brothers.
I'm asking you Bishops
to forgive the white man's sin-
just as God
forgives yours.
Look at this,
preacher!
See this hole
I got in me.
It came from one of them
nigger zip guns,
and you say that I'm
supposed to love them.
Man, you're not real!
Hey, man.
My brother died from
a Mau Mau rumble.
And you say you want me
to love them honkies?
Yeah, man,
I'm gonna love 'em.
I'm gonna love 'em
with a sharp blade.
Now you shut up
and listen to me.
You say you gotta kill them
because of what they did to you.
And you've got to kill
them because of what
they've done to you.
Everybody's gripping about
this atrocity and that tragedy.
All I hear is what
a rotten deal we've all got.
Let me tell you something.
Jesus Christ was perfect!
And they
crucified him!
He never said one
complaining word.
And when he died on that cross,
he was a man!
Like you, he had
the same fears
and the same feelings
that you have.
He felt pain just
the way you feel pain.
He had those nails driven
into the flesh of the hands.
His hands, his hands, the most
sensitive part of his body.
And his feet, they drove
a spike into his feet.
And they nailed his hands
and feet to the cross.
And he didn't have to let
them do that to him.
He could have called down
a whole legion of angels
to take him down
from that cross.
He could have slaughtered
all his tormentors.
But he didn't.
He hung there.
Bleeding. For you.
And he died there.
For you.
So you wouldn't have
to die here today.
to kill here today.
Why don't you stop crying
about the sins of the past.
Stop paying
for those sins.
Man, it's all paid up.
It's free!
All you have to do
it just accept it.
Just open up your hearts and
let all that bitterness run out.
And let Jesus Christ
come in!
(Echo the voice of preach)
Just open up your hearts
and let all that bitterness
run out and let
Jesus Christ come in...
Come in... come in...
Listen!
All you white cats!
And all you black cats!
Listen to me.
Now you been hearing
about the power of love.
Well, I'm going to tell
you about another power.
It's gang power.
And that's
where it's at.
Now the Bishops and the Mau Maus
are having it out here tonight.
And you're going
to be in on it.
You can't get away.
All the exits
are shut off.
And you might
as well face it, man,
we are going to have it out
right here and now!
[Shouting with music]
Cool it.
I said cool it now!
Hasn't there been enough
killing and cutting?!
Weren’t you listenin'
to the preacher?
Well, I heard
the preacher...
I don't know
how to say it.
He's here.
You feel him.
You all feel him.
He's here in this room
and he wants to touch you.
If you ever want your lives
changed, now is the time.
Put your weapons away.
There's not going to be
a rumble here tonight.
You're in the presence
of the almighty God.
Come on up
here together.
Stand.
Come on.
Not as saints.
Don't wait till
you're good enough
because that day's
never gonna come.
Come on.
Come on with all your hangups
and let Jesus clean you up.
And would you come.
Let your coming say it.
God I need you.
God forgive me.
God I give myself to you.
Hey, man.
I know you got love.
I can feel it in ya.
'Cause I ain't scared
of you no more.
Nicky!!
Man, I got your life
right in my hands.
I can take it away,
or I can give it back to you...
I'm gonna give it
back to you.
Wow, man...
I really don't dig this
scene tonight at all.
God loves you,
he loves you
just as you are
now standing there
in your cold, dark
and bitter, little world,
he loves you, he loves you
his hand is reaching out...
I'm gonna give
my life to God, Davey.
It better work 'cause
I damn near got killed for it.
...and his love is stronger
than anything...
This is the miracle,
Nicky.
The miracle I've
been praying for.
God loves Nicky, too
this is the miracle
I'm talkin' about.
That you're gonna find
yourselves tonight.
You're gonna know in your
hearts it was a miracle
so you'll never trust
in you own flesh again.
But in the flesh sacrificed
for you by Jesus!
I want you all
to have Bibles.
Gomezes, help
me please.
Hey, hey,
hey preach.
How about givin' us one
of those big books
so people can really see
what we’re carrying.
Hey, preach,
me too.
Me too, preach.
You look kinda
different, Nick
how?
Bright.
All kinds of shiney.
Maybe it's because I'm about
two minutes old right now.
I'm different too.
I know.
You kicked the junk.
Oh, Nicky,
I'm free now.
I'm really free.
Hey!
I'm all over
this book!
My name
is in the Bible!
Israel... Israel...
I'm practically
on every page.
[Laughter]
[Preacher speaking]
So this was the beginning.
The breakthrough that was
to make the ghetto my church.
Little did I know it was going
to lead to our own center,
a home where lonely,
mixed up kids
could be given
a new beginning.
Or that from the tortured
streets of Harlem and Brooklyn,
the Teen Challenge
concept would spread
across the land
to other cities,
to other Nickys
and Israels and Rosas.
Surrounding them with love
instead of hate and fear.
One thing
I already knew,
in the battle for souls
that surges through
the tenement lined alleys
and the back street,
you can take it from
this skinny preacher
from the hills
of Pennsylvania,
the cross is mightier
than the switchblade.
}}