[ Bird screeching. Loud ]
Shush.
Polly.
Sahib Wales.
You should not have come.
In this room.
My dear man.
Ramdaz.
Here is ten rupees.
It is yours.
If you leave me alone in
this room for ten minutes.
No.
Maybe the commissioner ..
Will blame me. Ramdaz.
I am more interested in finding
out who murdered your master ..
Than the police.
The commissioner say to me: 'Ramdaz'.
'Everything stay same here'.
'Until the chief inspector, he come'.
Stand over there.
Stand there.
Sit down.
A stupid mess.
Stupid.
Ramdaz.
I say, can't you understand ..
Now listen.
I'll give you 20 rupees, 30 rupees.
Will you do what I ask?
Will you please do what I ask of you?
Ramdaz, I could strangle you.
I say.
I say, Commissioner Grimshaw.
Are you there?
Mr Wales, I am thoroughly exasperated.
You have not only disobeyed police
orders but you're becoming a pest.
I see.
See here.
Hang it all.
Listen.
I am positive that I can identify
the woman who killed Spencer Lee.
Explain yourself.
No. It would be most unwise
to mention her name.
You see. She is very highly connected.
In official circles.
Careful, Mr Wales.
You're treading on dangerous ground.
It is best that you wait there.
We'll be right along.
Delzante. This man Wales is insane.
Now he intimates it was a woman.
Highly connected in official circles.
Highly connected in official circles?
These records show.
That this woman was heavily veiled.
Tommy-rot. All Tommy-rot.
Most of Spencer Lee's women
callers were heavily veiled.
Most of them, married women.
Yet, immediately after her departure ..
The crime was discovered.
Yes. Edward Wales arrived at the house
just as the woman was leaving.
He found Lee on the floor with
a knife wound in his back.
He died in Wales' arms.
Without speaking.
Let us be moving along.
I would like to speak with this ..
Mr Wales.
- Just a moment please.
Get me Sir Roscoe Crosby
at the residency.
You found no fingerprints of this woman?
- No.
Although tea had been served
her cup had not been touched.
Sir Roscoe?
This is Commissioner Grimshaw.
I wish to advise you, sir.
That Inspector Delzante of the
Criminal Investigation department.
Arrived in Calcutta this afternoon
and sends his respect, sir.
Thank him, Grimshaw.
And assure him that my office is at his
service for any assistance he requires.
Here. You have missed one.
- So I have.
A very good one too.
- Rather.
That was Grimshaw.
Inspector Delzante of the Criminal
Investigation Department has arrived.
Sir Roscoe.
I know I am wrong, and I just
cannot explain my feelings.
But at times I find myself hoping.
I hope they never find the culprit.
Come, my dear.
I admit he was a bit of a rotter.
But you mustn't feel that way.
Father, now please
don't start preaching.
Mother wasn't thinking
of Spencer's morals.
Were you, darling?
- No.
I was thinking of the woman.
And Roscoe.
I have a feeling that it
was that veiled woman.
And I dread learning who she is.
Nellie O'Neill.
I say.
Do you think something could be wrong?
Nellie.
Nellie, wait a minute. Please.
Nellie O'Neill.
You know, you are stubborn.
You are just plain stubborn.
Richard.
When a woman loves a man
as much as I love you ..
It is hard to say 'no'.
Nellie, I don't want you to.
There's nothing that would make me
happier than to marry you, but ..
I can't.
What is it then, dear?
Everything.
Do you realize you don't even
know who I am or what I am?
Nonsense, darling. I don't care.
Don't you see, dear?
There is a great difference between us.
So that's the bee in your bonnet.
You think because you're my mother's
secretary that you shouldn't marry me.
Nellie, look at me.
Nellie.
That can't make any
difference to us, dear.
It never will make a difference.
You don't seem to understand.
- Darling, don't be silly.
You come along with me and
we'll settle that once and for all.
Do as I say. Come along.
Nellie is a brick, and I shall
jolly well cherish her as a sister.
I suppose we shall have to be
reconciled to Richard's choice.
After all, it's really his wedding.
Well, rather.
Roscoe, you're an old dear.
Top hole, Richard.
The family sanctions
your choice of a wife.
Thanks, Helen. Awfully nice of you but I
feel you put the cart before the horse.
What do you mean, Richard?
Mother.
- What is it?
Nellie is all fussed-up
because we've got money.
She thinks that I am ..
You know, what they call in
books, 'marrying beneath me'.
Suppose you listen to an old woman.
- Old?
Well, old enough.
Now then. Listen.
When I married Richard's father.
I was a schoolteacher.
And he was a youngest son.
A captain in the army.
We had no money.
But we were awfully in love.
Just for the sake of argument.
Suppose I had taken your attitude.
Why, Nellie.
We should have missed
many years of happiness.
And we still rather like each other.
Now if you want my real opinion.
I think Richard's
pretty lucky to get you.
Yes, my dear. Take us as you find us.
And we'll all try to be happy.
Now the thug.
Has his victim at his mercy.
Release me. You're strangling me.
All that beastly thing lacks
is a mouth with fangs.
I say, doctor.
The professor seems
a bit of a thug himself.
Yes. He gave a bit of a
realistic demonstration.
And so.
That's the method the thugs use
to remove their enemies, eh?
Yes.
Which proves to me conclusively.
That they had no hand.
In the killing of Mr Lee.
You don't think that Lee's articles
attacking the Thugee cult ..
Prompted his death?
A thug.
Never spills blood.
You forget the veiled charmer, doctor.
She is my choice.
No. I haven't forgotten the woman.
Now that Delzante is
here for the investigation.
I feel pretty sure that her
identity will soon be disclosed.
Look here.
To aid the crown in its
search for the guilty one.
I propose a whiskey and soda.
And a rubber of bridge.
A charming idea. And Nellie.
See if you can find Richard.
He is probably with
Sir Roscoe and Mr Wales.
I told her it would be
a jolly good idea.
Surely, Howard. You are spoofing.
I grant you it's a bit grotesque.
But nevertheless.
Edward Wales has prevailed
upon Lady Crosby.
To allow that spirit medium or ..
Fortune teller or whatever you call it.
To give a seance here tonight.
- That would be perfectly thrilling.
A marvelous idea.
- I see.
So tonight we are to dabble
in witchcraft and occultism?
If she is a true medium
your eyes will be opened.
I attended a seance in
Berlin at Madam Bogarts.
And through her spirit control.
I conversed.
With my dead mother.
By Jove.
I have an idea.
We should call on the
spirit of Spencer Lee.
And I shall say to him.
'Spencer, dear old chap'.
'Tell us. Who killed you'?
Howard.
That's just sacrilege.
It is not.
- Don't be silly.
I am serious.
But I don't understand what
you are talking about.
Mr Wales, I demand an apology
for what you just said.
Richard, calm yourself.
Mr Wales, I am waiting.
- Richard.
In your eyes my action is almost ..
Indefensible.
I am admitting that.
But I have very good reasons for asking.
What I am asking.
Sir Roscoe.
I've been your close
friend for many years.
You've trusted me and believed in me.
I ask you not to announce Richard's
engagement to Miss O'Neill tonight.
After all.
24 hours can't make any
difference, Richard.
And it may save you all a
great deal of unhappiness.
Mr Wales.
I don't know what you will discover.
But it's nothing of which I am ashamed.
- Dear, you mustn't mind what he says.
But I do.
I know it's about my mother.
The most wonderful woman in the world.
I won't have her attacked.
Miss O'Neill.
I don't know your mother.
I've never even heard of her.
- Then you should explain ..
Richard, I would rather be
shot than do what I am doing.
But if I'm wrong I will come
to you gladly and say so.
I'll apologise to Miss O'Neill
on my knees if she likes.
Ned, I don't know
what this is all about.
But knowing you as I do
I shall take your suggestion.
But father ..
- Richard, please.
But I warn you.
Tomorrow I shall expect you to explain
everything to my entire satisfaction.
You have my word, Sir Roscoe.
- Very well.
I think we'll let the matter
rest for this evening and ..
Join Lady Crosby.
Dad, could I speak to you just a minute?
Will you join the ladies, Ned.
Dad, you can't ..
- Richard. Richard.
Ned has evidently gone off on
the wrong foot somewhere.
But don't worry.
Things will right themselves.
Have we time for another rubber?
- I don't think I would.
They're here in a minute.
I'm afraid this seance is
going to be a frightful bore.
Don't say that.
You needn't come.
Edward.
Madam La Grange, the fortune-teller
you sent the car for has arrived.
May we see her now?
- Certainly.
Chotee, ask Madam La Grange
to please come here.
I say. Do you really suppose she
expects to be taken seriously?
But then, if we don't laugh at
her we'll have no end of fun.
I will rag her terribly. And she'll
never know it in all the world.
Mary.
I shouldn't do that.
Edward says she's quite clever.
The great Madam La Grange.
I'll bet you I can describe her.
A tall dark-haired creature.
A regular adventuress. Am I right?
She is the most remarkable
woman I have ever known.
Madam Rosalie La Grange.
Good evening to all of you.
How do you do, Madam La Grange.
Very well, thank you, ma'am.
- I'm glad.
How are you, Mr Wales?
To be sure, it was a grand
hack you sent for me.
We wanted you to be comfortable.
I was that.
Do you know?
When the Hindu gentleman came for me.
I thought at first it
was the Rajah himself.
I hope you were not frightened.
Definitely not.
I'd like to see the Hindu
that can frighten me.
Nice boys them Hindus.
And most of them good Christians.
When they are asleep.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you, ma'am.
Are you quite comfortable?
- I am.
So, you tell fortunes?
No, Miss. I do not.
I get messages from them
that has passed on.
I don't hold with the cards or
tea leaves or any of them tricks.
Miss.
Once in a while.
I give advice.
If I were you.
I'd pay that bill of a thousand
rupees that you owe in the bazaar.
We are expecting great things from
you tonight, Madam La Grange.
How did you know I owed
a bill at the bazaar?
Well, you left the bill in
your bag in the hall.
While I was waiting I read it.
How did you know it was my bag?
Sure.
The stuff on the bag.
Matched that stuff on your dress.
Then it's all trickery?
It is now. And then it ain't.
That is the sort of demonstration
we're going to get from you tonight?
Didn't Mr Wales tell you?
- I've told them nothing.
Well then, tell them now please.
You see.
As I told you some time ago.
Madam La Grange has done things that ..
That cannot be explained.
When I asked her to come here tonight.
She said she would
under certain conditions.
You mean test conditions?
- Not exactly.
What she said was, that no
money should pass between us.
And that anything she
would do tonight ..
Would be honest.
You would not play us any tricks?
If I do, I will tell you.
Yes, of course. We understand
all about spirit rapping.
Rather. That's old stuff.
Well, what do you think of that?
You have to be near a table
or something like that.
And then.
Maybe a chair.
Or a desk would do.
- Yes?
And then in the dark.
Of course. In the dark.
You get one rap for 'Yes'.
And two for 'No'?
Are there spirits near?
Please don't laugh.
Is it Laughing-Eyes?
Are you happy?
Is there someone here you don't like?
[ One rap. ]
A gentleman?
[ Two raps. ]
Dear, dear. A lady?
[ One rap. ]
Is it that one?
Laughing-Eyes don't like you.
Marvellous.
The most wonderful thing I ever heard.
But I don't think ..
- It can't be a trick.
She stood right there and I
watched her hands every minute.
Well, you watched the wrong end of me.
I've got a wooden sole in my shoe.
I do it with my big toe. Inside.
Like this.
[ Two raps. ]
Sure. That time.
So then, if we get any
messages it will be ..
If we get any messages.
Well, sir. I am telling
you the truth now.
Most of the time it is tricks.
But tonight.
There will be no faking.
I know I am a stranger to
all of you except Mr Wales.
I don't know whose house I'm in.
That's quite true.
You gave her no hint of any kind?
No.
On my honour.
- Madam La Grange.
Sir.
I know a man who saw
this woman Paladino ..
Lift a table just by
putting her hands on it.
Would someone give me the
little card table over there.
I suppose this is going to
be another fake trick.
It can be done.
I don't know if I can
do it in the light.
But if you want.
I will try.
- Please do.
Please, without trickery.
I mean.
Like this.
Miraculous.
The most remarkable
thing I've ever seen.
Now. Now you all know what I can do.
I can fool you too.
So you have to take my
word for it that I won't.
Now I will go into a
trance for you, if you like.
The spirit controls
a sweet little child.
Named 'Laughing-Eyes'.
Wait.
Don't speak.
Don't.
Don't say anything.
There's a message coming.
There is a message.
No.
No. Laughing-Eyes is gone.
It is the unbelievers.
Most of you don't believe.
It's hard to get messages that way.
I think.
I think I might as well
go about my business.
I thought she would when she found
out she was at Sir Roscoe's house.
Did you now?
Won't you please stay?
- I'm afraid I can't, ma'am.
You see, I'm not just myself.
I'm not feeling just right.
Madam La Grange,
under the circumstances ..
I am sorry, sir.
But I got to go home.
- I think it's a shame.
I think she is quite right to go.
Her sort of tricks aren't for
people of intelligence.
Well.
Won't you please stay?
I must not, Miss.
- But won't you?
As a very great favour to me?
Please.
Well, Miss.
Since you ask it.
I'll stay.
Madam La Grange.
I assure you I am very interested
in the outcome of this seance.
I warn you I shall watch your
manifestations very closely.
Do so, sir. I want you to.
I am going to ask you to
submit to certain conditions.
Anything at all, sir. Anything at all.
To forestall any
assistance from outside.
I want to suggest.
That all the doors and windows
of this room be securely locked.
Yes.
And I suggest that we
search Madam La Grange.
That is of course, if she is willing.
Why not?
There's no holes in my stockings.
I suppose it will be very difficult
for you to get results ..
If we're all so antagonistic.
It's up to them.
If there's any that wants to
communicate with anyone.
Maybe they can reach us.
I don't know.
Sure, I don't understand you at all.
I show you my tricks.
Would I do that if I wanted to fool you?
I would not.
Then why not give me
credit for being honest?
I don't think any of
us doubt your honesty.
They are just sceptical.
Thank you, ma'am.
I don't think we need submit
Madam La Grange to being searched.
I'm sure I don't mind, ma'am.
That is, if none of you fine
ladies will be shocked.
Seeing plain, hand-sewn underwear.
Then will you come with me?
I am sure we won't be shocked.
I wear that kind myself.
- Do you now, ma'am?
We shan't be long.
Ma'am.
Would you mind if all the ladies came?
Then they'll all be sure I'm
not concealing anything.
I really believe that woman
has a power of some sort.
Look here, Wales.
What are we supposed to do?
Ask her a lot of silly questions?
I am going to find out
who killed Spencer Lee.
You are going to do what, Edward?
I am going to try to communicate.
With the spirit of Spencer Lee.
So that's your reason for bringing
this woman here tonight?
Precisely.
Have you any objections, Sir Roscoe?
No.
Look here, Wales.
Spencer Lee was an out-and-out rotter.
Brandon.
- It's the truth.
His killing was good
riddance to bad rubbish.
Wait. Spencer Lee was my friend.
Gentlemen, I beg of you.
You see, Mary.
It was quite a waste of time.
Quite absurd.
I am perfectly satisfied anyway.
You should be.
I am glad of that, Miss.
Did you expect to find trap doors
and fake spirits up my sleeves?
One can never tell.
No.
And suppose that mine is the
only trade there is any tricks in.
May I?
Thank you, Miss.
Ma'am. Would you tell the gentlemen ..
To put the chairs in a circle.
Then I'll be right along.
I hope you forgive us
for being so sceptical.
I hope she has some good
news to tell us anyway.
At least we found out that she
had nothing concealed on her.
Darling.
- Mother.
I did not know.
I wouldn't have come here
for anything in the world.
I wouldn't.
They just brought me here.
I didn't know where I was coming.
Don't tell them.
Don't make me shame you
before your fine friends.
I'll get away as quick as I can.
- Mother.
Don't say that.
There is no shame, darling.
I am proud. Proud.
Don't ever say that again.
Alright, darling.
Tell them if you must.
But let me get away first.
No.
Now I must go or they'll think
there is something wrong.
Come along.
I do wish you would let me tell them.
- No.
Yes, gentlemen. In a circle, I think.
Sorry, Sir Roscoe, if you
feel that way about it.
Not a matter of feeling.
I'm just a little sceptical perhaps.
On the table I think.
You sit there, Howard?
- Yes. I sit here.
One, two, three, four.
Yes. I might want lights.
Richard.
If I call for lights, give them to me.
Don't wait for anything.
Right, dad. I'll sit right there.
I assure you she has
nothing up her sleeve.
Well, well.
I am glad you are satisfied.
Yes.
Yes. That's right.
That's the way we want it.
Now if you all sit in a circle.
- Madam La Grange.
Will you sit here?
I will. Thank you.
I will so.
Now if you all sit down.
How shall we sit? I mean, do you
want us in any particular order?
Anywhere at all, sir.
I sit next to you, sir Roscoe?
I've always wanted to
hold your hand, my dear.
Don't trust him, Grace.
- I won't.
I'll chaperone them.
Will you sit by me, Miss O'Neill?
You know, I am really
getting quite a thrill.
What's the joke, Madam La Grange?
Well, Miss. I didn't know
anything would give you a thrill.
You don't like me, do you?
I am crazy about you.
Chotee, I want you to put
those keys in your pocket.
Now, I want you to lock
this door on the outside.
Now, Stand outside the door and
don't unlock it until I tell you.
Understand?
- Yes, Sahib.
Are you there, Chotee?
Now I think we're ready.
Edward, wait.
There's thirteen of us. Don't sit down.
I don't buy those superstitions.
- But ..
What will we do now?
If you'll all join hands.
- That will be jolly.
And then keep quiet.
Don't try to think of anything.
By Jove. That will be easy for me.
Now, now. We can't get results if
you're going to treat this as a joke.
Yes. I think we should do
as Madam La Grange asks.
I suppose you'd like the lights out?
You'd get better results that way.
Richard, will you put out
that light when we're ready?
Right you are, dad.
You must not be frightened if I cry out
out or moan when I go into the trance.
I'm not in pain or anything like that.
I don't even know that I do it.
But I'm told sometimes it happens.
Now, sir. You can put out the light.
[ Female scream! ]
There's a hand on my face.
There's a hand on my face!
- Lights on.
Look. It's a trick.
I was going to ask you
to tie my hands just now.
But I thought I would
show you this one first.
I don't see how you did that, even now.
No, Miss. I hardly thought you would.
You see, Miss.
Things happen in the dark.
The sense of touch.
Ain't much developed.
Unless you are blind.
When the young gentleman
took his hand away from me.
To turn out the light.
I took my other hand from
the gentleman there.
When you all joined hands again.
The two gentlemen was holding hands.
As comfortable as you like.
And I was free.
It's an old trick.
All the mediums use it.
Anyone can do it.
Now, sir. If you'll tie me in.
We will go on.
- We'll see to that.
We'll want something strong.
Handkerchiefs. They're strong enough.
They'll do very well.
We shall want three more.
Here's mine, dad.
Here is mine.
- Thank you.
Now, Madam La Grange. If you don't mind.
Now, I don't see why
you did that just now.
I wanted to make them tie me in.
I wanted you to be sure.
Why?
Because I think something
is going to happen.
I feel there will be manifestations.
I wanted you all to be
sure I was not faking.
I don't believe all that is necessary.
Why not if they want it?
Doctor.
Will you check up after me?
- Right.
There. That's alright.
Now I am sure you can't get away.
Yes. So am I.
So if you will all join hands again.
You have to reach over and
take my hands this time.
Now, just keep your minds free.
That is all you have to do.
Now, sir.
You can put out the light.
I can't stand this. I can't stand it.
Be quiet please.
She asked us to keep still.
Laughing-Eyes is saying.
They say.
A long way off.
Bad people. Bad people.
Unhappy.
She is unhappy.
Yes.
Spencer.
Wants Ned.
Spencer wants to tell
him about the letter.
And the pain in the back.
In the back.
What was in the back?
Ask him what was in the back.
Ned.
He wants Ned.
What do you want?
Ned. The swimming pool.
Don't forget.
The swimming pool.
You mean, the time you went in
after me when I was drowning?
Spencer says he can't rest.
You.
Promised.
Spencer. Of course I remember.
What do you want me to do?
Find.
Find .. the letters.
You mean, you want
me to find the letters?
Someone came.
You're trying to say who killed you?
Ask.
You know who killed you?
Ned.
He wants Ned.
You want me to ask?
Do you know who killed you?
This is horrible. Horrible.
Quiet, daughter.
Can .. can you tell the name?
Quick.
Quick. The name.
The name.
Spencer, can you tell who killed you?
You must keep asking.
Who killed you?
Who?
Ahh!
Wales, is anything the matter?
Richard, the light.
Turn on the lamp.
Look at him.
Stand back please. Stand back.
Doctor.
He's dead.
It's impossible.
Look at your hands. Oh.
Chotee.
- Yes, Sahib?
Telephone the police
commissioner's office.
Get Inspector Delzante if you can.
Tell him to come here at once.
Stabbed in the back.
Just as Spencer Lee was.
It was just as he was asking ..
Just as he was going
to find out who killed ..
What is it?
Inspector Delzante is on his way, sir.
Shall I unlock the door?
No.
Not until the inspector tells you.
Sir Roscoe, you know you had no
right to move Mr Wales' body.
Yes, yes. I know. But we couldn't
leave him lying here on the floor.
That was a little too much.
You see, we were all locked in here.
Now, if you ask me ..
- Just a minute.
Locked in?
- Exactly.
You mean as I found you when I came?
Yes.
All the doors and windows
were locked for the seance.
The servant had the key.
I refused to let him unlock
the door until you came.
So you were in the dark?
Wales was stabbed in the back.
The lights were turned on.
By the way, who turned on the lights?
I did, Inspector.
I was sitting there in that chair.
Close to the light purposely.
So that we could expose
trickery if we found any.
You must let me have
a look at that knife.
We did not find the knife.
You looked carefully?
- Everywhere.
While we were waiting for you.
That places all of you ..
Under suspicion.
Every one of you.
So, whoever used that knife ..
Still has it.
I should think so. Undoubtedly.
With the exception of
Sir Roscoe and his family.
I know none of you.
So I have to ask.
Now.
That.
Rather gruesome thing there.
I think we will remove it.
Will some of you gentlemen
carry Mr Wales body ..
Into another room.
Will you gentlemen take the feet?
Doctor, you and I can ..
Just a moment.
Well.
The test did not work very well, did it?
The four of you hesitated.
Certainly, you can't all be guilty.
Well.
We'll have to try something else.
Now, I would like to visualise
the scene a little more clearly.
Let's form that circle again.
Of course, this time without Mr Wales.
You all sit just as you
were sitting at the seance.
Well. Richard sat there.
Madam La Grange was next to him.
And I was sitting next to her.
How were the others placed?
I am trying to remember.
It's queer what a jumbled
memory one has.
I sat next to you, Sir Roscoe.
Don't you remember?
We joked about holding my hand.
Who sat next please?
Inspector, I can place them all for you.
If you will be so kind.
This young lady was there.
And this gentleman sat next to her.
And this young lady sat next to her.
She .. she was here.
Now, that gentleman came next.
You are wrong there.
I wasn't. No, you're right.
I was there.
I remember saying:
'Won't you sit by me, Miss O'Neill'?
Then who sat next to Dr. Mason?
Why ..
This young lady.
Something seems wrong here.
No. That's right.
I was sitting next to you, doctor.
Inspector, must we go
through this again?
I am afraid so, Lady Crosby.
Who occupied this seat?
Mr Wales.
I know because I sat here.
And I was next to him.
Thanks.
Now, you are all sure that
you have the right places?
There is some mix-up here. I know.
I was not next to Mr Wales.
Of course you weren't.
I don't know what I can
have been thinking of.
I sat where Mrs Eastwood is.
Yes.
I was beside Mrs Standish and Dr. Mason.
I knew I was in the wrong seat.
Then if you ladies exchange places ..
I want you all to be extremely careful.
I don't want any surprises.
Did the messages come
for anyone but Mr Wales?
No. The calls were all for Wales.
He kept on saying:
'Do you know who killed you'?
Did she mention a name?
No.
She gave a long moan.
Then Edward Wales continued to ask.
He said:
'Tell me who killed you.
I want the name'.
Suddenly he gave out an agonised
scream and cried out that he was hurt.
He was dead when we
turned on the lights.
Matron is here, Inspector.
Thanks.
One more question, Sir Roscoe.
Did you get the impression that if
Mr Wales had not been killed ..
His question would have been answered?
- Yes.
It was well established in your mind.
That Wales was the only
person able to get a message.
I'm positive.
Then he was killed in order to
prevent his question being answered?
That's the impression we got.
- Surely.
That leads to the conclusion
that whoever killed Wales ..
Knew who had killed Spencer Lee.
Well.
There is a police matron in the other
room who will search the ladies.
Grimshaw, the men. One at a time.
It makes no difference to
me in what order they go.
I have nothing to conceal.
I'd rather you waited a few
minutes, Madam La Grange.
I am quite ready.
- So am I.
Thank you very much.
You need not sit there anymore.
Unless you wish.
Richard.
Madam La Grange.
Sir?
There is a question I wish to ask.
Anything at all, sir.
When Mr Wales asked you for the
name, why didn't you answer?
I don't know, sir.
I was in a trance.
Then you did not hear the question?
How could I?
- I didn't ask you that.
I asked you why you didn't answer him.
Why did you not carry out
your part of the bargain?
I don't know what you mean.
My words are perfectly plain.
Why didn't you carry out
your part of the bargain?
There wasn't any bargain.
- Your whole seance was a fake.
It was not only planned but rehearsed.
Between you and Wales.
He saw that a woman
had killed his friend.
And he told you about it and asked
your help to discover the murderer.
I don't know what you're
talking about at all.
Perhaps this.
Will refresh your memory.
'What do you want'?
Answer:
'Don't forget the swimming pool'.
'Don't ever forget the swimming pool'.
Then.
'Do you mean the time he went
in after me when I was drowning'?
Then later.
'Spencer Lee says he can't rest'.
And so on and so on down to ..
'Do you know who killed you'?
The answer to that
would have been: 'Yes'.
What did she say?
She did not answer that question.
The next question is.
Can you tell the name?
Then.
He was to have told a woman's name.
Just the first name.
Sir Roscoe, what did she
reply to that question?
She moaned and cried.
'Keep on asking. Keep on asking'.
Why didn't you do as you agreed?
I don't know what you're
talking about at all.
You don't?
Mr Wales. Sure he was.
That a woman killed Spencer Lee and
he was sure that he found that woman.
But he dared not accuse her.
Or even tell me her name.
But he knew she would be here tonight.
He thought he could play
on her superstitious fears.
That when her name seemingly came
from the spirit of the dead man.
She would confess.
He told Madam La Grange the name.
You agreed to all this.
Why didn't you speak the name?
I don't know anything about it.
He must have forgotten to tell it.
No. He didn't.
There wasn't any name.
He didn't tell me any name.
- You came here for that purpose.
And after you got here.
Something happened.
To make you change your plan.
Something unexpected happened.
Now.
What was it?
- That is over.
Mrs Eastwood.
What did you say was your first name?
Mary.
- Mary.
And yours?
- Grace.
Sir Roscoe, your wife's given name?
- Alice.
Alice.
Mrs Trent.
Helen.
And yours, Miss O'Neill?
- Helen?
You see, I was christened Helen
but my friends call me 'Nellie'.
I see.
Helen.
So there are two .. Helens.
Two.
Helens.
Sir Roscoe.
When Madam La Grange first came tonight.
Did she show any surprise at
seeing any of the people here?
I was not in the room.
I was in the library with
Miss O'Neill and my son.
Then Miss O'Neill was not in
the room when she arrived?
So there were two Helens.
Everything was going along smoothly
until Miss O'Neill came in.
The extra Helen.
Rosalie La Grange.
What is that girl to you?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
- Nothing at all?
Then why did you try to deceive
me as to where she sat?
Why did you place her so that I wouldn't
know she was sitting next to Mr Wales ..
When he was stabbed?
It was just a mistake.
I didn't ask her to do it.
- I'm afraid that won't do.
You spoke of your plans and
the name you were to speak ..
Was 'Helen'.
What is the use of lying to me?
You tried your best to shield this girl.
And I want to know why.
I didn't ask her to do it.
I never heard of the young
lady before in all my life.
What is that girl to you?
- Nothing.
Nothing at all.
You old harridan ..
- Leave my mother alone.
Leave her alone.
I thought perhaps.
I would get it that way.
There, dear. It's alright.
Of course it is alright.
We'll have the fingerprints and ..
If you think for one moment ..
- Richard, my boy. Please.
Think.
- Think nothing.
Young man .. don't be foolish.
I am sorry.
But it is too clear.
Clear?
Lordy be, how could it be clear?
You will never accuse my
little girl of a thing like that.
She was next to him.
She had only to free one hand,
strike, and take his hand again.
No.
There was something else she had
to do before she could do that.
She had to have murder in her heart.
Look at her.
Look at the eyes of her.
At the face of her.
Is a murderer there?
Man. Haven't you got eyes in your head?
No knife on them, Inspector.
- I know where it is.
Tell the matron she will
find the knife on this girl.
Take her away.
Inspector.
Don't do it.
I'll tell you anything you like.
Only keep your hands off my little girl.
I did come here like you said.
And when I seen my own
child I lost my head.
I'm a silly old woman
that ain't got any sense.
I tried to save her.
And I've only made matters worse.
But you've looked at her.
You can't think she'd
do a thing like that?
Yes.
Then, Inspector. You are a fool.
And god helping me, I'll prove it.
No. I can't.
I don't know why you ever allowed
this woman to come here.
Is he still there, Howard?
- Yes.
And I hope he takes root there.
I hope he grows like a berry tree.
It's a beastly outrage.
Here we are, searched and held
prisoners like common criminals.
Father.
They searched and found nothing. Can you
insist they release her from that room?
I'll see what I can do, Richard.
- Please.
Richard, where is her mother?
I don't know. They only told me to come
in here and wait until I was wanted.
Oh god.
Show me the way.
Sure, I've been a faker all my life.
I have tricked them.
And fooled them.
But honest.
I never knowingly done harm to anyone.
And there is a power.
It came to me before.
Oh god.
Give it to me again.
It is fate.
My little girl.
For the sake.
For the sake of your son.
Amen.
I quite understand but is it necessary
to keep her locked in that room?
Who turned off those other lights?
I did, sir.
- Why?
Well, sir.
I was praying.
Praying? What for?
Guidance.
I hope you get it.
I will, sir.
Take her to the matron
and have her searched.
Unless of course.
You want to give up the knife now.
I got no knife.
And I've been searched once.
- Exactly.
But then you were allowed
to come into this room.
We're rather anxious to
know what you found ..
While you were in here.
A feeling of comfort, sir.
A feeling that the innocent ..
Had come to no harm.
Take her to the matron.
Take her out of here.
I'm going.
You wanted me?
- Yes. Sit down.
My dear girl.
- Sir Roscoe.
If you caution her in any way.
You're interfering
in this investigation.
I beg your pardon, Inspector.
I say, Ellis. What happened
here at the window?
The old woman turned the blind
and stood gazing outside.
Did she throw anything out the window?
- No, Inspector.
Now, young woman.
Let's see what you have to say.
I've already told you there
is nothing that I can say.
Well, You'd better make
up your mind to talk.
Now. Out with the truth.
She will 'out' with nothing.
You say you got the fingerprints of the
girl that was in Spencer Lee's room.
And you got my Nellie's fingerprints.
Why don't you compare them?
- Mother.
What were you going to say?
- Nothing.
Inspector.
The fingerprints compare perfectly.
- That is a lie.
Sir Roscoe, we have taken this
young woman's fingerprints.
And there is the cup which we
took from Spencer Lee's room.
Her fingerprints are on that cup.
I never touched a cup.
Thanks.
I know that fact.
Then you said that just to trap her?
There are no fingerprints on the cup.
We merely wanted her admission.
She was there.
Nellie.
Look at me.
Look at your old mother.
Mother.
What if she did go there?
She had a good reason for it.
What did you go for, darling?
I can't tell you.
Nellie, dear. You must tell me.
Dear, listen.
You know that I trust you.
You know that we all love you.
Now explain to him, dear.
Well?
I'm waiting.
I didn't do anything.
Yes, my dear. We know that.
But why did you go?
Did you know Spencer Lee?
Of course she didn't, father.
Why doesn't she speak for herself?
Because I'll speak for her.
My dear, can't you answer
even that question?
Don't you see what they'll
think if you don't?
Nellie, you must tell me.
Nellie.
You're shielding someone.
- No, no.
That's the first lie you ever told me.
I want to know who you are shielding.
Tell me who it is.
- Please dear.
You're her sweetheart. Make her tell.
Dear, you must. You must.
- Richard, I can't.
Even if you are protecting someone else.
I think you ought to tell us.
Break her word, is it?
She should not.
There never was an O'Neill
yet that was an informer.
She needn't tell.
I know it myself now.
It is blind, I've been.
You.
You're the one who found
out there was two Helens.
'The extra Helen', says you.
Well, send for the other Helen.
And ask her.
- Mother, stop.
Stop? I will not.
Wait, please.
Did my daughter send you?
Because if she did we
can't accept that sacrifice.
I want to know the truth.
Did my daughter send you?
Did you go for my daughter?
Yes.
I knew it.
My daughter sent you?
What for?
Some letters.
- Why didn't she go?
She was afraid.
- Go on.
Tell him, dear. It's alright.
I don't know what to say.
Why not tell the truth?
Tell the inspector what happened.
Nothing happened.
They were silly letters Helen wrote to
Mr Lee before she married Mr Trent.
You see.
Mr Lee knew that Mr Trent
was terribly jealous, and ..
He threatened to send the letters to
him if Helen didn't come to his room.
Helen confided in me
and I went to Mr Lee.
He said that he loved
Helen and was desperate.
It seemed like a funny kind of love.
But I didn't tell him that.
Then he gave me the letters.
Was it before or after
Mr Lee ordered tea?
After.
I compliment this young lady.
That was ..
Beautifully done.
Grimshaw, get Miss Trent.
- Yes, Inspector.
You don't believe?
- Not a word.
Not one word.
She wasn't protecting your sister.
She was protecting herself.
She went for the letters of course.
But the tea was served
before she asked for them.
Not afterwards.
- How do you know that?
The butler would not serve tea
to a man she had just killed.
You ..
- Richard.
She was engaged to him.
He had compromising letters
she had written to him.
So she went to get them.
Then, when he wouldn't give them to her.
She killed him.
Mrs Trent.
Yes, Inspector?
Did you ask this girl to go to Mr Lee's
rooms to get letters you wrote to him?
Did she what?
Did you, Mrs Trent?
Certainly not.
Helen, I ..
- Keep still.
Are you sure?
- Of course she is sure.
Please answer my question.
I never wrote a letter to
Spencer Lee in my life.
I don't know what she told you.
- Never mind what she told me.
I want to be very sure of this.
Did you ask this girl to
go to Spencer Lee's room?
No.
She had no letters of yours?
- No.
Nellie didn't know Lee, Helen.
And you did.
- How about that, Mrs Trent?
I think Nellie knew Spencer Lee.
I hadn't seen him for months.
He used to come here a good deal.
He wanted to marry me.
But I didn't like him.
And I certainly never wrote
him letters of any sort.
Thank you, Mrs Trent.
That is all I want to know.
Helen, you're lying to save yourself.
You must tell the truth.
She tells the truth.
- She's not.
Richard, wait.
Please.
I'm sorry, Richard.
Father, you don't think ..
- No, dear. I don't.
Inspector, do you need us anymore?
- Not anymore.
Thank you.
Grimshaw.
Take her to police headquarters.
No. Not my Nellie.
Inspector.
I wouldn't do that if I was you.
I know who done it.
- You know? Who was it?
I can't tell you yet.
But I will, I will.
Give me a chance.
Give me time.
Give me an hour.
Keep them all here in the house.
An hour more.
I'll give you.
Ten minutes.
Ten minutes?
Bless me.
No, darling. Not now. Go away.
Inspector, won't you take them all away?
Please.
- Alright.
Go away please.
- Come.
Ten minutes.
What can I do?
I said I knew who done it.
But I don't.
Sure, Laughing-Eyes.
You're no good to me now.
We've faked all our lives.
Now, when I want the real thing.
I get nothing at all.
If only I could get ..
A real message.
Laughing-Eyes.
Are you going to let me be beaten?
By a scheming ..
Cold-hearted murderer?
[ Two raps. ]
I didn't do that.
It's come.
After all these years.
A real message.
I will take it.
Believing.
And trusting.
The time to be sure.
Glory be.
The knife.
I knocked twice.
But you didn't hear me.
I heard you.
That was a message.
Just the same.
Inspector.
I got to speak to you alone.
I got to.
You must let me.
You've got to let me.
Very well.
The constable outside is ordered ..
To arrest anyone leaving this house.
What did mother mean, Richard?
What did she mean, 'a message'?
I don't know, dear.
Please.
Please, Inspector.
Do as I ask.
Give me a chance.
Then, if it does work.
You can take my Nellie and lock her up.
Please, Inspector.
I know my Nellie will do it.
Let's see if the other one will.
What you are asking me to let you do ..
Is insanity.
It is unheard of.
Inspector, please.
Don't you see?
I am drowning.
And I'm snatching at the last straw.
I hope you will.
Grimshaw, go with Madam La Grange
and do what she tells you.
You can't mean it, Inspector.
What she asks is too horrible.
Do what I say.
God bless you, sir'.
You will bring them right along?
- Yes.
The brazenness of the girl.
Saying she sent Helen for the letters.
[ Door knocks ]
I say, Inspector. You are most welcome.
Can we all go now?
- You shall not.
I must ask everyone to
return to the other room.
Look here, you have the guilty party.
Is there no end to this red tape?
- Thank you, Mr Trent.
Your assurance that I have the
guilty party gives me a great relief.
Will you come please?
I guess that's alright?
- Yes, sir. That is alright.
Don't be worried.
You go back to Nellie.
Please, please.
Now you will all do as
Madam La Grange asks.
Now, if you will all
take the same places.
Look here, everyone.
We should refuse to continue
with this tomfoolery.
I think this is a beastly outrage.
Sir Roscoe, must we continue with this?
Inspector, is this necessary?
- Quite necessary.
Mr Standish, your demonstration
is unnecessary.
Unnecessary? Unnecessary?
I say, sir.
That is the dead body of Edward Wales.
Inspector, this is a little too much.
It's too much.
You really are going too far.
We can't bear this.
We really can't stand it.
Sure.
The innocent.
Need have no fear of the dead.
No.
If you will all sit down.
Please be seated.
This is horrible.
Horrible.
Father, must I? Must I sit here?
Inspector.
Is is necessary for my
daughter to sit there?
Please.
Why not?
The innocent need have no fear.
My Nellie will hold his other hand.
Now, Inspector.
Please close the door.
I say.
I say. We're not going to sit
in the dark with that, are we?
This is dreadful. Dreadful.
No.
If you will all join hands.
Now just keep your minds clear.
That is all you have to do.
Now, sir.
You can put out the light.
Oh, this is horrible. Horrible.
A message.
Has come.
You, that is hiding.
Come out.
You, that is skulking.
I call.
On the spirit.
Of Edward Wales.
I call.
On the spirit of Edward Wales.
I.
Am.
Trying.
To reach.
You.
I am.
Far .. away.
That is .. that is Wales' voice.
But Wales .. is dead.
I come.
A long way.
He is moving.
I can't stand it. I can't stand it!
Mother.
Mother. He is taking his hand away.
Look.
Mrs Eastwood. Mary. My hand.
You are touching my hand.
Take him away.
Take him away. I did it, I did it.
I did it!
I did it.
Grimshaw.
Yes, Inspector?
Get ready to take down
Mrs Eastwood's confession.
No.
You believed Wales was the only one who
could get the message from Spencer Lee.
You killed Wales to prevent that.
Yes. And you killed Spencer Lee.
Why?
I had to.
I had to. I had to.
He deserved it.
Oh, he deserved it!
Only one thing mattered.
That my husband had gone
to London on business.
But he hasn't, he hasn't, he hasn't.
He found out about Spencer and me.
And he left me.
I was there with him that day
in his room when Nellie came.
Oh, the beast! The rotten, rotten beast.
Knowing that I was there hiding.
He tried to make love to Nellie.
Then she left.
I went crazy.
I went mad.
I grabbed the knife in his
desk and I stabbed him.
I killed him!
That's enough. That's enough. Please.
You don't have to know any more.
Please. You don't have to know any more.
That chair. Where is Richard?
That chair was empty when
I turned on the light.
Sure, sir.
It was Mr Richard who put the
cane in poor Mr Wales' sleeve.
So he would point his arm in the air.
I see.
Nellie darling.
Excuse me, sir.
Father. Father.
I lied about Nellie.
I lied about those letters.
I know, my dear.
I know.
Oh Nellie.
Laughing-Eyes.
Are they going to live
happily ever after?
Remember.
And one for Yes.
[ One rap. ]
Richard.
I love you so.
..s-d..