The film The Wildcat
was presented for the first
to the public in 1921.
The intertitles in the surviving print
were different than
the ones from the pages of the official Censor.
The new intertitles were prepared from
the Censor archives.
The Wildcat
Comedy in 4 acts
Hanns Kräly & Ernst Lubitsch
Director: Ernst Lubitsch
Scenery and costumes: Ernst Stern
Cameraman: Theodor Sparkuhl
The characters
The commander of the fortress ... Viktor Janson
His wife                      ... Marga Köhler
Their daughter                ... Edith Meller
Lt. Alexis                    ... Paul Heidemann
Claudius, the head of the gang of thieves
... Wilhelm Digelmann
Rischka his daughter          ... Pola Negri
Pepo, the timid thief ...Hermann Thimig
Dafko                 ...Paul Biensfeld
Zofano                ...Paul Grätz
Masilio               ...Max Kronert
Tripo                 ...Erwin Kopp
Location:  near Piffkaneiro
First Act
Quiet!
Lili, the Commander's daughter.
Ministry of War
General Piffkaneiro
To the Commander of the Fortress Border.
Lieutenant Alexis is transferred
It is imperative,
as Lieutenant Alexis
is best known to the female sex
as "Alex the Seducer",
to maintain very strict
discipline with him.
Signed: General Piffkaneiro
Finally, a handsome man!
What a pig!
How can you speak so about Alex?
Alex prepaes to leave his home.
My darling!
A word of goodbye.
Rómpese el corazón,
lágrimas se derraman.
My heart breaks, tears
expand, nostalgia grows and
enlarges the ball in my throat
Go in peace and may your path be easy.
You made me happy!
Goodbye, Daddy!
Claudius, the head of the thieves
and his accomplices are the
terrors of the border.
Hello, friends!
Hello, Chief!
Come on, give it up!
What have you stolen now?
Where have you hidden it this time?
I was at the movies.
Not behind the head!
Rischka, my child.
She hit me!
Me, too!
You should not indulge her, too!
Handkerchiefs!
Ah, the handsome man!
Take off your pants!'
What you do to me, I'll do to you!
End of the First Act
Second Act
The Brigands!
... attacked the Lieutenant.
Tell us what happened!
Suddenly, a shot!
Now I have eaten enough.
Go immediately and look for Lt. Alexis!
But I am the ...
Lieutenant.
The pajama pants are very cute.
Let me introduce you to my wife!.
And my very precious daughter.
- Do you like my daughter?
- Pardon? ?
But you will not get my daughter's
hand so easily!
Idiot!
This is unbelievable.
Why did you let him escape?
... and such a beautiful pajama pants,
I wish I had had such a pair.
They would have been too small for you.
You have no idea how I froze.
The punitive expedition against the thieves.
You may make the coffee now.
Children, you look great!
If you please, Mr. Conductor!
They have already drawn!
Don't be rough!
War is war!
We should not even permit them a slap.
At your service!
That girl has guts!
End of the Second Act.
Third Act
Victory along the entire line.
You have fought valiantly, just
as Hector faced the cannons!
We will reward you for this wonderful victory.
As thanks, I offer you my daughter's hand!.
But I absolutely cannnot accept.
But yes, you may even demand it!
Nothing can be done otherwise...
The victory celebration.
I have never felt so good!
Rischka!
Busy!
Aren't you ashamed to dress in my closet!
We will soon be husband and wife!
I am afraid!
This does not help me.
I need you to stop.
You, come out! Impertinent person!
The air is unhealthy!
Ten legs, five men, and it plays!
End of the Third Act.
Fourth Act
Rischka dreams.
Can you hear my heart beating?
Ah, the season of love ...
Now is the time to marry that girl!
You promised him that one
of us would marry her!
I will do what I promised!
You must marry!
And don't speak so crudely!
Who would want to marry me?
I would like to!
For Rischka, the big day ...
Will you make my daughter happy?
Always be honest and faithful
forever, and to the grave.
The daughter of the commander of our fortress,
after having given him every confidence ...
will marry Lt. Alexis.
The marriage will take place today..
Lieutenant, we must now leave
for the wedding ceremony.
This could be your size.
I'll make myself more comfortable.
Why are you so taken with our daughter?
He loves you more than he does me!
I will cure him, however difficult it will be!
Where were you hidden all this time?
End
Music:  Marco Dalpane (2000)
Director: Marco Dalpane
Recorded: Teatro Consorziale di Budrio
Sound: Franco Visioli, Nicola Zonca
Post-production: Thomas Schmölz
Editors: Nina Goslar
Production: Foundation F.W. Murnau
in collaboration with ZDF / Arte