Patricia"-
Patricia, where are you?
The plane is leaving in an hour
Patricia"-
It' s almost 20 past 12
I' m due for the meeting at 12:40 to go
I' m already late for the hair-dresser
Patricia"-
Today is holiday
She should try not to be late
for a while
But why must send her out today?
Vacation starts with entry
She must go back to college in Munich
Patricia
Patricia"-
She isn't anywhere
I don' t know where she is
Go look for her
Patricia, you got to be late
Will you hurry?
Patricia, hurry up
Good morning, everybody
Oh, Patricia
Something wrong?
Hi, father
Hello, mother
You should be ashamed
Of what?
I hope you' ll excuse us
Oh, no---I think she' s charming
This is ticket to Munich,
First Class-"darling
And there' s little something
as posture to morale
I wouldn' t tell your mother
I' ll keep it our secret
Thank you, Dad
You' ll work hard and enjoy yourself
I' m sorry I can't go with you
But Miss Kito will drive you
to the airport
Se you soon and have a good trip
Patricia
Hm?
I' m only going to Munich
But you're going alone-"I, m worried
Surely you' ll send us telegram
As soon as I arrive
You need this money, my darling
But I won' t tell your father
Yes, indeed
But Patricia"-
You know I trust you, my dear
I know you' ll be a good girl
Oh, my God"-
I' ll be late for the hair-dresser
and write to your father
Sure
Passengers to Munich Luthansa Flight 317
immediate boarding at Gate No.6
Oh, I' ll miss you, darling
I don' t want to live without you"-
my dear
I come to Munich
As soon as I raise the money, I---
What' s your name?
Why do you want to know?
Just tell me
Sol Dosloman, so what?
Sol Dosloman?
Yes
Okay
Would you put this ticket
in Sol Dolsoman' s name please?
So you two like to go to Munich?
Yeah, sure...
but I' m broke to bring her
Okay, you're in business
Yeah, but why?
Just do me a favor
Send out this cable from Munich"-
make sure to my folks
Yeah, certainly
Passengers to Munich Luthansa Flight 317
immediate boarding at Gate No.6"-
Hello, can I do something for you?
No, thanks
Oh, you're American
No, I' m Chinese
I suppose you're just waiting
for the bus
No
I' m on my way back to Abbey
Where are you heading?
Wherever you are
Have you seen my company?
Who hasn' t?
But I find it really boring
Would you like to stop at my place
for a drink then?
That sounds superb
I' ll have the whole afte3rnoon off
By chance I just saw my boss off
to Munich
How convenient
I' ll be right with you
What' s in it?
The red is Campari-"the rest is secret
Secret?
Nothing worse than poison
Cheers
My name is Dimus Roberts-"what, s yours?
Elizabeth - -- Elizabeth Baker
from New York
But friends call me Elly
Elly?
You' re a model, I imagine
What makes you think I' m a model?
Well---your body
If you like---if you need a job---
I mean work---I have many contacts
Helping people?
Well, why not?
Can you hear my heart pound?
Pounding like crazy, come and feel it
It beats for you
Could it beat like that for hours?
Caress me
Kiss me, Dimus
Are you married?
Oh, yes---you might say so
in open-minded country
That' s nice
Neither of you are jealous?
You' re looking at an elderly swinger
I' m 5B years old
I' m free as a bird, darling-"okay?
How do you like to kiss my tonic?
She missed the plane, you know?
Who?
Your wife
What?
She missed the plane
She missed her plane?
You saw her?
She was running after us
Then she must be on her way home
I thought you said you're free
as a bird
Hurry-..
You don' t mean she' sjealous?
Jealous?
If she finds you here,
she' ll chop me into pieces
Hurry---please
Dimus...
Where' s she?
I saw her boarding your car
You must have brought her home
I
Don t try to cheat me like a fool
How dare you do this to me
immediately after I' m away?
Chou, swinger
Please listen to me
I don' t want to hear any of your
explanation
I' ll never forgive what you've done"-
Taxi"-
(In Greek)Damn it...
see what you've done to me
I' ve made up my mind
Whether right or wrong, I' ve done it
I want to learn things in my own way
I don' t need Munich for that
At the airport, I gave my ticket to
a couple of love-sick kids
Here I' m still in Greece
I' m still loving n
This afternoon, I had a bump trial with
a middle-aged man
What an artic piece"-
crazy to see what they got to
You may guess I' ll have my first night
alone
I want to go to sleep---
just near de Polem
Hello
(In Greek)Do you mind giving me a ride?
It' s great to me
Give the bag to me---no sweat
Please don' t speak Greek, dear
Speaking English?
Huh?
Do you speak English?
(In Greek)What' s your origin?
Arlenika
What' s Arlenika?
She' s Arlenika
You only speak Greek?
You---Arlenika
Me-"Hard Rock
He' s very good Cocksman
Hark Rock?
Right
I' ve got a hot whiskymshe' s ready
She' s quite a pretty, huh?
You know it
Hey, you like to make love at Max?
Arlenika and Hard Rock?
Hard Rock and you babe right on
That' s good
That' s heaven, kid
She' ll do?
She' s ready
Shall we try?
We can get a shot for trying
Why don' t you ask her first?
How is it for a bitch?
Okay, you may tear off a piss
A Piss?
Hard Rock' s piss?
What did I tell you?
She' s ready
Let' s not keep the lady waiting
Okay, you win-"okay
Let go of me
You guys should me a good time
She' s speaking English
James, what' s the matter?
Nothing, dear-"absolutely nothing
What are you gazing like that?
You look ill
Good heaven-"James, close your eyes
Put your clothes
on your shameless husky body
You' ve never seen a pair of bulls?
What language-"hippies?
She got to be a hippie
Give me a break, Sir
James, I' ve told you to close your eyes
Jamie, look---
LOQk...
See heaven
Young lady, you go away from here---
or I' ll call the police
Bye, honey---bye
Bye...
I hope the son of a bitch will show up
I' ll kill her
Oh, what I want to do is to find
the damn car
Hey, look-"here, s the car
She has left the key in it
Gentlemen"-
You should know you can't park here
What does this jerk want?
The jerk says you park at where says
'No Parking' and
will cost you 1,000 ranus
And for the jerk, that' ll cost another
1,000 ranus
That' s 2,000 ranus altogether
2,000 ranus?
Oh, as for your insolence,
there' s a special charge which brings to
3,000 ranus
The more we talk, the more it costs"-
great
Your friend has a great fortune
If I lay my hand on that bitch---
I' ll get this all back and
I' ll take n out in kind
And so, on this second day of this odyssey
in which I bumped into
in the same old way
Except for the gorgeous scenery- --
otherwise I encountered an attempted
rape by a couple of guerillas
who kept yelling
after getting kick from my boot
Poor fellows
Why everyone is so hung up sexually?
Why they always go bananas?
Does it have to be such a big thing?
Why can' tit be natural?
Hello
I was hungry, so I help myself
It' s good soup
What do you do?
You drop by the sky?
Out of space
I hope you've got a nice fall
I' m sorry
I don' t mean to disturb you
But you're really into it beautifully
You two really have a ball together
I should hope so
What would you do in our case
by watching?
What are you saying?
It seems so funny
What?
I always thought watching people make love
would turn me on
I guess I was wrong
You want to try it?
No
You might learn a few tricks
You have a place to hold on tonight?
I thought if I could stay here
Okay with you?
Sure if you don' t mind
Do you love her?
Sure...
If I didn' t, I wouldn' t make love
with her
I don' t know
Have you known her very long?
Three whole days
You don' t think other girls
in love with?
I love them all
Oh...
Baby, I want you now
Let me go-"baby, go away
Keep hard for the little boy' s room
I' ll join you
Did you say you had to go too?
I intend to
Hey, you're not timid, are you?
Me?
No point being shy what comes natural?
You got your hang-up-"I got mine
After you, my lady
Thank you, my lord
Sure you don' t mind what I do, sweetie?
No---l' m sorry
Hello
What are you doing here?
I'm lying down-"who are you?
What' s the idea?
You got any good idea?
I'm fresh out-"what do you want?
Come in---I entertain your visit
You want a cigarette?
They' re mine
So?
Mind to take me on this cruise?
I don' teat much"-
though I don' t bump on the right side
And suppose I don' t need a female
aboard?
No Problem...
If you're not hurry---
I look for another boat
You want to bet he' ll have me aboard?
I warn you---Joe is a bastard
But you're nobody at all
Okay, a good cruise is hard to find
Can you cook?
No
Don't you ask silly questions?
I suppose you got a name
Barbara---it' s just a trial
I was supposed to work in Munich
Who wants to work at 19?
I caught out
My old man then pulled the poor banana---
so I grew up broken crazy
Tell me about yourself
Here-"drink up
So, what' s the story of your life?
The name is Tom---the age is 28
I' m living in a friend' s place in Purais
I' m a foreign correspondent
for a news agency
I spend as much time on my boat
doing nothing as I can manage
My father is in the best of his health
My mother is hardly normal
How many girlfriends you've got?
None at present
How many you've known?
I'm no good in statistics
Approximately
Why would you want to know?
I always want to know what' s that
Are you saying you never took a girl
to bed?
I must be frank you mean?
Yeah
I' m sorry it' s not true
You make jacker?
Hm...
You got to be a jack then
You got to be a dice
Don tbe so sure-HI' m not
I' m not so sure what I really am
I' m not so sure what' s a dice worth
and I don' t care a damn
So far what you're doing,
the smell is what I' ve found
Thanks
It' s so far false, don' t you flatter?
How about a trial?
Don't you sometimes
feel so lonely all by yourself?
I'm not alone now
You' re not-"right
Be careful, the deck is slippery
Barbara“.
Barbara, I' m talking to you
Are you talking to me?
Of course, who else?
Who said my name is Barbara?
Barbara was the name you said
Oh, yes-"it, s the one
You won' t say I' m stoned, will you?
No-"just not
You think I' m gonna crazy?
A little
Question---
can a hermit and fruit make together?
Do you think I' m nude?
You' re really superb
You' re even better on your own yacht
And I got a lovely girl in the cabin
What do you plan to do tonight?
Do you really think I can fall asleep?
You keep mosquito here
No...
You won' t go to help
Are you coming over to kiss me
goodnight?
You' re supposed to do that
I never have to do that
Women are supposed experts for
such a thing
I guess you should
You know I think I' m in love
You mean you're not sure
How can I be sure?
Sometimes it just happened that way
On a Greek island,
I met a wonderful man
His name is Tom-"handsome and gentle
And I feel good when I' m with him
I still don' t know---
is it because I' m in love or
because he makes love so well
But after all, what makes the difference
if I' m in love and great?
If I' m not, so what?
But counted I' m happy like everyday
I can use new discovery
as nothing after the foam
Not a single buddy I should look at
twice
It must be kidding us
about all the actions in Greece
It got to be some asshole around
like our girl friend is
You call that asshole---
As a matter of fact, she' s a bitch
I call it
I' d still rather be a poor fellow
than a bishop every night
Yeah, maybemtime' s up
You know what I need?
Nothing-"you have me
I need sunglasses
Well, you can a pair anywhere
There---
Where?
Al Trimond
I' ll wait for you
Take all these
I!
ll try"-
Hey, you' ll break the camel' s back
Hey---I need a pair of sunglasses
You shouldn' t hide some videos
Thank you
No-"they, re not my style
How about the white one?
Not too big for me?
That' s perfect
Now, look---
Yeah-"how much are they?
For you, they' re free
I got something else you like too
It' s for you
No...
Please, you must
I couldn' t
Yes, you could-"you, ll please me
Greeks like to push you sometimes
Do they?
He was nice
He gave me the shawl
He refused to receive anything
for the sunglasses either
Hey...
Chou"-
You' re coming to the party tonight?
I don' t know yet
Come on---l' ll teach you to dance Sasaki
We' ll think about n
I don' tthink you' ll push for tonight"-
do you?
What about if I turn on
and like the guy, can I?
Let' s put more tomorrow than
what we get today
What you do you' ll make yourself
a table each guy you get off with
Hm?
Let me hear one
---they all get crazy as they get"-
Your mind so crazy"-
No---
don' t really say you' re
May I really get confused"-
I think you're just nuts
Huh?
You plan on wearing this shawl
for the Greek tonight?
If it' s good, why not?
Tom...
Tom, come here-"quick
Oh...
Look, one hand“.
You' ve got yourself a sailor
Hey, come and dance
Oh, sure
Come on-"let, s try it
No---l' m not up to it
In that case, you just have a look
Huh, what do you know?
Hey, man-"you look
Son of a bitch-Hit' s her
We' ll give that bitch a lesson
Later on
You had enough of that stuff
Is it? I' ll have n all
Oh, come on---l' m bored
Let' s dance
I' m none of this-"so, let' s split, okay?
I' ll out it out
Alright, we have 2 ways
So I see---she gave you the finger too
So what?
She really gets it, doesn' t she?
She has the life gun
Her body drives you against the wall"-
right?
You can't say she' s worth 3,000 ranus
that much"-
a little thief
Yeah"-
Still it all depends
It' s not much that gets from the pro
A hot lass can supply
Get under-"she knows the angles---
just like pilling
Excuse me
Shelefl
Where did she go?
They told me the activity
They went to love together
You know what that means
No-"thanks
All life is love---
all life is to beloved
Without love, that' s death
We must take love when it' s here
No
Love is all
Here-"get hold of this to your pals
What do you mean?
3,000 ranus is too much for one
What' s this 3,000 ranus?
Don't play damn with me
You know what I mean, baby
That' s what you call the butcher"-
right?
That' sit
Hi
Won' t you drink one more?
Why not?
I'm glad you come back
I haven' t stopped thinking of you
Why you keep staring at me?
Tom---kiss me
Don't you want to?
Let!
S Q0
What kind a game you play with me?
It' s not a game---l' m in love with you
But I don' t want you to get the wrong
idea of me
Do you understand?
No
Tom ---I have problems
Such as?
Myself
I figure that
You really don' t understand, do you?
You don' t understand anything about me
No
I' m not what you think
You went to bed with the Greek---
didn' t you?
Yes-"yes, I did
Why did you come back?
I don' t know
Why can't you accept me the way I am?
I don' t even know who you are
Neither do I
I' m trying to find that out
But, in any case, I' m not
what you're thinking, Tom
You still haven' t kissed me---
don' t you want to?
What I got to lose?
Tom, what do you want?
I'm telling you the truth
You know I' m supposed to be in Munich
But I' m here in the beach as my world
How does a Greek beach get to be
a world?
I'm with you as a world
What' s so interesting in me?
I like how you think-"your body"-
your action
And you're crazy when you get mad
that makes me look so miserable
Was I wrong to leave?
Well, you should
Something is growing to love?
Maybe not
Take your blouse off
What?
Take it off
Anything wrong?
You won' t rather do it for me?
Now what?
Touch your breasts
But why?
Because I ask you
You mean like this?
Caress them
It' s your first time, isn' tit?
I should not-"why?
Now tell me how you feel
Warm-"good
Take the nipples in your fingers
That exacts you?
Yes
I suppose you often get up like that
Yes, sometimes
Tom---kiss me
No-"not yet
Why?
That' ll turn you on?
You do this for others too?
What others?
The ones you sleep with
What do you mean?
The trick you toured with the Greek
dancer
I' m a whore you think?
I go for August
Why you buck me?
I don' t have to do this thing
So ask me---
don' t have any secrets
So mind your own business
You can treat yourself like a hooker
if you need a pro and get one
Get dressed---l' m taking you back
Oh, don' t go into trouble"-
you're so busy
Tom, what' s your telephone number?
You' ll find me in the phone book
Tom, you're a fool
It' s finished-"Tom is gone
Goodbye, my heart
It' s too good to that
So, here I' m on my own again
Hurt so much doesn' t help the pride
The day I stayed with Tom was like
a dream
on the island-"on the boat
He was so kind-"so gentle
No man ever gave me so much pleasure
I' m a fool
I should go and find him---
and ask for his forgiveness
But I have my pride-"bastard
Why did he do it?
It' s hard to believe
I shouldn' t let him hear this tape
I made
---this is the most sacred shrine
in Greece"-
ancient zero---
I think he' d have understood me better
It now turns out to be that I set him
in my trap
---the ancient theatre of liberty"-
Here on my left is Yagora architecture
remarkably well preserved - --
one of the warmest ancient
Greek life before Christ"-
Come on...
Well, few days and nights I' ll be okay
Over 3,000 years everywhere
you've seen the whole island were---
Good, face this way please
---the love story inevitably turns out
to be 'Never On Sunday'
At least it was fun on the last day
None would go banana in that regard
Once more---flat---wider---
that' s your profile
There we got it-"hold it---just like that
Once more-"yeah-"that, s great
Would I buck you if I watch?
Huh?
My name is Beatrice
Hi---Bernie
Hey, what' s the matter with you?
I thought we were here for work
You shut up-"it, s finished
Roy, tell her
change her clothes please
I get trouble-"you know that
No shit
I' ve been dumped by a guy I love
I' m looking for a good way out
He' s practically a straight guy---
but now I hate him
Why?
What did you do?
Who with?
With a Greek guy-"I made love to him
But it' s to prove that Tom wasn' t real
and I wasn' twrong
Did I shock you?
Oh, no---surely
And you---never been in love with you?
How would you like to work with me?
Sure, I might like that
Will you present nude?
Huh?
You' re shy, aren' t you?
I'm not shy at all
You like it?
Do you mind if I stay with you---
I work for free
Tom took all the money when he left and
I' m broke
Do as you like
But I' m warning---it' s a hard day
That' ll be okay
He has got a sister
His sister works on the states
of the hotel
That means we won' t get pay expenses
What you're doing is already overpaid
Thanks a lot
That' s good-"only relax-"relax a little
Okay, Beatrice
You too, Amanda"-
try and lie on your thigh
Good - --now move closer together
Yeah, just like that, right-"very good
Now, I' ll get some close-ups
Oh...
Hold it"-
Get your hair up, Amanda"-
Qet UP"-good
Play the pose-"good
You know it' s marvelous
with the photographer
You think so?
He' s a little too topsy with almighty
Good-"not that all
We' ll get few more shots in the water"-
come on
You don' t like cameraman, is that it' s?
I do really, I mean it
And I' ll follow you
He' s pathetic
Okay now-"Amanda, turn to the side
and Beatrice, you turn to a full profile
You mean a real flap?
He' s as quick as a treat of a duck
He should get it up as it should
Beatrice, return your back to me-"right
Alrightmthat' s it for the day
Take a swim or something
You can get sick of the damn sun
Save your expenses-"you don' t need soap
No man can complete for a second
You want to turn him on?
If you're willing"-
So aml
Do you think he' s watching us?
Hm...
Come on
I got the impression he' s ready
I won' t be surprised
I won' t really think she can make it
Hold me tight
No way she' ll make it
No way
You know what you really want?
First is this Tom---then is the Greek
Could be a lesbian
I' m disappointed it' s normal
What I want is love
However, I can make it
You really think you can make it
with her, don' t you?
Why not?
You seem available by now
May I?
What?
Let me go
Good"-
Good fight"-
Slop it...
Lousy creep"-
The only way he gets it up is by the
flash light
Tom was straight-HI' m a real bummer
Where is Tom?
He shouldn' t have gone
You' re the only one
Who does it for me?
What I do is this stupid thing
like that to be stolen
But I guess I have to
Why I just call this island off?
Thank you
Good morning
I need a room with secret bath
or a large suite
Does it say anything?
It does to me, Miss
I send the room boy immediately
Don't bother-"I have just one bag
Good morning
Is this free?
Yes, have a seat
A Teguila please
I believe we' ve met-"Martin Muler
Can I buy you a drink?
Buy what you want with I included"-
of course
You' re on vacation?
Yes
May I ask where you're from?
Surek
Where are you from?
Constanibal
Constanibal?
You mean Istanbul?
Istanbul is in Turkey
which is for the crusade
$6.09
You alone?
Yes-"I, m here on my vacation
I like foreign surprises
You must be roasted with this shoot up
How do you like this dress?
Yes, it' s very sexy
Of course, you like it---
shoot up my boot, right?
It' s beautiful"-
obviously your busts
covered inside like that
Round and full---you want to try them?
What?
You mean here?
The bartender doesn' t mind, does he?
But...
How about your room then?
You really got balls
Help me...
Help me please
What' s the matter?
Shut the door-"quick
He' s a criminal
The creep is a criminal?
Rapist or anythingmhe' s a monster
I' ll take care of that son of a bitch
Lady, you just watch this
What?
Shg! S m5' Qil~I
You' ve made him just good
Come on, baby
Let me deal with you
Nobody will help you get away with it
Get in there
Strip it off
Let' s dance first
Hurray---
What' s this?
Don't expect the last tango
can play me trick
Take it off
Any visitor?
You ask room service?
Yes, bring us some champagne"-
3 bottles please
Very well
Enjoy yourself, Martin
Goddamn bitch
Ask for Muler
if you want a good fuck
Excuse me---
Can you tell me what room
Mr. Muler resides?
Room 112
Thank you very much
Keep the change-"bye
I didn't order 3 bottles
But you were here when ordered
by the lady
Let her pay for them"-
and get out of here
Oh, no---...
We' re going to need the champagne
Leave them here, my dear"-
and go along
Go along---what' s it?
So you're Mr. Muler
Oh, I' ve been waiting so long for you
Hi, there
Hello, princess"-
How have you been?
Not bad-"nice to see you
Where' s your love life?
Which love life?
Mousie
Oh, Mousie---
She got picked up an hour ago
by a Rolls Royce
Are you sad?
Sad?
We had a moment-"no complaint
How about yourself?
Have you met the man you like?
Love turned out to be a bummer
Why aren' t you with him?
He' s a jerk
So what?
You love a jerk?
Yes, I do
What are you waiting for then?
Go find him and be happy
It makes sense
LQt: Q . 1L1 MD in
You won' t be here forever
I' ll show you how it' s done
Chou
Hello-"just call me Pat
Don't mind me---finish what you're doing
You really know
how to make yourself at home, don' t you?
I don' t really mind
Why don' t you fill me in?
I told you when I' m in---
my name is Patricia
Where is Tom?
You' re a friend?
I mean he knows you?
I'm his fiance-"he should know me
Fiance?
His room mate is in the back there"-
but he' s tied up right now
I' ll see to that-"no problem
Go right ahead
You know her?
I'm not interrupting anything, I hope
Do you mind waiting me outside?
I love to---...
just call me until you finish
Are you Sakia?
Call me Manico
So, did you find what you want?
And more...
Can I take a bath?
Sure, why not?
There' s a bathroom upstairs
Don't put too much oil, Manico
Anything else?
For the moment that' ll be all
Hi,there---
Do I know you?
Why you ask silly question?
Did you hear me ask who you' re?
No, but"-
Is it okay if I share the water?
What?
Do you mind?
No
Who is the girl?
Huh?
The girl in his bed
What girl in what bed?
The bitch with Tom
His girl friend-"you know Tom?
I should-"I do
I' m his fiance
It' s good
Will you pass me the soap?
Thanks
Have been together very long?
Who?
Tom and the girl he had in bed
Half a month, I guess
It' s not real then
I understand how you feel
I don' t think that matters much
Don't you care him with other girl?
You want to wash my back?
Okay
Be careful when you wash my bottom"-
it' s fragile
Oh, come on...
Wash-"I don' tfeel a thing
lhOpe...
Let me show you-"turn around
The bottom-"now how do you feel?
Nice
Next of kin turns on, right?
Shall I do the front?
Really?
You think I play you off?
Turn aroundmyou' re not afraid?
Gosh, no-"allow me---only not used to
Oh, so tiny"-
Is this something you always laugh at?
No, we can fix that
Why should I have to leave
for that bitch?
Don't give me a hard time
We haven' t finished---
What are you doing?
Don t go away
Is that all it is?
We have a problem now
You got to hang on with it---
or try it yourself- --bye
Did Tom split too?
Answer me-"did Tom split it gone?
Well, what' s the marvel"-
you've been funny
Why you ask a silly question?
I hope she didn't go mad
She surely did
Would you console her?
Huh?
Glad to see me?
What do you think?
Why did you leave me alone so long?
You were not exactly alone
Getting company is nothing to me---
only one time-"like you
ls one girl enough for you?
It depends who she is
Stupid
Man, why didn't you pick her up?
Either
Oh, I need a drink
I doubt if you need more than that
Why you return?
Well, maybe I felt like you
If I were in love,
I' d send roses
I have a lot to learn
Start now
There' s a rose on the table
That' s for you
For you is white-"it tells you something
It tells me I' ve been stupid
You' re right-"only no more than I
So, what now?
So, you don' t know?
You' re all that I want
I' m so happy back with you, Tom
We can do it another time
We should be together, right?