We can't overlook
that age is a factor here,
particularly in recovery time.
Have you been taking any pain medications?
Ibuprofen.
Any history of opioid use?
No.
Well, I'm
surprised you can manage it.
The nerve impingement alone
has got to be very painful.
How about sensation?
Still having numbness in the fingers?
It takes a couple days to come back.
Well, soon it might not.
How soon?
Hello.
That was gorgeous, Jane.
Thank you.
Get it, Sexual.
Dancers speaking in German...
Singing in German...
Announcer speaking in German...
Reporter.
♪ New love ♪
Oh, Aurora.
Driver speaking in German...
♪ Soon enough, love is tragic ♪
♪ You're falling back to Earth ♪
Two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Energy, don't just mark it.
This is not the zombie follies
or whatever the hell you call this.
Six, seven, eight.
Energy, energy, energy, energy.
♪ But don't crush ♪
- T-Bone.
- Hey, baby.
Hey, Spenny.
You're late, Hawkins.
There she is.
Welcome home, honey.
Good.
Go get more height, though, come on.
- Please.
- Six, seven, eight, one.
Your eight is late.
God on Earth!
Up, up, up.
Oh, my god, you guys look horrible.
Seriously, seriously, seriously,
let's stop, let's stop.
I've been doing circus shows,
- dinner theaters, you know.
- Ooh, slumming it.
I'm dancing as fast as I can.
Hey, you take whatever
gig, as long as she pays.
Well, not in my relationship.
That's why I'm not in one.
Your husband's loaded.
You don't need a gig.
I'm dancing as fast as I can too, girl.
Well, you look good slumming it.
She's been here five minutes.
What, you disagree?
And here we go.
There's something going here.
What's different?
- Change your hair?
- Mm, no.
It's her new boyfriend.
- Woo-hoo.
- Where you been, girl?
- Ooh.
- She gets D-1.
This is what you call seniority, people.
I can't believe this is
gonna be the last tour.
Don't believe it.
Yo, we're back in!
♪ If I burn it down ♪
♪ Until my life ♪
Good.
Come on.
♪ And you start telling me ♪
♪ The truth about it ♪
Oops.
Hey, cut the playback, please.
We're not gonna have a third tier on set
the first couple of
dates, so we gotta modify.
- Okay.
- All right, let's take it
from the second verse.
Second verse, right, or
is this the second chorus?
Yes, yes, got it.
- Do it.
- I'm over here.
All right.
♪ And be through with you ♪
♪ Gonna burn it down ♪
Good.
Okay!
♪ And I start feeling safe and sound ♪
Lean it back.
Okay, here we go.
All right.
Right here, turn and cluster around her.
Remember, jewels in the crown, people.
Good, and then we're gonna turn right.
No, wait.
No.
Left.
Cut it!
Paloma!
Come here!
Come over here.
You know the numbers, right?
Could you please get off
your phone for a second?
You know the numbers?
Uh, kind of, but...
Go on in.
Let's take it from the second verse.
Get in there, honey.
You got this.
- Yeah.
- Ugh.
It's so bright in here.
Jesus.
Ladies and gentleman, Paloma.
Paloma, Paloma.
Ready, T-Bone.
And.
Good.
♪ And I start feeling safe and sound ♪
♪ And you start telling me ♪
Okay!
Take a quick break, and keep warm.
You and I are gonna watch playback.
Spenny, I have two
left feet, you know this.
Yeah, well, so does your mom.
Don't make me do this.
Hi.
I'm Runa Wolff.
Your agent said you were okay with me
writing a piece on you.
Yeah. Hi.
Aurora's the superstar.
She's the story.
Oh, but that number you choreographed
for the Grammys was incredible.
People need to know who you are.
- Piece of gum?
- Do I need it?
Oh, no, I was just offering.
All right, just in case.
Do you mind if I ask
you a few questions?
Shoot.
So, they still call you The Hawk.
You did your homework.
Yeah, it's harder when it's
pre-internet history, but...
Well, that's prehistoric.
I want to sit down with
you, tonight, I hope,
and get a real in-depth
interview about your career
and celebrate everything
that's happening here,
but, first, a little history.
- History?
- Oh, I'll take it.
Life for me started
when I learned how to fly.
- Your aerial career.
- Mm.
Yes, well, we'll get to that, but...
Life starts at flight,
that makes for a great headline, actually.
But there is a gap from
your gymnastics career.
Yeah, well, you did your homework,
so you know how that ends.
This is the story that's worth telling.
Hey, you know what, I'm so sorry,
I just realized that I
have to go do something.
We can talk after rehearsal, okay?
Okay.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Are you the reporter?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Cool.
Hey, aren't you...
The daughter.
And I'm out of the will
if I don't do something useful, so...
You seem nice.
Write that you saw me doing this, okay?
Okay.
You okay?
Yeah.
I'm good, I'm good.
Listen, while
I figure a few things out,
can you get them up in the air?
Oh, I thought I'd give them
a day to settle in, at least.
We don't have time to settle in.
- Hey, you.
- Hey.
New lighting units
are going in right here.
- T-Bone.
- Oh, we've got time.
Is this a load issue?
Mm-mm, new ones are actually lighter.
Jane.
Well, don't worry.
No, wait, can they share the same truss?
We're not starting from scratch.
I know it's not from scratch.
Downstage motors gonna
- have to shift.
- T-Bone, give us a minute.
Yeah, Iris has a wrist thing
anyway, so it's probably...
- Iris is indestructible.
- Chief, this will take
- two seconds.
- Yeah, well, they're
my two seconds.
Yeah, but safety first, right...
We don't have time for safety first!
Can you get them in the fucking air?!
We have two weeks.
It's not enough time.
Can you just make it happen?
Yes, we can work low.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
What are you looking at, Hathaway?
Fuck.
I'm gonna go hang some hammocks.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
The fuck was all that about?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Okay, let's do it again.
And one, two, three, four, and spin,
six, seven, eight, up and in,
three, four, bird arms,
six, seven, eight, and up,
two, three, four, five,
six, seven, splat it!
Yes!
Now that's a good time.
Waking up.
- Oh, Lord.
- Hey.
How is it?
It was easier last year.
Ha, you were in better shape.
Girl, has anybody washed these?
You know they haven't.
Hathaway, would you...
I know, have they?
Would you have them
run through this please?
Oh, yeah, yeah, sure.
Hey, you guys, do it again.
Stay low, please, and
don't do anything stupid.
She's ready, but,
look, it's your decision.
I just need to make this happen now.
Yeah, we're gonna have to go to,
like, plan B or plan C
or whatever the fuck.
And I was just in there and I almost was,
like, passing out, so...
Of course.
All right.
Thank you, Richard.
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
It's not, it's back.
I'm out here smoking like
it's the fucking cure.
Does Aurora know?
You know how
spooked she gets before a tour.
Spencer.
I just told Richard, though.
Fuck, I thought I could get
you guys through rehearsals.
You don't have to.
We got this.
What about you?
Are you up for this?
How's the body?
I'm fine.
I'm scared, Jane.
Come on, come on.
We've survived the road and each other,
and we've thrived on the
road with each other.
It's been the greatest
experience of my life
to be part of this family.
But you guys are all gonna have
to go out there without me.
I'm sorry.
But I know you can handle it.
You're all well-behaved.
I'm not looking at you, Hathaway.
But if there are, like, any
squabbles going forward,
Jane is now senior officer on deck.
Okay, got my cigs, I'm
gonna go stand on a beach.
We're gonna go with you.
No arguments.
- Yeah.
- Paloma, stay and rehearse.
I can't stand in for your
mama anymore, darling.
I can rehearse on a beach.
Hey, we all can rehearse
- on the beach.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- I'll bring the music.
We love you so much.
Love you so much.
All right, enough, please.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Get him, get him.
Grab my boots.
Bring wine.
Please bring the wine.
Oh, something's come
up, I can't do tonight.
Can we do tomorrow night?
You guys wanted
out of rehearsals, right?
Good excuse.
Hey.
Hi.
I thought the dancers were assigned
the same rooms as last time.
Oh, well, Jane's letting me stay here
so I don't have to drive back to the 'Bu.
Oh.
And so where is Jane crashing?
She didn't tell me.
I barely recognize it.
Sure this is the place?
My eyes aren't that bad.
Seven, one, three, two.
Ow.
Hey.
That little cut is not the issue.
You could barely hold
your knife at dinner.
You should go see the gal
that put me back together.
She can put things back together?
I'll give her a call.
I'll hook you up.
I'm fine.
If you're the director now,
you can take the time to recover.
There were no aerials
in the show before you.
You made this show.
It's a family effort.
Wouldn't take this
family stuff too seriously,
especially with Richard.
He's all right.
You coming in?
I got a long drive.
Oh.
Call her.
Walk me to my car?
I almost forgot.
You're gonna wanna open the gift first,
before you read the card.
Okay.
And don't worry, it's not a knife.
I moved on from those.
Are you kidding me?!
Dan.
Ah, I'm practically cutting
myself on your biceps,
so you must be real.
I wasn't surprised not to
see you at the funeral,
but I thought, "Just maybe."
Well, even if I wanted to
go, Gayle wasn't having it.
Oh, the new wife is always
leery of the old wife, I guess.
Leery?
She sent lawyers after me.
Oh.
She was surprised to discover
my name was still on the title.
That explains it.
Explains what?
When she came to clear out their things,
I caught her trying to throw
out a box of your stuff.
I have stuff?
Just old documents, gymnastic medals,
I put them back in the attic.
She thought I owed David something.
So now you owe her something?
But what?
The house?
No.
They haven't lived here in
forever, so don't sweat it.
He didn't hate me?
No.
To David.
It's a special effects shot.
- Ooh.
- Yeah, and you know what,
it's only our second night,
really, of performing.
- I'm zooming.
- I'm zooming myself in.
Ooh
♪ I flew away for the summer ♪
♪ And you went away with another ♪
♪ I could hear the wind blow ♪
♪ Howling from my stereo ♪
♪ And thinking of what might have been ♪
♪ Is the hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
Paloma.
- Paloma.
- Yeah.
You good?
Hi.
Do you mind if I ask you a few questions?
I'm a Pisces.
Water sign.
Oh, oh, oh, you mean about that one there.
Oh, sure, sure, I got a minute.
Press record, I'll tell
you a couple of stories.
Great.
- All right.
- I don't wanna do this.
I understand that this is hard.
Yeah, 'cause it doesn't take a genius.
Look at me.
I'm not her, I'm nothing
like her, I couldn't be,
- even if I wanted to.
- We don't want your mom,
we want you.
Your body doing the moves.
Your voice singing out.
Oh, no, I'm not doing that.
Paloma, you used to sing like a bird.
Yeah, but I don't anymore, all right?
That's her thing.
She owns that thing.
What, all right, let's leave
that at the door, all right?
This is a job, so step up.
If you drag your feet,
we all drag our feet, okay?
But why do I have to sing?
What is the point of that?
Because you've gotta engage,
you've to do it all, that's the act, okay?
This isn't for her, it's for us, okay?
Okay.
And I know you can be cuter.
Come on, come on.
- Come on, come on!
- Okay.
- Come on, okay, okay.
- All right.
Come on, come on, get a
little sass in that ass!
She's ready.
Back to one!
Okay, we're going from the top again,
this one's for Miss Paloma.
Aerialists on the ground,
just land drill, please.
And T-Bone, music.
♪ I'm packing my bags tonight ♪
♪ Watching while you're sleeping ♪
Aw.
♪ Thinking what might have been ♪
♪ Is the hardest part ♪
Spencer never had to sing.
That's right.
Nice.
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
we've got a lonely lyra.
Where's Hathaway?
Hathaway!
Hath...
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
What?!
♪ Happy birthday, dear Jane ♪
Director One!
Yes!
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Yeah!
Check it.
- Yeah.
- Check it!
Somebody eat this.
Come on.
Not if we're gonna keep twirling.
We've been in the air enough.
Come on.
My boys will take care of that.
- Oh, yeah.
- Come on, join in, join in.
57 candles, if you must report the truth.
Oh, I can leave that part out.
Oh, that's all right, I don't care.
You got a cut?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
It's nothing.
Hey!
What's happening?
It's Jane's birthday!
Oh, my god!
Jane, come over here.
It's my birthday.
570 years!
Call the fire department.
That's a crazy family
- we got here.
- Yeah, I love it.
I turned and I looked and it was Jane.
And even though she fell flat on her face,
she still came off stage
and said, "Good show."
Oh, I was there.
But, you know, Jane only
had a small wild phase.
And maybe only made one mistake.
- Mm-hm.
- Several times.
- Oh, yeah.
- Just the one, one mistake,
- but more than once.
- Several times.
Yeah.
But again and again.
Uh, can I help you?
I was supposed to wait for Richard,
but wanted to see how you guys rehearse.
I'm Xavier.
Zee, for short.
I'm gonna be taking over for Spencer.
Like hell you are.
Yeah, should've waited for Richard.
Look, I just want you guys to know
that I am a big fan of Spencer's work.
He did some cool stuff back in the day.
And I get his style, so
this will go seamless.
This is so not happening.
Wait, I thought Jane was director now.
Yeah.
You're Jane Hawkins?
I've been looking forward
to working with you.
Happy birthday.
Richard, I don't
understand your thinking.
It should be Jane directing, if anybody.
This guy is like throwing a wrench
- into a well-oiled machine.
- Who is he, anyway?
I've never even heard of him.
Who cares about who he
is and where he came from?
We don't need him.
You a roadie?
Concert technician.
Who's that?
That's a reporter.
And she is not going to
give a shit about you.
She's here for Jane.
And the other one is the
daughter, you know, the daughter,
someone I raised since
she slept in road cases.
Please, don't even think of going there.
Capiche, amigo?
Richard, come on.
She has more experience
- than anybody.
- She has enough
on her plate already.
Her solo's a big part of the act,
she manages all the
aerials, deals with safety.
It's just too much to...
I can deal with safety-
- Ask her to, let me finish.
Just too much to ask because
this is not just another tour,
so we don't want to give the fans
just the same well-oiled
machine, but some real surprises,
and some fresh blood is
gonna help us do that.
Come on, we have to open our arms here,
and let some new family in,
especially now that
Spencer's stepping away.
Come on, let's just commit
to putting on a show
that everyone will remember
for the rest of their lives.
Okay?
Jane?
Does Aurora know?
Yes.
Okay, then.
So, let me see what you've
been rehearsing up there.
Oh, we spent all morning in the air.
We're done.
Ah, but you've been resting,
partying, arguing about me.
Come on.
Let me see it.
Please.
You good?
- Yeah.
- Okay, then.
One.
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
Two.
♪ But you can return ♪
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ You can't go back, but you can return ♪
That was great.
Really great.
Just want to try something, though.
What's your name?
Iris.
I want you to switch with Hathaway.
Can they switch positions?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Don't have to run the
whole thing, just want to see
what this looks like.
It's just those abs and those abs...
Creating symmetry, people.
Okay, thank you. Let's run it.
Jane, can you have Iris
hang on the hang thing
for just, like, two eights more?
Just till we hit blackout.
The meat hook?
Yeah.
I love you.
Okay, and music please.
I'm Zee.
- Runa.
- Seven, eight, one.
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
Two.
- Iris, you good?
- Yeah.
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
You okay?
Iris.
Oh, my god.
- Oh, shit.
- Oh, my god, oh, my god.
- Oh, my god.
- Iris.
Move for me, move for me.
You okay?
Are you sure?
Just knocked
the air out of you.
Oh, Iris.
Oh, my god.
Hey, this is a closed set.
- I thought...
- Not a word of this gets out,
or all access is cut.
Hey.
Oh, come on, what's happening?
Did that hurt that much?
It didn't hurt me.
Oh, honey.
Oh, Iris, Iris.
So, she's good?
Yeah, she's pregnant,
so we're gonna need to
make some adjustments.
Well, what do you
mean "make some adjustments"?
Define "adjustments."
And another thing, when
I say we're done rehearsing
in the air, we're done
rehearsing in the air.
Oh, hold on, I didn't
hire the pregnant lady.
She's six weeks.
She didn't know she was gonna keep it.
Now she knows, we can make some changes.
I'm sorry, no.
That is definitely not happening.
That is not a part of her contract
and it's not a part of the show.
Why are we even talking about
this, it's abs, abs, symmetry!
Okay, I might know a couple
of people who are available.
That's okay, I got this.
Wait, these are very specialized skills.
There aren't very many
dancers who can do aerials,
much less aerialists that can dance.
I said I got this.
You know, I was wondering
why you looked so good.
You remember Carmen
from the Brittany tour?
- Mm-hm.
- She's got two kids now.
- Right?
- You'll be fine.
- I know.
- Iris.
What size are you?
No, that motherfucker
is not trying to fit
someone else into your costume.
What the hell, man?
Hathaway, why do I think
we're gonna get along so great?
I have no idea.
Listen, I'm sorry that
Iris has to quit, and you do,
and I know that everyone
wanted to celebrate,
but now we're a person short,
which means we have to find
and train a someone new,
and this is not me
being insensitive, okay?
She's known for, what, six weeks?
Dude, seriously.
Yeah, seriously.
So what's her size?
A zero, obviously.
Thank you.
Look, I'm just gonna put this all out here
just so we're all on the same page:
This show might've been a walk
in the park back in the day,
but not this time.
We are going to refresh the older numbers,
we're gonna add some new
ones, so eat your Wheaties,
lose some weight, drink your Ensure...
Hold up.
"Drink your Ensure"?
You Dunning-Kruger motherfucker.
Bianca.
You see what's he's doing, right?
I mean, they didn't send him
in here to tweak the show.
No, they brought this genius
in here to blow it up.
- Yup.
- Mm-hm.
"Drink your Ensure"?
Bitch, I can run rings around you.
We all can.
She's right.
You know what?
Come on, Iris.
- No, Bianca...
- No, no, this girl's
got a real family going on,
I'm gonna go be a part of that,
'cause this one here is dead.
- Come on now, it's cool.
- You'll see.
Come on, Bianca.
You'll see.
Okay.
Anyone else?
You've said enough.
Hey, if the wheels are gonna come off,
- I'd rather it be now.
- Oh, you want something
- to come off, buddy?
- Hey, okay, all right,
everybody calm down.
Bianca will change her mind.
Change her mind?
When has she ever done that?
Okay, we're on break.
Fuck.
Jane.
- Hey.
- He kicked me out.
I'll get you back in tomorrow.
Tell him you're my assistant.
Well, what about tonight?
The interview?
Tomorrow night, I promise.
Well, I can't, I've got a flight.
Can we just do this over the phone.
You gotta get down here.
Iris and Bianca just quit.
This guy is toxic.
Look, I don't
know what to tell you.
Artists need to try new
things to stay relevant,
and this guy is the new thing.
Richard.
I'm sorry, but
everyone is expendable.
Expendable?
Hello?
Hi.
Is this Kelly?
Yeah, this is Kelly.
Hey, Kelly, it's Jane.
I was calling Aurora.
Oh, I'm sorry,
she's not available.
Hey, I'm just curious,
this is her private line, isn't it?
It is, but
Richard changed her number,
he just wants her in the bubble.
He's got her on lockdown, no
distractions until we open.
Could you give me that number?
It's really important.
I would, but you
can only get it from Richard.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Thanks.
Take care.
I was 43 when I stopped
trying to have a baby.
A doctor told me I was too old.
Now Iris is having one at 43.
I have two now.
Somewhere.
I have a career.
I'm not gonna let that twerp burn it down.
The oldest aerialist in rock and roll.
You do know how dumb that sounds, right?
It's what I got.
I mean, that's not even a category.
Anyway, I can't quit.
I leased my place in Vegas.
Let me go ahead and
state the obvious here:
You're in a house you own.
Maybe it's time you got off the road.
And do what?
Give massages?
Hey.
I was in the hood
and wanted to talk to
you about what happened.
But I see you're busy, so.
Hey.
Catch you tomorrow.
Thank you, for the cake
and remembering.
That reporter was asking a
bunch of questions about you.
Seemed kinda personal.
I hope you don't mind I
just told her to fuck off.
I want one of
these everywhere I go today.
Did I miss a party?
Nope!
Just fulfilling my destiny.
Someone's gotta bring up the rear.
Mm, nice voice.
Compared to who?
I need to find some other
way to impress Mother.
I read some interviews
where she had nothing
but nice things to say about you.
Can you interview me so I
can get a message back to her?
What do you think of Jane?
I think I like her better
when she's not playing second mom.
Oh, god.
So comfortable.
Hey, are you guys dancers on this show?
Thank you.
That is better than being carded.
Come on, dancer's are this way.
Let's go.
Good Morning.
Hey, I'm sorry about yesterday.
Had to do that for legal reasons.
But I guess, if you're
gonna do a story about Jane,
falling's gonna be part of it.
You have free reign today.
Thank you.
On one condition, though:
If you solve the mystery
that is Jane Hawkins, please tell me.
Over drinks sometime.
Sure.
Hey, I'm Beth.
Taylor.
That's Mom, I'm Dad.
♪ Don't crush ♪
♪ Crush ♪
♪ Ooh, if it's early days,
expect an early night ♪
♪ Don't crush ♪
♪ Crush ♪
♪ Ooh, until they treat you right ♪
♪ You can never trust your crush ♪
Okay, so I know that the
choreography has been the same
for the last few tours,
but let's give it a twist.
Jane, Hathaway, in the
back, men in the middle,
Taylor and Beth up front.
I've been loving this
whole expressionistic flow.
It's like a greasy robot thing.
T-Bone, music.
♪ Don't crush ♪
♪ Crush ♪
♪ Ooh, if it's early days,
expect an early night ♪
♪ Don't crush ♪
♪ Crush ♪
♪ Ooh, until they treat you right ♪
♪ You can never trust your crush ♪
Hey, hold, everyone.
Zee, can I...
Is there a problem?
No, I'm good.
These girls are beautiful dancers,
but I need to see if they can fly.
So you want the room.
Yeah, and another thing...
Always another thing.
Have you thought about what these babies
are gonna look like next to Aurora?
It's the whole point.
This is not the Dinosaur Tour anymore.
What is the point of this?
To see how strong you are.
Beth, you're up.
I have great form.
What's the first thing
to go when you're weak?
You're gonna say form.
Mm.
Great.
All right, show me your form.
Take your time.
Safety first, okay?
I know.
Jane, honey?
Look what I found.
You're an archeologist, T-Buddy.
Yeah, well, let's just
show him what you got, huh?
Hey.
How they doing?
Beth is strong.
Taylor not so much.
Stick her in a circle thing.
A lyra?
I'm not putting anyone in
the air who isn't safe.
Look, putting dancers in the air
is supposed to be your thing, so do that.
Please.
Thank you.
♪ I know you ♪
♪ The kinda man that can go astray ♪
♪ And you know me, the
kinda girl who can play ♪
♪ But you better not fade away ♪
♪ I can feel your heartbeat kicking in ♪
♪ You can feel my blood start simmering ♪
♪ With every little touch ♪
♪ We slip and we spin like
a top about to fly off ♪
♪ So hold me, hold me, or lose me ♪
♪ Yeah, you gotta hold
me, hold me, or lose me ♪
♪ Yeah, you gotta hold me,
hold me, hold me, hold me ♪
♪ Or you're gonna lose me, lose me ♪
♪ Lose me, lose me once again ♪
That's not already in the show?
Huh?
No, it got cut.
Nobody's ever seen it.
It's good, huh?
Yeah, it's fantastic.
Let's put the new girls in it.
What?
You said yourself, Taylor's
a little physically weak,
so this will be perfect for her.
No, no, no.
Does everything have to be a battle?
Okay.
What the fuck?
- No, it's good.
- This is our thing.
No, no, fuck that, no.
Hathaway, I...
Jamal.
Beth, Taylor.
Now.
Climb up.
Go ahead.
Go up.
All right.
Twinkles.
- Darling.
- Mm.
Do me a favor?
Grab a mop.
Oh, I'm not cleaning that up.
- No.
- Thank you.
I don't need money this bad.
We can't let this happen.
Yeah, you're gonna go
up, you're gonna go down
- and down there.
- No, yeah, I don't really,
no, just...
No, I don't think we need,
just send me somebody...
A word with you, Satan?
Yeah, I'll just call you.
The fans know us as The Family
and we have been performing
for them for nearly 20 years,
and you come in here and
treat us like we're nothing?
- Okay, okay, hold on.
- That is not okay.
- Hold on a second.
- No, he needs to hear this.
It's either us or him.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Yeah, really.
Bubba, okay, calm down.
Could you give us some space?
No, I kinda want to hear this.
Would you please come with me?
Come on.
The fans would've loved to
see Iris, just getting bigger,
and we could have had a dancer replace her
- when the time comes.
- No, listen, listen...
Bianca, all she needed was for us
to say that The Fam is still The Fam.
Bianca made her own choice.
Okay, well, then let's make ours.
It's either us or him.
- We're going to Richard.
- Richard doesn't care.
That's what I'm trying to tell you...
Then we go to the diva.
No, I don't know that she cares.
Richard told me that all
of us are expendable,
every single one of us.
- What?
- Yes, exactly.
And that means he is too.
If we say we're all outta here,
then Richard will fire him
- in a heartbeat.
- He won't.
He...
Come on, yes, he will.
- Let's do it.
- Let's go.
No, no, no, no.
I can't. I can't.
Okay, Jane, come on.
We fight together.
I know you're scared, it's all right.
It's too risky, I can't.
Dammit, this doesn't work without you.
You'd really just let me go?
Please.
You have to destroy everything?
- Jane.
- Please,
- it's not that simple.
- Jane.
It's not.
It really is.
Watch.
You suck.
I quit.
See? Simple.
Is that it for today?
Hold tight.
Janie.
I wanna get down.
Come down.
All right, come down easy.
Come down easy.
All right, you're okay.
Okay.
That's it, I'm done.
Don't go. Please.
I'm already gone.
Please, come on.
You know, I was counting
on the money for this.
I already leased my apartment for this,
but, Jane, I'm not gonna do this!
And I can't believe I let them
go and I didn't follow them.
But you know what?
It's because I always followed you!
Sure you still want to do this?
Yes.
I felt I had to lie
about my age at first,
but then I really learned
that you can't tell
how old someone is on stage,
especially when they're in the air,
so I booked work in Vegas pretty quick.
And you reconnected with Serena.
I saw some video of you two rehearsing.
Yeah.
You made the gymnastics
team for the 1980 Olympics.
And then Russia invaded Afghanistan.
Ah, the boycott.
And you tried again in '84,
but ruptured your Achilles.
Yeah, that's what I was known for.
But what happened after that?
You dropped off the radar.
Couple years of suicidal thoughts.
Can I show you something?
Where did you get this?
At the gymnastic
camp where you taught.
This was how I bounced back.
You started performing.
Mm.
I found one reference of you
training for the '88 Olympics
with a coach named Sergei Kilinski.
Is that true?
Yes.
So you were trying
for your third Olympics.
It's all I knew how to do.
I was too old, probably.
I didn't realize how much
the sport was changing,
it was getting tougher, younger.
The young girls can do these crazy tricks.
Their center of gravity is higher.
They don't have any hips.
I'm sorry, it's my own private summer.
Sergei was expensive.
How did you afford him?
I had a sponsorship with IGC.
A sponsorship?
Well, I didn't have
him that long, anyway.
When I didn't make it to
the trials, I walked away.
I got married.
I'm sorry about your ex.
David would sit right
where you're sitting.
Did you ever want to have kids?
Let's not make the
article about that stuff.
You called the dancers your family.
They are.
Family is important to you.
Sure.
Then why didn't you fight for them?
Excuse me?
Seems like you could have today.
You know what?
I think it's time for sleep.
Okay, I'm sorry, I'm just
trying to get inside your head
so I can paint the right picture.
You're clearly very driven.
Your life reflects that.
You seem to choose career
over relationships, though,
which I'm not judging, I'm
just trying to figure out
whether you're naturally a loner
or whether you wanted family
and it didn't work...
I want to go to sleep.
Okay.
You do realize that I'm
trying to write an article
about you, the person, not
just the stuff you've done.
I need more from you than stuff
I could get off the internet, so please,
I'm sorry to get intense here,
but I've come a long way.
Let me in a little bit.
I'm sorry if you're the
latest person I let down today.
Thank you for your time.
What kind of story are you writing?
I was hoping a good one.
Might be too late for that.
♪ It was just one year ago ♪
♪ We were building a fire ♪
♪ And letting it grow ♪
♪ Then you stole my heart ♪
♪ But you left my soul ♪
♪ You're my heartbreaker ♪
What the hell?
I wanted to bring the
kids in for early rehearsal.
You already know the choreography.
Actually, I'm kinda changing it.
There are seven of them.
Warm up, jump in the
back when you're ready.
♪ So good together ♪
♪ It wasn't a lie ♪
All right, from the top.
Sergei was expensive.
How did you afford him?
I had a sponsorship with IGC.
A sponsorship?
Well, I didn't have
him that long, anyway.
When I didn't make it to
the trials, I walked away.
I got married.
Eight, and spin it, two, three, four, hup!
Up, up, up, up, up!
Up, stand up!
I didn't say splits.
And splits.
Seven, eight, back to double stag.
Find it, find it.
Beth, more arch, more arch.
Straighten your legs,
straighten your legs.
Okay, hop up.
Everybody ready?
Pencil spin.
Hands on, beautiful sous sous.
Gorgeous.
Beautiful.
Try looking like you enjoy
it, that would be nice.
Hi, yes, I'm trying
to find some information
about the past IGC sponsorships.
I called earlier.
Yeah, yeah, I'll hold.
♪ Soon enough, love is tragic ♪
♪ You're falling back to Earth ♪
♪ Then it's six feet further, why ♪
♪ Do I ♪
Okay.
Thank you for going to the trouble.
I saw you once, in
Vegas, when I was a kid
and I told my mom, "That's
what I want to do,"
but she wasn't having it,
not after she saw your friend fall.
Ah.
So I'm kinda getting a late start.
I was 42 when I started,
so you're not late.
Jump up.
So what
have you done to yourself?
I don't know.
I stopped going to see doctors.
You do know that I'm a doctor, yes?
Resist.
Well, I know that you helped Serena, so.
Mm-hm. This way.
This way.
Yes, I did help Serena.
Lay on your stomach.
That was hard for her.
She had to stop.
I wouldn't tell you to stop.
Plus, athletes never listen anyway.
They push through, until they break.
I don't think it's age with
you, I think it's injury.
Age is an injury
Oh, so this is it?
Yeah.
Any other big falls?
I was attempting an Omelianchik on beam.
Well, what would possess you to do that?
I was young and stupid.
Can you turn over for me?
That is not a move somebody
does in their spare time.
I was training for '88.
Oh, you were trying
to get back in there.
Mm-hm.
Oh, you fell, you landed right here.
Yes.
I thought so.
How can you tell?
The body remembers.
Hey.
What's going on?
You okay?
I've done everything wrong.
I made the wrong choices.
Hey now.
I did it to myself.
The body remembers, and
it never forgave me.
Hey, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
I don't have anybody.
I'm alone.
Hey, I count, a little.
And you've got your dancing family.
No, I let them down.
I let everybody down.
Everyone lets everyone down,
says or does something stupid.
That's what families do.
It's too late.
Maybe not.
I mean, if it really was a family,
there's gotta be some forgiveness there,
if it's worth anything.
Like, I'm forgiving you right now
for getting snot on my favorite shirt.
Hey, hey.
Really.
The family you choose,
you can choose again.
Hey, Hollis.
Hey, hummingbird.
I just need a minute with her.
Can't, she's in the bubble right now.
Have you heard about The Fam?
No.
All gone, everyone, except me.
Fucking Richard?
You know what?
He can try to get rid of me too.
Thank you.
♪ I break down in all this ecstasy ♪
♪ I just crush ♪
♪ And give all I have to ♪
You're supposed to be rehearsing.
The show we're working
on isn't her show anymore,
and I think she should know it.
She does know.
Hollis doesn't know.
That means she doesn't know.
You know what?
I don't have to explain this to you.
We need to cut overhead.
It's just business.
You didn't want to
buy out our contracts,
so you want us to quit.
You need us to quit.
It's her last tour.
People are gonna come no
matter what kind of show it is,
or who's in it.
You bastard.
Jane!
It's been fun.
Fun's not over.
♪ You can never trust your crush ♪
Ooh, y'all putting in
some good work today.
Damn.
All right, I want you to
enjoy your day off tomorrow,
but don't party too hard... Taylor.
All right, we gotta big week coming up,
Aurora is here on Friday!
Woo, woo!
So start getting it in your
brains that, when she's here,
you don't make eye contact with her.
Okay?
Skedaddle.
Jane!
Yeah?
I want to be really clear on this,
so I'm gonna make eye contact
with you: I'm the director.
You got a problem, you come to me,
you don't go over my head, ever.
Well, I'm the aerial choreographer,
so I'm kind of over
your head all the time.
I'm cutting your solo.
I could drop a motor on him.
Insurance will cover it.
Our girl deserves better.
She does.
Mm-hm.
Do you still have
the keys to this place?
Mm-hm.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
I'm thinking, "How is
it we're the same age?"
You were right.
Oh, my god.
I miss you.
I missed you too.
You're glowing.
I'm not nauseous.
Hathaway, you home?!
Come on.
Now the road's gonna go on with out us,
be like we were never there.
I wonder if Aurora is
even going to notice.
So, who was that guy
with the greasy hands?
Don't tell me he was a masseuse.
I'm not buying it.
My neighbor.
No.
If I've been running cold lately,
it's because I am so
very, very goddamned hot.
They should call them burn flashes.
Ah.
It's not you.
Wow.
Cheers, young lady.
To a family that matters.
To the family that matters.
Woo.
So, what's this crazy idea you have?
♪ When you fall ♪
♪ You fall down ♪
♪ When you do ♪
♪ When it happens to you ♪
♪ Let me be your ground ♪
♪ You're like a meteorite ♪
♪ Like a volcano at night
lighting up the sky ♪
♪ No matter how you fall ♪
♪ You rise up ♪
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ No matter how you fall ♪
♪ I won't let you hit the ground ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm gonna catch your fall ♪
♪ You're gonna get back up ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm gonna catch your fall ♪
♪ You're gonna get back up ♪
Okay.
Yeah, do the double stag.
Yeah, that's good.
Beautiful.
Yes.
Awesome.
Great, there we go.
♪ When you do ♪
♪ When it happens to you ♪
♪ I will keep you safe and sound ♪
Jane?
How does that feel, from one to ten?
Eight.
How can you sleep at an eight?
I dream of a seven.
I said I would never
tell you this, but stop.
Just keep me in one piece
a little bit longer, okay?
That's not my actual job.
You know that, right?
♪ Kiss your heart goodbye again ♪
♪ Can't believe you're
letting someone in ♪
♪ Oh, you'll finally get what you give ♪
♪ Oh, like you never ever did ♪
♪ Oh, and as long as you
live, you and I know ♪
♪ You're gonna throw it into the dark ♪
♪ Let it go and only hope
your heart's all right ♪
♪ 'Cause it can't take
another break down ♪
Why are you all so tired all the time?
Tired of your shit is my guess.
♪ I left the keys in the hallway ♪
♪ And whispered the
line that they all say ♪
♪ Can't go back, but you can return ♪
♪ You can't go back, but you can return ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ And maybe when the wind blows ♪
♪ You'll hear me in your stereo ♪
Paloma.
It's distracting.
Lip-sync.
Hey, I want the circle things, the lyras,
to spin in the opposite
direction when the chorus hits.
No.
No?
No, it's not possible.
I mean, physically.
Were you under the
impression those are motorized,
because they're on swivels.
It's momentum that's making
these young'uns spin around.
It's nothing else but mass times velocity.
Can't just change the laws of physics
when the chorus hits, kid.
I actually had to Google Dunning-Kruger.
You know what?
You're fired.
Pack your shit!
All right, that's
it, everyone take 30.
30?
Jane!
- Oh, god.
- Jane!
You're not running this show.
I can make a safety call anytime.
Check my contract.
Yeah, well, it's in my contract
that I'm the director,
which means I get some goddamn respect!
You think that?!
Yes!
For fuck's sake, what is your problem?
You're supposed to be a team player.
Richard said, "Don't worry about Jane."
He did?
Yeah, but all I have is
Jane all up in my face,
contradicting me in front of everybody,
shitting on my ideas,
and shutting down my fucking rehearsals.
I'm actually trying to help you.
Oh, because you think that
I don't know what I'm doing.
I've choreographed quite
a few tours before.
Not with this many elements.
Not with aerials.
Yeah, but I have the vision.
That's why I got the gig.
That's why I get respect.
Got it?
Okay, just listen to people
with more experience than you, okay?
Just do that.
- Oh, just try that.
- Mm-hm.
Learn from the ancient ones.
You know what your problem is?
You want this gig.
Get over it.
Fire me.
Go ahead. Fire me.
You can't, you can't.
You can't do what I do.
You cut my solo, for what?
To get back at me?
You just lost your costume change.
- Okay, well...
- You can't fire T-Bone.
He's the most important
person on this tour.
They would fire you a hundred
times before they fired him,
and the reason you don't know
that is because you're green.
You don't know how a tour works,
you don't know how I work,
and you certainly don't know how close
you just came to losing an arm.
You grind me down without a clue
that I am the best person
to have in your corner.
And the worst part about it is,
you have no fucking clue
that you're being used.
Hey.
Still here?
I'm sorry about the other night.
Is that it?
Is that the article?
Why did you lie to me?
I lied to you?
When you said you had a
sponsorship with the IGC.
I did have a sponsorship with the IGC.
With the IGC.
No, I mean for '88.
I checked and you didn't.
Maybe my memory's failing too.
Is that something I should write about?
What is your deal?
I agreed to a story about
my aerial career, that's it.
But you're digging into my history,
asking everyone questions that
are none of your business.
It's a story about you, Jane.
Of course I'm gonna ask questions.
But why stuck on the past?
Why?
I wanted to know how you got here.
And why focus on my failure
trying to get into the Olympics?
It's your gymnastics career.
How is that off base to ask?
Because I don't want
my entire life exposed.
It's just background information.
Fine.
Totally off the record,
but how did a young woman
with no affiliation,
sponsors, or financial support
pay for a top coach like Sergei Kilinski?
Are you even a reporter?
- What?
- You wanna know
how much money I had, how
I could afford Sergei,
you're looking for dirt
in my personal life.
Are you working for Gayle?
- Who?
- Gayle Bishop.
- I don't know...
- My ex-husband's widow.
- I don't know her...
- I don't owe Gayle
a damn thing.
Tell her to back off.
- Jane...
- And if she thinks
that I have assets that she can have,
she is out of her tiny mind.
I never had any money,
especially after my Achilles.
You wanna know how I paid for Sergei?
I sold my eggs.
And it was the worst thing I ever did.
So whatever it is you're up to,
whatever's written there, just stop.
This story's over.
Told you she was in a bad mood.
I can help you.
Get you a scoop.
"An insider look at today's
most secretive pop star."
Come on, no reporter gets that.
I'll sneak you into tomorrow,
to Aurora's show and tell.
You can at least get
something out of this.
You definitely don't need Jane.
Thank you.
Did you learn anything?
Is she dating somebody?
Is she a martial artist?
Did she give you any hint
that she wants to retire?
I would like to know that.
She's focused on her career.
She doesn't have time for anything else.
How long can that last?
Because she's so old?
Because she's so injured.
You haven't noticed?
Get some sleep, everybody.
Remember, tomorrow, eyes down.
T-Bone, thank you so much
for your continued services.
Mea culpa.
Goodnight.
Easy.
You were right, I need to listen more.
Okay, well, let's just
make a good show, all right?
Yeah, and the thing you
said about the costume change,
yeah, I screwed up.
Okay, obviously, your
solo still has to go in.
The only thing, I
haven't actually seen it,
and right now, I really need to.
This is when
I'm over the audience.
The dancer pulls in the
fabric and I offload.
We actually need to extend
this moment just a bit.
No, no, it fits
perfectly with the music.
No, I added a headdress to her costume,
so it's gonna take a little bit more time.
Can you vamp on it, or something?
Just vamp a bit.
- Okay.
- Just extend it out.
Okay.
That enough?
We just need a little bit longer.
Keep going.
We'll make the music match, don't worry.
Okay.
Almost there.
Good?
No, no, no, keep going.
Okay.
Keep going.
I can't.
I gotta come down.
You really were a time bomb, Hawkins.
Good thing that didn't
happen on the tour, huh?
You want me to call 9-1-1?
No.
- Need to go to the hospital?
- No.
No.
Dislocated.
MRI in the morning.
My guess, surgery in six weeks.
Can you move your fingers?
- No.
- That may come back.
But right now, your body's
making a decision for you.
It wants you to stop
and you have no say in the matter, okay?
Right now, your biggest healing tool
is right there, so use it.
Oh, the director
said I could watch.
Sorry, you're
incorrect, 'cause now, it's my set.
But he promised me.
It's really important...
Hey.
That I'm here.
Hey, no, it's cool,
she's gonna hang in the back.
No, she's not.
Ma'am, please collect your things.
Well, my car is blocked in.
All right, well, you're just
gonna have to wait upstairs.
I'm sorry, let's go.
♪ New love ♪
♪ Can seem like magic ♪
♪ You feel your heart can really fly ♪
♪ You can feel my blood start simmering ♪
♪ Burn it down ♪
♪ Until my life ♪
♪ Is the hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ Back around ♪
I don't understand!
Where are the aerials in that number?
I wanted to
keep it on the ground,
you know, just keep the focus on you.
No, no, I don't
want the focus on me.
Put the aerials back.
And that's your choreography?
Yes, but I was trying to...
emulate Spencer's style.
Oh, honey, I
don't know what you were...
What's up?
How you doing?
What's up, bro?
Hi, how are you, sweetie?
My man.
You okay?
Hey, what happened?
Richard, what's going on here?
It's a new approach.
We just need time to adjust.
There hasn't even
been a single costume change!
What am I supposed to
do, prance around nake...
What's your name?
Runa.
Give me the phone now, Runa.
Now.
I'm sorry, I didn't
know I couldn't listen.
Let's go.
No, no.
I thought we were done.
What's next?
The car's waiting,
but T-Bone says there's one
more number for you to watch.
Uh, no there isn't.
Hey, Zee.
No, this is my set, okay?
- Quiet.
- Shh.
We never play this song.
♪ You never know what life has in store ♪
♪ When you chase a dream
walking out that door ♪
♪ I had his love, but I wanted more ♪
♪ So I traveled further
than I had before ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ When you were born, I was on my own ♪
♪ Ha ha ♪
♪ Just you and me in an empty home ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ha ha ♪
♪ I had your love, but I wanted more ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ha ha ♪
♪ And all the things I never had before ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ So I hit the road ♪
♪ Ooh, and I said goodbye ♪
♪ I left you home ♪
♪ And they danced all night ♪
♪ Danced all night ♪
♪ To my siren songs ♪
♪ And I found my place in the disco wave ♪
♪ And the molly bombs ♪
♪ And the years went by ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ And I missed you grow ♪
♪ So I'm back for good ♪
♪ Now you're my show ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I want you to know ♪
♪ You're my home ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ And you're where I wanna be ♪
♪ This is home ♪
♪ And you're where I wanna be, yeah ♪
♪ It's home ♪
♪ This is home ♪
You're singing again.
A little bit.
Will you come home tonight?
You'll come home too?
Yeah, baby.
I'll come home too.
Janie, my love.
What happened to you?
Are we working you too hard?
Oh, she's been working us.
Midnight rehearsals all week to do this.
We won't all be able to come with you,
but we wanted to give
you a proper farewell.
What do you mean, "farewell"?
Why can't you come?
Well, Iris is pregnant, for starters.
You slut!
But I can still dance.
Then you're coming.
- Ah!
- And what's your excuse?
Well, we didn't fit the new vision.
Yeah, we're not of the new breed.
Basically, we were
told we we're too old.
- Too old?
- Mm.
Who's too old?
Well, to be clear, I never
said anyone was too old,
I was just told to bring
the show up to date.
Up to date?
Yeah, but I agree, that
number was fantastic,
and we are gonna put it in.
"Up to date" is your little
euphemism for "saving money."
Richard, I want The
Family back in the show.
And these new young dancers?
They have been working so hard,
and look at how cute they are.
Let's bring them too.
We can talk about it.
We are talking.
And while we're talking,
The Family already has
one really great director.
And we don't need another one.
Yeah!
You know I can't hit
certain high notes anymore,
so maybe you don't go so high, either.
But you are not quitting.
She's not quitting.
Okay, now, you and I are gonna talk.
Okay, hold on, I was just doing
- whatever you told me to do.
- Hey, Zee.
Let's take a walk, man.
Outside.
- Come on.
- Ooh!
We're a family!
Welcome to the family!
You should take a break to heal.
How are you supposed to
get the show together
if your body's not together?
I'm fine.
You always say that.
Anyway, I was able to get
an extra week of rehearsal in Nice,
so hopefully, we'll able to
work the kinks out there.
Either way, the show must go on.
Okay.
What about this show?
This house.
Well, until I sell
it, do you wanna split
whatever comes in from the rental thing?
Okay.
Every little bit helps.
Dan, you must get a real estate agent.
I told you, I'm not doing that.
Hi.
Got a sec?
We were just leaving.
Well, flight's not till four.
Got a few minutes.
This is Runa.
Ah.
Should've interviewed me.
I know all her secrets.
I'm Dan.
Would you put the bags in the car?
And I'm gonna go put
the bags in the car now.
Give me a hand?
Thank you for sending your articles.
I'm sorry I was so paranoid.
You're a good writer.
Can't imagine what you're
gonna write about me.
We need to take this down.
Well, look at you.
That was really beautiful
what you did for your friends.
Where did you learn to do that?
When I stopped
competing in gymnastics.
A gym rat.
My mom was on the East
German team back in the day.
She wanted a child she
could raise the same way.
She looked and looked to find someone
who'd be the perfect match.
Didn't get the hair color, but otherwise,
she got what she wanted.
Lucky girl.
She's passed on, now.
Oh.
Same thing
that made her infertile
eventually came back.
I'm sorry.
Took a me awhile before
I decided to go looking.
And then when I did, I realized
no one was looking for me,
which made it tougher.
But I'm good at researching.
I know you are.
I always knew there
was a mystery between us,
our differences and
why she called me Runa.
There was a hidden story there,
which is probably why
I got into journalism.
So I kept looking.
When you say looking...
For the perfect match.
I'm really sorry, I have to go.
It was back in '88,
though they didn't end up
doing it for another few years.
They tried and tried, and then it worked.
And they got me.
From you.
I didn't know if you wanted to know.
I had to be certain.
I already had a great mom
and I didn't wanna ruin it,
if somebody didn't want me.
I checked your DNA to be certain.
I stole your Band-Aid.
Sorry.
My arm has to heal so that
I can hold you properly.
It will.
Injury, not age, right?
Yeah
What does Runa mean?
It means secret.
Now I have some questions for you.
Wait a minute, I can't leave.
You have to go.
No way. Dan?
- Dan.
- You rang?
Wait, I need my phone.
- Where's my purse?
- Wait a minute.
- You can't do this.
- What, yes, I can.
- Your bags in the car.
- Give me your phone.
- No, no.
- Okay.
- It's gonna be fine.
- Look, what's happening here?
This is my daughter.
Say hello.
Wait a minute. What?
Yes, and I'm coming off the road
and I'm staying at the
house and I need a phone.
No, this tour's gonna start
- a whole new career for you.
- I don't care.
- I do.
- I'm not leaving you.
It's okay.
This is the story I wanted to tell.
Since I just became an
honorary uncle here, I vote stay.
- Yes.
- No.
You have to go.
You're a director now.
Okay, but if we're gonna
fly, we've gotta fly, now.
- Come on, come on.
- Wait, no, no, don't, no.
It's okay.
I'll be here when you get back.
I promise.
♪ I'm packing my bags tonight ♪
♪ Watching while you're sleeping ♪
♪ Thinking what might have been ♪
♪ Is the hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ I flew away for the summer ♪
♪ And you went away with another ♪
♪ I could hear the wind blow ♪
♪ Howling from my stereo ♪
♪ And thinking of what might have been ♪
♪ Is the hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ I left the keys in the hallway ♪
♪ And whispered the
line that they all say ♪
♪ Can't go back, but you can return ♪
♪ You can't go back, but you can return ♪
♪ And maybe when the wind blows ♪
♪ You'll hear me in your stereo ♪
♪ I traveled all around the world ♪
♪ A journey so revealing ♪
♪ I finally let my fist uncurl ♪
♪ From the anger I was feeling ♪
♪ And thinking of what might have been ♪
♪ Is the hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪
♪ You can't go back, but you can return ♪
♪ Can't go back, but you can return ♪
♪ The hardest part of leaving ♪