The Passengers
I've come to pick up a 4th grade student,
Marc Letessier.
Your name?
Moineau.
Too bad Madame Letessier
could not come.
Moineau.
Excuse me?
She is Madame Moineau now.
Oh, forgive me.
I forgot.
I find her decision to take Marc
out of school regrettable.
It will disturb him needlessly.
Couldn't it wait until summer?
It's not for me to decide.
I hope Marc was not
put in this school...
only because we teach in French.
Do you know if your wife
plans to put Marc...
in a religious institution in Paris?
He will go to a regular school.
Very well.
Tell Marc Letessier his step-father
is waiting in my office.
Has Madame Moineau
quit her job at Air France?
No, she was transfered to Paris.
Come in.
Hello, Marc.
Hello, Madam director.
Hello.
Hello, Alex.
Put your seatbelt on.
We're being followed.
Come on!
I think you lost him
at the turn.
You'll see.
The last time I saw you
we were on familiar terms.
I've forgotten.
Here he is again.
Put your seatbelt on.
He was parked
in front of the school.
I saw him follow us
from there.
Sit up
and put your seatbelt on.
Maybe he's a spy.
Who?
The guy who's following us.
GPU...
Have you heard?
First of all,
it's not GPU...
it's called KGB now.
And why
would they follow us?
Simple!
They mistook our car for another.
A bit amateurish
those spies of yours.
Or maybe
they're industrial spies.
Or a private detective paid by...
the school director
to make sure I donate at churches.
You don't believe in God?
Why do you ask?
Just asking.
Here's the entrance
to the highway.
What are you doing?
Just like I thought.
What?
They're taking the highway too.
Of course!
No law forbids spies
to use the highway.
Will you put
that seatbelt on?
Really, old man,
1897 km of nagging...
Won't be fun.
1897 km?
I did the math
from the map.
We'll be there after tomorrow.
After tomorrow?
Why didn't we fly with mom?
Your mom wanted us
to bring her car.
Your mom loves her car.
Since I love your mom,
I promised to bring her car.
She doesn't want us
to drive at night,...
so it will take 3 days.
If you want the whole story,
your mom figured...
it would do us good
to spend some time together.
So we get to know each other.
She didn't ask my advice
when she married you.
I don't see why
she'd feel guilty now.
Don't flatter yourself, kid.
It's not about guilt.
If you don't want us
to be friends...
your mom will get over it,
and I will too.
It's no tragedy.
So far I like your type.
And what type is that?
The no nonsense type.
What will it be?
Black coffee for me.
And for the young man?
What would you like?
Same thing as you.
You're not having black coffee.
Cappuccino
with lots of milk.
Not a cappuccino!
Makes me sick.
Black coffee at your age?
My age, my age...
Like you know anything.
You don't have to be rude.
Give him what he likes.
A black coffee.
I didn't want to offend you,
but...
I don't like to be treated like this,
that's all.
I am not offended.
Would you like some sugar?
No.
Could you ask for some milk?
It tastes bad.
A drop of milk, please.
Full tank, please.
Don't say anything.
I'll try to guess.
Milan?
Enno, you try.
- Rome?
- No.
- What then?
- Paris.
Two in a row.
Impossible!
Paris!
They all go to Paris!
That's our route?
Yes.
Where do we stay tonight?
Look, it's written there.
Orvieto.
Holiday Inn Hotel.
It's all booked and all that?
And all that.
Couldn't you plan more?
Believe me,
after driving all day...
I'd rather not have to search
for a hotel room.
Like I said:
mom is marrying an organizer.
That's a big change for her.
Really?
Oh yeah.
By the way,
what do you do for work?
Accountant?
Engineer.
What about your career plans?
Hey.
I asked you a question.
Writer.
Writer?
Yes.
Why didn't you want
to tell me?
I was afraid you'd laugh.
Laugh?
I think it's great.
Really?
I'll still have to pay your bills...
when you're 40.
Not necessarily.
Some writers
make a lot of money.
Yes, some do.
Did you see that?
Yes, I did.
How do you explain that?
Simple.
Instead of stopping
at the cafe with us...
he had his coffee break here.
And since his speed
is equal to ours...
it was inevitable
we'd meet again.
Are you convinced?
You'll say the same thing
if we see him after dinner.
If everyone did like you,
life would be easier.
They all come
between 7 and 8.
It's always a big mess.
Now is the perfect time.
- Going far?
- Paris.
I'll take a burger with salad.
Some people are lucky.
All my life I've dreamt
of going to Paris.
You'll go, some day.
How much do you think
I make here?
With or without tips?
With tips.
Not much.
So how could I go to Paris?
- Are you expecting someone?
- No!
- How about...
- Yes, burger and salad.
I am done.
What?
You can't leave all that.
You said you were hungry.
I don't eat very much.
You'll get used to it -
I sleep a lot instead.
I sleep like crazy.
If I'm not woken up,
I sleep 13-15 hours.
It always scares mom.
She always thinks
I'm dead or sick.
Have some cheese though.
And what if I don't?
I'll leave you here to hitchhike.
No problem.
I'll wait for the guy
who's following us.
- Something to drink?
- Nope.
I have a girl friend like that.
She never drinks while eating.
She says it makes you fat.
I don't believe it.
Actually,
I will have a coffee.
I am sure you're married,
with 5 kids.
No.
What about that coffee?
In life, you need to go
after the things you want.
Instead of waiting
for them to happen.
What do you think?
If everyone stays in their corner...
without trying to communicate...
it's the end.
I am for communication.
Please.
There is no need to be afraid of women.
I've noticed that...
When women know what they want
and say it...
men get scared.
What's gotten into you?
Wait, wait!
Sir!
Good evening.
Evening.
Are you alone?
Yes, alone.
Why haven't you stopped before?
Where before?
At the restaurant.
What's wrong?
Was I going too fast?
No. Show me your papers.
My papers? Of course.
Here.
A pilot?
You're a pilot?
What?
You are an airline pilot?
Yes.
How do you know?
This is a pilot's license.
My mistake.
Here is my driver's license.
You're French?
Yes.
Show me your passport.
Come with me.
What have I done?
What's wrong?
It's taking a long time.
Open the glove compartment.
What for?
Open it and you'll see.
I can't because of the seatbelt.
Take off the seatbelt
for a moment.
What do I do now?
Look inside the glove compartment.
What do you see?
Kleenex papers, tapes, and candies.
Ah, you don't like candies.
Have I offended you?
Deeply.
Sorry about that.
Still offended?
Stop fooling
and give me a candy.
Here.
Thanks.
You know you always say that?
What?
Stop fooling.
Could be.
Looking at your watch
won't make us go faster.
Has he gone back?
Too bad.
Why bad?
We will never know
what he wanted.
All the better.
I will bet you 1000 francs
that I can calculate how many cars
will pass by inside 5 minutes.
Old or new francs?
Old francs.
Alright.
Thirty five.
Thirty three and seven over.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Zero.
You owe me 1000 francs.
Play again?
No thanks.
How did you do it?
Remember you scolded me
because I looked at my watch?
I calculated the average,
I verified it inside an hour,
And I inferred mean timings.
Brainy stuff, huh?
You forgot to be dumb, you.
I don't understand.
You were fine in Rome.
Why go back to Paris?
Because it's my home,
you know that.
Paris or Rome
As long as we stay together.
How do you think I felt
when I called you
and you said you were getting married?
Did you think about it?
No.
We haven't been in touch
for a long time.
What does it change?
I don't know.
It hurts again?
It's nothing.
You still haven't been to a doctor?
It's nothing, I am fine.
I refused a private flight
last week.
What happened?
It's always the same
At first everythings goes well
and then one day - boom
someone tells them about my accident.
You mean, for three years
someone has been calling
your employers
just to tell them you were
responsible for the accident?
It's not impossible.
A mechanic has been trying
to pin everything on me.
Vittorio?
The one who didn't check
the landing gear?
I know he didn't check it.
I thought the control tower was responsible.
They have forgotten too...
The control tower too!
They never wanted to admit it.
Was it the control tower or Vittorio?
I don't like it when you do this.
Why do you laugh?
They think they got rid of me.
I searched their car at the school carpark.
I found the map, their route, hotels -
everything.
Even your address in Paris.
Then why follow them?
Since you have my address?
Why follow them?
It's mom!
Hello?
Mom?
Jean-Marc, how are you?
Fine!
And you?
Your trip is going well?
Yes. We were followed.
I swear.
A guy in a van.
We lost him at dinner time.
So he didn't follow you for long.
What else?
Nothing.
I extorted 1000 francs
from your boyfriend.
Well played!
I love you very much.
Me too mom. Bye!
Hello Nicole.
How are you doing?
So-so. I miss you two.
We too.
What's with the apartment?
Painters are done.
Waiting for the furniture.
I've enough of sleeping on a mattress.
Alone?
There was a painter but he left.
- What bad luck.
- It happens.
I love you.
Me too.
Then say it.
I'm not alone.
So what?
My son won't drop dead
if you tell me you love me.
I love you.
You could do better.
How is it going with Marc?
We're doing just fine.
What  about that guy who followed you?
It's just a story he made up.
A game of his?
Yes, just a game.
Well, kisses...
A big kiss...
Do you have a free room?
It depends.
On what?
On nothing. I just like to joke.
I joked all the time with my husbands.
Advance payment.
Cards, cheques, golden watches are not accepted.
6500 lira.
Room 235, second floor.
Great room with a shower.
You're lucky.
Thank you.
Hey!
No dying here, ok?
I don't want problems.
It's nothing. I only have a headache.
I see. Have a good night.
You're not sleepy?
No.
I shouldn't have told mom, right?
About what?
About the guy who's following us?
Maybe it's a woman, who knows?
It's not important.
I didn't want to make her worry.
What is it?
I think about what you just said.
That it might be a woman.
A blond with big tits.
Why do you say that?
Every night I think about death.
There is only one thing that distracts me:
Women's tits.
It helps to think of them.
Why is that, do you think?
It seems logical.
Logical?
Sure.
Do you know why grown-ups smoke?
No.
It reminds them of their mom's tit.
Oh yes.
Good night.
Sleep well.
Are there fingerprints?
Don't know yet.
Should I ask you by registered mail?
Time of death?
Five-six o'clock.
Motherfucker.
So?
It's not their fingertips.
We have the bastard!
We don't know that yet.
What?
Not everyone has a file.
The subversive who did this has a file.
We arrested him 24 times at protests.
Identity check.
The usual thing.
Dear sir, you have broken windows
and burned down cars
you have assaulted guards...
It's your right -
we live in a democracy.
So what can we do?
We take your name, fingerprints
and we let you go.
You may continue to break windows
and burn down cars.
Or even kill a policeman.
Or it could be a madman.
Or my grandma in a wheelchair.
We'll get him in under 24 hours.
Way to go!
Don't be afraid.
It hurts.
You are scared.
It hurts!
What will I do?
It will be as before between us.
Exactly as before.
We'll be fine together.
Yes.
You will let me kiss you.
Touch you.
Yes.
Make love to you.
We will live together.
Yes.
People will stop trying
to stab me in the back.
It will be...
...as before.
You get on my nerves!
You say yes
but you mean no.
You know...
I've never stopped loving you.
Never.
At no time, you understand?
I love everything about you...
...everything, you understand?
Your voice...
your eyes, your mouth, your body...
...your movements, everything.
When I think about you...
...especially when you're asleep...
...it's crazy how often
I've watched you sleep.
It makes me...
It almost makes me cry.
Where do we eat?
Right after Florence.
Can I put on the radio?
You don't like it?
You don't like the music?
It's fine!
Why didn't you tell me?
What about?
Don't take me for a fool.
Maybe it's not the same van.
A bit too much for a coincidence.
True.
What are you doing?
You think he will stop?
We'll see.
What does he want?
I don't know.
What did he say?
Put on your seatbelt.
I already have.
What will you do?
I will try to lose him.
There are speed limits, you know.
What if a tire blows up?
He will have plenty of time
to catch up with us.
I know.
What does he want with us?
I don't know.
Do you think he knows us?
No.
Then why is he chasing us?
He needs to chase someone
and he chose us.
You mean, a madman?
Yes.
Why not go to the police?
I thought about it.
What will we tell them?
Sir, a guy is following us...
Why not?
He didn't do anything to us so far.
There is nothing we can do?
Seems so.
Can we change our route?
Because of some crazy guy
who thinks he's Steve McQueen?
Even if I asked you?
You're scared?
Yes.
So what do you propose?
Take the first exit...
at Cusi.
You go all the way to Sienna.
At Sienna get back on the highway...
...and ride up to Florence.
Easy, no?
That's your plan?
Yes.
Fine.
Say goodbye to our friend.
He was going to Paris...
...he was handsome...
...and he was scared?
Of what was he scared?
Of women.
What women?
You mean, of you?
Yes.
A fag?
Not necessarily.
Some frustrated type
who eats his own shit in the mornings.
What else can you report?
Light hair...
...dark glasses, checked shirt...
You didn't see his car!
He wasn't a fag.
How do you know?
Because when I looked down, I saw...
What?
He was hard.
Come in.
Enough ma'm, you may go.
Goodbye.
Well?
No luck...
He doesn't have a file.
We've just received a telex.
He's doesn't have a file?
Nothing at all?
Did the lady report anything?
She said he had a hard-on.
It's the clutch?
Yes.
Do you have a carjack?
Can I use your garage?
Yes, but there is no mechanic.
I don't need one.
Do you have a size 11 wrench?
Sure.
Here.
Thank you.
You're French?
Yes.
Where from?
Paris.
You're going there?
Yes.
I am going to join my wife.
She's already there.
And my son.
You have a son?
No, but it's as if I did.
It's her boy.
From her first marriage.
He's almost 12 years old.
They're sweet at that age.
I bet it's going to rain before tonight.
No way.
About the detour...
You added only 25 km...
...before going back to the highway.
So what?
You never intended
to lose him for long.
Never.
You are a liar.
I am a liar indeed.
We'll be in France tonight.
Tonight we'll make it to the border.
Tonight, when we talk to mom...
...we should not tell her.
Really?
I was planning to tell her everything.
Do you often see your father?
Almost never.
It's better that way.
Why?
Because he has his family.
Children from his new marriage.
When I get there, it's a pain.
What do you mean?
I remind him of a previous marriage...
...and everyone gets upset.
You've been married before?
Yes.
It didn't work out?
It did.
Why did you get a divorce then?
I didn't.
I don't understand.
She died.
Tell me if you need to go
to the bathroom.
I am fine but I feel it coming soon...
I don't understand.
You're not alone, little guy.
Why are you laughing?
Because they don't know
what to think.
Even if they had discovered
that I know their hotels...
...they have to get
to their planned destination.
I did all I had to do.
Why tonight?
It's less risky at the hotel.
It's better.
Isn't that clever?
I am clever, huh?
You are.
You should not have left me.
Say it,
that you never should've left...
I should never have left you.
You should never have
moved to Paris.
Lucky you parked near the motel!
I didn't know it was the entrance
of the restaurant.
You look funny.
Did you see yourself?
Hello?
3606 ?
Yes!
Hold the line.
Mom?
Marc?
How are you?
Did you arrive safely?
Yeah.
Without a problem.
You're not very talkative...
Me?
Do you have a headache?
Did you catch a cold?
Give me Alex.
Kisses!
Kisses. Here he is.
Nicole?
What is going on?
Nothing! We drove all day,
we are both tired.
What's up with you?
The furniture arrived.
The couch doesn't open.
We'll need more furniture though.
There's a bed, a table, chairs...
You'll see.
I miss you.
Me too.
I love you.
All I do is wait.
I wish you'd arrived already.
Me too!
Don't say the same thing all the time.
Wait...
Why don't you go take a leak?
Why?
I don't need to!
Maybe you could try?
Are you insane?
I am old enough to know when to go.
Ah, now I understand!
Don't be too long, ok?
Come on!
Still there?
I got rid of your creature.
What do you mean "my creature"?
Alex, home is empty without you two.
I want you so much...
Me too.
Here you go again.
What good it did to get rid of the boy.
Sorry, I am doing my best.
I want you...
Me too...
Is it true that all is well
with the kid?
He's perfectly OK,
why?
There was something in his voice...
Maybe I am getting ideas...
No need to worry,
he's doing very well.
Good night.
Kisses.
See you tomorrow.
Are you asleep?
Yes.
You should be too.
She sensed there was something wrong.
It's always been that way.
I could never hide anything from her.
I wonder how she does it.
She doesn't know herself.
What?
She doesn't know
how she does it.
An animal in the woods...
Suddenly, it raises its head
and runs to hide...
Way before anything happens...
Because it senses danger.
This can't be explained,
it just knows by instinct.
But she's 1500 km away from here...
You see...
it's the same thing - she just knows.
Say...
Do you think we lost him?
Yes.
The last time we also believed that.
This time we lost him.
Go to sleep.
What did he want from us?
We'll never know.
Go to sleep, kid.
Yes, sir.
It's raining buckets...
They're all dead...
This is a cartridge from the mother's room.
I am looking for a guy
who killed two policemen.
There's no connection.
How do you know?
This is a family murder.
A father...
Father?
A father killed his entire family?
His children, his wife...
and himself.
Why?
He left a note...
of religious character.
His son was a junkie, his daughter a slut -
and the wife gave birth to that.
Couldn't it be true?
Sure.
A cutie, eh?
My daughter is her age...
Alex!
Someone is trying to force the lock.
Listen!
Do you hear?
It must be him.
Lock the door
and don't let anyone in!
Got that?
When I am back...
Make me talk
to make sure it's me.
Ok.
Lock the door after me.
I must hear it.
Be careful, Alex!
What do you want?
Who are you?
If I understood correctly,
you have no explanation to offer?
None at all.
You have never seen that man before,
and don't know who he might be.
For the fifth time : no!
You don't make things easy for me.
I'll be going.
What will you do?
The usual : search for the suspect.
What do you want?
I want police protection.
I want an agent next to our door
until we depart.
I want motorcyclists
to escort us to the border.
But...
No buts!
We'll do our best.
Thanks.
Feeling better?
Take this for pain.
Not more than twice a day.
Do not leave too early.
Thank you doctor.
So, kid?
Don't look sour!
I am still here!
Mister Moineau?
Yes.
Inspector Boetani, federal police.
We've already seen policemen...
I know.
I drove 700 km to talk to you.
Two policemen have been...
Two policemen were shot
on the highway yesterday.
You think it's the same guy?
I know it.
Everything fits.
Because if it was different guys...
...who could possibly believe that.
Your son?
My wife's son.
Please, take a seat.
What would you like to know?
Why was he following you?
Why did he try to kill you?
I don't know.
I've never seen this man before.
Are you sure?
Positive.
And the kid?
The kid didn't see him.
It's not because you don't know him
that he doesn't know you.
What do you mean?
May I see your passport?
I've already...
Please!
In the last eight years...
...you've been...
...13 times to Algeria.
I work for a company
that does business there.
Are you involved with politics,
Mister Moineau?
What do you mean?
Do you have party membership,
a right-wing party?
No.
What's the connection?
Are you sure?
Where were you
during the Algerian war?
In Paris, and in Rome.
Forgive me for insisting...
...what about OAS?
Not even a little?
This conversation is getting...
Don't get upset.
I was in Paris in 1960.
I remember it all.
And I am not alone.
You said an unknown man
tried to kill you.
I am trying to understand why.
What if there's no reason?
It's possible.
Everything is possible.
But it's improbable.
Why kill the policemen?
Who knows!
I was counting on you to tell me.
I've never seen this guy before.
I don't do politics.
I have no enemies.
And I don't understand
why he tried to kill me.
Violence doesn't just happen
one fine morning.
And God has not chosen you
out of the blue.
I will be able to offer you protection...
once I know what's it about.
I am sorry, inspector,
but I have a long way to go tomorrow....
and I need to rest.
Mister Moineau!
Have you ever been incarcerated?
You never know.
You're not sleeping?
I was listening to you.
Back to bed!
He has a point, you know...
How so?
It's true that we weren't chosen
by chance.
There must be a reason.
I know.
Slept well?
No.
Where are the motorcyclists?
Motorcyclists?
I asked to be escorted to the border.
Yes of course.
I cancelled them.
What do you mean?
You didn't tell me anything.
Give me a reason
and I'll protect you.
You get nothing
if you give nothing.
Fine!
I'll call my embassy.
It's useless.
He's dead.
The ambassador?
The guy who followed you.
We found his car.
Not far from here at 6 am,
burned.
The guy burned inside.
Are you sure of that?
Absolutely.
You should have said so.
I wanted to surprise you.
You still don't want to tell me
why he followed you?
Know what?
I am so relieved.
You bet. Me too!
A guy dies and we're happy?
Not nice but...
It's just the way it is.
Coming back from Saint-Malo...
I met three camels...
I put them in my bed...
And, mom, I loved some tit...
They have round hats,
long live Bretons!
Coming back from Saint-Martin...
I found three little rabbits...
I put them inside my slip...
And they ate my little carrot.
Coming back from Saint-Quentin...
I found three little sluts...
I put them in my pocket...
And they ate my little noodle...
Personal belongings?
All the papers were burnt.
A watch, two rings, a bracelet.
I knew it was a fag.
Ah you were good looking
in your youth!
Don't push it.
You didn't wear glasses.
I took them off for the photo.
Why?
You don't like glasses?
No reason.
We'll see what we can do
about contact lenses.
It must be possible.
Passports please.
Easy!
Good!
A potato baked in the ashes.
You like?
It's from this car's blaze.
A homosexual farmer!
We're dealing with a rustic fag.
How long is this tunnel?
I've no idea.
Do you have a trip counter?
I do.
Switch it on.
Done.
What now?
I will bet on 20 km.
How much?
Fifty francs.
Old money?
You must be kidding.
I accept.
Did you ask about the tunnel
to test me or because you didn't know?
What do you mean?
You might have read about it.
That wouldn't be fair play.
Oh really?
I swear I didn't know...
Take off your seatbelt!
Lie down in the back!
Between the seats!
Don't look!
Stay down!
Marc, lie down!
It was a Ford van.
They thought it was him...
and we left.
Incredible!
How come the plates are from Rome?
It's my wife's car,
she lived there.
Incredible!
It's your daughter?
It's my wife's son.
Hard to know these days.
You think a girl is speeding,
you stop them and it's boys!
You're ok?
You got off easy...
What a sight!
Come to the office.
Do you have insurance?
For road accidents.
What's the connection?
You've spoken to Italian police...
They've confirmed your story.
So?
They've closed your file.
The guy is dead.
But he just attacked us!
The kid is my witness.
Italian police saw him dead.
You left and now
you got into an accident.
I don't want to get involved in your
insurance schemes.
Give me that phone.
Why?
To call the police.
I am the police!
You're incompetent!
Don't touch the phone!
I will call from elsewhere!
No one will believe you!
You know it.
Or they will refer you back to me...
Because it happened in my district!
If it wasn't for your daughter,
I'd arrest you to calm you down!
You can call the Prefect
or the Pope!
You'll still have to deal with me!
Let's go!
Look at him!
You'll leave it there?
What else can we do?
No one will believe us.
Let's go!
We need a new windshield.
Do they have one?
Out of stock.
What are you doing?
We need to be warm.
Here!
Put that on too.
Hello?
Nicole!
I have great news!
Me too!
Tell me first!
No, you go first.
I am starting work on the 1st,
we'll have 8 days together.
Are you happy?
Very!
Listen...
Hey there guys!
What's that?
You're not at a hotel?
That's the thing...
We decided to go directly to Paris.
I thought you didn't want
to drive at night.
We miss you too much.
And I'm not at all sleepy.
We should get there at 3am.
What do you say?
The boy will sleep in the car.
It's true he can sleep anywhere.
Precisely.
I'll warm the bed for you...
I'll put the kid on...
You always flee
when I become tender...
Mom?
How are you?
So you confirm he's not sleepy?
We're both in top shape!
Don't worry!
Be careful!
I'll scold him if he takes risks.
Bye mom!
Many kisses!
Bye mom.
You're done?
Done.
Hot chocolate...
One coffee...
Call to Paris...
Can I ask you something?
Why drive all night?
The sooner we get to Paris,
the better.
That's the only reason?
Yes.
Can you think of another?
Try again!
Come in!
You know,
that fag of yours...
I have the proof
it is not him.
Not him?
We found a finger
less damaged by the fire.
The fingertips don't match.
Connect me to the police of
Grenoble, Lyon, Vintimille, Dijon, Paris...
and Interpol in Rome!
Don't fall asleep!
Let's try singing...
No.
I can't, I am too cold.
Please repeat...
I don't have the man's description
or the car's number.
But a Mister Moineau
is driving to Paris...
I believe it's a political case.
Moineau?
That's all?
What about his car?
A blue Renault 5
registered in Rome.
They must have crossed the border
this afternoon.
Try to determine their route...
Boulard is already on the case...
Give me Victor...
Boulard.
- I got the gendarmes.
- Let me talk to that fool.
The incident happened at 2pm.
It was a blue Renault
and a kid inside?
You didn't take the car's number
or it's destination?
But how could I know?
Do you remember the address?
On the license it was written
Alesia Street...
Alesia street.
House number?
I can't remember.
We found Moineau's address.
We couldn't reach him,
I sent a car.
What is this crazy story?
A complete mess...
You see, it's strange...
It's not as if I were asking
for the moon...
I only want to get back
what was taken from me...
That's all.
I'd like you to understand that.
I don't see you...
Nothing!
He moved three months ago...
Looks like he got married...
To a certain Letessier.
Nicole Letessier.
Fabio...
Don't say anything.
I am glad to see you.
Explain how...
Here I am,
I wanted to see you.
You drove from Rome
just to...
Yes!
What happened to you?
Oh it's nothing.
May I come in?
It's very nice.
Listen...
I'd rather you went...
I had to see you,
so I came!
Do you have something to eat?
Eat?
Yes, I am hungry.
Just a second!
Are you well covered?
Yeah, I am ok.
So?
She's in Rome.
She works for Air France there.
I don't care how late it is!
Find a Nicole Letessier,
in Rome,
She works for Air France.
And ask her if she's married
to a certain Moineau!
Would you like to buy it?
No.
With what I owe you
you can afford it.
What about this one?
Nope.
Alex, listen...
What is it, kid?
If it's going to go like this...
I won't make it.
You're cold?
It's not that...
I am talking about
something else.
What is it?
I am scared.
It's a knot in my stomach.
If this doesn't stop soon...
I won't be the same person.
Listen, kid...
You don't know
what people can withstand...
We've done 500 km
and he hasn't shown up.
There's only 100 km to go...
You'll make it.
Are you a fast runner?
Yeah.
I bet 1000 francs
that I can beat you over 100m.
Agreed.
We'll run to that column there.
We run around the column
and touch down there!
Let's start here!
One...
First I say: ready...
Go!
Cheater!
It does warm you up!
Not bad for a guy
who doesn't like sports...
Oh my!
Feeling better?
How long since you last ate?
Listen...
I know why you're here.
You called
and I told you I was leaving...
You wanted things back
as they were.
You suffered beyond words.
You still love me.
I am saying it
so you don't need to humiliate yourself.
But it's all over, Fabio.
It's over.
Since a long time.
I don't feel anything for you,
I'm sorry.
I'm married to a man I love.
You must understand.
No.
Why no?
No, I can't understand.
We were fine together.
You said everything would be
like before...
That I could touch you...
Kiss you...
I never said that...
You did!
In the van, you did!
What van?
Driving up here...
You can't say it's over
when you know it's not!
You still get those headaches?
Have you been to a doctor,
like I asked?
You're my doctor.
I said no!
You're even prettier
than before.
My husband will arrive soon.
How do you know?
He did that to me.
What are you saying?
Don't worry,
we'll take care of him.
I don't like it
when you do this!
Be nice, be nice!
I left everything...
I drove like a madman...
I killed two policemen...
Now I am here...
Be nice! Be nice!
Leave me alone!
No!
Calm down...
It's me...
Calm down!
Come here...
It's ok!
Calm down...
It's me...
How many times
did we make love, Fabio?
One more time
won't change anything.
You know my body...
Quiet!
I don't love you!
What have you done to Alex
and my son?
Nothing happened,
I missed them.
What do you mean:
missed them?
Where is my son?
Don't do that!
It's not you I love!
Not you!
I don't love you!
Tell me we're close...
Almost there, kid.
Listen well...
Don't cry or get nervous,
do as I say...
I am counting on you.
Who is it?
Moineau.
What is going on?
Please keep hold of the kid
and call the police.
Why?
I can't explain but it's urgent.
Please!
Listen: stay right here,
do not go anywhere!
I am warning you...
Don't say anything
or I'll shoot.
Here I am.
Let go of him!
Watch out, Alex!
Get out of here!
Alex, run away,
get out!
Let me do it, Nicole...
You know him?
Yes.
Where is Marc?
It's over now.
It's nothing, kid.
I didn't want you to die.