Plants
Screenplay
Suliko Jgenti
Director
Rezo Chkheidze
Director of Photography
Abesalom Maisuradze
Set Designers
Zurab Medzmariashvili
Tatiana Krimkovskaia
Music: Nodar Gabunia
Sound: Davit Lomidze
Grandpa Luka - Ramaz Ckhikvadze
Kakha - Mishiko Meskhi
Grandma Elisabeth - Mary Joreli
Tsitsino - Sesilia Takaishvili
"Georgian Film" 1972
Winds blew in February,
March sewed the dress..
April prepared itself for tillage
(Folk saying)
Kakhaber!
Come here, boy
They've all dried off, Kakhaber
Can't anything be
done about it?
What is there to be done?
Even a tree is mortal
in this world
I'm to blame
I didn't tend them
enough, lately
I had to replant
them last spring, but...
I couldn't attend to it all
How's it going, Anthimos?
Can it be saved?
You wouldn't wish it
to your worst enemy
It's all dried up
No trace of life
Such a cold winter
we had this year
The kind of wind,
that blew in December
Would wither any tree
Such a winter is unheard of,
in these areas
Everything comes to an end
These trees have lived
for at least 2 centuries
Isn't that so, Luka?
Yes
Around so
"Khechachuri" pears lived here
long before that, but they've wilted
But these ones
My grandfather Giorgi planted
Before my father was born
Bless his soul
He sure had a
beneficent hand
Here,
It's been more than
a hundred years
He's lying in the ground
But these trees kept on living
You won't find
"Khechachuri" any more
In these areas,
they've exctinted long ago
Child told me about it
I almost beat him
I thought it was a joke
It had fruits, like honey
True
It's like my grandfather Giorgi
has passed away this right moment
Up to now,
I considered him alive
Kakha
Kakha!
Kakha, where are you
You, miserable!
What's the matter, woman
Let me go
What's all the fuss
with this "Khechachuri"
Why do you harp about
these trees all the time
What's on your mind?
Travelling so far away
I'll get the plants and
see a bit fo this world
It's been half a century I haven't left this place
Oh My!
Such a long distance
Such a big city
So what
It isn't the first time
I'm visiting the city
How would I know?
You haven't been there,
since we're together
So what?
I clearly remember the place
The boy will see the world
It is time to
All right
All right, all right
Oh my!
What is this?
Kakha!
Grades
Grades, eh?
English - D
Here you go
Wha's this, boy?
Aren't you ashamed?
If you think English is so easy to learn, go on and learn it yourself
For example, the word "light" is written in the book
"light" is written, but you have to read it as 'lait'
Or let's take the word "whisky"
You have to
pronounce it as "uiski"
Boy!
If it's called "uiski",
why don't they just write "uiski"?!
I won't study this English at all
Why should I
make such effort
Let those englishmen learn Georgian, are we any less?
Here you go!
The boy is right
We are leaving now
Right!
Let's go
Good bye
Bye!
Good bye Granny
Go inside now
Why are you howling like that
Hello Grandpa Luka
Come down,
I'll give you a lift
What is this boy?
Your bulls look shattered
Or the carriage
Come now,
don't start it your way
Look how you've
dressed yourself up
I've never seen you decorated like this before
And the boy looks
like a city boy now
Heading to the city?
I am, my friend
You too, grandpa's boy?
Me too
Come now
Does anyone go so far away
for just "Khechachuri" pear plants?
We have "Prangula" pear seeds
in our nursery garden
It fruits in just two years
I know them, those pears
They taste like unboiled potatoes
They give you two abazs for kg
And if you aske me..
Nobody's asking you
Grandpa, Grandpa
This world bears
so many blockeads
Grandpa Luka
"Khechachuri" fruits only
after 12 years, right?
Right, so what?
So what?
Waiting 12 years for
couple of pears?
You are all so impatient
Always in a hurry, wanting it
all at this very minute
I prefer today's egg,
over tomorrow's hen
It's a silly proverb
Otherwise, we wouldn't have neither egg, nor hen for now
Grandpa Luka
you must be around 70
The world was falling apart, but the jackal held the wedding
(folk saying)
Kakha!
Come down here
Come now,
what did I say such?
Neither my song,
nor my word pleases you
What a strange man you are
Grandpa, grandpa
Kakha
Kakhaber
What is it, grandpa?
We have to buy tickets
The station is this way
Good day
What?
I would like a ticket
For Sachkhere train
The train for Sachkhere
has already left
Left? where?
The train left at 11 in the morning
Things are bad
Come back tomorrow
Thank you my dear
Thank you
What can we do, let's go
Let's see the
sights of the city first
And spend the night
at the hotel, right?
Right
Kakhaber
See that garrent?
Right?
Yes
Me and my friend
used to live there
Arqipo?
Yes, Arqipo
If you only knew what a boy your grandpa used to be back then
What about Tsitsino?
There
That pretty Tsitsino used
to live behind that bridge
Her father was a tenant
I remember his tiny
clean white house
If you only knew Kakhaber
How many times has
your grandpa jumped over here
The whole world wondered
How did this dreary old man managed to have this beauty child
She would stand on the balcony, just like a moon
The carriages would
hold still at her sight
In short, man couldn't
ask for more beauty
I'll show you that
house right away
Everything has been changed
The house is gone
Wait, wait
Come
Thank you very much
You're welcome
Good day to you
Won't you recieve
some guests?
I wonder if he's deaf
Good day to you
Raise your head
And answer my greeting
I have grandchildren
of your age
Good day,
we have no rooms
How's that?
Won't you let me
spend the night?
No place, what can i do?
Shame on you
Violating hospitality tradition
At least, trouble youself a little
Apologize maybe
I treat guests in my own family
Visit me and scold me
if I don't treat you well enough
Men like you come 300 and 400 times a day, grandpa
You're also right,
what is there to do
Are you on a mission?
What did you say?
I asked if you're
on a buisness trip
I've got my passport
and money in the pocket
Got any documents?
Where are you
coming from, where to
My story is to be told
as a fairy tale, my boy
I'm here for the plants
What are you lookint at
I was told to get
some pear plants at the...
What plants are
you talking about
We're about to recieve
lots of scientists for the symposium
Mr. Sharmon is coming
any time now
Who's coming?
Mr. Sharmon
He shook hands with Einstein
Mr. Osada from Japan
In a minute
Good day to you
All right,
you take care of him and..
We'll take care of our own
Good bye
Excuse me, my friend
You said you are
looking for the plants
That's right, we're
heading to Zenati  and..
"Khechachuri" is the king of pears, as we used to say in old times but..
Right so, but you
won't find it nowadays
They extincted little by little..
"Khechachuri"
"Tarujula"
"Zape pear"
"Kacistava"
(manhead)
What a breed, what a breed
Now what about
old grape varieties?
"Ojaleshi" ,  "Aladasturi"
"White Odessa"
"KiKhvi", "Bulleye"...
How's it called?
"Chkhaveri"
I remember, I celebrated my
wedding with "Chkhaveri" wine
Now, what about forests..
I heard it from the old men, that
We used to have such forests,
that even a bird wouldn't get through
Plentiful spring waters would flow almost everywhere
I remember,
my father used to recount
He came out in the yard, one night
Suddenly the wind blew
and extinguished his wick-lamp
My Grandfather  told him then
'Someone must have
cut the tree in the forest'
Right, that's so
They write a lot about it, nowadays
There was an article in the
newspaper recently, saying that...
50 million tree is
going to be planted
What for?
You won't snatch an
axe from these people's hands
You're right, my friend
Where are you from?
I am Kvintradze, from Kvakude
What are you saying?!
My grandmother, Akhaladze's daughter
was also from Kvakude
No, we are as relatives then
My mother was also Akhaladze
This is my grandson, Kakhaber
He is a good boy
Thank you
Oh, by the way
The tourist bus over there
is heading to Tbilisi
The interpreter girl
is of our kind
I'll tell her to take you with her
Let's go, let's go
I sure do like to have a conversation
But I don't understand your language, what can I do
My girl
Come here
Tell me what this honest man is trying to say
Mr. Fletcher wanted to know
if you're also on the sightseeing tour
I told him that you're heading to faraway village
to get some plants
God bless you
Mr. Fletcher is very interested in this subject
Last year he also planted new apple seeds in his farm
Good work my friend
Khechachuri, my man
He says he doesn't know this breed
It's a pear breed
ancient breed
It grows as tall as an oak
It will grow so tall in 15-20 years
That you can hold a wedding under it's branches
The fruit it bears, is sweet like honey
Oh, and if you store it in a special jar
The flavour will be kept for over a year
Where are you from, my friend?
He's from America grandpa
You're from far away as well
Luka Odilavadze
Of course
I'll send it to you next spring
He says, that's his adress
Thank you very much
Here, hold it boy
Write down our adress
in their language
Before you plant the seed
Store it in the water
for couple of days
Don't touch the plant
for the first 3 years
Then replant it
It will bear first fruit
in around 12-13 years
If not in 13,
it won't take longer than 15
You know what?
Nobody asked a man
before this planet was born
Nor its destruction will be asked
Tell him that
Kakhaber, help me
Help yourself
You're of my age
So drink this vodka for me
That's the way it is
Help yourself, It's "Khachapuri"
Here's for you my friend
This is "Chacha"
God bless you! Here, eat an apple
Grandpa, grandpa
What about me?
What, you want to drink it too?
Sure
Say something in their language boy
Now I'll say it
Don't say anything bad,
don't embarass me
Rain, rain go away
John and Mary want to play
Grandpa, Grandpa
Here's road to Senaki
Have a nice trip
Good bye
Good bye, good bye
Visit us some day
Farewell grandpa
Good bye Kakhaber
Wouldn't it be great..
When I send those seeds
to that american
And Georgian "Khechachuri" trees
will grown on american soil
Grandpa grandpa
Teacher said that
American and our astronauts
will soon fly together
Is it true?
Yes, that's how we've decided
Host
Who is it?
Village must be
far away from here
Hello
We're passengers
and would like to spend a night
Come in
Blessed is the guest
Thank you my friend
I'm Luka Odilavadze
This is my grandson, Kakhaber
Hello my boy
Come inside
We're here for the plants
And night caught us on the way
Hail to God, peace to you
This way, Mr. Luka
Have a seat
Thank you
Come here Kakhaber,
its warm by the fire
I'll leave you for a moment
Go ahead
I got really tired
I'm not as strong as I used to be
Here, let's eat and the
fatigue will go away
Don't bother yourself
We just had a snack
Good Evening
Good Evening to you
We came across some
Americans on our way
And had a little feast
Americans?
I look at my boy
Such a small boy
But you wouldn't know how well he speaks in English
Good Evening
Ketevan
Good Evening sir
We're sorry to bother you
It's nothing
He amused all those Americans
Telling them all
the things in the world
Who has the biggest eyes?
Octopus
Octopuses live in the oceans and seas
Where they hide under big rocks
Sometimes they hide out
in the depth of the ocean
Where it is very dark
It has to watch carefully for the loot
This is the reason Octopuses have moulded big eyes
during the centuries
During the shooting of a film
The tiger escaped from the crew
People were delivered from the
trouble by a 3 year old kid
Who...
Time for supper, Mr Luka
Maybe the boy got hungry
No my friend, he never
eats when it's time
We just had our supper
Thank you
If so, I won't bother you any more
Have some rest
Good night, Mr Luka
Good night
Famous french traveler..
Expressed concern about...
Plants and animals
of the Mediterranean sea
He says that..
The sea might be
dead in 20 years time
Grandpa
Go to bed, til you've
fallen in that fireplace
Yes, let's go to bed now
We got to leave
early in the morning
Grandpa
Do you really believe
in existence of God?
No one knows that
for sure, my boy
It's embarassing
What will the man say
Grandpa
Your hair's gone gray
Where?
Hair is that matters,
who cares about gray
I hate shaving as hell
Say this..
Good morning, Mr. Luka
Excuse me sir
Excuse me
Don't excuse yourself
Good morning my friend
I heard your singing
I want to teach him
all the old songs I know
I'm keep telling him..
Learn these songs
Till I'm alive
When I'm gone
You won't hear them
on the radio
Or read them in books
You're right
Good Morning Ms.
Good morning sir
Good morning
You've woken up
on a daybreak, Mr. Luka
We have a long way
ahead, my Davit
Don't bother, Mr. Davit
You're about to have a
guest in the family
Help yourself
Thank you
Al those trucks outside..
It's about road
construction, right?
No Mr. Luka
It's for the artificial sea
Sairao sea
Much been written about
it in the newspapers
Sairao used to be
the name of this village
But..
The village..
Is it going to be flooded?
You won't find
the village anymore
There's only one
household left
And they are also
going to move next week
Mr. Luka
Kakhaber
We, people you
face right now
We are neighbors
and relatives...
Of this family
This family...
Knows how to
treat it's guests
Here, the guest..
Is never recieved
from the back door
But...
Don't condemn us
today, Mr. Luka
Today...
The family is in grief..
I did sense, but...
How could I imagine
such a thing..
One...
Peaceful...
Honest working man...
Has left us...
All his life...
He was....
Dedicated to agricultural
work and now....
The same soil is where
he will find eternal rest
Orphile Vashakidze
will be remembered
Mr. Nikoloz
The head of collective farm
Mr. Parnavaz, our accountant
My condolecenses
Close relatives..
Mrs. Nunu, his sister..
His nieces...
Mrs. Albete, his wife
My condolecenses
We're all children of death
Daughters..
Great is your loss
The young should live
Grow up as a big boy
My condolecenses
Good Morning my friend
Good Morning
Apple, isn't it?
May it rejoice and fruit!
Good day
Hello
Zenati thrift, isn't it?
Quite right
Where's the chief?
There's his cabinet
But he's not in right now
Here, he comes with his suite
Which one?
The tall one
We are not to blame
Working in the field
from dusk till dawn..
Good day to you
Won't anyone pay us
some attention?
What do you want?
I'm here for "Khechachuri" plants
I was told to get them in Zenati
And here I am
We don't have
"Khechachuri" plants
Don't refuse, I beg you
Bikenti, Yovel.. do we have "Khechachuri" plants?
No, no.. we never had any
It takes at least
10 years to fruit
Who's gonna wait for it
We have to fullfil
fruit plans annualy
Oh, I'm lost
I beg you, help me out
Don't let me off
empty-handed
We don't have those plants,
what can we do
What should we do now
Harping on this "Khechachuri"
Don't you see?
No one's interested
in it but you
Don't you see?
I see
Then let's give up
and go home
Let's go
Grandpa
Wait
Kakhaber, get it in your head
It's not only about
'Khechachuri" tress
What will you reap tomorrow...
If you don't sow it today?
My grandpa must've been
strolling just like me
Otherwise our "Kchechachuri" trees
wouldn't rejoice by themselves
Grandpa
When I grow up..
I'll travel around the world
and get the plants
And sow them in our garden
All right, all right
Let's try something out
I want you to know
It's better not to go
back to the village at all
Then go empty-handed
Let's go
He said..
The Sun is my mother..
The Moon is my father..
And those tiny...
Come now
Those tiny...
Stars
Are my sisters and brothers
Good boy
Grandpa
The well, grandpa
Come
Go, quick
Who's out there?
Life and prosperity to this family
Come inside
Excuse us please
For this intrusion
Come in, come in
No, no..we're passengers
And got thirsty
Come in please
Coming was your free will,
but leaving is host's wil
Good day to you
Good day sir
We're passengers and
we're in a hurry
As soon as you step
in our yard, you're a guest
Come in sir, come in
What are you staring at sir?
It's "Khechachuri"
Planted by my grandfather,
bless his soul
God bless it's seeds
Who will sow it nowadays
This is the reason of our journey
I was told to find
the plants in Zenati
But imagine that..
It turned out to be a lie
Come here
Over there, Robinzon Dateshidze..
Coutivates "Khechachuri"
plants, but...
What good does it do?
He's just a rude,
rough man
He wouldn't trade
it for money or else
Are you that interested?
You'll drive me crazy
We travelled through
the country for it
If so...
He lives over there,
on that island..
You'll get there by boat
Go and see him..
Maybe some miracle happens...
But I doubt
Host
I wonder if he's deaf
Go inside, grandpa
Good day to you
I'm Luka Odilavadze
This is my grandson,
Kakhaber
Come here boy
Hello
Odilavadze?
From North?
Yes, coming from
North to see you
See me?
Right so
We've been told that..
One kind man coutivates..
"Khechachuri" plants and..
What do you need them for?
What?
"Khechachuri" plants
What do I need it for...
What kind of question is this?
I can't give it to you
What did you see there?
What is there?
The bottom..
The bottom is of "Panta" pear
This is "Naperala"
And this is peach
Right
I wasted my time
in this early spring but..
Nobody cares
You can look out if you like
The whole world is seen
from here as if on a palm
Much obliged
I'll give you 10
God bless you
Moscow train has left
If so, give me at least 25
Won't 15 be enough for you?
Neither mine, nor yours
Make it 20
That's all right with me
But in one condition
What condition?
Follow me
Here are "Khechachuri" plants
Go ahead, dig them out
But...
Don't pass this stone
What?
Follow this path but...
Only until this stone
Odilavadze
I'm not joking
You can take the plants
But don't go
further this stone
Grandpa
Pass it from this side
Can I pass by from this side?
No no, you can't
pass by from there
You have to follow this path but don't pass the stone
Shame on you
I know your kind but..
How can I slap
the man of your age
A man has to be
virile and honest
Even a mole can
do the ploughing
Let's go
A man's gotta have brains
Am I to blame,
that you're short of brains?
The blame is all yours, Odilavadze
Get up
Step right here, sir
Hold this
Drop it
Drop it, I said
20 sapling is mine
You deserved it my Luka
Bring them and come here
Right away
God bless it's saplings
Look
How tall they've grown
As I was telling you..
Achiko had coupled eyebrows
So we called him
Achiko Browie
"Achiko Browie!
How are you doing?"
I would cry after him..
There was one girl,
named Abkhazia
Flirting with him
Gee, he will die
from happiness..
When he sees me
after 40 years
Grandpa, who was
the prettiest
Tsitsino or Abkhazia?
Boy, are you crazy?
There was no woman
prettier than Tsitsino
She was peerless
Peerless, that's so
Look Kakhaber, Look!
Didn't I tell you?
He's got blessed hands
It's Garden of Eden
Grandpa!
Come here
Let's stay here for the night
and go home by the morning
Hello
Come right in
Come come
Tell me this..
Where is Arqipo Ketiladze?
He's at home
So he's at home?
Go and tell him this..
A man at the gate
sends you the message...
Arqipo the Browie!
Present yourself at once!
Here what I say?
Like this..
Arqipo the Browie!
Present yourself at once!
The Browie?
Yes, the Browie..
don't forget to say it
The Browie.. the Browie!
Arqipo the Browie!
That tree..
Is it avocado?
Avocado
Look how tall it's grown
The first time we saw it,
in Aspazia's yard
It was this size
Grandpa
Where's Arqipo?
I wonder if he's asleep
He is Arqipo
Where's the other Arqipo?
A man of my age
There's no other Arqipo here
Maybe he lives in
another household?
I don't know
I haven't heard of another Arqipo
Good day to you
Come in sir
I...
would like to see Arqipo...
Ketiladze
Arqipo?
Right so
Oh my, sir..
You problably mean my
husband's grandfather
Probably, yes..
He's been gone for a
long time, sir
When I was brought
in this famiy
He was 2 years dead by then
What did you just tell me..
Grandpa
I wish I knew what the
man sitting in there..
Is thinkg about
right now
He must be thinking
about the land
What else..
Grandpa
Grandpa!
I'm here my boy
Grandpa
Things are bad, Kakhaber
It's about to rain
These 4 started to wither but..
I think we've planted
them just in time
In 20 years time...
When you'll get
on the top of this tree
You will be able to
see this entire area
Untie the tree and
put the coat on
No, my boy
The tree is weak
If I untie it, it will die
Put it on, anyhow
Come now
Granda entrusted me
to take care of you
The place is not bad, either
Yes, the sun will reach here
Let's go
Go inside my boy
Excuse me sir
Excuse me
Have a seat, grandpa
Thank you
Hello Chichiko!
Boy, is that you?
Come down, let's have a cognac
Which number are you in?
Right here
What's this?
Whose are these plants?
Mine sir, mine
Are they any good?
These are "Khechachuri" plants
What's this "Khechachuri"?
It's pear
Give me couple of saplings
I'll give you one
Pick out the good one
Take it
How much?
Don't mention it
Tell me where to plant it then
Which place is better
Don't plant it on stone..
Otherwise, any
place is good for it
In 12 years time..
It will bear fruit
What?
12 years of waiting...
For this?
Are you in a hurry?
Funny man you are
Should we go Chichiko?
Come down
I'm thirsty
Follow me
Wake up my darling
My dear
Eat now
My dear child
Eat now, eat
Come, come
Don't cry
What is it?
Excuse me
You're Tsitsino, right?
Yes sir, I'm Tsitsino
Hello Tsitsino
Don't you recognise me?
I recognised your voice
Your voice is still the same
Yes, I recognise you
How old you've grown, boy
Remember?
Do you remember...
Excuse me sir, excuse me
Remember...
How I threw paper wrapped
stone in your room?
It took me 3 days
to write that letter
Good times they were
How many silly things
we've done
This is my grandson
Hello Grandpa
This is my friend
We grew up together
What is it?
Tell me what's going on
The child is right
You're not that kind of man
You'll spoil the plant
You got greedy,
didn't you old man?
If you don't know
how to treat elder..
I'll teach you
Let's have a seat
Give it to me
Grandpa, are you ill?
I don't feel well
Who was that woman?
What woman?
The one you were
talking with on the train
Did you like her?
Didn't she still have
that old charm?
Yes
Was that Tsitsino?
How do you know
what she looked like
Like rising Sun
That's what she looked like
Kakhaber, my boy
Aren't Dilitauri mountains
seen yet?
Not yet grandpa
Do you want anything?
No, nothing
It's all beacuse you
took the coat off yesterday
You shouldn't have
Won't you give up
teaching me how to live?
These plants, my boy
You have to plant
them in the garden
I know, grandpa
Don't forget those Americans..
No Grandpa
Send them the seed by the fall
As it's been said..
One has to keep the promise
Don't disgrace me
in front of that foreigner
I won't grandpa
Hand me that bucket
Do you want some water?
Kakhaber
Hand me those plants
I'll have some water
Grandpa
Why are you up?
Things are bad, Kakhaber
When a plant withers like that..
It has to be rescued in time..
Even though I told him,
we had a long way ahead...
But...can you imagine?
Grandpa
Here's a nice place
Yes
Get to work now
Won't it need watering?
I don't think so
The soil is damp
Grandpa
Grow, rejoice and..
Rejoice others..
Grandpa Luka,
have you fallen ill?
I don't feel well
Seems as it has rained
Yes, it rained a bit
in the morning
Help me, help me
(Speaks Russian)
What have you done, you fool
The brakes have failed
Help
Quick, help me
It will slip
Go, bring some stones
Quick, till it slips
Go grandpa,
fetch a big stone
Hurry grandpa
Good grandpa
Put some more plants
Things are gonna be bad, if it slips
Thank you, brother
I've spoiled such a good jacket
One has to chop his head off..
It had nothing to do
with the brakes
Must have been unexperienced
Can you drive so fast
in this moist?
Wasn't grateful enough, either
Let's go grandpa
At least..
We've stopped for the water
What is it, my boy?
Spring will come
next year, won't it?
The Sun is my mother...
The Moon is my father...
Those tiny stars..
Are my sisters and brothers
Subtitles made for KG
by lilacwine
The End