In the 14th year of the Kyoho era,
under rule of the 8th Shogun Yoshimune,
in Saga Castle on Kyushu island, which
controls a territory of 370,000 koku,
Lord Nabeshima Tango-no-kami governed.
In those times a very mysterious
and improbable story occurred.
It is called...
SECRET CHRONICLES OF THE GHOST-CAT
[Hiroku Kaibyo-den]
Planning: Akihiko Suguro
Writer: Shozaburo Asai
Cinematography: Hiroshi Imai
Sound Recording: Yukio Kaihara
Lighting: Hiroshi Bima
Art Direction: Seiichi Ota
Music: Michiaki Watanabe
Editing: Hiroshi Yamada
Sound Effects: Nobu Kurashima
Action Director: Eiichi Kusumoto
Assistant Director: Rikio Endo
Production Manager: Akihiko Murai
Narrator: Gen Kimura; Developing: Toyo Lab
Cast:
Koujirou Hongou
Naomi Kobayashi
Kamei Mitsuyo, Rokkou Toura,
Kouichi Uenoyama, Ikuko Mouri, Akihisa Toda
Akane Kawasaki, Natsuko Oka,
Yuusaku Terashima
Shouzou Nanbu, Shintaro Nanjo,
Shousaku Sugiyama
Kazue Tamaoki, Seishiro Hara,
Horikita Yukio
Eigoro Onoe, Jun Fujikawa,
Kiyoshi Kasuga, Tadashi Iwata
Gen Kuroki, Yuutarou Ban, Yorie Santo,
Higashiyama Teruyo, Youko Atsuta
Chiaki Shirakawa, Katsura Wada,
Kyoko Miwa
Director: Tokuzo Tanaka
- Hanazaemon.
- Yes.
Mr. Mataichirou.
Well, well. Is this Mr. Hanazaemon?
- The Master has arrived.
- What? The Master?
The Master was not coming here,
he arrived unexpectedly.
Yes, I decided to leave for a walk.
But now I would like to drink some tea.
Certainly. Sayo!
- Mataichirou!
- Yes?
I have not seen her for long time,
she has grown more beautiful since then.
What?
Do you say so about my younger sister?
Thank you.
Listen, Sayo!
I did not expect the Master to arrive
during today's outdoor tea ceremony.
Really, I was surprised as well.
But it seems to me he was satisfied...
And that is the most important thing.
Sir, Mr. Komori has arrived.
What? Mr. Hanazaemon?
Mr. Mataichirou, forgive me for
visiting at such a late hour.
Don't mention it. Welcome.
- Please, come in.
- Excuse me.
Please...
Miss Sayo.
Could you leave us alone?
Yes.
It is strange for the Master to
have arrived so late.
Well, the Master demonstrated his
bad inclinations again.
Brother, what about the Master?
He sent the Chief of Servants Komori
with a mission to Ryuuzouji's house.
To Ryuuzouji's house?
He wants to take Sayo, Mataichirou's
younger sister, as his concubine.
Really...
If the Master has gotten something into
his head, it's impossible to stop him.
All right. If Sayo comes to the castle,
I will send her away within three days.
I think these are all intrigues
plotted by Mataichirou.
You see, his ancestors governed
this castle in former times,
and he is unsatisfied with his allowance
of 3,000 koku. He wants power as well.
In any case, Mataichirou
will always interfere.
But if so, I will send away
both him and his sister.
If I declare this proposal off,
you will not carry out your mission.
And then your position...
My position doesn't matter.
The only thing which matters is: what
do you and Miss Sayo think about it.
But Sir...
You and I are childhood friends,
that is why they sent you.
Mataichirou!
I am sure, there is no reason to worry.
Four generations ago, the Ryuuzouji
family governed in Saga castle.
But my ancestor was dismissed
because of some insignificant fault.
His Main Vassal Nabeshima
took his place.
And until the present day, we get an
allowance of 3,000 koku as sufferance.
However, Mr. Hanazaemon,
although we are ruined,
I will never allow my younger sister
to become a concubine.
Your words are justly spoken.
Please tell them, that
my younger sister Sayo
is very awkward, and unfit
to be a concubine of the Master.
I understand everything,
so I will tell them.
Thank you.
Wait.
What did Ryuuzouji answer?
- I will tell the Master in person.
- Tell me.
I will tell the Master.
- What? Mataichirou refused?
- Yes.
What impudence!
He has delusions of grandeur!
I think, he cannot forget,
that Ryuuzouji governed here in
former days, rather than Nabeshima.
Former days don't matter!
Call Mataichirou immediately!
It is necessary to tell him
he oversteps his position!
This evening Mataichirou should arrive
at the castle for the party of Go.
You will be able to discuss it
with him during the game.
- Is it raining?
- Yes.
It began falling several minutes ago.
Tama has disappeared somewhere.
Really? What is wrong with her?
Usually she doesn't move a
single step from your side.
Brother...
You are upset, aren't you?
Never mind.
Sir...
the palanquin has arrived
for you from the castle.
It seems to me,
it is better to decline today.
No, I will go.
This...
This is because of me.
Oh? Do you know already?
Don't worry.
I have already sent my refusal
to the Master through Mr. Komori.
- Well, Sayo...
- Yes?
We get from the Master an
allowance of 3,000 koku,
I start to feel myself somehow
uncomfortable recently.
Well, I will refuse,
and we will be able to leave Saga.
But let us discuss it after my return.
Tama!
Why are you here?
Well, come on, come outside now then.
Come outside!
What's happening? You understand that
you cannot go to the castle with me.
Well, come outside now then.
Ouch! That hurt!
Why do you disobey this evening?
Sayo!
Yes. Well, Tama. Come out of there!
Maybe, she fell ill?
Take care of her.
- Yes.
- Good kitty.
Well, stay at home quietly. Is it OK?
Good, good kitty.
Ti, 12.
I, 16.
Ri, 16.
To, 16.
Tama! Tama!
E, 16.
Re, 10.
Yes, it's a dangerous
situation, Mataichirou.
- Call off your decision.
- Do you mean about the stone?
I mean about Sayo.
If you are speaking of that request,
which Mr. Komori communicated,
my sister is very awkward.
She absolutely does not match you.
But if I insist on having my way?
Please, excuse me.
Your move.
Re, 11.
Ta, 11.
Wait! Wait, do not move thus.
- No.
- Do you refuse to replay?
It was your saying, was it not:
"Game on the board -
is alike with the duel of swords."
Well, well,
let's not discuss it further.
- Re, 8 then.
- Re, 8?
- Please, wait.
- Wait? Wait for what?
Mataichirou, what did you say just now?
- "Game on the board..."
- No, I'm not talking about that.
To Re, 8...
I made my 20th move.
- You are mistaken!
- No, I am sure!
- And I confirm, you are mistaken.
- No, I am not.
Mr. Gyoubu, please, return a white stone
to its place, where it was earlier.
Mr. Mataichirou, are you asserting
that I removed a stone intentionally?
No, probably you simply forgot to
place it, when I called my move.
- Stop these accusations!
- Accusations?
Mataichirou, we were kind with you
because you are blind.
But you imagined about yourself heaven
knows what, and came on a bit strong.
- Master, I have just said the truth.
- Do you still dare to argue?
You have to play Go with a pure soul.
One can see your nature on the board
in its true appearance always.
Mataichirou, you dare to assert,
that I played unfairly?
Master, in aspiring to victory, you
have commited an unsuitable deed.
Do you disregard me?
Me? Do you dare to despise me?
Master! You attacked me!
Throw him in! Do it quickly!
- Keep silence about this!
- Yes.
Mataichirou left the castle alone.
Tell the servants this without fail.
- It will be done.
- Fill the well with earth and sand.
Nail down the cover.
What? Mr. Mataichirou has not yet
returned from the castle?
Yes. Yes, up to now he has always been
brought by palanquin from the castle,
no matter how late it was.
He never played Go with the Master
for the whole night.
Yesterday I had a day off, and wasn't in
the castle. Did you send someone there?
I sent Yousuke for my brother
early this morning...
Last evening he refused to take
the palanquin and went alone.
- Refused to take the palanquin?
- Yes.
That is strange...
I will immediately go and check the
road by which he could have gone.
Thank you very much!
We shouldn't have killed Mataichirou...
What are you talking about? Though his
ancestors ruled here in former times,
it was necessary to punish him
for his spurn of the Master.
Master, please, have no doubt!
There is a younger sister in
Ryuuzouji family besides him.
If we undertake nothing, Mataichirou's
death will be revealed some day.
However, what should we do?
Miss...
Did you find my brother?
Not yet. Is there any news from Komori?
He searched everywhere,
but he found no tracks thus far.
He had to return to the castle
for his service.
Brother?
Tama?
Tama, where did you find it?
Miss, a messenger arrived
from the castle.
- From the castle?
- Yes.
Servant, leave us!
The order.
Ryuuzouji Mataichirou
and his younger sister Sayo,
although you received the undeserved
benefaction of Lord Nabeshima,
recently you commited
an unforgivable deed.
You forgot yourself,
you exceeded your rights,
therefore you are deprived of your land
and you are banished.
I want to address the Official
of Secret Supervision.
This order is not subject to discussion.
But Mataichirou, the Ryuuzouji family
head, has not returned from the castle.
I have nothing to do with it.
So you must leave this house
by tomorrow noon.
I have communicated this
order to you exactly.
Miss!
What did the messenger want?
Nothing.
- Yousuke.
- Yes.
Excuse me, please. Could you go now
to the temple Zyorin?
To the temple Zyorin?
I want to visit the graves of
my ancestors tomorrow.
Tell the Prior about it, please.
But... Could I do it tomorrow morning?
I want to go there tomorrow
in the very early morning.
I know, it's night already,
but I beg you to do it.
Yes.
Kikuro, you went out on the commission
of the Official of Secret Supervision?
To the house of Ryuuzouji.
I see. What matter have you got?
They say, if a cat drinks human blood,
it will receive magic powers
and a devilish nature.
Tama.
If you have not forgotten,
that my elder brother always loved you,
curse those evil people who killed him!
Well, Tama, now then, now then,
drink my blood.
Become a real devil,
and receive magic power.
And curse the house of Nabeshima.
Now then... drink my blood.
Tama... You understood...
You understood me...
Miss Sayo!
Did Sayo kill herself?
Yes. Komori told me about it just now.
It serves her right!
Toyo!
You have to bear an heir
as soon as possible now.
You will conquer the heart
of the Master then.
And then all 370,000 koku of
Saga castle will be ours.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Mr. Main Vassal, let us
celebrate our victory this evening.
- What is it?
- Have you heard this cry? It is a cat.
- No.
- It is strange.
Probably, it seemed so to you.
Well, I will go make preparations.
Attention!
Beware of fire!
Bewa...
Madam, have you heard a cry?
Yes, it was in front of the entrance
to the kikyo room.
I beg your pardon, I have to
go for my duties!
Who are you?
Oh, Mrs. Sawanoi.
Mr. Komori, Chief of Servants.
This is female territory.
- Who permitted you to come here?
- Pressing business. Permissions later.
- What pressing business?
- Did not you notice?
Two maids perished
under strange circumstances.
What? Two maids?
Yes.
Whatever occurred on female territory,
this concerns only us.
- You should leave.
- But...
Yes.
Get out!
Wha... What the hell!?!
Someone! Here!
Master! What's wrong with you?
Mataichirou... There was the head of
Mataichirou on the Go-board!
Master!
It was there.
- Leave.
- Yes.
It is strange.
Bloody tracks of a cat in the castle.
Komori, are you sure?
It is the truth. The maids from female
territory saw these tracks besides me.
I also saw bloody tracks.
Moreover two maids perished
under strange circumstances.
All of this is very unusual.
Thus, you think,
that this was made by the cat or
some another strange creature?
I think that we do not have any
other explanations.
Mr. Shimazaki, what do you think?
We should strengthen
the protection of the castle
and dispel this fear.
There is no other solution.
Mr. Gyoubu, what is your opinion?
- Komori!
- Yes!
You know the castle better than others,
and you are the Chief of Servants.
Attend to this business.
It will be done.
If you need, I permit you to go
into any part of the castle.
- Including female territory.
- Yes.
- Miss Sanae.
The Master's wife has already awakened.
She takes a bath every morning,
do you understand me?
Yes, I am ready to take her there
at any time.
- Miss Namie, what's about breakfast?
- Everything will be ready in time.
The new cook does not know yet,
what the wife of the Master likes.
It is impossible to cook fish and meat.
She hates dried tunny,
even if it is in the soup.
- Explain it to him properly.
- Yes.
Where is the sword?
Someone, come here! Here!
Master! Excuse me!
Please, open!
Who is there?
Komori Hanazaemon, the Chief of Servants.
I must look around everything here.
Something strange occurred in the
bedroom of the Master. Be careful.
Certainly, sir.
Blood!
- Madam!
- I thank you for your concern.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, I've just had a headache
since this morning.
Seven days have passed already since
the death of Miss Sayo.
Funeral ceremonies are finished.
Yes. Thank you very much.
Miss Sanae expresses her gratitude.
Miss Sayo and I were very close,
we were friends all the time
that I served in the castle.
Even now, I can't believe she is gone.
By the way, Mr. Hanazaemon.
You said that the castle
is terrorized by the cat,
which lived in the house of Ryuuzouji.
I think about it all the time.
The cat mysteriously disappeared
from the place of Miss Sayo's suicide,
and cat tracks were discovered
in the female territory of the castle.
The cat, which obtained devilish power,
cannot distinguish good and evil.
Two maids have perished already.
It is necessary to figure out
Mr. Mataichirou's destiny.
We can't allow the ghost to
continue to have charge of the castle!
- Miss Sanae.
- Yes?
Did you note something strange
in the behavior of Mrs. Sawanoi?
Anything?
Mr. Komori, when I was yesterday
on female territory,
I saw bloody cat tracks in the corridor.
Bloody? And what else?
Mrs. Sawanoi stood next to them.
- Next to them?
- Yes.
Mr. Komori, it appears,
this woman is a ghost?
I cannot assert it now.
Anyway, Miss Sanae, keep an eye
on Miss Sawanoi attentively.
Certainly, sir.
Attention! Beware of fire!
Sawanoi!
Have you seen?
You have seen!
- Hey, are you the maids of the wife
of the Master? Get on the ball! - Yes.
Madam!
Have you already awoken?
May I prepare your bath for you?
Bath?
Well, I feel a bit languid this morning.
I see. Then breakfast right away?
How are you?
Just awful... I tremble all over.
You bet.
Sawanoi was possessed by ghost.
It is good that nothing happened to you.
Hey, you! Keep silent about
the events you saw yesterday!
Is this my breakfast?
Yes, your usual breakfast.
Bring me another one!
This breakfast will not give me energy!
Bring dried fish!
- What's wrong? Bring it immediately!
- Yes.
Did you sleep well?
No. I could snooze a little bit
just before the morning.
You have too weak will,
you should be stronger.
Do not worry because of Sawanoi.
Master, you should entertain yourself
this evening. Admire the moonlight.
Master, how are you?
Much better.
It's very well.
Bring sake.
Master, you should move to another
house as soon as possible.
Yes, it's a very good idea.
I brought you sake.
Are you crazy?
- Master!
- Release me!
Master!
Toyo! Take him away immediately!
Toyo.
Where did you go?
I prepared a restful decoction for you.
Are you still frightened?
Please, drink it.
This is sake, it will
put you in good spirits.
She took a bath every morning before,
and not once, from the day Sawanoi died
till the present day?
Yes.
On top of that, she eats fish
with pleasure three times a day,
which she hated before.
Probably the ghost possesses Madam now?
I do not know exactly, but in any case,
you should be careful with Toyo.
Certainly, sir.
- What's about the Master?
- I do not understand.
Don't you understand?
Yes. I really do not understand why
he lost so many energy in one night.
He became very tired, as if
something sucked all his energy.
- Do not say such terrible things.
- Excuse me.
Attention!
Beware of fire!
Come here, come!
Come?
What? The ghost possesses Toyo now?
Yes. I know it is difficult to believe,
but I must tell you about it.
Near the pond, where Miss Namie
perished, we found it.
We should find a way to banish the
ghost from Toyo as soon as possible.
It is clear. Remove this dirty fish.
You can go.
- But it is very important...
- I said - leave!
Yes.
I cannot believe it...
Toyo hated fish so much,
and now she eats it every morning.
To be on the safe side, lock her
in her room this evening.
Tell her, let her pray
for the health of the Master.
Yes.
Invite monks from Raydzinyama.
Let us pray that the ghost
will leave her.
Depart, ghost, depart!
Miss Sanae, Miss Sanae!
This is my...
Is this... an amulet?
Yes. When I was a child,
the monk of Dzerin temple gave it me.
Sir! The Main Vassal, sir!
There is no doubt about
the true appearance of Mrs. Toyo.
- Komori! - It is necessary to gather
all the archers this evening...
Komori! Do you want to kill Toyo?
If it is necessary to save Master,
although it would be a pity...
- Wait!
- No.
It will be dawn soon.
The ghost will not be able
to act in the daytime.
And then there will be one
final battle this evening.
Komori...
I have an idea.
Please, trust me.
Shiose, have you already
prepared the archers?
Yes. They will stand in the wings
after sunset.
I placed them as you ordered.
It is good. What's about Toyo?
No information since then.
Mr. Vassal, do you really
intend to kill her?
She was my younger sister,
but she is a ghost now.
We must protect the castle.
- Will you go?
- Yes.
It would be better you don't go there.
Komori, please, do not move a step
from my side this evening.
Yes.
- Shiose, Kamata!
- Yes.
- Follow me!
- Where?
Where doesn't matter. I want to leave
the castle for this evening.
- Did you hear this?
- What?
This ringing. And a cat crying.
Cat?
Yes...
Toyo!
Brother...
Brother... You were going
to leave your younger sister?
Wait, wait! Toyo!
Komori, Komori!
Are you here?
Tango-no-kami!
Now you will know the vengeance
of the Ryuuzouji family!
From that day, in the middle of
November, year 14 of the Kyoho era,
horror had left Saga castle.
Tango-no-kami was disgraced,
he restored his obligations
to the Ryuuzouji family,
and this terrible story was finished.
Hanazaemon left these places
in search of relatives of Ryuuzouji,
who lived in Hirado, Chikuzen Province.