Listen, can you help me?
I've got a flat tyre.
Thanks.
You're so kind.
What's that?
Help!
"The Police are Blundering in the Dark"
Another photo-model missing.
Four in eighteen months.
The Police are
blundering in the dark
Housebound Artist: Seeks young
couple for help with housekeeping.
Excellent conditions.
Hi! What a terrible journey.
You don't call me for months
and then all of a sudden.
What's this all about?
You're hurting me!
You're still the same.
What happened to your car?
It's been like that for two months.
Damn!
Your face looks tired?
You know I have to sleep at
least 12 hours till I'm fine.
- The usual story.
- No, Lucia...
I don't believe you. This time you've
really got to hold it together.
- Thanks, Goodbye.
- Good Evening, Miss.
Please.
Thanks.
- Goodnight.
- Such bad weather.
- Yeah.
You scared me!
My daughter, I could lose my soul
but I'd never spill a drop!
Doctor, you're always joking around.
You're such a nice person.
At my age girls like you
always tell me I'm a really nice guy.
Ah! Dear daughter,
is Eleonora ready to play cards?
She'll be here in a moment.
But you need to wake up a little
first if you want to win.
But I'm so lucky in love!
Where is Edmund?
He's next door, with Sarah.
Has he finished impressing
his girlfirend?
Yes, she's gone.
Such a lovely lady!
These girls do a job I would
never do If I were a woman...
Just imagining myself
naked like a worm
in front of someone
in order to be shot by this device which
makes me feel like it's about to explode
would make my blood freeze!
Well, I would do it!
Oh, my dear,
be careful with the crysanthemums.
They need a constant
supply of cold water.
Flowers are sensibile
creatures but also impotent.
They need to be cured with
kindness and patience.
Damn, I can't see a thing.
What's wrong?
I'm going to get a jug
of water for the guests.
I'll get it, you can go to sleep.
Sarah, you're so kind
wanting to help me.
Uncle, it was you who got
me into photography...
It's all I want to do now.
- Such bad weather.
- Right.
It sends shivers down my spine.
Oh, aunt is here.
Is the Doctor here yet?
I think so.
He's in the lounge, as usual.
So, the usual game tonight?
I'm tired.
Me too, I'm so tired.
I'm going straight to bed.
Please excuse me tonight.
Goodnight Uncle.
Goodnight Eleonora.
Excuse me, is there
a mechanic in the area?
A mechanic? Haha! No, there
are no mechanics here.
- A telephone at least?
- Just look around you!
A token (for the phone) please.
Thanks.
Hello?
It's me Giorgio.
Your jalopy broke down
and I was left outside in the rain!
Yes, yes. I've got petrol.
I really don't understand
what's happening.
Hello?
Giorgio, listen to me.
I'm not really sure.
Excuse me, where are we?
-In paradise! (Heaven)
Hey! I'm not in the mood to joke around.
Can you tell me where I am?
You're on the provincial road,
about 30 kilometres from Rome.
On the provincial,
about 32 kilometres from Rome.
- Where are you calling from?
- It's some sort of bar.
We've even got guest rooms
with central heating.
Giorgio, please do me a favour and
come here as soon as possible.
How can I Erica?
Ottavio can let you use his car.
Please, come quickly!
Ottavio is not in Rome.
Surely there's a mechanic around?
It seems like there's
none around.
And then, at this late
hour, how will I find one?
Please, find a way to come here.
Listen Erica, it's impossible.
Ive got work to do.
I'll catch up with you
tomorrow morning.
But Giorgio!
Don't be so childish.
I'll see you in the morning.
Okay, I'll see you tomorrow.
Imbecile!
- Do you have any rooms?
- Like I said earlier...
I'll stay for the night.
My car is broken down
in the middle of the street.
- Could you help me movie it?
- Sure thing, miss.
It's cold, isn't it?
- Thank you.
- Don't mention ot.
I'll pay you now.
- Could you show me to the room?
- Come this way.
Who is he?
My son. He was born
like that, poor boy...
but he doesn't
cause any trouble.
Here is your room,
it's the best in the house.
Yes, but it's so cold in here!
I'll get the fire started now.
- The fire is working well now!
- It's a lot warmer now, eh?
Definetely!
Is there anything to eat?
I'm so hungry.
There's very little
left, Miss...
However I'll go and see
if there's a ham sandwich left.
Thank you.
It's better than nothing.
I'm worried about my plants...
It rained so hard today,
I didn't expect it.
Tomorrow I expect to have
a lot of work to do.
What are you doing?
Don't tear them up like that! Why?
They aren't nice photos.
A mother
never kills her offspring...
My dear friend, you haven't
been well for some time.
Try to relax.
I've told you many times to rest.
And also you my dear Lady.
Alberto!
Yes, Sir?
Alberto, please accompany
Dr. Dalla to the door.
Actually, drive him home...
The roads are very wet and dangerous.
- Sweet dreams.
- I'll see you tomorrow at breakfast.
You can tell me
all about your plants.
Come on, drink up.
It'll do you good.
Goodnight...Goodnight.
Sarah, you will sleep alone tonight.
Yes?
My God!
- Excuse me?
- Tell me.
Excuse me!
Everyone has gone to the village fair
today, I'd do well to close up myself.
Go and serve the customer.
Well?
Has Enrichetta Blonde left already?
Who?
- Enrichetta Blonde!
-So, that's her name then!
I didn't ask her name.
Did you see her leave?
No. I was still asleep.
The less they work...
Call her and tell her
that her friend Giorgio is here.
You tell her, she was
so anxious to see you!
- Go to hell, you witch!
- Like I don't know you?!
She's not there!
She hasn't even packed.
When did she leave then?
She must have left during the night.
This way.
Listen...Listen....Wait!
Again? You're the only
person around today.
That door by the side,
is it closed at night?
Why should I close it?
What's it to you?
Don't you realise a woman
has gone missing from your hotel?
Like it's the first time a girl
has gone missing around here!
What do you mean?
Another one went missing last month,
and her bag was found in a ditch.
Maybe a truck driver
took her away from here?
No!
Marlboro.
Who is he?
The new porter for the Parissi's.
He is very strange.
And also very curious.
- Can I help you?
-I'd like to speak to Mr. Parissi.
- Who should I say is calling?
- Giorgio D'amato, a journalist.
That's Mr. Parissi's wife
and their niece Sarah.
- How did you say you were called?
- Giorgio D'amato, journalist.
- Please, make yourself at home.
-Thanks.
Sir, this is Giorgio D'amato.
I don't like journalists,
they irritate me. Please, sit down.
- What paper do you work for?
- I collaborate with various ones.
Tell me...
I haven't come here as a journalist.
Well then?
Last night I received
a strange call from Enrichetta Blonde.
I wasn't convinced by her.
She had no personality.
- She's disappeared!
- Another one!
Excuse us! I hope we're not
interuppting anything important?
Eleonora, my wife.
Sarah, our niece.
This is Giorgio D'amato, a journalist.
Pleased to meet you.
Well, let's go dear. Excuse us.
Certainly, Mr Parissi,
surrounded by such beauty...
an artist can cultivate
their good taste.
You're too kind.
- Will you stay?
- Stay for dinner with us.
- Thanks, it would be a pleasure.
- See you later, then.
Alberto.
You called, Sir.
Yes, Alberto. My friend Mr D'amato
will be dining with us tonight.
Very good, Sir.
Come, I'll show you some of the most
beautiful photos you've ever seen.
Your work
as a journalist must take you
to some very interesting
places, I imagine?
Yes, certainly.
Both surprising and singular.
If I wasn't a medic
I'd have been a journalist.
My poor father wanted me
to be a doctor, so here I am.
Right.
- Excuse me, Sir.
- What is it?
Lady Sarah asks to be excused for her
lateness. She will be here in a moment.
Thanks.
Tell us about your work.
You seem too young to be a journalist.
Even if he has all the requirements?
What has been your biggest story?
I'm still waiting but I hope
something big comes along soon.
You're ambitious.
Surely ambition is a virtue, not a vice.
Certainly.
One should solicit fortune
and exploit good opportunities.
- Right. What do you want in life?
- Everything! Everything it can give me.
Our friend has very clear ideas. This
is what a young man needs to get ahead.
- Sometimes like is unfair.
- No. Life isn't unfair.
There is good and there's bad.
What do you think, Dear?
It depends...
What counts in life is having
passion for something.
Like I have for my work.
Forgive me,
I really needed a shower.
It was so relaxing I forgot
about the dinner and our guests.
But above all, our guest, Sarah.
For a moment
I was envious of the water.
Envious?
Yes, I have
a very impulsive temperament.
Lucia, continue serving.
This wine is very nice.
Ah! Yes, but like women
it can also be our traitor!
Thank you.
That's enough.
You, on the other hand, must be
very lucky with the women? Right?
I don't do too badly.
Sometimes I have to hide
from them to escape.
You know what you want, eh?
Bravo! Bravo!
No thanks.
Excuse me, please.
Do you want the bread?
Yes please.
No thanks.
Finally, a pretty waitress.
She isn't bad is she?
To tell you the truth, there are three
things that are important to me...
Flowers, good wine and women.
Flowers because
they are beautiful,
wine because it brings love
which is something I need!
And women?
Women have all the qualities
of flowers and wine, and they are women!
I was forgetting
the purpose of my visit...
You were forgetting
you were a journalist?
Now you only have one friend...
Amongst new friends.
Thank you. It's an honour
to be accepted as your friend.
Aren't you hungry, Dear?
To be honest, not really.
But thanks for your consideration.
You're not well Edmund,
you should rest.
For our uncle,
his only job is to rest.
For me it's quite the opposite.
Resting is my work!
Are you the village doctor?
You could say that, but in this
village everyone is quite well...
Except for Edmund.
This is a fixation of yours! Why?
Why do you want me sick?
Sick.
I'm well...I'm well.
It's just work.
A work I don't understand.
You've never understood my work.
Not only that.
It's a good thing I have Sarah!
My presence is perhaps...?
Don't worry about it,
Doctor Dalla is used to this.
Please excuse us,
until now we've been treating
you like one of the family.
Deep down they love each other,
I assure you. I know them both too well.
What do you know about love?
Its like a big splash in serene water...
It hits you when you least expect it.
- Imagine if they both loved each other?
- Doctor Dalla is always joking around!
What have I said that's so wrong?
It's perfectly natural, no?
Coffee is ready,
will you please come to the lounge.
Alright.
Please.
My dear, you know how I always
like to joke around.
Apart from being my niece,
Sarah is also my best friend.
Her father was my brother.
He and his wife died
in an aeroplane crash...
Since then,
Sarah has been with us.
Although we are affectionate
to her, she has always missed them.
She's a beautiful woman, so simple.
Yes, that's right.
We are very close,
she likes to help me,
but this is not enough...
I've been trying to convince her
to meet people her own age.
- More whiskey?
- Yes please.
Let's talk about you Mr. Parissi.
I'd like to know more.
I've heard much about your work
but I know little about you.
- I noticed a collage in the hallway.
- A nude of perfect linear composition.
Right, if flesh weren't
imbued in desire
and tinged with pleasure,
it would be a virtue.
Vice, unfortunately,
enters from all angles,
as if carried by the
wind and the air...
To preserve ones virtues
one needs a constant line of defence.
So true!
You aren't usually this quiet, my dear.
What's wrong?
Nothing uncle, the rain
is getting me down. I feel scared.
You should sleep together
tonight, she's just a girl.
Doctor, you seem tired.
Please don't stay on our count.
Yes, it's better I get some rest...
Alberto, please take the doctor home.
No, there's no need.
My bike is better than any car!
- Will I see you again young man?
- I hope so!
Yes, I believe so.
Trust me, I know these things!
- Goodnight.
- See you tomorrow, Doctor.
- See you around.
- I should also be leaving soon.
Come and visit us again.
We'd be honoured and I'm sure
Sarah would also be happy.
Alberto.
Bring our guests car round to the front.
I wouldn't want Mr. D'amato to get wet.
Yes, Sir.
But dear, isn't rude to send
our guest away in this weather?
Yes, you're right.
Alberto...wait.
- Stay here tonight.
- Really, I don't want to impose!
I would be very upset if I learnt
you caught a cold because of us.
Alberto, prepare his room.
Your room, Sir.
That's the maid, she hasn't
finished cleaning the room.
It doesn't matter, goodnight.
Sleep well, Sir.
Aren't you tired, girl?
I need someone!
Meet me in my room upstairs.
It's the second door,
near the bathroom.
- It'll be great, you'll see!
- Really!
Let me go.
Lucia!
- Is there something you need?
- Excuse me.
Do you suffer from insomnia, Sir?
Right. However, seems like
I'm not the only one...
But I'm doing this for my work.
And you?
I'm thirsty.
There's water in your room, Sir.
Goodnight.
You look like a ghost!
Take me away!
- I beg you!
- Why are you so scared?
You've got nothing
to worry about.
The people here adore you
and you have everything.
I can't explain, it's difficult.
Sometimes it feels like there's
a chasm opening under my feet.
You must think I'm crazy...
But I'm not!
I don't think so but you must explain
yourself, I need to understand.
I really can't explain.
Eleonora makes me do
whatever she says...
What are you saying?
Why don't you tell your uncle?
No! I can't tell him anything.
Like everyone else,
he's at Eleonora's mercy.
But he adores you?
He's so egotistical,
I've always been scared of him.
Since I was a child.
You'll help me, right?
Of course...Of course!
I'll take you away from here.
And you just sit there! You worm!
You make me mad!
- I'm terrified of what may happen!
- What could happen?
Let me go to the city, I beg you.
You'd have the courage
to leave me alone here?
Forever!
I've had enough.
You said it would be a short stay,
instead we've been here for
2 years, away from the outside world.
I like it here and I'm staying.
I work well here.
You'll be distracted in the city...
Don't forget, this air is good for me.
I'm getting better.
But I'm not a nurse!
I'm a woman.
Let's seperate...
- I want to live with you.
- Won't you be scared?
- I'm scared here but not with you.
- What if I'm not who you think?
- You are!
- You'd abandon your uncle?
You haven't understood.
My uncle only scares me!
Why?
He's cruel and he only
cares about his invention.
Invention?
Yes, he's managed to perfect a method
of photographing human thoughts!
- He's a genius?
- He's a madman!
- He's impotent.
- What do you know?
No, don't think like that,
he's always respected me.
It's his wife Eleonora who...
Continue.
She forces me to do what she wants.
- Now I understand.
- But I don't participate.
I'm forced to do it, out of fear.
I'm scared!
But now that you're here, I can feel...
How can you force me
to live here as your wife?
I'm your husband.
Listen, you've destroyed my life and now
your destroying your niece's life too.
You're finished,
at the end of your career.
Forced to live
in that wheelchair...
In your work,
in life, you're finished!
This isn't true. It's not true...
You're impotent!
Only a man like you would watch me
sleeping with another man in our bed...
You can go if you want!
Is this what you want?
I'll never let you call me a whore!
I've found a sick, depraved
way of satisfying myself.
Getting your kicks looking
at your niece's body!
Damn you! No....
Edmundo!
Damn you!...Damn you!
We are... two happy....
Two happy people, Edmundo....
- Is it your first time?
- Yes.
The others are all sleeping
and don't want to be disturbed.
If you want to leave,
I'll see you off.
Okay.
- What do you want?
- Am I needed?
- No.
- The gentleman...
We don't need you, go away.
You'll pay for this!
I swear, you'll pay!
Are you sure
you don't need anything, Sir?
No.
What are you trying to do?
For once I'd like
to do this my way!
You stay in your place,
it's better for all of us.
Do as you want, I'm fed
up keeping an eye on you.
Listen to me carefully!
Do you really think that you
and those hysterical
that we serve, may keep me here?
No! I want to live...to live!
Do you understand?
Doctor Dalla!
Coming.
What is it? Is Edmundo sick?
No, Doctor.
I'm here for other matters.
What then?
Did you see Eleonora
and a model leave here on Saturday?
I don't think so. However,
on Saturday I was at the villa. Why?
She's vanished.
Do you know anything?
I'm very concerned
about this, let's go inside.
It's been two years.
Since I've known her I've been worried.
And Sarah?
Poor girl, she's so
intimidated and scared by her.
But Eleonora could warn
the police or someone?
Pity young man, pity...
It's about time we called the police
and informed them of our suspicions...
There's something strange Doctor.
Sarah told me a secret only she knew...
What?
Edmundo has perfected a way
of photographing the human mind.
Yesterday evening, during the meal,
he was photographing our thoughts.
Mine too?
I think so.
He's a madman...a madman!
- Hello?
Are you Doctor Dalla?
It's me, Eleonora...
- Good Morning, madam.
- I feel scared and frightened...
What's wrong?
Sarah disappeared this morning.
She told Alberto she was going
to the city to see her grandparents.
It's a little out of
character but don't worry,
we'll try and do something.
Stay calm.
But Doctor, I am calling you
from her grandparents home!
Here, in Rome.
I came immediately.
In Rome?
She hasn't been here.
Not only that, they haven't seen her...
and she hasn't even called.
I'm so desperate! Who knows what could
have happened to the poor girl?
- Stay calm, Madam.
- What's happened?...Sarah?
- Madam?
- Please help me!
Listen, stay where you are.
I'm sending Mr. D'amato to you.
In the meanwhile I'll head over
to the villa, please wait!
You must go immediately
to the city, Via Clemente 87.
You must hurry,
Eleonora is waiting there for you.
I'll come straight away.
Alberto...Alberto!
Alberto!
What do you want?
Go away... Go away!
Go away.
Dirty beast!
Go away!
Certainly, it was
what she believed in.
Erotomania
in a hypermanical state...
Erotomania!
Yes, the morbid desires
of her sexual instincts.
- Paranoia, Schizophrenia...
-Then it's dangerous!?
It depends on her state of arousal,
the stimulants that provoke her...
But, I'll be more precise,
I've got all the details here.
Here...
The doctors in the
neuropsychology clinic
where she was recovering
ten years ago,
agreed after some deliberation,
that her state of equilibrium
didn't respond to a latent state.
I understand.
My suspicions were correct.
Is this the first time you've
left there by yourself?
Yes, of course.
We always went out together.
- Let's hope Sarah meets us soon.
- Yes, she'll arrive on time.
So, this morning,
she preferred to go to the police.
If what Sarah said is true, this
will be the big story of my career!
My God.
It's him!
Alberto!
- Wasn't that Alberto's car?
- It looked like it.
Quick, let's catch up with him.
Alberto... Alberto!
What have you done to her?
You're a crazy murderer!
Why?
Why kill?
Why carve up the bodies
of these beautiful woman?
Only to bury them
beneath the lettuce!
You've discovered a method of
photographing other people's thoughts...
What about you?
You could have saved
yourself the pain
of discovering that
you are the assassin!
Now you'll even kill this poor woman!
Confess your crimes!
You know very well
that you killed her!
No! It's not true.
You'd be happy to see me
fall, but I'm somebody!
Anna, Anna! You killed her!
Even this poor woman.
Damned murderer!
Alberto... Alberto!
He killed this woman as well!
Damned murderer!
This was in Doctor Dalla's thoughts.
No...'Stefanelli'.
Yes... 'Professor Stefanelli'
He was an illustrious surgeon...
who killed his wife, Anna,
in a schizophrenic attack
during an operation.
which she was undergoing
to resolve a difficult birth.
Then he changed his name
and convinced his friends to get him the
post of medical officer in the village.
He bought some property,
and lived reasonably well.
Are you the butler from the villa?
Alberto Garcia...
Private Investigator.
Does he work for you?
Yes, as a butler.
I had no idea he was...
I've been following the case of the
missing photomodels for some time...
and seeing how the police
were blundering in the dark,
if you'll forgive me Commissioner,
I decided to start my own investigation.
My agency has been
open for many years...
but without much success.
I was thinking this could
be my lucky break...
The chambermaid,
was she also your agent?
She was my sister.
Poor Lucia...
Now, Commissioner,
if you'll come with me,
I want to demonstrate
this technique I have perfected.
What will you do with your machine?
I don't know.
I haven't decided yet, but...
I think... I'll give it to science.
A discovery like this must...
Yes! It must be used
to serve society,
but in a society run by men
of a superior intelligence!
Subtitled by Sir Gawain
& The Green Knight for Cinemageddon.
30th March 2008.
Revised, re-formatted and resynched
by meridarpax  for Cinemageddon.
18nth January 2019.
Mankind is separated from mere
animals and beasts by one virtue:
Intelligence.