You have 2 new messages.
You know it's Wednesday, right?
- Of course.
I'll finish up and I'm off.
Should I wait for you?
- No.
I'll say it again, it's impossible.
Is the paycheck ours or not?
Ours.
This article will be published
in the weekend edition
of the city's number one paper.
That's 300,000 readers,
all of whom are our customers.
Fortunately, the editor
owes me a favor
and he's letting us
publish a response.
I'll take care of it.
First thing in the morning...
Not in the morning.
Now.
Sit.
We have till 5 a.m.,
when the paper goes to print.
You have to find out exactly
what did or didn't happen,
and write an accurate,
comprehensive...
Hey...
and courteous response.
Tonight.
You're paying for the cab. That's A.
- And B?
And this is B.
OK, where's that fax...?
Here, we'll put it on...
Are you too hot?
Here, take this.
You want Mom?
Soon, soon...
There's an employee number
on this paycheck, or part of it.
I tried that. It doesn't work...
- I'm sure. Let's see.
"First name: Yehuda.
Last name: Elbaz."
Where's the baby?
Right here...
It's OK.
Look, little guy.
Found Her!
Yulia...
What is it, Petrecke...?
Petracke.
Pretty, isn't she?
Looks very young.
What department was she in?
- "General employees".
They clean up the shit
no one wants to touch.
In our case someone forgot to tell us
he was missing an employee.
In this case it was
the night shift supervisor.
That was her last shift.
You remember her?
Of course.
She's a foreign worker, right?
Any family?
- Didn't you ask? - No.
I'm going to talk
to the night shift supervisor...
Negative. I'm coming with you.
- Negative, you're not.
I want to know how come
we forgot Julia.
We didn't forget anyone,
take this cute little thing home.
But I... - Tomorrow.
- But... - Tomorrow!
Yacov Ohana, Yacov Ohana, come
to the office during the break...
Hello.
I'm the HR Manager.
I know who you are.
I'm looking for one of your employees.
Yulia Petracke.
She's here?
No, Yulia doesn't
work here anymore. - Oh, really?
I fired her.
- I see.
How long ago,
if I may...?
I don't know.
About a month ago.
Fine. Thanks.
Let me ask you something else.
How does a night shift supervisor
let someone go without notifying HR?
We paid a salary, taxes,
social security...
for someone who doesn't
even exist in the system?
Excuse me. Yulia Petracke
was a temporary worker
and I had full authority to dismiss her.
- Is that so?
Excuse me.
Just like that?
Your choice to make?
Did you know she has
a degree in engineering? - Well?
You sent the poor woman to scrub
floors and you blame me now?
So she got an extra paycheck,
so what?
Deduct it from my salary,
and let me get back to work.
I have nothing more to say.
Your engineer was killed
in a suicide bombing
at the Mahane Yehuda market.
She's been lying in a morgue because
no one realized she was missing.
Then someone found
our paycheck on her,
and now they're accusing me,
the widow, and everyone here
of criminal neglect
and lack of humanity.
Understand?
Authority or not,
look at the damage...
OK, no harm done.
You said she was no longer with us for
over a month so there's no problem.
Next time just report it, that's all.
Alright, back to work.
Thank you.
"The bakery's response
to the paper's accusations.
"...If your esteemed newspaper
showed some sensitivity..."
"Sincerely yours,
Human Resources Manager"
Are you nuts?
I almost ran you over!
I need to talk to you.
May I?
Come to my office tomorrow.
- Please. Just a minute.
Thanks.
Enjoy it.
Thank you for coming.
Why couldn't this wait
till tomorrow?
I didn't mean
to fall in love with her.
We would just go smoke together.
We would talk about the shift,
the bakery,
as much as we could,
she barely knew any Hebrew.
I'd wait outside,
holding my lighter.
Scared she might not come out.
Then she'd come to where I stood,
in the dark,
and...
I was in heaven.
Every two hours,
for five minutes, I was in heaven.
Then my wife noticed.
Caught me singing one day.
You see, I'm fixing her medicine
before the shift,
and I'm singing...
What can I say.
I fell hard.
I quit... three months.
So I let her go.
I didn't want her
to hate me,
and wanted to help her
get by till her next job,
so I kept her on the payroll.
Yulia Petracke,
employee No. 535.
General Cleaning.
Well...
I have to go take care of all this.
It's OK.
You forgot again it's Wednesday?
The kid is alone at home for hours.
Can't you be trusted?
What do you want? A worker
was killed. Did I have a choice?
I heard.
I already told her.
Look, I...
- Wait a minute.
Is everything alright?
- Yes. Everything's fine.
Go.
- Thanks.
I'm with you.
- I'm working late tonight.
Stay with her until I get back.
OK, no problem.
- Bye.
Bye.
At 03:05 pm an explosion terrifies
the heart of Jerusalem.
A suicide bomber blew himself up
at a bus station
in the center of the city
while riding a bus
headed to Talpiot.
16 people were killed.
The police say he got
on the bus a few stops back.
Here is the bus
passing the...
Daddy.
Hi, sweetheart.
I thought you were asleep.
Sorry about the mess.
One of your workers died
and you didn't know.
Forget about it.
How was ballet?
How come you didn't know?
- I don't know, darling.
Forget it. It's not important.
You have a class trip next week,
don't you? Lucky you.
I'm not going.
- What do you mean?
I don't feel like it.
Sweetie, I know it's hard,
but what can you do?
It's hard.
It's hard for me and your mom too.
What if I join the trip?
As a chaperone.
You'd like it?
Can you?
- Sure I can.
I'll call your teacher tomorrow.
OK?
Make some room, fatso...
Dad, Mom will be back soon.
- OK, we'll wait for her.
If you press the button now
400 shekels can be yours...
It was a female suicide bomber
who blew herself up today...
Make it louder.
Ezra, I can't see...
I don't appreciate him that much...
Great place. Really.
Feels like home.
What can I do for you?
I'll have another one
and some more peanuts.
I charged it to your room,
hope it's OK.
Your boss said it was OK.
Alright. I've read your response -
"Terminated almost three weeks
before her tragic death".
You found a way to retroactively
fire her just to get off the hook.
It was a bureaucratic error
by a supervisor. - Who?
Describing it as
a monstrous lack of humanity...
Look, they found a paycheck
of yours on her body when she died.
You kept her for a week in a fridge
for your article, and we are inumane?
Listen, Mr. Human Resources,
I'm not worried about the dead.
I care about the living.
And I hate the ease
in which you corporations...
Corporations? We're a bakery!!!
...exploit their workers...
and then forget they even existed!
So she spent a few more days
in the morgue cause of me, so what?
If I can squeeze some emotion
out of my indifferent readers
and make them a little angrier
at your wrongdoings, I've done my job.
And that's moral for you?
- What can I say, tough times.
Listen, my article's going to press,
whether you like it or not,
so maybe instead
of wasting your time,
you should go to the morgue
and identify that poor woman.
Think about it,
she has nobody else.
It's your job, isn't it?
Or is HR just a temporary gig
till you get through
with the divorce? - Listen...
At this very late hour
we try to look for some solace
that will ease our souls.
Here are some tunes...
Hello?
Hi.
- You scared me to death.
I'm looking for one
of the bombing's casualties.
The pizzeria?
- No, the marketplace.
I'm from the bakery.
Glad you came by.
We've been waiting for you...
We'll be sorry to see her go,
you know?
We get used to them after a while.
We even give them names.
We called her "Angel".
So what was her name?
If you'd called us instead of that wease
from the paper, you'd already know.
Look, we were angry.
Two, three days went by,
no word from anyone
and that "weasel",
he's around here a lot,
offered to help.
So who is our honored guest?
I would like to thank you
on her behalf.
Yulia...
Pretty name.
We figured she came from there.
- Anything else?
Come, sir.
Let's take a look.
No way.
I gave you her employee info.
I'm not her relative
or her friend or anything,
I'm her employer.
I was.
Let me explain
something to you, sir.
To release Ms. Yulia
I need a positive ID.
The truth is
I don't really remember her.
You came all this way.
Please.
Come.
Now you'll see what I meant.
Wait.
First time? I see...
Come.
These are her keys, right?
- Yes.
I have the address.
- So?
If one matches the other,
we have a positive ID.
No... - It's much better than a visual ID
by someone who didn't know her.
Look, it doesn't work like that.
Excuse me?
Beth Israel street?
Go straight and turn right.
- Thank you.
Beth Israel street?
- Right here. - Thank you.
Excuse me, Beth Israel 3?
Yulia...
Are you looking for Ruth?
Where does Ruth live?
There, come with us.
It's over there.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
"Ruth"
"Har Ha'Zofim morgue".
- I'm inside. We have an ID.
OK, but you should know
it doesn't work this way.
It's unacceptable.
- We'll do better next time.
You have to sign...
"Dear Yulia, from your friend
on the night shift"
"Mori"
by L. I Riklis
They'll add that the bakery's
representative identified the body,
our condolences, we share
the family's grief...
Good work. You did very well,
I thank you very much.
You did above and beyond.
Good work.
It's OK, main thing is
we're off the hook.
I have to rest my head.
- Wait.
I've decided to admit
it was our fault and apologize.
Hi, David.
I also intend to repent.
We'll have a dignified funeral,
like she deserves.
We'll take care of her daughter...
- Son. - What?
She had a boy, not a girl.
I don't get you.
I spent the whole night
getting us off the hook,
and now you decide to confess?
Are you punishing me?
- Come on...
That's what it is.
- You hate your job, I know it.
Trapped in that office.
You need action.
So unwind for a few days.
So you are from the bakery.
Yes.
Yulia believed that God
lead her to this city.
She was happy here.
She'll have a nice view?
- Yes,
facing the Liors Gate.
The best seat in the house.
Been in Jerusalem a long time?
It took me a long time to get here.
Nothing is easy here,
and everything is complicated.
Tell me about it.
But it fills your soul.
Thank you so much for contacting us.
What happens next?
Now we'll contact your
social security bureau
and make the burial arrangements.
The owner of the bakery wants
to do all she can to help Yulia
and she has a lot of connections
with the city.
One phone call from her
can work miracles.
If you don't mind our involvement,
of course. - Not at all.
Yulia deserves a miracle.
"Appalling inumanity
at the city's biggest bakery"
"HR Manager: I'm guilty."
Good evening. I'm sorry,
Madame is sleeping now.
Sleeping?
You can come in.
Sorry for not getting up,
I can hardly stand on my feet.
I apologize.
I wanted a partner. Someone
to share the burden with me.
A scapegoat.
That's what you wanted.
Stop making such a fuss.
Who cares about that tabloid?
I don't. And I don't care
about the readers.
I care that you went
behind my back.
If you're not happy with my work,
say so.
So here, I'm saying so.
Great.
Don't act like a child!
You want to talk - we'll talk.
When you asked me
to bring you back to Jerusalem
so you could take care
of your personal affairs,
I said "gladly".
I care about you, as an employee
and as a person, you deserve it.
So I vacated the job
and waited patiently for you
to come back and fit in...
And you came back
but only in body.
Your soul, your head, they were
somewhere else, opening factories.
King of the hill.
You know who you sound like
right now? - Yes.
What did your wife want?
Just for you to come back
and be here for her.
What's that got to do with it?
You want my resignation?
It will be on your desk
first thing in the morning, OK?
Oh... you're so dramatic.
I know I owe you for all
you've done for the bakery.
But you owe me, too.
Want one?
I understand the family wants
to have the body sent to them.
So tomorrow morning
Yulia Petricka...
Petracke...
- Petracke.
Will be flown out
with compensation
from the bakery and...
you will represent us at the funeral.
The next wave of terror attacks
in Jerusalem is certain...
This terrorism is
beating down on us
it has shocked city residents,
but I'm telling you:
Let's be strong until this passes.
- But that could take a long time,
and in the meantime?
We must be wise and careful
and keep our children safe.
If you really wanted to come in
you'd bring flowers.
You'll miss her class trip.
You know that. - Why?
Her trip is on Wednesday. I'll be back
Monday, Tuesday, at the latest.
Wednesday I'm on the bus with her,
with a smile, a hat and a sandwich.
Actually it's none of my business.
Even where you're here,
you're absent.
Come back whenever you like.
Great.
You really think I need this...?
I don't, OK? I don't.
I don't need this whole
humiliation journey.
But you're going, aren't you?
You can't say no to the widow.
That has nothing to do with the widow.
There's a boy there, her family.
You can't send a coffin
without a representative.
Turns out the widow isn't too happy
with my performance in the department.
She's punishing me.
Stop.
Hey, sweetie.
Hi, Dad.
Don't worry, it's just for a few days.
By Wednesday I'm back. I promise.
Promises again?
Don't promise!
It's the employee I told you about...
- Yulia?
I'm taking her home.
I told you someone
would look out for her, didn't I?
Great. Now one more
but with a smile.
What are you doing here?
- Follow-up, bro.
I'm with you all the way.
Stay away from me.
Got it?
No, no, no,
I'm not in charge here, OK?
Someone from
the Israeli consulate will...
they need to be here.
Look how late it is.
He's here already.
Oh, my God!
When did you get here? - An hour ago.
Where's the Consul?
I am the Consul,
nice to meet you.
Is that all you brought, that wallet?
- Wait... - No, let me...
you look like you're about to faint.
Thank you.
The officer made me sign a...
I released the coffin
and they're about to load her,
the poor thing.
My husband, the Vice Consul.
Hello. I'm very sorry for your loss.
A big tragedy.
Really, very big.
Those good-for-nothing!
Wait here.
Mister Officer?
- Yes, Ma'am, yes.
What are you doing? You're leaving?
- Yes, Ma'am.
Where is the truck?
- What truck?
To transfer the body.
- I don't know. Is it signed? It is.
I want to talk to someone
in charge here. - Please calm down.
Is there a problem?
- Yes, there's a problem.
You signed for the body,
now you're responsible for transport.
What?! - You don't sign anything
carelessly here.
I need to be back
in Israel in 2 days.
Don't worry,
he will moan and groan,
and eventually he'll send a truck.
Arert you giving me a truck?
- Ma'am, it's impossible.
Excuse me.
Let me explain something,
Mr. Human Resources Manager.
Here you're neither in the East
nor in the West.
Things don't work
the way you're used to.
Wasting money is exactly
what I was trying to avoid.
After two flights I have no time
for bureaucracy.
Anyway, these are the bakery's
private funds.
Oh, well, excuse me,
Monsieur Baron Rothschild...
Mister Officer, where is the truck?
Excuse me, what about this one?
- Don't even think about it!
It's a consular car,
not a funeral vehicle.
Stop, wait.
Is he with us?
- Not with me.
When they assigned me here,
I said no thanks. I knew it was a dump.
But what's the first thing
I see when I get off the plane?
This cuddly thing,
holding up a sign with my name.
Spelled with seven mistakes.
He was a driver,
now he's Vice Consul.
Can't speak a word of Hebrew,
but has the soul of a Jew...
That's all that matters.
Look at the road, you want to kill us?
So what's the plan?
Everything's arranged
with the Anti-Semites at the church.
The funeral is Monday morning.
We'll stop at the husband's place
to sign the burial certificate.
For him, you, me and the entire
Jewish nation killed the lady.
We are very experienced
in this kind of procedure.
Your poor worker isn't
the first to come back in a coffin.
But you're the first boss to come
with the body. Very impressive!
He's the first one to escort a coffin.
Nice, right? - Bravo.
Bravo.
You see? A good Jew.
Let me see it.
Ten. Ten. - How much?
- Ten. - Four.
- Legenda n達o traduzida -
OK, five.
- Five.
Well?
I'll be back soon, sweetie.
No, it's just a formality. You can
meet the gentleman at the funeral.
That's alright.
A real gentleman, as I told you.
Believe me, no need for this bread.
Hello. I'm the Israeli Consulesa.
This gentleman came with your
wife's coffin. My condolences.
Very sorry, sir.
Tell him that we're very sorry,
and hope that this modest amount
will help him overcome...
- No, I'm sorry,
you can't come here spreading
money everywhere.
He just has to sign.
How do you say "thank you"?
- "Multzumesk".
Thanks.
Thank you.
I'll keep it but I can't help you.
I can't sign
because we are divorced.
He says thanks for the money
but he won't sign
because he's not her family,
they were divorced.
You were divorced, right?
- Yes.
You and your private funds
really fix everything...
What about the son?
They have a son, right?
Let him sign.
Mr. Petracke, is your son here?
The boy is not here. He's gone,
he doesn't know where.
He doesn't even know.
Doesrt know what?
The boy doesn't know
about his mother.
Police! Run! Police!
Left, left!
No, Stop!
No, it's not here,
let's go.
Police!
Don't touch me!
I hate you!
Let me go!
My son.
Look...
We want to talk to you
about something important.
You speak English, yes?
Can I get some help here?
The lady wants to talk to you.
So shut up and listen! Can you?
Can you listen!?
- You shut up!
Who told you to come here?
You kicked me out of the house.
Fuck you
and your stupid friends!
You can all go to hell!
Get your hands off me!
- This kid is an animal.
Child, calm down.
Something bad...
happened to your mother.
You think you know everything?
Do you?
Go look in the car.
Go!
Strange people.
They killed her.
They can take her back
to the market where she died,
burn her body
and spread
her ashes everywhere.
That's what they can do.
You can tell them that.
It's not helping, OK?
You know what the boy said?
I'm sorry,
this is not a normal family.
Tell them I want Nana.
Tell them to bring Nana.
They're not bringing Nana,
so you can forget about that!
She's Mama's family,
not yours!
What is it? - He wants us to bring
his grandma to the funeral.
Which grandmother?
- Yulia's mother.
Just have the boy sign the papers.
- He can't, he's a minor.
Can the grandmother sign?
- Yes.
Then we'll bring whoever he wants...
How generous of you.
- Shut up.
Excuse me, but that grandmother's
village is over 0001 km from here!
There's no airport there.
- Fine, a helicopter then.
Will you tell them?
Mr. Petracke, we'll bring her
with a helicopter.
OK, let's go home for dinner...
Blessed are you Lord our God,
who has sanctified us
and commanded us... - Amen.
To light the candles of Shabbat.
Amen.
Good Shabbos.
- Good Shabbos.
Most important is how to bring
Mrs. Petracke to eternal rest...
If we go to church without
a signed burial certificate.
They'll send you back home,
coffin and all.
Not that I'm worried.
Did you locate the grandmother?
Again?
She can't be reached...
He's driving me crazy
with the grandmother...
You're making a mistake.
I'm telling you again.
A big mistake.
And a dangerous one, too.
Yes. No? Thanks.
So? - I told you, it's a holiday,
no rental cars.
And they said on TV
that there's a storm coming,
maybe even today.
- I'll manage.
By noon I would have arranged
all the certificates...
All this mess is because
the boy wants his grandma?
No, because I'm stuck
with the body. That's the mess.
And by the way, it's 039 kilometers.
We'll make it.
Can I have the keys?
- Sorry, the van won't make it.
Certainly not in the weather
they're predicting.
This is where you are mistaken,
Madame Consul.
Don't think about this old van.
Think about the new van you'll
be able to buy when we get back.
You're not in the East...
- Nor the West, I know.
A trip to the Holy Land?
The bakery would love to invite you
on a vacation to Jerusalem.
You think I have time for a trip?
Next year in Jerusalem!
- Or Australia.
Why do all you Israeli men
think you're irresistible?
Thank you.
- My pleasure. Any time.
Hey! You're not leaving
the reporter here!
I wish...
Does the widow know about this?
It wasrt part of the deal.
Besides, don't you have a school trip?
Back by Wednesday, tops.
Please meet our driver.
Very good with cars,
trucks, everything.
Are you sure about him?
He does messenger work for the Consul
for many many years.
I'm very sorry, but with my eyes
we wouldn't get very far.
It's OK. - But maybe I can be
diplomatic liaison. Translator.
If your wife doesn't mind,
I don't care.
What are you doing? This work is not
for your delicate hands.
He asked me.
Try to be civilized with these people.
You bring him back safe and sound, you hear me?
I find one little scratch on him
I'll make it a consular affair!
You hear me?
I'm on your side!
Fuck you!
- What does he want from me?
Hello?
- What's up?
I'm OK, how are things?
You promised to call
when you got there.
I tried,
there was no reception here.
Is she home?
- No, she's at ballet class, remember?
- Legenda n達o traduzida -
Finally I'm taking her
to her mother's village to bury her.
Great.
- Crazy, right?
So you won't make it on time...
Of course I'll make it.
Within a half a day
I'll be done with it.
I'm sure you will...
Is there any way this thing
can go faster?
OK, five minutes are over.
Son of a bitch! Fuck you!
- Enough, enough...
He's a friend.
I'll talk to him. Let's go.
From the bakery.
You know,
your mama worked here...
yes?
Very good worker.
Yulia... a very special person.
Don't get offended. Maybe he
doesn't like bullshit on his bread.
- Legenda n達o traduzida -
Let me have some.
You have to touch all of them?
This is bread from the Holy Land.
Bread from the Holy Land.
- Thank you.
Did the grandma call?
No, no, everything is OK.
OK, bye, love.
Tzwika?
No, it's too early for me.
Thank you.
Is she OK up there?
She hasn't complained yet.
So?
The Consul says hello.
And...?
No word from the grandmother.
OK, let's go.
Can you get the driver, please?
Don't you get it?!
- It's OK.
Get lost! Get lost! - Leave him
alone already, we're going.
I just want his picture.
I'm checking an incident.
What's going on here?
This is the decision.
Do you like good news first, or bad?
First of all,
we no longer have a driver.
Turns out his license expired
five years ago.
I take full responsibility, of course.
I'm sorry but I didn't know...
- Legenda n達o traduzida -
What else?
- What else.
Burial certificate
is for two days ago.
So officially
we are tomb raiders.
He also says there's a cemetery right
here in town and the municipality
will be happy to arrange,
for a fee,
a plot and a priest
for the deceased citizen.
The good news is
there are no charges.
Charges? What charges?
My condolences.
Fuck your condolences...
Sir... sir...
Look.
We came all the way
from Jerusalem.
Jerusalem, Israel, so that she can
be buried with her family.
At her sors request. OK?
We're bringing Yulia Petracke home.
Can I get some help here?
- My friend,
Mrs. Petracke is already home.
Where her body goes,
is a municipal concern.
Believe me,
she doesn't care anymore.
Goodbye.
Our condolences. We will help
with the burial arrangements.
Funny, huh?
That this is how it ends.
Not ha ha funny, I mean.
Depressing funny.
A nowhere woman
in a nowhere place.
Let's get the coffin.
03, 30, Go to the school,
there's a problem!
Copy.
On our way.
Hello.
Hi boss. Good news.
I got you on an earlier flight.
Great, what time is my flight?
Be at the airport
tomorrow morning at 00:7 a.m.
Hello? Do you hear me?
Boss?
- Hold on...
Call you later.
- But what about the ticket...?
What are you doing?
Let's get out of here!
- Mama, we're out of here!
Move it, move it, let's go!
Go, go, go...
Cool! Cool!
What's he saying?
- He says you are cool.
Come on...
It's not funny.
Stop already...
What's this nonsense?
Great...
You're killing me...
She's big now, she's...
Thank you.
But she doesn't like
when I take her photos anymore.
She's waiting for me
to come tomorrow.
I didn't tell her there's no way
I'm going to make it on time.
No way.
But she knows.
She knows, she always knows.
Because I'm not there.
I'm never there.
There was no time to call till now.
Because.
I didn't call just to fight.
We'll talk when I get back.
My battery's low.
Bye, me too.
Bye, Mom.
Thanks.
So tell me,
the bakery's "Special Operations"
division. What was that?
The truth is I enjoyed it.
A lot of logistics,
improvisation...
A bit like the army.
I liked it.
So what went wrong?
You left in March and were due back
by the end of the summer.
But you didn't get back
till February.
Did your wife change the locks?
Something like that.
Never considered bringing them over?
- How about you?
You have a family? A wife?
- We're talking about me now?
You live with your mom, huh?
That's nonsense.
I don't know what
the widow thinks of our crusade.
We're making one
hell of a detour here.
1000 kilometers out of our way
just to do the right thing.
I'm afraid the storm is coming soon.
Maybe we should stop
somewhere tonight?
Of course.
Maybe I have an idea.
Back in communist days some people
thought that if Armageddon comes
this place will save them.
Now I'm not so sure.
OK, but let's have a look.
What the hell is this place?
Only five stories deep.
No big deal.
I'm not staying here.
Sure you're not.
Get the hell in.
I'm serious, the stupidity,
the injustice and
appalling and inhumanity
it is all materialized here,
in this bunker.
Excuse me, can I have
another drop of this Tzwika?
How can you eat this crap?
It's like the tower of Babel,
only in reverse.
We're like the generation of
the flood who tried to reach God.
Digging and digging,
10-20-30-50 feet under the ground, as deep as technology will get us,
and all from fear! Fear of the food, fear of the apocalypse -
Digging ourselves
into holes and bunkers,
building underground
shelters and hangars.
I decided not to go down
into bunkers anymore, get it?
Someone has to show what happens
to those who stay outside!
Enought already,
let me eat.
By the way, this guy, the Human Resoucers Manager
who thought your mother was "so special"?
"A good worker who everybody loved?"
He didn't even know her, didn't know if she was alive or dead!
I'm the one who set this whole thing in motion.
The only reason he's here is because of me
and because his boss made him.
Leave him alone.
He doesn't understand a word.
He understands me perfectly well.
Right, kid?
You know, he didn't even
want to identify her body,
I made him go.
But who knows if he did or not.
Maybe he got cold feet, signed
the papers without even looking...
- You don't get it?
- Maybe it's not even her in there.
Who knows? He doesn't ,
I promise...
One more word and I'll lock you up
in this bunker for life, understand?
He has a right to know
that this whole trip is for PR.
- Shut up! Let go!
- Let go!
Mama, mama.
Please tell me you're not in there.
Please, mama, I don't want you
to be in there.
Mama, mama!
- Mama, mama!
- What are you doing?!
You want to catch pneumonia?!
- You little...
- Let me go!
Fuck you!
You are not my father.
Go back home, you ass.
- Understand?!
- I'm sick of your people.
- Want to see if she's there?
- No, no.
- Let's see.
- No, I can't see.
Let go of me!
No, no.
- Don't open it.
- Come, let's see you!
No, don't!
Don't open, don't open.
- It's OK, it's OK.
- Don't open.
Dont cry.
She's there, OK?
I'm sorry but she is.
She's there.
Don't cry.
He was right, you know?
I never met your mother.
You understand every word
I'm saying, don't you?
How old are you?
- 13? 14?
- 14...
and 3 months...
- And 26 days.
- 26 days.
Son of a gun.
O que foi?
Stop, stop, I'm OK.
- You sure?
- Yes, I'm OK.
You are not OK.
You scared me.
Are you OK?
Can you help me, please?
I know these viroses.
24 hours and they's gone.
- Dude, you haven't moved in two days.
- Really?
- But that's cool, we're in no rush.
- I have to call my wife.
I notified everybody.
Look, I'm sorry about the...
It's just that...
What's happening?
The van broke down.
The gear broke.
So both you and the car can't function.
We should re-consider the plan.
Excuse me?
A miracle!
Back from the dead!
Israeli infantry!
Stomach of steel!
- How's the van doing?
- No resurrection there.
- Can you ask him what this is?
- What's this?
Ladies and gentlemen, we present...
Bogdan, Adi...
Tiger 2 Humvee from original
Gorky automobile factory!
215 horses,
turbo diesel, six cylinders.
He says no one's going to miss it
if it disappears for a few days only.
What do you say, boy?
Shall we take it?
OK. I want you to wait here for the mechanic,
then take the van back down. Both of you.
What? No way!
I told you I'm whith you all the way.
- There's not enoght room
- Are you sure?
I promised your wife
I'd get you back in 2 days.
I'm in trouble already.
Just so you know,
I'm on to you.
You want all the glory for
yourself, it's not fair.
Let's go, boy.
But your better document
the wole thing, or else!
And take care of her.
Because without my follow up,
my readers will keep
thinking you're an asshole,
your wife won't changes the locks.
And you'll be stuck in that
lousy hotel like a tourist.
- Take it.
- What is it?
Don't worry, it's
the bakery's money.
We're in the same payroll, right?
Just whem we finally
had a "moment"...
Regards to your mon.
Bon voyage!
To you too.
Let's go.
Michael Jackson!
Get in here before
you freeze your ass.
- Hello?
- Hi, dad. What's up?
Hey, sweetie!
What are you doing at home?
- I didn't go on the school trip.
- Why, sweetie?
- I didn't feel like it...
- Sweetie...
It's OK, dad, as long as you
bring Yulia back to her mother.
Yes, but...
Dad, I gotta go.
Yes, OK.
I'll call you when I
get to the village. OK?
Kisses.
OK, dad.
For mom, too...
Hello?
Did you come here a lot
with your mother?
It was the last time I see her.
Is here!
God, such a big boy.
I'm sorry.
This is Yulia's son.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
I have a few things of Yulia's
from Jerusalem.
This is the Hebrew name the girls
in her neighborhood gave her.
Ruth.
They found this on her
the day she left us.
The keys to the apartment
in Jerusalem.
I...
I apologize. This is a...
I need you to sign.
Ask him if Yulia was happy there.
She wants to know if...
Yulia was happy there.
I don't know.
He doesn't know.
So why did you bring her here?
Thank you.
I thank you
but it's a mistake.
It's a big mistake.
What did she say?
She said thank you.
That I understood.
What did she really say?
She said you made a big mistake.
OK.
She thinks that Yulia
does not belong here.
She lived in Jerusalem,
she died in Jerusalem,
she must be buried there.
What do you think?
Me?
Yeah, you.
What do you think?
I think...
for her, this place is
the end of the world.
She wanted to go as far as possible.
Even the city was not far enough.
Thank you.
It's nice here.
- What are you doing here?
Did you miss me?
- A bit.
Come here, you moron.
When they re-opened the airports,
we got on the first flight out.
It took two hours!
Let's go to Grandma.
But truly, I prefer your way,
the scenic route.
Otherwise it gets boring.
It's also not as good for the article.
Thank you.
OK, where do we eat around here?
Hello?
Hi.
I'm coming home.
I'm glad.
Bye.
One, two, three...
You OK?
I'll come visit...
Soon.
Bye, kid.
See you.
Wait!
Stop!
Come on!
Damn it...
Subtitles: Cinematyp Ltd.