Who created these horrible
weapons?
From there, the war and
carnage started
And the way to a cruel death was open.
However,
don't blame this miserable.
We're the ones who don't
know how to use what he gave us.
To defend ourselves from the
wild animals.
The time is coming near
and the fatalities
with God's will,
will decide, which one of us
forgetting of ourselves
will cry, because the destiny
will bring  a  cruel and violent death
in the worst time of war
to a captain so loyal.
That had only a few shots,
in that war that he commanded
to the achievements that we're waiting from him.
Because on these days
it's normal to trespass people.
Even more using intrigue
and politics.
From Your Highness Frederico
Gonzaga, Marquis of Mântua
to the Famous
Alfonso D'Este, Duke of Ferrara:
SignorJoannino,
was brought, yesterday, Mântua
To be treated of a leg wound.
that he got from a shot fired by the
army of Frendsburg
But the doctors said that he
is between life and death.
It's not enough being loyal,
as you are
if your good name isn't recognized
By our religion and our faith
that we follow since our birth.
By the dawn of the day,
he woke up, with a lot of pain.
And, at the time he saw me,
he told me to ask Maria, his wife
to send his son, Cosimo
And when he was talking,he could feel
the death coming for him,
and got sad.
He told me to bring his company bed,
so he could die like a soldier.
At this time, his eyes were looking
like glass
And the light gave place to darkness.
I heard that even His Holiness became moved.
Although he could stop to cry
the tragic fate of SignorJoannino, his nephew,
The Holy Priest recognized the evil side
that he had.
and that it was bigger than the good side.
But we'll not say nothing more about this.
because God found a medicine.
Signor Joanni De'Medici,
Captain of the army of His Holiness
Clemente Vll,
became ill, which lasted for 4 days.
and then he died in the land of Grifone.
from a fever.
after he got shot in the leg
by a cannonball
in Mântua, in the last day of November.
of 1 526.
Six days before
German cars!
Throw it on the river!
Today, saturday,
joining the army from the
lansquenetes, on the border of Pó,
Signor Joanni D'Medici
and his cavalry,
rided with such heart
that the enemy retreated,
losing several cars of provisions.
General!
Captain De'Medici attacked our provision cars!
That demon and his dark group
- Let's maintain the order.
And avoid any confrontation.
The reason for this hostility is clear now.
Let's avoid losses and cross
the river immediately.
The Elite Forces of Emperor Carlos V,
invaded the country with a infantry
of 18000 men.
and they loot a few of our cities.
But they received only half of
their salary
and to make matters worse,
they don't have any artillery.
The progression from the German invasion
met with
General Della Rovere
and his Pontifical army
whose infantry of 8.000 men
and 600 elite men.
are preceded by Joanni de'Medici
with 600 armed men
and the same number of cavalry
which responsability
is to delay the Germans, attacking them,
day and night.
And Captain Médici
polished all of his weaponry
to surprise the enemy in the darkness.
At first, we're uncertain
about which way the Germans took
and whey they were 8 miles
away from Mântua,
il looked like they wanted to
cross the river
in Bogoforte or San Nicolo Po.
But in that part of the river
there were no more bridges
so, they have a bad time crossing it
So, they stopped.
The bridge fell.
The soldiers of the pontifical army
had cut the ropes.
The supreme German Commander,
General Frundsberg,
was in a hurry to go back to Rome
because he had trained his soldiers
to kill the priests
and to stole the wealth of the Church.
He had a gold rope that was always
with him.
Claiming he was going to hang
the Pope with it!
Prepare yourselves for an urgent message.
A messenger!
Prepare the messenger to leave.
A message to Captain De'Medici!
We have to expel Frundberg
before he crosses the river,
and opens his way to Parma.
If he refuses to fight us,
it's because he wants to go back to Rome.
In the middle of the winter, he won't
find neither food nor amunition.
He now how to find it.
That Luteran!
Not for a long time.
To Francesco Maria Della Rovere,
Duke of Urbino,
Supreme Commander
of the Pontifical Army.
It looks to me
that the Italian army,
not being disciplined,
and don't obeying any orders,
our infantry can't
take the attack
of the German Army
Although that army
doesn't have artillery
And it would be better
to attack
this army of lansquenetes
through skirmish and sudden attacks,
to cause them damage and to stop
the renew of their stocks,
the only way to destroy
the order and obtain victory.
upon people so weel organized.
Your faithful and obedient
Giovanni De'Medici.
Here's the reward for a soldier
of these days.
a bullet flattened as a coin.
Colonel Cuppano,
the new fire weapons change the wars,
but the wars change the world.
For the honored
Captain De'Medici.
Your Highness can be sure
that you're so important to me
that i'll always regret
when you make me a request
that I can't fulfill.
like this from today, regarding
the artillery
that you ask, and I can't do.
And certainly, I don't know anyone
that can do that on these dark times.
That is the reason
that i ask you, Captain De'Medici,
that you forgive me, because I can't
do what you're asking
Your brother,
Alfonso D'Este, Duke of Ferrara.
A long hair and a long beard are both
a nest for lices.
And is an advantage to the enemy.
I'm so hungry that I could eat a pig.
- And i'd eat even it's bones.
Those bastards, of all races and religions
just do evil things.
They rape women,
burn the grass and kill the cattle.
they stole our things,
and what is worse
they don't have any respect for our
land and our people.
The Pope's army is poor, they don't
have any money.
Enough!
No money! Ruffians!
The faster we get rid of the Germans
the faster we the rid of the Pontificals,
that are worse than the Turkish.
Bastards! They hurt the ones they
have to defend.
as the one who they have to fight.
To end this war with the minimun cost,
We should allow General Frundsberg
to pass.
through the passage of  Curtatone.
The German is in a hurry to cross the Pó
to get rid of the pontifical soldiers.
Fog today, clouds tomorrow.
If the lansquenetes can have
on day ahead of the pontifical.
they can cross the river and
open the way to Milan.
Guards!
- To your work!
Inform the vicar that Gonzaga said,
that tonight we'll let General Frundsberg pass.
and so his Army.
- Yes, Your Honor.
In the name of the father, the son
And The Holy Spirit. Amen.
What they'll say in Mântua
when they see me
asking favors for other people?
You'll be put aside.
Here you have,
the reward for my honor,
that, without hesitation,
I delivered for everyone to see.
Everyone is watching
the love that you've been showing.
They know that I trust you
They know that I never denied
any favors.
It's too cruel
that from this love,
that I though that it was eternal
I got only disgrace
All that I have left
is to bear the disgrace of my husband.
And I can only hope for
a disgraceful fate.
In the name of Your Majesty,
the Emperor,
The german Ambassador
for the Duke of Ferrara,
Alfonso D'Este!
Your Precious Imperial Highness,
Carlos V,Emperor Of Germany
Sent me in person,
a noble Ambassador
so that I can share.
of your honored investiment.
And also to bring the wedding contract.
Between our son, Hercule
and your beloved daughter
the distinct Margarida of Áustria.
Artillery piece known as
"falconetto",
a new mecanism of reloading from
the back, allowing
a faster charging and a greater fire power.
Hurry up!
Hide this.
My beloved wife,
please, send me six plates,
some bowls and cups.
Two towels and 8 napkins.
Two blouses,
Because is very cold in here.
Since our last report,
nothing happened in here,
that we should tell you, Your Highness.
And if wasn't for these letters,
it wouldn't bother you
in your absence.
Keep it straight.
For God's sake.
Keep yourself on the border.
With the chain!
That's it! Well done.
I'm Matteo Cusastro,
Chanceler of the Marquis of Mântua.
I bring greetings from Your Highness,
and the promise of hospitality
to General Frundsberg
and his Imperial Army in Gonzaga's Fort.
Fill it, so it'll last the whole night.
Read something to me.
Here's what Maquiavel wrote:
"The loyalty of the mercenaries
is short.
"Why should them be loyal to the ones
they don't know?"
"Why Gods and Saints would we make
them swear?
"The ones they love,
or the ones they hate?
"I don't know anyone they love.
"But i know they hate everyone
"Nothing is worst than the idea
"that all the wars are created
because of money.
"Instead Of politics."
- Capitão De'Medici!
Who's there?
They located Frundsberg
in the road of Mântua.
Between Montanara and Curtatone.
preceded by a squadron, with
Gonzaga's weapons.
You're sure?
- According to our patrol.
That bastard Federico
swears loyalty to the Pope,
And then offers protection
to the Germans.
It's politics, Monsieur Aretino
Like Maquiavel wrote,
the politics is worst than the weapons.
The Germans had gone back
to cross the Pó.
We can't stop them now.
If we stop Frundsberg,
we'll stop the war.
To proceed at night,
the great risk is the swamp.
The worst thing for the soldiers
The wars represent only
problems, dear Luc'Antonio.
The cavalry must be ready to leave.
Guards!
A moment!
Wait!
A car will leave.
Let it pass!
Raise the door, but don't
block the chains
Two sentinels waiting for orders.
Where are you going at this time?
You're searching for hell
or there are crows in your rooftop?
You're damned souls without rest?
De Profundis Clamo Te Domine.
We're searching the camp
of the pontificals.
Search for your salvation,
your ignorants..
We're living times of ignorance,
and the triumph of the Beast
For your there is no forgiveness,
no salvation,
Is there anyone in here?
Answer!
We're searching Captain De'Medici.
They're gone for a few hours.
Let's go.
We'll keep searching.
Pontifical mail.
Inform captain De'Medici!
The Germans entered through
the passage of Curtatone!
Ride faster.
And stick together.
Vicar, release the guards.
All torches must be thrown away.
Hurry! They can't see the light.
Silence.
Raise the bridge and tie the chains.
Order everyone to be quiet tonight.
You, where you're going?
Stop! Customs from Parma.
Who are you, venicean dog?
I bring salt.
From Ferrara to Mântua.
Always authorized.
Screw you
And your mother too.
ANd your father, that pig.
Hurry up!
Tonight, we did it.
Commander Frundsberg
allowed me to know that he understands.
the damage caused by those soldiers on
this land.
But that's war, there's nothing you can do.
And to you, he'll always be grateful.
For let him pass.
Giving him an advantage on the pontificals.
and cross the Pó in Ostiglia,
the only bridge still in one piece.
But, to leave no doubts.
We'll send an urgent message to
His Holiness.
To tell how Your Highness
Ask him for forgiveness.
For what i was forced to do,
Because i could never had stopped the
lansquenetes from passing
they would pass anyway.
Guards, open.
Lower the bridge.
I'm Giovanni De'Medici,
Captain of the pontifical army,
asking for passage.
We're searcing the germans from Frundsberg! Open it.
Tell the vicar to give the order.
In the name of God, don't answer.
In the name of His Holiness,
and Your King.
That the eternal Lord kill us right now.
Open this door.
Betray the church.
Or tomorrow i'll cut your throats,
starting from the vicar.
And this bastard Gonzaga
Traitors! Bastards
Bastards!
What is that at this time of the night?
It's captain De'Medici.
He's in the passage of Curtatone
with his men.
He's searching for General Frundsberg,
in the middle of the night.
He manaced the vicar and Your Highness.
He said that if we don't lower the bridge.
Tomorrow morning, heads will roll.
firewood for the fire.
We need to get warm.
Look!
What a strange Christ.
The Christ of the poors.
of the hungry,
the homeless.
Bivaque Bande Nere near the walls of Curtatone
If the money dows not came from Rome.
What we'll say?
TO be happy with the blessing
of the Pope?
Wine against the cold??
Dear Luc'Antonio,
in Rome, you know
that the blessing without weapons
doesn't win wars.
Get him up.
Pull the head.
See if he bites you.
Or send you to hell to burn your ass.
To warm myself
i'd burn the Christ and the Virgin Mary.
My beloved wife,
i want you to go to Rome,
the faster the better.
You know my needs.
Explain that to the Pope.
How i'm without means to continue.
In the war, tho ear the
respect of the soldiers.
we have to spend as much as we can.
I ordered a little bed,
so that 2 men can carry without problem.
Our little Cosimo had a fever
during two days.
but we had no doubts that he would be
better soon.
so we left Rome.,
although is snowing.
Sunday, 24 of November.
Where is the vicar?
You, go and tell Federico
Who's always doing bad things
That when I find the Germans,
I'll be back
So I can have a good talk with him
who didn't let me in yesterday
I'll punch him until he pukes shit.
It's our fault.
that the vicar didn't open the door
to no one, at that time?
If he had talked to us,
like everyone should do
we would ask him to open.
the passage of Curtatone.
But Your Highness
Knows SignorJoanni better than anyone.
He was always very violent.
When he was young, killed a friend
with his sword
Holy Mother,
what a fog.
In the border of Pó, near Mântua,
in a discrete place.
General Frundsberg received
the four pieces of artillery
given in secret by Alfonso
D'Este. Now, the german.
knowing that will surprise the pontifical army
with the cannon
decided to cross the Pó
in Ostiglia
to get rid of Captain De'Medici,
whose cavalry were coming to get him.
Gaining time, riding through the bay of
Bagnolo San Vito,
Where he's getting in prior of
the german army.
who's been advancing for hours.
When our country get rid of these armies.
well be free of this war.
It looks like the head of the column.
It's the personal guard of Frundsberg.
But he's not there.
Armors in the center.
Take positions on the hill.
Take the right distance to fire.
Load!
Don't resist!
Keep yourselves in the border
they're retreating!
Don't fight.
BASTARDS.
FIght as soldiers.
What kind of men are you?
Bastards sons of bitches.
Although last friday and saturday
we've had an horrible journey,
through cold and snow.
We arrived on Rome last night.
In our father's house.
safe and sound, thank God.
We've been imediately received by our
uncle, the Pope.
With affection and attention.
I spoke to him about our necessities
on the war.
His answer was
that he would give us support,
day or night.
every time we needed.
We should prepare to go back
before the night falls?
Before night fall
There's one more thing.
To expel Frundsberg!
By horse, two by two.
Rapid cavalry
two by two.
Why are you so proud?
Where are you going,
armed as killers?
You don't need our weapons
TO exterminate the people in this world.
Listen to me! Be careful
The Lord's vengeance is too powerful
More than all of your swords.
Shut up, priest.
The real wealth is not from this world.
Stabulum hoc praeponere coelo!
That's him.
It's an ambush.
Retreat.
Artillery.
General Della Rovere
inform your HIGHNESS.
that they did not took him to the
dormitory yet,
What we now for sure
is hat he got hurt in a skirmish with the lansquenetes,
that were hidden nearby
in San Nicolo da Po.
Joanni went there with his cavalry.
In the ambush, he got hurt in
the leg by a bullet.
The General Della Rovere is worried
because he doesn't know from where Frundsberg
artillery is coming from.
We already informed
His Holiness, the Pope
That Marquis Federico
does not have this artillery.
And the few we have
we want to save it, as our only defense.
and nothing more.
So, we don't take any advantage
and no one shows so powerful weapons
paid by the church
the Pope, actually
The German artillery
for what we know
Belongs to the Duke of Ferrara
who delivered to Frundsberg
during the night.
in boats used to transport salt
And neither the Duke officials,
nor ours.
have looked closely on these boats
Look!
It's snowing.
Holy Mother!
The renowned Signor De'Medicis,
Commander of the Pontifical Army,
The last shot of "Falconete"
Bad Luck!
- The Real bad luck
is that the winter is really wild
and the cold causes more damage than
the weapons
And our own MesserJoannino
is the first between those fanatics.
Even polished the metal of his armor
to fight during the night.
What could be worse?
Famous General,
Our error was to attack the germans,
who have a god commander
they already have an advantage on position.
But if they refuse to admit
their error.
They cant blame us for the incident
with the passage in Curtatone.
It remained closed, as usual,
since the world is world.
Messer Gonzaga,
Captain De'Medici searched for
your protection, and no one else
May God reward you a thousand times.
for helping us.
It is a great reward to
help Captain De'Medici.
With a wound in the same leg
he wounded in Pavia's battle.
It was a great honor to me
to be in the battlefield by your side
Your cousin, Marquis Federico,
is coming to visit you
with the General Della
Rovere, Duke de Urbino.
General!
- My respects.
Dear cousin,
We all regret
the bad luck of our
Joannino.
Without Captain De'Medici in the battlefields
His Holiness, the Pope,
will have all the reasons
to be worried with the result
of this war.
That's strange, a general like yourself
abandon the battle to visit a sick one.
However, I should be happy with my luck
Because, even with all the bad things
that already happened
I had the honor to be brought
to the house of MesserLoyso,
who is like
a brother to me,
and, if I die here,
I wouldn't be seen
as an enemy of Gonzaga Family.
Our renowned
Marquês Federico
had rapidly called
the surgeon, Habram,
that will take care of you with
all of his knowledge.
For all of this, i'm really grateful
to  Messer Federico
for our old friendship and his charity.
And I thank you all,
My dear friends.
But, above all, I thank God
who allows us to do everything.
Master Habram is here.
Great, let him do his job.
Monday, 25 of November
It doesn't worth it
The leeches are not working,
we've tried twice
That's a signal that the blood is deteriorated.
The wound is full of worms
It's been 20 hours since he was treated.
The doctor said he is in
danger of death
Although nothing is for sure.
before the end of the fourth day.
Your impetuous nature
always stopped you from
make use of my wealth
As I wanted you to do.
Ask me anything now
Worthy of us both.
Love me, when i'm dead
so that my wound
don't contaminate my whole body
There's no other way
we have to cut the leg off.
Do what you have to do
We need clothes to make sheets
In my house there's no one
Promise me that you'll send some
But I don't know what i'm gonna do.
Send two towels,
and two crosses.
And also
two packs of roses
to put on his bed
and give him a good fragrance.
Wednesday, 27 of November
Everyone, get out.
Cut it!
With the help of God Almighty
I'm sad because I couldn't send
everything you asked.
As i wrote, one day I'll have
more money
and then, i'll serve you better.
Am I healed?
Friday, 29 of November
Inform Maria not to believe
so fast in a disgrace.
and that, in the next moon,
i'll be back home
This is only to inform you
that, right now
i'm about to give birth
And i'm sure that the child is
from Your HIghness.
Although I don't ask for money right now,
I ask you a favor.
please, write to my husband
that, in respect for Your Highness
he doesn't leave me alone, as he did in the past
only in the interest of the unborn child
because she'll have his blood.
Please,
Read something for me
During my whole life,
I've always lived
as a soldier
as I would've lived
by the rules of the religious
If I had chosen that path
that you did.
From the abyss, I call for you, my Lord.
Hear my voice.
Hear my prayers
If you remember all of
our sins
How can we be saved.
Have mercy of me, Lord.
Freed me of my unhappiness
And, with all of your Love
erase all of my sins.
Óh, death, where's your victory?
Where is the blade of your sword?
The inevitable weapon of death
Is in the law of sin.
But I hope that you save me, my Lord
and my soul believes in your
forgiveness.
and my soul is waiting for You.
more than the sentinels wait for the dawn.
The Famous Signor
Joanni De'Medici,
Captain of the army of
His Holiness Clemente VII,
remained ill for four days
and then, died of a fever
after he got shot by a cannon
in Mântua,
In the last day of November
of 1526
The German kept walking
along the river
In Ostiglia, they crossed the Pó.
Free of Captain De'Medici,
nothing else could stop them.
The General Frundsberg,
badly ill,
Had to abandon his army, and go home
The army of your majesty
The Emperor Carlos V,
joined with the army of Bourbon,
and then conquered the city of Rome
In May of 1527.
Because of the dead of
Captain Joanni De'Medici,
The most famous commanders and
captains of all armies
expressed their wish
that the fire weapons would never be used
against the men