From 1929 to 1970 the
Diehl brothers ran
Germany's greatest
stop-motion studio
in the city of Graefelfing.
The "pioneers of puppetry cinema"
produced over 60 fairy tale
and educational movies.
THE SEVEN RAVENS
from 1937 was the first
German feature-length
puppetry movie.
Even today the movie impresses via
its lovingly crafted characters,
its naturallstic decor,
and pollshed use of llght.
Due to the old stock, the picture and
audio quallty don't
meet current ideals.
The Seven Ravens
a Diehl brothers movie
Oh children.
lt's not exactly a pleasure
to lie in such a dark box.
Broken into two pieces.
And the head wrapped in silk paper.
But I'm only a puppet.
Then it's of course
all the same to me.
llke that are the humans.
And they fancy themselves
as something quite exceptional.
A human should just try
to walk onto the stage...
and attempt to repllcate all the
wonderful events
which we'll show you.
We, on the other hand, will entertain
you this evening with our act.
Our tricks will move you into
a state of astonishment.
By an act ... which is
about, how some
humans were
transformed into ravens.
ln short. l swear:
You'll be much amused
by our movie ...
The Seven Ravens.
The Seven Ravens
- A beautiful girl.
- She's beautiful, yes.
But also to blame for
her brothers's misfortune.
Her ...
to blame for her
brothers's misfortune?
What do you mean, dear women?
l better let your mother tell you that.
She knows it better than l .
Don't you know the
story, neighbour?
You ... mother?
What is it?
The women at the well
said something terrible.
What is it?
Has an accident occurred?
The women said, that l'm to blame
for my brothers's misfortune.
Mother, tell me.
Do l have brothers?
- Who have said that?
- The women at the well.
Those terrible people!
Can't they just leave us alone.
Mother, tell me about my brothers.
I'm so terribIy frightened.
l'll tell it.
They ought to have left you alone.
Mother. Please, please
tell me what has happened.
- What l've done.
- You haven't done anything.
lt was a misfortune back then.
Alas!
And to what use is it to talk about
a misfortune which you can't revert?
But mother, why do
people then point
fingers at me and
say that I'm guilty?
No. They should not do so
and they're not allowed to do so.
But now it has happened.
I didn't want it.
So you'll discover
everything, by God.
Sit yourself down here...
in the chair...
as a sensible person.
Yes.
lt's true.
You have brothers.
Seven of them.
By God, seven great boys.
And they filled the house to the roof
with their shouts and racket.
Then the both of us fervently
wanted a llttle girl.
Such that a llttle gentleness
would also enter our house.
But for a long time our
wish remained unfulfilled.
But finally ... you were born.
And our joy was great.
But you were frail and small.
And due to your frailty you
needed an emergency baptism.
Then father sent your
oldest brother to
the well ... to get baptismal water.
But the six others
ran along. Because
each wanted be be
first at the bucket...
the jar fell into the well.
There they stood...
and they didn't know what to do.
And no one dared to go home.
As they didn't return
father was anxious and said:
For sure, they have
once again forgotten
about it during play.
Those unruly boys.
But he was frightened.
You could die unbaptised.
And in anger he called out: "l want
all the boys to turn into ravens".
Barely had the words been uttered...
before he heard a buzzing
in the air above his head.
He looked up...
and saw seven
ravens black as coal...
llft off and fly away.
Thus all seven of them ...
had really turned into ravens.
So that's why the women
at the well said...
that l'm to blame for
my brothers's misfortune.
Oh, how can people
utter such twaddle.
Only the heavens...
have imposed this misfortune on us.
But ... if l hadn't been born...
then my brothers would
have remained human llke us.
Certainly, ... my child.
Nevertheless were you only the
innocent cause of all the misfortune.
You mustn't grieve.
Since l was the reason
for the misfortune...
then surely, l should also
be the one ... who frees them.
Oh child ...
How would you do that?
No person knows
where they've gone to.
No one have heard
anything from them since.
- Have you searched for them?
- Look among the
ravens in the field,...
they have as black
feathers as the others.
And their voices, ...
oh dear, they're as unintelllgible
to humans as raven voices are.
But they're no ordinary
ravens, mother.
So they'll not be llving and
dwelllng among the other ravens.
lf one only tried to look for them, ...
one would be sure to find them.
And even if you wanted to travel
to the end of the world...
you would still not
be able to find them.
What can a frail human do ...
against the power of the heavens?
But now it's time to go to bed, child.
Father will come home late today.
Good night, mother.
Good night, child.
- Good evening, lady.
- It's you, father?
ls the girl already in bed?
What's the matter?
You're so quiet today.
What's going on?
Those wicked people.
You have your trouble with them.
Why?
What has happened?
They've told her about her brothers.
Then nothing could be done.
l had to tell her everything.
Can't they just keep shut!
And what is the girl then up to?
- Tell me.
- It has naturally gotten to her.
Who knows ...
what will come of it.
Where are you going to
so early, llttle one?
l go to search for my brothers.
Oh, then you first
need to grow wings.
Such that you can look
in the raven nests.
What are you doing there, girl?
l go to search for my brothers.
Dear God!
Your brothers.
No road leads to them.
Oh, girl.
Why do you come here?
Have you lost your way
while looking for berries?
Oh no.
l go to search for my brothers.
Here?
ln the centre of the forest?
Here is only bears
and wolfs, my child.
But your brothers, ...
them you will not find here.
Come.
I'll follow you home.
l have no fear of bears or wolfs.
l don't want to go home
before l've found my brothers.
lf just someone would tell me...
where my brothers are.
Your brothers llve far from here
in the shining mountain.
lf you want to keep silent
for seven years...
and spin seven shirts...
such that you can make
this into a promise to me, ...
you'll free your brothers.
Yes, good fairy.
l'll promise it to you.
Very well.
Then you shall see your brothers
again in seven years from now.
Healthy and joyous.
That is the story of seven brothers
who were turned into ravens.
But where have they gone to?
lt's told, that they llve
in a shining mountain...
at the very end of the world.
There they llve in the
shape of ravens, but...
with their human
hearts in their chests.
Waiting for the day on which
they'll receive their freedom.
And what has
happened to the sister?
She has left her home
to search for the brothers
Now she has been away
for about six years.
No person knows what
has become of her.
The story is good. But what l
smell over there is much better.
An amorous odour reveals you.
ln such a way,
can only a ready roast smell.
Do you hear, cook?
The roast is ruined
if you let it wait any longer.
Just look how the tears run down.
These disgusting, oily, greasy tears.
Hands off!
The prince hasn't returned yet...
- and we have to wait for that.
- I see, the prince wants meatloaf.
- Why meatloaf?
- Soon it'll be tough llke leather.
And then you have to exchange
the prince's knife with a chopper.
Shut your loose mouth!
The prince must have lost his way.
Do you hear it?
They aIready blow the horn.
Who are you, my love?
What are you doing here in this wild
forest? Don't you want to talk?
Why?
Are you mute?
Have you lost your language
here in this lonellness?
Whoever you may
be, keep it a secret.
Never was there such a beauty.
Will you come with me?
You'll get everything you desire.
So the prince is back again.
lt was about time.
Otherwise something
would have happened
to the loveIy roast.
- You ate a lot, you did.
- Ate a lot here, ate a Iot there.
For me a juicy boar haunch
in drippings is more precious...
than a mute forest virgin
inside a hollow tree.
What!
Is she mute?
As mute as the carps
in our castle moat.
And even then she wants
to become the prince's wife?
Why not?
She doesn't complain, doesn't talk
back, and he always
has the last word.
l couldn't wish for
a better wife myself.
- Look, there she comes!
- How beautiful!
They've sent a courier to the castle
to try out the prettiest dresses there.
Hey ... Hans!
Well, you must hurry in advance
to the castle and bring the news...
that the prince and his
future consort will enter shortIy.
You, Joenk. You shall report the
prince's command
to the majordomo.
That everything should
be prepared for the wedding.
This time sayings were wrong!
To the wedding!
Hey ... lady.
You're celebrating
a wedding today, right?
Certainly sir.
Our gracious prince is marrying.
- That's it?
- Yes.
- And what's the name
of the princess?
- The princess?
He has found her in the forest.
No one knows...
...obviously. Look at
the disgrace. That
a prince doesn't seek
out a better wife!
- You, see how pretty she is.
- It's such a shame that she's mute.
God forbid that their
children will be mute too.
You, her brothers are...
Come with me to the fairground.
Oh yes!
lt was a magnificent wedding party.
Since then no poor
has had to starve.
Come Marta.
Let's go.
It's time.
She has a tendency to compassion,
the good princess.
The people say that she know of
no other sorrow than the poor.
lf she would just become
an example for many...
of the comfortable in the country.
l hear that she keeps
the llght on late
at night and sits
working assiduously.
llsten gentlemen,
and let me tell you...
now the bell has rung ten times.
Extinguish the fire and the llght...
so no harm is sent to you.
llsten gentlemen,
and let me tell you...
now the bell has rung twelve times.
Extinguish the fire and the llght...
so no harm is sent to you.
Lord, today is the most
beautiful spring morning.
Let us rejoice that
the awful winter is over.
- It's dangerous to stroll in the park.
- Why is that?
Because the trees leap out,
the grass shoots and the sun stings.
Well done, jester.
Enter.
l have the very dellghtful task
of reporting to Your Serenity,...
that this very night
two princes were born.
Two princes you say.
l must see them.
Your Serenity is asked
to wait a moment.
Until they've been washed.
Tell me.
Do you know ...
whether they can talk?
Your Serenity may be unworried.
They've already impudently
shrieked loudIy.
Thank heavens!
Such fine llttle boys!
The gracious lord shall present
them to us in a ceremony.
We're exposed to
such noble princes.
Good Lord!
She's a witch!
Keep silent...
otherwise you won't
free your brothers.
lt is so.
ls it really true?
Talk.
For my sake.
For your sake, for your children's
sake! Tell me, explain
what it means.
She is a witch...
that's what it means.
And I tell you, she's a witch.
And l tell you, you're a donkey.
A donkey. A donkey!
So you know better than
the high court, jester?
She's accused of the witchery ...
and tomorrow the court will be held.
Accused. Accused.
Accused have many with souls
as pure as this cup of wine been.
lf she's a witch, then l'm
the devil's grandmother.
The jester is right.
The woman have
noting wrong done.
She cared for the poor
llke for her children.
llke for her children. Yes, yes,
she turned them all into ravens.
Well, all right.
lf you're without blame ... so talk!
Where are your children?
You're under suspicion
of the sorcery.
Do you hear?
lf you know of a
defence ... then talk.
Judge, you see that
she keeps silent.
l ask you for the Iast time.
Let us know through your mouth.
Or through the mouth
of someone else.
Where are the both of your boys?
Since you stubbornly
and persistently keeps silent,...
doesn't give us
information and direction...
about what has happened
to the both of your boys, ...
we declare you guilty ...
of the witchery.
l break the rod over you
and sentence you to death by fire.
Death ... by fire.
That's dreadful.
Poor brother. It's nevertheless so.
You've fallen victim to a witch.
To a witch?
No.
So beautiful, ...
so pure, so noble...
- can that be a witch?
- That's exactly why.
Hideous and base-souled
she would never
have been able to
bewitch your heart.
Because she's a sorceress, she can
choose any form to
seduce a human heart.
- You're heartless, sister!
- No. I aIso loved her.
But can you deny that your
children have turned into ravens?
Can that have happened through
anything else then sorcery?
The court's envoy.
ln the name and commission of
the high ecclesiastical court...
here is the sentence.
The tribunal asks for your signature.
My signature?
No.
My prince, ...
remember...
- if you don't sign,...
- Well?
they would say that in your country
there's no longer any justice.
She have handed
over the inheritors
of the country to the evil powers.
For her there's no judgement...
- because...
- Well because?
because the love of
the prince safeguards her.
They would say that your judges,
know how to strike the poor...
but the powerful are allowed
to commit every crime.
Sister.
What do you think?
You don't have any choice.
Let me be alone.
What do you want?
- Inside, strict sir.
- In prison?
That couId only a jester wish for.
She must be sorrowful,
our princess.
I think, that to allow a few
songs might do her good.
There's nothing here. She is no
longer a princess.
Do you understand?
A witch condemned to death
is heId prisoner here.
What do you say?
Condemned to death?
Then the prince would first
have had to sign, l believe.
The prince have signed.
Signed, ... you say?
The prince?
Signed.
They want you dead.
l can't object against
them if you don't talk.
Only you can prevent the horror.
You can trust me completely.
Tomorrow...
the sentence will be consummated.
Do you hear?
Call on me ...
if you change your mind.
Your time...
have not yet passed.
Think of...
your brothers.
Father, ...
get your morning soup.
l can not eat anything, child.
Today they want to
burn the princess.
Yes.
The good days are over now.
l am old and bllnd.
But ...
this one thing l know.
The princess is innocent.
Come Marta.
Let us go.
I no longer have any peace.
- They've sentenced her.
- To the stake.
- They want to burn her.
- We'll not allow it.
- She has only done good.
- She's no witch.
- They should set her free.
- Yes. Release her.
Shut your mouths!
Or you'll go to the tower!
Come.
Your sister have freed you.
But now she stands
on the verge of death.
ln particular...
since she has been
convicted of sorcery
and deallngs with evil spirits,...
she shall by the
power of a sentence
from the high ecclesiastical court...
be punished with death by the fire.
And your decision stands, prince?
Here's the document.
You actually want to resign
the throne, brother? Outrageous!
l've convicted an innocent to death.
l don't want to be a
distant judge over a people.
You've only done
what the law requires.
The law may say that she's
guilty a thousand times.
My heart tells me, ...
that she was innocent.
Hand over the horse, peasant!
It won't be to your loss.
Run, brothers!
As fast as your legs allow!
- l'll ride on ahead.
- You have to save her.
Look.
The zealot hovers the arm.
That's the sign to light the woodpile.
So.
The poor thing.
Stop!
- Stop!
Sister, dear sister.
lt's us. Your brothers.
You've freed us.
What are you saying?
- Her brothers freed her.
- She got her children back.
- There they come.
- Who?
- Her brothers.
- Where?
- There.
- Make way, make way!
The prince comes.
So, you donkey.
Didn't l tell you?
Or what?
Didn't l teIl you all along.
What did you tell me, jester?
That she's as innocent
as you're stupid.
Do you perhaps still doubt?
You,...
that is now dangerous.
The jester is right.
- The jester is always right.
- Yes, now you get it. That's right.
But if it had gone according to your
will, then she would
no longer be alive.
You keep quiet now.
The prince will be entering shortly.
Then no one in his
entourage may err.
The End
End of third act