- Where should I put it?
- In the bedroom.
Will that be all?
I will return to the boss.
Ténin!
Come here!
Go buy your father's medicine!
Be quick about it!
Fanta? Have you arrived?
And the family in Dakar?
Oh, no.
Ténin has been well-behaved.
She hasn't given me any worries.
Hurry back.
I need to see you again.
No, I couldn't get all the medicine.
You have the best wishes of everyone.
You're leaving us, Sekou?
Yes.
We've worked together
for a long time.
If working made me happy...
I would do it.
In fact, it oppresses me.
What are you trying to say?
In five years, I have...
never moved up.
I only make 10,000 FM.
Can anyone support
a family with that?
Where do you want to go?
I want to leave the factory...
and try elsewhere.
Sekou, you do not
deserve to succeed.
You think yourself so clever...
for trying your luck elsewhere.
But you learned everything
you know at my house.
That's true.
And you know that
I'm not afraid of work!
Give me a raise, and I'll stay.
If not, I'll resign.
You prefer the easy way out.
You're pursuing his shadow.
Be patient,
and you'll get a raise.
If you leave...
you won't see another penny!
I understand that.
You are rich, and I'm not.
"Although God gives
us misfortunes today...
"we are still responsible
for tomorrow"...
I'm leaving, but before I go...
know that I have understood well.
The rich are ungrateful.
Shut your mouth, fool!
I'll get another son of a bitch...
who knows his place.
And I'll get a new boss.
Hello, Adams.
You, Sitan, what's up?
We're mad.
You're playing deaf.
I didn't hear.
Other than that, how's it going?
Where are you going?
Shopping.
Who's this?
My little sister.
What's her name?
Hi, Ténin.
Did you fall out
of heaven just for me?
Definitely not.
Jealous?
No.
Well, then, I'm on my way.
Goodbye.
Sekou, what are you telling me?
I quit the factory.
Why?
I could never get ahead there,
so I'm going to look for something else.
We depend on you.
Have you forgotten that?
No, father.
This is rather alarming.
You quit a job that supports us.
Why are you looking at her like that?
Is she mute?
A case of meningitis,
when she was 6.
And this trip, it's still on?
Yes.
I'm saving.
Already?
You've been gone a long time.
We've been shopping.
After girls, no doubt.
Go on, let it out.
You don't think it's true?
You're lying!
Come on Adams, we're leaving.
Ténin, go with Sekou.
Meet at the movie theater.
Turn down the music!
We're not deaf!
Where is Ténin?
At the movies.
Give me a drink.
Where are you going with Ténin?
To visit my parents.
Say hello to them for me.
Don't stay too long.
You're here? It's late.
I'm hungry.
Go try the kitchen.
Hello.
Is that you, Diaby?
It's been a long time...
And here you are as well, my pretty.
Hello, Salimata.
Hello, Mah.
How are you?
Very well.
I'll leave you,
I have some business at the house.
We can't talk anymore.
There will be another time.
Goodbye.
Where have you been?
The driver...
he was late.
Let's go sit down.
Where is Malick?
Somewhere else.
Where's that?
Not here, get it?
No.
He'll be here shortly.
Want to dance?
Let me take over.
If you want.
Sambou, come here.
Where are you taking me?
You'll see.
If I make you happy, say so.
Don't hide anything.
Look at me.
You're not bored?
You know that I'm attracted to you?
What time is it?
Four o'clock.
It's late, we should go.
Stay longer.
We have to leave,
because of our parents.
I'll go with you.
Where is Adams?
I have no idea.
Ténin, where is Adams?
You must know.
She didn't say anything to me.
- Were you arguing?
- No.
I told you to
leave the children alone.
I didn't do anything to your niece.
She's out on the town.
Ténin, would you leave her?
She can go to hell!
I scoff at her!
You could say that again
if you were spotless.
You're already full?
You have to eat.
Pass me the water.
I got delayed.
I had to wait for her father to leave.
We are already swimming.
That doesn't matter.
Thief! Thief!
Sekou has consulted me...
about his financial worries.
I can already see the solution.
He has consulted me as well.
He must pass by here.
We'll catch him on his way.
What did the spirits say?
Hey, you, stop!
Here's your share.
Are you satisfied?
Yes.
He seems rich.
Yes, I would say.
Leave me alone.
I can't.
I love you.
I don't.
What's wrong with you?
Are you sick?
Do you have a fever?
Do you have a headache?
Take this, and you'll feel better.
No? What, then?
My photo?
Take it.
Already? Hang on.
I'll come with you.
Fanta?
Is my bath ready?
Diaby, the coffee is ready.
You haven't made a stew today?
I got out of bed late.
Always the same!
This must not go on!
I prefer stew, you know that.
If God approves,
I shall go on a trip soon.
Where will you go?
I don't know.
You remember...
I loaned money to Djakouraka
No sign of him since.
He hasn't paid anything back to you?
No, he's going to make
me get it back myself.
You cannot trust people anymore.
Give me a drink.
Is the doctor in?
Which one?
Doctor Diané.
He's busy.
I am Mrs. Diaby.
Wait your turn.
Out of the question.
I am in a hurry.
Many people arrived here before you.
You'll have to wait.
No, tell him I'm here.
Very good, I will.
I have taken all the medication.
You have followed
Dr. Guindo's instructions?
Madame, here is your doctor.
What is the problem?
I am worried.
MY daughter is feverish...
and dizzy.
I do not understand.
Here's the prescription.
Your daughter is pregnant.
Ténin, who has done this to you?
The scoundrel!
You'll have to come clean
when your father gets home.
You won't respond?
Wicked girl!
You have shamed us!
You gave yourself to him?
To that thug?
What's this?
You've beaten her again?
Sit down, Oumar.
Why have you beaten her?
Do you know him?
This thug worked for me.
What's this photo?
It's her friend.
So what? What can I do?
He has impregnated her.
What?
She is three months pregnant.
Are you listening, Oumar?
This is above me.
The world is huge.
Ténin can go where she wishes.
But she will never
darken my doorway again.
Excuse me, Oumar.
Calm down, Diaby.
Accursed wretch!
She who bears
the honor of her family!
Calm yourself, sit down.
I have done so much for her.
This is how I'm repaid.
My life is worth nothing.
Get ahold of yourself, Diaby.
Do not avoid the truth...
that God sends you.
Listen to me, calm yourself.
It's so hard to see her alive...
that one begins
to think of her death.
Oumar, you know me.
All that I possess...
I have shared with her.
Here I am well paid.
I prefer killing her
to seeing her like this.
Justice shall decide my fate.
God creates children.
But we, the parents,
are left to mold them.
What do you mean?
Make of your
daughter a tax collector...
and she will tax you.
You have spoiled Ténin.
You have given her too much freedom.
Do not be amazed.
This was bound to happen.
But it's not what I wanted for her.
Diaby must visit Sekou's parents.
He will marry Ténin.
That's crazy! Marry that thug?
Not while I'm still living.
Who else will marry her?
It's just like you.
Like mother, like daughter.
Me, a whore?
You didn't know that?
Well I became one in your house.
Do you think
I'm fooled by your trips?
I will continue to
go see my parents.
I said nothing,
but I knew what to think.
Shut up or I'll kill you!
Calm yourself, Diaby.
God watches over me.
She will be silenced!
Well, shall I kill myself?
Diaby, your brothers are here.
Tell them I'm coming.
Amadou, I have called you
together this evening...
in order to tell you
something important.
Something that cuts to my heart.
God has already taken
my first son, Karim.
All that I had,
I intended for him.
God has taken him back from me.
I suffered then,
but not forever.
I returned myself to God.
The impossible has happened.
It has happened in our house.
Ténin is pregnant.
We are dishonored.
It is unacceptable for the family.
Ténin may go where she wants.
If she returns here,
it will be over my dead body.
I ask you to have to same attitude.
I warn you.
If Ténin goes to your house,
it's over between us.
That's what I had to say.
Yaya, Amadou, Abdoulaye.
Have you heard well?
Always look on the bright
side of things.
But to each his own fate.
I leave you at your word,
my brothers.
Yaya, you heard what I told Amadou.
Malamine has chosen drama...
and destruction.
Don't imitate him.
God be with you.
That's all.
You have heard what was said...
on the subject of Ténin.
Let us convince Malamine
to act calmly.
Ténin has done badly,
but only against herself.
If he has decided
to throw Ténin out...
we must let her stay with us.
Your place, lbrahim's
or mine.
We cannot leave her on the street.
Then we can return
to placating Malamine.
The prophet himself grants prayers.
Therefore a sensible
man is also a capable man.
Malamine is our eldest,
he will understand.
To disown Ténin is absurd.
She may leave...
but her name will stay with her.
That's all I wanted to add.
No one could say it better.
I have nothing more to add.
He stays to consult with
his intimate friend, Oumar.
You speak without knowledge.
I, Malamine Diaby,
never reverse...
my decisions.
Malamine, it's for me to decide.
You are stubborn, Malamine.
I have come to inform you,
and that's all.
Listen to you father, Malamine!
Otherwise be quiet!
I knew you wouldn't agree.
But I had to warn you.
I'll be on my way.
Help!
Malamine has gone crazy!
Fatouma, warn Fanta,
he wants to kill his daughter.
I make a note in my book...
the date of my reports.
You admit to having slept with her?
Therefore the child is yours?
That, I deny.
She did not sleep only with me.
Do you have proof?
She was not a virgin.
That's not true! That's impossible!
She didn't go
around with anyone else.
Do you know this by your daughter?
Are you asking me that?
It's she who told me!
That day, you brought
her home by moped.
It was April 13th,
Two o'clock, by the river.
She was still trembling
as she told me.
Interesting...
For a mute, she...
gives plenty of details.
You forget that I'm her mother.
Watch your mouth.
Where do you think you are?
Excuse me, Madame,
he speaks like a child.
He says whatever
comes into his head.
That's no child.
He knows what he said.
But he doesn't
give a damn about me.
Leave me to it, Madame,
I'm going to lock him up.
That will put his ideas
in their place.
Lock him up until further notice.
No, inspector,
don't do that.
There has been enough
unhappiness like that.
I simply want him, one day,
to acknowledge his child.
Stop!
Come back!
Did you hear what she said?
Yes.
It will be as you wish, Madame.
But you, be careful.
I'll cuff you the
first chance I get!
You'll see him again someday.
He is capable of the worst.
Get out, hoodlum!
Madame, you may leave.
Thank you.
Give yourself to a thug!
Not even capable of
acknowledging a child!
Your life won't amount to anything.
Go on, disappear!
Didn't you hear me?
You disgust me! Leave!
You are very beautiful today.
Who is it?
A mute.
Alas, my God!
Alas my brother,
what's happening to him?
Misfortune is immense,
but it does not measure up to God.
God's design is obscure.
God reunites us in joy.
Ténin has killed herself
and left us here.
Everywhere one cries Ténin!
Ténin is dead!