Gather up!
- Get together, lazy bums!
- Hurry up!
Let's go!
Hurry, go!
Gather up in the field!
Come on, faster!
Stand in order!
Fall in line, faster!
Come on, go! Walk!
Come on!
Attention!
Salute!
Report!
There are 90 flocks of inlanders,
consisting of rebels and dissidents
who do not want to pay taxes.
The robbers and criminals
are ready to do forced labor.
Report completed!
Lieutenant!
Where's the prisoner from Kandanghaur
who rebelled against the Company?
He's on the left end of the line,
ready to be interrogated.
Here he is, sir.
De Boer,
you have to treat this man seriously.
I have a hunch that
this guy is very dangerous.
Yes, sir!
What's your name, young man?
Answer my question, rascal!
My name's Parmin.
People call me Jaka Sembung.
Your people call me a rebel.
Satisfied?
How disrespectful!
Betron!
Tell them all to leave!
Yes, sir!
Line, right-face...
go!
Walk! Go!
Hurry up!
Let's go!
Move!
Hurry up!
- Good morning, Maria.
- Good morning, Daddy.
All of you can go.
- Daddy.
- Yes?
You torture the prisoners every day.
They're already weak and suffering.
How can they work well?
Maria,
not only do rebels have to work,
they also have to be taught discipline.
We must not be weak.
We're in charge.
- Come on!
- Hurry up!
Hey!
You just got to work
and you already wanna drink?
I'm thirsty, sir.
Get to work!
Come on, stand up.
Don't help him!
Come, get on!
Continue.
Work! Come on, back to work!
Hurry up!
Save him.
Get those bastards!
Chase them! Don't let them get away!
Run!
- Everybody, run!
- Come on!
What?
Jaka Sembung got away?
Bloody hell.
You are crazy, man.
That's crazy!
For him to stoop this low...
He's a dangerous man!
You must hurry and catch him, De Boer!
Do you understand?
Yes, sir!
I'll do it immediately!
Wait, Captain.
Catching Jaka Sembung won't be easy.
His followers are everywhere.
Yes, sir.
Wouldn't it be better if we ask
Resident Cirebon
and Governor Hederald himself
in Batavia for help?
No, it won't.
They'll laugh at us
if they find out that we failed to solve
such a small matter.
Wait, Captain.
Didn't the Batavian government
enact divisive policy
to deal with the indigenous people?
I don't agree with that kind of policy.
I'd rather just kill anyone
who rebels against the government.
Your way of thinking is too shallow,
De Boer.
You only know how to kill people,
even though there's
one more effective tactic.
What do you suggest?
There are many heroes in this country,
yes.
Let's gather them to catch Jaka Sembung.
How?
Let's make it a contest.
Exactly.
"A contest!"
"Looking for tough champions
to catch a master robber
named Jaka Sembung."
"The prize is a hundred gold."
"Signed, Captain Van Schram."
CONTEST
A contest!
Water.
CATCH A MASTER ROBBER NAMED JAKA SEMBUNG
Stop.
What do you want?
Don't ask!
Hey, wait!
Stop!
Surround him!
Get him!
What's that noise outside?
I don't know, sir.
Come!
Come to me!
What do you want, making a fuss here?
I want to meet Meneer Van Schram.
What do you want with me?
I'll join your contest
if you pay me 300 gold.
Right, sure.
Of course.
But you
must be tested first.
That's because Jaka Sembung
is not an ordinary man.
You understand?
He can be a master,
but Kobar
is a hero of all masters, sir.
Good.
Prove it!
Parmin,
I'm worried.
Right now, your enemy
is not only the Company,
but also their mercenary heroes.
Hubbul wathan minal iman.
"Love for our motherland
is part of faith."
They'll be damned
for helping the non-believers,
especially the ones
who kill their comrades.
Parmin,
you're a known leader of the people here.
Don't stay in one place.
La haula wa la quwwata illa billah.
"There is nothing that happens
without His permission."
That's true,
but there are a lot of spies here.
You better gather your forces
in a safe place.
Okay.
I understand how you feel, Surti.
If God wills it,
I will face the Company
and the apostate heroes who oppose us
until my very last breath.
Open up!
Open the door!
- Everyone, hide!
- Okay.
Come on, hurry up!
Where's the so-called Jaka Sembung?
Where?
He isn't here.
This isn't his house!
Great!
Turns out that
Jaka Sembung is just a coward!
Come on!
Let go!
Shut up!
It seems you're working with the Company
that's just greedy for money!
Shut up!
Indeed, Kobar needs money.
But I also need your head!
A hero whose basis
isn't religious knowledge
only becomes a tool for murder.
Oh, my God.
Wait!
Go home if you don't want
to end up like him...
and tell your master
that Kobar died in my hands.
Let's go.
I was amazed by his power.
How strong would our army be
if someone like him would unite with us?
All of you can go.
Go.
- Excuse us, sir.
- Excuse us.
Kobar is dead.
Which hero should we look forward to,
then?
At this rate, where's our pride, sir?
What do you mean, Lieutenant?
We have troops.
We have enough weapons to destroy them.
But I don't want that.
Why?
Because other than
our use of tactics and policy,
I want the indigenous people to know
that we colonists don't like violence.
Good afternoon, sir.
Who is he, Van Holland?
He's a shaman
who wants to join the contest.
He can bring a corpse back to life
to kill Jaka Sembung.
What?
Really?
Is it possible, Meneer Van Holland?
Even the great Kobar was defeated.
Let alone a corpse.
Sorry, sir.
Even though Ki Hitam's a corpse,
he has Rawe Rontek magic
that gives him immortality.
When a part of his body is cut off,
it can come back to life
when it hits the ground.
Nonsense!
If your story is true,
why would he still be a corpse?
Because his head was hung on a tree
and his body was kept
in a separate coffin.
He was defeated by Ki Sapu Angin,
Jaka Sembung's teacher.
All your stories are lies!
You swindler!
You only want this, right?
No!
Help me!
Help, let me go!
Let me go!
Help me!
Help me, sir!
Put him down.
My heart...
You better bring Ki Hitam
back to life to help us.
Yes, sir.
Next time, watch your mouth.
Oh, god. Your magic is so magnificent.
For the will and the power
that controls the universe,
I call you, Ki Hitam,
inside your dark coffin
to be present again in this life.
Search for your head.
I'll follow your steps.
Wake up, Ki Hitam.
Ki Bidin, my friend,
I know you purposely
brought me back to life
to help your employers, those foreigners.
Yes, to kill Jaka Sembung,
Ki Sapu Angin's student,
and our great enemy.
All right.
I'll atone for my defeat.
Let's start!
Come on, get out!
Come on, go there!
Hurry! Go out!
You're so slow!
Forgive us.
Hurry up! Faster!
Gather all of them up at the square!
Hurry up!
- Here's your order.
- Thank you, sir.
Jeez!
Come on!
All of you, come out!
Gather over there!
Come on!
Catch them and gather them up!
Don't move!
Come with us!
You know what this is?
Where are you going?
You crazy Dutchmen!
- You're crazy!
- Don't run!
Crazy Company!
Crazy Dutchmen!
Out of my way! The Company's there!
- I have to go there. What happened?
- Move!
Step aside!
You're crazy!
Step aside, sir, I wanna pass!
You...
- Step aside, sir!
- Wait!
Step aside!
- Help!
- Crazy Dutchmen!
There are crazy Dutchmen!
What's wrong with Harjah?
- Hey!
- What happened?
- What's wrong, Ja?
- What's with the noise?
- The Dutch?
- Crazy Dutchmen're going there!
- What's going on with them?
Going there.
Where's Parmin?
Over there.
- Let's go!
- Come on.
Parmin.
The village was ransacked
and everyone was arrested by the Company.
What should we do?
Everyone calm down.
Don't take any action.
Hey, you inlanders!
You probably already know
why the Dutch government is in charge.
We want to make this country prosperous,
rich with spices,
and free from the rebels and robbers
like Jaka Sembung.
He's a bad guy.
All of you have to tell us
where Jaka Sembung is hiding,
you understand?
No! Jaka Sembung isn't a criminal!
He's a hero of justice and truth!
Shut up!
Back off!
- Hey, come here!
- No!
- I don't want to!
Let go!
- Come!
- I don't want to!
- I'm afraid!
- Sir, don't kill my child!
She's my only child, sir!
- Mom!
- No!
No!
Calm down, ma'am!
I'll count to three.
You're going to tell me
where Jaka Sembung is hiding.
Don't kill my child, sir!
- Mom!
- Hurry up!
- Please don't, sir!
If you don't,
my bullets will go through
this child's head.
- Mom!
- Please don't, sir!
Ma'am, calm down!
One!
Mom!
Two!
Three!
Hey, foreigner!
I can't bear to see a child die
just because of me.
Really?
Looks like you finally gave up, asshole!
No! Don't give up, Warrior!
Let my child be the victim!
Continue your fight!
Yes! Don't give up, Warrior!
Yes! That's true!
- Don't give up!
Continue!
Continue! Don't give up!
- Go! Continue!
- Go, Jaka!
Calm down!
- God is great!
We don't need to worry!
The struggle to liberate this country
will not stop even without me.
If one goes, there'll be another!
I admire your dirtiness.
Bastard!
Everyone, step aside!
Dammit!
Harjah, where are you going?
Don't act like a hero.
Everyone, get behind me!
Good job, Ki Hitam! Great!
Tie him up,
and take him around the village...
so that everyone knows
what punishment awaits
for a robber like him!
- Jaka Sembung's been arrested!
- What? Where?
Over there!
Mr. Bendol, come out!
- What happened?
- Jaka Sembung has been arrested!
Hurry up!
Come out!
What's wrong, sir?
- Pull him!
- Make way!
- Get out of the way!
- Go!
Hurry up!
Keep going!
Come on!
Step aside! Out of the way!
Step aside!
Everyone, step aside!
Open the way!
- Parmin!
- Move!
Come on, faster!
Hurry up and walk!
Get out of here!
Step aside!
- Step aside!
- Parmin!
- Hurry up!
- Step aside!
- Parmin!
Hurry up! Go ahead!
Put him in a cage!
Don't give him anything to drink or eat!
Come on!
Go ahead!
Hurry up!
- Hurry up!
- Okay!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Hey, look. It's him.
Come here!
Hurry up!
Come on!
Come on, hurry up!
Get in there!
Where are you going this late?
Dad, we can't just do nothing.
We have to hurry and free Parmin.
You mean we'll invade their camp?
Yes, Dad.
No, my daughter.
Our strength can't be compared to theirs.
It's just the same as suicide.
That's the risk of war, Dad.
I can't bear to see the Dutch cruelty
against Parmin.
We have to free him, Dad.
We have to free him!
Calm down, Surti.
Calm down.
I know you love Parmin.
Dad.
Let's hope for the best,
and may God make a way for all of us.
Who are you?
Jaka, I'm here.
What're you doing here?
Calm down. I want to set you free.
I'm a rebel,
a criminal,
and your father's captive.
That's true, Jaka.
But you're a warrior of your people.
I'm surprised...
that someone like you calls me a warrior.
Jaka, I pity you,
- and...
- Maria...
can you take your hand off my face?
Why?
My religion forbids it.
Okay.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm here to set you free.
Maria.
Well done.
You did very well, didn't you?
Daddy heard everything you said.
Come here, sweetheart.
I said come here, dammit!
I'll take you back to Holland
and don't ever dream
of coming back to Java.
Do you understand?
Dammit!
And you, rebel.
I'll torture you before I hang you!
Dad, no!
Dad!
Step aside!
You're so cruel, Dad.
You want a smoke?
It's quite cold.
- You bring it?
- I lit the fire.
Who's that?
Don't run!
Chase him!
Stop!
- Come here!
- Catch him!
- Genteng!
- Yes, sir!
Who is it?
Come on!
She's Jaka Sembung's subordinate.
Very well.
Good.
So you're here to free your leader?
- Genteng!
- Yes, sir!
Put her in jail!
Dammit!
Come on!
- Move.
- Get in there!
- Stay still!
- Who is she?
A prisoner, sir.
Come on!
Let me go!
Get in there!
Let's go.
Open up!
Open the door!
Let me go!
Open up!
Open the door!
Let me go!
Surti.
Forget it, Miss.
Don't dwell in sadness.
No one dares oppose your dad.
Yes, that's true...
but I can't leave it like this.
Don't ever talk about it anymore.
We can't do anything
except give up.
It's getting late.
Let it all disappear in your dreams.
God.
Oh, God.
God...
God.
In the name of God,
the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Parmin.
- Parmin.
- Surti.
- Your eyes.
- Yes.
We have to go.
Get out! All of you!
Shoot them!
Come on, get out!
Wait!
I'll be in front!
- Let's go!
- Come on!
Come on!
Halt!
Patience.
This is my business.
You don't have powers anymore.
Parmin!
Hold!
Let her run!
Let her bleed to death!
I'm worried
about Jaka Sembung's fate.
What if he turns back into a human
and takes revenge?
No, sir.
That pig'll either starve to death
or be killed by the villagers.
Sir, you should know
Muslims in this village really hate pigs.
Let's kill it!
Pigs are haram!
No! Don't beat him!
Don't kill him!
Parmin.
Calm down, I'll help you.
Come on, kid.
You're so pitiful, Jaka.
It's hard to fight Ki Hitam's magic.
Hopefully, with God's permission,
I can turn you back into a human.
I seek refuge in God from Shaitan,
the accursed one.
In the name of God,
the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
God...
May it be so, O Lord of the Worlds.
Teacher.
Come here.
Your opponents are highly skilled.
You're no match for them.
Your powers need to be replenished.
In this blindness,
how could I do that?
Don't worry, Jaka.
A follower of yours who secretly loves you
has given up her eyes.
Who is she, Teacher?
Surti.
Surti?
She just passed away a moment ago.
Where is she, Teacher?
Come with me.
She's lying in front of you, Jaka.
Surti.
You're my hero...
as well as my lover.
You sacrificed a lot...
to help in this fight, Surti.
I won't forget you, Surti.
Goodbye, Surti.
Verily we belong to God,
and verily to Him do we return.
In the name of God,
the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Good.
You've mastered
the ultimate technique
to fight Rawe Rontek.
Thank you, Teacher.
But you have to remember.
The pieces of his body
should not touch the ground.
My people have lived here long enough.
Personally,
I'm against my father's method,
oppressing the indigenous people
in this country.
Yes.
Especially for those who hate
the colonial government,
the struggle to liberate this country
from the colonists
is the right of the people themselves,
which is strange.
They're all arrested...
tortured, and imprisoned
without trial.
Even though our people
live from their sweat
and the wealth of the land
of this country.
That is the reason why I'm sympathizing
with Jaka Sembung's struggle.
The ideals of the deceased
were very noble.
We all have to support it,
without exception.
If it's not all of you
who'll continue their struggle,
who will?
Jaka?
- Peace be upon you.
- And peace be upon you too.
My comrades, I bet you're surprised
to see my complete presence, right?
I'll tell you all about it later.
I heard what you said, Maria.
I didn't expect the child of an invader
would fight with us.
My determination to liberate this country
is also the determination of the people.
We must be one with them.
The people are the backbone of the fight.
And this intention will come true
if Maria wants to help us.
It turns out that
my own child is a traitor...
betraying her father and the Company.
It seems that all this time,
you were secretly meeting
Jaka Sembung's people.
It's true.
Your daughter Maria disagrees
with your arbitrary actions
against indigenous peoples.
They fight for their rights.
They want to live freely,
relishing the wealth of their own country.
We just...
live temporarily here.
Dad...
You're so greedy, Dad!
The Company is too cruel!
How can you say that to your own father?
You're such a brazen girl! How rude!
Maria!
Apparently, you believe this
under the incitement of those rebels.
No, Dad!
I realized what I was doing!
Not like them,
who betrayed their own people for money!
Dammit!
The two of you...
have to capture Jaka Sembung
who came back to life!
Yes.
We're ready.
Sir's orders will be fulfilled.
Good.
If you fail,
both of your heads
will be the replacement.
- Understand?
- Understood, sir.
God is great.
- God is great.
Peace be upon you,
as well as the mercy of God
and his blessings.
Peace be upon you as well.
Peace be upon you, as well as
the mercy of God and his blessings.
Peace be upon you, as well as the mercy
of God and his blessings.
- Praise be to God.
- Amen.
May prayer and safety be given...
Amen.
Don't!
You're not his equal.
Hey, you apostates!
What did you come here for?
Do you want to know
that I'm no longer a blind pig?
It turns out you're a student
of Ki Sapu Angin,
my nemesis.
I've prepared a grave for you...
the arrogant Jaka.
Thank you,
but my spirit will be sad
if I die at the hands
of Company minions like you.
You can choose any part of my body...
all you want.
You have to remember.
The pieces of his body
should not touch the ground.
Burn him!
Make sure not to touch the ground!
- Let's go, carry him!
- Carry him!
Take it there!
- One, two, three.
- Let's go!
- Harder!
- One,
- two, three.
- Let's go!
- One, two, three.
- Attack!
- Yes!
Catch him.
Don't let go! That hurts!
Oh, God!
Come on, Somat, help me!
This is my hand! Help!
Take my hand!
Oh, God!
Come on!
Don't let go! Oh, God!
Mr. Company, don't let go!
Oh, no! I fell!
Die!
God is great!
Separate the men.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
Open all of it!
Get out! Hurry!
Get out! Go!
Get out!
Boys! Come on, everyone!
Kill all of the rebels!
Come on, hurry up!
Get out!
Come on, run!
Let's go, Somat!
Come down! You said you wanted to fight!
Van Schram.
Now, you can be proud of your death.
No.
That only applies to you.
You're looking to die, young man!
You rascal!
Miss Maria, wake up!
Jaka Sembung and his friends
are attacking us outside.
- Jaka Sembung?
- Yes, Miss.
You damn rebels!
Dad!
I'm sorry, Maria.
I had to kill your father.
I have no power to avoid this destiny.
He's a great person to your people, Maria.
I respect him.
That's enough, Maria.
Let's bury your father's body properly.
- We'll punish you!
- Maria, watch out!
Maria!
Maria...
Dad...
Maria!
Jaka...
In this last moment...
I...
want to tell something...
- to you.
- What is it, Maria?
I...
love you...
Please continue your fight!
Maria!
Maria...