(HEAVY RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- Sorry, sorry, sorry,
sorry, sorry.
- Hurry, hurry, hurry.
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(GASPS)
Oh!
(CHUCKLES)
Ah!
(SWING SQUEAKING,
AX THUDDING)
(CHILD COUGHS)
(CHILDREN SHOUTING, LAUGHING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Ch-ch-ch.
Ah, okay.
Okay.
Cowboy.
(WHISTLES)
(LAUGHS)
(CHILDREN WHISTLING)
Ah-num-num-num!
Ah-num-num-num.
Hello. Hello.
Good morning.
I have to pay my taxes.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Madloba.
Madloba.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Didi madloba. Didi madloba.
- Madloba.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Didi madloba.
Didi madloba.
- Madloba. Madloba.
- Didi madloba.
- Madloba.
And, uh...
(OINKS LIKE A PIG)
- Ah, no.
(CLUCKING LIKE A CHICKEN)
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Didi madloba.
- Madloba.
(DOG BARKING)
- Did you shit?
- Little gatito shits.
(MAN SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(DONKEYS BRAYING)
(CLAPPING)
(SNAPPING FINGERS)
(PIG URINATES)
(LAUGHS)
- Oh...
- Take a picture!
Take a picture!
(EXHALING)
- Can you... can you reach...
Can you reach here?
- Yeah, but not after
doing some of them.
- But can you do it like that?
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
(SHRIEKS PLAYFULLY)
(CHILD SHOUTS)
(WHISTLING)
- Number one, my friend!
Oh, yes.
Oh.
(TRILLS TONGUE)
- Your wife?
- Fiancée...
will be his wife.
- She can carry?
- She can carry, yes.
- Yeah, don't...
don't worry about me.
No, I'm strong.
- Number one, my friend!
My friend.
(LAUGHS)
- Number one.
Yeah.
- Without horse,
without donkey...
100 lari a day.
- In Svaneti, it was 60 a day.
- In Svaneti, yeah,
but here's Khevi.
- Yeah, I know.
- Local price.
- My friend, number one!
(ALL SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Why don't we...
Can we make it
a little bit cheaper?
(CAR ENGINE ROARS)
(METALLIC BANG)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(SOFT THUD)
(DOG HOWLS)
- Do you want this?
- Yep.
(LAUGHS)
Shh.
(GIGGLING)
(WOMAN SINGING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
♪♪
(BOTH SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Madloba!
- Madloba.
- Denver Nuggets!
- Yeah, Denver Nuggets.
(UPBEAT DANCE MUSIC)
♪♪
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MAN SINGING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(LIVELY MUSIC)
♪♪
(MATTRESS SPRINGS SQUEAK SOFTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
(ENGINE ROARING)
(WIND BLOWING)
- Didi madloba!
- You said "thank you" to him.
- "Madloba" means...
- That's "thank you."
(LAUGHS)
Gamarjoba. Gamarjoba.
- Gamarjoba.
(DOG PANTING)
- Hey, be careful.
He is not pet dog.
He can bite.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, yeah, really.
And he has... fleas.
Dirty dog.
- Look at that goat.
It has three horns.
- Yeah.
- The king sheep.
- Mutant.
(LAUGHS) Mutant.
- You always have
a goat with sheep.
Goat is very smart,
and sheep is stupid.
And sheep will follow goat.
If goat fall off rock,
sheep fall too.
- So are we your sheep?
- Whoa.
Stampede.
- One, two, three, four.
- Hey, hey!
Wait me! Ho!
- What?
- Wait me.
Give me rucksack.
- No, no, no, it's okay.
It's okay, Dato.
- No, no.
- It's okay.
I'm fine.
(SHOUTS)
- Oh!
(LAUGHS)
- Be careful!
No, no, I'm fine.
I don't need help.
It's okay.
I'm fine.
Thank you.
(LOOSE ROCKS CRUNCHING)
(ROCKS CLATTER) Oops!
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Fine.
(TENSE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
♪♪
- What is it?
- Very nice stone.
I don't know English name.
Georgian name is...
(SAYS GEORGIAN WORD)
(BOTH REPEAT GEORGIAN WORD)
It help many problems...
liver problems,
stomach problems...
Kidneys problems.
And in Asian country,
this is very expensive.
$800.
- Wow.
- And it make your skin
very good,
is very beautiful,
like baby's ass.
You can take.
- Thank you.
I just have to rub it all over
my body every day,
and I'll be perfectly healthy.
And beautiful.
- After shower.
- Hey.
You think he just made that up?
- Let's see.
(LAUGHS)
- No, no, don't lick it.
Don't lick it.
Let's see it.
- Hold it for a second?
Come back with my rock.
- No.
(LAUGHS)
Give me the rock.
(ROCK RATTLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(TENSE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
♪♪
It's amazing.
- Hey, come.
- Alex...
- Come on.
Okay.
(CAMERA BEEPS)
- Three weeks,
and you become a bear.
- I know, I'm gonna... l'm gonna
shave it when we get back.
- Hey, guys?
Do you know what this is?
- What is it?
- You can eat.
Eat it.
Good?
- Mm, strong.
- Mm, it...
- So now we are waiting
two hours.
And after, you will die.
Die.
Sorry.
- We what?
We die?
- Sorry.
This is joke.
Th is is k'vliavi.
Good.
- What is it?
- It's cumin.
(MURMURS)
- Mm-hmm.
(PANTING)
(RUSTLING)
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DISTANT WHIRRING)
- What is that?
(CLATTERING)
- You know, Chinese government
say we are too much people,
and we must...
some people, castration.
And... but Chinese doctors
is not enough.
And come...
(GASPS)
- What happened?
- Okay.
(BLOWS)
Yeah.
Ready?
Let me go a bit...
There... no, a bit more.
Yeah, yeah.
- Ah, yes.
- Ah.
Didi madloba.
- Okay.
- You're welcome.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- So...
- So!
(LAUGHTER)
Castration!
Chinese castration.
- And come Georgian doctor,
and he make
a thousand operation
for one day.
This Chinese doctor ask,
"What happened?"
And come look what is...
And Georgian doctor
take two rocks
and... on the balls.
Push, bah!
One, two, three!
And so, thousand.
- A day?
- Yeah, a day.
But they ask,
"Maybe this make big pain?"
Yeah, yeah, big pain,
when your finger...
if your finger come in between,
this make big pain.
But thousand operation
for Chinese people...
Nothing.
This was not enough.
And come Gurian person,
Gurian doctor.
Do you know Guria?
It is west part of Georgia.
Very funny people, very smart.
And he make 10,000
operation every day.
And so you make
big people line.
Bend over and put balls in...
Ah, mouth.
And after one push...
ow!
And... ow, ow, ow.
And then...
(VOCALIZES)
Very cheap and very fast.
(LAUGHS)
But this is not enough
for Chinese people.
They are too much.
Both: 9 chimpanzees,
10 chimpanzees,
11 chimpanzees, 12 chimpanzees,
13 chimpanzees,
14 chimpanzees,
15 chimpanzees, 16 chimpanzees,
17 chimpanzees, 18 chimpanzees,
19 chimpanzees, 20 chimpanzees,
21 chimpanzees, 22 chimpanzees,
23 chimpanzees, 24 chimpanzees,
25 chimpanzees, 26 chimpanzees,
27 chimpanzees, 28 chimpanzees,
29 chimpanzees, 30 chimpanzees,
31 chimpanzees, 32 chimpanzees,
33 chimpanzees, 34 chimpanzees,
35 chimpanzees, 36 chimpanzees,
37 chimpanzees, 38 chimpanzees,
39 chimpanzees, 40 chimpanzees,
41 chimpanzees, 42 chimpan...
- Alex, which car do you have?
- Bicycle.
- Only bicycle?
- Yeah.
- Next year, I want buy
four-wheel car.
Toyota Land Cruiser.
All square, you know?
- Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- My neighbor
buy from America by internet,
but you must be careful,
because sometimes
they say car is okay;
you pay money,
and after come,
car with many problems,
with engine problems
or something.
I think some black people...
- Dato...
- Make this special...
- Don't say it like that.
- And that I want buy
from Japanese.
Japanese people,
they are correct.
If they say car is okay,
car is okay.
(RUSTLING)
- What are...
(BIRD SQUAWKING)
(IMITATES BIRD)
- Ah-ah-ah...
No.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(IMITATES BIRD)
(TENSE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
♪♪
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
- Up.
- Cut it?
- Cut.
Yeah.
Oh-bah.
- Watch it.
- Be careful.
Please make knot.
- Like that?
- Mm-hmm.
- Again?
- Mm-hmm, one more.
Okay, yeah?
(BLOWS)
Take.
- Nice!
- Yeah!
- Op, op, op, op.
Op, op, op.
Eh!
- Wow.
(CHUCKLES)
- Take foot... your hand.
- My foot?
- Your hand.
- Other hand?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- Ow.
- Now your khachapuri is mine.
- Now I eat like this.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
Okay, open.
Open!
(GIGGLES)
- Wait, wait.
This is not easy.
- With the knife.
- Okay.
- Be careful.
Careful.
(LAUGHS)
Now put...
- Good, good trick.
Now put it back together.
- Salvador?
- Yes.
- Armenia?
- Bhutan?
- No.
- Cuba?
- Yes.
- Kyrgyzstan?
- Sierra Leone?
- No.
- Turkmenistan?
- Albania?
- Comí.
Comiste.
Comió.
Comimos.
Comimos...
Comi-eron.
- Comieron.
- Uh-huh.
Mm...
Querer.
- Queri.
- Mm-mm.
(CHUCKLES)
- Que...
- It's irregular.
- Ah, si.
Qui... quise.
- Uh-huh.
- Quisiste.
Quiso.
Quisimos.
Quisieron.
- Yeah.
Uh...
Poder.
- Pode? Pude?
- Uh-huh.
- Pudiste.
Pudo.
Pudimos.
Pudieron.
- Cojear.
- Cojeé.
Cojeaste.
- Uh-huh.
- Cojeó.
- Mm.
(LAUGHS)
Cojeamos.
- Sí.
- Cojearon.
- Bien.
Eh...
Remember tener?
- Tiene.
Teni?
- It's irregular as well.
- Ay!
- Tuve.
- Tu...
Tuviste.
Tu... tuvio?
- Tuvo.
Tuvimos.
(WHISTLE HISSING)
(SOFT WHISTLE NOTES)
(CHEERFUL TUNE PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(WHISPERS) Hey.
No.
Nica, no.
He's right there.
He's right in front of us.
Come on.
No.
He's right in front of us.
- You like it.
- Of course I like it.
I don't like it that he's...
Shh, shh.
Shh, shh, shh.
Shh... don't.
You're making me...
(CLEARS THROAT)
(LAUGHS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
"The mountains close in
more and more tightly,
and it seems as though
there's no longer any hope.
Only a bit of sky is visible
directly above our heads.
It has a disheartening effect
on us.
We are overwhelmed
and keep silent.
Suddenly at a sharp turn
in the road,
a huge chasm opens up
on our right,
and quite close to us,
we see the ice-covered peak
of Mount Kazbek
with its glaciers
sparkling white in the sun.
It is cheek byjowl with us,
placid and tall, mute.
A mysterious feeling
courses through us.
The cliff stands there as if
conjured up by the other cliffs.
We feel as though
a being from another world
is looking at us.
I scramble out of the carriage,
get behind
the folding top and..."
(ALL SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
(LAUGHS)
(MURMURING IN GEORGIAN)
What does it mean?
(SPEAKS GEORGIAN)
This means "son of beach."
(BOTH LAUGH)
- "Bitch."
"Beach," it's, uh...
Beach.
- Beach!
- Yeah, yeah.
I take my bitch to the beach.
- I take my beach to the beach.
- I take my bitch to the beach.
- I take my bitch to the bitch.
ALL: I take my bitch
to the beach.
I take my bitch
to the beach!
- I take my bitch to the beach!
Okay, okay, okay.
Now we must drink.
(LAUGHS)
(LIQUID POURING)
- Hey, thank you.
Thank you.
- Ah.
- Ah!
Ahh.
- Yes, mine, mine, mine.
- Mmm.
- Now we drink.
- Do you have a bug on you?
- We drink to woman.
Okay?
- Okay.
- You must stand up.
- On the... no, not... not...
Sit down.
On the knee.
- Oh, on the knees?
- For... to woman!
- To woman!
- Yes.
Without woman, life is nothing.
I cannot.
(BOTH LAUGH)
- Gaumarjos.
- Oh.
(GASPS)
Oh, ho-ho-ho-ho-ho.
(LAUGHS)
Next lesson.
I...
I take a shit
on the sheet.
- I take sheet
(CHUCKLES) No.
Okay.
- I take shit...
- A shit.
- Shit.
- Shit!
- Alex.
- Hmm?
- I have to pee.
- Yeah.
(RUSTLING)
(ZIPPER UNZIPPING)
(URINATING)
(SPLASHES)
- Whoo!
Ahh.
Whoo.
- One, two...
Good.
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
- Almost, almost.
Perfect throw.
One, two...
- Gamarjoba.
(SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
(ALL SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
Amerikuli...
(SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
(ALL SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
(ALL SPEAKING HEATEDLY
IN GEORGIAN)
- Dato?
(ALL SHOUTING IN GEORGIAN)
- What's going on?
(SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SPEAKS QUIETLY IN GEORGIAN)
(SPEAKING GEORGIAN)
- Nica?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(FOOTSTEPS CRUNCHING)
(BIRD CHIRPS)
(BRANCH SNAPS)
(INSECT BUZZES)
(TENSE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
♪♪
(MUD SQUISHING)
(BOOT SCUFFS)
- I have a rock in my boot.
(PEBBLE CLATTERS)
(SNIFFLES)
(MUD SQUISHING)
(ROCKS RATTLE)
(WINCES)
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
No, thank you.
(WATER RUSHING LOUDLY)
(WATER TRICKLING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(SLURPS AND GASPS)
- Hey, guys!
Do you want take photo?
Good place.
- No, thank you.
(BEDSPRINGS RATTLE)
(METAL CLINKS)
(DRAWER SLIDES OPEN)
(BLOWS)
(GLASS CLINKS)
(PAPER RUSTLING, CRACKLING)
(BLOWS)
- Hey!
About ready?
- It's the same house?
- Yeah.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(COUGHS)
(MATCH STRIKES)
Where are you going?
- To take a piss.
- Take the poncho!
What did they want?
(RAIN PATTERING)
(PLASTIC CRINKLING)
Give me a verb.
Come on, give me a verb.
- Escuchar.
- What?
- Escuché.
Escuché?
- Sí.
- Escuchaste.
Escuché.
Escuchamos.
Escucharon.
- Yeah.
Good.
Hmm...
Oir.
- Is it "smell"?
- No, that's, uh, oler.
Oir is to... to hear.
- Oh, yeah.
Oye.
- No, that's...
Oye is like, "Hey."
Kind of like,
"Hey, hey, listen, hey."
Like, "Oye, oye!"
♪ Oye como va ♪
- Yeah, yeah.
Oye, oye, oye.
- So...
- Oí.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oíste?
O... oyó?
- Oyó.
- Oyamos?
- Oimos.
Oy... oyeron.
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Eh...
You want another one?
- Yes.
- Hmm.
Hacer.
- Hacer?
- Uh-huh.
- Hice.
- Haciste.
- Hiciste.
- Uh-huh.
- Hicio?
- Hizo.
(TENSE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
♪♪
(STREAM RUSHING)
- What about here?
- No, he's gonna look
for the widest part
because that's where
the current's a bit slower.
- Wait me.
I go look.
Keep your rucksack loose.
No belt.
Okay, tsavidet.
(WATER RUSHING)
- Go ahead.
- No, you can go.
- You sure?
Okay.
- Please.
Oh!
(SPLASHING)
(WATER RUSHING)
- Rucksack, rucksack!
Rucksack, get!
- Get the backpack!
(WHIMPERING SHIVERING)
(WHIMPERING)
It's okay.
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(SPACE BLANKET RUSTLES)
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH SINGING IN GEORGIAN)
- Beautiful voice.
(LAUGHS) No...
Alex is the singer.
- And beautiful girl.
- Oh.
No, he's amazing.
He plays the guitar.
He knows-
like, he hears a song once,
and he can play it right away.
- Ooh.
- Yeah.
- Very nice.
- Now we teach you a song?
Our turn?
- Ah, this is...
- This is good.
- Difficult, very difficult.
- All right, Señor Don Gato.
(LAUGHS)
I go like this to you,
and you say...
you say,
"Meow, meow, meow," like a cat.
- Meow, meow?
- Meow, meow, meow.
- Meow...
meow, meow, meow.
- Yes, okay.
- Okay.
I am ready.
♪ Oh, Sefior Don Gate
was a cat ♪
♪ On a high red roof
Don Gato sat ♪
♪ He went there
to read a letter ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
(LAUGHS) Good!
♪ Where the reading light
was better ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
(LAUGHS)
♪ 'Twas a love note
for Don Gato ♪
♪ "I adore you,"
said the lady cat ♪
♪ Who was fluffy, orange,
nice and fat ♪
♪ There was not
a sweeter kitty ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ In the country or the city ♪
♪ And she sw...
she saki she'd wed Don Gate ♪
♪ Oh, Don Gate ♪
(LAUGHS)
♪ Cried so happily ♪
♪ He fell off the roof
and broke his knee ♪
♪ Broke his ribs
and all his whiskers ♪
♪ Hey, meow, meow, meow ♪
(LAUGHS)
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ And his little solar plexus ♪
(LAUGHS)
♪ "Ay, caramba!"
cried Don Gate ♪
- I'm gonna go to sleep.
Okay?
Good night.
- Good night.
Nahvamdis.
- Okay.
♪ And so all the doctors ♪
♪ Came on the run ♪
♪ Just to see if something
could be done ♪
♪ They began a consultation ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ About how to save
their patient ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ How to save Sefior Don Gate ♪
♪ But in spite
of everything they tried ♪
It goes on and on.
(LAUGHS)
♪ Poor Señor Don Gate
up and med ♪
♪ No, it wasn't very merry ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ Going to the cemetery ♪
♪ For the ending oi Don Gate ♪
♪ When the funeral passed
the market square ♪
♪ Such a smell of fish
was in the air ♪
(BOTH LAUGH)
Um... how does it go?
♪ Such a smell of fish
was in the air ♪
Uh...
♪ Though his burial was slated ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ He became reanimated ♪
♪ Meow, meow, meow, meow ♪
♪ He came back to Hie,
Don Gate ♪
♪ For he had nine lives,
Don Gato! ♪
(LAUGHS)
- Oh, very long and very nice.
I am singing only in mountains,
when I am alone and nobody...
- You sing good, Dato.
- Yeah...
- More chacha!
- More chacha.
- Cha-cha-cha.
(CHUCKLES)
Ah.
So I say toast?
- Toast, yeah.
Without toast, it's...
- Okay.
- Not possible.
- So I say toast to you
and for everything you teach us
and for...
- For life!
- Life!
- Yeah, life is good.
- Yes.
- But good life is better.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah.
Gaumarjos.
(MUFFLED LAUGHTER)
(SUNGLASSES RATTLE)
(MUFFLED CONVERSATION)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(BLOWING)
- When you make marriage?
- November.
- Ooh.
Good time.
What this means?
- What?
- What's this?
Tattoo.
- Oh, something stupid I drew
when I was 18.
- And this is mushroom?
- Ah.
- And why mushroom?
Many of my friends
made tattoo with blood type,
you know, in West Georgia,
in Abkhazia War.
- Mm.
Were you in the war?
- Not the last war, no,
but I was in '90, '92.
Ah, terrible time.
I want to drink...
toast to those people
who died young in wars.
You know,
war help to die young.
(SPEAKS GEORGIAN)
- Gaumarjos.
(LIQUOR HISSES ON COALS)
- You want?
(CLEARS THROAT, SNIFFS)
Many...
Many, many of my friends died.
And I start
too much drink.
Too much, every day.
And this was big problem
for my wife.
- You're married?
- Yeah.
- I didn't know
you had a wife, Dato.
- I was... I was married.
Like you, very young.
- How old do you think I am,
Dato?
- I think 21, 22.
(LAUGHS)
Thank you.
I'm...
- No, 23?
And okay.
- I am 30, Dato, but thank you.
- No, no.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Maybe you use good skin cream.
I know skin creams
because I sold before.
- You sold skin cream?
- Yeah, not only skin cream.
Many, many different things.
For example:
socks, soaps,
underwear,
bra, and, uh...
woman's nylon.
Car too.
Yeah.
Yeah, it was
very difficult time...
for life.
- What happened to your wife?
- Mm...
I drink... drink too much,
and my wife leave me.
And she's going in Holland
and marry.
He...
and she find Turkish man.
Not European, Turkish.
You understand me?
And, uh, this is nothing,
but she take my son.
- You have a son?
How old is he?
- My son...
(CLEARS THROAT)
One time she call me,
and she had problem
with this Turkish guy.
And she call me,
"Dato, okay, come.
Come, and we can
begin everything..."
"Now."
And I come.
I collect money.
I borrow money.
I took credit.
And I go.
I love...
I love my wife.
And, uh, you know,
when I come,
I cannot understand this woman.
She was correct...
different.
And she talk
different language,
and, uh, she has
a different mentality.
My son cannot speak Georgian
and don't understand me.
And he... my son...
he was afraid of me.
And I was two months
in Holland.
I find some job,
and I work 16 hour every day.
But when I come home,
I was alone.
Nobody talk with me...
not wife, not my son.
And...
I come back to Georgia.
Two months.
- Hmm.
(SIGHS)
Well, to children.
(CHUCKLES)
For children, yeah?
For your future children.
- Ah.
Gaumarjos.
- Gaumarjos.
(SIGHS)
(BLOWS)
Promise?
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES)
Promise?
- Closed.
Closed.
- Keep 'em closed!
- Yeah.
(LAUGHS)
No problem.
Closed.
(URINATING)
- Okay.
You can open.
Okay.
- Are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Ooh!
So your wife, she went back
to the Turkish guy?
- Yeah.
She was going to Turkish guy,
and, uh...
After one month, when I leave,
they die,
auto crash...
in auto crash...
With my son.
(CLEARS HIS THROAT)
Yeah, after my wife,
I don't touch woman
four orf ive year.
And I come here,
and I live here in mountain.
I like.
This here is real life,
real people,
and you can understand
everything,
what means.
For example: food, water,
and warm fire.
Everything.
Maybe I...
I stay here until my finish.
(CHUCKLES) My death.
May I kiss you?
- What?
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
- Dato!
(LAUGHS)
"May I kiss you?"
- Why not?
- "Why not?"
You can kiss my cheek
or my hand.
You can kiss my hand.
- Only hand?
- Uh, cheek.
- Okay.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS)
(TENT UNZIPPING)
(UNZIPPING)
(ZIPPING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(BOTH MOANING)
(BOTH GRUNTING, PANTING)
Wait, wait.
Wait.
I feel pukey.
Stop.
Wait.
- What?
- I'm sorry.
I feel pukey.
(GASPS)
Okay.
(UNZIPPING)
(COUGHS RETCHES)
(MOANS)
(COUGHING)
- Nothing?
(COUGHS)
(RETCHES, GAGS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- You want to try again?
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(GAGS COUGHS)
(METAL STAKES CLATTERING)
(RIVER RUSHING IN THE DISTANCE)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(TENT UNZIPPING)
(TENT STAKES CLATTERING)
(ZIPPING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(TENT STAKES CLATTERING)
(METAL SCRAPES)
(ZIPPING)
(RUSTLING)
(BOOTS STOMPING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(FOOTSTEPS CRUNCHING)
(ZIPPING)
(BAGS RUSTLING)
(BIRD CHIRPS)
(FOOTSTEPS RUSTLING)