THE DEATH OF MARIA MALIBRAN.
Every day
the lovely daughter of the Sultan
took a walk in the evening
at the fountain
where the pale waters play.
Daily stood the youthful slave,
in the evening
at the fountain
where the pale waters play.
Daily he grew pale and paler.
Then one evening came
the princess to him,
speaking rapid words:
"Tell me what your name is,
where you come from, your clan!"
And the slave spoke:
"know then Mohammed am l.
I come from Yemen
and my clan is that of Asra,
who must die
whenever they love.
And my clan is that of Asra,
who must die whenever they love.
The mad woman comes prancing
vaguely remembering
something from her past.
The children mock and stone her
as if she were a blackbird.
She raises her stick
and threatens to pursue them
but then she goes her way.
On the way she loses a shoe,
but she does not notice.
Long spider legs
move about her neck,
but it is just her hair.
Her visage
has no human features
and she suddenly
bursts out laughing
Iike a hyena.
She mumbles
scraps of phrases
which very few could make sense of,
even if they were to try.
Her skirt,
full of holes,
jerks about her scrawny,
dirt-spattered legs.
She goes on her way,
borne away like a poplar leaf.
She,
her youth,
her hopes and former happiness,
on which she looks back
through the mist of her mind,
shattered by the turmoil
of unarmed powers.
Her gracefulness is gone,
her former beauty.
Her gait is crude
and her breath reeks of brandy.
If people were happy on this earth,
it would astonish us.
The mad woman
reproaches no one.
She is too proud
to complain,
and will die
without revealing her secret
to those who are interested in her.
But she has forbidden them
to address one word to her.
The children pursue and stone her
as if she were a blackbird.
She has dropped a roll of paper
from her bosom.
A stranger picks it up,
Iocks himself up at night
and reads the manuscript
which runs as follows:
But when you say
I love you
my eyes are filled
with bitter tears.
Let me
in to you
before it is
too late.
Your longing
means nothing to me.
The apparition vanishes.
I seek the laws.
When you embrace me
I experience humility,
and can bear without pain
your esteem of me.
She is dead.
Maria!
I implore you, God of Love,
take her in your arms.
A sailor dressed in white
walked along the road
with the rolling gait
of a seaman.
I looked at him
without really knowing why.
He was much younger
than I had ever been,
and more handsome and fairer.
And his manliness
was so evident
that I felt
a moment"s pang.
Our paths crossed,
and as if he had seen
a tell-tale flicker in my eyes,
he cast me a knowing,
inviting glance.
Such a glance as he probably cast
at any of those carefully made-up
habitués of the cafés.
If this glance
had lasted one more second
words would surely
have been spoken
Iike the usual thing:
Hey, baby, don"t I know you?
My face glowed
and my heart was in my mouth
as I hurried on
and tried to stare in front of me.
He had caught me unawares
for a moment
because I had not
really thought of him,
but of the letter in my pocket
and of Helmut.
As I crossed the street
I wondered what
he could have seen in me.
I was no longer so young
as to believe
my walk or the way I held my hands
could have attracted him.
No,
it had to be something else,
something I dared not
look in the eye.
For that would be
like looking into the dazzling sun!
Something I dared not
look in the eye.
For that would be
like looking into the dazzling sun!
It was half past nine
and he hoped
to be home by ten.
It was very presumptuous of him
to act as if he were sure
of knowing the future.
It was very presumptuous of him
to act as if he were sure
of knowing the future.
Might some unforeseen obstacle
bar his path?
And would such circumstances
be so extraordinary
that he dared interpret it
as an exception?
Why does he not consider it rather
an abnormal fact
that so far he had been able
to feel free of unease,
and happy,
so to speak?
Indeed,
with what right could he say
he would reach home unharmed,
if someone
watched and followed him
as if he were their future prey?
I long for you so much!
This means death for me.
Judgments on people
are more valuable
than the people themselves.
If I allow people
to despise me
they should not forget to say
that this is all
I can do for them.
What shall I do now?
I should not have given him
my love!
He is dead!
Let's put it off till tomorrow.
FEDERlCO GARClA,
MARlA MALlBRAN"S FATHER.
God be with you.
Where are you bound?
For Eisenstadt.
Then we can
keep each other company.
I think that for a young man
the best way
of meeting his needs
is to ply the needle.
To bind the tread
of firm footwear
is the noblest task
of a southerner.
But it is my belief
that the article I deal in
is equivalent to fine,
warm clothing.
Clothing the naked is senseless,
for I know that the tread
of he who wears my footwear
is so firm
that he needs no warmth.
I would advise you
to get a stock of provisions.
For my part, I shall obtain enough bread
in that hamlet.
The way is short. We shall
reach our destination before dusk.
I am not afraid, Hugo.
You will regret it!
If you give me
one of your bright blue eyes
I will give you
something to eat.
You may eat your fill
but in return,
I will pluck out an eye.
Where are we?
In a place
where you may finally rest.
There is an alder by the pond.
A blue flower grows at its roots.
Whoever makes a potion of it
and gives it to a sick man
would soon make him whole.
You know many things, but my science
is greater and could help many.
In the capital they're dying of drought,
the fools!
Yet they could have enough water.
But how?
- Before the east gate stands a beech.
A white horse browses on its leaves.
Ride the horse
thrice around the market place
so that sparks fly!
And you?
All the blind
could see again at once
if they washed their eyes
with this morning's dew!
I can
see again!
If you give me one of your eyes...
I don"t know you.
I have never been here before.
I am a singer.
You, too?
I"m a singer, too.
Perhaps we shall meet again.
IN THE YEAR 1814.
When your foot slides over a frog,
you feel disgust.
But if you run your finger
just lightly over a human body,
the skin of your finger will crack
like the scales of a slab of mica,
shattered with a hammer.
And like the heart of a shark,
already an hour dead,
still beats on
the bridge tenaciously.
Thus our innards still writhe
long after being touched,
to the last fibers.
So great is the horror
inspired by man
in his fellow man.
So great is the horror
inspired by man
in his fellow man!
The ancient temple of Denderah
Iies one and a half hours
from the left bank of the Nile!
Today,
countless multitudes of wasps
have invaded the waters and roads
along the banks!
They swarm about the columns
Iike the dense waves
of a black head of hair!
The only inhabitants
of the cold aisle,
they guard
the entrance to the forecourts
as if it were their inherited right!
I compare the buzzing
of their metallic wings
with the ceaseless grinding
of ice floes
that clash during the ice thaw
in the Arctic seas!
But when I think
of the behavior of him,
whom providence granted
the throne of this earth,
the three wing-tips of my pain
resound with a louder buzzing!
But he is dead.
Maria,
he is dead,
dead, dead,
dead.
EVEN HlS GRAVE lS HlDDEN FROM ME.
TEN YEARS LATER.
Can you
imagine it?
I am not aware of any guilt.
I say it for the last time,
l"ll not work with him anymore.
But please,
I only want the best for you,
the best for you.
I cannot work
with Federico anymore.
I do not want to,
nor can l.
I can"t!
- Please, Madame Malibran.
You must sing.
- lt"s impossible!
You promised.
- It is madness!
It is madness to force me!
Madame Malibran,
your daughter
has just taken her own life.
Now no one can compel you anymore
but I tell you,
it"s for your own good!
You must do it,
even if only for my sake!
Soon you will be
an angel in heaven.
I shall die,
but my death will avenge me at least!
I shall not die alone
and someone will follow me.
Subtitles:
TlTELWERK, Annie Grossjohann