Felipe!
- Felipe!
- Yes?
Bring up some number two wick.
- We're going for water.
- When you get back.
All right.
Mr. Denton.
You indicate west
for the wind this morning.
It's always west here. Never changes.
To a seaman, Mr. Denton,
there's a big difference
between west and west-southwest.
I'm not a seaman, captain.
Obviously.
And this is no ship, either...
Captain Moriz.
Will?
Number one or number two?
- Number two, and hurry up!
- All right.
Was that sail or steam last night?
It was too dark to see.
Steam ships always carry
a white light amidships,
a green to starboard and a red to port.
I think I've told you that before.
Yes, you have.
Sometimes I don't think
my heart's in my work.
Then you shouldn't be in this work.
Is she still lit, captain?
That light is much too yellow.
It's the whale oil.
You can't see whale oil two miles.
I see it everywhere.
Can smell it, too.
I've had ships, Mr. Denton...
Captain... this is not a ship.
This isn't just another job, Mr. Denton.
And that's not just
another light up there.
Nope, it's an argand burner
multi-wick, oil-fed dioptic system
with a beam...
- That's enough, Mr. Denton.
I begged them to give me a crew of seamen.
Captain, I'm sorry
I'm not a seaman, but...
Seeing that light on a black night
is as close to looking at god
as most men ever get.
And the devil himself
won't put it out while I'm alive.
But does it take a seaman
to keep it lit, captain?
No.
It's a job for old men and...
Felipes.
Why are you here, Mr. Denton?
Why?
Will!
- Good morning, Felipe.
- Morning, captain.
Good morning, Mario.
Did you have a lot of trouble
with Felipe last night? Huh?
Who put that light out? You? Or Felipe?
I think I saw a deer
this morning, captain.
There are no deer on this island, Felipe.
- Could've swum over.
- I think I saw one, captain.
- Captain, can we try for it?
- All right.
I hope you weren't dreaming
you saw a deer.
Here's the key to the gun cabinet.
Thank you.
Good luck.
- Shh.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I did see one.
Are you married?
No.
I ran a gold mine.
Will...
The wind, it shifted.
It's south.
Southeast.
Nah.
Never changes.
Always west.
Mario!
Mario, Mario.
Mario.
Will!
Felipe.
You hit him!
Look, there's blood. Can't be far.
Was I right, Will? Did I see a deer?
That's a strange looking deer,
but let's get it to a frying pan.
We'd better hurry.
Not without this fresh meat.
Mr. Denton, get up here!
Mr. Denton, drop that.
Get up here at once.
- Felipe.
- Yes?
- Gun.
- Oh.
And I'll tell the captain you're coming.
She's coming in.
She's flying a distress flag.
Sickness, maybe.
That fresh meat's for us.
A distress flag, I said, Mr. Denton.
We'll share what we have.
Thank you.
Come along, Felipe.
And leave your animal behind.
They'll think we're savages.
Hm?
Now you be a good boy, huh?
Whoa.
Whoa!
Denton!
William Denton.
This... is your captain. Hear me.
This light will burn no more.
You stand accused
of the cold-blooded murder...
Of lightkeeper... Andrew Moriz...
And assistant lightkeeper, Felipe Mendoza.
For these murders... you will die.
Unless...
You surrender.
Put your trust in your captain.
Am your only hope.
Hey. Hmm?
Come on, eh?
Mario.
Mario. Mario.
Hmm?
What's this?
Hey.
Yeah, this'll do.
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
Hm.
Ooh! Aww.
Ehh.
Damn good, too. Here, try some.
You're hungry.
Hey!
Mario. Mario!
Come here.
Mario.
Come back here.
Mario!
Mario.
Whoo!
Ehh. Ehh, ehh.
Ow! Ow!
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Jonathan Kongre...
Your captain.
Mr. Tarcante. My very excellent mate.
Mr. Virgilio,
a bulwark of my establishment.
Why did you murder them?
Do I detect an American accent?
How very agreeable.
I used to have dealings
with your countrymen
during the happy days of the slave trade.
Most profitable.
Most revealing... about human nature.
But while I am amusing myself,
reminiscing, you are starving.
Seems a pity to waste
Balduino's culinary talents...
On a man who's about to die.
Is this your companion?
Little chattering man.
What a sense of humor god must have.
Emilio.
Mario.
Mario, Mario.
And now, Mr. Denton...
Perhaps you feel refreshed.
And ready for a little exercise.
Who are you?
Yeah!
Denton.
Arriba!
Mario!
Whoa.
Release him!
Huh? Jeez, look at that. That's gold!
That's gold, girl. Gold!
Gold!
Goddamn cheat!
Hey now, come on, Matt.
Now, have a drink. Come on, please.
Look out!
Rocks ahead! The port bow!
Vamos.
I am delighted to have this opportunity of
making your acquaintance, miss, uh...
You are English, I take it.
My name is Arabella Ponsonby.
I am traveling from San Francisco to
England on the California Flyer.
I am a respectable woman.
My father was the honorable
Charles Ponsonby of Puddletown, Dorsetshire.
A lady.
May I offer you my arm, miss Ponsonby?
She's salvage, captain.
We must use our salvage properly,
Tarcante.
It would be a pity to damage it
before the time comes for the sharing out.
Look how its white skin burns in the sun.
What's all this?
Wreckers.
My name is Giuseppe Montefiore.
- You the cook?
- No, the ship's engineer.
Just what I need.
Now...
- We better get out of here.
- Who are you?
- Assistant lightkeeper.
- What happened?
I'm out of a job.
My clothes...
I have no clothes.
Mrs. Fanshawe, my aunt...
Where is my aunt?
It's wonderful how perfectly the female
mind understands the priorities.
Her clothes, first.
Her aunt, poor lady, only second.
Was she a fat lady, your aunt?
Fat?
Old. My chaperone.
- She was...
- Fat.
I believe I have
seen something of your aunt.
There you are, my dear.
Open it.
A keepsake.
You have survived only because my
associates found you as pretty
as the rings on your poor aunt's fingers.
You're no Christian.
Oh, your dress... My apologies.
Virgilio!
What is your color?
Cerise?
Apricot?
Virginal white.
Oh, how delightful it is
to talk of such delicate matters.
Captain.
The men wish to look at her.
Well, never mind.
We'll gossip over dinner.
Don't worry, they won't touch you.
Don't leave me, please.
You may proceed, Tarcante.
Sir, help me!
I shall dress for dinner.
- They call you seamen, huh?
- That's why we have ships.
Everybody but me.
Can't we do anything?
Nothing.
Just stay alive.
Come on, let's try to find some food.
Ah.
They can't stay here forever.
We just wait
for that relief ship to get here.
Never really got to know him
till it was too late.
You never give up.
If captain Moriz could see
what was happening to his lighthouse.
He wouldn't like it.
Huh?
Ahh, Giuseppe, I take it all back.
It's a big one.
That little monkey would cuddle up
around Felipe's ear,
and he'd go bouncing along,
twanging away on that damn Jew's harp.
Yeah. I miss him.
The way they were killed.
You know, I was lucky. I...
Ah, Denton.
Y un amigo.
Our fish!
You drink like a man, Arabella.
I'm used to living among men.
Oh, yes.
Very few women in California.
In California,
they chase after gold, not women.
But certainly...
A woman of your beauty...
Almost as beautiful as she was.
But then girls always look their prettiest
on their wedding day.
Look.
"To William, our best man.
Affectionately, Matthew and Emily Jane."
Who is...
How would you like...
To enter a charade with me...
Emily Jane?
Why did you call me Emily Jane?
Does a name mean so much?
William...
loves you.
Loves me?
Desperately, Emily Jane.
For 12 long years, he has loved you.
He has kept every letter
you ever sent him.
Tied in blue ribbons.
Blue ribbons.
And now you have come back...
as young and beautiful as ever.
A miracle.
They say every woman is an actress.
For a woman of your background...
it is a role...
worthy of your talents,...
Miss Emily Jane.
I'll do it.
Was she on the ship?
I think so.
Strange.
Emily Jane?
Miss Emily Jane?
Emily Jane!
The captain would like to see you.
Will! Will!
Will!
Are you crazy?
- Was she alone?
- I don't know.
We had a lot of English families.
English.
Emily Jane!
Pleasant walk, Emily Jane?
Why do you want him so much?
Isn't it obvious?
He knows.
He's the only man left who knows.
But I know.
Every ship that passes
must pay a tribute to this rock.
A tribute to me...
as yours did.
Why is your ship leaving?
Target practice.
Wouldn't want me
to blow up my own schooner.
I reserve that for
Mr. Denton's relief ship...
When it arrives.
Her name was... Emily Jane.
I loved her, but...
she married somebody else.
Matt Edwards. He was a gambler.
Cheat.
He used to come around on paydays
and clean out my crew.
Then one night he pulled a gun and...
Well, I had to shoot and...
I killed him and...
Of course, she never talked to me.
Never had anything
to do with me after that, but...
She was the only woman I ever loved.
I still love her.
Will.
Look.
We cannot let that false light
wreck another ship.
- And still we do nothing?
- That's right.
- Just try to stay alive.
- They'll wreck her.
We just stay alive.
Distress rockets.
Will.
Will!
Emily Jane.
Will.
Will Denton.
You're not her.
Will.
It's not her.
Why?
He made me.
Mr. Denton, help me. Help me, please.
Whoo!
Whoo, whoo!
Denton is alive, Mr. Tarcante.
I want him back.
Are you sure?
Yep, I'm sure.
Why?
Because I have to.
Maybe.
But the same crazy man who saved my life.
Ahh.
Ah.
What are you doing here?
Well, when a lady cries out for help...
I am not a lady.
I'm a maid.
I'm not Emily Jane,
I'm not Arabella Ponsonby.
She was killed
with all the others on the ship.
I just took her name because I thought
that way I could stay alive.
But I was her maid.
I'm a nobody.
A nobody.
I'll help a nobody, then.
How dare you
come into a lady's room like this.
Come on.
Hurry!
I can't.
I can't. I...
Where do I go?
To a cave to be hunted like you?
Here, at least I've got clothes,
food, a bed.
What can you give me? Nothing.
You asked for help. We risked our lives.
Will, please understand.
I understand.
Denton!
On this 15th of November,
in the year of our Lord, 1865.
I, Jonathan Kongre,...
by the authority vested in me
as sovereign of this latitude,...
and as your captain...
do accuse you, William Denton,
and the person of one,
Giuseppe Montefiore, peasant...
of the callous...
and premeditated murder...
of six citizens...
of this realm.
Come out, Will!
Claim your peasant!
I hardly think
there is any doubt of your guilt.
You're not man enough to get Denton.
Little chattering man.
Sir...
You slept well, I trust, miss Ponsonby?
By all the pleasure I can bring to you.
Have brought me, miss Ponsonby.
Please!
He has been sentenced.
I did what you told me!
I want Denton!
- I want him alive.
- Alto, alto, alto!
Call the men on board,
the woman is theirs.
Everybody on board, the woman is yours!
At last, a queen of tragedy.
You made me an actress.
I'm not Arabella Ponsonby at all!
I lied to you, I lied, I lied!
No! Kongre!
Kongre!
That will eliminate temptation.
Remember, Kongre...
I can save you.
They'll believe my story
when the relief ship gets here.
So...
you will be the lightkeeper.
And I?
You can be a passenger
on that wrecked steam ship.
You evil son of a bitch.
I can smell you from here.