It
fills the streets.
With one eye open.
It never sleeps.
She's got it loaded.
Always ready.
She's not afraid.
Yeah, she holds it real steady.
She won't run away.
She won't run away from
the wolf in the night.
Run away.
She won't run away.
She's tough and
tender, does it right.
Ungh.
Always moving, like
a shadow hard to see.
When she finds you, like a
knife, she'll cut so deep.
She's got a heart
full of passion.
Won't break in the
heat of the action.
She won't run away.
She won't run away from
the wolf in the night.
Run away.
She won't run away.
She's tough and
tender, does it right.
She's tough and tender.
She does it right.
Yeah.
Whoo.
Run away, run away.
She won't run.
She won't run away.
She's tough and tender.
Run away, run away.
Yeah.
She's tough and tender.
She'll make you crazy.
You wanna love her.
Like a magnet, you
want, you want.
She won't run away.
She won't run away from
the wolf in the night.
Run away.
She won't run away.
She's tough and
tender, does it right.
Run away.
She won't run.
She's tough, tough and tender.
Run away.
She won't run.
The
following program is
brought to you by NOON, the
New Organization of Nations.
Your
attention, please.
The president of NOON, the
New Organization of Nations,
is about to announce an event
of the utmost importance.
Citizens of the world, as you
all know, the letters N-O-O-N,
NOON, stand for the New
Organization of Nations and are
the symbol for the rise of
mankind, which has now reached
the high noon of its destiny--
conquest of space.
Therefore, all
nations of the world,
with the exception of
a few small islands,
cozy and sunbathed republics,
have resolved to enter together
into the new age of space,
which will bring peace
and prosperity to all nations.
This has only become possible
through the invention
of a totally new means of
interspatial communication.
It's called the Space
Jeep and has just been
launched on its first voyage.
After the successful completion
of this first test flight--
This is a message
from Clean Space,
the anti-pollution commando.
The voice you're
now listening to
is being broadcast worldwide
from our ultra-secret space
transmission center.
We have lost our fight against
pollution of the earth.
We shall win our fight
against pollution of space.
Your Space Jeep is
therefore under our control
and will remain so as long as
you do not meet our demands.
Clean Space requires
the cancellation
of the entire space program.
Remember, your pilot
and the Space Jeep
are from now on in the
hands of our technicians.
Get me Space Center, quick.
Yes, sir.
Hi, Fred.
Listen, we've got to
change Sam's trajectory.
What?
Sir, that's out of the question.
Changing trajectory
means changing orbit.
Nothing doing.
Don't argue.
That's an order!
Yes, sir.
Henry?
Yeah?
Start up number three,
slow, and move from H to six.
Got it?
Yeah.
But if you ask me, you're
gonna blow up the whole thing.
You heard what the man said.
Orders.
OK, OK.
You're the boss, I'm the wiz.
I just hope you know
what you're doing.
Here we go.
Three, normal.
H six plus three.
Overheating on the first.
Trajectory?
Unchanged.
H six, danger point.
Back to four.
Temperature of the
cooling system?
208.
H six on to five.
Temperature?
220.
Four everywhere.
Six minus plus five.
Five minus plus four.
We're locked on four.
Temperature?
220.
Move H to infinity.
Impossible.
Saturation of the module.
Temperature?
225.
Back to three.
Well, Mr. Nelson, we
can't do anything now.
Our signals are being reflected.
We'll try to shut the circuits.
OK, try it.
Get me Brussels.
Training center?
No, not the training
center, headquarters.
Mr. Barrot.
Yes, Nelson?
Sure, I know.
The president's
address was worldwide--
and so was the ultimatum.
They're bluffing.
I doubt it.
I've given orders for a test.
They're trying right now
to change the trajectory
of the Space Jeep.
Hold on.
Shit!
Well, keep trying!
That's what I'm doing.
Cut number one.
Connect to three
block in parallel.
Well, it's no bluff.
Our signals keep
coming right back.
All circuits broken.
Locked in free thrust.
How the hell did they do that?
Let's try again.
All right, if you say so.
But remember, if we
bust that module,
the whole thing blows up.
All this crap to please
that damn Nelson, huh?
Not quite.
Remember, there's a guy up
there in that Space Jeep
spinning round and round.
What they do have is
probably a magnetic barrage
against outgoing signals, same
kind as their TV interference.
It blots out anything
we try to send out
and gets anything
they want on the air.
That's the story.
So what can we do?
We've got a spare
one ready for launch.
Ah, you mean that girl, uh,
Jane Dantine, Sam's stand-in?
Sure, fine-- uh, that is if
she can take off right away.
Sure.
She's as good as he is.
They were both trained together.
Barrot, remember, she needs
protection, for those Clean
Space characters.
All right.
Don't worry, I'll
pick her up myself
and bring her to the plane.
Put on 305.
Would you please get
my own car ready?
And please rush a security
car over to the center.
NOON
security car number 27,
go straight to the
training center
to meet Mr. Barrot and
astronaut Jane Dantine
and escort them to the airport.
Car number 27?
Gotcha, kid.
We're on our way.
Hey, what's this?
An accident.
Jesus.
Come over here, will you?
I have a date with
some cute astronaut,
and we're going to be late.
Bah!
Hurry!
We gotta pick up the astronaut
before Barrot gets there.
Oh, uh, Mr. Barrot
couldn't make it.
He sent us to drive Miss
Dantine to the airport.
Well, let's go.
Where's Dantine?
She's gone already.
What?
Get me to the airport, quick.
This is a message from
the organization Clean
Space, space without pollution.
You are already aware
of our preventing
your signals from watching
your so-called Space Jeep.
We know that without those
signals, your man in space
will remain in orbit forever.
We also know that
only one other person
able to pilot your spare
Jeep is presently our guest
and will remain with us
as long as necessary.
But we are not murderers.
On the contrary, we want to
save the world from pollution.
All you have to
do to save them is
to cancel your space program.
End of message.
Find a way to get this
cassette to General Boele.
And now, boys, we
are going to Guasura.
I'm telling you, it's
right here on the cassette.
Jane kidnapped, tied to
a chair, and poor Barrot
killed on the road.
Well, if they want
to play it rough.
We figured the exact site
of Jane's disappearance
at Ostend Harbor.
An abandoned ambulance
we found there two
days ago fits the description--
We'll play it even rougher.
I'm gonna send you the
toughest cookie in our job.
Dammit!
Run away.
Just be at the airport
when she arrives.
I'll get you the exact flight
number and the time, OK?
I'll
send her an official car.
No, no, you don't have
to send an official car.
What this lady has, you
wouldn't want to camouflage.
All she needs is a chauffeur,
on time, at the airport.
You see, this lady gets
into action real fast.
A boat called Lord Byron
left Ostend yesterday.
Don't know where
it was headed for.
The owner is a woman.
Before leaving, she did
some heavy recruiting
around the harbor.
Wander around, you
could learn some stuff.
Here's her name.
Barbara Wims.
Anything else I can do for you?
No, thanks.
That's all.
Excuse me, sir, but is there
the slightest chance you know--
Hey, you two up there.
Yes, you.
I'm looking for a boat that
probably has a big sign on it
with the name "Lord Byron."
I got it.
Hello.
I'm a friend of Barbara.
Is she here?
Do you know where she is?
I have a message for her.
It's very important that she
gets it as soon as possible.
Make sure that she gets it, OK?
Ugh!
Uh!
Oh!
Ugh!
Ah!
See anything around here?
Hmm, Ramirez.
Probably one of
Barbara's clowns.
Coteras, Guasura.
Our local operative's
a real dynamo.
There aren't many
like him anymore.
Frank Randall is his name.
Wait till you see him in action.
Now, we all know how
dangerous this operation is.
He's the one with
that little surprise
package we spoke about.
But remember, only to
be used in emergency--
a last resort.
I'll keep
my eyes open for the package.
You keep your ears
open for the good news.
Here's Randall's
address in Guasura.
3 Plaza Mayor, Coteras.
Time for action.
Nelson's agent's coming to you.
Well, I didn't expect to
see anything quite so lovely
this time of the morning.
Uh, you here for
the sun and the fun?
No, I'm here for the action.
Frank?
Yeah, I think so.
Ilona.
Beautiful name,
beautifully lady.
Won't you come in?
You know, this a
pretty rough place.
Do you think you can take all
these characters around here?
Ah, the last of the macho men.
No, beautiful women
are my favorite pastime.
Like collecting
butterflies, huh?
Anna-Lea.
She's my bodyguard.
You want one?
Root beer on the rocks.
Now, uh, did you receive
a diplomatic pouch
with my name on it?
No, I only get junk
mail around here.
It's hot stuff, so when
it does come, get it to me.
Sure.
So, que pasa?
Nada.
Nothing.
Oh, yeah, I got an
address on Ramirez.
He runs a dive down
by the waterfront.
Hmm.
Anchors away.
Aye aye, sir, or miss, or--
Don't shoot!
Ah!
I want her alive!
Ah, let go of me!
Ow!
No!
Everything's cool.
Oh, lovely, you
came incognito.
I said it was a rough
place down here.
Rough trade.
Fear not, lovely ladies, I have
solid contacts, so after you.
You sure they
don't know you here?
Just a lucky guess.
My contact should be
around here someplace.
I think that's him.
That's him?
Yeah, the one with the
Julio Iglesias haircut.
You keep the bartender busy.
When duty calls.
The boat--
Lord Byron-- uh--
the boat--
If you wanna fight,
fight, don't talk.
You want a date, right?
Ugh!
What'd he say?
He's bilingual.
Well, he mentioned
something else about a boat--
Lord Byron.
Oh, Lord Byron, ah.
Yankee, go home.
Wrong game.
I play football.
Oh, you do?
What position?
What else?
Kicker.
Ugh!
Be back in a minute.
Fear not, eh?
Well, I told them not to
drink the worms in that stuff.
Let's get out of here.
Let's get to the airport.
Hey, wait a minute.
I have to call my mother
and buy a toothbrush.
Do you think we should
have children right away?
You know, this is
awfully sudden.
This is not an
escape, it's an arrival.
Ah, you're
expecting something.
Six somethings.
Sensibility reigns.
Six phantom jets?
No.
Six attack choppers?
Six Gremlins?
No.
Six girls.
Aha.
What next, special cavalry?
Missed.
Oh, look, the Dallas
Cowboys must be in town.
Right league, wrong team.
This is the Panther Squad.
And this is Frank,
our man in Guasura.
Claims he works for the consul.
Say hello to Frank.
Hello, Mr. Frank.
Dumpy, Grumpy,
Slumpy, and Sleazy.
Do they do windows too?
No, they jump through them,
and they shoot through them,
but they don't clean them.
Well, you can't
have everything.
Come on, girls,
here's the minibus.
OK, girls, we're dealing
here with a circus.
Their main stunt was to kidnap
one of NOON's top astronauts.
They're real clowns.
But since they won't live up
to your idol, Tom Selleck,
I'll know where you are nights.
The astronaut is
probably being held
on a boat around the harbor.
We'll hit first
thing in the morning.
Today, just relax, and
welcome to sunny Guasura.
Oh, an oasis.
Who's in a rush?
It's great.
Let's go for a swim.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I'm tired.
Come on.
Beats watching
football, doesn't it?
Yeah, it's, uh,
great while it lasts.
Meaning what?
Oh, Antonio and his
friends can get nasty.
"The Empire
Strikes Back," eh?
Hmm.
Shaky.
5% nerves, 90% liquor.
And you are 100% correct.
Like one?
Root beer.
So, uh, when should we
expect the trouble to begin?
Ooh.
Tomorrow.
The next day.
Things move pretty
slow around here.
Ugh!
Help!
Ah!
All right, recess is over.
All right!
You and you stand watch,
the others hit the sack.
And get your power sleep.
Ah!
Was it good for you too?
Thanks for cleaning up that
mess that burned on the lawn
yesterday.
Oh, and, um, did you see which
way the young ladies went?
No, but they mentioned
about called, uh, Lord Byron.
Frank Randall?
Sometime.
Sign here.
Who's it from, Max Factor?
From the consul.
These guys are red hot.
You can bring in
our ace swimmers.
Yah!
Oh, boy, goodie.
Playmates.
You'll get front page.
Now that you had
your warm up, take the Jeep
and keep your eyes
on that truck.
I'll catch you later.
There's a roadblock further
up according to the map.
See any way we could avoid it?
All right,
ladies, take a hike.
I'll handle the roadblock.
Maybe, but let's be prepared.
I want to take all
the precautions I can.
And I want police dogs too.
But everything is quiet.
I've got news.
They're having
trouble on the yacht.
The two guys keeping
watch have been attacked.
Shit.
But the women who did
it have been captured.
Get them up here fast.
They're coming.
I got a call from the truck.
Good.
I wonder why they use women.
It worries me.
Why?
On the contrary.
It will give our
men an incentive.
Maybe.
I'll double the number
of guys, just in case.
Don't overdo it.
We're in control, so relax.
Still, I'd like to warn
the boys on the road.
Don't.
No one knows that Jane is here.
There is no point to start
those mercenaries guessing.
All we want them
to do is to check
the cars on the road, period.
Uh, I'm a tourist.
Would you please take
some photos with me
and your friends as a souvenir?
You're from the Lord Byron?
Yes.
Come on.
If you want to starve
yourself to death, go ahead.
We need you away from the
space center, dead or alive.
A hunger strike will
not free you earlier.
Earlier than what?
You'll be free as soon as
the New Organization of Nations
accepts cancellation of the
entire New Space Program.
You must be joking.
They never will.
Meaning that you will stay
with us for a long, long time.
To keep you
company, Miss Dantine.
Jane Dantine, we'll
get you out of this.
Shut up!
We need some
discipline around here.
Bullseye.
The insects are bad here,
but we'll need more than Raid
to kill off that pest.
OK, divide and conquer.
You, you, you, to the
bar, and you go get nosy.
You with me, come on.
Ugh!
Cover that door.
Ah!
Ugh!
Let's get out of here!
What about them?
Shoot them!
Ugh!
Oh!
What took you so long, huh?
They finally have
us under attack.
Everybody to the fort.
They're gone!
They took Jane.
Let's go!
Ugh!
Leaving
without even a doggy bag?
Wah!
They went that
way, didn't they?
Who?
Come on!
That's the most relaxing
drink I've had in a long time.
Barbara to
Clean Space chopper.
Just finish up that red
Jeep and what's inside.
Sounds like some
big bird's watching us.
Chopper to Barbara.
We'll teach them what macho is.
Frank, get out!
Hey, boogie.
Frank, get down!
You think you
might need some guns?
Yeah, and some bullets
if you've got 'em.
OK.
Enough target practice.
Now down to business.
OK, first thing--
where are we, anyway?
At this point,
all the roads lead
to the government headquarters.
There is one?
General Carlos, right there.
Ah.
OK.
Come on, girls, we're gonna
make a special delivery.
Special delivery--
hey, wait a minute.
I forgot your gift.
How long have you had this?
Let's go.
Me too?
You first.
And now let me
express our gratitude
to Professor Fonestran.
Professor.
Professor Fonestran
is a genius.
It is he who invented the
magnetic barrage which prevents
the space centers of
the world to communicate
with their stations in
orbit, their satellites,
their astronauts!
The magnetic barrage originates
in our own space center,
right here under the palace!
From there, we will
dominate the world.
Only one device completes
the magnetic route we
have built around the planet--
their new Space Jeep.
And only one person has
been trained to operate it,
a woman called Jane Dantine.
Now, listen!
Jane Dantine is down
below in our dungeons.
She's our prisoner!
Bravo!
Professor.
There is nothing and no
one who can stop me now.
I will be the lord and
master of the world.
The so-called great powers
will be reduced to slavery!
You, my people, you, my
faithful companions in arms,
you will rule the universe!
As president of Clean
Space, and in the name
of my organization, I take
issue with the declaration
you just made.
We have given you
our support, and we
have given you our assets.
We offered to use our
technological device
for the exclusive
purpose of impeding
the pollution of space.
This way.
You have betrayed us.
I withdraw our support.
Take that stupid
ass out of here.
I don't want to listen
to all his nonsense.
You won't have to anymore.
No one will-- ever.
Soldiers, friends,
companions in arms!
Today we celebrate
the dawn of a new era.
There was the age
of the Roman Empire.
Today begins a new age--
the age of the Guasura!
Wine for everybody!
You, get high, this
way around the back.
You go with me.
Ugh!
Ooh!
Ah!
Surrender or I'll
blow your Nikes off.
Come on, girls.
Let's show 'em how to party.
You stay here.
The odds are only 40 to 1.
General!
There is nothing
to worry about.
I know what I'll do.
Blow your brain
cells, probably.
I'll blow up the
world if necessary.
These trans-magnetic
rays are powerful enough
to interfere with
worldwide television
and prevent all outgoing
rays from reaching space.
I can set off an explosion
in any nuclear power plant.
There are hundreds of
them around the world.
I know how to do it, right
here from our space center.
We'll go there right now and
take Jane Dantine as a hostage.
Come on.
Buck.
Hurry up.
We are taking her as a hostage.
Yeah.
General.
However fantastic your
plan happens to be,
it can only harm mankind.
But you will fail.
That will teach
you, you moron.
You must destroy--
destroy-- destroy
the space center.
They fooled us.
Their space
transmission center--
they want to destroy the world.
They can do it from their
space transmission center.
You must get there before.
You must destroy the generator.
Destroy it.
Go now, quick.
We've been fooled all along.
Go.
Come on!
Get the others.
Drop that gun!
You just take care
of the astronaut.
You son of a bitch!
CLEAN SPACE PRESIDENT
You must destroy--
destroy-- destroy
the space center.
You must destroy the generator.
Only to
be used in case of emergency--
a last resort.
CLEAN SPACE PRESIDENT
Destroy.
I need a drink.
Citizens of the world,
after an incident of no great
importance which slightly
delayed the launching
of our space program,
it will now proceed as planned.
A few seconds from now, you will
be watching on this same screen
the take-off of Jane Dantine
piloting our second Space Jeep.
Mankind's new age
of space has begun.