- So me and Brian
just got up and got ready,
made the bed in the tent...
and set up.
I think our plan for today
is to just hang out here
in the tent.
- Man, that smile.
That smile didn't change.
Those eyes didn't change.
I...those eyes...
they would get her
out of so much trouble.
Didn't matter how old she got,
she would always be
my baby girl.
No matter what she, you know,
how much trouble she was in,
it didn't matter.
She was still my baby girl,
you know?
These are
all I have left now.
- People would meet her
and just fall in love
with her.
She just had this presence.
I don't know what it was.
It was just magical.
There's so many good memories
over the years,
but the one thing
that I hold dear to me
is the hug that we had
before she left
for the trip in the driveway.
* *
It's just...
It's still unbelievable.
I don't understand it.
It doesn't make sense.
Sense...
- In June of 2021,
Gabby and her fiancé
embarked on
a cross-country trip.
They were traveling in Gabby's
2012 white Ford van...
* *
And documented their journey
on YouTube and social media.
- Doing some morning yoga.
- We've been lucky so far
at all the places we've stayed.
- Oh, my God!
- She maintained
regular contact
with her family members.
However, that communication
abruptly stopped
around the end of August.
- If you've been active on
TikTok or watching the news,
you've probably
heard of Gabby Petito.
- Everybody's on this case.
Everybody's talking about it
because
we have to find this girl.
- The twists and turns
throughout this case
have been bizarre.
- We have this moment
where we see behind the scenes
of their perfect
Instagram van life.
- People became obsessed
with this case.
They wanted to find her
and they wanted to
solve this case
really more than anything.
- The media and the internet
just went crazy.
- I am going to walk down here
a little bit
because I see something.
- Oh, my God,
there's that van.
- Right here
is where they think
that it's a shadow
of someone digging.
- Human remains
were discovered,
consistent with the description
of Gabby Petito.
- It was like every
parent's nightmare just, like,
in a flash of a second.
- Brian is currently
on the run and hiding.
- He could be in
the Appalachian Trails.
He could be in Mexico,
Canada.
- Earlier today,
investigators found
what appears to be
human remains.
- The remains matched
the dental records
of Brian Laundrie.
- It's just been confirmed
the cause of death
is a gunshot wound
to the head,
and the manner of death
is suicide.
- There are so many questions
that we just don't have
answers to.
- Who is Gabby Petito?
- She wasn't just a YouTuber.
She was an amazing individual,
and she was our daughter.
- Gabby,
Gabrielle Venora Petito,
was born in March 1999.
I was 20 years old,
so...it was scary for me.
She was a big baby.
She came out crying
and ready to start life.
It was her for the first
few years, just no siblings.
So it was nice just to have
that mother-daughter bond.
She was just
such a loving kid.
I mean, she would sleep
in the bed with me sometimes.
She loved to snuggle,
and I don't know.
I loved all those years.
- I was 20 years old
when Gabby was born, you know?
A new baby is terrifying,
terrifying,
and when she was born,
I mean, she...
I can hold in her my hands,
you know, like, tiny.
And you're responsible
for this perfect innocent,
you know, baby.
It's just an instant bond
that it'll just never go away.
She was just awesome
to be around, you know?
Her smile, her eyes,
all that stuff,
and I just remember melting,
you know,
and she have me wrapped around
her finger quick.
You know,
that didn't take long.
That's my perfect little girl.
- Gabby was two,
just about turning three,
when I met her
for the first time.
She had these little,
like, pigtails
and you know, her blonde hair,
these bright blue eyes,
and she was just
this happy kid.
She was pretty amazing.
And I saw the way
Nichole was with Gabby
and how amazing
of a mother she was.
I'm like these...
they're beautiful.
They're awesome.
- Jim is just as much
as a dad that I am.
Tara is the only person that
Gabby has ever seen me with,
that she would even remember,
you know,
and she is just as much
as a mom as Nicki.
So she always had
four parents.
- And I never looked at Gabby
as my stepdaughter.
She was my daughter.
I started dating her father
when she was a year old,
and I fell in love
with her instantly.
I loved just being with her.
I loved spending
time with her.
We used to sit there.
I used to tell her.
I'm like, "Gabby, I got
a secret. I got a secret.
I got a secret to tell you,"
and she would come running up
and whisper in my ear,
"I love you."
- Blue Point is a small town.
It's a small school.
She had a lot of good friends.
She was a baton twirler.
She did that a little bit
in her late elementary years.
Middle school,
she ran some track.
You know,
she always tried new things.
Just a spitfire,
she had goals,
and she did what
she could to get there.
As she got older,
she just loved
to take lots of pictures,
lots of videos.
- When we were always
together,
all she wanted to do
was take selfies.
She was always taking
pictures of things
and put her twist
of her artwork into it.
- She'd start uploading
pictures and videos,
and she was putting
her life out there,
and she would post
a new picture or a new story
on Instagram
every couple of days.
- She wanted to put her stuff
out there online
for people to see.
- Gabby and Brian
met in high school.
- They had the same group
of friends in school,
common interests, you know?
They liked to
do things together.
They're both artistic.
- Very artistic, yeah.
They started dating
after the first road trip,
the one when they took
the car to California.
They were kind of friends
when they left.
* *
Came back dating, yes.
She was so happy.
Gabby and Brian were dating,
and he would come to my home.
Brian would be there, and
he was very polite, very kind.
- Get your guard up as a dad,
you know,
especially when
it's one of your girls,
but when he would come over,
he was respectful,
very quiet, very polite,
and, you know, he would
actually take the time,
and he would, like, color
with our younger daughters
and stuff and talk with them.
- I didn't see anything in him
that would worry me at all.
- No.
- When her and Brian
started dating,
and he was like,
"I'm moving to Florida,"
and she was like,
"Can I come with you?"
So she had no problem
doing that.
She had no fear
to move to another state.
I said, "You know,
"you're always welcome
to come back home.
If you don't like it,
this is your home."
- Gabby was living with Brian
and his parents
in North Port, Florida.
- Gabby did have a close
relationship
with Roberta
and Chris Laundrie.
They treated her
like their own daughter.
* *
- They were engaged.
So it was exciting,
but I was like,
"Well, just make
sure this is...
"You know, you're young,
and make sure
it's what you want."
But I couldn't tell her,
you know,
you can't get married now
because I got married
very young.
- You know, as a dad,
you're like, okay, you know,
that's great, you know, you can
settle down a little bit.
* *
You're happy for her,
you know, that she's found
who she wanted to be with.
- We're not going
to talk about it.
- We're not going to
talk about it.
- I thought she should
finish school, get a job,
do all that stuff,
you know, the traditional way,
but she had a different plan
and a different vision
in her head,
and she knew what she wanted,
and she did it.
- And she was like, "I...
We got to get a van
and do this."
- They were fixing up a van,
and they're gonna do this
whole van traveling thing.
We didn't really...
kind of heard of it,
but we didn't know
what it was about.
She couldn't wait to show us.
And then
when she opened the doors,
and we looked inside
and we saw it,
we couldn't believe it.
- I was like-my mouth dropped.
- I was like,
"This is unbelievable."
- "You did this?"
- Every little nook and cranny
of that
was planned out for storage,
the bed that folded up
into a couch,
these fold-out tables
that they could eat on.
Every little piece of it was...
- Just so creative.
... Was so detail-oriented.
- Everything has to
have a place,
and not to the point
where it's OCD,
but just liked it
neat and clean.
That was her van.
She loved it so much.
- I love the van.
* *
- I was like,
"People don't get to live
their dreams all the time,
"and you're doing it.
"Like, this was your goal,
your dream,
and you saved your money
and look what you're doing."
It's proud...
I was proud of her.
I really was.
I have so many good memories
over the years,
but the one thing
that I hold dear to me
is the hug that we had
before she left
for the trip in the driveway.
It was just a long, long hug.
I don't know.
I can't describe it.
It was just...
I know I was
saying goodbye for a long trip,
but it just felt different.
I don't know.
Now that I look back,
it felt so different,
and I squeezed her so tight,
and I said, "I love you.
"Please be careful.
This is going to be great.
You're going to have
so much fun."
And she...
you know,
she squeezed me back,
and it was just really...
It was great,
and I'll cherish it.
* *
- Gabby and Brian were
the perfect young couple,
started this journey together.
When you see that
on social media, you think,
"I want to be like them."
- A lot of people
felt close with Gabby,
getting to know her through
her Instagram or YouTube.
That's how I related to her.
I saw myself in Gabby.
She wanted to experience
the world, kind.
I mean, she seemed like
she was always smiling
and happy, full of life.
- Gabby Petito
never goes outside.
- As soon as you look
at Gabby Petito's Instagram,
it's hard to not
fall in love with this girl,
and people started
watching her
and becoming a part
of her life.
- Hello, hello,
and good morning.
It is really nice
and sunny today.
It's only 10:00 in the morning,
but it rained
all afternoon yesterday.
- Gabby set up a YouTube
channel called Nomadic Statik.
She wanted to document her life
on social media and eventually,
as influencers do,
make money doing it.
Gabby was
such a positive force,
and she did a really great job
enframing everything
she was putting out
on social media
as a positive experience.
- Oh, my God!
The tent
is just coming in on me.
The wind is so bad!
I've just been sitting here
like this for a while.
- We looked forward to seeing
new posts of where they'd been,
and, you know, Gabby had no
fear when it came to doing,
you know, surfing the sand
dunes and climbing the rocks.
She just went for it.
- Me and Brian just got up
and got ready,
made the bed in the tent,
and set up.
I think our plan for today
is to just hang out here
in the tent.
Brian's stretching,
doing some morning yoga.
- Brian seemed to be
a very quiet, calm person.
- He kind of seemed like a guy
who focused on being
one with the Earth.
- He definitely had
an affinity for art.
He did his own illustrations.
- He liked to draw,
and he created some
almost comic book-like
sketches.
Some of them were pretty dark.
There was definitely an edge
to Brian's posts,
whereas Gabby was showing
these beautiful locations,
and it seemed like
he was using it as a platform
to say something else.
* *
- Their first stop
was Monument Rocks, Kansas
on July 4th.
On July 8th, they reached
Colorado Springs, Colorado.
Their third stop, July 10th,
Great Sand Dunes, Colorado.
- We are right outside
Capitol Reef right now,
in a free disperse camp spot,
and we've been lucky so far
at all the places we've stayed.
But I'd say this is
one of the best so far.
- Gabby was posting
almost daily,
showing how she was living
out of this van,
how she was making
her own food.
- Now I'm going
to make some yogurt.
All the chocolate melted.
- That is so melted.
I know.
It's a river of chocolate.
Be cautious.
- You can't keep chocolate
in Utah,
not in July.
Or in a clear
plastic container...
- Or in...yeah.
- That is always in the sun.
* *
- On July 16th,
Brian and Gabby
arrived at
Zion National Park, Utah.
Next they went to Bryce Canyon
National Park.
And then, after 24 days
on the road,
they reached
Mystic Hot Springs, Utah.
What you post on social media
is what you want
the world to see,
and people were crazy
about Gabby's life
because she put forward this
front of this beautiful girl
enjoying these adventures
and also this beautiful life.
- But there was definitely
more to this relationship
than was being shown
on social media.
* *
- Before they embarked
on their cross-country trip,
I've heard
from Gabby's friends
that Brian was a little
jealous and overprotective.
I heard a specific incident
where he didn't want Gabby
hanging out
with one of her girlfriends
just because he didn't like her
or thought that,
you know, she might be
a bad influence on Gabby.
It seemed Brian wanted Gabby
all to himself.
He didn't want her
socializing or going out.
Hearing that from Gabby's
friend, it seemed a little odd.
Gabby, didn't have that many
friends here in North Port.
She had just moved here,
and so for him to be,
you know,
that controlling at that time,
it just seems,
you know, very manipulative.
It seemed like one
of those red flags.
* *
- In Utah, Gabby wrote
a postcard to Brian's nephew.
- Looking at this postcard,
it's clear that Gabby
felt so connected
to the Laundries.
She felt that they were
one of her own,
and she was one of their own.
- We would be in touch with her
every day, for the most part,
but, you know, if we were busy,
or she was busy,
it would be,
you know, every couple of days.
- I had spoken to her
on the 24th of August.
She was in Utah.
We were working on the website
for the Nomadic Statik stuff.
She was having trouble
with the email.
So we worked on it together,
and we got it to work
and said, "I love you,"
and she said,
"I love you," back,
and "I'll talk to you
in a couple days."
* *
- The last text message
I received from her phone
was on the 30th of August.
And it said,
"Can you call Stan?"
which is her grandfather,
who she referred
to as Grandpa normally.
- It was very odd to see.
So I said, "Okay,
there's no service happening.
I'll leave her be."
And then, you know,
I told her grandfather,
"Just let her be
for a few days.
She's in a place
with no service."
And that was the last text
I received.
- We realized
that's not right,
and that she wasn't planning
to head to Yosemite.
They were planning on going
to Yellowstone in Wyoming.
One's slightly north
of where they were.
The other one's
hundreds miles west,
and it didn't make sense.
- And then we started
to worry.
And then when her mom called
me up and said, "Hey, listen,
I haven't heard from her,
you know, in a few days"...
And that's when we started
making phone calls.
- Kept texting,
I would text every day,
thinking I got to get
a response at some point,
and that's when
I started getting worried.
- It wasn't uncommon,
different parts of the trip,
depending on where they were,
where they would kind of be
out of range of cell services.
So sometimes the social media
posts weren't every day,
but they were
every couple days, and...
it just stopped.
There was nothing.
- The thoughts that were going
through my head were,
"Something really bad
has happened to her,"
whether it was an injury,
lost or something,
and I needed to get
in touch with her.
I'm thinking maybe
they went a hike,
and they're hurt somewhere.
The worst things
are coming into my mind.
I did text Brian's mother.
I said, "Have you heard
from the kids?"
I didn't say,
"Have you heard from Gabby?"
I was concerned
for both of them.
Got no response.
I texted his phone,
got no response.
And, I mean, I was just like,
"What is going on?
Why would anybody
respond to me?
I'm asking if you've heard
from the kids,
and I'm getting nothing.
- It was like every
parent's nightmare just, like,
in a flash of a second,
we just went into,
like, autopilot
as parents, like, she's gone.
She's missing.
* *
- Out of nowhere,
Brian suddenly showed back up
in Florida in Gabby's white van
without Gabby.
- Brian did not inform
Gabby's parents
that he had
gone back to Florida.
If they had a fight,
if she had met somebody else
and had gone her own way,
why wouldn't he just call
and tell her parents about it?
- We started making
phone calls...
- That was...
- To his parents,
and no one called back,
not a text, not a voicemail,
not a missed call.
- Something wasn't right.
- Like, we weren't
getting anything back.
- Finally,
on Saturday the 11th,
I walked into a precinct
and say,
"My daughter is missing."
I knew the night
the detective came to my door
to tell me the van
was in Florida. I knew.
* *
- You okay?
- I knew she was gone
that night.
* *
When I knew
the van was in Florida,
I knew that my daughter
was gone.
I didn't know how,
but I just knew.
I didn't tell anyone else that
because I had to do
what I had to do.
I had to report her missing,
and, I mean, I had to get her
missing pictures out there,
and I just...
We had to find her.
- Gabby's parents filed
a missing persons report
on Friday, September 11th.
Brian had actually driven
the van home to Florida
on September 1st,
ten days before she was
actually reported missing.
Had Gabby's parents known
that Brian had come back
on September 1st without her,
they obviously would have
called the police much earlier.
- Can you tell us a little bit
about your daughter?
- Do it.
- Gabby's
22 years old.
She's an absolutely beautiful,
beautiful soul inside and out.
She's incredibly artistic,
creative, loving, caring.
- We love her very much,
and we miss her,
and we want her to come home.
- Is there anything
you would like to say
directly to her?
- Gabby, we just want you
to come home.
Call us, let us know
you're okay. We just...
Come home, please.
- We miss you.
It's just scary and surreal.
You go with the motions.
You don't sleep. You don't eat.
You just...like a zombie.
- We just couldn't sleep.
We were up just searching
anything we could
and getting online,
trying to get the word out.
Friends and family calling.
Everybody offering to help,
you know, and at the time
we didn't even know
where to start.
- Brian was seen mowing his
lawn, running some errands,
acting very bizarrely
for somebody
whose fiancée went missing.
- His family took him
on a camping trip.
Who does that? You come home
without your fiancée.
You're in her vehicle,
and you go on a camping trip.
- Developing this morning,
an Instagram adventurer
mysteriously disappeared
during a cross-country road
trip with her boyfriend.
The boyfriend's back,
the van's recovered,
but there's
no Gabby Petito yet.
- I was hoping it was a hoax.
Like, I was.
I was, like, "So what?
"I'll take the brunt of it.
I'll hide you away.
"I'll shelter you somewhere,
let the media attack me.
"I've got big shoulders.
I'm fine, you know,
and I'll take care of you,
you know, whatever."
But...
- I tried to have as much hope
as possible,
but you still have
that gut feeling.
- Night I reported her missing
I went onto Facebook
and created the Find Gabby page
and just kind of shared it
with everybody
that I'm friends with.
I said, "Please share this,
my daughter's missing."
And I don't know,
by the next day,
it had had, like, hundreds
of thousands of shares.
- After that came out,
social media went crazy.
- Gabby Petito.
- We're talking about
the Gabby Petito case.
- Gabby Petito went on
several...
- Brian Laundrie...
- Everyone wants to know,
what happened to Gabby?
- It started going around
on TikTok and online.
"Hey, she's missing,"
got shared and shared.
- If you've been active
on TikTok or watching the news,
you've probably
heard of Gabby Petito.
- Gabby Petito's disappearance,
I want it
to go as far as it can go.
- It became a big story,
a big, big story.
- Things are changing
by the hour.
- And I believe if my child
was missing,
would I want everybody
in the country
to be talking
about my child missing? Yes.
- Everybody is on this case.
Everybody is talking about it
because
we have to find this girl.
* *
- I was covering
the story at first,
and Gabby was missing
when the police from Moab,
Utah released a 911 call.
- Grant County
Sheriff's Office.
- Hi, I'd like to report
a domestic dispute.
- Where's it at?
- They just drove off.
They're going down
Main Street...
- And what were they doing?
-...but, um,
we drove by, and the gentleman
was slapping the girl.
- He was slapping her?
- Yes, and then we stopped.
They ran up
and down the sidewalk.
He proceeded to hit her,
hopped in the car,
and they drove off.
- You could hear the caller
actually say that they saw
Brian slap Gabby and then chase
her down the sidewalk.
- Okay.
You said it's a white van?
- White Ford Transit.
So you're right there
by the post office?
- Right across the street,
yep.
- Okay, and when they turned
on to Main Street,
they went right or left?
- Right.
- Right? So they went north.
- That caller was concerned
enough to call 911
and to get police out there
because he thought
the worst would happen.
And then the bombshell.
This video became public.
- On September 15th, the Moab
Police Department in Utah,
they released
this bodycam video.
- I haven't been able
to bring myself
to watch it, the whole thing.
- He hasn't yet.
- I can't. It's too upsetting.
- I'm sorry.
- Earlier that day,
she posted to Instagram.
I would say they looked like
a couple very much in love,
but then again it's all about
what you see on social media.
It became very clear
that Gabby's Instagram photos
of the two of them just loving
their adventures together,
smiling,
holding onto each other,
that this was hiding
a more complex
or even tumultuous
relationship.
- It was a completely
different side to Gabby.
All we've seen of Gabby
up until that point
were the YouTube videos
where she was extremely
happy, very cheerful.
* *
- I wanted to jump through
the screen and just hug her
and bring her home, but...
- Oh, okay, that's cool.
* *
- So in a domestic dispute,
you want to get their stories,
get their stories separate
so that one cannot
influence the other,
so that's the reason
for the separation like that.
- Brian appeared to be
very calm, cool and collected.
- The fight itself according
to Brian was because
he had gotten
the back of the van dirty,
and that's something that was
really important to Gabby
was to keep their very small,
very tight living space clean.
- Gabby didn't have the OCD
where everything had to have
its, you know, exact way.
You know, she wanted, you know,
she wanted things clean.
- She wanted...
It was her artistic vision.
She wanted to see things
in her artistic vision.
- You know, when people
talk about, yes,
if she had a vision
in her head for her art
or the way she wanted
to have something look,
that's one thing,
but she wanted things clean.
- In the Instagram and YouTube
posts that Gabby
was putting out,
the van was in perfect shape.
It was very carefully
maintained.
And then during
that bodycam footage,
we get this glimpse inside
the back of the van,
and it's really
in a state of chaos,
and I think that was
sort of a peek behind the veil
of the sort of Insta-perfect
life that they were portraying.
- But the interesting
piece of this is
that she actually
took responsibility
saying no, she had
struck Brian first,
that then he responded
by hitting her,
and then she downplays that.
"Oh, it was really just
grabbing my face."
- I feel like that's almost
what threw things off
a little bit
is all of a sudden,
we're watching this,
and she's the one saying,
no, I started it.
No, I'm the one
who hit him first
when the original 911 call
was because Brian had
allegedly struck her.
- They decided, having spoken
to both of them
for about an hour,
that the best thing to do
was just to separate them
for the night,
and so they put Brian
up in a hotel,
and Gabby was able to stay
with the van for the evening.
- It was so, so eerie, yeah,
for him to say that.
It really chills your bones.
- It makes me sad,
and I wanted to hug her.
I think once the Moab video
came out,
you got to see
a real human behind...
everybody looks great
on YouTube and Instagram,
but people got to see,
"Oh, my gosh, she's
a real person with feelings,"
and...
I think that touched
everyone
when they got to see
that she was hurting.
Just it's amazing how so many
people could relate to her.
- It was an absolutely
viral video,
and, you know,
this is also really
where the Internet detectives
in all of this came in
and started
to dissect this video.
- The Internet went crazy.
- This is a part of this story
that is so weird to me, okay,
that we have this moment
where we see behind
the scenes of their perfect
Instagram van life.
- She was just showing
so many signs of a woman
that has been
severely gaslit emotionally.
- First of all, there's a lot
of conjecture
around a cell phone.
- He clearly has a phone.
He's seen using it outside
in front of the officers
in this exchange
while Gabby is using her phone
in the squad car.
- It is literally 4 a.m.
Where I'm at,
but I cannot sleep because
of this Gabby Petito situation.
- That Brian tells police that
he doesn't really have a phone
and then he says he doesn't
have a phone which is,
like, either you do
or you don't, bro.
It's one or the other.
- There's just so
many questions
and people really
want answers, including me.
- With social media,
we found there's a lot
of crazy bad stuff out there,
but there's also a lot of good
stuff that can come out of it.
I always say it's like
a blessing and a curse,
but in this instance,
it was a blessing for us.
You know, a lot more great
stuff came out of it than bad.
- They're incredible,
the sleuths.
- Yeah, Internet sleuths.
- The Internet sleuths,
they do a great job.
They really do.
- I think the hashtag FindGabby
hit, like,
over a billion people,
you know.
We saw it as an opportunity
to help, you know,
get the word out there,
and it did.
- When we were looking
for Gabby,
what I would do,
I would scour Twitter,
Instagram and Facebook
and Reddit and YouTube
to find clues or tips for
the FBI and screenshot them,
and I probably slept
about an hour a night at best.
I didn't stop.
- In addition to watching
the news unfold
about what was going on
with the search for Gabby,
they were also analyzing
the posts on her social media.
- The thing that stood out
the most
was Gabby's final post.
- Gabby is holding
a knit pumpkin in her hand,
and the caption reads,
"Happy Halloween,"
but it's August 25th.
So it's interesting, right?
- And so that was
really alarming to people.
They really didn't think
she posted the image.
that it was a recent photo
of her either.
And then alongside that,
the caption had, like,
happy Halloween,
made absolutely no sense.
And so it left people
scratching their heads
and confused.
- She didn't put any hashtags.
She normally likes
to hashtag her journey,
and it was very short,
* *
- On September 16th, the North
Port Police Department
held a press conference.
- Two people went on a trip.
One person returned,
and that person that returned
isn't providing us
any information.
- So we think Brian
is holed up in his house
with his parents,
not coming out,
and on the advice
of their lawyer,
they were not speaking
with police as well.
As a person of interest,
Brian still was not obligated
to talk to police.
- A person of interest,
what it means is that a person
that is potentially a subject
in an investigation
but that you don't have
enough information
to make that person
into a chargeable person.
So a person of interest
is a person that
will likely become a suspect
but is not currently a suspect.
- He is the only person
who was on this trip with her.
He is the only person
who is not talking right now
about where she might be.
He's not helping
with the investigation.
That is so suspicious.
- We are pleading with people
out there
to give us information,
point us in the direction
that we need to be
and help us find Gabby.
- A reporter explicitly asked,
"Hey, do you have know
where Brian is?"
And the chief said,
"Yeah, we do."
- Do you know where
Brian Laundrie is right now?
- Yes.
- They said they were
respecting his rights.
They were respecting
his space as well.
- The Fifth Amendment gives
them the right not to talk
and not
to incriminate themselves,
so under no circumstances
are they going
to be forced to talk.
- My focus isn't to bring Brian
in right now.
It's to find Gabby.
Brian is exercising
his constitutional rights,
and I have to respect that.
- That time when we were
looking for Gabby was...
it's a blur.
- Horrific.
- It's really like...
- It's horrific.
The whole time, we were trying
to stay as positive as possible
that we would find her.
- All right. What I need
from everybody here is help
because the goal
is still not met,
and that goal is
to bring Gabby home safe.
All right. And I'm asking
for help from everyone here.
I'm asking for help,
everyone at home.
I'm asking for help
from the parents of Brian,
and I'm asking for help of
the family members
and friends
of the Laundrie family as well.
You know, there is a tip line
that you can call anonymously.
Whatever you can do to make
sure my daughter comes home,
I'm asking for that help.
- Still in the back
of your head, you know,
that we wouldn't get
a positive outcome,
but we tried to still have...
I think that's what
we were working on.
I think that's what was
keeping us going was our hope
that we would find her.
- Anything else,
it comes second to this.
Thank you.
- We'll answer any
follow-up questions.
Thank you.
- At that point,
it was a search mission,
and it was also so fascinating
because I don't think
the Internet thought
they were trying
to help figure out a mystery.
- I mean, this story has...
it's gone viral in every
aspect
from the investigation
side of things
to people like myself
that have been helping out.
I feel like
I'm pretty proficient
in audio-video software,
specifically video software,
so I would spend
the better part of the night
and the evening
looking for clues.
But there's a community
of people
that have all done
the same thing.
It's overencompassing,
the amount of people
involved in this case.
It's mind-blowing.
- And I've seen a lot of videos
being like, "Oh,
why are people talking about
Gabby Petito case so much?"
I think a lot of it has to do
with maybe he did
just leave her somewhere.
Maybe he did just leave her
and went home.
Like, there is a chance
she could still be alive,
and I think people are trying
to find her safe.
- I thought maybe
I could help find her.
I'm really good
at the Internet.
I set out my mission to see
if I could find anything.
I looked at hundreds
and hundreds of photos,
zoomed in seeing if it caught
her van in the background...
- The whole Internet
was obsessed with the case.
- Even restaurants,
tagged images, stores.
- A group of people and I were
looking through Google Images
that were posted within
a certain date period
in Jackson Hole,
which is where Gabby and Brian
were spotted at a restaurant.
- Anything I could find,
I was looking.
Wow, on this Gabby Petito
case, so hear me out, wait.
I think I found something new.
I kept thinking, you know,
they were hiking.
They could be on trails.
What are the trails?
I found a trail app,
AllTrails.
Well, I found Gabby Petito's
and all the trails she saved.
I was like, this is crazy.
She could be in this area,
hoping people locally
would go look
or, you know, volunteers,
and then I passed it
onto the FBI as well.
Here we go, Grand Teton Park,
Grand Teton Park,
Colter Bay, Colter Bay.
Now here we go.
- No matter where you go,
there's always people.
There's always
pictures being taken.
They were truly never alone.
- Now starts north
of Colter Bay,
it goes way up
into the middle of nowhere.
I was hoping
he left her somewhere,
and people could find her.
Maybe she was lost.
That's what I was hoping for.
- On the morning
of September 17th,
I went to North Port outside
the Brian Laundrie house,
and it was just chaotic.
- Arrest Brian! Arrest Brian!
Arrest Brian!
Bring Gabby home!
Where's Gabby, Laundries?
Where's Gabby?
Where's Gabby!
- We had residents.
We had people really from all
over the state of Florida
in front of the Laundrie home
just yelling,
"Hey, Brian, speak to police.
Tell us what's going on."
Everyone believed that he was
inside of that house
alongside with his parents.
- I was there for the better
part of the day
until the police
started showing up.
Us reporters, you know,
there's a gang of us
outside the house.
We're standing around.
- Where is Gabby?
- We were all so confused.
We didn't know
what was going on.
We thought that the police
were going to bring
Brian out in handcuffs.
- Where's Gabby?
Where's Gabby!
- And, you know,
people were yelling,
and they had signs,
and it was just a circus
outside of the Laundrie house.
It was like a scene
out of a movie.
There was so much noise.
- Where's Gabby?
Where's Gabby!
- I see a couple
of police officers leave,
and we then find out
that his parents
were there
talking to the officers
because they were filing
a missing person report,
so Brian was not in the house
like we had thought.
He was gone.
- I thought I couldn't be
more surprised after that.
Then the revelation that he had
been missing four days before
and that they had waited
four days
to call the police
and tell them.
- You think, oh,
it can't get more weird.
- Brian is now missing.
The internet went crazy.
- The motherlover is missing.
- How did Brian leave
his parents' house
without nobody seeing him?
- When I found out
about this information,
I was just kind of like, what
the hell is this all about?
- I find it so crazy
that all of a sudden,
they're saying
that Brian Laundrie
is a missing person as well.
He's not a suspect.
- How does he get away? How?
You have him home at his house
with his parents.
He's there, you know,
and he gets away?
He could have gotten away
any other time,
but he's right there.
It was crazy.
- When Chris
and Roberta Laundrie
did eventually tell authorities
that their son was missing,
they said he'd gone
to the Carlton Reserve.
- The 24,000-acre preserve
is about the size of Manhattan
to put it in perspective,
and so you have
a starting point for Brian
to look for him.
It is the difficulty
of this area being flooded
that makes this
into a very difficult case.
There are wild boar.
There are alligators.
There are snakes.
There are all kinds of dangers
there that made it difficult
for law enforcement to operate
in that environment.
- So we later learned
that Roberta Laundrie
drove Brian's Mustang
back to the family home,
and it was at that point that
one of the surveillance team
from North Port Police
saw Mrs. Laundrie,
thought it was Brian Laundrie
returning to the family home,
and so they were under
the mistaken belief
that Brian was at home.
- But, you know, people want
to know, where is Brian,
and can we get him
to tell us what happened?
- From a social media
standpoint, it amped up.
They really, really wanted
to find Brian.
- It seems like the more
and more social media
dives into this case,
the odd eerie facts
continue to come out.
- Everybody wanted answers.
Everybody is thirsty
for answers.
- I'ma keep y'all updated
on everything going on.
This case has my full
attention, you guys.
* *
- They're using their
spare time and their passion
for this to,
you know, try to help.
- I thought, well, you
know what?
Maybe this is going to work.
Maybe, you know, someone is
going to come up with a clue.
I was not prepared
for the type of clue
that happened along the way.
- Y'all, look at this.
It's the freaking Tetons.
It's been on our bucket list
forever. I know it's been on...
- The Bethunes are a family
from the Tampa area.
- Pretty cool.
- Yeah, I mean,
without the smoke, it would be,
like, even more spectacular,
but...
- They're also a van life
family.
They have a couple of kids,
a couple of dogs,
a little bit of bigger van
obviously to hold this family,
but they were on
a similar trek.
- Let's keep driving to our
spot, Captain, Captain Kyle.
- The Bethune family had been
traveling through
the Grand Teton National Park
in Wyoming on 27 August.
- They were also in the Grand
Tetons at the exact same time,
and they had a dashcam,
and then all of a sudden,
it struck the owner
of that YouTube channel,
and she was like,
hey, I think I saw that van.
So she went back, took
a closer look and there it was.
- On August 27, 2021,
we got camera footage
going through the Grand Tetons
Park around 6 to 6:30 p.m.
- When the YouTube video
came out with Gabby's van,
I was like, oh, my gosh.
- As we're coming up on it,
we're approaching it up here
on the left-hand side.
This is most definitely Gabby
Petito's Ford Transit van.
Here it is on the left.
- But the fact that they drove
through at that time,
at that day,
at that precise moment
and just happened
to hit record, it's like, wow.
- Immediately, everyone
across the internet, YouTube,
Instagram, Twitter, even TikTok
were deciphering this video.
I was as well looking at it.
What could you see?
What could you not see?
- If you look in the far left,
there's a little bit
of a shadow,
so somebody think
someone is digging there?
- So I zoomed in on the screen
recording
where people are thinking
that we see somebody
digging on the video.
- Here, let me just highlight
this right here, okay,
is where they think that it's
a shadow of someone digging.
- There was a lot of things
going around,
all kinds of weird conspiracy
theories, so I took that film.
I got the 4K version,
and I went through it
with my software
to start debunking
these theories.
Putting the film
inside of the software
helped me slow things down,
really clearly show
that what people were saying
was happening
wasn't actually happening.
When I zoomed in to see that,
I saw something new.
I was able to go through
and blow it up
and work my magic
to stabilize it
and essentially enhance
the footage.
When I zoomed in...
I saw the door close.
It completely blew my mind
and sent a chill up my spine.
When I saw that,
I instantly knew
that there was life
in that van.
- I watched that video
of the van
and seeing the door closing,
like, probably 100 times.
I was like, I really believed
that was Gabby
closing the door on the van,
so I just kept watching it.
I don't know.
- The law enforcement agencies
were already
in that area searching,
but it just basically
helped them
pinpoint the site
where the van was.
- And that was a giant break,
and I know that the FBI were
tipped off to that location,
and that's why they started
their grid search.
That was massive.
- I think everybody was still
at that point in time
holding onto a little bit
of hope
that maybe it was an accident,
or something happened.
She disappeared.
She's hiding.
- I was in Wyoming when
they were looking for Gabby.
It struck me pretty quickly
that it was unlikely
that she was just lost.
It could be 80 degrees
in the middle of the afternoon,
but at night it got as cold
as 27 degrees, you know.
It was a very big
temperature swing,
and I just can't imagine
anyone being able to survive
that without the proper
camping gear,
you know, without shelter.
- So a body has been found
in the area
that they were searching
for Gabby Petito.
Now I can't say this is Gabby
or not, but if it is,
it makes me really sad
because I was hoping.
I was really hoping by chance
they could find her alive.
- Earlier today, human remains
were discovered
consistent
with the description
of Gabrielle "Gabby" Petito.
Full forensic identification
has not been completed
to confirm 100 percent
that we found Gabby,
but her family has been
notified of this discovery.
- So when Gabby was found,
you know,
there still was some testing
that needed to be done,
but based on the stuff
that she was wearing,
we were confident
in what was being said to us
and what was being
relayed to us.
- You still don't want
to believe it.
You still don't
want to hear it.
Your body goes in complete
and utter shock
that you're hearing
this information,
and it's like
your whole world is destroyed.
- The hope goes away.
- The hope.
- First and foremost,
on behalf of the FBI personnel
and our partners,
I would like to extend sincere
and heartfelt condolences
to Gabby's family.
- Even though I knew I was
going to get the call,
I just didn't want the call.
- Once they discovered
Gabby's body in Wyoming,
the focus of the story then
immediately turned to Brian.
Where is Brian Laundrie,
and is he going
to get arrested?
- We still at that point
didn't know how Gabby died.
Did she accidentally fall
and hit her head, you know?
Did something happen?
It became a intense inquiry.
Where is Brian, and what does
he have to tell us?
- The anger just from
the public,
it was all pointed
towards Brian's parents.
- There were journalists camped
outside the front of the house
trying to get answers,
being stonewalled
by the Laundrie parents.
- The FBI is on a manhunt
for Brian Laundrie.
To search the terrain
in someplace
like the Carlton Reserve
is so difficult.
The number one thing
you need is manpower.
You need the proper vehicles,
and drones are crucial
in this case
because they have special
devices that can be used
to track things
like heat, heat of a human.
- There were multiple
K-9 units from surrounding
police departments
that all came into North Port
in order to conduct
this search.
ATVs, swamp buggies, more
vehicles than I could name
were coming in
and out of the park,
and you could tell it
was one of those efforts
where they were going to search
every single corner
of it no matter what.
They were also focused on those
walking trails very close
to the entrance of the park
that Brian was known to go.
- Brian was very upset
when he left,
and Chris conveyed to me
several times that,
you know, he wished
he didn't let him go,
but he couldn't stop him.
Brian is a grown man,
young man, 22 years old.
He wanted to walk out the door.
He was entitled
to walk out the door.
- On Sunday, Gabby's body
was discovered in Wyoming.
By Monday morning, the FBI
was at the Laundrie home.
Tuesday is when we learned
it was indeed Gabby's body
and that she died
by homicide.
It was shocking, you know?
It was like a crescendo
of incidents.
- Yeah, it was just...
It's still unbelievable.
I don't understand it.
- Yeah. It's...
- It doesn't make sense.
- No. I have no words for it.
- I know that I speak
for myself and the entire world
that's watching
when I say this that I wish
we would have had
a better outcome.
- We all pretty much knew this
is what they were going to say.
Now they need to find Brian.
And I hate to say this,
but I hope he's alive and well,
so he can suffer in jail
for the rest of his life.
* *
- We have some huge breaking
news
in the Gabby Petito case.
The FBI issued
a federal arrest warrant
for Brian Laundrie.
- But it's not for homicide.
It's for bank fraud.
- Ten minutes to air,
we're all out there.
We're reading the bulletin
from the FBI
and realizing it's for
transaction of roughly $1,000
that Brian used on
someone else's bank card.
- We found out that from
Steven Bertolino,
the Laundrie lawyer,
that it was Gabby's
bank account
that Brian had used.
- This is not the charge
that you're chasing Brian for.
You want to get Brian for the
murder of his fiancée, Gabby.
But in the meantime, this is a
legal device that could be used
to be able to secure future
arrest warrants
or secure future
search warrants.
- He's wanted on a federal
arrest warrant,
and they'd be able
to detain him.
So this was really meant,
I think,
to help rev up the search.
- After that federal warrant
was issued for Brian's arrest,
social media
went into overdrive.
- Looking for Brian,
poring through
his Pinterest accounts,
his Spotify playlists,
anything
really to search for signs
about where he might be.
- When an Instagram Live
was made for 3 seconds,
and all you saw was someone
in a boat and a body of water,
they all speculated
that that was Brian.
He's on the run,
and he's taunting people.
- He appeared on Instagram
Live accidentally
for two to three seconds,
and viewers saw water,
as if he were on a boat.
- The Internet erupted.
Social media went crazy.
- Two seconds in a boat
surrounded by water.
- If you go live, doesn't it
show you where you are?
So...My gut tells me tonight
this guy is going to be found.
- There was someone sitting
there,
clearly a foot
with a camo Croc shoe,
and people were saying,
"Oh, well, is this a sign
that Brian Laundrie
is still alive?"
This is fake. I know it's fake,
and I'm going to find it.
I have to find the original.
- You guys want to know
where that screen recording
of Brian Laundrie
on the boat actually came from?
I'll tell you.
It didn't come from Brian.
I found the original video
was from a TikToker
from Florida from 2020.
Someone...he had taken just
a little snippet of the video
and used that to claim it was
Brian Laundrie on a boat.
Brian Laundrie did not
accidentally go live.
There's multiple buttons
you have to press to do that.
- It's quite possible that they
are just posting these videos
to get more viewers.
- I've learned two things
from this.
Social media can help, but it
can also hurt with rumors
and false accusations
and things like that.
They're not sorry
for what they do.
People believe it.
They fall for it because
everyone wants, you know,
something crazier out of this.
It has to get crazier.
People like that.
- On September 26th,
before Gabby's remains
were even able to be
brought back to New York,
her family held
a memorial service for her,
and it was
a very touching ceremony.
They put it out on a live link
so people could watch.
- Gabby is the most
amazing person I've ever met.
So if you're going
to leave here today,
I'm asking that
you guys be inspired
by the way she treated people,
all people.
- You had people turning up
to the memorial
who didn't know Gabby
but just felt
a connection to her.
You had people tuning in
online
who really needed to grieve,
who really felt connected to
her and to this tragic case.
- And it was a beautiful day.
It was...
The funeral home
did a great job,
and all of the people
that came out supported us.
It was amazing.
It was a really, really
beautiful tribute to her life.
- This trip you guys
want to take, take it now.
Do it now
while you got the time.
If there is a relationship
that you're in that
might not be the best thing
for you, leave it now.
- Get out, get out
before it's too late.
I mean, you can't help
but wonder if he was
directly referring to,
you know, Gabby's situation.
- He did tell me to shut up.
- After Gabby's memorial,
there was an intense feeling
of frustration
among the public about,
where is Brian Laundrie?
You know, we'd seen
the body cam footage from Moab.
- He, like, grabbed my face
and was, like, like this.
- There was just
an intense desire
* *
- They said Gabby died
by homicide fairly quickly
after her body was discovered,
but we never knew how she died.
We had to wait three weeks
for that information.
- The Teton County
Coroner Office
is filing the following verdict
in the death
of Gabrielle Venora Petito.
We hereby find the cause
and manner of death to be,
the cause...
death by strangulation,
and manner is homicide.
Her body was outside
in the wilderness
for three to four weeks.
- He wouldn't say much
during that announcement,
citing state laws.
He wouldn't answer
big questions like,
what state was her body in?
- But at the end he slips.
Somebody asks him, "You've done
missing person cases before.
"Have you ever dealt with
a case
that has received
this much media attention?"
- Unfortunately, this is only
one of many deaths
around the country of people
who are involved
in domestic violence.
- He characterizes this
as a domestic violence case.
He doesn't say who did it,
but, you know,
the internet went crazy.
- Just a warning,
this information
could definitely
be triggering to some.
- The coroner most of the time
won't give their own thoughts
and interpretations
of the results of their work,
but this coroner did.
- Now we know
some big pieces finally.
- There were criminal charges
against Brian Laundrie.
He used Gabby Petito's
credit card,
but he was not
a criminal suspect
in the case of her death
at that point.
- Right after this
news conference ended,
we were emailed a copy
of the determination of death,
and it was actually manual
strangulation/throttling.
It's a very violent
and personal death.
To hear that she had died
in this horrible
and very personal way,
I think really hurt
a lot of people.
- The mood really just
changed to, who did it,
and why is there no suspect?
Why is there no arrest warrant?
Why are there no charges?
Really everyone was thinking,
"Only Brian can provide
the answers."
- Haywood County 911.
What's the location
of your emergency?
- People were saying that
they saw Brian everywhere,
and we constantly hear
that he's in this state
and then that state.
It becomes chaotic.
- People thinking he could be
in the Appalachian Trails.
He could be in Mexico.
He could be in Canada.
- He was acting funny,
and I'm 99.99%
sure that was him.
- Everyone thought that
they were seeing
Brian Laundrie somewhere.
- There was a sighting of him
in a Walmart in Tillmans
Corner in Alabama.
- There's a lot of people
that look like Brian Laundrie.
- I don't personally think
that Brian is
in the Carlton Reserve,
where they've been searching.
I think that
that was a diversion.
- But there was some
information they had
that kept sending them back
to the reserve.
Every day the search
would go on for hours,
and we'd be out there waiting,
and they would find nothing,
like, literally
not one piece of evidence.
And so a lot of us
were questioning,
why do they keep going back
to this reserve?
- We just have to believe that
they know what they're doing.
- So the manhunt continues.
Let's just all hope that
this guy is brought in alive.
- On October 19th,
part of the reserve
was open to the public
for the first time
since this all began.
That marked an end
to a chapter in the story.
They had been searching this
place for more than a month.
They haven't been able
to find anything.
They're going to open it
to the public now.
What I wasn't prepared for was
the day after it was opened,
that Chris
and Roberta Laundrie,
while searching with the FBI,
found some of Brian's
belongings,
his backpack and a notebook.
- And it was quite soon
after that
that the human
remains were located.
* *
- According to the
Laundrie attorney,
Brian's parent alerted
the FBI last night
they wanted to search the park,
met them here this morning
and then went to a trail,
where they found
Brian's belongings.
- Almost within half an hour
to an hour,
they had located
Brian's backpack.
- And late this afternoon,
North Port police clarified
exactly what they found.
They described it
as skeletal remains.
- Earlier today, investigators
found what appears to be
human remains
along with personal items,
such as a backpack and notebook
belonging to Brian Laundrie.
I know you have
a lot of questions,
but we don't have
all the answers yet.
- Is it him? Is it not him?
Too many speculations.
- It is crazy.
If this is, in fact, him,
I mean, there's so many people
confirming it.
Why would his parents
go there if it wasn't,
all this kind of stuff, right?
- The remains that they
retrieved from the reserve
matched the dental records
of Brian Laundrie,
and that's how
they were able to confirm.
- I see Twitter going,
like, crazy.
And it's been confirmed.
The human remains
that they found are
indeed Brian Laundrie.
- Brian Laundrie is no more,
and for a lot of people,
this is a relief.
- That was probably one of
the oddest days
in my career thus far.
The Laundries show up,
crack of dawn
to the very same park
that his Mustang was parked
at now over four weeks ago,
going back in once again
to look for their son,
and this just happens to be
the time that they find an item
belonging to him in a place
that had already been
searched many, many times.
- You telling me that all of
these trained professionals
could not find
any of this stuff,
but the father just so happened
went to the exact place
where Brian Laundrie was
and found his bag?
- Everyone is like, "How
the heck could the parents
find these things
when the FBI and police
have been searching?"
- Back in September,
the reserve was 75 percent
covered in water.
When
Roberta and Chris Laundrie
returned to that park
in that very spot,
the water had receded
considerably.
- They said he had gone
to hike trails there.
These were trails
that he was familiar with.
- That's why they were able
to find his belongings
and then his partial
human remains.
- The items that
were located today
perhaps couldn't be seen.
We're not just saying it.
I'm not just saying it.
The FBI is saying it.
Everyone is saying it,
and yet these platforms
are still running amok
with these ludicrous
and, I have to say,
you know,
nonsensical theories
of the parents
planting things there.
I mean, enough is enough.
The Laundries have been
cooperating with
law enforcement both locally
and federally since day one
with respect to Brian.
- So the notebook
may be the key.
It could tell us what went
through Brian Laundrie's mind,
what his actions were,
why he did what he did.
It could provide a confession.
That confession
will lock him in to the crime,
but we may never know
exactly what was in there.
- I really don't know
what justice for Gabby
looks like at this point.
The one person who probably
knows what happened
and why she died is dead.
- This is tragic, but I will
tell you this tragedy
brings us all together,
and the end result is one team,
one family working
to bring closure.
Again, our thoughts and prayers
are with the family members,
and it's a tragedy.
Thank you.
- You cannot try
a dead person.
So there is no case that is
going to be brought forward
against Brian Laundrie
in this matter.
If there's no criminal
investigation,
there's no criminal prosecution
in this case
that is going to be
brought forward.
For the most part, this case
is, in reality, ended.
- Okay, so it's just
been confirmed
that the cause of death is
a gunshot wound to the head,
and the manner of death
is suicide.
This is in relation
to Brian Laundrie.
- This case was one of
those things that just...
it was crazy
from the beginning,
from the get-go.
But there it is. But there's
more questions, right?
Where's the gun?
Where is the gun?
I mean, they told us
everything else they found.
Why didn't they say,
"We found a gun, as well"?
Why didn't they say that?
Why are they not able to get
anything from the notebook?
Like, where's that update?
Is the end of the case
for Gabby?
- We may never know why,
now that they're both dead.
We may never know
why this happened
and why it had
to end this tragically.
* *
- Gabby's story got
a lot of attention,
and everyone deserves
especially if they go missing.
- I want Gabby's legacy
to prevent this
from happening to someone else.
Even if it's just one,
that's something. That's a lot.
- We received a tremendous
outpouring of support
from our community,
from our friends,
our family, from people
all across the world,
and we were very lucky
to have that,
and we want to be
able to use the platform
that we made for Gabby
as that voice for other people.
- It's amazing how many people
have reached out to us,
either saying their story
or how Gabby inspired them
to leave
an abusive relationship.
It makes you feel, like, that
her light did reach the world.
Her light, her bright beautiful
light touched a lot of people.
- You see how much the planet
has come together for Gabby.
So we should do that
for others, too,
because everybody deserves
to feel safe at home.
Everybody deserves to be found
that is missing, everyone.
- It makes me proud of her
that she put
herself out there,
and everybody fell
in love with her,
and I am just
really proud of her.
Her and her legacy are gonna
do so much to help everyone.
- I miss seeing her.
I miss hugging her.
I miss calling her.
I miss hearing her say,
"I love you, too."
- Gabby Petito
never goes outside.
- I find myself watching
that video that she had online
just
so I can hear her voice again.
- The tent is just
coming in on me.
The wind is so bad!
- Just so I can hear her.
- I've just been sitting here
like this for a while.