Masha ?! Why are you sitting here?
Son, pour tonight.
Have you talked?
- We talked ...
- Have you agreed?
Pour?
Why are you sitting, talking straight?
Got a portfolio?
What did you agree on?
There is nothing to agree on. They will be interrupted.
- Take shanezhki, maybe you want on the road?
- No, I don’t want to.
- Sit down, I'm for advice.
- I'll get there.
Did these come for me?
Pavel Vasilievich, you would first
say hello. You are not bursting with your wife in the hallway.
Sit down.
Well, tell me. What's the news? Galina how?
Fine. What will happen to her?
But mine is something sick.
The doctor says it is necessary to
go to the regional hospital . There is no one to treat in the district.
I won't give them the sawmill.
And no one takes it away from you.
- Yes, to hand it over for scrap - they will give more.
- Well, you lived without a sawmill.
Year?
I understood you, Klavdiy Stepanovich!
Wait a minute! He got it! What did you understand? Sit down!
From the district, according to your soul, they
've already cut off my entire phone
The head himself drove for half an hour on the bald head,
I asked you to do everything more accommodating ...
These showed up, the envelopes are shoved.
I have never taken them and am not going to take them!
Back off, Pash. It will not end well.
Will you pay off the sawmill loan?
I
sold my mother's house where I grew up to raise money.
I pushed Sevrilov to the farm, into the shack!
Pash, well, I can't beat you off from them.
Do you think they have the
first competitor on the road?
And then what kind of competitor you are to them ...
they press you so that others do not divorce.
If you don't give the sawmill back, they
'll burn it to hell ... or even worse ...
There - burned the man in
Odnoverovo, killed the dog to death,
and he and his wife were almost sent in pursuit.
Do you need it?
- Danilka, great!
- Hello!
For knowledge? Also true ...
You are ... send hello to it.
Timov! Come to us!
- Will you drag on?
- Not.
Why? Are you afraid your mother will smell it?
- Don't be a horseman, take a pause!
Have you smoked?
So the bull is closer.
Great.
Let's go. Sit down.
Aunt Katya, let me help.
Don’t, Danil, I’ve almost done it.
- Have you brought some water?
- Yes.
- Have you learned your lessons?
- I will learn it, I will have time.
When?
- I'll check it in the evening.
- Check it out.
To which Suleima are you transferring the boards again?
I would go even to the people,
even to the Pashin guys.
- What is there on the sawmill - there are not enough boards?
- Yes, the boards are dofiga - not a pity ...
- To cut the bread?
- That's enough.
Maybe Claudius in some way will
persuade them to leave the sawmill?
Who will listen to him?
He's alone there in the afternoon.
Every week he
goes to the district administration to bow.
Now for gasoline, now for light ...
It does not interfere, and okay.
Pasha, we will.
Let's live somehow without a sawmill.
And I don’t want to somehow.
Well, do people live?
They live.
And if like on Verov? We don't have a dog.
Calm down, huh?
- Can I bargain with them? We have a boyfriend.
- No, maybe.
When the state farm was ruined, my father, like the
others, was on the sidelines. Somehow ...
Then he hid his eyes from me for the rest of his life.
Then times were different.
We all have the same time.
Give me the garlic.
Danka, catch her!
Thank you, Tribute! Without you I wouldn't catch.
Solving problem number 319.
We cut out a beam from a round log,
with a rectangular section of the
largest area.
Find the dimensions of the beam section
if the section radius is ...
Hello!
Hello. What do you want?
- Come home, still small!
- Yes, not for me!
Not ashamed to tell lies? Not for daddy.
So what?
What did you pin on?
AND?
Has your mother stopped sucking a boob for a long time?
Give me another one already? Young male!
Couldn't you take anything better?
There is a shop nearby.
Will you?
As you want...
- Go while sit in the barn.
- What?
What have we not seen here?
Showers additives.
I said fuck you out of here! Alive! Both!
Come out I said!
- I'll take it?
- I'll take it for you!
Come on ... Don't be afraid - I won't drink everything ...
Why froze?
These devils won't sit there for long.
Well
let's go, take a ride, show us the surroundings?
Don't you know?
Well, as good as you - no.
Let's go, we have beer with us, barbecue ...
Let's relax on the river. Let's go?
Such a girl is good and so sad.
Well, how is that?
Sit down, I'll bring it.
Do not need.
Offended for the bath?
I'm sorry - I was stupid ...
Sit down - on the way after all.
Will you not be angry for ages?
Behind the swamp, the forest was broken by a hurricane.
Like matches.
A lot?
No, not really. Stripe.
Don't you like me at all?
The main thing is that you like your Pebbles.
And I'm not asking Pebbles, but you.
And I, Pash, have a husband.
Husband? I ate pears ...
How much is a husband ?!
Get off, I'll get there.
Maybe I want to marry you too.
What is it like?
Yes, just like that.
I'll divorce Pebbles - I'll marry you.
You will give birth to me more children.
Have arrived already, groom.
I'm serious.
Why is it that you were drawn to love me?
Maybe I have been drawn to you all my life ...
It's time to make up your mind.
We will not succeed, Pash.
Don't be in a hurry. Think about it.
There is nothing to think about.
Drive home - Galina is waiting.
Fuh, Danka, scared ...
What are you? What did the mother send for?
- Not.
- And what did you want?
Help.
To me?
Why aren't you at school?
The director let everyone go to help.
Every year they let us go like that - for potatoes.
Come on, assistant. Take the shovel.
Do you want a drink, Tribute?
Go fetch some water from the kitchen, I'll drink too.
Where were you today?
I stayed at school.
My father rattled with a shovel.
This is with sciatica!
The assistant has grown up.
Not ashamed?
Come for dinner in half an hour.
Will you be dressed to wash?
Raise your leg.
Another.
- Great!
- Great, Stepanych!
Hello!
- What - they cut everything off?
- All harvests, up to the central branch.
Have you come to mock?
Above what?! To mock ...
Was this one like a tie?
Three months. And yesterday as luck would have it.
I slept through the guests, serpent ...
It smells more ...
Yours?
There are no such in our store.
They don't have labels on them.
My brother came in the winter and brought it.
Timofeich, bitch!
Maybe you helped him cut the wires?
Your brother has come!
Would she have survived with you since winter ?!
To fire ...
Who!
Not ours. It looks like the area.
They have a large ZIL with a cabin. Blue.
Rooms?
So the night is dark, the mud is smeared ...
She feeds you ... She feeds you!
And you sold it for half a liter ...
Go away.
Attach in the shed.
If anyone sticks around - do not hesitate.
Pasha, do you understand that it was them?
Klavdiy Stepanych, I would have gone from here too.
Kindly.
Yes, I'll go ... Hey ...
Last week Agafonia the partisan
withdrew, so that there was no one left.
Those wires will be enough for you,
and I'll give you a tractor and a cart.
- So Muscovites come to her for the summer!
- Nothing, they will sit without light.
Get out of here while you're safe.
But the fact that?
Are you stupid or what?
Take the buckets into the house.
The old man wants to transport the grandmother to us.
The bear house will be free for us.
I will repair it - we will live there.
Is it so straightforward to live?
Well yes. Like husband and wife.
Have you found yourself an oldish wife?
Not. You are young and beautiful.
I will be a good husband.
I will not drink. I'll go to work.
Dad will take it to the sawmill anyway.
- When are you going to teach?
- I'll find the time.
You're getting something early today from school.
Don't you skip?
Not.
I'm late for the farm because of you.
- How many lessons were there?
- Six.
- No twos?
- Not.
Why haven't you been there for so long?
- Where do you disappear after school?
- I'm not lost.
I was in training.
You yourself wanted me not to sit at home.
What training session?
I signed up for volleyball, the physical education teacher leads.
We are preparing for regional competitions.
So. Soup on the table. Learn the lessons.
Wait-wait-wait-wait-wait ...
They are animals, they are cleverer than people.
- Who are you talking about?
- Yes, my Danka, has changed completely.
Doesn't want to study.
Previously, you could not drive out of the house,
but now it disappears, do not understand where.
If she didn't know how timid he is before girls,
I would have thought that I would have started some curl.
Will lead more.
Yesterday's milk was poured out to the calves again?
The creamery again
takes it for a pittance , so where is it?
Finish your studies, and then start.
What will hang,
so surely it will not be up to study.
Now they still study at school,
and they themselves jump into bed with the peasants.
Yes, and in our time there were enough whores.
The whole herd would have been killed at once.
Neither we nor the cattle would be tortured.
It's more profitable to drain the whole thing.
Well, let me help you to the
hut, Mikola, to get there.
Hi Gal.
Sorry, I was delayed.
I scratched the smut, otherwise my drunk
will come and get sick, God forbid.
Wait, you grunt!
Why did you tell your mother about us?
I did not say.
How does she know?
Maybe you saw us?
And if anyone else has seen?
Nobody else walks here ...
And let her see.
To entice us to meet, Tribute.
Why? I don't skip school anymore.
We must beckon. For a while.
What did she tell you?
Do not listen to her, she is not a decree to us!
Is it because of Kolka? He won't know anything.
And even if he finds out, I will not give you an offense!
Give me a hug.
Where is the student?
“I don’t see it during the day.”
- He plays volleyball.
Volleyball? At school chtol?
At school.
Katka Popova's in the bathhouse.
- What - do not understand?
- Got it.
Well, if you understand so, talk to him.
You are the father.
He should finish school.
Maybe he will go to school too.
And he got in touch with a woman
who suits him as a mother.
What will come of this? Why are you silent?
Why don’t you talk then?
This age has come,
he still needs a woman.
Better with Katka.
Why are you banging something wrong?
Why are you hunting? To
bring him with some young schoolgirl in the hem?
Come on, motherfucker, understand!
And people will find out. What a shame!
Pasta on the stove, if you like.
I have to run to the evening milking.
Aren't she ashamed?
With her husband! We do not achieve the mind ...
And Kolka finds out - he will knock ours down.
He is sober and bad,
and drunk is wilder than the wild.
That's it, gone.
What did you want, Pash?
He's a child yet, he doesn't understand.
You twist the kid's life.
He, Pash, understands more than you and me.
Leave him, I say!
Can we have love?
Who?! The very thing is not funny?
Something I don't understand, Pash, who are you
grieving about? About the boy or about yourself?
Well, why are you if not a man?
So that on Saturday at the disco
was, we have a mahach with the district,
if you don’t come - uroyu, okay?
I got it ?!
I can not hear!
Come on over. You will dance, you will smell the woman.
Let's go for a walk.
Don't come to me for now, that's all. That's better.
What's better? Let's go to the
bear, grandma will let us in.
I have some money. In the summer I
will go to logging, there I will earn.
- All, Tribute, I'm on the farm, let me go.
- Why?
Yes, you will
have so many girls besides me .
I'm good for you as a mother, not as a girl.
- I do not need them!
“You don’t understand, right?
I will say it in a simple way.
I'm tired of you.
Played.
I'm not interested in you
more, even disgusting.
And it's disgusting to see you,
and disgusting to touch. To the nausea.
Clarified?
And do not try to come to me tomorrow
, and this morning
also. I have a legal husband
, I live with him.
I don't need a second one. Let me go!
I will ...
Come on!
Thank God I sat down ... I barely managed ...
Where is he?
This one I suppose?
Will come, will not go anywhere.
At least I came to supper and thanks for that!
Sit down until the potatoes are cold.
How is it! Have you fed?
Mamma's delicious cooking uzho?
Soon you won't come home to spend the night!
So what now?
Waited 16 years ...
All my life the guy blocked.
Trouble, Vasilich!
I was just conscious
, moaning, cursing.
Him to a first-aid post or an ambulance from the area?
What first-aid post ?!
There is nothing besides bandages and gandons.
I'll take it to the area myself - it will come out faster.
Come on, come on! Come on!
Yes, they crept up behind, did not see.
Where were you on Saturday? Jerk off ?!
Why are you cringing like a woman?
AND?! Are you a fagot ?!
That's why you don't fuck anyone!
Every day you will receive like a fagot!
Until you fuck anyone!
What do you need?
What are you doing? Quiet.
Sveta is your name?
Shall we ride?
Yurka, thank God,
got off with one concussion.
They will be discharged in a week.
It would be good. Talk to Danila.
Yurka needs to be replaced
while he is on sick leave.
There is not a single drinker,
even if you take Timofeevich back.
Like they say it was encoded again.
The guy will quit school because of her.
Where then? Only in the army.
I went to the cops, an attempt, I say,
with the infliction of grievous bodily harm.
And they already know.
There would be no sawmill, they say,
there would be no damage.
What will he become without education?
Drinks like everyone else!
Sawmill to him ...
Fig them, not the sawmill!
I'm going to go crazy because of him ... Pasha!
Who is there, the owners?
There is.
Marry me!
Go away.
Get out there, you moron! What did you hatch for ?!
You still have to
suck your mother's tit , not marry!
Get lost, you moron!
Mother come out. We need to talk.
Didn't hear ?!
What are you? Are you going to cut your daddy ?!
I will.
Pasha! Pasha!
Why are you doing something! Stop it!
Vasilevich!
Hello guys. Sit down.
- Does anyone know where Sveta is?
“They took her to the hospital.
- What happened?
- She was raped by the district.
What? All the same, everyone will find out.
Danila!
What are you worth? Take off your clothes.
How did it make you so happy?
You will warm up now, now.
Oh, you fucking subcloud! In my bed!
Go home!
Don't say anything to anyone, do you hear?
Do not say anything!
Take your clothes in the hut!
Go home. Go.
They will carry it away anyway.
Kolka departed.
Katya is shining a dozen. What - no?
Have you forgotten what?
I killed Kolka.
I scissor him in the back.
Fear God!
Danila, why are you saying that?
He wanted to strangle her, I killed him.
Well, shut up.
Shut up, do you hear!
Don't tell anyone that.
Everyone knows that Kolka Fraerlich
made a decision about the bottle.
What do you want
to go to jail because of that beast?
Outside and okay! Nobody even felt sorry for him.
- It is not her fault! I need to be arrested!
- Who is to blame ?! Who is guilty?!
She's to blame.
The husband will never strangle his wife.
I sinned and almost dragged you with me.
Have pity on me at least.
Don't tell anyone!
Okay?
Well, promise your mother!
Where are you going?
To school. I'll have time for the second lesson.
Hello! I'm sorry, but where is Danila?
At a big break, he got on a
day bus to the district.
Thank.
Boy, buy shoes - Lipetsk factory!
Look, it's worth noticing early,
when the humps just caught fire.
And they sensed
that the sawmill began to be seized by fire.
Why am I soaring now to you ...
Vasilich, I didn't tell you just now ...
You already grab the knives ...
Before it puffed, I saw how Danka
got out of your run, hiding behind that mowing.
I didn't say it right away. I thought you’ll suddenly hurt the kid.
Great!
Great.
So what? How is he?
What would happen to you?
By the way, I didn’t sleep for two days either.
Two murders, fire.
But here on the collective farm they mainly sowed livestock.
What else will happen now?
Yes, what will be, it will overgrow, the forest will be.
Breadwinner.
Danya .....
Let's go ... Well let's go!
I killed Kolka Popov.
Who are you to?
What is Kolka Popov? Who are you?
His neighbor is from Ozernoye.
Sanya, here is
some kid from Ozernoye on your case ...
Came to give up.
Hit ... with a
clenched sheep shear.
He choked her on the floor,
as if I hit him from above. Right here.
He immediately fell on his face.
The scissors stayed in it.
It is not her fault. It's me.
Listen to me, Robin Hood ...
- She protects me!
- And I do not care who protects whom!
The suspect
killed her husband in cold blood ...
He's a killer himself!
- Yes, we know without you!
- It's not fair! I killed him!
She didn't touch him! I scissor him ...
Shut your mouth!
And listen to me carefully!
If you want to go on a
youngster - I'll give it to you quickly
will arrange. She is a grown
woman, unlike you.
And he gives a report that he says what he is doing.
You are given a chance, you have your whole life ahead of you
so I grabbed my legs in my hands,
and left here!
Run!
Until I change my mind.
I want to see her.
Came out!
Ivanych, let the kid out.
Hello. Can you tell
me where Svetlana Lukashina lies?
- Are you a relative of her?
- Classmate.
Nuuu ... Am I going?
Why did you come?
Just...
Do you love me?
Not.
What are you doing that ?!