( music playing )
( dogs barking )
( woman screams on TV )
( both laugh )
THAT MARLIN, MAN,
HE IS ONE BAD FISH.
( laughter )
Priest:
BOYS,
THE HOUR
IS DRAWING NEAR.
DON'T YOU THINK
WE COULD BE MAKING
A LITTLE BIT BETTER
USE OF THIS TIME?
WELL, FILL ME IN
ON THE PROTOCOL, PADRE.
HOW EXACTLY
DO WE DO THAT?
WELL, YOU MIGHT
CONTEMPLATE
THE NATURE
OF YOUR CRIMES.
REPENT OF YOUR SINS.
- YOU HEAR THAT, L.H.?
- YEAH.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
THINKING ABOUT ALL THE BAD,
BAD THINGS WE'VE DONE.
- OH.
-( screaming on TV continues )
( both laugh )
YOU KNOW WHAT, FATHER?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THIS WAS A GOOD IDEA.
HEY, HEY, HEY, LOOK!
IT'S US!
Christy Carruthers:
The executioner's song
is playing tonight
for the bloodthirsty
Burne Brothers.
The eyes of the nation
are on Metro City as these
sadistic siblings
await side-by-side seats
in the electric chair.
"Mad Dog"
and "Little Henry" Burne
were the first criminals
to be convicted
under the city's controversial
anti-firearms amendment
for their part in
the Metro City Mall robbery
two years ago,
which ended in the massacre
of six bystanders
and three
Metro police officers.
Ironically,
the brothers' fates
now rest in the hands
of the very person who
led the crusade
to abolish all weapons
within the Metro City limits,
Mayor Eleanor Grimbaum.
Early today,
by order of the governor,
Grimbaum was given penal
jurisdiction in the matter.
Only a phone call
from her
can save
the condemned men now.
( TV clicks off )
( dials )
MR. LEE,
IT'S MAYOR GRIMBAUM.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE, IS IT?
OH, THANK GOD.
MM, GOOD. GOOD.
UH, ADD A SESAME CHICKEN
AND A PORK RICE TO THAT,
WOULD YOU?
- MM. FRIED.
- ( chuckles )
-
( flashbulbs clicking )
( hushed whispering )
( metallic squeaks )
( yells )
( chatter )
( gate creaks )
ONE QUESTION--
HOW SHALL I SERVE YOU?
COME AGAIN, WARDEN?
AFTER YOU'RE COOKED.
SHALL I SERVE YOU
WITH POTATOES OR STUFFING?
WELL, DON'T GO PREHEATIN'
YOUR OVEN JUST YET.
THERE'S BEEN A CHANGE
OF DINNER PLANS.
( yells )
( screaming )
( yells, laughs )
DAVID COPPERFIELD
DOESN'T HAVE SHIT ON ME.
SOME LAST-MINUTE SUBSTITUTIONS
IN THE CAST TONIGHT, FOLKS.
ROLL IT, HENRY.
( screaming )
SORRY, NO REFUNDS.
( screams )
- MOVE IT!
- I WANNA SEE THOSE
FUCKERS DANCE AROUND AGAIN.
COME ON, DROP IT,
WE'RE OUT OF HERE.
- ONE MORE TIME.
- NO!
-
( sirens blaring )
( music playing )
( motorcycles revving )
( chatting, laughing )
- ( gang cheers greetings )
- MAD DOG!
HEY! MAD DOG!
WHOO!
IT'S SHOWTIME.
WHAT A SORRY BUNCH
OF DRUG ADDICTS,
- DEGENERATES, AND WHORES.
- Man:
YEAH.
- DAMN, IT'S GREAT TO BE BACK!
- ( gang cheers )
I WANT TO THANK SKIN
HERE FOR--
WELL, FOR RUNNING THINGS
FOR ME WHILE I'VE BEEN
ON VACATION.
- HE'S DONE A DAMN GOOD JOB.
- ( applause )
NOW, SKIN ASSURES ME THAT--
WELL, NOW THAT I'M BACK,
THE TRANSITION
OF POWER,
WELL, WILL BE
A SMOOTH ONE.
-
( crowd cheers)
- ( gags )
LATER, SKINS.
( laughs )
( gang cheers, laughs )
NOW, IF YOU
WANT TO ROB ME
AND STEAL FROM ME,
GOD BLESS YOU.
JUST, UH, WELL,
- JUST DON'T GET CAUGHT.
- ( crowd laughs )
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS NO TIME
FOR CELEBRATION.
MY BROTHER IS DEAD.
AND HIS BLOOD
IS ON THE HANDS
OF THAT
FUCKING WOMAN
WHO PUT US
IN THAT HOLE
AND TRIED
TO SHUT US DOWN.
WELL,
TONIGHT...
WE'RE GOING TO RIP THE TITS
OFF THAT FUCKING BITCH
- AT CITY HALL!
- ( gang cheers )
( music playing )
Man:
GET RID OF HER.
-( dispatch chatter )
- You're new.
You know what?
I'M GONNA ENJOY
BREAKING YOU IN.
( gang laughs )
( dispatch chatter )
THAT SON OF A BITCH LANDED
RIGHT IN OUR LAPS!
You know,
you better warn the mayor
because they're
coming after her tonight.
( pipe clanging )
I'M TELLING YOU
if I can isolate Mad Dog,
I'm taking him out.
NO, DON'T
DO ANYTHING STUPID.
( sighs )
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU LIKE THE LEATHER
FOR THE WEDDING
or you into
the traditional white?
ALYSSA, NOW DON'T
DO ANYTHING CRAZY.
- JUST WAIT,
WAIT FOR BACKUP.
- I got to go.
ALYSSA, WAIT FOR BACK--
SHE NEVER WAITS.
IT'S ABOUT
FREAKIN' TIME.
WHAT WAS YOU DOIN'?
CHECKIN' FOR WORMS?
DON'T MAKE ME
HURT YOU, BOXER.
OH, YEAH. ALL RIGHT.
WHEN BALLERINAS GROW
BALLS, RIGHT?
WHEN BALLERINAS
GROW BALLS.
( sirens blaring )
( music playing )
ALL RIGHT, LET'S
CUT TO THE CHASE.
PRESS IS TRYING
TO CRUCIFY ME.
HOW DID THEY GET
SOMEONE ON THE INSIDE?
FIREARMS PAST THE SCANNERS?
ANSWER ME THAT, HIGGINS.
UH, WE DON'T KNOW YET,
YOUR HONOR.
WELL, I'VE GOT
SCANNERS EVERYWHERE.
I'VE EVEN GOT ONE
AT MY GYNECOLOGIST'S OFFICE,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKES.
HOW DID THEY GET PAST
THE ONES IN METRO PEN?
WE BELIEVE IT WAS
A PLASTIC WEAPON, MA'AM.
OR A RESIN COMPOUND.
FROM THE REMAINING TRACES
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO--
Grimbaum:
YEAH, YEAH, WHATEVER.
WHAT ARE WE DOING
TO FIND MAD DOG?
WELL, WE'VE GOT
A G6 MO-TECH UNIT
ON THE SCENE AT THE PRISON.
UH, THEY'RE SEEING
WHAT THEY CAN DIG UP
AND, UH, WE'VE ALERTED
THE U.C.s IN THE FIELD.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE "U.C.s"?
UNDERCOVER OPERATIVES.
WOULD YOU CUT
THE MATT HELM SHIT, CHIEF?
YOU-- HONEY,
I AM DOING A
PRESS CONFERENCE,
NOT "OTHELLO."
WOULD YOU BLEND THIS?!
NOW LOOK, BOYS,
MARK MY WORDS,
IF I GO
DOWN ON THIS,
I SHALL DO
SO WITH MY NAILS
FIRMLY IMPLANTED
INTO YOUR BALLS.
HAVE YOU GOT THAT?!
THIS IS
AN ELECTION YEAR.
MY APPROVAL RATING'S
AT 33%. OW!
AND THAT WAS BEFORE
MAD DOG ESCAPED.
Man:
31%.
I HAVE NO TIME
FOR KISS-ASSES, PROFESSOR.
HOW CAN
I HELP YOU?
PERHAPS WE SHOULD DISCUSS
HOW I CAN HELP YOU.
Higgins:
AND WHAT ARE
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
LAZARUS.
OH, THE PROM
IS OVER, JACK.
STOP ASKING ME
TO DANCE.
EVEN IF I TOTALLY APPROVE
THE LAZARUS PROJECT,
WHICH I DON'T,
THERE'S NO MONEY
IN THE BUDGET TO SUPPORT IT.
- SHE'S RIGHT.
- I SUGGEST YOU FIND IT.
OR ELSE?
OR ELSE THE VOTERS
WILL LOOK AT YOU
AS THE WOMAN
WHO GAVE METRO CITY
BACK TO THE CRIMINALS.
THAT'S HARDLY FAIR.
AT THE TIME,
WE ALL REACTED FAVORABLY
TO THE CIVIL
UNREST AMENDMENT.
IF OTHER MEASURES
WERE TAKEN
IN CONJUNCTION WITH
THE ABOLISHMENT OF GUNS.
LAZARUS WAS
ONE OF THOSE MEASURES.
YOU HAVE TO MOVE FORWARD
ON THIS, IT'S A MATTER
OF SELF-PRESERVATION.
( phone ringing )
YES?
YES. THE MAYOR?
IS THIS A RELIABLE SOURCE?
STRANGE TIME
TO BE WASHING WINDOWS.
- ( yells )
-
( music playing )
( screams )
( groans )
PROFESSOR CROWLEY,
PLEASE PUT YOUR GUN
ON THE TABLE
AND PUT YOUR
HANDS BEHIND
YOUR BACK.
YOU'RE IN VIOLATION
OF THE CIVIL UNREST
AMENDMENT.
BLOW IT OUT
YOUR ASS, HIGGINS!
I'M GREEN-LIGHTING
LAZARUS AS OF NOW.
OTHER THAN A CHECK,
WHAT DO YOU NEED?
A CANDIDATE.
( music playing )
( crowd cheering )
( phone ringing )
HELLO?
IT'S OUR FRIEND.
YEAH?
YEAH,
I'M LISTENING.
BAD NEWS
FROM CITY HALL?
SHE'S ALIVE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
- THERE'S A RAT ON BOARD.
- Man:
A RAT?
- FLUSH IT OUT.
- ( gang chatters )
Man:
IT'S NOT ME.
ARE YOU A RAT?
WHAT?
YOU WERE INSIDE
A LONG TIME AND I
WAS JUST THINKING--
YEAH, WELL, I GOT
A LOT ON MY MIND.
GO DOWN ON ME.
MAKE IT QUICK.
WELL, CAN'T WE GO
SOMEWHERE A LITTLE
MORE PRIVATE?
DON'T. JEEZ!
( groans )
ARGH!
SHE NEVER WAITS,
SHE NEVER WAITS.
THIS IS U.C. 159 TO DISPATCH.
WE GOT TROUBLE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU GOT NICE EYES.
( screaming )
- SURVEILLANCE CAMERA.
- NO.
AUDIO?
HM-MM?
( screams )
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THE RANGE IS ON SOMETHING
THIS SMALL, HUH?
CAN'T BE TOO FAR.
CHECK IT OUT.
( groans )
- ( group laughing )
- ( groans )
- WAKE HER UP.
- Woman:
HERE WE GO.
GET UP!
( groans )
Man:
SOMEBODY WOKE UP
ON THE WRONG SIDE OF THE BED.
( laughter )
ENOUGH!
TAKE A SEAT, PIG!
I SMELL BACON.
- Mad Dog:
PRETTY PLEASE?
- ( yells )
SEE THIS GUN?
WELL, THIS IS
MY MOST PRIZED POSSESSION.
LITTLE HENRY
KNOCKED OFF
HIS FIRST LIQUOR STORE
WITH THIS BABY.
AND, WELL,
I ONLY TAKE IT OUT
ON SPECIAL OCCASIONS.
YOU PLAY GAMES?
WHY DON'T YOU
CUT THE BULLSHIT?!
WE HAVE YOU COLD,
THIS PLACE IS GOING
TO BE CRAWLING--
SAVE IT!
NOW...
I'VE BEEN READING
POKER FACES SINCE I WAS...
EIGHT YEARS OLD.
AND YOU KNOW
WHAT YOUR FACE SAYS?
"THAT THERE'S
NO HELP ON THE WAY
AND I'M SO
AFRAID TO DIE."
YEAH? WELL,
I'M BLUFFING 'CAUSE
IT SAYS GO FUCK YOURSELF!
- ( gang whoos )
- Man:
SHE TOLD HIM.
I CAN READ
YOUR HAND, BABY.
AND YOU
GOT JACK SHIT.
TIME TO FOLD, ANGEL.
( yells )
NOW...
HOLLOW POINTS--
- THE ULTIMATE MIND EXPANDERS.
- ( mimics gunshot )
NOW, THIS IS CALLED
DEALER'S CHOICE.
AND THE GAME
IS CALLED
- "ONE UNLUCKY
PIG'S HEAD EXPLODES."
-( gang laughing )
- THIS IS WHAT YOU DO.
- Man:
HEY, CAN I PLAY?
YOU TAKE THE GUN
IN YOUR HAND,
PUT YOUR FINGER
ON THE TRIGGER,
AND PRESS.
YOU SAY A PRAYER.
NOW IF GOD'S
LISTENING TO YOU,
- WELL, THEN, CLICK.
-YOU BETTER BE PRAYING.
IF HE'S LISTENING
TO YOUR FRIEND OVER HERE...
- BAM!
-
( gang laughs )
( grunts )
GIVE ME THAT.
WELL, I GUESS GOD'S
ON MY SIDE, ANGEL.
NOW, UH,
I'M GONNA THROW
IN A WILDCARD HERE, ALL RIGHT?
NOW, IF YOU TWO PLAY FAIR,
WELL, THE WINNER CAN TAKE
MY PERSONAL MESSAGE
TO THE MAYOR.
WAKE UP!
COME ON!
NO ONE LIKES A GUY
WHO FALLS ASLEEP
AT PARTIES.
JEEZ.
NOW, UH,
WHERE WAS I?
NOBODY LIKES A GUY
WHO FALLS ASLEEP AT PARTIES.
THANKS.
NOW, IF YOU MOVE
THAT PIECE AN INCH,
YOU'RE BOTH
FUCKIN' DEAD.
- LET THE GAMES BEGIN!
- ( crowd cheers )
COME ON, MAN.
DO IT!
( clicks )
- ( clicks twice, fires )
- OH!
( crowd cheering )
Man:
SOMEBODY GET
A HOLD OF HER.
NOW, NOW.
ALL RIGHT, NOW LISTEN.
I GAVE MY WORD, RIGHT?
Man:
THAT'S RIGHT.
- WHAT'S FAIR IS FAIR.
- Man:
FAIR IS FAIR.
Man:
GIVE HER ANOTHER BULLET, MAN.
( motorcycles revving )
( music playing )
( sirens blaring )
- Doctor:
NON-RESPONSIVE TO PAIN.
-
( EKG beeping )
PUPILS HAVE DILATED.
HE'S GOT A BLEED.
PREP HIS HEAD. GET ME COEN.
WE'RE GOING IN, STAT.
Doctor:
THERE'S POSSIBLE PENETRATION
TO THE LUNG CAVITY.
Nurse:
GET THE BLOOD TYPE DOWN.
PENETRATING TRAUMA.
MASSIVE BLOOD LOSS.
TUBE HER.
- ACCESS FILE 2-2-5-0-1.
- Computer:
Accessing file.
Subject name:
Alyssa Lloyd.
U.C. operative,
badge number 751.
NEXT OF KIN?
Searching.
One moment, please.
Subject history
shows no living relatives.
- STATUS?
- WELL, HE'S GOT
SERIOUS BRAIN DAMAGE,
- BUT THE CAT SCAN
WILL SHOW--
- THE WOMAN.
WELL, IT'S NOT
LOOKING GOOD.
( EKG beeping )
OFFICER LLOYD,
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU ARE GOING TO DIE,
BUT I CAN OFFER YOU
A SECOND CHANCE.
DO YOU WANT
THAT CHANCE?
DO YOU WANT IT?!
( flatlines )
- I UNDERSTAND.
- MOVE!
WE'RE GOING
TO LOSE HER! MOVE!
- Nurse:
CHARGE 200.
- CLEAR.
AND AGAIN.
- CALL IT.
- NO, THERE'S
STILL A CHANCE.
CALL IT!
Nurse:
BE RIGHT BACK
WITH THE RESULTS.
WHO ARE THESE GUYS?
THIS IS AN EMERGENCY ROOM.
- Man: GET OUT OF
THE WAY, PLEASE.
- Man #2: EVERYONE OUT.
Nurse:
GET THESE GUYS
OUT OF HERE RIGHT NOW.
- Man #2:
GOOD? LET'S GET
HER OUT.
- Man:
GOT IT.
Man #2:
MOVE. LET'S GO.
ROLL ON, ROLL ON.
LET'S GO.
Crowley:
IT'S BEEN 72 HOURS SINCE
THE FUNERAL OF ALYSSA LLOYD.
THE FIRST PHASE
OF THE PROCESS
HAS MET WITH
CONSIDERABLE SUCCESS.
ALL LIFE SIGNS
APPEAR FUNCTIONAL.
THE REST IS UP TO HER.
GOOD MORNING, MISS LLOYD.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
WHERE AM I?
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU ARE?
- AM I DEAD?
- YOU WERE.
MY CONDOLENCES.
BREAKFAST?
WHERE'S MY PARTNER?
SERGEANT DUPRE
IS AT CITY GENERAL.
HE'S VEGETATIVE.
THERE'S NOTHING WE CAN DO.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M PROFESSOR
JACK CROWLEY.
I'M IN CHARGE
OF THE LAZARUS PROJECT.
YEAH? WHAT THE HELL'S THAT?
AT THE MOMENT, YOU.
LOOK, COULD YOU
BE MORE SPECIFIC?
( gasps )
LOOK AT YOUR HAND.
IN THIS NEW AGE
OF BIO-MOLECULAR
MECHANICS,
THIS IS GOD.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE TO ME?
REPLACED YOUR BLOOD
WITH AN EXPERIMENTAL
PLASMIC SERUM
OF ENGINEERED PROTEINS.
THINK OF THEM
AS MICROSCOPIC MACHINES
THAT WORK IN CONJUNCTION
WITH YOUR BRAIN
TO STIMULATE
LIFE FUNCTIONS
IN DEAD TISSUE.
DEAD TISSUE?
SO, WHAT, YOU'RE
DR. FRANKENSTEIN?
WHAT THE HELL
DOES THAT MAKE ME?
I'M A SCIENTIST,
NOT A PHILOSOPHER.
I'VE BEEN COMMISSIONED
TO CREATE A SOLIDER
OF JUSTICE.
SOMEONE TO WAGE WAR
ON THE CRIMINALS
OF THE CITY
WITH ABSURDLY
EXTREME PREJUDICE.
NO. SORRY TO INFORM YOU,
PROFESSOR,
BUT I RETIRED,
OKAY?
I THINK THAT
THAT OPTION COMES
RIGHT ALONG WITH DEATH.
NOT ACCORDING
TO RIDER
48c OF YOUR
CONTRACT.
WHAT? THAT'S, LIKE,
AN ORGAN DONATION ADDENDUM.
YES, EXACTLY.
IN THE EVENT OF
AN ON-THE-JOB FATALITY,
YOUR BODY
BELONGS TO THE CITY.
IS THAT
YOUR SIGNATURE?
( music playing )
WHY? HERE TO CONFESS
FOR A LIFETIME
OF SINNING?
I DON'T THINK
I'M QUITE READY
TO MEET THE MAKER YET.
DESPITE YOUR SURPRISE
ATTACK ON CITY HALL.
I MEAN,
YOU ALMOST DID ME IN.
- YOU MEAN YOU DIDN'T
GET THE NEWSLETTER?
- ( scoffs )
VERY FUNNY, ASSHOLE.
PLEASE, HIGGS.
THE LANGUAGE.
THIS
IS
THE HOUSE OF GOD.
LOOK, PAL.
IF IT WASN'T FOR ME
YOUR ASS WOULD BE
FRIED WONTON.
-
YOU OWE ME.
- LITTLE ADAM
DOESN'T OWE YOU.
HE'S DEAD.
GOD REST HIS SOUL.
I'M SORRY.
BUT THAT WASN'T
MY FAULT.
I WANT MORE.
I WANT A FULL
PARTNERSHIP.
A FULL PARTNERSHIP?
WELL, WELL, WELL.
LET ME BRING IN
MY BUSINESS NEGOTIATOR.
( dog growls )
NEGOTIATE.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU--
WHAT IS THIS, HUH? HUH?
WELL, HIGGS.
HE'S WAITIN' TO HEAR
YOUR PITCH.
OKAY. I-- I GOT--
ACCESS TO GUNS.
CONFISCATED GUNS.
I GOT THOUSANDS OF GUNS.
YOU KNOW WHAT, HIGGS?
I'D PICK UP THE PACE.
I THINK MY NEGOTIATOR'S
GETTING A LITTLE HUNGRY.
ALL RIGHT, LISTEN. LISTEN.
WE'LL ARM ALL
THE CRIMINALS, ALL RIGHT?
AND THERE
WILL BE TOTAL CHAOS.
GRIMBAUM WILL BE DEAD
IN THE NEXT ELECTION,
I PROMISE.
OH, I THINK SHE'LL BE DEAD
WAY BEFORE THAT.
WE GET A NEW MAYOR.
THAT'S IT. WE GET
A NEW MAYOR.
HE REPEALS THE C.U.A.
I TALK TO SOME PEOPLE,
WE GOT BACKING.
A NEW MAYOR!
HUH?
YOUR NEW
BUSINESS PARTNER.
ME?! HUH?
DOWN. DOWN,
SWEETHEART. DOWN!
DON'T WANT TO BITE
OUR NEW PARTNER.
WHO NEEDS ANOTHER MAYOR
WITHOUT BALLS, HUH?
PULL IT BACK.
( music playing )
Crowley:
PROGRESS REPORT.
SUBJECT'S STRENGTH
INCREASES EVERY SESSION--
UP 52% SINCE MONDAY.
SPEED AND EYE-HAND COORDINATION
HAVE MORE THAN TRIPLED.
-
THE SUBJECT GOES THROUGH
SPARRING PARTNERS...
- ( groans )
...LIKE HUMAN DOMINOES.
SHE'S BECOME
A FIERCE PREDATOR.
ITHE QUESTION IS,
WILL SHE BE ENOUGH TO SATISFY
THE MAYOR'S WAR ON CRIME?
I UNDERSTAND, MAYOR.
YES, I KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON OUT THERE.
IT WOULDN'T BE WISE
TO RUSH THE PROCESS. THERE--
YES.
SINCE YOU PUT IT THAT WAY,
YES, AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
( music playing )
TENSE PHYSICAL ACTIVITY
WILL COMPROMISE THE SOLUTION.
A BOOSTER TO THE JUGULAR
WILL TEMPORARILY REVERSE
THE PROCESS.
FOR HOW LONG?
RESULTS VARY DEPENDING
ON THE STRESS LEVEL
OF THE SUBJECT.
YOU KNOW,
YOUR SUBJECT HAS A NAME.
CLEAR YOUR MIND.
ELIMINATE THE PAST.
STRONG EMOTIONS
WILL COMPROMISE
THE SOLUTION.
AND I'LL ACCEPT
NO COMPROMISES.
( gasps )
Crowley:
CONCUSSION GRENADES,
30-METER RANGE.
TELESCOPING STAFF
WITH TITANIUM CARBIDE
ROTATING BLADES.
IT WILL CUT THROUGH
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
A HIGHLY COMPACT
ASSAULT WEAPON.
THE SIGNATURE GRIP
IS BASED
ON THE SPECIFIC HEAT PATTERN
FROM YOUR HAND.
ANYBODY ELSE
WHO TRIES TO USE IT
IS IN FOR
A BIG SURPRISE.
INTEGRAL LASER MOUNT,
400 YARDS.
YEAH, WELL,
DON'T EXPECT PERFECTION
ON THE FIRST
TIME OUT.
I WAS TRAINED
IN CLOSE-RANGE TASERS.
I EXPECT NOTHING
FROM THE OLD YOU.
I DEMAND PERFECTION
FROM WHAT YOU'VE BECOME.
( music playing )
LET'S MOVE
THE TARGET BACK.
THE PROCESS HAS MUCH
IN COMMON WITH DIALYSIS.
A SERIES OF NEEDLES
PENETRATE MAJOR ARTERIES.
BLOOD IS FLUSHED FROM
HER BODY AND REPLACED DAILY
WITH A SYNTHETIC SOLUTION
OF NANO MACHINES.
THIS SOLUTION RAPIDLY
REGENERATES DAMAGED CELLS
OR, WHEN SUFFUSED
WITH UNFILTERED BLOOD,
RAPIDLY DESTROYS THEM.
I'M IMPRESSED, JACK.
IT'S GOT MEDIA SAVVY.
I THINK SHE'S
GOT THIS KIND OF
JOAN OF ARC THING.
SHE'S REALLY--
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH IT?
- ( moaning )
UH, I THINK IT
MUST BE SOME SORT OF--
NEUROCOGNITIVE RESIDUE.
I'D LIKE TO SHOW YOU
SOMETHING.
( gasping, whimpering )
( music playing )
( laughing )
( piano playing )
NO, I'M NOT GETTING BACK
IN THAT THING.
YOU HAVE TO.
WHAT, BECAUSE
OF MY CONTRACT?
SUE ME.
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME
TRYING TO SQUEEZE MONEY
OUT OF A CORPSE.
MISS LLOYD,
THE NANO CELLS
HAVE A FINITE LIFE SPAN.
WITHOUT A DAILY
TRANSFUSION IN THE CHAIR,
MASSIVE ORGANIC DEGENERATION
WILL TAKE PLACE.
YOU'LL ROT.
YEAH, WELL,
IT'S MY CHOICE TO MAKE.
YOUR CHOICE TO MAKE? YES.
YOUR CHOICE TO MAKE.
A CHOICE SERGEANT DUPRE
UNFORTUNATELY CAN NO LONGER
MAKE FOR HIMSELF,
THANKS TO MAD DOG
AND HIS COMPANIONS.
( computer beeping )
CAN I EXPECT
YOUR COOPERATION?
( machine beeping )
( piano playing )
-Subject Alyssa Lloyd.
- ( computer beeping )
U.C. operative,
badge number 751.
Current status:
deceased.
Deceased.
( keypad beeping )
YOU WALKED OUT ON
AN EXPLOSIVES TRAINING
THIS AFTERNOON.
I'D LIKE
AN EXPLANATION.
I WONDER IF ANYBODY
PUT WHITE ROSES
ON MY GRAVE.
I LOVE WHITE ROSES.
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
IS THAT IN YOUR FILE?
DAN LOVED MY LIPS.
I WONDER
IF HE WOULD NOW.
I MEAN, WHAT WOULD IT BE LIKE
TO KISS SOMETHING
THAT'S DEAD?
I WOULDN'T KNOW.
YOU'LL HAVE TO MAKE UP
YOUR TRAINING TOMORROW.
( crying )
( clanging )
( gasping )
- ( laughter )
- ( gunshot )
( groans )
( keypad beeping )
( machine beeping )
IT'S OKAY, BABY.
THIS IS ALL OVER
FOR BOTH OF US.
( flatlining )
- Lloyd's voice:
WE HAVE YOU COLD!
- Mad Dog's voice:
SAVE IT!
Dupre's voice:
ALYSSA, WAIT FOR BACKUP!
Mad Dog's voice:
I'M GONNA ENJOY
BREAKING YOU IN.
Lloyd's voice:
GO FUCK YOURSELF!
Crowley's voice:
I CAN OFFER YOU
A SECOND CHANCE.
DO YOU WANT THAT CHANCE?
DO YOU WANT IT?!
Mad Dog's voice:
WHAT A SORRY BUNCH
OF DRUG ADDICTS,
DEGENERATES, AND WHORES.
Crowley's voice:
SERGEANT DUPRE IS
AT CITY GENERAL.
HE'S VEGETATIVE.
THERE'S NOTHING WE CAN DO.
- Mad Dog's voice:
IT'S GREAT TO BE BACK!
-
( gang cheers )
Crowley's voice:
WITHOUT A DAILY TRANSFUSION
IN THE CHAIR,
MASSIVE ORGANIC DEGENERATION
WILL TAKE PLACE. YOU WILL ROT.
Mad Dog's voice:
IF GOD IS LISTENING TO YOU,
WELL, THEN, CLICK.
IF HE'S LISTENING
TO YOUR FRIEND OVER HERE...
- BAM!
- ( Lloyd screams )
Lloyd's voice:
IF I CAN ISOLATE MAD DOG,
I'M TAKING HIM OUT.
TAKING HIM OUT.
WHO WAS WATCHING
THE MONITOR WHEN
SHE WALKED OUT OF HERE?!
AS A PRECAUTION FOR THIS,
WE HAD HEAT SENSORS,
WE HAD ALARMS.
- YOU WERE CAUGHT
COMPLETELY UNPREPARED.
-( door opens )
HELP ME.
- NO.
- ( gasping )
I'M DYING!
HELP ME!
WHY? YOU HAVE
NO ONE TO LIVE FOR.
WHAT'S THE USE?
MAD DOG.
I WANT MAD DOG!
IN YOUR CURRENT STATE,
I SERIOUSLY DOUBT IT,
MISS LLOYD.
PUT ME IN
THAT CHAIR NOW!
YOU NEED ME.
- GO.
-
( music playing )
Crowley:
HOOK HER UP!
YOUR SUIT AND BODY ARMOR
HAVE BEEN REINFORCED
WITH BULLETPROOF
AND FIREPROOF KEVLAR.
THE BUILT-IN TRANSMITTER
INSIDE YOUR MASK
ALLOWS FOR TWO-WAY
COMMUNICATION BETWEEN YOU
AND YOUR CUSTOMIZED CYCLE,
WHICH HAS AN 11.2-SECOND
RESPONSE PER QUARTER MILE.
IT TOO IS BULLETPROOF,
NATURALLY, WITH AN ONLINE
COMPUTER BUILT INTO THE DASH.
IT'S BEEN CALIBRATED TO FIT
YOUR BODY MASS WITHIN A
THREE-POUND VARIABLE.
SO WATCH YOUR WEIGHT.
THERE'S BEEN A SERIES
OF HIJACKINGS AT METRO HARBOR.
WORD IS MAD DOG'S STOCKPILING
MERCHANDISE FOR CASH.
PROCEED WITH CAUTION.
USE OF EXCESSIVE FORCE
IS AT YOUR DISCRETION.
Boxer:
I SAID SHUT UP!
HURRY UP!
SHUT UP!
WHAT DO YOU THINK THIS IS?
A UNION JOB?
DON'T SAY A WORD.
DON'T EVEN
CRY OUT IN PAIN.
- ( groans )
- ( laughing )
( motorcycle revving )
I BET YOU AIN'T
NEVER SEEN ONE OF THESE
IN A LONG TIME, HUH?
I BET YOU WISH
YOU HAD ONE OF THESE
INSTEAD OF THAT
SORRY-ASS CATTLE PROD.
( laughing )
THAT'S COMING OUT
OF YOUR ASSES!
NOW PICK IT UP,
YOU UGLY FUCKS!
OR I'LL PUT SOME
REAL LEAD IN YOUR ASSES!
( laughs )
( music playing )
WHAT?
( screams )
HOLY SHIT!
( groans )
( blades whirring )
WHAT THE FUCK?
FUCK!
YES!
THIS MUST BE MY LUCKY DAY!
( beeping )
Computer voice:
Excess body mass.
Access denied.
- SHUT DOWN.
-
Access denied.
Boxer:
WHAT THE FUCK?
WHO'S DENIED?
( brakes screech )
WHOA! SHIT!
DAMN! SHIT!
WHAT'S THE MATTER, BOXER?
NEVER SEEN A BALLERINA
WITH BALLS BEFORE?
OH, NOW,
WAIT A MINUTE.
IT CAN'T BE YOU
'CAUSE YOU WAS DEAD.
WHO WAS DEAD?
OH, LORDSY,
LORDSY NOW, LADY.
YOU WOULDN'T KILL
A BOXER, WOULD YA?
IN A HEARTBEAT.
( music playing )
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOUR APPROVAL RATINGS
HAVE RISEN CONSIDERABLY.
I SIMPLY RESPONDED
TO THE VOTERS' NEEDS.
DEMOLITIONIST IS
THE PEOPLE'S WEAPON.
WELL PUT,
YOUR HONOR.
ARE YOU READY
FOR YOUR PRESS DENIAL?
OH, CHRIST.
BRING 'EM IN.
Reporter:
HERE WE GO.
LET'S SET UP ON THIS SIDE.
Reporter #2:
MADAM MAYOR, CAN I HAVE
THE FIRST QUESTION?
Reporter:
A CLEARER SHOT HERE.
MADAM MAYOR,
SINCE THE APPEARANCE
OF THIS MYSTERIOUS PHANTOM
IN METRO CITY, CRIME HAS
BEEN ON A STEADY DECLINE.
COINCIDENTALLY,
YOUR APPROVAL RATING
HAS SHOT THROUGH THE ROOF.
- CARE TO COMMENT?
- OH, I'VE NEVER
GIVEN TOO MUCH
CREDENCE TO THE POLLS,
MISS CARRUTHERS.
ALTHOUGH I MUST ADMIT
MY CURRENT POSITION IS
RATHER FLATTERING.
( laughing )
CRIME IS DOWN.
GUN RUNNING IS AT
A TWO-YEAR LOW,
AS I PREDICTED
AND PROMISED. SO THERE.
NOW YOU GOT SOME GOOD NEWS
TO REPORT, MISS CARRUTHERS.
FOR A CHANGE.
I'LL SANDWICH IT IN
BETWEEN MY COVERAGE
ON THE MAYORAL RACE
AND THE QUESTION
THAT'S ON ALL OUR MINDS,
YOUR HONOR.
WHICH IS?
WHO IS SHE?
SHE'S NOT REGULAR POLICE.
WHO IS
THE DEMOLITIONIST?
THAT'S AN
INTRIGUING QUESTION.
AND THE ANSWER,
AS FAR AS THE GOOD PEOPLE
OF METRO CITY ARE CONCERNED,
IS THAT
IT'S COMPLETELY IRRELEVANT.
GOT TO EXCUSE ME,
I'VE GOT A CITY TO RUN.
Reporter:
MADAM MAYOR,
ONE MORE QUESTION.
SO THE QUESTION REMAINS.
WHO IS THE WOMAN
BEHIND THE MASK
OF METRO CITY'S
CRIME-FIGHTING PHANTOM?
WHO IS THE DEMOLITIONIST?
VIEWERS ARE ENCOURAGED
TO DIAL IN THEIR
SUGGESTIONS AT
1-900-555-DEMO.
AM I, LIKE, REALLY SHINY?
( sighs, urinating )
( door closes )
YOU CALL THAT A DICK?
IT LOOKS LIKE ONE,
ONLY SMALLER.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
ARE YOU CRAZY?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHO OR WHAT
IS THAT PSYCHO BITCH
IN THE OUTFIT?
SHE'S BEEN KNOCKING OFF
MY BOYS LEFT AND RIGHT.
WHAT?
THE DEMOLITIONIST?
IT'S A GODDAMN
PUBLICITY STUNT.
GRIMBAUM'S TICKET
TO RE-ELECTION.
WELL, SHE'S ONE
GODDAMN DETERMINED
PUBLICITY STUNT.
PULL THE PLUG ON HER,
YOU HEAR ME?
NOW! NOW!
SORRY.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE THE MUSCLE.
NOW IF YOU CAN'T HANDLE IT,
I'LL TAKE MY BUSINESS
TO SOMEBODY WHO CAN.
YOU KNOW, WE DON'T HAVE
AN EXCLUSIVITY CLAUSE,
YOU KNOW.
YEAH, WE DO.
HERE IT IS.
YOU SCREW ME, HIGGS,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
AND THIS WILL BE
THE LAST TIME
YOU PISS STANDING UP,
GOT IT?
YEAH.
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
NOW YOU GET ME
THOSE FUCKING GUNS...
AND I'LL TAKE
CARE OF IT. OKAY?
( zipper zips )
GIVE ME
THE FUCKIN' MONEY
AND YOU'LL GET
THE FUCKIN' GUNS.
LEAVE ME ALONE.
STOP.
LET GO OF ME.
STOP, STOP!
HELP! HELP!
LET GO OF ME!
LEAVE ME ALONE! NO! LET GO!
( crying, screaming )
( groans )
( sirens blaring )
Lloyd's voice:
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU LIKE THE LEATHER
FOR THE WEDDING,
OR YOU INTO
THE TRADITIONAL WHITE?
( alarm sounding )
( music playing )
( door opens )
WHAT'S ALL THIS?
I THOUGHT
WE'D CELEBRATE.
I GUESS YOUR
CREATION IS THE REAL
TALK OF THE TOWN, HUH?
WHAT IS IT?
NON-ALCOHOLIC?
YOU KNOW ALCOHOL
DOESN'T MIX WELL WITH BLOOD.
WHAT? THESE ROSES
AREN'T EVEN REAL?
SO IT NEVER DIES.
OPEN IT.
IT'S FOR YOU.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
RARE.
SYMBOL OF OSIRIS.
OSIRIS?
EGYPTIAN GOD
OF THE DEAD.
CONTROL YOUR EMOTIONS
OR YOU'LL COMPROMISE
THE SOLUTION.
I CAN'T CONTROL
MY EMOTIONS!
I DON'T WANT
TO CONTROL THEM!
GOD, DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND THAT THE DAY
THAT I'M ABLE TO
CONTROL HOW I FEEL,
THEN I'M REALLY DEAD?!
KIND OF LIKE
HOW YOU ARE NOW!
EGYPTIANS WORSHIP
THE DEAD.
P.A.:
Ho, ho, ho.
A Christmas reminder
to all of our customers.
It's never too early
to start thinking about
the holidays.
With that in mind,
Metro City Bank is offering
a one-time Christmas bonus.
Customers opening
a holiday account
on Friday will
receive a toaster.
- MOM.
- STOP IT.
...bagels and all your
holiday toasting needs.
Just our way of saying
thank you for using
Metro City Bank.
( music playing )
- ( gunshots )
- ( crowd screaming )
WHO DO I SPEAK TO
ABOUT MAKING A LARGE
CASH WITHDRAWAL?
I HOPE IT'S
NOT THIS MAN.
( tires screeching )
Computer voice:
211 in progress--
Metro City Bank.
( beeping )
Higgins:
STAY DOWN. DO NOT
GO IN UNTIL I GIVE THE ORDER.
- DO YOU COPY?
-
( dispatch chatter )
WE WON'T NEED YOUR
HELP ON THIS ONE.
WE'VE GOT THE SITUATION
UNDER CONTROL.
UNDER CONTROL?
A BANK FULL OF HOSTAGES?
THERE ARE WOMEN
AND CHILDREN IN THERE.
AND I WON'T
ALLOW A BLOOD-BATH,
NOT ON MY WATCH.
WE'RE NEGOTIATING
WITH THEM.
YOU CAN'T NEGOTIATE
WITH ANIMALS.
I'M ORDERING
YOU TO STAND DOWN.
YEAH, WELL,
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU.
FINE.
DO IT YOUR WAY.
- HOW MANY ARE IN THERE?
- FIVE, MAYBE SIX...
INCLUDING MAD DOG.
YEAH.
COME ON! MOVE IT!
PUT THE MONEY
IN THE BAG!
COME ON! PUT SOME COINAGE
IN THERE, TOO, ALL RIGHT?
I GOT TO DO
SOME LAUNDRY.
- OH, SHIT!
-
( motorcycle engine roars )
WE'LL BE LEAVING NOW.
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOU'RE KILLING HER.
HERE. HERE,
TURN AROUND, HONEY.
IT'S OKAY.
THE BIG BAD
BITCH IN BLACK
DOESN'T WANT
TO HURT US,
DOES SHE?
( beeping )
( screams )
( explosion )
Higgins:
YOU'RE SURE SHE'S OKAY?
BECAUSE WE CAN HAVE
A DOCTOR LOOK AT HER
IF YOU'D LIKE. ALL RIGHT?
( sirens blaring )
-DAWSON, GET A MEDIC ON THIS.
-( radio chatter )
-
( door opens, closes )
- ( whistling )
GOOD WORK, PROFESSOR.
CREATED QUITE A MONSTER.
YOU'RE OVER-REACTING.
NO. I LEFT
A LITTLE GIRL TO DIE
BECAUSE I WANTED
MAD DOG.
OKAY, I MEAN,
I DIDN'T EVEN THINK
TWICE ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW, I JUST DID
WHAT I WAS CREATED TO DO.
I MEAN, I DON'T--
I DON'T EVEN THINK OR FEEL
LIKE A HUMAN BEING
AT ALL ANYMORE.
I'M JUST-- I'M JUST, LIKE,
SOME WEIRD KILLING MACHINE.
AND YOU BLAME ME?
MISS LLOYD,
YOUR PASSION FOR VENGEANCE
HAS SHAPED WHAT YOU'VE BECOME
MUCH MORE THAN
LAZARUS EVER DID.
AND WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
YOU OBVIOUSLY
HARBOR EMOTIONS
FROM YOUR
PREVIOUS LIFE.
FROM THAT NIGHT MAD DOG
HAD YOUR LOVER KILLED.
MY CONTRIBUTION
TO YOUR PSYCHE HAS
NOTHING TO DO WITH THAT
OR THAT UNFORTUNATE
BUSINESS WITH THE CHILD.
THE CHOICES YOU MAKE ABOUT
WHO YOU ARE NOW ARE YOURS.
AND YOURS ALONE.
EXCELLENT CHOICE.
( music playing )
( door opens, closes )
Higgins:
I AM HOLDING.
I HAVE BEEN HOLDING.
HIGGINS!
WELL, HOW LONG DO YOU
EXPECT ME TO WAIT?
YEAH, GET ME
CHRISTY CARRUTHERS, PLEASE.
I HAVE SOMETHING
SHE MIGHT BE INTERESTED IN.
Has The Demolitionist,
Metro City's guardian angel
lost her wings?
Inside source has obtained
exclusive, shocking footage
that proved
the crime buster's heart
may be as black
as her wardrobe.
Luckily, Metro Police were
able to extract the grenades
from the crying child
and detonate them safely.
An inside source
at the mayor's office re--
HOW UNFORTUNATE.
THAT SHOT WILL MAKE
THE COVER OF EVERY PAPER
IN THE STATE.
CONGRATULATIONS,
JACK.
WHAT DO WE GET
FOR AN ENCORE?
I'M SURE IT WAS A BIT
OF A POLITICAL SETBACK.
YOU CALL LEAVING
AN INNOCENT CHILD
TO DIE A SETBACK?
REGISTERED VOTERS
HATE THAT CRAP!
IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT.
I'M CUTTIN'
MY LOSSES RIGHT HERE.
SHE'S OFF THE STREETS.
I'VE GIVEN ORDERS
TO SEE TO IT.
IT'S A MATTER OF,
HOW DID YOU SAY IT?
SELF-PRESERVATION.
- YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
- NAW, STOP BLEEDING, JACK.
LAZARUS IS FINISHED.
IL FAIT ACCOMPLI.
ALYSSA LLOYD SAVED YOUR LIFE
AND YOUR CAREER, MAYOR.
YOU PULL THE PLUG ON LAZARUS,
IT'S JUST LIKE MURDERING HER.
NO, IT ISN'T, JACK.
SHE'S ALREADY DEAD.
( music playing )
Officers need assistance.
Parking structure,
corner of Roosevelt and Fifth.
( tires screeching )
GREAT RESPONSE TIME.
SHOULDN'T YOU BE OUT
EATING DONUTS SOMEWHERE?
SHOULDN'T YOU
BE DEAD?
( groaning )
THEY PULLED THE PLUG.
THERE'S NOTHING
I COULD DO.
HOW MUCH TIME
DO I HAVE LEFT?
ENOUGH TIME
TO GET AWAY.
THEY'LL BE
COMING FOR YOU.
AS IF THEY'D
STAND A CHANCE.
GO. QUICKLY.
JACK, THERE'S STILL
SOMETHING I GOT TO DO.
WHAT?
FINISH WHAT WE STARTED.
OKAY, JUST
BE CAREFUL. GO.
Carruthers:
Later tonight, Mayor Grimbaum
will spend several hours
volunteering in the Metro City
Homeless Shelter,
serving dinner
to the less fortunate.
In national news,
President Bono called
yesterday's mortar attack
on the White House
"sad, really, really sad
and kind of freaky."
No suspects have been named.
( music playing )
MM-MM. AIN'T YOU
THE INSTANT HARD-ON?
-
( groans )
( gunshots )
I'M BARELY COVERIN'
MY COSTS HERE.
DON'T EVEN BOTHER ME.
YOU KNOW WHY?
IT'S THE WORK,
I LOVES IT.
LIKE THIS THING TOMORROW,
I'M TALKING A 32-METER
FLASH POINT TARGETED
PYRO SWEEP,
INVERSE
CONCUSSION GRENADE.
BOOM! I AIN'T JUST
BLOWIN' SHIT UP.
I'S CREATIN' NEW SPACE.
YEAH, YEAH. JUST SO LONG
AS THE MAYOR ENDS UP WASTED.
OH, DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
ALL THAT'S GOING TO BE
LEFT TO BURY
IS A HANDFUL OF ASH.
( laughs )
I HOPE YOU'RE USING
A TIMER ON THAT THING,
PORK BOY,
BECAUSE IF YOU HAVE TO RUN
FOR IT, THEY'RE GOING TO BURY
YOUR FAT ASS IN A PIANO CASE.
- ( laughs )
- LIGHTEN UP!
LET'S NOT GET PERSONAL.
I'S WORKING ON MY WEIGHT ISSUE.
( knock on door )
- WHO THE FUCK IS THERE?
- Lloyd:
ROOM SERVICE.
YOU FAT BASTARD!
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF A DEAL!
YOU ONE-EYED BITCH.
I DIDN'T ORDER ANYTHING.
I SWEAR I DIDN'T.
SOMEBODY GO
CHECK THE SHIT OUT.
AW, MAN.
- I DON'T SEE NOTHIN'.
- Big Frank:
WHOA!
( screaming )
( music playing )
( yells )
- COME ON.
- ( groans )
( dog barking )
( groans )
FUCK!
( tires screech )
HA!
-
TOO BAD.
WE GOT IT DONE NOW.
-
BRING THE CASH.
DID YOU BRING YOUR MONEY?
AS YOU CAN SEE,
WE'VE DELIVERED
THE GOODS.
NOW IT'S TIME
TO PAY THE PIPER.
-TIME TO DIVVY UP NOW.
-COUGH IT UP.
-
COUGH IT UP.
HEY, HERE'S MINE.
-
COULD BUY
A FEW BEERS HERE, HUH?
-
NICE, NICE. GOOD HAUL.
- A LOT OF MONEY!
-
( crowd cheers )
YES, THERE IS.
FRIENDS,
THE REVOLUTION HAS ARRIVED.
Gang: YEAH!
TONIGHT,
WE UNITE AS ONE.
- THE STREETS ARE OURS!
-( gang cheers )
AND TOMORROW
WE MARCH ON CITY HALL!
NOW FOR OUR
NEXT ORDER OF BUSINESS.
- ROLAND, GRAB 'EM.
- ( crowd cheers )
-
COME ON! NINE!
NUMBER SIX!
-
NUMBER NINE!
LET'S GO, EIGHT!
- NUMBER 14.
-
( crowd groans )
OH, OH! OH,
HEY, THAT'S ME!
THAT'S FUCKIN' ME!
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT IS THIS?
- WHAT RAFFLE?
I DIDN'T GET A NUMBER.
-( laughing )
THAT'S BECAUSE
YOUR NUMBER'S UP, HIGGS.
HEY, LOOK, PAL,
YOU CAN'T BE SERIOUS.
- YOU CAN'T KILL
A CITY OFFICIAL.
-
( laughing )
YOU KNOW WHAT, HIGGS?
WHY NOT-- WHY NOT MAKE
MY FINAL THOUGHTS OF YOU
PLEASANT ONES?
INSTEAD OF TELLING ME
WHAT I CAN AND WHAT
I CANNOT DO, HUH?
I HAVE A KID. I MEAN,
I HAVE A FAMILY, HUH?
-I'VE GOT A KID.
- YEAH, WELL, WE'RE, UH,
WE'RE RAFFLING
THEM OFF TOMORROW.
NUMBER 14.
( crowd cheers )
( motorcycle engine roars )
- WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED?
- EVERYONE'S WASTED.
- THE MAYOR?
- WE NEVER GOT A CHANCE.
( moans )
Mad Dog:
WHAT THE HELL
IS WRONG WITH YOU?
- THAT WHORE SHOT ME IN THE ASS!
-( crowd laughing )
- WHAT WHORE?
- THE SAME ONE THAT ICED
HAMMERHEAD AND BIG FRANK.
THE ONE IN BLACK.
- I'VE SEEN SOME
SORRY-ASS SIGHTS.
- FUCK YOU!
SHE DROPPED THIS.
- WHERE IS SHE NOW?
- I TOOK CARE OF IT.
YOU TOOK CARE
OF HER, HUH? HOW?
SHE'S UP IN SMOKE, OKAY?
I DONE HER UP GOOD.
NOW WILL SOMEBODY PLEASE
GET THE CAP THAT SHE POPPED
IN MY ASS OUT?
- PLEASE, BEFORE IT
TURNS GANGRENE!
-
( laughter )
WELL, IT'S
A CLEAN ENTRY.
NO TATTOO MARKS.
I'D SAY THAT PUPPY'S
IN ONE PIECE.
ROLAND, YANK IT
OUT OF HIS ASS.
HEY, HEY. WAIT A MINUTE!
WAIT! WAIT ONE MINUTE, GUYS!
HEY! ROLAND!
YOU STERILIZE THOSE THINGS
BEFORE YOU USE THEM, OKAY?
WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT YOUR ASS HERE.
I KNOW WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
MY ASS. THAT'S THE POINT. OW!
- Mad Dog:
COME ON,
TAKE IT LIKE A MAN.
- ( screams )
- WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
- ( beeping )
IT'S SMART,
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
YOU HEAR THAT, PUNCHY?
SHE SET YOU UP.
IT'S A GODDAMN HOMER.
-
BLAST IT!
HOW COME IT WON'T DROP?
- GET OVER THERE AND CHECK
THAT SHIT OUT.
- WHAT?
SOME SORT OF TRICK.
Computer voice:
5... 4... 3... 2...
( gang groaning )
( gasping )
THIS IS WHAT YOU WANT,
ISN'T IT?
HUH?
THIS IS THE SECRET.
THIS IS WHAT YOU NEED.
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
UNDER ARREST?
REALLY?
( groans )
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDER
OF ALYSSA LLOYD.
ALYSSA LLOYD?
WELL,
YOU LOOK LIKE SHIT.
ARE YOU A GHOST? HUH?
NO, NO, WAIT.
YOU CAN'T BE A GHOST
BECAUSE YOU'RE PACKING HEAT
AND WEARING KEVLAR.
YOU KNOW WHAT,
ALYSSA LLOYD?
YOU SHOULD HAVE KILLED ME
WHEN YOU HAD THE CHANCE.
- FUCK YOU!
- OUCH!
SHAME ON YOU.
SUCH LANGUAGE.
NOW, ALYSSA. I WANT YOU
TO TELL ME YOUR SECRET.
TELL ME HOW
IT WORKS.
AND ON MY WORD,
ON MY FUCKING WORD,
I'LL WASTE YOU FAST.
HUH?
YOU WANT TO
KNOW MY SECRET?
YES, I WANT TO
KNOW YOUR SECRET.
NO TRICKS.
JUST TELL ME
HOW IT'S DONE.
( groaning )
HERE'S MY SECRET.
( heartbeat pounding )
( pounding intensifies )
( screaming )
( groaning )
( music playing )
( sirens blaring,
helicopter blades whirring )
- JACK.
- YES, ALYSSA. I'M HERE.
I CAN BRING YOU BACK
OR I CAN LET YOU GO.
WHATEVER YOU DECIDE.
I'LL UNDERSTAND.
LET ME GO.
99th FLOOR.
JACK, THIS IS A PROUD
MOMENT FOR ALL OF US.
( music playing )
YOU SHOULD BE ENJOYING THIS.
YOU EARNED IT.
YOU KNOW, I WOULDN'T
BE HERE WITHOUT HER.
HM-MM. IT'S A PITY
SHE DIDN'T MAKE IT.
EXACTLY.
IT'S A PITY.
( mournful music playing )
( rock music playing )
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR ADVENTURE
IF YOU'VE GOT
NOTHIN' TO LOSE
THEN YOU GOT
TO PAY ATTENTION
YOU GOT TO
BREAK ALL THE RULES
SO IF YOU'RE
LOOKIN' FOR ADVENTURE
IF YOU GOT NOTHIN'
TO LOSE
THEN YOU'VE GOT
TO PAY ATTENTION
YOU'VE GOT TO BREAK
ALL THE RULES
COME WITH ME
WE'LL TAKE A TRIP
I'M GONNA LICK YOU
FROM LIP TO LIP
DEMOLITION
WE'RE DEMOLITION
I'M GONNA TAKE YOU
ON A WILD RIDE
I'M GONNA ROCK YOU
FROM SIDE TO SIDE
ROCK, ROCK,
ROCK, ROCK
ROCK, ROCK, ROCK...
DEMOLITION
DEMOLITION,
WE'RE GONNA ROCK YOU
WE'RE DEMOLITION,
WE GONNA ROCK YA
WE'RE DEMOLITION
WE'RE DEMOLITION.