Things in my life
wasted with strangers
I was bottled up in
disposal  containers...
take one down and
I'm drinking alone.
take my memories and
call them your  own
I'll give you
every detail
every embarrassing
secret
all for the
killer in the name of
entertainment and love
in the end you got
nothing to keep
always watching just
makes you feel cheap
so don't look away
and don't look back
hold it
together for...
decisions decisions
good luck with that
American dream
it used to be
the girl...
now it's
salvation in a day...
it's a way to give up
and say thanks
so don't look away
and don't look back
pull it
together for...
decisions decisions
good luck with that
American dream
Can I have
another helping?
[simultaneous chattering]
High school, noun,
A secondary school, especially,
in the United States,
Usually including
grades 9 through 12
And serving students from
about 14 to 18 years of age.
Typically, high school's offer
college preparatory classes
For advance students,
General education classes
for average students
And remedial courses
for those who are struggling.
Hey!
Hey.
[whispering]
[bell rings]
Good morning, everyone,
and welcome to high school.
Here's the syllabus.
Now, we're gonna take
about 15 minutes
And go through it,
So you don't have to worry about
asking any questions right now.
Okay.
Yes?
This says we have
to keep a diary.
Yes, a journal.
It is required.
It's 10 of your grade.
A journal about what?
About anything.
You can write about
the day you're having,
A conversation you had
with your mom or your sister,
Whatever you want.
And I'll only read the pages
that you want me to read.
If you write something
that's too personal
And you don't want me
to read it,
Just fold the page over and
write "please do not read this"
And I won't read it.
Let's get it started.
The first part of the syllabus
is called the requirements.
Now don't throw
your syllabus away
Because you need to refer to it
throughout the course, okay?
Thuman.
Venquist.
Winterpock.
Here, sir.
You have five minutes from
the bell to get ready, got it?
[whistles]
You've got football game
last night?
Yeah, dude.
How was school today?
Did you make
any new friends?
No, I didn't make
any friends...
Guess I wasn't cool enough.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
I'm the diet challenged kid
who sits in the front seat,
Probably bigger now
than I was this morning
Because your class
is right after lunch.
I wanna sit in the back,
So you don't have
to constantly hear,
"we can't see around Jimmy."
And I don't get teachers.
Why do you guys pile it
on the first day of school?
Can't you let us get use
to the idea that Summer
Is really over?
Three half pages a week
is tough.
Why don't you
just ask us to write
The great American novel
and say it's due in June?
New school sucked.
Except for leaving
Paul I'm glad we moved.
And then, I'm in high school,
Maybe things will
be different,
At least, I hope so.
I don't know anyone here
except for Nate.
Went to elementary school
together.
Didn't think
I'd ever see him again.
My sister,
she goes here ,too.
She's okay
with the new school.
She already knows
people here.
I did sit with
the blonde girl at lunch,
She seems nice.
And Robb, the quarterback,
he's in my PE class.
There's my half page.
I still don't know
why we have to do
This stupid journal.
[simultaneous chatters]
I ride the same bus as you.
Oh, yeah?
Where do you sit?
I sit in the back.
Well, I'm gonna get a dessert,
The cookies here
are the best.
Do you have to
be so noisy?
be so ugly?
Mom!
Be nice.
Have fun on the bus.
Are you sure Jimmy
can't ride with you?
Mom, there's only
so much room.
Besides, he takes up
two seats.
Jessica!
[simultaneous chatters]
[laughs]
You're in here?
Yeah, I was in
Smith's class.
I heard he's easy.
That's why I changed.
I have to sharpen
my pencil.
I have to keep
a sharp pencil for my notes.
We have to do our journal
in pen, though.
I hate using pen.
Journal?
Oh, we have to keep
this stupid journal.
Wasting trees, I say.
I like journals.
I can say what I really feel.
I like to write poems
and use big words.
I think I'm euphemistic.
Oh, I'm sorry.
[bell rings]
All right, everyone,
get out your homework.
This is Roger Presley reporting
from the intersection
Of brown and Madison,
the last known location
Of Kimberly Taylor,
a 17 year old from Hanover.
According to friends
and family,
She was on her way home
from band practice
Walking through
this neighborhood
When she
disappeared.
I was watching that.
Let's find her.
Who her?
The missing girl.
Then we could be famous.
You're kidding, right?
Are you kidding? It would
solve all of our problems.
It would get me
out of the house.
I've got enough stuff
to do already.
Think about it, dude.
Soon she'll have
turned up and we'll
have missed our Chance.
Paul and Jimmy,
teen dicks.
That means detectives.
I'm not stupid.
[music]
Right now I'm sitting in my room
writing my half page.
Today, Paul came over
to eat pizza and watched TV.
I still think this journal
is a waste of time.
I mean, who cares
about my boring life.
[bell rings]
[simultaneous chatters]
Hey, stupid!
Yeah, you!
Don't you know?
This is our spot.
I didn't know.
Hey, cutie!
Is this your locker room?
Look at that chest?
It's bigger than Whitney's.
[laughs]
So are you, like, a d-cup?
[whistles]
What's going on in here?
Nothing, coach,
Just chatting
with the new kid.
Well, hurry up,
get dressed.
Hey, guys, I
was thinking,
Maybe we should
change our mascot
To the big, round,
blueberries.
[laughs]
[music]
All right, everybody,
let's make sure
We've got our
homework out.
We're going to be
studying the chapter
On elements
and compounds,
Everybody needs
to know where we are.
Hey, Jimmy, did you do
your homework last night?
I need to make sure
I got mine right.
Well, hand it over.
I wanna make sure.
Yeah man?
Mr. Larson, does this
honestly look right to you?
Yeah, that looks fine.
You're doing great.
Okay, you're all set.
Winterpock?
What's the definition
of a compound?
Uh, compounds, um--
[stutters]
it's, uh, when...
Two elements combine.
[imitates Jimmy]
did you do your homework?
Yes, sir.
Where is it?
Did your dog eat it?
No, sir, it's, um,
I just don't have it
with me.
Well, when you get it back,
I don't want it.
You can keep it.
But, anyway, let's not forget
Monday, we've got a lab, okay?
Bring all your stuff--
I wasn't finished.
Winterpock! Turn around,
you knucklehead.
That's a detention.
I will see you after school.
All right. Let's go.
Let's go over the homework
For everybody that
actually brought
Theirs to school
with them.
I couldn't
rat her out, mom.
She copied your homework
and you protected her. Why?
I don't know.
She's my friend.
Well, you need better friends.
She's really cool.
She'd probably
just got home late
From cheerleading practice
or something.
Well, okay, I guess you
can't rat out your friends.
[music]
[laughs]
A dark cloud still hangs
over this community.
It's been one month since
Kimberly Taylor disappeared
And one week since her body
was found in the wooded area
20 Miles from here.
Hey, hon,
finished your homework?
Yeah.
The search in
the community
For young
Kimberly Taylor's killer
As the community
anxiously awaits...
I sure hope
they find her killer.
I can't imagine
how her mother feels.
...Twenty or even
thirty pounds?
If so then
we have a new
Product just
for you.
Introducing thermo-slim,
a revolutionary new
Weight loss
product guaranteed
To take inches off...
Come on.
All right.
Hi Jimmy,
I'm Dr. Jeffords.
It says here we're doing
your annual checkup.
Yeah, I guess.
Playing any sports
this year?
Um, no,
But I'm in the
jazz band.
See what I'm going to
do is check your lungs.
What I want you to do is
take in a deep breath for me.
Breathe in.
Breathe out.
In.
Out.
It sounds good there.
Jimmy, do you ever find
yourself getting winded
Or tired or
short of breath
For no reason?
Um, not really.
Maybe a little.
Really?
How are things at school?
Everything at school okay?
School's okay.
Well, you know, I guess things
could be a bit better.
Yeah? How's so?
Well, it's kinda hard
to make friends.
Yeah, school can be tough.
Jimmy, it says here
that you're 14.
Yes, sir.
You're 188 pounds.
Well, I guess,
I'm a bit overweight.
The kids in school,
Except for a few
and my teacher,
They say things,
Mean things.
Jimmy.
I was picked on
a lot when I was a kid.
The jocks and
the cool kids,
They were
always teasing me.
And I didn't know
how to deal with the pain.
And so, I'd eat.
I'd eat when I was happy,
I eat when I was sad,
Even when I
was bored.
And no matter what,
I was always left feeling
Empty.
Do you know
what I'm trying to say?
I'm sure you are a great kid.
Obesity is a fat kid.
Truth is if you don't
lose the weight,
It will never stop.
And believe me, that will be
the least of your troubles.
I promise you that.
Jimmy, what are you doing?
Jimmy, what is wrong?
Jimmy!
I'm sick of being fat
and everyone making fun of me!
I hate school.
I have no friends!
And I hate you for having
all this junk in the house.
I wanna lose weight!
Jimmy.
[music]
What?
You sure write a lot.
I have a lot to say,
don't you?
Sometimes.
But you always fold them down,
so Mrs. P can't read them.
So what's the point?
I read them.
Well, do you write
about guys?
Alright, everyone,
time to turn in your journals.
I wrote about how teachers
always give tests on Friday.
They think their class
is the only one.
We do?
[announcer]
attention, at the bell,
All students should report
to the gym for the pep rally.
[music]
Please don't read this page.
Last Friday when I was
sitting in the pep rally,
Might as well been
alone in my room.
Usually, at school,
I'm invisible,
Except when someone
wants to laugh at me.
Not then.
That's when I'm really
in spotlight.
And when they say
things about me,
The more I think that
what they say might be true...
That I am a loser,
That I don't matter.
And if I wasn't here,
no one would even notice.
Don't they know
that I'm a good person,
That I'd love to be
one of them?
To hear the cheers
because I'm on the team.
Because I'm popular.
They have everything,
but they make fun of me,
The fat kid.
All I can hear is Robb
talking about my chest.
Apparently, he comes
to school to play football
And to make my
life miserable.
When mom came in
to say good night,
I had to pretend
I was asleep,
So she wouldn't see
me crying.
[music]
[rock music playing]
Hey!
You need a jogging buddy?
Come on, let's go. Run!
don't you think
So you talked to her
once and you like her?
Right on!
Hey, you want some advice
from the master of love?
Yeah, but do you know
someone like that?
Hey, he's kicking
your butt right now.
You suck!
What does she look like?
Well, she has
a black sweater,
Black shirt,
black shoes--
What are you in love
with Darth Vader?
So is she, you know--
What?
You know, big, like you?
Actually, no.
She's actually thin.
Probably too thin, though.
That could be a problem.
Even for
the master of love.
[voice from pa] attention,
a reminder to all students--
Hey, Sable,
did you see the news?
About that girl?
That's where I used to live.
Maybe she just ran away,
Maybe she got
so sick of everyone
That she had to leave
or she knew--
Alright, um,
So are you going
to the game tonight?
Football's
for Neanderthals.
Yeah, but it's homecoming.
Allen will be there.
We could see
the freshman float.
Makes it even worse.
[cheers]
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
guess what?
Sable went with me and Allen
to the homecoming parade.
The theme
was "reach for the stars,"
But it should've been
"let's boo and terrorize
the freshman float."
I almost caught one
of those little footballs
That cheerleaders throw
into the crowd
And I met the mayor.
And even though Sable
doesn't really like football,
I still think
she's pretty cool.
[cheers]
You know, if you ever wanna
talk about being euphemistic,
I'm a good listener.
That's so sweet.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
today was pretty good.
Man, I'm so--
Did you see
the game last night?
Fingers hurt from playing
guitar hero.
I have a lot to say, but--
Mr. Larson is crazy.
Don't tell him that, though.
Please don't read this page.
Man, I tell you I wish
I was an only child.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
please don't read this page.
I feel alone.
I am alone.
I wish I could be invisible.
Does anyone care?
They have everything.
I am invisible.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
today was sunny.
What's the point
of playing the game
If there are cheat codes.
I don't ever understand Sable.
I have to study.
Today was hot.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
please don't read this page.
Am I the only one
who feels this way?
Please don't read this page.
Kids make fun of me.
School sucks.
Does it ever get better?
Those kids are hard--
Please don't read this page.
School sucks.
I don't feel like writing.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
I made an a.
It was cold.
I was up all-night studying.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
today was rainy.
Hey, Mrs. Pope--
[guitar playing]
Did you jog this morning?
I've lost 14 pounds.
Really?
That is great, Jimmy.
Alright. I have to head
to the airport.
I'll see you guys
in a few days, hmm?
This is gonna be fun.
Alright. And, yes,
this counts as a test grade.
Alright. And look,
you can work with a partner,
You can work by yourself
Or if you're schizophrenic,
you can do both.
Yes?
Are these traps new?
Yeah, most of them.
Some of them
might be leftover
From last year's
cafeteria catastrophe.
Oh!
I'm just kidding.
Alright. So anyway,
everybody gets a new mousetrap.
Alright.
Farthest car wins.
And you've got to be careful,
these things are dangerous.
Jimmy, can I be your partner?
No!
Oh!
[bell rings]
So how about
this weekend?
Friday night?
I'll think about it.
Hey, Jimmy, coach says he needs
a trainer for the team.
What do you say?
You wanna give it a shot?
Okay.
After school, you gotta
come down to the locker room
And meet some of the guys.
Why?
Uh, you got to talk to coach,
see what you have to do.
It won't take long.
Friday?
Maybe.
Watch this.
Okay, let's go.
Go!
Yeah! Whoo!
Go! Go!
[clapping and cheering]]
Whoo! Yeah!
That's right.
Man, that guy was crazy.
Yeah, and he's training
for the team.
Oh, no! I'm not doing that.
Come on, don't worry.
Open.
Open the door.
Please.
Open the door, please.
[crying]
Hello, Winterpock.
There's no one here.
Hang in there.
Maybe they'll
grow up one day.
I did.
You keep doing
what you're doing.
Don't think
I haven't noticed.
You'll be alright.
Come on.
Let's go.
How could you do that?
It was funny.
And Jimmy's okay with it.
How would you know?
When have you
ever been made fun of?
You didn't
have to do that.
Yes, I did.
And I will never go out
with a jerk like you!
I think I'm gonna
invite Sable to church.
Yeah, man,
I wanna check her out.
Okay, okay,
no checking.
So how's school?
Uh, you know,
not much different.
My teachers suck.
Someone told me you've got
suspended for a couple of days.
Who?
Well...
Well, what?
Did you get suspended.
Man, bet your mom freaked.
My mom?
She was so drunk
when the principal called
That she didn't even remember
by the time I got home.
I left every morning
And acted like
I was going to school.
Whoa! My mom would kill me.
Twice.
What you writing about?
Stuff.
School, nothing, really.
Why?
What time?
For what?
At church on Wednesday,
you asked me to go with you.
You can go?
We'll be reading this
for the next month.
Have the first chapter
read by Monday.
Where do you live?
We'll come by and get you.
[music]
Can you believe it,
she said she'll go.
Cool.
She can witness your utter
destruction in foosball
Whatever.
Anyways, um...
What--what's it like
to kiss a girl?
Hey, I read this.
Guess what they're
gonna call you?
I know.
I saw it on page 5.
Can't wait.
You know, I think my dad
might lose his job.
Oh, man.
Yeah.
Looks like I might have
to live with my uncle.
He's even a bigger
drunk than my dad.
The good news is
he lives close here.
Cool.
You know, they still haven't
found out who killed that girl.
I don't care
what they say.
It's not the boyfriend.
I say we get the killer.
What do you mean
"get?"
You know,
like lore him out.
Do you have any pictures
of your sister?
Oh, and about kissing Sable,
it's nice.
You should try it.
And now, Sable,
You have to watch me
kill Jimmy in foosball.
Foosball...
I will own you
at foosball.
[laughter]
Come on, Jimmy.
No.
I win.
He let you win.
Jimmy is nice like that,
but I'm not.
Move, loser.
Bring it on.
What happened
to your arms?
How did you get
all those cuts?
Hey, guys.
Are you all ready?
Hear you're going
with us. Yeah.
Warm enough in there?
[music]
Dear Mrs. Pope,
Life is hard.
Piggy.
Piggy! Piggy!
Piggy! Piggy...
Wait a minute.
I don't know about this.
How do you know
it'll work?
Everybody's on MySpace.
Besides, she's so hot,
or will be.
Photoshop is great.
Photoshop?
Yeah, man, she'll have
a huge rack, big lips,
Tough looking, sexy.
Oh, my God, I'm dead.
We're good.
We're smart.
Oh, and
what's her name?
Starr?
Dude, she look--
She looks like a hooker.
Kidnappers like hookers.
Look, if we don't get a bite
in a couple of weeks,
Then I'll take it off.
Couple of weeks?
Relax.
You worry too much.
[bell ringing]
[music]
No, I haven't
given up pizza.
I've been--
working out, right?
Who did this?
You've got to
answer to me.
my love's like
a boomerang
boom boom,
right at you
my love's like
a boomerang...
Holy... I'm...
They're all over school.
Who would do this?
You're so sweet.
I can't go back.
That's awful.
Great picture, though.
Mom, make him shut up.
Stop it, Jimmy!
I've got homework.
Hey, um--
I might have
to join the circus,
Or run away
or both.
Cool.
Can I go?
Dude, I'm gonna be grounded
'til I graduate.
Okay, okay.
Hey, guess what...
And somebody wrote
on Starrs MySpace.
They wanna meet her.
Wow.
When?
This Thursday.
Right here
at the grill.
Can you believe it?
[laughter]
[background chatter]
Next week, we'll be
starting my favorite play,
And we'll be acting
it out in class.
This play is so cool.
I empathize with
the character Juliet.
So we have our Juliet.
Any guys for Romeo?
Hey, Jimmy.
Jimmy.
Anyone?
No one volunteers,
I'm just gonna have
to pick someone.
Hey.
Um, can you go to church
with me again?
Ah, geez.
Don't do that.
Stop playing
with the camera.
Now, I can't see.
Gotta go run in the corner
and act like I don't know him.
Would you stop
being so jumpy.
You really are gonna
give us away.
Besides, the guy is looking
for a girl named Starr.
Is that you?
No, but--
And remember,
she has big, you know?
Uh, nothing.
Are you almost ready?
It's 5.
He's cautious,
just like us.
Not cautious, nervous
and hungry.
What kind of
a stakeout guy are you?
Not very good.
And don't say stake,
you know, I'm--
What kind of hat
does Todd going to wear?
A blue baseball hat.
Oh, man, that's Todd.
Ah, what's he doing here?
He lives here, remember?
Oh, my God.
Holy crap.
What's she doing here?
They're going
to ruin our plan.
The murderer will see Jessica
and think it's Starr.
What if he's starts talking
to her-- she's my sister.
She's safer than we are.
She's with a bunch of guys.
How long are we gonna be
in here?
Not long,
as soon as they leave.
Ahem.
Uh, taken.
[makes farting sound]
Oh!
Good luck, dude.
That burned.
Ow.
[makes farting sound]
They're just
sitting there.
It was a set up.
Oh, man.
We might never
get out of here.
Um, I didn't know
what time it was.
So with all those people
around you,
You couldn't ask?
It was your bike
outside the grill.
No, it wasn't mine.
We kept dinner warm
for an hour.
I'm calling Paul's dad.
No.
He'll get yelled at
big time.
You didn't know
what time it was?
I've got some homework
I need to do.
We're not finish here,
young man.
[knocking on door]
Hey pal.
How are the workouts going?
Okay.
Hey, can I go
to Paul's house tonight?
I thought you said Paul's family
was living with his uncle?
Well, yeah,
but they're cool with it.
I guess you've earned it.
Don't be up late.
We're going
to church tomorrow.
[video game noises]
I got it, dude,
you've got to let me play--
Hang on, I got one.
Great, then, grenade me.
You're getting Dusty--
how are you losers doing?
Are you watching
"American idol" reruns?
So, Jimmy, how's school?
It's okay.
Okay. I hope you're doing
better than Paul.
Hey, do me a favor.
I need a favor.
Could you try
to send some
Of your smarts
Paul's way.
Thanks.
Sorry.
Sometimes
he can be nice.
Hey, man, check this out.
No, man.
You know I don't do that.
Let's get out of here.
You mean like, like out?
Yeah, man.
Our parents are gonna be
sleeping in a minute.
My mom's not gonna wake up
'til tomorrow
And dad won't--
he's not gonna care.
I can't.
Fine. Then just sit here.
I'm going to a party
down the street.
Maybe I should just
call my dad.
We won't be gone
30 minutes.
I promise.
Come on.
You know some
of the folks there.
Jimmy, you're my
best friend. Come on.
I--
Hey, Sable might be there.
Alright, 30 minutes.
But I ain't smoking.
No smoking, 30 minutes.
I promise.
Dude, dude, I thought
you said no smoking.
I didn't know you meant
me too, whatever.
I don't know.
I do.
I hate it at my house.
I'm going to this party.
You know what, every second
I'm not at home is a good one.
Cool.
Look, you'll have fun.
It will help you
out with those guys.
You know,
you won't be Jimmy
That fat kid at
school anymore.
Come on.
Hey, man.
Hey, how is it going?
Come on in.
Wait, wait.
He's with me.
He's good.
what's up babe?
getting money like
it ain't no thang.
see me sliding
down the street
they say what's
up babe?
Who are you?
Um, I'm Paul's friend.
Great.
Who are you?
Jimmy--Winterpock.
He's busy.
can I get back
and reload
everybody
wants my...
but everybody
can't deal with...
ain't nobody
else come up...
got to smash up
like somebody
all the time
what's up babe?
Jimmy!
What are you doing here?
I never thought
I'd see you.
Um, I can't drink.
Hey, I thought your
mousetrap...
Look who's here,
piggy!
Is he hitting on you?
Are you bothering her?
No. We we're just--
we we're talking about school.
Hey, guys, Jimster was comparing
his boobs to Whitney.
He says his are bigger.
Oh, yeah?
I bet mine are.
Whitney! Whitney!
[cheers]
Your turn, piggy.
Piggy wins
biggest boobs.
[laughter]
Awesome!
ready to roll
I pull up on
the block
and you all
lose control
[crickets chirping]
What are you stupid?
How could you do
something like this?
[screaming and crying]
What did I tell you?
[screaming]
[punching sounds]
I hate you!
Hold a second, huh!
How can you be
so stupid?
Who do you think
I learned it from?
You,
my alcoholic parents!
I don't need you, I don't need
the police in my door.
Stop!
Let him go, you...
That's great.
Now you've got your
fat friend defending you.
Wow.
Lucky you.
Dad, don't.
[crying]
Did something happen
last night at Paul's?
Just his dad's such a jerk.
Uh, people are mean because
they don't like themselves.
[music]
Winterpock!
What's wrong with you?
I'm okay, just tired.
I didn't get much sleep
last weekend.
I volunteered you
for a project.
A new student
needs some help.
And since you're the best in
here, I didn't think you'd mind.
Who, sir?
I don't see anybody new.
How about this, Robb Thuman,
star quarterback.
Oh, no.
Alright, everybody,
turn to page 85.
Why wouldn't you
play Romeo?
I don't know.
Maybe because I hate getting up
in front of everybody.
That's why.
Why do you cut yourself?
Why do you think
I cut myself?
'cause I like it?
'cause I enjoy it?
I do 'cause I'm dying inside.
Does that answer your question?
You think you're the only one?
I went to a party
last weekend,
And everybody said
I had a bigger chest
Than most of
the girls there.
How do you think
that made me feel?
Now everybody in school
knows about it.
Don't talk to me
about your problems.
At least you're not fat.
You don't get it,
do you?
You think it's all about
the way you look?
Let me tell you something,
Jimmy Winterpock.
There are way worse things
than being fat!
Some of us have scars
that can't be healed
By running around
the block.
Grow up, Jimmy!
You think you're
the only one with problems?
Everyone's gonna forget
about that stupid party.
I thought you were cool.
That you got it.
Boy, was I stupid.
"the pile of guts
was a black blob of flies
That buzzed
like a saw.
After a while,
these flies found Simon.
Gorged, they alighted by his
runnels of sweat and drink.
They tickled under his nostrils
And played leapfrog
on his thighs.
They were black
and iridescent green
And without number;
And in front of Simon,
The Lord of Flies hung
on his stick and grinned.
At last, Simon gave up
and looked back.
Saw the white teeth
and dim eyes, the blood,
And his gaze was held
by that ancient,
Inescapable recognition."
and on and on the
road she goes
secret even
time don't know
and time and
time her paramour
will take his
weight in gold
Oh, no.
And nobody knows
where he is?
Okay, we will.
Who is it?
Jimmy, I've got some bad news.
Paul's dad is dead.
He committed suicide.
Oh, my God!
And Paul's gone?
Yeah.
Wh--where's Paul?
Nobody knows.
[music]
it's better to
be born lucky
It's okay if you
read this, Mrs. Pope.
My friend Paul is gone.
Nobody knows where he is.
He ran away after his dad died.
They never got along but I know
how much Paul wanted his dad
To love him.
He used to tell me
how they were gonna go
To a baseball game together.
But they never did.
Now, they never will.
There is a quote one day,
"nothing endures, not a tree
Not love, not death
or violence."
Now I know what it means.
And how it feels.
The world is different,
And I'm worried
about my friends.
There's nothing
I can do about it.
[knocks]
Hey, buddy.
How about we
go for a run?
It might make
you feel better.
I don't know.
Not right now.
Well, I'm here
if you want to.
Um--
Why don't you invite Sable
to church on Sunday?
... I left my heart
but a picture
of Jesus
that covers a crack
in the wall
Alright, look.
This doesn't change anything.
You get bragging
points and I get to pass
This stupid class.
Well, that's a good start.
Come on.
I don't want everybody knowing
I'm getting help from you.
Oh!
Uh!
Who am I kidding?
I'm not going to college.
Listen, we all have
something that's hard,
That we'd rather not deal with.
I don't need you
lecturing me.
I'll go home if I
want that.
Who are you to tell me
things are hard?
What?
We're not that different,
you and I.
And you need me.
You need to pass math.
Alright, then.
Let's go coach Winterpock.
Give me question 1.
We've got a call
from Paul's grandmother.
He's in Colorado.
Colorado?
Headed west probably.
Well, that's Paul.
He always said he would try
to get as far away as possible.
But there's been an accident.
Paul's been hurt.
We don't know how badly.
He was my best friend.
Hey.
He still is pal.
And I'm sure
you're still his, too.
And he's gonna need you more
than ever when he comes home
In a couple of weeks, okay?
Come here.
Let's go.
Hey, Robb.
What do you want?
Uh, how's it going?
Fat freshmen are not
allowed to talk to me.
How are things going
on with Robb?
Great.
He's getting better.
bring me down...
my girlfriend tried
to tell me...
she said boy you
better make a plan
...Cause I won't let
you bring me down
on and on and
on and on and on...
Failure is an inevitable
part of life.
It does not mean
that we are defeated forever
Or that we should give up.
Failure is a mystery,
And it is even divine.
It humbles us and it makes us
more compassionate to others.
It often is God's way of
leading us to our true selves
Or to a better position
in our lives.
How often have you
heard someone say,
"it's a good thing I didn't
get that job or promotion
Or scholarship or whatever?"
Some experiences that seem like
tragedies at the moment
Lead us to opportunities that we
would have not found otherwise.
Amen!
There is no way that
we can know and love God
Except through the discovery
of human intimacy and community.
We must open our souls
To the love
that humanity offers.
Everyday,
Every hour,
Every moment is sacred...
I heard about Paul?
And we must embrace life...
Where have you been?
As if it is both
fragile and strong.
I had to get better.
[preacher continues]
He will turn our failures
into success.
I know you tried
to be a good person
And people picked on you
because of how you look.
[preacher continues on]
You're the bravest person
I know, Jimmy Winterpock.
And we are all tested.
But how you respond
will define your life.
Giving up is easy.
Getting back up is hard.
(all) Amen!
For five months, the boyfriend
was the primary suspect.
However, recent evidence
has led police to arrest
Kimberly's councilor,
Jeffrey Hickman.
I know it was you.
What?
Starr.
I'm sorry.
I know.
Winterpock!
Hey, we've got a test
today in math.
Yeah, I know.
Can we go to the library
during homeroom?
With me, a fat freshman?
Yeah, with you, fat freshman.
Yeah, well, I don't think I
can be seen with a dumb jock.
I'm just kidding.
Oh, really?
Really.
Alright, I'll see you
in the library.
If I profane with my unworth--
Unworthiest hand
this holy shrine,
The gentle sin is this,
My lips, two blushing
pilgrims ready stand
To smooth that rough touch
with a tender kiss--
[laughs]
I quit.
These words are screwy.
Ryan, it's okay.
Just try it again.
I don't want to do it.
Alright, settle down.
Settle down.
Does anyone want
to play Romeo?
Alright, it's about time
to go, anyway.
You guys think about it.
You should do it.
Me?
Yeah, you. Romeo.
Some girls might
find you Romeo-mantic.
Is that even a word?
Are you?
Am I what?
Romantic?
Oh, fair Sable, you are cern'ly
grapes in Waldorf salad.
Uh, Mrs. Pope,
Jimmy would like to play Romeo.
O, then, dear saint,
Let lips do what hands do;
Okay, that's it for today.
Nice job.
Alright, for homework--
Finish reading act 1
and act 2,
And don't forget
your test in two weeks.
Hey, piggy!
[locker slams]
I saw your Juliet
tried to kiss you.
But you turned away.
[locker slams again]
What are you
afraid of girls?
You're not afraid of little
debbies are you, fat boy?
I'd love to kiss her for you.
Hey!
You leave him alone.
Go pick on someone else.
[locker slams]
Actually, next time I see you
bother anyone, you bother me.
Do you understand?
I said, do you understand?
Thanks.
Fat freshman or not,
you're my friend.
Are you alright?
Come on.
[breathing]
What?
Paul's grandmother called.
He's home.
Well, actually,
he's in the hospital.
Hospital?
My God.
Oh, that poor kid.
Can we go see him?
Tomorrow.
They said we should wait.
I'll take you over.
Are you gonna be alright?
I don't know what to say.
Well, just talk to him.
He's still Paul, just talk.
Talk like you always did.
You'll be fine.
Thanks, dad.
[music]
Hey.  You sleeping?
Well, what do you want?
It's me, Jimmy.
Hey, man,
what happened to you?
I almost didn't
recognize you.
Decided to lose some weight.
Sort of for survival.
Yeah.
I guess I lost
a little weight, too.
I heard.
I'm sorry.
I wish that didn't happen.
Yeah, I wish a lot of things.
Do you want to see my leg?
No.
So, how's Sable?
She's great.
Oh, look at this.
I knew it.
See.
I bet it was the councilor
who wrote us on MySpace.
You'll be a great detective.
Investigator Paul grove
here, ma'am.
I'm sorry about my dad.
I guess he just forgot
how to be a good person.
It's time for
therapy Paul.
Good timing, huh?
Glad you're back.
Sable's a cutie, man.
If you're not careful,
Someone's gonna steal
her away from you.
See you later.
[background
hospital chatter]
[music]
hold on
sweetheart
...It won't be long
before we get home
and just five
more minutes
I'm driving faster
than ever before
oh come on
sweetheart
[music]
hold on
sweetheart
You should have seen
your son at school today.
Jimmy?
Okay, okay.
I kissed Sable in school
in the cafeteria
In front of everybody,
is that so bad?
That's my boy.
[music]
So, what did the
coach want?
Oh, he was just talking to me
about how proud he was of me.
And not everybody gets
a Chance to go to college
And play football.
Is it a scholarship?
A full ride.
I passed.
I'm going to college.
Thank you.
It wasn't just me.
[sighs]
Still want that ride
to the hospital?
Yeah, that'd be great.
Hey, Mrs. Pope,
I can't believe this is my last
journal entry for the year.
I remember complaining about
writing in a journal.
Boy, was I wrong.
It helped me make it through
some tough days.
Writing my thoughts on paper
has made it easier for me
To say things to people.
Yesterday,
at church youth group,
I was asked to talked about
how I lost weight this year.
What I ended up
talking about was
How my whole world
has changed.
Looking back, this has been
an amazing year.
Not all of it has been good.
Actually, a lot of it wasn't.
There were times
when I almost lost hope
But I'm thankful
I have my church,
I have my friends
And I have my family.
In the end, I
realized it wasn't
Just about
losing weight.
It was about
figuring out who I am.
And I learned
how to figure that out myself.
When you're finished
with my journal,
I'd like to get it back.
My kids might get a kick
out of knowing their dad
Was a big fat kid.
Anyway, thanks for
everything, Mrs. Pope.
Sincerely your student,
Jimmy Winterpock.
I couldn't say what
was in my head
when you
said that I was...
it was still
so new...
supermagical...
I first tried to
walk over...
one two
three four...
still I didn't
know what to do
just hung around
...Told me you were
over it and I...
...Waiting for a moment to
come...
I feel so dumb
and tired...
that's how
Summer went...
---the end---