Where are you?
Can you come and get me?
Zahra dear...
Salt! Bread!
Zahra dear! Massoumeh dear!
We have to go.
Where's my husband?
Salt!
Bread! Salt!
To the director
of the Welfare Department.
We hereby inform you
that in Valiasr, Tehran,
on the road to Saveh,
at No. 10 Sajadi Avenue,
lives - or rather survives -
a family made up of a man,
a blind woman
and two 12-year-old girls.
The two girls
have never been out of the house.
Even their door is locked.
They cannot speak.
They haven't had a bath for years.
All the neighbors
are complaining about the situation,
but no one dares intervene.
So, we, the undersigned,
request you to take urgent action.
A film by Samira Makhmalbaf
Screenplay and editing:
Mohsen Makhmalbaf
THE APPLE
You've enough to live on.
But you lock up your children and leave!
lsn't that right?
lf you want to see your children,
l'll take you.
Your poor girls are innocent!
Madam,
do what you can
to let their mother see them.
All right.
First, let me see their mother.
- She says they'll hurt her children.
- l'll do what l can.
We don't hurt children.
Open the door.
The neighbors filed a complaint
with the Welfare Department,
so we took action.
You wouldn't let the neighbors
take the girls to the public baths.
They haven't been washed in ages.
Zahra, Massoumeh, come here.
Can we go in? You go first.
These children have no contact
with the outside world.
What?
- What's that?
- A glass.
What's in it?
What's your name?
What?
Massoumeh? How old are you?
Massoumeh, how old are you?
Mom... mo...
You want to see your mom?
What about you, Massoumeh?
Do you want to see mom?
- For God's sake...
- That's why we did it!
They must have a future,
a role in society.
They should get married.
l'll look after them at home.
The fact is, they're prisoners.
For years now,
they've been living like prisoners.
Even prisoners are allowed fresh air.
But they're not!
Their father locks them up all day.
Do you want to go to school?
A lot of children
with blind parents go to school.
Even orphans go to school.
How do they manage?
lt's Fate, it's destiny.
You're tired.
l'll bring you some water.
They say:
''lf the morning sun doesn't warm you,
the evening sun won't.''
Well done. Do the same shape.
Look how l do it.
Of course,
if they'd studied like other children,
both l and society would benefit.
But that's the way it is.
You didn't let them study.
lt's my fault,
l'm not saying it isn't.
Shall we go home?
Let's go see the children first.
Do you want to?
Do you want to see them?
Do you?
These girls are twins.
Should they be apart from their family?
We visited them on two occasions
and concluded
that in this case,
we had to remove them.
Do you want to take the children home
or stay with them?
Don't worry.
We'll take good care of the children.
Zahra, who's this?
Massoumeh, come here.
Go kiss her.
lt's Zahra. Are you Zahra?
Good girl, Zahra.
Why don't you come home?
Where's your headscarf?
We took it off to wash her hair
and clean her up.
We changed their clothes.
Zahra, come over here too.
Bring a scarf to cover her head.
Little bitches.
l'm not insulting anybody.
Bring a scarf,
so we can go home.
Give me my children!
l promise l'll wash them.
Do you promise?
Then l'll let you take them.
Why did you take off their scarves?
To wash and cut their hair.
Come on. Let's go.
Don't cry.
Come on, husband, let's go.
We clothed them.
Let's go home!
They're her children...
Zahra dear... Let's go home.
She's Massoumeh. That's Zahra.
Let's go home.
They said
not to lock the door anymore,
that they must be allowed out.
You can take the children home,
but you mustn't lock the door anymore.
We'll fix the refrigerator
so we can drink cold water.
We'll be just fine.
l'll take the children
to the public baths.
l'll pay to have them washed.
lf we do all that,
we can keep them.
We have to keep them clean,
or they'll be taken off us again.
Flowers.
Flowers!
Help me, husband, l'm scared.
You see, my girl,
l put the saucepan on the stove.
Forgive me...
lf l'm teaching you this...
There are four of us.
For me,
you take a full glass of rice.
You pour it in.
Do you understand?
For your mother,
you don't quite fill it.
For you, you half-fill it
and for Massoumeh, the same.
Look carefully!
Here's a full glass.
That's for me.
You pour it in.
Watch now!
When you get married,
you'll have to know how to cook.
Then, people won't say:
''Because of her blind mother,
she never learnt anything.''
So, you watch me!
God made woman
for her to marry.
What's that?
God made woman
for her to marry.
She mustn't remain alone.
l don't want people to say:
''Her mother was blind,
so she never learnt anything.''
lsn't that right, Zahra?
- l didn't want to come see you.
- Why?
Because you slandered me.
That's very serious.
l won't forgive you.
And nor will God.
What you said were lies...
...that l didn't let my daughters out,
that l chained them up!
That is slander.
The person who said that was wrong.
But everyone knows
that for eleven years,
you imprisoned your children
and didn't feed them properly.
Everyone says
you didn't look after your children.
l've been slandered.
ln the whole country, on TV,
in the press, it's all they talk about.
lsn't it good that the Welfare
Department looks after your daughters?
lt's good for all of you.
l wasn't the only one to take action.
Everyone's pointing me out.
But you did lock them up
for eleven years, didn't you?
l kept them at home,
l'm not saying l didn't.
l didn't send them to school.
But l didn't chain them up.
lt's slander.
Why am l being dishonored?
Being chained up
and being locked up at home
is the same thing!
People say: ''He was on TV
and in the papers.
He chained his kids up!''
But they were locked up.
The rest is unimportant.
No, it is important!
You dishonored me.
l didn't chain my kids up.
lt's all lies.
There's no difference
between chained up
and not seeing the sun for eleven years!
l'll pay you
to pray for my children.
No, even if you gave me a million,
l wouldn't take it.
l don't want your money.
l won't take it
because of all these lies.
Pray for my children.
l mean to say...
the newspapers wrote
that l chained up my children...
- Don't cry.
- Why would l have done that?
Their mother's blind. She locked
the door, so they wouldn't get out.
But why did you slander me?
l won't forgive you,
and nor will God.
l'm humiliated. l'm so angry.
ln this heat,
everyone's drinking water,
has a fan, or air conditioning.
But l don't. l have
enough worries. Don't add to them.
Neither God nor the Prophet
will forgive you.
l'll leave you the money. Goodbye.
Massoumeh, my dear,
Zahra, my dear...
One of you can wash the clothes,
the other can take the broom
and sweep the yard.
Otherwise the social worker
will say you haven't learnt anything,
that you haven't washed,
that you're dirty.
She'll take you back and keep you.
Go on, girls.
One of you wash the clothes
and the other clean the yard.
l'll make the meal.
Well done, girls.
See to the clothes.
Zahra, wash the clothes.
lce cream!
Delicious ice cream!
Come see!
lce cream!
Delicious ice cream!
l want...
Do you want one?
That one? Give me the money.
Which one do you want?
This one or that one?
10 tomans. Which do you want?
- Go get the money.
- l don't have any.
- 10 tomans.
- So you don't get an ice cream.
- Give it to me.
Give me the money.
10 tomans, 10 tomans.
l don't have any money.
10 tomans.
So, go away.
Go away if you don't have any.
Zahra dear!
Massoumeh!
Come eat!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Massoumeh, here you are.
Zahra dear, eat up.
l don't want any... l'm tired.
''O God, l am weary,
''weary of this life.
''l have had enough of this earthly life.
''Direct me to the gates of death
''O God
''Or free me
''from all my chains.
''ln the prison of misfortune
''l have been buried.
''Alas, l never understood
what l did wrong
''My God, l have never complained
about my solitude
''For it has always been my destiny...
Yes?
l came to see your neighbor.
He has shut his door and gone.
- Are you Mrs Farokh's son?
- Yes.
ls your mother home?
No.
How can l see the children?
- l'll bring you a ladder.
- Thank you.
Careful.
See what's going on over there.
The kids are locked up.
Let me climb up.
Hold my notebook.
Hello, children.
How are you, Zahra?
- Hello, madam, how are you?
- Why did you let them come back?
They must be educated outside
and by their family, too.
- You did the right thing.
- Thanks.
Their father locked them up and left.
- Can you open the door?
- Yes.
Thank you very much.
Hello, children. How are you?
What's that?
A spoon. Let's see.
You OK? What are you doing?
- Prisoner...
- Prisoner? Why?
- The door's locked.
- Locked?
- Where's your father?
- l don't know.
Why these spoons?
What?
To hit? What for?
l see. ls there anything you want?
Apple.
OK, next time l come.
This time, l brought something pretty
so you can see yourselves.
This is for you...
and that's for you, dear.
l also brought you a comb
to comb your lovely hair.
Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
Are you well?
Where were you?
l went shopping.
You promised not to lock
the children up anymore.
- l had to.
- You had to!
- Well, yes, ma'am.
- No, you didn't.
l look after the house
and l have to do the shopping.
Their mother can't go anywhere.
l can't leave my family to starve.
l have to buy bread and ice.
l bought some ice.
l have hot bread in one hand
and ice in the other.
What else could l do?
Leave the children in the yard.
Ask the neighbor
to keep an eye on them.
We talked about this. You promised.
Your girls are back home.
You should treat them better than this.
lf l don't lock the door,
boys climb over the wall.
Their ball falls in our yard,
they want it back,
so, they climb over the wall.
l can't let the girls play in the yard.
lf anyone touched them,
l'd be dishonored.
You could lock the front gate
and ask the neighbor
to keep an eye on them.
Oh, the neighbor! She doesn't care!
She knows
that my refrigerator is broken.
No one brings me any ice, even though
my refrigerator doesn't work.
l had to...
- You see...
- l'll take the key.
You should understand what it's like
to be cut off from people.
You'll see what it feels like.
We talked it over, but it did no good.
Go out, children. Go on.
Go play in the street
like the other children.
Go play outside like them.
Go on. Off you go.
That's enough.
You should go out by yourselves!
So...
we'll see how you like
being shut in!
They're so used to being locked up
that they come back.
Go back outside.
Go on, off you go.
Soghra!
Come here.
Look after the kids
before they get run over.
Let me go see them.
Son-of-a-bitch!
They'll get into trouble.
No insults now.
Why did you let them go outside?
lf you don't change your attitude,
l won't let them stay.
l'll take them away.
You let them go outside.
You heard what she said!
Zahra, Massoumeh, come here.
They won't come back!
l won't let them come back.
They've been set free.
She says you won't let them go free,
you lock them up...
and you don't let them out.
Soghra, l told you already.
l wanted to take you to see the doctor.
You should get out
and talk to your neighbors!
This is no life!
Ask for the key
so you can get the kids.
You're not dumb, ask her.
No, l won't give it to you
until you promise not to lock them up.
l won't open this door.
You'll stay here.
lf anything happens, too bad!
lt's better than their life in here.
Soghra... speak.
- l already asked her.
- No, l refuse!
You see...
l didn't lock them up,
they came back.
Even when l open the door
so they can get some air,
they lock themselves in.
You taught them to.
- No, it's them...
- You taught them to do it.
Their mother's blind,
she can't go anywhere.
That's just an excuse.
Go back outside, children.
l've had enough.
Go out and make some friends.
lce cream!
Delicious ice cream!
Come see!
lce cream!
- Want one?
- Yes.
- You have to pay.
- l ca...
Pay for the ice cream.
Now it's melted,
you want to give it back?
Come on, hurry up.
What do you want, kid?
Now the ice cream's melted,
you want to give it back?
- What do you want?
- She didn't pay.
- How much is it?
- 20 tomans.
She was locked up for 11 years.
Can't you leave her alone?
She won't pay me.
- How much did you say?
- 20 tomans.
Wait, l'll pay you.
- You were locked up for 11 years?
- Yes.
That's no reason
not to pay for your ice cream!
Here.
That's for her ice cream.
That's for her sister's
and that's for you.
Now, don't fight.
Here, this is for your sister.
l'll give you mine.
What's that for?
Thank you.
Here.
Drink some water. You must be tired.
lt's hot in the sun. Drink it.
l already fed the children.
l wasn't feeling too good,
so l didn't eat.
lf you like,
we can eat together now.
Please go ahead.
l told you...
l have to lock the door,
because the kids' ball
comes over the wall.
They ring the bell.
No one answers,
so they climb the wall.
l have to lock the door
for my girls' sake.
l don't know what l'd do
if anything happened to them.
- Throw us our ball, please.
- We're sorry.
We'll be careful.
Thank you.
The problem is that they're girls.
lf they'd been boys,
they'd go out with you.
They'd play outside.
And they'd even climb walls.
- Do you know ''Advice to Fathers''?
- No.
Know what it says about girls?
Here, read what it says about girls.
lt says: ''A girl is like a flower.
lf the sun shines on her,
she will fade.''
A man's gaze is like the sun
and a girl is like a flower.
lt's like putting cotton next to a fire:
it will be consumed.
Did you go to school?
lt was the old method.
l studied for four winters.
At which school?
lt was at a friend's house...
lt was the old method.
There wasn't school in those days.
What's your job?
l don't have one.
People give me money,
friends and others
give me rice and oil...
and in return, l pray
for God to forgive their sins.
Run. Try to catch it.
Catch it.
Jump and you'll get it.
Go on, jump.
You won't make it.
You can't do it.
Even if you jump higher
than a horse, you won't make it.
Jump.
Who wants an apple?
Wait a minute. l'm coming.
lf you want an apple, follow me!
- Hello.
- Hello, madam.
Do you have a saw?
l wanted to thank you
for bringing the kids back.
That's all right.
lt was my duty.
Do you have a saw?
- What kind?
- A hacksaw.
No, l have a wood saw.
Thanks anyway.
Hello, do you have a saw?
No.
Why are those children
back with their parents?
lt'll sort itself out.
Do you have a saw?
We go to the trouble
of getting them out and they come back.
No, l don't have a saw.
Thanks anyway.
Hello, madam.
Do you have a saw?
- Yes, what kind?
- A hacksaw.
Yes, l'll get it for you.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
What's up with those kids?
You take them, you bring them back...
Either keep them
or leave them to their parents!
lt'll be OK, madam.
Right. Thank you.
- Where are you?
- l'm here.
Come here a minute.
What is it?
Look, l have to go.
l have other children to see.
l'll give you this saw.
OK.
You may need to get out.
lt's locked, so here's the saw.
Either you saw through the bars
or you break the lock.
Saw through the bars?
But, madam...!
You have to do it yourself.
There'll be someone
from Welfare along to see you.
lf the door isn't open,
they'll take the children.
Do l really have to?
Yes.
l'm going.
lf you don't saw the bars,
we'll take your children away.
You bastard, don't saw those bars!
You'll destroy the place.
Madam, stop him!
You work for the authorities.
Don't let him do it.
Don't cut through them, husband.
All right, l'll let the children
play in the yard.
Don't, you son-of-a-bitch!
l won't lock the door anymore.
Don't saw them.
l'll only lock the door at night.
Don't saw through them.
Stop it! Stop it!
Sir, l want some apples.
You want some apples?
They're 200 tomans a kilo.
- Got any money?
- We don't have any money.
- You don't have any?
- No.
You have no money
and you want to buy apples?
Go ask your father for money.
Don't touch, kid. Go on.
Put them away.
Don't touch. Hands off!
Off you go.
Go ask their father for money.
lt's 200 tomans a kilo.
l told you not to touch.
200 tomans?
l'll ask their father for the money.
Don't cut through it.
You'll damage the lock.
lf you cut through it, we won't
be able to lock the door at night.
Don't cut it, you bastard.
Mon... Money.
They want some apples.
Zahra, Massoumeh, where were you?
l was worried.
Sir, give them some money.
They want some apples.
They take everything they see
from other kids.
Boy, l'm not so much of a miser
that l don't give them money.
One day, l gave them 1 toman each.
That evening,
Massoumeh couldn't eat anything.
She'd swallowed the coin.
She spent 24 hours in the hospital.
lt cost me a fortune
to get that 1 toman out.
Give her a bill,
she won't swallow that.
Here's 300 tomans.
l'm giving you 300 tomans.
100 for Massoumeh.
There's 100 tomans left for Zahra,
and 100 tomans for you.
l'm a prisoner here.
Keep an eye on them.
l'll take 100 tomans.
And l'll give you 200 tomans.
The social worker
wants them to do
the shopping themselves.
She's the cause of all our problems!
l'm off now, girls.
You go buy some apples.
No, that's not fair. lt's my turn!
Keep out of the way.
Move away.
Get away!
Let the poor things play too!
Sara, l think they're boys.
l think this one's a boy,
and the other's a girl.
Are you a boy or a girl?
Gi...
What?
You play with me, and you with her.
How's that?
Come here.
Come on.
Jump on the second square.
Not like that.
Like this.
lt's my turn.
Good.
Look, when you jump,
keep your legs apart.
Then, like this, and like this.
What's your name?
- What?
- Mass...
What?
You hitting me?
Sara, l don't want
to play with them anymore.
Sorry.
l forgive you.
OK, let's play.
Look how l do it.
How old are you?
Sara, let's not play with them.
Sara,
let's not play with them.
No, l don't want to.
You hit me,
then you give me an apple?
l wanted to teach you
how to play.
Eat it.
Thanks.
Thanks very much.
Girls!
Let's have a race
to see who can eat her apple first.
One, two, three!
Hurry up, you're last.
Massoumeh, hurry up.
l'm eating it slowly.
That way, l can savor it.
You're going to lose
if you eat it slowly.
Eat it quicker or you'll lose!
l'm going to win.
How do you know?
Don't be scared.
Massoumeh!
Come on the swings.
Do you want a watch?
Come on, let's go buy one.
We know a street seller
who has nice watches.
Do you want one
like my father's?
lt rings every Saturday morning,
every Sunday, Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday.
My father turns the alarm off
on a Friday so he can sleep.
Don't buy one like that,
because it rings
very early in the morning.
My friend, Roghieh,
always get full marks in dictation.
Once, l complained to the teacher
but she told me to be quiet.
My mother has a watch.
When she goes embroidering
at Mrs Pari's house,
she wears her watch.
lf l had enough money,
l'd buy the same one. lt's so pretty.
You buy the same one, OK?
lt's really pretty.
My watch is pretty, too.
Buy the same one.
The big hand's always on 4.
Sara's is no good.
The big hand's always on 8.
Don't buy that one.
So, which one do you want to buy?
One like that
or one like my mother's?
lt's so pretty!
You'd love it if you saw it.
lf l had enough money, l'd buy it.
The gate's open. Come in.
Hello.
May l?
Come in.
- Are you well?
- Fine. And you?
How are the girls?
Did you see their photo?
No.
Look.
Proceedings brought
against the father of the twins
Oh, woe is me!
We wanted to help you,
to save the children.
For the past 65 years,
nobody knew who l was,
nor where l lived.
The newspapers exaggerated.
They shouldn't have...
They dishonored me.
We're sorry for you.
We think of your children
like our children.
''How hard it is to put back together
the pieces of a broken mirror!''
lf only their mother wasn't blind...
l have to look after my daughters.
What else could l do?
We only wanted to help.
We wrote to Welfare
so they'd help your children.
You can see how they've changed.
They couldn't speak
or communicate before.
Now, they play with other children.
They say hello, and so on.
They buy ice cream.
Before, they didn't even know
what real food was!
lnstead of eating an ice cream,
they'd just throw it
in the gutter.
But l'm dishonored.
My family's in the paper.
Your daughters were unhappy.
l'm trying to cut through...
People say l chained my children up,
but it's not true.
Look, l'm sawing
through the bars of this door.
There's a street seller
who has nice watches.
There's one that sounds
like a train: ''Choo choo...''
Buy that one.
Massoumeh, buy that one!
They're really cheap.
You won't believe how cheap they are!
All right? You buy that one.
lt's just so cute.
- Will you buy it?
- Yes.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello, miss.
l want a watch
that goes ''Choo choo''.
l don't have any like that.
The other day, you had
a watch that went ''Choo choo''.
Just as you came,
a train went past, going ''Choo choo''
and you must have thought
it was the watch.
Massoumeh,
which one do you want then?
This one.
This one?
Come back with your father then.
OK.
We'll come back with your father.
- Hello.
- Hello, children.
They saw our watches
and they want one too.
We went to the watch seller,
and they chose one.
The man said
to come back with their father.
ls he their father
or their grandfather?
He's their father.
Sir, they want a watch.
You must buy them one.
Their father can't get out
until he saws through the bars.
For now, he's staying where he is.
Mrs Mohamadi,
please open this door.
l'm tired.
l'll finish it this evening.
l told you already: you must
saw through the bars to get out.
l won't open the door.
l'm tired, l can't go on now.
l'll do it this evening.
No, you must do it now.
l told you, l'll do it this evening.
l locked the door.
l won't go back on my decision.
l'll give them the key. lf they can
open the door, you can get out.
Let's see if Zahra can do it.
Can you open the door?
Go on, try. You can do it...
Well done.
Come buy us a watch.
Soghra! We're going out.
Me and the girls.
Look after the house.
The door's open.
Where are you going?
Zahra...
let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Zahra...
come and eat.
Zahra dear, let's go.
Zahra dear...
Where have you gone?
Zahra dear, Massoumeh dear...
Zahra, don't go.
Zahra, stay here.
Where have you gone?
Come back!
Help me, husband.
She said she'd take
my children off me.
l'm scared, husband.
Help me get my girls back.
Take them by the arm
and bring them back.
Zahra dear...
Come on.
Zahra, don't go.
Where have you got to?
Leave my chador alone.
Leave me alone.
Come here.
Don't let go of the children.
Come home.
Take the children by the arm.
Come back to me... Zahra!
Let's go back home.
Don't let go of them.
Bring them to me.
Director:
Samira MAKHMALBAF
Director of photography:
Ebrahim GHAFOURl
Assistant:
Mohamad AHMADl
Sound:
Behrouz SHAHAMAT
Screenplay and editing:
Mohsen MAKHMALBAF
Assistant Directors:
Marzieh MESHKlNl - Akbar MESHKlNl
Cast:
Massoumeh NADERl - Zahra NADERl
Ghorban-Ali NADERl
Azizeh MOHAMADl
Zahra SAGHRlSAZ
[ Skipped item nr. 754 ]
[ Skipped item nr. 755 ]
Subtitles:
J. Miller - S. Farsi
Subtitles processed by C.M.C. - Paris