A King Hu Film
THE VALIANT ONES
~ PAL ~ 102:19 min. ~
Many Chinese fishermen gathered
along the coastal areas.
Since the 13th century, Japanese ronin
gangs teamed up with local bandits
in the Pirate group.
Robbing and slaughtering everywhere.
In 16th century. National affairs were
disorganized. Administration lost control
Those pirate groups grew and grew
landing and wandering in Fujian and Zejiang
Wherever they passed by. They raped,
robbed and torched.
In the history book, it's
called Disaster of Ronin
The fiercest among them were:
Bodojin. Xudong and Caimen
The Government sent the army to annihilate
them many times. But always failed.
The defense project prepared by the King
Court to the Japanese Emperor failed
as some Chinese Officers and Japanese
Consulate took bribes from pirates.
It was impossible to get rid of all pirates.
Even the emperor got involved
in this matter.
The Ronin brought us so much trouble.
And the problem won't settle down.
Your Majesty. Vice Attorney General Zu Zhe
submitted a memo the day before yesterday.
Have you read it yet? If it looks ok
to you, then let him do it.
Zu Zhe. Step out.
Your servant Zu Zhe is here.
Zu. I'll assign you a position like
Governor of Zejiang, Military
Commander of Zejiang and Fujian.
Right. Governor of Zejiang. Military
After you get there, you must
annihilate all Ronins.
For our country. You must
do it fast and swift.
You can go now.
I'll obey your Command.
Governor of Zejiang.
It's been almost 2 months since I came here
and the pirates are behind over 30 cases!
General Zou.
You're in charge of military force.
Do you have any good ideas?
Governor. These pirates means nothing.
No use wasting our time
taking them serious.
only because we didn't
have a long-term plan.
Stop talking of these Ronins.
A chief of South native clan need to go
to Capital. Are you able to escort him?
I guarantee it in my name and title.
South native clan.
You lead guard and take the credit.
Thanks. Governor.
Annihilating pirates is not so easy. Only
the strong and wise will make it.
I heard Guard of Zhangzou,
Yu dayou. is good at strategy.
He is my friends child.
He's very good.
Governor. Please give me more time. I'll
deal with the pirates. No need for help.
But I need someone reliable who can
escort the chief of South Clan out safely.
Governor. Yu Dayou is self-important
and arrogant.
It's incorrect.
I decided
I'll inform the emperor. You send a document
to Zhangzou. And get Yu Dayou here.
He is here.
Sir.
General Yu.
How are you?
I want to go back to
the camp with you.
Don't you feel comfortable here?
It's boring.
Have you recalled all the guys like I asked?
Yes.
Sir.
Keep blowing your flute.
It may lure a pirate here.
I'm expecting them.
Change your cloth quickly.
Li. How are the states of thing around here?
Robbed!
How about you?
They have never been to my place.
There's nothing of value here. But
they're coming soon, the Ronins.
Why?
Because you're here,
I mean, how dare they rob soldiers?
No different.
In which direction do
they com from mostly?
No one knows where their base is?
Do you think there are
any spies in your village?
Not only in my village. But
also in the government.
Beware.
Wang, did you ever try water-fried shrimp?
Oil-fried shrimp.
Water-fried-shrimp is much delicious.
Excuse me.
Archers. Let's do some exercise.
General.
Li.
This is for you.
Go buy yourself a new fish net.
No need. You got rid of the pirates for
us. How can I accept your money?
It's our duty. Don't mention it.
I won't take it any way.
Then you buy a new net for me. Is it enough?
Enough!
Don't tell anyone about last night. Or
the pirates will never take the bait again.
I know.
Let's go.
Kejian.
You go set up a tent by the bay.
You go wait for them by the
shore with your guys.
Watch over there.
Hello. Guests. Please have rest here.
The bun and tea are just ready now.
Let's have lunch.
Hot tea.
Would you like some wine?
No bother of price while you drink.
Taste it first.
My friend. Your accent doesn't sound local.
You have good ears. I'm from Northeast.
Had to come to make a living here.
Where are you two from?
Taichang.
How about that gentleman? Where is he from?
Hi. Boss. Did you ever hear of
Tonglong Currency Exchange?
Everywhere in China, Tonglong has a branch.
That gentleman is our young boss.
Is this wine OK?
Very good. One more bottle
Boss.
Gui. Come and have a drink
I am sure you'll be here.
Right here waiting for you.
Tie them up.
The three of us are so stupid to insult you.
Really, you're stupid.
Please spare us
Shut up! You tried to pierce us before. We
must have a good talk with your boss.
We're blind. I didn't know
that you're an expert
We're not the same as you.
Tell us where you're from. We'll repay you.
Mount Flying Tiger. Camp Flying Tiger, I'm
Yellow Flying Tiger. You heard of me?
No?
Sorry. No.
Now I see.
Stop joking.
Are you making fun of us? You
won't have made this trip in vain.
We put 20 taels of silver
under that big stone.
Please take it as present.
Do us a favor
Wait!
It's negotiable.
We'll act like we never met you before.
Get the money first.
All right
20 taels only?
We're very poor.
You have a profitable location.
Until now, I have had no
business in half a month
I don't think so.
A pharmacy owner was robbed
by you a couple days ago
Including merchandise and currency.
He lost over 5000 taels.
How do you know?
Unless we make everything clear,
we won't do business here.
Such a great amount of money.
We've sent it to the base already.
Base?
In that case. You guys have a boss.
Poorly skilled men like us, how can
we rob on our own?
Then tell us who is your boss.
Bodojin. Xudong. And Caimen.
Don't joke.
My boss...
Retreat!
Run.
Get him
Three died.
Investigate him.
You and I will visit the commander
Yu Dayou's waiting for your order, Governor.
Take it easy.
I've been waiting for you for over a month.
Since I received your instructions, I did it
my way instantly. But I got distracted.
It's all right
Is this Tang the?
Tang is awaiting your order, Governor.
Take it easy.
Dayou. This is General Zou You both
should co-operate well from now on.
General.
I heard that you're a good talent.
You... please give me a hand.
I have a lot to learn from general.
This way. Please.
Guardian Yu.
Nice to meet you.
I heard Prosecutor Lin is good at
investigations. I might enlist you one day.
I'm flattered.
Anytime. I am glad to work with you.
It's too early to say
Dayou. Kejian. You listen.
The Creed says: Yu Dayou is assigned to
Special Commander of Defending Pirate.
Tang Kejian assigned to Duty Captain.
Both under command of Governor
of Zejiang. Zu Zhe
Dayou.
Could you let me know how
soon you can clear this area?
I can't tell you now.
At least. You must restore the transmitter.
It's useless with merely
the transmitter ready.
We must find the base of the pirates first
But Chief of South Clan, its urgent
that you go to the Capital
For his safety. He'd better
wait a few days
Captain Tang
What do you think?
Governor. The most important point is
we can't send an army after the pirates.
If we alarm them, it might mean
withdrawal. Then it's a real headache.
Dayou. Your opinion?
Kejian is right.
Governor please prohibit General
Zou for taking any ruthless actions
and keep my new assignment a secret.
Beware of spies.
My guys will disguise as business men.
And wait for the pirates on the shore
Hey. What's wrong?
I don't know. We're stuck here.
Don't worry. Let me see.
Looks like heat stroke.
I will get some water.
Who is your boss? Talk!
Don't beat him.
Brother. What scope is that?
Let me take a look
Captured two more.
Hand these two over to you.
Any information
He's mute.
Mute?
Wang.
Take off his shoes.
Japanese.
Ask him in Japanese
How?
Says nothing.
You didn't kill him, did you?
Mr. Wu don't allow me to torture him.
Mr. Wu is right. Only if toughness
doesn't work out.
Sir. I understand.
Boss. You are always nice but I'm afraid
good words wont lead us to their base.
Why not lead them to us?
I don't know how.
I have an idea
Wang.
Boss.
You see.
Wine.
Our boss is planning a big
business deal,
worth of 100.000 taels at least.
So much.
I don't know.
I tell you.
I heard those are treasures from abroad.
A pearl there is as big as a ducks egg.
This big?
Where will we get them?
You get them. Then I will escort
them to the Capital.
Return it to the government?
Yes.
How can someone chose us to escort?
Do you know if you're boss made
a deal with the government?
This business is not easy.
Why?
Traffic is blocked.
We won't take the regular road.
Which way?
White Tree Mud.
When will we leave?
Tomorrow morning.
We can make money out of it?
Of course.
Then you can return the 50 taels you owe me.
Why do you keep on mentioning it?
I don't mean too but it's
about your credit.
You're so narrow-minded. I have good credit.
How can you be so rude to your creditor?
Watch your mouth.
You need to be taught a lesson.
What do you want?
Shameless.
You hit me.
You hit me first.
Stop.
What are you doing?
He owes me money and then hits me.
You're not kids. Shame on you.
All right.
Wang.
You go to the city and receive
the merchandise with me
Dayou's plan sounds like a child's trick.
In battle, the trickier the better.
Dayou.
You think...
They will step into your trap?
Not 100% sure.
Then take the chance.
Can you escort him to the border?
It is urgent to get him to the Capital
Waiting a few days longer will be good idea.
We don't have to bother Dayou.
We can escort him.
Dayou. What do you think?
I'd figure out the pirate's plan
before General Zou.
I have my own schedule.
You worry too much.
Dayou. Anything else?
I need more hands in the delivery.
Here they come.
Sit down and relax.
Teach me Bare-hands Vs. Blade Skill.
Get a blade.
Once again.
You got it?
Keep practicing.
Mr. Wu. You're good.
Not much.
I guess those Japanese nips
won't come today.
They will for sure.
They're coming. Get the package ready.
Follow me.
Mr. Wu. Take a look.
Could you recognize who
is in that over there?
It's General Zou.
Too bad.
It's him. Go!
General. Why are you here?
I have come here to see you.
How can I be ambushed?
General you're important.
Why risk your life?
Being a general shouldn't
mean avoiding danger.
Don't you know? I let those pirates go
in purpose. But you messed up my plan...
Don't worry. I won't steal credit from you.
You missed the point.
Brother Wu. How is the situation?
I chased them. But when that
general arrived, things turned messy.
Shut up.
General.
Your subordinates are too much
Mr. Wu is a friend who came to help
us. Not to work in the government.
Identify him!
A normal person.
Open it.
Boss, take a look.
Just open it.
I guess they won't take the bait any more.
Boss. My trick will work for sure
The Japanese are cunning
Kejian
If you were one of them, what
would be your next move?
I'll hide for several days or longer,
until I get a clear image in my mind.
And you?
I'll immediately send some
assassins to the opposite leaders.
You're both right. We'll find
out tomorrow morning
What happened?
Don't waste time.
Go to the side of the bay
and approach them
Brother. You hide in the trees.
Wang. You come with me to the hills.
I bet those Japanese won't come out so soon.
Do you agree?
Commander said you're the
No. 1 swordsman in North.
Same in the South.
Your commander is kidding.
Uncle. Is "Wind Blow" your nickname?
That's not right?
They say your opponents always fall down
without seeing you pull your blade out.
You must be dreaming.
Uncle Wu. Please teach me.
I'm not greedy. Too beat
Japanese is what I want.
All right.
You promise?
Learn to control your breathing first.
Good. Breath control how?
When I say freeze, you must hold
your breath and freeze instantly
No matter what you see or hear,
you cannot move.
Well...
So...
Uncle...
Freeze.
It's ok now.
What a guy.
Am I studying this skill?
Take your time.
Look at the yellow big island over there.
Cliffs on 3 sides. The rest unknown.
It's not an island. Some parts are
connected to the Mainland.
Follow me.
Commander.
Li.
Take it easy.
What's wrong?
The Japanese robbed our village.
When?
Early this morning.
Wang. Summon the others.
Try and find some survivors.
Dayou.
Check this.
There are more over there.
Brother.
Commander.
What?
I remember. Lin visited here today.
Who?
Prosecutor Lin.
Lin?
Prosecutor Lin in the Government?
Right.
Then what happened?
After the pirates finished
robbing, Lin appeared
He whispered to the pirate leader. They
withdrew. No time for the treasure.
Did you look good?
No mistake. I looked from when
I was hiding in the tree.
Tell them to go back. I'll go to see
the Governor. You wait for me here.
Lin?
Damn it! He's left with General
Zou this morning.
Where are they going?
Escorting the Chief to the Capital.
Didn't I request a few more days delay?
The chief does not want to wait.
Zou said he guarantees his safety.
Which way were they going?
Probably the main road. I'll send
some people to arrest Lin right away.
Please don't. Wait till he
reaches the Pirates base.
He may escape.
He may not.
Sir. General Zou is in trouble.
Waiting to see you in the parlour.
Governor. I accept any punishment.
Stand up.
Prosecutor Lin. Where is chief?
He...
Sir. Let Lin arrange the funeral first.
Prosecutor Lin.
I'll write to the Emperor and
will take responsibility.
You can't get away of this either.
You're not on duty. From now on you
wait for my instructions.
Get back.
Who is this one?
He's my assistant Lin Tong.
Here is the highest classified place.
How can you bring your assistant here?
It's my fault. My feet were hurting
so it was inconvenient to walk.
Be careful next time.
Prosecutor Lin.
Where was your assistant this morning?
In his home.
Let me explain. I was supposed to
go with Prosecutor Lin
but I suddenly suffered a
bellyache. So I missed it.
I didn't ask you.
It's true. Just like what he said.
That's all. Thanks for answering.
Quick.
Kill him.
Hero. Don't get me wrong.
I am your friend.
Who is your friend?
Enh...
Either a pirate or bandit. Either
government or not. I have a lot of friends.
Just identify yourself and
I'll give you a share.
You're Prosecutor Lin's assistant
but I don't buy it.
My position in the Government is
a fake. Actively I work all over.
No more. This is ridiculous.
You go back and tell Prosecutor Lin. He
must show himself tomorrow morning.
Otherwise. I will put his
assistant on his trail.
Go quickly.
Stop
Tell Lin to come here alone.
Alone.
No tricks.
He won't.
Li's Temple.
Prosecutor Lin.
Who are you?
You have nothing to say?
Could you tell me your name?
Have you heard of "Wind Blow"?
"Wind Blow"? Are you from Northeast?
Good memory.
Yes. You're so very famous.
I was a famous thief there.
And you're an officer there too.
Just a small potato. Unworthy to mention it.
Could you please tell me your real name?
Wu Jiyuan.
Right! Wu Jiyuan. Now I remember.
All right. Brother Wu. How much do you want?
It's not about the money.
I see.
You should have heard about
the kind of person I am.
No matter who you are or where you're from.
Show me respect, then I'll be friendly.
You have many friends.
That's why I looked for you.
If you need my help in any way, please
don't hesitate to give a shout.
Could you introduce me to Bodojin?
Who?
Bodojin. The Japanese in
the Double Fish Island.
Brother Wu. Are you joking?
I am a prosecutor. Now you ask
me to bring you to pirates.
Do I look like I am joking?
If you do as I say, I will repay you.
Or I'll send Lin Tong on the trail.
Brother Wu. You're not pushing me too far.
Forget it.
Brother Wu. Even if you send him to
trail me, he may tell you nothing at all.
I am a prosecutor any way.
I will tell you something. I'm the
same as you. I am a double-spy.
I work for Yu Dayou.
Not such a high rank. But I can put
an order on the government
You have good prospects then.
Good but not profitable. Well, so long.
Wait. Wait a minute
I may help you to locate Bodojin.
You should hand Lin Tong to me first.
Don't play games. You must do this first.
In this case. Will you break
ties to Yu Dayou?
Bodojin accepts me. I will break ties.
All right. Let's make a deal.
Good. You wait here.
Master.
Take it back.
When will you bring me there?
Anytime.
The sooner the better
How about now?
Now?
Look
Prosecutor Lin.
Don't you want to see Bodojin?
This is his number one aid.
Lin. You're so dirty.
You know too much about me.
Get him.
Shoot him.
Prosecutor Lin.
Brother Wu.
No more surprises from now on.
How can I contact Bodojin?
West coastal. Lin Tong will lead you there.
Ok. You can leave now.
Here it is.
What a fine place.
Please
Wait a minute.
This way.
Please have a seat.
Please stand up.
Sit. Sit...
Please sit down.
He is the Island Owner.
How are you?
Mr. And Mrs. Wu. I heard
you two would join us
Owner.
I heard you two are really experts.
Some of us have learnt enough.
Played some kung fu before.
Could you please demonstrate
some kung fu in front of us?
Sorry I am shy to show off myself.
2nd Brother. Who do you think
should play with Mr. Wu?
Gu.
Right.
Mr. Wu. Please teach me.
OK. Don't take it serious.
Up to you.
Stop.
You sit down.
Right.
Why?
Your back.
Yu and brothers. You all need
to learn from Mr. Wu.
Mr. And Mrs. Wu. We brothers
like to learn from you.
It's unnecessary. I'll take you all.
Stop. Stop...
What are you doing?
Say thanks to Mr. Wu for his kindness.
Check your wrist.
You can't use your right hand now.
It'll be ok in a couple of days.
Get back
Mr. Wu's kung fu is so impressive.
I am flattered.
Monk. Would you like to
try Mr. Wu's archery skill?
Mr. Wu. Would you like to spar with me?
I'm not good. Maybe she could
learn something from you.
All right.
Madam. Please teach me.
My bow.
Please.
OK. I'll spar first.
How do you like it?
Wonderful.
You try.
I admire you.
Owner. I think...
Hold.
Brother. You might spar with
the blade with Mr. Wu.
Mr. Wu. Please teach me.
Learn from each other.
Please.
Don't take it too serious also.
Up to you.
Now I'll start.
Stop. Stop...
Mr. Wu's blade is invincible.
I am flattered.
Please excuse me.
I am lucky.
Please have a seat.
Your back was cut.
Mr. And Mrs. Wu.
After watching the match, I
think you're the ones we need.
Not yet.
I'll try him.
Mr. Wu. This Japanese friend
wants to learn from you.
Tell him it's unnecessary.
Mr. Wu says no.
Nonsense
Mr. Wu. Please play with him.
He's an expert of the blade. You be careful.
Don't worry.
You come here.
Don't be afraid. Take it.
Mr. Wu.
Go.
Mr. Wu. You're as great as I heard.
We can't afford losing you.
We're just a small group here.
Nevertheless. We have our rule.
Temporarily. You are a captain
under the 2nd Brother's command.
After you'll get some credentials,
you'll get a raise.
About the regulations here,
2nd Brother will tell you later.
Thank you, Island Owner.
Since I am here, position
doesn't matter much.
After all the sparring, I prefer
being a guest here.
I don't understand what you mean.
I am not ready to join you yet. Taking my
share in each business will be good.
But Mr. Wu. It's against our regulation.
What a pity. Good bye.
Wait.
Mr. Wu. Every visitor here
is not to come or leave. Only if it is his
wish. I sincerely invited you to join us.
2nd Brother. Persuade Mr. Wu for me please.
Mr. Wu.
Excuse us.
Hold on please.
Mr. Wu. The Island Owner never
takes his words back.
Same as I.
What is this?
Be quiet and sit down.
Open the door.
I am sorry. Please sit.
I am Bodojin.
It's my pleasure to meet you.
Your suggestion right before is acceptable.
I'll take it
By the way. Since you're to be with
us, your heart should be steady.
It will.
Good. You must provide a deposit.
No problem. Speak out.
I want Yu Dayou. Dead or alive.
How soon will your good news come?
In 3 days. Have someone sent for me.
Has he left?
Did you see it with your eyes?
Yes. All killed. None survived.
Did you see it well?
Good. Welcome him back tomorrow.
This guy is untrustworthy.
Let's set a trap for him.
Wait here.
Retreat.
Ambush.
They're coming.
Look at that.
Yu Dayou gathered all his force.
I think we should go back.
No.
They already know where we live.
We can't go back now.
Let's flee. Find another hiding place.
Wu knows we're here. We can't flee.
We should divide into three groups and
switch tactics when their backs are turned.
What is this trick called in Chinese?
Sneak Attack
Right.
Commander. I think we can't
stay here. How about...
Be patient.
Commander.
General.
Ridiculous. Never think of
a battle in this way.
I go to watch now.
Strange.
They're ambushed.
Let's retreat.
No. Go.
Charge.
Look.
Go.
Wait. Wait...
We fell in the trap.
Retreat.
We can't.
We must fight our way out.
Go and bring Bodojin here quickly.
Seems they're fleeing.
I will go and get Bodojin. This one I
leave to you. He is very good at kicking.
You should try your best to hold his ankle.
Shaotang.
Get back here.
Wang. Watch the arrow.
Brother.
Untie me quickly.
Bodojin run away now with the treasure.
When I got close, they
shot me with an arrow.
How can I
possibly board the secret port?
Shameless.
Xudong.
If you surrender now, I'll appeal
to Governor to spare you.
You would redeem yourself, if you
help us to capture Bodojin.
I'll recommend you a position in government.
What do you think?
Good. Tell me where he is now.
I am afraid it's too late.
Take cover.
Although in this victory, a gang of
pirates were annihilated.
Zejing Governor. Zu Zhe.
For unwilling to bribe his superior,
he Committed suicide.
Yu Dayou got demoted.
Nor was the Japanese pirates tamed
up till the end of the Ming dynasty.