I picked up a pistol.
Need to do something with it.
The present situation is
better than anytime.
Let's go see Nishikawa, after a long time.
To threaten or protect someone...
I'm sorry, sorry.
Even shoot to kill easily.
What happened? Let's go.
- What are you standing up to?
- Saying goodbye.
Listen to me.
After all, it looks stupid
just send me home
I have been consulted in various ways
because it's crying
I was a nice person, really
I encouraged you seriously?
Oh I'm sorry for you.
Always like a beast well sure.
No.
Nishikawa didn't want me to say beast.
Not what has just begun.
Longing for American culture.
From defeat to the present...
What's that.
Ae for Japanese...
Isn't it dangerous?
Possibility to do something with a handgun.
The joy of having a handgun.
That stimulation is important.
Long time no see.
Ah, such a long time.
Hey boring
shall we go to the dining room together?
No.. okay.
I really like this lecture.
Begins on September 3, 1945.
7 years throughout the occupation...
I'm hungry.
Hey.
No no no I'm not myself.
I emailed you last night
the story...
The cute one is for you
I'll do it.
So it's no good today.
Me recently I have no sex at all.
Seriously.
Don't go crazy.
nothing, it doesn't matter if I'm gone, right?
If you are always
did it do well?
Cheers! Whistle.
Excuse me.
Ah coming!
Akani! It's a crab!
It will be a crab platter
crab! Crab!
I am sorry.
Look at this, I like crabs.
- Hokkaido? Origin hokkaido?
- From Tokyo...
What what what? Stop it...
I'll definitely do it today.
Not pretty.
For me today it doesn't matter.
Good, good, good..
I'll do it I'll do it!
Let's go karaoke.
We go to karaoke next?
I understand.
Let's drink again in a little quiet place.
I'm not interested in this woman, but...
Thanks to the pistol
I was in a good mood.
No...
Did you wake up? Sorry.
The people who hated me doesn't bother me.
Wait a sec!
Let's do it because we only need one more time.
You want to do it again?
Speaking like this will get angry.
If you really want to do it.
Be quiet, wait for the coffee.
Yes please
I have a boyfriend
let's meet when we like each other.
That's fine, right?
Yes America and others support.
The Syrian Democratic army, which is mainly kurdish power,
fully surround the city...
Coffee beans Columbia supremo.
Next time come to play.
Yup the Syrian Democratic army.
It is estimated that there are 3000 people in lacka city
against islamic state combatants...
I'll eat this fruit every morning
because it's delicious to eat.
Arakawa, itabashi-ku, Tokyo.
The man is lying down
there is a 110 call.
The police officer who rushed
I found the body of a man.
Dawn last night
near arakawa in itabashi-ku, Tokyo.
The body of a man was discovered.
Men with guns
there is a mark that was shot in the head
5 days after death
seems to have passed.
Men seems to be in his 40s to mid 50s.
Identity not yet clear.
At the metropolitan police department
see this as shooting.
Including the whereabouts of guns that seem to be weapons
investigating.
Next is sports.
Marlin's ichiro is in the history of media
carved its name.
Ichiro goes to cubs...
Ichiro is amazing.
What's wrong? Something is blue.
What?
Why is your face
June 11 since the pirates
I got a chance to start ichiro.
Sorry, bathroom.
All right?
I spit a little.
Really?
Okay, sorry.
What...
Wait! Hey what!
I hate it!
Through the act of polishing a pistol.
A pistol and deeper communication
I thought I could get it.
Hello.
Mom? What's wrong?
Hmm?
What is that?
It's ok.
I'm sorry, I'm a little busy
yeah yes.
It was an empty room until yesterday.
Have you moved.
How easily you can kill your opponent.
Such human desires.
This silver color embodies.
Symbol of death.
Tanatos itself
I'm telling you to stop!
It hurts! It's a rush!
Sorry! Sorry!
You're saying it's sour!
Sorry!
Ah!
The voice of the last woman
I heard it next door.
You are? Hmm?
I did it.
How was it, tell me.
From now on
it seems to let me do it.
Are you going out?
Just do it
I had a friend and it was convenient.
Nishikawa is a terrible guy
Dangerous hmm?
Who has said that.
you're silly.
What the fucking shit.
Jabbe.
Now I have do a part-time.
It's like picking up in the next town.
Yes yes.
You're definitely back.
University is boring, isn't it?
I think I'll quit recently.
But it's only two years from now.
Why don't you skip it?
I don't really understand.
Yeah, it's subtle.
There is something interesting.
Hey you,
you don't really remember?
I'm sorry where did we meet?
Look, at the club for a year
there was a new party.
Then at that time, we come out together
I went to eat.
Remember? Ah.
Eh...
Yoshikawa..
Yoshikawa Yuko.
You has changed a lot,
that time your hair was short, right?
It might have been short.
There have been various things since then
I went to America homestay.
I recently returned to school again.
It was boring over there
this may be more.
Could I drink coffee too.
Where is the coffee?
Over there thank you
I want to do something fun.
What do you want to do.
Yeah I can't understand it myself
so thinking about you
Do you have sex?
Eh? No matter what.
So do you plan for that?
Can I get a cigarette?
When I first met you
I feel like it was fun
With a woman named Yoshiko Yuko
dare to take a long time.
Let's purposely become intimate
the idea came to me.
It hurts! Hahaha.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
What's wrong?
Aah, I'm a little drunk.
I'm just resting like this
are you alright?
But there's something strange around here, so
please go home early.
Dangerous? What happened?
Recently, the snatch case
it happens a lot.
It's aimed at young women,
snatched?
By the way, recently.
A warning sign you often see.
Well men have to be careful too.
As soon as possible.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Then
I'm sorry.
Something?
Maybe drugs
did you find it around here?
Eh?
That's why drugs are like that.
Found around here.
Excuse me.
Why do such things do you ask?
Recently, a police officer with a dog
you often see it.
Is there a drug dog?
In any such case
I wonder if there was.
Oh, but this is on investigation...
No, I don't know.
One of the drug groups came
a few days ago.
It is true that the metropolitan police department arrested..
oh dear.
Um... excuse me
why such a question?
Ah.
Graduation thesis
I'm doing deviance theory.
Such as drugs and suicide
data and preventive measures
I'm learning could be a little worried.
Graduation thesis is.
Are you in college? That's right
Professor
don't rely only on books.
Actually in the police and juvenile schools
we go visit.
What do you say.
So I asked around a little bit.
Excuse me, when I get drunk
because the number of people will increase a little.
I see.
I hope we can cooperate
I also have a job.
As soon as possible.
Thank you.
Thank you for your hard work.
If you have a handgun.
Would have been more nervous.
At that time
unbearable anxiety and fear
I was interested in stimulation.
From now on
let's carry a handgun.
Aim slim
to Allah and his apostles
I just declared my unbelief
the death penalty is imposed.
Islamic consensus.
Shooting a handgun
I often think about that.
Someday to shoot a pistol.
That's true.
Because this is a pistol.
Huh.
Yup there is something like that.
What are you thinking
I don't know
I don't really understand what it is
I'm the one who gets rid of the thoughts
that I hate.
Something great
I felt like saying.
That's not the case now.
It's weird to say
that kind of use.
That's a lie
you're making fun of many people
I hate it's good.
Give me a cigarette.
Because of you
it's become a habit again.
Nishikawa!
Let's go
I saw oh?
She's a good woman.
Eh, she? No way.
But I'm thinking..
so you haven't done it yet?
But that's good
as expected it looks good
I have a good body.
Did you fall in love? No way.
No...
Let's do that.
Let's go drink today.
- Tell us something.
- No, it's no good today
I will go shopping again ok.
Okay, not shopping.
Sometimes it's a sardine
sometimes it's always you.
Let's talk about women
Hello.
Hmm? Now university yeah.
Mother? What.
Keisuke.
My parents
neither are true parents
I was in the facility.
Eh?
Is it really critical?
Hmm? Are you surprised?
I like that expression
I like this kind of face.
Yeah.
Ah, dad it's been a while.
Yeah that's right.
Why dad?
I've been home since this time.
Ah yes.
No, I'll go.
You're dying and you want to meet?
Whichever is okay to be honest
I didn't go to see you
it's scary if you get a grudge.
Oh yeah.
It's a pinch this month
I wonder if you can send about 10,000 yen.
No, I made a lot of effort.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah I understand
I'll get in touch with you.
Mom seems to be crying,
making fun of me.
"I'm already old."
Ah, it's already a class.
Bye again.
Alright, from now on
I'll go with that girl.
Uh! Is that cute child?
No, it's the one I did last time.
Why are you there? You're in love that woman.
Because I have to do it just to be able to do it,
is it a loss?
Oh... well no.
But for that cute girl
I have to go unnoticed.
Oh yeah.
Bye.
You can't be serious.
Huh phone's okay?
Hello.
What's wrong with that scar?
Oh!
You smell!
It hurts! I hate it! Stop!
Let's do it!
What's your name! Ah!
4-34-1 takashimadaira, itabashi-ku.
Well... room 102.
This is not the first time.
In tomorrow I'll be there.
Uh... the apartment name
could you tell me?
Why are you crying
I hate it!
Ah!
What happened?
Now it's a station.
Let's meet.
Well then in the university? Yup.
Hey.
I'm sorry I'm not good today.
There's no reason why it happens sometimes.
But.
Can you be with someone I'm glad.
Because she wore jeans,
a little boring.
What about your boyfriend?
Are you listening?
Boyfriend? There's no one.
Isn't it? You're kidding?
It's not a lie.
Man is good for a while
I'm fed up, when I'm done.
Do you feel lost.
Feeling worn
I don't know for men.
Is it worn out.
Somehow I feel like I understand
I don't know.
So what happened?
If you don't want to say
you don't have to say.
No, nothing.
It's a common thing.
But it's common
can't you answer me?
Don't laugh.
Walk a while?
What about me?
What?
Nothing.
Something strange for me today
I'm sorry
I'm sure I apologize.
What?
But there are times like that.
When no matter what you think.
There is.
So don't worry.
Wait, wait no.
Hey, can you come to my room?
but it's messy.
Why?
Ah... It's too late.
It's close to my house.
Oh stop.
If I go to your room now
I can't stand it
I'm weak.
You're weak now.
I may use you for that.
But like other guys
I have no confidence
I want to take good care of you.
Well think about it.
After getting well.
You can always call me.
To see her smile
I was satisfied
Thanks dear.
Here?
I don't really understand.
Many things have come to mind.
But something made
me feel good today.
Maybe in this way.
From now on I might rely on you.
Thank you.
Yup.
See ya.
Good night good night.
Until now.
I never tried to grasp.
something like this
Make it easy...
Oh!
Thank you.
It's toru, nice to meet you.
There are many friends here, so let's go.
What is your school like?
I'm doing alright.
Your parents seem to be fine
thanks to you.
From now on
because your blood-connected father.
You'll be nervous too.
What is superfluous I thought.
Hear that you will come
I was relieved and happy.
But why do you want to see me?
I know your feelings.
Maybe death is in front of you.
for various reaons,
you might want to apologize.
Yeah I think so.
This is it.
Sakuma-San Sakuma-San.
Sakuma.
Your son came here.
Creepy, his eyes and nose are similar to me.
Are you Toru?
If I shake my head here
I thought it would be interesting.
Toru.
Forgive me.
Will you give me
I got an interesting idea
I don't care anymore.
So get well soon.
Ah, ah!
What!
Sit down
I'm not toru
I'm sorry.
How was it?
Didn't look too alike.
Thank you! Eh?
Sakuma-San?
Sakuma!
What the...
What.
Are you sleeping?
Yes.
Excuse me, it's police.
I'm sorry.
I have something to ask you.
Do you have time now?
What is it? Suddenly
it's like a drama.
you really show a badge or something.
It's not a big deal.
It's not a stray cat.
It's a terrible story
I want to know something.
Near your home it's a park there.
And then I don't know anything.
Well, I'm visiting and going around.
Well me too I have a cat.
Really a terrible person
I'm sorry.
That's what police mean
are you carrying investigation?
Yeah.
Well that I'm not investigating.
The problem is.
Out of the cat's body.
The bullet was found.
It's a bullet 357 Magnum bullet.
It's powerful.
Too much that in Japan
it's the type that hasn't been released
I mean, the guy who played the cat.
Had a pistol
does that mean? Right?
In this case, even if the police is strange,
isn't it strange? Hmm?
Is that so yeah.
It's tough
I have to catch it quickly.
White jacket
you don't have around the waist
I have after all.
I have been witnessed you.
Well that.
Well here to talk, well that's it.
You see your neighbors no?
Even if you put it in a little
is that okay?
No, that's a little... I'm sorry
I'm sorry it's messy
I'm a detective, ha ha
I won't steal anything.
A stranger um...
I don't want to put it inside
is this normal?
Nmm.
Is that so? Yes.
Well then
would you like to talk in a coffee shop near you?
You too,
I doubt you chould clear it up.
I'll be waiting.
At that time
I heard a sound like a gunshot
there is a person.
On that day
a young man in a white jacket
I saw running near here
some people say.
To your parents before
you tried to send a photo stand.
Is it a wedding anniversary or something?
It broke due to the negligence of the store.
When I heard that story
I was a little surprised.
You then.
If not angry
I'm sorry I don't have one.
Compensation for the amount of money
I heard you didn't receive it.
The clerk who witnessed and the clerk at that time
was the same clerk.
I remember well.
The day a cat was shot when?
Certainly recently around here
I ran back
I have to get back to my room soon.
What are you doing?
Up to that do I have to say?
Well for reference only
I kept her waiting in the room.
I made dinner and waited
are you right?
That thing is
I really don't care
I'm really worried there is.
Why you then.
With your right hand in your pocket
did you run?
I don't remember well, but my smartphone was about to fall...
You know the arakawa incident, right?
Eh?
It's a case where a man was killed.
You know
I saw it on TV yup.
With bullets coming out of the man's head.
The bullet that came out of the cat's body.
It was the same kind.
Please give me a favor.
Is it a murder this time?
Okay...
Drink coffee it's almost over.
Welcome
2 blends. Yes.
That badge
can you show me again?
Eh? Why?
No, I'm really a detective.
Here you go.
Excuse me. yes.
Something to write
can you lend me.
Ah yes.
Is this alright? Thank you.
Aida...For that reason
I can't think of being suspected.
Ok.
Let's get started.
Yup.
Actually I just lied to you.
Bullet from a cat
I don't sure if it was true.
It's also unknown if the cat was shot.
Eh? However.
The information that you heard a gunshot is sure.
Unfortunately cats
it's burned at the public health center.
From there
the bullet never came out.
Cats.
Clearly it seems that it was an artificial corpse.
Arakawa incident.
As a murder case involving gangsters
I'm investigating...
Me originally in charge of the case
I am a student
it doesn't matter at all.
Sorry I made you wait.
I'm digging that case.
From the beginning
I think that man is a suicide.
That corpse.
For being shot
it's too unnatural
One single shot to the right temple.
How to kill like that drama
there is no one who can do it.
It's not like shooting a gun.
It's originally an ugly scene.
Shooting messed up.
The person who was shot is off the key point.
Struggling struggling I'm dying.
As humans I was shot by a gun
I can't die right away.
By the time I die.
It takes a long time.
Yeah the man committed suicide.
And at the scene
I stopped by accident.
Ah maybe.
Someone who used to have a normal life
I took away the remaining handgun
I think so.
The guy who picked up the pistol.
That guy
I'll shoot the animals first
I was wondering.
Then I heard that I heard a gunshot.
The dead cat corpse
To be honest, I was a little excited.
While putting your right hand in your pocket.
Young man.
Even if the gift to the parents is broken
I didn't make one sad face
that man.
but smiling.
I was running with excitement
witness testimony.
Very interesting.
That is it, it's your guessing.
The resolution of the case
it all starts with guessing.
You need proof for that, right?
I have proof.
Then try saying that
your attitude.
There is no mistake
you have a pistol
I'm sure.
You and this case
I wanted to listen badly.
Really I want to hear your story.
When I first met you and said I'm police.
You're trying to hide your upset.
If there is no annoyance
you don't have to do that
and what a strange person.
When I shoot a cat
I'm sure it happened suddenly.
Still doing that.
You talk theoretically.
Even somewhere superficial.
It's just a lie.
But that's not proof.
You need proof, right?
Well there is no evidence.
From you.
Only evidence you are saying.
The criminal is.
Often the evidence
I want to hear it...
May I go back?
Not too persistent
I'll call the police.
How about another one?
Two blends.
Yes.
You.
Next time I want to shoot a human
don't you think.
Hah?
Humans come after cats.
Even if there are bullets left
maybe one or two more.
Get your pistol right now.
If you hate it
throw it away somewhere.
If you shoot, you will definitely get caught.
If you don't want to get caught.
Disassemble and put together with other junk
throw it away.
Then everything is over.
Killing people.
It may be strange, but.
Ordinary reason I can't say.
Like it.
My life will not be terrible.
You are young.
Sorry I made you wait
I will come again.
Thank you very much.
Ah.
You can understand what you say!
You said I would do it here!
Are you stupid!
You.
Next time I want to shoot a human
you're thinking.
Oh really? I really...
Humans come after cats.
Take care of yourself!
Fool!
It hurts..!
It doesn't hurt!
Already! Quit!
If you shoot, you will definitely get caught.
If you don't want to get caught.
Disassemble and put together with other junk
throw it away.
Throw it away somewhere.
Huh.
All right?
I've always liked it.
Eh? I can't stand it.
What are you saying?
What are you talking about?
Let's stop!
Huh.
Hey, stop it!
Quit! Oh!
Ow! Aa.
Why are you laughing.
Oh? What are you saying?
I'm not laughing.
Why are you laughing!
Huh.
Shoot people.
Pistols were built to shoot people.
Can kill people easily
it was built to be able to
I have it.
To shoot people
I think of it in my head.
Inevitable.
Then why with a pistol
shouldn't you shoot people?
Shouldn't you kill.
A person who can die.
Including me
overflowing in the world.
Conveniently here too.
Hey, let's go to another house.
Hahaha!
Are you coming?
I was coming!
Sorry! I was waiting!
Drink! Let's drink!
Who's the kid?
just a relative's child.
Then it's no good.
No, all right I sleep outside.
Look, sleep outside sorry.
Hahahaha...
The woman next door is in the supermarket
Tuesday or Thursday 8pm-9pm
I often went.
Do you want to try it on?
No I will just take it.
with handgun
I felt like I was alive.
What is it?
Is it cheating again? Good
I'm counting on you, daddy
only when this happens.
Ah dangerous
look ahead.
Wow!
Excuse me.
Is it alright?
Yes.
Hey what? So Sudden.
Wait inside.
Let's enter the room.
Stop.
Hey, stop it.
Hey you.
Stop it!
Are you out of your mind!
Hentai!
Ah.
Welcome.
What is it?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Who? Shinji no.
With Misato
I did everything for Denny's...
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Hey, really
I want you to tell me.
But don't go to college say dj.
Every Saturday seems to be.
Shinji's name
you can put it in for free.
Excuse me. yes.
One blend please
I have one blend.
You made fun of it, right? About me.
Don't play around
I feel like that.
Would you explain to me
I have to be clear that if
I'm the bad guy.
A good dj is on the way back from the event...
Hey, are you listening?
You should say something.
"I hate you"
"I didn't like that.."
It's not a big deal.
Hey Nishikawa.
Mr. Nishikawa!
Yes?
You seems to be strange.
I have no idea what you are thinking.
thank you very much.
From the beginning
I was interested.
You're fun.
Training of training.
You shouldn't train.
But what happened?
Don't you know
what I'm thinking?
I don't know.
I don't care about that.
What? I can't hear that.
That's why I don't care.
I don't care.
Of course you don't understand
I'm dead, you're dead.
My father died
someone there is dead.
Well I'm not dead yet
which is fine.
I don't care that.
No big deal anyway.
There's no such a thing.
Anyway, I...
Wahtever you like.
That's the case, then we
do something here.
For example.
This table this table...
Nishikawa thank you for the meal.
Thank you very much
Mr. Nishikawa!
Ah!
Ah.
Good evening, it's 7 o'clock.
I will tell you the news.
In ota ward, Tokyo
for a two month old daughter.
Use a baby bottle
if you killed them by giving them drugs
21-year-old mother was arrested.
Ito mika
before the incident on sns.
The child posted that it was annoying
despite being a real child.
With children etc. Who were entrusted from the facility
I explained it to my friends.
For interrogation the suspect.
In a baby bottle
I didn't put any tablets.
Denying the charges.
In short.
If you kill it.
That child too.
Crawfish scissors
will stop tearing.
In short.
If you kill it.
Like me.
will be able to
live a peaceful life
In short, kill it.
It's a big deal.
Not a big deal.
Kill people.
Really not a Bacca.
Hah, really.
Killing people.
It may be strange, but.
Ordinary reason I can't say.
Fuck!
Why!
I can't do it.
Why.
Uh.
I'm going to join today
will you come?
It looks pretty cute.
See you again
seriously stingy.
This may be the best so far.
May be the most cutey.
There is no point in living
I knew.
I decided to live till I die.
The big change is the realm of sex.
By the war with America
4 years American movies wasn't released
in Japan...
Nishikawa see you then.
Again.
Maybe.
Maybe we could.
You got a problem.
Inside me
there are similar ones...
Yes.
problems...
What is it.
It may be cured
it may not be cured.
Even if it doesn't heal.
I might be able to ease it.
But now I'm angry.
But I'll wait.
I have to do it
there was something that didn't happen.
This is the side
I couldn't leave it.
Soon, Tokaijin exit.
The exit is on the right.
Tokaijin here.
Please watch your step.
The door closes.
in Line 1 the door will close.
Please be careful.
So late, this guy!
Please answer the phone!
Ah? How many hours did you wait.
Eh?
Don't come in
I'm not going to enter.
Oh, I'm in trouble.
This is MA.
Tell me what.
Eh?
Hahahaha... you...
Hahahahaha.
It's annoying, so get off.
Pick it up.
Oh you.
What? This.
This toy.
Oh I understand.
Look, oh yes yes.
I'll kill you.
Haha kill me quickly.
I'll try.
This is different.
This is nothing.
Throw that gun away
You don't need that
You don't need it in your life.
What? It's funny.
Funny funny.
A little more.
Next is Hasama.
The next station is Hasama.
Soon.
Hasama.
Next is Hasama.
The exit is on the left.