This film is dedicated to prisoners of war.
Their unbroken spirit is the
symbol of a moral victory
for which no bells have pealed.
And which will
not be remembered
with the battle names on
regimental colors.
It was a war in which
no decorations could be given,
but to have come out of it
with a whole spirit
is its highest honor.
These are a few of those men
captured in the summer of 1 940.
They were the men who
stood on the Dial,
the Somme,
and the La Basi Canal,
who fought at Calais,
April, St. Valery,
and the vital perimeter around
the Beaches of Dunkirk,
the men who held on until the German armor
thundered past their lines.
220 miles they marched
into captivity,
through that blazing, gusty June,
through France, through Belgium,
through Holland,
to the Rhine.
Ahh...
Beer isn't what
it used to be.
I hope the French beer isn't what
it used to be, either.
Remember the last time, Ted?.
Yeah, I remember something
better than beer, too.
Ooh, she was
a smasher.
I can see her
hair now,
blacker than coal.
Ooh, boy!. She taught
me a thing or two.
Pity you kept it to yourself.
It's proud we should be married
to a couple of Don Juans.
Don't believe a girl
ever looked at him twice.
Poor old dear.
Yes, you looked twice, didn't you?.
You caught me off me guard.
I was low following the flu.
Wonder what made you marry me.
You don't know?.
That wicked tenor voice you have.
Leave them.
That's men tend to that.
Any more for any more?.
No, thank you.
It's nearly 1 2:00.
We've got to be at the depot at 700.
Come on home,...
we'll have 'em both back
before you can turn round.
War will be over
by Christmas.
by Christmas?.
Where have I heard
that before?.
It's a shame we got to
close the business.
Why, it's just habit
we've got into,
fighting the same war
every 20 years.
Nasty habit, too.
Good night, Flo.
Good night.
See you in the morning.
All right.
She's a troubled worrier,...
Shame she never had kids.
And her always wanting them so much.
They'd have took her mind off things.
Well, it's too late now, I suppose.
Are you sorry Glad and Mary are grown up?.
Well, I am and I'm not,
in a manner of speaking.
What about starting
all over again, old girl?.
No, thank you, Ted.
I'm too old for that kind of war work.
Ha ha ha!
Thanks, Stephen.
I liked that a lot.
The boy definitely shows promise.
Nearly 1 :00.
May I catch a lift?.
Yes, of course.
Come on, Carol.
Put your bonnet on.
Cheerio, Stephen.
See you before you embark.
Right-o, Robert.
Good-bye, Stephen, darling.
Take care of yourself.
Good night.
Well, wait for me.
Stephen.
Come on, Carol!
All right, Robert!
Caroline.
Caroline!
Stephen.
Caroline.
You left your scarf.
I know.
I had to come back.
Robert.
What about him?.
I wanted to tell you.
It's all over with Robert.
I think he understands.
I told him 3 weeks ago.
We met 3 weeks ago.
I wasn't sure until tonight.
Caroline.
You've only 48 hours
before you go to France.
It's nothing and it's everything.
Everything.
I hope you know how
to get a special license.
And don't forget to write, David.
Yes, Mum.
And let us know if there's
anything you want.
Thank you, Mrs. McDougall.
Will you write to me, Elspeth?.
David, I will.
You see, l--
Yes, David.
Good-bye, David.
Good-bye, David, my boy.
Good-bye, Mother.
Take care of yourself, David.
Yes, Mrs. McDougall.
Elspeth, you see, l--
Me too, David.
What did you say?.
I love you.
Elspeth. Elspeth,
will you marry me?.
Yes, David!
What's he talking about?.
Sorry.
I've no idea.
Can I be of any help?.
Do you speak German?.
Good.
He says the officers must be
separated from the men.
But we must keep the wounded with us.
We've only got one M.O.
among the lot of us.
He says they may stay with us
till we reach the camp.
Thank you.
Anyway, a lot of them will remain
automatically on the orderlies'...
That's right.
Well, come on, lads.
In we go.
How's tricks,...?.
Mustn't grumble, sir.
You'll feel better
with a...
Thank you, sir.
I don't know that you ought
to smoke with that chest.
Oh, it's nothing.
Wound's practically healed.
It's a pretty bad show all around.
I take it you fellows feel the same as I do.
We mustn't let the Jerries see we're down.
Take the Jerries to get me down?.
It's them ruddy cobbles.
What can I do for my feet, sir?.
Do what I do.
Try to forget 'em.
I can't take 'em off, can l?.
How are you, Lennox?.
Eyes hurting you a bit?.
A wee bit, sir.
We'll get the Jerries to give you
some proper treatment
As soon as we reach camp.
Thank you, sir.
How about you?.
Mustn't grumble.
You okay?.
Not too bad.
How's the arm?.
Feels better now,
sir.
Good boy.
All right, lads.
It won't be long now.
Then you'll be able to have a real rest.
Thanks for the help just now.
Useful man to know.
Perfect German.
Dalrymple's my name.
31 st Lancers.
Geoffrey Mitchell,
5th Oxfordshire light infantry.
Oh, where did the
Jerries pick you up?.
Oh, really?. I didn't know the 5th
were anywhere near there.
Yes.
March to attention!
Good afternoon.
Do sit down, would you?.
Thank you.
My name's Celia mitchell.
I've heard my husband may
be a prisoner of war--
Captain Geoffrey Mitchell.
Maybe. Didn't the war office
notify you, Mrs. Mitchell?.
Well, no, you see, I don't suppose
he put me down as next of kin.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Your husband's regiment?.
5th Oxford
light infantry.
General index. Give me particulars
of Captain Geoffrey Mitchell,
5th Oxfordshire
light infantry, will you?.
I'd like to send him parcels.
I suppose I can do that.
Oh, yes, certainly.
... flag 27.
Prisoner of war number 1376.
Thank you.
Hello, Mummy!
Hello, darling.
Have you had a lovely day
with Grandpa?.
Will Father ever come back to us,
Grandpa,
Even when the war's over?.
Well, would you be glad if he did?.
No. He used to make Mummy cry.
He is a prisoner.
Hello, Desmond.
Hello, Mummy.
Janet, I'll leave you in charge.
Well?.
He didn't put me down as next of kin.
Well, that seems to be the final gesture,
doesn't it, my dear?.
It was only logical, I suppose.
Poor Geoffrey.
Poor Geoffrey?.
Well, I for one don't intend to shed
any tears over him.
Father?.
I'm going to write to him.
You are?.
Yes.
Can't do any harm or good.
They must be glad
of any news of home.
I don't suppose poor Geoffrey
ever portrayed
the faintest interest in his home.
I can tell him how the children
are getting on.
I can see Geoffrey regaling
his fellow prisoners
with news of the children he's
scarcely ever seen.
You're afraid, aren't you, Father?.
Certainly. I'm afraid that you may let
yourself be carried away
by sentimentality and suggest
patching things up with him.
Don't worry.
We said so many hard,
cruel things to each other.
I'd like to wipe out
the memory of them.
And then if we should happen to meet
when the war's over,
it won't be as enemies.
Here. Go easy
with the soap.
Sorry, old boy.
We may make it last 2 days more
if we're very careful.
After that, we've got to make
do with godliness.
I say, Padre, what are you smoking?.
Sauerkraut?.
Fag ends, fag ends, fag ends.
Lucky fellow. I'm down to
Mr. Middleton's specials.
I hear there's a bush up by the...
That's not too bad in a pipe.
Had a marvelous
dream last night.
Anybody I know?.
Eggs and bacon.
Tomato ketchup this time.
We must have lost
a shocking lot of stuff.
There's nothing to stop 'em.
He's bound to invade
before the end of summer,
And that's the end of us.
Here, steady.
What about the home fleet?.
What about the Luftwaffe
waiting for the home fleet?.
Well, of all the damn defeated!
Well, if you prefer to be a ruddy halfwit.
What about the RAF?.
Hitler can't stage an invasion
until he's got control of the air,
and I don't see the boys handing
him that on a plate.
Hear, hear!
You can't judge Hitler
by ordinary standards.
If he thinks he'll invade,
he'll invade.
My old woman makes the kids pay a penny
a week for the Red Cross.
I'm writing to her to stop that caper.
Red ruddy Cross!
Bloody sausage we
ever get out of it!
It's only 2 months.
Don't forget, there were only a few
hundred prisoners here before.
Now there are tens of thousands.
It's a big job.
Yeah. Don't let's kid ourselves.
Nobody worries about us anymore.
We've been written off.
You're a pessimist.
How do you spell "sufficient"?.
Same as the Sergeant
Major's blessing,
Two "F"s and 1 "C".
Writing about the grub.
Muck, I call it.
Bit of the old woman's cooking,
is what I'd like now.
What a sucker I was
joining the ruddy army.
Pitching meself coming it loose with some
of those rowdy old French dames.
Here I am shut up in this place,
then I'll be past it.
You ought to have joined the Navy
and let the world see you.
Now, son, there's no use you blowing off.
Take things as you find them,
That's always been my motto.
The way I look at it is--
Look at you!
Drip, drip, drip.
You turn me up.
You're worse than a woman.
Knock it, sonny.
I was swinging a rifle
when your nappies was
swinging on the line.
Swinging a lead, more like it.
Here, if you're looking for a kip
on the ear, my lad,
you've come to
the right person.
Ohh!
That cigarette.
Let me see it.
What do you mean see it?.
Well, it's a Player's.
Where did you get it?.
Saved it up, of course.
What's it got to do with you?.
I had 3 Player's left.
You stole it!
Ah, go chase yourself.
Hand it over!
Pipe down, you little Welshman.
Give it back.
You did pinch that fag of young...
Yes, I did. So what?.
Just this.
Ooh!
Been asking for it, sonny.
I'm a man of peace, and peace is what
I'm gonna have plenty of in here.
Blimey. They'll have to have you
at the peace conference.
How are you today, Jessup?.
Mustn't grumble, sir.
Managed to get on his feet.
We'll soon get you out of here.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Morning, Lennox.
Oh, good morning, sir.
Got some good news for you, David.
Yes, Padre?.
Yes, my lad. You'll be rejoining
the rest of us tomorrow.
Oh, that's fine, sir.
And I'll be able to take this bandage off.
Not yet, I'm afraid.
You'll have to wait till the optic nerve
is completely healthy again.
Then they'll send you to the
eye hospital for an operation.
So you'll have to be
a very patient patient, my boy.
I'll do my best, sir.
That's right.
I'm sorry, mate.
I'll give you a packet of 20
when the Red Cross parcels come.
Losing my temper over a fag.
I shouldn't have left them roving about.
You know, you wouldn't be a bad lad,
if you got rid of
some of your nasty habits.
Don't knock it.
Leave all that reforming stuff to the padre.
What's your job in
Civvy Street?.
Only suckers work.
Oh, a "Y" boy, eh?.
You bet.
Me and Ted's
in the building business.
What about learning
the trade when we get home?.
I'll be home long
before you two mugs.
You got out of tougher
spots than this, eh?.
Sure.
Got a plan?.
Dozens of 'em.
For instance--
You know, I can't make up me mind
whether to turn this into a brigantine
or a schooner.
I wonder how Jane's
getting on these days?.
Who is Jane?.
Your girl?.
No, no, the Jane,
the strip in the "Mirror".
Oh, yes, the strip in the "Mirror".
Well, I suppose a highbrow like you
wouldn't read the "Daily Mirror."
Why highbrow?.
I mean, perfect German
and all that sort of thing.
Spent much time in Germany?.
Yes, as a matter of fact, I have.
Come to think of it, it's funny
that none of the rest
of your chaps
got caught with you.
Yes.
Did you have a company?.
Yes, machine gun company.
Machine gun company?.
You see--
I think I'll turn it up.
Wound's hurting a bit.
And all I have to do is stow away
in one of them garbage bins
Or something--why,
it's as easy as--
If you're planning
an escape, Mathews,
may I give you
a piece of advice?.
Individual escapes
hardly ever succeed.
These things have to
be very carefully planned
and coordinated by
a whole group.
All the same, sir, I'm
gonna have a go at it
If you have no objections.
Well, good luck to you.
Good luck.
Two-faced bleeder.
I don't know what it is,
but there's something
phony about that bloke.
Always sucking up
with the german m.O.
Like...
Or somebody.
Look, men.
That settles it.
But they do have machine gun
companies in the German army.
Do you seriously think
he's a traitor?.
He speaks German
as well as any German.
Of course he does.
Why shouldn't he be a German
planted here
as a stool pigeon?.
That would account
for a lot of things.
Yes, we're always
talking about home.
- He never does.
- I hate to believe it.
Come in.
May I report
something, sir?.
Go ahead.
Well, it's rather
confidential, sir.
It's about somebody
we think's a 5th colonist.
An officer?.
A matter of fact, sir, it is.
Captain Mitchell, sir.
There you are.
A minute ago, he overheard me
planning a breakout
and went straight over and talked
to one of the German guards.
Thank you, Mathews.
Keep your mouth shut
for the time being.
Very good, sir.
There's only one thing
to do with a rat.
String him up!
Here, wait a bit.
Man's innocent
till he's proved guilty.
Don't let us behave
like a bunch of nazis.
Come on.
Oh, Mitchell, you didn't destroy
your identity card, did you?.
No, why?.
Oh, just check up.
Have a look at it?.
Do you mind duplicating
your signature?.
You can't do it, you swine,
'cause your name isn't Mitchell!
Come on, what are we waiting for?.
Let's get it over with!
Stop it!
If you have anything to say,
you better say it quick.
It's a long story, and--
You wouldn't believe a word of it.
You're dead right,
we wouldn't!
Shut up!
Go on, spill it.
I'm not a German.
I'm a Czech.
A Czech in British
officer's uniform?.
That's bloody likely!
I'm in charge here.
Shut up, and that's an order!
Go on.
I escaped from
a German concentration camp.
I got through to France,
and I took this uniform
and the identity card
from Mitchell's dead body.
It was my only chance if
the Germans caught up with me.
If that's the truth,
why didn't you tell us at once?.
Would you have believed me
any more than you do now?.
Besides, I have more to fear
from the stool pigeons than you have.
You've no proof of your story.
None. How could I have?.
How do you come to speak such
perfect English and German?.
My father was at the Czech embassy
in London after the last war.
I spent my childhood there.
German is a sort of second
language in Czechoslovakia.
I became professor of English
at Prague University.
I'm not much of a soldier, I'm afraid.
What were you talking about
to that guard just now?.
Oh, I was trying to get
a chess set for David Lennox.
Achtung! Achtung!
All British prisoners
will parade at once.
You may get proof
of my story after all.
How?.
The civilian. His name's Forster.
- Gestapo.
- How do you know?.
For a time, he ran
the concentration camp I was in.
You think he'll recognize you?.
Well, if he does,
he'll do your job for you.
- Achtung! Achtung!
- Come on.
All British prisoners
will parade at once.
Stand your men at ease, please.
Stand at ease!
Gentlemen, I present to you
Herr Forster-- the foreign office.
Gentlemen...
For the time being,
all communications
between Germany and England
are at a standstill.
Your letters, therefore,
cannot leave this country.
To keep you informed, however,
our news bulletins will be
broadcast to you in English.
And as you cannot hope
to receive news from home,
arrangements have been
made for you
to broadcast messages
to your next of kin.
Will all those
who wish to avail themselves
of Herr Forster's offer,
take 3 paces forward!
You are the senior British officer?.
Yes.
Are your men afraid that this is
some sort of propaganda trick?.
Well, it's just possible.
As you wish.
Your name?.
- Mitchell.
- Mitchell?.
You are the officer acting
as hospital interpreter.
Yes.
I understand you speak
almost perfect German.
That's rather unusual
for an Englishman.
Is it?.
I wonder why your face
seems familiar.
I have many friends in England.
Possibly we met there.
Possibly.
Excuse me.
Yes?.
Do you wish to continue
this conversation?.
No.
Prisoners cannot be required
to answer any questions
other than those relating to
name, rank, and number.
Quite, quite.
The matter is of no importance.
This is today's
official war communique
Issued by the
German high command.
The battle of Britain has entered
upon a new and final stage.
Annihilation of England's towns and cities
by the all-conquering Luftwaffe.
Last night, just before sunset,
air-raid sirens sounded their
ominous wailing notes
To the 9 million inhabitants
of greater london.
All night, an endless stream
of bombers roared about the city
Discharging their loads
of high-explosive
and incendiary bombs.
Anti-aircraft opposition
was negligible,
For the British do not possess the guns to
defend their homeland.
And this attack will continue
tonight from dusk till dawn
until the nerve center and capital
city of the British empire
Is reduced to a vast pile
of rubble, dust, and ashes.
The words of our great battle
hymn have come true at last.
We march against England.
Come on, boys.
Let's give 'em our great battle hymn!
Roll out the barrel
We'll have a barrel of fun
We've got the blues on the run
ing, boom, terrara
Sing out a song
of good cheer
Now's the time
to roll the barrel
'Cause the gang's all here
Come on!
Roll out the barrel
We'll have a barrel of fun
We've got the blues
on the run
Zing, boom, terrara
Sing out a song
of good cheer
Mow's the time
to roll the barrel
'Cause the gang's all here
You should have come to see me
before this, Mrs. Evans.
Nothing wrong, is there?.
No, but you're not
exactly robust.
I had the flu last year,
but nothing since.
And you're over 40,
aren't you?.
Only just.
Well, we needn't make
any decision yet.
Decision?.
I may have to suggest
an operation.
I see.
Thank you, doctor.
I was at Finn's
the night before last.
Miracle none of us copped it.
The guvnor was just
standing around.
This one's on
the house, he said.
And it was.
Well, dear?.
Everything's all right.
Waste of time and money it was,
making me come and see the old doctor.
Your dad wants you
to make quite sure, you know.
Yes, of course.
I always felt
I'd failed him,
but never a word
of reproach.
There's kind he is,
all through.
But now,
now I won't fail him.
I know I won't.
Stephen wrote that for me.
My application's
been approved, Carol.
Staff job, west end...
I was going to ask you
for a photograph,
But perhaps I'm better without it.
Look, Robert,
Ever since Beryl's been
living here with me,
I've seen how crazy
she is about you.
Why don't you and she--
Beryl and I might have
made a go of it
if I hadn't met you first.
I'm sorry, Robert.
I did treat you shabbily.
No, you didn't.
I realize now
you were never more
than just fond of me.
You'd have realized it, too,
even if Stephen hadn't turned up.
I always will be
fond of you.
As long as you're happy.
That's what matters.
That's sweet of you.
My dear.
I'm sorry.
I'm not.
But it's got to be
good-bye, Robert.
Good-bye, Beryl.
Last Christmas,
I had my first concert.
It's there
I met Caroline.
Last christmas, I was in Dachau
concentration camp.
Christmas eve, a new batch
of prisoners came in.
One of them brought
me news of my family.
They'd been caught
giving food to a polish Jew.
They were taken out and shot.
My father, my mother.
All of them.
Only 36 shopping days
to Christmas.
Christmas. Parked around
a blazing fire
with a great bowl of hot rum punch.
Looks like it's snowing again.
That should raise
the temperature a bit.
What binds me is living
by courtesy of Jerry.
Can't see any future
in it, really.
They say the first
7 years are the hardest.
If the next 6 are
anything like this...
Well, the Red Cross parcels
are bound to arrive soon.
You've been saying that for
exactly 4 months.
I've been meaning it
for exactly 4 months.
All I can think
about is food.
Roast turkey,
mince pies, Christmas--
Oh, shut up!
Well, lad, it's me again.
Yes, padre.
David, they can't operate.
Not ever?.
No, David.
I won't ever see again?.
I don't believe it.
It's that German doctor.
When I get back
to Scotland--
No.
David, it's no use.
You've got to face it.
I'll not need this anymore.
You feel now there's
nothing left to live for,
And that feeling will
go on for a long time,
But then you'll begin
to remember the things that are left.
You'll begin to realize that this
darkness of yours is not absolute.
David, the things that make life
worthwhile for all of us--
Kindness, affection,
companionship--
The loss of your sight
can never argue those things, David.
We're your friends here.
We offer you our help
and understanding.
And waiting to
welcome you home
when all this is over,
are your own folk who love you.
I'll be all right.
18, 20, 21.
What's for tea?.
Fancy cakes.
Just fancy you've had 'em.
Good job we haven't got any
brass monkeys in here,
We'd have the RSPCA
down on us, and no error.
Can't you do anything
with this ruddy stove?.
Isn't there anything
else to burn?.
All right.
I never said a word, did l?.
Go on, burn the ruddy thing.
It's enough for a brew up.
They've come!
Hundreds and hundreds of 'em!
All right, I'll bite.
Hundreds of what?.
Red Cross parcels
with ruddy...
[all shouting]
The Red Cross parcels
are here!
Hooray!
Red Cross parcels
are here!
Hooray!
O come all ye faithful
Yoyful and triumphant
o come ye, o come ye
to Bethlehem
Come and behold him
Born the king of angels
O come let us adore him
Christ the lord
Sing choirs of angels...
O.C. Sports--you.
O.C. music--Stephen Harley.
Anything else
I haven't covered?.
No. Extraordinary, isn't it?.
We seem to have
specialists on every subject.
Aren't you an expert
on anything?.
Only racing, I'm afraid.
I had thought of starting a little
bookmaking business.
Why not?. Anyway,
your money will be safe.
You can't welsh on us.
Ha ha!
Ok, number 4 shift.
How far?.
About 3 feet.
Good. By the way,
doc, I put you down
O.C. Entertainment.
Fine.
What about me?.
I've had masses of experience backstage.
What sort of experience?.
No need to make low
insinuendos, old man.
Come on, fellows!
Here it is!
Mail from home!
Baker!
Here!
Macdonald!
My father's been thrown through
the dispensary window.
What, by an angry patient?.
No, a bomb.
Well, well, they've requisitioned
the church hall.
I say, that's serious.
What is?.
Veronica.
She sweats all night.
Well, surely she can
do something about it,
With all these
advertisements and things.
Don't be a halfwit.
Veronica's a filly
and is getting ready
for the flat.
Oh, sorry, old boy.
I thought she was a...
My kids have been
evacuated to the country.
And my girl
joined the land army.
Said she'll wait for me
till the cows come home.
That's one way of putting it.
Listen to this.
"Dear Daddy, today is your birthday.
"l hope it will be your last."
Hello, David.
I didn't notice.
Shall I read your letter for you?.
Thank you.
It's signed...Elspeth.
"Dearest David,
"Your mother says I am
silly to worry about it,
"but it seems queer
not a word from you yet.
"Do please send me a line
when you get this.
"The three of us had
a little party on your birthday.
"Wouldn't it be wonderful,
darling
"if you were home again
for your next?.
"l miss you all the time.
"Your loving Elspeth.
"P.S. I'm going to join
the Wrens."
Will you do me a favor?.
I'd like to answer it at once.
Yes, of course.
Here's a form.
I've got a pencil.
Ready when you are.
My dearest Elspeth,
I am dictating this
letter because my wound
Is not quite better yet.
I've been thinking things over.
And this is to ask
if you will release me
from our engagement.
I realize now I don't feel the way
I fancied I did about you,
So it's best to make
a definite break.
Yours, David.
David, why not
tell her the truth?.
It is the truth.
About your eyes, I mean.
Why not let her decide
when she knows?.
Will you please
send that letter?.
But David--
Please!
All right, David.
Ted, it's it!
It's it!
Wonderful news, man,
wonderful.
It's Delish.
There's a baby coming.
Good old Di!
I reckon that's
the best Christmas
present you ever had.
I can see her now,
the way she smiles with her eyes.
Aye, indeed.
It's lovely to--
How do I look
for a godfather?.
Why, yes!
That's it, man.
You and Flo.
It goes without saying.
And what's the matter?.
Got the same chit
from the income tax as me, old boy?.
Well, don't worry.
They can't put us in jag.
We've had it.
What wouldn't I give to see
Queen's Park play Rangers this year.
Never mind, padre.
They'll be playing over here one day.
Achtung! Achtung!
All British prisoners
will parade at once.
Hello! What's cooking?.
Forster's on the warpath. They're gonna
search the camp with a fine comb.
Forster again.
Achtung! Achtung!
All British prisoners
will parade at once.
Achtung! Achtung!
All British prisoners
will parade at once.
Gentlemen, we have
discovered your tunnel.
Since you have thus abused
the amenities accorded you,
and pending reconsideration
of the camp's security measures,
all these amenities will be removed
until further notice.
I've given instructions, therefore,
to confiscate all books, writing material,
music, all tables and chairs,
mirrors, knives,
and shaving equipment.
You may dismiss the...
Right. Dismissed.
I suppose I shall have to
grow a beard after all.
I don't know whether to have
one of those 2-pronged affairs
or a natty little imperial.
Wonder how long
they'll keep it up.
Not more than a month,
I should think.
Well, I'll keep on nagging
at the commandant.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Good afternoon.
I hope this slight setback won't
prevent you from trying again,
But I must add
a moat will be dug around
the whole perimeter,
which, as you know,
makes tunneling impossible.
Captain mitchell, who speaks
such excellent German...
What's he want this time?.
Wants to know why I haven't written
a single letter home.
Well, why should you?.
Mitchell may have had nobody
particular to write to.
But he had.
This came today.
It's from his wife.
You must answer it,
or she'll make enquiries.
You'll have to fake it.
Seems a pretty
cruel fraud.
You're wearing
a dead man's shoes.
You've got to get
used to the feel of them.
My handwriting. She'd know at once
it wasn't her husband.
Yes, take a bit of figuring out.
Alibi for using your left hand.
That's what you need.
I can't see much point in this,
Now the blighters
have taken away the football.
Well, anyway,
it's good exercise.
Think so?. I suppose next week
they'll give us back the football
and take away
the goalposts.
Come on, it's
your turn now.
Ready?.
Look out!
Good morning,
Mrs. Mitchell.
Thank you.
Oh, look.
I've mastered the boiler
and the tire pump.
I won't be defeated by
a miserable wireless set.
I've heard from Geoffrey.
Really?.
Is he well?.
I don't know what to make of it.
He seems so changed.
Good. Any change in Geoffrey
could only be for the better.
Well, the change
seems to include his handwriting.
Hurt his hand.
Using his left.
Listen to this.
"it is a world cut off
completely from the real world.
"Time stands still here.
"The future is remote.
The present empty.
"Even the past begins
to seem unreal.
"But a man must have
something to hold onto.
He must forge lengths
to keep him sane.
"Will you write
to me again, celia,
"as though I were
a stranger?.
"Somebody who knows nothing
of your life and your home.
"Even of yourself."
Changed?.
Why, he's even learned
to write grammatically.
Write to him as though
he were a stranger.
Robert!
Come back to be briefed.
Sort of a hush-hush job.
Thought you wouldn't mind
if I just called in this evening,
Say hail and farewell.
Of course not.
Come in.
You look ill, Carol.
I'm all right.
I ran into Beryl
in an odd sort of mood.
I gather she isn't
living with you any longer.
No. No, she left
soon after you went away.
Heard from Stephen yet?.
Oh, yes, I've heard
from Stephen.
What's he say?.
That our marriage
is all washed up.
What?.
He got a letter accusing me
of having an affair with you.
Carol, l-- but who?.
Beryl.
Ahh...
I see.
And he actually believed it?.
Yes.
I'll write back myself
and tell him the whole thing's
a deliberate, malicious lie.
What for?.
What for?. You don't want Stephen
to go on thinking this, do you?.
I don't care
what he thinks now.
Carol, you mustn't
take it like that.
Stephen's a prisoner of war.
If you were in his place,
would you pay two seconds' attention
to a poison pen letter?.
I don't know.
I'd never been
in love before.
I thought being in love meant that
you trusted each other completely.
All the things he said,
I believed every word.
Killed my love for him.
Caroline, my darling,
I can't bear to see you cry.
Don't forget to
drop us a line, dear,
if there's anything you want.
I've tried to get used to it,
Bu I still can't believe it.
We were so much in love.
Ah, it's a mystery to me.
He has a right to
change his mind, I suppose.
Could it be that he
doesn't think it's fair
to make Elspeth
wait on and on?.
Do you think it might
be that?.
No. I don't think
David's the kind
to make that sort of sacrifice
for that sort of reason.
Good-bye, my darling.
Good-bye.
The photograph I'm sending
makes me look
absurdly young,
but I'm no longer young.
The one of Janet,
that funny expression's
only shyness,
not a stomach ache.
I can see her now
through the window
telling her grandpapa
how to plant tomatoes.
I'm worried about her teeth.
Father thinks she should wear
one of those wire things.
And that hulking boy is Desmond.
9 years old yesterday.
The village is livelier
than it's ever been.
We have a large contingent
of evacuees
and a lot of other visitors
that come and go.
Everything's changed and yet
nothing's changed.
There's the whistle
of the 4:35.
Half an hour late as usual.
Mrs. Trusket still serves
her homemade toffee.
Where she manages to get
the sugar from, I can't imagine.
And there's still cricket
on Saturday afternoon.
Oh, what a kick in the pants
that turned out to be.
5 times more officers
than other ranks
and they have to knock
the stuffing out of us.
It was a mistake having Longarm too
close to the wire.
If he has to run back to take a catch,
- he's had it.
- Yeah.
Do you know what the
Jerries want for a new ball?.
- What?.
- 500 cigarettes.
Sheer blackmail.
Oh, I think it's worth it
if this marvelous weather
continues.
I wonder if they've been having
an early spring at home.
"The apple trees are in
full blossom already,
"making the orchard
look like a sheet of freezing snow.
"And 1 0-Acre Meadow
is all white, too.
"Because this year,
"that's where the ewes are
pastured with their lambs.
"Soon the garden will
be filled with the scent
"and color of the May.
"And beyond the river,
"you can see the first
vivid green of the larches
"and the bluebell wood."
- Ted?.
- Yeah?.
Remember that redhead
I told you about?.
Let's see, is that your
own true dream girl lovey pie
Or cheerio, toots?.
It's my steady.
She says the works manager's
fallen for her.
Says he s a key man.
Sounds like one of them
backdoor key men to me.
You and your pinup girls.
My pinup's Tessie O'Shea,
with a...
Yeah, but in my experience--
Your experience?.
God blarmy, one sniff
of a barmaid's apron,
and you'd be on your knees,
sonny boy.
That's all you know.
Teach you
a thing or two.
What's the matter, Ted?.
Bad news?.
Ted?.
Blimey, I never saw that one.
Hey, my old woman's
got on the buses.
Oh, you'll be walking the kids
when you get home.
If we get home.
It's a firm stand
I'm gonna take.
The rest of them
you can eat,
but not Lili Marleen.
She's got such
a trusting look in her eye.
Besides, next winter
I shall use her as a hot water bottle.
I've had a letter.
Amazing.
Perhaps there's one for me
With news
of the baby.
No letter for you.
There is news.
Flora's all right?.
Not Ann-Marie?.
She's okay.
Letter's from her.
"It's a baby girl.
She's doing nice.
Until its..."
You'll have it
sooner or later.
Seems that doctor warned
her about it being dangerous,
Because of her age.
She wouldn't be put off.
Flo was with her
at the end.
It was all over
quite quick.
Flo's gonna look
after the baby until you get back.
The play's the thing.
We're in our catch
the conscience of the king.
Well, what happens
in the end?.
Do they thump the
dirty old basket off?.
Well, there's a sort of
all-round massacre,
And Hamlet gets killed
himself.
That's gangster stuff.
The old boy certainly
knew his onion.
You wait till we get to
"Richard lll."
There's a murder
on practically every page.
You're getting pretty hot
at this business, David.
Oh, it's easy. But I'm still terrible
clumsy with my hands.
Oh, I don't know about that.
That tobacco pouch you made
was a smashing job.
I've got sort of used to it now.
And, well, you've all been so...
You get on with your reading.
I want to know
what happens next.
Right.
Celia, your letter has arrived
with the photographs.
They're in front of me
as I write.
You ask me to describe
our life here
so that you may picture it
in your imagination.
From where I sit,
I can hear the sound of a piano.
It is my friend Stephen Harley.
I wish you could hear
this music,
for it describes our life here
better than I could ever do
with words.
It tells of men emerging
from the twilight.
Turning their faces inward.
through wire.
Creating in miniature
a world of their own.
It tells of men who have
come to terms with the present
and find it far from empty.
Men who no longer lie down
to fate
but face it.
And find their own ways of beating it.
All this goes to make up
the picture of our life here,
made bearable only by
the letters and parcels
we receive from home.
They keep our bodies
and our faith alive.
And that is true not only of us
here in our little wired
enclosed cinder patch,
but also of the scores of
other camps throughout Germany.
Great sprawling towns
of 20,000 men
or hamlets of a few hundred,
each a little piece of England.
Months pass and my thoughts
are constantly of you, Celia.
Summer gives place to autumn,
autumn to winter.
Another Christmas
come and gone.
Another batch of prisoners
to swell our numbers.
They don't make the housing
problem any easier.
They bring us eagerly awaited
news of the outside world.
A little while ago there was
a rumor
that some of us
were to be repatriated.
I allowed myself to dream
that these letters of ours
could come to life.
I could see with my own eyes
your home, the children,
Yourself.
But the commission
never came.
Were we forgotten?.
Or was it just
one more reprisal?.
Being they are prisoners,
this practice must come to rest.
Orders.
Finally,
the recent operation...
As a reprisal for such
an unwarranted action,
All British prisoners of war
of cellblock 27
until further notice
remain manacled
from dawn until dusk.
Brigade dismissed.
Carry on.
Cigarette?.
Thanks.
It's easy.
Sardine key.
Turn to the right.
Turn to the left.
Bob's your uncle.
All part of the
Red Cross service.
Ha ha!
Our third winter
is approaching
bringing with it a new enemy.
It's not the duration
but the indefiniteness.
But if a man knew the length
of his sentence,
he could plan accordingly.
Afterwards in our memories,
we shall relive
only the sunny days
or pleasant scenes,
a freedom of mind
and the comradeship.
We shall forget the wet days,
the wet weeks.
Those days when it seemed
an effort to do nothing
and our bunks were
the only release.
Deep down in the hearts
of all of us,
there dwells a lonely ache,
a desperate yearning
for those we love
and a fear, fear of becoming
forgotten men.
Write to me
again soon, Celia.
You could never know
how great the comfort is
that your letters
bring to me.
They're more than comforting.
They give me strength
and hope and happiness.
You will never know how much
they mean to me.
Oh, my dear, I am so terribly
moved by the way you write.
Is it too late to recapture
the happiness or our best years together?.
I have no place
in your past or your future, Celia.
You must think of your husband
as dead.
This is good-bye.
I understand.
Don't be afraid.
I'll help you back.
I'll give you back
your strength,
the strength you've given to me
writing to me through these dark years.
I'll wait for you.
Fortresses.
They'll soon
be able to see the channel.
They'll be home
in time for tea.
That's exactly 157
pounds you owe me.
Cut you through the pack.
Double or quit.
Not on your life.
I've got me old age
to think of.
Blood sucker.
Oh, well, there goes
my gratuity.
Cheap enough
to pass the time.
Funny how much you learn about time
when you're killing it.
Such as what?.
I've got a theory that
everything that counts
Is done by busy people.
When you've got
too little time,
it's extraordinary
what you can do with it.
And when you've got
all the time in the world,
Iike us, you don't do
a damn thing.
That's it, doc, you're becoming
quite a philosopher in your old age.
Why not?. The war hasn't exactly
chosen us to be heroes.
I know exactly what
I'm going to do with my time right now.
I'm going to climb
into my bunk
and do absolutely
nothing till supper.
They're talking about
tiram for the derby this year.
It'll be the fourth
derby I've missed.
4 derbies. That's a hell
of a lot of time.
With nothing up
or down on the books to show for it.
Bloody leeks again
this year, Donny?.
I was thinking
of trying some asparagus.
Asparagus?.
That takes 7 years a crop.
Aye.
I don't give it more
than another year myself.
Another year?.
With it will be 4.
Flo's hair has gone
all white, she says.
Everything's changing.
Do you think we'll
be able to pick it up?.
The business
and everything?.
Search me. We're not
as young as we were, Donny.
No, Ted, we're not
as young as we were.
Surely they'll invade soon.
Yeah, that's what
you said last year.
And the year before.
What, it's the holiday list?.
Yeah, it's there
for all of us. 1 949.
I wrote that
for Caroline.
Somehow it expressed
what I felt when I first met her.
It was after a concert.
There weren't any taxis.
We walked back
across the park.
After a bit,
it began to rain.
So I carried her
on my shoulders.
You're still in love
with her, aren't you?.
I've tried to shut her
out of my thoughts completely.
But I can't.
I long for her all the time.
I'm a bigger fool
than you are.
Falling in love
with a photograph.
A dream.
And a home
in a strange land.
Achtung!
Oh, carry on.
Good afternoon,
gentlemen.
Oh, please,
do carry on.
Each time I visit
this camp,
I'm intrigued as
to where we met before.
But now I think
I know the answer.
Your name wasn't always
Geoffrey Mitchell.
Your identification
photograph is being sent
To Gestapo headquarters
in Berlin.
They have a large collection
of photographs there.
It will be interesting
to make comparisons.
I suppose it had to come.
They always catch up
with you in the end.
Repatriation, fellas!
Repatriation!
Great news, gentlemen,
great news! Repatriation!
And this time
it's the real McCoy.
The thing that makes me mouth water,
real live girls.
Hundreds of 'em,
all lining up waiting for me.
Bipeds, old boy, furnished with
two of practically everything!
A mixed German and Swiss
medical commission
will examine all those whose
names are down for repatriation.
Apparently it's a rush job,
so anybody who gets his ticket
will leave in a week's time.
So you've got a chance.
Yes.
But we must have positive evidence
to justify repatriation.
Of course.
Ah. Anything else,
Corporal?.
Well, sir,
every time I breathe,
I can feel me liver
knocking up against me kidneys.
Come here.
Cough, please.
Cough?. Blimey, do you want me
to bring up my appendix?.
Yah.
You have passed.
Thank you, sir.
Matthews.
I wonder if you'll
get through.
Hello, Evans.
You'll soon be seeing your youngster.
Yes, indeed.
I'm sorry to
hear about you
And Captain Grayson, sir.
Oh, well, the flat racing
season's over.
Do you know that Swiss fellow
actually had the nerve
to congratulate me
on my fitness.
Ha ha! Well?.
- I got my ticket, all right.
- Fine.
You have passed.
Suits me, sir.
Captain Mitchell.
Ah.
You need not strip,
Captain Mitchell.
I regret your case
is deferred
until the next board
in 6 months' time.
Morris.
And once it's discovered
he's not Mitchell,
he's sunk.
They'll have no mercy.
We've got to
do something for him.
Yes, but what?.
Excuse me, sir.
Can we put up a scheme to you?.
Sure. Sit down.
What's it all about?.
We know the spot
Captain Mitchell's in.
We thought we'd fix up a stunt
to get him out of here.
What's the scheme?.
Well, sir, there's
a list of bloke for repatriation
In the commandant's office.
We thought if
we could get hold of it,
alter the names...
Stage a break-in, sir.
Hear, hear, hold on.
We aren't professional burglars.
Well, yes, sir,
as a matter of fact,
well, I was.
Were you really?.
Well, how awfully interesting.
Commandant's office--
only one wire to cut.
Yes, but what about
the perimeter lights?.
They always put them out
when there's an air raid.
And they've been as
regular as clockwork lately.
Gosh, I believe
we've got something.
Suppose we do
get the list. What then?.
I can type.
Scratch out one of
the names beginning with M
and type Mitchell's
on instead.
Just a minute.
Don't you see,
the chap whose name goes off
has to stay behind.
Well, uh, my name
begins with M, sir.
You'd really give up
your ticket home?.
Why not?.
But I thought
all the girls were lining up
for you to come home?.
Well, so they are.
But they'll wait.
You are a sportsman.
Gentleman,
we'll have a snack.
Now, as I see it,
the drill is this...
My eyes are clear,
I cannot see
I have not brought my--
Here come the boys.
Bang on the dot.
What do you mean?.
Well, just another raid,
old boy.
All right, chaps,
lights out and sing out.
Well, they had
better start.
I know. God bless
the R.A. F.
Here he is.
Good boy.
Look out!
All clear.
That's the lock
you've got to pick.
Good, there's a typewriter.
Get down!
Type on the floor.
It's tougher than I thought.
Let me try.
Must be a bit out of practice.
I'll say.
Good, this is it.
Sing, you so-and-sos, sing!
- That'll do.
- Come on.
That'll fool 'em.
Let's split up and get back
to our own huts.
Ok, sir.
What's going on?.
You're not supposed
to know.
The boys were out there
putting your name
on the repatriation list.
Darn.
You will all remain here
until the other huts have been checked!
Permission to go home, sir?.
Yes, provided you put
a... for me.
It's you that ought
to be going home.
Oh, don't you believe it.
I'm a social parasite.
The sort we're fighting
to get rid of.
That's right.
I've got to stay here
and exterminate him.
Ha ha.
Go slow with the...
Don't forget
to save a couple of
peach-fed blondes
for your Uncle Jim.
That's a promise.
Oh, I was kidding.
You're one of those
one-woman blokes, aren't you?.
Yes, that's my trouble.
Sorry, then.
Always putting my foot in it.
Don't forget to tell the girls round
Hammersmith Way
that I'll be home
soon and I've got
plenty saved up
to give them a treat with.
Yeah, you bet.
I'm gonna keep
my job warm for you.
Horsfall, Evans,
and Mathews.
Unlimited.
Hello, Mathews.
Feeling all right?.
Yes, it's all right, sir.
I was a sissy
passing out like that.
I can never thank you
for what you've done.
Well, forget it. Just keep your head
down on the parade
And pop your uncle.
- Thanks.
- Don't worry, sir.
You'll get through all right.
We'll be right
behind you, sir.
One other thing.
What about the German M.O.?.
He's certain
to be on parade,
and he's more likely
than anyone
To remember that
Mitchell's name wasn't on the list.
I know.
I've thought of that.
I'm going to start up
a conversation with him
while they're
calling the names.
He only speaks
about a dozen words in English.
You leave it to me.
Hello, David, my boy.
Good-bye
and good luck.
Good-bye, sir,
and thank you all.
See you again before
you know where you are.
- Yes.
- Come on, David.
Don't forget.
We've got a bridge date tonight.
Don't forget the cigarettes
you owe me, padre.
Play you a double
at quits tonight, jim.
Ambrose.
Anderson.
Burns.
There are a lot of
things I'd like to say, but--
But I can't.
Go on.
Off you go.
Good-bye.
Good luck.
- So long, old boy.
- Good luck.
Keep out of
the German M.O.'s eyeline.
Grant.
Hanley.
Hunt.
Horsfall.
Jackson.
Jessop.
How soon do you think
the war will end now, doctor?.
6 months or one year
if you're light.
By then, you'll be
speaking fluent English.
You think I've made
good progression?.
Oh, terrific.
Ha ha.
Yes, you Germans
certainly have
the gift for languages.
You think so.
Of course.
Yes. Ha ha.
After the war,
they make me
headmaster of
Oxford University.
Mitchell.
Miter.
Acton. Ashe.
For the gang's all here
I'm sorry, madam,
but you can't go in.
I must.
It's my husband.
Please.
Excuse me.
What's happened to
the iron gate, Mother?.
It went for salvage
2 years ago.
I'll miss the squeaking
of that old gate.
Have there been
any other changes?.
No. I kept your room
exactly as it was
the day you went off
to France.
Same old smell.
Sunlight, soap,
and furniture polish.
You come in here
for a minute
and I'll get you
something to eat.
David.
Elspeth.
That last letter.
Your mother showed me.
Telling the truth
about your eyes.
So that was the reason.
The reason for what?.
For breaking
our engagement.
But you can't go on
being engaged
when you're not
in love any longer.
You can't go on breaking
a person's heart
to satisfy your own
stupid pride.
I'm not prepared
to discuss the matter.
Neither am l.
David...
Why did you have to make me
so dreadfully unhappy?.
Caroline.
But--but what are you--
There were some things
I left behind.
Caretaker let me in.
I had no idea.
I'll go now.
Caroline.
Yes, Stephen?.
Are you all right?.
Why are you crying?.
Because I'm a fool.
Are you unhappy
with Robert?.
I'm not with Robert.
Oh, Stephen.
Why did you have to
believe that idiot?.
It wasn't true?.
No. Not then.
Go on.
When I got your letter,
it was as if
all I'd ever believed in
didn't exist anymore.
I didn't care
what happened.
He was in love
with you?.
Yes.
And you?.
No.
Let me go now.
Please.
Listen, Caroline.
There, everything
seemed so--
so out of proportion.
I think I was mad
for a bit.
You see, I loved you
so desperately.
Still do.
Always shall.
Stephen.
Thanks, mate.
Thanks.
Well, this is it, Don.
Yes.
How do you feel?.
Empty.
Empty inside.
Me, too, like it wasn't me
standing here at all.
Come on, Don.
Let's get weaving.
Hello, old girl.
Hello, Ted.
Doing you all right?.
I'm seasick.
Stomach always was
your weakness.
Suits you.
Oh, Ted.
There, there.
I can't leave don out
in the cold like that.
Oh, don.
Hello, flo.
Oh, it's lovely
to see you.
Come on in.
- Where is she?.
- In here.
Hello, Gwyneth.
Hello.
Do you know who I am?.
Yes. You're my
Daddy, aren't you?.
That's it.
Look.
I made this in
the prison camp for you.
Can she shut her eyes?.
No, she can't.
My doll can.
She's lovely.
So that's settled.
Captain Hasek
reports to duty
to Czech headquarters.
There was something
I wanted to ask, sir.
About Mrs. Mitchell.
Oh, yes.
Very awkward, of course.
Don't worry, Captain Hasek.
We've got that
matter in hand.
I wanted
to suggest, sir,
as it's my responsibility,
that if the notification
of her husband's death
could be delayed until I've seen
Mrs. Mitchell myself.
She'll have to be told through
the usual channels, you know.
Yes, sir, but in
a case like this, it's--
War office will
look after it.
Or if you like,
go down and see her yourself.
There's nothing
to stop you.
I see.
Thank you, sir.
Looks like rain.
My dear.
It's no good going on hoping.
You must face up to it.
That he won't come back?.
That he won't come back.
Grandpa. It's
starting to rain.
Come help me put the chairs
in the summer house.
Oh, come on.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I was expecting someone else.
Mrs. Mitchell,
I came to see you.
I have some news for you,
of your husband.
Oh.
Come in, please.
What?.
Your husband is dead.
Dead?.
He was killed 4 years ago
in the fighting at Saint-Ardennie.
I heard from him.
From the prison camp.
Your husband was never
in that prison camp.
He was never
a prisoner of war.
But--the letters.
I wrote those letters.
You?.
Yes.
But l--
I took these from
your husband's body.
I took his name,
his uniform, his identity.
For 4 years, I've been
Geoffrey Mitchell.
But why?.
To save my life.
The Germans
were after me.
The letters?.
Later in the camp,
I had to write.
They suspected me.
If I hadn't answered
your letters,
they'd have been
on to me.
You had to answer
my letters.
I understand that.
You--
You even had
to go on writing.
I understand that, too.
Why did you have
to write the way you did?.
I believed
every word you said.
At first, I had
to make you tell me
as much as possible
about yourself.
I was fighting
for my life.
And then...
I got your other letters.
Photos of the children.
Glimpses of things lost
to me forever and...
It was as if you were
offering me a new world.
It was easy out there
to delude oneself.
And I believed
a wonderful thing had happened.
My husband had left me.
And those letters made me believe
he was mine again,
That everything would be
as I'd hoped it would be.
I planned for the day
he'd come home again...
For a new life together.
What a fool I was.
You were still
in love with him?.
How I can tell now?.
I know there's no excuse
for what I did, but--
Will you go now, please?.
You must believe that
I meant what I wrote.
Your letters came
to be my life.
You see, I fell
in love with you.
It was a dream then.
Now it's reality.
I allowed myself to dream
these letters of ours
could come to life.
That I could see with my own
eyes your home,
the children, yourself.
Celia, you're wanted
on the telephone.
Who is it?.
Captain Hasek.