Singoalla
Subtitles by Nostromo
A long time ago,almost in the time
of the fairy tales,there was a castle
which had for centuries
belonged to the family Månesköld
It was said there was
a curse over the castle
Reverend Father, I have to speak with you.
Yes,I understand
The evil has returned and
possessed Sir Erland.
-Yes
-I already knew that
It was written in the stars
But when will this curse cease?
It's not a curse, but all
according to the planets
- Saturn...
- Saturn?
Exactly, Saturn.
-But Reverend Father
It can't depend on Saturn?
All in the family of Månesköld is under
this curse and must die young.
It is the punishment for the first member
of the family of the Månesköld
for all the crimes of Sir Knuth
Pure superstition, Erasmus.
Instead everything is settled
by the Stellar Constellation
You see, Sir Erland's fate was to be
born under the sign of Scorpio
With the Saturn in the 8th
house, the house of death
We are meeting again, Sir Erland
Poor creature! You were probably
born under the sign of Cancer
Yes, yes, stay here and
I'll try to chase him to you
Käck! Grip!(dog names) Come on!
Käck! Grip!
I am not scared of you!
You are beautiful.
What's your name?
You're not from the neighbourhood
How clever you are.
Where are you from?
From nowhere.
And from everywhere,
if you need to know
Don't you know whom you are addressing?
I'm Sir Erland. And this whole
area belongs to me.
That's not much.I would choke in your place
The whole world is owned by me.
Do you like the colour?
It's the colour of the blood.
My name is Singoalla
No
We were just discussing
your son, your Grace.
The stars say that Sir Erland can
be free from the curse of the moon
only through a Blessed marriage
Seven generations have already served
God with humility and piousness
If Sir Erland will join them
there might be no further
Divine Judgement
It is not just the question of the evil
possessing Sir Erland, Revered Father
It is also about the name of the Månesköld
Remember, Bengt, my husband,
died at the age of 25
Hugo, Erland's grandfather,
at the age of 23.
And Sigurd, Erland's great
grandfather, was 26 years old.
If Erland would now pass away,
the Månesköld family would be extinguished
Therefore, I have decided to marry him
with Sir Gudmund Ulvsax's daughter
The sad thing is that just the word
marriage makes Erland ready for.....
How strange
Usually Erland gets so depressed
when the darkness falls
-What do you think of?
- Me? Nothing,My Lord
Well... yes, keep on.
What a lovely evening!
One such a night, the stars can only
bring luck,I suppose, Reverend Father
No, Mr. Erland, tonight the stars
have told us something extraordinary
They bode a great event.
A blissful happiness
- Really?
-A meeting
A meeting?
With a young girl.
That's unbelievable!
Why?
Unbelievable!
And this young girl...
Will she love me?
Passionately.
I know that the idea of marriage
doesn't appeal to you very much, your..
- Who put those thoughts in your mind?
- I got that impression.
Everything has changed, Reverend Father
Singoalla!
Yes!
Sir Erland
Maybe I'm just an old fool.
But when you were a child
I was the one who taught you to trace
wild boar, elk and wolf
And to mimic the sounds of the birds
It was me, who made your first
bow and your first arrow.
Yes, I almost lost my eye because of that
So, perhaps, you may forgive me if I ..
Let me be!
She will never return.
It's just as you met
her in your dreams
As if she had never existed
I know she will come back.
She is beautiful,
Maiden Helena Ulvsax
Yes, yes, I would love to
marry her in your place.
And do you a favour
Yes, naturally,in case she wants me
But she probably doesn't want to
Fool
Erland, why are you not coming down
and welcome your chosen one?
It's a good match
She is very beautiful. And
of course, very virtuous
And chaste. Even in
her dreams, isn't she?
And her father is a rich and powerful Earl
What else could be missing for to be happy?
Nothing! Except the true happiness.
I'm not in love with Helena.
So, you're asking for love too?
Remember that you belong
to the family Månesköld.
And that you are not Master
of your Own Destiny
The only thing that matters is
the future of our family
Come on, let us go
Listen to me, my son
When your dad got married,
he did not love me.
We had to learn to be happy
Without happiness.
Is that possible?
I don't know.
It was for such a short time.
Our children seem to be a great
match, Sir Gudmund
Our possessions would expand
Ulvsax and Månesköld coming together
that'll be stupendous
You know of the plan's of our parents?
They would like us to be engaged
Your future spouse must be the
most happy man in the world
You are very beautiful.
Your eyes are tender, like an angel
But the black colour,isn't that
too grim for your age?
The black colour?
Yes, the widow's veil
Look at them, all three of them
Has no one told you about the curse of the
of the Månesköld family?
You become widow quite soon here
But you would become an charming widow
Erland
Why are you always having
such cruel thoughts?
The horror, Helena.
The horror possess this castle.
Can't I help you?I am not afraid.
The making of the cross of a young
girl would deter the Devil
Would not the curse,then be vanished by
The love
Your Highness., we are some poor
travellers who appeal to your mercy
Behold, in these hands you can
see the chalice of bitter suffering
Your faces and your manners don't
appeal to me.What do you want?
We ask if you could allow us
poor travellers, to rise our tents
for a few days in your forests
-We have heard a lot of your kindness
- Really?
And I've heard a lot
about you and your pack
nothing but liars,thieves and sorcerers.
-Get out of here
- Mother!
What!
You allow wild boars to roam
around your forests
But you refuse old women
and children to camp there
Yes, the wild boar would be
salted and smoked by someone
but these beasts are unfit
for human consumption
They are like wolves!
I understand your anger, Your Highness
But be careful, you must yield
to Erland's whims
And the Heaven will let
your wishes be fulfilled
Let it be. Allow the strangers to stay
God Bless you for this great kindness
We'll never forget it
Look here, which month were you born?
Yes, that's long time ago,
I can't remember ..
I think February 23rd
23rd of February ? Pisces?
Mercury in the second quarter.
Mercury. That's the patron of the thieves
Thieves?
Can't be possible! I must have
mistaken the date,Your Reverend
Look at her! She is the most beautiful
-Beautiful in the moon light, huh?
-Yes
And are you looking at them?
You wanted to kill me the
first time you saw me
Yes... it's just me.
I noticed you didn't want to be aware of me
Last spring we said we
were to marry this winter
And when the winter came,
you said this spring
And now?
Singoalla!
There is no one else you love?
If you do that..
You have just arrived
I always knew you
were coming to me.
I saw you constantly before me
wandering on the roads
I really wondered what it could be
Lived in a sort
a nightmare, as in a shadow world.
Even the sun became a shadow
and there was no day anymore.
There has been no day for me too
but a dim joyless light
-Damned ugly
-That never ended
When I saw the snow falling, I
thought you might freeze
And when the cold wind touched my lips
I imagined your mouth had gone cold
When the pale winter light swept your hands
I wanted to cry.
When the ice started melting on the lake
I knew you were not far away
The first flowers told me
you were on your way
and the birds song that you were coming,
God bless the spring!
It's getting dark, my love
Soon I will not have you anymore.
Why?
I'm just a traveller.
And you...
You are powerful and rich.
You own all this land
And you love me.
If this is a dream
never let me wake up
Do you remember
when you told me you
owned the whole world?
Now, now I own immensely more
We must be born under
the same star.
Don't talk about the stars.
Why not?
Because Saturn doesn't like me
Do not do that. It's witchcraft
Are you superstitious?
Don't laugh, don't
trifle with witchcraft
See, that sign means sadness.
And this means joy.
Last night, you danced with a young girl
She was very beautiful
Are you jealous?
My jealousy is boundless
My mother wants me
to marry that girl.
But I don't want to
My father also wants to marry me
Do you want that?
Do you hear the song?
I have to go now
Singoalla is not here. Have you seen her?
- What, what is it?
-It's dark.
What can I do about that?
Your daughter has been away from
the camp since late this morning
and she has not yet come back
-Isn't that strange?
-Don't bother about it
Bother?So I should not ,although
my own son is to marry her
You old owl
Singoalla hasn't come back yet
She left the camp early this morning
and have not come back yet,
strange isn't it? Huh?
By all means, if that's
how you feel about it.
It's not me who is going to marry her
I trust her. And I can't stand you and
the others going around gossiping.
Have you understood?
Aha, yes
And you didn't notice anything
yesterday at the castle ?
She and the young knight,their eyes were
captivating each other,you fool
Assim
Come on!
Listen!
There is gold and silver and other precious
things in the chapel at the castle.
We should make a small farewell
visit before we move on
-Yes
-And then?
We disappear
You will be my wife
Your wife.
Assim!
No, Erland! Save him!
And you, you
are you sure you can leave all this?
Are you not going to long back?
To my wonderful castle?
It's the castle of sorrows,
owls and the black veils
where the wind is shrieking and crying
Oh, and to leave all this to
live with you travelling around
Where the wind just sings!
You are the one who will deliver me
Oh my love...
You will only exist in my
heart until the face of death
I swear to love Erland until my
death and to be faithful to him
If I betray him, he is entitled to kill me
And the great God shall shut the gates
of paradise for my lost soul.
Now it's your turn to swear above
Aloko's stone, the God of our tribe
I swear to love Singoalla until my
death and to be faithful to her
If I betray her, she
is entitled to kill me
And the great God shall shut the gates
of paradise for my lost soul.
Now you are my Lord
and I'm your slave
No...
My Ruler
Sir Erland, that's not possible
-There's no Sir Erland anymore
-But that's madness
-Yes, I'm insane. Insane by happiness,
-If I only dare to..
You had already done what
you could to convince me
Before I disappear forever, I just want
to say farewell to you, old friend
Keep the secret to yourself
But wait at least until tomorrow
You know that this night is holy.
The whole castle, the chapel even
my workshop, everything is in mourning.
And as always, the monks are in
deep prayer until dawn
for God to have mercy of the
soul of Knuth,your sinful ancestor.
-Good Bye, Erasmus.
-You can't..
You can't leave us
But you!
Can't you do anything!
Prevent him! Perform a miracle!
Can't be that difficult for you!
You are so powerful! And so plentiful !!
Let him understand that
he can not leave us.
Put that thing down.
And you stay here by the wagon
but keep your eyes open!
She is waiting for Erland to come.
What an honour for the leader
and have a knight as a son-in- law
I should think so.
You do not mean we should wait for him?
Well, if he's so keen to be my son-in-law
he may come running after us
Don't worry old witch
Come along!
Father! Erland hasn't come yet.
Start moving!
But why are you driving so fast.
We have to wait for Erland.
We would have to wait ages for him.
Your knight has made fun of you.
Start!
Wait!
You have to wait!
Erland!
Get up in the cart for a
while, you are exhausted.
Now be wise and obey me
Obey?
You are speaking as we've been
married for a hundred years.
With you I could go to
the end of the world
It's not the men's fault, but
the horses can't take it anymore
Should not we stop for a while?
- There is no danger anymore.
-We must go on, continue
We are far from Månesköld's grounds
And the drink is ready.
Now we are far from your castle.
My castle? You mean my prison.
Well, .. do you enjoy our new life?
Share it with your husband
You are a bad coach. Keep the rains
The chap will get his drink
- Drink.
-No, you must drink first
I never drink wine.
Erland are you sick?
I do not know.
There is something with the eyes.
.
It's like I saw through a veil
You're really hot
It's nothing dangerous,
I'll be fine soon enough
It burns here. My head...
My God, my God
Riders, there are riders who pursue us
Quick, take wagon up the hill!
Hurry! Hurry!
You gave me a drink!
Erland!
No, let me go!
Take the coffin in the wagon
and hide the treasure. Fast!
- We're losing!
-No, idiot! We have hostage.
Stop!
- Erland!
-It's your son's life against our lives
Villain
Swear that you give us
free passage, otherwise...
You have stolen the treasure
of the Månesköld
It's here now
- Never!
- No!
-Your Highness..
-Watch it! Who advised me?
Do you dare to appreciate some gold
things more than my son's life?
It'll be the way you want.
We have just given him a sleeping drink
They will receive a nice gift,
he will die soon
The treasure? Where is it?
Where is it? Where has it gone?
It's gone
They have deceived us.
They have run away with the treasure.
Harlot!
You've dishonoured me!
You have dishonoured our whole tribe.
You have dishonoured, Alako, our God!
Your place is no longer among us!
I prefer to live among wolves
and snakes rather than with you
I loved him.I loved him so much
And you have killed him. Cursed be you all!
- Your bitch! Get out!
- No!
She's staying. And if you chase
her away,I'll be leaving too
Cursed you all!
The poison
It was she who gave it to me
Ten years later.A terrible plague,which
have been carried by itinerant gypsies
from the Far East to Europe is approaching
A dark skinned boy is supposed to
herald the arrival of the plague
The plague is coming.
Nothing can stop it. The sky
is deaf to our prayers.
Cover your faces, abandon your villages!
Escape to north!
The plague!
Sorgbarn (eq.child of sorrow), my dear,
come and rest for a while.
I'm not tired, mother.
That's true, a man is never tired.
Here.
Oh, look mother!
An arrow and a branch.
Are we going to the left?
No, to the right.
But is that not a halting place?
Yes, just that. Look, they
are stopping here.
Make way for the knight!
Mr. Knight
You are cowards! Cowards!
Don't cry, they are not worth it.
They are mean and envious because
you are of blue blood.
If you knew how beautiful your father was
There has never been a more
beautiful man than him
-And he had a wonderful castle, mother.
-The most wonderful of all castles.
And never have a man loved
a woman the way he loved me.
Our tribe hates his kin.
Therefore, they tear me away from
your father and killed him
And he was even stronger and
braver than they were?
They killed him cowardly with poison
When I grow up, I'll be strong like father.
I'll defend you.
Tell me about the treasure, mother, about
everything they stole from him.
God punished them,they lost it.
And nobody knows where it is?
No...
You're sleepy, my dear
I often dream that I
find the treasure.
It shines. There is a big find of gold
With rubies around the wrist.
Yes, and a crown, also of gold
With emeralds and diamonds.
Like small pieces of the sun
You sleep my dear
You'll see, I'll probably find the treasure
And I'll help you
You,now again
Can you imagine if they had seen you go in?
Imagine if they saw you
sitting and talking to me
You would be despised too
Your own mother would deny you
Why are you coming here?
Why can't you leave me alone?
Poor Assim.
Sometimes I almost feel sorry for you
I just wanted to ask if you needed
something.You or the boy.
What would I need?
Poison maybe? Or abuse
Or a whiplash in the face.
That's all I've got from Alako's people.
-How you hate us.
-And for everyday I hate you more
The moment will come when the
punishment will strike your heads
And I pray to heaven that
I will see that day
I will follow you like the revenge
goddess on invisible wings.
And they want to drag me down
with you, your own curse
The plague
It's the vengeance over us
Mother?
-What does this mean?
-It means castle
I like you so much,mother.
Look!
Gracious God, it must
be the plague boy!
The plague is coming,wherever
he shows his face
We are lost.
The plague boy!
Father! Father!
- The plague boy.
- Erasmus!
It's just a poor child.
But he spreads death himself
Come here, dear friend. Come here and
tell Sir Erland and us all who you are.
Sir Erland?
Why are you staring at me like that?
It's strange. I don't know this boy.
And yet it's as if he
reminds me of someone.
-I'm Sorgbarn and my mother. -What
something -You are hurting me!
You're a gypsy... Gypsy...
And you dare...
Get out of here. Ge out of here!
Erland, how can you?
And you're asking that
Should I forget the poison that
brought me near to death?
And buried my mother,as if
she had been drinking it too?
Should I forget the endless
hours you spent at my bed?
Your anxiety?Your despair?
Which made me insane when
I was lying there paralysed
Should I forget those dirty hands of the
thieves who groped over my treasure?
And got away with it
She... she the most mean of all
... who first bewitched me
and then poisoned me!
If you've forgotten all
this, I haven't!
Erland, I wish I could forget it
but this boy is innocent!
Innocent? Look, look at his eyes!
And then talk about innocence!
It's the fire of the hell
that burns in them
Now, you shouldn't cry anymore.
Don't cry
Come with me, tell me, are you Christian?
- I don't know, I..
-Can you make the sign of the cross?
-Yes, yes, is it not like this?
-That's fine, that's fine
Also, tell me, who are your parents?
I never knew my father.
And my mother is very unhappy
Where are you from?
I do not know. I left my tribe and I've
been going along nights and days
But why did you leave ?
To look for the treasure
and the beautiful castle
-What treasure?
-Yes, and it's wonderful
There is a hand of gold with rubies.
And a gold crown with emeralds.
-How can you know ?
-Yes, I've seen them
-Have you seen them?
- Yes, in the dream.
Was it in a dream?
Yes, there was a voice that called me.
It can't be a pure coincidence.
What do you mean, Reverend father?
I don't know, I can't say it yet
But Sir Erland has to keep this boy here
I see it... in his eyes.
Is he away again
that lazy dog?
He is just a child.
He has to learn to obey!
Stop it!
What are you looking at?
I'm getting crazy with that cacophony!
He sits staring at me
like a faithful dog.
I can not stand it anymore!
I don't want to see you anymore, you'll
be leaving already tomorrow morning
Maybe I was hard against you, Sorgbarn
But don't worry about it anymore
I said I would chase you away
but you may stay
Now, now, sleep my boy
Now, sleep now
-He's alive!
- My dear!
You can't run away from me like that.
I've been so worried
Come on, we can't stay here.
In this country we are all hated.
Don't you understand? I'm saying
that father is alive
I know.
I also know that he has
married and he has a child
You have not talked to
your father about us?
I felt that I wouldn't do that
He hates me, doesn't he?
He thinks it was I who
wanted to kill him that time
-How can he believe such a thing like that?
-Don't be sorry, mother
I will bring him to you
and you will tell how it really was
Nobody's coming here, go away
Go away
No one can touch me,
everything is futile
I feel that I'll leave you soon.
And this voyage I have to do alone
Assim
You will be my successor.
That is my last command
Everything remains the same,
you will still go on living
With the sky as a tent,
my wishes to Singoalla
and say that she was known
for the wrong reasons
and her father's heart
If you were here, I would say
Excuse...
The chief is dead.
Excuse Singoalla? Maybe we should
ask her for forgiveness instead
- Mother!
-Do you know where Singoalla is?
Do you know where she is?
She has abandoned her tribe and
gone back to Sir Erland
- Erland?
- Yes. He's alive. Do you hear? He's alive!
And now? What does the new
leader commands us to do?
I guess continue our journey. But our
tribe's honour, what are you doing with it?
And the law of our people, which
punishes betrayal with death
When Singoalla betrayed Assim,
she betrayed us all!
Yes, you're a cowardly wretches,
all of you,cowards
Mangy dogs! Fie! What are
you afraid of? To die?
What does it help now that
the plague has caught us?
You there! Look at his cheek, there it
begins. And I, I also have a plague.
And Singoalla
She continues to live happily with
her knight at the beautiful castle
Turn around!
My beloved...
It is you!
Let me have a look at you.
Singoalla. Where have you been so long?
I have suffered boundlessly
as if you were dead, my love
I also wanted to die, to be with you
When I saw the snow falling, I
thought you might freeze
And when the cold
wind touched my lips
I thought maybe your
mouth had become cold.
When the ice started melting on the
lake, I knew you were not far away
You can't see me, my love
When the first flowers appeared,
it reminded me that you
were on your way here
and the birds' song that you had come
God bless the spring.
You can't see me.
You can't hear me.
- But why are you crying?
-I want to die.
If only I could die!
He does not love me anymore.
He saw me and he did not look at me.
It was my shadow he spoke to.
-That's more grim than death itself
- Don't cry, mother.
This morning how did he behave?
This morning? As usual.
Don't tell fibs.Tell me the truth.
He was dark and gloomy.
And he said he had an evil dream.
That's what I've become for him,
an evil dream
If he would meet me during the
day he would kill me.
He's sick, mother.We'll make him healthy.
If he just can see the treasure,
then he would understand.
-You are sweet, my dear
- I think I know where it is
Perhaps in the big cliff?
Yes
Or in the hollow tree,
don't you think so?
Yes, it must be there!
- Look, mother!
- Yes my dear.
Night
Night!
Always this black night!
- No no!
-What is it, my friend?
This dreadful dream.
I don't want to.
She mustn't come back.
I dreamed that I was at the spring.
There she sat waiting for me.
Light! Torches!
I can't stand this eternal night.
Calm down, Erland.
Calm down.
Let me be! Go away!
Forgive me, Helena.
Sometimes I'm not myself.
You know that.
I'm another person
Someone I don't know
Here's all I got
It appears that all animals
are afraid of the plague.
They also
Yes, one of your gloves.
I found it at the spring.
So it wasn't a bad dream...
Then it was real!
Why do you stop?
Where is she? Tell me where she is!
Take me to her right away!
Son of a snake! You're gonna die!
Both of you have to die!
- What's the matter?
-I can't really understand it
I think Sir Erland is raving mad
So, Erasmus, drink!
Come here!
Why don't you drink?
Drink! Drink!
You! All you, why are you not drinking?
Pour into your glasses!
One should drink before the hunt
We're going out witch hunting!
She hides somewhere in the woods.
But the dogs will get her scent
I will nail her alive at
the port of the castle
And then...
Then,finally I'll be calm during night
Father...
I wanted to find the treasure...
... before...
My own boy...
Mother has never hurt you
My boy
You must like her very very much
But child... What's the matter with you?
Yes, it's fine. I'm so happy with you.
Sorgbarn!
My son...
I've killed my son!
Sorgbarn!Sorgbarn my dear!
My dear!
Erland... what have you done?
Singoalla, my love.
Look how beautiful he is.
Here it is!
As fast as possible!
Come, my love
Let me support you.
Here you have your castle.
-You are tired.
-My road was endlessly long
... before I found you.
Do you hear?
The song...
The bells ..
It's for us. It's for our wedding.
Yes, my love.
Your hand...
Do you notice the smell of roses,Singoalla?
The whole room is filled with roses.
You
There is only you in the whole world
There has never been
a love like ours.
But I think I have to sleep now
But I'm with you,
even when I sleep.
Give me something to drink. I'm thirsty.
Now you're my prisoner.
I'll never let you go anymore
My Singoalla...
Your Singoalla...
Is it you, Sorgbarn?
Is that you,my boy?
You are playing
You mustn't be noisy
Your mother is just going to sleep
Subtitles by Nostromo