[film projector turning on]
[film projector off]
[eerie music]
[eerie music builds]
[JODIE] Tilly?
Tilly?!
[child's laughter]
Hello!
Wow! Look how many apples you've got!
Can you tell me how many there are?
No?
[distant radio: big band music]
Shall we go find some llamas?
- [TILLY] Llamas!
- Yeah?
Okay. Let's go this way.
[radio: big band music]
[OLIVIA] How long is the project for this time?
I think i'll be gone a week, tops?
Will the farm be okay,
with you gone that long?
She doesn't need me to do all this.
Besides we've got some great help this month.
How is she?
Sam?
It's little things.
The disease seems to like stress,
and with the coop going down,
miss-communication amongst the workers,
memory, tremors...
her limping…
a few cracked eggs.
Roger and I were thinking of selling up
and buying out one of your neighbours.
[SAM] Moving here?
I just wouldn't bet on it with Jodie.
Where is she?
Maybe the horse or those damn llamas.
Every single day she rides.
We had a late night
and she still got up at dawn
to make sure she rode
before you got here.
She won't quit.
You're a good egg Sam,
best on the farm.
Now go get her.
[radio: big band music]
[JADE] Alright Sam?
So what,
she's going to end up with dementia?
No you pleb, that's not it.
She's like that Hawking bloke.
She's going to be in a bloody wheelchair.
I know lad.
I can't believe they're related to us.
Fecking idiots.
I'm going to go get her.
Just make sure you don't burn hers too much.
Burn them?
[Tilly's laughter]
[SAM] You’re dad’s going to
burn the whole damn farm down
if we leave him at that barbecue.
Don't you remember our wedding?
Thought you would have learned to keep
my dad and food prep at arms length.
Come on you, just a couple more hours,
and they're all off.
Promise?
Can we keep this one?
So, llamas.
Do you think they like to eat little girls'
left arms or their right arms?
I don't know... I think llamas like to eat both!
[laughter]
[SAM] Let's get you
back to your mom and dad.
[distant radio: big band music]
- [thunder claps]
- [torrential rain]
Happy anniversary my lovelies.
Thanks mum.
[distant rolling thunder]
[insects]
[radio: swing band music]
- [JODIE] What did she pitch this time?
- [SAM] That they buy the Mabley place.
What and be our only neighbours
for miles around?
No thank you.
Besides i've come to love Mr Mabley
and his nosey behaviour.
He's not nosey, he just has-
No- he's just a super friendly
stuck-up bastard
who loves the fact
he lives so close to a farm.
And my god did you see my cousins?
Take a fucking photo why don't you?
Although judging by
Jade's new size zero eating habits
they'll be gone long before either of us.
- How about a cup of tea?
- I'll do it.
They just care kiddo.
You know we have to start thinking
about what we're going to do eventually.
Jodie.
Jo.
English Breakfast?
- Jesus...
- Earl Grey?
I don't care,
talk to me.
I don't want to talk about it.
Well fuck, I do,
I want to talk about it,
I want to have that talk!
Why do you make it so hard?
Why do I make it so hard?
I'm not doing anything
I'm the only one
who's acting normal around here.
Why can't you just be on my side for-
[radio volume dramatically increases]
[Radio volume decreases]
The hell was that?
I don't know maybe
you should go and check on it.
Yeah?
[back door slams]
[distant fire crackling]
Sam!
Get your ass over here.
- [Russian accent] 'Gentlemen'...
- [laughter]
- This the old shed?
- Oh you bet!
I told you we wouldn't waste it.
How you guys doing, all good?
[PYOTR] Can't complain.
Everyone's happy.
You and Jodie put on a good show.
[Sam guffaws]
It's all her.
I'm good man- look guys,
Jodie and I had a busy week,
and with me gone, just...
make sure she doesn't do too much of the
heaving lifting around here, you know?
Try to help out as much as you can.
[GRIGORY] Oh Sam...
you know she doesn't like that.
That's why I mean as much as you can,
I know that means extra
but i'll take care of it, just make sure-
Don’t worry about it.
While we are here, it's our pleasure.
You go, build your 'pretty building'.
Thanks guys.
Actually yeah, I'll take one of those.
[fire crackling]
[sad music]
Fuck.
[sad music continues]
[morning insects and birdsong]
[phone alarm]
[alarm stops]
[eggs frying]
- Thank you.
- Take a seat or you'll be late.
[pan on stove]
Tuck in.
[laughter]
[car horn beeps]
[soft dramatic music]
Morning boys.
Morning.
[muffled sound of chickens]
[chickens]
Morning Aggie.
Shall I start sorting?
Yes, please.
But Jodie-
Don't worry,
I'm just double-checking this lot,
you carry on.
Where's Irmante?
[somber music]
Irmante?
Where are Josef and Else?
- They didn't say?
- What?
- I'm so sorry Miss Jodie-
- Just Jodie, please
They left. Last night?
Josef got a masonry contract in Surrey,
but he has to start today.
I thought they would let you know.
They didn't.
I can do their share.
No. Absolutely not.
It's not your fault.
I can do it.
Besides, you never did tell me
what your plans were for next summer.
[Irmante guffaws]
[engine turning off]
[car door]
Afternoon gents, how's it going?
How are we today?
We're fine.
Although I just found out
that Josef and Else have left,
so I've been doing the apples all morning.
What are the gloves for?
I'm sick of seeing this pile,
thought I’d lend a hand.
But we've only got the two axes.
We couldn't find the other one.
[GRIGORY] Maybe Josef took it?
I'll have a look later.
Okay fine.
I'll load this onto the Animal,
you guys carry on.
[wood being loaded onto the truck]
[Russian language]
[wood landing on the truck]
[Irmante and Agatha laughing
and talking: inaudible]
[JODIE] All good?
[AGATHA] Perfect, those ones over there are ready.
[Irmante and Agatha talking: inaudible]
[large exhale]
[Irmante laughing]
[Jodie breathing heavily]
[JODIE] Shit!
[IRMANTE] Miss Jodie!
I'm fine, I'm alright.
Clear this up, and load the rest.
[somber music]
[somber music continues]
- [horse galloping]
- Good girl!
That's it, keep going!
[horse neighs]
[eerie music]
Come on Miranda, walk on.
[horse trotting]
Hello.
And good afternoon,
or is this the evening?
When does the evening start?
I suppose when the sun starts to set?
You know, when it starts to go down?
Let's just agree that it's late in the day,
and this is my property you're on,
and I'm sorry
I still don't know who you are.
- Your name?
- Yes, my name is Jamie.
- And you are with...?
- Just myself today.
No, I mean do you have any ID?
It's in my vehicle.
Im looking for someone.
I'm the owner of Plum Farm,
so i'm in charge here.
Were looking for someone
to talk about produce?
No, just that i'm looking for someone.
Have you seen anyone new in recent days?
New?
Anyone you've not met before.
Here, on this, farm.
Or the area around the farm?
No I can't say that I have seen anyone new,
Just the usual faces, all familiar now.
Is this your domicile?
My domicile?
Yes, mine and my husbands.
May I speak with him?
No, he's away on business.
And what of these smaller domociles?
The caravans are for my workers,
and as I said before,
I know each and every one of them.
No, new faces here.
Now I'm very sorry,
but I have to sort my eggs for delivery,
as it's almost evening now.
You're welcome to come back later
and talk to my workers
once they've finished.
You'll find all of their papers in order
and the farm's too for that matter.
Any other problems, you can
come and see me again,
or give me a call.
Goodbye.
[eerie music]
[rustling]
Jodie?
Excuse me, Jodie?
[JODIE] Hey guys, what's up?
Go on, Aggie.
Who was that woman earlier?
She looked important.
To be honest, I'm not sure.
Okay, where are Pyotr and Grigory?
[AGATHA] They went to the pub.
The Crooked Arm? That's 10 miles.
It means they're always sober
when they get home.
Or they think they are. [laughs]
Look, I don't want anyone to worry,
because it seems like nothing.
But, well, you should know.
She was just snooping around
looking for someone,
She didn't say much,
she didn't say anything at all.
I guess she works for the government-
I, I, forgot to ask... [sighs]
Maybe I should have pressed her, it's-
[tired sigh]
Look it's been a long day,
the point is...
I don't think it's anything serious.
I'm sure it's nothing.
And she didn't say who she was looking for?
No, just...
Just tell me if you see anyone suspicious.
No- anyone new.
Let Pyotr and Grigory know.
Have a good night
[IRMANTE] Goodnight Jodie.
- Irmante...
- Stop it.
Lets get an early night, eh?
[eerie music]
[electric buzzing]
[buzzing stops]
[eerie music]
[Russian language]
Wow!
[distant rumble]
[Russian language]
[low suspenseful music]
[Russian language untranslated]
[Russian language]
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
[Russian language]
[someone wretching violently]
[wretching continues]
[wretching]
[Russian language]
- [laughter]
- [wretching stops]
Hey...
[Russian language untranslated]
Hey... buddy.
Good?
What did you eat?
It's all cool man...
[suspenseful music]
[Russian language untranslated]
Hey... buddy.
[animalistic stomach sound]
What did you eat?
[silence]
Okay it's all good now.
[howling roar]
- [Flesh tearing]
- [Pyotr screams]
[Flesh torn by teeth]
[Screams]
[More flesh tearing]
[More screams]
[silence]
[soft dramatic music]
[footsteps]
[muffled chicken sounds]
Where are the boys?
I don't care if they're hungover,
we need more woodbundles for tonight.
We didn't want to worry you, but...
[JODIE] What is it?
They didn't come back last night.
They sent a couple of texts.
[IRMANTE] It's nothing, really.
Show her.
Show me what?
Come on...
What am I looking at?
Looks like a flashlight.
[IRMANTE] He says it was in the sky,
that they went to have a look.
Look guys they're at the pub,
I'm sure they'll show up.
Did you tell them what I told you last night?
[IRMANTE] Leave it, Aggie...
I texted them. I let them know.
[IRMANTE] Don't worry, I doubt it's that.
Right. Of course.
Shit. Okay.
You load the eggs on The Animal,
I'll chop some wood.
- [IRMANTE] Let us help you.
- Eggs.
I've got this.
[wood chop]
[tired breaths]
[tired sigh]
[catching her breath]
[grunts]
[deep breaths]
[plane overhead]
[grunts]
[catching her breath]
[gasp]
[breathing] Okay.
[grunts]
[deep breaths]
[gasp]
[catching her breath]
[grunts]
[door creaking]
[deep breaths]
[gasp]
[door creaking]
[catching her breath]
[grunts]
[gasp]
[deep breaths]
[grunts]
[catching her breath]
[gasp]
[pained gasp]
[catching her breath]
[laughs]
[deep breaths]
Right.
- You really think so?
- Absolutely.
Pyotr and Grigory are fun, but,
at the end of the day they get into
more bad than they do good.
Would it really surprise you if they've run off?
Well what about the lights?
Please.
Just one last practical joke.
You think it's coincidence
they run off same night
that woman from government
was snooping around?
No one said she was from the government.
Then where else would she be from?
Irmante.
Be honest.
Do you feel welcome here anymore?
[AGATHA] Why else do you think Josef and Else
were so happy to head to the city?
It's no better.
How do you know?
London could be.
My brother's happy there.
London voted in.
Let's not talk about this.
People have changed.
[gasp]
Hello there.
[eerie music]
Hello.
You were at our farm yesterday.
[WOMAN IN BLACK] The farm yes.
I spoke with your superior.
My colleague and I were wondering
if you'd seen anybody new in the area.
- No.
- [MAN] More volume!
[IRMANTE] No.
As our 'superior' told you: no one.
We are all here legally.
At least I know for a fact that I am,
and she is.
Come on Agatha. We have to
get this food back to the farm.
People are expecting us.
[IRMANTE] Don't look back.
Okay, you win. Let's talk.
[eerie music]
[faucet drips]
[electric buzzing]
[sighs] Fuck's sake.
[buzzing stops]
[mysterious music]
[approaching footsteps]
This doesn't look good.
We need to talk.
So you're leaving?
We still haven't seen Pyotr and Grigory,
and with that woman yesterday
we think that maybe it is time to move on.
- [JODIE] But there's still a few days work to do-
- You have to understand,
we don't want trouble, and it's harder now.
We don't want to risk what we have, Jodie.
And those lights-
something's not right here.
I'm sorry Jodie.
What about your pay?
Here.
[IRMANTE] This is where we'll be.
You can contact us there.
It's where Josef got the work in Surrey.
We think it could be good for us.
[AGATHA] It's just that woman
and with what's happening,
it'll be better there than here.
But you have nothing to worry about.
We can call the police about Pyotr and Grigory.
[IRMANTE] Please, Jodie, we are so thankful to you.
You and Sam are fantastic,
but it's time for us to move on.
And Josef has found us
something immediate,
it's now or never.
Okay.
I'll get you some food and water
for the journey.
[deep breath]
[scream of rage]
[phone rings]
[ringing stops]
- Hey.
- [SAM] Hey you!
I wanted to call earlier but
couldn't get away from Terry again.
Everything okay?
- Jodie?
- Yeah, everything it's, fine, it's fine.
It's so good to hear you.
Oh baby i've missed you.
Before I forget, the lights surged again
like the other night,
that's three times now.
Why don't you call the neighbour
and see if he's had the same thing?
Sam, do I have to?
Jodie.
Okay, fine, I will.
But it's definitely not the fuses.
Anything else going on?
Jodie?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
When you're back.
I love you.
I love you too.
[phone lands on the table]
[tired sigh]
[insects]
- [distant indistinct crash]
- [distant gutteral howl]
[suspenseful music]
[indistinct crash, closer now]
[music stops]
[shallow breathing]
[silence]
[cup crashes into the sink]
[gasp]
[scared breaths]
[breaths getting quicker]
[slow approaching footsteps]
[footsteps getting closer]
[shallow breaths]
[footsteps faltering]
[body collapsing]
[birdcall]
[footsteps]
[Mouthing: "What?!"]
[Shotgun placed on the steps]
[mysterious music]
[eerie music]
[indistinct groan]
[drawer closing]
[faucet drips]
[TRAVELLER: groans]
I don't know if you can hear me...
but my name's Jodie.
I'm not going to hurt you, okay?
You're safe here.
[mysterious music]
[soft footsteps]
[faucet running]
[Jodie drinking]
[sigh]
Jesus!
Good morning.
[JODIE] Do you speak English?
[JODIE] Do you want something to eat?
Eat?
Sit.
[rustling]
[refrigerator door opening]
Cereal.
You eat it?
[bowl placed on the table]
[gulp]
[stomach noises]
[vomiting]
[bowl placed in the sink]
[faucet running]
You have to eat for that to heal properly.
Eggs?
Meat?
Eat.
[violent chewing]
[slurping and chewing]
[cutlery dropping]
[plates dragged on the table]
[curious music]
Who are you?
[curious music continues]
Rest.
[receding footsteps]
[door hinge creaking]
Shi-
[soft dramatic music]
[OPERATOR] The number you have called is not available.
If you'd like to leave a message,
please do so after the tone.
[message tone]
Hi Norman, it's Jodie from Plum Farm.
I'm just calling to see
if you've had any electrical problems
over the last few days.
Like power surges or something similar.
[faucet running into sink]
Give us a call when you can.
No need to come over.
Just a quick call.
[faucet running into glass]
[faucet running into sink]
Hope you're well.
[soft dramatic music]
[industrial egg machine]
[JODIE] Jesus!
- [machine stops]
- [muffled chicken sounds]
It's okay.
Eggs.
[JODIE] Do you remember these?
Do you understand me?
Do you know what I'm saying?
No, wait, you'll-
Okay.
[industrial egg machine starts]
[soft dramatic music]
[chickens clucking]
So this is all Plum Farm.
My husband and I own it.
He's away on business.
Over there are the orchards,
and the horse patch.
The barn...
and there, is our closest neighbour.
Did he do this to you?
[Jodie laughs]
Sorry.
He's a nice man I suppose.
Is this similar to where you're from?
This?
You?
Were you in hospital?
Did you have an operation?
Who hurt you?
Come on.
[wood hitting the truck bed]
Whoever you are,
I may just have to keep you on.
That's enough.
[Jodie gasps]
- [eerie music]
- [strange vibration increasing in intensity]
[vibration stops]
[shocked gasp]
Right.
[door closes]
[mysterious music]
[brushing]
[horse neighs]
[mysterious music continues]
[chickens clucking]
[knife cutting through meat]
[indistinct crash outside]
[another crash]
It's okay.
Stay here,
and I'll be back soon.
[footsteps]
[JODIE] Hello?
What the hell?!
I'm sorry I was just looking-
No, you were sneaking!
Last time you came to the farmhouse
during working hours- that's fine.
That's what normal people do.
So, once again.
This is my property and as you're here
without my permission,
you are trespassing.
Have you seen anyone?
No.
Did you find the person you were looking for?
No, we're still in the process of looking,
which is why I was looking in this...
building.
Well as you can see there's no one here.
Yes I know, we're still looking.
Not here, you're not.
We're looking for a particular individual.
[threatening music]
Very dangerous.
An escaped convict, if you will.
A different class if convict.
Not from here.
Are you sure you haven't seen anyone new?
As I said, no.
All of my workers have left, and
my husband will be returning soon.
In the meantime,
my cousin is staying with me
back at the farmhouse.
I'm not alone.
May I speak with him?
No you may not- leave now.
In fact,
I'd like to make a formal complaint.
Which department of the government
did you say you work for?
Goodbye, Miss.
[threatening eerie music]
[footsteps, door opening]
She's looking for you, isn't she?
That woman.
You're running.
Where are you from?
[mysterious music]
[JODIE] Here.
This is where we are right now.
Here.
Me.
[paper rustling]
[pen on paper]
[mysterious music]
[JODIE] No wait, stop, stop!
You're going to need more space.
[mysterious music]
You are from up there.
Those lights were you.
Those light surges, that was you.
But there were lots of surges.
That must mean there's more
than just that woman looking for you.
Whoever they are,
you are safe here.
I promise.
[phone rings]
[ringing stops]
Hey!
[SAM] Oh baby, I thought you'd never pick up.
You alright?
Yeah.
Well sort of. All the workers left.
- What?!
- No! It's okay, everything's alright.
Most of the picking's done, and-
But why did they leave?
It's a long story,
- but they've mostly gone on to work in Surrey.
- Oh Jesus Christ...
No, Sam, Sam- its okay.
I've found some more help anyway.
And it's mainly just the coop,
and there's not much fruit, usable fruit.
Okay...
You do that,
I'll do this.
Get some sleep.
I'll be back soon, sooner if I can,
I promise.
Kiddo, are you sure there's nothing else
you want to tell me?
I love you.
I love you too. Sleep tight.
I'm holding you close.
[wistful music]
[birdsong]
[sigh]
He's eaten all the meat.
[birdsong]
You ate all the meat.
No meat.
[tired sigh]
[JODIE] It's nothing.
I know.
You need more food than we do.
A lot more.
Bear with me, I need to go out.
Get you some more food?
Now you stay here,
I'll be back soon.
Actually,
come with me.
[television: cowboy music]
[JODIE] Push these.
I'll be back soon.
[television: news bulletin music]
[PRESENTER] This is the news at mid-
[television: cowboy music]
[front door opening]
[front door closing]
[refrigerator buzz]
[supermarket customers]
[BUTCHER] Love?
Excuse me, Miss?
Oh, er, sorry.
I know a man about a cow, you know.
May be a lot easier than taking all that.
Are you okay?
Yeah, fine.
Just a bit tired.
Thank you though.
Have a nice day.
You too.
[shopping cart rattling]
[rattling gets louder]
[TV ACTOR] School.
[TV ACTOR] I remember always hearing about you.
- [TV ACTOR 1] [gasp]
- [TV ACTOR 2] Sorry!
[television: police siren]
[television: cello music]
[television: sludge music]
People just don't feel welcome here anymore.
[PRESENTER] But is that-
[television: romantic music]
Dad?
[TV ACTOR] You really do look just like her.
Your donations help immeasurably.
Allowing us to produce videos like these,
which will help you,
or your friends and family,
come to terms with
a life-changing diagnosis.
Primary progressive MS effects about
10 to 15 percent of people diagnosed with MS.
It is called this because
from the first primary symptoms,
it is progressive.
Symptoms gradually get worse over time,
rather than appear as sudden attacks,
or relapses.
People with primary progressive MS
can also experience problems with memory,
or thinking,
known as cognitive symptoms.
- Although usually any symptoms are mild.
- [stomach noises and rumbles]
[ DOCTOR] Then there is your balance and co-ordination.
- Why are problems with the legs so common?
- [violent stomach noises]
Well a likely reason is that
primary progressive MS tends
to involve the spinal chord,
a vital part of the nervous system
for controlling this part of the body.
This could also be why
symptoms of the bladder,
bowel, and sexual function
can accompany problems with the legs.
These parts of the body also rely heavily
on messages from the spinal chord.
[drawer opening]
[curious music]
[can lid hits the floor]
[stomach rumbling]
[supermarket customers]
[food landing at the till]
[food scanner beeps]
[beeping frequency increases]
[vibrating sound]
- [vibration getting louder]
- [beeping getting louder]
[supermarket ambience getting louder]
[loud beep]
[silence]
[foosteps on gravel]
[violent stomach noise]
[trees rustling]
[rustling gets louder]
[rustling returns to normal]
[plane overhead]
[distant horse neighing]
Are you sure you're
going to be okay to drive?
I'll be fine.
I just lost my balance.
It goes sometimes.
I just need to rest.
- Just wait shall we?
- I said i'm fine!
I'm alright.
Thank you.
[creepy music]
[horse neighs]
[distant truck engine]
[engine turns off]
[JODIE] Take them inside.
[tired gasp]
[tired sigh]
[deep exhale]
[shallow breathing]
- [eerie music]
- [strange vibration increasing in intensity]
[vibration stops]
[catching her breath]
I knew it.
The other night.
When I lifted you up,
I was dead, right up until...
Wait!
[JODIE] Thank you!
- [strange vibration]
- [JODIE] Thank you!
- [Jodie gasps]
- [body hitting the ground]
[catching her breath]
I didn't know, I didn't understand!
It just felt so good!
[laughs]
[regretful music]
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Come on.
You must be starving,
I'll get you some food.
[footsteps]
[knife cutting meat]
[chewing]
[gulp]
I haven't cooked any more.
[cutlery on plate]
[refrigerator opening]
[refrigerator closing]
Why don't you let me cook that for you?
[creepy music]
[violent chewing]
[violent tearing]
[slurping tongue]
[knocking at front door]
[louder knocking]
[knocking]
Sorry to bother you madam.
Not at all.
I'm Constable Cleough.
I was wondering if you have a few minutes,
do you mind if I come in for a moment?
It's just me.
Can I see some identification?
It's Andy, only my mum calls me Andrew.
Tea?
[ANDY] Thank you but no.
I was just at the end of myself shift
and you're the last house I have to check on-
well bar your vacant neighbour,
the only house.
How can I help?
Well you see a couple of people
have gone missing in the area,
and we're just canvassing to see
if you've noticed anything amiss.
I see your caravans are empty.
Yes, the workers left a few days ago.
Seasonal help?
Yes, all registered.
I have their details if you want them.
What, local?
Better than that, mostly Eastern European.
Right.
But when did they go missing?
About three nights ago.
You haven't noticed anything
strange in the area?
Madam?
Not that I can think of.
My husband's been away on business-
he's an architect,
and I've just been so busy with the farm
that honestly if anything had gone amiss
I probably wouldn't notice.
Had company did we?
Oh, no! [sigh]
Please understand it's just me here,
and I haven't cleared up
after the last few meals.
How embarrassing,
you must think i'm a monster!
[laughter]
Not at all, you should see
the state of my domicile.
- [eerie music]
- Just picture takeaway boxes everywhere
instead of plates.
Look i'm sorry constable, but as I said,
I've been really busy with the farm,
- I should think about turning in.
- Not a problem.
I'll just leave you my card.
So you can ring me,
or any of the officers on duty,
- if you remember anything.
- Thanks.
[suspicious music]
[laughs]
Something funny, madam?
We used to live in London
before we moved out here last year,
and I just realised that
that was the last time I saw a policeman.
I've never seen one out here.
Sounds about right.
Well, have a good evening madam.
You too.
[receding footsteps]
[distant car engine]
- [soft dramatic music]
- [heavy rainfall]
[rainfall on the caravan roof]
[heavy rainfall]
[flashlight on table]
[footsteps approaching]
[gasp] Stop doing that!
Two of the workers who lived here,
I don't know if they ran off,
or if they're coming back.
They went to the woods,
somebody said they saw lights.
In the sky?
But I don't know if those lights were you
or if they were that woman
who was here before.
[exasperated sigh]
You have no idea
what i'm saying, do you?
Shit.
Maybe I should have mentioned
something to that policeman.
What if the people that are looking for you,
what if they're behind
these people going missing?
What if...
Okay.
I've got an idea for tomorrow.
Come with me.
[shotgun blast]
[lingering echo]
[gun snapping open]
[Jodie sniffles]
- [shells being loaded]
- [gun snapping closed]
No, no!
Never do that!
Never.
You never know.
Okay?
[gun blast impression]
[exploding impression]
Oh, sorry.
Just copy me.
No.
No, this isn't going to work.
Come with me.
Right.
They come, you hide under.
Okay?
They come.
You hide.
Oh wait, one more thing.
[footsteps]
Just in case.
Jesus christ I hope you're getting this.
[knife knocking the bed frame]
Okay.
Let's get to work.
[soft dramatic music]
[muffled sound of chickens]
[chickens moving around]
[soft dramatic music continues]
I need you to do something for me.
It's a big ask.
She means everything to me.
And I haven't been able to ride her-
[strange vibration increasing]
- That's enough!
- [strange vibration stops]
That's more than enough!
Thank you!
[low intense rumble]
[rumble increasing]
[horse gallop approaching]
[optimistic music]
[horse galloping]
I wish you could talk to me.
Tell me what your world is like.
Is it a world?
I suppose if it was nice
you wouldn't be running.
Or hiding.
Is that what this is?
That woman,
the woman who was here,
I didn't like the way she made me feel,
talking to her.
But you, you...
You're more like a child.
[laughs]
No it's more than that.
I trust you.
Wish you could understand
what I was saying.
There's so much that I want to know.
We should go to the eggs.
But we need to-
Wait!
We'll take a break, but just this once!
[kettle boiling]
[stops boiling]
Well, I'm impressed.
The right tea, the right mug.
Pretty damn good.
[laughs]
So, I was thinking about,
all the things
you may not have experienced,
and...
Well, one of them was...
['Responder' by Teeth of the Sea plays]
No, no, wait, it's good, but wait...
When it kicks in...
- Here.
- [the music beat kicks in]
Yeah?
Sam and I used to live in London.
We used to go out all over,
and Teeth of the Sea,
live?
Oh man...
and this track?
It was everything.
It wasn't just the booze and...
the other shit. It was...
It was more than that, it was...
music...
the people around you...
the night.
[music continues, muffled]
I just need to go out for a minute.
No. Please.
On my own.
No!
You shouldn't.
I just need to...
Okay.
Let's get out of here.
[birdsong]
[footsteps]
No.
The town is that way,
I want to go this way.
Come on, this way.
What are you doing?
No.
This way.
What was that about?
[rustling]
[phone: Pyotr inaudible]
[Pyotr inaudible]
- [Grigory agitated, inaudible]
- [Pyotr inaudible]
[Pyotr inaudible]
[PYOTR: Hey, buddy...]
[What did you eat?]
[It's all cool man.]
- [howling roar]
- [Pyotr screams]
[Flesh tearing]
[Pyotr screams]
[phone cuts out]
Stay away from me.
Stay away.
Leave.
Go.
Fucking go!
[Jodie sobbing]
No, no!
Stay away from me!
Go!
Leave!
[mournful music]
[heavy breathing]
[soft dramatic music]
[paper scrunching]
[sad music]
[PHONE OPERATOR]
You're through to emergency services,
which service would you like?
Hello?
[phone hitting the table]
[Jodie sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
- [dramatic music]
- [insects]
[muffled sound of chickens]
[dragged footsteps]
- [truck engine]
- [hopeful music]
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on!
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up!
Fucking hurry up!
[exasperated sigh]
Great.
- Hi Norman!
- Jodie, Jodie, Jodie!
How are you?
I just got back from the Lakes last night
and heard your messages.
Thought I’d come straight over this morning.
Yes, of course.
Surges, eh?
Seems all the electrics in my house are fine.
Oh, look- that's all good now.
Look, Norman, I've got to get going,
I'm looking for someone.
Looking for someone.
Not one of those new faces, eh?
[truck engine turns off]
New faces?
- Have you seen him?
- Who?
Oh you mean the bald fella?
What?
Big lad, with his, well,
I assume it's his wife, or partner-
whatever you say now.
Tall, blonde, black coat?
Yes, that’s the one.
When did you see them?
Last night, on the lane by the house.
I said hello to them,
asked if I could help and...
And?
Well...
They said no, they'd...
What was it?
They'd given up and were going.
Did they say where they were going?
Yes, they did.
Where, Norman?
[relieved sigh]
Home.
Was anyone with them?
No, just them.
Is everything alright?
Yes.
We'll pop over soon, I promise.
I better get going, lots to do.
- Cheerio then!
- [truck engine starts]
[truck engine recedes into quiet]
[trees rustling]
[muffled washing machine]
[birdsong]
[yielding dramatic music]
[emotional music]
[silence]
[car parking nearby]
[engine turns off]
[car door closes]
[approaching footsteps]
- Hey.
- [SAM] Hey!
Thank you.
Man, I'm beat.
That drive was awful [laughs]
- Sorry if I was-
- Sam?
Will you make me a cup of tea?
Yeah, sure.
[tea tin opening]
[kettle starting to boil]
[tea tin closing]
[mug on work surface]
[refrigerator opening]
[refrigerator closing]
[kettle reaches boil]
[water pouring]
[spoon on the work surface]
Thank you.
[Sam moving a chair]
[Sam sitting]
It's good.
Okay.
Let's talk.
[yielding dramatic music]