Early 21st century
More than half of humans died due to infection
And the humans that barely survived...
Divided into two groups
Very shortly...
Everyone who is out of the CURIO area, please return immediately.
Everyone who is out of the CURIO area, please return immediately
Very shortly...
Everyone who is out of the CURIO are, please return immediately.
Katsuya!
Why are you doing this?
Hey...speak to me Katsuya!
You sure are worthy of being a NOX member.
Will you be okay if your head gets smashed in?
Didn't I tell you that we were friends?
Why are you doing this?
Didn't you say that you wanted to talk and be on good terms?
But you never gave me a chance you bastard.
You look down on us don't you?
You're drinking alcohol aren't you?
You can't do that Katsuya!
You can't make good judgments in that state...
Shut up!
That's dangerous you bastard!
Don't spread it to me!
Katsuya...
We can coexist!
Didn't we make a promise that we'd go home together?
Katsuya!
Thanks to you, we have to endure such a shitty lifestyle.
My grandparents and my parents as well...
Things must be changed by our generation.
Katsuya...
Hey, stop it!
Please stop!
I'm not a slave of NOX!
I'm a child of the Sun!
We found it! It's right here!
Over here! Over here!
It's right here!
Take a look!
How could this happen?
Dad!
Don't look!
Where is Katsuya?
Go look for him!
Katsuya! What have you done?
Is that you Onee-chan?
He was your friend...
I can't stand NOX!
Turn yourself in. Please!
What are you saying?
The village will be destroyed! Please!
I'm going to Shikoku! It's a revolution!
This isn't only your village!
Onee-chan!
Don't you want to live a nice life?
We're both humans!
Katsuya!
Damn you!
What have you done?
This is because of your stupid little brother!
It's over!
How are you gong to take responsibility for this!?
This village is done for!
What are you doing?!
Junko can't do anything about it!
Hey! This village is done for!
Stop wasting time and look for him!
It's on fire!
It's on fire. Alright! Let's go!
It's dangerous! Get back!
Step back! It's dangerous!
Decades ago when people died of the new virus infection...
The people who stumbled upon the antibodies became NOX.
They lived a totally different life then us.
We're different than NOX.
We will die once we are infected.
Although these differences exist...
Humans aren't based off what their parents did.
We can't be treated differently at birth.
We and NOX are equal.
Sounds good?
Although it's a little far from here...
There are people who live well without depending on NOX in Shikoku.
I talked about the autonomous region before.
I already explained it but...
Can anyone else explain it?
Me!
Alright, what about Takahashi?
Loud and clear!
They don't rely on Nox...
What do they do if they don't rely on them?
Me!
You can't answer?
You can't rely on these girls to answer for you.
What do they do if they don't relay on NOX?
Okay!
Okay...let's see..
They have their own law administration.
What is this administration?
Me!
Alright...how about...
-They're here! -You're right!
Really?
-It's my mom! -No way!
Alright! You can go home when you return the textbooks!
Okay!!
-Hayase-san will teach math tomorrow.  -Okay!
-Farewell! -Don't drop anything and be safe on your way home!
Okay!!
Nox school's have activities like exercise and work right?
That equality is a lie isn't it?
You're late!
Your Dad's ethic class is too long!
Your mom isn't going to come?
At 8pm, we have a special announcement in the government Palace!
People over 20 years old, please come to the meeting place! Thank you!
NOX people will come at 8pm!
Please come to the meeting place everyone!
Best regards!
Yes!
I have just arrived.
Yeah.
That isn't a problem.
Yes.
Dad! Are they coming?
They're just in time.
We might get busy in the future.
Yes! Good work!
To be honest, I was shocked!
The past 10 years of economic blockade has been so awful.
Someone just recently died right?
There's 44 people now.
10 years ago, there were 307 people.
Is everyone in Shikoku?
Some people did...yeah.
They simply abandon their hometown if the economy does bad.
It's not their fault.
Okudera Junko-san!
Your little brother killed a NOX member.
His family has finally forgiven your brother's crimes.
Please be grateful!
This is a special case.
It's because of the generosity of his family.
Please be grateful!
I hope you can respond to me.
Be grateful or apologize. Either one is fine.
It's rude to let me speak alone.
Thank you...
Speak up. Put some volume in that voice.
-Thank you  -Louder!
-Thank you. -Louder!
-Thank you! -Louder!
Thank you!
Thanks for that.
They're saying something to Junko-san.
Shit! Why is it just the adults?
But wow, it must be really hard for you to survive in this environment?
In our opinion, it is in a primitive era.
Let's start with infrastructure first!
We will also provide medical support.
Also..if your child is under 20, please raise your hand.
After 10 years, the lottery for conversion surgery will be carried out again.
I will send the application materials to everyone later.
Now then! It's time for a new beginning!
Let's return back to the cultural age.
Have a seat.
The boy over there! Look straight!
Let's shake hands as a sign of reconciliation, Okudera-san.
I'll publish the photo in the newspaper.
Look forward.
It's okay. You can't catch anything with a handshake.
Please get a good shot!
Okay!
I'm taking it!
Damn, that's bright!
What was that?
NOX people are weak to light.
Now then! We will give you the medicine for the virus.
This is medicine for preventing the infection.
Alright, I'll have the 6 of you come follow me over here.
Go ahead.
Please take off your jacket and stand in line here.
Alright! Over here!
Please take off your jacket and come over here.
Please take off your jacket and stand side by side in front of the bar.
We're going to spray you with medicine to prevent the infection.
Here we go!
Please come over here.
Please take off your jacket and stand side by side in front of the bar.
Over here!
Okay! The next person please!
Please take off your jacket and stand side by side in front of the bar.
Please stand side by side in front of this bar.
Alright, here we go!
Alright, that's it!
Alright, for those of you in front, please come over here for a simple check.
The next person please!
Please go inside.
Please go in the middle.
Go inside please.
Soichi?
Are you Soichi?
It's me! It's me!
Kaneda! From Iiyama!
Kaneda?
Kaneda Yoji?
Oh, Soichi! You are still here?
Still here?
I'll always been here!
It's okay. You won't catch anything by a handshake.
I'm 55!
If I get infected then I'm going to die.
But man...you've gotten so old.
You're too youthful for your age!
Who is that?
My daughter!
Nice to meet you. I'm Kaneda.
I'm your Dad's childhood friend.
How old are you right now?
19.
That means that you still haven't gotten the surgery.
Why did you come here?
I'm a doctor.
I thought about helping out my hometown.
More and more people are getting sick after all.
Take off your glasses.
Weren't you on our side before?
Why are you talking to me like this now?
Alright! Let's start!
Such stupid crap!
Are you okay with going back first?
Without Junko-san.
What's up with you?
When did you start talking like that?
I'm gonna take a bath first.
Do you need something?
Permits will be available next week.
Umm...
What are you doing?
Hold on! Don't move!
Ah, no...umm...it's nothing dangerous!
Put it on the ground!
It's okay! It's okay!
-Throw it out! -It's okay!
It's a mask.
I heard that NOX can't handle the sun....
It's iron so it's a little heavy...
If you put that on...
You can avoid the sun.
What am I going to do about my body?
The back of the head is also exposed!
It's too bad but...
Unauthorized transactions are strictly prohibited.
This is umm...
A greeting gift!
I will be a NOX member next year.
The lottery system was restored after all.
What are the chances of being selected?
Seven people under 20.
But no one else will sign up!
I'll probably be the only one...
Why don't they sign up?
Everyone hates NOX after all.
I want to study at a NOX school...
And learn some technical jobs!
Before I go there...
I want to learn all kinds of things!
That's why...
Umm...
I want to become friends!
With me?
Yeah!
You can't.
I'm working.
You can become a NOX member now!
They have volunteer applications for one week.
So what?
You'll be twenty next year.
This is your last chance.
Didn't you hate them?
Old man Mitake is over 80 and probably infected.
You can't be afraid of the virus forever.
You can become a NOX..
That's why...
Mom left right?
I won't become a NOX member.
You've been there the whole time?
The people in Shikoku...
Can live without relying on NOX right?
I'm going to Shikoku!
What are you going to do in Shikoku?
I'll learn how to make everyone's lives better.
What are you going to do after that?
Come back home!
I'll show you!
That Mom was wrong.
I heard that you couldn't have children.
I heard that the child couldn't be saved.
I've gotten used to it.
This is the 10th miscarriage.
Science is advancing but birth rates aren't going up.
I'm sorry that I'm not capable enough...
Aren't you in the medicine field Kaneda-kun?
That's true....
I wonder if there's no love in my sex with Seiji-san?
If you're okay with me...
I can be your partner anytime.
Stop that.
Why?
You're having sex with other men besides Seiji-san right?
Yeah.
But former CURIO people are awkward.
You still have those kinds of feelings huh?
I became a NOX member later on.
You were 30 during that time huh?
20 is the upper limit now.
Be the way...
I saw your ex-husband in the CURIO area.
Soichi?
Your daughter too.
It was Yuu-chan right?
They're still there?
It's a pity.
They were basically deserted there.
Is he old now?
Yeah.
CURIO people age quickly.
That's right.
I heard that 72 people were born in Osaka.
You still have a chance.
Kaneda-kun said that adoption is an option as well.
I don't agree with him.
You're using avocado again?
I heard that it is good for conception.
That is superstition.
It seems like the Miura family next door are adopting.
They adopted a six year old boy.
The earlier the surgery, the better.
Seiji-san?
Before I became a NOX member...
Do you remember how I gave birth to a kid?
Yeah.
I heard that she is still in District 8.
She'll turn 20 next year.
What kind of child do you think she is now?
Who knows...
Maybe I should go and see her.
It would be better if you didn't.
They have their pride as well.
Besides, she was only three when you came here right?
She probably doesn't remember how you look.
You guys better not sign up!!
I'm 23 anyways.
Who will be the next village chief if I leave?
Why do you want to be a NOX member Mitsuhiko?
You'll never see the sun again!
Is that okay?
That's fine!
I'll be able to eat yummy food!
And I can go to a good school. It's the best!
You skip classes!
Shut up, you ugly hag!
It's because your Dad is so preachy!
You flat chest! Flat chest!
Stupid! Try and stop me!
Hey hold on!
Don't jump down damn it!
Come on! You ugly hag!
Hold on!
Why are you running away?
I'll tell your pops!
That his class is boring!
Hold on!
Hold on dummy!
Stop running!
Ugly!
Come on! Come on! You're too slow!
Do something about your pops!
Hold on Mitsuhiko!
You're too slow!
Come on!
Hold on!
Too slow!
Catch him!
You're weak! Too weak!
Where are you going?
Over here!
That hurt!
Only stupid people join NOX!
Shut up!
I'm stupid because I was born as a CURIO!
It's because I'm stuck here!
Do you know what CURIO is?
What?
It means antique.
It's a discriminating term.
For real?
That pisses me off.
You dummy! You don't know anything!
Shut up!
Don't sign up! Alright?
Don't sign up!
We won't!
Bye bye!
Shut up! Flat chest!
Shut up!
Geez...
He really is an idiot.
If he put up with it then he could make money selling meat and vegetables.
He can also watch TV.
He can drive a car too.
There will be all kinds of new things coming in.
Is that okay?
Of course!
We've been enduring this until now.
Everyone is going to have a nice life together.
We want that don't we?
I improved it!
This will protect the back of the head!
I'm sorry for calling you out here.
You are a person of interest.
This is my little sister and news reporter Sadako.
Nice to meet you. I'm Sadako.
I should have chosen a less flashy name...
Hey...
Can you talk to me for a little bit?
I'm curious about people of the sun.
How does that sound?
Communication is permitted again.
You can talk about anything.
That's fine...
Thanks!
This is a gift. Here you go.
Where is your thank you?
You say thank you when you get something from someone.
Words are also a gift.
Thank you.
Sadako!
We don't want to be seen by people, so please get in the car.
I'll talk to your father about old times.
Kaneda-kun! The key.
Call your big brother by his first name!
Wanna drive?
You haven't done it before right?
You can step on the gas a little harder.
It will automatically control the speed.
Umm...
Can you stop staring at me?
What is this?
My mother became a NOX member when I was three.
She abandoned my father and me.
She said she wanted to leave the village.
She didn't want to live a poor life.
It seems like she said that.
I was always crying, my friend's mother gave this to me.
When I get lonely, she told me to hold on to it.
What is her name?
Junko-san.
She's a good person huh?
It doesn't hurt at all does it?
I polished it a ton!
Also the back...
Here...
And here.
Light will come through the slits.
I know that!
Damn it!
If only I had a solder!
A solder? What is that?
It's used to join and mold metal.
You're from NOX and don't know what it is?
Unlike Curio, we have a better division of labor.
Don't say CURIO!
Don't say Curio!
Why not?
It's a discriminatory term!
We don't call ourselves Curio!
Then what do you call yourselves?
Humans.
Hey Sadoko-san...
You're my Mom aren't you?
How did you know?
I don't really get it but...
When you touched me, I got that feeling.
For you to find out when you don't really know is amazing.
You're a smart girl.
I thought about killing my Mom if I ever saw her!
I'd hit her a ton!
And kick her!
And say awful things to her!
I'd push her down from a high place!
I'm frustrated!
I was abandoned!
Thanks for today.
If you'd like...
Come to my house and have some fun next time.
Are you trying to take away my daughter too?
Soichi...
You've gotten so...
I've gotten old huh?
I'm old aren't I?
It's been 16 years since you've gone.
Yuu has...
Don't say her name!
You don't have that qualification!
Get in!
Ouch!
Do you want to join NOX?
After you met your Mom, you wanna be a NOX?
Stop it!
You can live a good life there can't you?
You can make friends and have a good job.
Get ready to leave and pack your bags!
Shut up!
I'm sorry about the other day!
Reiko was in the wrong.
I don't know if it's her motherly instinct or what.
Even if she abandoned her, it's still her daughter.
Kaneda-kun!
How old were you when you became a NOX member?
I was 17.
How did it feel?
Refreshed is the perfect word for it.
When I opened my eyes, the scenery and my vision changed...
And I felt like everything was under the control of logic.
I was fully able to conquer myself.
I was born into it so I don't really understand.
Seiji-san...
What are you so anxious about?
Reiko says she wants to adopt a Curio child.
Nox's low birth rate is a fact.
That is true...
I can't get rid of the prejudice behind Curio.
I'm the same way.
They are too attached to their feelings and relationships.
That's why they can't escape the poverty and violence.
I'd take care of an adopted son.
What's wrong?
Murai is back!
Murai?
Yes! Murai!
It's Murai?
Yeah!
Where?
They're in the foothills!
What are you doing?
Why is it always just the adults?
There's things that children shouldn't know!
Go home damn it!
Stop screwing with me!
Don't treat me like a child!
You're a child aren't you?
I'm not a kid!
In Shikoku... It's much worse than what we thought.
All of the rumors are false!
They're not living good lives in Shikoku?
We're lucky that we left so soon.
The rest of them are suffering...
War and plunder has caused many deaths.
Some eldery women have even starved to death.
Fortunately the children still have a chance to become NOX.
Become NOX?
They have a hard time giving birth.
They have no choice but to adopt.
Many children have been adopted in Shikoku legally.
Well but...
The children are guaranteed to live as NOX members.
They don't have to worry about it.
Is that what NOX gave you?
Isn't that Sake?
Katsuya...
Umm...
Where is Katsuya?
I don't know.
What are we going to do now?
We're not going to do anything.
The people who left have come back. That's all.
Go on without me.
I remembered something.
Hey! Soichi!
Come get a drink!
What is it?
This...
Does this mean what I think it does?
Wasn't she always reluctant?
She said that she was going to revitalize the village...
Everyone just came back...
Today is the last day right?
Please.
Soichi.
Soichi!
Hey...Pops!
What happened with the application form?
Why are you doing this on your own?
Who asked you to do that?
It's a lottery.
You don't know if you'll get chosen or not.
I told you that I don't want to be a NOX member!
Why did you do it on your own?
This village is done for.
If you have even the slightest bit of chance...
You don't know that!
It's because of that, isn't it Dad?
You're trying to kick me out of the house right?
Then you can live together with Junko-san!
In that case, you should just get married to her!
Junko-san has always been waiting for it!
But like...
You don't have to care about what other people think of her! Just be with her!
That way I can leave the house peacefully!
Why did you do this on your own?
You know that I don't want to be a Nox member...
Why do things always turn out like this?
That's why Mom left you!
Good evening.
What can I do for you?
Umm...
I would like to go here.
In order to go into NOX territory, you need to schedule it one week in advance.
Not just anyone can go in.
They said if I showed you this I could get in.
Hold on a second please.
Souga Reiko-san.
They are spouses that serve in the district government.
You should get in with this.
I'll confirm it.
Yeah.
It will be fine if she comes.
I'll come and pick her up right away.
This is a three hour visa.
The consequences will be severe if it times out so please be cautious.
Go one Kilometer ahead and there's an old bus stop.
It seems like she's going to pick you up there.
I'll hold on to this for you.
Thanks.
Be safe.
It's time!
Is there any way you can secretly invalidate it?
I can't.
They're watching us.
The 8th district!
This year's minors...
Will get the NOX conversion surgery.
The applicants for residency are two people.
I'm sending the application now.
Yes? Hello?
Did you get it?
It's done?
It's done already?
Yeah.
The results came right away.
If you told me about this sooner, I could have arranged for you to stay over.
Why did you do this all of the sudden?
I want to ask you something.
If that's what you are talking about then it's true.
The Shikoku region was a total failure.
It's a pity that companies were investing heavily into them with high expectations.
The ending result was faction struggles and chaos among the Curio.
I want to confirm it with my own eyes.
If you want to go no matter what, then I don't mind granting that request.
It's just...
After you arrive in Shikoku the only thing you will see is despair and violence.
Yuu...
I have a plan.
Shit...
You could separate the pieces.
But light will get in right?
Attach the adapter.
I know that!
You're so annoying with all your blabbering.
You seem a little impatient today Tetsuhiko.
The results for the lottery are coming out.
Shit!
What a mess!
I'm sorry Tetsuhiko.
It was no good.
You can try again next year, okay?
How did I fail?
Let's go home for today okay?
Tetsuhiko.
You can do it again next year.
You can enjoy the sun this year...
I don't need the sun!
Let's go home Tetsuhiko.
I'll go home on my own! You old hag!
Tetsuhiko!
My uncle killed a NOX member right?
I lost because there's criminals in my family right?
Why was I born in this household!?
You shitty old hag!
Hey Tetsuhiko!
You...You...
You look down on me don't you?
You discriminate us!
I don't need your pity!
Why?
Why wasn't I born as a NOX?
I..I...
I wanted to live a good life and eat yummy food!
I can't stand this place anymore!
I've had enough!
Your uncle said the same thing 10 years ago.
Damn it!!!
Yuu! Where did Yuu go?
Are you looking for Ikuta Yuu-san?
That's right!
Hey! Where did she go?
She went to the other side at around 8pm.
-Yuu... -Hey!
Yuu!
-You can't! -Yuu!
You can't do that!
-You can't go without permission! -Let go!
Stop!
I said let go!
Morning!
Good morning.
Where's everyone else?
Dad wouldn't let them come here.
Yuu-chan is going to become a NOX right?
Where is Tetsuhiko?
He's depressed.
He'll come back to work in a few days.
Are you okay?
Yuu-chan...
Go home for today.
But...
Go and prepare lunch with your Dad.
Okay?
Yeah...
You said that you would live together with us right?
Your shoes!
Why?
Why are you running away?
I wasn't the one who did it.
But you were chosen!
I haven't decided to become NOX yet.
Then why were you in that NOX place!?
Shut up!
Don't yell at me!
You...
You're going to become NOX right?
My Dad decided that!
Are you going to leave me? Hey!
I won't forgive you!
You don't have to forgive me!
Don't screw with me!
Stop it! Stop it!
No!!
Let go!
Yuu!
-No! -Get back here!
-I like you! -Stop!
-I always have... -Stop!
You said that you would be together with us!
-Stop it Takumi! -Yuu!
-Takumi! -You said we've be together right?
No!
Stop it!
Stop!
Please let me go!
Takumi!
Stop it!
Yuu!
You little shit!
Hold on damn it!
Hey!
Damn you!
Soichi!!
Hey! Soichi!
What have you done?
-Damn you! -Stop it!
Soichi!
Let me go damn it!
Stop it!
Get over here! Explain this to everyone!
Hey! Sit down!
Why did you do something like this?
Huh?
Say something!
Hey!!
I don't blame you for losing the lottery.
I'm going to go running.
I'm sorry about saying those awful things the other day.
It's rare for someone to become my friend.
If you'd like...you can hold on to this for me.
There's no point in me having it.
Tetsuhiko...
Do you want to go on a trip with me?
A trip? Where to?
Anywhere is fine!
Japan is very vast!
Look!
It's different than the one I see at school...
This is NOX's map.
Is there anywhere you'd like to go?
I want to see the ocean.
We can go.
We can go by car.
But you can't in the afternoon....
That's why you can drive in the afternoon and I can drive in the night.
I work all the time.
This is unprecedented.
A NOX and Curio trip.
You don't have to say CURIO.
Alright!
Let's plan this out!
Maybe someone can sponsor us!
That why we'll get money for it!
That's a joke right?
They can't do something like that.
I'm a CURIO.
I need to apologize...
I need to apologize to Tetsuhiko...
It's fine...
-I need to apologize! -Yuu-chan!
Yuu-chan!
Stay back!
This is my problem.
That's not true!
NOX isn't perfect!
But everyone goes to a proper school right?
I'm different than you.
I can't make something like this.
The schools that you can get into are based on your IQ that you are born with.
The assigned work is also determined by a fitness test you take as a child.
You say it's alright but in the end it's just separation by class.
In order to increase the birth rate...
Personal freedom is useless compared to economic rationalization.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about me.
I want to see a world I've never seen before.
That's why I want to go on a trip.
Shit!
You!
Are you Tetsuhiko?
Who are you?
It's me! It's me!
Have you forgotten your uncle's face?
You've gotten so big!
You haven't been eating good food but have gotten so big!
You must be a fool!
What?
Did my nephew do something?
Isn't the sanction over?
What the hell is this?
Surveillance?
No...
For crying out loud!
This village hasn't changed at all!
What have they been doing for 10 years?
Umm...
Drinking while driving a motorcycle is illegal.
Look at the full moon!
Just kidding!
Oh, this?
Umm...can you let me go?
That's impossible...
Let him go!
He's my friend!
Friend?
With this guy?
You're being deceived.
You're stupid so you've been brainwashed.
Right?
That's not true!
Your friend here is trying to act cool with a Curio friend...this bastard!
We aren't pets...
Everyone one of them are the same!
Their hearts are stones!
You messed up the village didn't you?
He's the same as them!
You are...
Okudera!
Shut up!
Get back! It's dangerous!
Your wounds will get infected if they touch his blood!
Umm...I think you're getting the wrong idea...
-We... -Enough!!
You lie to us with your rhetoric!
Your specialty is speaking.
That's your ace!
For now..
Can you let me out of this?
I won't file an assault incident.
You bastard...
Don't you dare look down on me!
Stop it! Stop it!
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Well...hang in there.
Shit!
Hey! What are you doing!?
What the hell? What the hell?
What the hell is up with him?
Shit!
How do I get this off?
I'll get some help!
I'll open it! I'll open it!
It won't open without my certification!
You can call someone to come from the other side!
It would be bad if someone saw us!
Someone is going to see us!
It's not as simple as economic situations!
Shit!
What are we going to do? If the sun comes out...
Do you have any wire cutters?
Wire cutters?
It can be anything that can cut!
Something that can cut! Something that can cut!
Wire cutters! Wire cutters! Wire cutters!
Wire cutters...wire cutters....wire cutters!
-Tetsuhiko!-Wire cutters!
Tetsuhiko!
What happened Tetsuhiko?
I-I need something that cuts!
-Something that cuts! -Something that cuts?
Why?
Hey!
Tetsuhiko!
Are you okay?
I'm fine!
Katsuya...
Hey, that's scary....what is that?
I was looking a lot for something!
-What's going on? -Please don't touch me!
I'm bleeding!
That was dangerous! Listen to me!
Sorry!
Hold on! Hold on!
You need to be more careful!
Careful? Got it!
Be careful Tetsuhiko!
Ouch!
Shit!
Damn it!
Very shortly...
Shit!
Everyone in the CURIO area...
Hey Tetsuhiko! Let me see it!
Please return immediately.
Geez!
Hurry up!
Very shortly...
Everyone in the CURIO area....
Please return immediately.
Very shortly..
Everyone in the CURIO area...
Hey! It's starting to get brighter!
Please return immediately!
Shut up! I know!
The Mori Mask!
The sun is about to rise.
It's no good! Damn it!
Tetsuhiko!
The Schlalf is in the back!
The Schlaf?
Bring it!
The sun is about to rise.
Schlaf?
The sleeping bag!
Say that sooner!
Sorry...
The Sun is about to rise.
It's okay!
I'll do something about it!
The Sun is about to rise.
Yuu! Yuu!
Hurry up Yuu!
I know that!
That's hot!
The sun is impossible....
What happens if the Sun hits you?
It will probally be the same as the person who died 10 years ago.
The sun is about to rise.
Damn it!
The Sun is about to rise.
Tetsuhiko!
A rope!
Tie my arm with a rope!
Tie it!
Hurry up!
Alright...
Cut off my hand with your axe!
Cut off my hand!
I can't! I can't! I can't!
I'm strong.
Rather than being burned alive...
I will be able to take less damage!
Hurry up.
Hurry up Tetsuhiko!
Tetsuhiko! Tetsuhiko!
Tetsuhiko...
We're going on a trip right?
You're the only one who can do this.
Be careful not to get my blood on you...
Please...
The Mori mask...
I'll definitely save you!
-Stabilize it! -I know that!
That's dangerous!
What are you doing?
Stay back Dad!
He has the Mori mask on!
-My uncle... -We need to hurry!
-Your uncle? -My uncle...
You can't!
You can't open it Dad! Don't open it!
-Hurry up! -You guys...
What have you done!?
Hold on! Hold on!
-Cover him with this! -What have you done!?
Don't stop us Dad!
Soichi-san?
Long time no see!
You...
Yuu!
Is that Yuu?
You've gotten so big!
You're a woman now!
Okudera Katsuya!
I've come back from Shikoku!
What's up with you?
It's me!
The picture of my sister shaking hands was published!
She's still alive huh?
Huh?
Is it that guy?
He's still alive huh?
Katsuya!
Why did you come back?
I thought about doing something for this village.
But every one of you haven't changed at all!
You've always been confined in the forest so that's why you're so old school!
I finally gave you guys an opportunity.
Why won't you fight?
I've been reflecting like an idiot for 10 years.
How long are we going to be these people's slaves?
That's dangerous Tetsuhiko!
Stop it Tetsuhiko!
You can't do that Tetsuhiko! Violence is no good!
Don't be fooled by NOX!
Don't screw with me!
This is common in Shikoku!
Stop it!
-Hey Katsuya! -Yes?
Since you came back, why don't you go over to Junko-san's place right away?
Oneechan?
Do you know how she felt for these past 10 years?
Stop it Tetsuhiko...
I know!
You don't know!
You...
You ruined her and this village for 10 years!
You have been brainwshed Soichi-san!
This is NOX's fault!
It's not NOX that ruined this village....
It's you!
And us!
We destroyed it ourselves!
Soichi-san!
You bastard!!
Stop it! Stop it!
Don't touch her Yuu!
Neechan?
Oneechan!
Neechan!
Neechan...
Neechan?
Why didn't you get back here immediately? You shouldn't have come back!
Neechan!
She was worried about you and the village until the very end!
Katsuya!!
Junko-san...
Junko-san!
Mom?
I'll never forgive you...
Katsuya!
You bastard!
Katsuya you bastard!
It's because of you the village got ruined!
Don't come over here Soichi!
Don't come here.
Stay back!
Don't come here!
Don't interfere!
We've made our decision!
Dad...
Dad!
Dad! Dad! Dad!
Shit!
I'm going to die in a place like this?
In a place like this?
Shit!
NOX's blood!
No! No!
I'm going to get infected!
No!
You bastard!
I'll never forgive you!
You ruined this village!
Dad!
Hey Dad!
You can't go!
You can't!
Tetsuhiko!
You can't go!
Tetsuhiko...
Don't let him go!
You bastard!
-I'll kill you! -Tetsuhiko...
Tetsuhiko....
Katsuya!
Is he dead?
Don't worry.
We'll give you an injection first.
Then after that, Reiko's blood will be pumped into you.
Then it will be over.
It's not scary.
Alright...
Inhale it slowly please...
We're starting...
Are you okay now?
They helped me deal with it as an accident.
Is that right?
Are you okay?
Yeah!
How does it feel to be changed?
It feels kinda refreshing.
I feel like I was a fool for worrying about it.
There is a constant feeling of power flowing in my body...
I feel very free!
It makes me feel courageous.
If I would have converted earlier, I could have done a lot of stuff.
I was always thinking about what I can change....
Why haven't I done anything?
I feel like I wasted my youth.
You told me to hurry up and become NOX too!
I'm going to study more and more!
I'll work hard for people like you and Tetsuhiko!
It would be good if everyone was happier and lived a better life right?
What's wrong Dad?
What?
Why are you crying?
I don't know.
I don't know why...
What's going on?
What's wrong Dad?
Even if you go to the other side...
Become excellent!
Yeah!
Be healthy!
You're healthier than us now though...
Be careful!
Yeah!
You'll be together with your new family.
Yeah.
It's okay if you forget about me and the village!
That's not true.
Go now!
They're waiting for you!
Yeah!
Thanks for everything Dad!
It's okay!
You won't catch anything by a handshake.
Hey!
Oh crap!
There is a road that's not on the map!
Where is it?
Go where the sun is. That's the west.
There's no mistaking it!
Then it's a right!
Most likely.
I can't see it though.
Morishige!
Does your arm hurt?
If you can avoid the bumpy roads as much as possible, I'd appreciate it.
This car is old so it's quite bumpy.
It's been repaired quite a bit.
I bought this with my salary.
Alright....
We'll change shifts when the Sun goes down!
Yeah!
Be careful!
Thanks for watching! Like my Facebook page at Rjgman56 japanese drama subs fanpage!