♪ SNAG IT
♪ SHARE IT
♪ DON'T FORGET YOU GOT TO SHARE IT ♪
♪ REMEMBER, YOU DON'T HAVE A LEASE ON THAT BALL ♪
♪ TOGETHER, PASS IT
♪ THROW IT
♪ BUT BE SURE THAT YOU DON'T BLOW IT ♪
♪ REMEMBER, YOU DON'T HAVE A LEASE ON THAT BALL ♪
♪ DON'T GO TOO FAR, YOU'RE NOT ALONE ♪
♪ EACH MAN'S GOT TO BE A PART OF IT ALL ♪
♪ DON'T BE A STAR OUT ON YOUR OWN ♪
♪ PASS THAT BALL, OR DIVIDED WE FALL ♪
♪ REMINDING IF I ASK IT
♪ TEAMWORK'S THE WAY TO MAKE A BASKET ♪
♪ REMEMBER, YOU'LL HAVE A LEASE ON THAT BALL ♪
TAKE ME BACK HOME.
I DON'T WANT TO BE HERE. I WANT TO GO HOME.
TAKE ME HOME. YEAH, I WANT TO GO HOME.
SECOND QUARTER, PITTSBURGH ARENA,
AND AGAIN, THE PITTSBURGH PYTHONS BEING BOMBED.
WITH THEIR SEASON RECORD NOW AT A DISMAL 10-26,
THEY'RE BEHIND HERE, 65-47.
THERE'S A GOOD SCREEN BY TUCKER.
AROUND IT COMES MOSES GUTHRIE, THAT MILLION DOLLAR BABY,
BUT HE EXPOSES THE BALL, THEY STEAL IT,
THROW THE LENGTH OF THE COURT,
AND JOHNNY JONES PUTS IN ANOTHER DEUCE.
OH, NOW IT'S 67-47,
AND THE PYTHONS JUST CAN'T GET ANYTHING GOING AT ALL.
[CROWD BOOS]
MATTER WITH YOU, FOOL?
LOOK AT YOU, THREW THE MAN THE BALL.
EASE OFF, MAN.
OFF? THERE AIN'T NO THROWIN',
AS FAR AS I COULD TELL.
IF I COULD DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT, I WOULD.
ALREADY DID. MILLION DOLLAR BABY, MY ASS.
I WISH THEY'D TRADE ME OUT OF THIS MESS.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO. HUSTLE.
HEY, MAN.
UNDER THE BASKET, WIDE OPEN, IS TUCKER.
GUTHRIE'S GOT THE BALL. HE WILL NOT GIVE IT TO HIM.
HE PUTS UP AN 18-FOOTER THAT COMES OFF THE HEEL OF THE RIM.
NOW A LONG FACE, AND A VERY UNHAPPY MAN,
MOSES GUTHRIE STARTS DOWN THE FLOOR.
[FUNK MUSIC PLAYS]
OOH, MISS BRANDY, HONEY,
THESE PYTHON CHILDREN ARE TRULY TIRED.
[WHISTLE]
[COACH] DEFENSE. DEFENSE.
HEY, WAY TO GO, MOSES. THAT'S STAYING ALIVE, MAN.
[COACH] D-UP. STAY THERE.
I WAS WIDE OPEN, MAN. WHY'D YOU PASS IT TO HIM?
HEY, GREAT. WAY TO SHOOT, MOSE. HOW TO GO.
FINGERTIP CONTROL. HOW TO GO, MOSE.
IT'S TOO LITTLE TOO LATE.
TOO BAD HE DOESN'T MAKE MORE OF A HABIT OF IT.
TWICE A NIGHT WOULD BE NICE.
ALL RIGHT NOW, DEFENSE. DEFENSE. GET THAT TURNOVER.
AAH!
SORRY, COACH.
BRANDY...
HUH?
WATCH THIS. WATCH THIS.
WHOO!
HEY! HEY, YOU GUYS!
HEY, YOU GUYS!
Y'ALL WANT SOME OF THIS?
IF YOU GOT IT,
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO WITH IT,
PROBABLY DROP IT OUT OF BOUNDS.
AAH HA HA!
[WHISTLE]
TUCK-TUCKER.
TRADE ME.
TRADE ME, MAN.
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
[WHISTLE]
TUCKER, PUT SOME WATER WITH IT.
WHY DON'T YOU LEARN HOW TO COACH, TURKEY?
YOUR MAMA.
OOH. OOH.
O.K., YOU DEADBEATS, WE GOT TWO MINUTES.
HEY, GUTHRIE, I WANT YOU
TO TAKE A FEW MORE SHOTS OUT THERE.
HEY, MAYBE I OUGHT TO SIT, COACH. I'M COLD.
I DON'T CARE. SHOOT. THEY'RE LEAVING YOU OPEN.
SO HE'S OPEN.
THEY DON'T WANT TO WASTE A MAN
PLAYING ONE ON NONE.
TUCKER, WHY DON'T YOU STAY OUT OF THIS?
HEY, YOU MAY BE JIVING THESE CHUMPS,
BUT YOU AIN'T JIVING ME.
I AIN'T JIVING NOBODY.
HEY, NAME'S TUCKER, NOT SUCKER.
I KNOW YOUR PROBLEM, FRANCHISE.
HEY, THE MAN IS ONLY INTERESTED
IN PLAYING FOR THE BUCKS,
THE SPENDING KIND.
WHY YOU ALWAYS ON MY CASE, MAN?
I AIN'T SEEN YOU MISS NO MEALS.
YO, WHY DON'T YOU CATS JUST COOL IT, O.K.?
TAKE A WALK, MIDGET.
OH. HEY, MAN,
WHY DON'T YOU QUIT ALL THE FATMOUTHING?
WELL, TRADE ME, SUCKER.
I DON'T NEED THIS MISERY.
YOU BETTER LEARN ANOTHER TUNE.
HEY, I'M SICK AND TIRED OF ALL THIS CRAP
ABOUT HIS GODDAMNED SLUMP.
YEAH, BUT YOUR HAND ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
SHIT, YOU TREAT HIM LIKE HE'S BABY JESUS.
MAN, YOU KNOW WE IN YOUR CORNER.
OH, MAN.
TUCKER'S RIGHT, MAN. THIS AIN'T SHIT.
THIS IS A GODDAMN CIRCUS.
SAVE YOUR FIGHT FOR THE GAME, GUYS.
I'M TRYING TO GET YOU GUYS A RAISE.
I DON'T NEED NO COACH.
I HEARD THAT. GET OUT OF HERE.
TELL THAT TOOTHLESS GENERAL MANAGER HE CAN HAVE THIS JOB.
YES, SIR, MR. TUCKER.
AND HIS MOSE BABY, TOO.
'CAUSE TUCKER DON'T WANT NO PARTS OF IT.
YES, SIR, AND IF IT'S CONVENIENT,
I'D LIKE TO INVITE YOU BY FOR DINNER
ON THE WEEKEND. MY SISTER'S COMING OVER.
OH, MAN, GET OUT MY FACE.
HEY, TUCK, WAIT. HEY, HEY, HEY, GUY.
HEY, GUY, WHERE'S THE OLD SPIRIT, HUH?
WHEN THE GOING GETS TOUGH, THE TOUGH GET GOING.
RIGHT? RIGHT?
WHAT YOU TALKING ABOUT?
GULP-- I SWALLOWED MY GUM.
I SWALLOWED MY GUM. HELP.
THAT NIGGER'S CRAZY.
WHERE YOU GOING?
GOT AN EMERGENCY HERE.
YOU TOOTHLESS, SIMPLEMINDED TURKEY.
SAY, SAY, GUYS.
LOOK I CAN STRAIGHTEN IT OUT.
I'M GOING RIGHT UP TO THE FRONT OFFICE.
I'M GOING TO TRY TO STRAIGHTEN IT OUT.
HEY, LITTLE BUDDY.
LOOKING KIND OF LOW, MOSES.
MAN, I'M NOT PULLING MY WEIGHT.
JUST CAN'T FIGURE ANYTHING OUT.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST COME OFF IT?
CAN'T YOU SEE? JUST ONE MAN ALONE
DON'T MAKE A BASKETBALL TEAM.
JUST ONE MAN ALONE--
HEY, THAT JUST DON'T BREAK IT.
LOOK, FORGET ABOUT TUCKER.
YOU'LL BEAT THIS SLUMP. I KNOW YOU WILL.
I APPRECIATE THAT, PARTNER.
I'M A PISCES, MAN.
WE NEED A LITTLE STROKE FROM TIME TO TIME.
GUESS I SHOULD HAVE CHECKED MY HOROSCOPE THIS MORNING.
HOROSCOPE?
WAIT. WAIT A MINUTE.
NOW, YOU TALKING ABOUT ASTROLOGY, RIGHT?
YEAH. YEAH, I CAN DIG THAT.
♪ YOU MOVE JUST LIKE THE SUPERSTAR YOU ARE ♪
♪ YOU WEAVE YOUR MAGIC FEELING FROM AFAR ♪
♪ YOU'RE LIKE A DANCER
♪ ALL ALONE ON STAGE
♪ MOSES, MOSES
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE
NOW FOR MURRAY SPORTS AND TONIGHT'S SCORES.
HI, EVERYBODY. I'M MURRAY. LET'S TALK SPORTS.
MURRAY SPORTS. HOW ARE YOU, EVERYBODY?
WELL, THE GOVERNOR HASN'T DECLARED IT,
BUT THERE'S A DISASTER AREA
DOWN AT PACIFIC ARENA TONIGHT.
I SAW IT WITH MY OWN EYES.
THE PITTSBURGH PYTHONS,
THE DWELLERS IN THE CELLAR RIGHT NOW,
FOUND A NEW WAY TO LOSE TONIGHT.
THEY ACTUALLY GAVE ONE AWAY.
COACH WILBUR DELANY, I'M SURE, NOT ONLY THREW IN THE TOWEL,
I BET HE TOSSED IN THE WHOLE DARN LINEN CLOSET...
OH, TYRONE, WOULD YOU HELP ME HERE A MINUTE?
INSTEAD OF FLYING DOWN HERE,
THEY COULD HAVE STAYED UP IN BEANTOWN
AND MAILED THIS ONE IN WITH THAT KIND OF A DISASTER.
WHAT ABOUT STAR MOSES GUTHRIE?
THE MILLION DOLLAR BONUS BABY
IS HAVING A MILLION DOLLAR SLUMP RIGHT NOW,
AND I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED IF BEFORE TOO LONG,
HE'LL BE PAYING THE FANS TO WATCH HIM,
INSTEAD OF VICE VERSA.
♪ WHO MYSTIFIES THE MASTERS EVERY TIME? ♪
♪ WHO SHINES ABOVE THE REST AND BLOWS MY MIND? ♪
♪ WHO FLOATS AROUND THE COURT? ♪
♪ IT'S SO...OH BIG-TIME
♪ MOSES, MOSES
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE
♪ MOSES, YOU'RE THE ONE
♪ HMM-MM-MM
♪ MOSES, MOSES
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE
♪ MOSES, YOU'RE THE ONE
♪ HMM-MM-MM
♪ OH, OH, OH
♪ MOSES, MOSES
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE
YOUNG EINSTEIN,
IF I'M NOT INTERRUPTING SOME GREAT THOUGHT,
COULD YOU JUST PUT YOUR BRAIN ON HOLD,
OH, A COUPLE OF MINUTES
AND GIVE ME A HAND OUT HERE IN THIS KITCHEN?
HEY, SIS, DIG.
YOU KNOW THAT HOROSCOPES ARE FREQUENTLY SET UP BY ASTROLOGERS
FOR STATES, CORPORATIONS?
AND EVEN WHOLE NATIONS USE CHARTS TO PREDICT PROSPERITY.
HEY, MAN, THIS GETS INTO SOME DEEP SHIT.
COME ON, TOBY, MAN. I'M ONTO SOMETHING HERE.
WHAT I WANT YOU TO GET ONTO, TYRONE,
IS OUT IN THE KITCHEN.
ONE OF YOUR FRUMPY SOCKS HAS STUFFED UP MY SINK.
TOBY, THIS IS IMPORTANT.
I MEAN, WE REALLY GOT SOMETHING HERE.
WHAT?
WELL, ASTROLOGY CAN DO FOR BASKETBALL
WHAT THE, UH, LIGHT BULB DID FOR NIGHT BASEBALL.
CAN YOU DIG?
YES, I CAN DIG, TY.
I CAN ALSO DIG THAT I AM WORKING MY BUNS OFF
DOWN AT THAT FACTORY, AND FOR WHAT? HUH?
SO THAT MAYBE SOMEDAY
WE CAN MOVE OUT OF THIS DUMP.
BELIEVE ME, TOBY, I DIG.
I MEAN, THAT'S YOUR THING-- CAPRICORN--
ALL WORRIED ABOUT PROVIDING.
TYRONE, PLEASE BE SERIOUS WITH ME FOR A MINUTE.
BUT I AM SERIOUS.
RIGHT HERE--ASTROLOGY.
'CAUSE, SEE, THERE'S SOMETHING IN THIS
THAT I KNOW COULD TURN THIS TEAM AROUND.
♪ SOMEWHERE THERE'S HEAVEN ♪
♪ SOMEWHERE THERE'S LOVE
BESIDES, BY THE TIME
YOU'RE BACK ON PLANET EARTH,
I'LL HAVE FIXED IT MYSELF.
♪ NO ONE CAN TELL YOU
♪ WHICH WAY TO GO
♪ YOU'LL NEVER FIND AN EASY ROAD ♪
♪ SEARCHIN' FOR A POT OF GOLD ♪
♪ WHEN YOUR LUCK IS DOWN AND NO ONE CARES ♪
♪ JUST BELIEVE IN YOU, AND YOU'RE HALFWAY THERE ♪
♪ OH, LISTEN TO YOUR HEART
♪ NEVER FEAR
♪ AND FOLLOW EVERY DREAM
♪ FOREVER
♪ LISTEN TO YOUR HEART
♪ LAY STILL
♪ AND FOLLOW EVERY DREAM
♪ WHEN CLOUDS APPEAR
♪ I FELT THE SUMMER
♪ I SEEN THE SPRING
♪ EVERY TIME I TURN AROUND ♪
♪ I'M WISHIN' FOR ANOTHER DREAM ♪
COME OVER HERE, LITTLE MAN.
♪ WHO KNOWS THE ANSWER?
♪ WHO HOLDS THE KEY?
♪ IS IT IN A STORYBOOK?
♪ OR IS IT IN YOU AND ME
♪ YOU CAN FIND THE WORLD YOU'RE LOOKING FOR ♪
♪ DON'T GIVE UP UNTIL YOU'RE THROUGH THE DOOR ♪
♪ OH, LISTEN TO YOUR HEART ♪
♪ LAY STILL
SO, WHAT CAN MONA DO FOR YOU?
UH, I'M TYRONE MILLMAN.
I PHONED ABOUT AN HOUR AGO--
THE TERM PAPER.
TERM PAPER? AN HOUR AGO?
OH, YES. I WAS EXPECTING SOMEONE A LITTLE BIT OLDER,
BUT YOU'RE RATHER CUTE.
ARIES, RIGHT?
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
OH, ARIES IS THE CHILD OF THE ZODIAC, VERY IDEALISTIC.
YOU KNOW, THAT MARS ASPECT IN YOUR VOICE--
STRAIGHTFORWARD, DIRECT--
AND THAT SMILE...
IT'S VERY RAM.
WHY ARE YOU LYING?
I MEAN, ARIES ARE SUCH TERRIBLE LIARS, AND...
WELL, JUST COME CLEAN.
THIS ISN'T FOR ANY SCHOOL PROJECT, IS IT?
UH, NO.
SEE, THE ONLY REASON I SAID THAT
WAS--WAS BECAUSE I WANTED YOU TO TRY A BASKETBALL TEAM,
AND I WASN'T SURE WHETHER OR NOT YOU'D BE INTERESTED.
OH, BASKETBALL.
WELL, I'LL HAVE YOU KNOW
I CHARTED AN ENTIRE YEAR OF DOG RACING,
NOT TO MENTION THE SUPER BOWL.
YOU KNOW, SPORTS ARE LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE.
THEY ALL DEPEND ON THE STARS.
YOU KNOW, GIVEN THE PROPER INFORMATION,
I CAN CHART PRACTICALLY ANYTHING.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO BE OUR TEAM ASTROLOGER?
OH, I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
I MEAN, ALL THOSE BIG GUYS
RUNNING AROUND IN LITTLE SATIN SUITS
AND...CROWDS AND NOISE AND...
SWEAT SOCKS.
NO, NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
I MEAN, I HAVE SUCH A WEEK AHEAD OF ME.
THEY'RE ALL PISCES.
ALL PISCES?
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
YES.
YOUR CAR IS READY, SIR.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
VERY GOOD, SIR.
IF YOU'RE READY TO COME DOWN, YOUR CAR IS WAITING.
WHAT? HELLO?
BETTER BELIEVE I'M COMING DOWN.
[HORN HONKS]
TYRONE. WHAT THE HELL YOU DOING IN MY CAR, MAN?
HOPING TO PROVE YOU A POINT.
THE ONLY POINT YOU GOING TO PROVE
IS THAT I AIN'T ALWAYS
THE SWEET, MELLOW DUDE EVERYBODY MAKES ME OUT.
GET OUT. COME ON, GET OUT.
WOULD YOU JUST GIVE ME A CHANCE TO EXPLAIN?
O.K., MY MAN. YOU'RE IN THE DRIVER SEAT.
RUN IT BY ME.
YOU KNOW, MOSES,
I COULD DEAL WITH THESE WHEELS.
OH, YOU CAN, HUH? YES, SIR.
THEN HOW COME WE AIN'T MOVING?
WE AIN'T MOVING FOR THE SAME REASON
THE PYTHONS AIN'T MOVING.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WELL, ABOUT TEAMWORK.
HEY, LOOK, I NEED TO BORROW YOUR FEET
FOR THIS PART.
MY FEET? COME ON, MAN, I GOT THINGS I GOT TO DO.
AW, NAH, NAH, NAH. COME ON,
YOU WORK THE PEDALS, AND I'LL STEER.
YOU'LL DO WHAT?
PILOT TO CO-PILOT, HIT THE GAS.
[ENGINE STARTS]
SEE, WE WORK GOOD AS A TEAM,
SO HOW COME THE PYTHONS DON'T WORK AS GOOD AS US?
ANSWER THAT QUESTION,
AND YOU GOT YOURSELF A JOB AS THE COACH.
OH, I KNOW WHY.
TO ME, IT'S VERY CLEAR.
SEE, IT'S BECAUSE
THEY'RE ASTROLOGICALLY INCOMPATIBLE.
THEY'RE WHAT?
ZODIAC, MAN.
SLOW DOWN.
SEE, YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT PULLED MY COAT LAST NIGHT
TALKING ABOUT YOUR PISCES TRIP.
YOU SEE, WHAT WE GOT TO DO
IS SURROUND YOU WITH CATS
THAT ARE ON YOUR SAME PLANE.
THE PISCES, MAN.
I MEAN, WHAT WE GOT NOW
ARE FOUR LEOS, A GEMINI--
THAT JUST DOESN'T MAKE COSMIC SENSE.
SLOW DOWN. SLOW DOWN.
ALL THE CATS ARE CRYING TO BE TRADED ANYWAY, RIGHT?
I MEAN, THEY'RE READY TO PAY TILSON TO CUT THEM LOOSE,
SO THAT LEAVES YOU.
I MEAN, YOU'RE THE FRANCHISE.
NOW, UH, SAY YOU GOT A COUPLE OF CHICKENS--
A ROOSTER AND SOME HENS.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG WITH THE ROOSTER.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG WITH THE CHICKENS.
THEY JUST DON'T SEEM TO GET ALONG.
GET RID OF THE CHICKENS.
YOU GET SOME CHICKENS
THAT AREN'T ON A ROOSTER'S TRIP.
SLAM DUNK. HA HA HA. WE GOT EGGS.
IF THAT AIN'T ABOUT THE DUMBEST IDEA.
YEAH, ABOUT AS DUMB AS A 14-YEAR-OLD
CRUISING PITTSBURGH IN A ROLLS ROYCE.
HA HA HA HA.
TYRONE, WHAT MADE YOU THINK I'D POSSIBLY GO FOR THIS?
SIMPLE. PISCES ALWAYS RESPOND TO LOGIC.
HA.
[HORN HONKS]
MY LITTLE BROTHER'S UNWORRIED.
OF COURSE HE'S UNWORRIED.
HE'S NEVER HAD TO WORRY IN HIS LIFE.
EVERYTHING WAS DONE FOR HIM.
MY FATHER LOVED HIM BETTER THAN ME.
HE NEVER HAD TO WORK A DAY IN HIS LIFE.
I WAS THE GUY WHO KEPT THE DAMN THING TOGETHER,
BUILT THE BUSINESS UP, DID IT ALL.
WELL, LITTLE BROTHER, I TELL YOU SOMETHING,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO WORRY NOW.
OH, YES, YOU LITTLE TRUST FUND RETARD.
JEEZ, I'M UPSET, HUH?
I CAN SEE HIM PLAYING WITH THAT BIG COLOR TV SET.
OH, LOOKING AT THE BASKETBALL TEAM,
JUMPING UP AND DOWN.
OH, YEAH, HE'S GETTING HIS JOLLIES--
LOOK, LOOK, LOOK--
AND TAKING A BIG DUMP IN HIS DIAPERS,
AND THEN SAYING, "HEY, WHERE'S MY CREDIT CARD?
I WANT TO BUY A TEAM. I WANT TO BUY A TEAM."
BEGGING YOUR PARDON, SIR,
BUT YOUR BROTHER DID INHERIT
80 MILLION AND THE FAMILY ESTATE.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING, FRIESMAN.
DON'T RUB ME THE WRONG WAY.
I'LL HAVE YOU RUBBED OUT.
THIS, INCIDENTALLY, HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH MONEY.
IT HAS TO DO WITH THE FAMILY NAME.
THAT'S WHAT'S AT STAKE RIGHT NOW--
THE FAMILY NAME,
WHICH IS DAMNED IMPORTANT. UNDERSTAND?
WHEN I GO ON OUT THERE TO THE CLUB
AND THOSE PEOPLE OUT THERE,
MAKING A MOCKERY OF THIS THING
AND LAUGHING AT ME, CALLING ME AN ASSHOLE.
OH, MY, MY, WHAT A PRESENTATION.
EXCELLENT. CONGRATULATIONS.
OH, MY, MY, YOU'RE REFRESHING.
YOU'RE REALLY REFRESHING. WALLY...
YOUR PRESENTATIONS IN THE PAST
HAVE BEEN A JOKE,
USING THOSE GRAPHS YOU HAD IN THE PAST
AND--AND POINTERS. OH, OH.
HOW ABOUT A COUPLE OF TRAINS
TO PLAY WITH? HMM?
REALLY, H.S., WE HAVE A MAJOR CRISIS TO DEAL WITH.
PLAYER WALKOUT AND NO COACH.
WE CAN'T AFFORD TO WASTE TIME.
WE'VE GOT TO ACT FAST OR ELSE.
HMM. FAST.
HOW FAST IS THE SPEED OF LIGHT?
WELL, THROUGH UNIFORM TRANSPARENT SUBSTANCES,
SUCH AS AIR,
186,000 MILES PER SECOND.
MY, HOW REFRESHING YOU ARE.
BUT IT'S REALLY QUITE SIMPLE.
I MEAN, IT'S A MATTER OF BASIC COMPATIBILITY.
COMPATIBILITY--
YOU'RE THINKING RIGHT ALONG MY LINES.
YES, YES. I REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
I HEARD THAT WORD.
FUNNY THING ABOUT WORDS. IF I RECALL,
IF YOU USE A WORD THREE TIMES A DAY
AND USE IT THREE DAYS A WEEK,
IT BECOMES...YOURS.
YEAH. YEAH, YOU SEE, 'CAUSE THE ANSWER
IS IN THE COSMIC COMPLEXITIES OF THE SITUATION,
LIKE, UM, LIKE SAY, FOR EXAMPLE, THE '69 METS.
OH, YES, YES. UH...
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I HAVE A DOZEN DOUBLES OF TUG McGRAW.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SWAP?
BUT DO YOU KNOW WHAT McGRAW WAS?
OH, YES. HE WAS A RELIEF PITCHER.
HE WAS ALSO A VIRGO.
MR. TILSON, PLEASE.
WE HAVE A MAJOR CRISIS ON THE COURT.
WE SHOULD BE THINKING OF UNLOADING THIS TURKEY.
QUITE FRANKLY,
NOW'S THE TIME TO RESPOND
TO YOUR BROTHER'S LAST OFFER.
I'M SURE HE KNOWS THE TROUBLE WE'RE HAVING.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT MY BROTHER. HE'S AN IDIOT.
ALL HE'S EVER CARED ABOUT
IS MONEY, MONEY, MONEY, MONEY, MONEY.
WELL, ANY IDIOT CAN MAKE MONEY.
IT TAKES SOMEBODY TO MAKE LAUGHTER.
HE'S NEVER MADE ME LAUGH ONCE.
♪ CHANCE OF A LIFETIME
♪ IT'S THE CHANCE OF A LIFETIME, YEAH ♪
♪ DO-DO-DO-DO DO-DO-DO-DO ♪
♪ GIVE IT UP
♪ DO-DO-DO-DO DO-DO-DO-DO-DO ♪
♪ GIVIN' IT ONE MORE TRY
♪ DOIN' IT TILL YOU FIND EVERLASTING PEACE OF MIND ♪
♪ EVERLASTING PEACE OF MIND ♪
♪ KNOWIN' IT'S DO OR DIE
♪ LAYIN' IT ON THE LINE
♪ WHEN YOU KNOW WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND ♪
♪ YOU KNOW WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND ♪
♪ OH, YEAH...
OW! THIS IS JACKHAMMER WASHINGTON,
MRS. W's BOSS BABY SON,
THE DAPPER RAPPER,
THE EBONY WHIPPERSNAPPER.
HO, THE RHYME KING, FOREVER ON THE SCENE.
AW, BUT THE NEXT TIME I SEE Y'ALL,
I WON'T BE SPINNING SIDES. I'LL BE SPINNING BALL.
SO REMEMBER, THIS IS JACKHAMMER,
THE WINDJAMMER,
TAKIN' A TOKE.
♪ CHANCE OF A LIFETIME
DIG MY SMOKE.
♪ YEAH
♪ DO-DO-DO-DO DO-DO-DO-DO ♪
♪ DO-DO-DO-DO-DO DO-DO-DO-DO-DO-DO ♪
♪ CHANCE OF A LIFETIME
♪ YEAH
[BELL CHIMES]
♪ JESUS, WHOA, LORD
♪ COME ON
♪ JESUS, FLOW STRONG THROUGH ME ♪
♪ JESUS, YEAH
♪ JESUS WILL SET YOU FREE ♪
♪ WE NEED YOU, YEAH
♪ JESUS, WON'T YOU WALK WITH ME? ♪
♪ WELL, IF YOU CAN PART THE WATERS ♪
♪ SET THE CHILDREN FREE
♪ YOU CAN FIND THE TIME TO WALK WITH ME ♪
♪ IF YOU CAN TALK TO MOSES
♪ SET MY CHILDREN FREE
♪ LISTEN TO THE CHILDREN
♪ JESUS, WALK WITH ME
♪ WELL
OH, WHAT A GLORIOUS DAY THIS IS.
BROTHERS... SISTERS IN CHRIST,
LET US LOWER OUR EYES
AND JOIN OUR HANDS
AND TAKE THIS MOMENT
TO REBOUND IN--
I MEAN, REJOICE IN
THIS MOMENT OF COMMUNION WITH OUR LORD.
CAN I GET AN AMEN OUT THERE?
AMEN. AMEN.
HALLELUJAH AND PRAISE THE LORD.
O LORD, WE WELCOME YOU HERE THIS MORNING
AND ASK YOU TO BLESS THIS HOUSE
AND ALL THESE FREE THROWS--
I MEAN, FREE SOULS GATHERED HERE
IN YOUR PRESENCE.
UH, DEACON SMITH,
WOULD YOU PLEASE HELP ME WITH THE PRAYER?
PRAISE THE LORD.
PARDON ME, BROTHER.
IN YOUR PRESENCE, WE ASK YOU, LORD,
FOR YOUR FORGIVENESS AND GUIDANCE
IN THE TRIALS AHEAD,
AND, UH, AND, UH...
WE COULD USE SOME HELP DOWN HERE, LORD.
HIT IT!
♪ JESUS
♪ JESUS ♪ JESUS
♪ I CALL YOU ♪ JESUS
♪ IN THE MIDNIGHT HOUR ♪
♪ JESUS ♪ OH, JESUS
ALL RIGHT!
YOU PEOPLE WILL LISTEN UP!
AND SECURE ALL NOISE!
YOU...
STOP ALL THE GRAB ASS,
AND YOU WILL FORM UP IN AN ORDERLY THREE-RING.
FALL IN!
♪ CHANCE OF A LIFETIME
♪ CHANCE OF A LIFETIME, YEAH ♪
FRIEND, I THINK THE PLANETS ARE AGAINST US.
HEY, I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING,
BUT FIRST APPEARANCES
HAVE A WAY OF BEING DECEIVING.
THERE'S TALENT OUT THERE.
I CAN FEEL IT.
YEAH!
♪ CHANCE OF A LIFETIME
♪ IT'S THE CHANCE OF A LIFETIME, YEAH ♪
[INDIAN WAR WHOOPING]
YO, BLOOD!
YO, BLOOD BROTHER.
BLOOD BROTHER?
WHO ARE YOU CATS, MAN?
[BOTH] DOUBLE TROUBLE.
BROCKINGTON!
WAIT A MINUTE.
HOW TALL IS YOUR MOTHER?
TERRIFIC PROSPECTS, MR. CANTRELL. GOOD PICKING.
A MOMENT OF YOUR TIME, BROCKINGTON.
STEP INTO MY OFFICE.
CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG, BROCKINGTON,
BUT YOU ARE AWARE OF ALL THE CHANGES GOING ON
IN THE ORGANIZATION LATELY?
YES, SIR.
FINE.
NOW, THERE'S ANOTHER CHANGE
THAT MR. TILSON AND I
WANT TO INFORM YOU OF, EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY.
WE'VE DECIDED TO NAME YOU THE NEW HEAD COACH.
IT'S JOB I TRUST YOU CAN HANDLE.
Y-YES, SIR.
YES, SIR.
WHEN I CALL OUT YOUR NAME,
I WANT YOU TO STAND UP SO COACH BROCKINGTON HERE
CAN HAVE A GOOD LOOK AT YOU.
JACKHAMMER WASHINGTON.
O.K., JACK WASHINGTON.
WHAT DO THE REAL PEOPLE CALL YOU?
PUDDING AND TAINE.
ASK ME AGAIN, I'LL TELL YOU THE SAME.
THAT'S TERRIFIC, TERRIFIC.
REMIND ME TO TAPE YOUR MOUTH
WHEN I DO YOUR ANKLES, HUH?
IF YOU WAS WISE, BUBBLE EYES,
YOU'D COP YOUR JIVE ATTITUDE TO THE SIDE.
JACKHAMMER WASHINGTON WILL PUT YOU TO THE TEST
AND SHOW YOU WHICH DUDE CAN RAP THE BEST.
RAPPING AND SLAPPING-- THAT'S MY CLAIM TO FAME.
PLUS, I GOT A MEAN B-BALL GAME.
AND FROM THE CORNER, IT'S A GONER.
HA HA HA.
BUFFORD. UH...
HERE.
HORACE BUFFORD.
YEAH, I'D PREFER IF YOU CALL ME SET SHOT.
IT'S YOUR DIME, BUFFORD,
BUT PLEASE STAND UP SO THE COACH HERE
CAN GET A GOOD LOOK AT YOU.
I AM STANDING.
HOO HOO HOO.
OH, YEAH. SURE. WELL, UH, SIT DOWN, BUFFORD.
SET SHOT.
O.K., SET SHOT.
LOOK, DON'T WORRY. WE'LL DO SOMETHING FOR YOU.
HANEY.
JOSEPH HANEY III.
THE THIRD.
HI.
YOU CAN JUST CALL ME DRIFTWOOD.
WAIT A MINUTE, WAIT A MINUTE.
HEENEY. JOSEPH HEENEY. ST. BONAVENTURE.
WHERE'D YOU DISAPPEAR TO, SON?
THERE WERE 12 TEAMS
READY TO SIGN YOU ON THE SPOT, LATE SIXTIES.
OH, YEAH. YOU KNOW, I WAS PROTESTING THE DRAFT.
YOU MEAN YOU RAN OUT ON A WAR?
NO, NO, MAN. I WENT TO WAR.
I RAN AWAY FROM THE BASKETBALL DRAFT.
THOSE GUYS ARE ANIMALS.
YEAH, SURE, UM,
BULLET HAINES.
UH, DON'T YOU HAVE SOMETHING TO SAY FOR YOURSELF?
O.K., HAINES, IT'S BEEN NICE TALKING TO YOU.
MALIK, UH, JAMAAL TRUTH.
RIGHT ON.
UH, WHAT KIND OF A NAME IS THAT, "TRUTH"?
THAT'S A FREE MAN'S NAME.
I LEFT MY SLAVE NAME IN THE SLAMMER.
SEE, THIS IS A NEW DAY,
AND WE'RE A NEW GENERATION.
AND THAT'S THE TRUTH.
AMEN.
RIGHT ON, BROTHER.
A TAG TEAM.
KENNY RAE AND BENNY RAE.
[BOTH] WHAT'S HAPPENING?
THEY'VE BEEN A PAIR LIKE THIS SINCE NOAH'S ARK.
HEY, TELL ME, YOU GUYS, UH,
HOW ARE WE SUPPOSED TO TELL YOU APART?
WE'RE NOT EVEN TWINS.
NOW, YOU KNOW ALL BLACK PEOPLE LOOK ALIKE.
TACKLE THE BIG PROBLEMS FIRST, HARRY.
THE LITTLE ONES, UH--
LET'S MOVE ON. LET'S KEEP MOVING.
WINSTON RUNNING HAWK.
UH, BETWEEN ME AND YOU, TONTO,
ARE YOU PLANNING TO DO A LITTLE TICKET SCALPING
ON THE SIDE?
WITH A FACE LIKE YOURS,
YOU SHOULD TAKE A TIP FROM THE LONE RANGER...
AND WEAR A MASK.
HA.
OHH.
AHEM.
I DIDN'T HEAR MY NAME.
OH, YEAH, YES, YES.
UM, REVEREND, REVEREND JACKSON.
REVEREND.
IT ISN'T EVERY DAY A FINE COACH LIKE MR. BROCKINGTON...
[SCATTERED CLAPPING]
IS UNITED WITH EQUALLY
AN OUTSTANDING CONGREGATION LIKE YOURSELVES.
I BELIEVE A FEW SECONDS
OF SOLID DEVOTION ARE IN ORDER.
♪ OOH
♪ OOH OOH
LORD...
WELL...
TAKING US RIGHT BACK TO SLAVERY.
[SET SHOT] HAVE A LITTLE RESPECT, HUH?
RESPECT FOR WHAT?
HE LOOK LIKE AN OLD LEPRECHAUN.
HE NEED TO GET HIP TO ALLAH.
AMEN. THANK YOU, LORD.
♪ AMEN
THANK YOU.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOOKS LIKE THE GONG SHOW.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
NOW--CHALK. WHERE'S THE CHALK?
SOMEBODY STOLE THE CHALK.
WHAT? [WHISTLES]
CHALK. CHALK.
RESOURCEFULNESS.
IT DOESN'T MATTER THAT YOU DON'T TALK.
INITIATIVE AND...
GOOD FINGERTIP CONTROL.
ALL RIGHT, MEN, NOW, LISTEN UP.
WE TAKE ON DETROIT...
FIVE DAYS.
NOW, THAT'S NOT A LOT OF TIME,
BUT... I AM SURE THAT YOU MEN
ARE GOING TO BE... EQUAL TO THE TASK.
BECAUSE WE ARE GOING TO...
KICK ASS.
PULL TO-GETHER.
THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
WE ARE GOING TO GET THE JOB DONE.
WHEN THE GOING...
GETS TOUGH...
HUH?
THE TOUGH GET GOING!
ON YOUR FEET!
ON THE COURT!
YEAH! YEAH!
ON TO VICTORY!
WHOO! YEAH!
HELLO AGAIN, EVERYBODY.
FROM COURTSIDE AT THE PITTSBURGH ARENA,
THIS IS CHICK HEARN,
AND I'M AS ANXIOUS AS YOU ARE
TO FIND OUT WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN TONIGHT
TO THE PITTSBURGH PYTHONS.
SAY, MAN, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I BETTER LET TYRONE EXPLAIN.
THANKS, MOSES.
O.K.
NOW, I GOT TO TELL YOU GUYS SOMETHING.
THE REASON YOU WERE ALL PICKED,
AS YOU ALL MUST'VE FIGURED OUT BY NOW,
IS BECAUSE YOU'RE ALL BORN
UNDER THE SAME SIGN OF PISCES.
THE FISH.
A FISH?
YEAH.
SEE, YOU CATS ARE ASTROLOGICALLY COMPATIBLE.
THIS MEANS THAT TOGETHER-- TOGETHER, HEY...
I MEAN, YOU CATS CAN DO ANYTHING.
I MEAN, YOU CAN TAKE ON A WHOLE ARMY AND WIN.
THAT'S BECAUSE THE UNIVERSE, THE COSMOS...
ARE ALL ON YOUR SIDE.
NOW, I KNOW THAT THIS DOESN'T MAKE A WHOLE LOT OF SENSE
TO Y'ALL RIGHT NOW,
BUT, EACH AND EVERY ONE OF YOU, WAIT AND SEE.
HEY, WHEN YOU GET ON THE COURT, YOU'LL FEEL IT.
I MEAN, YOU'LL FEEL LIKE YOU'RE A PART OF SOMETHING
THAT'S BIGGER THAN JUST YOU. AND YOU'LL SEE
THAT EVERYTHING WILL JUST COME DOWN RIGHT.
AND REMEMBER,
IT'S THE CHEMISTRY THAT YOU GOT TO BELIEVE IN.
IT'S THE PISCES COMBINATION
THAT'LL MAKE IT ALL WORK.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, THE PITTSBURGH PYTHONS.
[BROCKINGTON] LET'S GO, GUYS. LOOK SHARP, NOW.
SET SHOT.
YEAH, YEAH.
COME ON, MAN. WAKE UP.
IN THE HANDS, MAN. LEARN HOW TO PASS.
CHECK THIS GUY OUT.
DO YOU BELIEVE THAT, MAN?
DIG THE ARABIAN GUY WAY DOWN THERE WITH THE GLASSES.
HE LOOK LIKE AN ARAB.
THIS CAT CAN SET PRICES OF OIL.
LOOK AT THE BOBBSEY TWINS DOWN THERE.
HEY, LOOK AT LITTLE ISAAC OVER THERE.
WE GOT OLD MELON HEAD.
MELON HEAD DOWN THERE, MAN.
I GOT A BOW AND ARROW FOR SITTING BULL.
ZING.
CAPTAIN HOOP.
OUR LUCK. AN EASY NIGHT.
LET'S GO.
PLAY BALL, PLAY BALL.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS. LOOK SHARP. LOOK SHARP.
HEY, WHERE DID THEY FIND THESE DOOFUSES,
AT THE FUNNY FARM?
YEAH. I THINK IT'S THE TRUTH.
OH, CHILD.
WAIT A MINUTE. THAT BALDHEADED ONE
IS KIND OF CUTE, GIRL.
BULLET HAINES. OH.
HEY, I LIKE THAT NAME.
BULLET? HONEY, WITH A NAME LIKE THAT,
HE BETTER BE ABLE TO SHOOT.
BRANDY, DEAR.
WE GOT IT, MAN.
OH. OH, MY GOSH.
[MUSIC STARTS]
[HORN BLOWS]
MARV.
HEY, MOSE.
WHERE'D YOU GET THESE CLOWNS FROM, MAN?
[BROCKINGTON] COME ON, FELLAS!
YOU GOT A CRYSTAL BALL OVER HERE, BIG FELLA.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH HIM?
IS HE SPELLBOUND OR SOMETHING?
YO, REV, GET THE TAP.
COME ON, LITTLE BABY, LET'S GET DOWN,
LET'S GET DOWN.
♪ AHH
♪ AHH AHH
♪ LISTEN TO YOUR HEART
♪ AND NEVER FEAR
♪ FOLLOW EVERY DREAM
♪ FOREVER
SOMEBODY BETTER CALL MRS. SPORTS
'CAUSE HER LITTLE BOY MURRAY MUST BE DREAMING.
HELL OF A LUCK SHOT. A LUCK SHOT.
GET BIG "D"! BIG "D"!
WOW. THESE GUYS ARE PASSING,
THEY'RE SHOOTING, THEY'RE HITTING THE OPEN MAN.
SOMEBODY TAUGHT THEM THE GAME OF BASKETBALL
ALL OF A SUDDEN.
[TRUMPET BLOWS CHARGE]
[CROWD] CHARGE!
[TAMBOURINE RATTLES]
WOW. I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
THESE GUYS ARE SWISHING LIKE THE BOLSHOI WAS COMING TO TOWN.
WOW. THESE GUYS ARE PASSING LIKE CHAMPIONS.
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING.
IF THE PYTHONS CAN KEEP THIS UP IN THE SECOND HALF,
YOU BETTER CANCEL THEIR DEATH NOTICE
AND DUST OFF A FEW THOUSAND SEATS IN THE ARENA TO BOOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
MAYBE THE SEASON'S SUPPLY OF VITAMINS
ARRIVED A COUPLE OF MONTHS LATE.
THE PYTHONS ARE PLAYING SUPER BALL.
I'LL TELL YOU, THIS TURNABOUT BY THE PYTHONS
HAS EVEN GOT THE REFEREES SHAKING THEIR HEADS.
WOW. A SUPER PLAY BY THE PYTHONS. REAL TEAMWORK.
WELL, IF YOU OR I ARE SURPRISED,
THINK HOW DETROIT'S PLAYERS MUST FEEL.
YOU KNOW THEY WERE PUTTING THIS ONE IN THE WIN COLUMN
BEFORE THEY GOT OFF THE BUS.
[ORGAN PLAYS CHARGE]
I TELL YOU, BY THE WAY THEY'RE PLAYING THIS HALF,
THE PYTHONS SEEM DETERMINED
TO BRING BASKETBALL BACK TO PITTSBURGH.
DEFENSE!
LENGTH-OF-THE-COURT PASS,
AND IT'S ANOTHER 2 FOR THE PYTHONS.
AAH!
WHOO WHOO WHOO.
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
WOW. WHAT A HALF.
THE PYTHONS' BEST 24 MINUTES OF THE YEAR BY FAR.
[BROCKINGTON] WINNERS NEVER QUIT.
WINNERS NEVER QUIT... QUITTERS NEVER WIN.
WHO ARE THESE GUYS?
I DIDN'T KNOW THEY COULD PLAY BALL LIKE THIS.
GUTHRIE'S KILLING ME.
I NEED A REST.
BULLET! BULLET! BULLET!
BULLET! BULLET! OH, BULLET, BABY!
BULLET!
AAH! AAH!
WHOO HOO-HOO! LORD, HAVE MERCY!
YOU ARE FINE, HONEY! YOU'RE SO FINE!
LORD! NUMBER 52!
OW, 52, 52! OH.
"NO LET-UP.
"COMPETITIVE GREATNESS MEANS NO LET-UP.
"COMPETITIVE GREATNESS MEANS TO BE AT YOUR BEST
WHEN YOUR BEST IS NEEDED," RIGHT?
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
[PLAYERS SHOUTING]
I THINK THAT SAYS IT ALL.
YOU CAN'T MISS, YOU GUYS.
SO FOR THE MOONS OF NEPTUNE,
PUT YOUR SIGNS ON THE LINE.
ALL RIGHT. YEAH.
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ HAVEN'T YOU, HAVEN'T YOU HEARD? ♪
♪ OH, HEY
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ SPREAD THE WORD
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH
ALL RIGHT.
WHOO! WHOO!
♪ WHAT'S IT GOING TO BE?
♪ SHOUT IT OUT, LOUD AND CLEAR ♪
♪ TELL THE WORLD IT HAPPENED HERE ♪
♪ SPREAD THE NEWS, EVERYWHERE ♪
♪ ALL ACROSS THE LAND
♪ WAY TO GO, WAY TO TRY ♪
♪ IT'S ALL ABOUT OUR TEAMWORK, GUYS ♪
♪ FATHER TO SON, TENDER WORDS ♪
♪ TRYIN' TO SAVE YOUR LIFE ♪
♪ HEY
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ SPREAD THE WORD
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ WHOA, HEY
♪ OW
♪ GOIN' AGAIN
YAY!
♪ SPIDERMAN, SUPERMAN
♪ NO SIX MILLION DOLLAR MAN ♪
♪ EVEN WONDER WOMAN'S SPINE ♪
♪ DIDN'T HAVE THE STUFF
♪ SUCH A TEAM COULDN'T BE
♪ SO FAR FROM REALITY
♪ NOW IT'S JUST HISTORY
♪ HAT'S OFF TO THE FISH
♪ OW
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ FISH
♪ HAVEN'T YOU, HAVEN'T YOU HEARD? ♪
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ OW
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY...
[MURRAY SPORTS] WELL, WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT PEOPLE
WHO WERE BORN AGAIN, YOU JUST HAVE TO PUT
AT THE TOP OF YOUR LIST THE PITTSBURGH PYTHONS.
I'LL TELL YOU,
IF THEY GAVE A COMEBACK- OF-THE-YEAR AWARD
TO AN ENTIRE TEAM, YOU KNOW IT WOULD GO
TO THIS INCREDIBLY GUTTY GROUP OF GUYS.
THE PYTHONS HAVE WON 12 STRAIGHT, INCREDIBLY ENOUGH,
IF YOU'VE BEEN SLEEPING UNDER A ROCK
THE LAST COUPLE OF MONTHS.
IT'S HARD ENOUGH TO DO ON YOUR HOME COURT,
WHERE THEY BEAT THE LIKES OF L.A., DENVER, PORTLAND,
CHICAGO, PHILADELPHIA, AND SAN DIEGO.
BUT DIG THIS-- THE PYTHONS HAVE ALSO
RUN OFF A STRING OF CONSECUTIVE VICTORIES
AGAINST SEATTLE, KANSAS CITY, HOUSTON, BOSTON, INDIANA,
AND SAN FRANCISCO ON THE ROAD.
AND YOU JUST DON'T DO THAT
IN THIS LEAGUE THESE DAYS.
UNLESS, AS IT'S RUMORED ABOUT THE PYTHONS,
THE TEAM IS BEING MASTERMINDED BY A WOMAN ASTROLOGER.
WHOEVER IS CALLING THE SHOTS,
THESE GUYS WERE HAVING FUN AT THAT INDIANA GAME
WITH A 30-POINT LAUGHER FOR THE PYTHONS.
AND ANOTHER STAT THAT'S PROVOKING SOME SMILES--
4 CONSECUTIVE 30-POINT GAMES FOR MOSES GUTHRIE.
THE PYTHONS ARE BEGINNING
TO AMAZE PEOPLE AROUND THIS LEAGUE
WITH THEIR COLLECTION OF WEIRDOES, MISFITS,
AND, UH, SOME OTHER GUYS.
THE PYTHONS SURPRISED EVERYBODY,
PROBABLY EVEN THEMSELVES,
CERTAINLY WASHINGTON. THEY STUNNED THEM
WITH SOME VERY SNAPPY SCORING.
SOME STATISTICS? WELL, LISTEN TO THIS.
MOSES GUTHRIE-- 43 POINTS.
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
BEGINNING TO EARN YOUR MONEY, MR. GUTHRIE.
TYRONE, WHAT'S THE SCORE?
AND SOME NEWCOMERS
ADDED IN TO THE SCORING DISPLAY.
SET SHOT BUFFORD AND JAMAAL TRUTH WITH 20 APIECE.
NICE GOING GUYS. WELCOME TO TOWN.
THE SCORE, THE SCORE, COME ON.
OH. UH,
THE FINAL SCORE IN THAT GAME, INCIDENTALLY,
IS, UH, PYTHONS 122, WASHINGTON 118.
GET DOWN, PYTHONS! GET DOWN, PYTHONS!
MY TEAM. PYTHONS.
GET DOWN, PYTHONS. GET DOWN.
LET'S CHECK THOSE OTHER SCORES NOW.
WELL, THERE ARE NO OTHER SCORES.
THAT WAS THE ONLY ACTION TONIGHT.
HEY, WINTER BASEBALL GETTING UNDERWAY WITH THOSE MEETINGS,
AND LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
♪ MAKE A WISH FOR ONE, MY DEAR ♪
HEY, MAN.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT. WHOO!
I WONDER WHAT'S NEXT.
OH, WOW.
I GOT TO QUIT SMOKING THIS SHIT.
HA HA HA!
HEY, YOU GUYS LOOKING FOR YOUR UNIFORMS?
YEAH. YEAH.
YEAH, LITTLE BROTHER. WHAT'S THE DEAL?
LISTEN UP, EVERYBODY, O.K.?
WELL, I GOT A SPECIAL ANNOUNCEMENT.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
PLEASE, PLEASE, PLEASE.
PLEASE. JAMMING THAT THING IN MY FACE.
THIS IS A FUN NIGHT.
NOW, PLEASE, ALL THE TEAM,
WOULD YOU GATHER 'ROUND?
THIS IS A JOYOUS OCCASION FOR ALL OF US.
CERTAINLY ME.
YOU KNOW, I'M JUST SO EXCITED TONIGHT.
I REALLY AM.
YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN PLAYING OUTSTANDING BASKETBALL.
MARVELOUS, MARVELOUS.
AND THE FANS ARE JUST ECSTATIC ABOUT YOU.
I GOT A COUPLE OF SURPRISES.
UH, TYRONE, WILL YOU--
HMM? YEAH.
GET ONE OF THOSE PINK BOXES.
ONE OF MY SURPRISES IS
THAT WE'RE CHANGING THE NAME OF THE TEAM
FROM THE PITTSBURGH PYTHONS TO THE PITTSBURGH PISCES.
[MURMURING]
TYRONE, PLEASE. BRING THAT IN, IF YOU WILL.
'CAUSE THIS IS-- THIS IS SOMETHING ELSE.
HA HA HA.
OH, BLESS YOU.
HERE, YOU TAKE THE TOP. O.K.
UH, MOSES, WOULD YOU COME HERE A MOMENT, PLEASE?
HERE'S YOUR NEW UNIFORM.
HMM? HUH?
[MOSES] IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
HEY, THE PISCES.
[CLAPS]
IT'S AN AWFULLY TROUBLE JAM.
YEAH!
THE IDEA-- YOU KNOW, THE PISCES--
IS THAT HE JUST GOES IN THERE AND DEVOURS...
EVERY OPPONENT THERE IS,
UNLESS, OF COURSE, YOU'RE...AN ARIES.
HA HA HA.
WELL, LISTEN, HOW ABOUT GETTING RIGHT OUT THERE
AND WINNING ONE FOR THE FISH TONIGHT?
LET'S DO THAT, GUYS. LET'S WIN.
COOL.
OUT OF SIGHT.
I'M HIP. WHATEVER.
♪ DOO-DOO DOO-DOO
♪ A LIFE WITH TWO...
BALLOONS FOR EVERYBODY.
HUH? DON'T COST YOU A PENNY.
HEY, YOU GUYS.
I GOT SOMEONE I WANT YOU ALL TO MEET.
THIS IS MISS MONA MONDIEU,
OUR TEAM ASTROLOGER.
OOH.
FOXY LADY.
HOW YOU DOING, SUGAR?
YOU MUST BE MR. TRUTH.
WHAT SHE DOING IN HERE?
HOW DO YOU DO?
WHAT AN EXCITING PLAYER YOU COULD BE.
IT'S TOO BAD ABOUT THAT CANCER IN YOUR THIRD HOUSE.
HOW'D SHE KNOW THAT?
DON'T WORRY. PEOPLE CHANGE.
BROCK, WHAT IS THIS?
NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO DAMES IN THE LOCKER ROOM.
HARRY, SHE'S NO DAME.
SHE'S A LADY HERE TO TEACH US.
TEACH US?
COME ON, BROCK. THIS MYSTIC STUFF
HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
HARRY, LOOK, WE CAN'T LET OURSELVES
GET UPSET BY THE UNEXPECTED, RIGHT?
WE HAVE TO LEARN HOW TO RELATE TO THE PLAYERS.
KEY WORD IS "RELATE."
WHOA!
SHE'S TOUCHING THE BOARD.
HEY, DON'T TOUCH THE BOARD.
DON'T TOUCH THE MAN'S BOARD.
BROCK DON'T LIKE THAT.
TYRONE.
UH, MR. BROCKINGTON,
WOULD YOU HAVE ANY OBJECTION
IF I BRIEFED THE TEAM BEFORE TONIGHT'S GAME?
SURELY NOT.
ALL RIGHT, NOW, ITEM 1--
WHAT DO YOU CALL IT
WHEN YOU'RE ALL OUT THERE RUNNING AROUND,
AND TWO GUYS KEEP BUMPING INTO EACH OTHER?
[TYRONE] MATCH-UPS.
UH, MOSES.
YEAH.
MOSES, WHO IS YOUR MATCH-UP TONIGHT?
THIS GUY NAMED HAYWOOD.
OH, HAYWOOD.
TAURUS WITH A STRONG CAPRICORN INFLUENCE.
AS THE EVENING PROGRESSES,
THE BULL'S ENERGIES WILL DISSIPATE.
HE WILL GROW WEAKER.
WHAT MONA MEANS
IS THAT YOU JUST SHOW HIM PLENTY OF SLACK,
JUST FOR THE FIRST HALF.
THEN SERVE HIM UP IN THE SECOND HALF.
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT... STARS IN CON--
CONJUNCTION, BENNY.
HOW'D SHE KNOW THAT?
YOU KNEW I WAS BENNY?
WELL, YOU'RE TWO MINUTES OLDER.
IT'S EASY TO SPOT
THE DIFFERENCE IN YOUR RISING SIGNS.
WOW. THAT'S THE FIRST TIME.
HEY, BUT, WAIT. WHAT DOES THIS JIVE
HAVE TO DO WITH PLAYING BASKETBALL?
WELL, YOU SEE,
WHAT MONA MEANS IS THAT,
HEY, WHEN YOU TWO GUYS ARE OUT ON THE COURT...
YOU BECOME ONE GREAT PLAYER.
INSTEAD OF TWO ORDINARY ONES.
OOH.
[LAUGHING]
BULLET, YOU DON'T TALK,
BUT YOU'VE GOT A LOT TO SAY.
YOUR CHART SHOWS THAT THERE IS NO BLOCKAGE
ON THE COURT TONIGHT.
GREAT. JUST SAVE SOME OF THAT MAGIC
FOR THE GAME.
NOW, JACKHAMMER AND RUNNING HAWK...
BOTH YOUR CHARTS INDICATE,
OR RATHER JUPITER AND MERCURY DO,
THAT YOUR STRONG SUIT TONIGHT IS DEFENSE.
SAY NO MORE. JUST SHOW US TO THE FLOOR.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL...GENTLEMEN, FOR THE PAST FEW MONTHS,
JUPITER HAS BEEN IN A FIXED POSITION
AND YOU'VE ALL BEEN VERY LUCKY.
[GRUMBLING]
A LITTLE LUCK, A LOTTA SPIRIT.
LUCK AIN'T NOTHING BUT--
BUT AS OF THIS EVENING,
SPECIFICALLY, AT 7:45 P.M.,
MERCURY GOES INTO RETROGRADE
AND THINGS WON'T BE ALL THAT EASY.
WHAT? ARE YOU KIDDING?
AT WHAT TIME?
SPARE ME.
BUT REMEMBER THIS...
THERE ARE POSITIVE ASPECTS...
AND WHEN YOU ARE WITH MONA...
THE STARS ARE WITH YOU.
SO TRUST ME.
WITH A BRAND NEW UNIFORM...
WITH A BRAND NEW NAME...
THE PITTSBURGH PISCES HIT THE FLOOR AT PITTSBURGH ARENA.
HI, EVERYBODY. I'M CHICK HEARN.
A NEAR-CAPACITY CROWD HERE TONIGHT
TO SEE PITTSBURGH LOOK FOR ITS 13th WIN IN A ROW.
TONIGHT'S OPPONENT...
A TOUGHIE, COMING IN FROM NEW YORK CITY.
AND OF COURSE, THE PISCES,
WITH THE ONLY OFFICIAL ASTROLOGER IN THE LEAGUE...
MISS MONA MONDIEU.
TIME OUT! TIME OUT!
TIME OUT!
LET ME CHECK THESE UNIFORMS OUT.
NICE, MAN. VERY NICE.
VERY GOOD. VERY TOGETHER.
ALL RIGHT. SHOW'S OVER.
LET'S GET THIS GAME GOING.
SAY, MAN... WHAT'S YOUR SIGN?
UH...
♪ MYSTIC LADY OF THE ZODIAC ♪
♪ COME AND SET US ON THE WINNING TRACK ♪
♪ MONA
♪ YOU'RE A NEVER-ENDING MIRACLE ♪
♪ PISCES GOTTA HAVE A MIRACLE ♪
♪ MONA
♪ YOU'RE THE QUEEN OF THE STARS ♪
♪ IT'S MAGIC YOU ARE
♪ MAGIC, MAGIC MONA
♪ IT'S GOTTA BE MAGIC
♪ OHH...
PUT IT UP!
SHOOT!
♪ TELL US, ARE THE STARS CONJUNCTIONING? ♪
♪ MONA
THAT'S YOUR WEAKNESS. THE STARS DON'T LIE.
I DO, BUT THEY DON'T.
LET'S TRY THE REVEREND IN A GAME OF THREE.
THREE!
YEAH! ALL RIGHT--
YOU KNOW THE TERM "RETROGRADE ASTROLOGY"?
YEAH. YEAH.
SOMETHING ABOUT BACKWARD MOTION OF THE PLANETS.
YEAH. WELL,
THIS IS WHAT I CALL RETROGRADE BASKETBALL.
MOVE THE BALL! FIND THE OPEN MAN!
SHOOT IT! SHOOT THE FOUL!
YEAH, SHOOT THAT BALL!
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
SHOOT! SHOOT THE THING!
BACK OFF MY TEAM! BACK OFF!
♪ MONA
♪ MAGIC, MAGIC MONA
♪ IT'S GOTTA BE MAGIC
♪ OHH...
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
FOUL ON YOU. 52 WHITE. BLOCK.
WHAT, ARE YOU NUTS?
WAIT! WAIT A MINUTE, COACH!
REF, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THAT'S OFFENSIVE CHARGING!
REF! WE HAD POSITION!
THE MAN RAN RIGHT OVER HIM!
NEXT TIME, BRING A TIN CUP, WILL YA?
ONE MORE WORD OUT OF YOU,
AND IT'S GOING TO COST YOU A TECHNICAL.
WHAT?
[WHISTLE] TECHNICAL FOUL.
[BOOING]
COACH, WHY DON'T YOU BE COOL, MAN?
DO YOU THINK THE TEAM CAN SPARE YOU
FOR A LITTLE BIT? I THINK WE'RE IN NEED
OF A LITTLE VISUAL AID DEMONSTRATION.
THE PISCES HAVE PLAYED
THEIR POOREST HALF OF BASKETBALL
SINCE BROCKINGTON TOOK OVER AS THE HEAD MAN.
AS WE NEAR THE END OF THE FIRST HALF,
15 POINTS BEHIND...
THANKS, KID.
GENTLEMEN...OBSERVE.
HOLD IT! HOLD IT!
NOW LOOK, MISS MONDIEU.
THE--THE CHART AND SQUIGGLE STUFF
IS ONE THING. THIS IS NO TIME
TO BE WATCHING TELEVISION!
LET'S GET ONE THING STRAIGHT!
I AM THE COACH OF THIS TEAM.
STOP RACING YOUR MOTOR.
NOW PARK IT AND PAY ATTENTION.
FOR OPENERS, THERE'S A FREEBIE OUT THERE
COMPLIMENTS OF YOU.
THIS IS THE WORST-CALLED GAME I'VE EVER SEEN IN MY LIFE!
YOU CANNOT LET THE REFS GET AWAY WITH THAT STUFF!
CAN YOU?
TO BE FORETOLD IS TO BE FOREWARNED.
[SIGHS]
ROLL 'EM.
TWINS...
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU TWO?
IN ONE EAR AND OUT THE OTHER THREE?
CONJUNCTION, REMEMBER?
WORKING TOGETHER... ONE GREAT PLAYER.
SEPARATE...TWO AMATEURS.
MOSES. NOW, SEE HOW YOU STARTED TO DOMINATE
LATE IN THE HALF?
HAYWOOD'S FADING.
CHALLENGE HIM HARD,
AND THE SECOND HALF'S ALL YOURS.
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT. YEAH
HEY, NOW! TAKE IT OUT! TAKE IT OUT!
GIVE IT HERE! ALL RIGHT! YEAH!
REVEREND JACKSON...
I'M WITH YOU, MONDIEU. KEEP IT OFF THE FLOOR.
ALL RIGHT... YOU GOT ALL THE ANSWERS.
HAVE YOU FIGURED OUT HOW WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO MAKE UP 15 POINTS IN THE SECOND HALF?
FOULS...
FREE THROWS...
[WHISTLES BLOW]
HEY!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
I'M ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT!
IT'S ALL RIGHT. I'M MAKING IT.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
OH, MAN!
SOME PEOPLE GOT HEIGHT. YOU GOT HEART, TROOPER.
GET UP?
YEAH. YEAH, UP.
ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT! HARRY!
HOW YOU FEELING?
I'M SEEING DOUBLE.
[CROWD] OHH!
I'M FINE. LET ME BACK IN.
SET SHOT GETS BACK INTO THE BALL GAME.
NEW YORK'S GOT THE BALL.
THEY BRING IN IT TO THOMPSON AND GIVE IT BACK TO BEARD.
THE PRESSURE OF THE BALLGAME RIGHT DOWN ON THE LINE NOW.
[SET SHOT] I'M READY.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
CHARGE!
TELL THAT TO ME, MAN!
THE GAME HAS ONE SECOND LEFT TO PLAY ON THE CLOCK.
IT'LL BE A PAIR OF FREE THROWS, IF HE CAN DO IT.
HOW DOES THAT SET SHOT DO IT?
[CROWD CHANTING] SET SHOT! SET SHOT!
TWO SHOTS! TWO SHOTS!
TWO!
NO PROBLEM.
COME ON, SET SHOT.
YEAH! ALL RIGHT!
ONE MORE, SET SHOT.
ONE MORE.
ALL RIGHT?
O.K., O.K.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
♪ WHEN YOU TOUCH ME
♪ I FEEL SO ALIVE...
CAN I HAVE YOUR AUTOGRAPH?
I'LL SETTLE FOR A KISS.
ME, TOO!
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
TREDESSA. T-R-E-D-E-S-S-A.
♪ MUST BE LOVE
EXCUSE ME.
HEY, LISTEN. I'M SORRY, GIRLS,
BUT YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO WEAR OUT
THE MAN'S SHOOTING ARM.
MR. GUTHRIE, WE HAVE TO TALK.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
O.K. I WAS JUST GOING TO GIVE TYRONE A RIDE HOME. WE COULD--
ALONE.
OH, THAT'S O.K. I'LL CATCH A RIDE WITH SET SHOT.
MOSES, THINK ABOUT YOUR CHART.
YOU KNOW, THE PART ABOUT THE OFF-COURT CONFRONTATION.
YEAH, O.K. I'LL SEE YOU GUYS LATER.
I'LL BE VERY HAPPY TO TAKE YOU HOME, TOBY--
UM...MISS MILLMAN.
♪ IT'S JUST GOOD TO ME
♪ WHEN YOU TOUCH ME
♪ I FEEL SO ALIVE
♪ IT'S THE MAGIC I SEE IN YOUR EYES ♪
♪ IS IT LOVE?
♪ IT IS LOVE?
♪ MUST BE LOVE
♪ IS IT LOVE?
YOU WANTED TO TALK?
MR. GUTHRIE...
YOU'VE GOT MY LITTLE BROTHER
BELIEVING THAT ALL HE'S GOT TO DO
IS GROW UP INTO A 7-FOOT FREAK, GET HIS CHART DONE,
AND ALL HIS TROUBLES ARE GONNA BE OVER
FOR THE REST OF HIS LIFE.
HEY, NOW WAIT A MINUTE, LITTLE SISTER--
I AM NOT YOUR LITTLE SISTER, O.K.?
TYRONE--
NO! NO, YOU LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT TYRONE.
NOW, TYRONE IS NOT DOING A THING AT HOME,
HE'S NOT DOING HIS SCHOOLWORK ANYMORE,
HE'S GOT HIS HEAD UP IN THE CLOUDS,
AND IT'S BECAUSE OF YOU.
YES! TYRONE IS NOT GOING TO BE PAID A MILLION DOLLARS A YEAR
TO RUN AROUND IN HIS UNDERWEAR.
THE ONLY WAY HE IS GOING TO COLLEGE
IS ON A SCHOLARSHIP.
FOR GOOD GRADES.
AND HE'S NOT EVEN GOING TO GET THAT
IF HE'S PATTERNING HIMSELF AFTER SOME OVERGROWN ADOLESCENT
WHO CAN ONLY COUNT IN TWOs.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH TWOs?
YOU KNOW, I BELIEVE IN TWOs.
COME WITH ME.
♪ RUNNIN' UP THE BACK COURT ♪
♪ NEVER MISS A BEAT, YEAH ♪
♪ LOOKIN' FOR THE QUICK SHOT ♪
♪ GOTTA BEAT THE HEAT ♪
♪ YEAH
♪ SNAP FROM THE SIDE LINE ♪
♪ WORKIN' ON YOUR MIND ♪
MM-HMM, THAT'S RIGHT, BUDDY.
♪ SECONDS ON THE SHOT CLOCK ♪
♪ RUNNIN' OUT A TIME ♪
♪ YEAH
AND IT'S MESSIN' WITH YOUR MIND.
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
[MOSES] I HAD TO LEARN TO SQUEEZE THROUGH THAT HOLE,
AS YOU CALL IT, FOR MY FUTURE.
IT WAS SERIOUS BUSINESS, NOT PLAY.
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
I HAD TO LEARN TO WALK AND LEAN ON AIR.
I HAD TO LEARN TO LISTEN
TO THE RHYTHM INSIDE MY BODY.
I HAD TO LEARN TO PUSH MYSELF
TO SEE HOW FAR I COULD GO.
I HAD MY DREAMS THEN
JUST LIKE TYRONE HAS HIS.
♪ YEAH
♪ EVERYBODY'S ON ALMOST EVERY MOVE HE MAKES ♪
♪ PRAYIN' THAT YOU MAKE THAT ONE MISTAKE ♪
♪ YOU CAN MAKE IT HAPPEN ♪
♪ IF YOU JUST KEEP THE FAITH ♪
♪ YOU GOTTA RUN REALLY HARD ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪'CAUSE NO ONE DOES IT BETTER ♪
♪ YA GOTTA STAY IN SHAPE ♪
♪ IF YOU WANNA KEEP YOUR JOB ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪ 'CAUSE NO ONE DOES IT BETTER ♪
♪ YOU'RE JUST FLYIN' THROUGH THE AIR ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪ 'CAUSE NO ONE DOES IT BETTER ♪
♪ YOU GOTTA GET A PASS, SWISH ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪ 'CAUSE NO ONE DOES IT BETTER ♪
♪ NO ONE DOES IT BETTER ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT
♪ NO ONE DOES IT
♪ NO ONE DOES IT BETTER ♪
♪ MIGHTY, MIGHTY PISCES ♪
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ GONNA BRING 'EM TO THEIR KNEES ♪
♪ MIGHTY, MIGHTY PISCES ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH
♪ NOW YOU'RE MAKIN' HISTORY ♪
♪ OH, YEAH
[MURRAY SPORTS] IF YOU'VE BEEN NOTICING
SOME GIDDY EXPRESSIONS ON THE FACES OF THE PEOPLE
NEXT TO YOU ON THE BUS THESE DAYS LATELY,
YOU GOT TO UNDERSTAND THAT'S IT'S PROBABLY FISH FEVER.
IT'S TAKEN THE TOWN BY STORM.
NO WONDER.
PITTSBURGH PISCES HAVE BECOME THE CINDERELLA TEAM
NOT ONLY OF BASKETBALL,
BUT PROBABLY OF ALL SPORTS FOR ALL TIME.
STARTING FROM LESS THAN GROUND ZERO
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE SEASON,
THEY MADE IT 2/3 OF THE WAY
THROUGH THE PLAYOFFS SO FAR,
AND THEY'VE TAKEN THE LAST SERIES
DOWN TO THE FINAL GAME.
JUST TO REVIEW THEIR EXCITING CINDERELLA FINISH--
THEY BEAT CHICAGO 3 OUT OF 5
IN THE FIRST ROUND OF THE PLAYOFFS.
AND THAT INVOLVED WINNING TWO GAMES ON THE ROAD,
SOMETHING THE PISCES HAVE DONE
WITH STARTLING REGULARITY
SINCE THEIR AMAZING TURNAROUND IN MID-SEASON.
THEN THEY WENT DOWN TO THE NATION'S CAPITAL
AND STOLE THE PLAYOFF SERIES
FROM WASHINGTON, 4 OUT OF 7.
AND THEN THE FISH FEVER REALLY BEGAN TO SPREAD.
TALK ABOUT A CINDERELLA TEAM,
AT THIS POINT YOU CAN FORGIVE THE PISCES
IF THEY THINK THEY'RE WEARING GLASS SLIPPERS
INSTEAD OF TENNIS SHOES.
BUT NOW IT GETS EVEN MORE EXCITING.
THE COUNTDOWN TO THE FINAL GAME
OF THE FINAL ROUND OF THE PLAYOFFS AGAINST L.A.
PISCES HAVE TAKEN L.A. ALL THE WAY
IN A 3 AND 3 SERIES, SO FAR.
AND THEY'VE GOT THE GOOD FORTUNE
TO BE PLAYING THE FINAL GAME IN A SERIES
AT HOME TONIGHT HERE IN PITTSBURGH.
FOR THAT THERE'S A RECEPTION
BEING GIVEN FOR THEM BY THE MAYOR OF THE TOWN.
AND HE BETTER PRINT UP A LOT OF KEYS TO THE CITY,
THEY'RE GOING TO NEED EVERY BIT OF LUCK THEY CAN GET
AS THIS FINAL CHAPTER
OF A FAIRY TALE SEASON UNFOLDS.
WE CAN KIDNAP BROCKINGTON, SIR, OR--
NO, NO, THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT THEY WANT US TO DO.
NO. GIVE ME ANOTHER IDEA,
COME ON.
THE ASTROLOGY WOMAN?
MONA MON--
MONDIEU?
EXCELLENT, EXCELLENT.
REMEMBER, YOU SAID IT, I DIDN'T.
THIS IS YOUR JOB, YOU HANDLE IT.
ALL RIGHT, NOW,
I THINK I HAVE TO LOSE ABOUT 10 FAST POUNDS
AND, UH, YOU JOG ABOUT, OH,
SAY 10 TO 15 FEET AHEAD OF ME.
RIGHT?
HERE WE GO.
HEY.
GET GOING, GET GOING.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THE PAPERS.
MOVE IT!
DON'T WANT TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
I DON'T WANT TO KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT IT,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
I WANT IT DONE BEFORE THE PLAYOFFS.
I KNOW JUST THE TWO MEN FOR THE JOB, SIR.
EXPERTS.
[CAR HORN]
[CHEERLEADERS] GET DOWN, GET DOWN, PISCES!
GET DOWN, GET DOWN, PISCES!
YAY!
THE MIGHTY PISCES HAVE EVENED THE SERIES
AT THREE GAMES APIECE.
BUT, FOLKS, THAT'S ALL HISTORY.
AND HERE WITH US TONIGHT TO DESCRIBE
THAT INDESCRIBABLE PHENOMENON
THAT IS KNOWN AS FISH FEVER
IS PITTSBURGH'S OWN MURRAY SPORTS.
LET'S GO TO MURRAY NOW
IN THE L.A. LOCKER ROOM DOWNSTAIRS. MURRAY?
MARV, THEY TALK ABOUT FISH FEVER HERE IN THE ARENA,
BUT I'M STANDING WITH A MAN
WHO THINKS HE MAY KNOW THE CURE.
I'M WITH LUCIEN TUCKER,
THE STRONG FORWARD OF THE L.A. TEAM.
AND, L.T., I GET A FEELING
IN THIS LOCKER ROOM TONIGHT, UH,
OF AN ATMOSPHERE THICK WITH TENSION AND EXCITEMENT.
AN ATMOSPHERE THICK WITH AN APPREHENSION,
THICK WITH PERHAPS, UH--
THICK LIKE SOME SPORTS HUSTLER'S FAT TONGUE
WORKING OVERTIME.
LONG TIME AGO, LUCIEN.
HEY, WE GOT A BIG SEVENTH GAME HERE TONIGHT.
ALL THE MARBLES ARE ON THE LINE,
AND I THINK THIS IS A BIG ONE.
YOU MUST HAVE A GAME PLAN.
IF YOU CAN SUM IT UP IN JUST ONE WORD, L.T.,
WHAT WOULD THAT WORD BE?
REVENGE.
ALL RIGHT.
'CAUSE I DON'T TOLERATE...
THAT'S RIGHT. TALKIN' ABOUT REVENGE.
NO ASTROLOGICAL HOCUS-POCUS.
AND MOST OF ALL,
I DON'T TOLERATE NO MOSES GUTHRIE.
O.K.
THE MAN HAS A BAD JONES
FOR TRYING TO CRAMP MY STYLE.
MM-HMM.
SO I'M GOING TO STAY ON HIS ASS...
MMM.
LIKE WHITE ON RICE.
UH-HUH. YEAH.
LIKE COLD ON ICE.
YEAH.
LIKE STINK ON SHIT.
[PLAYERS] YEAH!
[APPLAUSE]
THIS IS NOT A HAPPY MAN.
FRIESMAN, TELL ME...
HOW'S OUR LADY OF THE STARS FARING?
WHY, OUT OF SIGHT, OUT OF MIND, SIR.
OH, THAT'S CORNY.
HERE, TO THE LEFT.
HERE YOU ARE, SON.
DON'T SPEND IT ALL IN ONE PLACE.
VERY IMPRESSIVE, SIR.
AH, THE VICTORY TOAST.
YES, YES,
THERE'S THE TOAST.
MIGHT EVEN SAY THAT'S THE BUN.
YES, I WANT TO TELL YOU SOMETHING,
I'VE OFTEN SAID THIS, FRIESMAN,
THAT WEALTH IS THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IN THE WORLD.
BUT IT ISN'T THE MOST IMPORTANT
UNLESS YOU'RE HAVING FUN!
AND I INTEND TO HAVE FUN TONIGHT.
THE MOST IMPORTANT FUN IN THE WORLD!
TONIGHT, THE WORLD IS YOURS, MR. TILSON.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
GIVE ME ABOUT TWO HOURS,
AND I'LL HAVE THAT OLD WORLD
RIGHT THERE IN THE PALM OF MY HAND.
TONIGHT, FRIESMAN,
THERE'S GOING TO BE AN OLD-FASHIONED FISH FRY!
GOD DAMN.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN...
THE LOS ANGELES TEAM.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
MMM! MMM!
MMM!
MR. COMMISSIONER,
I JUST, UH, WANT YOU TO HAVE
THIS SPECIFIC BALLOON.
THEY'RE ALL BASICALLY THE SAME.
HAVE PISCES THE FISH THAT I DESIGNED,
ALSO MY NAME'S ON THIS.
I SIGNED THIS MYSELF.
I MEAN, LITERALLY SIGNED OVER 30,000 OF THEM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, TILSON.
IT IS AN INCREDIBLE SCENE
HERE IN PITTSBURGH.
A CAPACITY CROWD IS ON HAND,
AND THEY ARE VIEWING ONE OF
THE STIRRING MOMENTS IN SPORTS.
IT IS A SPORTS HAPPENING.
THERE IS PANDEMONIUM ALL AROUND ME.
INCREDIBLE! AS THE PISCES
MAKE THEIR WAY FROM THE SKY!
GET THEM, MOSES!
PARTY, FISH!
LET'S GO, PISCES!
WHERE THE HELL IS MONA?
WHAT TIME HAVE YOU GOT?
[SET SHOT] ALL RIGHT.
WHERE THE HELL IS SHE?
THANKS, TY.
HOW COME NO MO?
LORD, GIVE US A SIGN.
FELLAS,
THE DEVIL IS LOOSE TONIGHT.
I HEARD THAT, MAN.
WITHOUT MONA, MAN, I THINK IT'S DEAD.
MONA'S NOT HERE?
ALL RIGHT, MEN, LET'S LIGHTEN UP.
LIGHTEN UP. NOW, THE STARTING--
STARTING LINEUP ON THE BENCH. ALL RIGHT?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
ALL RIGHT, NOW,
WE MAY NOT HAVE MONA, BUT...
WE'VE STILL GOT HER CHAIR.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO
IS EXECUTE.
WE HAVE TO EXECUTE OUR GAME PLAN.
WE HAVE TO EXECUTE BALL CONTROL.
MEN, THE NAME OF THE GAME TONIGHT
IS EXECUTION.
[STARTING HORN]
MEN, THERE'S ONLY ONE THING LEFT TO SAY--
IF THERE'S NO TONIGHT, THERE'S NO TOMORROW.
IF MONA WERE HERE,
WE ALL KNOW EXACTLY WHAT SHE'D SAY. HUH?
HUH?
I THINK THAT SAYS IT ALL.
ALL RIGHT?
PISCES FISTS.
O.K., LET'S GO.
I'LL BE HERE IF YOU NEED ME.
PISCES GOT THE POWER.
POWER TO THE FISH.
OUR FISH, FISH...
HELLO AGAIN, EVERYBODY,
FROM COURTSIDE THIS IS CHICK HEARN WELCOMING YOU
TO THE LEAGUE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME.
LOS ANGELES AGAINST THE PITTSBURGH PISCES.
WHAT A GAME IT SHOULD BE.
LOS ANGELES WITH PEOPLE LIKE KAREEM ABDUL-JABBAR,
CONNIE HAWKINS, LOU HUDSON, NORM NIXON,
LUCIEN TUCKER-- ALL TO CHALLENGE
MOSES GUTHRIE AND HIS TEAMMATES.
LOS ANGELES CONTROLS THE TIP.
A HOOK SHOT NO GOOD FOR LOS ANGELES.
REBOUND IS TAKEN OFF THE RIM BY BULLET HAINES.
AN OPPORTUNITY FOR THE PISCES TO HIT THE SCOREBOARD FIRST.
BOUNCE PASS COMES OVER TO GUTHRIE.
HIS PASS INTERCEPTED. NICE PLAY BY BILL PINE.
NOW DOWN THE FLOOR THEY GIVE IT TO NORM NIXON,
THEIR LITTLE POINT GUARD, AVERAGING 18.5 POINTS A GAME.
HE GOES TO THE FREE THROW LINE.
HIS 15-FOOTER IS GOOD!
AND LOS ANGELES IS IN FRONT 2 TO NOTHING.
IN WHITE, THE PISCES ON THIS PSYCHEDELIC FLOOR.
ONE OF THE MOST UNUSUAL BASKETBALL FLOORS
MAN WILL EVER SEE.
REVEREND JACKSON WITH IT.
HIS PASS COMES INSIDE, BACK TO JACKSON.
UNDERNEATH THE BASKET, TRAVELING IS CALLED.
OVERPASSING ON THE PLAY.
THE PISCES, THEY LOOK A LITTLE BIT TENSE.
THEY CAME OUT IN A COUPLE OF THE GAMES
IN THE PRELIMINARY ROUNDS OF THE PLAYOFFS THE SAME WAY,
BUT RALLIED, AND HERE THEY ARE IN THE CHAMPIONSHIPS.
KAREEM ABDUL-JABBAR,
A DOMINANT FACTOR IN THE HISTORY OF BASKETBALL.
AND OUTSIDE, LUCIEN TUCKER BURNS HIS EX-TEAMMATE.
DOESN'T HE LIKE THAT.
NO LOVE LOST BETWEEN TUCKER AND PARTICULARLY GUTHRIE.
LOU HUDSON KNOCKS THE BALL AWAY.
HIS TEAMMATE GETS THE BALL, AND THAT'S TUCKER.
DOWN THE FLOOR TO NIXON.
BEAUTIFUL PASS UNDERNEATH TO RON CARTER.
AND A SPINNING LAY-UP.
OH. A SENSATIONAL PLAY BY LOS ANGELES.
BACK ON DEFENSE, THE 7'2" KAREEM ABDUL-JABBAR.
A LOT OF PUSHING AND SHOVING,
PARTICULARLY IN THAT 3-SECOND AREA.
THE BALL COMES OUT IN FRONT.
THE PISCES PUT UP A SHOT, AND THEY DRILL IT HOME.
NICE SHOT OUT IN FRONT BY SET SHOT BUFFORD.
STOLEN. THEY HAVE THE BALL ONCE MORE COMING BACK,
AND DOWN THE MIDDLE GOES LOS ANGELES.
A SLAM DUNK-- LUCIEN TUCKER.
AND HE HAS A SMILE
AS HE COMES BACK DOWN THE FLOOR.
O.K. I WANT YOU TO GET A NOTE OFF TO THE L.A. BOYS
'CAUSE THEY'RE GONNA WIN, AND THEY'RE GONNA WIN BIG.
I WANT TO SEND THEM SOME LITTLE GOODIES,
SOME, UH, SOMETHING IN THE ORDER OF A BASKETBALL,
MAYBE A PAPIER-MACHé WITH THEIR INITIALS ON IT.
BE KIND OF CUTE... AND CHEAP.
UM, HOW ABOUT SOME EXOTIC FRUITS FROM THE ISLANDS?
OUR ISLANDS.
AND THIS--THIS IS UNIQUE.
GET THIS DOWN.
BLACK THINGS FOR BLACK PLAYERS
AND WHITE THINGS FOR WHITE PLAYERS.
THAT WAY, WE HAVE NO PROBLEMS.
THE LOS ANGELES CLUB WAS FAVORED COMING INTO THIS GAME,
DESPITE THE BRILLIANCE THIS YEAR,
IN THE SECOND HALF OF THE SEASON, AT LEAST,
BY THE PISCES.
HERE'S SET SHOT BUFFORD AGAINST MITCHELL.
TAKES IT OVER TO MOSES GUTHRIE.
GREAT PLAY! THE FIRST STEP BEAT LUCIEN TUCKER.
AND NOW THEY ARE BUMPING HARD WITH ELBOWS.
AND SOMETHING BIG COULD COME OF THIS.
LET'S HOPE NOT.
WE DON'T WANT TO SEE EITHER MAN
EJECTED FROM THIS GAME.
INTERCEPTION! JAMAAL TRUTH,
THE ARABIC HEADDRESS BLOWING IN THE BREEZE.
HE'S GOT A SLAM DUNK! HE MISSED THE SHOT!
AND THAT'S THE TRUTH.
OH. WHAT A BIG PLAY IN THIS BALLGAME.
LOOKS LIKE OUR CINDERELLA TEAM'S
ABOUT TO TURN INTO A PUMPKIN.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I SAID THE CINDERELLA TEAM'S
ABOUT TO CHANGE INTO A PUMPKIN.
IT'S A CRYIN' SHAME.
I CANNOT BELIEVE THAT THE PISCES
HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO PLAY BETTER...
CINDERELLA...
MIDNIGHT...
LOS ANGELES HAS BUILT UP A COMMANDING LEAD.
AND THEY ADD 2 MORE TO IT TO GO UP BY 15 POINTS...
EVERYTHING IS WRONG OUT THERE TONIGHT,
AND NOTHING'S HAPPENING RIGHT.
WHY IS THAT?
A STRANGE ASTROLOGICAL CONFIGURATION THAT HAPPENS
ONCE OUT OF EVERY 12 YEARS.
THE PISCES IS BLOCKED. THEY'RE JAMMED.
UNTIL TOMORROW.
WHICH IS EXACTLY, UM...
AN HOUR AND 45 MINUTES FROM NOW.
BUT AFTER THAT...
AFTER THAT, WE'RE...
HOME FREE! HOME FREE!
ALL WE GOT TO DO IS STALL UNTIL TOMORROW.
AFTER MIDNIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT CAN HAPPEN.
HERE'S HAINES FLIPPING THE BALL OVER TO THE RUNNING HAWK.
AND HERE'S THE END OF THE HALF.
[HORN BLOWS]
AND AT THE HALF, LOS ANGELES LEADING 62 TO 47.
WHAT'S GOING ON OUT THERE ANYWAY?
NO HUSTLE! NO FAITH!
NO HEART!
CHALK...
IF YOU WANT TO MAKE YOURSELF USEFUL...
FIND MONA. FIND MONA.
YEAH.
YOU GONNA CHANGE THE TIRE?
YOU CHANGE THE TIRE.
I GOT THE GAS AND THE BEER.
I GOT RIGHTS, YOU KNOW.
I JACKED UP THE CAR.
NOW YOU GOTTA CHANGE THE TIRE.
I DRIVE THE CAR.
YOU GOTTA CHANGE THE TIRE.
AS OF NOW, AMATEUR, YOU AND I IS A WASH!
[STARTS CAR]
THE GIRL!
YOU SEE THIS?
I KEEP THE END WITH THE POINT.
I THROW AWAY THE END WITH THE ERASER!
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
NO MORE MISTAKES!
TONIGHT WE HAVE A CHANCE TO MAKE HISTORY!
BUT ONLY IF WE WIN!
COMING CLOSE DOESN'T COUNT.
THIS IS BASKETBALL!
CLOSE ONLY COUNTS IN HORSESHOES AND HAND GRENADES!
SO, TYRONE, HOW ARE WE GOING TO DO THAT?
WE JUST TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF THE SITUATION.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
ALL THE WAY LIVE.
LET'S WEAR IT OUT, Y'ALL.
SEE YA LATER, T.
♪ YOU GOT THE POWER
♪ DON'T LET NOTHING STOP YOU ♪
♪ TOO-DOO TOO-DOO DOO
♪ YOU BUILT THE TOWER
♪ DON'T LET NOTHING SHAKE IT ♪
♪ TOO-DOO TOO-DOO DOO
♪ YOU GOT TO PSYCH 'EM RIGHT OUT OF THEIR SHOES ♪
♪ THE ZODIAC IS WITH YOU-OOO ♪
♪ YOU GOT THE JUMP, YOU GOT THE JUMP ♪
♪ MIGHTY, MIGHTY PISCES
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ GONNA BRING 'EM TO THEIR KNEES ♪
♪ MIGHTY, MIGHTY PISCES
♪ OO-OO-OOO
♪ NOW YOU'RE MAKIN' HISTORY ♪
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ LET'S SHAKE 'EM UP, LET'S SHAKE 'EM UP ♪
♪ NOW IS YOUR TIME TO SHINE ♪
♪ LET'S TURN 'EM OUT, LET'S TURN 'EM OUT ♪
♪ THE BALL'S IN MOTION
♪ KEEP YOUR HEAD TOGETHER
♪ TOO-DOO TOO-DOO DOO
♪ YOU'VE GOT DEVOTION
♪ YOU CAN'T LOSE IT EVER
♪ TOO-DOO TOO-DOO DOO
♪ YOU'VE GOT THE GAME IN THE PALM OF YOUR HAND ♪
♪ THE STARS ARE ON YOUR SIDE ♪
♪ JUST KEEP IT UP, JUST KEEP IT UP ♪
♪ MIGHTY, MIGHTY PISCES
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ GONNA BRING 'EM TO THEIR KNEES ♪
♪ MIGHTY, MIGHTY PISCES
♪ OO OO OOO
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
AFTER WHAT WILL UNDOUBTEDLY WIND UP IN THE RECORD BOOKS
AS THE LONGEST HALF TIME IN BASKETBALL HISTORY,
IT SEEMS THAT WE'RE FINALLY READY
FOR THE SECOND HALF.
[WHISTLE]
GET THE BALL!
AAH!
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON HERE?
LOOK AT THAT!
THOSE ARE FLOATIN' BALLS!
[WHISTLE]
BROCKINGTON! GIVE ME ANOTHER BALL!
SHIT.
TWO MINUTES, BROCKINGTON!
YOU GOT TWO MINUTES
TO GIVE ME AN OFFICIAL BASKETBALL!
IF YOU DON'T,
THIS GAME'S GOING TO BE FORFEITED!
I'VE HAD ENOUGH!
WELL, AFTER THAT LITTLE BY-PLAY,
IT LOOKS LIKE WE'VE GOT A REAL BASKETBALL
FILLED WITH REAL AIR.
DOWN THE FLOOR COMES BULLET HAINES FOR THE PISCES.
HIS PASS IS INTERCEPTED BY LUCIEN TUCKER.
DOWN THE FLOOR COMES LOS ANGELES.
NORMAN NIXON ON THE SCORING END OF THE PLAY.
AND LOS ANGELES REALLY MAKING A FARCE
OF THIS BASKETBALL GAME RIGHT NOW.
HERE COMES MOSES GUTHRIE.
HE ALMOST LOST THE HANDLE ON THE DRIBBLE.
MAKES A GREAT WRAPAROUND BOUNCE PASS.
IT GOES OVER TO THE FAR SIDE.
A LITTLE JUMP SHOT THAT'S WAY SHORT,
AND NOTHING IS GOING RIGHT FOR THE PISCES TONIGHT.
THEY ARE HAVING ALL KINDS OF TROUBLE
IN EVERY FACET OF THE BASKETBALL GAME.
THEY CAN'T SHOOT IT. THEY CAN'T CATCH IT.
THEY CAN'T DRIBBLE IT.
THEY CAN'T PASS IT.
AND WHEN YOU'RE IN THAT KIND OF A SITUATION,
IT'S GONNA BE TOUGH TO CATCH A TEAM
AS GREAT AS THIS LOS ANGELES CLUB.
INSIDE, A WRESTLING MATCH GOING ON.
AND A LOT OF PUSHING AND SHOVING.
LET'S SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
TUCKER REALLY JUMPS IN, AND HE KNOCKS HAMMER DOWN.
HE KNOCKED HIM DOWN HARD,
AND THEY EXCHANGE A FEW UNPLEASANTRIES.
THIS BASKETBALL GAME
IS GETTING A LITTLE BIT OUT OF HAND FOR THE PISCES.
AND IF THEY'RE GOING TO RALLY AND WIN THIS CHAMPIONSHIP,
THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE TO REALLY TURN IT ON,
AND DO IT VERY QUICKLY.
OH. JACKHAMMER FOR TWO.
TUCKER, I'LL MAKE A FOOL OUTTA YOU.
ENOUGH OF THAT!
YOU'RE ON.
[WHISTLE]
HA HA.
[CROWD] AWWW!
[CROWD CHEERS]
WHOO-HOO!
HA HA!
WE'LL NEVER MAKE IT TO MIDNIGHT.
ONCE AGAIN, LOS ANGELES ON THE MOVE.
CONNIE HAWKINS PASSED TO KAREEM ABDUL-JABBAR
FOR THE DUNK SHOT.
TIME OUT HAS BEEN CALLED NOW BY THE PISCES.
THEY TRAIL 101 TO 91.
I'LL BE DAMNED.
THIS TEAM AIN'T GONNA ROLL OVER
AND SURRENDER TO NO CLOCK.
NO WAY.
SUNSHINE. AFTER 14 YEARS OUT THERE
BARNSTORMING FOR PEANUTS, MAN...
YOU'RE NOT GONNA LET THE GOLD
SLIP THROUGH YOUR FINGERS NOW, ARE YOU?
AND, YOU, TRUTH.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT TAKING SHITTY BOUNCE
AFTER SHITTY BOUNCE JUST TO GET TO THE BRIDGE.
NO MAN ALIVE SHOULD STOP YOU FROM CROSSING OVER.
AND, YOU, JACKSON.
YOU'VE SPENT YOUR WHOLE LIFE TELLING PEOPLE
WHAT YOU THOUGHT THEY SHOULD DO
WHEN A SITUATION'S JUST LIKE THIS ONE.
DON'T LET THAT FAITH YOU'VE GIVEN THOSE FOLLOWERS
DESERT YOU.
NOW, WE'RE ALL MEN.
IF THE TIME IS NOW FOR US TO BE TESTED,
THEN LET IT HAPPEN.
DON'T YOU SEE?
THE ASTROLOGY THING IS JUST A MIRROR
FOR US TO LOOK INTO.
AN AID PUT THERE TO GIVE US A LITTLE BIT OF GUIDANCE.
SOMETIMES.
WELL, WE GOT HERE 'CAUSE OUR MAGIC'S MADE OF SWEAT.
AND STRAIN...AND PRIDE.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TAKING BACK OUT ON THE GODDAMN COURT.
IF YOU CATS ARE REAL MEN,
AND I KNOW YOU ARE,
YOU'RE GONNA COME BACK OUT THERE WITH ME...
AND YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE FIRE IN YOUR HEARTS,
AND YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE BLOOD IN YOUR EYES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA DO WHAT WE CAME HERE TO DO!
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
I DON'T KNOW HOW ELSE I CAN PLAY...
BUT RISE, LAZARUS.
BACK ONTO THE COURT COME THE PISCES,
TRAILING IT BY 10 POINTS.
[WHISTLE]
♪ GIVIN' IT ONE MORE TRY
♪ DOIN' IT TILL YOU FIND EVERLASTING PEACE OF MIND ♪
♪ EVERLASTING PEACE OF MIND ♪
♪ YOU KNOW IT'S DO OR DIE ♪
♪ LAY IT ON THE LINE
♪ WHEN YOU KNOW WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND ♪
♪ YOU KNOW WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND ♪
♪ OH, DO-DO DO-DO-DO DO-DO DO ♪
♪ DO-DO DO-DO-DO DO-DO DO ♪
♪ DO-DO DOO
YOU KNOW,
ACCORDING TO MY CALCULATIONS,
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE FOR THE PISCES TO WIN TONIGHT, BUT--
BUT WHAT?
SEE, THE THING IS I KNOW THAT,
AND YOU KNOW THAT...
BUT THEY DON'T.
GO GET HIM!
[WHISTLE]
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
LOS ANGELES HOLDING A 104-103 LEAD,
AND TIME IS RUNNING OUT.
TUCKER! GIVE ME THAT PUSS WHEN YOU GET OUT THERE!
DON'T USE IT HERE, SITTIN' ON YOUR BUTT!
NIXON!
WHEW!
JABBAR.
YOU DON'T SCARE ME!
BIGGEST MAN IN THE WORLD?
GET UP THERE AND PUT IT IN!
[GAME HORN BLOWS]
LISTEN, HOW ABOUT A CONDOMINIUM?
HOW ABOUT A USED CAR LOT?
A BLONDE, HUH?
A LEAR JET. AIRPLANE.
I'M NOT KIDDING. I CAN AFFORD THESE THINGS.
WHO IS THIS FOOL?
I'M WORTH $8 MILLION.
YOUR OWN BROTHER.
WHAT ABOUT MY BROTHER?
GET OFFA ME, MAN.
GIVE ME SOME GOOD NEWS.
[SOBBING] WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH ME?
OH, COMMISSIONER, ISN'T IT NICE?
MY BROTHER IS FINALLY HAVING A GOOD TIME.
3 SECONDS LEFT TO PLAY.
BALL OUT OF BOUNDS.
BASELINE BACK COURT.
HUDSON TAKES IT OUT.
HUDSON'S PASS IS KNOCKED DOWN.
FREE BALL!
THEY SCRAMBLE FOR IT ON THE FLOOR.
1st AND 10 SHOULD BE THE CALL,
BUT WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A JUMP BALL.
NOW LET'S SET THAT UP FOR YOU.
WE CUT THE CLOCK DOWN.
WE LOST TWO SECONDS THERE,
AND IT'S DOWN TO ONE SECOND LEFT.
HEY, REF!
WHAT'S HE TALKING ABOUT? HE FOULED ME.
[WHISTLE]
♪ LISTEN TO YOUR HEART
♪ AND LET US IN
♪ FOLLOW EVERY DREAM FOREVER ♪
♪ LISTEN TO YOUR HEART
♪ AND LET US IN
♪ FOLLOW EVERY DREAM...
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ HAVEN'T YOU, HAVEN'T YOU HEARD? ♪
♪ OH, HEY!
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ SHOUT IT OUT LOUD AND CLEAR ♪
♪ TELL THE WORLD IT HAPPENED HERE ♪
♪ SPREAD THE NEWS EVERYWHERE ♪
♪ ALL ACROSS THE LAND
♪ WAY TO GO, WAY TO TRY ♪
♪ IT'S ALL ABOUT OUR TEAMWORK, GUYS ♪
♪ FATHER TO SON, TENDER WORDS ♪
♪ TRYIN' TO STAY ALIVE
♪ HEY!
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ SPREAD THE WORD
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ SPIDERMAN, SUPERMAN
♪ NO SIX MILLION DOLLAR MAN ♪
♪ EVEN WONDER WOMAN'S SPINE ♪
♪ DIDN'T HAVE THE STUFF
♪ SUCH A TEAM COULDN'T BE ♪
♪ SO FAR FROM REALITY
♪ NOW IT'S JUST HISTORY
♪ HAT'S OFF TO THE FISH
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ FISH!
♪ HAVEN'T YOU, HAVEN'T YOU HEARD? ♪
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ HEY!
♪ HAVE YOU HEARD?
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ IT'S THE FISH THAT SAVED PITTSBURGH ♪
♪ WHOA OOH OH, HEY
♪ FISH
♪ HAVEN'T YOU, HAVEN'T YOU HEARD? ♪
♪ IT'S THE FISH
♪ HAVEN'T YOU, HAVEN'T YOU HEARD...♪