THE NUDE VAMPIRE
- Do you have an invitation?
- I don't have one.
Then I'm sorry.
Get out.
You were on Ile Saint-Louis tonight.
You mean at your townhouse?
I wanted to see it.
I've told you before
not to meddle in my affairs.
But ....
I am your son.
If you want money, you'll get it.
Women, there's no shortage..
But mind your own business.
I could have been killed last night!
Stay away from my business!
So that's it.
You hold private parties on Ile Saint-Louis,
you kidnap a girl,
and no one says anything.
I've had enough.
I'm going to find out what my father
and his two partners are up to.
- Very good, Solange.
- Thank you, Mr. Radamante.
One more thing, Solange
please, tell my son
I won't be home for supper.
I have business to attend to.
- And serve us some drinks.
- Right away, Mr. Radamante.
Everything is fine.
I follow his every step
Don't worry, he won't see me.
Everywhere he goes I'll be there,
in the shadows.
And so the show -
We didn't come for that.
What's going on?
Are the premises suitable?
I hope you know what you're doing,
Radamante.
- All this is costing a fortune.
- Not to mention the risks.
Everything is as I like.
You must leave quickly.
You'll find your father at his office.
Go there at once.
Other mysteries await you.
Is that you, Pierre?
I am very busy.
What? Animal men?
A young girl?
What are you talking about?
You want me to come down in the car
in the middle of the night?
You're in danger? Okay, I'm coming.
Where are you?
Drive you to your father's office?
Okay. Wait for me.
There was a spy at the townhouse.
- Who was that?
- Do not know. He escaped.
We must clear the townhouse
and bring her here.
Leave it to me.
She'll be here before dawn.
What is this?
Blood analyses
with names and occupations.
Night watchman, bouncer-
they all work at night.
There are hundreds of them.
The blood, the night -
And why photos of the girl on the wall?
She could be a robot. That explains
why the bullet didn't kill her
She put her hand on my face.
I touched her. She's not a robot.
Sir!
Sir, they have just caught two men.
They showed their faces -
in front of her.
- What? Did she see them?
- Yes
One of them is your son.
What's this, Radamante?
Does your son know about it?
My son does not know.
So why is he here
in the middle of the night?
Bring my son right away.
Don't forget,
I have the most to lose here.
- But -
- No buts.
The only way out of this is to give
part of the solution to my son
Who is that girl?
How did she survive those bullets?
Who are those lunatics
who kill themselves in the townhouse?
What are you doing here?
Why do they put hoods on
when the girl goes by?
Since you ask specific questions,
I'll give you straight answers.
Firstly, that girl is my protégé.
She's an orphan.
lam all she has
Secondly, it suffers from a
unknown blood condition.
Any wounds she has heal right away
as long as her vital organs
aren't injured.
Thirdly, in the eyes of some fanatics,
she is a goddess.
I was happy for this suicide sect,
which worships her,
to use my townhouse.
That's it.
We are looking for someone with
the same blood type as her,
and therefore the same disease,
to try to cure it.
We look at people who live at night',
because those with her con condition
can't tolerate sunlight
The hoods are to hide
their faces from" her.
She has never seen
another human being.
She mustn't know she is different.
She would suffer too much.
Satisfied?
- No.
- What do you mean by "no"?
You're an accomplice to murder
at your townhouse. Why?
Do you know who is your prisoner?
Enough.
We're not detaining her,
we're protecting her
from those who want her
for motives less noble than ours.
What are your motives?
We are scientists, researchers.
Listen, Pierre.
I'll let you go, you and your friend.
Give me 48 hours to justify myself.
Come back tomorrow
and you'll find out everything.
Very good.
Robert will accept the extension.
Forty-eight hours.
Beyond that,
I don't promise anything.
My dear friend,
we must hush this up.
Otherwise we both risk
being compromised.
The corpses that have been found
near my townhouse -
My name mustn't be -
Your name?
Understood, my friend. Understood.
I'll see you very soon.
Mr. Gray, is that you?
It's Radamante.
Sell everything, even at a low price
the townhouse on lle Saint-Louis,
office building, everything.
That's an order.
What do you have for sale?
I need something discreet, isolated,
something outside of Paris.
I must be able to move in today.
ls the chateau furnished?
How far is it from Paris?
Sixty miles? Perfect.
We leave in an hour.
Lock the girl in the van
so no sunlight can penetrate.
Get the bags ready.
You're coming with me.
Notify my associates to join us here
with two armed drivers.
- We'll be safe here.
- But what are you afraid of?
It was I who found the girl.
There are others of her species.
Someone is coming.
Mr. Radamante, I can't accompany you,
but the doors are open.
The chateau belongs to you now.
Treat it with respect.
- But -
- He leaves just like that!
We don't even know
where the rooms are.
It's not important. Come along.
This will suit me nicely.
Solange will join us tonight.
My son stayed in Paris.
As for his friend Robert -
Oh yeah, what about him?
He knows too much.
You needn't worry.
In a few minutes, he'll be gone.
Who will do the job?
Who else are you going to involve?
Solange. At this very moment,
she should be with him.
But my son mustn't know of it.
Robert was his friend.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
- I came to ask for help.
- Ask me?
Yes.
I want to leave Radamante.
He's going to commit more crimes.
That girl is a vampire.
She feeds on human blood.
Radamante wants
her power of immortality.
For that, he needs someone
with her type of blood,
another vampire
with whom to mate her.
But tell me,
What are you doing?
They organized that suicide cult
who kill themselves to feed her
We do not know yet how the vampires
recognize each other.
They research,
analyze,
study.
They must be stopped!
Where is everybody? Have they fled?
His father and his associates
have left Paris.
I have stayed behind
to pass on his orders to you.
Where's your friend?
Robert is at home.
He wants nothing more
to do with my father.
Forty-eight hours from now,
will call the police.
Unless, that is,
my father proves he is innocent.
I want that girl.
I want to know her secret.
- Voringe. Voringe!
- What is that?
It's me, Fredor.
Can you hear it?
- The drum? Of course I can.
- What is it?
- Where is Radamante?
- Come on, we'll find him.
What is it? it's you.
- Can you hear it?
- Must be the drivers.
Drivers? Playing the drums
in the middle of the night?
Wake up to the drivers.
Make sure they are armed.
Both are dead.
That's the signal.
She is free.
- Pierre, you've arrived in time.
- Don't touch her. What's going on?
They are going to attack us.
They tried to kidnap the girl.
I'd like to believe you.
Close the doors.
She mustn't see the daylight.
We must prepare for a siege.
We'll discuss later.
- Well?
- Pierre has arrived at the chateau.
They have shut themselves
in the library.
The young girl is in their hands again.
We won't attack tonight.
It'll be daylight soon.
We must free her. I don't want to
take the risk of fighting until then.
I'm waiting for an explanation.
The problem is simple.
We need to find a way to feed her.
I want to know the whole story.
This girl has a great power:
immortality.
Those who only feed on blood
and can not tolerate sunlight
have this power.
- Like vampires?
- Yeah, like vampires.
We have been trying to find out ...
how such a physiological marvel
could exist.
But we had to leave Paris
especially since you and your friend.
I understand. You want her powers.
But Pierre, think about it.
Immortality!
At what price?
You tortured her in your laboratories,
you subjected her
to your experiments,
you terrorized her
with your strange guardians.
- You kept others from her view.
- Until today.
Thanks to you,
she has seen our faces now.
- Who are your enemies?
- Other monsters, no doubt.
Monsters?
I thought you were protecting her.
All right, I want to see these monsters.
Who are you looking for?
Your friend was killed tonight.
But, how?
He was killed
on the orders of your father.
On the orders of my father?
I have seen this sign before.
The woman who saved my life
at the townhouse
by killing one of the animal men
wore the same sign.
You, too, will carry the sign one day
like us, like her.
The girl?
She is one of us.
You also are one of us.
Don't you know that yet?
Who are you?
On the grounds you will find someone
with the answers to your questions.
Who are you?
What are you doing?
- I was meditating.
- Why?
Because within these walls,
there are innocents locked up.
And a crime will be committed soon.
- A crime?
- Yes
Are you a priest?
Not
I am not a priest of any religion,
although I celebrate a cult
because those who will be killed ...
have protected the life
of someone who is mine.
- The girl?
- Yes.
She is mine too.
Is it possible to keep her alive
without any more sacrifices?
Yes, I can. You can.
They shot at her, and she's alive.
Who is she?
I'm the one who knows.
You're one of us.
What you have seen tonight,
what you will see, is not real.
Your father and his associates
believe in vampires.
So they will see vampires.
But before dawn,
the mysteries will become clear,
and evil will be punished.
As for you,
let me be your guide.
Look at me. And you will know
the one who you are destined for.
Now let me.
Before the last crime is committed,
I must meditate again.
You have betrayed me, you little pests.
I have always despised you.
But now, there will be
no more obstacles
between me and Radamante.
Pierre took these risks.
But where is Solange?
Ah, Solange. Well?
Robert is dead.
- Two traitors have also paid more.
- Who?
Your two loyal little puppies,
Mr. Radamante.
They told her son everything.
I fear he is against us.
Shoot, Solange, shoot.
Quick, we must escape.
We are powerless against them.
We can not harm them.
I'll give the signal to attack.
Take care of her.
Don't let her get near the fighting.
Let's go.
Please take it.
So... you're not vampires?
Who are you?
Let them go!.
They have lost and they know it.
You must return to the chateau.
You must go and see your father
and his associates.
Afterwards, you will be one of us.
But how will I find you?
Await guidance, you'll find us.
Pierre, listen to me.
I will guide you.
The time has come for you
to gain the knowledge
Here's another one.
I'm so happy.
He is so young.
Come, come.
I have come.
We know.
You always end up coming here.
We guide you here.
We await your arrival, with
the same joy, for over 50 years.
In a moment,
you will go through those curtains.
This is just an antechamber.
We will never meet again.
Let us look at you a little longer.
They are gone so quickly.
Is it true? You don't know yet?
You don't know who you are?
Who we all are?
I know you. You are the one
destined for the young girl.
The girl?
- Where is it?
- Do not be impatient.
The time has come for you to know.
Here, take this ring ...
and go through the curtains.
So,
now our waking commences.
Sometimes two come, sometimes three.
Sometimes none at all.
We just have to wait.
He went in there.
We must follow it.
- I think it's too dangerous.
- You can not count on us.
Okay, I'll go alone.
Do you understand this?
No. I think she was a vampire
Radamante kept prisoner for 20 years.
- But was she a vampire in the end?
- I don't know.
The experiments were inconclusive.
That's true. All my capital went into
that townhouse and the office block
The only thing they found out
was that the girl's blood
belongs to an unknown type.
It's a bit limited to conclude
that she was a vampire.
She was perhaps no more
a vampire than you or I.
- You forget all those immortals.
- Well, these things happen.
Radamante must have thought
when kidnapping her
that one day
her family would look for her.
If Pierre hadn't interfered,
the vampires wouldn't have found us.
Oh, him! Fallen in love
with a vampire. Can you believe it?
But is she a vampire?
She is something. In any case, vampire
or werewolf, we are ruined.
- What will happen to Radamante?
- Too bad for him.
Anyway, now that they have managed
to lure him to the chateau,
there is little chance of seeing him alive.
He is not immortal.
- Where is my son?
- Careful, this man is not -
It will not work.
We are not in the same dimension.
In reality,
you haven't left the chateau.
- Where is the vampire?
- You are the real vampire.
You made her accustomed to drinking blood.
You kept her from sunlight.
Look.
For the first time,
she sees sunlight.
She is one of us, like Pierre
We are not vampires.
One day, the human race will be
like this young girl, your son and I.
All will have the power
of immortality.
We are the prototype of future man.
The first mutation
of the human race,
announcing tomorrow's race.
Vampires never have existed,
but there are mutants.
You will all disappear.
You are powerless against us.
You are powerless against evolution.
Tomorrow, today,
at any time,
the day of the mutants may arrive.