They abandoned their homes
and crossed the deserts...
...carrying their children on
their backs...
And with their men they made
the Mexican Revolution.
I'm going to sing a song...
... that everybody sings...
... about a woman from the
troop...
... who everybody knows.
Who are you?
Villa's people.
Go ahead.
That's Antonio Zeta,
the colonel.
Colonel Zeta?
He had 600 men.
What happened?
And in Conejos town...
... by a very calm street...
... comes the brave
Antonio Zeta...
... he's sad and beaten.
What eyes that man has!
How can we live in peace with
so much anger?
Poorpeople's blanket!
Killed for being brave!
He sang to St. Peter!
The soldier in frock coat!
- Where's the quarter?
- Over there.
Hey!
Where are you from?
From the "Sabino".
We're the only left.
Look how's the Revolution here,
Colonel.
Yes.
Where do you go?
I look for Colonel Zuñiga.
Who are you?
- Antonio Zeta.
- Tell him.
Are you Colonel Antonio Zeta?
- Yes, I am.
- Come on in.
- Antonio Zeta?
- Yes.
So that guy is Antonio Zeta
with his "North Panthers"!
Colonel...
I waited for you at the "Sabino".
Don't tell me...
I didn't know it.
That's what I have left.
I started the attack thinking
you were coming.
My people died; women,
children...
Mendoza was killed at the
trap.
But you... why you didn't come?
Because I'd end up as Mendoza.
And colonel Villa's orders?
I learned about Mendoza and I
was getting ready for the...
...attack.
- Did you attack?
Well... there are no supplies.
I have few people.
You have few guts!
If I reply that, we'll die.
But my life's for the Revolution.
You're not such a soldier.
Captain... arrest him!
- What can I do?
- I won't turn this fight into...
...a vulgar argument.
- At your orders, Colonel.
Disarm him and take him.
We'll see...
We 'll see what
Mr. Carranza thinks about this.
He's my Major.
Look after the wounded.
Search a place to stay.
Let's see the guns, Major.
What guns? There are no
supplies.
I don't want any women here.
Soldier!
Follow the order!
All of you, women, get out
of here!
Take them away, Pascual.
Make them go with all
their stuff!
That one too!
- Don't take that!
- I obey the Colonel.
He said women; I'm a soldier of
the Major State. Go!
- OK.
- Hurry up!
I have news: Colonel
Zeta is about to arrive.
He's believed to be the devil.
He fought in Chihuahua and...
..."El Paredóón". He comes to
arrest Zuñiga; Villa ordered it.
Villa ordered it?
- He didn't say so.
- I did, but you didn't listen.
Move! Move, people! Here
comes your hurricane!
I know! Your "barrel".
Right. And give me a cognac
bottle. An expensive one.
- I want it here.
- On credit?
- Well...
- Oh, no!
Give it to her and
charge it to me!
This is made of gold, and
she's Mendez's!
- Isn't she?
- Lf you say so...
Don't grow hot. You'll grow
cold later!
That's right!
This gold doesn't buy
"La Cucaracha"!
Thank you!
Charge from here.
It's made of gold, too.
But don't forget the change.
Keep it so you stop being
heretic, so it takes care...
...of you.
Take care of me... I took it
from a dead soldier.
If he was that good and he
died, what do I want it for?
I don't trade with sacred
things...
I'll give you credit.
- "Trumpet"!
- Yes, chief.
At your orders.
Here's the bottle; defend
it with your life.
Let's see how much Colonel
Zeta can stand.
- OK.
- Who invites the drinks now?
That's how you pay for fun?
I'll pay you, Jacobo.
So I won't see you again.
The new colonel is finding
things out.
- So?
- He realized there are not...
...supplies here.
- So what?
So what?
You can't traffic
with the guns.
What's the matter?
What are you talking about?
Don't act dumb. You and the
other bastards hid the guns.
You were going to sell them
tonight, right?
Don't shiver; you'd better leave.
You give me the creeps.
Go away!
Mendez...
I want to talk to you.
Come with me.
You were right, Colonel.
The guns are here, but nobody
would say anything.
We may be standing over them.
What about Zuñiga
and the others?
They won't speak a word.
Our effort was in vain.
- The troop?
- It's a small and bad one.
People are fed up with it.
- And the woman?
- Well, let's say it this way:
She's a slut, that's why she's
called "The Cockroache".
- I don't understand.
- Yes...
Cockroaches are not fine with
a single male. They manage...
...to take other cockroaches'
males.
- Now what?
- We'll follow Villa's orders.
What if we don't find the guns?
We'll follow his orders!
... give him some help...
... tell that man to come
on in...
Tell him to come, if he's a
real man!
... I want to know his
betrayals...
... if I have to know his name...
... l'll help him ifyou love him.
"Cucaracha", why do you
take care of that bottle?
Take care of what
is important!
Where's your wife?
Whom is that cognac for?
Don't you know the news?
It's for the what's-his-name...
...of the what's-her-name.
Even the "Trumpet" is
guarding it.
What's-his-name's your dad,
what's-her-name's your mom...
The "Trumpet" is your
godmother!
What kind a person is one
with such relatives!
Chief, I don't think that
guy is coming. Maybe he...
...doesn't drink.
- I didn't say you could rest.
A meeting?
What's going on?
He doesn't drink.
Really?
I'm not the greatest man,
I don't want to be...
...but I order because I was
sent for that.
To triumph, you have to die.
Let's die quickly so others can
come back and work, so they...
...are not lazy.
I want you to understand...
...so we search the same goal,
the same way.
Trinidad...
...bring Zuñiga.
Melesio Lopez, Jacobo Mendez...
One step ahead.
Ricardo Zuñiga, Melesio Lopez
and Jacobo Mendez will be...
...shot now, for treachery.
You're in charge, Lieutenant.
Follow me.
Let me explain... I don't know
where the guns are.
Let me explain...
It's not fair, Colonel...
I don't understand you.
Maybe you like to lose.
Yes, sir. We can't enter by this
way, nor this one, nor that one.
There are no guns nor people.
They are in St. Blas.
If the point is dying, it'll be
easy.
You're right, Major. We'll go
over St. Blas tomorrow.
- The point's dying.
- Dying of laughter.
- With what guns?
- I said no women here.
By now, instead of soldiers
there are people of the town.
Call those who know how to
use a gun.
Walk. Come on, walk!
Colonel!
I'm talking to you!
Why don't you kill me too?
Beacuse I'm not sure.
- Of my being guilty?
- Of your being a woman.
- Really?
- I don't kill women.
Colonel! The horse's ready.
It's the best I could get.
- Did you buy it?
- Well, I gave them a receipt.
A receipt...
- What do you do with women?
- He lectures them as with the...
...soldiers. Zeta knows how to
speak.
The only thing he knows!
He's not for this stuff.
Here, the Revolution isn't about
dying nor sowing the land.
Revolution is fighting and
and drinking: That's...
...the best part.
- Neither dying nor sowing.
People don't know about
lectures. They take a gun and...
...kill anyone in exchange
of a drink.
- Lf you don't kill, you die.
- Even worse: You don't eat.
The 2 mules I'm talking to are
busy.
Look, "Cucaracha"...
...I'm here to fight, that's what
I do. And you're here for...
...what you do.
- I don't think the colonel...
...likes what you do. Don't dress
like that. Why did you steal...
...the gringo's clothes?
Dress like a woman.
Excuse us, Coronel. Don't pay
heed to small things.
You waste your time.
Maybe the priest doesn't
know about the guns.
I'll take care of him. I'll
be in the church.
Drink some blessed water, not
my cognac!
I bought it to share it with you,
but now it's all mine!
He's such a "saint"! I can't make
him fall.
Don't you drink my cognac!
Walk! Walk!
For God's sake!
Don't take him away!
Calm down, lady. The boy is old
enough to die.
No, please.
Colonel!
I refuse to obey your orders.
I've never shot a gun and...
...I never won't.
I'll be a useless victim.
I'm with the Revolution, but not
for killing.
I can be of more use,
with my work. Let me explain.
But they are just children!
Colonel!
Gabriel!
Where's Gabriel?
Colonel, my husband, Gabriel
Puente... it's a mistake.
He's the teacher; he's been
taken with the other men!
Ask anyone. He's the teacher.
He teaches the children. He
can't kill. You're taking all...
...the men. What do you want
Gabriel for?
He can help Revolution in
another way.
I'm talking...
What do you want Gabriel for?
Don't go!
What will you ask God for?
Hypocrite!
You're Antonio Zeta...
I know what you come for.
I don't know about the guns.
Are you taking all men to
St. Blas?
- You need them all.
- I do.
Let me go on. My husband was
taken to the quarter. Please!
Gabriel!
Go home, ma'am.
Go! Go!
Bastard!
Come in, boys!
St. "Cucaracha" will make a
miracle. Don't go with the priest.
Let's see if he's that good...
There you are to spit on
St. Blas!
Yes...
The point was dying.
Where is he?
What are you waiting for?
What are you making a
bonfire for?
- Put out those bonfires!
- Don't you!
Do you want us to die sooner?
Forgive me, Captain, but those
are Colonel Zeta's orders.
- Where is he?
- You know where.
- Where?
Damn! Now we have to obey a
crazy man.
The bonfire!
We were supposed to take
St. Blas... where one dies.
Yes...
Only because they didn't
feel like...
...they didn't kill us all.
We knew it was insane to take
St. Blas.
But who understands now?
Sending us to this hole...
...so we are more visible.
And I say:
"Lord...
...send me back to my village.
- Don't be mean."
- Yes...
That'd be good. But He is
not here to endure all this.
Have you seen Mr. Gabriel?
Mr. José...
...have you?
Look...
...how gorgeous is that woman.
- She must be cold.
- Get close to her. Her husband...
...must be dead.
So, Felipe, you kill Zeta.
Hurry up! He's hard to get.
Take Meco in case Zeta goes
crazy.
No, you'd better not. First,
go for Ventura.
He may not agreed.
Have you seen the "Trumpet"?
Bear it, love, bear it.
You'll soon have it.
- You'll see.
- Why did you bring her here?
She's a soldier. She must go
wherever her man goes!
She's not like other women.
She's new. She doesn't know.
But she will endure this.
I'm leaving. I have to watch
over. I'll be right back!
I wish...
- It must be a boy.
- What for? It'd better die.
It's not your baby!
Look. They'll fight and won't
know who killed them.
Or they'll grow old in misery.
What will life give this child?
Chief!
You were right. The thing will
happen soon; there's much...
...noise up there.
They are so sad, look.
Look, "Trumpet", get all the
drinks you can. Hurry up!
Yes, chief.
Shut up, women!
Instead of being here, go to...
...cheer your men up.
- We won't get it, not even...
...being naked!
- Lf you don't move, the sun...
...will burn you.
Where are you going?
Come heat them up; you have
a pretty face.
Gabriel! Honey!
Honey!
You're not...
...you're not Mr. Gabriel.
- I'm not, but if you want me to...
...that's OK.
- Why do you have his blanket?
- It was a present.
- It's my husband's!
A sleepy-eyed fancy man?
- Yes.
- He doesn't need it any more.
He remained stiff, looking at
the sky, and for a long time.
- No, no!
- Yes! He got a shot in the head.
Oh, my God!
Calm down! Stop your whining!
If you lose your man, find...
...another one. You'd better
find him soon!
- Poor woman!
- Nothing will change here.
- You're right.
- Chief! Here 's the "fury".
Hand it out.
We go with the people, and as
soon as hearing the shoots...
...raise that rag very high.
I think Zeta is crazy.
- That's it.
- No.
This won't be their hole, as
they've planned.
Zeta didn't fool us; let's be
straight.
If he gets crazy, I'll take
care.
- But you won't betray him.
- Lf you say so.
We pretended to be garbage...
... a hurricane came and
lifted us...
... and we were flying high.
I'd like to be a worthy pearl
for your earrings...
... to bite your little ear
and kiss your cheeks.
Why are you so pretty that
you drive me crazy?
Passion rules my heart...
This was called Demetrio Luna.
He lived far away.
Come on. Come and help me;
my back aches.
These deads are a nuisance.
OK, but... who will bury us
tomorrow?
- I can see...
- Shut up.
Hey, guys, here we have fire!
If I drink tequila today...
... l'll drink sherry tomorrow...
Colonel!
Here they come, Colonel, they
come in a hurry!
That's what the fire was for.
We're sorrounded by federals.
The "Cucaracha" spoiled the
people, they are very drunk.
- I don't know what you can do.
- Go back to your position.
Let's hope God helps us.
OK, Colonel.
Colonel Zeta...
We agreed not to follow your
orders. We'll be an easy target...
...with those bonfires, and
people don't want to fight.
We'll leave as soon as the
enemy attacks.
With all respect, Colonel, I'll
take care of your reaction.
You're late.
The people is ready to fight.
Listen to them.
...biting your ear and
kissing your cheeks.
You are the kind of person...
...who takes the fortress
or dies trying.
But those damned bonfires...
I need your help, Captain.
Help me.
You'll soon know why we die.
Tell me what you think.
I say to myself:
"Zeta is a sincere man, and he's
a soldier. He doesn't let...
...his people die without
a reason."
You can count on me, Colonel.
Come here.
It's time, guys!
They're coming!
The federals are coming!
The federals of St. Blas
are coming!
Where is Colonel Zeta?
Glorify my soul, Lord.
- Has the baby been born?
- No.
He won't be born!
Why?
There are many!
And more keep coming.
He won't be born!
Don't worry.
Move.
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Don't you kill each other!
No!
No! No!
What time is it?
Don't cry, "Chipotle". I'll
give you weed so you sleep...
Come on.
"Trumpet"!
Don't die, "Trumpet"!
There's a lot to do!
- Chief!
- You're screwed.
Kill them!
Kill them! Kill them!
There's no supply!
Tell them some swearwords!
They hurt too!
Federals are sons of!
Gabriel!
Gabriel! Gabriel!
- Stop crying and let's go!
- No!
No! No!
Don't refuse it! Hold her!
Come here! We're here to...
...be killed!
Retiring?
What time is it?
Right now we're taking
St. Blas, boys!
General Villa is entering
St. Blas!
That's what we're dying for.
Time! Time!
We should be killed when...
...Villa entered.
You've given me a good
lesson, Colonel!
Come here, Sergeant!
It's time, people! Hurray for
the Revolution...
...let's enjoy it!
Ma'am, I...
I'm not important here.
There are better men.
I'm a soldier.
I'd like you to allow me...
...to talk to you.
You're alone.
You haven't chosen any
men yet...
If you wished...
Sorry for having thought...
That one is gorgeous.
Look at it.
No, no. I like that one.
It's expensive.
Well... you're right.
So you don't want to buy it?
Not at that price.
Give me 20.
20 pesos?
I wouldn't be here if
I had them.
Take it. I'll buy the shawl.
Take it, ma'am.
A present.
Don't think about it, ma'am.
Take it.
Give it to the Colonel...
...for one of his lovers.
I didn't mean to offend you.
No, of course you didn't.
But keep your shawl...
...as I kept my cognac.
This is not enough for me.
You couldn't be my boyfriend.
Then what?
Well, I take the cotorina.
The cheapest one.
With my own money.
Don't be mean.
I just want you to like me.
It won't be easy.
You have to give me flowers.
I'll give you flowers.
To my grave, when I die!
You won't ever get
me to like you.
Give it to me.
Who is it?
Who else? It's me.
I brought some presents.
Go away. The door's closed.
I couldn't wait until you die...
I said: "I'd better go now."
Here you are.
And cognac, if you want
to share it.
And the 20-peso shawl.
I only ask once.
I ask many times.
I've only asked twice.
I said it wouldn't be easy.
I don't want your flowers...
...nor your bottle...
...nor your shawl.
But you liked the shawl...
...you look nice.
Don't touch me.
Accept it.
Let me go!
Don't you ever hit a man.
Never!
Take your clothes off.
You'll be a woman.
Your clothes off!
What's up?
I'm fine, Colonel.
We're here, fighting.
St. Blas is nice, right?
Ready?
Wait a minute.
Yes.
Don't move.
Very nice!
Thanks.
Enjoy your meal, Captain.
The same for you, Colonel.
When I was a kid, I liked
eating flavored ice.
Then buy some ice for me.
I like your eyes.
They were dark before.
They looked wild.
They were shining last night.
Now they're calm.
They're laughing.
Your eyes never looked
like that.
I'll love you very much.
Do you remember when
I laughted at you?
I did it again.
I wanted you to see me.
But you didn't do it.
That's why I bought the cognac.
I didn't have another way to
express...
...that I wanted to be with you.
You know?
I wished to die...
...so you suffered seeing
me dead.
It's good I didn't die!
Antonio Zeta.
Nobody is called Zeta.
You have a nice name.
You know?
Though I've been with many
men, you're the one.
I'm going to love you much.
Yes.
Now take your ice.
I'm in love with a woman...
... I feel better only
when I'm drunk...
... with much wine...
... to wander.
And if you were nice to me...
... you'd have my protection...
What a pretty woman.
And so reserved.
They call her widow, but
she's a lady.
Yes.
And she's hard to get.
She doesn't pay heel to anyone.
Nobody gets close to her.
Don't hate me.
I don't order. I just follow
orders.
And I have to obey them.
Without knowing faces,
nor names.
I'm sorry for what I did.
If I could give you back what
I took...
...I would so you don't cry.
I was given this.
I was given these cents as...
...a compensation for my
husband's death.
I think he betrayed himself.
He didn't want to kill.
He could have given a great
service.
As a teacher.
But you didn't listen to him.
Where is he?
Among all those unknown...
...dead people.
Don't think about that.
We're not here to listen...
We'll listen to other people
later.
Now, it's all about dying.
That's unfortunately true.
Conejos town was occupied by
federals.
They burnt it.
You can't go there.
We'll leave in 2 weeks.
I'll stay in St. Blas.
Be with us.
We need women like you.
Take care.
If you need something...
...let me know.
The Cockroach...
... the Cockroach has died...
No. Now she's being born.
She'll be a soldier.
It's the first time I see you as
a woman. How does it feel?
Get another husband and you'll
know.
Children, don't snoop the
teacher's widow!
Come here!
Look, "Cucaracha", hats have
other uses besides protecting!
The lady has good manners,
right, Colonel?
- I was about to go with you.
- I wanted to hurry.
Maybe you don't take your hat
for me.
Don't say so. I love you.
- But she... is a lady.
- And what about me?
You're my woman. Why do you
want me to flatter you?
- You're right.
- I'll be out some days.
- I'll receive orders.
- I go with you.
No. You know you have to wait
for me.
OK, Colonel, but don't be away
too long.
- Give me a blasthole, quickly.
- I want a bullet.
Take it. Give me the
blasthole.
Here come the federals!
Hey, don't mess with her.
There's no man to protect her.
She must look for one. She has
tricks to find him.
Maybe she doesn't like men,
"Cucaracha".
Why do you insult me?
Why do you care about me?
Don't lecture me!
I do what I want!
Everybody knows that.
You have to be smart to find a
good man...
Look for him. Don't take
what is...
...not yours!
You're in the church.
My ass! Go look for a man.
I don't know how. I'm not a
slut.
That's how easy women are
called.
And good-for-nothing women
are called mules!
Here, you have to fight.
Don't be finicky.
- You defend your job.
- You do the same!
Were you crying for your man?
The Revolution...
...gives you a new one!
There are many out there.
Some are more useful than
your guy.
No one.
My husband was the worthiest
man.
But I pleased you...
...if the man I like wouldn't
have an owner.
Though his owner is nothing
but a...
Take him away!
Come on, do it!
With whatever you have.
What I have is much for you...
...soldier woman.
I lost my peace of mind...
... because of a mean woman...
It was a hard day.
Yes. Go and tell the people.
We have some hours to sleep.
Good night, Colonel.
... since she didn't have
feelings...
... and she was a bad woman...
... she went away with my love...
... for ever more.
Give a bottle, Sr. Cosme.
Yes, Colonel.
- Is it him?
Valentín Razo wants to meet
a Antonio Zeta...
...and drink with him.
At your service.
I'd better serve and
you drink.
Why?
Just because I want to.
No, don't go. I want to drink
on behalf of coincidences.
Both of us are Villa's
colonels.
Both are famous for being
true men.
And both of us...
...have known the same woman.
She might not remember me...
But I...
...still feel her taste
in my mouth.
Congratulations, Mr. Zeta.
If I didn't respect you...
...I'd ask you to share
her with me.
Your words are not good.
Your words may cause your
death.
He didn't fall in the trap.
That man's dangerous,
Colonel.
Don't mess with him.
I am the dangerous one!
He has my woman, and he
doesn't want to fight for her.
How could I love her?
Excuse my anger. Major.
Have some drinks with me.
You know, I'm bewithched.
I came following her.
I dream of her.
I prefer her dead before...
...seeing her with another
man.
And I find her...
...engaged with another man!
And look who is it.
I spoke with fury.
I can't regret now.
The truth is that this colonel
seems to be...
...very brave.
And now...
...I'm compromised.
What a nice shawl!
It looks so nice on you!
It's good you're here.
I waited for you forever.
What did you do?
I met a man called
Valentin Razo.
He's a tough man.
Hard talk.
He seems to be dangerous.
I think you know him.
Why?
It looks like you hurt him.
Valentin Razo.
I don't know him.
What happened?
Nothing. I broke a glass.
My cross.
Your cross.
Colonel Zeta...
I've been following that woman.
She promised to come back
with me.
This is the man.
Valentin Razo is apologizing
for what he did.
Don't just keep my words,
Colonel Zeta!
I can't keep the humiliation!
I didn't remember him.
Don't keep that mean woman...
...without sorting things out!
You took her from me...
That's not right.
But now you can face me.
I'm here.
I'm waiting for you,
Colonel!
You're a man.
I'm a man too.
Try to prove you're more
man than me.
You took advantage once.
Now come down!
Come down, here!
Let's kill each other!
Come on!
Shame on him.
Or shame on me.
Yes.
Take this bouquet...
... of fresh flowers...
... taken from the field.
Tell me if you have...
... a new love...
... so I won't be in your way.
Don't get angry, Colonel.
She doesn't deserve a thought.
Well, I say so.
Keep it, please.
A drink?
OK.
Thank you.
I'm glad you came with us,
ma'am.
My name is Isabel.
Isabel.
The three of them walked
in silence...
... they were thinking...
... while the blind destiny...
... was weaving a new plot.
What?
I almost died.
When that man yelled at you
and you went to kill him.
Then I waited for you.
That man died...
...for loving her.
Don't you say "that man".
You didn't know him.
I don't care if he died!
You don't forgive yourself.
Why do you blame me and...
...treat me like a trash?
I don't.
It's my guilt for not having...
...forgiven Valentin Razo.
You should have.
Do you feel that bad?
And the ones you killed before?
I remember them.
But they died for the
Revolution.
And this one died for a woman.
When Valentin Razo died...
...the air uncombed his hair.
Then I imaged you the way
I like...
...waiting for me, wrapped
in your shawl.
And I felt ashamed.
I love you.
But I feel I must stop
loving you.
You can leave.
Pay attention to me.
You prepare the food and I
sing for you.
And when in war, you can
carry my gun.
And I can shoot.
What the hell! I like you and
you like me.
All of those things...
...are not that easy.
Easy? Just looking at you all
is easy.
A night and calm night...
Thank you for having come.
Sometimes one feels cornered...
...and words are good.
I always remember when you
caressed me...
...there, in the church.
...when I most needed someone
to be nice to me.
I felt your hands in my hair.
The first caress...
...since that awful battle.
Your hand in my hair.
Why do you betray me?
You're not worthy any more.
You leave me alone and
then you treat me bad.
You aren't worth it.
You're not a loyal man.
But you have bad habits!
You're not woman enough
for me!
You're a cheap slut.
This pigsty makes me sick!
I lied to you, Colonel.
I don't care about her rage.
I don't care if she cries.
I want her away from here.
Away from you.
I've been alone...
...among all these men...
...day after day...
...and neverending nights.
I don't want more Ioneliness.
Don't listen to me, Colonel.
I had to say it because I...
...have got used to this way
of living.
As you wished.
I beg you not to hear me.
I wish I could be a soldier.
But I'm a strange here...
...even for you, Colonel.
Let me go.
I appreciate you allowed
me to stay.
But I can't stay any more.
I can't do it.
Women!
If you love me, I know how
to love...
... if you forget me, I know
how to forget.
But I have one single pride...
... and I don't know how to beg.
Oh!
The shoe that I throw away...
... I won't everpick up again.
Oh, oh, oh!
Give me another bottle,
Martin!
Hey, you! Sing with your heart!
They are not singing to you,
but to me!
I want you to sing that Zeta...
...is the worst man of all.
The worst...
But I don't know any song with
that topic!
He's such a bastard! He doesn't
have a song.
Mr. Boni, let's make a toast
against them.
Against who?
Against men, of course.
Or against pigs. It's the same!
But I'm a man too!
Only in your memories, old man!
Drink it!
Let's see if you get
the insult over!
You too, Lola.
We'll dedicate another song to...
...that treacherous man!
OK. Let's hope your Colonel
goes to hell!
My Colonel...
That bastard is now with
that slut.
I think it's strange.
What?
That you just left him go.
When have I begged?
It hurts you, you can tell.
I've been hurt by his actions.
But him...
I don't care!
To those who don't like
anything at all...
Hey, pretty! If you're going
to flirt, start with me!
I'm tired of your talking...
...of that Zeta all the time!
I don't like the "Zeta" nor
you!
Let's see, bastards...
Silence me if you dare!
So why do we fight?
No, no.
Was it real or a dream?
Hey, answer!
Was it real?
What?
I said a lot of lies...
...about a man that I love.
It was true, sister.
Don't believe it, Lola.
He's not like I told you.
He's a real man.
And I have him here.
I see clear now.
He took me high.
He made me forget about
myself.
I didn't appreciate it.
Don't sleep, Lola!
I need you to hear me.
I hear you.
I'm nothing but trash.
Can you see the trash
that I am?
There's something good inside
of me.
I'm having a child.
A child of Antonio Zeta.
No one can take it from me.
He's got nothing from me.
Well, he has a golden cross.
But I have his child.
I want it to be like its dad.
With brave eyes.
With a tough voice when
angry.
Sometimes smooth.
I'll love it very much.
I'll apologize.
I'll dream a while, Lola.
Where are you going,
"soldier"?
I'll fire you!
Don't tell me, "Colonel".
My cross!
Did you get my cross?
Laugh now!
Like in the church.
Remember?
Laugh!
Give me my cross!
Keep that bastard!
I'm ashamed of having his
baby.
His?
Or the troop's?
Colonel.
Why did you come back?
I know Carranza didn't order...
...this march.
Let me mention that I follow
Carranza.
I follow orders, given by...
...Pancho Villa.
If the chiefs don't get along,
they will.
That's not my business.
Go ahead.
Your women are fighting,
Colonel!
Colonel, you want me to...
Go in front of the column.
OK, Colonel!
Kill her, "Cucaracha", kill her!
Don't be scared. I was...
...going to fight.
Hey, gossiping women!
They are far. Let's go.
Let's go!
Don't be sorry!
Finished?
Because I'll go with
Antonio Zeta right now.
Beat it!
Is this yours?
A bullet!
Do you cry because you lost?
For you.
No, I wanted a bullet!
The dust of the road sounds...
... in the horse's caskets.
An unfinished love...
... goes away crying.
Horse!
This is Villa's order.
Read it, please.
Read it.
"Colonel Antonio Zeta...
...march to Zacatecas against
Carranza's will right now.
Gather some loyal people and
reach me there.
Regard Carranza's followers as
traitors to the Revolution."
Signed by General Francisco
Villa.
Antonio!
You taught me to shoot, to
fight without fear for the...
...Revolution, to understand it.
But this is not a revolution!
If you follow that order, there
will be a slaughter here.
Antonio, break that paper!
I'll obey the order.
I understand he ordered you to
kill me.
Or I should kill you.
- That's what I understood.
- You misunderstood.
I need Villa's orders to be
followed.
If you're with Carranza, go away
with your people.
Because this place is mine,
Captain Ventura.
I don't know who's right.
But I know that, with
Villa or Carranza...
...we have to take Zacatecas.
I think...
...you're the best Colonel.
Hurray!
To Zacatecas!
This is the good one.
May God be with us.
The eagle's already flown...
... the nopal is alone.
The fruit ofher love...
... is now forgotten.
Please...
...it must have been born
by now.
Help me.
Come here.
It comes in a bad position.
It will die.
What do you want it for?
So it knows the sun...
...the cold.
- So it runs in the plain.
- What'll misery give your child?
It'll live a bad life... if he's
not already dead.
I don't care if I die.
It must be alive.
- It must be alive.
- There's no remedy.
We must pull it out; otherwise,
you may die too.
I'll give you anything, whatever
you want, but it must be alive.
Endure this!
Shut up!
Hold something!
Endure it!
Here comes Pancho Villa!
Hurray for the Revolution!
- Where's the priest?
- Wait.
What can I say?
I don't know.
I never lit any candle for you.
What for?
Everything was just a sin.
But I didn't know.
You know I didn't.
You know what happened.
Forgive me, God.
Forgive me.
I brought my child to you.
- Good morning, father.
- Good morning.
Baptise my child.
Yes.
Let's see.
He's old. Why didn't you
bring him before?
I was...
I was ashamed of coming to
the church.
I come from far. His father
will pass by here, and I want...
...him to know the baby.
He doesn't know him.
It's good you came.
Father...
...he comes with another
woman.
I knew about that before,
but now...
Don't worry. I'll baptise him,
and you'll show him to his...
...father.
What will his name be?
Antonio, I baptise you.
Here he comes, father.
Thank you very much.
Is this Colonel Zeta's troop?
- Is this Colonel Zeta's troop?
- General.
He died at Zacatecas.
Here it ends the song...
... that I sang for the
"Cucaracha".
AND WITH THEIR MEN AND
THEIR CHILDREN...
...THEY MADE
THE MEXICAN REVOLUTION.