Are you fucking kidding me?
SubText: NoRMITA.326
Whoever named this town Downers Grove
had a sick sense of humor.
The suburbs are the ghettos
of the meaningless...
unless your town has its very own curse,
where a senior dies each year
the week before graduation.
Now that suddenly gives your town
instant meaning.
You asked for it and more!
102.3.
A beautiful sunny day here in Illinois,
a whopping 88 degrees.
Summer around the bend.
Got a big shout out to all our seniors
at Downers Grove High School.
One week to graduation.
Make it count.
Don't get caught up in the curse.
Ha ha!
We're gonna keep playing all the hits.
Your hit music channel.
Only the best music.
Hey.
What's he doing?
Whoo!
Danny, come on!
Yeah, yeah!
Oh, shit.
It's the fucking curse.
It's only as few days before graduation,
and the curse hasn't happened yet.
Maybe it won't happen this year.
Maybe all the other accidents
are just a coincidence.
Hut!
At last year's sobfest, the class president
read a poem
that went something like...Don't try
to understand everything
because some things don't make sense.
But I can't help wondering
if the curse could be real.
The tall swarthy astronaut-type
is why mom dragged us here.
It's a bummer having a single mother
who's miserable.
So if astronaut-guy makes her happy,
astronaut-guy it is.
I mean, come out of the suffering
and problems that you face in life
brought on because of the choices
that you make.
You simply reap what you sow.
Whoa!
No one said a word about Rich
the whole way over,
and I..I would...
I would like your opinion.
Well, he isn't a meth addict.
Can I go now?
Sure.
Mom, I like him.
He seems nice, and I can tell
he really likes you.
I think he does. Thank you.
My angel.
I like him, too.
Who knows what Rich has on his filthy,
repressed religious mind.
Cut him some slack. He's
taking her to Vegas.
Be happy or fake it.
I checked his Match.com profile.
- He enjoys frisky women.
- I don't wanna hear this.
And one day hopes to host
his own reality show.
Let's hope for the best.
Okay, so you've got all the information.
We're at the...
Mandalay Bay and you'll be back Friday.
Okay.
I never left you alone before,
so please, please, please tell me
not to worry.
It is about that time the curse
of Downer's Grove rolls in.
Oh, my God. I didn't even think of that.
Mom, the curse is complete B.S.
We'll be fine.
Go. Have a good time.
Okay. God, I love you guys.
Oh, my angels!
Come here.
No drumming after 7:00.
Wish me luck. How do I look?
Is it okay?
Okay, Dave, you don't have
to hear this part.
I love you guys.
Okay?
Hey, Chrissie!
There's your stalker boyfriend.
Stop it.
- He's harmless.
- He totally likes you.
For the zillionth time,
her room's all pink and lace and shit.
Not your type.
Do you really think I'm interested
in her room?
What am I, an interior decorator?
You misread me completely sometimes.
Did I just pass your morn
and her new dude?
- For an older guy, he's not bad.
- I totally agree.
Drop it. Diner?
And you're looking exceptionally hot,
Tracy.
And you're looking exceptionally 15, Dave.
I think it's adorable that
you like me all the same.
Has she seen our Facebook page yet?
Uh, I don't think so.
I would've heard, so, no.
Cool.
I'll be jamming here later, if you
wanna hang or whatever.
Why are we going this way?
Diner's in the other direction.
I thought you might want to see
if grease boy was still working.
His name's Bobby.
What? How do you know?
Because I asked him.
When?
First semester, when the brakes
on my mom's car went,
I was sitting in the shop waiting,
and we got to talking.
Why didn't you tell me?
Oh. Oh, I see. You gave it up to him
in some hot steamy love pit out back,
didn't you?
You have to ask why I didn't tell you?
You guys have been at it like bunnies.
No. Nothing happened.
We're friends.
- With benefits?
- No.
Not even minimal benefits?
Not unless you count giving my mom
a discount a benefit.
So wait, hold on.
What's he like?
Actually, he defies the cliché
of townie mechanic.
He's smart, ambitious.
He can reassemble an engine in a day.
Why would anyone want to do that?
Just drive.
That's his car.
Dude, that's a lime green
fucking muscle car.
So? I like that about him.
It's unique.
So you already broke the ice
and then some?
Ruthless withholder!
What am I supposed to do with
this battery in my backseat?
You lost me.
I was supposed to take it
to the recycling center,
but then I selflessly thought,
Hey, wouldn't this be a nice opportunity
for Chrissie to meet her crush?
Ask him to help
with the battery...
Apparently I'm out of the loop.
You gave it up to him
in some hot steamy love pit out back,
didn't you?
He's totally your first, isn't he?
You raging 'ho. Why the hell didn't you...
I bet it's gonna be Matt Goldberg
or James Rocchi.
I have a weird feeling.
Plus they're super secret Internet pervs
into underage shit that'd make you puke.
Total sinners and begging to be punished.
I bet Lauren Solomon.
Bitch.
What are you doing?
Trying to work out who's next.
Did you ever think maybe
there'll be no next?
After so many in a row?
There's gotta be a next.
Says who?
Well, the curse.
Oh, so you spoke to the curse?
Chrissie, ever since '04,
a senior's died right before graduation.
'05, Nina Golden drowned in the quarry.
'06, Scott Riley drove over the embankment
at Knoll's Hill.
Both of them were drunk, by the way.
2007, Jason Martin shot
in the liquor store.
2008, Myra Crawford, OD'd.
2009, '10, '11, '12.
Frank Esposito ripped in half
by the train.
Jennifer Licari, vanished.
Amy Mazur died in her sleep.
Keith Hardy, farming accident.
Last year, Michael Shaw, water tower.
We were there, Chrissie.
We saw it.
I saw a meth head choosing
to climb a water tower,
not a curse.
I have to go. I have a paper to finish.
You still have homework? We're
graduating on Saturday.
I'm late with my big report. Mr. Keller
gave me an extension.
I'm having a really hard time
concentrating.
Why? The curse?
Yeah. I mean, someone we know
is gonna die.
Look, we make choices.
Those choices produce results,
good or bad.
Climbing a water tower high?
Bad choice, bad result.
Going home to do your report
and forgetting all about this curse
so you can finish?
Good choice, good result.
See what I'm saying?
See you guys tomorrow.
Or maybe you won't.
Not funny, Chrissie.
She's right. Don't joke about it.
Lighten up.
Way to clear a room.
Look, I want to believe in a better place.
I remember all my Sunday School stories.
Woman who turned into salt, Noah's Ark,
the burning bush, the star in the east.
I just hope they're all true
and not a bunch of made-up stories
thrown into a book.
I mean, if there's a God,
why would he make my dad addicted to meth
so he could abandon a wife and two kids?
And why would he give
my 12-year-old cousin
incurable bone cancer?
These are just personal gripes.
I'm not even gonna to get into wars,
gas fucking ovens, ethnic cleansing,
random, meaningless violence and all that,
'cause we'd be here all night.
Wow.
That's hardcore deep shit, man.
I have a lot of stuff on my mind.
Way too much stuff.
What the fuck?
Cut the shit! Jesus!
What's your problem, guy?
Are you psychic?
My name is Guy.
- No shit.
- Yeah, shit.
We were wondering if you girls
wanted to join us
on a little adventure.
Maybe next time when you don't
scare the shit out of us.
You don't know who he is, do you?
Um, no.
Hi, pretty.
I'm Chuck. What's your name?
I'm Brittany, she's Courtney.
But we have to go.
Finals for college.
College? Really?
You guys look like maybe
you're still in high school.
And maybe you're worried about the curse.
We survived the curse.
We're at Northwestern.
Where do you go?
Willow Creek.
Chuck is our star QB. Do you guys
not read the paper?
He was our back-up junior year...
Hey, Guy, shut the fuck up.
Why don't you guys come to a party
over on our side of town?
It'll be fun.
No.
Hold, please, Chuck.
Please don't make me beg.
Willow Creek's in another county.
We'll do a drive-by.
If it's sketch, we'll get out of there,
okay?
Please.
- Chuck?
- Yeah.
It's a bad night. Maybe some other time.
What if I promise to have you home
before you turn into a pumpkin?
Scout's honor.
Let's not do anything stupid, okay?
When have I ever?
- Really want me to answer that?
- Yes!
Actually, no.
He's kinda cute.
You could totally make out with him.
I wouldn't say anything.
It would just be between you and me
and everyone else who's watching.
One, two, three.
Alright. Let's go find those boys.
I'll be there in a sec.
You'll be okay, right?
I'll be fine. Very fine.
Hey.
Hey, you.
It's good to see you.
I didn't think you were gonna come.
Yeah, me, too.
- You alright?
- Yeah, no, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Shh.
Whoa. Um...
I have to pee.
Sorry. I'm just gonna...just a sec.
Just a sec.
Hey.
What was that?
I had to go to the bathroom?
Relax, relax, relax.
It's okay, it's okay.
- Um...
- It's okay. Shh...
Why are you freaking out?
- I'm not. I'm just...
- Shh...
- Um, Chuck, I feel like...
- It's okay. You feel like what?
I feel like I should probably
go find Tracy.
Make sure she's okay.
- She's fine.
- Chuck...
Hey. Whoa! Slow down.
Hey! Whoa! Chuck, come on, please?
Chuck, please?
- Please.
- Shh...
What the fuck is wrong with you?
I'm just...
Please don't!
Stop it! Please!
Come on! Stop it!
- Wait till we finish.
- Get the fuck off me, Chuck.
This is it.
Hey!
Fuckin' finish it, bitch!
Fuck off me! Get off of me!
Get off!
Where's Chuck?
Are you okay?
What the fuck does it look like, you idiot?
Tracy? That guy Chuck tried
to fucking rape me.
Get out of there! It's not fucking safe!
Hey!
- Are you okay?
- Get us out of here.
Okay, so definitely not one
of my best ideas.
Do you think the curse
may be on one of us?
No.
I mean, one of us would be dead, right?
If it was on one of us.
Maybe it just, like, passed over us.
Shut the fuck up!
Okay. It's gonna be fine.
No, it's not gonna be fucking fine!
Why not?
Because I think I just poked
some fucking guy's eye out,
so it's so far from fucking fine!
We can never tell anyone about this, okay?
Okay.
We need a plan.
Shit.
God, if you do exist and can hear me,
please let this all be a bad dream.
Our friend seems to be awakening.
I...where...where is this?
Where am I?
Do not be alarmed, my friend.
My man Ivan found you in the crypt.
Shit.
Oh, God!
Fu...
Oh, shit.
Oh, God!
What are you doing?
Let me see your eye.
Oh, my God!
What happened to you?
- Can you see?
- No.
- What?
- No, I can't see!
You know what that does to your
fucking football career?
No, I don't know!
They won't even hire a fucking
one-eyed mascot!
I busted my ass for years to get you out
of this fucked-up town!
And now...
Damn it!
Someone we know is gonna die.
I've been dreaming about Indians
since I was a little girl.
Maybe it's because our town was built
on land that was stolen
from the Indians in 1832.
I can't help but wonder
if this has something to do
with the curse.
But if that were the case,
then all of America would be cursed.
Maybe we all are.
Stop it.
You're making connections
that aren't there.
There is no fucking curse,
God is elusive if he exists,
and you poked out some goon's eye
at a party
after he tried to rape you.
That's reality. Get out
of your head and deal.
What are you doing?
The acoustics in the basement
started to sound funk-defied.
It's five in the morning.
Everything sounds...
whatever it is you just said.
You came in last night like you
were in a wrestling match
with an engine.
You finally get into it
with that mechanic?
Hey, what is going on with you?
What happened last night?
Nothing.
Hey, hey.
When Dad was around and had his fits,
you always protected me and mom.
The least I can do is step up
and help when you need it.
Okay.
I don't even know where to start.
Ask me about last night.
Whatever you want.
Did Tracy say anything about me?
Dweeb.
I have other follow-ups.
That was just my lead-in.
What?
Did you give any of them your real name?
Hell, no.
What about your purse with your ID's?
Do you still have it?
Hell, yes. Good night.
It's already morning.
Sorry.
It's okay. I'm just jumpy.
You know, we've been friends
since we were in kindergarten,
and there's something weird
happening between us.
I can't take it anymore.
What do you mean?
You haven't answered my texts in weeks.
What did I do?
Nothing. I've just been really busy.
Is it the mechanic?
Are you keeping tabs on me?
Your brother is a fond of useful info,
and...
I happen to care a little bit.
- Come on. I'm parked near you.
- Alright.
I guess I have been avoiding you.
Why?
I don't wanna hurt you.
Hurt me from what?
You know, we went to prom,
and that happened.
It's just weird.
Because you laid a sloppy kiss on me?
We were drunk, and we kissed.
So what?
I don't want to lead you on.
Whoa. You thought I spun a drunken kiss
into some kind of potential relationship?
Really?
I'm such an idiot.
I can just erase it from my mind,
if you so wish.
Want me to...okay.
There you go. It's gone.
Come on.
Where are we going?
I don't remember what I was doing.
You and Monica Chase?
When did that happen?
Uh, recent, recent.
Very recent.
Sorry. You should wait here for a second.
What are you doing here?
You're not a very nice girl.
I mean, why the fuck would
you do something like this
to somebody who has an
earnest interest in you?
An earnest interest in raping me.
Is that how you remember it?
I seem to recall it differently.
No?
What do you want, Chuck?
What do I want?
- Can I get a ride?
- No.
Dave, right?
How do you know his name?
I'm Chuck.
Pleasure.
By the way, I'm really sorry
to hear about your dad.
It's...terrible.
No kid should have to go through that.
- Hi, pal.
- Hi.
Who the hell was that? And how
does he know about Dad?
Chuck Whitmore, starting QB for Willow
with a really fucked-up eye.
If either of you ever see him again,
just stay away from him.
Why are you here on your day off?
The sooner I get the cars
into racing shape,
the sooner I can sell them.
What's wrong?
Are you mothering your mom again?
No. She's away.
I just did something really stupid.
Like what?
You know that group of Willow Creek
football players?
Yeah. They drive by wasted all the time.
Yeah, well, Tracy and I went
to one of their parties,
and that guy Chuck tried to attack me.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Look, if he ever comes near you again,
just promise me you'll
come to me for help.
You're pretty cute when you're worried.
Nice. That's nice.
How about when I'm not worried?
Un-cute?
No, no, no, no.
You're beautiful.
But, um, you worry a lot.
- So...
- I...
Nice save, Bobby.
- I should go.
- Uh...
No, well, look, don't...you don't
have to leave.
I'm gonna be working on this car
for a while,
so you're more than welcome to stay
if...you still want to.
Bobby, mind if I make a complete
and utter ass of myself?
The floor's yours.
I've been coming by for months.
We share all these intimate secrets,
and...
why haven't you asked me out?
I..I don't know.
Okay, uh...
sorry for putting you on the spot.
Bye.
What did the doctor say?
You can play, right?
Spot me. Spot me.
Alright. One more.
- What did the doctor say?
- Shut up!
Would you just shut the fuck up?
What'd the doctor say? He said
I'm fucking blind.
That if I'm lucky, I'll be seeing
in my right eye
in about 35 fucking years. That's
what the doctor said.
That someday maybe I'll end up being
some fucking townie piece
of shit loser like you, Guy.
Maybe someday if I'm fucking lucky!
Fuck!
Chrissie.
Ian, what's wrong?
What happened?
I was jumped.
- Did you see him?
- Who?
- Whoever did this.
- It happened too fast.
Does this have to do with you?
It's better if you just keep away from me.
But...
- So you hold it like that.
- Yeah?
- Make sure you press here.
- But what's that going to do?
Just ignore that. That's just decoration.
- Decoration?
- Yeah.
- You drew that?
- That's pretty cool.
- Yeah?
Okay, show me.
Show me.
Ugh!
God, this is not happening.
- Seriously?
- Wait! Hey!
Dave said the freak show showed up
at school today.
Shit, man.
Yeah, he came by school,
knew exactly who I was,
who my brother was, mentioned Dad.
Yeah? Hmm?
What are you doing?
You know, I think the freak show
was probably just trying to scare you.
What?
What are you not telling me?
I'm sorry.
In advance.
You agreed to what?
A fucking party here?
- Are you out of your mind?
- It was her idea.
- We came up with it together.
- It's all over Facebook.
Yeah, if you checked your page,
Tracy's page, or my page,
you would've known last week.
What's that supposed to mean?
- Tell her, Tracy.
- Yeah, tell me, Tracy.
We were just thinking you
could use a little social jolt
heading into summer.
How selfless of you both,
but no fucking way.
Tracy, you may like hooking up
with random dudes,
doing whatever drug they put in front
of your face,
but that's not me.
I have a dad who's an addict, okay?
Could even be dead by now, for all I know.
I don't want people doing weird shit
in this fucking house!
Cancel it.
What? Post it on Facebook.
Canceled.
It's not that easy.
It's been on our Twitter feeds.
We sent out a mass e-mail.
If you paid more attention to social media
instead of lurking around a gas station
between honors classes,
- you'd know.
- Shut up! Shut up!
Find a way to cancel that party.
And stop smoking that shit in the house!
Hey, Bobby. What's up?
Um...uh...
Chrissie's best-kept secret
here in the flesh.
Bobby, is it? I have heard so many
rad stories about you.
Weren't you in the middle of something
really important?
Oh, yeah, right, the party.
Tuesday night.
I hope you can make it, Bobby.
Urn, so...
Y..Yeah...
I came over here to, uh...
just to ask you if you would
like to go on a date with me.
Now?
No, not..not now. We
don't have to go now.
If you don't, if you can't...
I can come hack.
Now's perfect. Uh...
I'm just gonna go change real quick.
Okay.
Ohh...
It's beautiful.
Question...what where you thinking,
going to that party in the first place?
Why? Do I sense a little jealousy?
Let's...call it concern.
Next question.
What does a girl like you want
with a grease monkey like me?
God. I don't know.
You're, uh...
You're different.
So what do you think about this curse
everyone keeps talking about?
That's like asking if you believe in God,
the afterlife, the supernatural.
Do you?
No. The curse? Absolutely not.
What about God?
I mean, I'm not really a religious guy
or anything,
but just look at that sky.
Impossible that was man-made.
It's made up of molecules.
The clouds are made up
of tiny droplets of water
and ice crystals so light
they hang in the sky.
I flunked in whatever class
you learned that in, but...
let's agree it's not man-made.
Okay.
Um...
What about physical attraction?
Is that made up of molecules, too?
Sorry.
You're fucking...
You're fucking out of your mind, dude.
What the fuck are you doing here?
I need to talk to her.
It's really important.
No, it's not! Get the fuck out!
Bobby, it's fine, okay? I'll be back
in one second.
Hey, it's gonna be fine.
This is something that I have to do.
Roll your window up.
He's high as hell.
He tried to fucking rape you.
Bobby, I can handle this.
What? Are you stalking me?
Did you attack my friend Ian?
No.
I, uh...can I just...I need
to talk to you.
About what?
I've been thinking about
that thing you said.
The question you asked.
What question?
About what I want.
I don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
Um...I had a dream.
And it was fucking vivid.
And then all of sudden, it just...
all this stuff made sense.
What? What made sense?
This.
What are you talking about?
See, I know that you...
you're feeling the same thing I'm feeling.
Chuck...
I don't.
Yeah, you do. Yeah, you do.
You have to.
- No. You're crazy.
- Right?
No, Chuck.
Yeah. And...
and that's why this all makes sense.
You know, that's why I forgive you.
Forgive me? Are you kidding?
That's why this is gonna work for us.
Chuck, there is no we.
There is no fucking us.
Whatever you think you know about me,
it's all fucking made up in your head.
All this shit you're doing, following me,
you need to stop it,
and you just need to keep the fuck away
from me, Chuck.
Stay the fuck away from me.
He followed us to the bluff.
What did he say exactly?
He thinks we're in some kind
of relationship.
Unfortunately there's not much
we can do with that.
This guy's serious.
He tried to rape me.
- Any witnesses?
- No.
He cornered me in a bathroom.
Hey, look, I mean, she's here now.
Do you guys really want to be the ones
who were warned
and then dropped the ball after the fact?
Can't just arrest him.
I can pay him a visit,
let him know we've been made aware.
Usually that's enough.
What's his name?
- Chuck Whitmore.
The WC football player.
Chuck Whitmore.
Yeah, Charlie Whitmore's son.
Charlie's one of us.
So what, that makes him untouchable?
I think it's best if we show it
to Charlie first.
That's enough for now.
When we know more, you'll know more.
- So that's it?
- Yeah.
That's it.
His dad's an ex-cop?
Right, yeah. Which is not a good thing.
Didn't make me feel any better.
As soon as I mentioned his name,
they completely changed.
I'm definitely staying over.
Awesome.
On the couch.
That's cool.
Jake pissed on it a bunch.
It's been cleaned.
I don't know if it ever really,
truly comes out,
but if you want to...
Stop. Please?
Well, hey, I don't want
to invite myself over...
Yes. Stay.
That'd be good.
Okay, cool. Well, um...
I guess I just need to let my boss know
I'll be in and out.
Are you sure you don't mind
sticking around?
No, of course not.
Does that thing work?
Okay, well, use it.
What are you doing?
Jesus!
I'm sorry.
I took a mean spill.
Your brother has some serious weed.
Hey, it's Bobby.
I don't have a condom,
and even if you do in your wallet,
I'm still a virgin,
and I'd like for it to stay that way,
temporarily.
You know, it hadn't even crossed my mind.
I was kidding.
It did, but I got rid of the idea quick.
Okay, um...
I should probably go to sleep 'cause
I have school tomorrow.
Will you be here when I get back?
Yeah, of course, if it makes you feel safe.
No sex.
Okay.
Maybe there is a curse,
and this year it's on me.
It's the curse.
Maybe I'm the curse.
Is that the mechanic's car?
It's nothing. Thanks for the ride.
It's not nothing. It belongs to that guy.
So why'd you have to fucking ask, Ian?
- Sorry.
- It's fine.
You barely said a word
the whole ride home.
You got a stranger's car in your driveway
and this look on your face like someone
is trying to kill you.
Oh, and your locker blew up.
You can't pretend like
it's just another day.
Hey, look, I've known you
since kindergarten.
You can tell me anything.
If you're worried about the curse,
there's only three days left to graduation,
and if there's...
Bobby, whose car it is, we started dating
and...
and the rest is PMS.
Guys, get out of your PJ's and
cancel that fucking party.
We tried. We posted Facebook messages
and...
We did our best, but it's in the ether,
and we can't stop people from showing up.
What's wrong? Something happen?
Are you sure it was him?
The fucking car battery
was in my locker, Tracy.
Where are you going?
It's probably better if
we don't talk about it.
- You can't.
- The hell I can.
If I don't do something about it,
it's just gonna get worse.
Bobby...
Come on.
Hey, listen to me.
Bobby?
Bobby, I'm serious. Come on.
Look, you don't know me that well.
I can take him.
You're right. I don't know you.
But I know that if you do
something stupid,
you could wind up in jail or worse.
And I'm not up for that.
Okay.
We'll do it your way.
- What is your way?
- I don't have a way.
I can't think.
You know, it might not be such
a bad idea to have the party.
Just hear me out. If this guy's
stupid enough
to show up at your door uninvited
with a bone to pick,
we'll have plenty of witnesses.
And as long as I can make sure
you're safe,
then the cops or his dad won't
be able to save him.
It's just nights like tonight that
I get so concerned about,
the nights where I won't be here.
I don't get off till 3 a.m.
I'll be here when you get back.
I promise.
You better be.
Your new boyfriend is rad.
And your girlfriend is a slut.
You're not gonna hear any complaints
from me.
She feels bad enough. So do I.
You remember how Dad
taught us how to shoot?
Yeah. I have permanent ear damage.
Well, I guess he was too scared
to use his shotgun on himself
before he left and forgot it
when he split.
It's in my room under my bed.
Good to know.
It's the curse.
Guys, please!
Guys!
Please?
Do you hear that?
Sounds like it's coming from outside.
Hey, Jake, what is it?
Call the cops.
Bobby!
If you keep this up, it's only
gonna get uglier.
Keep what up?
You made your point, alright?
Just let it go.
No, man.
I haven't even come close
to making my point.
So tell me, Bobby,
what the fuck are you gonna do about it?
Whatever I have to.
Let's take a walk.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Back up, back up, back up!
Back up, back up.
Put that down.
Let's do this like men.
Put it down.
I love that you think this is
gonna make a difference.
When I'm done with her, you're
going to be tasting me
for the rest of your life.
Ooh!
There you go.
Good stuff.
I learned a lot about conflict resolution
in my advanced psych classes.
- Oh, did you?
- Mm..hmm.
The last resort is physical violence.
I would've had him had he not
cheap-shotted me.
Look, you know about my dad
and meth, right?
What I never told you was
that because of that
he owed some money to some bad people.
I spent too many nights
either fighting him off
or mending him.
So, please, do not go after Chuck again.
Hey, look at me.
Look at me.
Say it.
I won't go after him again.
Good.
We gotta figure out what to do.
We can't just fucking sit around here
and just...
We're gonna fucking do something.
As soon as Chuck figures what we're doing,
we're gonna go fucking do it.
Whatever he says, that's
what we're gonna do.
What the fuck are we gonna do
about these two?
These chicks, man.
They think that they can get...
- Son of a bitch.
- I'm gonna fuck her friend.
- Her little faggot brother, too.
- I'm gonna fuck...
- So what are we gonna do?
- We're gonna do something.
We're going to fucking do something.
As soon as Chuck says what we're gonna do,
we're gonna do.
What about her faggot-ass little brother?
What about her brother?
You know what I think?
What did you say, Chuck?
I think she took my life,
and I wanna take hers.
Just like it says in the Bible, man,
an eye for an eye.
Clean this shit up before my dad
gets home.
Okay.
I think we got enough for the party.
Two parties.
- Come on. Go, go, go.
- Shit.
Go.
Lock the door. Don't open it.
Hi, Dave.
What's with the ski masks?
Hitting the slopes?
You got lots of stuff in the car.
Are you going to some big party
or something?
It'll distract me from my boredom.
How's that? Hmm?
That wake you up?
Are you still bored?
Where's Chrissie?
You tell me.
That's the spirit.
I want in that car.
Guy, take this little fucking scab
out back.
Teach him a lesson.
Fuck!
Get him!
Tracy, open the door.
Tracy, you open that door, and
I will kill you personally.
Leave him the fuck alone!
Fuck him up.
Aaw!
Ooh!
God, Dave, it looks like it
hurts so bad, huh!
Go and do it again.
One more time.
Okay, do it again.
Do it again.
Leave him the fuck alone!
Leave him alone!
You tell Mom?
- Not yet.
- Good. Don't.
I'm fine. Let her have her time.
She needs it.
You know who these guys are and yet
you do nothing.
We paid the boys a visit.
They were all nerves.
I could tell by their pupils
they were partying.
That's great. That's amazing.
So what's next? A line-up or something?
They were partying in their homes.
No contraband was visible and our
search warrant was rejected.
So what are you saying?
We don't have enough to arrest them yet.
They broke his hand in broad daylight.
Line them up.
Our hands are tied here, Chrissie.
I'm sorry.
Please leave me with my brother.
Please just go.
Just go.
This is all my fault.
There's good news.
What's that?
I'm like a hero to Tracy now.
This is gonna go down big for me.
I'm gonna milk it. Trust me.
It might even get me a home run.
Hey, you alright?
But we did get everything
we need for the party.
We got beer, vodka, tequila, cups.
Don't worry. I'll be okay.
You don't know who he is, do you?
Hey, what is this?
You're not a very nice girl.
What happened?
I was jumped.
See that fat fucking Beaner up there?
He just signed a guaranteed hundred
million dollar contract.
Fucking...
Know what Dolphins' first-round pick's
getting this season?
- 7.6 million goddamn dollars.
- That's a lot of money.
Yeah, that's a lot of fucking money,
isn't it?
You'll never find out. That's
for goddamn sure.
What the fuck is this?
Fuck.
Is this that Swanson girl?
Yeah.
I need your help.
I need you to keep everyone away
from that fucking party.
Okay. Yeah.
It felt like something was
creeping up behind me
and then nothing was there.
I'll..I'll call you right back, okay?
You're security?
I almost feel bad fucking your shit up
all over again.
Not me. I've been dreaming
about fucking your shit up.
What the fuck...
- Oh, my God!
- Turn the lights back on!
Shit. Dave?
Hmm? You scared now?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
- I am.
- No, you're not!
Don't fuck with me.
I was thinking about that dream you had.
Don't lie to me.
You're so beautiful.
I'm so sorry.
Please.
- I wanna be with you.
- No, you don't.
- I do.
Get off!
I'm so sorry.
Chuck...
Please. It's okay.
Stop!
Get the fuck off me!
Get off me! Get off me!
Get off me!
Get off me, please!
- Leave me alone.
- Get off of her!
Get off of her!
Slop!
You okay?
Stay here.
Okay.
You son of a bitch!
Bobby.
Are you okay?
Who taught you how to shoot like that?
So...
you just told the cops
that you took all those guys down
in self-defense,
and that's it?
And that's it.
You must be traumatized.
I passed that phase yesterday.
So let's do a head count.
Not the fucking curse again.
Seriously, have any seniors died yet?
Uh, not to my knowledge.
So the curse could still be real.
Ian, we bring this on ourselves.
There's no curse.
Some drunk senior is probably
about to drive
into a head-on with a semi
as we speak.
I should..I should go check on Bobby.
You're a mess. You need to chill for a sec.
Remember we used to push each other
to see who could get highest?
Do you love grease boy?
Don't be a dick. His name's Bobby.
Bobby doesn't deserve you.
Ian...
Don't.
I've always loved you.
- What happened?
- I was jumped.
We pray to thee, our God, this day.
But from ashes to ashes
and dust to dust...
I feel for all the people
who grieve for me.
And from where I stand,
I can say for sure that I was wrong.
The curse of Downers Grove is real
because the curse is everywhere.
The curse is life.
Another graduation called off
and a funeral to take its place...
Don't expect me to tell you
to believe in fate
or that there's some supernatural force
guiding us all.
I can only say this.
It doesn't end here.
Someone we know is gonna die.
It's the curse.