[Woman]
Things was different
back in 1935.
It was hotter,
for one thing,
and we didn't have
TV neither.
Nobody had
discovered them yet.
My mamma and daddy
lost about everything,
but we didn't give up.
No, sir.
That's the way
we were brought up, I guess.
The way we figured it,
if we hung on and gave it
everything we got,
things would get better.
And we were wrong
about that,
but so were a lot
of people back then.
I'll never forget
those days--
how wonderful it was
to be alive,
to be young.
The common fella
didn't have a chance.
Big oil took over
everything,
but they weren't the ones
that built the business.
They just grabbed
the apples.
And that's what
they were--grabbers.
It was the catters
that made the business--
the wildcatters--
men like my father,
men like h.L. Hunt,
dad joiner,
and Teddy coon.
Everybody knows about them.
But then there was Mr. Cox.
Now, Mr. Cox
was something else.
[Chuckles]
Some of the catters
were just born to be lucky.
Mr. Cox...
Now, he was just lucky
to be born.
Captioning made possible by
Warner Bros.
[Tries to start car]
[Cat meowing]
All right. All right.
O.k.
Oh...
[Cat meows]
O.k., o.K.
[Cough]
All right.
Let's go.
Let's get out
of here.
Let's go, kitty cat.
Let's go.
[Meow]
Hop in.
Where you headed?
Oh, big stone.
Hoo-whee!
Would you look
at this place?
Thank you very much.
Ma'am.
Well, see you
around, kid.
Yes, sir.
Hey, here!
Hey, hey!
All right!
Hold it!
One at a time,
damn it!
You, what's your age?
What?
What's your age?
How old are you?
21.
More like 51.
And a crip
to boot!
It don't take
five digits
to be
a tool dresser.
[Contractor]
It does for me.
Hey!hey!
Hit him hard!
Get him!
Hit him!
Yeah!
Uh!
Oh!
Whoo-hoo!
Uh!
Oh!
Hit him hard!
Come on.
Get lost, will you?
What did he say?
Who? Mac Holland?
Yes, Mac Holland.
Son of a gun
wouldn't allow me
past the gate.
That is it.
I can't believe you
no more.
You are always talking
about how you
made him rich.
The way I hear it,
he chased you off
with a gun.
I heard that a Derrick
that you built
fell in and nearly
killed the man.
That could have
happened to
anybody.
That could have
happened to anybody?
When we lost our bit
in crystal,
you said, "that happens
all the time."
Our rig freezes up,
and you say,
"that could happen
to anybody."
I have been through
hurricanes and fires,
shaft cave-ins,
and it don't happen
to everybody.
Seymour, what you
fail to realize
is you're a whiner.
You're a whiner
and a complainer.
As far
as I'm concerned,
me and Matilda
can just do fine
by ourselves.
Oh, yeah?
That's another thing.
You spent $20
on that damn
oil-smelling cat.
That thing couldn't
smell her food
if you stuck it
up its nose
with a stick.
I have been made
a fool of long enough.
Only thing
I got left
is that car.
Believe me--
I'm using it
to get far
away from you.
All I want to hear
out of you
is where you
parked my car.
Sure. Sure. Sure.
You just go left
on pickett street,
and you'll
come to it.
Very good.
Ooh, good luck, buddy.
You're going
to need it.
In about 40 miles.
[Knock on window]
No noise. No liquor,
no foul language.
Your cat
starts anything,
you both go.
75 cents.
Tell you what.
All right.
Double
or nothing,
all right?
Oh, damn.
Come on, baby.
Let's go.
O.k.
Still playing the cards,
huh, Mr. Cox?
What?
Ha ha ha!
Henry.
Well, then.
I heard you hit
the big one
down
in the basin--
you and Dave
mcdermit.
Mcdermit--
that son of a bitch--
he cheated me
out of every dime
that was coming to me.
Worst mistake
I ever made in my life,
hooking up
with that guy.
I'm sorry
to hear that.
I really am.
Yeah. I'm all
washed up. Finished.
You'll be back
in it, Henry.
You don't
give up easy.
I'm an old man,
broke as the day
I was born.
I got me a ride
back to California
in the morning.
I have only one thing
left to do,
and that's dying.
I want to do that
with my family.
Don't talk like that.
You're not dying.
You're living.
We're all dying,
all of US.
You're not dying.
Good night, Mr. Cox.
[Cat meows]
Hey, delbert!
Hey, Henry.
Here's an old
friend of mine--
Mr. Cox.
Sure,
I remember you--
back in crystal.
You're the one
lost your bit
1,600 feet down.
That's a tough
piece of luck.
Henry tells me
you're headed
for California.
Yeah. Sure.
Sure.
Hey, what the hell.
Toss your stuff in.
You going for business
or pleasure?
Well, eh...
Take a little rest,
I guess.
Might look into
the real-estate game.
Damn sweet racket,
I hear.
Yeah. We'll see.
[Delbert]
Real estate, huh?
Yeah.
California,
here we come, boys.
Uh, let's see,
delbert.
Make a left here.
Yeah. That will
take US out of town.
[Horn honks]
I'm going to
stretch my legs
a bit.
Sure. Sure.
No hurry
here.
[Meow]
[Man]
How you all
doing?
[Delbert]
Doing all right.
Check the oil
for you?
Please do.
[Attendant]
Fine-looking
automobile you got.
Yeah. They
don't make them
like this
anymore.
Nice day.
Dry, though.
Yeah.
Oil's good.
Get that windshield
for you.
Thank you.
[Sniffing]
You smell it?
Do you smell that?
[Meow]
Act like nothing's
going on.
[Meow]
[Sniff]
Lord.
Henry! Henry!
Come here a minute.
I want to
show you something.
Come on. Come on.
Wait a minute.
Come on.
Now we, my friend,
are standing on top
of the biggest
anticline
you ever heard of.
I can smell it,
Henry.
I--i can smell it
so big
it almost knocks me
off my feet.
Oh, no, no,
no, no.
Yes, sir.
Other people have
tried it before.
I drill one
not 3 miles
from here.
Well, you just
grabbing at straws.
[Horn honks]
Let's go, boys.
Hold on.
Wait a minute.
Hold on here.
I need a partner
here, partner--
somebody
I can trust,
and that's you.
You cannot
stay here.
What are you
going to do?
Hey, I mean,
I'm a doodlebug man.
I'm going to find
the window, Henry.
I'm going to
bring it on in.
That's what i'm
going to do.
This is your chance,
too--you and me.
Stay with me.
Stay close, Henry.
No. Stay with me,
Henry.
Stay with me.
Come on.
Good luck, Mr. Cox.
I'll pray for you.
Yes, sir.
I'm coming.
What the heck's
going on, Henry?
Suitcase!
[Henry]
Crazy old coot.
O.k.
He's not coming.
[Car starts]
You take care, now.
Bye, Mr. Cox.
Good luck!
Exactly
where are we?
Henrietta's about
a mile that way.
Henrietta.
Henrietta, Oklahoma.
Henrietta, Texas.
Yes, sir.
I know it well.
Now, let's see.
Henrietta.
Clay county.
Wichita county.
Now...
Yes, no, or maybe?
Yes.
Northeast more. Yes.
Yes. Wichit--
yes. Yes.
Yes. You got
a pencil? Yes.
Yes. Yes.
There.
Where?
Right there.
That's it.
[Meow]
Yes, sir.
That's it.
Howdy.
Can I help you?
Nope.
You all right
there?
Fine. Fine.
What you doing?
Uh, just doodling.
Doing what?
Just go on
about your business.
I'm sure you got
plenty to do.
O.k., o.K.
Don't tell me
that fellow wasn't nosy.
Daddy!
You being
a good girl?
How did it go
in town?
I don't want to
talk about it.
Here, sugar.
[Baby crying]
[Whimper]
It's o.K., puppy.
[Girl]
Pauline, come here.
Here, pauline.
Catch the ball.
[Pauline]
I got it!
Throw it back.
Here.
[Horse whinnies]
Come on, honey.
[Baby crying]
Girls, you-all
get on in here now.
Get in the house.
Come on.
[Woof]
Oh...
Ooh!
Here, kitty cat.
Here, kitty.
Here, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty.
Here...kitty.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Here, kitty,
kitty, kitty.
[Cat meows]
Here, kitty, kitty.
Here, kitty.
Ooh, kitty.
Here, kitty, kitty.
Here, kitty,
kitty, kitty.
Oh, kitty, kitty.
Oh!
Ooh.
Mister!
You all right?
Come on, now.
Come on with me.
I have to find
my cat.
What?
I have to find
my cat.
Your cat?
Forget
about your cat.
Here, kitty,
kitty, kitty.
Come on now.
We got to get
out of here.
Oh, my lord!
[Coughing]
Come on in.
Come sit down.
Pauline, go fetch me
a clean cloth.
Is he going to
be all right?
Go on, honey.
Beatrice, go fetch
my sewing kit.
Yes, ma'am.
Sewing kit.
Oh...
There we go.
[Cat meows]
[Meow]
Hold on. Hold on.
Here I come.
[Meow]
[Cat meows]
Honey, what
are you doing?
Looks like
a real character
we took on.
Come on
back to bed.
Oh...
Mmm.
That-a girl.
Smell it?
[Sniffing]
My little doodlebug,
you're the one.
Best little
doodlebugger
in Texas.
Go get it, girl.
Go find it.
[Beatrice]
Look at those
pretty green eyes.
[Pauline]
Melissa, this is kitty.
Good morning,
ladies.
I haven't had
the pleasure.
My name's Beatrice.
Nice to see you.
And who are you?
She's pauline.
Well,
I'm Mr. Cox--
not Duke,
not lord,
just plain old
Mr. Cox.
One for you.
This here's
Matilda.
She can't read yet.
Give her
something
to look
forward to,
won't it?
Says here
you're an oilman.
There ain't no oil
around here.
You in the oil
business, too?
No, but i--
why don't you
leave it to
a fella
who's made
a study of it?
I want you ladies
to come with me.
I want to
show you something.
Come here.
All right.
Go get me
some oil.
Now...
Now get down
on your knees.
Get down.
Here we go.
Now put your ear
down on the ground.
See?
There.
[Cat meows]
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
See?
You can hear it.
Sounds like sea shells.
I can hear it!
[Mother]
Beatrice. Pauline.
I don't believe
a word you say.
Oh...
Hey, you two.
[Mother]
It's time
to get going.
Huh?
I did hear it.
Oh, well, don't you
ever forget that either.
Pauline.
Go on. Go on.
Get cleaned up.
Morning.
We're fixing
to go to church.
You're welcome
to join US.
Oh...
I wouldn't miss that
for anything, ma'am.
I got a lot to be
grateful for today.
[Choir]
♪ I love ♪
♪ to tell the story ♪
♪ of unseen things above ♪
♪ of Jesus and his glory ♪
♪ of Jesus and his love ♪
♪ I love to tell the story ♪
♪ because I noticed, too ♪
♪ it satisfies my longings ♪
♪ as nothing else can do ♪♪
Three damnable
years.
Land's turned
to dust,
and you think
our government
gives a deuce
about US?
I'm here to tell you
they don't.
Listen. You might
learn something.
Truth is, we bled
the land dry.
It's been getting
worse every year.
It ain't rain
we need.
It's new soil.
You think
the government
will give US that?
No way in hell.
Ooh, you good kitty.
There's a good kitty.
This cat's about
the best friend
I got.
Yeah--the good
kitty cat.
I never had
a cat before.
Didn't you?
Well, we'll see
about that.
Your turn.
Go ahead.
Did I win?
As a matter
of fact,
you did.
Excuse me,
honey.
Something I need
to discuss
with your daddy
right now.
O.k.
You hold Matilda
for me.
O.k., I'll be
right back.
I always had
an admiration
for a man who
worked the land.
Now, that's
a coincidence.
I always had
a secret admiration
for salesmen.
Well, I'm not
a salesman.
I'm in the oil
business.
Well, no offense,
but you don't
look like
much of an oilman.
Well, yeah.
I've had my
ups and downs.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
I'm familiar
with your business.
As a matter of fact,
about 10,
maybe 12 years ago,
I worked on a well
in south Texas.
Is that right?
Now, there's a lot
of oil down there,
if that's what
you're looking for.
There's a lot
of it right here.
You think so, do you?
I know so.
I knew the first day
that I got here.
That's probably
quite a shock,
you being a farmer
and all.
That's all Mac Holland was
before he met with me.
Who?
You never heard
of Mac Holland?
He's one of
the richest men in Texas.
He's got two yachts
and a house back there
in Florida or Europe
or somewhere,
and he was a farmer
just like you.
What are you
looking for,
Mr. Cox?
You want a lease?
I couldn't do that
to you.
Do what?
Stealing money
out of your pocket
like that.
I would be,
if we did it by lease.
12% for you, tops.
Now, I ain't no lease hound.
We're talking 50-50
right down the middle.
[Hammering]
We're talking partners
here, partner.
Partners?
Excuse me?
What do you mean when you say
partners, Mr. Cox?
Well, partners,
dear lady,
is--is--is 50-50.
I got a pretty good feeling
what my 50 is.
What's your 50?
Well, expertise,
Mr. Don day.
30 years of drilling
under the most adverse
conditions you can imagine.
Cable, rotary--
I know it all.
I do. I really do.
I'm willing to put
that expertise on the line,
and I'm doing you a favor.
I'm talking about 5--
less than 5,000 here.
We'll make millions.
$5,000?
Yes, ma'am.
I know that's
a lot of money to you,
but you have neighbors,
and they look up to you and Don.
Now, hear me.
It's coming to me.
We could go to them
as partners, together.
Cut US a pretty
respectable deal.
I want to tell you
something, Mr. Cox.
The truth is,
you look
more like a hobo
than any oilman.
That's all right.
No harm in that.
Maybe we ain't
much better off
ourselves,
but you think
I'd get my neighbors
involved in this?
I think you better go,
Mr. Cox.
This would be good
for everybody, Mr. Day.
Not just me--
your neighbors,
the little girls,
your children--
the whole community.
It really would.
[Door banging]
Well...I'll just
get my things,
if you don't mind,
and I'll be on my way.
$5,000.
Wish I had
Crazy man.
[Ding]
Yes, sir?
Can I help you?
I'm looking
for Norman sward's
room number, please.
No, no sward here.
No sward.
Well, how about
Cedric hartman?
No. No, sir.
And, uh, let's see...
P.g. Pratt?
Yes, sir. Mr. Pratt.
But I believe he
said he was going--
well, there he is
right there, sir.
P.g.! Good
to see you, sir.
How you been?
Mr. Cox?
I'll be damned!
Alex, come here.
I want you to
meet somebody.
Hey.
Alex is from Yale,
but he's o.K.
Ha ha ha!
Why, hell,
I haven't seen you
since old Mac Holland
got after you with a gun
right after that
Derrick collapsed.
That wasn't
my fault.
That was that
Mexican boy.
Whoa, now. I remember
you was telling me that.
You staying here
at the hotel, Mr. Cox?
Actually, p.G.,
I'm working
on a deal
to get set up
out there in, you know,
Wichita county.
Now, it's about
2,100 foot down,
maybe 22.
We can get to it
for 12,000
if we go rotary.
We could go cable,
but rotary's better.
I assume
you've tested?
I have evidence
to believe there's oil,
if that's what
you mean.
This thing's
sitting on top of
a salt formation
just like spindletop.
Spindletop.
Yeah. You've heard
of spindletop, I hope.
There were salt formations
at Rochester and sweet pie.
I never heard of them.
I'm not surprised.
There wasn't any oil there.
Oh, I see.
Now, we're all
on the same side.
Look, p.G.,
I got nothing against
your Yale boy here,
but I'm handing you
the chance of a lifetime.
I know it's there.
Nobody knows
where there's oil.
Is that right,
college boy?
Well...i know.
Yeah. I know.
Really?
Yeah.
How is it
you know so much?
You got
a geologist's report?
Soil samples?
Anything at all?
Well...i been there,
I seen it,
I heard it,
I smelled it,
and so did Matilda,
and that's a damn fact.
Ma--
yeah.
This is the real thing.
I mean, it nearly
knocked me on the ground,
my friend.
We better go.
Jessie's waiting.
Mr. Cox,
it's been nice
chatting with you.
It's always
a pleasure
to see somebody
from the old days.
Now...
[Mr. Cox]
Mrs. Pickens, I'll give you
the opportunity to get in
while there's still room.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
I can understand.
Well...I'm sorry
to hear that,
but if that's
the way you feel.
Yeah. Well,
you got--all right.
Good-bye and god bless.
Maybe another time.
So much for the widows.
[Meow]
Now, let's see...
I call it mother ground.
Some people call it
mother earth.
In that ground--
what's in the ground?
What do we have in the ground?
Oil.
Oil! Sure. Right.
Now, how do we get this?
Here's a good kitty.
Here's the good kitty.
It's o.K. Here we go.
Good girl. Right there.
Hello.
Hi there.
Uh...let's see.
Greek food.
That sounds interesting.
Ha ha!
Well, uh, this lamb
sounds good.
Uh...maybe have
some of that later.
I'll start with coffee.
Coffee.
Yeah. Maybe
something later.
I'll just start
with coffee...
And cream, a lot of cream.
I like cream.
[Purring]
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Easy. Yeah.
Here you go.
Oop. Here you go.
Yeah. Kitty, kitty. Yeah.
[Glass breaking]
[Man]
Steal from me?
I'll show you!
I want that colored
son of a bitch
to pay for this!
Next time,
I'm hiring
a white man!
No two ways
about that.
[Man]
Bring that
son of a bitch here!
Come on.
Trying to strike
again.
It's mine,
you understand?
Steal my apron?
Hey, you.
Who, me?
You a boozer?
You hit the bottle?
That's none of
your business.
I'm talking, see?
You're broke,
ain't you?
O.k. My name's ligstow,
buddy.
I own this place.
Best Greek restaurant
in Texas. Ask anybody.
I just caught
one of my boys
lifting food,
so I'm down
a dishwasher.
A dishwasher?
Well,
I'm an oilman,
you see.
J. Paul getty's
one of my busboys.
Oh.
I'm offering
12 bits a day,
free bed,
and 25 cents off
meals.
You don't like that,
that's fine.
Plenty of other men.
I'll just get
one of them.
[Caruso singing
opera music]
Beatrice?
Where's
your sister?
I don't know.
Aren't you
supposed to be
keeping an eye
on her?
Yes, sir.
It's getting late,
Raymond.
Yes, sir.
Good night, bea.
Good night, Raymond.
Pauline,
what are you doing?
Nothing.
Just listening to something.
What?
Oil.
Well--
ha ha ha!
I don't think
you can hear oil,
even if there
was some.
Mr. Cox says you can.
Well, listen now.
Don't listen
to everything
people
tell you, o.K.?
Especially people
like Mr. Cox.
You canhear it!
O.k., o.K.
Maybe you can.
Come on.
What?
Oh, sugar.
Listen.
It, uh...Sounds like
a sea shell.
That's what
Mr. Cox said.
He did?
[Mother]
Come on, you two.
Bedtime.
What's oil, papa?
Huh?
Oil. What's it doing
in the ground?
Well, to tell you
the truth, I don't know.
Come on, honey.
Oh, my. You are
getting heavy.
[Water sloshing]
Mr. Cox...
What is, uh,
your Christian name?
Mister.
You're a cool one,
huh, Mr. Cox?
Huh?
Old Zeke, he used to--
he was a talker.
He'd run on
about anything.
Uh-huh.
He said more
in a minute
than you'd a-said
this week.
We got three tables
on station four.
Yeah. Yeah.
[Meow]
Hey, baby. How you doing?
You being a good girl?
Yes, you are.
You're a good girl.
There's a good girl.
Yes. Yeah.
You're a pretty little thing,
ain't you?
Huh? Yes, you is.
You like cats, don't you?
I ain't never had me
no cat.
Most colored people think
they're bad luck.
Ain't that silly?
Look at you.
You seem to be
making out just fine.
Yeah. Sure.
Meow.
[Meow]
Meooow.
[Imitating harmonica]
♪ I used to have me
a real big dog ♪
♪ but he wouldn't
stay that way ♪
♪ he turned into
a chicken ♪
♪ when my cat
chased him away ♪♪
I bet you're
partial to music,
ain't you, Mr. Cox?
I like a dance tune
now and then. Yeah.
I'm a-saving up
to get me a phonograph
right now.
Going to be a while...
[Music box playing]
But I'm determined.
I like that.
It's nice.
[Woman]
There must be
some mistake.
[Man]
Well, I was talking
to Abe melter.
He's from jacksboro,
you know, and, uh,
he tells me he's
down in Wichita falls
the other day,
and he sees Don
coming out of
stratmeyer's
oil equipment.
[Whispers]
Come on.
And he says,
"hey, Don,
how you doing?"
Don just
walks past him
like he didn't even
know him.
Later, Abe's talking
to stratmeyer himself,
and stratmeyer lets on
how Don was inquiring
about how much
it would cost
to drill a well--
an oil well.
So I'm sitting
in my office
thinking this over,
and I start
to wondering--
is Don planning
on drilling for oil
on your land?
That's the silliest thing
I ever heard.
Well, yeah,
that's what I said,
only, um...
Only what?
I called up
Mr. Stratmeyer
myself,
and he told me
Don is suffering
under the delusion
that there is oil
on this farm.
Now, it's not
my business
to butt in where
I'm not wanted,
but the truth is,
I'm afraid the loan
our bank made
in good faith
is in jeopardy,
and that makes it
my business.
People I've known
all my life
are losing
their land
and moving on.
You've been
a valued customer.
I don't want
to see that
happen to you.
Well, I appreciate
that, les.
Lee was a good
friend of mine.
Since he died,
I felt it's my duty
to look out for
your best interests.
I hope I'm not
overstepping
my bounds here.
You'll have your money
first thing in the morning.
I'm glad
we could nip this
before it got
out of hand.
Thank you, les.
You're welcome,
Mrs. Timminger.
It's the least
I could do for Lee,
god rest his soul.
Her name ain't
timminger, les.
Ain't been
for nearly 10 years.
Take your dirty hands
off my automobile.
I'll take my dirty hands
and stick them
down your throat!
Sick and tired of you
causing trouble for people!
Go on home, les.
Well, I know you,
Don day!
Yes, sir,
I know you.
I know how you
come riding in here
on a freight train!
I ought to
call the police.
I ought to!
You's one of
them nuts!
Honey...
Sit down here.
I need to talk to you.
What if that old man
was right?
What if there is
oil here?
I don't want to listen
to that talk, Don.
That money is
for our farm.
Our farm?
Well, you say
"our farm."
Your ex-husband
said it was
his farm.
I'll tell you
whose it is--
the bank
of henrietta's.
Oh!
Wake up!
We're losing
this place!
Another six months,
a year like this,
and we're finished.
We're not going to
have a farm.
You ain't never
lived through
seeing your family
get kicked off their land.
I have,
and I do not aim
to sit and watch it
happen again.
And I'm not going to
watch you
gamble
our farm away.
Who's going to feed
our children?
That old man?
Is he going to
clothe them?
You tell me
who will feed them
when our land is gone.
The bank of henrietta?
I want that money
back where it belongs.
Maybe I got something
to say about that!
I don't want
to hear it!
[Children gasp]
You girls
get upstairs...
Right now.
Yes, ma'am.
I want that money
turned over
to the bank.
I've been thinking
about that money
for the last week,
and I didn't know
what to do,
but I do now.
Then I want you
out of here.
You what?
I want you
out of this house.
You understand me?
O.k. Fine.
Fine.
[Door closes]
[Man]
Hey, there's
big Dave.
Good morning.
What you selling
today?
My arrangement's the same
with all my employees.
Just 'cause
a man's face is white
don't mean he gets
special treatment.
I ain't unfair
in that way.
I understand.
It's just I've
been working here
almost two weeks,
and if I didn't
need a new suit
as bad as I do,
I wouldn't
be asking.
There's a principle
working here
that's bigger than
just a few dollars.
No, sir, there ain't
nothing special about you.
Maybe you got
different ideas, but...
You're going to
have to wait
till the proper payday
like everybody else.
O.k.
I've been to every
so-called oilman
in town.
Might as well
be some...
Dago off the boat
as far as they care.
Hey! Zeke--
Zeke got a suit.
He bought it
the day before
they took him to jail.
It'll fit you.
Saved up his money
for 10 weeks to buy it,
and he didn't
get to wear it.
There it is.
And it's
brand-new, too.
What you been
hiding here?
Looky here.
That Zeke...
He sure know
how to dress.
[Music and laughter]
What can we
do you for, sport?
I'm just waiting
on a friend.
Come on.
You go sit down
over here
with these other
fellows.
Where?
Right over here.
That's right.
Y'all
have fun, now.
Hi, honey!
Follow me.
Lead on,
my lady.
All right, ladies.
Let's go downstairs
for payday!
Yeah! Round 'em up!
Round 'em up!
Cross that river.
A big-spending guy
like me
might have something
special here.
Ooh!ohh!
Come here. Right this way.
Let's see who's going to
get this little diamond.
Who's going to be
the lucky girl?
Me!me!
Who wants it?
Yes!
Do I know you?
No, but i'm
going to know you.
[Woman]
Whoo! Where'd you get
the duds?
Vaudeville?
Ha ha ha!
Keep that one.
She's a real card.
Ha ha ha!
No, uh...Old Mac,
Mac Holland, told me
to look you up.
Fine. Well, tell Mac
that big Dave says hello.
Say, Dave, I just
had a good one.
How about you and me
going someplace
and tossing down
a few?
No, I don't think so.
Mac made me swear
I'd treat you
to the town.
Well, I'm not much
of a drinking man,
but, uh...I have worked up
a bit of an appetite.
Sure, Dave.
You name the place.
I took you for
a steak man, Dave.
What do you
think, ed?
Oh, he doesn't think.
Must be a democrat!
You're not a democrat,
are you, Dave?
I can't say much
for the looks
of this place.
You been here?
No, but I heard
some gal almost died
from something
in her food here.
Mr. Cox!
Pleasure to see you.
Don't say nothing.
Shut up.
Hey, p.G.
How are you, sir?
Good to see you, sir.
No...i don't know.
I think that gal
did die.
Matter of fact,
I'm sure of it.
Well, good evening,
Mr. Cox.
Who the hell
is that?
The boys in Detroit
don't got
this problem.
The country thinks
Henry Ford
is a Saint.
Why? Boosting.
They can call it
public relations
or modern
advertising,
but it's plain,
old-fashioned
boosting.
That's it
in a nutshell.
That really is.
You can believe me
on that one.
[Mr. Cox]
Here's to luck,
queen of destiny,
and hail to oil.
Oh, my god.
I'll lay my cards
on the table.
I'd hoped to
stay away
from business,
but I've been
impressed
by the way we've
hit it off.
You know who's out there?
Big Dave mcdermit.
I'll bet he's
the richest man
in Texas.
Oh, do tell.
I think you
just might be
interested here.
I think.
Ha ha ha!
Did I say
something wrong,
Dave?
What did I say?
You're a hopeless
loser, Mr. Cox.
I just don't have time
for losers.
You say hello to Mac
for me now, you hear?
Mr. Mcdermit, let me
introduce myself.
I own this restaurant.
Well, good for you!
Ha ha ha!
I gave you a job
washing dishes,
but that ain't
good enough for you.
$13.50.
Got the money
for that...Oilman?
Take it out of
the money you owe me.
You ain't getting a nickel
out of me after this stunt.
I got a few
dollars.
All I want you to do
is go and phone the police.
Oh, I'll talk to you later.
Shirl, you call them!
So...this is
the way it is, huh?
[Glass shatters]
Oilman, huh?
You ain't nothing
but a cheap promoter!
Can't even
wash dishes decent.
I'm calling
the police!
Crazy.
Hey, this is
Larry ligstow.
Get me the police.
How much love or money
are you asking?
Well, I can't
sell her to you.
No, no, sir.
She's got too much
sentimental value
for that...
But I might
lease her to you.
Lease?
Well...
Say, $300 now
and $100
by the week.
Well...ha ha ha!
You've lost your mind.
That wouldn't
leave me enough
for pipe or timber.
You couldn't get
one of them
Wichita falls
spudders
for less than
twice that.
Now, don't take me
for ignorant.
I don't like that.
Yeah.
I tell you what,
boy.
I'll throw in
some timber
and three men
to help you
put up a Derrick.
I'll tell you what.
I just might be willing
to let you in
for a percentage.
I told you before.
Don't take me
for ignorant.
Ha ha ha!
[Laughing]
[Man]
Hold it. Step back!
O.k., red!
Got it, red!
There it goes!
All right.
Just go on back there.
[Unlocking door]
Get in there.
[Door closes]
Much obliged.
Really appreciate all your help.
Thank you.
[Car starts]
[Don]
Thanks!
You looking
for a job, Raymond?
Yes, sir.
There might be
some work here
after school
and on weekends.
Now, listen,
I don't want you
doing anything
dangerous, you hear?
Yes, sir.
O.k. Deal.
Get in there.
Yeah.
You look good.
You look good,
Mr. Cox.
Well, here's
your cat.
Good.
Come here, baby.
Sure missed you.
Look, I don't reckon
I'll be seeing you
for a while.
Got a letter
from home.
Mamma's sick,
so, uh...
Oh, sorry
to hear that.
Good luck.
Yeah.
Thank you, Robert.
You're a good man.
You are.
Oh, thank you, sir.
Bye-bye.
Yeah.
Well...
Who missed who
the most?
Bet you didn't even
miss me, did you?
I didn't miss you any.
Yeah.
This is it, darling.
I got to take care
of some business, all right?
Now, if I don't
come back,
I want you to hook up
with one of these roughnecks,
all right?
They'll take care of you.
They're good men.
But you got to behave yourself,
all right?
Give me
a little kiss, o.K.?
[Purring]
Yeah, good girl.
Yeah.
[Meow]
That's the way
it's got to be.
It sure beats
the hell out of me.
Everything seems
to be running
smooth.
Well, it ain't
going nowhere.
Just stopped.
Well, it got me
whupped.
How deep did you
say we was?
I don't know.
Maybe 1,300 feet.
1,300?
Yeah. So what?
Well, what the hell
you trying to do?
I told you before
this rig wasn't
built to go
more than
1,200 feet,
you damn fool!
The deal is off!
I want my rig back!
You never said
nothing about
no 1,200 feet!
Oh, the heck I didn't!
That's what comes
when you deal
with ignorance!
And don't you
touch that rig
till I bring
my boys over
to bring it home!
[Car door slams]
[Engine starts]
Thank you, sir.
Good day, sir.
Good day.
How can I help you?
I'd like a room,
please.
O.k. I've met
all kinds,
mister...
Not Duke,
not lord,
just plain old
Mr. Cox.
Well, Mr. Cox,
you'll be staying
in room 216.
[Ding ding]
Ha ha ha!
Take Mr. Cox
to room 216.
Thank you, sir.
Enjoy your stay.
For you.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you
very much.
O.k.
Dinnertime.
O.k., darling.
There you go.
Wait a minute.
[Knock on door]
Cora?
Cora.
What I did was stupid.
It was...
It was so stupid.
Maybe I thought
I'd do something
even your Lee
couldn't do.
I don't know.
We got till the 1st
to pay this note...
And I don't know
what to do about it.
I'm going to talk
to the bank.
Maybe they'll give US
an extension.
Stop saying US.
You're still my wife.
[Door closes]
[Furrows]
Don, it would be
against
state banking laws.
We're not talking
about a lot of time here,
just a couple
of months.
Well, I don't see
how you'd be
better off then.
I'm not just
asking for me.
[Telephone ringing]
Well, I can't live
Cora's life for her.
I'm just glad
Lee isn't alive
to see
what's happened
to his farm.
Why, it would break
that poor man's
heart
to have Cora lose
that land.
Lee was a friend
of mine, Don.
He wasn't
no daydreamer
like you.
No.
Lee was all man.
What are you thinking?
It ain't even worth
talking about.
Mommy!
[Pauline]
Help!
Mommy!
Help me!
Oh, my god.
Mommy!
[Dog barking]
Pauline!
[Beatrice]
Oh, my god,
no!
Pauline!
[Pauline]
I'm scared!
Mommy!
Pauline, I'm coming
up there! Don't move!
Mommy!
Raymond,
be careful!
[Beatrice]
Hurry! Get her
down!
Be careful!
Mommy!
Keep still,
pauline!
Mommy!
Help!
Please, god.
Pauline!
Aah!
No! No!
Raymond!
Daddy!
No.
I'll be back
soon, son.
[Thunder]
So, tell me, doc.
When are we going to
know something?
We'll know more
about it
in a couple of weeks.
A couple of weeks?
Well, I want
to thank you,
doctor.
You did everything
you could.
Mr. Rumsfelk?
I don't know
what to say.
Uh...I'll do everything
I can to pay
these hospital
expenses.
I don't know how,
but I promise you,
no matter how long
it takes--
you're Don day.
Yes, sir.
You're the one
that did this.
It's not enough
I've come
to this hellhole
to teach your
stupid children.
No, that's
not enough
for a man like you.
Cora.
Oh...
My husband
loves your son.
I think
you ought to know that.
[Door closes]
I'm fine. I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Children, come on.
Beatrice.
I can't move.
Oh, honey.
[Cox]
Dear Mr. Day,
good news.
It appears that I have been
successful
in interesting a number
of moneyed investors
in the oil venture
we discussed at your farm.
As yet, I've been
only able to raise
a portion
of the necessary capital,
though I expect
to have acquired the remainder
within a few days
or weeks at most.
Yours in good health,
Mr. Cox.
All right, let's see
what you bought
with all
that money, huh?
Couple pairs,
aces and tens.
[Big Dave]
Ha ha!
[Man]
Every time.
Yeah, well, this ain't
the boy scouts, doc.
What can I tell you?
Let's play
a man's game.
Five stud.
Ante.
Hey! Hey!
Don't anybody move.
You won't live
to spend that.
Hold it!
[Glass shatters]
[Woman screams]
Aah!
[Man]
Stay down.
Operator!
Ow!
Jeez!
Drop it!
Here.
[Grunting]
Aargh! Aah!
Ohh! Aah!
Come on!
[Groaning]
They're on
the second floor!
We'll take care of it.
[Groan]
Hello?
Check
the street!
I'll cover
the lobby!
[Big Dave]
I want him found.
You hear me?
Find him!
I want every room
in this hotel
checked!
I want this whole
damn town
turned
right upside down!
This is no time
to dillydally!
Aah!
Let's go.
[Meow]
This is no time
to dillydally.
Come on. Yeah.
Hello!
Mr. Day!
Mr. Don day!
Good morning.
Hello!
Mr. Day!
Mr. Don day!
It's me! I'm back!
What the hell
do you want?
I want to talk to you!
Why don't you
just go on about
your business?
No. I've been
traveling all night.
I just want to talk,
that's all.
Well, if it's
the oil
you're
interested in,
you can just wait
till the 1st.
Talk to the bank
about it.
It ain't got
nothing to do
with me no more.
Mr. Day, listen to me.
When I was out here
before,
I said I wanted you
as a partner.
That wasn't no stunt
I was pulling. I meant it.
Now...
Oh, did you ever read
my letter?
Did you get my letter?
I read your letter,
Mr. Cox.
Oh, ma'am. Yeah.
Then you know
I'm telling you the truth.
[Cox]
I wouldn't lie to you.
Now, listen to me.
Listen.
I make my living
from the ground.
Now, this is
a gold mine
we're standing
on here, lady.
I know it,
and I think your husband
knows it.
Now, I can get to it,
Mrs. Day.
I got the money.
I got the expertise.
Somebody is going to
get to it someday,
and I want it
to be US.
Now, think about it.
You have your children,
your house, your land.
Don't let this
all go to waste.
Do you hear me?
Does somebody hear me?
It's not
my decision,
Mr. Cox.
It's up
to my husband.
Oh, mamma!
[Cora]
Beatrice?
Honey?
Make him leave.
Don't let him
stay here.
Who--Mr. Cox?
It's his fault Raymond's
in the hospital.
If he hadn't come here
in the first place,
none of this would have
ever happened.
The reason
Raymond's in the hospital
is because
he fell off
the Derrick.
He was trying
to help pauline.
That's right.
He fell off
the Derrick
trying to help
somebody in trouble.
It's just
the way he is.
He'll probably
always be that way.
You can't blame
Mr. Cox for that.
Let me ask you
something.
[Groan]
Why did you
decide to drill
where you did?
Huh?
A hunch? A feeling?
Yeah, yeah,
a feeling.
All right, now,
where did you have
this feeling?
Where?
Yeah. You got to be
exact about this.
Was it here?
Did you feel it--
what?
Here or here?
In there? Here?
Right there.
That's right.
That's it.
That's exactly right.
How did you know?
That's exactly
what I thought.
Ha ha! Yeah.
So what the hell's wrong?
I said I felt it.
Nothing's wrong.
It's o.K.
What are you doing?
Oh...
Little trade secret.
Something I devised
called "oil to oil."
Oil to oil.
All right, now,
let's get to it.
Out of the way,
kitty.
Ha ha ha!
You're not an oilman,
are you, Don?
I never said I was.
That's right.
You never did,
did you?
How about letting
an oilman teach you
something?
When you feel it here,
that is zinc.
that, my friend,
is oil.
O.k., now,
let's bear down here,
all right.
Just watch
these sticks.
It might take a while.
Yes, sir.
Wait a minute.
I think
I do feel something.
Where?
Where do you think
you feel something?
Huh?
It's not there?
No.
Right in there.
Damn. Me, too.
Probably got a little coal
on your land, Don.
That's what
that means. Ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha!
God, what an idiot.
Ha ha ha!
Pardon me. Ha ha!
M-Mr. Cox.
Huh?
Mr. Cox!
Come here.
Come here!
Spread them
right there.
Right there,
no doubts about it.
Don't move.
Don't you move
an inch.
I'll show you
something here.
Ha ha ha!
You found it first.
You Mark it.
[Meow]
Ah...
You're a little late,
darling.
You come in third.
Ha ha ha!
Oh...
It's a hell
of a business, ain't it?
It's a hell of a business.
[Man]
I'll be with you
in a minute.
Let me do
the dickering.
I've dealt
with this bird before.
Lucas,
come over here.
Mr. Cox?
Huh?
By golly, Mr. Cox.
Roy, you son
of a gun!
I thought
that was you.
You looking
for work?
Yes, sir.
I could use some.
Well, you got it.
This is my partner
Don day.
Don, this is Roy.
Nice
to meet you.
Pleasure.
Well,
let's get to it.
Let's get started.
[Car doors close]
Come on, boys.
Here we go. Oh!
Get it up!
[Roy]
There you go, now.
Make sure it's even
down there.
We got her now!
[Don]
Coming up!
[Roy]
It's higher than it looks.
Hey, here's to luck!
Yee-ha!
Yes, sir.
Huh.
No wonder...
You got a flood in here.
What did
the authorities
have to say?
They don't know
about it.
They won't,
unless I choose
to tell them.
That gun was
found in a room
rented to a cheap
promoter named Cox.
Mr. Cox,
he calls himself.
I want him found.
And?
Just found.
How's it look?
Clay.
Huh?
Well,
I don't know.
We're nearly
1,800 feet.
See anything?
Nope.
Engine's kind of
running raggedy.
Losing power.
Might be a good idea
to get an overhaul.
Nope. Too much time.
We have to have it in
by the 1st.
Ha!
I think I'll have myself
a little walk.
Yeah.
Sure seems to know
a lot about oil,
don't he?
Uh-huh.
Well, you worked
with him
a lot of times,
haven't you?
Oh, yeah.
Several times.
There's Phoenix number 21
I worked on.
Then we done
Phoenix number 27.
And there's
some other Phoenix
I can't remember
the number of right now.
Well,
what's his affection
for Phoenix?
Does he name
them all that?
Up to now he has,
but that's just till
he hits his first strike.
His firststrike?
Well, who did you think
you was dealing with--
rockefeller?
You mean to...
You mean to tell me
that he's never...
Nope.
Not so far, he ain't.
Ha ha ha!
Well, I sure can
pick them, can't I?
Hell, I pull them
out of the woodwork.
[Gasp]
I wasn't doing
nothing bad.
I know, I know.
It's kind of
a long walk
to henrietta,
isn't it?
Ha ha!
How'd you know
I went to henrietta?
I heard the hospital
let your boyfriend
go home.
How's he doing?
The doctor said
one of his legs
might be a little gimpy.
I'm sorry
to hear that.
God, you're
a stubborn woman.
Not here.
I want you back
where you belong.
[Man]
Hello, Dave.
Yeah, I found him.
He's on a farm
about 3 miles west
of henrietta--
the day farm.
You done good.
Want me to notify
the authorities?
I said I'll
take care of it.
Go on back
to Houston.
Leave the rest to me.
Whoa.
What do we
have here?
Why don't you
just give that
to the old man?
Bea and I
will dish out
the rest of these.
Hold that, Roy.
Mr. Cox.
Yeah?
Oh, thank you.
If it's too cold
tonight,
you're more
than welcome
in the house.
Thank you, ma'am,
but we're too close
to the pay now.
We're almost there.
You really think so?
Oh, I do.
I really do.
I do.
Much obliged.
Thank you.
Roy!
Roy, get that lantern
over here!
Point it in here
and tell me what you see,
what you smell,
and what you taste.
I'm going to
let you get some.
Your first taste, son.
First--
first time, son.
It's better
than ice cream,
isn't it?
Mmm.
[Roy]
That's oil.
By god, you luckless bastards,
you did it.
Ha ha ha!
Woo!
Now, what I need
is storage tanks.
Go tell stratmeyer
we need those tanks now.
We need them tonight.
On the double.
Go on. Go on.
Hang on.
Take my truck.
Hold on. Come here.
Give this to him.
Go to his house.
You know where he lives?
On the double.
Don't get lost, Roy.
I won't.
Ha ha ha!
Mr. Stratmeyer!
97, 98, 99, 100...
No! I think
the line's out
of the shive.
Shut her down!
Shut the thing down!
[Shouts]
Come on. Move!
[Thunder]
Come on, boys,
let's go!
Get those out of here!
Get them out of here.
Go! Go!
[Whistle]
How are you doing
up there?
It's going to be
a while!
I think this thing
will blow over in a minute.
Yeah? That would
be all right.
[Horn honking]
The well's coming in!
[Whistles]
[Horns honking]
My lord, it's so late.
My mamma's going to kill me.
What's going on?
[Shouts and whistles]
Oil strike
at the day farm!
Beatrice, look!
Your daddy
did it!
[Horns honking]
Wait!
Please stop!
Stop!
Raymond?
Please, can we
go with you?
What are you
doing out here?
Come back here
right now.
Do you hear me, son?
What is she
doing here?
Raymond!
Oh!
[Shouting and horns honking]
[Urinating]
What the hell?
Button it up.
Let's go.
Get in the car.
Get in
the damn car.
Help!
Ha ha ha!
All right,
y'all get over there
and help them
on that thing.
You boys,
get them barrels down.
Get them storage tanks
over there.
We're bringing it in
for you, Mr. Cox!
You done good, Roy.
You brought half
the town with you.
All right, then.
See what he did?
Ha ha ha!
Roy done good!
There he is.
Put that thing down,
you damn fool.
Change of plans.
We hit gas!
Everybody, jump quick!
Everybody
get out of here!
[Screams]
Don?
Cora, get away
from here now!
Come on.
Come with me.
Stay back.
We'll take care of Don.
You all right?
Roy, get the nitro!
Don, get two
lengths of pipe.
We'll blow it out.
Blow it out?
That's the only way
we can get it out.
You better
get rid of this.
Come on back!
Bring it
on back! Easy!
Move it!
Bring it back easy!
Come on, bring it back!
Look out, now. Back up.
Bring her back!
All right, now.
Bring it back.
Bring it on back down!
Bring it back!
That's it!
Easy!
Bring it back now!
Come on now!
[Rumbling]
Woo! Coming out
of chute number four.
Don!
Cora!
[Pipes hitting ground]
My sister.
Oh, Don.
I'm all right.
Mr. Cox?
Oh, lord.
He's breathing.
[Rumbling]
Hey.
Hold it, boss.
[Cheering]
Oh, it's great.
Hey, that's mine.
That's mine!
That oil belongs to me.
That old bastard
used my money.
Don't you die on me now,
you son of a bitch!
You know damn well
that belongs to me!
You used my money!
I want my damn money!
Hey!
Get off my land!
All right, we're going,
we're going,
damn it.
You take good care of him,
you understand?
You take good care
of that old man!
Now, you know damn well
that's my money!
That oil belongs to me!
All right, all right.
Goddamn. How about that?
[Big Dave]
I'll be back!
Do you hear me?
How's it look, Don?
Ha ha! It looks
pretty damn good
now that you're
talking, Mr. Cox.
Ha ha!
Like nothing else.
Don. Don day...
What time you
got there, buddy?
What time is it?
Well, Mr. Cox...
It's 6:30.
June 19th, 6:30 A.M.
People will remember that
for a long time to come.
That's something nobody
can take away from US, Don.
No matter what happens...
They can't take this night
away from US. No, sir.
No, sir...
They never can.
Oh. Thank you,
sweetheart.
Thank you.
Yeah.
O.k.
Here we go.
Mr. Cox made it,
all right.
He did move
a little slower
than he did before,
and the doctor
said his hearing
would never be
the same again.
Don.
Yes, sir.
2,400 barrels a day now.
2,400?
That's good.
What's that
you say, Don?
[Louder]
I said that's
not bad!
No, it's not bad
at all.
Yeah. Ha ha!
Pauline, will you
give this man
some peace?
No, no, she's fine.
She's fine.
Mr. Cox,
you're going to
spoil her rotten.
He paid back all
his "investors" with interest,
even that horrible
Dave mcdermit.
Mr. Cox was an oilman,
not a thief.
Oilman or not,
it wasn't long
before Mr. Cox
got what he called
"bugs between his toes,"
or "itchy feet" as some
less colorful might say.
Here. Let me
take that for you.
Thank you, Raymond.
Thank you.
Thanks for the little
get-together, Cora.
You're welcome,
Mr. Cox.
Bless you.
All right,
this is it.
Raymond, bring that
over here.
See what you're made of.
Ha ha!
Throw it in there.
Yes, sir.
And, uh...
Be careful, Don.
You, too, Mr. Cox.
What was that?
I said you, too,
Mr. Cox!
Oh, I will be, Don.
I will be.
You can bet on that.
Yes, sir. Come here.
Get in, darling.
Kitty, kitty.
Come on. Get in.
Now...
I got a special
little gift
for a special little
friend of mine.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Now I'm going to
tell you something.
Nobody else
can hear this.
I promise.
You promise?
Well...
Well, folks,
there will be no tears
shed here today...
Including myself.
Ha ha ha!
You're fine people...
And I want
to thank you.
I really mean that.
So good-bye for now.
[Pauline]
Good-bye.
Get over there,
darlin'.
Get over there.
She doesn't want
to go. Ha ha!
Finest people
I ever knew in my life.
Till we meet again.
Bye. Bye-bye.
That was the last time
we saw Mr. Cox.
He sold out his interest
in the field,
and that was that.
He made a lot
of money,
no question about that.
Hail to oil!
But he could have
made a lot more
if he'd stayed around
a while.
The rumor was he took it all
to California
and got into real estate,
lost every dime he had.
Ha ha! I don't know
about that.
I don't think
it was the money
he really cared about,
anyway.
It was the life
he loved
and the game
that goes with it.
I'll never forget
what he whispered to me
in my ear that day--
"hitch your wagon
to a star, sweetheart."
I've lived my life by that.
Captioning made possible by
Warner Bros.
Captioning performed by
the national captioning
institute, inc.