Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
When you said middle of
nowhere, you weren't kidding.
- It's not much further.
- Wow, it's so
beautiful out here.
Yeah, that's why my dad
bought the place.
It's on 10 acres.
No one around for miles.
I told you we should
have gone to Aspen.
Thanks. Keep the change.
This is your house?
Well, my dad's technically.
Bling.
This place is B-L-I-N-G.
- It's really nice.
- What time is this
once-in-a-lifetime
meteor shower?
Oh, it's supposed to be
like 10:00, I think.
Sick.
This is going to be amazing.
Oh, God, I wish I could get
out here more often.
This is fire!
100k likes here we come!
Christ.
Deidre... is just...
really different.
Yeah, I know.
Wow.
Check out this
motherfucking piscina.
This will be sick
for my photo shoot.
What's up, guys? We're here.
We made it.
It's going to be amazing.
We're staying in this
really cool house
in the middle of
fucking nowhere.
It's 3:30
or something like that.
The sun is shining
and it's seven hours
countdown to the meteor shower
storm... thing.
- Live stream.
- D, don't.
Here we are with that
Yoga with Heather 97.
Check her out.
Follow her for
your spiritual fix.
Namaste.
Check out this bed. Whoo!
And Charlotte.
She's not on social media.
She doesn't believe in it.
It's not her thing.
And that's fine.
But this? This is not fine.
Check this out.
Retro!
See it and believe it, people,
because it's true.
Some people are living there.
Stone Age best lives.
She's hot, though.
Geek hot, but hot.
Hit her up.
Wait, no, you can't,
because what?
No social media?
So send her a letter,
a telegram,
a smoke signal or DM me
and I'll hook you up.
Squad goals.
Three hot babes stargazing.
We're here to party...
Whoo!...
and watch the biggest
shooting star event
since the dinosaurs checked out.
Alright, that's D.
- Deidre, what the fuck?
- What?
You'll get likes.
I'm telling you, mucholikes.
Geek hot is so far
at the moment.
- I don't want likes.
- What?
You're crazy.
Shit, girl. You need some.
Yeah? It's really invasive.
Guys, it's been way too long.
I'm so glad we did this.
Me too.
I love the pet store,
but I really needed
a couple of days off.
I really need to get laid,
guys.
It's been a while.
Yeah, I feel you.
You got any hot friends
out here?
Mnh-mnh. No chance.
Never met anyone
out here my age.
Nothing.
Literally no one around.
Oh, apart from this guy.
Hmm.
An actual cowboy.
You'd make a lovely couple.
Oh, please.
And that's it.
No sex this weekend.
You ever seen
a meteor shower before?
Mm-hmm. Once in Costa Rica.
It was amazing, guys.
That when you met Phillip?
Mm-hmm.
How's that going anyway?
Good. Okay.
He's teaching a yoga retreat
in Colorado this weekend.
Is he watching
the meteor shower, too?
Yeah, they're doing like
a whole ceremony thing.
Have you heard from Schoze?
Not since we got here.
His loss.
He's probably fucking
Candace this weekend.
He's only interested
because she's got like
a million followers.
Schoze will screw anyone
for a shout-out.
Fuck him.
And fuck Candace.
You're building a makeup line.
Oh, you guys,
I finally got the name.
Yeah? What is it?
I'm D, and I'm fine,
and it defines.
Huh?
I don't get it.
I'm D, and I'm fine,
and it defines.
That's awesome.
I know.
What?
Gimme.
Wow!
Beautiful.
Ugh. Fuck me.
Goddamn piece of shit.
What's a girl got to do
to get a goddamn signal?
Whoa!
Amazing.
- That one was huge.
- Motherfucker.
Fucking signal's fucked.
Fucking live stream, fuck you.
Deidre, you're missing it.
I've got no signal, either.
Wow.
Is it supposed to do that?
I guess. I mean, it is
a once-in-a-lifetime
meteor shower.
Unbelievable.
Here we are watching the event
of a lifetime,
and I cannot get
a goddamn signal.
Whoa.
Is it supposed to do that?
Wow.
Beautiful.
Margaritas. Nice.
Cheers.
I've turned the Wi-Fi
on and off
like a thousand times.
Still can't get any signal.
Whoa, that's... strong.
Ugh.
Whew!
It's just like old times.
You remember when we went
camping in school?
I fucking hate camping.
Yeah, especially when
D tells you stories
about killer bears
who only ate children.
Oh, my God. I remember.
Fucking terrifying.
- I was so scared.
- Yeah, me too.
I mean, I didn't leave the
window open until I was,
- like, 13.
- Get a grip.
- Seriously.
- I mean, you were pretty mean.
Is it my fault you're both
a couple of little babies?
Remember that time
you got your head beaten in
by that fat bitch,
Jennifer Hopkins?
Saved your ass then, no?
Yeah, you did.
Yeah.
You were pretty mean, though.
Tough. Not mean.
And cute.
Very cute.
You know, you can't just
let people walk all over you.
Shit,
you got to have a mean side
or how are you going to survive?
You're not.
You know, it happens to pussies?
No?
They get fucked.
What the holy fuck?!
Oh, my God.
Where the fuck that come from?
It's leaking.
What? Shit!
Get out of the pool.
My dad's going
to fucking kill me.
What the fuck is it?
Maybe it's a meteor.
- D, please help me with this.
- Right.
Just get it out. Get it out!
- Okay, hon, chill.
- My God. Get it out.
- You got it?
- Oh, my God.
You got it?
Yeah. I think so.
- Okay.
- On the towels.
On the towels! Oh, my God!
The decking!
Oh, my God, is the decking okay?
Tell me it's okay.
It's okay.
- It's not staining.
- It's not?
No. Look. See?
It's okay, honey.
- What is it?
- Looks too soft to be a meteor.
I don't know.
Oh, my God. It stinks.
It stinks of ass.
Oh, my God, that is so bad.
But what is it?
I think it's...
shit.
I think God took a shit
in your pool, Heather.
- That's not funny.
- No, but seriously,
it's shit from a plane.
You know, they freeze
all the passenger shit in planes
and then drop it at once
it's full?
Schoze knew this one guy
who was eating
a sandwich in his kitchen,
and then one day a giant block
of frozen shit
the size of a refrigerator
fell through his roof
and killed him.
- I don't think they do that, D.
- What do you know?
You don't even Google.
Well, what do youthink it is?
Oh, my God.
It's got a little face.
I think it's... an animal.
- What kind of animal?
- I don't know.
It's... It's kind of
balled up like an
armadillo or something,
I-I'm not sure.
Well, whatever it is,
it's fucking dead.
Oh.
Oh, my God,
un-fucking-believable.
This is content gold.
Don't think it's an armadillo.
Thanks.
- I'm okay.
- Drink it.
For your nerves.
I want it out of here.
I can still smell it.
It could be a bear
made with an armadillo.
What?
And taught itself to fly?
- Oh, yeah.
- What are we gonna do with it?
I mean, how are we going to
get rid of it?
I don't know.
Stick it in the trash?
Oh, my God.
We could bury it...
under a tree or something.
What? No!
It's got to go.
Come on, babe.
Let's get you off to bed.
- Charles?
- Hmm?
Oh, I'm going to stay up
for a little while.
Okay.
Stay away from it.
It could have a disease
or something disease.
- Disease?
- No. No diseases.
Hey.
Morning.
- You sleep okay?
- Mm.
Uh...
I'm sorry about last night.
I was just a bit...
Oh, it's fine.
It's your dad's place.
You don't want it
to get fucked up.
- We get it.
- You're the best, Charles.
- Thanks.
- Oh.
Oh, my gosh, my head.
- I am not used to tequila.
- Me neither.
Jesus Christ.
- It just died.
- So weird.
I'm actually
freaking out right now.
Don't you have a landline?
We could call a cab
and go into town.
People don't use
landlines anymore.
- What about yours?
- It's in the bedroom.
Can you get it?
Uh...
Do you have signal?
Yeah.
Oh, wait. What the...?
What's happened?
I don't know.
It just sort of...
Shit.
I mean, it is kind of old.
I was meaning to get a new one.
Great. That's just great.
How am I going to post
the photo shoot?
Maybe it's magnets
and the meteor shower.
There was this thing called
the Carrington Event
in, like, the 1850s,
like a geomagnetic storm
that knocked out all the radio
waves around the world.
Magnets in the meteor shower?
Magnetic storms?
Where do you get this stuff?
Mm. Books, newspapers.
People are going to think
I'm dead, like I've died.
- They won't.
- They will.
They'll post about it
everywhere.
Then my mom will see it.
She'll get freaked out
and then she'll kill herself.
Shit, D.
It's only been like 24 hours.
24 hours is like a lifetime
on the Internet.
I've got sponsors.
I don't post,
I don't get paid.
Fuck it.
I'm done. It's over.
I'm over. "Hashtag dead."
What about the thing?
- Shit.
- I totally forgot.
- Where is it?
- I don't know.
Maybe it can fly.
Is it really gone?
Where the fuck is it?
Wait here.
Hey.
It'll be okay.
We can clean this up.
No problem.
Careful, it's my dad.
Just be on the safe side.
Animals must have dragged it.
What animals?
Coyotes maybe.
- Coyotes?
- They're not dangerous.
Not really.
God, it's disgusting.
My God, what the fuck?
It stinks worse than yesterday.
Where's its shell gone?
That's what you're
worried about?
- Hi.
- Jesus Christ.
I'm Brett.
I'm here to do the garden.
Oh, great. You work for my dad.
My dad.
I don't know your dad.
Agency booked my brother.
He got sick.
Go on.
Ask him.
Ask him what?
The thing?
Oh, my God.
He can take it away.
Oh, my God, great idea.
Hi.
Got some shit on you?
Oh, we had an accident.
A thing. An animal.
Um, a dead armadillo or like
a bear thing fell on our pool.
Oh, yeah?
Ugh, it's still sort of here,
like, dead just over there.
- A dead armadillo?
- Right.
Well, we were wondering maybe
that you...
Listen, I'm just coming for
my brother.
Dead armadillo is...
That's, like,
another department.
I mean, we could give you
some money to take it away.
It would be really helpful.
How much?
It don't look like no armadillo.
Oh.
It stinks like ass.
$150 and a download link
to the photos.
You really are models?
Of course we are, Brett.
Nah, that's bullshit.
Deal's off.
I can just send you
the ones of me.
There's way hotter
on the Internet.
What the fuck?
Okay? A $150 in cash
and then we'll just transfer
you the rest
when our phones are fixed.
Do I look like an idiot to you?
No!
Please?
We really need your help.
There is one thing.
Unbelievable.
Okay, let's get this over with.
One quick kiss.
- With tongues.
- No, Brett. No tongues.
No hands. One kiss. That's it.
You break the rules, you're
gonna get punched in the face.
Okay?
Okay. Fine.
How old are you, anyway?
15.
And two months.
Fuck my life.
Ready?
Ready, Brett.
Okay, I'll go get the bear.
Okay, so that's $50 a piece.
- I don't have $50.
- I got you, Charles.
Anything to get rid of that
thing and get my phone fixed.
Here.
So, once Brett gets rid of
the dead thing,
here's the plan.
Quick trip to town.
Fix the phones.
Grab a juice, cab back then,
it's D-Fine photoshoot time.
- I don't really wanna...
- You're gonna love it, Charles.
I'm telling you
it's going to be fun.
- But I...
- Charles, you only put $7
into the get rid of the
ass-stinking dead bear fund,
- so please.
- But I...
I kissed the, you know...
...child.
Didn't seem like too much
of a chore, hon.
Hmm?
Looked pretty hot
from where we're standing.
What the fuck, D?
You should definitely ask him
for his number.
- Definitely. Hot.
- Oh, my God. Fine.
I'll do the damned shoot.
This is going to be excellent.
Fuck.
- Charles, any requests?
- Just that we get it over with
- fairly quickly.
- Oh, please,
you're going to love it.
I'll get the products.
Heather.
Fuck.
Fucking thing.
What the fuck?
Brett!
Oh, my fucking God.
No way.
We have to.
- No.
- Heather?
I don't care what Heather says.
I'm not letting you
kill an innocent animal.
- It's sick. It's already dying.
- Fucking Brett.
What are we going to do now?
How are we gonna
get rid of that thing?
My dad's gonna fucking kill me,
and my phone is still
- not working.
- Your dad cannot blame you
for a crash-landing armadillo.
No, it's definitely
not an armadillo.
Well, whatever it is,
killing it is the kind of thing.
- With what?
- I don't know.
This bat or poison?
You can't go around
killing things, D.
Of course you can.
People shoot sick horses
and dogs all the time, no?
People don't shoot sick dogs,
D.
We don't even know
if it's dying.
Oh, come on.
It's so is. Heather?
- Hmm?
- We put it out of its misery,
- no?
- You wantto kill it!
Don't be ridiculous.
You're a psychopath.
Heather?
you're a little baby.
Heather? We kill it, no?
What? Don't look at me.
I don't want to decide.
But can you please
put that thing away?
I told you it was dying.
Hey, little guy.
Charlotte, be careful.
Doesn't look well.
- Like I said...
- We're not killing it, D!
- It would be really bad karma.
- Jesus Christ.
Okay, okay. How about this?
We drag it away from the house,
at least,
leave it under a bush
or something.
I guess. I mean, in the shade,
it might get better.
We can leave it
a bowl of water.
Sure.
Fine.
You're both so lame.
Poor thing.
Shit, that motherfucker
is heavy.
I feel really dizzy.
I'm going to go and get it
a bowl of water.
Can we have some fun now,
please?
We came here to have
a good time, no?
Not drag some stinking dying
bear around in the blazing heat.
Shit.
Oh, my God.
- Heather.
- Huh? Huh?
- What? No.
The decking.
- Heather, wake up.
- Huh?
Charlotte.
What's going on? I'm asleep.
The thing, the bear thing...
- it's crying.
- Huh? What?
Come see it.
For fuck's sake,
Charles, go back to sleep!
Okay, buddy.
We can do is.
Whoa. Maybe I'm still stoned,
but you seem lighter.
Hey, little guy.
Are you hungry?
You were hungry.
Ugh!
What the fuck have you done?
Oh, hey, D.
Don't "Oh, hey, D" me.
I got two questions for you.
One, what is that piss-leaking
dog rat doing in the house?
And two,
where's my motherfucking shake?
What? What's going on? Shake?
- How did you even carry it?
- I don't know. Seemed lighter.
Get it out of my house.
It was crying.
- I couldn't just leave it...
- Out.
Okay.
Oh, my God!
I can't move it.
It's stuck its claws in.
It was crying.
It was crying?
Let me break this down
for you, Charlotte.
We're in the middle
of fucking nowhere.
There is an animal...
I don't know what it is,
I don't know where it's from.
You brought it into her house.
You fed it my protein shake.
Here's what's going to happen.
You're going to hitch
your little ass back into town,
find a vet
or an animal wrangler man,
get him to come down here
and get that thing
out of the goddamn house
before we all get rabies
or Ebola or both.
Okay?
Yeah. Okay.
Now, I'm going back to bed.
Do not wake me up
until it's gone.
And take the goddamn phones
and get them fixed too.
This is not what our weekend
was supposed to be like...
running around
trying to deal with a dead bear.
It's not cool, not cool at all.
I'm sorry.
- It's just it was...
- I know.
Crying.
I was a bit high too.
Okay.
But just don't ever, ever, ever,
ever,
ever pull some shit
like this ever fucking again.
Okay, I know.
My dad is a buggy in the garage.
The nearest neighbor is
this weird old lady called Edna.
We can drive down to Edna's
and see if she'll give us
a ride into town.
We can kind of vet.
Or Wrangler man or whatever.
Get my phone fixed.
Get rid of that creature.
Grab a latte, and get back
to chill mode.
We're calm.
I'm calm.
That's a good plan.
Now, I don't know
how reliable this is,
but I'm sure it'll get
us Edna's and back.
- Really?
- Mm.
Told you.
You motherfucker.
Hey, little guy.
Thirsty?
There.
Wow.
She lives out here
all on her own?
- Mm-hmm.
- Cool.
She's a bit eccentric.
Like, she's into
some weird science shit.
It's cool, though.
She's definitely cool.
And she gave me
some weed last summer.
- Nice.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's strange.
- What?
She's got this big dog
who normally goes crazy
when anyone comes by.
Miss Brunel?
Miss Brunel...?
- Wow!
- I told you.
Nothing.
What is all this stuff?
Okay, let's get out of here.
What about getting into town?
I don't know.
I'll leave her a note
in case she comes back.
- That's weird.
- What?
Isn't that yesterday?
The night of the meteor shower?
Mm-hmm.
Strange.
- How so?
- I don't know, it's just
really highlighted like a lot.
Well, maybe
it was her birthday.
Maybe.
Okay, let's go.
Charles, come on.
You want the bad news
or the bad news?
D?
- Huh?
- Edna wasn't there.
We couldn't get to town.
Shit.
That's bad.
D.
Hmm?
You okay, babe?
Oh, I'm sorry. Yeah.
Of course. Just a bit stoned.
Yeah, um,
we couldn't get the vet.
And the phones
are still fucked.
It's okay.
Don't worry about it.
How are we going to get that
thing out of the goddamn house?
Shit.
I'm with red on that one.
Huh?
Not my department.
Right. Okay.
Good. Great.
It is kind of cute, actually.
Do you want me to try
and move it again?
Yeah. Wait, wait, wait.
Actually, I can't take
any more of it screaming.
My nerves already shot to shit.
If it damages anything
in this house, Charlotte...
I will pay for it, I swear.
With what, Charles? With that?
I can make lunch.
Do you want some lunch?
- And I can clean.
- Un-fucking-believable.
Okay, fine. Make some lunch
before I lose my fucking mind.
I'm sorry, Heather.
Mmm!
That's good.
Mmm.
Mmm! So good.
Hungry?
- Huh?
- Nothing.
You gonna eat that?
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Mmm.
What?
Oh, I feel amazing.
Must be the fresh air.
Do you guys want
to work out in a bit?
It's, um,
it's a little hot at the moment.
- No?
- I'm good.
Suit yourselves.
- What the fuck?
- I know.
I really hope she's not
having another breakdown.
Like, I remember when she
split up with James?
Same thing.
She's totally flipped.
Maybe it's the come down?
For fuck's sake!
Oh, my God,
and it smells so bad.
Maybe we could give it a bath.
I mean, if you can move it
without it
tearing a hole in the rug.
I just think it didn't want
to go back outside.
You know what, Charlotte?
Be my guest.
Please, give
the fucking hyena a bath,
because you know what?
This weekend literally
cannot get any weirder.
Hey. Where's the...?
We put him in my room.
You did... what?
It's more comfortable
than the sofa.
Huh.
Nice day again.
It really is.
On the smokes already?
Hey, look.
What time are we leaving?
The phones aren't working.
Can't call a cab.
I have to get back
for work tomorrow.
Stoned out of your minds.
Jesus Christ.
I need to leave. Today.
The phones are not working,
Charlotte.
- What do you want to do?
- There's the buggy.
It's not going to get us back
to town, though, is it?
Don't you have to get back
for, like, work?
Chill, Charles.
One more day here.
It's hardly a prison sentence.
I'll lose my job, D.
You can do so much better,
though, really.
Sure. Okay, but...
Are you really just
going to lie here all day?
Wait for someone to come by?
That's the big plan?
Fuck it.
I'm going back to the cabin.
- What the hell for?
- I don't know.
Check the truck.
There might be keys in there.
Heather.
- Huh?
- Can I take the buggy?
- Knock yourself out, kid.
- Great.
Shit.
Mrs. Brunel?
Hello?
The fuck...?
She's dead... Edna.
Something is wrong.
We have to get out of here.
- D!
- Yeah, I heard you.
She's what?
She's killed herself.
Shit. That's fucked up.
I saw these drawings,
these diagrams and stuff.
Heather, Edna... she's dead.
It's terrible.
God is so fucked.
We need to leave.
That thing...
it's not safe.
What's it got to do with him?
Okay. I saw...
I saw a drawing.
A drawing?
Yeah.
Once the phones are working,
we'll call someone for help.
Yeah, definitely.
God.
It's so sad.
It's really sad.
What are you?
What the fuck is it?!
You went in the room.
What the fuck is it?
I'm not sure, but...
it's something really special.
- We need to call someone.
- Like who?
Like the cops
or other government.
Whoa. And what do you think
they're going to do with it?
They're going to take it.
That's what.
- And it's ours.
- She's right, Charles.
I think it's an alien.
I mean,
if it is an actual alien,
like, really like some
extraterrestrial shit,
then the first thing
we need to do is lawyer up.
The fuck? Heather?
You're the one
that wanted to keep it.
Imagine how much
an alien is worth.
I mean, asides from the PR,
and obviously porn.
This is insane.
You come across something
like this
and all you could think about
is how much it's worth?
This is America.
- It might be dangerous.
- Bullshit.
You just want to give it up.
You and your hippie
bleeding heart
are not going to fuck
this up for us.
Heather, the thing...
now it's ours, right?
- Heather?
- Right.
She's right, Charles.
I mean, this is a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
I feel amazing, like really...
I feel like I can just do
anything, you know?
Something really special,
and, I mean, you found it.
- Wefound it.
- Right. We found it.
- But Charles saved it originally.
- Yeah, sure. Sure, absolutely.
I mean, it's a three-way split
on, uh, any of the like...
Profits, dividends, shares.
And my dad can definitely help.
Right. I'm sure Schoze
knows people, too.
I mean, this is B-I-G.
What if it's dangerous?
I think Edna knew something,
- and now she's dead.
- Un-fucking-related.
Some ancient Looney Tunes bitch
blows her brains out
and you want to give up like a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity?
I told you. I told you she'd
try and fuck this up for us.
You're crazy, D. Like,
you've really fucking flipped.
No, Charlotte, you'recrazy.
You find an alien and you want
to fucking give it away?!
No, no, no, no, no.
No fucking way!
This is so typical of you,
Charlotte.
You get an opportunity like this
and you just can't help yourself
but fuck it up.
There is a reason you work in
a pet shop for a minimum wage.
Well, you're not fucking
this up for us. No, you're not.
D.
You were always like this,
Charles.
- Even at school, you were weak.
- D, what the fuck?
You've got no killer instinct.
Something like this lands
on your plate,
and you want to call the cops?
Fuck the police,
we're keeping it!
- Deidre!
- What?!
What the fuck is that?
What the fuck?!
Oh, my God!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- This is yourfault!
- What?
You brought that thing
in the house, you stupid bitch!
- What the fuck?
- I mean, how...?
What...?
Not good. Not good.
D...
...your eyes.
What the...?
Oh, my God.
- It burns!
- It burns! It burns!
It burns! It burns!
Help me!
Oh, my God.
You motherfucker.
What have you done to them?
I swear to God,
I will kill you!
D? D?
Why?
Heather?
Heather.
I'm sorry.
Aah!
Deidre! Please!
What the fuck?
I'm sorry.
Miss?
Miss, are you okay?
That crazy bitch
was gonna kill you.
We gotta get you
to the hospital.
I feel... amazing.
I'm sorry, D.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull