THE SUMMER OF FLYING FISH
two
Row harder!
Hey fa!
Ephah, come.
Come here.
Hey fa!
I don't see them!
Hang on.
-Rosa, where are the boys?
-I don't know. I do not know anything.
Call me back in an hour.
Wait, are you coming or not?
Will you leave me alone
with the children?
We had decided to do something else!
Would it have been asking a lot for you
to have let me know?
Dad, I was at the hot springs.
So early?
Yes, it was great.
There was no one there.
Esther, tell her.
You have to be careful.
The climate can change.
You might get lost.
When the Huaca Mauhida closes,
I don't want you to go out anymore.
Did you hear me?
Do you believe these stories?
Next time, leave a note.
Fuck!
Did you read the interview
with the engineer of the building that collapsed?
Listen:
"Do you think these
plans of yours were okay?"
"I think so."
"If someone at the construction company had
any questions,
would they have called you?"
"Yes".
"Did they call?"
"Not that I remember"
"Do you want to read the book of the work?"
"No, I think it's boring as hell.
For each building,
you fill out three notebooks."
"But this one is only six pages long."
"So. It was a fantastically
coordinated construction.
There was no problem at all."
Come on!
And it keeps going...
-Come on!
-But why?
-Come on, Francisco!
-Listen to me!
Let's go.
It's great.
Beautiful.
Let's go for a run.
She has wine in her mouth...
You have to spit it out!
But not here!
Wood.
Wood...
Chocolate?
Strawberry.
He's going to have dinner with us.
Wait.
Bring him a glass.
-Hello.
-Lorca!
-All good?
-All!
-Hello.
-How are you?
It should taste good...
All good?
With the taste...
-Wine?
-Yes please.
Esther, a glass, please.
Thanks.
-So, how are you?
-Good! And you?
-Pancho...
-Yes?
Did you read the article
in the Sunday paper?
No. What article?
A new SPA has opened in Santiago.
They use carp to
give you a pedicure.
Really!
You put your feet in a tank
and the carp eat the calluses.
You should do the same thing:
Open a SPA with all your carp.
Why don't you drain the pond,
let the carp die,
then fill the pond again?
Drain the pond. Good idea!
Who gets the cork?
-You or me?
-Oh dad, don't be annoying.
Well, someone has to do it.
Pancho, someone told me that carp
were introduced from somwhere else.
These carp are native to the Ura River,
on the border between China and Russia.
They brought them to eat the seaweed,
but Cucho didn't know
that they reproduced so quickly.
How did they bring them here?
They were brought
in special tanks with water.
-Where did you get that from? Nothing to see!
-And truth!
No, my father invented these stories.
Carp have been here forever.
Before there was a camp.
Pancho doesn't understand anything...
Holy crap! Again!...
What it was?
Hey? Francisco?
No, it's just the dogs.
That is all.
Until.
They say a lamppost
was taken down last night.
Again?
So it was.
Do you know who was messing
around last night?
Do you want a cup of tea?
Aren't they your friends?
Why don't you study more
instead of making a mess?
What mess?
It's better not to get involved.
Otherwise, El Cuero will take you.
Look, we spent two weeks
on a yacht in Belize.
I had never seen such a beautiful sea.
We went to a place called
Ambergris Caye.
We swam among sharks.
They were savages. It was amazing.
-And the women?
-A few.
Few and fat.
I didn't like that.
I would go again though,
because the place was divine.
-Shit!
-Come on!
What is this?
I hope it nothing happened
with the car.
It is not alright.
We were lucky.
You could have broken the windshield.
What is happening?
I don't believe this.
These police officers are very aggressive!
Take another path.
Stop!
-Stop, man!
-Okay, let's go back.
Look how they just grabbed him!
They must have done something, otherwise
they wouldn't be grabbing them like that.
They are very subversive.
There's more there.
Why is this girl
covered in blood in that part?
It wasn't blood, actually.
It's not blood, it's raspberry juice.
The house is made of candy.
The girl is there for the composition.
You, huh?
Me?
Do you like it?
Yes?
Which do you prefer?
This or this one?
I prefer this one.
I like them all.
I like these one-piece ones.
I like bikinis.
Also...
I forgot the word!
Man...
Where were you?
With Lorca.
AND?
What?
What did they do?
Nothing.
Liar! I know you.
-Do you like him?
-Nothing to see!
He might come for
vacation the last week.
Want to go swiming?
They are very ugly.
No! They are beautiful.
Stop, Manena.
Otherwise the few I have will run away.
Doing this will we see
how they manage to escape?
No, many have already fled!
Many have already fled.
Daddy!
Get the boys out of there!
Stay calm,
they are having fun!
Don't worry. Everything is fine.
Go, Pedro.
The wick is very long,
so you have time to leave.
Light it and wait for the wick to burn
a little, before throwing it.
Pedro! Pedro!
-Fuck!
-Holy shit!
Why did you leave
for dad to use the explosive?
What did you want me to do?
How delicious.
You never do anything, mom!
Man...
Thanks...
You know your father
better than me.
What happened to the carp?
I don't know and I don't care.
The carp flew away.
Rodrigo, in Temuco. Good morning.
Good morning.
Police are investigating
the attack on the helicopter
they confirmed that nine
millimeter bullets were used.
According to the investigation,
seven masked men participated.
Shortly before, the helicopter had
left five firefighters on land
to control fires
in forest plantations.
The firefighters fled in panic...
I think Rosa is right.
The carp must be
hidden in the mud.
I don't think I killed them all but...
-They were definitely dead.
-Clown.
I left them dead.
Why don't we ride
a business with triple...
-Triplets.
-Triploids.
-Triple...
-Speak.
-Tri-ploy-de.
-Triploid.
They have triploids and diploids.
Triploids have
three pairs of chromosomes.
And diploids have two.
Ask how I know?
Triploids do not reach the
sexual maturity and do not reproduce.
-Why didn't Cucho say it before?
-Forget my father...
These carp have always been here.
Dad, they want to know if the package arrived
from the Santa Margarita farm.
Yes, of course, I already told them.
He says it has arrived.
Where can we find these triploids?
They need to be genetically modified.
-It is not easy to find them in nature.
-No?
-Father...
-Hey?
It looks like Pedro
broke the eardrum.
-Carlos could examine it.
-The eardrums regenerate on their own.
Esther is drunk!
We drink and she gets drunk!
Cheers to that!
Take her out of the water.
Take her out yourself.
Stay alive!
Prepare her. I'm going to step on it.
No!
Poor thing, she's dying.
-Do I step on her face?
-Yes.
Hey.
I brought the check to the hospital.
You better get checked out.
Just to make sure.
No, I'm better now.
He is well...
I wanted to talk to you.
What?
Come on, I'll talk on the way.
My mother-in-law's mare...
Is your mother-in-law a mare?
No! Leave my mother-in-law alone!
Sir.
Thank you very much. They're very good.
I've already eaten four.
What I do not understand
about this is recovering the land.
They talk about historical debt.
What historical debt?
They never owned anything!
-Your ancestors did.
-No!
They were hunters and gatherers.
Their agriculture was minimal.
They just passed through this forest.
They enjoyed the forest.
They weren't the owners.
Everyone has a Mapuche ancestor!
I'm going to change my last name to
Huallipan or some other with two "L".
His last name is "Ovalle"
There are two "L"s!
I can see your feathers now!
You come from Santiago
to fill my bag!
You articulate very well!
What's with Lorca?
Are you invading her territory?
As long as he doesn't invade everything,
it is all good...
He's a nice guy. Talented.
Have you seen his paintings?
He comes more than you!
Turn!
A little more...
Go, you can do it!
Stop! You are on the edge!
Stop! He is well.
Pedro!
Come here.
Yes?
Come.
Sit down.
Houston, we have a problem.
That
Pedro...
You ate...
that foreigner from last time?
Remember, at that party?
-No, that doesn't count.
-Why?
Pedro is a gentleman!
She just wanted to give it to you!
Here.
She was a little chubby...
but fiery!
She likes the local product.
Hot brunette!
-I didn't understand.
-Did not you like it?
The two of them alone in New York.
Mom won't go?
She hates New York.
-You're going to be pissed.
-That's not your problem.
I could have asked before.
You wanted to see Manhattan!
Yes father. Not now.
You stink of marijuana.
No, that is not it.
Liar.
Is it true that you are putting up
an electric fence?
Since when are you interested
in the farm?
Honestly?
Of course!
How did you know I planned to
install an electric fence?
A guy from the community told me.
We are surrounding the
hazelnut plantations.
With barbed wire.
These bastards destroyed it.
-Why so many fences?
-Because of the cattle and the thieves.
What's wrong?
The farm is mine.
You should be grateful
for the privileges you has.
Woe to you if I find out
you are smoking marijuana!
Ecstasy!
It looks like a pudu.
A pudu?
You are very small!
-What was that song?
-What song?
No, idiot!
It was this...
The other, by Luis Miguel.
Luis Miguel's.
I'll forget you
Word of honor
You don't have it anymore, right?
Good thing we smoked everything!
Cool!
-Weren't you afraid?
-No.
I was!
Your Carlos...
Have you seen Chiquinho?
No.
Scales are growing on him.
-Scales?
-Yes.
-Like fish?
Like fish.
So try not to fish it out!
It was a joke...
It's dermatitis.
Contact dermatitis.
We have to change our washing powder.
-Ester, can you bring me some juice?
-Yes.
Funny woman...
Pedro, come here, please.
Can we do anything?
We have a filtration problem...
Pedro, I have a problem
with the cages.
-See?
-Yes.
-They are sinking.
They are losing tension
and they are sinking all the others.
-Can you fix this, please?
-Yes.
Hey, wait!
It looks like someone
sent me a message.
What?
Didn't you hear?
Are you talking about the fences?
I don't know. You tell me.
The community is not happy.
They say they have the right to go
anywhere to hunt.
You put
fences on the other side.
Tell the little brothers Huentrún
that if they have any problems,
they can come directly to me.
-Anything else?
-No.
No! I forgot one thing!
I need sluts.
Look at his face!
Just kidding!
You have no sense of humor!
What a sucker.
-Piranhas aren't a bad idea.
-Yeah, maybe.
A little radical.
Who has a pig face?
-Me?
-Yes.
I have a pig face.
Exactly.
There.
This embroidery is beautiful!
Leave me alone, Pancho.
I'm fed up. This is bullshit.
-It's not a joke.
-Yes.
-You're kidding me.
-I'm not kidding.
It's your turn.
I'm not kidding.
Daddy!
You are making fun of me
and my activities.
-No, it was a joke.
-Clearly.
You are very serious.
I am tired.
I think I'll win.
I decided that today I will win.
I never noticed the elephant in that
ring. I thought it was a moth.
-Francisco!
-What is it?
He wants to talk to you.
-Good morning, Mr. Francisco.
-Good morning. How are you, Juan?
-More or less the same!
-Why?
Your dog
killed my sheep.
-How do you know it was my dog?
-Because I hit him in the head.
-How much did the sheep cost?
-40,000 pesos.
Dude sheep, huh?
Do you have 10,000, love?
10,000 pesos?
Count it.
It is true.
See you soon, Mr. Francisco.
Pedro, take this animal, please.
Sing that Handel aria
and stop pouring wine over me.
Come on, sing.
Go!
Do you remember?
Sing "Per La Finestra".
Voglio enter for the finesse
Voglio "bebere"
this "little wine"
"Good Good".
Do you remember Monicaco?
The comedian?
"Good Good".
Funny.
What happened to Monicaco?
He was good.
What is this?
Shit! Again...
Congratulations to you
On this beloved date
Congratulations grandfather Cucho
We'll give you a saw
So you can cut.
Alive!
Congratulations, Dad.
May all your desires
become reality.
Cucho!
Hello!
No! Rest assured.
I'll send Nacho to resolve it.
Right? Understood?
He is well. Goodbye.
See, a bicycle.
What happened now?
We have to see.
Where's my shawl?
Give it here.
What happened?
Shit...
Are you going to leave him on the floor?
What, where? Who is it?
It's Juan.
He won't let us take him home.
"Leave me here, boss..."
Let's leave him here.
He's drunk as a skunk.
Let's go.
Hand me the tarp.
What are you going to do?
What happened?
Some boys entered the farm.
Dagobert shot
and released the dogs.
They almost ate one of the boys.
They had to take him to the hospital
in Temuco because he is injured.
They blamed Dagoberto
because he shot him.
He said he only
shot into the air.
But they arrested him anyway.
It's not that serious.
It's easy to resolve this.
What are you going to do?
I've already spoken to Nacho.
He will fix it.
Rosita, go to sleep.
Goodnight.
Good evening, Rose.
Can you make me a drink?
Pancho...
Why don't we buy
a farm further south?
Pirihueico is so beautiful!
I am tired.
I'm going to sleep, good night.
Idiot!
Run!
Patricio, please.
Lock the gate back there.
Who knows what they're going to do.
Thanks.
Dagoberto is on the phone.
Hello? Yes?
No one will fire you.
He's only going to Hualañé for a few days.
He won't say anything until he talks to Nacho.
Hold your tongue, whatever you do.
The problem is yours.
Yes. See you later.
Holy crap!
What will happen?
Nothing. Dagoberto didn't do anything bad.
That boy shouldn't
have tresspassed.
Dagobert shouldn't have fired either.
-Glad you came.
-Hello.
-All good?
-Good.
Where did you get those cool sneakers?
I made them.
It's my designer side.
They are really cool!
Do you like the DJ?
I thought the music would be different.
Lorca likes it, right?
Clearly!
Lorca, are you coming?
A friend of Isi.
What happened?
I sent Dagoberto
to Hualañé.
We need a new guard.
That's why you turned off the TV?
Seriously, Pancho.
We can't stay like this.
I want some tea.
Hi, Rose.
Bring two mint teas,
please.
Thanks.
They're waiting downstairs.
I'm not hungry.
My head hurts.
Your head hurts.
Pedro brought a gift.
How can he think a girl would
hang that shit in her room?
Pedro is a good boy.
Did you say "good boy"?
Why are you masked?
Like his friends?
He only fights for what is ours.
Stirring in the hornets' nest...
Instead of finding something
worthwhile.
Moves so much to stay
in the same corral.
It's what I think.
Do you know the Fiskales?
No.
The Fiskales Ad-Hok?
A Chilean punk band.
No, I do not know.
If you could understand
The color of things
It's not what you see
People don't care
If you don't have anything to eat
No matter how much I look
to the horizon
I never see what they see
No matter how much I look
to the horizon
If you could understand
These idiots broke in
to René's farm again
and burned two trucks.
There have already been 23 fires.
-Can you believe it?
-They are obsessed with the guy.
Do you know who is
behind all this?
The MIR, in front.
All these leftist groups
who now have nothing to do.
They are organizing and
using these idiots.
This has nothing
to do with politics, Nacho.
It's an economic issue.
Help me here.
-Sir. Francisco!
-Hey?
Ortiz!
-Goodnight.
-Goodnight. It's good to see you.
-How are you?
-Sir. Francisco.
-Lieutenant.
-Don Ignacio.
-My hands are dirty.
-Don't worry.
This is Sub-Lieutenant Díaz.
-Good afternoon.
-Sublieutenant.
I wanted to know if you received the subpoena.
Subpoena? No.
I did not receive anything yet.
Subpoena for what?
For the trial,
for what happened.
I didn't receive anything.
When is the trial?
Monday, the 22nd, at 9am.
-Can you go, Nacho?
-I'll be there.
He's my lawyer.
What happened?
I already told you. Dagoberto, the dogs,
the boys the other night...
What happens is that
the incident doesn't help us much.
It was an accident.
Choose a more peaceful guard.
Anyway,
I will take care of the boy's family.
It is the judge who will decide this.
I'm not bothered
by what the judge says.
-It's you who knows.
-I know.
We have to go. Excuse me.
Goodnight.
Be careful with the dogs.
They're tied up.
Only Samson could be free.
Just kick him in the nose.
It's better that way.
-Goodnight.
Pick up the soda along the way.
-What were you thinking, Pancho?
-What it was?
If you get in trouble,
the police will be the only ones
that will help you.
You are right.
You are very arrogant.
He was telling me
how to pick my workers!
No, I had to stop them.
You would have done the same.
Or worse!
-I would have sent them to Patagonia!
-They saw?
Perfect.
It's the right depth
for an ultrasound.
-What is the range?
-Thirty meters.
Nice gift...
-Here he is.
-Leave him there.
-Leave him here?
-AND.
I'm not going to use ultrasound.
It is not enough.
-Hello.
-Hello, Mane.
-Do you want to go and have dinner?
-No, I'm fine with this.
How many eggs does a carp lay?
A million.
I'll use rotenone.
Rotenone is toxic.
Carp are even worse!
You are crazy!
You have some problem!
What's the matter with you, Mane?
I'm fed up.
Dad is obsessed, Mom!
Don't talk to your father like that.
He adores you.
-What about you?
-Not me.
-Does he adore you?
-Who?
Daddy.
Not enough for me to
invite you to New York.
I do not want to go. Go you.
Shit...
Let's Dance. One two three.
Dance!
One, two, three, stop!
What an idea to burn
Dagoberto's house!
They are already here.
Park there.
Come on, some more.
That.
It is good.
DANGER
What happened?
A man died.
Apparently because
of police officers.
The policemen?
Hey, come here.
Mane!
Mane, come here.
Mane, come back!
Mane!
Subrip: Pix
Synchrony by DanDee