THE FORBIDDEN PHOTOS
OF A LADY ABOVE SUSPICION
Today,
I will give up cigarettes.
I will neither drink whiskey,
nor take these pills.
They say it's bad for you
to take both at the same time.
That should make Pier happy.
Do you know what I'm going to do tonight?
I'm going to eat at the fisherman's.
And I will call you from there.
I will tell you that I'm having dinner
with somebody else.
Dominique is right.
I should dress less like a decent lady.
There we go.
Maybe I should loosen this a little.
The way you like it.
When you return tomorrow night,
I won't let you make love right away.
I'll tell you
that I'm in love with someone else,
that we have to get a divorce,
but we could still be friends.
Then, after you make a terrible scene...
I swear that this is
absolutely my last one.
I won't take another.
- What do you want?
- You.
What do you want? What do you want?
Leave me alone!
It's no use, Minou,
you can't escape from me.
No, I'm not going to force you.
You will... you will have to beg me.
You will be begging me to take you.
On your knees!
On the ground!
If you want to know why your husband
has sent you here, I can tell you.
If you try to tell me that my husband
has a lover, I will never believe you!
We are one.
Your husband doesn't cheat on you.
He's a murderer.
No...
No... no...
You can go now.
No, no, I'll wait for you!
Bye, Pier. Take care.
A cognac, please.
Thank you.
Pour me another one.
Another beer, please.
Sit down.
- Minou.
- Pier!
Oh, my darling,
thank God!
He pinned me down,
and sat on me... with a knife.
Then, all of a sudden, he let me go.
If I got you right,
nothing really happened.
He held you down,
threatened you with a knife,
and then he disappeared like a ghost.
Look at what he did to my dress!
I ran into that bar
because I didn't want to be alone.
I wanted to be around people.
He said...
...he said that...
Oh, my God!
What if he had killed me?
But all of a sudden...
...he let me go.
But why didn't you
inform the police right away?
- Let's go there now.
- No, they just make you fill in forms.
Alright, it's up to you, darling.
But we have to go back to town now.
Excuse me. Unfortunately, I have to make
an urgent call to Munich.
I'm waiting downstairs, huh?
- Pier...
- What is it?
- I'm sorry for making you come here.
- Don't be, it's OK.
I had already postponed
all meetings for today.
So we could spend the weekend
together tomorrow.
But instead...
you get jumped by Jack the Ripper.
- You're back on them?
- No, no, it's an old bottle.
Yes, sure, an old bottle...
- Let's go.
- Yes, yes.
- Darling...
- Yes?
If this maniac had done something,
would you still love me?
That problem could have arisen
if you had told me: "Pier, I have a lover."
But why should I love you less because
someone has assaulted and raped you?
I'd still love you anyway.
Even if I would've been raped
by a blonde?
Pier... please don't joke about this.
Today I learned
how important you are for me.
That took you a while...
Hi.
That was Pier on the phone.
He will get here later.
- What?
- I talked to Pier.
He said, he'll be here later!
- I knew it. Always the same old story.
- Don't get upset.
- What?
- Don't get upset!
- Wanna dance?
- Sure.
Oh, look who's there!
- Who is she?
- Minou, she's a friend. I'll introduce you.
Wait for me at the table.
You come with me.
Who is the most beautiful girl
in the world?
- You!
- No, you!
Giorgio, Pier's right-hand man.
Dominique.
- Nice to meet you.
- Pleasure.
- Alessandro. Minou and Giorgio.
- Dance!
- Dance with her.
With pleasure.
Come on, Dominique, throw.
100!
- 200!
- I'll call.
Oh! Four kings!
Now don't make a toss
like the poor Dubois.
Dubois? Jean Dubois?
What did he do?
Don't you know?
They found him dead four days ago
while you were at the seaside.
Your husband doesn't cheat on you.
He's a murderer.
Wake up, Minou!
- Murdered?
- It wouldn't surprise me.
Everyone was wishing him the worst.
But no, Dubois died
from a cerebral embolism.
Why don't we talk
about something more cheerful?
- You're totally right.
- Hi.
- Wanna dance?
- Sure.
FINANCIER DUBOIS
FOUND DEAD IN HIS BED
"Similar diagnosis usually follows
"after severe accidents caused
by prolonged deep immersion
"followed by rapid surfacing
"without allowing sufficient time
for decompression.
"A phenomenon that perplexes
medical doctors. "
Prolonged deep immersion,
followed by rapid surfacing...
A phenomenon that perplexes
medical doctors...
Hey...
Prolonged deep immersion,
followed by rapid surfacing...
A phenomenon that perplexes
medical doctors...
Have you read what they say?
I hate to be cynical,
but he died at exactly the right moment.
He gave me a big loan.
But you have to pay it anyway, right?
There might be heirs.
Yes, yes, naturally.
They'll jump all over me.
Let's hope they'll contact us
as late as possible.
- Pier...
- What?
If something happened to you,
please, tell me.
No. At least nothing you need
to bother your little head about.
By the way, I won't be home
for lunch today.
I have a business breakfast.
But we have so little time together.
Give me some more time, please.
You'll see that everything will change.
I promise.
Alright.
- I'll go to Dominique.
- Do you want to make me jealous?
Because she has no qualms about
going to bed with someone?
But darling,
Dominique likes everyone.
And you should know that
all too well.
Weren't you with her
before my beauty hit you like lightning?
That's certainly true.
- Things to do today...
- Yes, sir!
At 5 o'clock, after visiting Dominique's,
come to my office
to meet Commissioner Poretti.
- No, Minou, you'll make me late.
- Yes, sir, be late.
Yes, yes, alright.
If that nag calls again, tell her that
the furnishing will be ready by the 15th.
Remind them to give you the check.
Who?
The photographer?
No, tell him I will call him back.
Ah, listen, I won't come in today.
No. Bye.
Come on, relax.
Is it still bothering you?
I can't see the problem.
Some guy suddenly jumps on you
in an isolated place...
It's basically a compliment
on your sex appeal.
Then you either like him and stay with him,
or you don't and dump him.
I wish something like this
would happen to me.
But what did he say to you?
He told me he knew something
that could harm Pier.
Don't tell me you're that gullible.
What should he know about Pier
that everybody else wouldn't know?
And have you seen him again?
So why are you worried about it?
You better not tell Pier about it.
In the end, he might accuse you
of having seduced him.
Yes, you're right. I'm way too gullible.
Let's go to my place.
I have some new stuff I'd like to show you.
- For you.
- Thank you.
What do you think?
Beautiful. Who took them?
A photographer, a new one.
I don't know him that well.
I assure you, he's not too shabby
for a weekend.
He performs well...
- But what if he sold them?
- That would be great! What publicity!
There would be a line at my door.
- Have a whiskey.
- Gladly.
- Won't you have one, too?
- No, thanks.
If it doesn't shock you,
I have something even more interesting.
Take a look.
- Pornographic photos?
- Have you ever seen any?
There's some good stuff
even in that genre.
Look.
Look at this one.
And don't tell me you don't like them.
I thought this wasn't your thing.
I like it all.
As long as it gives me pleasure.
- May I ask you something?
- Sure.
You and Pier...
Well, you know...
When you introduced me to him,
you two were very friendly...
...but how friendly?
- You want me to go into detail?
- I'm sorry.
It's in the past.
Besides, he was never my type.
It was my fault, naturally.
I like a change from time to time.
What have you found?
It's a pretty stupid one.
- How did you get this one?
- How did I get this one?
I went to Copenhagen.
They sell them in supermarkets there.
- Can I borrow it?
- Sure. Take it, it's a gift.
As I was saying, signora,
these things happen quite often.
Sex maniacs.
It was very wise to play along.
Otherwise, it might have been dangerous.
Don't you worry, however.
In general, they don't come back.
In any case,
here are my telephone numbers.
- I hope it won't happen again.
- Always at your service.
- Thank you.
- Excuse me, but I have to run.
- Bye, Pier.
- Goodbye.
- And good luck for your business.
- Thank you.
- I hope it all goes really smooth.
- I hope so, too.
- Goodbye, signora.
- Goodbye.
This way.
Please, Commissioner.
Goodbye.
- Bye, Pier.
- Bye.
Signorina, where's Giorgio?
Good, send him in right away.
- Why are you so nervous?
- I'm sorry, darling.
Is there something wrong?
I'm your wife, I have a right to know.
I already told you, Minou,
things aren't going so well at the moment.
But I hope to recoup everything
with the next season.
- They're putting pressure on me.
- Who?
The creditors, the bank,
the financers...
People like Dubois?
I want you to explain something.
Why does this damned Dubois
pop up every time we talk?
Because he's dead.
So let the dead rest,
and think about us for a change, OK?
Look at this.
These plans could revolutionize
underwater breathing,
but I can't get the financing.
Excuse me, Pier.
- Hi Minou.
- Hello.
That gentleman
from financing is here.
He doesn't want to accept the extension
without talking to you personally.
- Tomorrow.
- OK.
Excuse me, darling.
I'll see you tonight.
We'll go out for dinner, just the two of us.
Alright.
- Bye.
- Giorgio, would you show her around?
- Sure.
Give me signorina Dominique.
Yes, I understand, Giorgio,
but...
I feel Pier's so nervous,
troubled...
You know, Minou,
this is a very difficult period for us.
I know.
Pier told me that already.
That if that poor Dubois hadn't died
so unexpectedly... bye bye company.
I shouldn't say this,
but his death was a true salvation.
Dubois was a real loan shark.
- Excuse me, would you sign this?
- One moment. Yes?
What's that in there?
The new compression chamber.
Go in.
They're testing the new mixtures.
I'll join you.
- And here.
- Yes.
- Good afternoon, signora.
- Hello.
- Where you at?
- 15.
Very good.
Inside there's 15 atmospheres of pressure.
Look.
It's as if this man
is at a depth of 150 m.
Your husband
doesn't cheat on you.
He's a murderer.
Before he can get out of there again...
...and back to normal pressure
without risking his life...
...he needs to make long stops
at various intermediate pressures.
- It's very time-consuming.
- And if he doesn't?
Then he would die from an embolism
after a few minutes.
I love you, Minou.
I love you too, Pier.
Why don't you confide in me?
You're so distant, preoccupied.
Believe me,
if anything happened to you...
Pier...
I'll always be with you.
- Listen...
- Yes?
I want to ask you something.
When you were at the beach...
Who could it be?
It's almost 2:00am.
- Well, I'll go see.
- Thank you.
- Hello?
- Minou, remember me?
Now you know
who your husband murdered.
You do know, don't you?
Or do you still have doubts?
If you don't leave me alone
I'll go to the police!
I wouldn't advise that.
Otherwise, I'd give the police
a listen to this recording.
We should take him
out of the compression chamber now.
He's turning blue.
Are you sure nobody will suspect anything?
Sure, it will look like an embolism.
He was old, it happens.
You'll see, it will pass
as a natural death.
Did you hear
your husband's voice?
Tomorrow you'll go to
the address I told you. Alone.
If not, I will report him.
You will enjoy it.
Bye, Dominique.
See you tomorrow, huh? Bye.
Dominique?
What did she want at this hour?
You know Dominique...
She was supposed to call at 11:00pm
but she only remembered it now.
It's hopeless, she will never change.
- I'm not tired anymore. How about a drink?
- Alright.
Tomorrow you'll go to
the address I told you. Alone.
If not, I will report him.
How much?
How much I want.
How much you're willing to give me.
We should take him
out of the compression chamber now.
This belonged to poor Dubois.
He used it to record
his business conversations.
Sure, it will look like an embolism.
He sure didn't think he would ever record
the voice of his own murderer.
Give me that recording.
I have 1,000 dollars for you.
How did you get it?
I was at the right place
at the right time.
Sit down.
Sit down!
You don't have any power over me.
You just have a few colored papers.
You didn't understand
anything, Minou.
I'm the master of your soul,
of your body.
You're insane.
I want what I like, and I will take it.
Life is for pleasure.
Your husband is not insane, but he killed
a man just because he owed him money.
You're not insane, but you came here
to protect a murderer.
You who are not insane
can only do abominable things.
And you do it to suffer.
I, however,
do it for pleasure.
Let me go!
And open that door now!
Alright, go if you want.
But your husband
will go to prison for life.
You'll see, it'll be much more pleasant
than you think.
Alright, I'm here.
Do whatever you want.
Come on, do it!
But afterwards, I want that recording!
So what?
Didn't you hear me?
I said, I'm ready!
No...
Not like that, Minou.
You have to beg me,
to plead for my touch,
to long to be mine, without shame.
Like a slave,
like a whore.
Take off your coat.
Take off your coat!
On your knees!
Get down.
Undress.
Giovanni, is my wife back?
No, no, it's not important.
Don't tell her I called.
Pier, what's wrong?
- I've never seen you like this.
- I'm tired, Giorgio.
So far I've held up, but I don't know
how long I can go on like this.
Come on,
we've survived worse times.
Skip it.
What were you looking at?
The Dubois file.
This morning, a letter arrived
from the lawyer of the estate.
They're just as tough
as the dead man.
That gives us until the end
of the month to pay.
We could ask to pay by installments.
They are the Dubois.
- Tell them we'll pay.
- As you wish.
Yes?
Ah, yes, I'll be right there.
- Giorgio, wait here.
- Yes.
It's yours, you earned it.
Today you've learned things
your husband could never teach you.
- Hello darling.
- Hello.
- What did you do today?
- I drove around with Dominique.
Hi Minou.
Hi Dominique.
See that I was right,
Pier?
I told you she would make up a story.
How are you, dear?
Minou and I have prepared you
a little surprise.
We had bad timing today but I don't think
we should tell him beforehand, right?
No, no.
And a bit of jealousy
is always a good thing.
- Signore?
- Excuse me. Yes?
- They sent this over from your office.
- Ah, good.
- Get me the telephone.
- Yes, signore.
- Thank you, Dominique.
- No problem.
But what did you do anyhow?
You look like you came
from the slaughterhouse.
- You know, what happened to me today...
- Tell me later.
Go dress yourself for dinner,
I'll take care of Pier.
Thanks.
Alright, go if you want,
but your husband will go to prison for life.
You have to beg me,
to plead for my touch...
... to long to be mine,
without shame...
... without shame...
...like a slave...
...like a whore.
Undress.
And now... we'll uncork
this bottle of champagne.
As if it was your birthday, OK?
You're so funny!
No! No!
- No! No! No!
- Minou! Minou!
What's wrong, Minou?
What is it?
What happened, Minou?
What happened?
Nothing, Pier.
Nothing, nothing, nothing...
Don't leave me, Pier!
Don't you ever leave me. Please!
Don't leave me!
Madam is still resting.
I don't think I'm allowed to disturb her.
Give her this envelope.
We'll see if she gets up.
- No, I'll close it.
- Very well, signore.
I have all the negatives,
of course.
- It's my profession.
- Get out of this house!
You're my slave,
and you do as I say!
Unless you want me to send
these delightful photos to your husband.
Did you see the nice one
in which we're kissing?
You insane scumbag!
You're so filthy! A coward!
When my husband finds out
what you've done, he'll kill you!
It's hard for a husband
to be proud of his wife,
if she thinks he's a murderer and
consoles herself by going to bed with me.
How could you have possibly believed that
your husband could kill a man for money?
It was just a trick.
His voice imitated for the recorder.
I've never met Dubois.
- I made it all up.
- That's impossible!
This can't be true.
It's not true.
But why does it upset you
so much, my dear?
I'm telling you the truth.
You thought he was guilty, but he's not.
But you react this way?
Why did you do all this?
To have you.
Hello?
- Of course, dear, I'll wait for you.
- Who is it?
But no, come over now.
Bye.
It's Minou. She'd better not find you here.
Get dressed.
Exit by the service door.
I'll be waiting for you tonight.
- Bye.
- Dominique...
- What's wrong? What happened?
So that guy invented everything
just to get you in bed.
We have to admit that he earned it...
- Dominique, please...
- Sorry, dear.
You're burning up.
I can still feel his hands on my skin,
his wet mouth...
I washed myself a hundred times,
but I still feel dirty.
But you did it to save Pier
thinking he was guilty.
I don't know,
I don't know anymore, Dominique.
I believed that man,
you know?
I believed him right away
and went to bed with him.
- Please get me something to drink.
- Of course, my dear.
You probably think you subconsciously
wanted him? But no, Minou.
You had a more erotic adventure
than usual, and you enjoyed it.
I didn't enjoy it!
I did not enjoy it!
Come on, drink.
Listen, Minou,
there are two kinds of people,
those who need protection,
and those who give it.
I'm glad you came to me,
very much so.
I've always counted on Pier,
completely.
He's everything to me.
Husband, lover, father.
And all of a sudden,
everything changed.
I don't know what to do anymore.
We either convince that guy to drop it,
or we'll have to tell Pier.
No! I don't want Pier to know anything.
I already tried to offer him money.
He threw it in my face.
He's only interested
in his madness.
- How much did you offer him?
- 1,000 dollars.
- Is that all you have?
- I don't know.
If I sell all my jewels...
maybe 10,000 dollars.
OK,
I'll add another 10.
He's thrown 1,000 dollars in your face.
Let's see if he does the same with 20,000.
Everything has a price,
even madness.
Take it.
No... I just can't accept it.
Pier's business isn't going well.
I don't know
when I'll be able to pay you back.
I'm not making an investment.
Go ahead, take it.
Why are you doing this,
Dominique?
Did I ask you for anything?
Don't cause yourself any more problems.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dominique.
Come out.
Idiot!
You enjoyed it so much
that you came back, huh?
20,000 dollars.
Give me the negatives.
It's a nice sum, isn't it?
And I hope you will
leave me alone forever.
"Forever"... what a serious word.
Give me the negatives!
You offer me 20,000 dollars
for my defeat...
...because then
you can spit in my face.
Minou, if I had offered you 20,000 dollars
for your body, would you have come here?
- You're a dirty bastard!
- Would you have come here?
To kiss, to caress, to do everything?
Don't touch me! I hate you!
Would you come here
for 20,000 dollars?
No, certainly not.
So, how could you hope
to buy yourself free for 20,000 dollars?
You already got
what you wanted.
If you touch me one more time,
I will kill you first and denounce you later!
When you were lying under my body
you enjoyed it more
than ever before in your life.
Minou... you liked it so much
that you're now starting to pay me.
You're a son of a bitch!
Take your money and leave.
I'll give you three days
to think about it.
If you haven't come back by then,
your husband
will receive these photographs.
He will finally see
what you're able to do.
Three days!
Remember it, Minou!
- Three days!
- You pig!
Here, drink that.
And don't you get these ideas anymore.
If Pier loves you, he'll understand.
How could I have believed
that he killed Dubois?
Just like I believed that the blackmailer
would take the 20,000 dollars.
Of course he could have accepted it
and continued the extortion anyway.
I don't understand why he didn't.
It's puzzling.
This man is insane.
He doesn't think like others do!
Nobody can tell
what he's up to next.
He's not stupid
when he wants to lay a trap.
- Anyway, you need to tell Pier everything.
- How could I?
You're beautiful, Minou,
he'll love you despite all that.
Stay with me when I tell him.
I'm scared.
Alright.
It's better to tell him right away.
Tonight.
Call him at the office.
Stay calm, Pier, and listen to me.
Minou is right.
The death of Dubois, the recorder...
You know she's very impressionable.
However, she did everything she could
to get rid of that maniac.
After all, this situation of yours
could have actually happened.
No, it couldn't have!
The woman I love can't possibly think
that I'm capable of killing a man
just because I owed him some money!
I believed it up to the point,
when she slept with another guy
in order to destroy the proof!
Of course he's lying!
- Where are you going?
- I'm leaving, Pier. You're right.
I love you, and I also loved you
when I thought you had killed a man.
- But I have ruined everything.
- Stop!
Don't go away.
Sit down.
From now on we'll do it my way.
Commissioner Poretti, please.
It was here.
This is illegal, but you will testify
that we found it open.
- Are you sure it was here?
- But yes! Of course it was here!
This place looks like
it was abandoned a century ago.
Take her home.
I'll make some inquiries.
See you tomorrow, signora.
- Pier... you don't believe me, do you?
- Yes, yes, I believe you...
Pier, look!
Right here, there was a huge bed!
And here, there was a devil,
a completely red one!
All red!
And here, there were
lots of small white hands,
all attached to this.
But... you could be mistaken.
It's all empty.
No!
Why don't you believe me, Pier?
I told you that there was a huge bed here,
and a red devil over there!
And here were these small white hands!
I swear it!
Yes, but sometimes
people have bad dreams.
Why don't you believe me?
Why won't you believe what I told you?
- OK, I believe you.
- But...
But now we're going home, huh?
Are you still needing those pills?
They are the only things
that keep me relaxed.
And they destroy your nerves.
It's also my fault.
I upset you with my business worries.
Pier, I wish it was all just a nightmare,
that I was crazy.
- You think that I am?
- Oh no, you're just a little tired.
You need some rest, that's all.
Maybe it was the wrong apartment,
or you got the wrong address.
It was there, I assure you!
I don't know why it looked so different,
but it was there.
Yes, alright.
Now let's go to sleep.
- Pier...
- Yes?
Do you still love me?
But of course.
This hasn't changed anything.
Thank you.
It's the only thing that really matters.
- Pier! Pier! There's someone here!
- What?
- Someone's in the house!
- Someone's in the house?
It doesn't work.
They cut the lights!
It was probably just a blackout.
But I heard some noises
and then the lights went out.
Alright, I'll have a look.
Come one, we'll make a tour
of the entire house.
- The noises came from the studio.
- So let's go into the studio.
- I'm scared, Pier.
- Give me your hand.
Look! Look, Pier!
Wait here.
- Don't I deserve a cognac after that fright?
- Of course, I'll get you one.
- Pier! Pier! Pier! Pier!
- What's wrong, Minou?
- Look! He's here!
- But where, who?
- Now he's gone!
- He's gone?
- That man! He laughed!
- What are you saying?
- That man!
- But who?
- He was there, I swear it!
- Now stop it, Minou!
- Pier, I swear it!
- Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it, you're scaring me!
Relax now.
- Excuse me.
- Alright.
Breathe in.
Deeply.
- Hi Franco.
- Hello Pier. How is your wife?
The doctor is with her.
Have you found anything?
Yes.
That apartment has been empty
for more than a year now.
I thought so.
No, thanks.
I'm terribly worried, Franco.
Last night she even saw that
mysterious stalker at the window.
- Excuse me.
- Ah yes, doctor, come in.
Franco, this is Dr. Thomas.
Commissioner Poretti.
- Nice to meet you.
- My pleasure.
I've given her some drops
to calm her down.
She suffers from a serious form
of exhaustion.
I will have to hospitalize her
to examine her thoroughly
but, for now it's important
that she stops taking these pills.
Yes, I know, doctor.
I tried everything I could,
but without luck.
She needs a change of air.
A trip would do her good.
She would have to go alone,
or with a friend. I don't have time.
No way! Your wife needs you,
she needs to be near you.
Even if she has consciously
or unconsciously
invented this persecution story,
she did it because of you.
To attract your attention.
Perhaps you neglected her lately.
Yes, yes, that's true, but...
I have my business, my company.
At this moment...
Please stay with her.
In these cases, affection and love
have more power than any medicine.
I don't know...
I don't know anymore, Dominique.
I'm beginning to believe
that I'm going mad,
that I've invented everything.
Come on, don't let yourself go,
or you will wreck yourself.
Listen, I'll come over
after I've finished work.
Yes, please.
- You need to talk to a friend.
- Yes.
- I'll be waiting for you.
- OK. Bye.
Bye.
Thank you, doctor.
I'll keep you informed.
Please, it's very important.
- Goodbye.
- See you. It was a pleasure.
Well, Pier,
there's nothing more I can do.
Hello?
It was a bad mistake
to get the police involved, very bad.
I told you, three days.
- Three days!
- Pier! Pier! Pier!
- Pier! Come quickly!
- Yes, just yell, Minou.
- I will kill you.
- Minou!
It's him! On the phone!
The time is 11:38am.
The time is 11:39am.
Why won't you believe me?
I swear it!
It was him who called!
He said he wanted to kill me!
Pier, I didn't call the time service!
Believe me, at least you!
I just don't understand it.
That man who's pursuing you, signora,
what type is he?
- What does he look like?
- What he looks like?
This is what he looks like!
I have a photo of him.
Here.
But it was right here!
I'm sure it was!
I swear it, Pier, it was right here!
He took it!
Why is it gone? It was here!
I put it there!
It was here!
Minou...
Dominique... call Dominique!
Call her! Call Dominique!
Yes, yes, you could say
"pornographic", Commissioner.
Everyone can look at what they want
in their own home, right?
- I think that's normal.
- Yes, yes, sure, but tell him!
You remember it. At your place,
when you gave me that picture.
Honestly, I don't remember.
- Are you quite sure, Minou?
- Dominique... but why?
Didn't you like
my little dirty collection?
I would remember if
she had asked me for a picture.
Commissioner,
would you give me a light?
Thanks.
- He's a murderer.
- A photographer.
- It's a gift.
- Undress.
- Dominique!
- It's my profession.
- Take it.
- You pig!
You're welcome.
- Listen... we have to talk.
- Come with me.
These photos will never arrive, Minou.
They don't exist.
But they are my only hope, Pier.
They're the proof that I didn't dream it,
that I'm not crazy!
It was only a nightmare,
a bad dream.
You've never been with another man.
Isn't it better to think that way?
Alright, Pier, I will prove it.
Meanwhile, I will take your other rook.
- Let's let it ring without answering it.
- No, it might be something important.
Yes?
No, Giorgio, you have to try
and arrange it alone.
- Pier, they're waiting for you.
- Who's waiting for who?
But Pier, you set up this
"appointment of salvation".
At the Derby Hotel, don't you remember?
We'll have dinner with these two financiers
who came by plane from Munich.
- What is it?
- Wait a minute.
An appointment with the guys from Munich.
I'm supposed to have dinner
with them tonight.
It's OK, Pier.
Go if you have to, I'll wait for you.
- You really don't mind?
- No.
- Alright, Giorgio, see you there.
- OK, bye.
- Hi
- Hi.
They're not here, yet.
I told them we'd meet them at the bar.
- Got the plans with you?
- You have the plans, Pier.
- I have?
- Yes, don't you remember?
I gave them to you yesterday.
- Yesterday? Are you sure?
- Yes.
Damn, you're right.
I left them at home.
Try to entertain them.
I'll be right back.
Alright.
- Please, be quick.
- Yes, yes.
- Excuse me, please.
- We've been waiting for 30 minutes!
Yes, yes, he'll be right back.
You see? Now it works.
Want to call your husband?
Pier!
Pier... you see?
I'm not crazy, he does exist!
Stay right there.
Of course he exists, I invented him.
I directed his every move,
every one of his words,
to drive you insane,
and to make you commit suicide.
Unfortunately, this idiot continued
to play the sex maniac
and wasn't capable of killing you.
That's not possible!
It can't be true!
They will find a woman killed by a beast
and a beast killed by a loving husband.
Pier! Freeze!
One moment later,
and that maniac would have killed her.
Drop that weapon!
But Franco, I told you,
I came here when...
I said, "drop that weapon!"
You got it all wrong, Franco,
I told you that...
Madman...
Your call seemed incredible,
signora.
- Dominique!
- Minou!
Minou...
- Dominique!
- Oh, my poor dear.
Call the others to check the scene
and an ambulance.
- Minou! Minou!
- Signora...
- You remain at our disposal.
- Alright, Commissioner.
- Try to stay calm.
- Will you come with me?
- As soon as I'm finished.
- Bye.
Bye.
- Is it serious, doctor?
- No, relax.
She lost a lot of blood, but one transfusion
will be enough. Good night.
Take one from that side.
You know him?
Yes.
Take another one.
- Care for a whiskey?
- Double, if you please.
I really need one.
- But how did you know what was happening?
- I didn't know.
In the beginning I didn't pay much attention
to Minou's strange change of behavior
and to her mysterious blackmailer.
Please leave! Out!
- Go, go!
- Please continue.
I began to get suspicious
when Giorgio mentioned to me
that Pier had bulked up
Minou's life insurance
with an enormous sum.
I knew Pier well, and for money
he would have even killed his own mother.
Then, yesterday evening, after the story
with that photo, all doubts vanished.
- The story with that photo?
- That photo really existed.
It was Pier's only mistake
not to remember that he gave it to me
during one of our trips to Copenhagen.
There we met that man,
who apart from his photos
also sold his personal services.
- His what?
- Personal services.
And, to be quite honest,
not too shabby, Commissioner.
Commissioner,
a phone call for you.
Ah, thanks. Hello?
- Excuse me, do you have a cigarette?
- Sure.
No, impossible right now.
I told you it's not possible!
- Got a light?
- Yes, signora.
- I'll be at the station later on.
- Thank you.
Bye, bye. Here.
- Please, go on.
- Ah, yes.
Only Minou, Pier and myself
knew of that photo.
And he was the only one
who could have wanted it to disappear.
After that, I just waited for
the right moment to call you.
A rather dangerous game.
If I hadn't done it like that,
nobody would have ever believed me.
Is that professional jealousy,
Commissioner?
Nevertheless, I don't know
how to thank you. You must be tired.
I'll have someone escort you.
Sergeant!
One last thing, Commissioner,
I'm sure you wouldn't mind.
Instead of having me escorted
by the sergeant,
could I be escorted by him?
- If you wish.
- Yes.
Hey, you!
- Accompany the lady.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Out, out!
Out with the photographers!
- How are you feeling now?
- I've never felt better!
- I'll wait in the car.
- Alright.
The only thing I advise you
is to stay off those pills.
Yes, don't worry.
No pills, no whiskey.
Very good.
- Goodbye.
Don't worry about the company.
With the money from Pier's
two life insurances, everything will be fine.
Please, let's talk about it later.
I just want to rest now.
You're right, I'm sorry.
- Please.
- Bye.
Bye, Minou.
Bye, Dominique!
What shall we do now?
Listen, I have an idea.
Why don't we go to my place?
Some stuff from Copenhagen arrived
that I'd love to show you.
THE END