[music playing]
[bombs exploding]
[gunfire]
[sirens]
Here you are mum.
Keep your chin up, mate.
Time bombing there, chums.
Get cracking.
Blimey.
And I came here for
piece and quiet.
What's up?
Delayed action.
All a dud.
Corner of the hospital--
a 2,000 pounder.
All right, clear this area.
Every house within two blocks.
-Right.
You've reported it?
Yes, sir.
Bomb disposal--
crew's on its way now.
Many more patients
to get out, doctor?
Yeah, quite a few.
Around the back, Sir.
Like to have a look at it?
Mind looking at it most
stopping going off.
Get them all cleared out.
Good luck!
Yeah, we shall need it.
Everything ready, Sergeant?
Yes, Sir.
This way, Sir.
Went through a stone wall as if
it were a ruddy paper bag, Sir.
How long has it been down?
About 10 minutes, Sir.
SERGEANT: There it is, Sir.
For Lord's sake, be careful.
You're from the-- why,
Captain Stevenson, isn't it?
There you are.
All ready and waiting for you.
Drifted?
It didn't get a chance
to straighten out.
It must have been low.
CAPTAIN STEVENSON: We can't
take a chance moving it.
I'll deal with it here.
SOLDIER: Yes, Sir.
I want to go home.
Oh, Danny, you must be quiet.
You must lie quite still.
Hello.
Can't you get that child away?
I can't shift him.
He mustn't be moved.
He's got to be kept quite still.
Who's that down there?
Is it going to go off?
I want to go home!
That thing's not
going to hurt you.
You'll hurt yourself if
you don't keep still.
Remember what the doctor said.
I want to go home!
-Now, again--
-Danny?
Yes, Mister?
Did you ever have
your tonsil's out?
No, but I got a
sister what did.
Well, that's what I'm
doing to this fellow--
taking out his tonsils and
giving him a sore throat,
so he can't talk.
Why didn't you
take him away first?
Well, he came to
the hospital the same
as you and your sister.
So we've got to do it here.
That's only fair.
DANNY: But, Mister--
Now, Danny-- Danny, you
can help by keeping quiet.
I've got to listen
to his insides.
The quieter you keep,
the more I can listen.
Is there going to
be any more noise?
Shh-sh.
[church bells ringing]
Sergeant, all set.
All set, Sir.
2,000 pound, a new type.
Now removing fuse cap.
Fuse cap removed.
New type detonator head.
Time combination, delayed
action. tumbler not tripped.
Repeat.
Time combination, delayed
action, tumbler not tripped.
Right.
New type mounting.
Security pin.
Now removing security pin.
Mister?
Who are you talking to?
Friends of mine, Danny,
telling them what I'm doing.
Then if I do anything silly,
they can tell the next man
where I went wrong.
Why can't you
tell him yourself?
Quiet again, Danny.
Still as a mouse.
Removing pin.
Pin removed.
Detonator hasn't come away.
This is the ticklish bit.
Removing detonator.
Detonator removed.
OK, Sergeant.
All over?
All over.
Operation successful.
The patient died.
Well, Sergeant.
Good work, Sir.
Careful, new type.
Here's the Captain, now.
From the War Office, Sir.
Very urgent.
You know my coat?
Yes, Sir.
Sorry, Sergeant,
you'll have to carry on.
The brass heads want me
for some reason or other.
Good luck.
Thank you, Sir.
[knocking]
Captain Stevenson, Sir.
Now, I'm Perry.
This is General Weymouth.
How do you do?
How do you do, Sir?
Have a cigarette.
Thank you.
Well, Stevenson
before we begin,
just let's know if
we've got this right.
Your father was Colonel
Lawrence Stevenson.
That's right, killed
in 1916, in the war.
Yes, before that,
as a civilian,
he was consulting chemist
to the oil refineries
in [inaudible], in Romania.
You grew up there.
You were born there.
Yes, and I came to England
in school when I was 15.
After you left
school, you spent
two years in Germany--
The Berlin University--
chemical engineering?
Yes.
Well, now, don't you think
it's about time that we,
ah, you told Captain
Stevenson why we
asked him to come and see us?
Yes.
Well, Stevenson, the
fact is, the Nazis
are making poison gas on a
huge scale in a new factory.
In Czechoslovakia,
somewhere near Pilsen.
We've reason to believe they're
using a new formula-- fog gas.
Now we want to know exactly
what they're making,
and stop them making it.
In other words, we want someone
to get hold of the formula,
then blow the whole place
to blazes before they get
a chance to
distribute the stuff--
which might be at any moment.
PERRY: You speak
German fluently,
and Romanian like a native.
Yes.
You're a chemical expect, and
as things are at the moment,
you could get in
through Romania.
I'm afraid all I
know about spying
has been picked up from one or
two rather second class novels.
This is a sabotage job.
And a pretty long shot,
whatever way you look at it.
No one would blame you, if
you don't think got up to it.
When would you want
me to start, Sir?
Tonight.
Hello, Mother.
Where would you be off
to at such short notice?
Now, you know better than that.
Surely, you don't want me
to be a complete outsider
and give the lady away,
I'm not interested
in the lady, even
supposing she is from here.
Really?
I'm surprised at you.
There's been a special
messenger from the War Office
after you.
Hadn't you better find
out all about that first?
I have.
They want to make
it into a brigadier.
That's why I'm clearing out.
I can't stand the
responsibility.
You're not packing to go away
to someone-- or for very long.
A few days?
Oh, a bit longer then that.
A few weeks, perhaps.
Terry?
Don't you think I
deserve a holiday?
Is it far?
Fold that for me,
Darling, will you?
Will you be able to write?
You don't want me to
ask any questions?
That's about it.
Thank you.
Well, Duchess.
Your father used
to call me that.
Yes, I remember.
He did it the last time--
Shh.
Now, now.
[dog growling]
Hello, hello.
Percy thinks we're having a row.
I'm coming down to
store to see you go.
You always [inaudible].
No.
I'll check in.
Stay here.
Stay here and sit down.
Will you tidy up for me?
Look at the mess I have made.
You always leave your
mother to tidy up, don't you?
Yes and she always does-- a
very bad thing for both of us.
Well, take care of yourself.
Now I'll turn up again before
you know where you are.
Be a good girl.
[door closes]
[air plane engine revving]
I'd better get ready!
Please, Mister, if you please.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's no good.
I've told you before,
we've no vacancies.
But please, Mister, we
think it is necessary
that I speak with you.
Now look here, old man,
if there was anything
I could do for you, I would.
But there's nothing doing.
We're full up.
Now leave me alone.
But please,Mister, work please.
Oh, confound it, man!
Clear out!
Oh-- I wondered lonely as a
cloud, that floats on high,
o'er vales and hills.
When all at once,
I saw a crowd.
A host of golden daffodils.
Number 38-- [inaudible].
8:00 tonight.
[WITH FOREIGN ACCENT]
Believe me, madam, with me,
you have nothing to fear.
I am discretion itself.
Our love will be like
a secret symphony.
I am not as others, begging
for garters, locks of hair--
no, no.
Just give me some simple
little thing with nothing
personal about it all.
you know, gold cigarette
case, cuff links,
belt studs, Rolls
Royce, you know--
just some simple little thing.
[NO ACCENT]How's that?
How am I doing?
Grand, Romanian
iron guard as a life.
An officer, but not a gentlemen.
How well I knew them.
If you stay here in Romania,
you'd make a very good living.
Thank you very much.
Here's some more
about yourself.
Hmm?
Jan Tartu.
Hmm.
Enterprising chap, aren't I?
By the way, what happened
to the real Tartu?
He met with a fatal accident.
Oh, you fellows have been busy.
Here are young Tartu's papers.
His membership card of
the Romanian Iron Guard.
Until you cross the
border into Hungary,
this passport describes
you as a Greek merchant,
Petalis, a mythical character.
Am I all right as
a Greek merchant?
Well, you will be when
you get your overcoat on.
But don't worry,
you're all right.
Until you cross into Hungary,
everything's fixed for you.
But once you cross the
border into Hungary,
you must destroy
that Greek passport
and present yourself to
the German consul at Teget.
Teget.
Under the name,
Muller, Dr. Muller.
Dr. Muller.
Now you must get your visa
for Czechoslovakia from him.
We'll be standing by
tomorrow night, as arranged.
And then from Teget
onwards, well,
we can't be much use to you.
I must struggle
along on my own, eh?
Yes.
It's not going to be easy.
One last memory test--
I don't want to take
any unnecessary chances.
The whole thing
is one big chance.
Now when you finally get to
Pilsen, the man you contact is?
Peter Valek, the shoemaker.
His address?
38 Reichstrata.
Good.
Now remember, he's
our only remaining
contact to the
Czech underground,
so you realize his importance?
Quite.
[train tracks clacking]
[knocking]
Who is that?
Heil, Hitler!
What is it?
Friend of the
Reich, Dr. Muller?
Yes, yes, yes.
Please, please,
please let me in.
They're on my heels.
Please!
Why do you wait?
All right, all
right, all right.
-Friend of the Reich, eh?
-Yes.
I need proof of that.
Proof.
Please.
Romanian, huh?
I ran the border.
The Hungarian
patrol and sweep are
no better than my own
people if they've caught me.
No.
They tried.
I left one with a broken jaw.
Come with me.
What if they should
see me come here?
They were on my heels.
This house is German territory.
Please?
Heil, Hitler.
Your papers.
Romanian, Iron Guards, huh?
Your rank?
Division Battalion,
Captain, Second
Division, Bucharest Battalion.
Who sent you here to me?
Colonel Von Ritter, at
your legation in Bucharest.
You have his letter there.
Hmm.
He some nice things about you--
but damaging to the Reich,
if this had fallen
into the wrong hands.
Strange he would give
you such a letter
to carry across two
borders when you
could have used the telephone.
Maybe he thought
the telephone unwise.
Maybe.
Sit down.
Colonel Von Ritter,
German Legation Bucharest.
Dr. Muller, consul, speaking.
You know Colonel
Von Ritter well?
Oh, but of course, of
course-- like a brother.
All these months we worked
together-- hand in glove,
shoulder to shoulder.
You really think
that is necessary?
I do.
Most necessary.
Do I bore you?
No, no.
Not in the least.
I only worry that you should go
to so much unnecessary trouble
on my behalf.
Don't you worry about that.
Where do you intend
to go from here?
Well, Von Ritter
thought I could be
of use in one of the munition
or chemical plants in Pilsen.
He thought I could
be of great use.
They need skilled men,
I am a skilled man,
I'm a skilled chemist.
My only wish is to serve
the Furher-- heil, Hitler.
Von Ritter thought you could
give me Czechoslovakian visa
and recommend me to the
authorities in Pilsen.
Yes, he says that here.
Hello?
Is that Colonel Von Ritter?
This is Heinrich Muller,
consul at Teget, Hungary.
Yes, Teget.
What?
I can't hear you clearly.
Well, I'm sorry Colonel,
to get you out of bed,
but this seems important.
Yes.
I have a man here, an escaped
Iron Guard, Jan Tartu.
Did you give him a
letter to deliver to me?
Yes.
He's here now.
Oh, then you did
give him a letter.
I'm sorry, Colonel.
Yes, perhaps I should have
rung you in the morning,
but it seemed so important.
I assure, Colonel,
I'm very sorry.
I'm sorry, Colonel.
I'm very sorry, Colonel.
Do everything you can for him!
Good!
He's convinced.
Great.
You sounded like Dr. Goebbels
with a bilious attack.
Well, let's wind up
and get out of here.
[train engine whistling]
Passports!
Report immediately
for registration.
Police Headquarters, Section 3.
Can I stop at a shoemaker?
Why?
Well, look, look,
look-- it's terrible.
I can't walk about like this.
I might me a girl, you know.
Well man, you can stop anywhere
you please-- at your own risk.
Aha!
She's worth the risk.
Please, sorry, my
papers, please!
If don't register in an
hour, you'll have very
little space to walk in at all.
I'll be registered
in half an hour.
[bell chimes]
Heil, Hitler!
Heil, Hitler.
Can you repair this
please, while I wait?
I hope so, if you will bear
with the hearts of an old man.
Old man?
Ho, ho.
No women folk about
in your old age?
No family, hmm?
Well, I, too, "Wander
lonely as a cloud."
"That floats on high
o'er vales and hills."
"When all at once
I saw a crowd."
"A host of golden daffodils."
We are alone here.
Where are you from?
[inaudible] Bucharest.
And your mission?
The new gas plant.
I shall need help
from the underground.
Tonight, at--
Eh, this shoe is
splitting here!
You, repair it, please.
[bell chimes]
Quick work, you people.
Heil, Hitler.
Czech pig!
In the name of the
Reich, I arrest you.
Eh, what for?
Treason.
What are you doing?
Your papers?
Captain Jan Tartu.
I am Guard of Romania.
So, what are you doing here?
I've only just arrived in
Pilsen, I needed a shoemaker.
You, Guinea.
Well at least I shall
never have to touch
the feet of any more like you!
Take him out.
What's wrong with you?
One likes to admit they have
a certain rat-like courage.
It will be drained from
him till the last drop.
Good.
I see you have
not yet registered.
Go to Police
Headquarters immediately.
Certainly, Sir.
Heil, Hitler.
Permit for work.
Permit for food.
Permit for clothing.
Police identity card.
It is an offence to lose them.
Orderly, a room at
the Palacek House.
You will report to Inspector
Vogel, who also lives there.
Inspector-- a foreman
at the Skoda works?
INSPECTOR: Correct.
-But that is ridiculous!
Ridiculous?
What do you mean?
I am not an ordinary
munition worker.
Dr. Muller's letter tells
you that-- and I tell you!
All my life, I
worked at chemistry.
It is not much, I ask not
much to serve the Fuhrer
in the best way I can.
That is only common sense.
That is only reasonable.
I am an expert, but an
expect only at chemistry!
It
You will work
where you're told.
That is Party orders.
I have only one wish--
to serve the Fuhrer.
Heil, Hitler.
Don't worry, Tartu,
you'll have an easy time
working with the Czechs.
Every now and then,
some of them try
and interfere with production.
Keep your eyes open and
you will be well rewarded.
I can promise you that.
That's all.
Thank you, Sir.
Yes, I will keep my eyes open.
Yes, I can promise you that.
Sound your horn.
[car honking]
Someone important?
General Von Reizen,
Commandant of this area.
Ho, ho.
Heil, Hitler!
Good morning.
This is Captain Tartu.
He is billeted here.
We have no more rooms.
He will occupy your room.
You will move into the kitchen.
And be quick about it!
I can inspect the work
while you're here, Sir.
Do not bother to
remove your things.
I will take the kitchen.
Oh, but the soldier ordered--
The soldier-- tch-- I will
take the responsibility.
That is very kind of you.
Not at all.
If your room suited
me, I should take it.
Oh yes.
But it has no private entrance,
and likewise, no private exit.
At the kitchen, there
is a back door, mm?
Well, I am, though I
need hardly tell you,
you've only to look at me.
I am a man for the ladies, or
rather, the ladies are for me.
And with a lady at that
door she comes, she goes.
And the whole wide
world, nobody knows.
Very helpful.
Very encouraging.
You understand.
No--
[car honking]
Perhaps you have forgotten.
Our patient general,
or perhaps impatient,
is waiting for someone for
someone who lives here?
Maruschka Lanova.
Her room is upstairs.
A woman?
Is she beautiful?
The German officers think so.
A countrywoman of yours.
A Czech.
She has found it
convenient to forget it.
I'll take it to the kitchen.
Ah, Captain Tartu.
Heil, Hitler.
They called me
from Headquarters.
I'm to take you to Skoda works.
I'm at your service.
And I-- at yours.
MARUSCHKA: Anna, Anna!
Anna Palacek!
What have you got
to say for yourself?
Why, I don't know what you mean.
Don't stand there flapping
your tongue about, answer me!
Why haven't these boots
been saddle soaped?
And don't tell me
you can't get any,
because I might very easily have
some wrung out of your hide!
Maruschka, wonderful!
You're just as
beautiful when you're
angry as when you're pleased.
Thank you, Arthur.
How charming.
Pardon, Captain Jan Tartu
of the Romanian Iron Guard.
The inspector omitted
to introduce me,
I can well understand.
His attention was elsewhere.
But I would go further than he.
For me, your angry is
not only beautiful,
it is a burning flame, in
itself a fitting symbol
of the New Order.
Really Captain, your words are
as fantastic as your clothes.
Maruschka-- you're having
coffee with me this afternoon?
I'm sorry, Arthur.
What about dinner
then, tonight?
There's a new orchestra
at the casino.
My time is not entirely my own.
Will you ask me again?
Of course.
Will you, Arthur?
Elusive.
As elusive as she is desirable.
Who would not be a commandant?
My orders are to
take you to the Works.
Are you ready?
Perfectly.
Fantastic.
What?
What she said about
my clothes-- fantastic.
Though perhaps in
this country, they
would seem a little strange.
What do you think?
For me, I must always
be well dressed.
You know-- just a
simple little suit.
You think I should
wear something else?
At the works you
will get a uniform.
Good.
I'm always at my
best in a uniform.
Good.
I'm ready.
Now, the workers in this
room operate on 12 hour shift.
I needn't tell you
that you might think
that's the maximum efficiency.
They're the born laggers.
They look it.
[alarm sounding]
What is happening?
Somebody's been
detected at sabotage.
[footsteps creaking]
One of them is a
counterfeit, Sir!
I see.
Where did you get it?
Who made it?
You realize what
this means for you?
Of course, if you have
any accomplices here,
whose names you
might care to tell,
things might go easier for you.
Take her away.
Hopelessly stupid.
None of them ever tell.
How many shells went through?
About 600, Sir.
Put them away.
They're useless.
SOLDIER: I'm afraid
Sir, it's too late.
They are gone.
Check every shell on this line
before resuming production.
Yes, Sir.
How will you deal with her?
She'll be shot immediately.
It's
All right.
A favorite?
She lives at the house, a
daughter of the Palecek woman.
Attractive, oh yes.
Very.
But not to be compared
with the other.
There is something
about a beautiful woman
in a riding habit.
Captain--
Hmm?
I think it will be a good
thing for all concerned
if I gave you some advise.
But, please.
There is a rule, a strict rule,
that Party members should not
fraternize with Czech women.
Then this morning, the
commandant, he break the rule.
You force me to be blunt.
My dear Vogel, I don't
force you-- you are blunt.
Keep off Maruschka.
You mean the commandant
might be annoyed?
Or perhaps the inspector?
[shot]
[screaming]
Truly, inspector,
at least there's
one less left to argue about.
[alarm sounding]
[whistling]
Mm.
Smells good.
What is it?
-Veal Paprika.
Ah, delicious!
I shall look forward.
Sorry I'm late, Mother.
Be down to help you in a minute.
[banging on door]
How many women
live in this house?
Three.
Who are they?
Myself, my daughter, and
Maruschka Lanova, a border.
Are the other two in now?
Why, only my daughter.
Maruschka Lanova has
not yet returned.
How long has your
daughter been in?
I don't know.
I, I--
May be of assistance?
Captain Jan Tartu,
Romanian Iron Guard,
now foreman at the Skoda Works.
What has happened?
A German officer has
been killed nearby
in the [inaudible]
a few minutes ago.
Murdered?
By some woman.
She was seen running away.
Escaped?
So far.
I ask you-- how long has
your daughter been in?
I don't know.
I, I--
Ah, but I know.
I will bring her down.
Listen.
Do as I tell you.
A German officer--
Yes, I've heard about it.
What have you?
JAN TARTU: You Czech's seem to
think you can do what you like,
but we'll show you.
Yes, yes.
[crash]
You can stay with the woman.
JAN TARTU: [inaudible]
Don't think you can
hide anything from me, my girl.
No!
I tell you that is impossible.
Can't search your
room-- I'll show you
if I can't search your room.
You Czechs have got to
be taught to cooperate.
An officer of the Reich
has been murdered.
And if you have a gun here--
Nevermind, Romanian.
I'll handle this.
How long have you
been in the house?
About half an hour.
That's right.
I saw her.
But she came in
through the back door.
I often come in by the kitchen.
Are you sure she came
in half an hour ago?
I'm certain of it.
And now that I
remember, Major, she
had a funny look on her face.
I congratulate you, Captain.
your powers of discernment
are remarkable,
but your memory is faulty.
Did you hear us say
that this murder took
place less than 15 minutes ago?
Yes.
What?
Are you sure?
Captain Tartu will
never be a candidate
for our military intelligence.
All and the same.
Don't you ever dare tell
a member of the Party
that he can't search your room.
I suggest you spend your
first evening studying
what's contained in
those-- Party program,
behavior, future aims.
All that's interpreted
by the Fuhrer himself.
It will be an inspiration.
If anyone calls, I've gone
to the council meeting
at the bar house.
Yes, Inspector.
Heil, Hitler.
I think our Fuhrer must use as
many pigeons as he does men.
You saved my life.
We cannot understand why.
For whatever reason, I
shall always owe you mine.
In times like
these, you will never
know who your friends are.
Who are you?
I'm here on a mission.
I've come a long way,
that all I can tell you.
But it is so important.
After what you have done.
Pavla, you can help me.
You must know other Czechs as
brave and loyal as you are.
I must contact the
underground, understand?
The underground?
Yes.
I can't tell you
how urgent it is.
Every hour counts.
Tonight.
If you can.
I don't know.
I'll see what I can do.
You see--
Oh, so you're home for once.
Come upstairs and
take my boots off.
This Maruschka, tell
me something about her.
She boards here.
She seems a girl of
means, of education.
Her father owned a
big textile factory.
My husband works for him.
Is her father alive?
He and my husband
are both dead.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
But this intimacy with
high-ranking German officers,
rather a strange transfer
of affections, isn't it?
Some women are lonely only
to their own breed, Captain.
Yes, yes, I will.
Pavla, listen--
I can't talk now.
She wants to see you.
Maruschka?
Yes, up in her room.
Now?
Yes.
Command performance, eh?
Well, well, what can I lose?
[knocking]
Come in?
Fraulein.
Oh, Captain, Tartu.
Never have I climbed stairs
with greater anticipation.
I see you're incorrigible.
Have a cigarette and
give me one, will you?
Please.
Thank you.
Sit down, Captain.
I detest being forced
into apologies,
but it seems I owe you one.
I can hardly believe my ears.
Not only beautiful,
but unexpected.
A woman of surprises.
It is too much, too much.
Well, General Von
Reisend, the commandant.
I know.
He was telling me of the work
of your Iron Guard in Romania.
Very clever.
And very courageous.
I don't think you
warranted my rudeness,
so hereby, I apologize.
And hereby, I
accept your apology.
And what is more, I
too, can be generous.
There was, I admit it,
something in what you said.
You are a woman of taste.
No, just bad
tempered before lunch.
No, no-- a woman of taste.
You like me better
as I am now, eh?
Infinitely.
Ah, but I see a doubt, a
misgiving shadow in those eyes.
I know.
The pomade, yes?
Never again do I swallow
myself with the pomade.
From now on, it is an offence.
Never should it be
said that Captain
Tartu relied on the hair.
No!
You shall see me
as I am-- almost.
Almost?
Why not quite?
Who know?
It is possible.
We shall see.
What on earth is that?
Your dinner.
Dinner!
Water, milk, and
dried up cheese?
Where's that veal paprika?
The butcher had no veal--
More whining.
You just get it out of
here before I'm sick.
What a way to live.
Well, it seems I shall have
to go elsewhere for my dinner.
Will you give me the
pleasure of taking you?
Why, yes.
In fact, I rather
hoped you'd ask me.
Can I have half an
hour to get dressed?
Nothing could be better,
for in that half hour,
I, too, have most
important business.
May one ask, what?
I have to remove the pomade.
Heil, Hitler!
[music playing]
Maruschka!
Hello, Little One!
Paul.
Every officer in the room.
You're not enjoying
your evening.
Oh, yes, but we're
watched by too many eyes.
What's wrong with that?
Well, I looked forward
to this first time.
I thought it might be, like
you, rather unexpected.
Unexpected?
Mm-mm.
Away from my own country,
I'm a rather lonely man.
You're a very beautiful woman.
I grabbed at this evening like
a drowning man who needs help.
Help?
Mm-mm.
Every lonely man
needs a woman's help.
I hoped I might be
myself with you.
Instead, I dance around
like a performing animal,
watched by a grinning audience.
This evening is not yet over.
Outside it is
moonlight and quiet.
Let me take you.
Take me back to our table.
No?
-No, no.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
Why?
I feel in the mood for
talk, for real talk--
an exchange of confidences,
of hopes and fears.
This helps.
Well, you've done
a lot of talking.
You've told me the life
story of Jan Tartu.
What do you think of it?
Shall I tell you the truth?
Please!
I don't know what to think.
It was very highly colored.
But men will do
desperate things,
out of love for their country.
Or for their faith
in the New Order.
Why yes, of course.
Or for there love of freedom.
You know, Captain Tartu,
without the pomade,
there is something very
different about you.
Away from Vogel
and the commandant,
I would say the same about you.
My family have lost
everything and owe much.
I want to get it back.
That's why I risk my reputation
with our German visitors.
You risk something
of your reputation
as a good Nazi in your
little plot with Pavla.
Huh?
Mm.
There was a whole pot of
veal paprika in the kitchen
and you knew it, and
Pavla knew you knew it.
I'm not such a fool as Captain
Tartu must sometimes appear.
You may take me
into the moonlight.
Pavla told you everything?
Everything she knew.
Who are you?
Not yet.
You know Peter
Valek, the shoemaker.
He was my only contact.
You know, you're taking
a big chance on me.
I'm taking a big chance
on what's behind your eyes.
Look at me.
Will you do the same with me?
My country is being
tortured to death--
if I were to do anything
to increase that suffering.
I'm here to help.
You must believe that.
Do you want me to put you in
touch with the underground?
As soon as possible.
Tomorrow.
When you return from the Works.
Well.
You were right about this
evening-- unexpected.
I believe in you.
You give me new
hope and courage.
It's the courage
of people like you
who make it all worth
while-- something
to hang onto in this mad world.
Life and laughter and love--
they'll come back, if we do
hang on.
They'll come back.
The moon and moonlight--
that doesn't change.
It's about the only
thing that hasn't.
I sat under that
same moon at home.
Home?
My mother's garden.
Wild roses in the hedge, the
river at her feet, and life
ahead to do what we'd like with.
Queer to be talking
to you like this
in this little circle of peace.
Couldn't we pretend in this
little circle for a little
while, there's no war we're
free again, our lives our
own to do what we liked with.
Yes.
Let's pretend.
You know that fellow
Tartu, remember him?
Do I?
Mm.
Oh, yes, yes.
Well, he and I had
one thing in common--
we both think [WITH ACCENT]
you're a very beautiful woman.
I'm glad.
Though I don't very much
care what Tartu thinks.
I wonder what he'd
do if he were here.
Tartu?
Mm.
What do you think?
Oh, I'd expect he'd do
some simple little thing.
Now, Captain Tartu, things
aren't quite as easy as that.
Maruschka, are you?
Oh, Otto, I'm glad you've come.
Good evening, inspector.
What were you saying?
Has this fellow been trying--
Oh, no, no, Otto.
Nothing, really.
Those fools at the house
sent me up a dinner
which was utterly uneatable,
so I had to come out.
I pressed our Romanian
gallant here into service,
and the result was partly my
fault and partly the champagne.
Oh, Lady, I'm desolate.
I'd hoped it was my fault.
Really, Captain,
you flatter yourself.
Otto, let's find
a table inside?
I gave you some pamphlets.
Go and read them.
[sobbing]
[WHISPERING] Pavla!
Pavla, Darling, Darling, don't.
Don't cry, sweetheart.
No.
Couldn't you sleep?
I couldn't get back sooner.
That fool, Otto, turned up.
I shouldn't have
done what I did today.
I put all of you in danger.
No, Darling.
It's been over three
months since that beast
started telling the
others to be executed.
I shouldn't have let
him live that long.
I know, Daring.
But Karl got his
revenge today, because I
had Karl's own revolver.
And he fell right in
the gutter-- right
on his face in the filth!
Shh!
I'm all right.
What happened
about the Romanian?
You were right
about that, Darling.
I'm going to speak to the
council members in the morning.
I'm glad.
I knew I could trust him
the moment I saw him.
Strange, isn't it?
There's something about him.
Yes, there's
something about him.
He's so strong and honest
and gentle, at the same time.
Maruschka, I've never heard
you talk about a man like that
before.
What's happened?
You're falling in love.
Am I?
Yes.
I think I am.
I'm so glad.
You know when you are.
I remember Karl.
I killed the man
who killed my Karl.
It hasn't brought
Karl back to me.
Killing, killing, killing!
There's nothing left!
Nothing!
[sobbing]
No, no, no.
Pavla, Pavla, Darling.
There.
Do your sleeping at home!
[alarm sounding]
Well, what is it?
One moment, Lieutenant!
They know you've seen me.
Turn me in.
You must.
You're our only chance.
So, you young swine!
I've failed, but
others will carry on.
Keep her here.
Captain, the guard is
certain that this Tartu
here saw the girl pick up--
Please!
The door, it is open.
May we have it closed?
Shut it.
Thank you.
Yes, it was Pavla Palecek.
She had that bag in her hand.
More steel filings.
To burn out more motors.
Yes.
Why didn't you
say so out there?
But Lieutenant,
isn't it obvious?
Captain, surely you understand.
But it is so plain.
Already, I make friends
among the Czechs.
They begin to trust me.
The work that I was sent
here to do, it will go on.
But if these Czechs were
ever to suspect that it was
their new friend Captain Tartu
who gave this girl away--
well, surely now, Captain, a man
of your intelligence must see.
Yes, of course.
Quite right.
Good work, Captain.
It won't be made
public, I hope?
Of course not.
What do you take me for?
Start your machines again.
Have the girl shot.
Yes, sir.
Oh, Tartu.
Please.
You seem very quick
witted for a Romanian.
Oh, well, as I told him when I
first came here-- but not all,
are as quick as you,
even in the Party.
I am not an ordinary
munitions worker.
No, no.
I am a graduate chemist.
Is that so?
Chemist, eh?
Chemist.
Well, I will see
what can be done.
That is all.
Thank you, Sir.
[gun shot]
[alarm sounding]
Good afternoon.
How's the headache?
Frightful.
I didn't sleep a wink all night.
So don't tell me I have to wait,
because I made an appointment
early this morning.
Dr. Novotny will see you now.
[doorbell buzzing]
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Doctor.
Come in.
Please, sit down.
Well, Maruschka.
I understand you spent yesterday
with the Commandant again.
Anything to tell us?
Nothing yet.
Every time I brought up the
subject of the new air drum,
he avoided it, very obviously.
Then why call a meeting?
I wanted to speak
to the council
because I feel I have
something much more important.
It concerns a man
named Tartu, Jan Tartu.
Tartu?
Well then you know him?
We know he's living
in the Palecek house.
Yes.
And he's a friend, Dr. Novotny.
Yesterday, when they
came to see Pavla,
he hid the gun, saved her life.
He's on a very
important mission.
He wants to contact
the underground.
You didn't tell him about us?
No, naturally not.
I only obey orders.
But I want permission
to bring him here.
What makes you so
sure of him, Maruschka?
I told you-- he
saved Pavla's life.
Oh yes, he mentioned
Peter Valek.
And then, well, I've seen
so much of the other kind,
I'm not entirely insensible
to honesty and sincerity
when I do meet it.
Did you know Peter Valek
was executed yesterday?
No!
When did you last
see Pavla Palecek?
This morning.
This afternoon she was shot.
[WHISPERING] Not Pavla.
Oh, no!
Oh, no.
[crying]
Tell Maruschka how
Pavla was discovered.
The foreman came into
the head officer.
He said he wanted to
report her in private.
Why?
He said he was going the
confidence of certain Czechs,
that the work that he was
sent to do was going forward,
and that it would
spoil his plans,
if it was known that
he had reported her.
What was the foreman's
name Jan Tartu.
That's all, Yenna.
Thank you.
I might just as well
have killed her myself.
You were caught by the
oldest trick my dear,
he pretend to save Pavla in
order to get to the rest of us.
I'll do anything
to see him dead.
Anything!
It would be excellent to
have him out of the way.
We must be careful.
They are taking hostages.
From now on, any more killings
and 100 of our people--
200 even, would die in return.
If that is so, forgive
my putting it bluntly.
Are we wise to trust
this case to someone
who has already allowed her
sex to influence her judgement?
I have known Maruschka
Lanova since she was born.
The mistake she has
made over this man
will make her more
careful from now on.
Besides, you are on pretty
intimate terms with him.
I can do anything
I like with him.
Very useful, that.
A virtue of necessity.
You can trust me absolutely
to eliminate Captain Tartu.
I will kill him myself.
It will be easy.
He sleeps in the kitchen.
Tonight, I will take a knife!
No.
Novotny's just told us--
for every Nazi killed,
200 Czechs will die.
I would give myself up.
But it wouldn't do
any good, Darling.
It's always [inaudible].
Doesn't feel safe
unless it's 200 to 1.
No, it must be done
some other way.
Novotny asked me how
I was going to do it.
I said I didn't know.
I didn't, then.
I do now.
If he were to be done away
with by one of his own kind.
One sneaking coward
destroys another,
Anna-- and nobody the wiser.
[door opens]
I'll be back.
[knocking]
Yes?
MARUSCHKA: Otto,
are you dressed?
Maruschka!
Can we talk somewhere?
Oh yes, come in.
Is this respectable, Otto?
I think I refused
to come in here
last night-- for
some such reasons.
A girl can change
her mind, huh?
Your hat is pretty,
but you might
like-- to take it off, huh?
Well, let me get my breath
and have a look around.
This is very restful room, Otto.
Schnaps-- sent from home.
I'll bet this doesn't
come from home.
That?
Oh, that came from the finest
art collection at Pilsen.
Borrowed, for the duration.
Yes-- of my life.
Maruschka, to your
being here in my room.
To the success
of my being here.
Maruschka!
I said to the success
of my being here, Otto.
Otto, I need your help.
I need it badly.
And I know you're
one I can trust.
Always, Maruschka-- in any way.
You know I want to
get back with my family
own-- after the war.
I know, Darling, but
that's something I can't--
And I know you have a
Party career in mind.
Obviously a man of your
ability doesn't expect
to remain a mere inspector.
Oh, I've, I've plans
ahead that will put you--
We might realize both
our ambitions, Otto,
if you'll help me with
a certain individual
by the name of Jan Tartu.
Tartu?
What's he?
I think he's a spy.
OTTO: What?
I'm sure of it.
As you know, I detest the
insolent fool, Maruschka,
but you must be careful.
He's of the Romanian Iron Guard.
The party still
needs their help.
He came with credentials.
Iron Guard-- I doubt he
even comes from Romania.
No?
What makes you think that?
Well, I don't know.
There's an underground group
here of some sort working
against the Reich, isn't there?
Yes, yes.
Go on.
Well, last night
at the casino, he
hinted he was trying to
contact them to get their help.
Help?
For what?
Otto, when a man wants the
help of an underground movement,
it can't be for to
good of the Reich.
Oh, yes.
Now I didn't say anything
last night to you.
That was why I was
so easy with him.
I wanted to see if he'd
mentioned it to me again
this morning.
Well, did he?
Just as I was coming
out of my room.
He suggested that this
girl in the house, this
Pavla-- oh, yes.
I understand she was shot today.
Sabotage where she
works, or something.
Yes, yes, but never
mind about her.
All right.
He practically said he
knew I was her friend,
and that we could do something
for him with the underground,
or whatever it is
they call themselves.
Huh.
Oh, this is serious.
Well-- well, we can
easily prove about him.
How?
Call the Gestapo and tell
them to check up on him.
No, no, Otto!
Huh?
Not when we can get all
the credit ourselves.
Yes, but how?
I don't mind, Darling,
it's so simple.
You can use this can't you?
Yes, but I've got to be sure.
All it needs is
some little meeting.
such as in the
garden last night,
only you're behind the
hedge, to hear for yourself.
Hear what?
I scream, you shoot.
You and I are both there to
testify, an enemy of the Reich
lies there, disposed of.
I see.
I get what I want
and maybe they'll make
you a general or something.
Very clever, Maruschka.
When can you meet him again?
Tonight.
Where?
At the cafe, where
we were last night.
I'll be there.
There may people around.
For the good-- more convincing.
You know the alcove
on the terrace?
Yes.
Take him there.
I'll make arrangements.
I'll be able to hear
everything he says.
Darling, you're a genius!
And Otto--
Eh?
Do you know what
else might happen
for us, if we are successful?
What?
Next time I come in this room,
I might even take off my hat.
[music playing]
The Romanian again, eh?
I'm sorry to be late,
but it's been a hard day.
Pavla-- I suppose you know.
Yes.
Were you there?
She looked at me when
they led her away.
I'll never forget
that look-- never.
I know.
I know how close she was to you.
What is your real name?
I can't tell you now.
Later, I will.
I have other things to
tell you, things that can't
be told until my job's done.
Have you any news for me?
You see, well, I didn't
tell you last night,
but I'm not a member of this
underground group myself.
To be frank, I don't think
they're ready to trust me yet.
What?
But I was sure Pavla was, and I
thought through Pavla I could--
but now.
Do you know anyone else?
Well, I have to
be very careful.
Oh, I realize that.
But it's more important
than ever now.
Things are coming to a head.
I'm being transferred to the
new gas laboratories tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Darling, but
I'll work as fast as I can.
You know that, don't you.
Of course, of course.
So just let's enjoy
being together.
Yes.
Where would you like to sit?
Over there.
Shall we?
Just to prove I've found time
to think of you as something
more than an accomplice.
It just looked as
if it was waiting--
waiting to be bought for you.
It's lovely.
[humming]
Ah, that's better.
That's much better.
I've always liked that tune.
[singing in german]
You know the words?
Mm-mm.
They're German.
Yes, written years ago.
That sort of music is universal.
Strange.
They tell me that's one of
the Fuhrer's favorite waltzes.
Oh. tsk-tsk.
Well, if that music could
speak, I'm sure it would object.
In your country, do they hate
Hitler as much as we do here?
Well, I don't know that we
spend a lot of time hating.
After all, most of
us are working 24
hours a day to get rid of him.
I like to hear you say that.
Tell me more of what you're
doing to get rid of him.
I want to hear.
I want to hear from you.
[soldiers marching]
All officers-- report to me!
Trouble, I'm afraid.
Don't worry.
Attention,
attention, all Czechs!
By order of the
Commandant of this area,
owing to the illegal
and treacherous behavior
among certain and
corrupt Czech elements
of the local population.
All Czechs will be
examined for their passes,
travel papers, and concealed
weapons, under royal command.
All Czechs will collect in
the center of the floor.
Attention!
Czechs, march!
Stop!
[gunshot]
[woman screams]
Take him away.
[singing in german]
Heil, Hitler!
ALL: Heil, Hitler!
[knocking]
Hello?
I got mixed up with
a lot of Nazis.
Had to do my stuff.
I understand.
See you tomorrow?
Of course.
I'll be at the works all day.
MARUSCHKA: Jan?
Mm?
Let's have dinner at the
same place, same time.
Wonderful.
I'm looking forward.
So am I.
Good night, Darling.
Good night.
Here you are, Captain.
Where is the gas plant?
It's buried inside the hill.
Walk through the farm
halls and you'll find it.
Here.
Jan Tartu, reporting for work.
Very well, Tartu.
You put your personal effects
and valuables in here.
You can't take
anything in there.
Of course.
Your number is 82.
Thank you.
Is that everything?
Everything.
Tie pin.
Oh, yes. of course.
Take him to Dr. Willendorf.
First level.
Dr. Willendorf is expecting you.
It is an honor.
This way, please.
[alarm]
What is wrong?
-You have forgotten something?
-Hmm?
Forgotten?
Electric ray.
It says you have
some steel on you.
Missing?
Me?
Ah, the key.
I hate to part with it.
I only met her yesterday.
Oh, so it is one
of those things?
Lovely thing.
Most hospitable.
She lives with her
younger sister.
Sister-- pretty?
Oh-- from top to toe.
Is she attached?
Yes, but he's going to
Prague in a couple of days.
All right, I'll
see you later, huh?
Guard it with your life.
This way, please.
If there is an air raid
alarm, follow the signs.
Wait here, I'll
find Dr. Willendorf.
Dr. Willendorf?
Captain Tartu, Dr. Willendorf.
Heil, Hitler!
Come with me.
Who is this?
My new chemist, Tartu.
Captain Von Felisch.
Well?
What are you waiting for?
Only to serve the Fuhrer.
Heil, Hitler!
DR WILLENDORF: Tartu.
Gas retorts?
All of them, to my
own specifications.
I trust you know your
business, my friend.
We are running an
emergency schedule here.
I'm quite confident, Sir.
You have worked with the
metal in concert, right?
Oh, yes.
For two or for three years,
under Professor Bern,
at Munich.
Good.
This way.
You will find we are making
an amazing gas here, Tartu.
Start by learning the
formula thoroughly.
I didn't see any bomb casings
out there, Dr. Willendorf.
Are they filled
on another level?
No.
We ship the gas to
the various fronts
in two separate liquid forms.
There, the liquids
are compounded,
and the [inaudible]
cases charged,
just prior to operations.
But get that stuck in your
head as quickly as possible.
[music playing]
[alarm ringing]
I am very pleased
with you, Tartu.
Thank you, Sir.
Your new gas is
more than amazing.
It is almost inconceivable
in its deadliness.
And it will be put to good use.
I would like you to come one
hour earlier in the morning,
please.
Certainly.
All day tomorrow we shall
be running final tests
and I shall need
your assistance.
Final tests?
You're not ready with your
first shipment, are you?
Two weeks ahead of time.
Tomorrow night, they will be
loading it onto the trucks.
And soon, on some
beautifully clouded evening,
it will be unloaded--
on England.
Heil, Hitler.
Maruschka?
Where is Maruschka?
Out.
The Commandant
called unexpectedly
to take her to dinner.
She told me to tell you
that only that could keep
her from seeing you tonight.
-Where did they go?
Do you know?
-No.
Is there no way at all
that I can contact her?
No.
Can't you get a
message through to her?
No.
Look here, I've got to
do something tonight.
Take any chance.
Can't you help?
I can get you some supper.
Waiter, waiter!
Eh?
-Another brandy, Sir?
Brandy, rum?
How much have I been swindled?
I'm trying to get out
of this slop cave.
Here, Sir.
Who asked for that?
Give it to me.
Get out of the way.
Give me another brandy, quick!
Oh, you seem a pleasant
enough sort of fellow, hmm?
How about letting
me buy you a drink?
No, thank you.
Why not?
This is my limit
for this evening.
Thank you all the same.
Brandy, Sir.
Eh, you Czechs.
Think yourselves pretty
smart, don't you?
Won't fraternize.
Waiting for the hour
when you're going to rise
up and throw us out, eh?
Well, who's going to lead you?
Tell me that.
Blah.
Some of those amateur heroes
of yours that you've got
hidden away in that
underground army?
Hmm?
All right, don't talk.
But they are not going to
lead you, I can tell you that.
Why?
Because they won't be able
to rise out to the graves!
That's why!
I know six of the rats who
are going to be smoked out
by the end of the week-- six!
The Gestapo's have got
their names and everything?
Do you know why I know?
Because I happen to be-- Well,
maybe I'm talking too much.
Hey, you-- another
brandy, quick.
Coming, Sir.
There's plenty of
things I can tell you.
Plenty of things.
One of you must be
pretty good at ice hockey,
But if you're the people I
think you are, it was worth it.
Tonight you said you know
so of the names of Czechs
on the Gestapo's list.
Yes.
We want to know who they are.
Believe me, I don't know them.
I only talked like that
in the last hope of making
contact with the underground.
And I think I have, haven't I?
Supposing you have?
I'm a British secret
agent gentleman,
I need your help desperately.
We need more proof than
merely your word for it.
But that's all I can give.
No-- Peter Valek-- he was about
to put me in touch with you
when they caught him.
My job is a very big one.
I'm here to wreck
their new gas plant.
I'm working there now.
But I must have
help-- chemicals,
a place to make pocket bombs,
men to help make them--
tonight-- now.
They're shipping the first
batch of gas tomorrow.
You must believe me.
Do you think I'd be
mad enough to take
this chance if the situation
wasn't of the greatest--
One moment.
You informed on
the Palecek girl.
Why?
I had to.
They knew I'd seen her do it,
and she knew they'd seen me.
If you have a erect a
monument to Czech patriotism,
that girl's name should be
carved in letters as high as--
Grant you that.
What is your real name?
Kept Terrance Stevenson,
Royal Engineers,
now detached to a special work
with military intelligence.
Break this, swine!
Now that's there--
the Gestapo, I take it.
Correct.
It's not a nice sensation
for a man to realize he's
bungled his job, I assure you.
Your little display at the
bar was slightly obvious.
Evidently.
Well, what now?
We do these things quickly.
No formalities.
Just one shot at the
base of the neck.
Well?
Shall we carry on?
They want to get things ready.
If you care to write a message
to your family or anything
over there.
That's very kind of you.
We are also the
decoding office.
So don't try any tricks.
Having a difficult time, eh?
It isn't easy.
The first time I've written
this kind of letter.
Once is enough.
Just a moment.
Read it.
"Dear Perry, I'm sorry
I have messed things up.
Please let my mother know.
I'm sure you will be tactful.
Give her my dear love.
To you and all
friends, all the best.
Story to miss the victory binge.
Yours, Terrance Stevenson."
Let's see it.
I suppose you realize
this is all quite futile.
You can do your work with
me, but you'd have to do
it with the next and the next.
And no matter how long it
takes, the whole civilized world
will keep on coming at you.
Coming at you and coming again.
You know that?
Why--
Wait, Nestor.
You made a valiant effort
to contact the underground.
Congratulations.
You have.
Captain Stevenson,
at your service, Sir.
By Jove.
I'm Dr. Novotny,
I have the honor
to be Chairman of our council
By Jove.
That's the second
time I've said that.
[laughter]
I am sorry we had
to be so strenuous,
but you can
understand, I'm sure.
Yeah.
It certainly was a
convincing performance.
Look here, have you got
anything besides beer here?
Peter, some wine for all of us.
Oh, Doctor, we
mustn't waist a second.
A gigantic undertaking.
Yes, that.
I shall need all the help
we can get in at once--
a place to work, watch
mechanism for timing devices--
Yes, I know.
Get Yoban, either at
my office or his house.
All of the help we can
give you, you shall have.
We have our own laboratory here
on the cellar, crude as it is.
Splendid.
We'll manage.
Beautiful work.
I don't know what I'd have
done without your help.
The most compact container of
lethal power I've ever seen.
Well, we learned something, eh?
Yeah.
Is there enough
explosive in there
to blow up the entire plant?
-Yeah.
Properly placed, there's
enough nitrogen in these
to wipe out two entire blocks.
The only thing I can
understand is why they sent him.
[laughter]
Didn't you say you had to
report an hour earlier today?
Yes.
It is nearly seven o'clock.
Thank you.
Our time table
worked out perfectly.
These are set to go
off at exactly 12:15.
That gives me just 15
minutes after noon lay off
to drop them in and clear out.
And Nestor here will be in
the car by the south field.
From 12:00 on.
And I'll have the door open.
-Good.
If you don't, you'll have
to expect the passenger
through the window.
[laughter]
Good morning, Lieutenant.
I shall have to hurry.
I'm late.
Well, Tartu, I've been waiting.
Have you any news for me?
Oh, plenty.
See you in the lunch hour.
[alarm]
Same old sabotage.
Tonight, we use this together.
Aha!
Ah, Maruschka.
Maruschka, good, come.
Come in here.
So serious, Otto?
Serious?
Wait till I put through
a call and we'll see.
Hello?
Inspector Vogel
speaking, Division A2.
Get me Colonel Von Werder,
German Ligation, Bucharest.
Yes, that's it.
What is this little
drama all about?
When I got report
of this morning,
I heard that Tartu is now
working at the new gas factory.
Yes, he did mention it.
You knew he didn't
come home last night?
No, I didn't.
Oh, this is all too dangerous.
We can't wait now.
If anything happened
and it was found
out that you and
I were suspicious
and hadn't reported him, why--
Well, why the
call to Bucharest?
I inquired about his
credentials at Headquarters.
He came with a letter
from the Consul at Teget,
and was supposed to
have been sent to him
by Von Werder in Bucharest.
I'm going to tat source now.
Do you really think you need?
[telephone ringing]
Yes, Maruschka Hello?
Yes?
I'm waiting.
[QUIETLY] You mean,
he isn't Gestapo?
So there's a chance
I've made a mistake.
Still waiting.
An Inspector Vogel, in Pilsen.
Von Werder speaking.
Tartu?
That's impossible.
Tartu has been dead
over six months.
Ah, then he is a spy.
I thought his
papers were forged.
That's why I checked
with you, Colonel.
Yes.
He'll be dealt with at once.
Thank you, Colonel.
Yes.
Heil, Hitler.
Ha ha.
You made no mistake, my Darling.
You don't seem very
pleased about it.
Of course I'm pleased.
I don't know what all
the excitement about.
I told you he was a spy, and now
you find it out for yourself.
Yes.
But now he's working
at the gas factory.
I must have him
arrested, at once.
Hello.
While, if the Gestapo--
You talked about this
doing us a bit of good?
It will.
I don't believe in
waiting, not for a moment.
Hello?
Otto?
Don't you remember what I
said when I was in here last?
Maruschka!
You men.
You're all alike.
First it's me, and
then it's your future.
Same thing, Maruschka.
You are in my future.
This won't take long.
Don't be too sure.
I'm not used to be
treating like this.
Your telephone call can wait.
You might lose both
me and your future,
if you're not very careful.
Oh, I won't lost either.
I've never felt so strong or
full of confidence before.
Hello?
OTTO: Don't you worry
about me, Darling.
Inspector Vogel speaking,
I want the gas factory.
Emergency.
First time in my--
Anna!
Anna, quickly!
Anna, we were wrong about Jan.
How did it happen?
I can't tell you now.
We've got to save him.
There's no need
to tie his hands.
He is dead.
[telephone ringing]
Oh, I didn't mean to.
I wish I had been
able to kill him.
Think Maruschka-- Pavla,
Karl, your father.
He can only die once.
That is a pity.
We shan't be safe here now.
Go to Dr. Novotny and
tell him I'll report
to him as soon as possible.
[telephone ringing]
That's funny.
An inspector was
calling the gas plant,
and just when he
said, "emergency,"
he stopped and hung up.
Did you get the
number he called from?
Yes, but when I called
back, there was no answer.
You'd better report it.
Yes.
Have you got a permit?
No, but it's very urgent.
No, but I simply must get in.
All right, let her in.
Well, Fraulein.
Hello, Lieutenant.
Could I possibly speak
to a friend of mine?
He says he works here,
if he isn't lying.
Well, if you give me his name,
I'll see whether he is or not.
Jan Tartu.
Tartu?
Just think of the best
looking man in the place--
not counting yourself--
Huh, Tartu.
He certainly wasn't lying
about you, Fraulein.
Was he telling the
truth about your sister?
Didn't he mention me?
Lieutenant Krantz.
Oh, yes.
So you're Lieutenant Krantz.
Of course.
Lieutenant, couldn't
I speak to Jan?
Please?
Well, is an infraction of the
rules during working hours,
but--
Oh, but you can manage it, yes?
For me?
All right.
But shall we say,
for your sister, huh?
Where?
Through the fence there.
And don't be too long.
Oh, yes.
Thanks.
Well, well, little one.
Hello.
Jan, you've been discovered.
Vogel called Von
Werder in Bucharest.
When?
Just now.
You've got to get out of here.
They'll be coming in a minute.
[inaudible]
Not a phone call.
Anything can happen.
Von Werder calling the
Gestapo-- anything.
Jan, Darling, you've got
to leave this second.
I can't.
Yeah.
Maruschka, now listen carefully.
Get to Dr. Novotny and
tell him what's happened.
All plans are off.
I've got to plant those
bombs as soon as I can,
do you understand?
And if possible, get Nestor
and the car on the main road,
right away.
Oh, Darling, no.
Is that quite clear?
Oh, yes, but-- Jan,
there isn't time.
Go ahead then, Maruschka.
Oh, Jan, I can't leave you.
[LOUDLY] Do as I tell you.
Don't come here
bothering me again.
Be off now.
Go on.
Off you get.
Lover's quarrel, huh?
You have to put them in
their place now and then.
[sirens sounding]
Air raids.
[inaudible]!
Air raids!
The formula!
[inaudible]!
The formula, I will save.
[sirens]
Does anyone know
who gave the alarm?
I thought you did, Colonel.
One moment.
Colonel Hausmann, speaking.
Where are you going?
I have to see that
all valves are shut.
[sirens sounding]
Von Wellech, arrest Jan Tartu.
Arrest Jan Tartu.
NAZI: [OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
That's Tartu the Romanian.
He's a spy.
You two watch the lift.
Tartu, yeah.
Jan Tartu?
There he is!
[gunfire]
Don't shoot!
[whistle blows]
Tartu, tower number
four [inaudible].
NAZI: [OVER LOUDSPEAKER] Tartu.
Tower number four [inaudible].
NAZI: [OVER LOUDSPEAKER]Tartu,
tower number four [inaudible].
[inaudible]
[shooting]
NAZI: [OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
[inaudible].
Tartu, [inaudible] [inaudible].
[gunfire]
Any success?
I think so.
Step on it.
Have you got a gun?
Mine's empty.
[explosion]
They are operating tonight.
Everything I'm warming up.
How long have you got?
Less than 20 minutes.
Now, if we are to go
as planned, we must get
up there and watch our chance.
The dawn is with us.
Are you all ready?
Jan, Darling, I
can't come with you.
What?
You'll always be in my heart.
There's work to be
done here, still.
Nonsense.
Maruschka, there is nothing
more you can do for us.
You are a liability, in fact.
So, I order you to leave
the country-- in good hands.
Oh, Doctor.
Please, we must get started.
Well, Doctor, as you said
yourself, words, sometimes,
are poor things.
DR. NOVOTNY: Good-bye.
Good bye.
DR. NOVOTNY: Good luck.
CAPTAIN STEVENSON: Where
are we heading for?
PILOT: Water.
CAPTAIN STEVENSON:
In a German plane?
PILOT: It's all right.
We have prearranged signals-- 20
miles offshore, by secret code.
[airplane engines]
Perfect.
Now is our chance.
If we don't get away with this,
you'll always know, won't you?
Always.
Come on.
[whistling]
Coffee!
I'll bet you all the
marks in your pocket.
Hands up!
Right up and keep them up.
All clear, Bumpy.
[gunshot] Get over there
and face that wall.
Quickly!
Get in there.
Keep your hands up.
[gunfire]
Keep them up!
After him!
[airplane engine roaring]
PILOT: Are you all right?
Fine.
Headquarters!
They're taking off.
PILOT: If we get to that
cloud, we will lose them.
What then?
Snow!
What?
Just a simple little wedding.
[church bells]