SOYUZMULTFILM
THE BLUE BIRD
After M. Maeterlinck
Written and directed by
VASILY LIVANOV
Art director
MAX ZHEREBCHEVSKY
Composer
GENNADI GLADKOV
Camera Mikhail Druyan,
Sound Georgiy Martinyuk
Cutter Lidiya Kyaksht
Background art Boris Sadovnikov
Dir ass Natalya Kotovshchikova
Assistants: T Fedorova, E Novoselskaya
N Nikolayeva, R Bukmayeva N Nayashkova
animators Gennady Sokolsky, Yana Volskaya,
Anatoly Abarenov, Youry Kuziurin,
Youry Butyrin, Joseph Kuroyan,
Valentin Kushnerev, Natalia Bogomolova, Oleg Safronov,
Violetta Kolesnikova, Boris Butakov, Sergei Dezhkin,
S. Zhutovskaya, Kirill Malyantovich
artists Anna Atamanova, Stanislav Sokolov,
L. Chalaya, Z. Zarb, A. Solovjov,
D. Anpilov, Ye. Balabanova, S. Kuznetsov
Actors:
L. Akhedzhakova, L. Gnilova, R. Zelyonaya,
V. Kenigson, Yu. Yakovlev
Moscow State Choir
and The Children Choir "Sputnik"
State Symphony Orchestra of Cinematography
Conductor V. Vasilyev
Executive producer Lubov' Butyrina
script editor Arcady Snessarev
- Don't beat him!
- Don't beat him! He's just hungry.
- I'll tear his skin off!
Get away, or you'll get a trashing too!
- Take this, please.
Is it enough?
- Do you want to have the Blue Bird?
Take it. It's yours.
It's my gift to you.
- Remember, my boy.
You're holding a priceless treasure -
the Blue Bird.
The Blue Bird can't be bought or sold.
It might be only given.
Only given...
- You're not allowed in, understand?
If you want, wait for me here.
- But what did you go there for, mom?
- I've put flowers on their grave.
- I do remember granddad too.
He liked to play violin.
And grandma always told me tales.
- But I don't remember them at all.
- Mom, why have they died?
- Good night.
- Good night, mommy.
- Good night, mom.
- Are you sleeping?
- And you?
- I want to tell you a secret.
But don't reveal it to anyone!
- Look, mom has forgotten
to switch the lamp off!
- Just a moment.
- Oh! It still lights!
- What's that?
- I don't know. Let's go and find out.
- Well?... What?...What?
- What, what... Nothing to hear.
- Don't you have the Blue Bird?
- Grandma! Grandad!..
So they're alive!
- Grandma, Granddad!
So you actually haven't died?
- What are you saying! Just listen to him.
He's using unintelligible expressions.
"Died"! What's that?!
Some new word, eh? a new cult thing?
- Granddad... Grandma...
- How have you grown up!
And who's that girl? Who's she?
Isn't that our granddaughter?
- Yes, it's our granddaughter.
When we left her, she was just a baby.
- Ohhh! How she looks like me!
- Well, that's only your imagination.
She looks like me.
- Yes?
- Yes!
- Bro! Who are you talking to?
- Don't you see them?
Granddad and grandma.
- There's nobody there.
Only old things, plus it's quit dark.
And granddad with grandma
have died many years ago.
- There! You're always doing this!...
- Don't be angry at your sister.
She can't see us. Because we
only come to life in memories.
And she has no memories of us.
She doesn't remember.
- I'll tell everything to mom.
You've promised to show me the Blue Bird,
but now you're making fun of me!
There!
- Where,...where's my Blue Bird?
- Tell me, why do you hold
the Blue bird in a cage?
- Because it's mine.
- Yours?
- Yes.
- No, you're wrong!
The Blue Bird belongs to everybody!
To all who are kind, honest and brave.
It must fly over the Earth in freedom!
- But it was a gift to me!
And I'm happy with it...
- How can you feel happy on your own,
if other people are unhappy?
- But if I'll let it go,
I'll become unhappy too.
- Who knows, who knows...
- When you're keeping happiness
only for yourself, it's easily lost.
- Do believe us, we did spent a long time living...
- Indeed, a long time.
- Hurry down!
- My little friend!
I love, love, love you!
And you I love too! You too!
- Give me back the coin.
It's mine, it's my coin.
- Am I satisfied? I'm satisfied.
I'm satisfied.
Now I wish to make you happy
with my company.
You will be my guests.
- We cannot, we're searching
the Blue Bird.
- The Blue Bird?
But I'm searching the Blue Bird too.
- Why do you need it?
- You'll learn that now.
- Please.
- What's that?
- It's my War.
The two biggest ones have died,
but now I'm growing a third one,
and the generals I've bought
advise me to feed my little one
with the Blue Bird.
They promise that the new war will grow
incredibly huge then
and will conquer the entire world for me.
The entire world.
But I can't buy that darn
Blue Bird anywhere!
- I'm afraid! I want to go home!
- Just a moment. I'll give you
sweets, and you'll forget everything.
- But the Blue Bird...
- Rubbish, rubbish.
If I already can't obtain it with my money,
you will not be able to find it even more.
Don't obstruct me! Otherwise, for
your own well being, I'll use violence.
- Don't take it!
Don't take anything from this table.
Or you'll never find the Blue Bird.
The Blue Bird...
- You're seeking the Blue Bird?
There isn't one here.
- We've gotten so hungry!
- You got hungry?
Take this. Have some bread.
- How sweet! I have never eaten
anything tastier than this bread.
- And me too!
- And me!
- Listen! Listen! Listen!
The Night conceived a black deed.
It's her that sent her sidekick, the Cat,
to steal the Blue Bird from you...
the blue Bird...
Today before sunrise
Night wants to sell the Blue Bird
to the fat Rich man.
If you don't prevent that, the Rich man
will throw the Blue Bird into the War's jaws...
...into the War's jaws...
and an irretrievable disaster
will happen to the Earth.
Hurry on!...
Hurry on!... Hurry on!...
You'll be assisted
by...Fire...
...Water...
...Bread...
They all are ancient helpmates of man
and will
serve you faithfully.
Farewell!..
- Hurry on, human!
We all will follow you,
because you carry the light.
- Leave me be!
It's my bird! I bought it!
- No!
It can't be bought.
It must fly over the Earth in freedom.
The End
Subs by Eus, November 2015, free
after a translation by Pashka Geraskin