Wanna play?
- Let's play baseball.
- I'll get a ball.
"Summer, 1969"
- Bring your bat.
- OK.
Where?
- The usual.
- OK.
A bargain sale!
Cool!
- Lots of bananas!
- By the kilo!
- I want some.
- At a discount.
Come on!
- Thank you.
"What do you call cold hot cakes?"
"From Pun Boy"
"If they're stolen,
they're still hot cakes."
"Mr. Namiya"
Come again.
Hi!
- Hello, how are you doing?
- Good.
- Let's go
- OK.
"Namiya General Store"
"I get sick on buses,
can I become an astronaut?"
Apollo 11 lifted off with three astronauts
on July 16 from Kennedy Space Center, Florida.
It was launched by the Saturn V rocket.
On July 21 at 5:17, 40 seconds,
Japan Standard time
the lunar landing took place.
It was televised live from the lunar surface
to over 60 million anxious viewers.
"Astro..."
"Astronauts..."
"Sailors..."
- Bye, Mr. Namiya!
- Bye, kids.
Namiya Zakkaten no Kiseki
(The Miracles of the Namiya General Store)
"Even astronauts and sailors
get sick at first."
"Don't give up!"
Hurry!
"2012"
Oh, come on!
The battery's dead.
Piece of crap!
We'll have to walk.
What if the cops stop us?
I found a vacant building
when I checked out the area...
Over there.
For real?
Is it far, Shota?
I'm tired.
It's too far!
We're here.
What a mess...
What's this box for?
Milk. Never seen one?
A milk box...
Hold this.
It's open.
Give me that.
It's messy.
Unbelievable!
Look at this cash!
That's what it means to be loaded.
- Gimme!
- There.
And for you.
Do you think she'll be OK?
Who cares?
She wanted the orphanage
to become a love hotel.
I guess so.
We can hide among the
commuters in the morning.
There's no food!
It'd be old anyway.
What a dump!
Namiya General Store has everything!
We could sell it off.
What's this?
What?
What's it say?
"Akiko, March, 1927"
She's hot!
Show me.
That's creepy.
- But...
- It is.
What's that, Kohei?
I looked over here
and saw something drop.
Nobody was there.
"Dear Mr. Namiya"
Here! Namiya General Store.
"General Wisdom"
"At a general store in Tokigoe city"
"Yuji Namiya"
"people post personal questions
through the shutter at night."
"Mr. Namiya puts his advice
in the milk box the next morning."
the milk box...
Is he still doing it?
That's impossible.
The magazine's from 1973.
Right.
"To my mentor,
John Lennon died yesterday..."
Wait.
"John Lennon. died December 8, 1980"
So this letter was written 32 years ago?
It must be a prank.
Someone wants to spook us cuz we broke in.
What kind of prank is that?
Forget that.
Someone must have come.
The police?
We might get caught.
We better go!
Come on!
"From Fishmonger/Musician"
Stop!
We passed here before...!
What?
Did you see that?
What's going on?
We're back where we started...
You're the one who
brought us to this dump!
Lay off!
I'll reply to Fishmonger/Musician.
To a letter from 1980?
I'm never in the position of giving advice.
Give me a break...
I found it.
Have you ever written a letter?
No. I have no idea!
Just copy the musician guy.
Right.
Show me.
What's "mentor" mean...?
Write it your way.
Yeah.
"Dear..."
"Fishmonger/Musician."
"1980"
Hi. Katsuro. Sorry about your grandma.
I'll pay my respects later.
I thought you wouldn't show up.
Mom and Dad are already there.
You have a suit?
I borrowed one.
See you there.
You came.
Of course he did!
Dad collapsed the other day.
Hi, Katsuro. Let me pour you a drink.
How old are you now?
I'm 22.
So you're graduating?
I dropped out.
Sorry?
I quit the university.
Why would you want to do that?
He's a musician in Tokyo.
A musician! Can you make a living?
Not yet...
Big bro, you spoiled him!
Who'll take over your fish shop?
Mind your own business.
Come on! I'm worried about your health.
Come back
and help your dad.
Be quiet!
It's mom's funeral. Show some respect!
Dad!
What am I saying that's so bad?
I'm worried about your husband's health.
Sorry, everyone...
It's here!
"How can I score 100 points on every test?"
"100-point Kid"
"Get your teacher to ask you about yourself."
"Any answer you give will be correct."
"You'll score 100. From Mr. Namiya"
That's bogus advice!
You're a wise man, Mr. Namiya.
You can pay me by buying a notebook!
It's bogus!
"Dear Alley Kid."
"My advice is in the milk box."
You won't buy one?
Katsuro, the bath is ready!
Hey, bro.
Bath.
Is the Namiya General Store still open?
It closed. No one's there anymore.
What happened to the old man?
He closed the shop
and went to live with his son's family.
Remember the advice he used to give?
The more personal advice went in the milk box.
Did other kids look in the box?
No.
Not even the bad kids. We had an agreement.
Dear, Mr. Namiya.
to my mentor, John Lennon died yesterday.
I don't know what you think of the Beatles but
I was one of the impressionable fans
who got a guitar.
Three years ago I quit
school to take up music.
I've come to a crossroad.
"Dear..."
"Fishmonger/Musician"
then what?
Go for it!
That's stupid.
This dreamer needs a reality check
for his own sake.
You write it. Shota.
OK.
Are you satisfied?
Dear Fishmonger/Musician.
I read your letter where you sought advice.
With your family trade to fall back on,
it's a luxurious problem.
Not many people can make
a living from music.
What can I get you?
4 dried fish.
Right away!
My family's fish shop
hardly makes any money.
So investing in myself seems sensible.
God, he's clueless.
I know nothing about your music but
I sure know that you have no talent.
You worked on your music
for three years and gotten nowhere.
I'm not doing this as a hobby.
I'd like you to listen to my music.
Will he write back?
I'll wait outside.
No. You might be seen.
This is Seri's song!
I'd like you to listen to my song.
It's that song.
Yes.
If he wrote that song.
he must have saved Seri's brother.
I have to write to Fishmonger/Musician.
What will I say?
"Dear, Fishmonger..."
Katsuro!
Where have you been?
Dad collapsed again!
Thank you for waiting.
Doctor.
I'll show you the X-ray
and cardiograph results.
there's no abnormality.
I'd say it is fatigue.
His heart is working overtime.
Son, go back to Tokyo now.
Don't say that.
You should relax and get some rest.
Mind your own business.
If you insist on going back to work
I'll help with the shop.
What about your music?
Well...
I'll give it up.
I'll be the last fishmonger in the family.
You don't want me to take over?
Don't be silly!
If you wanted to be a fishmonger.
that's one thing.
But you don't!
I guess not...
Son.
You decided to pursue
music and quit college...
It's only been three years.
Try again, like your life depends on it.
You're up against Tokyo.
It doesn't matter if you lose
as long as you try your best.
Leave your mark in the world.
there's something I want you to know.
You definitely shouldn't give up music.
It has the power to save people.
And your music will be long remembered.
"Eight years later"
I'm here to perform for the kids.
I'm Minazuki. The manager.
Welcome!
May I?
- It's OK.
- Let me.
Say hello!
Hello.
Follow me.
Seri.
OK. Now for the next song.
Hello.
What's the name of the
second song you performed?
Huh. That's a song I wrote myself.
What's it called?
Reborn.
It's about being born again.
The kids loved it.
Another success. It was great.
Thank you.
Um, the girl who just talked to me...
You mean Seri?
She and her brother joined us a year ago.
They were abused by their parents.
Her brother Tatsutoshi only speaks to her.
Bad news.
A power failure has halted the train services.
What bad timing!
You can stay here. We have a spare room.
- I'm OK.
- Go on.
I'm impressed!
You heard it once and you remember it.
Will you become a professional musician?
I am trying hard...
But sometimes plans don't work out.
Please don't give up.
I won't give up music.
I've got nothing to lose now!
When my dad died I promised
to believe in myself.
It's cold! Let's go back.
Will you become a professional musician?
It's an emergency! Get up now!
There's a fire! You have to get out!
Come on. This way!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Calm down, everyone!
Is everyone here?
My brother!
What? Don't go!
Tatsutoshi!
Where is your brother?
He goes out to the balcony
when he can't sleep!
Seri, it's dangerous.
- Hold this!
- Tatsutoshi!
Hey!
Tatsutoshi, answer me!
- Hey!
- Seri!
Help me, Seri!
Hey, here you are!
It's OK, let's go.
Come on.
Cover your mouth. Let's go.
Go!
Tatsutoshi!
Katsuro...
Oh. no!
Katsuro!
Dad, do you think I left my mark in the world?
I didn't win but...
Thank you!
Thank you very much.
OK, now for the next song...
The composer of this song
taught me to believe in myself.
Katsuro Matsuoka wrote the music
and I wrote the lyrics.
He's the man
who sacrificed his life to save my brother.
I hope you like it. It's called Reborn.
"From you I learned the way of life"
"That I can't ever forget"
"Remnant of your precious love"
"Don't need solitude"
"I just pull a faint smile"
"And embrace the night"
"fading from the view"
"Cause in my heart I know"
"You're always here with me"
"Cause in my bones I feel"
"An invisible power levitating me"
"Someday again"
"We'll find each other"
"So say goodbye till then"
"Though I can't touch you anymore"
"I still feel you in the air"
"this song is the proof of life we led"
"With these words on my lips"
"I'll sing for you instead"
"Yes. from the bottom of my heart"
"Ever wondered where"
"You and I came from?"
"All on board this ship of life"
"Where do we go from here?"
"You handed me this torch"
"Now it's my turn"
"To pass it on to someone"
"Don't be sad. Don't lose faith"
"Don't look back. Don't be scared"
"Don't stop trying. Don't quit just yet"
"I want to live"
"As you did"
"Cause in my heart I know"
"You'll be reborn"
"And wait for me"
"Somewhere in eternity"
I hope he received our letters...
"Welcome back. Seri!"
Is it a coincidence that
Seri knew the Fishmonger/Musician?
And that Seri like us was at
Maruko Orphanage?
I don't know.
If we warn the Fishmonger/Musician
about the fire.
He'll live.
But Seri's brother might die.
If we wrote and told him,
he'd never believe it.
The facts around Seri
and the fire are impossible to change.
The old man must've agonized over his advice.
Like we are.
It was just his hobby.
But his advice could have
altered people's lives.
What a big responsibility.
This might work...
Maybe.
Here we go.
It still works.
"January, 1980"
Dad?
In here!
You still write advice?
As long as the letters keep coming.
- Can I have a beer?
- Sure.
Want one?
Maybe later.
Did you receive a difficult problem?
A woman of 25 and her married lover...
That's serious!
Though it is yet to be born
I already love my baby so much.
But is it unfair to raise
a child without a dad?
I apologize for burdening
you with my problem.
But there's no one else I can ask.
I'd appreciate your thoughts.
Kind regards, Green River.
Let's see...
If it's true, she should get an abortion.
Ms. Green River...
She knows she should abort
but she's looking for options.
Dad.
You should move in with us.
Fumiko is concerned
about your health. you know.
Did you hear?
Ouch...
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
Can I have a beer?
Hello, there!
"Autumn, 1980"
Hello.
the days are getting shorter!
Right. Does that make my life shorter?
- Tofu tonight?
- Hot pot.
Nice!
Ouch!
- What's wrong?
- My stomach!
- Are you OK?
- Can you get help?
Hang in there!
See here and here?
It's pancreatic cancer.
He has about three months left.
Let's not tell Dad.
Or should we?
I don't know what to do.
This is tough.
"Mom drowns. Suicide suspected."
"Midori Kawabe"
Mr. Namiya.
Let's go back.
"At 7:00 PM on December 24"
"an economy car drove into the sea
in Tokigoe city."
"A rescue attempt failed
to save the driver."
"An infant was thrown from
the car and survived"
"Police suspect suicide
as the brakes weren't applied."
Look at the dead mother's name.
Is she...?
the woman I gave advice to...
I think it's Ms. Green River.
For many years...
I gave advice to people with problems.
Is it possible...?
Say someone had a problem...
Then I gave them advice that
they followed exactly.
But that could have put them
in a worse situation.
I realized that's how it could end up.
As for me...recently
I've been having strange dreams every night.
People come to the shop to drop letters
in the mail slot.
And I'm watching from elsewhere.
That's not all.
It's happening in the distant future.
It happens decades from now.
The people who come and
drop letters in the mail slot...
People who'd asked my advice in the past.
And I gave them advice.
Because it had a profound
impact on their lives...
they're letting me know.
the dreams aren't just dreams.
I know it.
that's why I know if I go to the shop
there will be letters from those people
waiting for me.
So please, Takayuki.
Please...
take me to the shop.
Do you think
the sickness has made me lose my mind?
I don't have much longer.
Dad...
This is...
my last favor.
OK?
Please take me
to the shop.
Please take me.
This is my will.
You can read it now.
Thank you.
You can go back, Takayuki.
I'll wait here.
Okay.
On the 33rd anniversary of my death
I want the following announcement to be made.
On the XXth day of the month XX...
Fill in the XX with the date of my death.
Between midnight and daybreak
I, Mr. Namiya. will return to give advice.
I have a favor to ask of those who
visited my shop for advice.
Was my advice
helpful to you in the course of your life?
I'd appreciate your honest responses.
Drop your letter in the mail slot
just like you used to.
Accept my gratitude in advance.
Takayuki?
I'll be mad if this is a prank.
Akiko...!
I've always watched over you.
Always...
So you know my life was typical
of a boring man like me.
That's why my wife's life
wasn't easy.
But Mrs. Namiya says her life was so happy.
Oh, I wonder about that.
I hope you don't mind me
speaking to your husband, Mrs. Namiya.
It has been 50 years.
50 years...
How time flew...
Back then
I made it hard for you, Akiko.
It was not your fault, Yuji.
It was me who wanted to elope with you.
...Yes I know. My son, Takayuki
was a quiet boy but he wasn't a loser.
Was it when he was in 4th grade...?
He mastered the pullover on the bars.
And the smile on his
face when he did it...!
I'll never forget it.
He learned at his own pace.
As for my wife and I...
I guess we spoiled him.
My general store is worthless...
But to me it's as valuable as a castle.
You helped many people in your life.
The letters prove it.
I really didn't do much.
"Dear Mr. Namiya"
I hope you remember me.
I asked you how to score
100 points on every test.
I'm the 100-point Kid. "Your Test"
Your advice inspired me to new heights.
And I became a teacher.
I made sure all my students scored 100 points.
the parents were supportive of my method
and I'm now the Headmaster
at Tokigoe Junior High.
I suppose Mr. Namiya's family
will get this letter.
I'd appreciate it if you
could put this on his shrine.
Dear Mr. Namiya.
I learned about your return on the Net
and felt compelled to write to you.
"Maruko Orphanage"
I grew up in an orphanage.
My caregivers told me
that my mom died in a
car accident when I was a baby.
Are you scared?
Then...
I'm with you.
I was in my first year at high school.
In social studies
we researched events
around the time of our births.
I looked through old newspapers.
I found an article.
The woman in the article was Midori Kawabe.
She was my mom.
That came as such a big shock
that I just lost it.
Knock. knock!
Eiko.
Seri...
It's so nice out.
The breeze smells of spring.
I talked to the orphanage manager.
He told me why you first came to
the orphanage and how your mom died.
You understand nothing.
But I know everything.
I'm a love child.
She tried to kill me... My own mother.
You're wrong.
Here.
the Manager kept this for you.
"to Ms. Green River"
It was found in my mother's belongings.
It was your reply to her, Mr. Namiya.
"More than anything"
"the child's welfare is important."
"Would you put your child's
happiness before anything?"
"Without that resolve
you shouldn't have a child."
Your mom kept that letter with her.
That means
your mom decided to put
your happiness first.
She wouldn't commit suicide.
On the day of the crash
she'd been working night and day.
I had a fever and in order
to take me to the doctor...
Midori.
...she'd borrowed her friend's car.
Thank you.
We'll be there soon.
That's what her friend told the police.
She didn't commit suicide.
She just fell asleep.
Eiko, your mom...
She tried so hard to raise you.
So what?
She virtually made the accident happen.
If I hadn't been born
she wouldn't have had the accident!
Eiko.
Do you remember the fire?
Remember Katsuro Matsuoka,
the musician who played for us?
He...
He sacrificed his
life to save my brother.
That's why from now on...
I'll live my life
in gratitude to him.
I don't want anyone to die...
...you included.
Eiko, I want you to know
how precious you are.
And how much your mom wanted you.
Eiko.
You and I...
We have a great future ahead.
Why don't we believe that?
"Ever since that day
I accepted Mom's love"
"and I live my life to its fullest."
"I can say this with confidence now."
"I'm so glad I was born."
"From Green River's daughter."
I feel like I received
a wonderful reward at the end of my life.
Looks like another letter was posted.
Let's see.
I was here the whole time
you were in the shop, Dad.
And no one was anywhere near the shop.
Of course not.
Because all these letters
were sent from the future.
People learned from the Net
that I was returning for advice.
What's the Net?
I don't know.
How will the world
change in the future...?
What kind of man was Mr. Namiya?
I don't know.
Maybe he started giving advice
because he was lonely?
Who wants to know?
Oh, it's out!
We got one!
"To Mr. Namiya"
Dear, Mr. Namiya.
I recently graduated from high school.
I'm an office clerk by day
and a club hostess at night.
I'm a lost puppy.
A client offered to
help me start a business
if I agreed to be his mistress.
Now I'm in a fix.
I'm an orphan and I need a lot of money
so I can repay my foster parents.
Yours truly. Lost Puppy,
December 12, 1980.
No way!
This one's from 1980, too!
What are you up to, Kohei?
I'll answer.
To a greedy mistress?
I'll tell her not to work in a club.
You have to be more specific.
What's wrong with you guys?
We're fugitives.
Who needs advice from losers like us?
Be quiet!
Whatever.
She'll be tricked by various men
and end up being a single mom
to a no-good kid.
Just like you.
Say that again.
She's not your mother!
- She's...
- Stop!
Same goes for you too!
A baby left in a locker...
Stop it.
A mother who loses it
and abuses her own kid.
What advice is there?
We all have a destiny
and it can't be changed so easily!
OK.
Let me reply to this woman.
"1980"
This is what I told you about.
- Really?
- It's yours.
Thank you so much.
Come to my second house this weekend.
This weekend...
- What?
- I have a plan.
A boyfriend?
I have no boyfriend or a child.
A child...?
How old are you, Harumi?
19, I mean 20.
She looks young. You're 22, right?
- Almost.
- Are you a teenager?
- I'm sorry!
- No problem!
Wipe him down.
A little higher.
Poor Harumi! You came on your day off...
It's nothing.
Your fridge is empty. Can I get you anything?
If you could get some vegetables and...
some canned food please.
How about some sashimi?
I got paid so it's on me.
Remember, luxuries are sinful.
Are you OK?
I'm fine. Maybe I get too relaxed
when you come.
You'd better rest.
You after Mr. Namiya?
The shop's closed but
he still answers letters.
Right.
Do you know how to do it?
You have a fantasy view of the world.
Work earnestly as a clerk.
that's the best way to
repay your foster parents.
Dear, Mr. Namiya. Thank you for your reply.
Your harsh opinion disappointed me.
I don't have a fantasy view of the world.
to be a mistress and start a business
sounds like a fantasy.
I'll repay him when my business succeeds.
What if it doesn't do well?
I'll succeed by studying hard.
What will you study?
Do you have a business strategy?
More importantly, can you trust your client?
And why do you need money so badly?
I lost my parents early
and grew up in an orphanage.
When I was around ten,
I went to live with dad's uncle and aunt.
They helped me through high school.
Let me do it!
Can you. Honey?
They're old now and are
struggling financially.
They have a house mortgage.
I'd do anything to repay them
and help pay their debt.
that's all I want now.
Lost Puppy's an orphan, too.
Maruko Orphanage?
So what if it was?
I mean, everything seems connected...
Lost Puppy's such a good girl.
How do you know that?
From the letters.
What's going to happen to her?
I want her to be happy...
If you trust me and follow my advice
your wish might come true.
Lost Puppy, you shouldn't become a mistress.
- Harumi.
- Yes!
In a few years Japan will
experience an economic boom.
Work hard and prepare for it by studying
economy and finance.
I'm sorry!
Save up and buy a small condo
in central Tokyo.
Its price will rise.
Sell it and buy a better condo.
Repeat the process.
Use the profit as capital for stock
and a golf club membership.
Your homework will
help you make the right decisions.
"Little Puppy Co. Ltd"
"1988"
You deserve a larger office as a company owner.
A good building's on sale in Nishi Azabu.
But you'd better hurry. We'll give you a loan.
Actually I'm thinking
of liquidating some assets.
In this boom? Are you crazy?
The 90's won't be like this.
My life is so good, thanks to you.
I got to keep the house.
Don't thank me.
Who else is there to thank?
- Here.
- thank you.
Next in the news
Maruko Orphanage in Tokigoe city
burned down
and a musician died in the fire.
One child was trapped inside and
the musician, Katsuro Matsuoka,
attempted to rescue him.
the child escaped safely but not the musician.
He was found unconscious
on the first floor.
He died at the hospital
from carbon monoxide poisoning.
Thank you for the supplies.
I'm so sorry for the young man
who died in the fire.
It's good that all the kids survived.
Yes, no kids or employees were hurt
in the inferno.
Maybe my sister's protecting us.
Your sister?
the founder of the orphanage.
Akiko Minazuki.
Take care of this.
She had a heart problem and died very young.
I didn't know...
Right before she passed away
she said she'd watch
over everyone from above.
What was she like?
A very active, free-spirited woman.
She was a high school student
when she ran off with our servant!
Ran off! It sounds very romantic.
The servant felt unworthy
and ended the relationship.
That's how it was back then...
Now what else is there to do?
Sir.
If you don't mind
I'd like to help your orphanage in some way.
Thank you.
"December, 2012"
Atsuya!
What's up?
I missed you.
- We're playing cards.
- Cool!
Are you going to be a doctor, Atsuya?
Why?
Because you're smart enough
to be one.
"I want to be a surgeon"
It takes more than being smart.
Why?
Because.
Life's hard.
A love hotel?
Be quiet!
Who's that woman anyway?
Her company is in Tokyo
but her parents' house is here.
So she knew this place?
Yes. She's going to build a love hotel
and pachinko parlor here.
Are you sure?
I overheard the staff talking about it.
I'll go...
and ask Kariya.
The witch plans to demolish
the orphanage and get rich.
But then what will happen to the kids?
They'll be separated...
and go to other orphanages.
There's nothing we can do to stop it.
Shota, did you say she has a house here?
Yeah. She sometimes comes back on weekends.
I bet she has a luxurious condo in Tokyo.
Let's punish her.
I won't beat up a woman.
No, we'll just mess up her house...
while she's away.
Another padded invoice.
So Mr. Kariya keeps the profits
from inflated subsidies.
Yes. Maruko Orphanage is
close to bankruptcy.
Mr. Minazuki would be devastated
if he was alive...
Thank you.
"Maruko Orphanage Managing Policy"
"Manager Mamoru Kariya"
If you trust me and follow my advice
your wish might come true.
Liquidate your investments
before the boom suddenly ends in the 90's.
In the 21st century, cell phones and
the internet will change the world.
Mr. Namiya.
Everything turned out as you predicted.
New business opportunities will arise.
This is my last reply to you.
"Mr. Namiya is back
on the 32nd Anniversary of his death"
I'll no longer be corresponding.
Best regards, Namiya.
"December 20 from midnight to dawn"
"Mr. Namiya's back 32 years after his death."
"tell me if my advice helped."
32 years ago in the winter of 1980
I asked you for advice. I'm Lost Puppy.
Hello.
I've come here to discuss
an awkward subject.
Ms. Tamura.
I'm grateful for your support
which began before I was manager...
But I'm in charge of running the orphanage...
Mr. Kariya.
Yes?
In regard to the operations
I've had my people go over the accounts.
Be quiet and we won't harm you.
We won't let you turn Maruko Orphanage...
into a love hotel!
Hey, don't talk!
Wait! Who's turning the orphanage
into a love hotel?
Who are you?
Why would I do such a terrible thing?
Shut up! Hold this.
Let's go.
What do you think happened to Lost Puppy?
She'd be fine...
if she followed our advice.
Who'd believe a bogus prophecy?
I bet she threw it out.
Look at this!
"Mr. Namiya's back 32 years after his death."
So he died 32 years ago today!
That explains this strange phenomenon!
- Let's experiment.
- It's blank...
It'll be OK.
Watch the mail slot.
I'll post it.
Looks like another letter was posted.
Let's see.
Maybe I should write my last advice.
Yes.
- Well?
- Nothing came through.
I can vouch for that.
I knew it.
The letter I posted...
will be delivered 32 years in the past.
But what happens when it's dawn in our time?
I guess old man Namiya dies.
How did you find this place, Shota?
I followed that woman to find her house.
She dropped by here on her way back to Tokyo.
What for?
How would I know? She looked at the shop sign.
So I made a note of it.
Are you stupid?
No one lives here so I thought it was ideal...
What's the woman's name?
Haruko Tamura...?
Tamura...
Harumi Tamura.
"To Mr. Namiya"
32 years ago in the winter of 1980
I asked for your advice. I'm Lost Puppy.
I followed your advice
and went on to have a successful life.
I don't know how to
thank you for your wisdom.
Now it's my turn to help others.
That's the only way I know
to repay your favor.
How come...?
What's going on?
What the hell is going on?
There's something...
What is it?
This shop must be connected to
Maruko Orphanage!
It's like someone above is controlling us.
Right down to our break-in!
Shut up!
Calm down.
Are you thinking of turning yourself in?
You want to go to jail?
I'll go...
to her house.
Don't be ridiculous.
Shota...?
Hey!
Atsuya.
Do as you like.
- We have to untie her.
- Right.
Dear Mr. No Name.
Why did you post me a blank letter?
This old man tried to figure it out.
It's just a thought but
maybe it represents the state of your mind.
You can't see where your life's going now.
But please don't despair.
Don't give up hope.
Your future is a blank sheet of paper.
Your future is whatever you write on it.
Everything is up to what you do.
You're free to do anything.
The possibilities are endless.
Hopefully you'll make every day
of your life worthwhile.
Have a fulfilling life.
I thought my days of giving advice were over.
This last one was very challenging to answer.
I appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
Best regards, Namiya General Store.
Dear Mr. Namiya. Thank you for your kind reply.
I don't think my advice...
could change someone's life.
Then why did I write to her?
I just wanted her to be happy.
Perhaps her trust in me made her happy.
I want to meet her and tell her the truth.
It was her who made choices
that changed her life.
I can't comprehend the timeless encounters
we had last night.
But you taught me to believe
and I appreciate that.
I'm afraid you won't receive this letter.
But I think that you'll be
watching over us from somewhere.
Sincerely, No Name.
Who'd do this to you?
I have no idea.
We'll put more officers
on patrol.
OK.
Thank you.
"From you I learned the way of life"
"That I can't ever forget"
"Remnant of your precious love"
"Don't need solitude"
"I just pull a faint smile"
"And embrace the night"
"fading from the view"
Ryosuke Yamada
"Cause in my heart I know"
Nijiro Murakami
"You're always here with me"
"Cause in my bones I feel"
Kanichiro
"An invisible power levitating me"
Kento Hayashi
"Someday again"
Rico Narumi
"We'll find each other"
Mugi Kadowaki
"So say goodbye till then"
"Though I can't touch you anymore"
"I still feel you in the air"
"This song is the proof of life we led"
"With these words on my lips"
"I'll sing for you instead"
"Yes, from the bottom of my heart"
"Ever wondered where"
"You and I came from?"
Masato Hagiwara
"All on board this ship of life"
"Where do we go from here?"
Machiko Ono
"You handed me this torch"
"Now it's my turn"
Toshiyuki Nishida
"To pass it on to someone"
Executive Producer
Shinichiro Inoue
"Don't be sad. Don't lose faith"
Executives in Charge of Production
Daiji Horiuchi
Toshihiro Takahashi
Satoshi Matsui
Julie K. Fujishima
Masahiro Handa
"Don't look back. Don't be scared"
Produced by Shigeo Minakami
Producers Naohiko Ninomiya Hidehisa Chiwata
"Don't stop trying. Don't quit just yet"
Based on the Novel
"Namiya Zakkaten no Kiseki"
by Keigo Higashino
Screenplay by Hiroshi Saito
"I want to live"
Director of Photography
Atsuhiro Nabeshima
Lighting Director Takafumi Kitaoka
"As you did"
Sound Recording by Akira Fukada
Production Designer
Tomoyuki Maruo Masato Nakagawa
Edited by Junichi Kikuchi
"Cause in my heart I know"
"You'll be reborn"
"And wait for me"
"Somewhere in eternity"
"Our souls live on"
"Beyond time and space"
Music by Rayons
"Someday again"
"We'll find each other"
Music Produced by Shin Yasui
Theme Song "REBORN" by Tatsuro Yamashita
"So let's say goodbye till then"
"And many thanks to you"
"Until we meet again, say goodbye"
Presented by "The Miracles of
the Namiya General Store" Film Partners
A KADOKAWA DAIEI STUDlO Production
Directed by Ryuichi Hiroki
2017 "The Miracles of
the Namiya General Store" Film Partners