One, Two, Three
Start!
Go on!
Faster! Faster!
Uncle John,look at our horse
He's winning!
Fantastic!
Bravo!
He's still first,
He's won
He did it!
Congratulations Jane
- Thank you
A lesson Donald
We should learn not to bet on
longshots quite so often
With women,you're much luckier
With all except you
Sorry Peter,but I'm mad
about your bride to be
Then our new family will
require a new doctor
Very wise of you,
I must warn you that Doctor Wells
writes big bills as amusement
Talking of finances,
would you Uncle John?
Oh but of course
- Thank you
Hello Peter
- Oh Ted Burke
I have to speak to
him for a moment
Excuse me dear
Do you know, Donald
How come peter is so friendly
with the chief inspector
of Scotland yard
No idea, it cant hurt though
Having a policeman
for a friend
Hello Burke
- Hello Peter
Since when did you start
following the horses?
Actually I prefer football,
Real Madrid and Birmingham play today
At the moment 6 to 2 favour the Spaniards
But it's not over yet
What brings you here then?
- I'm here on business
There is a lot of money here
In banknotes
Ah of course
You're on the lookout for that forger
In the past week,
a great many five pound notes have turned up
watch out you don't get stuck Peter
- Thanks for the tip
Quite alright
What's happening?
Another goal for the Spaniards
See you tomorrow?
- I'll be there
Your wedding is one thing I'm
not going to miss
You're lucky Jane
Thank you
- You got top odds, Eighty for Ten
I'll try my luck again
- You dreamer
Her Majesty
- The Queen
Peter, I’m betting on this race,come along
- Not right now
Donald...
I'm not sure I'm doing the right thing
I love Jane
But I don't want to bring her any sorrow
That's a lot of nonsense
By tomorrow you're the envy of all London
You're a wonderful couple indeed
You're to be envied my friend
What is it Jane?
You look worried
The lucky bride should be...
- I'm not the lucky bride
I don't think I'll go through with it
My love is not enough for him
Oh you must stop this Jane
Don't be so foolish dear
Before she died,
I promised your mother I'd look after you
And now you've found Peter,
Peter is the finest,the best of men
Your Mother would have said...
- Yes,yes of course
Look Jane
I'm getting old,I'm not too well
I want to see you happily married
Why does Peter want to marry me?
I can't believe he loves me so
How can you feel that way?
He'd never have asked you
to marry him if he didn't love you
Hello Jane
- Hello Basil
Mr Leith
- Hello Hale
I just wanted to have a look at
the blushing bride here
Lovely as ever
Listen Jane,why don't you go dancing
with me for the last time
Basil.. you're impossible
- No more so than your fiancé, Peter Clifton
I must admit,I never thought you'd marry him
We might have had so much good fun my dear
Never mind your foolishness Hale,
it might not amuse Peter
Well..
Good day Clifton,I've just made my last
effort to take your fiancé away
It's impossible I'm afraid
Still,I expect an invitation
to attend your wedding
Don't count on it Hale!
Give up will you Hale
- Give up..
Why?
I might hold a trump you know
Then play it
Don't talk
All things in good time...
my dear boy
Five pounds on lord Byron
Thanks
Come over here,this note is forged
on the reverse side it's stamped
Dr Donald Wells
This is certainly his poorest job to date
They've been getting progressively worse
That hundred dollar note
last year wasn't too bad
Come look at this one
Here, here and here
Remarkably careless work, for such an expert
- No doubt he's getting over confident
Not very likely
I see you still cant resist
jumping to easy conclusions
But your deduction is incorrect Stanley
You see our forger is only a man
He has to have some off days, we all do
He has his weaknesses
Yes that’s true of course
But how do we explain such
obvious carelessness?
Perhaps he's...
And what if this
five pound note isn't his work?
This note is his work as sure as
two and two equals four
That I can prove to you
Simply compare this
five pound note with the
ten pound note,
he made three years ago
It was a fine job, but it revealed
a flaw on the left side
I'll pick it up Stanley
The press treat him like a film star
Yes, you see the mistakes
on this note are
almost identical with that
one of three years ago
Conclusive prove its the same man
Sorry Stanley, it can hardly
be called conclusive
It could very well be coincidence
- I can't accept that Chief Inspector
No, I put my bet on my theory
Its his work alright,I'm sure
And if his work is this poor
a clumsy forger is easier to catch
And this great forger
could fall into our hands
In time Stanley
But when a criminal knows
he's made mistakes
he becomes savage,
and much more dangerous
It takes over his thinking
And I'm absolutely sure
he would resort to murder if needed
Ah Bert,I'm glad Scotland Yard could be here
- Have no fear Peter
The whisky and I agree splendidly
Oh Doctor,do you have a moment to spare?
This is inspector Rouper,my associate
One question he'd like to ask you
- This bank note,did you use it?
It has your name stamped on it
- Yes I could have
I did bet, only yesterday
A five pound note, it's true
But who knows if it's the same one
In any case, you did pass it
So?
- It's forged
How did it come into your possession?
- Yes, I recall
A patient, he paid his bill with it
- Where is the patient?
Well he's right here...
Mr Clifton
Mr Clifton, where did you get it?
That question is difficult,
It could be a bank
I don't keep a record book
I'm not use to my bills being stamped
That's enough Rouper...
Mr Clifton will inform us
if he learns anything, come on..
I don't like it Peter...
Isn't the Chief inspector
supposed to be your friend?
As your guest,he should have tried to
prevent this embarrassment
Come on,let's get a drink
An inspector from Scotland Yard
here on business could be ill at ease,
but as a guest you're welcome
- Thank you,but you know I don't drink
I though you would have joined me in a
toast to the capture of the forger
Tonight,yes Chief Inspector
- Of course,cheers
Inspector Rouper behaves as if
you forged that note yourself
Why its possible for anyone to have
such a banknote and not know it
This forger seems a very
talented fellow indeed
Unfortunate,such talent
the bank of England could use
I prefer talent,did you know Peter
is a copper plate engraving genius?
Yes,Uncle John let me take a
look at some of his etchings
It's a hobby,I do very little
If I was blessed with
half your talent Peter,
I might have done paintings
that were acknowledged
Tell me, have you found that printing plate
that you borrowed from Peter some time ago?
I'm afraid not,
and I believe you're mistaken Peter,
I'm sure I gave them all back
But I'm not worried at all,
if you find it, good... if not, no loss
My goodness,it's hale
Well here I am...
There you are...
I do hope you're having fun
Now a toast,I wish you
both a jolly wedding night
And a house full of little kiddies
As it says in the bible,
be fruitful and multiply
And I will drink to the women,
girls everywhere by the millions,
Poor but pretty,and marry for money
He's drunk,no Peter
I know exactly what's happening here
You gave up your affection for me,
so your poor stupid sick uncle
could stop being a kitsch postcard Picasso,
and have security and comfort
Your motives are admirable
For you..
- This is for you!
Better open the door
I'm sorry Jane...
I must say this,your wedding day
has certainly been full of surprises.
May your lives together
continue to be as exciting
To get to Longford Castle by daylight,
we have to leave right away,excuse me
What luck you have dear,
that awful castle he chooses for a honeymoon
Mr Hale,you have a message
Who gave this to you?
- I didn't recognise him
Goodbye,thanks for coming...
Stop!
Peter Clifton!
I caught you before you got away
Stop! You can't avoid me
I'm aware of that
I've been through all this before
I'm Mrs Anderson,of course
he's never told you about me
We will not hold a discussion here
We can talk when I return to town
One moment!
I want this girl to know
the man she's going to live with
Calm down and hold your tongue!
You're guilty of stealing
his inheritance,
the birthright of your own brother
She's off her head, come..
Don't believe a word of it,
the woman is mad!
Stop! If the day comes and I think you're
getting away with any of this
I'll be ready to shoot
you down like a filthy dog!
You better watch what you're
saying you hysterical fool
It is foolish Mrs Anderson...
What you are saying can
have value for the police,
and shouldn't be publicly
announced like this
Why are you butting in?
I'm a friend of the accused,
Peter Clifton
Why didn't you tell me you had a brother?
I didn't want to bother you with
the affairs of my family
I was wrong,it's my fault
What she said,is it true?
- Of course not!
Sorry,I'm a bit upset I suppose
That stupid scene with the banknote
Those men from Scotland Yard, then that
scene with Mrs Anderson, have me on edge
Perhaps we would have been better off
with a honeymoon in Rhodesia
Do you have a goldmine there?
- Why do you ask that?
Just that,you're a rich man
uncle John says you're quite wealthy
That money was left to me by my father
There's no mystery
Why did you decide on Longford Castle,
do you own it?
No, I simply rented it for a few weeks
- Ever been there?
Yes, uncle John recommended it,
you'll find it comfortable
I hope we're done with those nerve racking
surprises at last, like Mrs Anderson..
Don't worry...
I'm not going to let my family
problems accompany us.
Especially not now...
He's coming, go!
Why?,he can't see in
through the mirror
I told you to go!
Ahh, Mr Basil Hale
And what can I do for you?
Here,you told me to come
I know.. I know
You wanted to speak to me,
Mr Blonberg?
Yes,to warn you once more,
stay away from Jane
Why? She attracts me,
and I like the game
It's my private affair anyway
As long as it doesn't
interfere with business,
I don't care how many
women you chase
But with Jane, I have my own plans,
is that clear?
I hear you..
You can go now
Well,what is it?
Some more cash
- 200 pounds just three days ago?
A shabby 200 pounds...
It's not my affair if you
can't manage your money
Now get out of here before I get angry
Out!
Is there something I can get you Sir?
No thank you James, that'll be all
You seem to be in rather a strange mood,
you don't look very happy
Really?
I'm afraid this isn't really
the time to talk about it,
but I want you to know,
that I plan to deposit
100.000 pounds in an account for you
That's generous
It's just money..
- It's a fortune, really
Apparently you think
it's enough to buy a woman
Jane...
It's most convenient for
you to buy a woman,isn't it?
Except for one thing,
you may never buy my love
Jane,I know all that,but...
I love you...
As my husband,you have rights
I want only what you are prepared to give me
Then I'm afraid we have nothing more to say
Goodnight
- Goodnight
Who's there please?
- It's me madam
I have been waiting
- Thank you
Who live in this room before?
- Oh nobody lived here
Why not? It's a nice room
- I don't know
You must know who owns the house...
An old gentleman who lives abroad,
if he's still among the living
The manager is Blonberg
Sometimes he comes and stays here for
a while madam, but I don't see him
What,you mean you've never seen him?
No madam, when Mr Blonberg comes,
he brings his own staff, a filthy bunch
They leave the place like
a pig sty,the filthy pigs
Where are you when Mr Blonbergs here?
I stay with my brother in London,
we're all given leave with full pay
Is there anything else
I can do for you madam?
No thank you
Then goodnight
- Goodnight
Peter!
Peter! Peter!
Yes,what is it?
Jane!
Oh Peter,a man was
in my room just now,
I'm so frightened,where were you
I've been in your room looking
- A man in your room you know who...
No, I thought he came in from outside
and then I thought maybe it was you
But I was down here in... the hall,
you wait here, I'll be right back
I've looked everywhere, I saw no one
Jane, you'll catch a cold,
come up to your room
No, thank you, I'm all right
Please connect me with
London west end 4316
You can't imagine how disturbed I am
Is it at all likely Peter,
that the man she saw was you?
That's what’s so un-nerving,
I have no idea whether I was in
her room last night or not
I think when she called out,
I was... downstairs
Help me Wells, I must know the truth
- We will see
But In your case,
I don't think you would have forgotten
I recall your father had an illness,
that you fear was hereditary
That doesn't mean you
must be sick too.
You must believe that
you're well and normal
You must be upset,but I think
your fears are unfounded
After all,didn't professor Clores
clearly say so?
And he's a respected colleague
Do you know Anna where the keys
are for the upstairs room?
Well Mr Clifton had them, but I...
- It's alright,I can find them
Did you find the keys?
Oh yes, one question Anna,
when did Mr Blonberg last come?
The beginning of April, madam
Stayed long?
- No, only one night
Most of the time, Mr Blonberg comes
in the evening and leaves in the morning
Thank you
Yes of course Peter, if it helps
you relax, I'll stay and be glad to
Thank you Donald, I'm in your debt of course
Oh, you have company
Good morning Donald
- Good morning
I've prevailed on Donald
to spend a few days with us
We have some matters we have to discuss
Yes, I ought to give my Marjorie a call
The telephone is in the hall
- Oh thanks
Say hello to Marjorie for us
- Of course
Peter, there's something I must show you
Is this that lost plate?
I found it in your room in a cabinet
- You've gone through my things!
Why shouldn't I?
- Jane excuse me, I'm shaky and nervous
In my things you say?
It seems uncle John gave
all the plates back then
I guess it was packed
into my luggage somehow
I've barely left London,
and my Marjorie is stepping out
Well I would say any tired marriage
needs something new eh?
Or it'll get dull
A man sometimes meets the right person,
a little too late
Oh but Marjorie is right for you
Yes of course, but knowing you,
I draw parallels
I thought you were Peters friend
True,but imagine what I would do
if I were not his friend
What you would do, is of no interest
Hello Jane,
I hope you're not frightened to see me
You are mad,
to risk getting another beating...
What do you want?
I brought Marjorie here,
and I knew I would see you meanwhile
How are you, are you contented?
No worries?
None of your business!
You have to know,
although you're his wife now.
I love you Jane
Leave me alone, get lost.. vanish!
Alright, I will... lots of luck
Of course you know that Clifton
married you under a false name
What do you mean by that?
Didn't he tell you that
Wellerson is his name?
Wellerson?
And of course you don't know why
Dr Wells is staying here with him
Because Peter got from his father,
not just money
he also inherited his madness
That's a lie!
That Wellerson was mad,
and died a prisoner in Dartmoor
After he murdered to innocent
victims for no reason
Now Peter calls himself Clifton,he's mad!
That's why..
You liar...
Don't believe me?
Just ask Dr Wells
I think you should realise what kind of man
your stupid uncle chose for you
I warn you Jane,
you're playing with a madman
Hale!
What are you looking for here?
Peter..
Do you dare to come here?
I thought I ought to open
Jane's eyes for her
One moment, Hale..
All of this nonsense,
we'll talk about later on..
But I'm going to straighten you out now,
for something else
This must be a joke..
You sneaked into my wife’s room last night
It's time you learned not to insult Jane,
and I'm going to give you the lesson
Peter!
Careful!
Hale!
What are you doing?
Now Jane, go!
- Donald... Donald!
You might need this knife
when you learn how to use it
I'm not yet finished with you
Peter Wellerson!
But I'm through with you
How come that Hale is here?
- He brought me out here
You have a special gift
for the complicating things
Blinded by love,
I must look after the fellow
Peter, you were absolutely marvellous
I really thought that you might kill him
Next time I could do just that
- It was awful..
What stories did he tell you?
- I just can't talk about it now
Forget about Jane,
of course I'm nuts about her,
but that isn't why I came here
What would a playboy like you want,
other than that?
You don't know me Doctor,
that's too bad...
How about I could tell you things,
that'll leave you speechless I'll bet
Longford Castle is a fantastic place,
it could be where our
forger friend plays his game
Surprised?
- Yes, very surprised
If I wanted to, I could reveal his name
Every now and then,
Peter seems so strange, dear
Peter isn't insane,if that's what you mean
No dear, but his father was.
The scars on his face might remind you,
his father threw acid in that face
when Peter was a very young boy
Please, I've heard enough
Yes yes, of course,
perhaps he just pretends madness
Nonsense, after all, I'm his wife now
Does Donald ever talk to you
about Peters illness?
No no, remember,a doctor never
talks about his patients at any time
well Jane, are you a contented wife now?
Excuse me, but I could relax now,
if... if I knew you were happy
Why?
Restless young wives attract men,
who are restless after years of marriage
I don't understand
- I speak of my husband
Now listen Peter, I've been thinking,
your recent thinking lacks clarity
Now for example,you don't know for sure,
if you were in Jane’s room or not
Understand?
- Yes
And the etchings you do..
Of course,they're excellent works
But that's not unusual for schizophrenics...
I mean that,a talent like you have
I can't say for sure,
but I can say that Hale,
thinks... you're the forger
That's absurd!
- Everything has to be considered
Donald, am I imagining that I inherited
my fathers illness or am I really...
Take it easy now..
I'll give you an injection later,
just to calm you
Yes, fine Donald
Is that you Peter?
- No it's me, Jane
I'm sorry Jane,
I thought that you were still up
This castle, I can't think
of it as home at all
You might go sleep in your house then
- I would, he doesn't want to
And how is Peter?
- I think he's sleeping
Donald gave him something to sleep..
- Oh good..
You didn't know that before
Donald came here, Thank you
He had a very poor
practise in South London,
we weren't very well off then
Matches are over there..
- Thank you
He met Mr Blonberg in London,
a hypochondriac
Mr Blonberg,
the manager of the castle?
- Yes, that's possible,
he dabbles in everything
Then he loaned Donald a lot of cash,
we moved to the West End,
and things looked up
Yes, Donald’s good at making impressions
Minds that are sick,
need a doctor
they can have faith in,that's all
What was that!
What... what was that awful scream?
No! no!
Turn on the light first!
What is it?
Nothing..
- Then what was it?
Maybe just an owl
- No no, that wasn't an owl,
that was a lunatic
Yes... yes, a lunatic
Donald once took me into
an asylum for lunatics
The things that I saw and heard there..
Shrieks and cries,
a man cried out just as if he..
What was that?
It's at the door!
I'll find out..
No, don't open that door, I beg you don't!
- No ones there at all..
I'm terrified...
Jane, come with me to my rooms will you...
Surely,if it'll make you feel better
Yes..
Are you really so frightened?
- How frightened I am, you can't imagine
One moment, I'll see if anyone’s in my room
No, Jane, thank you
- Sleep well..
Peter.. Peter..
Hale... you swine!
Jane, what are you doing
out here in the garden?
I saw you from the window..
- Hale!
Is he dead?
Yes, he's dead
Skull crushed,with a hammer I guess,
or something
Is Peter awake?
I have no idea,
I haven't been to his room yet
We'll go to him,we must touch
nothing here 'till the police come
Open the curtains will you..
What the... What's wrong with him?
I imagine it's the injection you gave him
- Yes, but it should have worn off
Peter! hello..
Peter!
Oh.. my poor head,
it's going to burst wide open
He's half dressed,
where are his other clothes?
That's not important now
Donald,that was a
strong injection you gave me
I feel awful..
Yes, it will soon go away
You look at me so strangely,
what do you want of me?
You should have a sedative
Peter, someone was killed in the garden
Killed?
Who?
Jane found the body, Basil Hale...
Hale... was murdered?
Do you know who...
Drink..
A London newspaper...
Yes, printed at 4 o'clock
But the body was found at about 7
That means they got
an early report
Perhaps it could be the
murderer himself
Alright, let's get the stretcher
aboard and get moving!
Burke! You're here,
that's a bit of a surprise..
Well, I don't know about that, Peter
I asked the Chief Inspector to come out
You know why..
I've no idea..
But Peter, don't you recall?
Basil Hale was Brutally murdered
Yes Peter, we told you about it
- Hale was murdered, when?
Last night, probably just after 12
How do you know it was after midnight?
Anyway, I slept through it..
Just before 12,
Hale gave Scotland Yard a call
He claimed that he knew Longford Castle
was the place that the forger worked
He said that a room hidden
behind that bookcase,
had a complete forgery operation in it
Forgery here, that bookcase?
- Yes, Hale was very specific,come on
Hello, Rouper, what brings you here?
You don't mind I hope,
Dr wells asked me to come
Yes, two inspectors
can find twice as much
Very good, let's check that room
Well look, now that's a surprise
Our boy is a fast mover..
There's now doubt about it,
acids have been used here
Yes, you can see where the
printing press was fastened
Do you believe the forger was in here?
- Once again, he's too fast for us
He is clever
Yes,but there's a murder,
for which I have our man, Mr Clifton
You're not serious Inspector
- I am
No, he is not serious,
Please ring up Scotland Yard and find out
who informed them of the murder
I already did that
The telephone operator
of the local exchange,
said it was Mr Clifton on the line
He recognised the voice
from previous calls
Even so Rouper,
we can't bring in Mr Clifton
until we find the weapon
with which Hale was killed
We've found no such weapon,have we?
Is it a wonder that the weapon is missing?
Do you really expect,
the murderer has it in his room?
He might think we're that naive
Who's there?
- It's me, Peter
Why do you lock the door?
- No reason
You're packing?
You changed my clothes last night..
A bloody shirt doesn't suit you.
Your hands had to be washed too
I don't remember that
I really killed that man
I've been terrified of
doing something like...
My father..
Jane...
I did an awful thing,getting you into this
Jane, you can still go away
I'm your wife,and I won't just give you up..
Thank you Jane..
There must be no secrets between us
- Should I tell Burke everything?
No, don't tell him yet, you can
tell him about the fight, but no more...
Good Jane, you go back
to London with Burke
He said he would take you
Oh, but it's here I want to be, dear
No Jane, I must handle this alone
But it means so much that you understand
That wasn't much of a honeymoon
- I might just go back tomorrow
Peter loves you, and you?
- You have to ask?
In London, they feel his money attracted you
That's partially true of course
But my feelings towards Peter
changed when I knew of his danger
Funny, Isn't it?
I can understand, and I'm glad for Peter
It doesn't look good for him at all
The circumstantial evidence is against him
Too bad the murder weapon
didn't turn up
It could change our entire approach
You tell me now, you wouldn't know
where the hammer might be?
I? How should I?
My dear young woman,
you want another thousand pounds?
That's a lot of money
- I'm not worth a lot of money?
Once my legacy is straightened out,
there will be millions in my hands
It won't go that far now Mrs Anderson
- What are you inferring?
You can thank your imbecilic son
Oh but Basil is a clever young fellow
You just have something against him!
Several times I warned him
to leave Jane Clifton alone
Still, he went out to Longford Castle!
Oh, but you don't understand
He's a born gentleman
who does what he wants to do
Come here, you don't seem
to read the newspapers
Basil Hale, murdered on castle grounds?
Dead! dead!
Peter Wellerson did it!
That beast.. monster... murderer!
My son,my son...
May I please speak to Longford Castle
Who is this?
Oh it's you, listen..
Good afternoon
- Good afternoon
Thank you
Take it to my room please
I'll unpack the suitcase myself
- Yes madam
A friend of Mr Clifton is here to see you
My Uncle?
- I don't know who it is
Goodbye Mr Burke,
and thanks for the ride
I'll wait here for you, if I may..
- Of Course.. bring some tea for Mr Burke
My name is Radlowe
Yes?
I am Peter's legal adviser
I've been reading all the morning papers
Embarrassing of course..
I decided to get right over here,
and not waste any time
Hale is responsible for it all
He's as crazy as his mother
A stupid old woman, Mrs Anderson
- Anderson?
She disrupts my entire office staff
when she shows up
Excellent arrangements have
been made for her
But she's always short, money
.. always the same
Mrs Anderson is Hale's mother?
In that case,Peter...
- Yes..
Annoying situation,
I think someone knows too much
This is not good for Peter
I'll have to do something to clear
Peter of this suspicion
If they read his fathers testament
correctly at least,it'll help
It's a mistake for Peter,
not to make everything public
Please have him call me immediately
There's no reason for him to hide anything
Goodbye Madam
- Goodbye
That was Peter's solicitor,
what did he want?
I missed what he meant,
His talk was confusing,
he said something must be done now
You're so right Mrs Clifton,
the whole situation is confused
But understand,that in theory,
I'm always on duty
But I have to relax once in a while
And since ten minutes ago,
I'm a civilian,and a very good
friend of Peter's
And so I'd like to talk
about a hammer at this time
And of a lost suit
And of course, the bloody shirt
Why mention it to me?
If I were sure that they were in the
hands of a person who is peter's friend
It would mean that I could relax a little
The tea
- Thank you, I'll take it
I have a weakness for tea
And a weakness for the poor..
Therefore if you had a secondhand suit..
- Please sit down
Thank you,well if you had an old suit,
and an old shirt..
I could make very good use of them
Tools too,
few criminals can get honest jobs
for lack of good tools
Don't forget Mrs Clifton,
Inspector Rouper is looking for
used articles, for his own poor
So if you... if you have something
you have to get rid of...
Then I would rather give it to you,
than anyone
That's very good,you know that Mr Rouper
could show up with a search warrant soon
Can you imagine how the police search?
- No..
Then I must show you how we proceed
Hello, taxi!
Taxi...
You wait here!
Stop! Who are you?
- My name is Miller, I'm an organist,
What do you want?
- Sorry..
Do you know the combination?
- No..
The code word for it is just this,it's Jane
So many secrets Peter and I shared together
He's only afraid..
- Afraid of what?
And there it is..
- What is it?
This is a book that Inspector Rouper
would like to find
A notebook
- A notebook? I didn't know about this
Neither did I, it's a diary he kept
You'd think Peter wouldn't be so careless
That indicates 240 hundred dollar bills,
United States currency
All very well made, and posted to Baltimore.
It's awful..
And here,700,000 on the
Swiss National Bank,
excellent plate,only two mis-prints
And so forth,and so forth, and so forth..
- Then,it is true
I'm sure I better put this
with the old clothes,
which I'm sure you will give me
without delay,Mrs Clifton
Whom can you trust?
You must trust someone now
At the moment,I don't feel on duty,
a private individual, hmm?
Wait right here
- Yes
Here are the old clothes
Inspector Rouper from Scotland Yard
Sorry Mrs Clifton, I have to
discharge an unpleasant duty
Unless the Chief Inspector
has already completed it
No, this is a social call,
do your duty my friend
My dear Rouper,
I have to carry my own laundry
to be cleaned, a bachelor you know
Goodbye Mrs Clifton
- Goodbye Mr Burke
Here's a search warrant,now show me to
your husbands room,if you please
Follow me
Hello Mary,is my wife at home?
Yes, I want to speak to her
Yes Jane, not encouraging I'm afraid
The professors opinion is that
my illness can strike again
The professor is guessing,
I don't believe it!
Oh, by the way,your lawyer
Mr Radlowe was here,
he wants you to call
I have no idea what he wants,
except it's important
It's now nearly six,
I'll leave here by seven,
I hope to see you by 9 o' clock
I can't wait...
Goodbye..
Excuse me professor,
I must ring up my solicitor
- Of course
What I wanted to say...
- A moment,after he makes his call
Hello,Mr Radlowe,this is Peter Clifton,
you said to call
A telegram I sent to your
London address is waiting for you
Things are not going well
- What shall we do?
I shouldn't continue to try
to keep things quiet?
Very well then...
In any case,I'll go to London
Yes,when you're ready,let me know.
Goodbye
Important?
- Maybe
Radlowe wants me to make a
voluntary statement
On what?
I'm not really sure,
it has to do with the testament
of my father though
Testament of your father?
Yes,Radlowe wants me to do it quickly
Don't be upset my dear,Mr Hale was no loss,
a miserable tramp
However,Peter worries me a little
I feel responsible for you marrying him
- You don't need to feel that way
Well of course you know I was a bit upset,
worried.. My illness,
I would have enjoyed
travelling south with you
No longer to be a postcard Picasso,
to give it all up
Oh,don't say that Uncle John..
Your pictures have always
been wonderful to me
It's not important
The important thing is you and Peter
Fortunately,you don't love him
Well,isn't that so?
Now listen Uncle John,
I've been getting to
know peter very well
He's my husband,and I'll stand by him
You mean you're in love?
Tell me,are you?
Yes..
- Why,that's wonderful
Well it's wonderful, if it
wasn't for this trouble
Now if Peter wasn't.. wasn't completely...
- You mean he's insane?
No,please don't mention it again
Oh by the way,here's that
plate that was lost
Oh,where was it?
In Longford Castle
- What did you say,Longford Castle?
Yes,somehow it seems to have
slipped into Peter's luggage
You see.. I said I gave all the
printing plates back to Peter
But a thought occures to me
that's frightening
I've been told by Wells,
that at Longford Castle
a secret room was discovered
And considering that Peter
is such an expert engraver, Well...
What do you mean?
That Peter really is a schizophrenic,
leading a double life
Peter in this life with you
And Peter the shrewd and ruthless forger..
Oh Uncle,stop it..
It's just too absurd
I am sorry my darling,
I don't want you to be hurt
But we must except
the conclusions that exist
Do you hear me?
Answer me Peter Clifton alias Blonberg
It was my son you killed,your brother!
You murderer!
You brutal murderer!
I'll kill you,I'll get revenge
Hello,excuse her please
- Who is this?
It's the Doctor,she's sick
Hello..
- Don't let it worry you my dear
Mrs Anderson is insane,she made it
very clear at the wedding party
Who isn't mad now?
Even I might be
She thinks Peter is the one
who killed Basil her son
Basil Hale was her son?
- Yes,it's all so confusing Uncle
My leather coat please
Tell me,what do you know of Blonberg?
- He's a broker,that's all I know
You know he's the manager of Longford Castle
- Yes,but is he involved?
I'm convinced that Blonberg
has a lot of answers for us
And I'm going to see him in person
Oh yes,my name is Blonberg,
I'm honoured by your visit Mrs Clifton
You manage Longford Castle,
I want the name of the owner
Be seated here,please
The owner of Longford Castle is an
old fellow who lives in Florence,
he's never been seen here at all
It seems strange doesn't it
We transmit his money to his Paris bank
- And his name,please tell me that
I know it sure,but I cannot
just give it out,you see miss
If the gentleman said not to
Another question,
do you know a Mrs Anderson?
No,this name I've never heard,
oh, but to be sure I'll ask my
employees if they know the name
No,you don't have to,
you personally do not know her?
- No
Then excuse all the questions
- It was no trouble
May I show you...
- Thank you,I know the way
Very well then..
Good day..
Hello Mrs Clifton
- Oh good day Chief Inspector Burke
Did you buy any real estate?
- You were watching me?
If you'll allow me,
I'll keep a bit of an eye on you
Oh,and the man who owns
Longford castle is Branes
You know you should have asked me,
for his name
I'll take you home,come along
Oh, I have to tell you something
that might be unpleasant Mrs Clifton
About Peter?
That depends,it's about the clothing
you gave me for the poor people
I found myself in the middle
of Westminster Bridge,
when I felt like a cigarette suddenly
Would you like one?
- Thank you
Does Peter smoke these too?
- Not these..
So, I put the parcel down
on the railing of the bridge
And then, I must have leaned
against it,or something
And then it dropped into the water,
Sank like a stone,
I imagine it was the tools that made it sink
I just can't figure you out Mr Burke..
You're more puzzling all the time
I'm just doing my job
Are you Mr Clifton?
- No,Mrs Clifton is here
A Telegram
- Hello,Mrs Clifton
Yes?
- A Telegram for you
From Peter?
- No,for Peter
I would still open it up.
Allow me please..
Come to Sydenham,document 21 ready at 3
Go to the police tomorrow
Signed Radlowe
- I guess Peter didn't call Radlowe
Document goes to the police..
A bit strange...
It's well past 8,
shouldn't Peter be here now?
I don't understand it,
I better ring up Longford Castle
Longford Castle...
No Mrs Clifton,your husband
isn't here now,he left
Yes, I'd say it's been 2 hours
- Thank you Anna
I don't understand,
Peter left 2 hours ago
I don't like it much either..
I'm off to Sydenham to see that lawyer
- I'll go too..
No no,if you stay here it'll be better
- Why must I,any reason?
Alright, if you wish..
It's very dark around here,
do you know the house sir?
There's Peter's car,it's right there
How come his car is here?
The smell of this is foul, please see
if the key is in it,and wait right here
Yes, the key is there..
- I'm not surprised..
But what does all this mean?
Can you drive it?
- Yes I can,but..
It's good we're here,
we'll drive around the corner,
we have to be careful
Yes but I...
You wait there,and don't
get scared when I come back
Open the car door,
quick!
Peter my dear,what happened,is he..?
- He's unconcious,but not hurt
Drive home at once,be sure
you're not seen bringing him in
And listen,Peter was not here at all
- Yes
Are you Mr Clifton?
Mr Radlowe is waiting for you
This way please,
Mr clif...
Call the nearest police station
Have them send the
homicide squad immediately
What are you waiting for?
All his notes are missing,
he had just started on the seventh page
If we knew what was on the last pages,
we would know the murderer
of Radlowe and Hale
Rouper,you're alert today..
- Think so, eh?
The housemaid has told us,
Radlowe had expected Mr Clifton to come
Think he was here?
- Not him Rouper
Mr Clifton sent me instead,you see
These footprints are still wet
I protest!
This is a scandalous treatment
for a good taxpayer
Indeed,I protest
- We found this man loitering about
Hey watch it,what are you doing?
Look out there!
Be careful!
Who are you?
My name is stone,I'm a neighbour
you see,I'm right next door
You live next door?
- Yes sir
About an hour ago,did you see something?
- Yes,yes I did
About an hour ago,I was walking
peacefully with Socrates,
that's my dog you see
And I'm sure I saw a man go to
the rear entrance here
You saw him?
- Was he tall or short?
Rather tall
- Was he relaxed or in a rush?
Erect or bent?
Did he walk erect or not?
He was erect, and in a rush
I rather expected that kind of description
Can I go now?
May I go sir?
May I please leave now?
May I go?
Something there?
- May I go now
This?
Nothing important
He's asleep..
He was conscious briefly,he got
out of the car,came in the house
Then he didn't remember a thing
Now I want to know Mr Burke,
at the house in Sydenham,what happened?
- Mr Radlowe,was murdered
Oh god.. that means that he..
- Please don't ask any further questions
Interesting,lots of cash
I removed the hand written confession
that was in his left shoe
Do the servants know Peter's here?
Yes,but I told them
he's here a long while
Everything is turning out for the best
And that brings me now,
to a fantastic performance
I believe I will consult a doctor now
A doctor?
- Yes,a psychiatrist,a pretty clever one..
That is,one who believes
in his own shrewdness
Goodnight
- Goodnight
Oh you, Mr Burke..
Sorry to disturb you so late,but I must
see your husband
Yes, please come in
Scotland Yard,in the middle of the night?
Yes,I'm playing a theatrical
detective, doctor
I've been wanting to act like
a television private eye,
but I hardly get the chance
Sorry, I've been working rather late
My head aches awfully
I have the feeling doctor,that tomorrow,
there will be a headache epidemic
Yes,that poor Peter Clifton,
and Mrs Clifton,and Inspector Rouper,
And you too,doctor
- I hope not
You better clear that up,
come in
This'll be man to man my dear
Ah,modern art..
Here's where you treat your victims?
You have a spoecial sense of humour
May I get you a drink,whisky?
No thank you..
I believe there's an admirable quotation
on the subject from Kipling,no?
Accept the first drink,or something..
- Fine...
Who are you after,and for what?
I haven't decided,
I haven't selected the quarry
But I'll soon pick on someone
You must have heard that,
an old lawyer was murdered
- Radlowe murdered?
I mentioned Radlowe then?
I merely said that an old lawyer
was killed,why Radlowe?
Well, I.. I know that he's Peter's lawyer
Yes, I heard them talking
on the phone,yesterday
Peter was to go and meet him
Yes Doctor, Radlowe is the
lawyer who was murdered
Stabbed by someone unknown
The murderer was seen by a neighbour,
who gave us a complete description
A neighbour saw him you say?
Yes that's right
A bit of luck eh?
You might say I came,
to avoid the possibilities
of stories that would put
Peter near Radlowe's office last night
- Yes Radlowe, it's awful
When and where did Peter leave you?
I would say we both left about 7 or so
He went to Radlowe
- And you think,he's the murderer?
No,you mustn't have heard that
I've said that,don't believe it!
That is,now that you say it,
I'm not so sure...
Don't worry doctor,
when we find the stiletto,
we'll have an easy time
finding the murderer
You see,as a rule,the classic murderer,
doesn't leave evidence
at the scene,
unless he uses it to throw
suspicion on another
Sometimes a cigarette case is left too,
so idiots like me will think
the man who owns it is a murderer
Yes, I have no idea
what I can do for you
Well...
You know Peter had been doped,
you prefer to use morphine
in these cases?
Are you accusing me of drugging Peter?
- I haven't mentioned that
I mean that you've been acting not
as Peter's friend,but for yourself
So, I think only of myself?
So what if I told you Peter
confessed Hale's murder to me?
What would you do?
I would arrest you on the spot..
- Me?
And if I might add,what charge?
Among other things,
I would charge you with using
a false banknote deliberately
Oh but, that note was Peter's
I would further accuse you of
violating your oath as a doctor
Chief Inspector,you don't
know what you're saying
I do Mr Wells..
I know what I say..
And I warn you,
leave Peter Clifton alone
If you plan to rob him of his millions,
just forget it
You were in Longford Castle
when Basil Hale was murdered
And you...
- I was in Longford Castle,yes,
but I haven't left my house since!
Admitted..
but before that,where were you?
Where were you between
Longford Castle and your home?
You're beaten Wells...
even cigarettes that Peter doesn't use,
and false notebooks by the forger,
wont be enough for you
Somebody will pay for the murders,
you can be sure of that,
but not Peter Clifton
Goodnight
Where am I?
- At home
At home...
Can you imagine how interesting it is,
to have a husband who can't remember
what bed he's sleeping in?
It seems quite difficult to be my wife.
- But it grows on you
Jane...
Don't underestimate Burke,
he collects evidence 'till he's sure
Then he strikes suddenly,
like an explosion
At Scotland Yard he's known as the bomb
If he's protecting Peter Clifton then,
I'm sure the murderers
name is in his hands.
It makes me nervous doctor
Oh don't act like a child,Rouper,
why are so worried?
To the best of your knowledge
you did your duty
What do you mean?
I simply did what ever
you told me should be done
You told me Clifton
murdered Hale, and more..
That you saw him in bed,
all covered with blood
And his bloody clothes
were in his London home
And there I would easily find them
And furthermore,you announced,
that in his safe I would find
a very interesting notebook
But nothing seems to be true at all
Why don't you tell Scotland Yard
that Clifton is an assassin?
I can still do it
What's that you say?
Mrs Anderson thinks Peter Clifton,
the forger and Mr blonberg
Are one and the same person?
Yes,it's a fixed idea with her
In her closet,she has a loaded
revolver hidden away
Leith,ah, doctor Donald Wells
Well what happened?
Yes,I spoke to Jane but
But it wont be as easy to carry
out the big plan, as we figured
Yes,oh sure good,
suppose that you can,
bring Peter arround to commit himself,
and turn his money over to Jane to manage it
What then?
We must let Jane into the plan,naturally
But she wont play along
Something has happened
that we didn't think, would happen
You see Peter's her husband.
Of course you can try that,
but don't get confident
Your appeal to the ladies
is overrated Wells
Anderson wants to avenge her son,
by shooting Peter Clifton dead
Shall I take the revolver away?
Let the Chief decide...
Good afternoon
- Good afternoon
How's Peter?
Asleep..
So, I must say,I'm glad I can see you alone
- Please...
It was an awful thing last night
You mean Radlowe?
- I mean Radlowe..
Then you believe that,
Peter is involved?
Listen Jane...
The fact is,that now it's
essential that Peter,
for himself,and in your interests too,
have to face the truth
He will always have his trouble mentally
I'm afraid that the truth about these
murders will come out some day
that would lead to a terrible public trial
Truly it would be a scandal
You would suffer for it too
So I think that its for the best
That Peter does something to avoid it
What do you suggest?
Jane, first both Peter and you,
must believe, I have just
your best interests at heart
And then?
- Yes then,
Peter must get an encompetance hearing
So that he will be declared
insane and confined
It's not really so shocking..
He'll be confined for maybe
a total of 5 maybe 6 years
In other words,Peter should
declare himself insane
Just a formality,and we'll do it quietly
It's the only way
Jane.. you understand that under the law
you would manage his fortune,
and if you wish
you can decide to call on your uncle,
or... or me.. as trustee,as you wish,
you must not ignore this
Jane.. your own social standing in London
As the wife of a sentenced murderer,
you would be an outcast...
So you say it's an absolute fact,
that Peter is mentally ill?
Yes,all the symptoms speak for it
Its evident when he talks,
he's constantly blinking
his entire behaviour..
These symptoms,would any
specialist recognise them?
Yes of course
For example,
Sir George Galthom or Dr Heinrich Strauss?
Naturally..
Such great doctors
are very busy people
And also the great neuro psychiatrist,
Sir Frederick Jackson?
Yes,without doubt
But jane,we can't afford
to let too many others
in on the murders that are involved
I've been playing a little game Dr Wells
The 3 doctors that I've been talking about,
came today for tea
And they have tested Peter,
and talked with him
And each of these 3 doctors assured me
that Peter is just as sane
as anyone can be
But,but it doesn't make sense
They're all mistaken obviously,
since Professor Cloors...
- Is a charlatan
that you brought in to help
put Peter in an institution
I'm on to your tricks Dr wells
I don't understand..
Now I would appreciate it
if you would get out of here
Dr Wells wants to leave..
I'll go of course,
if that's what you want
But I hope Jane,
you wont be sorry later on
I wont be too sorry
What's that?
Liverpool versus Glasgow,
the game is still nil... nil
The plates complete the case...
We can arrest,
Peter Clifton as the forger
That's excellent,why that's great
We just arrest the fellow,
and tomorrow I watch the kings cup game
The police searching Longford Castle
found the missing press,and the plates,
in the pond,right behind the park
The report is completely written up
Yes,I hope you didn't forget to mention
that in Longford castle,
a tremendous amount of
forged money was made
Thank you,
I put it down already
The 20 five pound notes,
you picked up last sunday from Dr wells
were probably genuine,
or the bank wouldn't
have accepted them
I have no idea what you mean
- I'll be glad to explain
You're under arrest Rouper!
You can't do this!
Let me go
One... Nil
So Burke is after you,
are you surprised about that?
My orders were to fake Hale's death
And you had no order from me to kill Radlowe
You know I hate violence,
look at the Consequences
What has been done,
can not be changed
I must get away,and right now too
- I'm not keeping you
I need cash
- You're a rich man
But an hour ago,
my wife took everything and left
I need your help...
And what about your fine plan with Clifton?
Listen Blonberg...
let me down now,
and I will not go down alone,understand?
I didn't say I wouldn't help you,
how much do you need?
Five thousand pounds?
Very well,come here at about eleven P.M
Someone will be waiting
Can't I come sooner?
No,you will be here at eleven,someone will
be here to meet you with the money
You must tell that person that
you are Blonberg,is that clear?
Good, I'll do whatever you want
Now, you know what to do Henry?
- I do Sir
And tell the distributers they will
get new merchandise in 8 days
100 Deutsche Mark notes
- I will Sir
This is Blonberg,tell Mrs Anderson
I want to speak to her here at 11 pm
Glad you're feeling better Peter
- Thank you Burke
Doesn't he look well?
- Indeed he does
I want you to hear this,
It was saved by Radlowe
On top it says without name change,the text
Mrs Alexander Wellerson,
that was your mother
was married to a man who by chance,
was her first husbands cousin
Mrs and Mr Wellerson,
that's your stepfather...
accompanied by their
seven month old child,
who was of the first marriage,
that's you Peter
Took a revierra trip..
Yes,but that means that...
That the Wellerson who murdered 2 people
and finally ended up in dartmoor to die,
was not your father at all..
- But only your stepfather
Who married Anderson later,
without benefit of divorcing his wife,
your real mother
Now then,the forger.. who is he?
You know him?
- I know him
You know where he could be hiding?
I know at least,where that so called,
Blonberg works
Where he'll meet contacts,
even tonight
That is all,I must go now
Blonberg 1,Blonberg 1
Do you hear me?
He went in just now,
be sure you're ready..
Are you there Blonberg?
Have you brought the cash?
Let's have it,quick
Money,you want money?
after you murdered your brother
in cold blood Peter Clifton
Murderer!
You dirty bloody murderer
Blonberg or Clifton
You're crazy,I'm not Clifton!
Murderer!
All is clear..
And if he doesn't come,what then?
- He's coming,no doubt at all
Halt!
It's too late, Peter Clifton
Peter!
What have you done Peter?
Nothing,
nothing at all
He wanted to do something,
but he didn't succeed
The lift signal,he's coming!
- Lights out!
Don't make a foolish move!
- Uncle John!
Mr Leith,or Mr Blonberg,
or the forger...
It's unfortunate Peter
I'm aware that you
tried to warn Leith
so that Jane might
not have been hurt
Marjorie told me where to find Uncle John
Peter,you knew?
- Yes Jane
That time at Longford Castle when
I found the forgery hidden away
And the plate that I'd loaned
a while ago to Uncle John
he pretended was lost
What's going on?
Excuse me please,
it was a goal for our side
Well I'm cheering for our team too
Oh Chief Inspector
Tell me,how did that
case come out then?
The best my friend,the best
Subtitles made by McD
From the english dubbed vhs rip by bgart13
10th July 2008
Thanx bgart13