The Wasteland
Lotfollah.
- Salaam, sir.
- Salaam.
Tell all the workers I need to see
them at my office after lunch.
Yes, sir.
Wives and children, too.
I have important business.
Shahu.
- Shahu.
- What?
No work after lunch.
Go to the office.
- The Boss wants to see you all.
- Okay.
He said everyone.
Even your brothers and sisters.
- I brought ice. Go get some.
- Okay.
Ebrahim.
No work after lunch.
Boss wants everyone at his office.
- I brought ice. Go get some.
- Okay.
- Mashebad.
- Yes.
Go to the office after lunch.
Boss wants to see everyone.
Very good.
Sarvar.
- Sarvar.
- Yes.
I brought ice.
After lunch go to the office.
Boss wants to see everyone.
Okay.
Sit down.
You have all worked here for years,
and have witnessed how ...
I have struggled to keep our
brickworks from shutting down.
Lotfollah knows this
better than anyone.
He was born here 40 years ago
and has been working here since then.
There were 50 brickworks on this plain.
They shut down one by one.
Only we are left and the Nayeb Kiln.
Building materials have changed.
Nobody uses bricks anymore.
Cement blocks have replaced bricks.
Fuel prices have gone up.
- Mashebad.
- Yes.
If you want to talk money,
go to Boss’s office now.
- Very good.
- Go now. He’ll leave for the city soon.
Salaam.
- May you be well.
- May you be strong.
- Go see him right now.
- Let me finish this wheelbarrow first.
Let me do it. Go
He might go on a trip and
be gone a long time. Go see him now.
Damn, I told Boss 100 times
to change these broken wheels.
Ebrahim.
Gohar.
Let’s go.
Now?  Ebrahim.
No, my dad will be right back.
He’s at the office. He needs time.
I told Lotfollah we’d go to his room.
Gohar, come with me.
Faster.
It’s noon. I’ll go make lunch.
Ebrahim,
tell your dad to get Mashebad...
to agree to give you Gohar.
My poor old dad isn’t against it.
Ask Mashebad why he ignores my dad.
He makes excuses.
He doesn’t want to give her away.
He wants his wages from Boss...
to send Gohar off to her sister’s.
He thinks she will waste away here.
Ebrahim has stayed here for Gohar.
Talk Mashebad into giving him Gohar.
He’ll take her to town.
Ebrahim is a clever man.
He did his military duty in the city.
Get Mashebad to accept.
What can I say?
Give me a brick.
I can’t help you now. I’m broke.
Maybe I can help you next week.
Let’s see what happens in seven days.
- Mashebad.
- Yes.
It’s better if Gohar stays here.
She helps you.
Don’t do this.
Wait a little longer.
Pay up your insurance.
My friend can help get a pension.
Then take your family and go wherever.
For now, let her help with finances.
Sir, God first and then you.
Help us out a little.
Let me take Gohar away for a bit.
The boy will forget about her.
And if Gohar isn’t here,
Ebrahim will go away.
After Ebrahim leaves,
I’ll bring Gohar back to help us.
Fine. Get back to work.
We’ll see what happens next week.
I have many things to do.
It’s late. I need to go.
I know you’re going away.
Inshallah, you’ll be traveling.
No. Who said that?
- Lotfollah said so, sir.
- Lotfollah?
Sir, you need to keep an eye on Lotfollah.
- Why? Did something happen?
- Well, he favors Sarvar.
On Thursdays, when you leave,
he takes Sarvar to the road to town.
He does Sarvar’s work to keep
up the number of bricks we make.
The workers are uneasy about this.
People think these two are scheming.
Who knows what Sarvar does?
I don’t know how
every Thursday when you’re gone,
she dresses up and goes to town.
She returns on Friday.
But what do I know, sir.
You need to know these things.
Very good. Now, go.
Tell Lotfollah to come see me.
Yes, sir.
Did Boss give you money?
He will,
but he doesn’t have it now.
When has Boss ever had money for us?
Don’t be ungrateful.
God is great.
We’ll work hard,
pay insurance, and I’ll retire.
Boss’s friend
will help me get a pension.
Then we’ll all go back to Mashhad.
Has any brick maker
ever retired?
No,
but Boss says there is a law.
You can retire after 60.
Boss has a friend
in the insurance company.
He will help us.
- Mashebad.
- Huh?
- How old are you?
- I’m over 60.
My National ID says I’m 50.
We applied for it very late.
You have all worked here for years,
and have witnessed how ...
I have struggled to keep our
brickworks from shutting down.
Lotfollah knows what I’m saying
better than anyone else.
He was born right here 40 years ago
and has been working here since then.
There were 50 brickworks on this plain.
They shut down one by one.
Only we are left and the Nayeb Kiln.
Building materials have changed.
Nobody uses bricks anymore.
Cement blocks have replaced bricks.
Bricks don’t bring profit anymore.
They sell for less than they cost.
Fuel prices have gone up.
Butane and kerosine prices increase daily.
Enough. Stop.
Where to Shahu?
I told you not to come here half-naked.
Hey, Shahu, I’m talking to you.
Stop! Shahu!
Why are you naked?
Didn’t I tell you…
- Shut up!
- You jackass!
Didn’t I tell you
not to come here naked?
Move away!
Lotfollah…
- Lotfollah…
- Shahu...
Get out of my way!
Shahu! Let him be! Shahu!
Ebrahim! Stop fighting!
Let me go!
Let’s see how full of shit he is!
- Shahu.
- Get out of my way!
- Out!
- Stop! Shahu.
Out!  ... Out!
I want my shoe.
What are you doing here? Go!
Gohar! Get back to work!
Ouch.
Get up.
Drink some water.
Let Shahu be, Ebrahim.
Stop messing with the kurds.
I told him not to come here naked.
He does it on purpose.
He's just being stubborn.
It’s too hot to work there in clothes.
You worked the kilns.
The bricks are hot.
Yes, it's very hot there,
but I never went
near the women naked.
I asked Boss to talk with Shahu.
- You talk to him.
- Let it go, Lotfollah
Boss will talk to him.
You keep saying that but
you haven’t once talked to Boss.
I didn’t need you to save me.
I’ll talk to Boss at the end of the month.
I’ll get my money and get away from
this hellhole. I’ll be free of all of you.
Why wait a month?
Go now.
If I were you,
I’d get my money now.
In a month Boss might be traveling.
You need to see him now.
He’s in his office.
Go.
- I need to finish here.
- I’ll take over, you go.
Lotfollah, tell Ebrahim to carry
bricks instead of fighting.
We're behind. I need
to seal the kiln with mud.
Keep your head down and get to work.
Don’t worry about others.
I'll tell Shahu to put his shirt
on when he goes near the women.
And you let him be.
I hear you make fun of them.
You curse their Caliphate.
You swear using Omar’s name.
Ebrahim!
Omar is a Saint for them.
Now, get going.
I have nothing for you in the safe.
Let’s see how the month ends.
Sir, These are not my words.
Lotfollah made them up.
He always sides with the kurds.
He visits them at night,
and they get drunk together.
There are women
and children living here.
Really? They get drunk?
Lotfala and them?
Very well. You should go.
Forget about these things.
You keep to yourself.
Winners
mind their own business.
Work hard for a while.
Save your money.
I’ll get Mashebad to give you Gohar,
and you two can go off together.
- Mashebad will never agree.
- He will.
If not, I’ll take you and Gohar to town,
and I’ll help you get married.
Without Mashebad’s permission?
- Impossible.
- Nothing is impossible.
I know people.
Everything in its own time.
Now it’s time for lunch.
Go, I have much work to do.
Sir, keep an eye on Lotfollah.
He sets the workers against each other.
He pays Sarvar special attention.
He sends her to town on Thursdays.
He takes her place on Fridays,
to keep up the brick count.
He tells us Sarvar goes to see family.
My mother says he’s lying.
Sarvar has no family,
especially in town.
- Who knows?
- Very well, now go.
I told you to mind your own business.
Tell Lotfollah I want to see him.
(In Azeri) Did you talk to Boss?
Yes.
What did he say?
He’ll talk to the kurds
and make them behave.
He said if they
don’t listen, he’ll fire them.
Woman, give me tea.
He won’t fire the kurds.
Take more bread. Eat your fill.
I’ll have a tea, too.
Ebrahim, give me the sugar.
Ebrahim, my son.
Keep away from the kurds.
Did Boss say anything about money?
He did.
What?
He said he’s broke;
to wait a little.
Oh, God!
How can Boss always be broke?
Ma, tell dad
to get Mashebad to agree.
If he doesn’t do this,
Boss knows people in town.
He’ll get us married
without permission.
I hope your words come true.
Ebrahim, my son.
Keep away from the kurds.
You have all worked here for years,
and have witnessed how I have struggled
to keep our brickworks from shutting down.
Lotfollah knows
what I say better than anyone.
He was born right here 40 years ago
and has been working here since then.
There were 50 brickworks on this plain.
They shut down one by one.
Only we are left and the Nayeb Kiln.
Building materials have changed.
Nobody uses bricks anymore.
Cement blocks have replaced bricks.
Fuel prices have gone up.
Butane and kerosine prices
increase daily.
Bricks don’t bring profit anymore.
They sell for less than they cost.
I have kept this place going.
I owe the bank money.
The government promised to help me;
they didn’t.
Shahu, come here.
- Did you talk to Boss?
- Go talk to him right now.
He said he can’t right now.
He can't now?
He can’t?
So we stop working now!
We can’t keep working like this.
Don’t stop now. Load the truck first.
Then you go talk to Boss.
Lotfollah, it’s too hot for a dog
down here, but we're still working.
Boss is up in his cooled office.
He doesn’t know about down here.
We can’t work for
wages from two years ago.
Brick prices have doubled.
And we are paid the same as two years ago.
We can’t go on working in this hell.
I know. I used to work there.
But you don’t have anyone.
You’re on your own.
I need to answer to the others.
Boss knows why we need money.
We can’t wait anymore.
Shahu,
If I were you,
I’d go talk to Boss. I’d say I need money.
How can talking help?
He says he has nothing.
Go talk to him again.
I will when it’s time.
It’s up to you.
Boss might go traveling soon.
Go to him now.
Get to work.
Let’s finish loading the truck.
Go stand by the truck.
Pass a brick.
I know it’s hot down there.
Especially in the summer.
If I get paid, I’ll buy a conveyor belt.
It will make things easier.
It’s not that bad with four people.
Until a few years ago
Lotfollah loaded the truck alone.
Bricks aren’t selling now.
Things will get better soon.
I’ll give you all a raise.
I’m okay with it, sir,
but my sisters and brothers aren’t.
Our pay is not enough.
It's the same as two years ago.
You know our father is on Death Row.
We can’t pay off
his accusers with this money.
I know people for this, too.
I will get
the accusers to pardon your dad.
Don’t worry,
I won’t let him be executed.
Everything in its own time.
Time will fix this.
Winners must be patient.
Get up and get to work.
Don’t worry.
- Shahu.
- Yes, sir.
When you do things at night,
like drinking, keep it to yourself.
Sir, I never did such things.
Don’t defend yourself.
I hear everything.
People can do as they wish,
as long as nobody finds out.
- Get it?
- Yes, sir.
Get back to work. It’s noon.
But Lotfollah
told you a bunch of stories.
He also does many things
that you don’t hear about.
He treats Sarvar special.
On Thursdays, he takes her to the road
and sends her to town.
He takes Sarvar’s place on Fridays
so we don’t fall behind schedule.
He tells us...
he sends Sarvar to see family.
But Sarvar has no family.
We all know it’s a lie.
This divides the workers.
You know this better than me.
Go.
Tell Lotfollah I want to see him.
Yes, sir.
(In curdish) What happened, Shahu?
What did Boss say?
Nothing.
He said he was broke and we had to wait.
When has Boss ever had money?
Daddy will be dead by the time
we get our money. This is bad.
- Pour me a tea.
- Lunch?
No, just tea.
Boss will stop the execution.
His friends will get
a pardon from the accusers.
Give me the sugar.
We need to keep working as we have.
It’s okay with me, but our brothers
won’t work for such little money.
You have all worked here for years,
and have witnessed how I have struggled
to keep our brickworks from shutting down.
Lotfollah knows
what I say better than anyone.
He was born right here 40 years ago
and has been working here since then.
There were 50 brickworks on this plain.
They shut down one by one.
Only we are left and the Nayeb Kiln.
Building materials have changed.
Nobody uses bricks anymore.
Cement blocks have replaced bricks.
Fuel prices have gone up.
Butane and kerosine prices increase daily.
Bricks don’t bring profit anymore.
They sell for less than they cost.
I have kept this place going.
I owe the bank money.
The government promised to help me,
They didn’t.
- Salaam.
Sarvar.
- I filled this with ice for you.
- Thank you.
- Reza, give me a glass of water.
- Boss wants to see you.
- Okay, I’ll go.
- He said to come now.
- What does he want?
- I don’t know.
- I think he has something for you.
- What?
- He didn’t tell me.
- You could have brought it for me.
He didn’t give it to me.
I’ll go later.
The clay will dry up.
Boss is going to town.
Go now, I’ll do this.
Lotfollah!
I sealed the kiln door.
Go up top and light the fire.
Okay.
Sir?
Why shouldn’t I come
to you this weekend?
This weekend is no good.
My wife is returning to Iran.
I’ll tell you when she leaves.
When will she leave, sir?
I don’t know.
For now, she’s homesick.
Maybe she’ll stay
two months like last year.
Or she might get
fed up with me and leave.
I got some things for Reza.
Go get them from my car.
Thank you very much.
Sir,
What will happen to Reza?
He should have gone
to school two years ago.
Is his National ID card ready?
I have a friend in City Hall.
He’s following up.
But you know
these things take time.
Thank you, sir.
I’m worried it will be too late,
if he doesn’t start school this year.
Everything is done in its own time.
Now, get back to work.
Yes, sir.
Reza,
Boss is getting your National ID.
You’ll start school
this year, and learn to read.
Mommy, did Lotfollah go to school?
No.
But he can read and write.
I know.
Mommy,
does Lotfollah have a National ID?
Put these away when you finish.
Sit down. Sit down.
You have all worked here for years,
and have witnessed how I have struggled
to keep our brickworks from shutting down.
Lotfollah knows
what I say better than anyone.
He was born right here 40 years ago
and has been working here ever since.
There were 50 brickworks on this wasteland.
They shut down one by one.
Only we are left and the Nayeb Kiln.
Building materials have changed.
Nobody uses bricks anymore.
Cement blocks have replaced bricks.
Bricks don’t bring profit anymore.
They sell for less than they cost.
To keep this place going,
I'm in debt to the bank.
I can’t do this anymore.
I’ve sold this place
to pay back the bank.
We shut down today.
You have until the end of the week
to pack your things and go back home.
About your salaries.
Write down the hours
you’ve worked and give it to Lotfollah.
I might not be able to
pay all of you completely.
But I will pay everyone something.
Later I’ll give the rest to Lotfollah.
He will tell you when he has it.
Lotfollah is our go-between.
He has my address in town.
Tell him if you have any
problems and he will let me know.
Now go and get ready to leave.
The new owners
will not keep the brick works.
Now leave.
Go with God.
Lotfollah.
How many bricks are in the kiln?
Three levels are still baking.
One is off.
Should I shut down the rest?
Let them bake.
I’ll send a truck tomorrow.
Tell the Kurds to load
the truck before they leave.
Yes, sir.
What will I do now, sir?
Go to town. Find a job.
Sir, I’ve been here since I was a child.
I have no place to go,
or anyone to go to.
All I know is brick-making.
You are 40 now.
You’re no longer a child.
You’ve been to town often.
You know how things work.
I’ll give you part of what I owe you.
Go find a room in town.
Find a woman like
yourself to come live with you.
You’ll find a job.
Get the timesheets from the workers
and give them to me when I come tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
When I get money.
I’ll settle our account.
Now, get going.
Sir, like me,
Sarvar has nowhere to go.
Lotfollah! Forget about Sarvar.
She’s no good for you.
She might be attractive,
but she's starting to age.
She will need help soon.
She will become a burden.
You’ll spend
all you make on doctors.
A wife must be
half her husband’s age,
so she can help him
when he's older.
She has nowhere to go.
What will she do?
She can take care of herself.
You just take care of yourself.
Now, go. I have things to do.
Yes, sir.
- Salaam.
- Salaam, Ebrahim.
Shahu.
- Salaam.
- Did you write it?
- Yes, come in.
Let me see.
How many months are you owed?
It’s eight months.
Give me the timesheet.
Tell Boss he promised
a raise after New Year’s.
When will Boss pay us?
We’re packing and leaving tomorrow.
We’re having dinner.
I’ll set you a place.
Thank you.
Ebrahim, did you make your timesheet?
- Here it is.
- How many months are you owed?
Ten months.
Last year, when the Kurds refused,
my dad and I loaded the truck. Tell Boss.
Last year?
Okay.
Lotfollah, when is Boss going to pay us?
We’re going back to our village tomorrow.
Lotfollah,
can me and Gohar go to your room?
Go ahead.
She’s in Sarvar’s room.
Tell her to come.
Mashebad.
- Mashebad.
- Yes.
- Bring me your time sheet.
- Okay.
Here you are, Salaam.
- How much are you owed?
- Nine months and ten days.
Gohar wrote it all.
We're still owed from last year.
I told Boss, but he didn’t accept it.
We don’t agree with that.
- Lotfala, when will Boss pay us?
- I don’t know.
We’re packing our things.
We’re going to Mashhad tomorrow.
I don’t know, Mashebad.
Sarvar.
Didn't you write what you’re owed?
- No.
- Why not?
Boss knows how much, I don’t.
Gohar, come here.
- Salaam.
- Go to my room. Ebrahim wants you.
- Are you leaving tomorrow?
- I don’t know yet.
- You’ll go to town, right?
- I don’t know, Lotfollah.
- Mommy, Mommy.
- Huh?
- Are we leaving tomorrow?
- I don’t know.
Mommy, is Lotfollah going away, too?
Go to sleep, Reza.
- Lotfala, let’s go.
- You go, I’ll catch up.
Run, Gohar, run!
Hurry!
Lotfollah.
- Salaam, sir.
- Salaam.
Why are the kurds waiting at the road?
They're supposed to load the truck.
Send the truck, sir. I’ll load it.
- Who's left?
- Everyone is gone.
They said I can hold the money,
and they’ll come and get it.
Is everyone gone?
Nobody's here?
Sarvar is still here, sir.
- Did you get their timesheets?
- Yes, sir.
Bring them to my office.
Tell Sarvar to pack if
she wants a ride to town.
Sarvar.
Didn’t you pack?
Don’t you want to leave?
I don't know.
Boss is here. He wants you
to pack and be ready to go to town.
Are you going to stay with Boss in town?
Lotfollah.
Boss took me as his
temporary wife years ago.
When I went to town
on weekends, I stayed with Boss.
I know.
I've known for a while.
I thought you wouldn't
stay his temporary wife.
- Here are the timesheets, sir.
- Give them to me.
I got the money for this place.
I can settle everyone's wages.
The new owners will be
here tomorrow to take over.
You be here, too.
We'll see what happens.
Yes, sir.
They might need a night guard.
If they do, stay with them.
They are good people.
Yes, sir. I have nowhere else to go.
Are the bricks ready?
Did you turn off the kiln?
They’ll bake until dusk.
I’ll shut off them then.
Very good.
Take these to my car.
Yes, sir.
- Is Sarvar ready?
- I told her, sir.
Here, lock up the rooms.
I don’t want any animals in them.
I’ll be here before the new owners
tomorrow. Do you need anything?
No, sir.
I found Sarvar work at a friend’s house.
She can work there for now.
Now, go help them in.
- Salaam.
- Salaam, sir.
- Anything else?
- Nope.
Good-bye, Lotfollah.