Can I give you a ride?
All the way into town?
I turn north at heatherton.
What are those for?
A funeral?
Why do flowers have
to be for anything?
Isn't it enough that
they have color and form
and that they make
you feel good?
You talk a lot, don't you?
Don't you, ever?
I could talk your eyes
out of your head.
But not small talk.
I'd be grateful to hear any talk
at all these days.
Talk big.
Red and green.
Duran died last fall
in a hospital.
You wouldn't know who he was.
It happens I do.
- Who?
- A French painter.
One of Les fauves.
He died in a hospital
in a white bed in a white room,
doctors in white
standing around.
The last thing he said was,
"some red, show me some red.
"Before dying, I want to see
some red with some green."
You're right.
You don't have small talk.
Artists are better off dead.
Why?
People pay more
attention to them
when they're dead
and not so troublesome.
Is that what you are? A painter?
They said Van Gogh
was crazy because he killed himself.
He couldn't sell a painting
while he was alive,
and now they're
worth $30 million.
They weren't that bad then
and they're not that good now
so, who's crazy?
I get out here.
You're from the clinic.
That's right.
I'm "out of touch with reality."
I'll take you up.
Are you being helped here?
How should I know?
If you don't, who does?
My analyst thinks he does.
Man: The fact which
I should like to convey
in this report to the trustees
is that our patients
now, more and more,
are shouldering
the responsibility
for their own affairs
in the hospital.
In dealing with the, ah,
borderline patients,
that is to say the people
who find it difficult
to cope with the normal strains
of living, and in whom the,
ah, the danger of a psychotic
break is always present...
Mrs. Demuth.
Man: All right.
We'll go on after that.
You've changed
Steven Holte to 5:00.
Oh, yeah. Well, I'll
work on it by myself tonight.
Patients' committee
meeting...8:30.
I know. Bedtime... 2:30.
Mrs. Demuth.
Dr. Mciver will see you now.
Mr. Holcomb is disturbed.
So is Mrs. O’Brien.
Mr. Holcomb!
Mr. Holcomb, are you all right?
Mr. Holcomb.
This is Dr. Devanal.
Devanal: I'd like
to talk to you.
Would you open the door, please?
Mr. Holcomb.
Shall I use my key, doctor?
What brought this on,
do you know?
He was pretty incoherent.
Something about the gardener.
- Curly?
- Yes. He felt he'd insulted him.
- When did this happen?
- Just a few moments ago.
Shall I send curly to you?
No, no. Is miss inch
in her office?
She was in the library
the last time I saw her.
Well, keep talking to him
and try to get him
to open the door.
I'll be back.
What's the price of this?
That's cotton wrap.
You wouldn't be happy with that.
What's wrong with it?
Well, there's
nothing wrong with it
but as long as you're investing
in drapes for a room like this,
why, you should have
a cheerful pattern.
Otherwise, you'd be better off
to let these old ones
make do until you...
well, it was not my idea
to replace the drapes,
the board makes these decisions.
I'm responsible for
getting things done
as economically as possible.
So I want to know what
this would add up to.
Well, that wrap is
$2.99 a yard plus sales tax.
191.36, less our discount.
Vicky. May I see you a moment?
12.5% on 191.365 times...
167.44 plus 3%
sales tax...5.02... 176.46 total!
Devanal: How's my best girl?
Up to my...
Vicky, we've got a situation here.
I need your help.
It's about curly.
It seems he has...
what do you want me to do?
Fire him?
He's been here 20 years.
Cost you twice as much to get
anyone else to do half the work.
Vicky, please.
You know very well
he won't listen to
anybody but you.
He's upset another patient.
And the last thing
in the world we want,
with the trustees coming
down next week, is a...
well, anytime the board doesn't
like the way I run my department...
Vicky, Vicky.
Everyone knows you do
wonders around here.
Well, do a tiny wonder for
me, now.
Tell curly to behave
with the patients.
Anything. Just so I can tell Holcomb
he's apologized. Hmm?
Go on! Work your magic!
Oh, Vicky.
Why don't you let me leave these
chintz samples here
for you to think over?
I don't think you're
going to be happy with that.
What's all this concern
about my being happy?
I have no intention of dancing
through the halls, shrieking
with laughter because we're
changing a set of drapes.
Now, then, leave
a duplicate order blank.
Let you know in a few days.
Ok, Vicky!
Well, there it is.
The house of Usher.
They talk of environmental therapy.
Some environment!
You should see the inside.
Like the inside of a dead fish!
Right now, miss inch...
you live in town,
you've heard of miss inch...
her old man shot buffalo bill or
somebody right near here.
Ha ha! I've heard of her.
Well, she's getting ready
to hang new drapes
in the library.
One look, and all the patients will hang
themselves alongside them.
Everybody's tilted here.
That's why you didn't
know who I was.
You can't tell the patients
from the doctors.
- Oh, but I can.
- How?
The patients get better!
Ha ha!
Thanks for the ride.
You're welcome.
And that evening,
we put her on the boat train for America.
Well! As you can imagine,
our joy and relief
was indescribable,
and we boarded the plane for Italy
happy and carefree as children.
I can see you've already
guessed what happened!
Well, sure enough, when we
landed at the airport in Rome,
we were greeted by the appalling sight
of miss Dalrymple waving hysterically.
Well, the rest of the trip was agony.
She literally...
Man:... Mrs. Dalrymple or I.
Well, finally,
we found a handsome young Italian...
Ah, Mrs. Mciver!
Oh! Dr. Wolff, how nice.
A most unusual pleasure
seeing you in the clinic.
And how's, ah, um...
Mrs. Wolff is very well,
thank you.
I tried to phone...
Stewart's been so busy
we haven't seen anyone.
Oh, I understand.
Well, sometime very, very soon!
Stewart, I...
oh! I'm so sorry!
I didn't hear anyone.
Karen, can't you see I'm busy?
I do beg your pardon.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
But I've just had an idea,
the most wonderful idea...
look, you know better than
to bust in here like this.
But, darling, it's after 5:00.
I thought you were through.
Ok, ok.
...your wife,
who looks as if anybody breathed
on her she'd break
out in a thick frost!
What is she?
A nymphomaniac or something?
What did you marry her for, anyway?
To wear on your lapel?
Why are you so worried about me?
Who's worried about you?
I'm worried about me.
All right,
I'm a charity patient.
You've got to have me
for taxes or something,
but you're still supposed to be
making me fit for normal life!
What's normal? Yours?
If it's a question
of values, your values stink.
Lousy, middle-class,
well-fed, smug existence.
All you care about is
a paycheck you didn't earn
and a beautiful thing
to go home to every night.
Stewart, darling!
Welcome home!
There's a fatted calf
on the stove!
This started before
she came in, though.
What's that?
An interpretation or something?
It doesn't go
very deep, does it?
Why don't you analyze my Oedipus
complex with my lousy father?
Suppose we let me
determine the course of treatment, eh?
After all, this is
your first case.
Don't you know how to do
any ID analysis here?
Isn't that the
classic procedure?
You're not a classic case.
Oh, insults now.
Stevie, since you
mention my values,
they include sitting here listening
to the bull you throw at me.
And I don't get more
than a little mad,
and I don't say "forget it."
Because one of my values
is not to toss in the sponge on
human commitments.
You have a genius
for belittling the world, Stevie.
Great. I'm glad you think
it's worth something.
You reduce me to
a fictitious character,
a predatory dolt.
This is what you do
to people and then
you wonder why you
can't relate to Th...
what a collection
of junky platitudes!
I don't know, maybe
you're sore at me
because you haven't got a woman
of your own, a home of your own...
Oh, stop it.
You're so brilliant.
I seem to be missing
a piece here.
I can't quite understand...
she gave me a lift
in that station wagon.
Did you know who she was?
Who do you think
you are, Stevie?
You're no different
from anybody else.
She's a good-looking woman.
Why shouldn't you have
certain thoughts about it?
You don't have to feel guilty
toward me or even afraid.
I'm not your father, Stevie.
And I'm not going
to run out on you like your father.
There's something
in the world besides betrayal.
What did you...Say?
Oh, Regina,
it's so funny! Ha ha!
Oh, yes, but this is
a new low in taste even for Vicky.
A dismal, dreary old
piece of wreck
you wouldn't even use
for washing the car.
Well, it's such a pity.
It's a beautiful old room,
and, well, that's where
I thought you could help me.
You have such beautiful
shops in Chicago,
and we have nothing here
but poor old Petlee's.
Well, I found myself visualizing
what I would choose
if it were left to me.
Well, you know that's fatal.
They shouldn't allow
me within 100 miles
of materials when there's
a budget involved.
Oh, well, Regina,
that's so sweet of you,
but it's not strictly true.
If I have any taste at all, it's because
I've absorbed everything you've taught me.
Well! Do you remember...
Daddy!
R-r-Rosie!
Mommy said I could stay
up until you got home.
That's swell.
I'll tuck you in myself. Hi, mark!
Hi, dad!
How are you?
Oh, uh, excuse me!
Listen, do you think you could
square things with Sadie for me?
Sure!
Ask her to get me something to eat.
I got to get right back.
- Ok.
- Good. Oowhaah!
Daddy, will you come up and
kiss me good night
before you go?
Well, I sure will.
I wouldn't miss that for the world.
Will you read me a story?
I'll read you a short one.
Daddy, what can we play?
How's about a little cribbage?
Ha ha!
Stay home tonight.
Now, are you sure
you have the measurements?
Right.
How long will...
yes, air express.
Oh, but Regina, how could you possibly
get them here for the meeting Tuesday?
Well, how on earth can he
make them that quickly?
Oh, how wonderful!
He must be a mad genius!
Good evening, darling.
I'll be with you in a minute.
That was Stewart.
No, I haven't had a chance
to tell him yet. I...
I don't know.
He may think I...
oh! Thank you. Thanks.
As a matter of fact,
I think myself he'll be pleased.
It's the first time I've
done anything for the...
oh, Regina, you're the most
extravagant, fabulous...
all right, darling.
You'll let me know?
And I'll leave word
if I'm not at home.
Good-bye, darling,
and thank you!
Have you got a moment?
Sure. I'm all ears.
Oh, darling, this is important.
Please sit down.
I'm sorry.
Go ahead, shoot.
I had an inspiration
this afternoon.
At least, I think it is.
How do you like this?
Chippendale rose
on antique satin.
It's very pretty.
What's it for?
Well, I first thought
of it this afternoon
when I picked up that
wild Fawn of yours.
In fact, that's what I came
bursting in your office to tell you.
I'm sorry I was so curt.
Oh, that's all right. I didn't...
listening to what you hear in there,
you get to feel it's a
little like a confessional.
That's a very high-strung boy.
Yes, I understand.
He's very attractive.
As I say, he's the one...
the feeling was mutual.
You made quite an impression.
- Really?
- Mmm.
What did he say?
Well, it got a little
complicated.
What went on with him?
Nothing.
We just talked.
Did he tell you about it?
Just about all of it.
Well, why do you
ask what went on?
Because I'm not sure what he thought
went on is what you thought went on.
He thought you were
flirting with him.
Is that what you think?
Karen.
This boy leads a very active
fantasy life with ladies.
He got going on you and
I couldn't stop him!
Is that my fault?
I didn't...
I wasn't really
thinking about you, Karen.
It's my job to think about him.
And what he felt,
not what I feel!
I'm not worrying about you!
I am about him.
When he saw you were my wife,
he got very scared,
went on the attack.
Said a lot of wild things about you,
about me.
What things?
It doesn't matter what things.
I've told you too much about
him already.
But you listen to them!
Of course I listen to them!
What do you think I'm there for?
And because they're
too sacred to tell me,
I get no chance
to reply to them?
Who expects you to?
Look, Karen.
Don't be so full of your feelings.
The point I'm making
is that this boy
has put his life in my hands.
I'm concerned about him, as I am
about everything at the clinic.
You might try to understand
that and share it.
I am trying to!
I came in this afternoon without...
by being so self-absorbed you
interrupt an hour?
I apologized for that.
And while you're
in your confessional
being a divinity
to your sick boy,
what am I supposed to be doing?
You're not supposed to be
showing yourself off
to my patients!
Give me one ounce of the attention
you give them day and night!
Now, what does that mean?
Just what you think it means!
How did the tournament go?
Fine. I'm in the semi-finals
playing conover.
Ooh, he's a tough one.
Hello, Sadie.
Good evening.
Oh, just skip the soup, Sadie.
It's your favorite.
Yeah, I know.
I don't have much time.
Just put something on a plate.
All right.
How long did you play?
Two hours.
Then we adjourned.
Hmm. You playing white?
Mm-hmm.
Looks like you've got a mate there if
you play it right.
What's your next move?
Well, I was going
to sacrifice my rook.
That's pretty fancy.
What for?
I take the Bishop with my rook
and his rook has to take mine.
Then I bring my queen
to knight 4
and threaten mate in one move.
Well! You know,
I think I'd better take up checkers!
- Sadie!
- Yes, sir?
Where's the Brandy?
Oh, it's on this side.
Oh, thank you.
With Martinis?
Sure! Why not?
What's tonight?
The concert.
Oh, Karen.
I'm sorry, I forgot.
I've got a patients' meeting.
Wouldn't tomorrow
night do as well?
It's their meeting.
I can't switch it around to suit myself.
It involves a dozen patients.
Well, can't Dev take it?
Oh, you know Dev.
Besides, this is my department.
I've been looking forward
to this for one week.
Look, I'll call
Meg Rinehart and ask her
to take the meeting if
it's that important to you.
It isn't, really.
I'm sorry, kare.
I'm sorry, too.
Mr. Appleton, if you please.
Appleton: Very well,
Mr. Holcomb.
We're not going to get
anywhere unless
we follow rules of
parliamentary procedure.
If everyone speaks at once,
it becomes very disorderly.
Please wait until
I recognize somebody.
Man: Well, hurry up.
Recognize somebody.
Holcomb: I recognize myself,
which I believe I have every
right to do. And I am...
woman: Oh, let someone else
talk for a change, Holcomb.
You blew your top
this afternoon.
Miss Demuth,
that is rude and uncalled for.
What's more,
if you don't like the way I...
I'm sorry. I... I am
sometimes a little dictatorial.
That's a fault I have...
I...I'm working on it.
Work harder.
Man: Oh, Dr. Mciver!
Sorry I'm late.
Oh, please, go right ahead.
Dr. Mciver, they're all confusing
occupational therapy with common labor.
Girl: Let's ask Dr. Mciver
what he thinks.
Sounds like a very vital topic.
What is it?
Holcomb: Quiet! Quiet!
Mr. Appleton,
you are being very difficult.
Actually, it was Mrs.
Rinehart's department.
Perhaps she would summarize.
No. Innocent bystander.
Well, Mrs. Jenkins,
then. It was her idea.
I had the impression
it was mine.
We both had the idea.
I was talking to Mrs. Rinehart this
afternoon about how there were going
to be new drapes in the library
when this scheme occurred to me.
Then we discovered that Lois
had had the same thought
when she was talking
to Mrs. Rinehart...
I still think mine came first.
Who had the idea first
is completely, uh...
- Irrelevant?
- Irrelevant.
The point is, we could
make them ourselves.
The patients, I mean.
A group project.
Girl: They'd be all our
own from beginning to end
and Stevie Holte could
make some original designs
and we'd put them
together and sew them.
Everybody's in favor of
it except Mr. Holcomb.
Now, now, just a moment.
I did not say that I was not
in favor of them.
I merely raised the question...
does Mrs. Rinehart
think it's workable?
Might be.
You don't sound
too enthusiastic.
I don't mean to.
It's an interesting idea.
Girl: It's a wonderful idea!
And you say Stevie Holte wants
to do the designs?
Girl: Yes.
Oh, thank you.
- Stevie?
- Yes?
Can you?
We figure on using
unbleached muslin.
Which I could wipe my feet on
and it would look
better than those.
Oh, is that the plan?
No!
No, the plan is to do designs of
our own lives here.
I don't know
what they'll be yet.
But when we get them up, it'll look like
our living room and not miss inch's.
What makes you so confident?
Isn't that obvious?
I'm scared stiff!
Does that mean all right on the
drapes, doctor?
It means all right so far.
Quiet! Mr. Appleton,
in the name of heaven!
Excuse me, doctor.
Holcomb: We're still
without any decision
as to whether this is
an administrative problem,
in which case we should
consult Dr. Devanal...
well, for the moment let's
say it's a clinical matter
since I'm here tonight
and Dr. Devanal isn't.
Now, uh...
Right over there.
Operator: Calling 4-1098.
Calling Mrs. Mciver.
Yes, this is Mrs. Mciver.
What?
Oh! Regina!
I thought it was something wrong
with the children!
What? On the plane tomorrow?
I don't believe it.
Oh, Regina, you're
a miracle worker.
Vicky inch? Oh,
don't worry about her.
I'll call her at once
and tell her.
She's no problem.
Oh, Regina, darling!
Thank you so terribly much.
And we'll see you
next week then.
Good-bye.
Yes, who is it?
Mrs. Mciver: Vicky,
this is Karen Mciver.
Yes?
I'd like to discuss something
with you for the clinic.
How have you been?
Satisfactory.
Darling,
could you speak a trifle louder?
I'm calling in the
intermission of the concert.
Everyone in town is galloping up and
down the corridor.
Close the booth!
Whew! I can't. I'll perish.
It's quite sultry here.
I never understand why this place
cannot be air-conditioned.
Inch: Money.
What, darling?
Inch: I said money.
How are you?
Inch: I told you satisfactory!
Do you want one of these?
No, but thanks so much.
I'll see you all later.
Inch: Karen!
Yes, Vicky. I'm calling about
the library drapes.
I've been talking with Regina.
Inch: Who?
Regina Mitchell-Smythe.
She has this material.
I have a swatch here
she let me have.
Well, if she'd let us have
a few swatches of money
it would be more to the point.
Vicky, I don't think the money
should be an obstacle.
Shouldn't it?
Last year the clinic spent over $100
just on thumbtacks.
Thumbtacks?
And paper clips.
We can't afford them.
Vicky, you're being
simply obstructive!
Am I?
Karen, there are
channels for doing things here.
I am beginning to doubt.
And traditions which newcomers
may not be familiar with.
Vicky, are you referring
to Dr. Mciver and myself?
I'm certainly referring to
Regina Mitchell-Smythe,
who seems not to know that I do
the decorating at the clinic.
She has been chairman of
the board for 5 years.
Sprung up like a toadstool.
What?
Toadstool!
Overnight.
Regina Mitchell-Smythe is
a most influential woman
and works very hard
for the clinic.
No harder than I do.
I've been with the clinic longer
than anyone except Dr. Devanal.
I remember when the late
Dr. Sanford Collins founded it.
Why, I remember when that building
was put up in the first place in 1907.
Really?
And those drapes
that are up there?
I didn't have to send
to Chicago for them.
I picked them myself
from Petlee's.
In 1907?
Let me warn you, Vicky...
hello?
Vicky! Vicky!
Jim Petlee?
Vicky inch.
Well, you can go
back afterwards.
That cotton wrap?
$2.99 a yard, 12.5% discount?
I'll take it.
You can send it out tomorrow.
Dev!
You go back to your seat, dear.
I'll join you.
Karen, we ought to
put you in the bank
and live off the interest.
You look like a million dollars.
Dev, I...I hate to bother you, but
I'm a little upset.
Could I talk with
you for a moment?
Why, of course!
Get you anything?
No. I'd like some
fresh air, please.
Absolutely.
Where is Stewart tonight?
Isn't he a music lover?
As a matter of fact, he's not.
He went back to the clinic.
Oh?
Now, what's fretting
your handsome head?
What can I do?
Dev, how do you get
on with Vicky inch?
Most of the time.
Why?
She was very rude
to me just now.
Is she here?
No. On the phone.
Oh! Ha! That's just Vicky.
Don't take it personally.
She made it
unmistakably personal.
Referred to me as a newcomer.
She even hung up on me.
Only once?
What was it about?
What do you think
of Regina, Dev?
Regina? Oh, very capable woman.
She's been very valuable to us.
Then I don't understand why
Vicky called her a toadstool.
A toadstool?
Regina?
Ha ha ha!
Vicky's a character!
In what connection, Karen?
Well, I looked in
the library today
when I stopped by the clinic...
Today? How did I miss that?
Well, I got my first real look
at those curtains.
They're a disgrace!
Vicky's doing
something about them.
Vicky spoke as though I had no right
to think about the clinic at all.
She made me feel
suddenly left out, unwanted here.
Unwanted? How could
you feel that?
I've never given you that feeling,
have I, Karen?
Well, you leave Vicky to me.
I'll talk to her in the morning,
give you a ring.
Oh, Dev, you're very sweet.
Better yet, why don't we meet
for a late-afternoon drink,
put our heads together?
Settle this in no time at all.
- Dr. Mciver?
- Yes, Mrs. O’Brien?
It's Mr. Wictz, doctor.
He's done it again.
Done what?
Had a party, last night.
Miss Kubiecki reports
it went on till 2:00.
Several of the
patients complained.
To miss Kubiecki?
No.
To you? No, among themselves.
Good. Then it's the business
of the patients' committee.
to take it up with Mr. Wictz.
That's what the committee's for.
Anything else?
I found out where he keeps it...
in his bureau drawer,
under the socks.
Keeps what?
The whiskey.
- How would you know that?
- I looked.
- You mean you searched his room?
- Of course.
Mrs. O'brien, you're a...
Human being and, as such,
you feel that you're entitled
to a certain privacy, right?
Yes.
And you'd resent it if
someone violated that privacy.
Yes.
Well, there's some evidence that
Mr. Wictz is human, too.
- Shall I take it away from him?
- Of course not.
But he has somebody
in for a nightcap every night.
I've got to do something...
see that he gets clean glasses.
But, Dr. Mciv...
Mrs. O'brien, 5 months ago,
Mr. Wictz wanted to cut his throat!
It's much better for him
to want somebody in
for a nightcap, don't you think?
Dr. Wolff's been coaxing
him out of his hole.
Once he sticks his nose out,
we can't bang down on it.
It isn't consistent.
You understand?
Yes, doctor.
Good morning, Stevie.
It...it wasn't Lois' idea
or Mrs. Jenkins'.
It was yours.
Well, what am I supposed to do...
get real flattered and be grateful
to you for the rest of my life?
You figure this will get me over
my neurotic inertia or something?
Get out of here!
You know what I think this is?
I think this is
a neurotic acting-out on me
as a surrogate figure
for your son.
Could be...
How did you know I had a son?
Well, I didn't.
I meant...
"Son" in general.
Oh.
You live alone.
How do you know that?
Well, I've walked by that, uh,
garage place where you live.
You divorced, or what happened?
My husband was killed in
a wreck 4 years ago.
So was our son.
I wasn't.
My mother...
Died last year.
That's when I fell apart.
Is your father still alive?
I don't know.
I don't know where he is.
He ran out on us
when I was a kid.
Did you love him very much?
He was a real louse.
Only I...I shouldn't say that.
Why not?
You're not supposed to.
My mother did
her loving best to ruin me.
I fooled her,
though. Got over it.
Withstood it, anyway.
How?
Got analyzed.
Now, I'm perfect.
You mean people...
Get better?
It helps, if you work at it.
Now, beat it.
I have to write a memo.
About what?
The price of muslin,
if it's any of your business.
I don't...Usually
ask questions much.
I'm not...Very interested
in anybody but myself.
I don't usually...
Tell people much, either.
You're going to hate yourself
in the morning.
Here.
I'm not sure you deserve them.
Vicky.
Oh. Uh, Dr. Devanal
is on the phone.
I know. Been trying to get through
for the last 20 minutes.
Who is he gabbing with, anyhow?
Mrs. Mciver.
Can you put these on cloth, Abe?
Easy, and silkscreen
them. They look good.
Good.
Let's go ahead.
You feel kind of proud, huh?
A little.
You should.
This boy's at the point
where he needs people he can trust.
He likes you, you know.
I like him.
That's good judgment
on both sides.
If we can make
this work, we may be able
to show him we're different...
good parents.
Oh, could I use
your phone a minute?
Surely.
This is Mciver. Will you
get my home, please?
Hello?
Sorry. I was in the shower.
Oh, I...I'm sorry,
dear. No, I can't.
I have a date
for cocktails. Why?
Well, um...
Never mind.
The lake will
be there next week.
Uh...
Look, Karen, it's been a long time
since we've had a chance to talk.
How about tonight?
No, I won't.
I'll be home early.
Ok, I'll see you then.
Good-bye.
Excuse me.
Can you tell me
where to take this?
It's material from Petlee's.
Oh, that must be the canvas
for Mr. Irwin.
No, it's cotton rep
for miss inch.
Miss inch?
Yeah.
Man: Good night, Mrs. Rinehart.
Oh, good night, doctor.
Oh, uh, miss inch's office is just
inside the service entrance.
Thank you.
Man: Stevie! Mrs. Rinehart tells me
your sketches are splendid, splendid!
Oh, they are, Stevie. I saw them.
They're beautiful.
I've never seen her so
enthusiastic about any...
Man: Ah! The Cezanne
of the psychos!
This is your moment!
Make the most of it.
You're on the assembly
line of success.
From now on, you'll hover
between exhilaration
and despair.
I pity you.
For a few moments of elation,
a mass of inflamed nerve ends!
I don't think you're very
funny Mr. Capp.
I think you ridicule
other people
to hide your own insecurity.
I detest myself.
Appleton: Gibbon captured
it magnificently
in his decline and fall
of the Roman empire,
but he missed the
delicious irony to be found
in the pattern of the Caesars.
Now, granted,
Caligula was a beast...
cruel, cunning, and licentious.
Nevertheless, it...
Yes? Come in.
I'm not disturbing you?
Oh, Mrs. Rinehart.
No. Come in.
It's nice to have a visitor.
It gets lonely here
this time of day.
I'm not keeping you
from your dinner, am I?
No, I was just having a Sherry
before I go in.
Always do.
Have one with me?
Why, thank you.
I'd love one.
You don't eat here
at night, do you?
No.
Where do you eat?
Oh...In town, usually.
Mmm, expensive.
Oh, isn't everything these days?
I... I understand your new drapes for
the library are costing a fortune.
270 plus.
The entire expense
is unnecessary.
It's a crime!
Have you begun on them?
Yes. Why?
Because, if you hadn't,
I think I know
how we can reduce
the crime to a misdemeanor.
But you've already begun.
Sue.
You wouldn't...
I mean, um...
Would you like to
go downtown with me
to the movies
tonight, to celebrate?
- No!
- Oh!
I'll get that for you, my dear.
A little water. That's
very easily mopped up.
Sue: Stevie?
Stevie, wait a minute.
I want to tell you something.
I'm ashamed of it.
Oh, I wanted to go.
Nobody ever asked me before...
But I just can't.
Why not?
I'm phobic.
I haven't been off grounds
since I came, not once.
It's what's wrong with me.
What would happen if you did?
I mean, I-like going downtown
to the movies?
Start screaming or something?
Well, they'd think
you were a critic, that's all.
Well...
I'd like to try,
though. I mean, well...
Maybe if you went with me
and knew about it,
it would be all right...
If you took care of me.
All right.
Let's go, then.
Oh, no.
I...I didn't mean now.
I just meant sometime.
Well...
I couldn't go suddenly.
Ok.
Sometime.
The muslin... cartoons?
Well... muslin cartoons?
Mrs. Rinehart, just
what are you up to?
I'm not up to anything,
miss inch.
I... I talked this over
with Dr. Mciver today,
and he feels that
from a therapeutic...
so that's why you're here...
so that woman can have her way!
What woman?
You cat's-paw!
Miss inch, I came here
to ask your cooperation.
And I thought you
came here to talk to me.
Muslin cartoons, indeed!
I never heard
of such taradiddle in all my life!
I haven't the faintest notion...
you tell your
Dr. Mciver you saw me
and I said you've gone too far!
And tell him to keep his loose,
busybody wife's nose
out of my affairs!
Karen: Oh, I'm sorry.
I seem to be coming
to you with all my problems today.
Marriage is a funny
business, Karen.
You can starve for something
you don't get in it.
Oh, it's a great institution
but, like all institutions,
something of the
individual gets lost in it,
so...Either we starve
or we look for it outside.
Dev, I...I'm not
complaining. It...
It's just that...well,
in the beginning,
when...When we lived in Chicago,
there was Stewart's
career, of course,
but it was exciting then.
We...we had a life together.
We seemed to bring
something to each other.
And now?
I'm not really selfish, Dev.
He wanted to come out
here and I didn't,
but I came, and now
gradually it's changed.
He's become so absorbed,
so...so unapproachable.
He has work to express
himself in. I don't.
I have nothing, and when I do try
to find something
to bring me closer to him, he...
I need...
I don't know what I need.
Hello.
Found your message at home.
Sounded urgent.
I didn't mean to drag you out.
Oh, it's all right.
It's on the way. What's up?
I'm afraid I made a
mistake...a bad one.
Some material came from
Petlee's for Vicky inch.
I... I tried to get hold of you
and then I went in to see her.
She took the top of my head off.
- She did?
- Mmm...
Heh heh! Well, I'll talk to her
in the morning.
Forget it.
I think I'd better
brief you a little:
I'm a cat's-paw.
You're using me to further some
sinister scheme
of Mrs. Mciver's.
Karen?
Mmm. Quote: Tell Dr. Mciver
to keep his wife out
of my affairs. Unquote.
More or less, minus adjectives.
Now, what does that mean?
I don't know. She wouldn't discuss
it further, stomped out on me.
Hmm. Maybe I better
call her from here.
May I?
Oh, of course.
Here...can I help you with that?
No, I can manage.
Oh, I'm sorry.
The bulb's out.
That's all right.
Wonder who put that
bat in her belfry?
Vicky?
Yeah.
Thought I should ask you.
What...you mean you think I am?
Using me?
Yeah.
No.
Here...I'll help you.
I'm afraid the place
is in a shambles.
No, that's all right.
Don't worry about it.
I'm really a better
housekeeper than this.
Looks fine.
Give me a week.
- Where's the phone?
- Oh, it's on the floor there.
Thank you.
Oh, hello, Vicky. This is Dr. Mciver.
How are you?
Good. Uh, look...
I, uh,
I want to unmix this
mix-up about the drapes.
No, no, no.
W-wai-wait a minute.
Karen called you?
Well, what's Karen got...
well, yes, of course,
I'll ask her, but I still don't know...
hello, Vicky?
Vi...
well, there's one thing you can't
take away from Vicky inch...
she does have her foibles,
and several other people's, too.
Oh.
You said something
last night about privacy.
Snooping is one of the prerogatives
of all medical men.
But not nurses?
Mrs. O'brien?
She's not a nurse.
She's a policewoman in disguise.
She'll learn.
That's a nice-looking
chair. You make it?
Yes.
Uh...Think I could trust it?
Stronger than you are.
Well, I should hope so. Heh heh.
What about Mr Wictz?
What if his drinking does
annoy the other patients?
Simple. Let the patient
committee call him on it.
Well, can he take it?
The patients?
Sure.
Well, he better.
He can't keep people up all night.
He's not Scheherazade.
Oh.
One thing I've learned
since I've been here...
a sense of humor's
indispensable.
Ah, it sure is.
You're in on so much suffering, so much
goes wrong all day, you begin to fray.
Then you don't have
anything left to give them.
And they need so much more.
Sure, they're starving.
Here.
Now, that's a good-looking case.
You make that, too?
No. My husband.
Oh, I'm sorry.
But, in a...
Kind of magic way,
somebody always comes up
with something.
Like these, uh...
Like these drapes of yours.
I haven't seen Stevie so eager
about anything
since he got here.
I owe you something.
That was sue's idea.
Mm-hmm.
I just made it contagious.
I thought it was
very skillfully handled.
I thought so myself,
until I was under your eye.
Then I got uncomfortable.
Tell me...how would you
have done it?
Well, I don't know.
There aren't any rules.
If your heart's in the
right place and your brain,
you just trust
what comes to you.
You think mine is?
Are?
Heh heh heh!
You work here
a few months more,
I'll let you know.
Oh.
Hey, you're right.
This thing is comfortable.
Certainly, it's comfortable.
So why don't I just
sit here instead?
Instead of what?
Instead of going out into the
night to do battle with Vicky inch.
Yes, sir. This is going to be
a friendly place.
Mmm, in another week or two.
It's friendly now.
Throw me out.
All right. Get out.
Thank you.
Let me know who wins.
Yeah, sure. I will.
Good night.
Who's there?
It's Dr. Mciver.
What do you want?
I want to talk to you. Open up.
I've retired!
I'll talk to you in the morning!
Vicky, this is forcible entry.
Open the door.
Wait a minute.
Dr. Mciver, I must
ask you to go.
I hope you realize
you're breaking the law.
This house and the ground
it stands on is my property.
I've asked you to leave
and you're trespassing...
Vicky,
stop drooling and sit down.
Sit down!
And shut up!
Now, first of all,
don't ever hang up on me
like that again, Vicky.
And if you do, I'll pull your
dress over your head
and beat some manners into you.
You wouldn't dare!
Dare me.
What's that for?
Dr. Mciver, I have neighbors.
What will they think,
with me not properly dressed?
You're dressed, all right.
I am not.
Then you want your neighbors
to see that you're not?
Dr. Mciver!
I'd like an ashtray, Vicky.
I don't smoke!
Then get me a saucer,
or don't you eat?
Thank you.
Now, just what...
sit down, sit down.
Just what is all this
nonsense about Karen?
I find it very peculiar...
I don't care what you find it!
And incidentally,
this act of yours...
going around,
frightening people...
I've seen it tried too often.
I know it frightens you more
than anybody else, so cut it out.
Our job running the clinic
is tough enough
without fancy dramatics.
Now, when did Karen call you?
Last night.
What about?
Swatches!
What I'm to do,
what she's to do,
what Regina Mitchell-Smythe is going
to do about drapes for the library!
I see.
Well, I'm, uh,
I'm sorry this got
so tangled up, Vicky,
but the decision on
Mrs. Rinehart's project
is one of therapeutic
policy. It stands.
The patients make the drapes.
They'll be very peculiar.
It's a matter of taste, on which
you are in no way the final arbiter.
Who's to explain
to the trustees?
I'm running the clinic,
Vicky, not the trustees.
I was under the impression
that Dr. Devanal is
running the clinic!
Didn't you ever
read my contract?
No.
How'd you miss that?
Dev keeps it locked in his desk.
Oh.
Well, Mrs. Rinehart will
be ordering a few things,
so whatever she needs,
you take care of it.
Uh...
This your father?
Yes.
Formidable gent.
He fought the Indians to
settle this territory.
Oh.
Well, good night, Vicky.
Uh, would you...
Could I get you
a cup of tea or something?
No, thanks, Vicky.
Dr. Mciver!
I...Do you think we could...
Get along better together?
Why, sure, Vicky.
My terms are simple...
unconditional surrender.
Good night.
Well!
Karen?
Mom? Come on and watch me
beat the tar out
of your husband.
I think I'll go up, mark.
Good night.
Karen,
I thought we had a date.
I got stuck at the office.
I've been waiting
3 hours, Karen.
I'd like to talk to you.
I'd rather not now.
I have a bad headache.
Well, then, what were you
drinking for?
You know alcohol
dilates the capillaries.
Oh, go write a book
if you know so much.
Well, there's one thing
I didn't know so much about!
Karen.
What are you quarreling
with me about?
What?
I said what are you
quarreling with...
what are you quarreling
with me about?
I'm not quarreling!
Why didn't you tell me
about these drapes of yours?
Seems odd I have to hear
about it from other...
when?
What?
When should I have told you?
Well, anytime.
What do you mean "when"?
Last night at the concert,
perhaps, during the intermission?
Oh, Karen.
I tried to. When are you
ever in long enough?
I even telephoned this evening.
Sadie said you weren't home.
I thought we had a date!
I was at Vicky's, trying
to straighten out this tangle!
Before you know it, we'll have
so many drapes around here,
we can wrap the
clinic up in them.
I straightened it out with Dev.
Dev?
Is that who you had dinner with?
Yes. Isn't that allowed?
Karen, you didn't go
to Dev to sweet-talk him
into these drapes, too, did you?
Did you talk about them?
Among other things.
Listen, I want
to tell you something.
Don't you ever again
go over my head to Dev
about anything to do
with this clinic!
Do you understand?
Meg Rinehart has a project on
for the patients to make
drapes of their own.
It's going to be tough enough without
any additional monkey business,
least of all with Dev.
Has it never occurred to you
that I might be interested in
talking to Dev with no purpose
except to talk with
another human being?
Ha ha!
We discussed a great
deal besides the clinic.
Yes, you must have.
What else did you
talk to him about for 4 hours?
As a matter of fact,
I talked about you.
Oh, I see.
You've been encouraging Dev
by weeping on his shoulder.
I don't weep.
You don't know what's going on
inside that man. Leave him alone.
Huh! Don't I?
When did you last have
a heart-to-heart talk with Dev?
Is that what you think you had?
I hate to break into your
little dream, Karen,
but you're not exactly a unique
event in Dr. Devanal's life.
It happens with
every woman he meets,
including his secretary and...
will you stop knowing everything
about everything?!
Rosie's asleep.
Don't turn into an
attentive father suddenly.
Now, what does that mean...that
I'm neglecting the kids, too?
Yes, the only ones
who get anything real
from you are those professional
children out at the clinic.
Yesterday in school,
they asked Rosie
what she wanted to be
when she grew up.
Would you like to know
what she answered?
A patient!
People...
Fight sometimes, mark.
Good night.
As it happens, when this "monkey
business"... as you call it...
about the drapes first
occurred to me yesterday,
I stopped by your
office to tell you.
I tried to tell you last night.
I thought you'd be pleased.
Now I'm sick of the whole thing.
I don't care
if they never go up!
I'd be home more, Karen...
If there were more
to come home to.
What, for instance?
A real woman.
You don't make me
feel like a woman.
What do you think I've been
trying to tell you for months?
I am a woman. I want
to be one, but I...
I have to feel I...
I'm desired!
Everyone thinks
you're desirable.
Do you?
Do you?!
No, you think you're
going to win this game,
but you're not!
Hooray!
Ha ha ha!
Has he or has he not
the authority
to let the patients make
their own drapes?
The patients do what?
Library drapes,
from start to finish.
Well, that's... didn't you know?
Don't you have to ok things like this?
Well, uh...
Aren't you administrative
head anymore?
What?
- Why haven't I seen Mciver's contract?
- You never asked me.
I'm asking you now!
Vicky, I'd only be too glad to
have you look at this thing.
It's in the bottom
right-hand drawer.
No, it's not!
Unlock it, and let's
have a look!
We'll have to continue this another time.
I have a patient.
Oh, uh, Cobby, send Mr. Capp in...
The minute he arrives.
Now, just a minute.
I want to dictate a letter.
I'll get my book.
No, no, nevermind.
Here. Use this.
Now, Vicky, you'll have to
excuse me.
Get out.
Pardon?
Inch: I said, "get out!"
All right.
Now, look here, Vicky!
I'm good and sick
of your high-hand!
What do you think you are
around here, the queen bee?
You're just another employee.
Then fire me!
Well, am I fired?
Of course you're not fired.
Don't be ridiculous.
Because you can't.
You gave that up,
too, didn't you?
Didn't you?
That's why you didn't want me
to read
Mciver's contract, isn't it?
Isn't it?
Why didn't you tell me?
I haven't even told Edna.
I have some pride left, Vicky.
You let me fight your battles,
when you knew I could
be fired for it.
Now, look here, Vicky.
We've been working
together for 20 years.
Friends are supposed
to be able to lean on each other.
A man should stand
on his own two feet.
I've been standing on mine
for 48 years.
It's time someone around here began
holding me up once in a while.
You think Mciver will?
Just last night,
his own wife was standing...
I remember Sanford Collins in here.
It was always a beautiful, big room.
It's a sad sight.
What is?
Seeing such a small man in it.
Oh, Mr. Capp...
Do you mind waiting
for me a few minutes?
Thank you.
Cobby...
Uh, what's my schedule
this afternoon?
Never mind. Clear me up
for the rest of the day.
I can't work anymore.
I'm due out.
Petlee? Inch.
Fine. Jim, this cotton rep...
I find it's not satis...
you better have Albert
come and take it back.
Uh, Cobby, take a memo
for me, please.
From the office of
the medical director...
To general distribution.
Subject: Library drapes.
It is my decision,
based on careful examination
of the elements involved,
and taking into consideration
the expressed wishes
of the chairman of
the board of trustees...
Sadie!
Mciver?
Yes.
Air express for
Mrs. Stewart Mciver.
You're welcome.
Sadie!
I'm not too early?
It's all right, Sadie.
Come in here.
We did have a date
for lunch, didn't we?
Did we? I don't remember.
Oh! Karen, I'm sorry.
Well, as long as I'm here, why don't
we drive out to the lake for lunch?
I can't, Dev. I'm not dressed.
I have... take your time, Princess,
there is nothing
I can't cancel this afternoon.
Oh, Dev, would you
care for a drink?
Sure, I'd love one.
I loved last night, Karen.
You know...After you left, I got to
thinking about something you said.
How we all go around...
Each of us shut up
inside himself.
Oh, it's nobody's fault.
It's just the way it goes.
Here we are...Both...
Searching for something,
hoping for something.
Well...
I thought...
What did you think, Dev?
That just because of a
few drinks and a steak
and your help with those
ridiculous drapes that...
Karen!
You make it sound so...so sordid.
Isn't it?
Well...Last night,
it seemed to me that we...
I really thought we...
What happened, Karen?
What happened with everybody?
Mark and Rosie will be home
from school any minute.
I wish you'd leave.
Dev, I...
I'm sorry. I...
I know I led you into this.
Wipe your face, Dev.
Got a cigarette?
May I visit, or am I rupturing
the delicate bud of creation?
Is that Genesis or synthesis?
It isn't finished.
You can see the others
in the barn.
Ah, incompleteness.
That's the only
triumph worthwhile.
With a finished work, you subject
yourself to public scrutiny, praise,
ridicule, and all the other vulgarities
that go with accomplishment.
That's why I congratulate you.
You've just been relieved
of a major responsibility.
Once again, talent is rejected.
The itsy-bitsiest triumph,
with that memo from Dr. Devanal
canceling your drapes.
What?
Didn't you know?
Where is it?
Holcomb's got it
in the barber shop.
I'm sorry, I thought everybody...
where's that memo?
Stevie, please,
don't be worried about that memo.
Everything's going
to be all right.
Gentlemen, please!
You can't have that!
Please, Stevie!
You must read...
"I waited for her,
and when I went to her..."
man: Stevie!
Stevie!
I'm taking my drawings.
They're not your drawings.
They belong to us.
Are you the only
one who has put any love into this?
Get out of the way!
I'd like to use your
office a minute, Mrs. Rinehart.
Come on, Stevie.
It's the first
I've heard of this.
But you don't want
an explanation.
You want to believe the worst.
Dr. Devanal there, miss Cobb?
Well, where is he?
I want to talk to him.
Any place you think he might be?
Yes, yes, there is a message,
and take it down,
I want him to get this verbatim.
Dear Dev, I think there's
a misunderstanding
on the subject of these drapes.
There's more at stake here
than the wishes
of the chairman of
the board of trustees.
Meanwhile, the patient's
committee will go ahead
with the drapes which
it already has in work.
Mciver. And have him call
me soon as he gets back.
Big man.
Not so big.
Are you going to send me away to
a closed hospital?
Depends entirely on you.
Start knocking people down,
we can't keep you here.
Is that what you're working for?
Oh, what's the difference?
I'm just so tired of being sick.
An hour ago I...
Don't laugh...
I thought I was well
enough to get out of here.
It's like trying to get
out of a greased well.
Not quite. Remember how you were
when you first got here?
That was closer to bottom.
What do you think?
I don't know.
You can't help me.
You may be right, you may not.
But when something like this happens,
if you can't hang on for 5 minutes,
you're never going to find out.
I'm free at 2:00, ok?
Let's get going on these drapes
before someone else horns in.
I'll talk to Devanal.
Abe's coming over tonight.
He's going to test it
on the silkscreen.
Good. Let me know.
Mr. Holcomb...
I'm sorry.
Stevie?
I made it myself.
Uh, Stevie,
I was thinking about what you said,
I mean, about going
to the movies in town,
and I think I could now if
you still wanted to take me.
Well, you don't
have to say anything right now.
You can think about it.
Oh, I'm glad you came, Cobby.
Cobby, my dear... But first,
I'm going to get you a little drink.
I don't want a drink.
Listen, I shouldn't
have come here.
Why, if anybody saw me here...
of course, you want a drink.
Wake you up.
Get the memo out all right?
Good!
We're going to fight, Cobby.
Know that? We've got
our backs to the wall.
You have, maybe, but I don't.
Do you really want me to
work, or not?
You said you had
some work to do.
What if somebody
saw me come out here?
Cobby, you're all I've got left.
You know that.
All I've got left.
You're important to me.
Sure...to answer the phone
when Mrs. Mciver calls.
Listen,
everybody's been calling me
wanting to know where you are.
How much longer can
you hide out here?
Who is hiding? Heh heh!
Still got a drink or two
up my sleeve. Heh.
What I said 4 years ago
to Regina...
I... I... I said,
"all right, Regina.
Bring in this Mciver whoever-he-is
if you want to."
"I am perfectly willing
to take a back seat for a while."
The phone's ringing.
Do you want me to answer it,
or what?
Huh? Oh!
But of course.
Hello.
Hello, Regina. Dev.
Regina, there's
an emergency here.
I want you to fly down tomorrow
before the others.
It's important.
Yes...what?
Oh, just a moment.
Now then, operator.
What...she's not?
Why not?
Well...
Keep trying, operator.
Cobby, get me
Vicky on the phone.
I want to talk to Vicky.
Get her yourself.
Oh...
That's all you got me
out here for.
It's the craziest thing
I ever got into.
Shhh!
Hello? Hello, Vicky.
Of course it is.
Who did you think it was?
I...oh, fine.
I'm fine.
Standing on my own two feet.
Vicky, we're going to fight.
This is the showdown.
Dev, where are you, anyhow?
And what are you talking about?
I'll tell you what to do.
Prepare a report.
Yes, that will do it.
Show the board...
you know what I mean...
how everything went wrong.
The mess Mciver's
gotten us into.
You know, late hours, drinking...
Patients taking over the place.
Pour it on!
And then we walk
into that meeting on Tuesday
and just throw it on the table.
What good will all that do?
Now listen, Vicky.
I'm going to clean house!
And you better be
on the right side, or out you go.
Mciver wants you out.
He's gone to Regina about it.
Sh-she told me, Vicky!
Mciver stays, and it's a-snickety bang,
off with your head. So...
woman: Maybe if the staff
could settle its problems,
the patients could
settle theirs.
Good point.
I promise you, we'll have a
policy meeting on this soon
as I can communicate
with Dr. Devanal.
The main point is
whether we have
self-government here at all.
And if we haven't,
don't tell us we have, Dr. Mciver.
Just hang up
any drapes you want,
and let's take all this rigamarole of
a committee and so and so,
and give it back to the Indians.
Or miss inch.
Look, all I'm asking of you at
the moment is to be patient.
What we're trying to
do here isn't easy.
Self-government never is.
But I think we can
all put it through.
Anyway, let's try, hmm?
Well, um...
Excuse me.
Oh, well, uh,
I...I...I think, uh...
if you think they'll make any changes
around here, Holcomb,
you're just kidding yourself.
Karen, I'm in a meeting.
I haven't
Edna Devanal?
What does she want?
I don't know where he is.
Nobody seems to.
Just threw his
stink bomb and ran.
I thought maybe you did.
I haven't seen Dev since...
I have to talk
with you about us.
I'm frightened
at what's happened.
Stewart, I...
Karen, I can't talk now.
Mr. Holcomb? Meeting over?
Adjourned.
Dr. Mciver.
Yes, Mr. Capp.
Uh...Holcomb's pretty upset.
Dr. Devanal missed
his hour today.
I see.
By the way,
have you heard from Dr. Devanal?
Thank you.
No. No, I haven't.
Did, uh...
Did he cancel your hour, too?
Yes, but I don't get
hysterical like Holcomb.
I feel fine.
Good. Good.
I'm glad to hear it.
Oh, miss Gavney.
Yes, doctor?
Dr. Wolff will be here
all evening, won't he,
in case anyone wants
to talk to him?
Why, of course, sir.
He's...
fine. Good night, miss Gavney.
Good night, doctor.
Thank you.
Good night, Mr. Capp.
Oh, Abe.
You're so right.
The world's becoming dehydrated.
What they can't
dry up, they freeze.
Slicing has become a lost art.
Now tell me, when did you last
see a woman
cutting an orange?
Listen, as far as I'm concerned,
the more art that's
lost, the better.
Well, if it isn't
the good gray doctor!
Hello.
Rinehart: Come in. Come in.
Thank you. I, uh,
saw the lights.
Irwin: Have a seat.
Give him a glass of wine.
Do you good. No, thanks.
I'll have to be getting along.
I, uh, just finished a meeting.
I don't think I did too well.
Oh.
Woman: Good evening.
Irwin: Careful with that, honey.
It's valuable.
Rinehart: Doctor,
you haven't met Abe's wife.
Well, no.
I haven't.
Shirley, this is the
world-famous mind reader
and deep-sea diver,
the great Mciver.
- How do you do?
- Very glad to know you.
Abe said it would be all right
if I came along.
I give him inspiration.
Good for you.
Well, Abe, how is
it going to work?
Ah, it's in the lap
of the gods, now.
You can only rely on my cool skill
and animal cunning.
Mciver: Stevie really
got Wolff, didn't he?
Irwin: He's got your immaculate
scientific preoccupation.
Mrs. Irwin: Won't you have
something to eat with us, Dr.Mciver?
He just said no.
Don't ply the man.
Now, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
I changed my mind.
Ply me.
Good. Here.
Start with this.
Ah, spaghetti.
Wonderful.
Rinehart: Will you be able to
stay for a great experiment?
I don't know.
How long is it going to take, Abe?
Irwin: Ah, be patient, doctor.
This isn't something
you can toss off
like mending a split
personality, or something.
This is art.
Well, Mrs. Irwin, I can see that
your child is going to be reared
with a healthy respect
for the arts.
Abe will have him painting like
the Venetians by the time he's 3.
Don't tell me you doctors
are going to start
analyzing kids before
they're even born, huh?
You wouldn't suspect it, but Abe's
pretty excited about being a father.
Rinehart: Everything is
debatable in life, except babies:
Husbands, careers, art.
When a baby is around,
nothing else counts.
How right you are.
Irwin: Ta-da!
Irwin: How about that?
Mciver: Hey, that's good!
Isn't it?
Stevie has a sardonic touch,
a sort of jovial Goya.
I think more like Steinberg.
More like you're all
a little drunk.
Oh...
Abe's really very pleased.
It's difficult to tell,
but I've had experience.
- How do you tell?
- He eats.
Whenever he eats,
things are all right.
Oh, it used to worry me
before we were married...
for days at a time... nothing.
Then suddenly,
at 3:00 in the morning,
he'd get hungry, make me
get up and fix him a sandwich.
And from now on,
it's going to be me who will have
to get up at 3:00 in the
morning, warm the bottle.
Serves you right!
Hey, Shirley, you know, it's about
time you ought to be in bed.
We can go on with this
in the morning.
We can't leave this mess.
Leave it.
- How are you going to get home?
- I'll manage.
If you need a lift,
I'll drop you.
Fine. Take her home, Abe.
You're a good man
in a chin fest.
We ought to do this
again at my house sometime, doc.
Just say when.
- Good night.
- Good night, Shirley.
Doc?
Yeah.
- You be sure to cure this kid, huh?
- We'll do our best, Abe.
See you.
- Good night... And thanks a lot.
- Oh, any time, doctor.
- Nicest part of every party...
- Hmm?
When everybody leaves.
Oh. You want to wash or dry?
I don't care.
More sense
of accomplishment washing.
You wash.
All right. Will you get a towel?
The first cupboard
on the right...
the one that says "clean rags".
Yes, ma'am.
* doo doo * there you are.
Thank you.
How long were you married?
6 years, 8 months, and 2 days.
Oh...
Boy: Come on, you guys!
Let's go get some chow!
Hey! Hey!
Any regrets...
Coming here and taking this job?
No.
It's only partly true, you know,
that hard work cures all sorrow.
Is that what you think
I'm doing?
Trying.
This, uh...
This work is a bridge for you,
isn't it?
To back among the living?
Mm-hmm.
Welcome back.
You're young. You've got
a whole world ahead of you.
It's up against
real competition...
the one behind me.
Yeah, I've been thinking
myself back into that one.
Well, uh,
"think" is probably the wrong word.
It's an impression...
A feeling,
an atmosphere around you.
Something inside.
Relax. Close your eyes.
That's what the couch is for.
All right.
You're in a small college town.
5-room yellow house.
Rented.
It's on a shady street
with a handful of others.
And outside, peaceful sounds:
A lawn mower clanking,
a piano playing.
In the first apartment
Karen and I had in Chicago,
the bathtub was in the kitchen.
Small, cozy, no big problems.
Except when
the Murphy bed was down,
you couldn't open
the front door.
I'd come home from the hospital
at 5:00 in the morning,
and there'd be
coffee on the stove.
I wonder where Dev is.
He's probably drunk someplace.
There's a real
deterioration in that man.
Now I'm going
to have to fight him
for the clinic,
and I don't want to.
Why not?
Because I remember him
when I was in training.
He and Collins were doing
really important work.
Is that why you've been
covering for him here?
What do you think
it would do to the patients
to see us at each
other's throats?
You know what I'd really like?
What?
To get back to that
feeling I had in the bar.
Talk, wine...
Beer wouldn't do?
Uh-uh. Wrong mood.
I'll put it in a red glass.
All right.
Could I use your phone?
Oh, yes.
Right over there.
Thank you.
Miss Kubiecki?
This is Dr. Mciver.
Have you heard from
Dr. Devanal yet?
Nothing, huh?
She does? Well,
switch me through to her, please.
Oh, hello, miss Gavney.
Who?
Oh, Mr. Capp.
Yes. Yes, he'll need sedation.
That's all right.
You can give it to him.
And if Dr. Wolff needs me,
I'm at 6258.
Mm-hmm.
Good night.
Hello. This is Mrs. Mciver.
Is my...
Is Dr. Mciver there?
Well, I...
It's rather urgent.
Oh, yes, thank you.
Give me the number if you will.
Thank you.
Rinehart: Hello?
Who is this?
Hello?
Information, 6258.
Under whose name is
that number listed?
Operator: I'm sorry.
We are unable to give this information.
We do not list
by telephone number.
It's hard for everybody,
but particularly for us...
Because all the sick
feelings out of the past
hook onto things in the present.
Now, this...
Being with you right now...
Is real, only...
My feelings about now...
How do I know where
they come from,
or have I got them
all mixed up with something else?
Good night, Stevie.
Thank you for taking me.
I couldn't have
done it by myself.
I couldn't have gone
with anyone else but you.
Good night.
Well, Mr. Capp,
you must be as drowsy as a kitten.
How about bed now...
And some sleep?
That's the wittiest remark
since the passing of Oscar Wilde.
Oh, Mr. Capp,
I gave you some sedation.
Yeah. Two capsules.
Are you sure the clinic
can spare it?
Mr. Capp, would it help if I
called in Dr. Wolff to talk to you?
Miss Gavney, please!
One doctor at a time.
Let's not interfere
with good old Devanal's work.
Ha! He's making me fit
to face the world.
The futility
and the emptiness...
The hydrogen bomb...
Say, I may even be fit
to cope with my mother!
There's a formidable
woman, miss Gavney...
quick of eye, steady of hand.
Never been known to miss
with a knife in the back.
* "m" is for the million
things she gave me *
* "o" means only that
she's growing old *
* "t" is for the tears
were shed to save me *
* "h" is for her heart
of purest gold *
Good morning, mark.
Morning.
Mother not down yet?
She's gone.
Gone? Where?
To the Springs.
She took Rosie with her.
You're supposed to take me
over to Billy Hormeyer's
for the weekend.
Sadie's not here yet.
Yeah, I'll... All right,
whenever you're ready.
I'll get breakfast
at the clinic.
So long.
Good-bye, dad.
Is Dr. Mciver here yet?
Should be any minute.
Well, please let me
know the minute he comes in.
I'll be at breakfast.
No. No, no, Mrs. Devanal.
We haven't heard
from the doctor yet.
Yes. Yes, I'll be sure
to call you.
Mr. Capp, why don't you
go in to breakfast?
I'll call you as soon
as the doctor arrives.
I'd rather stay here.
Cobby, did you know that
Thomas Edison never slept
more than 42 minutes
a night in his whole life?
No wonder he tinkered around.
Rinehart: Dr. Mciver!
It's Stevie!
I've taken all I'm gonna take
of these loonies!
Look at that.
I tried to stop him.
He was smashing the window.
He was trying to break down the door
when curly stopped him.
Curly got cut
with the broken glass.
Curly, what started this?
How should I know?
Man: Dr. Mciver!
Dr. Mciver, I demand to know
why those new drapes are put up in
the library, considering your promise!
What drapes?
Flowered brocade.
A very striking effect,
as a matter of fact.
Curly, did you see
which way he went?
Last I saw him, he was hightailing
it river way. Good riddance!
Stevie!
Doctor, something has to be done
about the noise in the annex.
It's impossible to rest. If something isn't
done, I'm going to call the police myself!
Miss Robbins,
you will do no such thing.
If you'll please go
back to your room.
I assure you,
everything possible is being done.
The state highway patrol
has been trying to get you.
I told them you'd call
just as soon as you got in.
All right, get them for me,
and put the call
through in my office.
Dr. Mciver, I came to this place
to be helped,
not to be driven out of my mind!
Miss Robbins,
perhaps you can tell me.
The noise upstairs,
and the laughing and the dancing...
How bad is it, Tim?
Pretty bad. We have
a very disturbed house.
There's been a lot of talk all day
about those new drapes,
and now this rumor about
Steven Holte's suicide.
They each read themselves into
it, and I never know what's...
Dr. Mciver, I found Mrs.
Demuth drunk in Mr. Appleton's room.
You see? I tried to persuade
her to go back to her own.
Dr. Mciver,
state highway patrol calling.
Does Demuth know I'm here?
I'll go up.
Doctor...
I'll see to it.
Mciver.
That's right.
I called the sheriff's
office around 2:00.
Definitely not.
He's not dangerous
to anybody but himself.
Don't send an officer out here.
I'll come down there.
Dr. Mciver, what'll I do about...
later, Mrs. O'brien.
Mrs. O'brien...
Mrs. O'brien!
Yes, doctor?
I want you to take these
down right away.
But, doctor... take them down
before more patients see them.
But what will I do with them?
I don't care what you do with them...
anything!
Put them in my car.
I'll take them to the dump!
But don't you think we ought to wait
until Dr. Devanal...
Stewart!
Where have you been?
Been? I've been
to the airport to meet Regina.
We had a few things
to talk about.
Just got in.
Now, look here...
Then you haven't heard
about Steven Holte.
No. Why?
Is he...Was he very disturbed?
I'd say so, Dev,
assuming he's still alive.
One of the patients?
My patient.
Stewart, aren't you being
a little melodramatic, perhaps?
You know this boy's history!
If you don't, why don't you come
to staff meeting
once in a while and find out?!
What are you in
this business for...
to cure patients
or to kill them?!
I didn't put up those drapes.
You know that.
Dev, if this boy kills himself,
I'll drive you so far
out of the profession,
you'll never find your way back!
Now, look here, Stewart!
If I were you, I would not make
accusations you may regret.
I'll regret nothing!
Now, just a minute!
This boy has
a history of suicide.
Do you mean to tell me
that knowing that,
you gave him
the run of the clinic,
let him become some kind
of celebrity around here?
Why wasn't he sent
to a closed hospital?
Because I'm a doctor,
not a jailer!
Mac, before the rest of
the board arrives,
I insist on a clarification
of what's going on down here.
I hear these rumors...
What rumors, Regina?
About laxity in the treatment
of patients... incompetence.
I want to know if there's any
basis to them.
Does Dev suggest there is?
Certainly not.
He completely denies them.
Same thing.
Mac, I take a serious
view of this.
Yes, so do I.
Don't try to run this place
single-handed.
We have a responsibility
to the trustees.
But not to the patients, huh?
The patients are yours.
Regina, the trustees can't run the
clinic without knowing the clinic,
and you can't know the
clinic sitting in Chicago!
Well, from what I've seen here
in the past few minutes...
well, take a few more minutes.
I can't talk now.
- Mac!
- Not now!
I just don't understand.
What are they doing?
They are mourning, Mrs. O'brien.
I think that's what
your people would call...
A wake.
Mr. Capp.
Mr. Capp!
Capp: Man shall not minister
to my disease,
plucked from the memory
of rooted sorrow.
Raise up the hidden
troubles of the brain,
and, with some sweet,
oblivious antidote,
cleanse the...
Mr. Capp, won't you
come to bed now?
Mrs. O'brien,
did I ever tell you
you reminded me of my mother?
And, with some sweet,
oblivious antidote,
cleanse the...
Bosom from that...
Hello, Otto.
I'm glad you're here.
I want to talk to you.
Mrs. Devanal is in your office.
Mrs. Devanal?
What does she want?
I don't know.
She's been waiting for some time.
Hello, Edna.
What can I do for you?
I'm sorry about
the boy, Stewart.
I've been trying to make up
my mind all night.
I know how you feel about Dev.
I can't justify
anything he's done.
Stewart... Don't you care at all
what happens to him?
I'm sorry, Edna.
It's not personal,
but I can't let Dev
go on like this.
But can't you do it some way...
some other way?
That's all I ask.
Just...Not this way.
Can it really matter
how many times
he's been at the realton hotel
with miss Cobb?
If it doesn't matter to me...
I've been through all that so long
and gotten used to it...
what can it matter
to anyone else?
If it's true
he really mishandled
the two cases
mentioned in there,
I suppose that is
serious, but mistakes...
have you any idea what it is
to live in the same
house with a man
who hasn't brought his
problems to you for 10 years?
But, Stewart,
if he loses his pride now...
He'll be through.
That's all he has left.
Edna...
Where did you get this?
It...Came to the house last night
by messenger.
I know I shouldn't
have opened it,
but Dev wasn't there, and...
I was so worried.
Has Dev seen it?
No.
Sally, get miss inch in here.
Mrs. Mitchell-Smythe called.
The board meeting is for...
I want miss inch!
Dr. Mciver's office.
Who's calling, please?
Yes, just one moment, lieutenant.
He's right here.
Yes?
What?
Where?
Lieutenant!
Can you identify this, doctor?
That shoe could've
been in the river for 3 years.
It doesn't mean he's drowned!
No one says it does,
but it's the nearest we've come.
Where'd you find it?
Out over there in that mudbank.
We figure that's where
he entered the river.
We're going to start dragging all
through here and work downstream.
Cal, let's get over to those
other two boats by the bridge.
Keep that searchlight
on us over here!
Lieutenant Ferguson...
tangled in the lines of your hook!
We've gone too far!
Dr. Mciver!
Boat 5 hooked something!
Man: Something's on the hook!
Second man:
I think we've snagged a body!
Do you want me
to take you to him?
No, he wouldn't
want me. Not now.
I'll be at home.
Will you call me,
let me know if there's anything?
Karen, forgive me.
I shall presume.
Tomorrow... Or whenever this ends,
if he will let you, go to him, help him.
He has much to work through.
Don't nurse your wounds.
Nurse his.
Thank you.
Pull it in slow!
What is it?
It's only a Fender.
You've just hooked a Fender!
Meg, I'm not going
to stand around
waiting for them
to bring up the body.
I can't take any more.
Any more of waiting?
Any more of myself.
Everything I've put my hand to
flies apart like a straw man...
wife, kids, Dev... Now Stevie.
What kind of a fool was I to think
I could take care of all that?
I can't even
take care of myself.
I'm no more fit to be
in this job than Dev is.
Well, let somebody else try
to put it together again.
It won't be me.
Why don't they just
leave it where it is?
You know the way a stiff acts?
It goes down to the bottom.
It don't drift away.
Just lays there until it bloats
enough to come to the top.
Oh, Meg...
Oh, Meg, Meg, Meg, Meg...
It seems a long time.
A long time.
I've been living in a dream
these last few days.
It has to stop.
I have to wake up.
I've been playing family again
with you and Stevie.
It was a wonderful dream.
I was dead for a long time,
and now I'm alive...
For which I thank you.
Meg, listen to me.
Nothing has to stop.
I think it does.
We can't stay out
any longer just to find a body.
Bring in the boats!
That's it!
I think I'm something...
something you had once
or wanted once, and...
It's easier for you
to start again with me
than go back and get Karen.
No, no, no, Meg...
I wonder if she doesn't need
some of the strength
you've tried to give
Stevie and me.
Maybe it's too late for that.
Well, leave her, then,
but don't make her suffer...
While you and I clutch at
our dreams in odd moments...
please don't!
Don't.
I could do that, too.
I almost want you that much.
Just not quite.
Not quite.
Well...
What should I do, Meg?
Who do you...
Think I am?
I'm late for the meeting.
I know. I want to talk to you
a minute before you go in.
When did you send
this out, Vicky?
I worked on it
Saturday and Sunday
and called a messenger
and sent it to your house.
I didn't get it.
I haven't been home.
This is Dev's copy.
But I...
Don't understand.
I thought...
All right, I believe in calling
a spade a spade.
You may be interested in
knowing that Dr. Devanal.
suggested that I prepare just
such a report as that against you.
Vicky, I hope,
for your own peace,
you won't present
that thing at the meeting.
And if I led you
to believe I wanted
that kind of help
from you, forgive me.
I understand that the drapes
hung in the library by your wife
were removed by you yesterday.
You will appreciate, Dr. Mciver,
that regardless of their
origin or suitability,
they are the property
of the clinic.
I must ask that they
be returned at once.
Vicky.
Under the circumstances,
I suggest we dispense
with the customary agenda
and get to the essentials.
I understand
miss inch has a report
which she believes may
clarify certain aspects
of our present situation.
Miss inch, may we
have your report?
I have no report...
Except the usual financial ones.
Much the same as last year.
Read them yourselves
to save time.
Regina, if I may,
I think I can save you
some time, too.
You all know what's happened.
None of it can be undone.
But what we can do
is learn from it.
Out of our needs
and our passions here,
we've...We've spun
a human cobweb,
and this boy's
been caught in it.
I know that a lot
of what's happened
is my responsibility.
I think I forgot
that if an analyst
is to be of any real help
to the people he cares for,
it must come out of
the way he lives.
Not just from how much he knows
or how hard he works.
We live very close
together here,
patients and staff.
And we bring everything we are...
strong and weak, good and bad...
to the smallest act.
If we realize this
and accept and use it,
that's the only way I know
of reconciling ourselves
to the present trouble
and trying to prevent
its happening in the future.
Now as to the conduct
of the clinic,
my basic views haven't changed.
More than ever,
I believe the self-
government program
is inevitable and right.
And the risks we take under it
with a patient like Steven Holte
are calculated and worthwhile.
If I stay here...
I propose to continue and extend
the present program.
Whether I do or not
is for you to decide.
"Having been associated
with this clinic
"and many of its employees
for over 1/4 of a century,
"it is with a deep
feeling of regret
"and a sense of
great personal loss
"that for reasons of ill health,
"I submit to this board
my resignation
"as medical director of
the castle house clinic
"for nervous disorders.
"Sincerely...
Douglas N. Devanal, M.D."
We've covered a lot of ground,
for two people
who have forgotten
how to talk to each other.
What do we do now?
Try to...
Help each other
as much as we can.
Be as honest as we can.
Stevie!
I...Came back.
You all right?
Came back...
For an explanation.
Explanation?
Where the devil have you been?
Waiting here for hours.
Where have you been?
Do you realize everybody's
been looking for you,
been dragging the
river all night?
Too bad.
What do you mean?
They won't find me.
Mciver: They'll find you,
all right.
I'll throw you back in myself.
It's all right, it's all right.
Come on, Stevie,
you can make it.
I made it...
Didn't I?
That's right, Stevie.
You made it.
Oh, say...
could...could you
get hold of sue?
- Tell her I'm all right?
- Yeah, sure.
Explain to her?
She's got a lot of
anxieties, you know.
Yeah, I know, I know.
Tell her I still got her bell.
What's Dr. Carmody's
phone number?
It's in the book.
Just...Thought I'd
lie down a minute.
You ever almost
drowned yourself?
No.
It's just silly.
I'll never do it again.
Oh, hi.
Is he going to be all right?
Yeah, mark.
I think he's going to be fine.
You know, mark, uh...
Sometimes it's
easier for a doctor
to take care of his patients
than...Than someone of his own.
I know, dad.
That's your job.
Can I help you?
You have.
I seem to...Keep running
into these things.