We all have two lives.
The second life begins when we
realize that we only have one.
Confucius 479BC.
Here we stand smoking.
As so often.
They leave us in peace.
We have stood outside and
smoked for 5 years now.
- Good luck.
- See you soon.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- You are beautiful.
- Thanks.
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
Leave it be.
OMG. Now let it just be.
Ok.
Breathe.
It is wonderful to work with you again.
I've missed it.
I can hardly believe that the tour has ended.
You can go with your family
to the summer cottage.
It's nice to be with family once in a while.
Yes of course.
- Let me take you to the hotel.
- No, it's not necessary.
- I'll drive you.
- No, I'll walk, I need fresh air.
I'm really happy for you.
- Take care of yourself.
- You too.
Goodbye. Bjorn?
Yes.
It should be okay.
No. Do not worry.
I promise ...
I'll take care of it ...
Karin!
Call an ambulance!
The VIOLINIST
- Can you feel anything?
- No.
- And now?
- And here?
- No.
Your fingers are still numb.
Sorry, I could not find the thicker needles.
Just a moment.
These are the green. You have to find the red.
Check out the top shelf. Thank you.
The accident destroyed a joint in your hand ...
... as well as the nerves in these three fingers.
- Can you operate again?
- We have done everything we could.
Karin. Where are my glasses?
Eemeli. Your phone.
- I am leaving now.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye!
Where is my phone?
Karin. Where are my glasses?
Well, yes, I left them there yesterday.
Karin.
How long will you go on like this?
Maybe you should accept what the experts say.
- You just want me to stay at home.
- No, sweetheart ...
Honey, let me help you.
If you will not accept my help ...
Karin, what do you want me to do?
This has been going on for eight months.
You do not have to do anything.
Doctors have said that you
have damaged three fingers.
-You don't even know them!
- That does not matter.
A top surgeon said that the nerves are dead!
- Accept it.
- I'm not going to start teaching!
I'm not a teacher, I am an artist!
Thank you for coming on such short notice.
Students who graduate this year are fantastic.
I heard that you have been selected as
one of the world's finest art academies.
- Congratulations.
- That's right. Thanks.
How's your hand?
Well, it is completely ...
The entertainment is simple but ingenious.
The structures are simple
and symmetrical shapes.
- And Mozart ...
- Hello!
Sorry. It's my fault.
Sofia, hello. Sorry I'm late.
Welcome. We've been waiting for you.
Mozart composed this in
Italy when he was fifteen.
It is the source of melody and drama.
I have read Mozart's letters.
He lived a hard life in poverty and misery.
But it was his own choice.
He had the opportunity to work for the Church.
It's a way to look at it.
It's about perseverance.
He did not want outsiders to affect his work.
- Why haven't you wokene me?
- I'm not your mother.
Before we start, let's make one thing clear:
You must not be late.
If you know you'll be late, you should not come.
Keep this in mind for next time.
Feel free to play.
Great, it was beautiful.
A little soft at the end of phrases.
It's not allegro amabile
but allegro con brio.
Play again from the 22nd bar.
The first violinist begins and the other follow.
You have energy, but try playing
together. Communicate more.
Add more flirting. It's an opera. A love story.
Let's go again.
Karin!
I do not know why I have
to run after those scores,
but the situation is as it is.
If you don't have the scores,
you'll have to order them.
It is impossible for tomorrow. They are lent out.
I don't care how you do it.
But I need Henles Urtext edition tomorrow.
Mendelssohn's Violin Concerto in E minor.
- Excuse me. - Hello, Karin.
Mendelssohn's Violin Concerto?
I have it. If you need it tomorrow, I can ...
It would be very kind of you.
I'm busy today, but Antti can drop it.
Right?
Yes, of course.
- Excellent. See you later.
- Thanks.
I mean goodbye.
Why did I say "thank you"?
I'm going to Pilates today.
Stop it.
I know I have not conducted in a few years.
But I have good credentials.
and ...
I just need to meet them ...
What?
What do you mean I can't
get an invitation there?
Have you been in contact with them?
Linda, good contacts are everything.
Linda, you're my agent, you should know that.
You can sit down.
Only one of my students. Damn it.
We'll talk later, okay?
You too. Goodbye.
- Thanks for the scores.
- You are welcome.
It's funny. We've played it with
Puumala the whole of last year.
Is that a ...?
Yes.
I've never touched a Stradivarius.
Can I try it?
My contract forbids me to let anyone touch it.
There are not many like that in Finland.
It is insured for four million euros.
Here.
Here you are.
Now?
Haven't you said that you've
played the whole of last year?
It's been a while ago.
Whoops!
Don't worry.
It takes time to get used to a Stradivarius.
You should not push it, otherwise it stops.
But once you've found the delicate technique ...
It shows its depth.
It;s somehow so romantic.
Don't you think it's ...
... almost too romantic?
Hey!
This is Antti, my student.
Hi.
You could have asked me to
go to the parents' meeting.
Why stay home if you do
not want to attend anything?
I should probably go.
You can stay and dine. I will cook lobster soup.
I have already eaten.
What is it? Does it taste so bad?
- Is it so awful?
- I have something in my throat.
Have you seasoned it in a different way?
I've tried making it without cookbook.
It's terrible.
Yes, it tastes quite strange.
- I think it's good.
- That's nice.
- Damn! Sorry ...
- Never mind. It will dry up.
Everything is alright.
Everything is fine.
What is it, Karin?
What is it?
Can't you at least look at me?
What?
Everything is breaking down.
It will be alright.
Hi.
- Can you be a little quieter?
- Excuse me.
Alright.
I've found this brilliant recording of "Requiem"
From Sarajevo, 1994.
Do you want to hear it?
What do you think?
I think about the movie when I listen to this.
- That ruined the song for me.
- I think it's a good movie.
I saw it for the first time when I
was eight, it was cold at the time.
Since then it has been a tradition
to watch it whenever I have a cold.
- Are you sick now? - No, I'm not cold.
I don't watch the movie,
I just listen to the music now.
I love that scene
where he dictates this piece
on his deathbed, note for note.
He was a big star then, that actor.
I wonder what happened to him.
How's Mendelssohn?
Really good.
Please, can't you get dressed?
I can not concentrate.
I need to work on this.
- You've played it for seven hours.
- I can play for seven hours.
Certainly.
You should not start vacuuming while I practice!
- Sofia! - What?
- Turn it off! - No, I will not.
Good. Play it again. at a slower pace.
Try to get more articulation in terses.
Now, let's raise the bar a little bit.
You can play this even with eyes closed
- so you do not have to worry
about how your fingers move.
Try to see the bigger picture now.
Close your eyes.
And imagine the piece ...
... as if it was a huge,
incredibly beautiful building.
See the big picture
and play without thinking about anything else.
The same part.
Good. The phrases were longer
but when I took notes,
you were a little tense again.
Just relax, no matter how nervous you are.
Give me your elbow.
Press it against my hand.
Play now, and press firmly against the bow.
Relax.
Just relax.
It sounds terrible, but just be relaxed.
It does not help. Okay, good.
Just like that!
Do not be afraid that it sounds bad.
It's not that I'm afraid of.
What are you afraid of, then?
Mediocrity.
Then you're like Mendelssohn.
A friend of mine said that
Mendelssohn was unsuccessful -
- because he was too talented.
Perhaps he also suffered from fear of mediocrity.
Did you hurt your hand?
The scar was already there.
Would you sign here?
It's just a formality.
Now that your scholarship
period has been interrupted.
Thanks.
Well then.
Good...
Then I'm leaving. Thank you.
This is a little embarrassing, but ...
Can I see it one last time?
Yes, of course.
In my work I have seen -
- that people can become
more attached to objects -
- than other people.
It's the music.
Happy Birthday
Happy birthday, dear Karin
A master chef told me once
that his taste is so developed -
- that he can taste different
flavors in his thoughts -
- and then combine the sensations in his head.
- Without eating.
What are you gonna do now, Karin?
I'll be conducting again.
My agent says that everything seems fine.
What do you do when nothing is enough?
- I heard that!
I meant when everything goes well.
I've realized something.
Karin, we are very much alike, you and me.
We are not content with
anything less than success.
- Are you going home now?
- Yes. What the hell am I doing here?
- Here are just old ladies.
- I've been looking for you.
- Nonsense. - Yes, I did.
You have flirted with that Swede.
You're completely crazy. - You deny?
It's so cool that you're our teacher.
I think you are absolutely fantastic.
Some people think that high culture is dead -
- and that food and drink
has replaced art in our lives.
Food has already become a religion.
- It's crazy. - Come and dance with me.
I'm coming, darling. Just a moment.
Is everything OK?
I just need that meeting.
I know that I'm not a famous conductor.
Linda, should I change agent?
I have to go now. Goodbye.
Hello. Do you have something to say?
I just want to explain
what happened at the party.
I apologize.
I am still your teacher.
And I am your student.
- I'm 45. - And I'm 27.
Hi.
Thanks. The taxi is waiting outside.
Excuse me, is Jaakko there?
Excuse me, who are you?
Karin Nordstrom.
- Jaakko's wife.
Excuse me, I did not recognize you.
Of course.
Hi.
- Hello. - Hello!
- Were you surprised? - What are you doing here?
I brought this for you.
- For me? - Yes.
-Why? - No reason.
Isn't it a nice color?
I'll try it. - Okay.
There must be more to
life than playing the violin.
- Okay. - I mean...
Being a successful musician
does not mean everything to me.
I have other dreams too. Just like you.
You have managed to combine family and career.
I do not want everything to
revolve only around music -
- and not have anything else in my life.
You know...
My father used to say that
I have a violinist's fingers.
That with a lot of practice,
I could be the next Karin Nordstrom.
Well.
It's funny.
I am your admirer.
I admire you, and now you're here.
It's strange.
Both Antti and I admire you.
We talk about you all the time. Or Antti does.
"Karin did this, Karin did that."
"Karin is so beautiful."
"Karin is so brave, successful and gifted."
Which is true, but it's weird.
He does it all the time.
Do you ever speak about us with Jaakko?
I mean at home. -No.
I speak of course of my students at home.
There is something I want to tell you, Sophia.
My job as your teacher is to
say that music is everything -
-but that does not mean
you are not entitled to both.
Career and family.
You can do whatever you want.
Whatever you want.
Is this where you practice?
Sorry.
Excuse me.
- Are you not the famous violinist? - No.
North ... something.
Nordstrom. Karin Nordstrom!
Are you not Karin Nordstrom?
What are you doing?
I told you I'll do the dishes.
Why can't we keep a simple deal here?
- Why are you always so angry? - I'm not angry!
It just hurts to see when you suffer like that.
- It is you who suffer. - I don't.
What's wrong with you?
I thought you would be
happy that you are alive ...
... that you will be with your family.
I am happy that I'm with you, darling.
I told you not to go on tour.
Why did you go on with it?
Why did you have to do it?
- Was it for Darren? - Forget it!
I think about it every day.
Do you think he will come here
just to hold a master class?
Why would he come to a place like this rat hole?
We both know why he's coming!
I am a man, and I know it very well.
Is there something going on?
-Be honest! No, there is nothing going on.
But it was something. More than ten years ago.
I can't forget it! Do you still feel something?
You have to work with it
and stop thinking about it.
I do. Answer me honestly.
-Is there something going
on between you two? -No.
Why is he here? -To teach my students.
Because you...
Listen, everyone! Please welcome Bear Darren.
Thank you.
It looks like a cocktail party.
Stand in a circle around me so I can see you.
And please, leave your bags, coats and all that.
So you can relax.
I usually do this. Then my hands are relaxed.
To feel that your hands relax.
It feels good.
I go around to get this fine ...
... connection between all of us.
Bear.
What?
My name is Bjorn.
- Antti. - Hey, Antti.
Nice to meet you.
- Jarno? - Yes.
And you are ...?
-And you? -Francesco.
You are from Italy? That's nice.
Wonderful.
Sofia. Wow!
-You have beautiful eyes.
-Thanks.
- You too.
- Really beautiful. Thanks.
This is going to be a fantastic week.
I really feel that you are talented musicians.
I've noticed immediately that you are talented.
Just as your charming teacher promised me.
You look good.
Teaching suits you.
- How's your arm? - Good...
According to the doctors I can never play again.
My arm is completely screwed.
Let me see.
Oh God.
I didn't know it was that bad.
I'm really sorry. You should have told me.
- What? - I thought you could help me.
I want to start directing again.
You realize that at your age you
can not become a top conductor.
You weren't exactly young when you started.
You've always been stubborn.
I mean seriously ... Yeah.
You know that I still love you?
I know.
I'll check my calendar, but I think it's gone be ok.
- I'll let you know. - Okay thanks.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
Oh my God!
What is it?
I have to go to Copenhagen.
- Now? - Yes, today.
You can not leave in the middle of the lecture.
- Vera Chen has a damn virus. - I need you here!
- I need you here. - I'm sorry, but I must.
I'm sorry, but I have to find a new soloist.
I need you here. Can't you call someone?
Rehearsals start on Monday.
- What are you going to play? - Mendelssohn.
The violin concerto?
- What? - Listen to my students.
I have practiced the piece with them.
- Did you choose our concert? - Yes I did.
- Hello! - Hello.
- We'll talk about it later. - I'll call you.
- It was a long time ago. - Yes.
Hi. Should we go? - Yes.
What are you waiting for? Begin, please.
Sofia? You can't be serious.
-Hello to you too. Did you hear what I said?
She plays like an angel.
She is totally unreliable and lazy.
She is always late and missing notes.
She is not ready for such a big challenge.
It's not your decision.
No. But I want you to get a musician -
- that's as good as Vera or me.
- And that would be? - Antti.
Thanks, that's enough.
You haven't seen what he can do.
He has star potential.
- You may go. - Thanks.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
I'm going with you.
I'll practice with him all week.
- Will you come with me to Copenhagen? - Yes.
- It's a big risk for me.
- I'll take the responsibility. I promise.
- You're not in love with him, right? - No.
I know you prefer Jallu,
but this excellent vodka will have to do.
Health.
I thought you could help me.
I want to return to the big world.
Why do not you talk to them in Seattle
and arrange a meeting for me there?
I want to be a conductor.
-It's very lonely being a god.
I have nothing else in life except the music.
I'm not sure if people love me,
or just want to take advantage of me.
I don't think you want to be in this position.
The conductor stick is much
heavier than you imagine.
Sometimes you have to lift it with both hands
and it still feels as if it's falling down.
You know nothing about this.
I can not be friends with my musicians.
Otherwise, I could not hear my music.
You should continue to teach, Karin. It suits you.
I just want to warn you because ...
... if you want to be king,
you're going to lose everything in the end.
You have your family. Do you want to lose it?
- You do not want to lose it, right? - Of course not.
Can I get a bottle of your
best champagne? Thanks.
I love this room!
It's just like being inside a violin.
Yesterday you've let me inside your soul.
Remember that.
I want you to know that you all did brilliantly.
You are all brilliant musicians. Keep that in mind.
The charming teacher has
promised to be with us-
-and be an instructor for the new soloist.
Ultimately, it was an obvious choice.
Welcome to the festival, Antti.
The flight is at seven o'clock on Monday.
What is it?
I just ... I can not concentrate.
I have too many thoughts in my head.
Then clear you mind.
This is an important performance.
I'm just so ...
I'm just so confused about all this.
I want you to do well.
- Why is it so important to you?
- Concentrate and play well!
So you want me to play well?
When I graduated Darren
asked me to join the tour.
I've left everything.
My family, my boyfriend, my home.
I had nothing but the music.
I'm not saying you have to make hasty decisions
but if you're so confused,
it's a sign of something.
I can not say what's best for your career.
I can not teach you anything
you do not want to find yourself.
But this much I can tell you that
you are forced to make choices.
I'm very proud of you.
I could take some time off
and come and listen to you.
I do not think that's a good idea.
I have to concentrate on playing.
-Of course I'll let you do it.
I have to make choices.
What are you talking about?
- What's wrong with you?
- I have to make choices.
Oh no ...
You're breaking up with me.
Is that what you want?
Is that what you're trying to say?
- Can you answer me?
- I have to focus on the music.
- Focus on the music?
- Yes, the music!
I have to take a decision. I'm so confused.
I'm being pulled in all directions.
I can not concentrate.
- I have to make choices.
- So then you must get rid of me?
- Is that so?
- I did not say that. Did I say that?
Do you love me?
It's not about that. Sofia!
You have to understand that
it requires great sacrifice.
Go then, damn it!
- Success requires sacrifice.
- Sacrifice? Seriously?
Fuck you.
It need not be the end.
Good luck with the concert
and the rest of your life.
You will probably be damn successful.
- Sofia.
- What?
- What is it?
- One more thing.
Say it.
Nothing. I love you.
Fuck off!
This is unreal.
Incomprehensible.
"Welcome to Copenhagen."
This is amazing.
Just remember everything I've taught you.
Of course.
After this we are going to Paris.
Okay. We can go anywhere in Europe.
I'll be your soloist and conductor.
Why stop there?
The world of music is bigger than Europe.
- I've always wanted to go to Sydney.
- I've been there.
- New Zealand.
- Been there.
- Mexico.
Svalbard.
- You need a firearms license there.
- I'll get one.
I'll shoot anyone who comes between us.
Great.
We're going to be a fantastic team.
I'll help you shoot.
Oh.
Sorry I rode so fast.
What are you working on currently?
A bit of everything.
My calendar is almost as fully
booked as in the wild years.
- That sounds good. - Yes.
How are you? You look great. - Thanks.
Have you met each other? This is Antti.
- This is Saulius.
- Antti.
- Nice to meet you.
- Antti!
- Welcome to the world at large.
- Thanks. It is a great honor.
Hey!
This way.
Hello! Thanks for the great experience.
It was great to play Beethoven with you.
- It was wonderful. Come.
- Thank you.
We are ready.
Well.
- Is everything okay? - Yes.
We start when you are ready.
So.
We try again.
I'm ready.
More feeling!
More love!
Shit!
Thanks! It's enough!
I do not know...
This is going to be a long week.
He was just a little nervous today.
No! That was the goal.
The kid is going to be fine. Trust me.
- It will be fine, trust me. - Well. I really hope so.
Actually it's a long story.
We played Mendelssohn's violin
concerto here in the concert hall.
Really? Wow!
- I should lie down and sleep now. - Let's dance!
What is it?
Do you think you're here on vacation?
I'm just taking a little break.
I thought we could go over there and practice.
In the bedroom.
What are you saying?
It would be nice if we could just fuck all the time.
- What is it? - Nothing. I'm just old.
You are not. You look wonderful.
You smell nice.
- Your hair is lovely. - Antti ...
Your cheek is gorgeous.
I really have to work now.
Okay. I apologize.
Stop! It was too fast, Antti.
Antti, you must introduce the orchestra.
It's your job, not the conductor's.
Let's return to the same part again.
No, I'm in the middle of an exercise.
Tomorrow? I'm going to be busy.
Much better!
Antti.
Do you know the Italian
name of this movement?
- No. - Never mind. It has three words.
Allegro Molto Appassionato.
Is there a comma between the words?
No.
It's not Allegro Molto, Appassionato.
Nor Allegro Molto, Passionato.
It is Allegro Molto Appassionato.
Play it again!
This was a mistake.
- You should have chosen Sofia.
- Darren is always like that.
It's going to be alright.
You have to move your things back to your room.
Jaakko and Eemeli will be here tomorrow.
- At the concert? - Yes, and Tivoli Gardens.
I can not see them for a while.
I got an invitation to Seattle.
I'll go there. - What?
I'm going to meet some people there.
- What about us? - What do you mean by "us"?
The two of us.
I never said that I would leave my family.
Come here.
Out with you.
It's the wrong way.
Off you go.
- What's this? - This is my student's room.
Do you live both in the same apartment?
Yes, this is a guest apartment.
Where is he now?
- I do not know. We have different rhythms.
Where would you like to eat?
I do not care. Where do the two of you eat?
- Maybe an Italian restaurant? - I want pizza.
Hi there.
Hello...
-You came. Yeah, just for a few days.
We thought about going to Tivoli
and come and listen to your concert.
Oh, it was ... the nice.
We are going out to eat.
Can you recommend something?
I am not aware of any. - Suggest something now.
There are many good places.
You have to stay strong.
You have to eat something.
- I've just eaten, thank you. - He has eaten.
Hi.
-Hello. He may well follow anyway.
Let's go.
Cheers for this amazing opportunity, Antti.
Cheers.
Cheers there too.
This was a dream come true for you?
Yes, I've been feeling really well.
Thanks for your interest.
When I grow up I want to be
as good a violinist as a mother.
Is not a little warm in here?
I don't believe so.
You and dad have identical shirts.
It seems so.
- Did you buy those from the same place?
- Mom bought it for me.
Where did you buy yours?
I can not remember.
This seems to be a best-selling men's shirt.
More love!
... Lake Garda, for example.
- Where is it? - In Italy.
- They have good ice cream there.
- Wasn't Veracini Italian?
One should eat pizza at the smaller places.
They have the best pizza.
I have a relationship with Karin.
What?
Karin and I have a relationship.
I understand English.
It has been going on for over two months.
I just thought you should know.
Is the ice cream was for you, sir?
Here you go.
A double espresso for her.
And we'll have two regular.
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
It's not what you think.
- Is not that? - Shut up!
- Eemeli, we go now. - Jaakko.
I want to stay here with Mom. She lied to me.
I want to eat my ice cream! - Leave it.
Let me explain. - It's not necessary.
I hope you understand what is at stake here.
Eemeli, let's go. Forget the ice cream!
Did you think you could achieve
success by fucking your teacher?
James!
James...
- Let me explain. - What's to explain?
You have a relationship. Fine. Congratulations.
That's not true. He's just my student.
This is completely unnecessary.
- Is he good in bed? - It doesn't matter.
- It's not about that. - What is it about then?
He is a gifted violinist. I wanted to help him.
- Help him ?! - This is about me.
- About you? - About all this.
- What? - The music!
Why are you lying to me? What do you want?
I want you. I want you.
You've had us. We've been here all the time.
But there is no place for others in your life.
There is only room for
your grief and your feelings.
I've wasted my best years for you.
So you would have a good time
and would be able to do your music.
I may not understand art,
but I understand people.
I took care of our family,
worked and paid the bills.
- Everything, dammit! - I also did my part.
Well, then fine.
Over the past year I have
tried to make you feel good.
So you could make music.
And when you had the
accident and lost your hand ...
It is not only you who have lost your hand.
It was also a loss for me. I lost my wife.
You have not lost me.
Let's go, Eemeli.
I'll go with you.
No, our marriage is over, Karin.
- Jaakko. - Let him go.
James!
Karin!
Karin, listen to me.
Wait.
I just wanted to be honest.
I apologize.
It was not the best way,
but now we do not pretend anymore.
Can you put your phone away?
Listen to me!
I just wanted to be honest.
Are you listening? Forgive me.
Okay. Let's be honest.
You would not have been selected without me.
Darren preferred Sofia.
He thinks Sofia is more talented than you.
And if I'm completely honest, I agree with him.
Why are you doing this?
Why do you play these games?
You're fucking crazy.
-You are all crazy.
I do not care what you think about us.
You just ruined my marriage.
What kind of marriage is that?
Did you hear? What kind of marriage is that?
Fucking idiot!
Where is he?
I do not know.
Excuse me. It was my mistake.
We will begin shortly.
I'm ready. We can begin.
Are you going to play with your jacket on?
Yes I am.
Listening to the orchestra, Antti.
From the beginning.
Too low.
Again.
Now it was too high.
Lets start from the beginning.
We'll try with just the solo violin.
Too low.
Still too low.
Still too low!
Too low.
Again too low.
Too high.
Still too high.
Again.
And again.
Again. Again.
Again.
Again!
And again!
Now let's try with the whole orchestra.
From the beginning.
Now Antti played well.
But the orchestra lagged.
You must listen to him too.
Imagine me as a great bird with big wings.
And when I do this ...
... imagine that you are under
my large wings protection.
And from now on play in sync -
- in my magic wings universe.
Let's start from the beginning.
You must not get out in the
middle of a trial, no matter what!
You look miserable.
Where have you been all night?
- Answer me. - Do not touch me!
I think I will do fine without you.
Calm down. Did you hear what I said?
I want to be at peace now. I have to concentrate.
You've reached Jaakko Helenius.
Leave a message after the beep.
Hi, it's me. You're probably at work now.
Jaakko, I think we should talk.
Call me please.
Tell me ... How long did you keep it hidden?
It's like an underground river.
It has always been there waiting.
There's something you should know.
This here ...
Do not say anything. I do not want to know!
What's between you and the
woman is none of my business!
But I can see that it gives you a lot of pain.
I just want to ...
When I was your age, I admired
one of my teachers tremendously.
An old Russian man. Strict as hell.
I was always trying to please him.
One day he taught me a beautiful lesson.
I was sitting in class and looked up at him.
He was a tall man.
He asked what I was watching.
I replied: "You, maestro."
He asked why.
I said that because I wanted to learn something.
He replied: "Do not look at me."
If you want to learn something, look at yourself!
You are nobody else's creation.
You are your own creation.
I really appreciate that you tell me this.
Forget what I said!
Fuck this and your appreciation!
Put everything in your music
so it can be heard tomorrow.
Fuck everything else!
I need that pain!
So give it all to me tomorrow!
It just think that all of this ...
... is going too fast and I can not ...
I do not know. It feels ...
However it feels ... it's good.
Give me everything you have.
Tomorrow you play it all for me.
Put it all in your music.
Yes.
- Health, as you say in Denmark. - Health.
I came to pick up my stuff.
I'll stay at the hotel the rest of the time.
You know what's strange?
When I came here it occurred to me ...
Once I've sent you a letter.
I was 12 years old.
It was a letter of admiration.
I do not know if you remember it.
I had read an interview where they asked you ...
... what you would do if you
could not play the violin.
Do you remember?
No.
You said you would play anyway.
In my letter I've asked
What kind of violin can only
play inside one's head.
You've never answered.
I can help you.
I can try to get you an audition in Seattle.
I'll go there tomorrow.
After your rehearsal.
All my life I have been afraid to be bad.
To be mediocre.
I've done everything I could to
be better than everyone else.
To be the best.
But what does that mean?
I do not care how I play tomorrow.
I no longer want to be the best.