This film contains graphic violence
and is intended for adults.
Out of respect for the victims and
Family pictures are not edited.
Can you hear me out there?
These things are great.
Our best investment ever.
Do you hear me?
- You do not need to test ...
Sorry.
We make a movie.
- Oh, we.
You too?
- Yes.
What?
- A horror movie.
You are joking.
- No.
We make a film about
bullies at school, did you?
Ours is about a monster ...
... and he killed ... actually ...
So basically he is a murderer.
And there is a secret
public service.
And enabled
to track down the killer ...
... and arrest him.
Because they do not know yet
that he is a monster.
And then there are two
detectives who are now dead.
But ... and they come from England.
And they are both brutal
murdered in a forest.
This is insane.
- Yes.
Our film is about two
students at school ...
... being bullied by a
gang,  The Dirties .
- And they take revenge by ...
- To murder them?
Yes! They have a
arsenal of weaponry, ...
... and they shoot them from
a distance down.
And then they go to
The Rectum club ...
... and murder them
them also and there ...
Wow
- Yeah, it's great.
That's the club from  irreversable .
And then there's a scene where
use the  Dirties  cocaine ...
... and we invade
with guns and going of ...
"Die, dirty bastards."
As these lines in  Usual Suspects .
He plays that other guy.
- Yes, I'm the other one.
And there's a scene where ...
wait a minute, where ...
I have to go.
- Yes I come, secondje.
Never mind, we
have also gone.
Here, have a script.
Our film is called  The Dirties
yours  The Visitor ?
Pleasant acquaintance.
- He's still ot off.
I hope you
film is timid.
Wireless microphones are recommended.
Ok ?, but he is not finished yet.
Peace .
To whom do you think those guys?
You're with the bracket.
I'm the smart who wrote the script.
That's us!
We should have them
say that it gets better.
But that's a lie.
- Simply lied.
They should stop now ...
- It's getting worse.
When I last
wife was in the world?
Then there was always a man ...
OK OK?...
Ok? Rauch.
Two Tangos at the entrance.
Blow their flikkerlul off.
Those with green bandana.
That's not getting laid tonight.
Considering he is so small created
it will be a difficult shot.
This film is sublime.
Come on.
- Yes, I'm ready.
Action!
What are you doing now?
I thought we were good.
Come Jared!
Puts you up against the wall.
Ok ?!
Detectives ... detectives ...
Ok ?, action!
You know how a Quarter Pounder
call with cheese in France?
They not call it
Quarter Pounder with cheese?
No idiot.
It is called as a Royale with cheese ...
... because of the metric system.
Royale with Cheese?
What do they call a Whopper?
They call it a Royale ...
I should do this as Bane.
"Generous and cheese ..."
Beware,  Dirties  ...
Is it friend?
- Damn ...
Is everything alright?
- Yes thank you.
Let my hand go, buddy.
What are you doing now?
- Let go of my hand.
Are you in love with me or something?
- I'll hold your hand not fixed.
Let go of my hand!
- I love them not solid guy!
Oh, you want some pulling and pushing?
Keep those other things.
Can we you
even interview for our movie?
It's really simple. Just a
few questions about bullies.
It's fun.
It is just simple and fun ...
... and you can wirelessly
wear microphone.
Oh god ... you make it
just stuck to your shirt or something?
Oops.
- These things are really timid.
What do you think of bullying?
In general...
Uh ...
- Outside it sucks ...
That is all
I could think of.
Do you have advice for people
which are often bullied?
You should talk to someone.
There are many teachers
you can address ...
... of both sexes.
There is certainly plenty of support here.
Anywhere I guess.
The children know
who they can trust.
Otherwise they
it just a chance.
It's a big step
they need to take.
Our teachers do not so much.
If they interfere
with a fight ...
... they get themselves beaten.
Gee, if you are not with them
can speak...
... and no one wants to help you,
then you should ...
Fighting back just.
- You have to.
Malkovich, Malkovich ...
If they do not understand it
I'm screwed.
They beat me up ...
- That happens all the time though.
They're going to strike me dead ...
when they see this.
Beaten to death ...
Why we use
no real girl?
We film Chrissy in the classroom
After her speech ...
... and we just stop it
in its entirety in the film.
This is Krissy B. and Chrissy H.
- Hey.
And this is our project for filmles.
Come with us.
We make them in.
Keep your mouth!
The Dirties  is much better.
- Shut up, Matt.
Get out, shut himself!
Wimp, sissy, wimp ...
Aside with your thick head.
Matt? Do you like big cocks?
H ?.
Where should you
mothers tits for?
Okay good. Can
back to the lights?
Fine, okay ?.
Are there any questions for
these ladies about the movie?
About their film ...
anyone have any questions?
Matt.
- Matt!  Big Matt
Why did you
"Help, save me" in the movie?
What?
Why you said, "Help, save me"?
I did not say that.
- What is not said?
- What not?
"Help, save me."
Let the detectives here
do not come near!
Help Save me!
- Shut up! Are you serious?
You get the purple glove!
You do not find this funny?
We can not use this.
- Why not?
Chris freaks out when she sees this.
What can our Chrissy cares?
Of course she's going to be angry.
We steal her likeness.
Remove it from there.
I do not think she gets angry.
How so? You stood here behind it all?
It is not good if she freaks out.
Oh, not good for you!
It would not be good for you!
What are you doing now?
- I klooi with your micro.
You hopeless infatuation
our movie is in the way.
It is not hopeless.
In the third year they gave me a note.
She said she me
liked. A 10 to 10.
Bullshit.
No, that really happened
in the third year.
You make it because
this clip want out.
It's true.
Therefore, I want him out.
Hot Chrissy was in love with you?
- A long time ago, but yes.
What happened? Are you flipped?
Yet ?? s time?
Shore Scene, sound, take two.
Old man passes
with little money in his pocket.
H ?, Give it back!
Come down there! Ok ?!
I have not eaten for days.
Begone bum.
All right, I'm leaving.
- What are you still doing?
These are background voices.
Sound effects!
As you  Baldur's Gate  which
have conversation at the inn.
"Well I just got here and I ..."
and then fades.
In each scene you have
the background noise.
This is the old beggar and gull.
Then I have to
bird but eat ...
Do not laugh!
The recording must be pure.
Stop laughing!
For example, the audio recording is not working.
Why are you in your underwear
for a sound?
As Chrissy in love with you
maybe they really want to participate.
She's not in love with me.
- Maybe.
That does not just evaporate.
How can we find out?
I've got it! We hide
a micro in her locker!
Great idea.
Not crazy.
With micro in her locker ...
... let's walk over Owen.
For example, therefore.
And then she says either:
"Oh god, there is Owen."
or "There is that flicker again."
That is a good plan.
And you do pass of Malcolm X.
You know.
Spike Lee teaches it to Denzel.
And then ... no idea
what year ...
... there was that girl of 16
or something with her butterfly tattoo ...
... I do not do anything about it ...
It was not working.
They did not notice.
Grab the edge
and really swing with your arm.
Again.
I think I want ...
I think I have this year
for another outfit to go ...
We can hear everything
what they say.
This girl is so dumb.
Shut up...
Hey Chrissy there's your boyfriend.
- What? Owen?
Too bad they laugh
as if it was a joke.
So, " Dirties  ..."
What should I say?
Say: " Dirties  That?
is my problem. "
"Ensuring you but better
numbers or both your pockets. "
"The  Dirties ? That's my problem.
Worry you, but for better grades ... "
"... Your pockets or both?"
- Yes.
And then we say, "The
Deputy wants this thing! "
The deputy? That will not be the case.
I need you to take away!
I told him he was worthless.
Listen. Why do you work double ...
Why do you work against the sheriff for help?
The chain of command.
I said it, worthless!
- Enough!
Here with your pennies!
And now: "Aaah!"
- "No" or "Aah"?
- "Aaaah"
Mr. Muldoon?
Take exactly the same angle.
So we sit in the same place.
Is it so?
What did I say? What did he say?
That chain of command and
then he is worthless.
I first do my Nick Nolte line.
This is great.
After all this time Kurt Cobain looks
still better off than Courtney Love.
That's funny, still ...
- But that is not ours, plagiarism.
Matt and Owen.
Owen, tell your mother
it was cute in her bed.
Got her appelvla
Matt already tasted?
She was lovely.
- Yes, that will probably man.
Where he has
in talking about?
You got us?
This should look very cinematic
because it is the last scene.
This is it.
The  Dirties  ...
I can not ... I'm so
glad this is the last scene ...
Yes, I would also finish.
But what do you think of this ...?
In the end we make a montage ...
... where we roam
and celebrate the fact that the film is finished.
We can bangelijk number
Best Coast  under it.
Come Rauch.
Here they are.
Remain silent and low to the ground.
We are left with three smoking
accomplices east of the school.
Use of the smoke to
to estimate the wind.
Mercenary 225, this mercenary
3  Romeo Actual .
We have  Dirties
in the crosshairs at 225 meters.
Ok? Rauch.
That Dirty with green bandana ...
... blow his dick off.
Tricky shot ...
Four hundred meter
small and apparently created.
We mow down the fagots.
- Not 'fags' say.
Here I do  Joker   Dark Knight .
Do you have the stuff? Oh!
The  Dirties .
Give me the keys, dirty motherfuckers affairs.
Give me the keys, dirty bastards!
What should I do with you?
The  Dirties  here waving the stick ...
... stupid bastards!
The  Dirties? That's my problem.
Think better of yourself.
- You go bags, you know?
- Oh? However, since we do not give a shit about!
We're here to kill.
Too many extracurricular
Matt activities ...
Too many extracurricular?
"Too many extracurricular ..."
- We go to the  Dirties  tackle.
- And then we come to you, asshole.
The chain of command!
This bureaucrat
totally useless.
Enough so!
Here with your pennies!
Tokens? Tokens?
We have none at all
tokens needed.
Ge me the keys, dirty bastard!
Ok? ...
You have to make adjustments.
- What? No wait ...
The cursing to get out.
The guns also.
No, we can
cursing censor.
A film in which you teacher
shoot, that's not.
You're going to pick him bald!
- No, I did not pick him bald.
Listen. Think about it this way:
you have a movie
made for adults.
This is your  director's cut .
Now I say it as a producer
it must be suitable for the cinema.
You get those things out ...
- Dare it, take the risk.
Take a risk for us.
Come on!
- We're going to do it.
You're going with this
material right away.
It is a good rough version.
You get those things out ...
... and show me tomorrow
a better version.
You make it a bit shorter
and the challenge is to ...
Ok? boys, attention please.
Attention. Here theconservation.
The teacher is now teaching.
Thanks. Silence please.
Ok ?. We have something
exciting for you today.
Matt and Owen have
made a blockbuster for you.
Yesterday I already have a
seen taster.
It was pretty extreme ...
... but really good.
There's some of everything.
Action, comedy, romance.
And it is a little
Gender-bender  ...
It is a  genre-bender
Sorry, what?
- It is a  genre-bender .
genre-bender  so.
You want some more
come on tell?
No? Ok ?.
Let's start there.
Are the lights out?
Ok ?.
Ready?
Ok ?!
"In a remote school
decided two students ...
... the local gang to wind up "
Is this a joke?
Thank you so fast
out, novice.
This was the only place
I could think of.
Can I trust you?
- Of course.
Are you ready for a blood oath?
- Show the knife but!
This is Detective Johnson ...
Look now but just
to the film boys.
No way back.
They're going to share AIDS.
Are you sure they're here?
Here we are.
This is annoying. I had something
with a singer here.
A real piece I've heard.
Can we please them
give our attention?
This is a spicy cottage ...
... but I do not think
Dirties  hiding here.
That's my girl.
She recognizes me probably not.
We both look different.
Malkovich, Malkovich ...
That's you. So are you really.
Come on Matt.
You do not think this suspect?
She seems to want to tell us something
What is this doing?
Fuck you  Dirties .
Damn, damn.
Stay away from me.
Blood?
Jesus Christ...
Damn ...
Let me look at it.
No, fuck off!
- Why are you mad at me?
Touch me just not on.
Did you see that?
What happened?
- My friend was hit by a stone.
Come on!
- Ok ?, damn ...
Need your help?
It's all right.
He has become accustomed.
By what?
- A rock.
We had those guys
? CHT have to shoot.
We had all the  Dirties
? CHT should murder.
Imagine that
we were able to show that film.
A film where everyone is dead?
No, if we just went ...
If we just ...
What did Muldoon again?
The fact that the film does not have a
school attack could go?
If we were to make a film ...
... where we only
bad guys shoot?
We did that already?
- But when we did the CHT?
When we went? Chte guns ...
... and only the bad guys killed?
They simply blow for the camera!
Muldoon would say:
"You really do not have
listened to me. "
"He was too dark when
you still pretending. "
"Now you murder them real?"
"Oh, you're going
they really cared murder? "
That is funny.
Oh, this is crazy.
And it comes down to
everyone knows ...
... we just have to
Dirties .
They know we only
for the bad guys to come.
We can do it on
put our T-shirts.
With a megaphone ...
"Do not panic! We seem dangerous,
and that we are ... "
"... but we are only here
to kill the bullies. "
"If you've teased us ..."
"... mighty, then
you have to be afraid! "
"We're really murder!"
This is a timid idea.
We need to write it down.
" The Dirties 2
My God.
You want some popcorn?
Hardest part
Writing songs ...
Owen, what do
You from here?
For the attack.
That's probably not safe.
For example, we promote a choking hazard.
What did they used to be?
You would die?
That used to sink.
The child dies if you
This draws on its head.
It says that
you could choke.
Well, what is this
the hell?
I lack nothing!
How about this?
Is this shirt say?
Both afscheurbroeken wear?
Then we walk inside
and everyone says:
"Look at that gay pants!"
And then we go from ...
It is now not perfect?
Crazed killers
always obsessed ...
... by  Catcher in the Rye .
Nice of you to jachtpet contributes.
No, not so!
That is better.
But this is still timid?
- Yes.
School Attack ...
The  Catcher in the Rye  theme ...
We are planning just a ball.
I hate this stupid game ...
Let us play!
Great.
Any Which jeans and shirt?
Can you bring two?
Can you something
bring on Owen?
My phone is soaked.
Therefore, I call a payphone.
No, I'm not done!
... Mom!
They have thrown him into the toilet.
As I said!
Hence the payphone.
Can you bring clothes here?
I stand in my gymnastics clothes.
Thanks.
Verdomse bitch!
"Why is your phone wet?"
"Why do not you call with your cell phone?"
Ok ?, well ...
Matt? Is she there now?
Just go already. I will wait.
Oh yeah? What is this asshole?
What the hell is this?
Who did this?
Was it you?
Hello, I'm looking at blueprints
my school ...
... for a school
Her name:  'Westmount High' .
Only the plans?
- Yes.
Then you have the
reception there.
Thank you.
Hello, I'm looking at blueprints
my school ...
... for a project.
Thanks a lot man.
Bye!
Is it not alarming
I just got everything?
No ... I had not even
my student card show.
They have really given everything.
How much is it
to print this?
What is that guy stone
Owen threw to ...?
My left, not your left.
Do not make it too obvious.
- Why use
Make it just not clear!
It does not matter, she can see it.
I appreciate her,
as a work of art.
Owen is obsessed with her.
- I'm not that.
Yes, that's what you do.
- Am I not.
At what life is you now ...?
I'm not obsessed ...
What did you like doing?
- Sorry.
Why do not you pay attention to?
Look, there's vanalles on my sweater.
This is an expensive sweater.
- Ok ?, sorry.
Look at me!
Why are you looking at the ground?
You spoil my lunch and punch
everything just down, damn it.
Apologize! Stand up!
Ok ?, I'm sorry.
What the hell was that?
Sorry, I wish you
lunch not interrupt ...
What are you doing?
Become a damn once mature!
Make your game off, pick that shit up
and make it a pleasant day.
Feeny!
Fe-e-e-ny!
Oh, fl ...
Matt, what the hell are you doing here?
Come on, I'll break you.
I do not care anymore.
I know. I release you!
No, just go away ...
Do your micro to.
They will not hear you.
I do not want...
- Do your micro to tight a second.
This is the classic escape.
I can clearly not
to come outside.
Grab your bike!
I release you Jimmy!
What is that? How do you call that?
What is that? What's that?
I call the double talk.
Did you then it invented?
No, it's called
double talk and gibberish.
The girls who taught me
called double talk.
How do you do it?
Idigo, idijis, idijoe, idiga ...?
You know what Nika Popeil
told me in the sixth year?
She said: "I and Mark went lovemaking
today, but then there was stuff out. "
And that was in the sixth year.
I wore
Ninja Teddy jogging pants.
And I went on: "WHAT?"
Ninja Teddy?
Yes, once in which
arcade near the school ...
Do you remember those?
Ryan Gahooley said:
"Hey, Johnson, jogging pants
out of fashion! "
I just walked away and left
two quarters behind the game.
Really?
- Yes, I was devastated.
That was the first time
I was bullied ...
... because I just
was myself, you know?
What is that guy
who threw the stone?
Shawn.
What's his name?
Spearing.
Who is definitely a  Dirty ?
Jackman.
Dylan.
Hold this a moment.
So it's eight in ...
Well ... more than enough.
Eight out of 62.
Take the end briefly.
Here the theorem of Pythagoras would
we do come in handy.
Go behind. What's the matter?
Should we be doing this now?
What? Measuring the school?
There is nothing wrong with that.
But it looks bad.
You're acting like a freak.
What do you think they feel?
We are dangerous
because we measure things?
We look innocent.
- No, rather ridiculous.
Nonetheless!
- We look strikingly out.
I look like  Encyclopedia Brown .
How does this look to you like?
You walk just past.
Jared, what does this on?
I measure something.
- Ok ?, but ...
And I take a photo of it.
What does that look like?
I measure your chest.
Is that dangerous?
Does this look dangerous Chrissy?
I measure Owen.
We are planning a school attack.
Really? Amazing.
Shall we kill someone for you?
- Yes, Mr. Bird perhaps.
Do you have commissioned
biology already created?
Uh ... no really
not yet. You do?
Owen later she texted me.
Would you have them too?
Yes please.
- Put your number in this.
Good luck with your attack.
Tell anyone though.
- I will not do.
They talk.
We have lost her play.
They must disappear.
She knows the whole plan.
She has seen measuring me.
- Ok ?, I get it ...
I even told her.
She must die, damn it.
We have to kill your girlfriend.
- I get the phone?
How do I go texting her homework?
- No idea why she smashed it.
Maybe she sees you just sit there?
Do you think?
Why would they agree otherwise with
texting homework?
That certainly does not make sense.
- So we make homework ...
I am fine.
Why are you so wildly?
I have it here somewhere.
SMS Chrissy, and tell them you
call at nine o'clock.
Why? What happens then?
- Just do it!
That's Chrissy.
Are you done...?
Wait a second.
- With you ... Jesus.
Hey?
Sorry, I'm at a party.
With whom I speak?
Sorry, I just find a quieter spot.
This party is just so noisy.
No, no problem. Secondje.
Hey? Ok ?, sorry Chrissy.
Do you understand me now?
Ok ?, great. Where you called for?
Right, the homework.
I did a little work on it.
It's just school, you know?
Nobody cares about.
Just give what you have.
Then I can judge it.
Do you  Do not Care High  ever read?
- Yes.
Korman?
- Yes, with all that extra cabinets.
Right, that guy is the baron of ...
Hi Owen.
Did you see that?
You got that?
It is not so much to them "hi" said ...
... but they did it
in front of everybody.
This is not just a greeting
like when you meet someone.
Everyone was there.
Do you understand how important that is?
Yeah, ok ?, what do you think of this ...?
I'm playing guitar in the hallway ...
... and if it passes,
I play a romantic song.
She then goes on:
"Owen, what a good song!"
What are you talking about?
- Girls love guitar, right?
You sound as if I
I remember a bad plan.
That plan seems to make sense.
Are you a Spanish gangster or something?
OK no problem.
Do you remember a good plan.
I will do that.
- Give me one now.
Wait till I get back
of my holiday.
The whole weekend?
I now need a plan.
I can think of nothing immediately.
- Yes, do it!
Wait three days ...
- Now give me immediately a plan.
Pest me now?
I can not wait
until you get back.
Let me come along.
I just go there some weapons
firing with my cousin Nelson.
Is that frightening
with his sunglasses?
I like guns ...
So you close your left eye ...
... and then you put the crosshairs right.
What does it mean?
Get that white
middle of that notch condition.
Like this? I get the check
not in my face or something?
At what sign?
Counting down from 50?
Wow,  damn it! .
Holy shit.
Want one
past my head shaved?
Just so I feel it?
- Ok ?.
Never mind just skim over.
As if I passed on a bicycle.
Hang on, I need a drink.
Damn.
Oh my God.
You see?
Oh my God. I hate you!
Why do you do such a thing
if I start to trust you?
That's why I do not trust you.
It's good to have someone at the same time
and can not be trusted.
It's OK?.
According to Nelson does not matter.
But where is Nelson?
- When the fire.
Watch out. Here lies mud.
Matt!
- Just come Owen.
Is it really okay? we're here?
- Yes.
Timid. Is this a friend of yours?
Yes, this is Scott.
Nice to meet you.
- Hey Scott, I'm Matt.
I do not know
whether it is ok? to wear it.
This is my only jacket.
I can take off him.
It was the only one we had.
I know I
a chief corpse.
My plan is now
to bake a cake at home.
Owen then pretends
who has stolen from a cooking class.
And then he put it to her
and he says:
"Chrissy, I stole this cake,
You want a piece? "
And then she thinks:
"Wow, what a tough guy."
Do you think that works?
- I do not know...
Cake Plan ...!
- I do not know if that works.
It's rather corny.
It sounds like a plan
such as in films.
But that really works! It's not like
he immediately makes a proposal.
I play guitar...
... just in general.
I show her
I play guitar.
And that you enjoy doing.
Right.
- This shows exactly who you are.
- That would be very cool.
Better than the cake plan?
- Yes!
If what they say ...
... you just imagine
something to drink something.
- And otherwise it's not so bad.
- No really .
Nothing lost, nothing gained.
Just do not creepy.
- I'm not creepy!
The cake plan is creepy!
- Yeah, forget the cake plan.
It comes down
you paranoid to do.
You have to pretend
really is in trouble.
That you're really screwed
if you can not sit down.
So you say, "Hey Chrissy,
May I sit down? It is urgent!"
"Damn, I stole this cake.
May I sit down? "
Once you're in the right.
- I gotta sit down.
Then you get to a point
where it just ... as a lunch date.
Nothing.
And if it does not work ...
... if you afwimpelt
go off when LeBron James.
With flour ...
I made this cake just
stolen from a cooking class.
We need to eat him.
You feel like it?
Puts you there.
I also have some forks
and signs on.
Beautiful.
Wait a second.
Is someone else's cake?
Yes, he was just standing there.
So now goes down?
- Stop!
Sorry, I have offended you?
No.
Birthdays?
Evan has scored us a cake.
- It is Owen!
He's very nice.
Yes, take it.
Help yourself buddy.
- He CHT good?.
What the hell was that?
- Why? It was amazing!
What was that?
That was not the plan!
Chrissy loved it.
No man. You have the  Dirties
made cake!
I've seen it!
You have given them cake!
He was Chrissy
and she loved it ...
Everyone loved it.
What's wrong with you?
Chrissy liked it ...
- Verdomse idiot!
Exit ...
We need to  Catcher in the Rye  lend.
It is funny
if we all take.
If we take them all
we seem insane.
Six copies.
We'll take them all, all three.
Why do we seem insane?
- Because it is funny!
Come on, poseur.
- Ok ?.
H ?, Owen.
How are you?
What does the word 'arbitrary'?
That means either a decision
for reasons that do not really matter ...
... or by someone who has the right
did not have to make them.
The decision was arbitrary.
It does not matter ...
... and you had no right
to make them.
Does that make sense?
- Yes.
Ok ?.
- OK thanks.
What was that?
She asked you ...?
- She asked what "arbitrary" means.
I explained her
and she thanked me.
What an idiot. Is she
'Grapes of Wrath' reading?
She does not know what "arbitrary" means?
I'm going to tell her what
a bad definition that is.
Define the better.
- Arbitrary?
So many times I did not.
What does the word 'arbitrary'?
- OK sorry. Arbitrary means ...
What does 'arbitrary'?
- It means...
Arbitrary means
You know something, but ... no.
I could not believe
you did something stupid.
Why do you do such a thing even?
It was not intentional.
I was just so concentrated.
I was also upset.
Then it goes on here ...
- Play it.
You know this from when
we had that plan.
I just have not seen it yet.
I have the dead
moments edited out.
Well, how does this look?
It looks fantastic.
This is amazing.
You have nothing
seen h ??
That last scene
looks so absurd.
Here, images of
on the bike you see.
Look.
What are they?
- Blueprints.
How so?
They are blueprints of the school.
I had not told you yet.
Why School?
- Yeah wait a minute.
I'll show you.
I put everything on it.
Where each room has
and who uses them and stuff.
They are damn gigantic h ??
Look, I have the  Dirties  put it.
And look, every room is labeled.
The gym ...
Mr. Macs class and Muldoon.
Everything is on it.
The times and ... wait a minute.
The leswissels where they usually
hang out and all cabinets.
Then I have a separate sheet
especially for ... all the Dirties.
... the first note, right?
There, right on that note.
Yes, all together in one big ... ?? sentence.
Sorry Mr. Bird, it will come.
Yes, it is to succeed.
Yes, like that.
All at once. Not going back.
Wait, I'll show you something.
It is a different language such as
speech, right?
So we play a phrase.
A sentence with a particular
rhythm and phonetics.
So you're doing ...
You see?
- Yes, but it sounds better to you.
You simply separate your hands.
I want to be this morning.
It does not sound like you.
Why? You have plenty of time.
You have to practice every day,
but the girls will love it.
How this guy called again?
Something with a D?
Dylan?
You do not know?
Where did you get all those pictures come from?
- From footage.
Oh, screenshots?
- Yes.
Why?
- For the film.
It's all the  Dirties .
What if your mom sees them?
- That never comes here.
When did her
here last?
Even then she just looks
a lot of pictures.
They might think it's for
is a film. That's it.
When she asked about it would
I just say.
She would say, "I do not know
once why I asked, blah blah blah. "
"Steven, you know it already?
Matthew is bla bla bla ... "
She would not even say that.
"Ok ?, I leave for my work. Day!"
Go tell her.
Go upstairs.
"M-m Mrs. Johnson, uh ..."
Mrs. Johnson, your son
is damn crazy ...
He hang pictures on the wall
of people he wants to murder ...
Get the photos off or something ...
- No!
Ok ?, I'm going home.
- What?
Owen?
-  I'm going home .
Tarantino!
Cute haircut man.
Excuse ...
Look at him.
This is like when  Snake Eyes
who made mistake ...
Please do something back.
Put the piece a minute but come ...
I need to do it here.
Put ?? s step back.
This is madness.
But that would not look so good.
- That does not matter now!
Of course it out.
This is a movie!
This is not a movie.
Just you and me.
This is a film. Trust me.
We'll go home and I'll show you ...
- It's sick how you behave!
What do you mean?
- It is always a movie for you!
It's pathetic!
Why are you being so weird?
- I'm not weird!
You conducted your very strange ...
I take a step forward and ...
This is exactly what I mean!
You're upset
and I try to calm down and I say:
"Listen, Owen, calm ..."
It does not care if you
a good scene would find in your film ...
It's Danny Glover in  Royal Tenenbaums .
"I do not know, Percy, she's ..."
Shut up!
I do not find it funny,
So who do you do it?
Is this about Chrissy?
- What does this have to do with Chrissy?
No idea. I do not think
I've done something wrong.
You act!
You do that all the time.
- I never do!
Even now you're acting!
I do not know anymore
what else is real to you.
This is real. I really do!
I really do ...
I'm standing on a cliff
I want to record a scene which is real!
Not if you Kung Fu and the passes
and the voices do with it ...
Yeah, calm! This is ridiculous.
Now, however, is suitable
to the scene to terminate them.
Well,  cut .
From there then.
Do not mess with me!
- Come on, turn again.
Get the fuck down!
Down I say!
Funny, h ??
If you see yourself on video ...
... it seems ... another person.
Loopy ...
Sweatpants are
out of fashion, Jackman.
Yo! That is my line.
The Gahooley: "Jogging Pants are
out of fashion, Jackman. "
You have about 45 minutes.
- Before the storm starts?
Hopefully, the storm does not blow as hard
if your mother yesterday.
What?
You heard me.
What? The storm blows ...?
Yes, you heard me.
It can give me some.
We come your murder with guns.
Do you know?
- Yes.
We will shoot you.
- No, not yet.
He's still not telling.
Therefore you are wimps.
- You're dead ...
You do not come up for yourself.
I have just explained so!
- Come on, stop ...
This is madness!
Owen, this sounds familiar?
"Joy, sadness, fear, fun ..."
"... can all be imitated."
"He knows the expressions, intonation
and body language. "
"He can not just light on ..."
"... his whole life
?? is a big scam. "
"His personality is completely
invented ... "
"... to deceive people."
"Psychopaths are proud
their deceit ... "
"... and share the fun."
"Lying is their profession."
"Even if the truth is sufficient,
they lie to the sport. "
This is exactly what you said about me.
Who are you calling?
Nobody.
Did you hear me?
I could be a psychopath.
Owen, I am perhaps a psychopath!
Who you texting?
What are you doing?
This man is crazy!
You do not laugh once.
I'm tired of this.
Let's do something else.
What do you mean something else?
I do not know, a video game?
Or  Magic  play cards.
Can you not care
I might be a psychopath?
I'm not going to play this game.
- What game?
You're a coward but
you do your tough love before.
You're the one
these tough trying to do!
Very texting time with
some hot chick.
I try to put a monkey.
You're the wimp!
No! You're a coward!
You talk tough but does nothing.
That makes you a wimp!
I make myself at least not wise
that a girl sees me sit ...
... while she does not care about me!
It is a silly goose!
The only reason she sees you
Thanks to my plan!
You do not know what you're talking about!
- Anyway!
No. anyway.
- I know that!
You're nobody!
You're nothing without me!
I'm your only friend!
You always pretend
you have to say ...
... but no one likes you
and nobody wants to deal with you!
And if you're really upset
you react it off on me!
Then you get mad about that girl
where you're jealous.
You're jealous of the only person
who sees me standing!
I'm not jealous!
She's stupid!
I want my best friend
not see embitter his life!
Why start over
if you do not care?
You're jealous!
You have no friends ...
... and you do it to yourself!
I do not count on it.
You know it's true!
Fuck you! Get out!
For me it does not.
Is it too corny?
This is nothing to me h ??
Do such a thing ...
Die, dirty bastard!
Is that scary?
If I come out?
The yellow glove
looks menacing.
I do not know why.
This is just perfect for a murder.
It looks like  The Cleaner .
"Now my glove
under the blood! "
This shirt is perhaps neon.
My extended family as bears ...
Is that weird?
You have to imagine
under the bloodstains.
Do I sometimes mad at you?
- Why? Who thinks you're crazy?
I do not know...
I seem not mad, are you?
- No, you're not crazy.
You sometimes does say crazy things.
I do not know why you do that.
Just before the show, I think.
- That Owen thinks.
Well, what are you doing?
This is just out of the blue.
So just without any context.
From where is that?
I do not know.
I thought there normally.
I read a book about ...
Well, what does it mean
to be crazy?
Technically, you were not
know what is real and what is not.
That means to be crazy.
If you have a grip
on reality.
You're a bit of a wild ...
I'm just wondering
where that comes from.
I do not know.
- Think you're crazy?
No, I do not think so.
I do not even know why I ask.
I had to
my notebooks burn ...
It must have likely
tuck yourself ... in the end.
I export them, but ...
Are you a student?
- Yeah, I'm just a little earlier.
Come in.
- Thanks man.
H ?, Josh ...
You're here early.
- It is a project for Mr. Muldoon.
Wow. Good luck!
Josh, huh? ...
- Look who's here.
Let go of my hand guy.
Jogging Pants are out of fashion.
It's all right.
I'm just here for the bad guys!
Owen?
Owen!
Come, come, out of here!
- Get out of here
Come on! Down the stairs!
Good heavens.
Owen!
Damn.
What are you doing now? It's me!