The little minister
Every spring in the Caddam Woods
near Thrums, in Scotland,
a troup of gypsies settles:
Every spring again to the
fright of the pious villagers.
Betty Compson as
the mysterious Babbie.
In the god-fearing Thrums unrest is
brewing, for a wage cut has brought
the weaver population to poverty.
Sanders Webster, himself already
an old man, earned with arduous
work the dry bread for his mother.
Old Nanny Webster, his mother.
"Nanny, Nanny, from which hand do
you want to get something from me?"
"Tea! Have you really come
by that honestly, girl?"
"It's terrible to be so poor,
that even the gypsies pity us!"
Tammas Whammond, first
elder of the Thrums church.
Snecky Hobart, another elder.
Hendry Munn, sacristan.
"Mother, I'm hungry!"
Gavin Dishart, the new minister
of the Thrum church.
Apart from the minister, doctor
Mc Queen is one of the most
seen men in Thrums.
"You've heared that the
factory owners, supported by
lord Rintoul, have suddenly
cut the wages. I deem our
weavers capable of fighting
for their right if need be."
"One of the factory owners already
acted very shamelessly.
There's been a disturbance then..."
"Has the police arrested no-one?"
"No. But we can expect any day,
that they come here."
"There comes the police!"
Andrew Mealmaker, on Sundays a
pious elder, during the week the
proudest rebel among the weavers.
"Will you feed our families if we
have ourselves taken to prison?"
"With everything I own! In compassion
and shame for your violence and crime!"
"They knew exactly the names of our
leaders. Who gave them that away?"
"That's that gypsy girl who
always prowls around us!"
"I've never seen her, but I was
told, she does a lot of good."
"A pretext! All gypsys
are thieves and spies."
"Let's chase them out of the
Cammam Woods for once and for all!"
"No violence! I will go
to them and warn them."
"He's a bit young though.
To be walking alone between
all those pretty gypsy girls."
Captain Richard Halliwell,
commander of the dragoons.
The castle Rintoul, where through the
ages, the lords of Thrum had lived.
The earl of Rintoul.
"There's been another riot in Thrums."
"It's so lovely, Felice, to
walk around free as a gypsy girl!"
"Lord Rintoul, there will be
no order in Thrums before it's
been brought in by the soldiers."
In Thrums too they want to be
prepared for the soldier's arrival.
"How many horns do we have?"
"Four isn't too much:
The guards need one each."
"Go to your stations:
As soon as you see a soldier,
you blow your horn three times.
"Now the gypsy girl
is lady Barbara again."
"If possible, Halliwell,
don't use soldiers preferably."
"It's your duty to maintain
authority in this region."
"Why don't you use your power
to bring the wages up again?"
"Babbie, don't speak along about
affairs you know nothing about."
"I believe that you're making an
immortal fool of yourself, father."
"Dear child, if you ever see that
your father makes a fool of himself,
I promise you on my word as Rintoul
that the wages will go up again."
"There's one exit that we cannot
guard, that's Miller's Arch."
"The minister hasn't returned
yet from the Caddam Woods!"
"I think that Sunday he will
preach about "women"!"
"Blow your horn:
There come the redcoats!"
"I'm glad that you've come!
I can't blow this here horn?"
"Why do you want to blow horn now?"
"Have you never heard those
wonderful echos in the valley yet?"
"Won't you teach me that
blowing of the horn?"
"They're already gathering!
They've understood your signal!"
"Andrew Mealmaker, send these people
home. Before blood is spilled!"
"Put down your weapons!"
"If you resist, women and
children will be shot down!"
"You've let yourselves be caught,
like mice in a trap!"
"That gypsy, that abetstress, wants
to incite you to fight! Go all
home and trust on providence."
"We are surrounded!"
"Listen! Miller Arch isn't guarded!"
"Do not trust her! It is a trap!"
"If you don't believe me: Here is
the horn with which I've warned you!"
"The leaders can escape
by Miller's Arch!"
"The others must hold the soldiers here
so long until the men are in safety!"
"You're too late: the boys that
you came for, are already in safety."
"The ringleaders have escaped, sir.
A gypsy girl arranged that plan."
"No woman may leave the village
before we've found that gypsy lass!"
"You may not pass before that
gypsy girl has been arrested."
"It was a dreadul night, hubby.
How tired you will be!"
"You're right, reverend.
You'd better take your wife home."
"My wife? But sergeant..."
"Of course darling!
I am simply proud of you!"
"My husband does all that's in his
power to maintain the legal authority...
But oh, that terrible gypsy girl..."
"But sergeant..."
"Yes hubby... say it!"
When a few days later peace
had returned to the ranks...
"You are everything that
a woman should not be!"
"Nanny says it's because of
the way in which I was raised!"
"Babbie, please don't tease me,
when I'm trying to be serious."
"Do you really think
that I am a bad girl?"
"You're a gypsy!"
"I loved that boy as a son...
but he's an unfaithful shepherd."
"It's sad work for the council of
elders, to have to fire such a boy."
"I have a warrant for the arrest
of the gypsy girl... She blew
the horn and warned the weavers."
"I am the man you seek...
I blew the horn!"
"The warrant speaks of a gypsy girl...
Only lord Rintoul can change that."
"Then see that lord Rintoul
changes this warrant."
"I've come to tell here that
not the gypsy girl, but I gave
the horn signal that night."
"I'm sorry for your wife, mr. Dishart."
"I have no wife."
"But the women, who went past
the guard as your spouse?
"That was the gypsy."
"I've come to bring berries
for the gentlemen, sir."
"Don't you know that this is Rintoul
Castle... The home of the man who
issued the arrest warrant against you?
"You don't have to be afraid... I've
told tem that I gave the horn signal."
"You've said that to save me!"
"I've said that because
it is the truth."
"I believe that you've said it,
because you love me."
"I am also afraid, that I've
done it because of that."
"Babbie, I love you!"
"But... You wouldn't
dare to marry a gypsy?"
"I would dare everything, Babbie, to
make you mistress at the vicarage."
"You will feel strange at first...
In such a big house!"
"I'll buy a real silk dress for
you... White, with flowers on it."
"I insist that the
minister be arrested."
"In the king's name I request you
to issue this warrant, lord Rintoul."
"You will not sign that warrant!"
"Babbie, you go too far, child.
What concern is that of yours?"
"He has asked me to become his wife."
"What! A village minister who proposes
for the hand of lady Barbara Rintoul?
Such an insolence!"
"I'm sorry for you father...
I've decided to marry him."
"Do you know, lady Barbara,
that he has introduced the
gypsy girl as his wife?"
"I wish she were his wife!"
"She IS his wife... He called her so
before two witnesses and in Scotland
that means a lawful marriage."
"Arrest that gypsy girl and
bring her to the vicarage."
"Tell the witnesses to follow lord
Rintoul and me to the vicarage."
"There's a special meeting concerning our
minister, who through his conduct has cast
a stain on the cloth of god's servant..."
"You said, mr. Dishart..."
"I didn't say anything, Thammas."
"Read the charge, Hendry."
"No charges necessary...
I already confess."
"The gypsy girl couldn't blow...
then I've done it for her."
"...firstly, that he, said
Gavin Dishart, sat with said
gypsy girl upon the wall
of Nanny Webster's garden, with
a space, not as big as the width
of a small bible, between them."
"...and that said Jeanne, maid of
said Gavin, declared under oath
that said Gavin desecrated his
bible, by drying a rose in it."
"...and that said Jeanne
has seen that said Gavin sat
with said rose in his hand,
so that she reasonably supposed,
that his thoughts were far
away from his sacred calling."
"There come the soldiers!"
"No violence, please!
They seek ME!"
"I ask an explanation milord,
why you come to disturb
a meeting of the elders."
"Your meeting comes very handy for me.
For I wanted to put a few things before
you concerning our little minister."
"He introduced her, to save her,
to these two witnesses as his wife."
"In Scotland that means a legal
marriage. Your little minister
is married to a gypsy woman!"
"The gypsies have moved out. I
believe that the girl is gone too."
"They've got the gypsy girl!"
"Allow me, mr. Dishart, that
I introduce you to your wife!"
"Babbie!"
"Lady Barbara!"
"Lady Barbara, what is
the meaning of this?"
"It means that I adore playing
a gypsy and marrying... and
getting arrested and such."
"You will not take advantage
of this, mr. Dishart...?"
"Perhaps he doesn't take advantage...
but here are three old men,
who have an interest... The boy and
the girl are married and that's it!"
"Remember your promise, father! As
soon as you'd do something ridiculous...
Tell them right away about their wages..."
"...ik will also see, that
the wages are raised again;
above the old standard."
"There will be joy tonight in Thrums."
"And...?
"Now we are married,
do you understand?"
"Babbie, god has been good to us..."
"I thought so too, Gavin..."