Long before the heavens
had taken form...
there existed an angel-like figure...
a goddess,
whom the ancients called Emperia.
From within her
came the seed of fire and light...
that was to issue forth all stars,
planets, and moons.
From this great beginning,
the planet Earth was formed...
together with its satellite,
the moon.
Then, one day...
the gods,
the prime movers of the universe...
gave life to an earthly creature.
The mightiest,
the most heroic of all men:
Hercules.
Many honors were bestowed upon Hercules
for his deeds on earth...
and he took his rightful place
on Olympus...
from where Zeus, King of the Gods,
ruled peacefully...
thanks to his seven
mighty thunderbolts.
But one day,
foolish and envious gods...
stole the seven thunderbolts...
and unleashed the diabolical forces
of evil and chaos.
Be quiet, maiden.
You'll disturb the gods.
The altar is set.
The appointed hour has come.
The fires await her silken flanks.
To the altar.
Bind her in her chains.
No, I’ve done nothing!
Quiet, be still.
Untie me!
Cry not.
'Tis an honor to be chosen.
No!
The moon is high.
We are ready, my dear Antius.
The city of Phagesta offers you
another one of its daughters.
No, don't give me
to the fire monster!
You're privileged.
This is your destiny.
You must die
so that your people will live on.
No, don't let him take me.
He is evil!
She is yours, Antius.
Don't do this!
Glaucia.
What is it?
Antius, the fire monster.
Ilia's dead.
I was there.
The ghoulish fiend swallowed her
in his flames, consumed her slowly.
lt was horrible.
Who gives him his power?
He'll swallow us all, Urania.
One by one.
Why do our gods permit it?
Why has our clan been chosen
for this horror?
No, don't blame the gods.
You must have faith.
Please, be strong.
I want to have faith.
-It's difficult, though.
-I know.
I knew you went there.
I wanted to stop you.
You forget,
you're our chosen sister.
Our fate is in your destiny.
Has it revealed itself?
No, I think it's too early,
my sister.
I’ve only the power to predict,
not to prevent.
lt is said...
that you shall be
the next victim.
Ilia had come to me in a dream.
I went to her,
but it was too late.
And now....
I’d be willing to die...
to save our people.
But what's the good?
It'll only be in vain.
He'll consume us...
like he did Ilia.
Antius is evil.
He must be destroyed.
-There is a way.
-What are you saying?
That there's a way to destroy him.
-How?
-With cunning.
-I’ll go to the Little People.
-Yes, they use cunning to survive.
And I’m sure
they'll give me the right answer.
Have faith, Glaucia.
I’ll be back by morning.
Little People,
friends of Zeus...
please listen to my prayer.
We know
why you are here, Urania.
Terrible things are happening
in the universe.
Even the gods
have been led astray.
Four of them
rebelled against Zeus...
and stole his seven
mighty thunderbolts...
the secret,
the key to all his powers.
lt is your fate that calls,
and your coming here was already planned.
The architects of the universe
have lost control of the heavenly bodies.
Our moon is coming towards us.
Your destiny is interwoven
in the celestial upheaval.
And it will lead you to the one man
who can help you.
Who is he?
Where can I find him?
He's the strongest man
who has ever walked the earth.
A man called Hercules.
Hercules is still.
Yes, the invincible son of Zeus.
lt was he
who divided the continents...
as it was he
who had formed the constellations...
and who defeated King Minos
and his vast empire.
Yes. Hercules the Invincible.
And yet, nothing's been heard from him
for ages.
They say that Zeus
sent him up to the heavens...
and placed him
among the brightest stars.
Destiny says
it is you who must seek him.
Go with Glaucia to the Forbidden Valley.
That's where you shall meet him.
-Hercules.
-Yes. The Invincible.
They are crying
for Hercules, Zeus.
And we seem immune
to their suffering.
I have hesitated...
because Man must learn
to stand on his own two feet.
I blame our own gods
if Man has failed.
There has been wickedness
here in Olympus, and I am powerless.
The moon is wild.
It looms bigger every day
as it moves in on its mother planet.
The foolish gods who stole my seven
thunderbolts are the cause of this disorder.
There is no other hope but to summon
the greatest warrior ever known.
He will stop the rebel gods...
and recover
my seven thunderbolts.
Hercules, return to Earth.
Retrieve my seven thunderbolts
which allow me to maintain order.
Make haste, Hercules, lest the planets
destroy themselves and all living things.
Hercules is here on Earth...
and has already converted
one of the seven thunderbolts.
Should he find all seven,
our plans will be shattered.
No. The lightning lies
in the bellies of monsters...
and they roam in places
inaccessible to man.
I hope you're right, Hera.
Zeus will be destroyed.
And as for Hercules...
someone has waited many years
for revenge.
-Am I right, Flora?
-I've arranged it all, dear Hera.
I've called upon
the warrior, Gorus.
He's ambitious, has few scruples,
and will consent to any request.
The fool seeks the status of a demigod,
but lacks the gentility.
He will serve us well.
Flora.
There you are.
First, you nearly blind me...
then you hide in shadow.
Why have you summoned me
to such a dreary place?
You always wanted to know
the secrets of darkness.
And now, your wish
is about to be answered.
Come.
This is....
-It's the secret tomb of King Minos of Thira.
-Good for you, Gorus.
His cursed ashes lie here.
But his knowledge and power
cannot be imprisoned forever.
Release them.
-He's nothing but bones.
-Of course.
But through resurrection,
he shall rise again.
But in order to have life...
one must take life.
Yours.
Poseidon.
Aphrodite.
Hera.
Minos can now be stirred
from his eternal sleep.
I have my misgivings, Flora.
Minos was always up to mischief
and deception.
But we've the power
to handle him.
Flora did well
to slay the warrior Gorus.
Now, the blood of this man...
will give life back to Minos.
Who awakens me?
'Tis you three.
What do you want, Hera?
Zeus has brought Hercules
back to life.
We need your help.
He must be eliminated.
And whatever you wish
will be yours.
No, Minos.
You know I’ve never put much stock
in the promises of gods.
But it's not often
that fulfilling one's obligations...
can be such a pleasure.
-Help! Help me!
-Easy. Calm down.
Calm down and I shall help.
They thought I was dead,
but they took my friend Urania with them.
-Who took her?
-The Slime People. They ambushed us.
They rise out of the mud and mire
and hold you by suction.
Where did they go?
Through the wild.
-Towards the great mouth of stone.
-The Forbidden Valley.
You should know
that this is a very dangerous region.
This way.
Glaucia?
Urania.
-Hercules. I thought you were still...
-Hurry, there's no time now.
Hold on.
Good girl.
Come on!
-Quick, inside the stone mouth.
-They're coming!
Inside.
-What was that?
-lt could be the work of gods. Careful.
But the gods always forewarn
earthly people.
There are evil gods.
-How can we tell?
-Don't worry.
For now, no one's bothering us.
They seemed afraid of this place.
And yet, they brought you here.
They were going to sacrifice me
to something.
Something that lives in here.
The currents change direction
at this point.
The airflow takes this way.
Come, follow me.
-Where do you want to--
-Quiet.
lt is we who trespass.
Welcome, earthlings.
lt is a rare pleasure to have you
in our midst.
Who art thou?
I am Euryale.
Come into my palace.
They look real.
These statues,
they look as quiet and still as mummies.
As if the sculptor
caught his subjects unaware.
They have a very realistic look in the eye.
They seem to be tense, quivering.
There is nothing more beautiful
than the human body...
caught in a moment of tension...
and sculpted forever in stone...
immortalized.
Great deeds make us immortal.
We can't all be so fortunate.
Come.
Where do you take us, Euryale?
To safety.
These caves are a labyrinth.
lt is very easy to get lost.
-Beyond these columns lies the way out.
-We didn't come in through here.
You'll find another way out,
down there.
Visitors on these lands
are forbidden.
I’ve led you safely underground
through the Forbidden Valley.
We thank you for your help.
Fight them!
Euryale's gone.
She's one of the Gorgon monsters
who turn men into stone at a single glance.
She's one of the gods
I’m looking for.
Now that we've passed the Forbidden
Valley, we'll continue the journey.
-But you must leave this dungeon now--
-But--
Don't tempt the gods.
You must go now.
Wait for me, I shan't be long.
I am over here.
Poor Hercules.
King Zeus sent you
on a long journey.
What a shame
it must end here.
Be stilled forever, like stone.
With me.
I will find you! I'm coming.
Yes, do come.
Let me look at you.
I’m over here.
Come look at me.
Look at yourself, dear Euryale,
and use my shield as a mirror.
The second thunderbolt.
Hercules has discovered
the second thunderbolt.
And Minos,
disappeared for three days...
and three nights.
Minos has been sailing east.
I know.
I followed him
to the edge of time and space.
-You could have changed the winds.
-His science changed them back.
He uses science against godly powers.
I don't trust him.
Our purpose is the same.
That is, to kill Hercules.
I must find a way to overcome
the fire monster's radiant heat.
I am not immune
to the energy Antius releases.
The Little People use cunning
against power.
-I think they'll listen to me.
-Then let us go to the Little People.
But to reach them,
we'll have to cross the Doomed Forest...
-where the demon Tartarus reigns.
-We can't go back now.
-Then you'll save the maidens of Phagesta?
-Fate has already willed it.
Zeus has sent me here
to find his mighty thunderbolts.
And one of them is inside Antius' belly.
It's so gloomy here.
Like a land of lost souls.
That's what they are.
They're dolls.
Hundreds of thousands.
It's the work of a fiend.
Once, they were humans
or demigods.
This resembles hell on earth.
And to think that Tartarus
was once a favorite of King Zeus.
Until one day,
he offended the king and was banished.
He's been living in this forest
for thousands of years.
lt is said he poisons the trees,
and that the splinters are deadly.
If we go another way,
we'll lose time.
-But--
-He could have attacked us had he wanted.
There's little else we can do but face him.
Wait here.
Urania, I’m scared.
I’m terrified.
-Show yourself!
-I’m here.
Let us cross the forest in peace.
I rule the world of the dead.
I have sent many a valiant soul
to Hades.
Did I frighten the son of Zeus?
You are doomed.
Die!
You will join my forest
of dangling souls.
-Where are you?
-Here.
Your death shall free the souls.
The third thunderbolt.
All beings but us will perish...
and I shall regenerate mankind
to my own likeness.
I am chaos.
This sword of ice
has existed from the beginning of time.
And with it,
you will have the gods at your feet.
I will have the gods
at my feet.
Yes, Minos. This sword was forged
for Cronos at the time of creation.
And later,
when Zeus conquered Cronos...
I stole the sword
and hid it for this occasion.
The gods have always
underestimated me, Dedalos.
And they will be punished
for it.
For the sake of my honor.
With this sword,
science shall triumph.
I give it to you now.
lt is to be used only once.
Beware, ye gods,
of the science of Minos.
Here we are.
That's the way to the Little People.
Through the ancient naos of Lacunt.
They see and hear
what we cannot.
-Then you'll wait here?
-Yes.
Good luck, Urania.
I won't be long.
Where the fires are high,
I invoke you, Klotho and Lachesis.
What brings thee here,
Urania?
You have made your choice.
You found Hercules,
and destiny is being fulfilled.
Yes, and we thank you for it,
and would ask you this:
How can Hercules stand up to Antius
and not meet his death?
To your question,
we do know the answer.
But first, Urania, you must find
the one and only substance...
that can give protection
to man...
against the flames
of the fire monster, Antius.
'Tis the healing secret balm
of Nomankril...
made out of drops of water
from the river Styx.
Where is it?
You and Hercules
must reach the sea...
and find there
the sanctuary of Thetis.
She will tell you what Hercules
and you must do to face Antius.
Fire can only be defeated
by water.
Yes, but how can we find her sanctuary
under such deep water?
You will have gills like fish
if you swallow these precious herbs...
and you'll breathe
like the inhabitants of the sea.
Take these golden leaves
of the consecrated gardens of Hespere.
Hercules, I’ve got the secret.
Tell me, how can we stop
the fire monster?
-We'll have to journey.
-Where to?
-No, you must stay here, Glaucia.
-Don't you think we should stay together?
The Little People
speak in the name of Zeus...
and we will have to do
what they say.
Their words reflect
the faithfulness of the gods.
They only speak the truth.
lt is best, Glaucia.
Wait for us here.
-And don't worry.
-We'll not be long.
You say the Little People
spoke of Thetis and a sea kingdom?
Yes, and the door to it
lies below there.
That's many leagues
beneath the sea.
We needn't fear.
We shall breathe like water creatures...
thanks to this.
The Little People gave them to me.
-Well, what is that?
-Time is short. Take it.
Didn't you say
the Little People always spoke the truth?
Look there.
Yes. It's the temple of Thetis,
the Nereid.
Welcome, my friends.
Do not be alarmed.
You don't see me speak...
but you hear the projection
of my thought.
You've come in the name of Zeus.
I know.
We have very little time,
and we need your help.
It shall not be denied.
The sacred balm
the Little People spoke to you about...
was made with three drops
taken from the river Styx...
that flows through Hades.
If you spread the balm from head to toe,
you shall, for a short while...
resist the incinerating flames of Antius,
the fire monster.
If I am able to resist the heat
for the time it takes to discover his secret...
then Phagesta will be free.
Yes, the maidens of Phagesta
shall be free of danger...
but not for long.
The thunderbolts that were stolen from Zeus
have caused havoc in the skies.
The moon no longer obeys the earth.
The tides have swollen the seas.
You must find
the remaining thunderbolts...
or our planet
shall surely be crushed.
-We'll be crushed?
-The moon.
Yes. It is coming upon us.
The meridians have been changed.
Unless cosmic balance is reestablished...
it will mean the annihilation
of all living things...
perhaps even the gods.
We cannot let this happen.
We must stop it now.
Hercules and Urania...
you hold the fate of all
that has been created in your hands.
I give you the sacred balm
you have come for.
Go, and face the fire monster
at once.
-Are you all right?
-Yes, let's go.
-Where is she?
-I don't know.
Glaucia?
Would she have gone around
that point?
But it's not like her.
It's strange.
Look there.
It's a shield.
I know this shield.
Whose is it?
lt belongs to the High Priest
and to his soldiers.
The priest who invokes
the fire monster.
That means they came here to get her
and to sacrifice her!
They can't be far ahead of us.
We'll reach her in time.
Great gods,
don't let me die. I beg!
Please, help me.
No, don't let me die!
I invoke thee, Antius...
Lord of Fire.
We offer you
the last daughter of Phagesta.
Come! Here is your victim.
It's ghastly.
It's hell. Hell on earth!
Take it away!
No!
It's Antius.
-I am ready for you!
-Hercules!
Antius is dead.
We've been set free.
Hercules has found
the fourth lightning bolt.
-But this is only the beginning.
-The beginning?
We are rid of the monster.
The problem is not just Antius.
Our Mother Earth is in great danger...
and mankind will perish...
unless we can help Hercules
find the three remaining thunderbolts.
I think Minos is up to his old tricks again.
Always experimenting.
We did not rebel against Zeus
only to join forces with disaster.
No. We rebelled against Zeus...
-to be free, completely free.
-Yes.
Should he succeed in collecting
all his thunderbolts...
Zeus will be back in full force.
Why hasn't Minos
stopped him yet?
Minos doesn't need
our advice.
The clashing of these two enemies
is unavoidable.
Minos is preparing
a nice little surprise for Hercules.
-ls he?
-At this very moment.
Meanwhile,
Flora is keeping Minos in check.
Yes. In fact he asked
that I appear before him.
Perhaps the three of us should appear.
He's diabolically clever.
But Flora's the one
who brought him back from eternal sleep.
-He seems to trust her most.
-He trusts no one.
Let us hope for the best.
-The stars be with you, Flora.
-Thank you, Hera.
You're late
in answering my call.
The gods have done
what you wanted...
yet Hercules succeeds
in his mission.
He's found four thunderbolts,
while you, you just disappear.
-You're acting as though you were a god.
-I am much more than a god, Flora.
You're mad, Minos.
The time has come
to dissolve the bond...
that ties me with foolish gods
unworthy of my talents.
Those gods will annihilate you, Minos.
Be careful.
Your concern for me is touching,
especially since it comes...
at the moment
when you should be afraid for yourself.
Flora, Goddess of Spring...
I deliver you
into the land of frost...
of ice!
The Little People
used to appear in this temple...
before the fire monster
destroyed it.
If only I can call them back.
What is it, Urania?
I feel another presence.
It's strange, as if....
Urania, are you certain
this is the place?
The temple has always meant a lot
to the Little People.
I’ve always talked to them,
but now I can't feel their presence.
There is another way,
although it's difficult and very dangerous.
-How is that?
-I shall consult an oracle.
-What oracle?
-The oracle of death.
Let me go now.
I’ll be back.
-Why the oracle of death?
-The Little People are spirits.
They're not of this world.
Have faith in me, Hercules, and wait for me.
Take this magic potion
in your hands...
and transmit
your thought to me.
I shall hear it.
Sweet oracle of death,
help me to reach the Little People.
Drink the potion.
We are sorry we couldn't come to you,
dear Urania.
But the earth is a difficult place,
even for spirits.
It's much safer here
in the astral world...
next to the stars,
moons, and planets.
They say
there is chaos here, too.
Where shall we ever take
our poor spirits?
We know that
you have come here, Urania...
to find out where the goddess Hera
and her rebellious sisters...
have hidden the rest
of Zeus' thunderbolts.
Not even the gods have secrets from us.
We could tell you where they are,
but your search will be extremely difficult.
You've been chosen
to help Hercules retrieve the thunderbolts...
but you weren't told
of the risks that are involved.
Zeus knows that for universal peace,
you are ready to sacrifice all.
Yes. lt will mean your life.
There's something strange
about this old temple.
Urania and I
have been here before.
-And she'd come to consult the oracle?
-Yes.
She inherited her powers
from her mother.
Her adopted mother.
A priestess of Corinth.
-And her father?
-We don't know.
But when her mother died,
she was taken in by my parents in Phagesta.
-And they've since died?
-We have had a hard life.
And that is why Urania
and I are so close.
My family and ancestors
had lived in Phagesta since time forgotten.
But after Antius descended upon us,
all changed.
Now we only live
to defend ourselves. We're....
-What was that?
-What did you hear?
Something that came
from that direction.
Are you certain, Glaucia?
Well, I thought I did.
I already told you
I had my misgivings.
-Who are these people?
-Women warriors. The Amazons of Scythia.
Be careful of the queen, Hercules.
She is the most evil of all.
The net.
Lower the net on him!
-What will we do with her?
-We'll come back for her later.
Yes, Captain.
Rise, Your Majesty.
Rise up from the fires,
my queen.
Rise, and let your burning flesh
melt together...
with the body of your victim.
You've a choice prize in your net,
O Queen of Spiders.
Hercules.
Hercules awaits you, my queen.
Go. Leave me.
Urania!
Glaucia, what happened?
You've bruised your head.
We've been attacked.
And they took Hercules.
And they left me there,
thinking that I was dead.
Who did it?
-While fighting the Amazons.
-The Spider Queen.
Yes. He is at her mercy,
caught in her magnetic web.
She's a monster
who has assumed the likeness of a human.
There's little we can do, Urania.
I call to thee,
powers of light...
transfer unto Hercules
thy energy to win.
Her love is evil.
He must kill her, or he will die.
The fifth thunderbolt.
I deliver it to you, Zeus.
The goddess Hera
was the instrument of my return to earth...
but not the cause.
Fate needed me here.
Now Dedalos, this is surely...
an important moment
for science.
For me, the goal of science
is to release chaos and disorder.
Dedalos...
make me the ally of trickery,
and of chaos.
lt will serve you well.
I bestow cunning,
connivance, and chaos.
We four gods are doomed, Hera.
lt was a grave mistake
to rebel against Zeus.
Poseidon is right.
Hercules has discovered
the fifth thunderbolt...
and soon Zeus
will shatter Minos.
No. Hercules cannot compete with Minos.
His science is invincible.
And once Hercules is defeated,
we shall rid ourselves of Minos.
Invincible?
Not from the looks of things.
Flora was instantly felled
by the sword of ice.
You carry on so,
and yet would consider yourselves gods.
You're like ordinary mortals.
Without dignity.
Yes, without dignity.
Science and chaos have given me
the power to eliminate you all.
Flee, Aphrodite. Hera!
Beware, Minos.
Beware of what?
Of your quivering frame?
A goddess in my power.
You did not conquer us.
I admit we were all divided by jealousy.
But Zeus will have his day.
Zeus is nil
without his thunderbolts.
And with Hercules' help,
they'll all soon be mine.
-He'll not agree to that.
-No, you're wrong, my dear Hera.
Hercules works for me,
though he's not aware of it.
But now you shall tell me
where the last thunderbolt is hidden.
-Never.
-I can wait.
Never is only
a question of time.
-Follow me.
-Where does this lead?
To the edge of the world.
But we needn't fear, Hercules.
Then these are the wastelands
of Hesperia...
the last bulwark
before ascending Mt. Olympus.
-Our destiny takes us up through there.
-Then lead on.
There are still two thunderbolts
for you to uncover, Hercules.
Be patient, my son.
I shall guide you to them.
Where are we now?
Quiet.
We're in the Temple of Echoes...
where the words of men
reflect those of the gods...
where everything reflects itself.
Look there.
The reflected light of a thunderbolt.
The foolish gods have repented.
Yes, the gods have been graced.
Now, Zeus,
it's time to crush the forces of chaos.
The time to fulfill our destinies.
Glaucia!
One move, and she dies.
The moment of truth is here.
I’m not who you think I am.
Glaucia is dead.
Yes, thanks to Glaucia,
I knew you revery move, Hercules.
Now that you've found
the sixth thunderbolt...
it's time we faced each other.
Minos, not again.
Yes, I’m back,
thanks to the gods.
Actually,
I’ve been back for a while.
From that time at that lonely beach
when you lost sight of Glaucia. Remember?
I had called upon Poseidon,
and he commanded that the waters...
drain the life
out of the real Glaucia.
It's not possible.
How can it be?
We created an exact replica
of the original.
Better than the original,
at least for us.
Her emotional and mental responses
appear to be the same.
But we scientifically altered
the course of her destiny.
She was not aware of it
until this very moment.
Hercules, there's no need
for us to fight.
With the aid of chaos, I have subdued
the gods who rebelled against Zeus.
Alone, without the full array
of his thunderbolts...
Zeus is no match for chaos.
The future belongs to chaos,
and to science.
Join us, Hercules. Come.
-Never.
-Very well.
Those foolish gods wanted him destroyed.
Instead, I shall use him.
Can you imagine a mankind
created in his image...
but scientifically programmed?
No error.
Glaucia, my dear...
we no longer need you.
Get rid of yourself.
Excellent.
I’m sure, Urania,
you know the way.
One must accept
inevitable defeat.
I can only accept it
as a challenge, Minos.
Very amusing.
You are viewing my sacred domain,
dear Dedalos.
I’m simply returning the favor.
No, you can do nothing, Zeus,
for though you are the light...
I am the darkness.
Thus, we are alike.
Except for one thing.
I possess time,
for I am the son of Cronos.
Father Time!
I have failed, Athena...
and allowed Minos to trick me.
It's yours, Hercules.
This shield will protect you from Minos,
and evil science.
But only
if you can save yourself.
The moon shall crush the earth
if Minos has his way.
He will sacrifice us all
so as to reign in the name of chaos.
Go onto Olympic skies.
I’ve the gods
in the palm of my hand.
My science has turned pure energy
into battling warriors.
But we have the greatest warrior
of all time, Minos.
Suddenly you're for Hercules.
We doubt he can change
the Earth's course.
Watch this.
There's one thing your magic shield
won't protect you from, Hercules.
Pure energy.
Cosmic light.
The sun's fire.
Take this, Hercules.
lt is of the same energy,
and you shall be infused with it.
You are the heart and the force
of the universe.
Minos challenged the universe
and the very secret of life.
His savagery
has been cancelled.
The maiden Urania is free
and the goddess Hera has repented.
Hercules did what no other man
could have done.
But danger
still lurks in the skies.
lt could all be resolved
by finding the last thunderbolt.
The oracles say
it was hidden up here on Olympus.
But that's not so.
How can the oracles lie?
lt is here.
Your secret
was revealed to me.
You, Hera, are my mother...
and you hid the last thunderbolt
within me.
ln my heart.
And I am
the final hiding place.
You're my mother, Hera.
Yes, it's true.
I created you from light
and I breathed life into you.
I had you formed
with beauty and goodness...
but only to conceal
what was hidden within you.
Yet, I grew fond of you
and often asked myself:
''Can she....
Would she ever feel love for me?''
And now....
And now, Mother, you must do
what fate demands of you.
I gave you life, my child.
I never thought
I would have to take it from you.
-You must.
-Please don't.
Mother, there's little time.
-But isn't there--
-Hurry.
How else can we save the world,
my child?
Mother, give me
the kiss of death.
Or love...
my beloved daughter.
Chaos has been defeated.
But if another threat arises...
the Earth is surely doomed.
Can mankind
withstand the dangers?
Only our fear can defeat us.
-Man always finds a way to conquer.
-Not without the gods.
But I am here, am I not?
How can a man stop the Earth
from colliding with the moon?
The way Atlantis did
at the beginning of time.
My new found powers
shall belong to him: Hercules.
Grow, Hercules.
Hercules, block the moon.
Stop the Earth.
Save mankind!
Now order is reestablished.
You sacrificed what was dearest to you
to save the universe.
And so, I forgive you.
And forgive those gods
who had lost faith and rebelled against me.
Let peace reign again and forever
on Olympus...
and on earth.
So be it for evermore.
To reward you for your sacrifice,
and Urania for hers...
I decree that she become
one of the Muses...
granting wisdom
from this time on to man...
and to the gods.
Urania, goddess and Muse
of space...
patron of astrology.
And you, too, Hercules...
greatest of men
and savior of the universe...
you, too, shall dwell
among the immortal gods.
And the example of your courage
will shine in the heavens...
till the end of time.