- I know you are god.
I can't believe I trusted you!
I work so hard.
And it all gets taken
away from me in an instant!
It's god!
I don't want to go on...
If I'm gonna be alone!
I don't wanna go on
if I can't trust anyone!
- Whoa! Well, come on in,
why don't ya?
- Hey, Mark.
Well, well, well,
Mr. Sherwood.
You know what they say about
a man dressed in a sharp suit,
don't ya?
- Yeah, I know what they say:
Don't spill anything on the suit
because it costs extra
to dry clean.
- No, silly, you look great.
- Ah.
- Michele is going to be
so excited when she sees you
waiting for her down the aisle.
- Thank you so much.
Hey, what do you got there?
- Not sure. But Michele said
that you need to open it
before the ceremony.
She also said that I'm not
allowed to stick around
and be nosy, something about,
"for your eyes only."
- Well, do you wanna stay
around and see what it is?
- Yeah, I do.
- Too bad, you heard my queen.
You need to get back
in there anyway,
because the maid of honor's
job is never done.
Hmm.
"I want him
to be a spiritual man,
"who would treat me really good.
"I've never had anyone
in a relationship treat me
gentle, loving and kind,
like a beautiful queen."
♪ here comes the bride ♪
♪ if only she knew
that this guy farts at night ♪
Nice, real nice.
Man, I'm loving we opted out
of the karaoke part
of this wedding.
- Cheers, man.
- Thanks, man.
- What do you got there,
big guy?
- Hmm, it's a gift
from Michele.
- A honey do list already?
This girl wasted no time.
- Oh, man, come on,
it's not like that at all.
This is the list
she told me about.
You know, I thought she was
just kidding,
but her and Jesse put this
together before we met.
It's got a list of these
qualities that she's looking for
in a partner.
- Oh.
And now she wishes
she had married me.
Better luck next time, guy.
- Come on, man, don't you wish.
- What is on this list,
seriously, that makes you think
you two are meant to be?
- Well, first,
we're both adopted.
And man, her parents
were so young.
- How in the hell could you
do this to me and your mother?!
We're not helping you
with this kid!
In fact,
you're just a kid yourself!
And that boy.
What in the hell kind of father
do you think he's gonna be?!
- I know he loves me.
And he'll do all he can
to take care of US.
- Loves you?!
- If he loved you, he wouldn't
put you in this position!
Sixteen years old and pregnant!
You're not keeping this baby!
And you sure as hell ain't
marrying some deadbeat
that doesn't even know
how to respect a woman
than to knock her up!
Especially when she's just
a kid herself!
- But daddy...
I can't...I can't get
an abortion.
- No, ma'am.
You're...you're not gonna get
an abortion.
You're gonna get away
from that boy,
as far as possible.
You're...you're gonna go live
with aunt Debbie
and you're gonna have
the baby there.
And then she's gonna help
figure out
how you can give this baby
a chance, with another family.
And I don't wanna hear
another word about it!
- ♪ When it all goes to hell,
will you still be my friend? ♪
- ♪ My face to the sea
and my back to the land ♪
- ♪ And if you can't
come with me... ♪
How would you like
to meet your baby girl?
- Oh.
- Oh, dear god, Terry.
Oh, she's beautiful.
God has blessed US
with a gorgeous baby girl.
Oh.
- God had a plan, alright.
First with Jo,
and now this adorable angel.
The heartache of being told
we couldn't have another child
just flew out the door
the moment I laid eyes
on this perfect angel.
- ♪ If you can't come with me,
I understand ♪
Ow!
- What a big baby.
- Hey, I'm losing a lot
of blood here, man.
These boutonniere pins are sharp.
Like samurai-sword sharp. Hmm.
- What a drama queen.
- Wow, how compassionate of you.
Hey, was that on Michele's
list too?
Yeah, actually, it was.
- I mean, family and helping
family has always been
really important to her.
She was just a teenager
when her family were faced
with one of their greatest
challenges.
- Hmm.
Ow! Ah!
- Michele, grab your sister
and get in the car,
your daddy's in the hospital.
It was some sort of accident
at work.
Hello,
Neil residence.
My god.
How many times have I told
you girls to get me
some more water?
Do I have to get it for myself?
- I can't today, Brenda, sorry.
Here, dad, let me help you.
I was just about to fill up
your water glass.
- I can do it myself, dang it.
I just need you and your sister
to keep my glass
filled with water,
is that so much to ask for?
- No, sir, it's not.
Oh, hey, come sit.
Is dad upset about
his water again?
- Yeah.
You'd think that water glass
was his life support system.
- Oh, he's just venting
his feelings
about everything
he's going through.
- Hmm.
- Um...Michele.
How would you feel...About US
moving from Minnesota?
- I...I don't understand.
I'm about to graduate.
And I have my music.
- I know, honey, but...
I've been offered a job
in Tulsa, Oklahoma,
at a brand-new hospital.
- What about my martial arts?
Mom, Brenda and I are about
to earn our blue belts together.
I'm sure they have
martial arts in Tulsa.
And...it's not just about
a bunch of oil Wells
and cowboys.
Besides, this job is
at the new, brand-new,
city of faith hospital.
I'll be making more money
than I've ever made,
and with it and the money
you and your sister make
from working part-time,
I'm sure we'll be able to get
this family back on track.
In no time.
- Mom. You know we'll all do
what you need US to do.
- Good! It's settled.
The Neils are moving
to Oklahoma.
- Where is everyone?
Church.
We're in the Bible belt now,
ladies.
Everyone goes to church
on Sundays.
- Unless there's a tornado.
Then everyone runs
for their hidey hole.
- Hidey hole?
No one said anything
about tornadoes.
- Oh, they're big. Huge.
Scary, too.
They'll rough right on the house
and take anyone in it.
- Don't worry, Joanne.
Mom says our place
has a storm shelter.
- It sure does,
and we're very close to a park
with a swimming pool.
- Michele,
do you have lunch money?
I saw a martial arts
place near my school
that I wanna check into
after school today.
- Oh, well,
I suppose that's fine,
but I need both of you
to look for part-time jobs.
Starting in a new city
costs money.
- Yeap, and we know dad's
not gonna find a job.
- No, not since the accident,
his disability
really limits him.
So it's our responsibility
to keep this family
housed and happy.
- Well, see, that martial
arts place is looking
for someone to sell memberships
and teach aerobics.
- Good thinking! Oh, my,
you'll be killing two birds
with one stone.
- Don't count on me
to kill any birds.
I'll just find a paper route
or something.
Okay.
- Yes.
- I have Raymond down for 7:00 pm.
Okay, great.
We'll see you both
when you're done.
Alright, bye.
Can I help you?
I'm interested in the job.
- So you think you'd like
to work here.
- I'd love to work here.
I'm a big believer in
maintaining a healthy lifestyle.
Careful what you wish for,
- Who do we have here?
- This...this is, uh,
she just walked in
off the street
looking for a job.
- I'm Michele.
I'd love to work here.
I took martial arts back home
and I'm a blue belt.
Well, I was about to get
my blue belt
and then my family moved here.
- Where are you from,
blue belt?
- I'm from Minnesota.
Brainerd, Minnesota.
- Brainerd, Minnesota?
Here in my dojo,
we train champions.
- Master is working with
the Olympic committee
to, uh, make taekwondo
an official sport.
- Blue belt, do you think
you have what
it takes to be a champion?
- Yes. I can do this.
I know I can.
- Well, this is Mel.
Not only is she one
of my most loyal
and trusted employees.
She's also a three-time
middleweight state champion.
Ranked tenth in the nation.
And...a student I take
great pleasure coaching.
This is more than a job,
This is a way of life.
- We can start you off
with selling memberships.
You have any other skills?
- Uh, I...I can teach aerobics
and other exercise training.
Good, come tomorrow
at 6:00am for training.
You get a discount
for working here.
And after school,
Mel will set you up
with training for sales
and other classes you
can help US with.
Hiyah! Kick.
Hiyah!
- Kick.
- Hiyah!
- Good to see you finally
made it, blue belt.
But you said 6:00am.
- Time is but a measure of one's
willingness to win.
A warrior does not know time,
but only being prepared
for battle.
What about you, blue belt?
Do you have what it takes
to be a champion?
- Yes, master, I do.
- What did you say, blue belt?
- Yes, I do.
Indestructible!
Alright,
let's get on with our day.
And be warriors.
Combo, get!
Hiyah!
- Kick.
- Hiyah!
- Not bad, blue belt.
You coming back this
afternoon for work?
- Yes, master,
I wouldn't miss it.
- Good to hear.
I see big things coming
your way, blue belt.
Now get to school.
Knowledge is nourishment
for the mind,
which runs the body
and the soul.
Everybody's dismissed.
Mel!
Meet me in my office.
- Yes, master.
Won't be long now.
Buddy, if you're thinking
about calling this thing off,
you'd better do it soon.
- Come on, man,
that would never happen.
I have never felt so connected
in my entire life,
I'm so much happier
because of it.
- That's good, but you know,
Michele looks like she's
a sweet, tiny package, but I bet
she packs a punch, yeah?
- Well, she was a national
taekwondo champion.
- What?! Oh,
that explains a lot.
- Wait a minute, what do you
mean, it explains a lot?
- Well, you know whenever
we play a game? She has to win.
- Well, first, you're not any
good at any of the games
we play, and secondly,
she did earn her black belt
in less than a year, so yeah,
of course, that competitor
spirit does run deep
in her soul.
- Fight!
- Yes, good.
- Very good.
- Good.
Very well done.
Now, that is the spirit
of a champion.
Okay, that's it for today.
Everybody get your rest
and I'll see you tomorrow.
Michele, meet me in my office.
Well, you've come a long way,
blue belt.
- I'm not a blue belt,
I'm a black belt now.
- Yes.
Yes, you are.
I'm sure you heard that
the summer Olympic games
in Seoul, South Korea,
will be featuring taekwondo
as a demonstration sport.
And our dojo,
under my direction,
will be the national
training grounds
for the chosen ones
representing our country.
- This is your opportunity
to show 'em what you're made of.
And to prove that our dojo
creates world-class champions.
- I really wanna make
the team, master.
- I believe you have
what it takes
to be a part of this team,
but you're gonna have to work
way harder.
- Oh, I will, master.
- You have to become stronger.
- I know I can, master.
- And you have to do everything
I ask of you,
no questions asked.
- This has always been
my dream.
I will do everything
I need to do
to make this team, master.
- It will take everything
you've got.
- Making this team
would mean everything.
- It is the only thing.
This team means so much
to the dojo, to the sport,
and to every American team
that follows.
- Where do we start?
What do I need to do, master?
- First, we need to get you
in more competitions.
We'll have you compete
in local tournaments,
regional, nationals...
- and finally,
the Olympic team selection
tournament.
- Yes. Yes.
Oh.
I got this...Knot
in the middle of my back.
Goes all the way up
through my neck.
So I hear you've been doing
some masseuse work.
Yes.
- Would you mind working this
out a little bit for me?
Yes. Yes, that's it.
That's the spot.
They taught you well
at your massage parlor
second job.
- Yes, master,
it's for my family.
My mother is the soul
provider.
I have a little sister
who's still in school and I...
I do whatever I can to help
mom make ends meet at home.
- That's very admirable
of you, Michele.
But working two jobs...
That can distract you
from your training.
- Oh, no, master.
I will make certain that I
will complete every training
you expect of me and more.
I'll come in early, work later,
whatever I have to do.
I know I can do this.
This is the most important
thing to me.
That's what I wanted to hear,
Do you know that building
where you do massages at
used to be a place where men
would have special favors
performed for them by women
of the evening?
Does that make you feel odd
at all?
Knowing that you work in a place
where women was taken
advantage of by men?
No, no.
I didn't mean to make you
feel uncomfortable.
You didn't have to stop.
Hmm.
Well, we need to stop
for now anyway.
You need to go teach your class.
We'll talk about this later.
The Olympics, that is.
- Knock-knock!
Mark, it's almost time!
Those are supposed to be for
the guests after the wedding.
- There's plenty more.
Mark, the guests are starting
to arrive
and Michele is almost ready
and soon you'll be married
to the love of your life.
- Thank you, you did such
an amazing job,
and I cannot wait to make
Michele my partner for life.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah,
what's next on this list?
- I wanna know more about
who Michele was praying for.
- Well, it says here that
she wants to have someone
who can understand her,
to know what she's thinking
even before she does.
And even to the point where
she needs some help
and is maybe afraid to ask.
- It doesn't make much sense.
She doesn't know what she wants,
and she's afraid to ask for it.
- Well, yeah, think about
the time when her mom
lost her job in Tulsa
and the family had to move
all back to Minnesota so her
mom could find another job.
- Whoa, they moved away
while she was training
for the Olympic team?
- Yeah, so they moved,
but Michele stayed behind,
and she continued to work
and pay bills
and help her mom and support
her dad and her sister.
Hold on a second,
so she's training
for the Olympic team,
her parents are gone,
she's sending them money while
working part-time at two jobs.
- Well, that's the thing, you
know, making the Olympic team
was so important to her,
that literally for over a year,
she was homeless while training.
She was living in the car,
barely making ends meet.
I tell you what, her will to win
made her so strong,
that after those times
she became so brave
that whatever came her way,
she could handle.
Michele,
you must get the victory.
You must win this fight.
Victory, Michele.
We worked very hard
for this,
represent our dojo,
get the victory,
you're a warrior, be a warrior.
You must win.
Win this, Michele.
Win it for the dojo.
♪ when I get there,
I'll let my feet row ♪
I'll break in your arms ♪
♪ I'll lose control ♪
♪ and then I'm ready ♪
♪ I know the answer ♪
♪ like I know, like I know,
when I get closer ♪
- Fight!
- ♪ Tonight you're my
sailing ship ♪
♪ got a feeling,
when you head for your trip ♪
♪ right out of this... ♪
- Yes!
- Quick, get the point!
- ♪ Straight towards
the warm sun and into his hand ♪
- Fight!
♪ I'll let my feet row ♪
♪ and when I get there ♪
♪ I'll break in your arms,
I'll lose control ♪
Get up!
Be a warrior!
Get up, fight!
Fight!
- ♪ Let me know, let me know ♪
- Good, fight, yes! Yes!
- ♪ When I get closer ♪
♪ let me know
when I get closer ♪
Yes, good kick,!
- ♪ Let me know
when I get closer ♪
♪ open that scar for me ♪
♪ when you say I'll dig
much deeper, I'll try ♪
- Now!
- ♪ when I get there ♪
- ♪ Will I get closer ♪
♪ will I get closer ♪
- You guys don't deserve
you be champions.
- We're getting stronger,
master!
You have to work
much harder!
Yes, master!
- You must commit
to working hard.
Yes, master!
- Harder than ever before!
- You must commit
to be working hard!
Indestructible, master!
- Harder than ever before!
- That's the way to work
like a champion.
- Not so much anymore.
- You don't have
to put up with that, you know.
- Really? Why do you?
- I do because...
Because I have nothing else.
You're a real champion.
You're very bit
as good as I am.
I'm good, but I'm not
as good as you are.
- Come on!
You're great out there.
You win all your tournaments.
You destroy every competitor.
- I can't turn my anger
into power.
- Well, we all have
to vent somewhere.
I just prefer to do it
in the ring.
- See? That's what I'm saying.
You have control.
You can make it
on another team.
- Another team?
I wouldn't even know
where to start.
I mean, I have...I have
to stay here to be successful.
- That's what I'm saying.
No, you don't, Michele.
There are other masters
who can help you make it
to the Olympics.
Well, there's nothing
that brings me more pleasure
than to see my two best
champions getting along.
- Of course, master.
You two ladies
bring me great joy
as your trainer.
I see you two doing
many things.
But it's not going to happen
just sitting here.
Get going!
- So did she make
the Olympics?
Is the medal part of her
wedding gown? Something old?
- Well, she did receive
her black belt
in less than a year.
Nobody worked harder
than Michele
to be part of the team.
I mean, she went to 15
competitions, state, regional,
and then eventually she was
ranked eighth nationally.
- And I found out online
that taekwondo used to be
a demonstration sport
in 1988.
- That's right.
Seoul, South Korea.
Summer Olympics.
- Can you imagine,
walking into the Olympic
stadium,
where all the eyes,
your friends, the world,
are on you?
Hm.
- Next part of the story
is my favorite part.
I wonder why.
But really, she worked so hard
to earn her spot on that team.
- Yeah, not only do you have
to be a great athlete,
but.
Even when you're at your best,
the world can come
upside down on you
- "Dear mom.
"All is going well
here in Tulsa.
"I just won another
competition,
"which makes me now ranked
eighth in the entire country.
"Not bad for a little girl
from brainerd, Minnesota.
"Master says that I have
a real shot
"of becoming a part
of the Olympic team,
"but what he doesn't know
is that I'm gonna make
"this Olympic team no matter
what I have to do.
"Then I'm gonna show him who
and what a real champion
"is made of.
"How's dad?
"I hope he's doing well
"and Joanne's making sure she
keeps his water glass filled.
"I think of you guys often.
"I just wanna make you
proud of me.
"I'm making a little extra
money and doing both jobs
"is working out just fine.
"My roommates...Are great.
I hardly even notice
that they're around."
- Yeah, I've got one.
Oh!
Hey, massage girl!
- Yeah, massage girl,
we're your next appointment.
Hey, massage girl!
- Is it too late
to make an appointment?
- Or are you egg-specting
someone else?
- The doors, check the doors.
- Get her out of this car!
Come on,
come out and play!
Come on, massage girl!
- Get out of the car!
- Man 3:
- Come on, get out!
Come on, massage girl,
get out of the car!
Unlock the door!
- You just ruined what could've
been such a great time for ya.
Are you kidding me?!
That's the best time
I've had all month.
Alright, everybody freeze.
You ever seen these guys before?
I've seen that one
around,
but they've never tried
to bother me before.
- What are you doing here
so late at night anyway?
- Uh, it's...It's a temporary
situation.
Just for a couple of nights,
it's not a big deal, really.
- Only temporary.
You know it's not safe.
These aren't the only
three guys
that are crazy in Tulsa.
- I know.
- I just work right there.
And I'm always
really careful.
It...it...it's temporary.
I'm just in-between
roommates right now.
- Only temporary?
- I have a girlfriend that
I'm gonna be moving in with here
really soon and then
everything will be alright.
- You have any other means
to protect yourself?
Pretty big gun
for such a little lady.
I guess you know how
to handle yourself.
- Yes, sir, I do.
- Look, I'm gonna let you off
with a warning,
'cause I know the owner
of the shopping center.
He doesn't like people
sleeping in or out of their cars
on his property.
- I...I...I didn't know.
There's plenty
of places to sleep.
If you need help with something,
a friend, someone to talk to,
you just give me a call.
But after tonight,
I don't wanna see you
sleeping here anymore.
- Thank you.
So, the Michael J. Fox film.
- Yeah, at the drive-in.
- Yeah, I think so too.
That would be pretty cool.
- Yeah, that would be
pretty cool.
- Hello, master Cho's?
- You wanna speak with Michele?
Alright,
give me just a moment.
Michele!
Come on.
- Hello, this is Michele.
Michele,
this is your mom.
I've been worried about you,
how you doing?
- Mom, hi. Yeah, sorry,
I'm fine.
Everything's good here.
Working out and training.
We just competed for regionals
and it won't be long
before we compete
for the nationals.
And then the Olympics.
- Oh, that's great news, honey.
I was just worried because
your letters all come
with a return address
from the dojo.
- Don't you have a place to live?
- Of course!
I have a roommate
and everything.
I'm just here at the dojo
training so much,
I just thought I'd have
my mail sent here.
Oh, well,
I guess that makes sense.
Thank you for continuing
to send money,
that really helps US out a lot.
Dad's better,
and Joanne's enjoying school
and rekindling relationships
with old girlfriends.
- That's so good to hear, mom.
- She asks about you
almost every day.
Joanne really misses you, honey.
- Oh, gosh, mom,
I miss you guys so much.
Are we gonna get
started or what?
- Tell Joanne hi from me, mom.
I gotta go.
Master's about to start
our workout.
So, I love you guys,
and I'll talk to you later?
- Love you, sweetheart.
- Okay, bye.
- Today is the beginning
of the end.
- Now, all of you
will be champions.
- So today.
I will push you.
To the end.
I don't want any babies here!
Are you a baby?!
Or a champion?!
Champions, master!
- Beaten by a girl?!
You're gonna let a little girl
beat you?!
You think the Olympics
is gonna let you fight a girl?!
- Is this what you wanted
to show me?!
You lying here
crying like a baby?
Be a man! Get up!
You're interrupting my work.
How many more babies
will cry tonight?
- Why am I seeing this?
You should be so much
better by now!
- Indestructible, master!
You all look
like glass flowers!
So easy to break!
- Are you breakable?!
- No, master!
- Then show me!
- Indestructible, master!
- I know you all hate me.
I know you all feel like
I am pushing you too hard.
You must be at your best
for this next tournament.
For some of you,
there will be no tomorrow.
You must show your strength.
You must be ready.
You must show your power.
Or you will not be.
I'm tired of looking at you.
Get out of here!
Neil, after you shower,
meet me in my office.
- ♪ One day I won't
lie awake ♪
♪ one day I won't
see your face ♪
♪ one day I won't hear
your name ♪
♪ like a ghost
inside my veins ♪
♪ one day I won't
ache this much ♪
♪ one day when
I've cried enough ♪
♪ I'll find myself
and get back up ♪
- ♪ ...every night I feel it ♪
♪ running through my mind,
I breathe in ♪
♪ every single word ♪
♪ a memory... ♪
- Hey. Neil, right?
- Yes.
- Hey, kiddo.
What's, uh,
what's going on?
Did you find that...you find
that place to...Stay?
Really need to work on that.
I'm guessing that's not why
you're...
You're at the police station.
Did somebody try
to hurt you again?
Yes.
But I don't think anyone
will ever believe me.
- Look, it's...it's hard
to be alone.
But you gotta find
somebody to talk to.
But you have to open up
to somebody. Let me help you.
- You can't!
Nobody can help me.
- That's not true.
My wife...She's a nurse,
you could talk to her.
How about if you let me
arrange for you two to meet?
You could talk to her,
maybe it'll be easier
for you to talk to her.
- Nobody can help me.
Nobody actually wants
to help anyone.
All they wanna do is to take
and to hurt.
- No, that's...no,
that's not true, no.
Look. You have my card.
My wife's name is Julie.
I'm confident she can help you
find someone who can.
Let's go inside
and set something up.
Come on.
- Hmm.
- Oh, this is my favorite.
"Compassionate listener."
- What?
- Compassionate listener.
- What? What...what does she
mean by that?
- Well, you know,
compassionate listener,
so, someone that's gonna really
listen to her.
Not that they have to have
these great words of wisdom,
or a plan to save the day,
but you know that together,
they can handle anything
that comes their way.
- Yeah, I so wish I had
a partner like that.
- Compassionate listening.
- Yeah, right, you know,
like, hers, mine, ours,
anybody's?
That's what makes her
a wonderful physician.
- Compassionate listening.
- Right.
Not just what someone's been
feeling, but what's in the soul.
'Cause that's truly what
drives the heart and body.
- She takes this into
consideration
with each and every patient?
- Yeah, man. It's not just
about winning or losing
and how you play the game,
but it's how you touch
the heart and soul of a person.
And that's how Michele
treats all of her patients.
And that is what made her
a mayor player
in the taekwondo community.
- Hmm, that looks
really good right there.
I am so proud of you.
This is amazing.
When you first walked in,
I thought you'd never be
anything more than a blue belt.
And a girl just picking up
everybody's towels.
But now, now you're on the edge
of becoming one
of my greatest champions.
After training,
we should go celebrate,
just you and I.
- I can't. Uh, I have to work
at the massage parlor tonight.
We have several clients
coming in late.
Well, I'm sure
you can squeeze some time
- in it for me.
- Uh, no, no.
Sorry, uh, I just can't. Sorry.
- Can't...or won't?
- Won't.
- Won't?
Won't?! Won't?!
We'll see about that.
You win a few titles,
you think you're too good
for master now?
We'll see who needs who.
Follow your match,
as you push the boundaries!
- ♪ Tonight I'm feeling mean,
I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ tonight I'm feeling mean,
♪ tonight I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ I am feeling mean,
I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ tonight I'm gonna pick
myself a fight ♪
♪ and if he swings at me... ♪
- Just as I thought,
we have an inflated champion,
not worthy of her reward.
- ♪ I am feeling mean,
I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ I'm feeling mean! ♪
You're still too weak
to beat?!
- ♪ Anyone's ever seen ♪
- You!
- ♪ Be on the eye
of the hurricane ♪
♪ but there's a heavy
price to pay ♪
♪ I, I'm feeling mean,
I'm feeling mean ♪
- What? Are you afraid
to lose against a girl again?
Do you wanna be part
of this team?
Quit toying with her,
be a man already!
Take her out or get out
of my dojo!
- ♪ I'll keep on 'til the dawn ♪
♪ I'm feeling mean ♪
- Coward! Get out of my dojo!
- Sorry excuse for a loser.
- ♪ Than anyone's ever seen ♪
♪ get out, I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ there's a heavy crash today,
'cause tonight ♪
♪ I'm feeling mean,
I'm feeling mean ♪
- You, perhaps you can teach
this young, arrogant champion
a lesson.
A lesson that will once again
have her respect
what her master has to offer.
♪ I'm feeling mean ♪
- Yes, that's it!
- ♪ I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ Than anyone's ever seen ♪
- Teach her the lesson
that she deserves.
- ♪ Tonight I'm feeling mean,
I'm feeling... ♪
- Stop!
This is her fight!
Get up,.
You're too good for this dojo.
You won't take home the gold
laying on this mat.
Get up and face
your destiny.
- ♪ I'm feeling mean ♪
- You're too good
for your master.
- ♪ I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ beat it out of me ♪
- I say who represents
this dojo.
I say who is champion.
You do as I say,
when I say, the way I say,
or get out of my dojo.
- ♪ I'm feeling mean ♪
♪ I'm feeling mean! ♪
- I used to hope you had
so much more to offer.
You disappoint me,.
Get out of my sight!
Ah!
What? My foot fell asleep.
- Really?
So Mark, Michele never
made it to the Olympics?
- No, she tore her acl,
mcl, and pcl.
And get this.
She couldn't afford a doctor,
so she worked out
the damage on her own.
Using duct tape.
- And learning what she could
on her own with rehab.
Man,
after all that sacrifice, too,
all the training,
living out of her car,
being alone...The abuse,
the unwanted advances
she took from that master.
No, she never competed
again after the injury.
Instead, she turned all of her
attention to massage therapy.
All alone,
seeking a new direction.
- And why didn't she move
back to Minnesota then?
It would've had to have been
easier than living
out of her car at that point.
- Well, yeah, and eventually,
she did get herself
an apartment,
but that was only after
her massage clientele
became more regular.
- And that's when she became
a master of massage therapy.
- She was.
She spent every moment reading
everything she could
about anatomy.
And that champion mentality
kicked in again,
and she read every book
she could get her hands on.
- Hi.
- Hey.
So how you been?
Really...pretty good.
Oh. Oh, my gosh,
you always know
right where to start.
- The more I learn about
how the body works,
the easier it is to zero in
on how best to help my clients.
- Hmm.
Mm.
You know, Michele,
it's been a little over a year
since you let Brian
introduce US,
and we finally started
getting to know each other.
Yeah, it's been great
knowing that I have friends
like the two of you.
And that there are even
people in the world like you
who care so much about others.
- And I see you so many times
take so much joy
in studying those
anatomy books.
- Well, you know my mom
is a nurse,
and I guess it was just me
watching her study all the time,
and...seeing my dad become
more disabled every year,
I mean, that all made me wanna
learn more about health.
- I see that.
But there's
also this determination.
- Well, I just, I don't wanna
be like them. Sick.
I mean, the more I understand
how the body works,
the more I...Feel like
I understand what it takes
to be healthy.
And the more I wish I could
find a way to help
others live better too.
Okay.
What I'm getting at, Michele,
is...
I mean, you're a great masseuse,
I've never experienced anyone
better.
And don't get me wrong,
I'm sure it's a great way
to make a living.
- Soon, I'll have enough
clients
to invest in a newer car.
- I'm really happy
for you, Michele,
but Brian and I have been
talking for a while,
and we believe you need a break.
- Well, to tell you
the truth, Julie,
I am so blessed to have
this job,
and to have you two
as friends and clients.
Plus, my list of clients
almost grows every week.
- Ah, I'm sure it does,
but you work so hard,
and with everything
you went through
training for the Olympics...
- Yeah, I definitely learned
a lot then,
about hard work and...
Especially about people.
Who to trust and who not to.
I learned what it was like
to want something so bad
and to be so close.
- Yeah, you've definitely
had a lot of obstacles
to overcome.
- And people who made it
seem like my goals
were so far out of reach.
- Okay, look.
You trust Brian and I,
don't you?
- Yes.
- And you know
we both want you to succeed.
- Yeah?
- So let US do something
for you, Michele.
I mean, we both think
it's yet to be seen
what your greatest
victory involves.
- I don't think I understand
what you're getting at.
- There's always been something
greater for you out there.
There always was,
there always will be,
but you have to set your mind
to it and make it happen.
Michele, do you understand?
- I don't. Taekwondo
is all I knew.
I mean, even if I had made it
to the Olympics,
I have no idea what
I would've done after.
- Okay, maybe it's time to start
giving some serious thought
to that, maybe it's time
to make a decision,
take a chance, and Brian and I
will take it with you.
- I still don't know
what you mean.
I can't compete anymore,
my leg.
And I just can't do anything
like that ever again.
- No, Michele.
But there are other things
you could be great at,
maybe even the best at.
But you have to decide
what that's gonna be.
Look, here's what we
have decided:
If you can decide what it is
you wanna be,
we wanna pay for your first
semester of college.
'Cause we wanna get you started,
'cause we know once you're
on your way,
there's no stopping you.
- Okay?
- Hello?
- Mom?
- Michele, my word!
How are you?
- I'm good, how are you guys?
- Your dad's the same,
and Joanne's busy
with who knows what-all
and who with.
And, uh, I’m...I'm good.
- That's nice, mom.
Can I ask you a question?
- Of course, honey,
what's on your mind?
- Why did you decide
to become a nurse?
- Ooh, lots of reasons,
I suppose.
Uh...geez, I...that was
a long time ago.
- Well, do you remember any,
or even just one of the reasons?
- Well, as a family, I...I knew
we needed the money,
even before your dad's
accident.
- So...was money
the only reason?
- Well, never really told
anybody this, but,
when your grandmother
was sick and in the hospital,
I noticed...Well, I noticed
the nurses were so attentive
with all the patients.
Her doctors were good,
but they all seemed so busy,
had very little time
to spend with US.
Or on the floor either,
for that matter.
But the nurses, well,
they made US feel like family.
They seemed to care as much
for the family
as they did about grandma.
And their compassion...Really
struck me,
and it made me realize
that I wanna do something
to help people.
In...in a very special way.
- I had no idea.
Why are you
so full of questions.
- I just...I think it's time to
start thinking about a future.
I mean, all I've thought about
the past few years
is taekwondo and...There hasn't
really been much room
for anything else, but now...
Now I think it's time to start
making room for a future.
- Well, first you need
to figure out
what you enjoy doing,
because you might be doing it
for a very long time.
And then...Let your heart,
your passion,
do the heavy lifting.
- Michele?
- I know what I wanna be!
- That's great, what is it?
- I'm gonna become a doctor.
- Well, let's go inside and you
can tell me all about it.
Come on, don't you
think this story
is getting a little
hard to believe?
I mean, she's...she's working
on being
a homeless Olympic champion,
and now she has somebody
footing the bill for college
so she can become a doctor?
- She became a doctor, dude.
- And a woman can be
anything she wants to be...
- that's right, yes.
- ...When she puts her mind
to it.
- Yes, but what I'm saying is,
maybe Mark is telling the story
with a little bit of bias
because he's so in love.
- I can vouch for Mark.
- Me too.
Or should we say,
we can vouch for Michele.
- Oh, yeah, Mark hasn't
told you this part, Jim,
but you're gonna find this
even harder to believe.
- Yeah, remember we set her up
with her first semester
of college, and then she didn't
need another dime.
- No. She did so well in school
that every semester,
she won scholarship
after scholarship
and put herself through
medical school.
- She sure did,
it was that champion mentality.
That will to survive,
and of course,
the encouragement of a few
great friends
that got her all
the way through.
- Oh, and let's not forget,
she went into medicine
to help people.
- And then she became a doctor,
and she met Mark,
and we all lived happily
ever after.
- Well, she...she did become
a doctor, but happy?
Well, that was still
a heartache away.
- Alright, Dr. Neil,
come on in,
I'd like you to meet
Dr. Connors.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you.
- I was telling Dr. Connors
you come to US as, uh,
sort of a first-round draft pick
so to speak.
With your, uh, impressive
scholastic resume
and your eagerness to put
your education into practice.
- Well, I really appreciate
that, but I'm just so excited
to learn from each one
of you at the clinic as well.
- Good to know.
And, uh, to get you off
to a good start,
I'm gonna have you spend
some time with Dr. Connors
for a few days,
to get acclimated
to how our practice
works around here.
- Absolutely,
look forward to it.
- Daniels.
- You can call me Kim.
- Alright.
- It's nice to finally have
another female doctor
around this place full of
antediluvian-thinking
- testosterone.
- Both:
- Usually, the first few days,
a new doctor will shadow
a couple of US,
just to see how the clinic works
and how we work with patients,
and how best to keep up
with the pace.
- Alright? Bye.
Well, you doctors have
plenty of time
to get acquainted.
Let's get out there and help
a lot of people feel better.
- Thank you.
"Get used to the pace"?
- Yeah, girl, there are a lot
of people around this place
who need our attention.
Bandaged up and set up
with the right medications
to help keep them going
each and every day.
- So how many patients
do we see in a day?
- Uh, you'll probably start
by seeing about ten.
- Really? Ten patients a day?
- Yes, but six months from now,
you'll be clocking in around 20.
- If you say so.
- You know, make sure you have
plenty of pens and script pads,
'cause you're gonna need 'em.
And the first couple of days,
you're gonna be with me,
then I'm gonna hand you over
to one of these
- Okay.
- By the way, if I were you,
I'd make sure I get myself
a comfortable pair of shoes,
that's the only way you're gonna
be able to keep up. Alright?
Mrs. Sanders, how are you doing
this morning?
- Well, I tell you, Dr. Connors,
my indigestion is back.
And my back, I can't seem
to get a good night's rest
from all the aching.
And of course, that just keeps
me so tired all the time.
- Hmm, I see.
- Do you think I should see
a chiropractor for my back
pain?
- Uh, hm, I don't think
that'll be necessary.
Did you use all the prescription
that I gave you last month?
- I did. But it just didn't...
- that should've helped you
soothe your issues.
- Well, I was certainly
hoping it would.
- I tell you what, let's try
something a little different.
This will help you
with your indigestion,
and I'll give you a little
something to help you sleep.
- What are you eating over
there?
- Oh this?
- Mm-hmm.
- Just a little hard candy.
I suck on them
throughout the day,
it seems to give me some relief.
- How many would you say
you have in a day?
- Hmm, never really
thought about it,
just eat one anytime the urge
strikes me.
- Okay, I'll have the ladies
at the front desk
call this in for you,
and...Make sure you take
each and every one of them.
That's gonna help US determine
specs on your issues.
- Well, I guess you know best.
After all, you're the doctor.
- Okay, now, if we were
to stay in there another second
with that woman, she would have
talked to you
to the end of most of the day
about everything that goes on
with her all week long.
- Couldn't that help US learn
more about why she's sick
in the first place?
- Maybe, but I doubt it,
and besides,
we have 20 other patients
to see today,
and if we talk to all of them
the way you tried to talk
to Mrs. Sanders, we'd only see
about four or five a day,
and that's no way
to keep your job.
- I get that, but couldn't there
be something else going on
that's causing her
all these symptoms?
- Are you questioning
my diagnosis?
I'll Chuck this down
as inexperience.
Mrs. Sanders has been
a patient of mine
for the past five years,
and each of those five years,
she comes with...in with
the same problems.
Now, it would be my guess
that she's not taking
her medication properly,
and her family history
dictates her medical issues.
- She's been coming in here
regularly for five years
with the same problems?
- Yes, she has. Now look,
we're doctors,
we’re not babysitters.
And what they do
when they leave here
is of their own, free will,
our job is to provide treatment
and the medication needed
to help relieve and hopefully
ease or get rid of the symptoms
that they come in to begin with.
- I'm sorry, ah...I didn't need
to step in any toes,
I'm just interested to learn
and help people.
- No harm done.
But you need to realize
that this is a job too,
and if you carry the whole thing
on your shoulders...
- Yes, doctor.
- ...it's just gonna be
way too much.
- Okay.
Hello, Mr. Leonard,
what brings you in today?
- Oh, my dear, your advice
made such a difference.
I've seen so many doctors
but none of them
has helped me as much as you.
- Well, keep doing
what we talked about,
and keep me up to date
on all your progress.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
So how's your family doing?
- Doing wonderful.
- She is this way with all
of the patients she sees.
Dr. Michele has been here
for six months
and she should be seeing
at least 12 to 15 patients
a day, and she is lucky
if she even gets ten in.
- Hmm.
I guess I have to have
a talk with her.
- I think so.
- Dr. Neil. Walk with me?
- Yes, sir,
but I've got appointments.
- They'll wait,
let's take some time.
So, uh, how's it going for you?
You getting used to how
things go around here.
- I think so, yes.
I'm still trying to work up
to 20 patients a day.
But...I don't know how that's
really possible
and truly find out what's
wrong with each one of them.
- Well, experience will make
you quicker with your diagnosis,
but, uh, I think by now you
should start to see
that you don't have to listen
to everything
that each of them says.
- Well, take Jane, for example.
She came in a few months ago
showing some signs
of an onset of arthritis.
- Okay, so you prescribed
a corticosteroid, right?
- No, I talked to her a little
bit more about
her family history.
- Oh, good idea.
And I'm guessing you found
a history
of rheumatoid arthritis?
- There were some.
- So you considered
more advanced treatments,
maybe a test or two?
- No, I asked about her diet
and her exercise
routine, if any.
- See, that's why your patient
count is so low, you see,
now this, uh...Jane woman,
she gave you a symptom.
You treat that symptom.
Then if she comes back in
because that treatment
didn't work, we have a test,
and you find further treatments.
- But she's doing so much
better just by doing
little things different.
Michele, I run this
clinic,
and I have for a very long time.
So I suggest you fall
into line.
- Yes, but...
- no, no, no buts.
When you're here at the clinic,
you get your patients' symptoms,
you offer the proper treatment
and prescriptions
dictated by this clinic's
standards, and then you move on
to the next patients
as quickly and efficiently
as you can and that's it.
You hear what I'm saying?
- Yes, I do.
- You can make your huggy
feel-good friends
on your own time,
but when you're here,
you're on the clinic's time,
and all these patients'.
- I got it, sir, I hear you.
Crystal clear.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
- Hey!
- Hi!
- I thought they'd send
some other quack in here.
- So, I'm so sorry to hear
about Liz.
- Yeah, she was definitely
the spark
that kept my flame burning.
I miss her so much,
but I don't miss
that list of chores she had
me do each and every week.
So,
what brings you in today?
- Well, I'd say, I've got...
Where,
I'm tired all the time.
And I have a dickens of time
getting much sleep at all.
And then it's just,
I have pains all over.
- Hmm, I tell you what,
I'm gonna go ahead
and write you a prescription,
but...What are you doing
for dinner tonight?
- Well, my usual chicken
dishes and a few sides.
- You think you got enough
for two?
- I'm not promising
anything fancy,
but I'm pretty sure I could
whip up a little something
to feed the likes of you.
- Good, then, it's a date.
I'll be around at 6:30.
- That's up in Branson.
Liz loved Branson.
I can't tell you how many
times we'd go to those shows
year after year, but she still
loved them all just the same.
- She told me.
She was pretty sure
you had a crush
on that cute actress.
- She was no Liz,
but she could put on a show.
Hope you like your fried chicken
a little medium brown.
- Have you always fried
your foods?
Well, to be honest,
Liz did most of the cooking.
- Do you mind if I look
in your cupboard?
- Help yourself?
- Okay.
Okay, let's see
what we have here.
- Okay.
- Oh, wow.
- Now these make
a good go-to snack.
The rest of this stuff?
Mm-mm.
- Hmm.
- Let me ask you a question.
So if you had to choose,
eat differently
or spend the rest of your life
taking one pill or another,
what would you choose?
- I guess I'd choose
eat differently.
- Good, then there's no better
time than now to get started.
- Right...right now?
- Yes, right now!
Let's go to the grocery store
now!
- What...I just stocked up
on groceries yesterday.
- Don't worry, it'll be
my treat this time.
It's definitely
like that,
you know, it's just...
- That's right.
- If I eat right.
- Mm-hmm.
- Take those vitamins...
- Yes.
- Keep going after that.
- I have no idea
what's going on.
- She does have the daily
patient count up
to where it should be by now,
but...You know,
a lot of her former
massage clients are stopping by,
maybe that's what this is?
- Yeah, but...
I think there's something else
going on.
- I agree.
- I'll see what I can do
to find out.
- Okay, I appreciate that.
- Hi.
- Hi!
- Michele, how are you? Come in.
- Good!
- It's nice to get together and
not just bump into each other
between patients.
- Oh, yeah.
I know what you mean,
sometimes I feel like
I'm running laps
all over that place.
It can definitely
feel that way, for sure.
But you know, there are a lot
of people who are impressed
by the way you've been able
to get your patient count up
and start to fall along
with the program.
- Yeah? Well, when I was
a massage therapist,
I would spend anywhere
from 30 minutes
to an hour and a half
with each patient...thank you.
- I bet you're glad you don't
have to do that anymore.
I can't imagine spending that
much time with Mrs. Sanders.
After about ten minutes,
that woman would talk
my ear off,
and I would probably wanna find
a way to sedate her
in one way or another.
Yeah, you would think so,
but when I asked
all the right questions
of my massage clients,
they and their bodies
would tell me exactly
what they needed most
and how best to help them.
- So...you didn't give
just the same massage
to each one of your clients?
My masseuse just asks me how
many minutes do I want it for
and if I want a deep tissue
or a Swedish massage.
- That's the thing,
your masseuse should ask
what's going on in your life.
Have you changed
your exercise routine?
Or did you finish training
for a big run?
Or has life just got you
stressed out a bit?
And you're in for a good
massage.
- The stressing,
that's why I usually go in.
Definitely the stress.
- A lot of people do,
but what's causing the stress?
Is it work? Stuff at home?
Or whatever it is.
Knowing this has always helped
me find the pressure points
I need to focus on
with each of my clients.
- In theory, what you're saying
does make sense.
But in practice, I just don't
see how it's ever gonna work.
- But it is working.
For over a year now,
I have been consulting with
my patients more
than a typical visit,
many on my own time,
to help guide them
to becoming well.
- Does Dr. Daniels know
you're doing this?
- No. But the results
are amazing.
85% of those that I have
worked with show significant
signs of improvement,
faster and more significant
than traditional methods.
- And the other 15%?
- They flip-flop.
They fall off the wagon
when it comes to their diet
or exercise.
- You're a brave woman, Michele.
As I feel pretty strongly
that if Dr. Daniels knew
what you were doing,
he wouldn't like it,
not one little bit.
- But it was his idea!
- Sorry, but I find that
very hard to believe.
- He told me to practice
like all the other doctors
are expected to in the clinic.
But he didn't care how I spent
my own time.
- I don't think he's gonna
see it that way.
And besides, I am positive
that he didn't mean for you
to go to your patients' homes
and cook them dinner.
Oh. Darn. This is the hospital,
and, uh,
I'm gonna have to cut
our visit a little bit short.
Look, all I'm saying is,
if you enjoy being a doctor
so much, you better talk
to Dr. Daniels right away
and get this all straightened
out.
Right now, though, I gotta go.
- Oh, Michele,
see you in my office, please.
- Yes, sir.
- Uh, Michele, you've, uh,
been practicing here
at the clinic for a little
bit over a year?
- Yes, 17 months.
- And in that time you feel
you've gotten a pretty good
grasp on how we operate here
at the clinic?
- I think so, uh, yes.
- And it's true, you have, uh,
gotten your daily patient count
up,
but your return-visit patient
ratio is much lower
than the rest of the staff,
now one might think
that that's because your
patients weren't happy
with the treatment and
were going elsewhere
to seek medical attention.
- What?
No, that's not it at all.
- No? Well, what do you think
it is, Michele?
I mean, do you imagine yourself
to be ,
miraculously curing all
your patients to the point
they no longer need
medical treatment?
- No, but I've been spending
some of my own personal time
reaching out to my clients
in order to figure out
what's wrong with them
and what got them sick
in the first place.
- You...what?
- I've been learning a lot
more about my patients
outside of this clinic
than I have been able to learn
while they are here.
- Patients come to this clinic
for our expertise,
and our ability to quickly
diagnose their symptoms,
not to become our friends
and certainly not to become
part of your own clinic
project.
- But they are our clients
and we have a moral
and ethical code that dictates,
that demands
we find out what made our
patients sick to begin with.
- They also all work for
this clinic,
a professional environment
with processes and procedures
in place set by doctors
with far more experience
and clinical expertise
than you.
It's the same policies
and procedures you'll find
in clinics across America.
- But I could show you results.
The difference in results,
practices all over are using
a more functional medical
way of thinking.
- I don't wanna see that,
nor does this clinic have
any interest in your...
Voodoo medicine.
My god, what were you thinking?
- I...I just wanna help people
be and think healthier.
- It's a shame, really,
since you showed...
So much promise.
With an attitude like that,
you're not gonna find
any clinic to take you.
And I have no choice but
to relieve you of your contract.
You're done here.
What am I gonna do?
Maybe Dr. Daniels is right.
I'm not fit to practice
anywhere.
God, why won't you give me
an answer?!
How am I supposed
to believe in you,
if you can't seem
to believe in me?!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You don't want this anymore,
it'll look good on my place,
a little bit of white-out
and I can change the name.
No.
- Girl, what's going on?
- You're acting like
you lost your best friend,
but I know you didn't,
'cause I'm right here.
- I lost my job.
Dr. Daniels fired me and said
that I'm a voodoo doctor.
Girl, come on.
You hated that place.
I just can't seem
to get anything to go my way.
I failed at
the Olympics,
now I'm failing as a doctor.
What am I suppose to do?
- This piece of paper still
says you're a doctor, right?
- Technically, yes,
I still have the license
to practice medicine.
- Then do it.
There has to be a clinic
in the area
that will recognize the genius
of a doctor that is you.
- Not according to Dr. Daniels.
He said no one would take me,
and if I can't practice
at his clinic, what makes me
think I could practice
anywhere else?
- You're gonna believe all that?
Not today, sister.
Not on my watch.
You know what we need?
- No, what are you looking for?
- Something to write on.
- What on earth for?
I'm a little bummed out here.
- All the more reason why
we need to make...A list.
Alright, so.
If you could find the perfect
place to work as a doctor,
what would it be like?
- First, there wouldn't be
any Dr. Meanie-pants.
That's a given.
- I wanna work in a clinic
that puts patients first.
Even above making money.
- Okay, that's a good start.
- And we wouldn't just prescribe
medicine,
we'll prescribe...
Prescribe life.
- "Prescribe...life." explain.
- Yes, we would get to know
more about our patients,
things, of course, such as
medical past,
family history,
vitals and such, but also,
their life.
What they eat, how do they
sleep,
exercise, relax,
all of those things that
make a complete person.
We won't just have a regular
office visit,
we'll have get-together,
study groups,
bring families together,
make being healthy
fun as it is important.
A place like that just
doesn't exist.
- Wait a minute.
What was I thinking?!
- What? You know somebody
that has a clinic like this?
- I sure do!
- Is it somebody
you work out with?
- As a matter of fact, I do!
This list. This list
is your clinic!
- What do you mean
by my clinic?
- Just like it sounds!
You find a place, rent space,
and start your own clinic.
- I don't know the first thing
about having my own clinic.
- Sure you do.
It's all right here on the list.
Together, we'll pray on the list
and you'll see.
It makes perfect sense.
At the other place
with Dr. Doom and gloom,
many of your patients came
from when you were
being a masseuse, right?
- Yes, and?
- And when they find out
that you're not
at yesterday's news,
they're all gonna be out
looking for you,
unless you decide
to make it easy for them
and let them know
that you're at the all-new
Michele functional medical
and good times clinic.
- We may need to work more
on the name later.
- Well, now that we're
in a groove
and making all your dreams
come true,
shouldn't we start on the list
for that man, too?
- Oh, please,
one miracle at a time.
We have to pray on the list,
so that in all of god's glory,
each item on the list
will come to a fruitful
and gratifying beginning.
Let's pray.
God, I thank you for Michele's
heart, I thank you
for her desire to prescribe
life,
and not to just
give people pills,
I thank you that she really
wants to hear their heart...
- and cut to the wedding
and they all lived
happily ever after.
- How did you get invited
here anyway?
- I am the best man.
- Well, he was the only guy
who fit in the free suit
that was offered
- in the wedding package.
- All:
- That's right.
- So I'm guessing that's when
the functional medical institute
just took off like gangbusters.
- Yeah, and tell US the story
about how you guys met.
- The functional medical
institute
did start off pretty good,
but it started off so good
that it began to take
its toll on Michele
and all she could handle
on her own.
- And that's when you came in
as her knight in shining armor
to save the day.
- Michele's not one
to have anyone save the day,
but actually, it was you
who did the day-saving,
by putting another list
into play.
- Really? That's how you choose
to remind me?
Stuff all over the floor?
Just more for me to have to do?
More mess to pick up
all on my own?
I can't!
I can't do this
by myself alone!
Honestly.
Why can't I find love?
Am I not worthy of love
in my life?
I've endured sacrifice.
I've experienced pain.
I've done all I can do
for others.
Yet, my heart still feels
such an emptiness.
Lord, if alone is all
you have left for me,
then you might as well
just take me home now!
- I believe I saved your mango.
- How long have you been Stan...
slumped over my doorstep?
- Oh, long enough to know
that we probably
need to make a new list.
- Thank you.
Every time I turn a corner,
you're right there,
picking up one mess or another.
As they say,
that's what friends are for.
Besides, you'd do the same
for me.
Okay. So.
What's Michele's perfect
partner like?
- Well, it would be great
if he believed and worked
in functional medicine too,
so I can get some help.
The clinic's been growing
really quick.
- Alright. I got it.
Someone who's okay with you
bossing him around.
- No! Of course not.
But I would like a partner,
where our personalities
and our abilities complement
each other.
And alright, just at least,
in the beginning,
- I'll be his boss.
- Good.
What else is on the wish list?
- I want him to be
a spiritual man,
not just a churchgoer,
but someone who practices
what he preaches by respecting
and doing right by others
that come in contact with him.
- Yeah, that's a good one.
- Oh and it would be really
nice if he was
extremely good looking.
- Okay, yes, I got it down,
he's gotta be a real hunk.
- That's all nice,
but I'll trade any of that
for a guy who would treat me
really good.
I've never had anyone
in a relationship treat me
gentle, loving and kind.
Like a beautiful queen.
- I'm sorry.
You've always handled life
so well,
I never imagined that you'd
never experienced true love.
I always thought
you were single by choice.
- Nope, by fear.
Fear of being damaged
beyond recovery.
I finally reached this stage
in my life where I'm ready
to let go of all the bitterness
and resentment of my past.
- Now let's get to praying
for this man of yours.
All you have to do is believe
in god's guidance
and this, too,
will come true.
It works every time.
Dear god, we pray for every
item on this list,
we pray for a man that will be
gentle and loving and caring,
who will love functional
medicine and be a real hunk.
I ask that you would bring him
swiftly across her path...
I appreciate
all of you coming out
to the gut dysfunction
seminar.
Remember, we are all
in this wellness life together.
- If you need anything at all,
please don't hesitate to call.
Thank you.
Incredible.
And Michele is pretty
awesome.
- She is, absolutely.
She's awesome, seriously, wow.
Amazing.
- I can't thank you enough,
Michele, working with you
has made such a big
difference in the way I feel.
- Well, the proof is
in the results,
and the results are looking
better every week.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
- Bye.
- Hello, I'm Mark Sherwood.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Michele Neil.
I really enjoy
your presentations,
I was actually here
a couple of months ago
for your class on motion.
- Oh! Yeah.
I think I remember
seeing you there, then,
you were on the right,
- three rows back?
- Yeah.
- You had a girl with you.
A brunette, if my memory serves.
Your girlfriend?
- No, no, no.
Just an acquaintance.
- Oh, that's too bad.
She's really pretty.
I thought my movement class
is kind of an odd place
to bring your date,
unless you two thought
movement means something
completely different.
Actually, I was wondering
if you'd accept my invitation
to spend a little time together.
- You're not gonna ask me
to go to another doctor's
- conference, are you?
- No, of course not.
I was thinking more along
the lines of dinner,
so we could get the opportunity
to get to know each other
a little bit better?
- If I say yes,
can I have my hand back?
- Oh, I'm sorry, I...I...I just...
- Me, too, completely...
- Forgot!
- Dr. Neil.
- I better tend to the rest
of my patients, until Saturday?
- Until Saturday.
♪ Make a wish, no I don't fake
this kind of feeling ♪
- Thank you, good job.
- ♪ My heart is on the table
'cause you're everything ♪
♪ I do-do-do, do-do,
I wanna marry you ♪
♪ 'cause when you're around,
I know it's true-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ the way you make me feel
is so good, baby ♪
♪ so good, so good ♪
♪ every single day we spent
apart I wanna be with you ♪
- Hello, Mark, welcome
to Michael B’s.
- Hi, chef Michael,
nice to see you.
- Well,
I see you're here for a date.
- Yeah, I think this may be
"the" date.
Well, then
I bet you're here to see
that beautiful lady
on table 3.
- ♪ When I wake up in the
morning and I see your face ♪
♪ I become blind
by your dazzling grace ♪
- Well, good evening.
- Good evening, aw, thank you.
- As I was walking in,
I saw how beautiful you looked,
and I felt as if I were
in the presence of royalty.
Would you mind
if I address you as
"my queen," your royal highness?
Okay.
- You look spectacular, Michele.
- Thank you.
- I'm so glad you agreed
to meet me here tonight.
- Of course.
- Hello.
Could we get a couple of waters
to start with, please?
- I don't see why that
should be a problem
as soon as
the waitperson arrives.
Thanks.
- Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Jesse.
One of Michele's most trusted
and dearest friends.
- That's right.
- And we thought
that if you turn out to be
the man that we've all
prayed for Michele to meet,
you wouldn't mind if I...
Came along and chaperoned
Michele tonight?
- Well, good,
'cause I'm starving.
- Michele, what do you think
is a healthy choice tonight?
Um...
And it was love
at first sight.
- It most certainly was,
I witnessed the whole thing.
- If I had seen you
at that dinner,
I'd for sure
have dined and dashed.
And that's why
we're at a beautiful celebration
of cherished love between
Michele and Mark,
and not a neanderthal like you.
Hmm. Yeah.
Silly me,
it was my understanding
the wedding is out
on the terrace,
not inside the groom's
dressing room.
Hmm.
What in the world
are you doing?
- Well, sweetheart, I was told
I wasn't supposed to see
my queen in her gown
before the ceremony.
- I'm not sure he's supposed
to tell everyone
her entire life's story before
the ceremony starts, either.
But here we are.
- But sweetheart,
it's that story
that makes you the most amazing
woman that I get to Cherish
my entire life.
- Not if we don't get down
there and say our vows.
- ♪ What a beautiful feeling
to be close to you ♪
♪ there's nothing else
I wanna do ♪
♪ ooh, from the fields
of flowers ♪
♪ you used to pick me ♪
♪ you spread sugar
on my misery ♪
♪ and I don't fake this
kind of feeling ♪
♪ never felt so real ♪
♪ my heart is on the table
'cause you're everything ♪
♪ I do-do-do, I wanna
marry you ♪
♪ 'cause when you're around,
I know it's true-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ the way you make me feel
so good, baby ♪
♪ so good, so good ♪
♪ every single day we spend
apart I wanna be with you ♪
♪ baby, take my hand and hold it
tight just like you do ♪
♪ feels so good, so good ♪
♪ and I do-do-do, do-do,
I wanna marry you ♪
♪ 'cause when you're around
I know it's true-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ the way you make me feel
is so good, baby ♪
♪ so good, so good ♪
♪ every single day we spend
apart I wanna be with you ♪