You
you.
you
Blessed be the Lord God of the universe
with giving this bird wisdom
distinguished Dave that's gratitude do a
good deed what's your exactly
This your idea of a joke have you
forgotten what happens Sabbath before
last between here and Jericho 200
zealots crucified for bearing arms 200
crosses against the sky and a few Roman
soldiers with a dagger like this in
their hearts
yes Romans can be killed too like other
men but we won't break the power of Rome
by wearing knives and our sleeves orders
from Jerusalem and to keep our weapons
concealed from now on till we need it
yeah it'll be safer there with mine yeah
you'll be safer too big brother
I'll forget that I'm not talking to you
as your brother now wasn't I chosen
ahead of the zealots in this village yes.
Joel but you had I mean to be obeyed
the lion doesn't bare his fangs until
he's ready to strike
You
come on
please what do you want water to wash it
you know it forbidden for us to speak
yes but a beggar could speak anyway
your lips are like a thread of scarlet
and your mouth is comely
you're altogether beautiful my life you
shouldn't see much from the Song of
Solomon
I know but know this much more I'll say
it all for you.
That is the first thing this morning I'd
like to be working in the fields and
second the fields you the scholar of the
family Scarlett
No.
I found him by the road at dawn he had
bound up his wound and was able to give
me the name of his village which lies
about one lead to the north more than
that he hadn't a straight to say
that's good it's good to be among
friends after the Romans Romans they
arrested me but I couldn't pay the tax a
chain on my wrist that I stumbled and
fell the soldier drew his sword now I
have no hand dogs the filthy heydon't be
warned they are coming why what is this
tax you speak up you haven't heard all.
Judea is being taxed in punishment of
the recent revolt we must drive his
Roman beasts out of our land but what
can we do without a leader to turn to
we're helpless a nation without a king
is a nation lost
nation lost he's right it looks as if we
will need our weapons Corvo zealous
together and we're wise either wait what
for you organize as elves in this
village you preach resistance to Rome
yet now you say we're not ready to
resist Judea was a nation once someday
she will be again I say wait and work
for that day go onto the fields I'll
tell father of this
Shoroma
Now my son will take up your study
incline thine ear alto vista mother I
han't applies thy heart to understanding
I have news important to the village the.
Romans have laid a new tax on our people
when did you hear it just now
well merchants who stopped within our
gates he had with him an escaped
prisoner prison yes this time it seems
they're taking prisoners as well as
money he's Joel this evil is still
distant from us but father when they
come here as they will we can't stop
them not now but we ought to begin to
prepare ourselves and we are prepared is
not the Lord with us always our only
duty is to follow his holy law as you're
a scholar scribe as you will be but we
need a king in Israel is it not written
that someday there will come a messiah
to deliver us someday we need the
Messiah now when the time is right he
will come wearing the crown of David and
with the sword of David in his hand yes
since he created his people the Lord has
not deserted us he has seen us through a
thousand tribulations slavery oppression
poverty the hatred of parents do you
think he will abandon us now I have no
fear this trouble that threatens us now
is only a shadow that will pants sit
down my son yes our time has come to
review your knowledge you'll scout with
the generations of sham the generations
of our Father I could recite those in my
sleep.
Oh see these are the generations of Shem.
Shem was 100 years old to get our facts
in two years after the flood and Shem
lived after he begat Arphaxad five
hundred years and begat sons and
daughters and our facts had lived five
and thirty years and begat Saylor and
our facts had lived after he begat.
Saylor four hundred and three years we
guess
sons and daughters a neighbor lived for
and 30 years and forget come on come hey
bruh
Ava and say they lived after he begat.
Eber four hundred and three years and
get sons and daughters and they ever
lived four and thirty years and forget
Joel father what's the good of learning
all this good is the history of Israel a
sacred heritage says but to me all these
names and dates as dry as the sands of.
Kidron they genuine the carpet merchant
is here to see you I come it's one speck
bring food and wine Leah yes sir the
best wines continue with your studies
Joel did you say it was Jamie oh yes Jim
you're the father
tomate it always has been ah you are
fortunate lemak to have two fine sons.
Zedeck then joel is an excellent young
man which all has possibilities he also
has his faults he's rather irresponsible
visionary and a bit unruly yet I have
great hopes of Joel it's my wish and it
was his mother's before she died someday
our firstborn should go up to study in
Jerusalem hmm I want Joel to follow in
my footsteps as a scribe but of course a
young man must marry and settle down no
matter what his profession is huh yes
you are blessed in your son's eye
unhappily have nothing but daughters it
takes a daughter to make a wife what is
the matter
and you know Tamil my eldest is a
manageable age already I've had several
offers for her hand and I don't wander
not out you have already arranged a
suitable match my mind is still open of
course you would provide your daughter
with a generous dowry oh yes I yes of
course in these hard times I don't well
well shall we say a chess the fine linen
at carpeted the best quality Tamil our
self is weaving it now a yoke of young
oxen and a flock of seven goats seven
goats of the wall you're her my herd has
been diminished lately by by wild dogs
and their seven goats eight look a dozen
goats now as a flock two dozen at dozen
and a half two does two dozen two dozen
ah for the honor of being allied with
your house in marriage scribe two dozen
goats ah
films are those generous know you taught
me a seed in my throat Leah sorry with
the wine what are you doing minding my
own business
you won't have yet you're learning I'm
learning.
Studious young man takes after his
father
takes after someone else if you ask me
I'm studying
want to hear the generations of sham
well Shem was a hundred years old to get
our facts in two years after the flood
tomorrow I've got something I've heard
something and Shem lived up people get
our facts it 500 years bigoted son and
daughter now faxing live five and thirty
years and forget
no one so beautiful as tomorrow
setting your scroll I've got to talk to
you I've got to tell you about about.
Shin know about us there's a women
gossiping isn't gossip is wonderful but
Joel there will be gossip oh that's all
right got to stop working for a moment a
carpet to get to my husband I have one I
can't tell you here that Jill tomorrow
No maybe it better not
please go father will be so angry peak
it's the time of year to pick herbs this
afternoon during the hour of rest a
little ravine beyond the treasure but I
couldn't I wouldn't do
Who is it I can't see it's nice and.
Indian keeper you know he's been to.
Tiberius to take the baths he'll be full
of moon watch the news from the north
hey the best news is that I left the
stiffness of my limbs of the hot springs
of Tiberius what about a new tactics Tex
out let me see I I did hear something
about it Tex
oh but but but let me tell you this
after the first day I could move one
finger the second day cool fingers and
the third day we know three fingers but
what news yes did you see any soldiers
on the road oh they're always soldiers
on the road but then my arms and my legs
they work did you meet any robbers no no
no no no rubbers you go all the way to.
Tiberius and you have nothing to report
why I didn't say that come come tell us
me come Knights and tell us the news
what if I were to tell you that a key
had appeared in Israel King did you see
em no I I didn't see him but one of his
followers a man called John told me that
his master would soon proclaim himself
king of the Jews are you sure he's as
truly well I believe this man John he
spoke with conviction he told me that
his mouth had gathered a multitude
around him and that they called him the
Messiah
speak of a king a messiah who is he
how do men call him why he's called.
Jesus the son of Joseph the Galilean so
back to our name as though we all hadn't
heard of man maybe you don't know the
man I mean but I do a carpenter from.
Nazareth
what good think ever came out of NASA
hell they say he's created a great stir
among the people of Galilee a trickster
a magician a preaching carpenter who
breaks the laws of the Sabbath earth
that his follower John says that he's
well learning in the law impossible I'd
like nothing better than to question him
maybe you'll have the chance John said
he would pass this way I hope so hey do
you believe in this man Jesus why
because well he has the multitude with
him
hundreds of people who soon become
thousand a veritable army
army Israel
Come on
lucky chairs are meeting like this I
remembered it was the time of year
Are you here well at least in here now I
continue you know I think this is the
first time in our lives we've ever been
a warm no don't be frightened I'm not
because we're we're betrothed my yeah
that's why I had to tell you your father
and mine have arranged our marriage I
heard them talking about it this morning
yeah well is it true did you bother him
not yet buddy well what I did to me
that's quite logical after all in this
whole village you're the most beautiful
and I'm the most intelligent still I I
can't believe it had to be your life my
wife what am I
four to nothing just tomorrow.
No.
A man's mind is like a house that's
always building he builds a room for
every hope he has won for his successes
fame dreams won for his love for his
country then he finds a woman he loves
he knows that the whole house is for a
woman is the Blackbird her heart is her
house and it's an empty house because I
love walks in
You go back by the ravine I'll go
through the fields
it's true marvelous is not to escape the.
Romans they're only a handful they feel
sure we won't attack them they may be
mistaken what are we standing here for
let's get back to the village find
George.
Oh.
What's all the excitement over I'm glad
I don't live in your village you'll feel
the weight of their hands wherever you
live.
You
The Romans do nothing why not fight the
fight when the time comes not now
For the people of Judea greetings from.
Herod Tetrarch of Galilee and from.
Pontius Pilate procurator of Judea now
he that whereas there have been
disorders in the land including armed
strife against the rule of Rome it is
hereby decreed that the people of Judea
shall pay an extraordinary tax as
follows for each household five shekels
of silver which shall be paid into the
hands of the text gatherer you as of
this day already paid our taxes this is
a special tank we're poor people workman
and farmer what would we get silver you
know very well we won't have any silver
until the harvest is over peace fellow
your governors have already thought of
that
huh stop your sniveling whereas if any
man shall not be able to pay in silver
coin he shall be taken into protective
custody and held and held until his debt
be discharged by the labor of his hands
in the service of the state that reads
slavery death of the Roman Kali's you
talk of disorders
they'll be worse disorders wait what's
your name Sadek sell of escribe Zedeck
son of the scribe for you howling about
to follow pay your taxes scribes always
the money it's done by order of Imperial
Rome issued in the 4th month of the
fifteenth year of the reign of Tiberius.
Emperor
over the love of Jupiter wipe your nose
I'll be at my usual patience Square to
receive payments in silver.
I come from my house prepare Joel my son
take this and pay it out to the last
shuttle it is all I have let each man
give according to his means yes you
better come with me while I pay these
vultures no remember what I said you
know what it means to be a soldier no
means your feet hurt and Jim you genuine
carpet merchant and but this year I've
only been selling little carpets I
married hmm hi Karen females yes I said
this is for me or my wife and for my
family one not three for any reduction
from Ali Thornton and how long Maddy
well she isn't exactly we haven't well
it's you're going to be married very
soon and she isn't married because I've
paid her dowry pan frog of dust I'm only
trying to save a little so I can help
the less fortunate neighbor free the
name of Lamech escribe that's enough to
pay for 10 households see that it does
mark it on your slate
doesn't your conscience they were hurt
no to my feet what do you do for sore
feet follow bathe them in water that
enlightenment all thanks friend friend.
Roman
these men were trying to escape over the
wall under arrest
put a guard over
don't hold them we'll pay the tax
somehow they tried to escape that the
crime against wrong is the crime to be
poor to love liberty enough hadn't told
me what to do who my feet I send you
along with him
Zenyk son of the scribe I don't suppose
you'd fight a man without your sword No
No I did do it keep you from making a
fool of yourself I'll kill him for this
stop talking nonsense
you still say do not yes you see all it
was before your eyes I'm trying to look
beyond if you can't understand that at
least obey orders here head up but what
is it missing my purse is empty but my
heart is
if a patriot should want to join with
other Patriots for the good of Israel
and swear eternal md2 wrong I swear by
this covenant of blood
I declare Nathan the innkeeper our
brother from now on his life like ours
has given to freedom for Israel if I was
you I called you together without
telling my brother I don't agree with
his policy of waiting I say attack a
Roman anytime you can you're right this
is a time for action yes if we could set
the prisoners free we must set them free
better to dive and run the Roman galleys
you all with me
hi good first we must be sure that the.
Centurion is well entertained the sea
you take care that mate with pleasure
then when night has gone after the
evening meal Sarah
my mother's jewels your father has a
from his father and gave them to your
mother when they repeat row
folic acid ah now Lord our God King of
the universe who has sanctified us with.
His commandments how many
My sons this has been a day of sadness
for our village but it has its thread of
joy a thread that runs through all the
tapestry of life this thread must not be
broken
I'm an old man full of years time I saw
my line carried on and my name
perpetuated today I talked with general
the father of camel with regard to a
marriage between our houses the
arrangements have been concluded the
betrothal will follow a hope displeases
you my son
you mean I I am to marry tomorrow so.
Jamiel and I have decided these jewels
will be your gift to her father you say
come on Sarah could it be
yes but I thought that I its usual for
the oldest son to be married before the
younger true in fact samuel first
suggested that you should marry tom ah
well then why but on consideration
realizing that should be many years in.
Jerusalem studying Jaime will decide it
you rather see his grandchildren born
here at hope but father this also fell
in with my plans are time enough for you
to marry when you become a scribe and a
rabbi of your people well then you mean
it term or Omar will come to live in our
house she'll be a sister to you and a
good wife to you my son as your well
father so Pierre you'll drink to this
betrothal
ciao
blessed are Thou O Lord our God who
giveth all good things
blessed be the fruit of thy vineyards
the Sun on the grape bring it to our
lips this sweet refreshment you're
drinking a good ear my friend
I can't neglect the hospitality of our
good host are you sure the prisoners are
we're guarded when I take prisoners they
don't escape a lot just the same I've
got an uncomfortable feeling that sour
cabbage you eat no I'm serious
I could spell danger you can't smell
anything but I'm afraid they're always
afraid you got the heart and the nose of
a rabbit these paper won't make any
trouble
well they might attack you oh they won't
attack the Roman Empire that's me
You
you
come on
crying you know my father just told me
we're not bound by fathers bargaining
yes we are their word is Lord what's
given it can't be broke a love can't be
broken
our love is great to us who knows our
fathers is greater I won't give you up I
want you I want you to but go away
together leave the village we'll go
tonight tonight how could we where could
we.
Sack dare to do this
yes I got really good man maybe I am the
least the prisoners are free you gone
behind my back you owe me a wrong turn
Thank you it I told you I smell dangers
have your yapping Korean sir you see the
birds have flown but Sir I thought that
the you thought you mean you didn't see
you didn't see any men standing around
- the fire did you there's only a trick in
- you well why don't you speak give me.
Leave and I'll put every man that's
bullet to the sword bloodthirsty isn't
he take your men to the end stand guard
over the silver
it I thought you said you never lost a
prisoner don't bother me I'm thinking
hmm this escape is a disgrace to Rome
I want those prisoners yeah but how can
you give them time they'll come home to
roost not why you are here of course not
we will draw from the village tomorrow
and a fortnight we'll come back and
force dagger for weapon of zealots so
entice their work in that case when we
come back I'll let Claudia indulge his
appetite for slaughter we'll clean out
this nest of vipers.
And must have dropped it outside did
some Jorian pick it up I saw it in his
head I heard him say we'll clean out
this nest of vipers
then there's only one thing to do strike
before he does he'll wait until morning
the Romans don't like working in the
dark wait longer than that he has enough
men to make his move now.
Centurions no fool he's in no hurry but
sooner or later you'll take revenge for
this nice board then why wait we
outnumber the Romans
what's the matter Joel have you lost
your nerve you're supposed to be our
leader but you seem to have no stomach
for doing anything
a pack of sheep threatened by wolves
and you want a new shepherd yeah alright
but hear me first I've said you'd do
nothing I've said wait not because my
nerve was gone and my stomach was weak
but because I had an idea now listen
this morning while most of you in the
fields Nathan brought word of a certain
man in the north the Galilean was
gathering the people around him
multitude to follow him and already
calling the king of the Jews I had made
up my mind to go and seek this man where
he may be the Messiah we've all been
praying for it seems to me this might
accomplish more than killing a few.
Romans for I believe that until we find
a leader for the nation none of us will
be safe
none of us will be free on my way I
meant to spread the word of revolt to
the country as I passed so that I might
offer this man the strength of a nation
now that's what I'd planned it's for you
to approve or disapprove I stay or I go
as you decide this sword belonged to a
man of my name who fought long ago in
the army of the great warrior judas
maccabees
take it and offer it to the man of.
Galilee my allegiance goes with the
sword yeah
and to him who accepted
everything's quiet yes too quiet
I notice you didn't come forward to lay
hands on the sword oh why not because I
think you're going on a fool's errand
maybe you're right
the man's on a fool's errand from the
time he's born but someday some man may
find what we're all looking for peace
happiness a chance to live you believe
in what's going to happen I believe in
making it happen now
yes you've proved that tonight and as a
result you brought danger on every man
woman and child in this village on
tomorrow ma why do you speak of her I
because I yeah now I remember always
always you looked at camera and asked
where you'll not follow that to the well
and evening I've loved her always as I
love her now sure dad
what is this evil eye here is it true
that you covet the woman I've chosen to
be your brother's wife I said I loved
her you will put this thought from your
mind this love from your heart that I
can't do if you could read my heart
you'd see but you can't all your noise
your books of the law speak to me so
your father I know you could have me
stone for speaking like this but for
once let there be truth between us Joel
how can I give up a love that's as great
as my love for Israel you look at me did
you see only what you want me to be not
what I am I shall beat you I'm not a
scholar I'm a patriot and I sell it you
you are a seller father hi no static
this is my affair you belong to that.
Park yup violence violence is the only
answer to Rome but it must be a nation's
violence what else can save us your
scrolls are dust your law is dead cave
our law is alive with the breath of
Moses and Abraham and all the prophets
men we're beasts until our law called
them to be the chosen of the Lord and
the Lord Himself came first into the
minds of men through the word that is
our law if there is just an outlaw it is
the desk of which the world was made
father I know you speak from your heart
but my heart speaks too and I I don't
want to go in anger you say Go Go we're
on a journey I planned he's going to
seek the Messiah some wonder-worker
Nathan told him about you you mean the
carpenter of Nazareth yes
you you're going to seek Him he may be
the savior of our people if you go from
my house you will no longer be my son
all my life I've Abed you without
question
I can obey you're no longer and go Oh
before I forget these I loved and
cherished you go before I curse you
yes
take it
don't you realize what an excellent
match I've made for you.
Lamech held out for 2,000 goals I'd have
given him three then you should rejoice
it is betrothal now isn't every girl as
a father with brains enough to marry her
to a son describe huh no all right you
can go now
hm well what is it what is it what is it
Rachel said she heard the prisoners have
escaped escaped oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
there be more trouble with this why do
you bring bad news into my house
I'm willing to go with you anywhere you
were coming for me weren't you
you said we'd leave the village to eat
some more we are going I'm going alone
the village is in great danger I must
get help if I can but it's more than
that it's greater than the life of any
one village or any one of us what are
you saying I'm going in search of a man
who may be the king that we need to lead
us an open war against Rome why it must
come if we're ever going to be anything
but slaves why must there be war why
must men fight
I don't care anything about this king
all I want is to be your wife and bear
your children that's all like please
take me with you I can't take
but it must be now I may never have the
courage again my journeys successful
there may be a chance new life for all
of us if this man is the Messiah and
this hope of freedom for Israel
If any man will come after me let him
deny himself and take up his cross and
follow me
who is this man I never saw him before
and yet he spoke to me as if he knew me
that's how I felt the first time he
spoke to me.
It was as if he called me by my name and
I'm seeking the man of Galilee I heard
he was near here you found him
no Huck I mean Jesus of Nazareth he was
called King of the Jews
this is he but where the multitudes that
falling he came here to escape the
multitude then it is true he has many
followers they increased even as the
flocks of a Good Shepherd but he has
more the look of a poor pilgrim than a
king his power and greater than that of
any king my friend what sort of power
you mean he's a magician as some people
say being called worse names than laughs
I must speak with him not now
the son of man has come not to destroy
men's lives but to save them
thou son of David have mercy on me
What wilt thou that I should do unto
thee Lord that I may receive my sight
believe ye that I am able to do this J.
Lord receive thy sight
who thy way
thy faith hath me be
I am a witness to you pause
I pray that you will use it to draw our
people together that we may smite our
enemies there's need for haste all the
country to the south is overrun by the.
Romans but there are thousands like me
sworn zealots ready to join your forces.
Master we offer you our Allegiance and
our swords all they they take up the
sword shall perish with the sword
put it away my friend he's the one man
who has no use for it.
Oh useful you mean he isn't ready to
take a bombs he'll never take up arms.
I don't agree with that I feel as you do
that our master must soon draw the sword
come along with us you and I together
may persuade him twenty rule to
Jerusalem for the feast of the Passover
my village lies on that road in why not
I would like to know more of this man
where he certainly has great authority
he has indeed I'm Joe son of lamech the
scribe
I am called Judas
For what is a man profited if he shall
gain the whole world and lose his own
soul or what shall a man give in
exchange for his soul I say unto thee
arise and take up thy bed and go thy way
blessed are the poor in spirit for
theirs is the kingdom of heaven blessed
are they that mourn for they shall be
comforted blessed are the meek for they
shall inherit the earth blessed are they
which do hunger and thirst after
righteousness for they shall be filled
blessed are the merciful for they shall
obtain mercy blessed are the pure in
heart for they shall see God
blessed are they which are persecuted
for righteousness sake for theirs is the
kingdom of heaven blessed are the
- peacemakers for they shall be called the
- children of God
I'm convinced he'll never take up arms
unless he's forced to the right you know
there were certain men before you joined
us who tried to seize him and force him
to be king yes
what happened he sensed their purpose
and escaped him if those men had
succeeded the history of Israel might
have been changed but they did not
succeed
or without fathers - here lies my
village the master will pass through it
he has friends in every village I'm
going on
Your camp here only this time no
blunders Claudian
most centuries around the wall when we
keep them out of sight come
But anyone enter but no one leaves the
village tonight you understand you have
your orders I'll be at the inn keep a
strict watch these people have a
fondness for striking in the dark
celebration tonight yes is the marriage
ascetic son of the scribe better I
remember him so he's getting married
mean to Tama told her a jam you a toast
the bride
well why don't you drink right I've had
enough I but we most of the village for
the town would marry Joel or Joel as
ethics brother mighty be the fellow I
knocked down on the square I yes yes why
so that extol his brother's bride oh no
it's also kinda our customer more you
have some strange customs you isrealites
go on drink what are we tasting a wine
you're trying to get me grunts that I'll
talk there's no use I can't tell you
anything do you recognize this it's a
dagger little memento I picked up the
night the prisoners escaped
all right I don't know a thing about
that you don't happen to know to which
one of your village zealots this dagger
belongs sell it no no I told you you lie
you're probably one of them yourself
I'd break your arm you might talk go
ahead break my arm Gimli I still gotta
tell you anything you'll talk when the
time comes
bring more wine will drink a toast to
the bridegroom
What freezes this the wedding feast of
tamarins are the son of the scribe what
exists
The
and and I
and I.
Legis all
these cool
what would be you.
Oh
they have strong sums as you have have
got one son your pardon rabbi
my sacred pond.
Long right - Tamar the bride
Lemme don't stir the wedding feast would
call the others together the others as
many as you can but not Saturday was
then once quiet I joke it's true he did
not accept the sword that's why I've
called you together the time has come to
force his hand we can do it how Joel
he'll reach our village tonight or
tomorrow I can't go to him because he
knows me but one of us you Laban will
approach him saying that your father
lies sick of a fever
for what purpose he never refuses the
sick you'll follow where you lead him
you'll lead him here the rest of you
away here and when he comes we'll seize
him and hold him prisoner then together
with Judas and other of his disciples
who feel as I do that he should use his
power will proclaiming King you're sure
he's worthy to be our King I'm sure I've
seen his great works everywhere people
greet him as a savior his disciples
would die for him all that's needed is
- for him to become a man of action it's a
- bold idea that appeals to me I say it's.
Worth trying
ah learn by tomorrow there will be a
king in Israel go to the marriage Day
I must speak with you
the Roman is at the end why I must leave
you now to prepare to receive a guest
during yes he's trying to find out who
the zealot are in our village
he remembered your name why yes he had
this I stood when he fell asleep I say
how many men is he with a mustache he's
alone along yes thanks
those men are the disciples of Jesus he
must have come during the night you know
what to say when I give you the signal
my father lies sick unto death come to
my home o master and Hylian wait here
You have returned yes sir I came back to
to ask my forgiveness to make your peace
with your father
all right yes sure you'll forget the
past you will be my son again hey come
you will drink a glass of wine together
then we'll go on with your life as I
planned it
no father I can't I've set a hand to a
certain task so far I failed yet you set
out to find the Nazarene I found him all
right but you were disappointed in him
told you there was no girl turn the man
oh he has virtue but he uses it only to
preach adoption his doctrine is
blasphemy what is that hypocrite no of
the law he's not a hypocrite father he
believes what he teaches you defend him
perhaps you believe in him no father I
told you yes that's why you won't go
back to my teaching this man has
poisoned your mind with his crazy
ranting you're wrong I've heard this
magic is such that it fails father
against son son against father for your
judge him when you don't know him I'd
like to have him in judgment before me I
would soon show you judge not
be not judge rusty
Our village is honored by the visit of a
carpenter Deb I asked
Moscow
what shall I do to inherit eternal life
what is written in the law Haridas thou
thou shalt love the Lord thy God with
all thy heart and with all thy soul and
with all thy strength and with all thy
mind and thy neighbor as thyself thou
hast answered write this do thou shalt
live and who is my neighbor a certain
man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho
and fell among thieves which stripped
him of his raiment and wounded him and
departed leaving him half dead and by
chance they came down a certain priest
that way and when he saw him he passed
by on the other side and likewise a.
Levite when he was at the place came and
looked on him and passed by on the other
side but a certain Samaritan as he
journeyed came where he was and when he
saw him he had compassion on him and
went to him and bound up his wounds
pouring in oil and wine and set him on
his own beast and brought him to an inn
and took care of him and on tomorrow
when he departed he took out two pence
and gave them to the host and said unto
him take care of him and whatsoever thou
spendest more when I come again I will
repay which now of these three thinkest
thou was neighbour unto him that fell
among thieves he that showed mercy on
him go and
like.
Master Mike
father a my brother Joe completely
something has happened to be in your
brother sanic or what do you say come
My son is big
please to kill the foreigner before he
died.
God of Israel my day of joy is turn
tonight my soul is broken within me
curse of a proposed or race murder
The dog still lives.
My leading to you
we'll have to hide the rooms money
I'll get help.
You got show witness
go and do likewise.
Do the likewise
you
go this your way of taking vengeance
choice he saw him on the part of the
Roman that's why I left the village his
plan just said it became was just of
line they need us
I come to take the body of my son
oh mighty God what class is on my house.
Jose why do you kneel beside this man
the murderer of your brother
this man is my brother also
Heeey.
Gloria
disregard all previous orders spare love
it.
Arrest him
I'm not hungry.
Katie like ham we're storm ever saw in
Jerusalem I've been locked up here I
don't know how many days what about me
I've had the Guardian I who made me mr.
Big spectacle on the hill today
crucifixion people faded all kinds of
excitement I had to miss it because of
you being the one from outside will you
accept the thanks of a Roman for the
facts you saved my life then why was I
arrested save you from your own people
now my friend you're free
free I should have come to you sooner
I've been on sick leave until the day
today I was on duty you mean I can go no
wait
one thing I would know is why did you
risk your life for mine I was your enemy
and yet you helped me why because I
because of a man I met and followed for
a while a great and simple man who
taught me it was right to show mercy to
anyone in distress anyone yes it's a
strange teaching who is this man
he's called Jesus of Nazareth Jesus of.
Nazareth.
I owe my life to him
and I
just now as he hung on the cross I trust
this spear there is child.
The Pilger came to the divot he said he
had orders from a Centurion to bring me
here I didn't know why this century well
I mean wasn't lonesome analogy all the
way with I waited not knowing anything
just hoping I'm free
when pull back together to our village
for no no to me they still hate you for
helping the vermin even though the
village was feared that they might kill
you if I must obey no no tomorrow I went
out seeking a leader I know now that I
found him his truth is mine I was
chairing with Joel it he died today
cross
if I die tomorrow what does it matter
truth in the teaching
go on
You.