The Awakened of the Pont de l'Alma
My God. I've slept badly.
My God.
I've slept badly.
What are you looking at?
The Seine.
Me too.
You have nice eyes.
My son will have your eyes.
In that case...
In that case?
Hadn't we'd better get married?
It only follows.
I'm happy to hear you say it.
That's surprising.
I think that it's going
to be rather shocking.
It's a shame our place isn't like yours.
Kiss me.
No.
We're being watched.
So what?
Married people often do such things.
Sir, do you have a light?
Such horrors.
I seem to have gone and asked you
for something that is too easily had.
I was just about to fall asleep
and now you've woken me up.
Sorry, but in fact I
would like to speak to you.
Not today.
Why?
Too much to do.
When could  I see you again?
In seven months.
Here's to our son.
He's here.
You feel him?
No. You couldn't feel him yet.
He doesn't think so.
You won't believe it.
He's moving with exactly the same
rhythm as that man's hands.
I love you.
I've got to fly.
I'll be back at 3 p.m.
Good day, Monsieur.
Good Day.
Monsieur. I've been observing
you for a long time.
You'd better stop
doing that immediately.
I don't like conversing with
strangers.  I prefer solitude.
If you're looking for somebody whether
that would be a homosexual, a barbarian,
or a philosopher, you're wasting
your time with me.
Monsieur, I'm not
exactly just a stranger.
I've read you with the same ecstasy that
gets on my nerves with a certain novel.
- But...
- But what?
You're promised to meet
me seven months ago.
So?
I'm a boxer, Monsieur:
I want to place myself at your service.
To do what?
To help support to you
in the insupportable.
You mean...
Need a light?
It's true that I don't sleep much.
Not much?
Barely sleep at all...
even less than myself?
- You, too?
- Mmhmm.
And how.
You like taking long walks at night.
I adore that.
Nothing better.
After all,
the most beautiful whores
only come out at night.
Oh? You like women?
Mmmm... that's my downfall.
I've had bad luck with women.
They'll play along a little and
then,  everything's over.
Women only like to make love and little else.
They're animals,
they can't help it.
You've gone out.
Speaking of making babies,
look down there at that woman.
I have had the privllege of seeing
that woman laugh. It was marvelous.
Don't talk of morals,
don't talk of humanity...
With symptoms like those,
that woman's pregnant.
Pregnant? Despicable!
Hold on. You're crazy.  Stop!
- Where are you going?
- Sleep!
Excuse me but do you
intend to rape here?
I feel an obligation to intervene.
That's it.
Again.
What are you waiting for?
- Me --
- Come here.
Never, I told you.
Oh yes.
She's sweet.
She doesn't seem outraged.
She's having sweet dreams.
My God. What are we doing?
I don't recognize myself.
I'm starting to get excited.
It was bound to happen.
But it's unthinkable....
me, rape a pregnant woman?
It's odd what I'm about to do.
I'll make a sort of double for myself.
Enough!  Start raping
and get off the double!
Just a second!
Hurry up, pine nut!
It's not easy. There all kinds of little
manipulations that are too obvious.
Are you done?
I never believed I'd again be capable of
intimacy with anyone never mind a woman.
Well?
That foreigner, she sure
got a good whiff of me.
Let's go have a coffee.
So you want to talk?
He'll talk, no matter when or to whom.
People let themselves to talk
very quickly. I think it's a shame.
So here we are in
some kind of struggle.
Good. That's given you some heart.
Do you like theory?
I adore it.
Having searched far and wide for
the causes of your transformations.
What would those be?
I believe I've found
the point of departure
for all of these theories:
I propose that getting lit
causes sleep disturbances.
That's an old one.
You're a bad apple, you.
So I've been told.
A rascal.
Well...
Yes, in general.
Look here.
This hand, for example.
This hand...
Who is making this hand
move if it isn't me?
Me?
Yeah?
Take it.
Yes, in fact or yes, maybe.
But maybe not.
Anyway, not me.
So according to you, we're
driven by hidden forces.
While we share the
bodily mass of a kind,
each mass is an independent system.
And within the interior of this system,
everything is mixed up.
I'm ready to share my system with you.
So it is very possible that my hand
should compose part of your body.
If only...
in the left knee.
Are you going to leave?
Right on schedule.
It could also be that both
belong to someone else.
Who else?
Go ahead and leave.  They
are making all of our decisions.
That's frightening.
Yes.
And this theory is a joke to you?
Forced to reexamine the dimensions of
this theory, I'm plunged into the depths
of function theory.
And that is what you've uncovered
about the motives of
our respective insomnias?
It's something like that.
Other stakes, they'll find out.
I believe in your bodily system theory
more than that
mysticism of my daydreams.
Not if you are not better.
You persist in remember.
I'll need to wash my hair.
I was only showing off certain reservations.
What is it?
Have I said something to upset you?
Hold on.
- You're pale.
- Indeed.
It's begun: the merger.
Yes. It has begun.
It's odd...
but everyone...
everyone is taking orders fromf a fetus.
Yes...
just a fetus.
Don't you need to cry about your son?
I don't need to any more.
He is being much nicer now.
He's almost not crying at all.
Much better.
Sleepy?
No.
I'm closing my eyes....
that's all.
See you soon.
- You again?
- That's right.
How onerous, these duties.
Your conversation enchants me.
But I do mean completely.
Can I ask you a question?
Personal?
Not really.
Go ahead.
Over the months, I've watched you
Often during the day over the past month,
You often return while it is spitting.
I'm waiting.
Waiting for what?
A barge.
A lighter in particular?
Yes.
And what in particular
about this lighter?
A kid.
A kid?
What kid?
I think he should be..
He looks like a double of myself.
It's a long story.
Spit it out, this sweet story.
On this barge,
there is... a child.
who has been beaten without mercy.
And?
That's all.
I'm crushed.
Feel that. It's getting nice.
The light is peeking
through the clouds.
It's all coming together beautifuly.
Have a look over there
at that woman with a suitcase.
But I know that woman very well.
You do, too.
My God, is it true?
What is she doing here, this time?
She's going to commit suicide
due to the shock of the rape.
What you're waiting for....
She's waiting for your lighter, perhaps.
Did I tell you that she's here due to
some marvelous coincidence?
Thanks.,
but I can't see what you're getting at?
You'd like to go to sleep, wouldn't you?
I tried but failed.
I've seen you.
Let me try again.
I'm begging you. Let me.
I really want to...
except...
oh, I don't know.
Except what? Shit!
Do you believe it's possible to sleep
here?
Absolutely.
A drink...
Drinking in my room made me lose sleep.
All right,
except if I understand you right,
Go to sleep. Shut your eyes.
I wouldn't want to fall asleep
before the little woman blows off.
Her, blow off?
My eye!
All right then.
Go ahead.
Sleep!
Are you asleep?
Oh yes.
It's wonderful.
Good.
My turn now.
Say "sleep" for me.
I meant to say sleep!
Say "sleep" for me... shit!
You've woken me up.
She's blown off.
Yes, it's true damn it.
She's coming back to see us, I hope.
That's the way it goes.
Every time I sleep, even for a minute,
something essential is lost.
Nothing but a blink of sleep!
Oh how hard I've tried.
No kidding?
I have a method.
What method is that?
Antoine, we're plunged
into such delirium
since the naval battle.
Thanks to Oedipus,
in the midst of sleep,
all anyone yearns for is
the sleep to come.
Yes, only for that.
While you sleep, a lot happens.
I maintain that when you fall asleep,
something essential is lost.
What can you drink while asleep?
A bit more than you can eat.
They never eat.
Oh no?
Is that right, Malraux?
Voltaire?
Say yes, my love.
The awakened don't eat,
they dream destruction.
Enough. You're fooling yourself.
What do you mean?
It was a pity, but he had to die,
since he'd eaten anothers' pie.
To this rebus,
I respond.
Such amazement, disturbed all brotherhood.
Be careful!
A word uttered in sarcasm
is a sin quite mortal.
I would have said it is quite Marcel.
Shit! Shit!
They don't like what you are.
Excuse me?
Surrounded on all sides, I still would
not like to observe your habits.
Yeah?
Perhaps I'm being a little naive.
Which goes to say,
that the supreme dream
is not to sleep but it is not
to sleep without disturbances.
And what disburbs you?
There's no telling...
Sleep!
That's it.
It's flooding over you.
Papa?
Yes.
Can I ask you a question?
Why, since you look after the dead,
have you shown me only one corpse?
Oh, that.
You haven't answered me.
If you won't talk to me any more,
I'm leaving.
See you soon.
Maybe.
I...
eat...
What is it?
What is it Michel?
What?
Are you done?
Get ready for the day.
This won't do.
See you soon.
Too late.
I'm waiting to get dressed.
I can tell you one strange thing.
It's that..
I adore getting dressed.
I get dressed to protect myself.
But I'm sure that I
was almost not dressed.
It's a certainty.
I... I adore getting dressed.
Do you believe me?
Yes.
Well.  Very well.
Do you think it may have
ecological consequences?
Listen.
Following my examination, I find that
you have been injured in a lover's quarrel.
I suspect what I'm about to tell you
may come as something of a shock.
In effect, as far as I'm concerned,
the circumstances interest us both.
and these coincidences
are also compelling.
So... in a few words,
some years ago, my wife had an accident
in circumstances similar to yours.
Following this accident,
she killed herself.
And I thought as soon as I saw you
that you would tell me the same.
Your accident,
perhaps for both together we could...
intimate an adventure?
Crazy ideas.
Cube, the sphere comes closer.
And then,
wounded,
the sphere refuses the union.
A little communication,
and then nothing.
Oh no!
Don't start that.
Do you find it easy
in general to amuse yourself?
Ah yes. I get it.
I... I discern
an old lady here.
Move her.
A little more.
Ah... that's it.
Enjoying that?
Trying to.
Wait.
Don't leave.
Wait for the end.
But...
it's not over yet.
He never waits for the end.
That's what leads to crime...
Nothing will stand, that old saying goes.
I am sure you'll share a lot of
interests the two of you.
Me, too.
And what is he waiting for?
Michel?
What is it?
He's not there.
Whenever he feels like avoiding
intimacy, he absents himself.
It's hard being deprived of affection.
Yes.
Papa?
Does the trees move
when no one's watching?
For a long march?
It's a little funny what you've
just said, very, very funny.
Boy?
Alain?
Alain!
Yes?
They're magnificent, all of these clothes.
Is there any dangerous that if I wear
it might raise your temperature?
No.
But it's a little big for you, that coat.
No. It's not too big.
This one here is:
the most beautiful.
It's magnificient.
That one's even moreso.
Anne.  Anne?
Anne, you're not going
to go out like that, are?
Yes. Of course.
But you'll see.  With resilience.
I'm going out like this.
Yes.
And Anne?
Anne looking good.
Sleep!
You really want him, this child?
...he wants me.
What do you mean?
I mean that we...
Hold on...
You talk like Violette.
I am Violette.
Do you love me?
I love you.
She's already fallen asleep...
Funny old thing, falling asleep
during sexual foreplay.
I love you.
That's not true.
Those who fall asleep during
sexual don't love their partners.
Good.
What are you doing at my place?
Don't be a fool , we're at their place.
A lot is coming our way right now.
- It's better this way.
- Yes, Marcel.
Good.
Alain. I've seen you.
You are very, very sick.
Yes. Very, very sick.
Don't move.
You know I want to kill you , chump!
I don't recognize you at all anymore.
As usual.
Ah, yes.
It's a dream.
Just one?
Clear that up.
Come with me.
You should leave by the window.
Ah no.
no, no.
I've already had this dream.
At least, that's something..
I was having fun while you were dreaming.
Doing what for example?
Making love.
Oh no, Marcel. Not that.
I'd certainly remember such a spectacle.
She's already sleeping.
Go ahead.
She's waiting for you.
See you later.
And the children?
Dream children.
Oh Antoine. You're funny,
how funny you are.
I love you more than anyone else.
Me, too. But in a fashion more or less Platonic...
Shit.
That blindman, for example.
He hears us.
But I have never understood him.
Which one? That one up there?
Being a being to be beaten
Hey, Monsieur?
Monsieur
Come here.
Closer.
Closer!
Much closer!
At your service.
And now...
Sleep!
He's fast asleep.
Since you're asleep...
See!
See what?
Good question.
Because when I look around,
I only see blurry shapes.
Tell me.
It's worse than we thought.
Nonetheless...
if I look around with a little more attention,
I can see
a cube
and a sphere.
What a winner.
He's cheating, this blind man.
You are more secret.
And you,
the sphere.
That's no fair, I wanted to be you.
He cheats!
He can't see well at all.
Where have you put she who
drinks more than all of us.
Yes.
I see a woman here.
Where is she?
Show her to us.
Here.
What does she
want here, this girl?
To sell herself.
But,
obviously, she wants to get married.
That's brilliant.
Woman:
Will you take in wedlock this man
to your right?
Yes, my love.
Will you take in wedlock this man
to your left?
Yes, my love.
And you?
Will you take as a wife
this drowned woman?
Who are you calling drowned?
I see.
Answer, Marcel!
Say yes.
Yes.
Shit!
You?
Well, yes. Didn't have I not already
indicated that by saying it for Marcel?
I hereby declare you husbands
and wife.
This blindman is beginning to annoy me.
Let me show you the way.
Get lost.
What's the word?
Good evening, Alain.
What's been going on?
We've been having a lot of fun.
Haven't we, Michel?
She's no fun.
Michel,
could you be nicer to Anne?
She's very sensitive.
And I would like you to be my wife,
if you will will accept.
Anne? Do you really believe that
this day is going to repeat itself?
Don't lose hope.
Today, you have agreed to speak to me.
Papa.
It's moronic to say you love her.
She doesn't love poets.
I have a little poser
who won't stop fidgeting.
Like your poems, poses
must be kept up.
Isn't that right, Alain?
I can see again that you're
going to be very happy together.
Formidable.
Papa?
I notice that you haven't hugged Anne yet.
That's not very nice of you.
Hang on.  That's true.
You'll see.
She'll be very happy.
Anne?  I'm waiting for you.
Oh yes. He would like to
present some charades tonight.
Instead of this?
Do what you want.
Anyway, you're already doing
the same thing, you know?
It's not the same thing at all.
The bridge.
The drowned man.
The two friends.
The scene is the philosopher's engagement.
The blinding of the captain.
The wind.
The blind man takes
the hand of the nude dancer.
The burial of remains.
The invalids' treasure.
See you soon,
maybe.
What have I done now?
No matter what you say,
he detests it.
poor kid.
I beginning to get exaspirated.
We're tired.
You tired?
That wouldn't be so,
if I weren't too much for us.
It's too late, you know.
No. It's not too late.
It's never too late.
Look.
He left.
For once I can talk??
I love you.
Who are you?
What a funny question.
Why?
And you?
Who are you?
Killers have told me who you are.
You are the cube
and also
you are sphere.
I knew it.
Curiosity is stronger than dreams
of which much the same
applies to my contemporaries.
I was coming through here by chance.
In that case, Goodbye.
Marcel!
Such a need for contact.
Such absurd affection.
Such adorableness.
Such unusual improvisation.
You always surprise me.
See you later.
I decided to follow up on your
experiments, afterwards.
A little behind, huh?
I intend to publish both of them
and have sent opinion letters
to the Journal of Freudian Analysis.
The thrust of it is, he wants to analyze us.
Ever do that?
With that woman, yes.
You'll consider it?
- So long.
See you later, old man.
Know how you can do to be sure
you aren't been sleepwalking?
How?
On its way.
A one-a and two-a...
There. That's better.
I'm sure that you will come.
Get something for that, Doctor.
Michel around here?
Marcel.
Are you there?
Yeah.
What does he like?
Football?
I don't like football.
What would you like?
Nothing.
Antoine.
Are you here?
Yes.
At day's bottom.
We'll see about that.
Michel.
Are you here?
It's not me.
It's a friend.
And what's he doing?
He's sad because his mother
didn't come to find him after school
and refuses to acknowledge him.
You never would have done that.
It's curtains, poor fool.
I think I'm speaking very well.
Precisely the problem. Less drunk.
Rascal!
So what?
I only tell myself that if you drink,
there must be a good reason.
- Is that possible?
- Well, sure. Why not?
Can I ask you to breathe
in deep for a moment?
And me? Can I?
Doctor,
it must be a pain to have to
bury so many women at once.
Well. What's your opinion?
By just a hair's breadth.
Shit. Just a few seconds left.
That went a too far.
I just had the same nightmare.
The drowned woman?
Good morning, Alain.
What's this?
You're here?
Well, I haven't gone out today.
It's true, papa.
She's had her fill.
But we can play together,
don't we, Michel?
Not with me.
My friend won't wait for me forever.
He's very jealous.
It's not said "jealouse," it's said "jaloux."
See you soon. Maybe.
Shit.
Well...
He shouldn't have said that.
My vulnerable little girl.
Allpowerful man.
Anne. I need to speak to you.
Since reflecting on what has
occured this morning,
I have thought of a way.
I'll confront him.
Again?
It depends. We'll talk.
But that's the kind of thing
you'd say to your wife.
Don't talk to me about that woman.
I hate that poor girl.
He has come, no?
Yes. He's here.
He...
Excuse me.
I beg you pardon, but
you must have some
idea if there is a bomb?
I must know everything.
Essential, but...
I could talk for a drink. A drink!
Focus.
Give me that.
I know everything.
First, a few words.
The men of this part of the world
reached an agreement that they would
exchange gifts among themselves.
Why would they do that?
Well...
Listen
For thousands of years, men were
living in misery and distress.
So then they decided
to find
a s...
savior of wax to
come and
save them.
Why d...
do that?
So
they'd b...
be saved.
So the poem is the good news:
God sent
the comet flying.
Seriously.
You know that Christ came to save us.
And that he came from a virgin.
What is a virgin?
A virgin is a woman
who hasn't had any relations.
What are relations?
Relations consist in being
hugged very very hard.
But, it's also
a message signed by a minister.
What is a minister?
A minister is a functionary
who delves into mysteries.
What is a mystery?
A mystery is a little fish.
And this is why
I don't want any more gifts.
Gifts are for the virgin.
Michel...
you're becoming pretentious.
Don't move.
The gift is over there.
It's still safe isn't it?
It's a car.
You believe in revealing everything
ever since he broke something?
I don't know.
I'll bore a hole through this...
swoon.
Swoon?
I said "swoon"?
That's what you said.
Curious.
Who are you?
I am your mother.
How do you know?
Because I've had my eyes closed.
Where are you?
I'm dead.
I know that.
My father told me about it.
He told you what?
That you were
up there.
But why "up there," precisely?
He didn't say "up there, precisely."
What did he say?
He said, up there.
But how up there?
Up in orbit, I guess.
No.
I floated.
You see.
That's the same thing.
Yes. I floated in the river.
Like a fish?
I am a fish, sadly.
What do you eat in the water?
I eat...
my likenesses.
Like everybody else?
I'm not like that.
Yes, my love.
You're precisely like that.
Sadly?
Yes.
Tell me about it.
Some other time.
You're abandoning me?
I'm going away.
I hear you.
but I don't have to read you.
Look at me carefully.
Touch.
Blood.
What's this wound?
It's my mouth.
You're can speak with that?
I breathe
through my wounds.
Sadly.
Yes, my love.
That's what you say to my father.
I know a riddle.
Your father sees a little fish.
Your mother
is a mouth.
Your uncles have some dogs.
Who are you?
I know that one.
The answer is:
I barely am.
Now...
look at me.
Touch.
Blood.
Drop.
I hear.
You're here?
Yes.
You're still not ready
to talk to me? Fine.
What?
I'm worried.
I mean,
your condition?
And according to you,
what is my condition?
You have no close friends.
Yes?
Not yes, wow.
And Pierre, that's wow, too?
My love,
I was very afraid that my son had been...
How should I put it?
Infected?
He's wasting away.
Tonight, it struck me.
You see everything so well
except what's right before your eyes.
What do you mean?
The stone.
Try to be serious for once and tell me
everything about this famous Pierre.
I'm going to.
Up there?
The reverse.
You dreamt about
undressing her with your eyes.
That was Pierre in my verdict.
What a joke.
Very funny.
Don't you recognized him?
He's your son, my love.
What exactly do you mean?
Disgusted by our love-making...
Is that right?
Yes.
You mean to say that this Pierre...
explain yourself, right now!
Very well.
This morning as I was taking my shower
it happened.
You're delirious.
This Pierre comes from Brazil.
I have an object in my cocktail.
It fell out of my stomach.
Very, very funny.
At least,
she isn't anthropomorphic.
Very funny.
You know why I'm laughing?
Today I contributed to knowledge.
and they say...
They say that explains everything.
You want to know?
Michel.
The time has come for you to go to sleep.
How sad.  I can't do it.
And can I find out why you can't?
Because.
Michel, you've going to lie down now.
I can't.
I'm talking with my friend.
Your friend is in the book.
Yes.
Can you see what he's doing?
Singing.
What is he singing about?
Pillage.
Is that you?
Yes. It's me.
Where is my son?
He came to see me, like you.
He's here?
He's always... here.
And what is he doing?
He's sleeping,
like the rest.
Like the rest of the children?
Yes.
My wife is here, too?
Of course.
They noticed. They feel everything.
They're feeling more
and more ubiquitous.
Who?
Your two uncles.
And me?
And you....
are the opposite
as usual.
You sleep at your place,
and while slumbering, you
betray you wife around here?
And the monsters,
where did they go?
Still here?
He's sleeping.
You think so.
He doesn't sleep any more.
You're happy with everything?
He sees to it that I miss
nothing during his absences.
It's getting late.
A shame.
I'll go.
You'll miss me.
All right.
Right now, you must be precise.
You're going to tell me
exactly what the two of them are.
- Was it...
- What have I....
No. Try to rember, would you please?
Was it right here?
A turn to the right?
Try to remember, please!
I don't know, I...
You can't recall if it was there or to
the left or right or in this place at all?
- Not here? Here? Over there?
- The only thing I know...
What do you need to remember? It was
either here, there, over here or over there.
Easy enough to know, if you
understand a word I've said to you.
Hold on.
I sense it was here.
You know much better,
I had to return for an examination.
Even closing my dead eyes, I have no
problems perceiving in particular.
I never knew.
Telling me to kill myself...
and the damage is done.
To be brief,
I'm also seeking to speak to your son.
Your son
disappeared into sleep
of that we can't have any doubts.
That one had eyes, too.
Sit down.
I can be buried,
after you apply this force,
somewhere up there.
You know where.
You're all-wise.
The insomniac acquires
the infinite mass of the dreamer's body
and my Sacre de Coeur.
And in this haze of dreams,
thick like caramel,
the birth of your son.
And two begot him.
Go ahead doctor, before it's too late.
Come in, doctor. Come in.
Do you know about us?
I've been told certain things.
What, for example?
- That.
- What a boor!
Sit down, doctor. I'll join you.
I may be a boor,
but I'm not a whore.
Everybody could tell you what he did.
Thus, we're in disagreement
about the entire discourse,
both the presuppositions and
the philosophical repercussions.
Opens his mouth, and what does he say?
So
there are things to prepare,
Marcel, to make yourself honest.
I'm always honest.
Oh yes. You sure have been since
my wife has rejected you.
A head to head.
You only have one reason,
but you have two.
Just wait for them to appear
to go to see the Doctor.
I think I'll have to
use force with this guy.
Thinks he's...
Yes. Better be careful. Isn't he charming?
I am certain of that.
I'm delighted by you, Doctor.
Just before it happened,
I said to Marcel, aren't you taking
things a little bit too fast?
In fact, this place is haunted.
But I sense that he needs to be
convinced.
Professor,
I have little time.
I'm looking for my son.
Stay a bit longer and you'll
decide you like it around here.
You see, according to Marcel, finding
son is nothing but chimerical.
Seeing a chimera is not
impossible, the chimera itrself,
that's another thing.
Around here, you have to laugh, Doctor.
Yes, indeed.
His manner is very funny.
Violette.
The beautiful Violette.
I'm scared stiff.
Don't leave!
All for nothing. Nothing, Doctor!
You son has been found. He's already
on his way.  Just a few minutes.
What's that?
It's necessary to
employ your knowledge,
once and for all.
Isn't that so, Alain?
To know what?
That's she's a whore.
Marcel. One doesn't speak of whores.
That's too obvious.
You see, Doctor,
Concerning people, no one
wonders since solipsism exists.
How can he tell the whole
that that it isn't solipsistic?
Alain
was my husband.
Wait.
Your husband?
This means she was a family whore.
He was my husband,
but I didn't love him that way.
Now,
I believe
that I love him.
What are these words of yours?
She wants to settle accounts.
She goes and tells you
now that it's too late.
Do you understand this
tragic situation, Marcel?
Even so, Doctor,
that's just what I was doing on
the bridge to your wife and hard.
Oh, no.  Marcel!
Not hard. Not like that.
I remind myself of nothing.
I remember nothing
Talk, Marcel.
It seems I'm being
recognized once again.
But I live with myself.
That's dementia talking.
Talk!
Telling me what? To obey that one?
She's given that away.
It's begun.
It's all for the best!
Antoine,
in one verb:
Sleep!
Quick!
Thanks for the hand.
Alain.
I'm here.
Where is my son?
I'm looking for him
like you.
It's more of the same.
He's waiting for you?
Have you told him I was wicked?
Yes.
Have you told him
that you are strong-willed?
I read your letters to him
and he heard everything.
So he must loathe me.
I adore you.
And yourself?
Come back.
Good morning, papa.
Where are you?
Here,
with mama.
You're dead?
No. You're living.
What's the difference?
Michel, don't twist words.
It's very different being dead.
As a doctor, I'm in
a good position to know.
Fine. If that's what you want.
I'm alive.
Where?
Here.
You're here?
Yes.
With your mother?
And...
what are you doing together?
Do you still love your mother?
Yes mama.
I'll always loved you.
And you?
Me?
I couldn't do otherwise.
You are my son.
Michel.
Answer me.
You must love your father, too.
I believe that
as soon as I wake up
he's going to beat me.
He is both of yours.
I don't like needing this father.
It's like being hidden
from only one person.
You know, mama,
I've heard that my fathers
are Antoine and Marcel.
Yes.
Make away, I'd ought.
Make away from me?
Go away.
Can I stay with you?
I could show my affection
before I go.
No.
Why?
Because I've just done my makeup.
I could at least blow you a kiss.
You didn't even get dressed?
No.
Why should I?
I've said I spent all day in bed.
Who goes out any way?
You always stay shut up.
Don't you want to go out?
No.
You're mistaken.
I'm almost never here.
I'm always with them.
And at this moment you're with them?
Yes.
I'm beginning to feel guilty
for having eaten those pancakes.
Have you found the disappeared one?
I'm only breathing thanks
to this freezing air.
Knock yourself out.
That would please me.
Let's go for something eat after all.
Thus, I ask you what has
given you this guilty feeling?
That's why man's heart
is seized by sadness.
Do tell.
I'm getting hungry.
Have you woken up yet?
A little.
Since when?
Dreams are full of wounds.
How unfair!
We fall asleep before we've woken up.
I'm certain that, today, the laws
of the heart can be determined.
That's fine. I want to have
been something before
you go crazy with sleep.
A triumphal arch for the son.
Yes. It should have been Oedipus.
I should.
Sleep!
Oh... no, no, no, no.
Yes.
- No!
- Yes. Just this once.
I have taken down your confession.
Let's go and have a nice coffee.
It feels like pretty soon,
it's going to snow.
There are other bridges to attend to.
And other children.
Marcel.
Marcel, never forget
what I'm about to tell you,
and nevermore will a child be begotten.
But why?
Disappearing the family father will suffice
to render a few hours very nice.
subtitles: depositio