SO, MAIA, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THE SCENERY?
THE LANDSCAPE, I MEAN.
NOT THE WOMAN PISSING
IN A FIELD.
IT’S LOVELY.
IT’S ALL RIGHT. A BIT OF
SUNSHINE WOULDN’T GO AMISS.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
YOU KNOW, MISS ALLMAN--
OH, CALL ME FRANKIE.
FRANCESCA AND MISS ALLMAN
MAKES ME FEEL REALLY OLD.
FRANKIE. I JUST WANTED
TO SAY THANK YOU
FOR AGREEING TO THIS
AT SUCH SHORT NOTICE.
IT’S NOT A PROBLEM.
IT’S AN ABSOLUTE PLEASURE.
BARBARA SHOWED ME
THE PHOTOS OF THE SHOOT
YOU DID IN 2009.
I WAS THOROUGHLY IMPRESSED.
THANK YOU.
SHE SAID THAT WAS
THE LAST TIME YOU MODELED.
THIS LAKE. IT’S BEAUTIFUL.
INDEED.
LET ME TAKE THAT.
DON’T BE SILLY!
YOU’RE MY GUEST.
RELAX. ENJOY.
I DON’T THINK THERE’LL
BE ANY TROUBLE THERE.
SO, DO YOU
LIVE HERE ALONE?
MMM-HMM.
AND DO YOU DO ALL OF
YOUR WORK FROM HERE?
MOST OF THE TIME.
SO, DO YOU HAVE
A PARTNER?
PARTNER? HOW
POLITICALLY
CORRECT OF YOU.
SORRY, I--
DON’T WORRY.
I’M ONLY TEASING.
TO BE HONEST,
IT’S A LITTLE
BIT COMPLICATED
AT THE MOMENT.
BUT WHEN ISN’T IT?
I HEAR YOU’RE MARRIED.
MAIA?
HMM?
MARRIED?
OH. YEAH.
YOU HAVE TO CHECK?
IT’S AN AMAZING HOUSE.
LET’S GO INTO THE DRAWING ROOM.
YOUR PHOTOS PAY FOR ALL OF THIS?
HA HA. WOULDN’T THAT BE NICE?
NO. THE HOUSE
KIND OF PAYS FOR ITSELF.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, I LIVE HERE ALONE
OUT OF SEASON,
AND THE REST OF THE
YEAR I HAVE COMPANY.
I RENT IT AS A HOLIDAY HOME.
I’VE HAD A FEW NAMES.
EVEN ROYALTY.
REALLY?
MM-HMM. I WON’T NAME NAMES,
BUT LET’S JUST SAY
THIS HOUSE HAS SEEN
A FEW THINGS.
IT GIVES THEM THE PRIVACY
THEY NEED,
WHICH GIVES ME AN EXCUSE TO
KEEP THE HOUSE LOOKING GREAT.
IT’S SO QUIET.
THERE’S SO MUCH SPACE.
[FRANCESCA]
NOBODY AROUND FOR MILES.
YOU LIKE READING?
WELL, I TRY. THERE’S
JUST SO MUCH OUT THERE.
[FRANCESCA]
HMM.
ALL OF THESE
YOUR PHOTOS?
MMM-HMM.
LOTS OF PEOPLE
ARE DRAWN TO THAT ONE.
IT’S FUNNY HOW IT HAPPENED.
SHE WAS A FRIEND OF MINE.
CAME TO ME STRAIGHT AFTER
HER BROTHER’S FUNERAL.
SHE WAS ABSOLUTELY
DISTRAUGHT.
SHE WAS SO VULNERABLE,
AND YET SO ELEGANT,
SO I ASKED IF I COULD
TAKE A PHOTO.
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
SHE STARED AT ME
FOR A FEW MOMENTS
AND THEN SAID,
"I DON’T GIVE A FUCK."
SO RAW.
IT’S BEAUTIFUL.
I COULDN’T AGREE MORE.
USE THIS AS
YOUR DRESSING ROOM.
STUNNING.
AND IF YOU WANT
TO FRESHEN UP--
THANK YOU.
I’LL MAKE US SOME LUNCH
AND THEN WE CAN TAKE
SOME PHOTOS AFTERWARDS.
DO YOU NEED A HAND?
NO. YOU’VE HAD A LONG JOURNEY.
RELAX, UNPACK YOUR OUTFITS.
THANK YOU.
TREAT THIS PLACE LIKE YOUR OWN.
I’LL CALL YOU WHEN IT’S READY.
ARE YOU HAPPY WITH
YOUR TIMELINE, ADRIAN?
YES.
DO YOU REALIZE
THAT THIS TIMELINE IS
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
FROM THE ONE YOU DID
THE FIRST TIME?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHEN YOU CAME IN
FOR YOUR FIRST SESSION
I ASKED YOU FOR YOUR
FIRST HAPPY MEMORY.
TODAY, YOU WROTE
YOUR FIRST HAPPY MEMORY
WAS THE DAY YOU PASSED
YOUR DRIVING TEST,
WHICH OCCURRED
AT THE AGE OF 18.
YES.
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT
YOU WROTE LAST TIME?
IT’S DIFFERENT?
YES.
UH--
I DON’T UNDERSTAND.
SO, HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT BEING HERE?
STUPID.
EMBARRASSED. ASHAMED.
YOU FEEL
ALL THOSE THINGS?
YES.
WHY?
BECAUSE NOW I CAN SEE
WHAT I DID WRONG.
I CAN SEE THINGS SO CLEARLY
WHEN I’M IN THE RIGHT
FRAME OF MIND,
BUT WHEN I’M WOUND UP, I--
WHAT DO YOU STRUGGLE WITH?
WHAT DOES ANYBODY
STRUGGLE WITH WHEN
THEY’RE WOUND UP?
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
WHY DO YOU HAVE TO QUESTION
EVERYTHING?
I SEE RED. I FEEL
PISSED OFF. ANGRY.
AND YOU’RE ANGRY NOW?
OF COURSE I’M FUCKING ANGRY.
YOU CAN SEE I’M FUCKING ANGRY.
AND WHAT DID WE SAY TO DO
WHEN YOU’RE ANGRY?
DON’T TELL ME.
RELAX.
STAY CALM.
DEEP BREATHS.
IT MIGHT WORK WHEN
I’M IN THE OFFICE,
BUT WHAT ABOUT OUTSIDE?
WHAT ABOUT IN THE REAL WORLD?
I’M NOT IN HERE FOR
PUNCHING A PSYCHIATRIST.
THAT’S GOOD, ADRIAN.
WHAT IS?
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
YOU HAVE BEEN SO HONEST
ABOUT YOUR VULNERABILITY.
OF COURSE, IT DOES MEAN
THAT I WON’T BE ABLE TO
SIGN YOU OFF TODAY.
OKAY. WHAT’S THE MAIN PURPOSE
OF THE VISIT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
WELL, YOU KNOW,
IT’S JUST IT’S BEEN
A LONG TIME, YOU KNOW?
MAIA,
IF YOU WANT ME TO DO
SOMETHING SPECIFIC FOR YOU,
THEN YOU HAVE TO LET ME KNOW
WHAT WE’RE AIMING FOR.
OTHERWISE, YOU WILL
LEAVE UNHAPPY,
AND NONE OF MY CLIENTS
EVER LEAVE UNHAPPY.
THAT’S QUITE A STATEMENT.
I NEED AN ANSWER.
WHEN I SEE THOSE PHOTOS,
I DON’T RECOGNIZE MYSELF.
THAT WAS A DIFFERENT TIME.
THAT WOMAN IS NOT
ME ANYMORE.
SO, WHAT WE’RE TALKING ABOUT
IS REINVENTING YOURSELF.
I GUESS SO, YEAH.
WELL IN THAT CASE,
IT WAS FATE
THAT BROUGHT YOU HERE.
THE THINNESS OF THIS MATERIAL
WILL REALLY PICK UP
YOUR BEAUTIFUL CONTOURS,
MAKE REALLY BEAUTIFUL
SILHOUETTES.
DO YOU THINK MY HIPS
LOOK TOO BIG IN THIS?
IT’S PERFECT.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO GET CHANGED NOW?
YEAH.
OKAY.
UM, LET’S
CHANGE POSITION.
LOOK AT ME.
HEAD DOWN SLIGHTLY.
MORE.
LOOK INTO THE MIRROR.
LOOK AT YOURSELF.
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING ABOUT, MAIA?
DO YOU LIKE WHAT YOU SEE?
[CAMERA CLICKS]
WHAT ABOUT YOUR HUSBAND?
WHAT?
WHEN’S THE LAST TIME
HE HELD YOU? MADE LOVE
TO YOU?
WHAT DOES THAT HAVE
TO DO WITH ANYTHING?
NOTHING. YOU’RE NOT ANSWERING
THESE QUESTIONS, REMEMBER.
STILL, I’D RATHER NOT
TALK ABOUT IT.
THAT BAD, HUH?
PLEASE CHANGE THE SUBJECT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I SAID STOP.
WHOSE FAULT WAS IT?
YOURS OR HIS?
FRANKIE, PLEASE!
EXCELLENT.
YOU’RE GONNA
LOVE THOSE.
GET CHANGED INTO
YOUR NEXT OUTFIT
AND I’LL GET US
SOME WATER.
NICE.
CARRY ON.
WHERE DID YOU DO IT?
THAT’S IT. DON’T LAUGH.
BE SERIOUS.
SCARY.
NO!
CARRY ON.
NICE.
BIT MORE OF THE VIXEN.
VIXEN?
VIXEN.
LOVELY.
DON’T YOU THINK
THEY’RE BEAUTIFUL?
THE DAFFODILS.
NEW LIFE.
NICE. CARRY ON.
AS IF YOU WISH
SOMEONE WERE KISSING YOU.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
ON THE BED.
GOOD.
AND-- TAKE YOUR SHIRT OFF.
WHAT?
TAKE YOUR SHIRT OFF.
WHAT’S THE BIG DEAL?
IT’S JUST-- I’VE NEVER
DONE TOPLESS BEFORE.
IT’S NOT REALLY
GOING TO BE TOPLESS.
TRUST ME.
MMM-HMM. RIGHT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IF THIS IS THE ONLY WAY
TO MAKE YOU FEEL COMFORTABLE,
THEN SO BE IT.
[MAIA] I’M NOT ENTIRELY
SURE THAT IT WILL.
THIS IS THE HUMAN BODY!
THIS IS MY HUMAN BODY.
YOU MAY NOT FIND IT
ON A MAGAZINE,
BUT IT’S MINE,
AND IT’S ALL I HAVE.
AND IN THIS WORLD,
IF SOMEBODY LIKE ME ISN’T SHY,
THEN SOMEBODY LIKE YOU
REALLY SHOULDN’T BE.
[FRANCESCA] I SEE VULNERABLE.
I SEE A REAL WOMAN.
I SEE YOU.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT NOW?
ADRIAN, WHEN YOU
FIRST CAME HERE,
I ASKED YOU FOR YOUR
EARLIEST HAPPY MEMORY.
YOU SAID IT WAS WHEN
YOU MET YOUR PARTNER.
TODAY, YOUR HAPPY MEMORY
IS YEARS EARLIER,
WHEN YOU PASSED
YOUR DRIVING TEST.
ALREADY, YOUR MIND HAS
CHANGED. YOU’VE CHANGED.
NOTHING IS PRE-DESTINED.
YOU CAN CHOOSE TO BE
WHATEVER YOU WANT TO BE.
NOW, IF YOU HAD TO CHOOSE
A WORD TO DESCRIBE HOW YOU FEEL,
NOT NECESSARILY RIGHT NOW,
BUT GENERALLY, RECENTLY,
WHAT WOULD IT BE?
ISOLATION.
GO ON.
QUITE OFTEN. VERY OFTEN,
I DON’T WANT IT TO BE, BUT--
AT TIMES I FEEL THAT
SECLUSION IS THE BEST
THING FOR ME, YOU KNOW?
I TRY SO HARD WITH
THE THE DAY-TO-DAY THINGS.
I GO TO WORK.
I COMMUNICATE WITH PEOPLE,
I EVEN FORCE A SMILE
IF I HAVE TO.
BUT EVEN THEN,
I’M NOT THERE. NOT REALLY.
SO WHY DO YOU DO IT?
GO THROUGH
THE MOTIONS, I MEAN.
WELL, WHAT ELSE IS THERE?
ADRIAN, WHAT IS IT THAT YOU
FEEL THAT YOU’RE MISSING?
LOVE.
LOVE?
WHAT DOES LOVE
MEAN TO YOU?
I THINK ABOUT THE WOMAN
I LOVE.
TA-DA.
OOH. THANKS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN’T
BELIEVE THAT IN A DAY
I FEEL SO MUCH BETTER.
IT’S LIKE I CAN REALLY
BREATHE HERE.
CHEERS. CHEERS.
LISTEN. I’M NOT DOING
ANYTHING THIS WEEKEND.
WHY DON’T YOU STAY AND
I CAN SHOW YOU THE COASTLINE?
IT’S REALLY STUNNING.
SORRY.
NO. IT’S NOT THAT.
I’D LOVE TO STAY.
IT’S JUST, MY HUSBAND
AND I HAVE PLANS THIS--
WELL, LOOK,
THE OFFER’S THERE.
I’M JUST GOING TO
RELAX,
GET SOME FRESH AIR,
AND IT WOULD BE
REALLY LOVELY HAVING
YOU YOU.
THAT’S ALL.
HI, HONEY. UM, NO.
UMM, NO, ACTUALLY.
I-- THAT’S WHAT
I WAS CALLING FOR.
I JUST WANTED TO
SPEAK TO YOU.
UM--
IT’S ABSOLUTELY
BEAUTIFUL HERE
AND THE PHOTOGRAPHER THAT
I’VE BEEN WORKING WITH
ASKED IF I WANTED TO STAY
FOR THE WEEKEND, AND I SAID--
NO. I SAID YES, BECAUSE--
IF YOU COULD
JUST SEE IT HERE,
IT IS SO BEAUTIFUL, AND--
OH, MY GOD. I’M NOT--
I’M NOT COMING HOME TONIGHT.
I’M STAYING FOR THE WEEKEND.
IT’S NOT ABOUT
THE SHOOT ANYMORE.
I JUST WANT TO STAY
FOR THE WEEKEND.
I’M GOING TO STAY.
IT’S ABOUT ME
NEEDING THE SPACE!
I’M STAYING AND
I’LL SEE YOU ON SUNDAY.
[LAUGHING]
IS THERE SOMETHING
WRONG WITH YOUR FOOD?
NO, IT’S LOVELY,
THERE WAS JUST SO MUCH!
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT HAVE
WORKED UP AN APPETITE.
OH, TREAT YOURSELF.
I SUPPOSE YOU’RE RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I’VE HAD SUCH
A GOOD DAY. THANK YOU,
FRANKIE.
DON’T BE SILLY.
YOU WERE FANTASTIC.
THAT WASN’T ME.
I’VE NEVER BEEN DIRECTED
LIKE THAT BEFORE.
BARBARA DIDN’T WARN ME
YOU WERE QUITE SO--
DIRECT.
THAT’S AS GOOD A WORD
AS ANY.
I ALWAYS TELL HER NOT TO.
THE ELEMENT OF SURPRISE
IS CRUCIAL TO MY WORK.
I WAS DEFINITELY SURPRISED.
ESPECIALLY WHEN WE BOTH
ENDED UP HALF NAKED.
I DID NOT SEE THAT COMING.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I DID.
LET ME SEE THE PHOTOS?
I NEVER SHOW MY WORK
UNTIL IT’S READY.
I’M GOING TO GET ANOTHER
BOTTLE OF WINE,
AND YOU GO INTO
THE DRAWING ROOM AND
MAKE YOURSELF COZY.
DRAWING ROOM?
WHAT?
I THOUGHT I JUST
SAW SOMETHING OUTSIDE.
MAYBE IT WAS A CRAZED FARMER.
WHAT CRAZED FARMER?
YOU KNOW PERCY BYSSHE SHELLEY
USED TO LIVE HERE?
THE POET?
YOU KNOW HIM?
BY NAME.
WELL, YOU KNOW HE WAS
THE HUSBAND OF MARY SHELLEY?
AS IN, THE CREATOR
OF "FRANKENSTEIN"?
THE VERY SAME.
AND THIS IS THE VERY SAME HOUSE
WHERE THE STORY OF
"FRANKENSTEIN"
WAS CONCEIVED.
AND YOU DECIDE TO TELL ME
THIS STORY NOW?
ONE NIGHT, A CRAZED FARMER
WITH A SHOTGUN
CAME TO THE HOUSE AND
SHOT AT PERCY THREE TIMES.
REALLY?
WHY?
NOBODY KNOWS,
AND THAT’S PRECISELY
WHAT LED MARY SHELLEY
TO WONDER THE SAME THING.
WHAT MOTIVATES A MONSTER
TO DO SUCH THINGS?
ALAS, THE IDEA
OF FRANKENSTEIN WAS BORN.
HERE?
RIGHT THROUGH THAT WINDOW.
SO, DID IT KILL HIM?
NO. HE DROWNED IN ITALY.
NOT THE LUCKIEST MAN
TO HAVE LIVED, WAS HE?
DESCRIBE HER TO ME.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, DO YOU FIND HER
ATTRACTIVE?
OF COURSE. IF ANYTHING,
SHE’S TOO ATTRACTIVE.
TOO ATTRACTIVE?
YEAH.
HOW SO?
SOMETIMES SHE GETS LOOKS
AND REMARKS OFF SCUMBAG
STRANGERS.
PEOPLE HAVE EVEN COME ON
TO HER IN FRONT OF ME.
AND DOES THAT
MAKE YOU ANGRY?
WELL WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT’S JUST SO GODDAMN
FUCKING RUDE
AND PEOPLE SHOULD
HAVE MORE RESPECT!
CALM DOWN.
DO YOU TRUST HER?
I DON’T TRUST ANYONE.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
JUST A MINUTE.
COME IN.
JUST CHECKING
EVERYTHING’S ALL RIGHT.
EVERYTHING’S
PERFECT, FRANKIE.
THANK YOU.
RIGHT.
WELL, I’M JUST DOWN
THE HALL IF YOU WANT
ANYTHING.
OKAY.
GIVE ME A SHOUT
IF YOU NEED ME.
WILL DO.
SHE’S SO INDEPENDENT,
AND ALTHOUGH THAT’S
ONE OF THE THINGS
I LOVE ABOUT HER,
I ALSO HATE IT.
THERE ARE MOMENTS
WHEN I WANT HER TO NEED ME.
WHAT, YOU NEED TO FEEL VALUED?
YOU WANT ATTENTION
AND AFFECTION?
YES.
WELL, THAT’S LIKE ANYBODY.
THAT’S NOT UNCOMMON.
IT’S NOT?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
IT’S PERFECTLY NATURAL.
SOMETIMES I JUST WATCH HER.
AND TO LOOK AT HER
WHEN SHE DOESN’T KNOW,
I CAN REALLY SEE
HER VULNERABILITY.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
FRANKIE?
FRANKIE, IS THAT YOU?
THEY’RE THE MOMENTS
I ENJOY THE MOST.
I’M NOT SURE
OF YOUR MEANING.
WHAT MEANING?
ARE YOU TELLING ME
THAT YOU’VE NEVER
LOOKED OR WATCHED
A LOVED ONE
WHEN THEY’RE BUSY
OR WHEN THEY’RE ASLEEP?
IT’S SO PEACEFUL.
AND IN THESE MOMENTS,
THEY DON’T EVEN KNOW
THEY’RE YOUR WHOLE WORLD.
I’M GOING TO BREAK
ONE OF MY RULES.
OKAY.
SERIOUSLY?
I THINK YOU NEED
TO SEE SOME OF THESE.
OOH!
ONLY A FEW, MIND.
OKAY.
CLICK LEFT TO SCROLL.
MMM-HMM.
WHAT IS THIS?
IT’S YOU AND A LITTLE GIRL
CALLED CHLOE.
DON’T SAY THAT NAME.
WHO’S CHLOE?
I SAID DON’T!
YOU DON’T HAVE THE RIGHT
TO DO THIS!
I’M SORRY, MAIA.
IT’S JUST I’VE NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
I DIDN’T MEAN TO HURT YOU.
I JUST SAW SUCH BEAUTY
IN THAT MOMENT.
ANYWAY, IT’S YOUR
PRIVATE BUSINESS,
SO YOU SHOULDN’T HAVE
TO TALK ABOUT IT
IF YOU DON’T WANT TO.
I PROMISED TO
SHOW YOU AROUND.
IT’S REALLY PEACEFUL HERE.
IT COULD BE JUST WHAT YOU NEED.
I REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
I CAME OUT HERE.
I WAS ABSOLUTELY PETRIFIED.
THE BOAT ROCKS SO BLOODY MUCH,
DOESN’T IT?
I’M TAKING YOU TO
A REALLY SECLUDED BEACH.
IT’S SO QUIET.
I COULD GO AND COME BACK
WITHOUT SEEING ANYBODY.
ONE OR TWO PEOPLE--
THAT IS A BUSY DAY.
IT’S THE CLOSEST THING WE’VE
GOT ROUND HERE TO PARADISE.
FREEZING, ISN’T IT?
[MAIA] ISN’T IT STRANGE
HOW SOMETIMES YOU
CAN FORGET TO FEEL?
WE TRIED SO HARD,
MY HUSBAND AND I.
FOR YEARS WE DID
EVERYTHING BY THE BOOK.
WE WERE DESPERATE
TO START A FAMILY,
AND THE DAY I FELT PREGNANT,
I KNEW. I JUST KNEW.
AND THE TEST
CAME BACK POSITIVE,
OH, YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN
THE LOOK ON HIS FACE.
HE PICKED ME UP IN HIS ARMS
AND WE MADE LOVE FOR HOURS.
I’D NEVER KNOWN HIM
TO BE SO TENDER.
HE INSISTED WE GO OUT
FOR DINNER TO CELEBRATE
AND ANNOUNCED THE PREGNANCY
TO THE WHOLE RESTAURANT,
AND THEY CHEERED
AND CONGRATULATED US.
IT WAS SURREAL,
TO FEEL SO IMPORTANT,
LIKE SOMETHING
OUT OF A MOVIE.
IT WAS THE BEST
NIGHT OF MY LIFE.
HOW DO YOU FEEL RIGHT NOW?
IF YOU HAD TO CHOOSE
ONE WORD,
ONE OVERRIDING EMOTION,
WHAT WOULD IT BE?
LOSS.
UNBEARABLE LOSS.
WE’VE LOST QUITE A LOT.
WE’VE LOST OUR WORLD,
AND I’M SO DESPERATELY
TRYING TO GET IT BACK.
I’VE JUST NO IDEA WHAT TO DO,
AND EVERYTHING I DO DO
JUST PUSHES HER FURTHER AWAY,
AND I DON’T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WHEN I ASKED YOU ABOUT YOUR
HAPPIEST MEMORY TOGETHER,
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT YOU SAID?
YES.
I SPOKE ABOUT
WHEN WE FIRST MET.
IT WAS SO NATURAL,
SO EXCITING.
THE FIRST TOUCH.
OUR FIRST KISS.
MY STOMACH WAS IN KNOTS,
BUT THEN WHEN I FELT
HER HEART BEAT SO WILDLY,
I KNEW SHE FELT THE SAME AND--
I KNEW EVERYTHING
WOULD BE OKAY.
EVERYTHING WAS FINE UNTIL
MY BODY STARTED TO CHANGE.
I PANICKED.
ALL THOSE YEARS OF
DIETING AND EXERCISE,
AND THEN SUDDENLY
I HAD NO REGIME.
EVEN WHEN I TRIED,
I COULDN’T
KEEP THE WEIGHT OFF.
I WORRIED THAT MY BODY WOULD
NEVER BE THE SAME AGAIN.
I STARTED TO IGNORE ALL THE
ADVICE THAT OUR DOCTOR GAVE ME
AND SUDDENLY,
I JUST HATED THE PREGNANCY
AND I WISHED THAT THE BABY
WOULD COME OUT OF ME.
IN THE END, SHE DID.
IT WAS ME THAT KILLED HER,
AND MY HUSBAND KNOWS IT,
AND NOW I HAVE NOTHING.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
ME AND MY HUSBAND,
WE’RE GOOD PEOPLE.
WE WANTED NOTHING MORE
THAN TO HAVE THAT BABY.
AND YOU’RE ANGRY
BECAUSE YOU FEEL CHEATED?
CHEATED?
NO. THAT DOESN’T EVEN
BEGIN TO COVER IT.
TO LOSE A BABY IS ONE THING,
BUT TO COMPLETE A PREGNANCY,
AND THEY TELL YOU THAT THERE’S
NOTHING THEY CAN DO--
WHEN YOU HAVE TO
GIVE BIRTH TO YOUR BABY
AND THERE’S
NOTHING BUT SILENCE,
AND YOUR CHILD’S THERE
TO LOOK AT,
AND SHE’S THERE
FOR YOU TO HOLD
BUT YOU KNOW YOU
CAN’T TAKE HER HOME.
TO KNOW THAT YOU’VE
GONE THAT FAR,
AND YOU’LL NEVER GET TO
KNOW HER, IS JUST--
HEY.
WHAT YOU HAD
TO GO THROUGH,
IT’S NOT FAIR,
BUT COME ON.
YOU THINK YOU’RE
THE ONLY WOMAN
THAT TRIES TO KEEP IN SHAPE
WHILE SHE’S PREGNANT?
I’VE BEEN AROUND MODELS
ALL MY LIFE,
AND BELIEVE ME MAIA, YOU’RE
NOT THE ONE WITH PROBLEMS.
IT WASN’T YOU FAULT.
MY HUSBAND DOESN’T
EVEN LOOK AT ME IN
THE SAME WAY ANYMORE.
I THINK WE’RE OVER.
WELL, SHAME ON HIM.
AND IF WHAT YOU SAY IS TRUE
THEN DARE I SAY IT,
MAYBE IT WASN’T
SUCH A BAD THING.
NO, HE’S A GOOD MAN.
NO MEN ARE GOOD, MAIA.
WHY DO YOU THINK
I’M THE WAY I AM?
TRUST ME,
YOU HAVE ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT.
EVERYTHING WILL FALL
INTO PLACE, YOU’LL SEE.
I WISH I COULD--
WHAT?
I DON’T KNOW, BE MORE FREE,
SELF-ASSURED, COMFORTABLE
WITH WHO I AM, LIKE YOU.
LIKE ME?
YEAH.
YOU’RE SO TOGETHER
AND HAPPY.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU WANT
AND DON’T CARE WHAT YOU SAY,
YOU JUST DO IT ANYWAY.
YOU’RE IN COMPLETE CONTROL
OF YOU LIFE AND IT’S ADMIRABLE.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU THINK OF ME?
OF COURSE.
THE BEACH IS
JUST OVER THERE.
LET’S BRING HER IN.
DO YOU HAVE ANY FAMILY?
UMM, JUST
MY PARENTS.
NO BROTHERS
OR SISTERS.
ONE AUNT.
MY LAST REMAINING
GRANDPARENT DIED
LAST YEAR.
MY GRANDMA WAS ONE
OF THE FEW PEOPLE
I COULD TALK TO,
SO LAST YEAR WAS
DEFINITELY ONE
TO FORGET.
WHAT ABOUT HOBBIES?
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
DO YOU HAVE ANY?
UMM, NO.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING.
DOES WALLOWING
IN SELF-PITY COUNT?
[LAUGHS]
I’M GLAD
THAT AMUSES YOU.
I NEVER REALIZED
THIS PLACE WAS SO VAST.
I WISH I LIVED HERE.
WHAT’S WRONG
WITH LONDON?
IT’S TOO CROWDED.
TOO CLAUSTROPHOBIC.
SOMETIMES IT GETS SO MUCH
I FEEL LIKE I CAN’T BREATHE.
[FRANCESCA] NAME
YOUR FAVORITE ANIMAL
AND THREE REASONS WHY.
[MAIA] WHAT IS THIS?
[FRANCESCA]
I’M ANALYZING YOU.
[MAIA] OH.
[FRANCESCA] AND,
ONLY ONE-WORD ANSWERS.
[MAIA] REALLY?
[FRANCESCA] REALLY.
[MAIA] UM, A CAT,
BECAUSE THEY ARE LOVING,
LOYAL AND PRETTY.
MMM, OKAY.
NOW YOUR FAVORITE
WILD ANIMAL, AND
THREE REASONS WHY.
OOH. WILD ANIMAL?
UM, A TIGER, BECAUSE
THEY ARE DANGEROUS,
POWERFUL AND
FEROCIOUSLY STUNNING.
OKAY.
THAT MAKES SENSE.
OH GOD, IS THIS WHERE
YOU TELL ME I’M IN DENIAL
BECAUSE ON
BOTH OCCASIONS
I CHOSE A PUSSY?
[LAUGHS]
NO!
THE DOMESTIC ANIMAL
IS HOW PEOPLE SEE YOU.
THE WILD ANIMAL IS HOW
YOU WISH TO BE SEEN.
AH.
SO, DOES NOTHING ELSE
EXCITE YOU
OTHER THAN MODELING?
HONESTLY? NO.
IT SOUNDS SO DESPERATE
WHEN I SAY IT,
BUT IT’S TRULY THE
ONLY THING I’M GOOD AT.
THERE’S REALLY
NOTHING ELSE TO ME.
I WOULDN’T SAY THAT.
[GURGLING]
IT’S OKAY. YOU’RE OKAY.
[BAR PATRONS LAUGHING]
♪ ...I’M TOUCHED
BY AN ANGEL ♪
♪ SO BE IT, I’M HERE ♪
♪ I’M YOURS NOW ♪
♪ TO KEEP ♪
♪ ’CAUSE WITHOUT YOU
I STUMBLE, I FALL ♪
♪ AND TONIGHT
YOU’RE IN MY DREAMS ♪
♪ WHEN I SLEEP ♪
♪ WITHOUT YOU I AM WEAK ♪
♪ I AM WEAK ♪
♪ SO COME BACK TO ME
TODAY ♪
♪ I’M WITH YOU, MY DEAR. ♪
[APPLAUSE]
WHAT?
YOU’VE ONLY
BEEN HERE ONE DAY
AND ALREADY PROVIDED ME
WITH THE MOST INCREDIBLE
STORY.
YOU SAVED A LIFE TODAY.
OH, MY GOD. I HADN’T
THOUGHT ABOUT IT
LIKE THAT.
[LAUGHS]
WHAT OTHER WAY IS THERE
TO THINK ABOUT IT?
I DON’T KNOW. I JUST
PULLED A MAN OUT OF
THE WATER, I GUESS.
BOLLOCKS.
OH, DON’T BE SILLY.
ANYONE WOULD HAVE
DONE THE SAME THING.
CHEERS.
[LAUGHING]
HEY, LOVE? LOVE?
KNOW ANY K.D. LANG?
I NEED A PISS.
THANKS FOR THAT.
GET THEM IN, BOYS.
♪ SHE ONLY GOT
AWAY FROM IT ALL ♪
♪ FOR JUST ONE DAY
TO FEEL FREE ♪
♪ TO OPEN UP
AND MOVE ♪
♪ IN HER OWN WAY... ♪
YOU ALL RIGHT, SEXY?
GONNA PUT ON A BIT
OF A SHOW FOR US LATER?
KEEP YOUR
KNICKERS ON, LOVE.
ONE MORE COMMENT AND I WILL
SLICE YOUR FUCKING BALLS.
WE’RE GOING HOME.
FRANKIE. FRANKIE,
HANG ON A SECOND.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT HAPPENED IN THERE?
FRANKIE--
I CAN’T STAND
OBNOXIOUS PEOPLE.
I JUST TOLD HIM TO STOP
BEING SUCH A PIG.
OH, YEAH, AND I’M SURE
HE LISTENED TO THAT.
COME ON, TELL ME.
WHAT HAPPENED IN THERE?
LET’S JUST SAY HE WON’T HAVE
THE BALLS TO SAY ANYTHING
LIKE THAT TO YOU AGAIN.
REALLY? YOU STOOD UP FOR ME.
I NEVER LET ANYBODY
SHAKE UP MY GIRL.
LET’S GO HOME.
[SIGHING]
MM-HMM.
COME IN.
I BROUGHT YOU
SOME FRESH TOWELS.
WHICH I’VE ALREADY DONE.
I COMPLETELY FORGOT. SORRY.
FRANKIE, WAIT.
THANK YOU. YOU KNOW,
FOR WHAT YOU DID
FOR ME TONIGHT.
THAT’S ALL RIGHT.
I JUST FEEL
THE NEED TO PROTECT
YOU, THAT’S ALL.
AND WHEN YOU PICTURE HER
WITH SOMEONE ELSE?
WHY WOULD YOU SAY THAT?
WHY WOULD YOU PUT THAT VIVID,
SICK IMAGE IN MY HEAD?
STAY CALM.
I AM CALM.
I’M SIMPLY ASKING.
YOU SAID YOU
DIDN’T TRUST ANYONE,
SO PRESUMABLY YOU’VE
PICTURED HER WITH OTHER PEOPLE.
YES.
AND HOW DOES IT
MAKE YOU FEEL?
JEALOUS.
I SEE RED. I HAVE THOUGHTS
OF HURTING THAT PERSON.
YOU HAVE VIOLENT THOUGHTS?
YES.
WOULD YOU SAY THAT YOU’RE
A VIOLENT PERSON?
COME ON! YOU’VE SEEN
WHAT I’VE DONE.
YES, BUT I’M NOT HERE
TO JUDGE YOU.
THIS IS JUST A PIECE
OF PAPER, WHEREAS YOU
ARE A PERSON.
I WANT TO KNOW IF YOU
SEE YOURSELF AS VIOLENT.
NO.
[GASPS]
WHAT IS IT?
THERE’S SOMEONE THERE.
THERE’S NO ONE
AROUND FOR MILES.
NO. THERE’S
SOMEONE THERE
AND I SAW THE SAME
THING LAST NIGHT
OUTSIDE MY ROOM.
LAST NIGHT?
YOU DIDN’T
SAY ANYTHING.
I THOUGHT IT WAS YOU,
AND THEN I WOKE UP
AND I FORGOT.
LOOK, THERE’S SOMEONE
OUT THERE.
HELLO? IS THERE
ANYBODY ANYBODY THERE?
THEY MUST HAVE MOVED.
I JUST WANT
TO CHECK OUTSIDE.
SO, THERE’S NOBODY
INSIDE THE HOUSE,
AND--
THERE’S NOBODY
OUTSIDE THE HOUSE.
I SAW SOMEONE.
I DON’T KNOW WHAT
TO TELL YA, BABE.
I’VE LIVED HERE
EIGHT YEARS AND NEVER
HAD ANY PROBLEMS.
BUT THAT’S
THE SECOND TIME NOW.
SO YOU SAY--
BUT THE ONLY PERSON I FOUND
WALKING AROUND THE HOUSE
LAST NIGHT WAS YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
NOTHING. IT’S JUST
BEEN A LONG WEEKEND.
YOU’RE TIRED--
ARE YOU SAYING
I’M MAKING THIS UP?
NOT ON PURPOSE.
BUT, THAT’S TWICE--
MAIA, WHERE IS
THE EVIDENCE
THAT THERE’S BEEN
ANYBODY ELSE IN THIS
HOUSE OTHER THAN US?
WHY DON’T WE GO
AND LOCK UP
EVERY SINGLE DOOR
AND WINDOW
AND CARRY ON FROM
WHERE WE LEFT OFF?
NO. IT JUST DOESN’T
FEEL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT. THEN I’LL
COME AND TUCK YOU UP
AND MAKE SURE
THE BOOGEYMAN DOESN’T
COME AND GET YOU.
NO. NOT ABOUT THAT.
ABOUT US.
OH.
NOT TO WORRY.
YOU GO UP AND--
I’LL LOCK UP DOWN HERE
AND I WILL CALL YOU
IN THE MORNING.
I’M REALLY S-
GO TO BED, MAIA.
ARE YOU THINKING OF HER?
ALWAYS.
I ADORE HER.
AND WHAT IS IT YOU MOST MISS?
I MISS--
LAYING NEXT TO HER.
[ADRIAN]
I MISS THE TOUCH OF HER SKIN.
THE SMELL OF HER HAIR.
SHE KEEPS ME WARM.
SHE MAKES ME FEEL WARM.
THAT’S WHAT ALLOWS ME
TO REMEMBER.
NO, STOP IT!
GET OFF!
WHAT’S WRONG?
MAIA, WHAT THE FUCK
IS WRONG?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I THOUGHT THAT’D BE
PRETTY OBVIOUS.
I WAS ASLEEP!
MAIA, YOU’RE THE ONE
THAT CAME IN HERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
JUST GO BACK TO YOUR ROOM.
BUT FRANKIE, I--
SHHH. I HONESTLY THOUGHT
THAT I’D HAD MY FAIR SHARE
OF WHACK JOBS RECENTLY,
BUT YOU--
FRANKIE, LET ME EXPLAIN.
NO! I’VE HAD ENOUGH OF THIS!
I GUESS WE CAN RULE OUT
AN INTRUDER IN THE HOUSE
BECAUSE YOU ARE FUCKING CRAZY!
JUST GET OUT!
AND WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER?
THAT WE’LL SURVIVE.
THAT WE’LL BE OKAY.
BUT THERE’S JUST ONE PROBLEM.
WHICH IS?
I THINK SHE’S
HAVING AN AFFAIR.
[CLANGING]
OH, FOR GOD’S SAKE, MAIA.
PUT SOME CLOTHES ON.
I’M SORRY.
I JUST LITERALLY--
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FOR BREAKFAST?
UM--
ARE YOU REALLY NOT
GOING BACK TO BED?
I CAN’T SLEEP.
BUT IT’S SO EARLY.
WELL, I THOUGHT
IF WE GOT UP EARLY
THEN WE COULD DO
WHAT WE PLANNED
AND YOU CAN GET
AN EARLY TRAIN BACK.
MAYBE I SHOULD
JUST GO STRAIGHT
TO THE STATION NOW.
NO, NO. WE MADE PLANS.
IT WON’T TAKE US LONG
TO DO THEM.
EGGS, BACON AND TOAST.
YEAH. THAT SOUNDS GREAT.
THANKS.
GET YOURSELF WASHED.
BE READY IN 20 MINUTES.
I WANT TO
SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
FRANKIE.
OH, WHAT IS IT NOW?
ARE YOU STUCK?
SOMEHOW, YES I AM.
FRANKIE, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING? HELP ME UP.
YOU KNOW, I WAS ABOUT TO,
BUT MAYBE THIS
IS THE PERFECT TIME
TO GET A FEW THINGS
OFF MY CHEST.
YOU’RE KIDDING ME, RIGHT?
NO, MAIA. NO, I’M NOT.
WHAT DOES IT FEEL LIKE, MAIA,
TO KNOW WHAT YOU WANT?
TO BE SO CLOSE
TO ACHIEVING IT,
TO PHYSICALLY SEE
WHAT IT IS THAT YOU WANT,
AND THEN TO BE TOLD NO
RIGHT AT THE LAST SECOND?
PRETTY FRUSTRATING, HUH?
WELL, I GUESS
THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU START
LETTING YOURSELF GO.
THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS
EATING LIKE A LITTLE FAT PIG
SEEM TO HAVE CAUGHT UP
WITH YOU.
STOP IT, FRANKIE!
IT’S A SHAME YOU DIDN’T EAT
LIKE THAT WHEN YOU WERE
CARRYING CHLOE.
HOW COULD YOU BE SO SPITEFUL?
HELP ME UP!
DID YOU JUST TELL ME
WHAT TO DO?
HAVE YOU EVEN GRASPED
THE SITUATION?
I MEAN, I KNOW YOU ARE NOT
THE SHARPEST TOOL IN THE SHED,
BUT YOU DO REALIZE THAT
YOU ARE IN NO POSITION
TO BE MAKING DEMANDS
RIGHT NOW?
I’M NOT KIDDING. I--
I DON’T THINK I CAN BREATHE.
OH, BUT YOU CAN, YOU SEE?
THAT’S THE BEAUTY OF IT.
THERE’S ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING WRONG WITH YOU.
IT’S JUST THAT YOU’VE
LOST CONTROL, A LITTLE BIT,
LIKE LAST NIGHT. MAYBE IT’S
A MENTAL, PSYCHOTIC TICK
THAT YOU HAVE.
[SOBBING]
SHHH!
CAN YOU HEAR THAT?
MAIA, CAN YOU HEAR THAT?
THAT IS THE SOUND
OF NOBODY CARING.
SOUND FAMILIAR? BITCH!
YOUR FUCKING HUSBAND
HAD A LUCKY ESCAPE.
HE’S BEEN DISCOVERING
ALL WEEKEND
HOW FUCKING BETTER
HIS LIFE IS WITHOUT YOU.
HE’S PROBABLY BEEN FUCKING
SOME LITTLE WHORE EVERY NIGHT,
WHILE YOU’VE BEEN HERE
TRYING TO FUCK WITH MY HEAD!
[SCREAMING, SOBBING]
[MAIA SOBBING]
OH, ARE YOU SAD, PRINCESS?
HAS SOMETHING HAPPENED
TO UPSET YOU?
WELL, GOOD.
MAYBE NOW YOU’LL UNDERSTAND.
COMING HERE, TREATING ME
LIKE AN EXPERIMENT
FOR A CONFIDENCE BOOST.
AND DID YOU EVER
THINK ABOUT ME?
ASK ABOUT MY LIFE?
MY PROBLEMS? NO!
BECAUSE YOUR LIFE IS
SO FUCKING IMPORTANT!
WELL, NEVER MIND.
LOOKS AS THOUGH YOU’RE
GETTING YOUR COMEUPPANCE
NOW, DOESN’T IT?
YOU SELF-OBSESSED,
MIND-GAME PLAYING,
ATTENTION-SEEKING
LITTLE CUNT!
STOP IT!
STOP IT, FRANKIE!
OOP.
STOP IT! STOP IT!
OOH.
OOH. THAT IS NOT
A GOOD LOOK.
I SEE UGLY.
JUST SAY PLEASE, MAIA.
PLEASE. PLEASE.
I COULDN’T HEAR THAT.
PLEASE!
JUST A LITTLE LOUDER.
ALL RIGHT.
SEEING AS YOU
ASKED SO NICELY.
[FRANCESCA] I’M SORRY. MAIA.
I JUST WANT TO GO HOME!
NO, NOT LIKE THIS.
YOU CAN STAY ANOTHER NIGHT,
AND I’LL TAKE YOU HOME TOMORROW.
I WANT TO GO HOME.
WELL, YOU CAN’T,
SO WHY DON’T YOU STOP
BEING SO SELFISH
AND TRY AND REPAIR
SOME OF THE DAMAGE
THAT YOU’VE JUST DONE?
THE DAMAGE THAT I’VE DONE?
WHAT THE FUCK
IS WRONG WITH YOU?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU CAN’T MAKE SOMEONE
LOVE YOU.
YOU’RE FUCKING CRAZY.
LIKE, WHY WOULD I WANT
TO SPEND ANY MORE TIME
WITH YOU EVER AGAIN?
HOW COULD I?
WE HAVE SOMETHING SPECIAL.
SPECIAL? I HATE YOU!
THE WAY YOU MADE ME FEEL
LAST NIGHT.
YOU SAID THAT YOU LOVED IT.
THE WAY YOU MADE ME
FEEL IN THERE?
WHEN I WAS TRAPPED AND SCARED,
AND THE THINGS THAT YOU SAID,
THAT’S THE WORST
THAT I’VE EVER FELT!
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
FINE.
NOW TRY GETTING HOME,
YOU LITTLE FUCKING TEASE.
PLEASE MAIA. PLEASE DON’T.
PLEASE STAY STAY STAY, PLEASE!
GET OFF ME!
I’M SO SORRY! PLEASE STAY!
NO!!!
[SCREAMS]
[END MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC FADES]