THE MOTHER TREE
(Kaidan Chibusa Enoki)
A Mitsugu Okura Production
Based on the Story "Enchou Sanyuutei",
written by Torao Tanabe
Assistant Director
Hiromichi Takebe
Starring
Katsuko Wakasugi
Akira Nakamura
Asao Matsumoto
Directed by
Goro Katono
What brought you back from
near-bankruptcy three years ago...
...is your ability.
It has nothing to do with
that simple painting of mine.
No, Shigenobu-sensei.
That is the brushwork of
the greatest artist in Edo.
Look how enticingly
her hair hangs.
It is a masterpiece.
It's not that good!
Indeed it is! This establishment
has prospered...
...on customers
wishing to view it.
If he is to paint for you,
have him do something colorful.
Fireworks, perhaps.
Fireworks on a temple
folding-screen?
Well, Sensei?
Perhaps a "sumi" ink painting...
...of the married dragons.
The progenitors of humanity...
Yes, Sensei, please!
I'll express what I've come
since my marriage to feel.
I very much hope
you will do that.
Excuse me.
Thank you for waiting.
The boat's ready.
Your man Shosuke insists
on poling it himself!
Look, Mayotaro...it's done.
This is for you.
He's asleep!
Look.
There's Takeroku up there.
Takeroku? That nice young lad?
I said I'd paint something for him
and I haven't even touched a brush!
Land us at the bridge.
Yes, sir.
"Cold Dumplings"
Don't worry. I'll do if for you.
That would be wonderful, sir!
Thank you very much!
We'll be looking for you
to come by.
Thank you!
I'll look forward to it.
Whoops! Careful on the stones,
Missus!
Don't drop the baby!
A pretty woman!
Namihei! Were you here
all along?
I couldn't take my eyes off her!
As usual, eh?
Who was that man
you were with?
Hishikawa Shigenobu.
A famous Tosa
and ukiyoe painter.
I see...
What is it?
I like painting. I'd like to find
someone good to learn from.
Could you help me become
a student of his?
I couldn't do that!
Not even for a friend.
My master dismissed me because
I was too interested in painting.
Yes, but still...
Wait!
I'm sure you can do something.
Are you sure you can't help?
But...
I know it's not much.
Don't be so damn proper!
I see...
All right, Namihei.
Taking so long over this...
I must be losing my touch!
You have too much to do.
The Nanzoin Temple has asked
again when you will come.
How long has it been
since I said I'd go there?
All right, I'll go now.
Tell Shosuke
to get my things ready.
I will.
It's such a help to have
a student like Namihei here.
He's very nice, isn't he.
The baby always likes
Namihei to hold him.
Did he buy you that comb?
Well, this is goodbye for a while.
There's my boy!
Be good till I get back.
Are you leaving now?
Yes. But don't worry.
I'll be back soon.
But I'll miss you...
Getting this job done
will be a load off my shoulders.
Take care of things.
I will.
I leave the women
of my house in your care.
Have no fear. Put your heart
into your work.
Kise, if there are any problems,
discuss them with Namihei.
Take good care of the boy.
Take care of your health,
and come home soon.
Don't worry.
Dear...
I'll be going.
Make yourself at home, Takeroku.
It's always a pleasure to see you.
No, we should go.
I feel guilty about being received
so well with your husband away.
I'm not saying this
just to be polite...
but I can't imagine leaving
such a pretty wife alone...
to go to some country temple
and paint!
Don't prattle that way!
But...
That's all right.
I'm very grateful
to Takeroku.
And why would that be?
It's because of him
we have a student like you.
You embarrass me.
Takeroku, it's getting late.
We should go.
But you've come all this way
to see that we're all right!
With the Sensei away...
...it's unseemly for us
to be here too long.
Oh, no!
It's time to go.
What's wrong?!
I'm sorry...I sometimes
have these spasms...
Does it hurt?
Please...bring me a cup
of hot water...quickly!
Just lay quietly.
Hana!
One more thing...
Move that in here.
What are you doing?!
Keep quiet!
Stop that!
I'll scream if you don't stop!
Go ahead.
I wasn't sick.
I think about you all the time.
I dream about you!
What do you want?
I love you more than
I love life itself!
This is wrong! Let go of me!
You mustn't!
Kise!
No! Let go!
If you refuse, I'll kill you
then kill myself!
If you want me so much,
then take me
and then kill me.
I'm a married woman.
This cannot be!
Then I'll take this child with us!
Wait!
Then you accept that it's my fate
to risk my life for love of you?
This is unfair!
To force yourself on a weak woman
by using an innocent babe...
...is cowardice worse than villainy!
Call me villain or call me demon,
I will pleasure you!
Shigenobu!
Be too much in the mind
and the body pays.
Your Reverence...
I don't know if it will help,
but have some tea.
I sent Hana on an errand.
We won't be disturbed.
You're nothing but a beast
in human form!
And now you're my mate!
You're an adulteress.
We're animals together.
You disgust me!
Ye Gods, forgive me!
As you wish.
Now, while we have time...
Take your hands off me!
The Sensei's coming home?!
I thought he'd be there
for weeks!
Kise!
No!
What do you think you're doing?!
You saw us!
You!
I don't know anything!
I swear I'll say nothing...
...about the two of you!
"Two"?
No, I mean...
You said "two"!
Please!
So you know!
I can't leave you alive
when you know our secret!
I know nothing!
Then will you do as I tell you?
I'm just an old...
Will you?
Well?
Yes! Whatever you say!
Some rich food is welcome
after so long a time.
I thought fish might be welcome
after weeks of temple life.
What do you think?
I've put my heart into it.
You'd think they were alive.
All that's left is the eyes.
I want eyes that might see
right into the next world!
But perhaps, Sensei,
you're working too hard.
I was speaking of this
to Shosuke.
Perhaps you might go
to see the fireflies at Ochiai.
Go out and wander around?
Yes. Good health requires
occasional rest.
Is that not so?
I've heard the fireflies
at Ochiai are a wonderful sight.
Shosuke, come with me.
I will.
I follow you, Sensei.
What?
Nothing.
Who are you?
What are you waiting for?
But...
Fool! Get going!
You!
Yes! Namihei!
You're an inconvenience.
So if you'll excuse me...
Have you gone mad?!
You fool!
Why would you hate me?
Tell me why!
Silence, dead man!
You'll pay for this!
To hell with you!
You'll pay!
Though you kill me
I will not die...
while my dragons
have no eyes!
Stubborn bastard!
Mayotaro!
Hello!
I thought this might happen.
You've gone and done it now!
You saw me!
I wouldn't do that!
The watch is to be told
if I don't happen to come back.
Why are you drinking
all that water?
What's happened to you?
It was horrible!
The Sensei was attacked
by thieves!
He's dead!
What nonsense is this?
Shigenobu came back here
and went straight to work!
It can't be!
Shosuke, what do you see?
Shosuke!
What's wrong?
Help!
Your Reverence!
What's the matter?
We found the Sensei
under Ochiai Bridge!
What?
His spirit yet wanders
among us...
"May his soul rest in peace."
I'll arrange a proper wedding.
Please say you'll marry me.
Please, Kise...
Kise! This has gone far enough!
We've lain together!
Where's the harm in it?
Soon people will stop talking,
and forget the Sensei.
Never!
You'll submit to me!
No! Don't touch me!
You'll do as I say,
even if I have to use force!
I loathe you!
Oh, you do?
Then I have nothing to lose!
Shut up!
Put that damn child to sleep!
With his father dead,
my milk has dried up.
The poor thing!
What do you want?
Girls...
Enjoy yourselves.
You know what I want.
You scratch my back, and I
scratch yours. Need I say more?
How much are you going to
wring out of me?
Don't tell me you've forgotten!
I mean, if I were to...
That's enough! Have a drink.
Really?
Good! I don't talk this way
because I like to, you know.
Let me pour you one.
Anyway, squire...
I'm a little short again.
What?
If it's a problem,
don't worry.
I would have asked earlier,
but you were busy...
Enough!
Don't ask me here.
Come with me to the house.
I'll give you something then.
Well, I'm certainly glad
to hear that!
I've made some broth
for the little boy.
Thank you.
I could never find a wet-nurse
for him this late at night.
Missus, even during the day...
We've been refused?
I've searched all over,
asked everywhere...
but because of the way
the Sensei passed on...
...all the wet-nurses are afraid.
I see...
If it goes on like this,
he'll die...
My poor baby!
Forgive me!
Rokusho Shrine
The Mother Tree
Give him to me.
Dear!
I don't care what happens to me.
I'll raise Mayotaro
so he may take revenge.
For that...
...I will live through any shame.
Until that day, forgive my sins!
When that day comes
I will appear.
Only then will I be able
to paint
the eyes of the twin dragons.
Dear!
Spirits!
Come back!
What's going on?
What's the Missus
doing out here now?
Kise?
You!
Fiend!
I can't do a thing like that!
Oh, stop whining!
I'll tell Kise he'll stay with
a family in your village.
I owe the Sensei gratitude!
I can't do that to his son!
It's cold-blooded murder!
The Sensei again?
Who helped kill that Sensei
you owe so much to?
We can both be crucified
for that!
Please!
I just can't do it!
Quiet!
You'll do as I say if you value
your life! Do you hear me?!
"Come to the Mother Tree."
"The Mother Tree."
Well?
I'll do it.
But please, ask no more of me!
I can't do that.
You're tied to me for life!
You're really taking him to
the best family in the village?
Fool! Don't you trust Shosuke?
But...
Shosuke's gone to
a lot of trouble over this!
Why are you crying?
He'll be much better off
with a healthy village wet-nurse.
Won't he?
Missus, I...
Well, Shosuke...
Yes?
Take good care of my boy.
Have no fear, Missus.
Tell them if anything happens...
that I'll hurry right there.
I'll be on my way, then.
You will?
I do this from fear of him.
Please don't hate me, child.
That Namihei is a demon!
Mayotaro!
Namihei said to throw you
into that river...
...but I know I heard
Hana's voice.
Pardon me, boy...
I'll leave you here.
Well, Shosuke? Did you do it?
Yes, I did.
You drowned him?
I did.
Well done, Shosuke.
Now I take leave of you.
You what?
Who are you?
We're leaving!
I can't go just like that!
Do you want to see your boy
or not?! Get ready!
My boy?
Stop wasting time!
We're going to see him!
Really?
That's Mayotaro!
Fool! Mayotaro's dead!
What? But you said...
That was to get you
away from Edo with me!
You killed Mayotaro!
It wasn't me!
Villain! Fiend!
Mayotaro!
I'll go to hell for this child...
before I let anyone kill him!
Yes, Namihei! Go mad!
Go mad!
Fall into hell!
Missus...
You have done well, Kise.
Now I arise
to paint in the dragons' eyes.
I leave Mayotaro in your care.
Dear!
What are you doing here?
The dragons have eyes!
His spirit is with us!
Shigenobu will watch over him!
Take good care...
...of my boy.
Rest with Buddha!
The End