Here's to Claudel.
Careful, Maurice,
there's bacon in the potatoes.
Not very kosher.
I eat it.
I'm flabbergasted.
It's the first time I've seen
someone of the Jewish persuasion
eating pork.
I eat everything.
I think you're a fine actor.
Why don't you get more work?
I'm doing a Claudel play
in Besacon in May...
Why is it good if he eats bacon?
Excuse me?
As if you enjoyed seeing someone
of the "Jewish persuasion" eat it.
- I don't quite understand.
- My wife means...
That wasn't called for.
Yes, it was.
I'm sick of these putdowns.
He keeps harping on it.
I just meant to say I've noticed...
that people of the Jewish persuasion
tend to stick together.
Never seen a mixed couple?
You must admit your people
don't mix very often.
That may be behind what's going on...
what's always gone on...
- You know he's staged all Claudel.
- Don't care!
- He's a great director.
- Big deal.
He meant no harm.
He thinks I'm a good actor.
Flattery goes a long way with you.
You think I have enough work as it is?
He may give me a role
in The Satin Slipper!
You're so paranoid!
He grills you about your origins
and I'm paranoid?
He's just curious about other cultures.
He is not! He just finds you weird.
That's not true.
But Goebbels won't call now.
For Claudel, right!
What are you doing?
I love your face when you're angry.
A rabbit in a pit bull skin.
What nonsense!
Nothing matters to you.
That's not true.
You matter.
The Great Role
- The movie star!
- Ah, Mr. Silberman...
Don't tell Perla you saw me.
You finally do a movie and don't
tell anyone? And it's on tonight!
You're in the paper!
It's just a bit part in a TV movie.
Don't act so modest.
- It's your picture they used.
- Don't tell Perla I was here.
Oh, hi, Benny.
It's my agent.
You know everyone...
I'm sick of that two-bit dubbing job.
It depresses me.
Say, you know everybody.
Who's this Grishenberg fellow...
the one they interview in the paper?
He seems important.
You know, the Goldberg boy,
the one who was summa cum laude
two years ago...
He saw Grishenberg at the Regina.
- Don't tell Perla I was here.
- Know my mother's maiden name?
Grishenberg. He must be family.
No doubt about it.
Go see him. Tell him I sent you.
You'll be famous.
I gotta run.
And no hello to Perla?
- Don't tell her I was here.
- Why not?
Because...
I take pictures of her on the sly.
I don't want her to know.
How he loves his Perla!
Pictures of your wife on the sly?
That's weird.
A movie star can be a bit meshugge.
Promise me: Not a word to Perla.
We said, not a word, so not a word.
Never, you hear me?
Never will you marry that tramp!
Elvira's never been my mistress,
you know that.
- Shit, your cell phones.
- You and your cell phones!
I'll have them confiscated at the door!
And you there, pipe down!
Will you turn that damn thing off?
That's not my ring.
- And I don't have one.
- Mine's on vibrate.
Really?
- Sorry, it's mine.
- Can you shut it off?
Just a sec, it's my wife.
While I'm at it...
You're not bothering me at all.
I'll call you back when I finish.
You sent me a message?
I'll read it right away.
Gotta go. I love you.
- That's tough to say.
- "Ashkenazi-if-you-ask-me."
15,000! You're kidding?
I can't talk long.
I'll call you back.
You know my mare Ocean Queen?
I sold her.
Say "Ashkenazi-if-you-ask-me."
We here to work or what?
I'd like to try new colors.
Maybe some red.
We could knock down that wall,
set up long tables,
to see the tailors.
Try saying "Ashkenazi-if-you-ask-me."
- "Ashkenazi-if-you-ask-me."
- What's that supposed to mean?
Why didn't you stop in the other day?
You told her?
Let's go.
- Why'd you tell her?
- You two and your secrets!
One takes pictures on the sly,
while the other...
Who?
The other, nothing.
- Let's go.
- What about the other?
Anyway, Perla has her own secrets.
Like planning a trip to Israel
to see her sister.
- Why say it, Mr. Silberman?
- Why tell him?
I can't tell a lie.
You drive me nuts with your secrets!
I'll be in a state all evening now.
We can't confide in them.
So, when do we leave?
Wednesday. Next week.
How about a kiss?
What's this about photos?
Nothing. Kiss me before I get mad.
We've been together four years.
Stay with me tonight.
- I can't tonight, Carole.
- Then introduce me.
I can't. I need time.
- Tell her about me. I'll go see her.
- I can't!
You're 38!
You waiting till your grandma dies?
Watch how you talk!
I'm leaving.
Don't bother calling!
Hi, Carole.
She doesn't understand
I can't introduce her.
It would kill Granny.
- Lend me 30 euros?
- You come to the races broke?
- She took the money.
- You're a pain.
I'm off to a birthday party.
- Don't like horses?
- No. So long.
- Where've you been?
- Attending ma'ariv.
- What's ma'ariv?
- The evening prayer.
Evening prayer now?
- Getting religious?
- With a beard?
With little corkscrews behind your ears?
That'll be cute.
Right, make fun of me.
- I saw Grishenberg at temple.
- Grishenberg attends ma'ariv?
Unlike you. He'll be there
tomorrow for Shabbat.
What's Shabbat?
Just kidding.
Why don't we go to temple tomorrow?
- We'll tell him we're actors.
- I'll give him my press book.
You make me sick! Going to temple
just to see a star! It's a sin!
I bet on 10 and he falls
before the finish line!
This is crazy!
What in the world...
did I do with it?
I'm sure I have one.
I don't remember seeing one
around the house.
From the Goldberg Bar Mitzvah.
- How long ago was that?
- I dunno.
About seven years ago.
Found it.
I knew I had one.
- It looks brand new.
- Does it?
How's this? Do I look like
a regular temple-goer?
- You really going?
- Just for a bit.
Kiss me. You're going to temple.
Kiss me again.
And again, just to see.
- To see what?
- I dunno.
This temple stuff does something to me.
Cut it out, they're waiting.
It's a good deed
doing it on Shabbat.
Okay, if it's to do some Mitzvah,
as Sami says.
You say "Mitzvoth"
that's the plural of Mitzvah.
I'll say Mitzvoth.
You said to dress.
Not in a tux!
It's temple, not Cannes.
Driving on Shabbat!
I was late. I wasn't gonna walk
across Paris!
I'm on time.
Brought your press book?
I'm not here for the fun of it.
C'mon, we'll miss prayer.
- Not if he's not here.
- Let's get a drink.
- Not staying for prayer?
- What for?
You make me sick.
He came by car, too.
So what do we do?
We can't leave Sami alone.
He sure has presence!
I like the way he is with his son.
Shut up, dammit!
Now you've got me swearing.
Don't pretend to pray, just listen.
- Page 180.
- Shut up, we're praying.
You have no shame.
- Where's Eli?
- I dunno.
- Did Eli leave?
He wouldn't miss this.
- Hush!
- All right, already.
Silence, gentlemen, we're praying!
Hi, I'm a French actor
See my picture. See?
I play roles like the merchant, the bad guy
J'ai beaucoup...
vous le connaissez...
Grichenberg directed a movie...
Come on.
Hai! Yiddish.
Yes
Why was he so pleased?
I said Shabbat Shalom in Yiddish.
- You rehearsed!
- The least I could do.
I'm off, Yael's waiting.
I'm not sure I got it.
He said something like "Chant of Nice."
- A Winter's Tale.
- Don't be stupid.
The Merchant of Venice!
- The one with Shylock?
- He can do what he wants.
- I gotta run.
- We're coming for Shabbat.
That wasn't planned.
Yael won't like it.
The thing is to be together.
So there'll be four of you?
- Can Perla come?
- And Keiko?
Who's Keiko?
How do you pick up all these girls?
There's a current between us.
I can't let them waste away.
How about a loving wife?
30 years with one woman?
Think I'm crazy?
Not everyone has a pearl like Perla.
He's right.
I only had one wife and she left.
- And I'm alone.
- I have my son tonight.
We can't cook! How many are you?
- Any more latkes?
- No, thanks!
This is what the Ashkenaz eat?
My wife said you were weird.
I did not!
It's Shabbat and there are kids here!
So Grishenberg's doing
The Merchant of Venice!
What's it about?
What's it about, Maurice?
It's about this merchant in Venice
who borrows from a Jewish
moneylender named Shylock.
They make a strange deal.
If the merchant can't repay,
Shylock claims a pound of his flesh.
Isn't it anti-Semitic?
- Was Shakespeare anti-Semitic?
- He was Jewish.
He was not!
Sure he was. He was Sephardic.
Anyone with any talent
is a Jew to Sami.
And Sephardic.
Doubt me? Shakespeare's real name
was Chaim Perez.
An old Spanish Jewish family
from Toledo.
His father emigrated to England
in 1564 during the Inquisition.
- That true?
- You bet!
Chaim became William.
Sounds the same!
- Where'd you get that?
- Ignore him.
His father was the same way.
He told me Louis de Funes was Jewish,
his real name was Eliahu Fenesh
and that he came from Gabes, Tunisia.
Don't believe me, see if I care.
Want some more strudel?
Yeah, Sami Perez.
If you insist...
- Let's walk home.
- It's far.
Put Maurice on.
Your agent.
At this hour. What a pain!
I heard that!
Tell Perla thanks!
This "pain" busts ass to get you work!
It isn't easy.
No one would've hired you guys if...
- What is it?
- Your cell's always off.
Grishenberg's doing
The Merchant of Venice.
- That so?
- He wants to shoot in Yiddish.
I got you four auditions for Shylock.
But not Edward.
- Why not?
- How should I know?
He wants to see everyone but not him.
I may drop him.
The audition has to be before Thursday.
We're going away.
Sure, Grishenberg can postpone his film
so Maurice Kurtz can take a vacation.
Plus I'll borrow his car
to take his wife out.
Where can I get the play in Yiddish?
I'm an agent, not a bookseller!
It's the key scene.
Give it your all. Don't hold back.
Okay?
It's about love here.
And about war there.
You're starving.
Let's have it violent, fast and furious!
Freeze!
No one move!
Where're the pigeons?
Cut, dammit!
Can't you release pigeons?
You worthless piece of shit!
I'll tell my father.
You're dead in this business.
Let's take a break.
Really, it was great.
Look what Perla found for me
at the Medem Library?
- What?
- Shylock in Yiddish.
- The only copy in Paris.
- No kidding!
- And us?
- Every man for himself.
Let's see. That sucks!
Don't you take your calls?
- We were shooting.
- I'd like a bigger role.
Check for my calls. I have urgent news!
Not for you, Edward.
Viviane made a cake.
Have some, you look bushed.
We can't shoot.
The pigeons didn't work
and Jerome's furious.
That's it for today. Thanks, gentlemen.
Why stick us with guys like that?
He's the son
of the biggest producer in town.
No more nude parts.
The audition's Thursday.
I told you, Perla and I leave
for Israel Wednesday!
I did my best. He's ready to lend me
his wife and his car,
but he won't put off the audition.
Ajoke, honey.
I don't even know his wife.
Going to see Sarah?
You should come dressed as a Jew.
- As a Jew?
- What's that mean?
Find Jewish outfits.
Shylock's a Jew, so dress Jewish.
Why can't I audition?
I need to practice Yiddish
with Granny first.
No more nude parts.
- If you could change the date...
- A.M. Or P.M.?
You bust my chops!
Let's go.
This is how they thank me.
What'd we say?
They're doing fine.
They manage all right.
There's Simon,
my grandson!
I told you, Granny, I'm not in it.
I just dubbed the actor's voice.
That's not me.
Ever since he was a child,
he wanted to be an actor.
Nothing else, just an actor.
- It's Maurice.
- Hello, Granny.
I xeroxed the play for you and the others
That's really nice of you.
When'll he find himself a wife?
I have someone in mind for him.
I'll see you out.
She loves children, she's beautiful...
Does this look good on me?
I had a blue pinstriped suit.
Have any idea where it is?
I can't get my lines down.
Would you read them with me?
- You mad?
- I'm sleepy.
What's wrong? What is it?
Nothing, I'm just tired.
"Is he not fed with the same food?"
Memorizing Yiddish isn't easy.
Something's wrong. Talk to me.
It's nothing. I want to sleep.
I'm afraid you'll leave me.
Why do you say that?
I've never felt you so distant before.
If only my folks could've seen this.
Tomorrow I meet the world's
greatest director.
What?
Nothing. I'm boring you
with my actor's worries.
Kiss me.
Everything's fine.
I love you.
I'm just a bit nervous.
About what?
About you.
Your audition.
That's all.
Good night, my love.
"I am a Jew."
What do you think about my voice?
Hoarse, but so what?
It's chronic.
Must be psychological.
- What will you do?
- I'm prepared.
That stunt never works.
Hello
We're here for Shylock.
Mr. Shylock...
"Shy...," right?
Especially with you, miss.
Nothing under S.
When did he check in?
It's for the movie.
Mr. Grishenberg...
End of the hall.
- Shy with you...
- Come on!
So Mr. Grishenberg's not here?
- End of the hall.
- Really?
Excuse me...
Silence, please.
The Venetians here, the Jews, here.
This is an outrage!
Find another way to call us.
I'm sorry
What a schmuck!
Excuse me, I wasn't called.
I'm with friends.
Could I see Mr. Grishenberg?
The name's Edward Weisbrot.
Simon Laufer.
That's me.
Mr. G. Will see you.
They only called up old-timers.
- You're not all actors?
- Actors, no.
But speak Yiddish, that we can.
We're the Marais Yiddish Club.
We saw an ad in the paper
about Grishenberg looking
for Yiddish redeners.
What's that mean?
Yiddish speakers.
But acting's a profession.
You need lessons.
Mister, let me tell you,
it's not only actors who act.
The whole world acts.
Even children act
just to make us happy.
The acting only stops when you die.
Am I not acting at being a survivor?
We're all survivors.
So...
why shouldn't we play Shylock?
We might even write it better
than Shakespeare.
You have to shoot in Ladino!
The Judeo-Spanish dialect!
Yiddish is meaningless.
You don't understand Shakespeare!
- Maurice Kurtz.
- That's me.
Mr. Grishenberg will see you.
He had a good laugh over
your friend Edward's tape.
A good idea.
He had a good laugh.
A lot of parts in theatre?
A lot of parts in cinema
A lot of parts in television
- That right?
- That's right.
Doesn't speak Yiddish but understands
Hello, Mr. Maurice
Hello
Mr. Grishenberg wants
to revive the tradition
of Yiddish theater.
- Can I speak English with you?
- Sure.
You like ce quartier in Paris?
What other neighborhood you like?
I don't know.
I like my neighborhood,
Belleville-Menilmontant.
Besides you,
what other actors living or dead,
you think could play Shylock?
I don't know.
Maybe Groucho Marx, Woody Allen...
Al Pacino or Edward Norton.
Very good
Have you ever been to America?
I don't speak much Yiddish.
But I've heard it spoken a lot.
What do you think of the color
of these curtains?
Can I do the monologue?
Yeah, but tell me first
what you think of the curtains.
They match the carpet.
What about the carpet?
Just a minute.
Be right with you.
Perla left.
At what time?
At 3. And the audition?
What's Grishenberg like?
Did you say we're family?
Where'd she go?
Some tall dark-haired guy
around 25 came for her.
A handsome Italian
in a fancy convertible.
She left with him?
I'm joking.
Think I'd have told you? You take me
for someone who can't keep a secret?
So, the audition. Have nothing to say?
- If you hate your cell phone, dump it.
- Now what?
- You're impossible to reach!
- What d'you want?
I want to know how it went.
Great. He asked me if I liked
the color of the curtains.
I knew anyhow.
Grishenberg's assistant called.
- And?
- He doesn't want any of you.
Thanks for delivering the message!
Hang on!
He doesn't want anyone except you.
He thought you were great.
Let me hug you.
- My neighbors are watching!
- So what?
I've been busting ass for you
for 10 years!
- Just kidding, Benny.
- Me, too.
Well?
Well...
He wants to see me tomorrow.
Great!
- We can take our trip later.
- I won't get the part.
Next week we're at Sarah's.
Sure you'll get the part!
I came by to pick you up today.
I left at 3.
I had to see a new customer.
Who was it?
A friend of Mr. Silberman's.
Really?
Italian?
No, why?
I have to tell you something.
What?
Never forget, I love you.
I love you so much it hurts.
What's wrong?
Okay, okay...
I won't tell you I love you again.
I don't love you.
I promise I don't.
I want you to get that role.
I'll get it.
"Three thousand ducats, well."
"Ay, sir, for three months."
"For three months, well."
Relax
"I am debating of my present store,
"And, by the near guess of my memory,
"I cannot instantly raise up the gross"
Of full three thousand ducats.
That's good
That's better
More relaxed
It's not theatre, it's life
"Go with me to a notary."
Shakespeare did know he was Shakespeare
It was a guy talking to his friend
To me
Shall I read it again?
"Go with me to a notary."
Listen
There are 3 guys for this role
I want you to be my Shylock
We are going to see you next week
Think, think. Work, work.
Keep it.
This is Jerome Saulnier.
We're re-shooting the pigeon scene.
I fired the assistant.
What time is it?
4:20 p.m.
Can I call you back?
Make it fast.
Still not dressed at this hour?
Haven't you been out?
I was going out.
You're home early.
You okay?
The final audition's tomorrow.
I'm nervous.
Go see your friends.
No, they drive me nuts.
What're you talking about?
I think they're jealous of me.
Aren't you exaggerating?
They're anxious for you.
Only I am,
no one else.
I'm the one who's stressed out,
not them.
I've struggled for years for a big break.
Why don't you grow up?
Last audition.
Think we'd abandon you?
We wanted to let you concentrate.
You were in such a state.
Go on, you'll be late.
Break a leg!
"I am a Jew!
"Hath not a Jew eyes?
"Hath not a Jew hands,
"organs?
"Dimensions, senses,
affections, passions?
"Fed with the same food,
"hurt with the same weapons,
"subject to the same diseases,
"healed by the same means,
"warmed and cooled by the same winter
and summer, as a Christian is?
"If you prick us, do we not bleed?
"If you tickle us, do we not laugh?
"If you poison us,
"do we not die?
"And if you wrong us...
"And if you wrong us,
"shall we not revenge?
"If a Jew wrong a Christian,
"what is his humility?
"Revenge.
"If a Christian wrong a Jew,
"what should his sufferance
"be by Christian example?
"Why, revenge.
"The villainy you teach me
"I will execute,
"and it shall go hard
"but I will better the instruction."
It's him
My Shylock.
Thank you
Well?
I think I got it.
You think?
You think you got it?
I got it.
Holy shit!
Mazel Tov!
Please, stop! Please, leave!
Sorry, they're just kids.
You home?
Maurice, I'm going to die.
I'm sick.
I'm very sick, Maurice.
What? Sick how?
I didn't want to tell you
because of your audition.
What do you have, Perla?
Cancer.
It's Philippe.
Hi, Philippe.
- Did she tell you?
- Just now.
I had no idea.
She hid her appointments.
Is it serious?
I just got the results
for the last tests...
And?
Is she right there?
No
I can't tell you like this.
Come see me.
It's Benny.
- I'll call you back.
- Wait a second.
Grishenberg's not giving you the part.
What are you talking about?
He'll phone you. The star he wanted
suddenly became available.
This is no time to joke.
It's not a joke!
I'll call you back.
Tell me we'll pull through.
We'll pull through.
And your audition?
Got the part?
I got it.
When do you start?
Soon. The shooting...
There's rehearsal Monday,
costume fittings...
I'll be on the set.
Then the shooting starts.
So when do we go see Sarah?
We'll tell her to come.
Here, you won 11 euros.
It's a rotten blow.
It's not all that bad.
There are more important
things in life.
It hit you that bad?
I couldn't care less.
You do care.
Look at your face.
Who wants to see Merchant
in Yiddish?
Maybe three rabbis
and some old Polish Jews.
We had as much fun
as if you'd got the part.
God gave you joy but not the part.
You've played Shylock
over and over in your head.
Perla's sick.
She mustn't get upset either.
It's not your first letdown.
She's very sick. It's serious.
What?
What're you talking about?
You bullshitting us?
What can we do?
How can we help?
I know she's in good hands.
You should keep her from getting upset.
Make her laugh.
A guy got cured from cancer once
watching Marx Brothers movies.
How'd she take your losing the part?
Pretty well...
She took it all right.
She said it didn't matter.
Don't leave her alone.
You should stay by her side.
What're you doing with us?
I wasn't going to tell her...
You're right. I'll stay with her.
If you need anything, we're here.
I can't do it, darling.
I won't manage.
Sami...
It's Maurice.
Can you tell the others
to be at Benny's in a half-hour?
You said you got it?
You let her think that?
She doesn't know?
You've lied for 2 weeks?
You'll make it harder for her.
I know. It escaped me that night
and I can't backtrack.
I just can't.
- What'll you do now?
- I don't know.
And this lie keeps me
from being home with her.
Tell her when you get home.
You can't do this.
I say what? "I was bullshitting you.
I'm not making the movie.
"I spend the day walking around."
Maurice, listen.
Want me to call her and tell her?
No way.
The worst is,
I see how happy it makes her.
She seems better
when I tell her about the film.
Who knows?
Maybe it can even cure her.
Still, it's a sin to lie.
Cut the religious stuff!
Are you nuts?
God didn't sin by doing this to Perla?
Don't talk like that.
Yesterday, there were tons of extras
playing Venetians.
Two or three hundred of them.
A big ship enters the port of Venice,
all recreated in studio.
It's magical.
The great Rudolph Grishenberg
is now in Paris
to shoot
The Merchant of Venice.
Turn that off.
They're talking about you.
Where?
On the radio.
I wasn't paying attention.
I'll turn it up.
Too late.
What a shame.
That must be the nurse.
You lied to me.
I'll never forgive you.
Try to understand, Alexia.
Understand what?
You make me swallow a lot of nonsense.
It's all Jim's fault.
He said he'd kill you
if I told the truth.
You're lying again!
I have to tell her.
Or she'll resent me even more.
We've thought it over.
Are we actors or aren't we?
Tell yourself it's a role
and Perla's your audience.
We've talked this over.
It can be done.
If you want,
I can play the director,
you're the lead actor.
You'll have to get up early.
Eli will handle the costumes,
Edward the props.
Come on, guys. This is outrageous.
You sure about this?
She'll never suspect a thing.
I know a printer. He can do magazines
with interviews and photos.
Her dreams will be full
of Grishenberg and Shylock.
I thought it was a sin to lie.
I worked it out with...
That's really great.
Look, I even had a sketch done.
Looks good, doesn't it?
- Mega realistic.
- What'll you do with that?
I'll explain.
Is my pal talented or not?
He's good, but aren't you overdoing it?
- Think how happy she'll be.
- It really looks great.
Gotta keep it simple.
This is too much.
Just a few interviews
about the shoot...
- We'll interview you.
- A few articles...
Sit down.
Benoit, take notes.
Are you glad Grishenberg
chose you to play Shylock?
Sure.
- Your salary?
- That sucks.
Why'd you accept the part?
It's a great part.
- That all?
- What can I say?
- Put something into it.
- Elaborate a bit.
Ask good questions, then.
Do I take that down?
Was it hard to get
inside your character?
Not bad.
But it's his job.
You're always so critical.
It's Perla!
Yes, honey.
I'm whispering
because they're shooting.
I'm wanted on the set.
Gotta go.
- Maurice, are you ready?
- Yes, I'm here
Can anyone tell me what's going on?
I can't do that.
Maurice can only ask you.
He can't ask me to take part
in a lie. And to a sick person.
It's not a complicated costume to make.
Black with embroidering on the sides.
Perla asked about my costume.
I don't sew anymore.
I sell fabric. Can I still cut?
You never lose it.
Shame on you,
making them wait like this!
They want me to lie to poor Perla.
So?
Let me hear it again.
What for?
I like the sound of Yiddish.
Nothing's coming to me.
Do a scene you did already.
Sure...
A scene with all the Venetian extras,
500 or 600 of them...
You had lines in Yiddish?
Of course.
You bet I did!
How'd you do it?
Say them again for me, please.
Actually, in that scene...
Because I'm...
Actually I don't say much,
almost nothing.
I said..."Shoin."
Is that all?
He cut a lot to keep
the general shot.
All I say is "shoin", but real loud.
- What about tomorrow?
- What about it?
What're you shooting?
You're acting weird.
I'm bushed. I'm up early tomorrow.
Where'd I put the audition scene?
Tomorrow we do the scene
with the chests.
Let's do it. What page?
If you think I look at that...
I work mainly with the Yiddish version.
- Where is it?
- It's not there?
Don't tell me I left it
in my dressing room.
I know it by heart.
It'll be hard following you.
I know, I know.
Oh my God!
A big fat herring,
crazy in the head...
Not like this, but that...
so there!
Is that all?
That's all.
It's like nordic languages:
Everything's very succinct.
Anyhow, I have a super coach on the set.
Is she cute?
What's she like? Pretty?
She's okay.
She's a Yiddish teacher, that's all.
Then why are you flustered?
I'm not flustered.
I know you.
Okay, she's pretty. But she doesn't do
anything for me, honestly.
If something happens to me...
I want you to know
that if you feel like...
Hush!
Read the lines with me?
- What's your coach's name?
- She doesn't exist.
For me she doesn't exist.
So, we rehearse or go to sleep?
Okay, ready.
What do you like in a woman?
- Poise.
- And in a man?
A sense of humor.
Your favorite scene in Merchant?
Rudy, okay
: Benoit
Okay?
I got it.
You can't film here.
Keep it up!
How's it going with...
Fuck you
Fuck you too
Come on!
I'm so glad Maurice got a day off.
They changed the schedule just for him.
It wasn't easy but...
Maurice is doing Shylock now?
I told you.
You told me it was...
John Wood.
No, Maurice's playing Shylock.
Really?
You're pulling my leg.
Maurice got the part.
You didn't know?
Benny said it was...
But finally it's Maurice.
But I thought...
I know, but, in fact, no!
I've got some good news.
You'll have scenes with Sean Connery.
Really?
The production called today.
He plays the judge
who sentences Shylock.
Okay.
Isn't that great?
I'm so glad Maurice is doing this film.
After this, you'll be world famous.
I hope I'll be around to see it.
Sure you will.
Doron and Sarah called:
They're coming.
What a day! Aren't we lucky?
I'm still surprised because...
Would you cut it out?
Have you lost your mind or what!
Maurice, it's 6:10.
Wake up, love.
Your driver will be here in 20 minutes.
Read your lines again?
He's a cheerful fellow...
but a big eater
and slow as a snail.
Good morning
- Been clubbing?
- They closed at 4 a.m.
I tried to get some sleep.
Sorry.
It'd be better if Sami picked you up.
He goes to temple every morning.
Drive. She's watching us.
- Where to?
- I dunno. Drive.
- What time is it?
- Must be 6:45.
6:45?
We watched him from a distance.
He's a great Shylock.
We couldn't get near him.
At least Grishenberg
allowed us on the set.
You should see
how they all cater to Maurice.
- Tom Cruise came by the set.
- Really?
You were still at lunch.
We talked for an hour.
What's he like?
Very short.
Like a dog.
He comes up to here on me.
He has a huge staff.
It's really impressive.
Lots of charisma. Very nice.
Simple. Relaxed. Tanned.
I found him a bit obnoxious.
He said...
some obnoxious things.
He's on a first-name basis
with Grishenberg.
That's normal.
Sure,
they work together.
And his coach is a dish.
A real A-bomb.
She's not my coach, she's...
Jerk! Why mention my coach?
I didn't know what to say!
Go on. I'll stay with her.
What am I doing here?
I'm going home. She needs me.
This sucks.
Forget it. It's impossible.
We've already discussed it.
You coming?
What for?
I have nothing to do in there.
Go on, I'm fine.
You sure?
I'll wait for you.
As you like.
Want to put on tefillin?
I'm not interested.
Try it.
He might be more merciful.
It's not a business.
I'm not trading things.
Hand me the bottle.
I'll have to go home in costume.
If she suspects something...
She say anything?
No, but it's just as well.
I couldn't have stayed home all this time.
You shouldn't drink like that.
Stand up straight.
"I am a Jew.
"Hath not a Jew eyes?
"Hath not a Jew hands,
"organs?
"Dimensions, senses,
affections, passions?
"Fed with the same food...
"hurt with the same
weapons,
"subject to the same diseases,
"healed by the same means,
"warmed and cooled
"by the same winter and summer,
as a Christian is?
"If you tickle us, do we not laugh?
"If you poison us,
do we not die?"
How're you doing?
Everything okay?
Why are you dressed like that?
I want to see her.
- She's sleeping.
- You smell of liquor.
I'll explain.
Tell me what's going on.
For 5 weeks you've been feeding
my sister all this crap?
Yes
She swallowed it?
Yeah, I didn't know how to...
You must tell her the truth.
I'll tell her.
What's the point now?
It's made her so happy.
He's been lying to her for 5 weeks!
This can't go on. I'm telling her.
No
What do you like in a woman?
Poise.
And in a man?
A sense of humor.
He's making a film
with Rudolph Grishenberg.
That's great.
You'd think he'd been doing it
all his life.
I keep dreaming of Grishenberg.
It's Maurice's fault,
he always talks about him.
We'll have to wait till I get better,
but...
I'd love to meet him.
- Don't touch.
- Just looking.
- But don't touch.
- I'm not, but...
- It seats how many?
- 5 or 6.
Stop it! Calm down!
Nice work!
Morning, sir
George!
Step on it!
Shit!
Can't do that, are you crazy?
Shut up
Are your crazy too
He says shut up, are we nuts?
You were to turn right.
Right, Sami!
What?
Because I've been kipnapped
by Maurice Kurtz...
who wants me to tell his wife...
that he is playing Shylock
We are going to... Maurice Kurtz,
Maurice Kurtz
My wife's ill. Just a little lie.
I can't
Why not?
I can't lie, I'm American
What'd he say?
He can't lie, he's American.
So what?
Americans don't lie
- Americans don't lie.
- Are you kidding?
Fuck you
It's for you.
If you need anything, I'm next door.
This game has gone long enough
You turn this car around.
You take me back to hotel immediately
You know what you are doing?
In two hours time,
you will be in news broadcast
all over the world
You are looking for big, big trouble.
Sami, turn around.
We'll take him back.
This has gone far enough.
I said, turn around!
This isn't a Mini! You're nuts.
When you get a haircut,
it makes headlines.
We're just ordinary people.
Maurice is a hero, a nameless hero.
So no one gives a damn.
Who, besides you and us, will know all
he's done to make his wife happy?
We see you sponsor foundations
and humanitarian associations,
but we don't know
how you treat your wife.
- I can't lie.
- Who's asking you to lie?
It's a show for one person's dreams.
The great role Maurice never got,
he's been playing for his wife.
It's the role of his life.
He just wants you as a guest star.
It's no lie, it's showbiz.
Acting isn't lying. It's the only time
when you don't lie.
I don't want to argue with you.
I want to go back to my hotel
The week's film event is
R. Grishenberg's new picture.
We met him in Paris.
Thank you for agreeing
to this interview.
Aren't you afraid of alienating your fans
by doing this film entirely in Yiddish?
Merchant of Venice is the most
problematic Shakespeare play.
But with the Middle East situation
and anti-Semitism, the time is right.
I've made so many movies to entertain.
I think I can make films
closer to me in Yiddish.
I hope the public will come.
As usual you've cast big-name talent
to play the lead roles.
Stars are the locomotives of Hollywood.
By using them,
I can shoot any subject I please
without the producer on my back.
So John Woodward's playing Shylock.
Sure, if you'd asked the production...
I'd have said yes.
I visit hospitals sometimes
Maurice, I'm sorry.
My film is waiting
We grew up with all your films.
They taught us how to talk to girls.
We all wanted to be actors
because of your films.
We've memorized your interviews.
You were this close to casting Maurice.
That means something.
You owe him.
We're just asking for five minutes
of your time.
It's not asking for the moon.
He is my friend Maurice
Debbie, not now
Sixth floor.
Now what do we do?
It was a false alarm.
We do nothing. Know who is he?
Want the Americans bombing Paris?
He'll be back down.
This is Perla, my wife
Hello, Perla
I was giving Maurice a ride home...
I thought it would be nice to meet you
He is a fabulous actor
A magnificent Shylock
I love working with him
I am lucky to have met him
I think he is lucky to have met you
He loves you very much, you know?
I know
I think you must be a very special person
to deserve someone who loves you...
the way he loves you
We don't all get the chance to enjoy
such a love in our life
We can miss out on everything
if we manage to love, really love...
we make a success in our life
That's what remains
It is very moving to me today
I am grateful that Maurice told me that...
how much you wanted to meet me.
Really, the honour is mine
Thank you.
What're you doing?
Learning it by heart?
I dubbed him in Yiddish.
We know, we saw it four times.
You coming?
I don't want to eat at the counter.
Think you'll do his next film?
If Al Pacino's not free, maybe.
By the way, Sarah had a boy.
What's his name?
Dunno. He doesn't speak yet.
It's a sin to tell
before circumcision.
Come on, one more!
There!
I always wondered
if you suspected something.
If you're not hungry, say so!
I'm coming!
Anyhow, there's always a wait.
Because we're always late!
What're you stopping for?
Move it, or forget the restaurant.
What're you so worked up for?
- We're hungry!
- Here I am!
So let's go!
How I miss you, my love.
How I miss you.