[MUSIC - BRAD HAYES, "SAY THOSE
THINGS"]
(SINGING) What you told
me not to do long ago.
If you love me,
better tell me so.
Say those things on your mind.
What's you're saying
is in between.
I'd wish you tell me
just what you mean.
You got to say those
things on your mind.
It's not the truth.
But it's not a lie when
you can't say the things
that you feel inside.
Feel like you're walking
on a moving track.
You take one step forward,
and one step back.
What you see is
not what you get.
What's underneath this
thing, come out yet.
You got to say those
things on your mind.
Go on and say those things.
JANE DOE: So Jimmy, are
you afraid of the dark?
So I guess we--
we started then.
JANE DOE: Uh-huh.
Are you afraid of the dark?
[laughs nervously]
And-- and that's
your first question?
JANE DOE: Uh-huh.
How about a first answer?
Well, yeah.
I guess in this situation I--
I am a little uncomfortable.
JANE DOE: Why?
Because I can't see you.
JANE DOE: Well, I
can't see you either.
Yeah.
But you probably
saw me coming in.
JANE DOE: Mm.
Yeah.
You're right, I did.
So that puts me
at a disadvantage.
JANE DOE: A disadvantage.
And you don't like that.
Do you?
Well, in this situation
I'm not too sure.
JANE DOE: What's the difference?
You can't see me.
I can't see you.
Yeah.
But I have no idea
what you look like.
JANE DOE: Why do you want to
know what I look like, Jimmy?
What do you mean?
JANE DOE: I mean, does it
matter what I look like?
What are you getting at?
JANE DOE: Oh, nothing.
Just tell me what difference
it makes what I look like.
Well, it doesn't
make any difference.
I just thought it would be nice
to see a face with the voice.
That's all.
Jesus.
What the hell is this.
JANE DOE: You wanted lights,
well, you got lights.
Is this a joke?
JANE DOE: Afraid not.
This is the way it's going
to be for the duration.
Is this really necessary?
JANE DOE: Oh, it's all
part of the process.
Oh, well, it's very good.
A good, dramatic effect.
The Nazi thing.
I like it.
JANE DOE: You'll get used to it.
Right.
JANE DOE: You got to do
something for me, Jimmy.
[sighs]
What's that?
JANE DOE: You have to answer
the questions right away.
I don't want you to think.
Well, I have to.
My parents made me promise.
JANE DOE: If you think,
you'll defend yourself.
And if you defend
yourself, you'll lie.
That's just the way you are.
You don't know
anything about me!
JANE DOE: I meant men.
Oh.
What's your name?
JANE DOE: That's not important.
You're not going to tell me?
JANE DOE: Mm.
No.
- Ever?
JANE DOE: No.
Why?
JANE DOE: Well, we
never give our names.
Things work better that way.
Why?
JANE DOE: Don't worry about it.
Well, there's another one.
JANE DOE: What?
Disadvantage.
No face.
No name.
This is like a blind
date from hell.
JANE DOE: The last thing
this is, Jimmy, is a date.
Don't forget it.
I promise.
JANE DOE: We're here to
find out about you, not me.
When I ask you a question, you
answer as quickly as possible.
Don't think.
Don't defend.
Just answer.
If you want to ask a
question about me, don't.
Don't even think about me.
It's none of your business.
Is that clear?
Yes.
JANE DOE: We're not
here to have fun, Jimmy.
This is serious.
You agreed to take
part no matter
what questions are asked.
You've committed to
answering them honestly.
Oh, and don't hold back
just because I'm a woman.
Don't tell me what you
think I want to hear.
Just answer.
I think I can handle that.
JANE DOE: Good.
So Jimmy, let's
talk about women.
OK.
Let's talk about women.
SEAN: No.
No.
No way.
You were in there for two hours?
Yeah.
Well, how long were
you guys in for?
I was in for
about a half hour.
Genius over there lasted
about five minutes.
Yeah.
Five minutes too long.
I'm sorry I even let you
guys talk me into it.
Gee, sorry.
I thought you might
learn something.
Are you serious?
I wasn't in there a
minute before this woman
started bitching at me.
She called me a rapist.
Yeah.
Mine called all men
fascist rapists.
Is that what yours said?
- Yeah.
That's what she said.
Mine also said that
all men are pigs, liars.
All they want is
sex, and that they'll
say or do anything to get it.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
That's what I got.
What a crock of shit.
- No.
It's the absolute truth.
Oh, Christ.
Here we go.
You are a lost cause.
So I'm not even going
to argue with you.
But Jimmy, come on.
You can't disagree with that.
Look, Tim, I don't--
Oh, come on.
When are you guys
going to wake up?
The entire industrial
military complex is
based on men's pursuit of sex.
The sooner we admit it, the
sooner we can change it.
You guys keep following
your dicks around,
we're never going
to get anywhere.
- I don't follow--
- Whoa.
Whoa.
Let me get this straight.
Are you saying that you never
follow your dick around?
Never.
Bullshit.
Unlike you, son,
I have control.
Oh-ho.
Spare me.
Control.
You sit down to piss?
Up yours.
So you going back?
Nope.
After talking for
about a half hour
she said she didn't
think I should come back.
Why not?
She didn't think it would
be insightful, because she
said I'm so well-adjusted.
Well-adjusted?
You?
Eat your heart out.
Are you going back, Sean?
Not in a million years!
Well, I think I'm
going to go back.
What?
- Right on, Jim.
- Hey, Jim.
Come on.
Him I understand.
But not you.
No.
She said some shit I
really don't agree with.
Don't bother.
They're just a bunch of
sexually repressed feminists.
All they want to do
is cut your nuts off.
Maybe.
But I'm going back.
Jim, yeah.
You, maybe.
But Sean?
I cannot believe
Sean took part in any
experiment conducted by the
women's studies department.
Yeah.
Well, we had to drag him
kicking and screaming.
[chuckles]
Oh, big surprise.
Yeah.
I don't know.
The woman I had
was tough as nails.
I mean, I lasted two hours.
But man, she was brutal.
- Why?
What'd she say?
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Oh, you know,
the whole men are pigs stick.
Yeah.
The same basic sermon I
usually I get on first dates.
Women say that to
you on first dates?
Yep.
MIMI (ON PHONE): Well, my god.
What do you do to make
them attack you like that?
No.
It's not about me.
It's always about their last
boyfriend, or a date they had.
You know, it's just a warning.
If you're a pig, they
don't want to have
anything to do with you.
Well, what woman would
ever think you're a pig.
Hey, I'm as much of
a pig as the next guy.
I've just learned to fake it.
MIMI (ON PHONE): Don't
even joke like that.
What are you eating?
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Cereal.
For dinner?
JIMMY (ON PHONE):
Hey, [inaudible]..
Oh, god.
You're so pathetic.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Thanks.
So how's the love life?
MIMI (ON PHONE): Dismal.
I haven't had sex
in so long I can't
remember what a man feels like.
Well, you know, if things
are that bad, we could always--
MIMI (ON PHONE): You know,
Jimmy, what I really want--
What?
Romance.
There's no romance in my life.
I have never really
had a wild romance.
I could be romantic.
A passionate love affair.
I could be passionate.
MIMI (ON PHONE): You
know, it's more than want.
It's like, I've come
to the point in my life
where I need romance.
I mean, how many relationships
have I been through since we've
known each other?
Like what?
At least--
Five.
MIMI (ON PHONE): Right.
And not one of them was
romantic or passionate.
There has got to be some guy
out there who's romantic.
Oh, god.
It is so depressing.
Mimi, do you think
all men are rapists?
What?
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Do you
think all men are rapists?
Well, no.
Where did that come from?
Well, the woman
interviewing me
today said that all
men are rapists.
Oh, god.
Tell her to get a life.
She also said that all men are
liars and that everything we do
is for sex.
Can you believe that?
Well, I have to agree
with her on that one.
Oh, so you think I'm a
liar and that everything I do
is for sex.
- Oh, no.
But you're different.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): I am.
How?
Oh, I don't know.
You're just not like
a lot of other guys.
Not like other guys?
MIMI (ON PHONE): Well, no.
I mean, you think about things.
I've never seen you
intentionally hurt anyone.
You're a nice guy.
But being a nice
guy, I'm still a liar.
And I'm still motivated by sex?
Well.
(GIGGLES)
And women aren't
motivated by sex.
And, of course, they never lie.
Well, it is
different for women.
So if sex isn't your
primary motivation, what is?
Oh, it's--
[sighs]
Hi.
My name is James Rovinski.
And I will be teaching this
course for the winter semester.
I'm too young to be
called professor,
too rude to be called James.
So if any of you have
anything to ask me,
please just call me Jimmy.
And just in case any of
you are in the wrong class,
this is Psychology
101, every college's
number one blow off course.
[laughter]
OK.
One, two, three, four, five--
10, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20.
OK.
Good.
Let's get started, shall we.
20.
Seven guys and 13 women.
13 young, nubile women.
Give me strength, god.
[knocking]
Can I take this off now?
JANE DOE: Hold on.
OK.
You know, Jane.
When a woman hits--
JANE DOE: You just
called me, Jane.
Yeah.
Jane Doe.
That's what they call an
unidentified woman at a morgue.
JANE DOE: Don't call me that.
That's sick.
Are you going to
tell me your name?
JANE DOE: No.
As I was saying, Jane, when a
woman hits 25, something snaps.
I mean, when she's 24
everything is fine.
Then she turns 25, and
she looks in the mirror,
and she sees a hag.
And suddenly she freaks out.
And it's a mad race to get
married before everything sags.
I mean, how do you
deal with that?
JANE DOE: What's the problem?
You're a big boy.
You take it or you leave it.
Yeah.
But nobody needs that kind
of pressure on a first date.
JANE DOE: Oh.
What?
You're telling me women want to
marry you after the first date?
JIMMY: No.
I'm saying that they size me up.
And if I happen to meet
their particular marriage
requirements, the
rest of the date's
going to be fairly predictable.
JANE DOE: Oh.
Please, Jimmy, enlighten me.
OK, fine.
In my experience
the average date
goes through three stages,
the past relationship
stage, the future relationship
stage, and the underwear stage.
JANE DOE: The underwear stage?
Yeah.
It's a little theory
I've been working on.
It starts with the past
relationship stage.
After you've gotten past all
the mandatory small talk,
you start to talk about
your past relationships,
good or bad.
Now, this is the
most dangerous stage.
Because a serious
fuckup here can
sink you regardless of your
score in the other two stages.
JANE DOE: Your score?
Yes.
Your score.
And don't you
believe for a second
that she isn't keeping track.
Basically, conversation
here is just a cover
to find out what
you're like, you
know, who you've slept
with, how many you've slept
with, et cetera, et cetera.
So assuming that you've
scored well here,
you move on to the next stage.
JANE DOE: The future
relationship stage.
JIMMY: Right.
You start talking about the
kind of relationships you want,
what your hopes
are for the future.
Pretty straightforward stuff.
But uh, uh, uh, uh.
Don't you believe it.
It is all a cover to find
out one all important thing.
Is the victim ready to commit?
JANE DOE: You're so
full of shit, Rovinski.
You obviously don't date.
JANE DOE: None of
your damn business.
Ha.
Right.
You see, the funny thing is, is
that even if you make it pretty
clear that you're
not ready to commit,
if you've done well in
the first two stages,
you'll usually make
it to the third stage.
JANE DOE: Oh, the
underwear stage.
Mhm.
The underwear stage.
If you make it this far, oh-ho,
you have passed the test.
You fit the bill.
And it is time to
get down to business.
It's time to start baiting you.
JANE DOE: Baiting you?
JIMMY: Mercilessly.
She'll start to talk
about her underwear.
JANE DOE: I'm not hearing this.
Mhm.
Lingerie.
Usually almost always black.
JANE DOE: I am really
not hearing this.
Somehow she will manage
to slip it in that she found
the greatest little lingerie
boutique last weekend,
you know, even though
people don't see it.
It's really important to wear
sexy underwear because it makes
them feel so blah, blah, blah.
JANE DOE: Women don't do that.
I swear to God.
And if it's not underwear,
it's something else
usually not so subtle.
JANE DOE: What?
You've had women do that?
Oh, yeah.
But here is the tough part.
Suppose after the
first two stages,
the guy isn't interested.
JANE DOE: So?
JIMMY: So she starts
talking about her panties,
and what do you think's
going to happen?
JANE DOE: What?
JIMMY: The poor sap is
going to have to reconsider,
even though she might
have totally blown it.
JANE DOE: You know, that's
why men are so pathetic.
I mean, all you ever
think about is sex.
JIMMY: Yeah.
But don't you see.
The guy didn't even
bring sex into it.
She did.
JANE DOE: She was just talking
about her god damn underwear.
But she was
baiting him with it.
She is trying to take
advantage of him.
JANE DOE: What?
You can't walk away from that?
A woman mentions her underwear
and you lose control?
Well, a lot of
guys won't walk away.
They'll sleep with
her, if they can.
And because they weren't really
interested in the first place,
they'll avoid her
calls, or leave town,
or do any of the
other stupid things
that guys do to make women
think they're assholes.
JANE DOE: But don't you
see how sad you are?
JIMMY: No.
Frankly, in that
situation, I think
both people are pretty sad.
Because here is the
point, my dear Jane.
By the end of a date
like that, not only do I
feel like a total slab of meat.
But my intelligence
has been insulted.
I've lost all respect
for the woman.
And worst of all,
I'm horny as hell.
JANE DOE: Has it
ever occurred to you
that maybe she's
not the least bit
interested in a relationship.
I mean, maybe she just
wants to fuck you.
Have you thought of that?
Yeah.
But as a man, I'm a real
macho, arrogant, son of a bitch
if I think that she just
wants to fuck me, right?
JANE DOE: Mm.
JIMMY: Right.
So let's just say with what
I am allowed to be thinking,
I'm giving her the
benefit of the doubt.
JANE DOE: Excuse me.
May I?
Be my guest.
Is something wrong?
[lighter]
[blows smoke]
It's kind of scary.
I've got one that's
been thinking.
[laughs]
Actually, women never talk
to me about their underwear.
How'd she react?
Well, she flipped.
Big wonder.
I thought you quit smoking.
I did.
Yesterday.
Oh.
So what else did
you talk about?
Women again.
Or, you know, at least
what I think about them.
I told her about Mimi.
You did?
Yeah.
Boy, you're really baring
your soul to this woman.
JIMMY: Yeah.
Well, I get the feeling she's
pretty negative about men.
So.
What else is new?
Right.
So I wanted to make sure she
knew I had female friends.
Aha.
Oh.
So you didn't tell
her everything.
What do you mean?
You only told her
Mimi's your friend.
She is only my friend.
So you didn't tell
her you're in love
with Mimi, your female friend.
I am not in love with Mimi.
I simply feel a sometimes
overwhelming potential
to be in love with Mimi.
A sometimes
overwhelming potential?
My god.
You've even defined your
way out of being in love.
It's no wonder you have
problems with commitment.
Commitment?
Jesus.
What about you?
I'm committed.
I just haven't found
anybody who'll commit to me.
I'm committed.
Yeah.
Well, I'm not having
such hot luck myself.
Bullshit.
You've had your chances.
- Yeah.
But I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I mean, I go out on
three dates with a woman.
And then I bail.
And I don't even know why.
Because you're
a simpering idiot.
I'm starting to think
maybe I'm homosexual.
- What?
- No.
I'm serious.
I was walking down the
street the other day
right behind this
long haired babe.
Right?
- Mhm.
I mean, she was really
good looking from behind.
So, you know, I
pick up the pace.
And I get up to her.
And I look in her face.
It was a guy.
[laughs]
And this qualifies you as
having homosexual tendencies?
JIMMY: Well, it got
me worrying about it.
Now I'm sure.
You are an idiot.
Homosexual.
JIMMY: What?
How did you ever
get a job teaching?
You never think about it?
I, for one, am perfectly
comfortable with my manhood.
OK.
Well, forget about sex.
I mean, you have never
looked at some guy
and found him attractive,
even in some remote way?
Wouldn't know an attractive
guy if he ran me over.
JIMMY: Yeah.
Right.
Unless he just picked up the
woman you were trying to meet.
TIM: Nope.
I just put that down to
poor taste on her part.
Sorry, Jim.
No confused thoughts up here.
SEAN: Drinky-poos anybody?
On me.
- Yeah.
I'm in.
Jimmy here is working his
way out of the closet.
And I'd rather not be alone
with him while he does.
I'll just change my shirt.
[phone ringing]
[beep]
Hello?
PAULA (ON PHONE): Hi there.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Paula, do
you know what time it is?
Mhm.
Do you?
JIMMY (ON PHONE): No, actually.
What time is it?
It's late.
Past midnight.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Well, you
shouldn't call this late.
People are sleeping.
It's Friday night.
You guys are all single.
Why aren't you out somewhere?
Well, Sean and Tim
are out somewhere.
But I was sleeping.
PAULA (ON PHONE):
Well, you don't
sound like you were sleeping.
Well, I was about
to be sleeping.
Good.
Then I called just in time.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): You
sound bored, Paula.
I'm never bored, James dear.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): What
do you want, Paula?
My.
You're in a bad mood.
My mother was right.
Never call a man after 11:00 PM.
Let me guess.
He's out of town.
No.
He's not out of town.
Gregory doesn't feel
threatened by my ex boyfriends.
I can do whatever I
want whenever I want.
Well, I'm so happy for you.
What do you want, Paula?
[sighs]
Your 30th birthday
is coming up.
And I was wondering if I could
take you out to dinner tomorrow
night to celebrate.
PAULA (ON PHONE): Oh.
Dinner?
Yes.
I haven't seen you
in at least a month.
And since I always take
you out on your birthday,
I thought it would
be a good way to kill
two birds with one stone.
Well, thank you, Paula.
That's really nice.
But I can't tomorrow.
Maybe next week.
I can't next week.
Tomorrow's good.
Well, then the week after.
I can't the week after.
Tomorrow's good.
Well, my birthday's
not for weeks.
I mean, we can do
it some other time.
Paula?
Happy 30th birthday, even if
it's not for another few weeks.
Thank you, Paula.
So seeing anyone
new these days?
Why do you want to know?
I'm just curious.
No.
I'm not seeing anyone.
Hm.
Have you been on any dates?
Yes.
I've been on a few dates.
Well, tell me.
I don't think so.
Jimmy.
Paula.
I just want to make
sure you're happy.
Paula, every
time we go out, you
always ask me who I'm dating.
That always leads to talking
about when we were going out,
which always leads to
you telling me what
was wrong with our relationship,
which leads to you telling
me what is wrong with me.
And that always leads
to you telling me how
happy you are now with Gregory.
So let's just talk
about something else.
OK?
That is not true.
Paula, please.
OK.
Are you still seeing Mimi?
Do you mean, are
we still friends?
Yes.
Friends.
Whatever.
Yeah.
I still see Mimi.
Hm.
How is she?
Why do you loathe
her so, Paul?
I don't loathe her, Jimmy.
I think she's a very nice
person for the person she is.
For the--
Sushi.
For the person she is.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
Really.
[scoffs]
OK.
I just think she's so plain.
You know.
I just think you can do better.
That's all.
Better than what?
She's just a friend.
She is just a friend.
Really?
Yes, Paula.
Really.
I can't believe you're
still jealous of her.
I am not jealous of her.
And I never have been.
I'm sorry.
You're right.
Besides how could
I be jealous of her.
She could never
have what we had.
Paula.
PAULA: Do you ever
think about us?
Paula, please.
I mean it, Jimmy.
Sometimes when I'm alone I
remember some of the nights
and some of the things we did.
Do you remember.
Yes.
[breathes]
Do you ever think
about those nights?
I mean, when you're alone.
Yeah.
Sometimes.
Do you miss them?
Yeah.
Sometimes.
[gasps]
PAULA: So do I. We
were hot, weren't we?
Mhm.
But then I always remember
how unhappy you made me.
[snaps]
And it just goes away.
Mhm.
We're better off this way.
You know, I'm so much
happier with Gregory.
[laughs under his breath]
Someday you'll find
somebody, Jimmy.
JANE DOE: And you
still see this woman?
Oh, at first I didn't want to.
But she was pretty
insistent about it.
And, you know, I kind of always
believe that people should
be friends after they break up.
JANE DOE: Oh.
Do you really believe that?
Yeah.
Well, I've always tried to.
JANE DOE: Mhm.
But after a while, I began
to wonder why she dumped me.
You know, I mean, what did
he have that I didn't have?
So I'd go out with
her to find out.
JANE DOE: So did you
eventually find out?
Yeah.
She finally told me
one night straight out.
We were eating Italian.
And it reminded her of how much
she hated my table manners.
JANE DOE: Your table manners?
Yeah.
I cut my spaghetti.
Well, she flipped out.
She said that no Italian
man would be caught
dead cutting his spaghetti.
Then she pointed out that no
Italian man would be caught
dead wearing my clothes either.
She even hated the fact that
I wasn't Italian, or French,
or something different.
And now she never
stops telling me.
JANE DOE: Are you a masochist?
Masochist?
No.
What do you mean, masochist?
JANE DOE: Well, let
me get this straight.
You must love this woman
if you're still seeing her.
No.
I am not in love with Paula.
JANE DOE: Well, if you're
not in love with her,
it was a painful relationship.
She dumped you you moved
in with somebody else.
And you're still seeing her?
You're either a
masochist or an idiot.
SEAN: You're an idiot.
JIMMY: I beg your pardon?
- No.
She's right.
You're an idiot.
And I've been telling
you that for years.
Just because I think
it's right to stay
friends with a woman after
we've broken up, I'm an idiot.
Jim, what's the point?
I mean, look at it.
You're not getting laid.
And chances are, you never will.
Worst of all, she's a bitch.
Sean, every woman
is a bitch to you.
Yeah.
But I mean it with Paula.
I don't get it.
She's fucking somebody
else and she dumps you.
A week later, she's
shacked up with the guy.
Now, nobody should have to
take that kind of abuse.
Why do you still see her?
Because, I mean, if we
can't be friends with a woman
just because we
slept with them, I
mean, where does that leave us?
Oh, it leaves us to
move on to the next one.
That's where.
I don't want to be friends
with women I've gone out with.
It just doesn't work.
Maybe that's
because you were never
their friends to begin with.
What?
Face it.
You just can't handle
being friends with women.
At least Jimmy's trying.
You're not mature enough,
and you don't respect them.
All right.
What about you?
What?
I have no trouble being
friends with women.
I respect and truly like the
women I've gone out with.
They are my friends.
Exactly.
All your friends except
for us are women.
So.
So you're like
their little pet.
I mean, what do you get
out of those relationships?
Stimulating conversation?
Certainly not sex.
I mean, Jimmy over here
may be a little mixed up.
But at least he's getting
foop once in a while.
[sighs]
It always comes
down to sex with you.
Does a friendship with a
woman require a sexual favor?
You are so full of shit.
If they were willing
you'd grab it in a second.
Your ignorance is
truly astounding.
This is a lovely
bearnaise sauce, Sean.
Oh, thanks.
All right.
What about what's her name?
Your latest best friend?
Who?
Shanti?
Yeah.
Shanti.
Don't tell me you wouldn't
foop her if she let you.
Leave her out of this.
Look, I'm not a walking
hard on like you.
And I don't happen to
want to foop Shanti.
Oh, what was that?
Did I hear someone
mention the word denial?
- I'm not denying anything.
- Yep.
Yep.
Capital D-E. Yep.
Denial.
TIM: You know, it's sad.
You really have no idea
what you're talking about.
It is so sad listening
to you go on like this.
Yeah.
Well, sad as it
is, at least I've
had sex in the last two years.
Which is more than I
can say for you, Timbo.
Yeah.
Well, at least I'm not going
to die of some sexually
transmitted disease.
[gulp]
- Excuse me.
I'll be right back.
[chuckles]
[sigh]
You know what those are.
Don't you?
[phone ringing]
Hi there.
It's late.
I'm tired.
And you've got a lot of nerve
to be calling at this hour.
So get to the point.
MIMI (ON PHONE):
Hey, hey, Jimmy, boy.
What's up, babe?
Hey, hey.
It's Mimi.
Oh, just sitting
here, writing away.
And how goes the
great epic novel?
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Well,
you know, a word here.
A sentence there.
Oh, it sounds
like a method, Jim.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Yep.
I tell you.
Once I get some of those
paragraphs going, woo.
[chuckles]
Is that water I hear?
Uh-huh.
Listen.
How about lunch tomorrow?
You aren't calling me from
the baththub again, are you?
MIMI (ON PHONE): Uh-huh.
God.
Have you no mercy?
[giggles]
Oh, jeez.
A little frustrated, are we?
All alone here with
the vision of that body
in a tub of steaming water?
Who wouldn't be?
Well, flattery will
get you everywhere.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Yeah.
Not with you, it doesn't.
Well, maybe you
just give up too easy.
Maybe you don't
give in easy enough.
Well, maybe I do
and maybe I don't.
Anyhow, we do lunch tomorrow?
Yeah.
Usual place?
The usual place.
Sleep tight.
- OK.
You too.
Don't miss any spots.
I'll be doing
inspection tomorrow.
Ooh.
I'll be thinking about you
while I'm toweling off.
- Oh, good.
- Goodnight.
Bye.
[beep]
God, I hate that woman.
[music playing]
[shower]
[razor]
[whistling]
[water flowing]
(SINGING) What you say
is all well and fine.
What I'm losing is
the bottom line.
You have to say those things
that are on your mind.
[clears throat]
[sighs]
MIMI: So before
he even finished,
I told him that was
the most pathetic
come on line I'd ever heard.
And on top of that, it wasn't
the first time I'd heard it.
Ooh.
So what'd he do then?
Well, let's see.
He-- well, he called me a cunt.
Told me I was probably
a lousy fuck anyway.
And then he walked straight up
to another girl to try again.
Ouch.
Aw, I hate guys like that.
You hate them?
Why?
It's not your problem.
- Sure, it is.
- No, it's not.
I'm the one who has to deal
with schmucks like that.
Yeah.
But I'm the one that
has to pay for it.
Oh, you.
How do you pay for it?
When the guy walked
off, how'd you feel?
I was pissed off.
Exactly.
So say you didn't know me.
And, you know, I walked up
to you five minutes later
and tried to strike
up a conversation.
What would you say?
I'd um--
I'd probably tell
you to take a hike.
Right.
I mean, you're so angry,
you shut the door.
And your night is shot.
So I'm the one who pays.
I mean, boneheads like that guy
ruin it for all us other guys.
Well, maybe if you were
like a really nice guy.
Mimi, women have
become so jaded,
they wouldn't know a nice guy
if he saved her from a dragon.
I mean, there's-- there's
just too many schmucks
like that guy out there.
I mean, jerks with
lousy lines like that
ruin it for jerks like me.
What?
With other lousy lines?
That's right.
And I swear to god.
That guy is following me
around, hitting on every woman
just before I do.
[giggling]
Uh.
Jimmy.
What?
- I can't believe you.
- Why?
What's wrong?
Well, what?
Have you got whiplash?
Did you see the way
your head just jerked
around when she walked by?
You're a pig.
I was just looking
at the woman.
Well, do you
know what it feels
like to be looked at like that?
It's degrading.
Degrading?
My god, Mimi.
She was a beautiful woman.
I was just looking.
Yeah.
Well, I don't think
she appreciates
the way you were just looking.
Well, I don't
think she minded it.
Oh, come on.
The makeup.
The outfit.
The woman wants to be looked at.
You were undressing
her with your eyes.
I didn't have to.
She wasn't wearing that much.
What's gotten into you?
You disappoint me, Jimmy.
Mimi, she was a gorgeous
woman, and I was just looking.
I'm not going to let you
make me feel guilty for that.
OK.
[knocking]
JANE DOE: Women think about
sex just as much as men.
Yeah.
But you just said they don't.
JANE DOE: No, I didn't.
I just meant they don't think
about it in the same way.
Right.
OK.
Look, what I want to
know is, do women not
look at men because they
just don't think about it?
Do they not look on purpose?
Or do they think
they're not supposed to?
JANE DOE: It's not a
question of whether they're
supposed to or not.
Women can do anything
they damn well please.
Look, I could not agree more.
But the way this stupid
society is setup,
the man always has to
chase after the woman.
So, of course, he's
always looking.
And because the woman
is being chased,
she doesn't have to look,
because, theoretically, she
shouldn't have to.
Right?
No.
I don't know about that.
This is the '90s.
Right?
JANE DOE: Yeah.
When was the last time you
asked a man out on a date?
JANE DOE: You're not
allowed to ask me--
JIMMY: No.
No.
Come on.
This is important.
When was the last time you
asked a man out on a date?
JANE DOE: Don't
ask me questions.
OK.
Well, then can we say
for argument's sake,
it's probably not that often?
JANE DOE: OK.
Great.
So here we are in the '90s,
after more than 20 years
of modern feminism, and women
are still sitting back waiting
for guys to ask them out.
JANE DOE: No, they're not!
Yes, they are.
Practically every woman
friend that I have
complains about how
they never go out.
And then when they do the
guy was always a schmuck.
But they never get off their
asses and do anything about it.
JANE DOE: Yeah.
Well, you know exactly
what a man thinks when
the woman makes the first move.
No.
What?
JANE DOE: He freaks
out because he doesn't
have control of the situation.
Bullshit!
I do not know one man
who would not rather have
the woman make the first move.
I mean, we always have
to risk rejection.
Do you know what that's like?
JANE DOE: Yeah, Rovinski.
I do happen to know
what it's like.
And if women aren't
asking men out,
it's because men
just can't take it.
Oh, I don't know that
there are too many men that
are thinking like that anymore.
And besides, even if you do
run into a guy like that,
it ought to take you
about two seconds
to figure him out and dump him.
Right?
JANE DOE: No.
It's not as simple
as you make it sound.
Oh, I think it's very simple.
I think when it comes
to initiating things,
men have had the short end
of the stick for too long.
JANE DOE: Men have had the
short end of the stick?
JIMMY: Yes.
Men!
I think it's about
time that women
took some of the risks too.
But I'm not saying I'm
going to wait around
for a woman to call me up.
I already tried that
and it didn't work.
JANE DOE: Gee.
Big surprise, Rovinski.
Thank you, Jane.
You know, I can
just see how quickly
the world is going to change
with charmers like you around.
[blows smoke]
SEAN: Hey, guys.
Remember Ramona Klein?
Yeah.
Well, last week
I saw her having
dinner with Teddy Pripstein.
Ew.
So I'm sitting
there, trying to eat.
Right?
He starts kissing her.
Ew.
Oh.
Yeah.
But get this.
She wasn't kissing him.
She was just letting
him kiss her.
What do you mean?
Well, she was
letting everyone around
know that even though
she was with him,
she didn't want to be with him.
Yeah.
So.
Well, don't you get it?
She's showing everyone that
she's available in case
something better comes along.
She's not tight with Pripstein.
But she's keeping him
close, just in case.
Ramona Klein was the hottest
girl I knew in college.
I mean, everybody wanted
to go out with her.
- I didn't.
- Heh.
You mean couldn't.
No.
I mean, didn't.
I never found her
that attractive.
You're nuts.
She's incredible.
Just look in any
fashion magazine.
There's lots of
women just like her.
Yeah.
Well, I'd do her.
Well, you know, I might
have done her if her bum
was just a little bit smaller.
What?
Her bums too big.
Yes.
She has a nice face.
But I don't like her bum.
And god knows what you'll
find when her bra comes off.
Woo.
Breasts?
Yea-- didn't you say you were
going to quit smoking today?
Did you hear today?
I said tomorrow.
Ramona Klein had guys falling
all over her 10 years ago.
And now she's hanging
out with Teddy Pripstein.
That's kind of sad.
What's so sad about it?
10 years ago the woman never
had any problems getting men.
She could pick and choose.
Well, she got too picky, and
now she's paying the price.
Jesus.
You sound bitter.
I'm not bitter.
I just think it's justice.
Justice?
What has justice
got to do with it?
Look, 10 years ago
I couldn't get a date
if my life depended
on it, especially
not with a woman like that.
I just think it's justice to
see things coming around a bit.
That's all.
But you still
can't get a date.
That's not the point.
JIMMY: No.
No.
It is the point.
I mean, you're right, Tim.
Romona Klein could pick
and choose 10 years ago.
Well, why not now?
And why is it that 10
years ago women like Ramona
always dumped me?
They always had control.
Whoa.
Snap out of it, son.
You've done your fair share
of trashing relationships.
But don't you see?
That is exactly the point.
It's all a power thing.
And that's what's
so sad about Ramona.
She thinks that just
because she's hit 30,
she hasn't got power anymore.
It's a cruel world, Jimmy boy.
And Ramona's proof.
A cruel, cruel world.
[sighs]
I'm just not willing to
settle for any of the men
I've gone out with.
Why should I?
I mean, I'm not to
settle for some guy
just because I want to
get married and have kids.
No way.
I'd rather be alone.
Wait.
Let me guess.
You want someone who is
good looking, intelligent,
can be your best friend, and
happens to be a great lay.
Right?
Yeah.
And he loves kids too.
Wakey wakey, Joe.
All that sensitive
guy double talk
is bullshit The
experiment proves it.
He doesn't exist.
Yeah, he does.
Mm.
No.
There are three types of
men in this world, honey.
Men you're friends with.
Men who pay the bills
and you have kids with.
And men you fuck.
And I plan to have
plenty of all three.
Well, that is pretty cynical.
Don't you think?
Bullshit, cynical.
It's reality.
Hi, there.
My name's Sean,
and I just thought
I'd drop by and say hello.
Well, thank you.
But we would have asked you
if we wanted you to say hello.
Well, then I'll get
right to the point.
I simply dropped
by to extend to you
both an invitation to a party
we're having Saturday night.
JANE DOE: Duh Boys?
SEAN: Yeah.
You know, the boys.
Duh boys.
Heh, heh.
It's a little play on words
my roommate Jimmy thought up.
Mm.
SEAN: Cool.
Huh?
- Do her?
I expect that from
erection head over there.
Think you can do her?
SEAN: So what do you say?
Saturday night?
Joe.
8 o'clock.
WOMAN: Joe!
I'll be there.
[music playing]
TIM: It has nothing to do
with pollution, dimwit.
It's the lights from the city.
No, it's not.
Yes, it is.
Fuck off.
Look it up, Einstein.
You're saying the light from
a city is bright enough to block
out the light from a star?
Yes.
Not a chance.
Those stars are sun.
That's right.
About 10 trillion miles away.
So what?
They're suns.
Excuse me, Mr. MBA.
But did you do a
degree in astronomy
while we weren't looking?
Come on.
It's common sense.
Yeah.
And I suppose they put those
telescopes on mountaintops
in the deepest, darkest
forests of South
America out of common sense.
Yeah.
There's no pollution out there.
Jimmy, settle this.
Why can't we see as
many stars in the city?
Lights or pollution?
What's the most romantic
night you guys ever had?
Uh-oh.
[sighs]
Gee, I don't know, Sean.
What is the most romantic
night we ever had?
Rovinski, every time we sleep
out here, you turn to mush.
When you get drunk you start
kissing us and telling us
how much you love us.
And when we sleep out, you
always start talking like this.
Jesus.
I remember the most
romantic night I ever had.
I was backpacking in
Italy, and I just started
seeing this girl named--
Daniella.
Yeah.
We were at this rooftop
party in Florence.
It was the beginning of
summer, and everything
was just starting to bloom.
It was warm.
And the air was so
thick and perfumed
you could almost cut it.
And all night long
I just couldn't
stop staring at her,
what she was wearing,
her hair, her skin, her eyes.
I couldn't believe that
I was with this woman.
I mean, she was
just too amazing.
Everybody was speaking Italian.
And I couldn't
understand a word.
But it didn't matter.
We both knew that we were going
to make love for the first time
that night.
And we were in no rush.
Oh.
I could've stayed at
that party all night.
It was like I could
feel time passing.
Like it was washing past me,
like wind making me squint.
I loved every minute.
And when we got back
to her apartment,
we didn't even have
to turn on the lights.
It was one of those weird
nights where it wasn't dark.
It was just kind of--
just kind of blue.
SEAN: And?
You did it?
[laughs]
Till it got light.
Yeah.
I was religious.
I didn't want it to end.
In a way I wish it
had never happened.
How come?
Well, because nothing's
ever been as good since.
Gee, that's tough, Jim.
Yeah.
We really feel for you.
Yeah, but don't you guys ever
worry about giving that up?
TIM: What?
Well, the first
time with somebody.
I mean, I think sometimes
that's the main reason
I'll never get married.
So don't get married.
What's the big deal?
No.
But I would like to get married.
I mean, I'd like to be able
to spend the rest of my life
with somebody, I think.
I don't worry about it.
I'll know when it's right.
I know it won't be
right for a long time.
But I'll know when it's right.
Yeah.
Well, I worry about it.
I mean, whenever I'm willing
to commit to somebody,
they're not interested
in committing to me.
And whenever somebody
wants me to commit,
I'm not interested in them.
TIM: Jim, timing's everything.
JIMMY: Yeah.
Well, I think I've gone numb.
Don't sweat it, Jim.
Men and women were
never meant to be
together for extended
periods of time anyway.
You know, Tim, that's
what I like about you.
You're so up.
You got to go back
and find that babe, Jim.
Yeah.
Italy.
I got to go back to Italy.
[wind]
[sighs]
JANE DOE: Look,
I want to see how
this guy is going to react when
he has to answer to a face.
Has it ever occurred to
you that some of these men
might feel protected by the
fact that they can't see us?
Protected?
No.
Yes.
I mean, they can hear us.
They know we're women.
But they can't see us.
It gives them an out.
My god.
It's like phone sex.
No.
It's not like phone sex.
Don't you think
that seeing us would
change the way they answer?
I mean, don't you think it
would put them more on the spot?
No.
I think that seeing us
would make them clam up.
No.
I disagree.
I think a liar is going to lie
no matter who he's talking to.
Look, if you do this I'll have
you thrown off this experiment.
Why?
This is my thesis project.
I set the rules.
And quite frankly, I am
happy with the results.
Why do you want to do this?
Look, this whole
project is experimental.
I want to try
something different.
That's the nature
of experimentation.
Experimentation?
Yes.
Experimentation.
Oh, my.
You are quite dedicated.
Aren't you?
No less than you.
WOMAN: Really?
Yes, really.
Look, I've been getting
really weird vibes off you
since this whole thing started.
Have you?
[sighs]
Is there something
about me that offends you?
I don't know.
Something about the way I dress,
or the way I am as a woman?
I don't trust your
motives, as a woman.
What do you mean exactly?
What I mean is I see
no good reason for you
to show yourself to this guy.
I think your motives
are personal.
Personal?
Uh-huh.
[laughs]
You think I want
to fuck this guy.
That's it.
Isn't it?
You think I want
to fuck this guy!
WOMAN: I don't
know what you want.
[laughs]
Look, you know, I haven't
really thought about it.
I mean, maybe.
Maybe I do.
But you know what?
I get the feeling that
would really bother you.
You can fuck anybody you like.
I couldn't care less.
JANE DOE: Really?
What are your motives?
[dance music]
Hi, Mimi.
Oh, hi.
Paula, how are you?
I'm fine.
How are you?
I'm good.
What are you doing shopping
in the middle of the afternoon?
Oh, it's been a long week.
You know, I thought
I'd spoil myself,
take a Friday afternoon off.
Oh, good for you.
You're a paralegal, aren't you?
Well, no.
I used to be.
But I've been a lawyer
for two years now.
That's stupid of me.
I don't know why I keep
thinking you're a secretary.
What kind of law are you doing?
Corporate.
Oh, good choice.
Good choice.
All those wealthy young
investment bankers.
Have you snared one yet?
[laughs]
I'm sorry.
A husband?
Oh, don't tell me you're
doing corporate law
for the challenge.
Well, actually--
Mimi.
To tell you the
truth, Paula, if I'd
wanted to find a
husband, I would
have become a divorce lawyer.
Right.
Well, I better be going.
I guess I'll see
you tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night?
Yeah.
Jimmy and the boys' party.
Oh, didn't you know about it?
Oh, I'm-- yeah.
I just have-- I have
so much on my mind, I
just completely forgot about it.
Well, then I guess I'll
see you tomorrow night.
- OK.
- Bye Paula.
- Bye.
JANE DOE: Listen, don't hand
me that shit about control.
I know plenty of women who
complain they aren't getting
enough sex from their men.
Well, good.
I think it's about
time men stood up
and started denying women sex.
JANE DOE: What?
[laughs]
You're saying men are
consciously denying women sex?
No.
I'm saying that they are
unconsciously denying women
sex, because somewhere
inside they're pissed off
with women's sexist attitude.
Women's sexist attitude?
Yes.
Women's sexist attitude.
That a man's sexual
desire is something dirty.
But despite that, we
should get it up every time
a woman snaps her fingers.
JANE DOE: Talking
about sexist attitudes.
I mean, what-- what
about the assholes
who expect women to
put out after they've
bought them dinner?
JIMMY: Yeah.
But don't you see?
That's all we ever
hear about are the men.
Nobody ever talks about
women being sexist.
Like it's a fucking
crime if you do.
Wait!
You're making men sound
like victims here.
No.
I'm just tired of always
hearing men take the blame
when relationships go bad.
I mean, I know.
Jesus.
I know we've got
a long way to go.
But I just wish that women
would admit that they've
got some changing to do too.
Like how?
Like maybe stop complaining
about being helpless victims
all the time.
Christ, I'm tired of that.
Listen, violence
against women--
I don't want to
hear about statistics.
I mean, do I look like some
kind of violent rapist to you?
Have I given you any indication
that I would ever hurt you?
I mean, my god, Jane,
it's just you and me here.
I mean, please, don't come at
me with a bunch of statistics
about sick fuckers.
That's insulting.
Yes.
But it's a real problem!
Well, you don't have
to convince me of it.
I mean, I know
what men are doing.
But when you come at me
with stuff like that,
you make me feel
like I'm one of them.
And I'm not.
You and I have gotten past the
point where we have to worry
about each other being psychos.
Right?
[huffs]
Yes.
So let's just stick
to the main issue
here, which is a
relationship between two
relatively healthy people.
Not some wackos are
doing out on the street.
You're right.
We should keep this
just between two people.
You're absolutely right.
[music playing]
JIMMY: Well, boys,
here we are again.
It is party time.
SEAN: Fucking A.
Let's do some damage.
Huh?
Damage?
Oh, lighten up, Tim.
Are you sure you don't want
to smoke tonight, buddy?
No.
I don't want to smoke tonight.
I don't need to smoke tonight.
No.
More than that.
I'm not a smoker anymore.
Why don't you wait till
tomorrow to not be a smoker
anymore, in the name of sanity?
You're not listening, Jimmy.
You're not listening.
OK.
Well, boys, we are the
hosts with the most.
And there are women here
tonight to be mosted.
So good luck, and godspeed.
Amen.
Yes.
[murmuring]
Simians.
SINGER: (SINGING)
No matter what I do.
I was learning how--
Mind over matter.
I simply had to think
about how utterly illogical
the act of smoking is.
I mean, inhaling the smoke from
a dried, burning plant leaf,
it's ridiculous.
Haven't picked one up since.
Really?
When did you quit?
This afternoon.
It's a drag really.
MIMI: Hey, Jimmy, boy.
Hey.
It's Mimi.
Good party, Jim.
Who's friends are these?
Aha, ha, ha.
Witty as ever.
Oh, hello.
Mimi Campbell,
this is Ben Calder.
Hi.
Ben and I were on the ski
team together in college.
Oh, I didn't know
you raced, Jimmy.
Mm.
So what do you do now, Ben?
Ben.
He just finished a two
year stint in Hong Kong.
Uh-huh.
He's taking the summer off.
And then he's going
to work in Paris.
Rough life, huh?
- Wow.
Jeez.
Is it ever?
I've always wanted
to live in Paris.
You're very lucky.
[laughter]
[dance music]
PAULA: Jimmy!
Ah, heh.
Paula.
Should I be angry at you?
You know you can't have a
party without inviting me.
[laughs]
Well, I forgot.
Remember Gregory?
Who can forget?
Hi, Greg.
(SPEAKS WITH ACCENT) Gregory.
Right.
Gregory.
Oh, look.
There's Mimi.
Hi, Mimi!
Ooh, la, la.
Who is that?
Ben Calder.
He's a college friend.
Oh, he is something.
Bet you a buck she goes
home with him tonight.
I hated him.
I can't believe he did this.
I knew it.
God.
I hate him.
I know.
Why'd you sleep with him?
What do you mean, why
did I sleep with him?
I didn't know I'd hate him.
Oh.
Oh god.
[cough]
- How you doing?
I saw your play.
I really liked it.
Hey.
[bump]
Ow.
I'm sorry.
It's nothing personal I was
just trying to squeeze by.
No.
That's fine.
[laughing]
Sure.
Excuse me.
Nice broach.
[exhales]
[dance music]
[giggling]
I can't believe
you take this shit.
[laughing]
JIMMY: Do you ever dream
of the perfect woman?
Only every night.
Well, my perfect woman
looks just like Paula.
Except she's smart enough
to overcome the handicap
of being beautiful.
SINGER: (SINGING IN SPANISH)
WOMAN: He's such a prick.
You know that?
He's a real prick.
I know.
Men are real bastards.
You know that?
Real fucking bastards.
I know.
So why'd you sleep with him?
Because-- I didn't know he'd
be that much of a bastard.
Oh.
[blows smoke]
SINGER: (SINGING IN SPANISH)
[whispering]
You can try.
Excuse me.
Do you have a bathroom?
Yes.
Would you like to use it?
Please.
Down the hallway.
Last door on your right.
Thank you.
But Problema.
Hey, Paula.
Fuck off, Sean.
OK.
[latin music]
WOMAN: I really
thought he was the one.
You know?
- I know.
I know.
[glass shattering]
But before we
even got started,
I had this really bad
feeling about him.
You know?
[breathing heavy]
I know.
So why'd you sleep with him?
Well, I really
thought he was the one.
Oh.
SINGER: (SINGING IN SPANISH)
Just so that I know,
Sean, is there a woman here
tonight you haven't slept with?
Yes.
Her.
[sighs]
How you doing?
Good.
(SINGING) So
not feeling always
til it's time to take to home.
Every time.
On an easy steal--
You've just been through
a lot of relationships.
You know?
Yeah.
Well, I guess I just
haven't been that lucky.
Lucky?
What about Rachel?
Rachel?
My god.
Mimi, that was ages ago.
What about Rachel?
Oh, come on, Jimmy.
She was nice.
Very nice.
MIMI: She was beautiful.
Like she was really beautiful.
Yeah.
So?
Well, what was wrong with her?
I don't know.
It just didn't feel right.
MIMI: Mm.
Jimmy, you shouldn't
have broken up with her.
Mimi, we had
nothing in common.
And I just wasn't interested.
Well, I just think you were
kind of lucky to be going
out with someone like her.
Should I be offended?
Why?
Well, I mean, you make
it sound like I didn't have
the right to break up with her.
What are you talking about?
Like who do I think I am?
No.
I just think she's beautiful.
And she's so nice.
That's all.
[clears throat]
So where's Ben?
Oh, he had to go.
Oh.
[laughter]
Oh, oh.
I got one.
What's the best way to
give a woman an orgasm?
Heh?
Hey?
Who cares?
[laughing hysterically]
Excuse me.
Hey, where you going?
It's late.
I got to go.
Well, come on.
Stick around.
The party's not over yet.
[laughs]
Yeah.
Well, it is for me.
Thanks for the invite.
Why?
You didn't even give me a chance
to tell you all about myself.
[laughs]
Who cares?
[knocking]
Shit.
Just a minute.
You lied to me.
I did?
Yes, you did.
You told me you quit smoking.
I-- Yeah.
I have quit.
Well, then I guess the
person smoking in here
just jumped out the window.
[laughing]
I guess so.
Why did you lie to me?
Um-- I--
What are you
feeling inside that
makes you have to lie to me?
Inside?
Mm.
You've been hurt, haven't you?
Uh, huh.
I know you won't lie to me
unless somebody's hurt you.
I know what you're feeling.
I know.
Mm.
[laughs nervously]
[moaning]
I mean, I'm sure women are
having a good time with me.
I'm just not sure they're
having a good time,
if you know what I mean.
You're not sure if
they're having orgasms.
I'm pretty sure.
I mean, they seem like
they're having orgasms.
But I'm just not really sure.
Oh, shit, man.
I gave up worrying about
that a long time ago.
What?
Sean, look, that's all I
used to ever think about.
Was it good for her?
Did she cum?
I finally realized
that I was so caught up
worrying about her
orgasm that I wasn't even
enjoying having sex myself.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And whenever I
asked if it was good,
well, they'd get
mad at me and tell
me that I had an ego problem.
So I figured, hey,
what's the point.
Yeah.
I guess.
Well, like I know they're
enjoying it with me.
Right?
I just wonder sometimes.
Look, I figure if the woman
doesn't have the guts to show
me what to do, or be responsible
enough to get herself off,
I figure she doesn't
deserve an orgasm.
Yeah.
Maybe.
But you know what I think?
I think it's all some
big female conspiracy.
What is?
Women having orgasms.
I think it's a myth.
[blows smoke]
I'll uh-- see you
in the morning, boys.
[muttering]
SEAN: Good party.
JIMMY: Good party.
TIM: Great party.
[laughing]
JIMMY: Great party.
SEAN: Nice babes.
JIMMY: Nice babes.
SEAN: Didn't score though.
JIMMY: Nope.
Didn't score.
SEAN: Tim scored.
[laughs]
JIMMY: Oh, Tim scored.
SEAN: Anybody else score?
JIMMY: I don't know.
I think Mimi's hot for
Ben Calder, though.
Oh, yeah.
How do you know?
I just know.
I've known Mimi long enough
to know when she is in heat.
And heat is right.
That guy's going to have
the time of his life.
What do you mean?
I mean, the woman is wild.
Shit.
Really?
How do you know?
SEAN: I fucked her last winter.
You did?
When?
SEAN: When we all
went on that ski week.
Yeah.
You weren't there.
Were you?
No.
I had to teach.
Wow.
You slept with Mimi.
SEAN: Oh, yeah.
She was great.
She was?
Awesome.
Best blowjob I ever had.
Really?
SEAN: And she's got the
nicest roundest breasts.
Huge nipples.
What a body.
Hm.
And can she fuck.
Really?
SEAN: Oh yeah.
She was awesome.
[laughs]
Shit.
That guy's going to get cranked.
Really?
[glass shatters]
Fuck.
Look, that'll be it
for today, folks.
I'll see you all on Thursday.
There's something
I want to show you.
I beg your pardon?
[laughs]
I said, there's something
I want to show you.
Oh, really.
Uh, what's that?
Me.
You?
Yeah.
Me.
You-- you were right.
We should keep this
just between two people.
[laughs]
You're Jane Doe.
Yeah.
Wow.
I thought we were
never supposed to see.
Oh, well, you aren't.
But I'm changing the rules.
You are?
Why?
Because I don't
agree with them.
You were at the party
on Saturday night.
JANE DOE: Yep.
And I'm probably going to
get in a lot of trouble
for doing this.
Oh, they may even kick
me off the experiment.
JIMMY: Oh, but you
spent all this time.
Oh, that's OK.
I mean, you know, I've
learned a few things.
I'll start my own project.
[laughs]
JANE DOE: You seem
uncomfortable.
Is there something wrong?
- No.
No.
It's-- no.
It's just, you know, strange
seeing you all of a sudden.
Well, I had a picture,
you know, in my mind.
- Disappointed.
- No.
No.
I mean, it's-- it's good.
I mean, it's good
to see you, finally.
[laughs nervously]
You know, I have--
I've really never met
a man like you before.
What do you mean?
Well, for someone as
physically attractive
as you are, it's
rare to find someone
so intellectually elegant.
My.
Thank you.
- Really.
I mean it.
I mean, you're really different.
You know, you're not afraid
to show your weaknesses.
You seem to almost
celebrate them.
Well, I don't see any
reason to hide them.
JANE DOE: And that's
what I like about you.
Humility and looks.
That's rare.
And you're really,
really good at it too.
Hm?
JANE DOE: Well, I'll bet
tons of women fall for it.
Fall for what?
Well, your con.
What con?
Your looks, your
elegance, your humility,
and, ungh, I can tell you,
it really is a turn on.
It's not a con.
JANE DOE: Yeah.
Jimmy, it's so good a con, you
don't even know it's a con.
But it's not a con.
Everybody's got a con.
I've got a con.
You've got a con.
We've all got a con
to get what we want.
And yours, it is-- mhm-- it's
really different, you know.
But it's all camouflage.
You think you're better
than most people.
[laughs]
- No, I don't.
Yeah, you do.
You're a bit of an
arrogant, self-righteous
son of a bitch, James Rovinski.
And I think you hide it
behind a wall of humility.
Really?
And I think that you
are really offended
when a woman isn't attracted
to you, offended to your core.
Look, I think I have
learned to live with the fact
that not every woman
is attracted to me.
Yeah.
Well, you may learn
to live with it.
But you don't accept it.
That's not true.
You never get the
women you want, Jimmy.
I mean, it seems to me, you're
attracted to intelligent women.
But somehow, they always
get away from you.
So?
So-- so maybe--
maybe they sense you're
looking down on them.
I mean, they can't explain it
because you hide it so well.
But they feel it.
And it turns them off.
Look, what are you--
you don't have the slightest
idea what you're talking about.
JANE DOE: Oh, really?
Think about it, Rovinski.
Just think about it.
[phone ringing]
JIMMY: Hi.
Thanks for calling.
Please leave a message for Sean,
Tim, or Jimmy after the beep.
Thanks for calling.
Bye.
MIMI (ON PHONE): Hey, Jim.
It's Mimi.
I'm just calling
to make sure we're
on for dinner tomorrow night.
Give me a call back.
Bye.
SINGER: (SINGING) Every time
she break if you relay every--
[phone ringing]
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Hello.
PAULA: Hello, James, dear.
Did I wake you up?
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Yes.
Well, it's late morning.
You should be getting up anyway.
Listen, I was just calling
to thank you about the party
Saturday night.
I really appreciate it.
JIMMY (ON PHONE): Paula--
Paula, you know how when
you go to bed at night
and you're not really
sure about something,
and then you wake
up in the morning
and suddenly you're sure?
Yes.
Well, I'm sure I don't
want you calling me anymore.
[laughs]
I beg your pardon.
I'm also sure that
I don't want to go
out to dinner with you anymore.
What?
As a matter of
fact, I'm sure I don't
ever want to see you again.
Jimmy.
Don't bother me any more.
OK.
Please?
Bye Paula.
(SINGING) All black nature.
Oh, hey Jim.
How you doing?
JIMMY: Hey, Sean.
Where are you off to?
JIMMY: I'm going to
Mimi's for dinner.
Oh.
Listen, Jimmy, it occurred
to me that maybe I
shouldn't have told you anything
about what happened between me
and Mimi.
You know, I was kind of
hammered on Saturday night.
And I just kind of forgot
how you feel about her.
Yeah.
Well, did you just
kind of forget
while you were fucking her too?
Come on, Jim.
I'm trying to apologize here.
JIMMY: Really?
Well, don't sweat it, Seany boy.
Maybe someday I'll
sleep with somebody
you're in love with if you
ever fall in love with anybody.
Yeah.
Well, just so you know, it
was one of those things.
We were drunk.
And it just happened.
It didn't mean anything.
Great.
Well, that's just great.
You know, I think that's
what bothers me the most.
Fuck.
Oh, come on.
You have more friends than this.
Yeah.
But these are the ones I like.
[laughing]
MIMI: No, really.
I want to have a big,
big party for you.
Honestly, I can't
think of anybody else.
Do you want to invite Paula?
What do you think?
I don't know.
No.
I do not want to invite Paula.
MIMI: Oh, I know.
How about Ben?
JIMMY: Ben?
You mean Ben Calder.
Yeah.
How about him?
Oh, Ben.
Well, Ben and I aren't, you
know, really that good friends.
Yeah.
Well, why don't we
just invite him anyway?
Yeah.
I guess so.
OK.
Ben and his girlfriend.
- He's got a girlfriend?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
He's got a girlfriend.
Oh.
What a bummer?
He is such a cutey.
[laughs]
What's wrong?
Mimi, why do you want
to have this party?
What?
The party.
Why do you want to
have this party for me?
Because you're my friend.
And it's your birthday.
And I thought it would
be a nice thing to do.
JIMMY: That's the only reason?
- Yeah.
JIMMY: Really?
Well, what are you getting at?
JIMMY: There is no other reason?
Like what?
Like maybe you're interested
in one of my friends.
And if he was at the party,
that would be the perfect chance
to get at him.
Is that what you think?
JIMMY: I don't know.
Yes.
That is what I think.
Should I?
What do you think I am?
I don't know, Mimi.
But why don't you just tell me
when you're interested in one
of my friends.
Why don't you just say,
Jimmy, I find Ben attractive.
Will you set me up?
I didn't know.
It just doesn't feel right.
JIMMY: Yeah.
And why doesn't it feel right?
I don't know.
Well, I'll tell you why.
Because we're not friends.
MIMI: What are
you talking about?
If we were
friends, you wouldn't
have any trouble telling me
who you're interested in.
No.
That's not true.
I always tell you
about my boyfriends.
Yeah.
When you're going out with them.
But whenever we're
single we never talk
about who we're interested in.
What is wrong with you?
That's just bullshit.
JIMMY: Oh, is it?
Then why didn't you tell
me that you fucked Sean?
He told you.
JIMMY: Yes.
He told me.
What'd you expect?
The schmuck is only
my best friend.
Oh, that son of a bitch.
Well, if we're such
good friends then
why didn't you tell me?
Because I--
I'll tell you why.
For the same reason that
you couldn't tell me
that you're interested in Ben.
Because you couldn't.
No.
I didn't want to hurt you.
[laughs]
And you think doing it this
way isn't going to hurt me?
Having a party for me?
How fucking ignorant
do you think I am?
I'm not blind.
Do you think I wouldn't be
hurt if you started seeing him?
Oh, what difference
does it make.
Nothing's going to happen now.
He's got a girlfriend.
No, he doesn't.
I just told you that
to see how you'd react.
You bastard.
Yeah, well, at
least now I know.
How many others didn't
you tell me about?
Oh, you know what?
I can't believe this.
What gives you the right to
say this kind of shit to me?
We're friends, Jimmy.
That doesn't mean
you can tell me
who I should be sleeping with.
- OK.
Fine.
And what a sexist
asshole you're being.
I don't hear you talking to
your guy friends like this.
Sean sleeps with
whoever he wants to.
Why don't you bitch at him too?
Because I am not
in love with Sean.
MIMI: Jimmy, you and
I are just friends.
If you can't handle that,
that's your problem.
You're right, Mimi.
Yeah.
It is my problem.
For five years it's
been my problem.
For five years I have watched
you go out with other people.
And you know what?
I'm sick of it.
And I'm sick of pretending
to be your friend.
I'm sick of having to keep my
distance when all I want to do
is just grab you.
We're not friends, Mimi.
And we never have been because
of the way I feel about you.
We are just friends.
And you're going to
have to get used to it.
No.
I've tried, Mimi.
I really have.
And we should be
friends, but I can't.
And I'm ashamed I can't.
And I'm tired of
feeling ashamed.
I'm tired of feeling hurt, and
jealous, and not good enough.
I'm tired of trying
to be your friend.
For five years,
Mimi, I have tried.
And I can't.
I really can't anymore.
So what are you saying?
I don't think we should
see each other anymore, Mimi.
I don't think we can be friends.
I did something I don't
think anybody's ever done.
I broke up with two people.
And I wasn't going out
with either of them.
Oh, Christ.
That's got to be a first.
JANE DOE: So if you ever do
find that one special woman,
what will she be like?
Rich.
Rich?
What?
You want to be a kept man?
Oh, yeah.
Well, it'd be nice.
I just don't want to have
anybody depending on me.
You know?
I have a hard enough time
being responsible for myself.
What else?
I guess I just want somebody
that can see my side of things
too.
You know?
Understanding.
Yeah.
I know it sounds sappy.
But yeah.
And uh-- rich.
Yeah.
Understanding and rich
with a great body.
[laughing]
You're a schmuck, Rovinski.
Uh, wait.
I've got something for you here.
[laughs]
Oh, well, thanks.
But they kicked me
off the project.
Oh, well, I'm
sorry to hear it.
Well, like I said, I'll
start my own project.
Well, keep it for
old time's sake then.
OK.
For old time's sake.
And if you ever need
another guinea pig.
Well, thanks.
I might just take
you up on that offer.
Well, thank you.
It's been interesting.
JIMMY: Interesting.
Ouch.
[laughs]
Well, I've got to get going.
Maybe we'll see you around
the department someday.
Yeah.
I guess.
Well, farewell, Jane Doe.
Farewell, James Rovinski.
By the way, my name's Jo.
JIMMY: I'm sorry.
My name.
It's Jo, short for Joanne.
Nice to meet you
Jo, short for Joanne.
Bye.
Hey Rovinski!
Listen, I know this is going
to sound weird after everything
we've been through,
but would you
have dinner with me some time?
Dinner?
Yeah.
Dinner.
You mean like a date?
Yeah.
A date.
[laughs]
I can't believe
you're laughing at me.
No.
I'm not laughing at you.
I'm-- I'm flattered.
Flattered?
I thought you'd never ask.
[MUSIC - BRAD HAYES, "SAY THOSE
THINGS"]
(SINGING) Words you
told me not too long ago.
If you love me,
better tell me so.
Say those things on your mind.
What you're saying
is in between.
I wish you'd tell me
just what you mean.
You've got to say those
things on your mind.
It's not the truth,
but it's not a lie
when you can't say the
things that you feel inside.
Feel like you're walking
on a moving track.
You take one step forward,
and one step back.
Words you told me
not too long ago.
If you love me,
better tell me so.
Say those things on your mind.
What's you're saying
is in between.
I wish you'd tell me
just what you mean.
You've got to say those
things on your mind.
It's not the truth,
but it's not a lie
when you can't say the
things that you feel inside.
Feel like you're walking
on a moving track.
You take one step forward,
and one step back.
What you say is
all well and fine.
But what I'm missing
is the bottom line.
You got to say those things
that are on your mind.
It's not the truth,
but it's not a lie
when you can't say the
things that you feel inside.
Feel like you're walking
on a moving track.
You take one step forward
and one step back.
What you see is
not what you get.
What's underneath just
ain't come out yet.
You got to say those
things on your mind.
Go on and say those things.
You got to say those things
if they're on your mind.