Subtitles by Quality Kingz Inc.
Dad.
My daughter.
Mae, I'm glad you are here
Your presence will certainly
brighten up this evening.
Don't pay attention.
Someday he'll accept you.
This is mr. Wong
- Who?
He's the one giving this reception
He is a businessman
and he's leading a powerful triad
Please, sit down
How elegant
- Mr Wong is very generous and very powerful
He is very distinguished.
- Totally.
I wonder how much he's worth?
Quickly.
There are 2 intruders in your office.
Block all the exits.
Who could that have been?
The question is not who it was,
but who gave the order.
Don't do it
Do you have him?
- We must go.
Bring the dragon to safety
We let them run for a while.
See you at the meeting
Our lifes will change, Tsu.
Thank you for coming.
We know each other from stories of others.
Everybody does his thing.
We can make our sport public together.
You want to do a game
so we can get to know eachother? I am Leo.
Hi, I am Logan
- Kenjee.
We make two teams.
Do you see that roof there?
The team that puts the ball there, wins.
The ball.
Yes, I have the ball.
Your turn.
Come on.
Here. Here.
The ball. Give me the ball.
Give me the ball.
I got it. I got it.
Yaguy.
- No.
Stupid.
Come on, here.
One point.
- It's not over yet.
He's got the ball
He got it.
Nice game.
New York?
That's tight as hell.
Where do you live?
- Africa. Kinshasa.
Bangkok, nothing beats that.
- Asia. Why not?
What is this about?
A gym for young people of the street.
come on.
Sorry. My little son is waiting for me
- I'm down for whatever, I love adventure.
I'll help. It's on the way.
Let's posse up and do this together.
Study long, study wrong, let's do it.
Come.
This is cool, Leo
When does the training start?
- We should do something like that over here.
This is gonna be great, guys.
It's magical
You have a paradise here
You really feel at home.
I became worried
Do you have it? Show me
- I dont have it.
I left it where it belongs
We're sorry we wasted your time.
Hire someone else.
No wait, she is still young.
Don't listen, master.
Let us show you our loyalty
By crawling for him?
We beg you to accept our apologies.
This theft should humiliate Mr. Wong
for the final strike.
Then this city is mine.
Don't fuck up again.
Kitano, you know the rules
Our members dont marry outsiders
I know.
Because I love a chinese.
I will be punished and chased away...
like a stray dog.
But I swear, Misawa,
that I will return as a master.
I give my family their lost honour back.
If you fail, you will lose a lot more.
You will lose your life.
And above all, your wife.
I can also succeed.
The greater the risk, the greater the reward.
I am his son in law.
If he likes it or not.
Watch out for Kien and Tsu.
They can betray you.
They are chinese themselves.
It wouldn't take a lot of effort for them.
They are hungry.
They're in it to win.
Yeah, holmes. I want chicken
I dont want your wiener!
No, the entire chicken
the chicken that I see there. boc boc boc.
For me and my peeps...
What the fuck is that?
I want the chicken, man!
Rice, chicken.
That chicken there.
Oooh, ok, ok..
The chicken..
Greetings...
How can I help you today?
Oh here you go, I've been waiting for you all day.
Grandma needed dentures,
but I'd rather not have this chicken shoved up my ass.
Be cool...
Chill out man.
- Be cool...
You see this motherfucker?
- Chillax man...
If I watch, I'm an accessory
- Control yourself.
Hey man, chill out!
My insurance won't cover this shit!
Hey, no need to get worked up.
You guys want some wieners?
Come on man.
Very good.
- That was amazing.
I know someone that will be happy
Come on, guys. Dont be afraid
There, no need to hide.
I hear you are going to your grandfather
- Yeah, I intended to go.
Has it been long since you saw him?
- I dont know him.
Perhaps that's why I'm a bit scared
He will be happy to see you.
- I hope so.
Our mixed blood will always be a problem.
Only the yakuza offer us a future.
Why you want to destroy everything
so close to the target?
We've made a mistake, Kien.
From the beginning.
My little sister that knows
and understands everything.
Someday the triads will kill us
for what we have done.
And if they dont do it, Kitano will.
You are wrong.
He needs us.
She didn't make sacrifices
to let us become criminals.
Because of her blood
the triads have banned us.
as outcasts.
Tell me what she has left us...
other than the curse of her blood.
She's dead, Kien.
She didn't abandon us, she's dead.
I will always be there for you.
Anyone wants to excersize?
This shit is wobbly!
- Let's try it.
OK, lets roll!
Look out!
Oh, they are trippin...
That ass is mine now.
Hey fools
You didn't get the message the first time?
Leo, do you know them?
Triangle
To understand your violent behaviour...
You must always put yourself in the
place of the person you are going to hit.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Hey boys, pass on this message:
Bangkok is a battlefield.
It's not a playground.
Come.
Thanks for your help.
- You are here on his territory.
Why? we didn't want to fight.
We just wanted to excersize.
excersize?
He can't see us together.
Go away, or he'll kill you all.
You should have warned us.
- I didn't expect this.
When I came there they wanted to scare me off.
I wasn't raised a coward.
I thought I was done with it.
- Which is not the case.
We have played with our lives.
- Sorry, but I'm not going to give up my gym.
The day when your agression
will dominate you...
it will be too late.
What are you going to do?
- Put my thoughts in order.
If you want to stay, you are welcome.
- thank you.
I've to go too.
And you?
- I'm going home. I've been gone too long.
Let's spend the night here.
Tomorrow we take a morning flight.
Come, we should find a hotel.
Is it far?
Are you counting?
No. They're the names of dead comerades.
I try to keep their memories alive.
What are you talking about?
The war in my village.
I'd rather not talk about it.
It's me. Is he there?
- Yes he is. Do you want to speak to him?
You want to talk with him.
- Put him on the phone
take it easy.
I'm far away, but I love you
and think about you a lot.
Really?
- You shouldn't doubt that.
Do you still have my necklace?
- I will never take it off.
Daddy, I miss you
- I love you and your mother a lot.
Mommy, daddy has to tell you something.
Hello, yes?
Everything ok with you?
- I'm good.
Tell me...
What do you want me to say?
Bye.
- Bye. Take care of yourself.
See you soon.
- Right, yeah. See you soon
Divorced?
- No, just far from eachother.
And you?
- I didn't find the right one yet.
Different than others.
Kien?
Come on in.
You got a plan?
I dont travel thousands of kilometers
just to fight in Bangkok.
That's not for me anymore.
I should have asked her.
- who? the small asian?
She's on the wrong side.
- I dont want to judge her so soon.
Have you already forgotten what happened?
- I know
She only brings troubles. Forget about her.
Kenjee, dont ruin your life.
He's not worth it.
No!
Cut it out, Kenjee. No!
What are you doing here?
Relax, it's cool.
Leave me alone.
- Can't we talk?
What are you afraid of?
You came looking for me.
Go away. Please.
Daddy.
- My boy.
I'm glad to receive you
here with me in my house.
I'm only here to make
my daughter happy.
It is good to reconcile our families
and cultures with each other.
Our ways are too different.
You will never understand that.
An old rule of our triad says
I will never be able to trust you.
Kitano.
- I'm sorry. I've to go.
Thank you for this second chance.
Wong has been waiting a while for
someone to follow him up.
This kidnapping will break his heart.
- I will not disappoint you again.
I'll be right back.
- Are you crazy?
Not today, guys.
Come back tomorrow.
They got away good.
- Do you want to trump them?
It is tempting.
- What?
I wont be part of it.
Yaguy, Come for a second
He is right, he's a father.
But I'm in.
Otherwise I can forget about my gym
We take him to the airport
and tackle them.
Alright, but quickly.
Take me with you...
There she is.
There.
Tsu, Kien wants to talk to you.
Tell him he solves it by himself
- Do it yourself.
That idiot still doesn't understand.
Mind your own business.
Hurry.
This way.
Come with me
Trust me.
Your grandfather knew that you would come
He has told me so much about you
that I know you better than yourself.
You have come a long way.
- Thank you for seeing me.
Your grandfather would have been proud if
he knew you would be amongst his people.
I should have come much sooner.
He's still here, you know.
His spirit still waits for you.
This temple is his residence
He has not left it.
He's here and there. Everywhere at once
He's in the trees.
He's in the wind. He's in you
They will never find us here.
- I want an explanation
What do you want with my life story?
- Maybe I want to stay then
You wont understand anyway
- We shall see.
He took care for me when I was small.
Without him I would be dead.
I can't just abandon him.
What is he to you?
My brother.
Let me help you then.
Wong has been waiting long for
someone to follow him up.
This kidnapping will break his heart.
Kitano was very serious.
We can also do it without her.
But what did she do with him?
Can't she see that he is dangerous?
You always think too much
It is time for action.
Thinking ahead prevent mistakes.
Tell that to your sister.
It's her fault that it came this far.
After the kidnapping Kitano
will take us into his group.
It will be a massacre.
Kitano will give us the chance
to make up for our mistake.
This is our last chance.
this time we wont let him down.
This is not the moment to be weak.
Why aren't you there?
- We must talk.
You want to talk? About what?
About Wong's son?
- Dont do it.
There is another solution.
Logan will help us.
You do it your way,
I do it mine.
Everything that will happen
will be your fault.
Kien.
I must stop him.
I must warn someone.
Think about what I've said.
Wait for me.
I will come back to you.
Trust me.
This is there hiding place.
After the first altercation, I followed them.
They wont stop until it's settled.
Hey pussy, do you remember us?
We'll get them later.
We dont have time now.
Shit!
You only had to block the road.
- Yeah, I went a bit too far.
Oh Fuck!
Did you have to blow up their shit?
It's time to roll.
- Let's go seperate. We'll see each other upstairs.
This way.
You wont get me.
What are you doing here?
You started it
We just hit back.
It was a big mistake to come here.
This will cost you.
You talk too much.
If you really wanted to kill me,
you would have done it already.
We Outi Byatchez!
We should never have trusted you.
You are no better than your sister.
The Yakuza and the triads will take
a bet on who is going to kill us first.
From now on it's each on his own.
We have no alternative.
The sister of Kien is here.
Kitano had ordered her
to steal your family seal...
and kidnap your son tonight.
With this you will not
erase the insult towards me.
But perhaps it will save
your life and the live of your son.
Do you think we are that weak?
- In a war no one is safe.
Even you.
I dont want to see you in this city anymore.
But before you disappear
you have to do something for me.
Mae, I put someone on.
She's going to tell you
something about your husband.
Yes.
Still nothing?
- Still nothing.
Mae just left.
I dont know where to.
I'm sorry...
my friend.
You can go.
What happens next...
only concerns me.
Kien and Tsu have betrayed us.
They've conspired to prevent the kidnapping.
Dammit.
I cannot abandon him.
Kien?
Did you deal with your ghosts?
- We have to leave here.
You have found her.
Where are they coming from?
Logan.
Our new master wants me to let you live.
For now.
No.
He appreciates your worthy help.
But the Yakuza tolerate no traitors.
Go and see if everything is ready.
I'm sorry. My friends are in danger.
I've to go.
The road to them brings you
closer to your grandfather.
You are always welcome here,
Son of the Wind.
Why did you follow us that evening?
What did you do to my friend?
Why do you care?
- It's your fault.
You owe me an explanation.
Dont say that.
- Are you going to hit me, like your brother?
He only wanted to help you
and now he's dead.
Master, it's him.
Your sister and her friend are impatient.
And we killed one of the french.
Where and when?
- Twelve o'clock at the industrial grounds.
If the door opens I'll kill you.
Where are you going?
If you leave from the wind,
you will leave from the life.
Dont be afraid.
Let the wind take you to us.
It's not time yet.
How are you feeling?
What happened?
- Logan, where is Kenjee?
That's not what he came for
It's true.
Now we are even.
They have my sister and your friend.
Who is he talking about?
- The Yakuza
By attacking us you have
destroyed their plan.
Now they want your life and mine.
Do what you want, but I'm going with him
Not all of us will not return alive.
So dont feel obligated to come.
We are in this together.
They are in the west wing.
And you?
- I have a meeting.
Where is she?
- Safe.
For now.
What did you expect?
Where is the other?
You are brave. But your sister will be dead.
- No. We have other plans.
Kenjee, everything okay?
No.
What's wrong?
He's happy to see you.
You've betrayed the
love of my daughter...
Now you must face the consequences.
I'm glad you are here.
You have insulted us and you will pay.
We have come here to defend our honour.
If you kill him,
you will become one of us, Kien
That's what you wanted, isn't it?
Here's the exit.
Wait a second.
We're not going to leave her brother.
Dont do it or you will become like them.
Master.
- It's over. There are too many of them.
My death will do.
I hope they will spare you.
Tell my wife I love her.
In a few minutes the police will come.
That's enough time for you to
follow your master in shame and blood.
Our master showed us the road.
If we sacrifice our blood in battle,
we wipe his honour clean.
Prepare for battle.
Do we Fight or run?
- Fight.
Over the roofs.
- No. Armed men are everywhere there.
you must conquer the
security of your victory
without fearing the defeat.
As long as you fight with dignity, you win.
You dont fight against others,
but against yourself
unite both our arts and
control your violent temper.
Then the road will open itself for you.
No.
Come.
Do you realize what we just did?
Imagine yourself.
Yaguy, We were almost dead
Let it sink for a bit.
Stay. Do it for me.
- I can't.
Guys, from now on, we stay together
We stay together, èh?
You must live your life
and I will live mine.
You have always said:
We never change.
You will never get him.
I had a dream.
The wind was floating me to you.
Do you remember?
Hey love birds,
What's up with that meeting?
What meeting?
- Be patient.
Subtitles Corrected by: Quality Kingz Inc.