(TRAIN WHISTLE)
Tonight, Doctor Craven,
marks the tenth
year of your treating
the young master.
I can still find no cure for the
boy. His ailment
is unprecedented.
Shall we expect you
again tomorrow then?
The day after.
I've business in town.
Are we expecting visitors, Mrs.
Medlock?
The Lennox girl is to spend
a few days with us
awaiting the arrival of
her mother and father.
I'm here to call on my
uncle, Archibald Craven.
Captain Lennox has no right
dropping his daughter
on our doorstep
just so he can go
gallivanting about
India. There's hardly
anything left of it.
Come in Mistress Mary.
We've been expecting you.
Was that..?
Is he..?
That was Doctor Craven.
Lord Archibald's cousin.
He is not the Craven
you're calling on.
I'm glad.
He seems a dour sort.
You may leave your things here.
I'll send Martha to fetch them.
Let us find you a room.
My uncle is here then?
Aye, but he'll not be
receiving visitors tonight.
Related or otherwise.
I'm told your stay is short.
You'll
likely not cross paths at all.
Suits me well enough. I mean
to travel abroad in a few days
and haven't any time for forced
pleasantries with
distant relations.
Well aren't you a pleasant one.
I'm told it runs in the family.
You may not recall, but I
met you once years ago.
You were barely the size
of a daffy-down-dilly.
Where am I to stay?
I was told that my uncle
lived in a grand estate.
People once called it grand.
Not so much anymore.
This place slowly went to ruin
after your Aunt Lily passed.
I never knew my Aunt Lily.
You were a wee thing and
probably won't remember
but your mother's sister
was a rare beauty.
Misselthwaite couldn't
survive her loss.
Misselthwaite?
It's the place you're in, child.
Once the grandest
of all Craven Industries.
Made a rich man out of your
uncle. And his
father before him.
A Craven lives where he works.
It is their way.
Hundreds of people lived
out their lives here.
Now, it's all that's left
of the Craven empire.
(CHIRPING)
What is this?
There's something staring at me
from behind the walls.
Don't tell fictions! Empty
pipes and aging walls is all.
Now keep up.
Here we are, Mistress Mary.
It's the
least crumbling of what's left.
Make yourself at home,
but be glad of the brief stay.
I'll send Martha along with
your things and a hot meal.
For ten years he's seen
to the young master.
And for ten years
the young master
has remained in
that wretched room.
If the boy gives
my cousin reason
to call on occasion, so be it.
Only your son stands to inherit
your empire before the Doctor.
He may have little motivation
to help the boy.
(THUNDER)
Mistress Mary? I'm Martha.
I've brought your things.
You may unpack that into there.
You're a funny sort of girl.
Whatever do you mean by funny?
(HOWLING WAIL)
What is that unearthly howl?
The steam vents will soon
shut off for the night
so you'll want to
settle in quickly
and bundle up until morning.
It's too cold!
You'll grow used to it in time.
Master Craven hasn't
allowed most of
the boilers lit since
Lady Lily died.
Then I should like to speak
to him about that.
I'll take my leave
now and be back
with breakfast in the morning.
Will Mrs. Medlock return
to dress me for bed?
Can't you dress yourself?
I never have in my life.
It'll do you good to
wait on yourself a bit.
Good night Miss Mary.
Good night indeed.
I almost forgot. It's been
ages since we had a guest.
This is a Craven
Industries Comm Box.
If you need anything, just push
the button and
speak your wishes.
Someone will hear
and come running.
That's more like it.
Important wishes only.
I'll not run in to tie your
boots or braid your hair.
But if you need extra blankets
or a good story, just ring.
What of my niece?
I'm told the Lenox
girl has arrived unaccompanied.
She is to join her family at the
railway depot in three days.
I've already informed her that
you'll likely not
see one another.
Was she agreeable?
In general, no.
But regarding that
particular subject
she seemed to pay it no mind.
Then we'll speak no
more of it until
you've informed me
of her departure.
(FACTORY WHISTLE)
COMM BOX: All rise for
work day number 219,672
at Craven Industries
Misselthwaite Factory.
What is that?
Porridge with
treacle and hot tea
to start your
morning, Miss Mary.
No. That.
That horrible noise.
There was a time this factory
had hundreds of workers.
The Comm Box talked them awake
and talked them to work.
There's not many of us
left to hear it anymore.
Well does it do that every day?
You must make it stop.
I suppose it could be stopped.
But
we've only one
full time mechanic
left these days and
it's all he can
do to keep the
steam vents going.
Making those announcements is
a proud tradition for him.
Give me his name. I should like
to speak with him at once.
Ben Weatherstaff is the
one you're looking
for, but good luck
tracking him down.
Tracking him down?
Send him to me.
You are an odd girl,
Mistress Mary.
The staff of Misselthwaite
seem painfully unaware
of the duties that
their stations require.
I'll send Martha by
with lunch at noon.
You're welcome to dress yourself
and walk the nearby corridor but
don't stray too far.
Seeking Ben Weatherstaff. Ben
Weatherstaff, please
respond at once.
VOICE: Eh? Who is this?
Are you Ben Weatherstaff?
I need him to come and
silence this box at once.
Oh. do you now?
Well, he's a very busy man,
Ben Weatherstaff.
MARY: Where might
I find him then?
He's most likely
in workshop five,
pounding on some
pipe or another,
and he loves nothing
more than visitors.
And where might I find
this workshop five?
VOICE: Just follow
the blue pipes
and you'll find him alright.
BEN: Boy! Stop fiddling
with the machines!
Hello?
Where is this blue pipe?
Excuse me.
Are you the one who can silence
the box from waking me?
I've two more days
before my parents
come to take me away from this
dreadful place and I'd prefer to
spend the mornings asleep.
You know, I met you once,
when you were a wee thing
unable to talk. I like you
even less now.
If you must have it shut off,
find the young lad, Dickon.
He'll know what to do.
Is your name really
Ben Weatherstaff?
It is. Have you got a problem
with that and all?
No.
Good.
It's peculiar is all.
Peculiar. I weren't always
called such.
It's on account of
my staff, see. Not
that it's got ought
to do with you.
Why? What's so special about it?
It's nothing more than the
fallen branch of a tree.
Oh is it now? Does every fallen
branch of a tree
give you the power
to call and calm the storm?
You can't possibly be serious.
You must think me a child
who believes in faerie stories.
Away with thee now! I've wasted
enough of my precious time.
I've got work to do here,
can't you see?
(FOOTSTEPS)
Doctor Craven. We weren't
expecting you until tomorrow.
There's been a change of plans.
Find the Lennox girl. My cousin
will want to speak with her.
Immediately, Mrs. Medlock.
Well then where do I find
this Dickon?
Is he the voice who
sent me here?
He is. Aye.
Unless you'd rather the boilers
die and us all freeze to death
you'll put that down!
Mistress Mary! Mrs.
Medlock, she's here!
You're to see your
uncle right away.
This is as far as I go.
Step forward, girl.
My cousin has brought
disturbing news from town.
Your parents were on a chartered
airship from India
and it vanished
somewhere over the Arabian Sea.
News has only just
reached these shores.
I haven't any other
family to take me in.
Even so, I will leave
in three days,
as my father and
mother promised you.
You'll be cared for here until
you're old enough
to be on your own.
I prefer not to become a burden.
If your parents are
truly gone then
your guardianship falls to me.
You'll remain here
at Misselthwaite.
Now you must go.
I'm tired. I have a long journey
ahead of me and I'll be gone for
several days but Mrs.
Medlock will
see to it that you're cared for.
(BELL RINGS)
I'd forgotten you.
Mrs. Medlock!
A word, please.
Of course.
I don't approve of
this situation.
How do you mean?
The Lennox family were always
financially reckless.
It's highly likely they've left
their daughter with
no inheritance.
The girl hardly
sounded as though
she wished to remain here.
Do you believe she intends
to profit by it?
I intend to find out.
Have you told Lord Craven?
Absolutely not, and
neither will you.
Archibald is too soft.
It might not seem
so, but he'd have
the child in his
will if she asked.
Your mother and father must have
been very important
to book passage on an airship.
I suppose.
I hardly knew them.
Hardly knew them?
I've been raised by servants
and nannies most of my life.
Perhaps my Aya loved me.
But she died when I
was very little.
Will you stay with us
here at Misselthwaite?
No. I shall explore
this place while
I am certain that
my uncle is gone
and leave before he returns.
I do wish you'd stay.
I think we might be friends.
I've never had a friend.
Besides Dickon.
Who is this Dickon?
Everyone speaks
of him, but he's never around.
Dickon is my younger brother.
He's usually off
by himself playing
in some dark corner
of the factory.
He wants to be a mechanic
like Ben Weatherstaff.
But, Ben says
there'll be no more
mechanics here at Misselthwaite.
I wonder what Dickon
would think of you.
He wouldn't like me.
No one does.
How do you like yourself?
Not at all really.
But I never thought
of it before.
Stay out of trouble. And ring
Mrs. Medlock if you need to.
No. Dickon wouldn't
like me at all.
(CHIRPING)
Hello?
There you are!
(CHIRPING)
But how did you get in there?
Wait!
(KNOCKING)
You could at least be that
young lad, Dickon.
He's always begging for one
task or another but then
when you truly need him,
nowhere to be seen.
I'm beginning to doubt
that he exists.
Just you wait for
a moment in time
when all you want is a little
cup of quiet or the tiniest
little sliver of peace.
He'll come running along.
Just as
sure as can be,
he'll come running.
Well. Is that it, girl?
How does one open a lock
when one doesn't have a key?
I've got no time for riddles.
I'm busy.
It isn't a riddle.
I've discovered a lock.
And there's over a thousand
rooms in this factory.
It's a lock in a corridor
of yellow pipes.
You mustn't go poking about
in there. It isn't safe.
I wasn't poking about.
A flying machine
led me there and
chirped at me from
the other side.
You've met the R.O.B.I.N.
That's good luck!
Met the what?
The R.O.B.I.N.
Don't you know?
Remotely Operated Binary
Industrial Node.
It's quite the mouthful, so we
just call them R.O.B.I.N.s.
There are others?
Oh, Misselthwaite used
to be full of 'em.
Mrs. Craven brought
them all to life here.
Lord Craven shut 'em all down
when the factory closed.
But this one, he refused to be
shut down and he kept on flying.
He's what we call autonomous.
Autonomous?
Aye. It means... it
means he does what
he wants, takes
orders from nobody.
(CHIRPING)
He knows we're talking
about him. He's
conceited, that one is.
I tell ya.
Likes to hear folk
talking about him.
He's curious, too.
He always pops his head in here,
see what I'm fixin'.
(FACTORY WHISTLE)
Well, save from duty rosters,
that'll be the end of my day.
Suspect that young
maid will be looking
for you to fetch
you some supper.
Will I see him again?
Aye. You'll see him again. As
long as he's of mind to be seen.
I'd wrap up warm
and cozy this eve
if I were thee, Mistress Mary.
I have half a notion
to call upon a
northwesterly wind
to sing me to sleep.
Don't go poking around
that yellow corridor.
Your uncle sealed that workshop
off for his own reasons.
But why?
What reasons?
Why would my uncle lock up
an entire workshop?
Mrs. Medlock said that's
not to be talked about.
But Mrs. Medlock isn't here.
There are lots of things in this
place that's not
to be talked over.
That's Lord Craven's orders.
He's given no such order to me.
I've hardly even
spoken with him.
It was Lily Craven's workshop.
There was a time
when she believed
she couldn't bear any children
and her heart was broken.
As a happy diversion,
Lord Craven
gave her the space to work in
and she just loved it.
She called it her garden.
A garden inside of a factory?
Ben Weatherstaff says it was a
mechanical sort of garden
for cultivating her inventions.
What kinds of things
did she invent?
I only know the bits
Mrs. Medlock has told me.
I was younger than you
when it... happened.
Years ago, before
either of us were born,
people grew the most
beautiful plants.
Full of colors and smells.
You could even eat them.
But then the wars came.
And set the skies on fire.
And the smogs rolled
in and made most
plants inedible, but what of it?
Well, Lily Craven
took it upon herself
to create new sorts of things
that could grow and thrive,
even inside of a factory.
I should like to see
this secret garden.
Oh but you can't!
Why not?
MARTHA: In her haste to
discover a way to purify
the smog enough to
bring life to her garden,
Lily Craven hid herself
away in the workshop
and released a tank of
her experimental mixture.
Only, something went wrong,
and the air was
even more poisonous than
what she started with.
When the factory's R.O.B.I.N.
drones detected the problem,
every door at Misselthwaite
was instantly locked shut.
By the time the
poison vented out
of the factory, it was too late.
Lord Craven had the
room sealed and shut
and deactivated all
of the R.O.B.I.N.s,
blaming them for
not rescuing Lily.
Within a few years, he had given
up on all of Misselthwaite.
(DISTANT WAILING)
Do you hear someone crying?
It was the wind, wuthering
around the factory.
You could barely stand up
if you were in it tonight.
No. No, listen. It's inside.
It's
down one of those
long corridors.
I shouldn't have
told you that story.
It's gotten you all worked up.
Shall I fetch more hot water
for your tea?
There! I told you!
It is someone crying!
It was the wind.
And if it wasn't?
And if it wasn't, then it
was Ben Weatherstaff
practicing his storms.
Good bye.
Pardon me, but does
anyone know where
the crying sounds
are coming from?
BEN: Find the red pipes.
You'll get your answer.
(DISTANT WAILING)
(WAILING)
(WAILS AND CRIES)
What are you doing here?
I turned the wrong corner.
I didn't know which way to go.
Doctor Craven, I trust you can
find your own way out.
I can.
What did I tell you
about poking around?
I heard someone crying...
You heard no such thing.
Now come
along. Back to
your own quarters.
This is precisely why
I instructed Martha
to see that you're
locked in at night.
Locked in?!
How are you to get a
proper rest if you're up
snooping about the
factory at all hours?
You mustn't blame poor Martha.
Martha didn't tell me where the
crying sounds were coming from...
Of course she didn't because
you heard no sounds.
The boredom of a shuttered
factory can drive you half mad.
Now go to sleep, and no more
talk of phantom cries.
And stay where
you're told to stay,
or you'll find
yourself locked up.
(THUNDER)
(FOOTSTEPS)
My patient mustn't be disturbed.
The girl meant no harm.
She'll not be under foot.
She that she isn't.
I'll escort you out.
I know my way.
I'll do it just the same.
(FACTORY WHISTLE)
(CHIRPING)
BEN: All rise for
work day number
219,673 at Craven Industries
Misselthwaite Factory.
Scheduled personnel
please report to duty
stations by 0700.
The weather is
sunny, soon to turn
cold and rainy,
damp and drizzly.
The cafeteria will provide hot
porridge and treacle
promptly at noon.
Tea time will be 1530.
Have all scheduled
tasks and duty rosters
signed by 1700 hours.
Good day!
Running a little bit on the late
side this morning, Miss Martha?
Perhaps your watch
is a bit fast.
I'm sure Mr.
Weatherstaff's watch is
quite accurate and our
Martha simply got
a late start on the morning.
I must say I'm surprised
to see you up
and about this morning Mrs.
Medlock.
I'm told it were a bad night
for the young master.
Just pray the worst is over.
If he goes, I don't
expect Lord Craven
will have further
use for any of us.
Awake already? You
must have been up
before the morning
announcements.
Yes. However, I believe
that the morning
announcement was a bit
earlier today than usual.
Don't let Ben Weatherstaff
hear you say that.
And don't let Mrs. Medlock
catch you eating off the cart!
I won't! I won't!
It's my day out today.
Your day out?
You didn't think I
stayed cooped up inside
this factory all
the time, did you?
I suppose I hadn't
thought about it.
Well, I don't. I'm off to
pay my mother a visit.
Ring Mrs. Medlock if you need to
and I'll see you tomorrow.
Try and stay out of trouble.
No promises. I've heard
the R.O.B.I.N. calling
after me today and
I'm off to find him.
Hello?
R.O.B.I.N.?
I can see a little smile
in there. That's alright.
Have you seen the R.O.B.I.N.
today?
I haven't seen the R.O.B.I.N.
today
Mistress Mary, I haven't, no.
But I have seen spring.
Can you smell it?
I only smell smog rolling
in off the moor.
That little R.O.B.I.N. will
start showing himself
more and more now,
each and every single day.
All the little beasties will.
What does spring time
have to do with anything?
He's a mechanical beast,
not a natural creature.
Oh, Mistress Mary, we make no
distinction here
at Misselthwaite.
No distinction?
We make none at all.
Back when the... when the
boilers were running full steam
there were no limit to
the amazing inventions
that were brought to life here.
Inventions like what?
It's of no matter now.
The boilers have long
been cold and the
pipes have been empty.
(CHIRPING)
You hear that? It's the
R.O.B.I.N. Do you hear him?
(CHIRPING)
Ah!
He's calling after
you, Mistress Mary.
(CHIRPING)
You should run. Chase him down.
Ask him
the questions that
you've been asking me.
He'll know a fair more about
things than I do.
Oh! Mistress Mary!
You'll need this
mask when you're
chasing him down.
The R.O.B.I.N. pays no
mind to the good nor
the bad air. He floats
wherever he pleases.
You, on the other hand, aren't
afforded such luxuries.
Take it wherever you go.
I shall.
That's a good girl. Now let's
see here. Where were ya?
There you are, you
little blighter.
Hello?
R.O.B.I.N.?
It's me. Mary.
Don't you remember?
Please come out.
(CHIRPING)
Are you there?
Where are you?
(CHIRPING)
R.O.B.I.N., wait! R.O.B.I.N.,
it's me! It's Mary. Please wait!
R.O.B.I.N.?
Are you in here?
Where are you hiding?
(CHIRPING)
Here you are!
We met before.
Don't you remember?
(CHIRPING)
It's me. Mary Lennox.
(BEEPS AND CHIRPS)
Am I to have it?
Every time things
seem a trifle better
they take a turn for the worse.
We thought it best to
call you right away.
Of course. That was the right
choice, Mrs. Medlock.
What business have you to be
snooping about in there?
I happen to live here now.
I instructed you to
keep to your quarters.
I was only looking
for the R.O.B.I.N.
I shall continue
to look elsewhere.
I thought the last
of those wretched
machines had been deactivated.
Well don't look to me.
It's none of my affair
what is or is not activated.
Take me to my patient. I've a
schedule that must be kept to.
If it were my affair
there would be no
flying contraptions or
unwelcome house guests.
(CHIRPS)
You best be looking after
Miss Mary. She's family now.
See to it she keeps
away from trouble.
(CHIRPS)
Well, go on. I'll not stop you
from making your rounds.
(CHIRPS)
Aya!
The thunders of heaven
above won't wake you,
but a tweak of your blankets
and up you shoot.
It's hardly past midnight.
Surely you haven't
brought breakfast already.
No, Miss Mary. I've returned
from my day off
and only meant to see that
you were sleeping proper.
Well, I was.
What do you think?
I've brought you a gift.
A gift?
It's adorable.
What is it?
This is Astrid.
Whatever is it for?
Haven't you ever had a doll?
No.
Dickon gave her me
after our first visit
to the factory, when
we were very little.
She'll keep you safe.
She's a good companion.
No one has ever given
me a gift before.
Not even your mother and father?
Certainly not.
Won't you miss her terribly?
I'll visit her now and then.
She's a bit worn.
Your Aunt Lily made her.
How do you know?
That's her mark. She used it on
most of her inventions.
Thank you.
It's Dickon who ought
to be thanked.
He patched Astrid up from scraps
he's collected here and there.
Now back to bed with you.
I'll see you in the morning.
(WHISTLE)
BEN: All rise for work
day number 219,674
at Craven Industries
Misselthwaite Factory.
Scheduled personnel
please report to
duty stations by 0700.
The weather is sunny,
soon to turn cold and rainy.
The cafeteria will provide hot
porridge and treacle
promptly at noon.
Tea time will be 1530.
Have all scheduled
tasks completed and
duty rosters signed
by 1700 hours. Good day!
DICKON: You found the key!
Who is that?
Do you like the doll?
Dickon! Is that you?
The R.O.B.I.N. told
me you found the key.
He showed it to me.
Oh did he now?
He never let on he knew
where it was.
Do you understand what
the R.O.B.I.N. says?
I think I do.
And he thinks I do.
I've worked with
machines so long,
they think I'm one of them.
How did you get in there?
Can't you climb out?
Of course I can. But not here.
Meet
me in Ben Weatherstaff's
workshop.
When? Now?
(PIPES CREAKING AND BANGING)
Good. I was afraid
Weatherstaff would be here.
How did you do that?
These pipes go all
sorts of places.
Since most of them aren't moving
steam any more, I use them.
(CHIRPING)
What's he saying?
Ben Weatherstaff is headed
this way. Come with me.
What?
(PIPES CREAKING AND BANGING)
What is this place?
This is my hideout.
I do all my most
important work here.
Well who are you hiding from?
There's no more jobs for
mechanics at the factory and
Ben Weatherstaff won't
take on an apprentice.
But I still like to tinker
and make repairs.
Especially for the R.O.B.I.N.
Would my uncle be angry
if he caught you here?
I prefer not to find out.
Can I have a look at that key?
It's the key to the sealed up
workshop, isn't it?
It's the key to every workshop.
To every room, closet, and
cupboard in all
of Misselthwaite.
When I was very little,
I used to climb
through the vents
into that workshop
and read your Aunt Lily's notes.
She had so many wonderful ideas.
Including this key.
What's the matter?
When I grew up a bit, I couldn't
fit through the pipe anymore.
I haven't been to that shop
in a long time.
But if this key
exists, maybe she
created some of
the other things.
Martha told me that
she tried to create plants.
Do you think that
she really did it?
We can certainly find out.
How still it is.
This place was her garden.
Never thought I'd see it again.
Is it all quite a dead garden?
I wish it wasn't.
There's still some life here.
Look here.
The vines are hollow tubes.
It's full of tiny vents.
But why?
It's part mechanical.
Look.
The vines are connected
to the central boiler line.
This is where I found Astrid.
I wish that I could put the rest
of her back together.
But I've never
worked with anything
mechanical my entire life.
All we need is a little bit of
steam to run through the pipes
and we could get things
growing proper again.
But my uncle hasn't
allowed many of the
boilers lit since
my Aunt Lily died.
That's true. But we could
solve that problem.
Will you come again
and help me to do it?
I'm sure that I can help, too.
I'll come every day
if you want me.
It'll be the most fun
I ever had in my life.
Shut in here, wakening a
mechanical garden.
We'll have your doll finished
soon enough I expect.
(FACTORY WHISTLE)
I have to go before Mrs. Medlock
or Martha come looking for me.
No matter what happens,
you would never tell?
Our secret's safe as anything.
Meet me here tomorrow,
first thing.
We'll spend the day at work
in the garden.
I've seen Dickon.
He showed me his hideout.
I knew you'd cross paths.
He's a fine lad.
I'm going to see him
again tomorrow.
He's helping me finish
constructing the doll.
Oh? I know he's got chores
for mother tomorrow.
He probably won't have time
for coming around here.
Dickon's had you
crawling through
the factory pipes, I see.
Oh, yes. It isn't the cleanest
way around, I suppose.
I'll take it with me tonight and
have it back good
as new by morning.
Oh, no, no. That
won't be necessary.
Nonsense. I'd never
hear the end of it
if Mrs. Medlock caught you
roaming around in such a state.
Good night, Miss Mary.
(FOOTSTEPS)
What was I thinking leaving
the key in my coat pocket?
Our first day in the garden and
I've already gone
and lost the key.
What will Dickon say?
(DISTANT WAILS AND CRYING)
(WAILING AND CRYING)
(WAILS)
(CRYING)
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
(WAILING)
Who are you?
Were you crying?
Are you a ghost?
You don't look as though
you've been crying.
I am Colin. Are you a ghost?
I am Mary Lennox.
I am not a ghost.
Why are you here?
I live here.
Archibald Craven is my uncle.
Archibald Craven is my father.
Your father? No one told me that
he had a boy. Why wouldn't they?
Come here.
Where did you come from?
My own room.
The thunder wouldn't
let me sleep.
And I heard someone crying and I
wanted to find out who it was.
What were you crying for?
Because I can't sleep either
and my head aches.
Tell me your name again.
Mary Lennox.
Did no one tell you that I'd
come to live here?
No. They dare not.
Why?
Because I should have been
afraid you would see me.
I won't let people see me
or talk me over.
Why?
Because I am always like this.
Unable to walk.
My father won't let people see
me or talk me over either.
The servants are not allowed to
speak about me.
What a strange place this is!
Everything is kept a secret.
Workshops are locked up.
Gardens are locked up.
And you. Are you locked up, too?
No. I stay in this
room because I
do not wish to be moved around.
Does your father come
and see you then?
My mother died and it makes my
father sad to look at me.
He thinks I don't know,
but I've heard them talking.
They say I'm not going to live
long, which is just as well.
I do not want to be a hunchback
like my father.
I think he knows this and
he hates me for it.
He hates the garden, too.
Because she died.
That's why he locked the door.
Locked what door?
Just a door... to
a workshop that
your father hates.
Nothing, really.
Why do they think
that you won't live?
I've seen the doctor here.
Can't he help you?
My doctor is my father's cousin.
If I die, he shall have all
Misselthwaite when
my father is dead.
I should think he wouldn't
want me to live.
Why do you keep looking
at me like that?
Do you see the curtain
hanging on the wall?
Yes.
Go and open it.
That is all that I know of her.
Your mother?
If she had lived, I believe
I would not have been ill.
I dare say I might have even
been able to walk.
She made this doll, too.
I believe it was one
of her last creations.
Draw the curtain again.
I do not want to see her
looking at me anymore.
I should go. I've been here
far too long.
I want you to come and speak
to me every day.
I will come as often as I can.
You must look every day
for the locked door.
I should like to see that place.
Perhaps I might find a way
to get in sometime.
Perhaps we might find a boy
who could carry you in there.
And we could go and it would
just be kept a secret garden.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Come in.
Miss Mary! I've never known you
to be up and about so early.
I haven't even prepared
your breakfast.
I was only hoping to come
and get my vest.
Of course!
I've just finished mending it.
Be more careful with
important things.
I will.
I promise.
And don't let Dickon
get you into trouble.
He's a sweet boy, but his
curiosity gets the best of him.
I found out what the crying was.
You haven't. Never.
(COMM BOX STATIC, WAILING)
What have you done?
I'm sorry, Master Colin.
I didn't
tell Mistress Mary
where to find you.
I want Mary Lennox to come
and speak to me.
You do?
And you are not to tell anyone.
But Mrs. Medlock
ordered me to never...
Have you to do what I please
or have you not?
I have to do what
you please, sir.
Has Medlock to do what I please?
Everybody has, sir.
Well. Then I order you to
bring Mary Lennox to me.
The world's coming to an end!
What is it?
You better come as
quick as you can.
If Mrs. Medlock find out, she'll
think I broke orders
and told you.
I'll lose my place.
No, you won't lose your place.
I'm the one who heard
the crying in the night
and I got up and
found Colin myself.
He was glad that I came.
He won't let strangers
look at him.
He let me look at him.
What's that matter with him?
I wasn't told of him
until a year ago.
After Lady Lily
died, Lord Craven
wouldn't set eyes on Colin.
(COMM BOX STATIC, WAILING)
You better go as
quick as you can!
DOCTOR: How long does my cousin
intend to remain
abroad this time?
MEDLOCK: All week, sir.
The travel might do
his health some bit of
good if you ask me.
DOCTOR: I did not ask you.
MEDLOCK: No sir.
DOCTOR: You say the boy's health
is further deteriorated?
MEDLOCK: I'm not
qualified to diagnose,
but the night terrors
are more frequent.
Perhaps, if he could
be made to walk...
- DOCTOR: I agree.
- MEDLOCK: Oh?
DOCTOR: You are certainly not
qualified to diagnose.
Any attempt to alter
his condition
is likely to make it worse.
I should like to see
that secret workshop.
We'll have to find a way
to transport you there.
You are supposed to find a boy
to help carry me there.
I know a boy who
may help, but you
haven't given me enough
time to ask him yet.
Besides, I'm not sure that he
can carry you all that way.
What is this?
This is my cousin, Mary Lennox.
Sir, I don't know
how it's happened.
No one would dare tell.
The servants have their orders.
Calm yourself, Medlock.
She heard my cries and she
found me on her own.
I'm afraid there's been
too much excitement.
Excitement is not
good for you, my boy.
She makes me better. I think
we shall have tea together.
He does seem a bit better, sir.
A mere trick of the mind. We
must not forget that he is ill.
I want to forget.
She makes me forget.
Mrs. Medlock, I expected better
control of this
household from you.
New recommendations
will be forthcoming.
Medlock.
You may bring us our tea now.
Tell me more about
this boy you know.
Dickon!
Martha told me that
you had chores
today and wouldn't make it.
I stayed up all night and
finished them this morning.
I couldn't stop thinking
about the garden.
I couldn't sleep either.
I've had the most
peculiar adventure.
MARY: How did this happen?
DICKON: I lit an extra boiler.
Won't we get caught?
I made sure the steam we need
only comes to this room.
You're a genius.
Ha. Tell that to
Ben Weatherstaff.
So, tell me about
your adventure.
I've made a strange discovery.
Stranger than a secret
workshop covered
in mechanical vines
and doll parts?
Do you know about Colin?
What do you know about him?
I've seen him.
He demanded that I
sit with him this morning.
He says that I make him forget
about being ill and dying.
And how do you manage that?
Well, I told him
about this place.
Will he keep the secret?
I think so.
He wants to visit,
but I told him that
I couldn't see him
this afternoon
so that I could discuss it
with you first.
I think a visit to a place like
this might do him some good,
but he's not able
to walk, is he?
No.
I wondered if we
might convince Ben
Weatherstaff to carry him here.
And spoil the secret?
I suppose it would.
Is your uncle still away?
For another day or two.
Meet me in my hideout tonight.
I think I have a
more suitable idea
for Master Colin's
transportation.
I'll not pretend
to know what the
pair of you is up
to with that key,
but our Dickon's not seemed
happier his whole life.
Yes, I... I suppose he does
seem happy. Doesn't he?
(DISTANT WAILING)
How dreadful that sounds.
He ought to be stopped.
It's his illness, Miss Mary.
He can't be held
accountable for something
he can't control.
Somebody ought to make him stop.
He
works himself up into hysterics.
Miss Mary! He'll do himself
harm. You must come quick.
No one can do anything for him
and he likes you.
I'm dressed for bed! Tell him
to gain control of himself!
That's the right humor.
You go and scold him.
Give him something
new to think of.
As quick as you can!
(CRYING)
You stop!
I hate your wailing.
Everybody hates it.
I wish that everyone
would run out of the
factory and let you cry
yourself to death.
If you scream another scream,
I'll scream too.
And I can scream
louder than you.
I can't stop!
Yes you can! Half that
ails you is hysterics!
COLIN: I felt it!
I felt the lump!
MEDLOCK: Keep up!
COLIN: I shall have
a hunch on my back
just like my father
and then I shall die
never having walked a step in
all of my life!
You didn't feel any lump.
There's nothing the
matter with your
horrid back. Nothing
but hysterics.
Sit up and let me feel it.
Mrs. Medlock, come
and sit Colin up.
Show her. She'll see then!
There isn't a single lump there.
If you say that there is again,
I shall laugh.
Do you suppose I could
live to grow up?
Of course you will.
If you can control your temper
and breathe in something other
than the stale air of this room.
I shouldn't hate fresh air
if we could find...
if Dickon could come and
help me move about.
Doctor Craven would never
allow such a thing.
Mistress Mary, you must come
get your sleep out.
He'll nod off after a while.
I will put him to sleep.
You may go, if you like.
Miss Mary, what was there?
What did you see?
I think that I shall sing him a
song that I learned from my Aya,
then I'll return to bed.
Good night.
MARTHA: Is Master Colin
really going to live?
What was it Miss Mary saw?
It is none of our
concern, Martha, and
if Miss Mary has
any decency in her
she'll never mention it.
But she certainly saw something.
And neither will you.
I almost told, but I stopped
myself in time.
Have you learned
anything else about
the way into the secret garden?
Yes. I have.
And if you will go to sleep,
I will show you tomorrow.
I think if I could get into it,
I should live to grow up.
Why is that?
It's just a feeling.
Do you suppose that instead
of singing me your Aya song,
you could just tell me what you
think it looks like?
Yes.
Close your eyes.
It has been left
alone for so long
that it's covered in
a strange gray mist.
Some of it is dead.
Some of it is still very alive.
And a R.O.B.I.N.
watches over it all.
You're late.
I had to convince Colin that
he isn't a hunchback.
I think it's time we get to
the bottom of Colin's illness.
Have you ever been to
your uncle's study?
Once.
And did he have a
mechanical chair?
Yes. A very odd sort of chair.
A chair on wheels?
Let's get the chair to Colin's
room before someone
finds us here.
DICKON: We'll come back in the
morning for him.
Won't Mrs. Medlock find
out that he's gone?
Martha can handle Mrs. Medlock.
Meet me here just after sunrise.
I'll be here. I don't think I'll
be able to sleep until then.
Here. I made some notes.
Look them over tonight.
I think you'll
be able to repair the
doll on your own.
(FACTORY WHISTLE)
COMM BOX: All rise for
work day number 219,675
Dickon! I'm late to meet Dickon!
COMM BOX: Scheduled
personnel please
report to duty stations by 0700.
You're late. Again.
I know. I'm sorry.
Shh! There goes Mrs. Medlock.
Have you already seen to
Miss Mary this morning?
I have, so I've come to look
after Master Colin as well.
That will be quite helpful.
I've a great deal
of preparation to
see to before Lord
Craven's return.
The corridor is clear.
Mrs. Medlock won't
be back this way
until lunch time.
Thank you, Martha.
You can hardly tell
he's breathing.
Doesn't anyone know
what's wrong with him?
How can a boy remain ill
for such a long time.
I don't know.
Who are you?
Colin. This is Dickon.
We've brought you a surprise.
What is it?
That's your
transportation to the
secret place I told you about.
Help me into it at once.
Now cover your eyes.
Alright. Open them.
This place seems so familiar.
And yet I've never
seen it before.
If only I were cured. I would
explore every single corner.
This place will cure you.
I'm going to walk?
MARTHA: I can't stall
Mrs. Medlock any longer.
She'll be in Master Colin's
room soon with lunch.
This place is full of life.
Can't you feel it?
The air is certainly different.
It is no longer stale.
Breathe it in. It'll make
your legs grow strong.
Doctor Craven says I
shall not grow anymore.
He says I shall
have a hunch on my
back and be barely able to move,
just like my father.
MARTHA: Perhaps none
of you heard me.
She's right. We should get Colin
back to his room for the day.
We'll bring you back here again
soon. And we'll make you walk.
We promise.
(CHIRPING)
What is that noise?
That's the R.O.B.I.N.
I was telling you about.
I want to meet him.
(CHIRPING AND CRASHING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
Where do you think
you're going, boy?
What have you done
to the R.O.B.I.N.?
I finally silenced the last
of these little beasts.
Your place is out on the moor.
You've no right to be here.
Dickon is my guest!
This boy is no concern of yours.
You
will do well to
stay away from him.
Mary is family and she may
do as she pleases.
Along with her guest.
They're going to
teach me to walk.
She's bewitched you.
Nothing more.
Filled your head with dreams of
walking about and exploring.
Nonsense. I cured him of
his fits just last night.
Leave the medicine to me.
The boy was already
quite ill and
I'm afraid you've made
matters infinitely worse.
Escort these two away from here!
I will see to
Master Colin myself.
Immediately!
How did you fix her?
We found the missing pieces
in the secret garden
then Dickon loaned me
the tools I needed.
(WAILS AND CRYING)
I'll be able to
repair the R.O.B.I.N.
I just need to bring him
back to my hideout.
What about poor Colin?
I thought the trip to the garden
would do him some good.
Maybe it has.
(WAILS AND CRYING)
We must be missing something.
Don't blame yourself.
Even Doctor
Craven hasn't been
able to cure him.
Should I go and
help to quiet him?
It will probably make the
doctor even angrier.
I'll take my chances.
(CRYING AND WAILING)
(CRYING AND WAILING STOPS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
You!
He worked himself into hysterics
claiming you promised
him a garden
that would heal him
and make him walk.
I made no such promise!
His fragile health couldn't
handle the emotional pain.
You've killed the boy!
Of this I am certain.
You are to blame.
No one is to enter
the boy's room.
My cousin will return tomorrow
and deal with all of you.
I didn't know... I...
I was only trying to help him.
Martha, see Mary to her room.
Stay with her tonight.
Find Dickon and send him home.
This tragedy will
destroy Misselthwaite.
Aye.
No question.
It shall.
I have to go.
Please don't try to stop me.
You know that I
didn't kill Colin.
Stay until your uncle arrives.
He won't blame you.
Colin's been ill
his entire life.
Doctor Craven blames me.
He'll convince everyone
that it's my fault.
Stay here until the morning.
Tell them that I was gone
when you woke up.
Be careful.
And write to me.
You're the only
friend I've ever had.
I will. I promise.
Looks like getting
hit jogged a lot of
memories in that
bird brain of yours.
(CHIRPS)
What's this?
It doesn't look like that man
ever really liked you very much.
(CHIRPING)
BEN: Dickon!
Dickon. Something
terrible's happened.
Young Master Colin...
He died.
Doctor Craven's blaming
Mistress Mary.
But they're sure
to drag you into
this by morning,
you mark my words.
You need to leave the factory
right now for your own sake.
I have to find Mary.
What?
Did you not hear me, boy?
The worst has happened.
It'll ruin us all!
Doctor Craven is a liar.
Check the R.O.B.I.N.'s memory.
I need to find Mary!
(CHIRPING)
Where's Doctor Craven?
Where's Colin?
Colin... Colin is...
Mechanical!
Look! I should have known it
when he showed me his back.
I saw my Aunt Lily's flower
on the back of his neck.
Lily Craven created her own
mechanical son. Of course!
So he can't have died!
But why would Doctor
Craven lie to us?
The R.O.B.I.N. showed
me everything.
Doctor Craven is
behind all of it.
Lily Craven's death,
Colin's illness...
All of it?
With no one to stand between
himself and Lord Craven,
he would inherit all of
Craven Industries.
No! But my uncle is alive.
And well!
I suspect that's only
because he wanted
to take care of
everyone else first.
He never was pleased
to have me here.
If Colin is a mechanical boy,
maybe we can fix him.
But I've just come from his
room. Dickon, he isn't there!
Doctor Craven must have
hidden him somewhere.
DICKON: Doctor Craven sealed
it up all over again.
Colin must be in there.
You said that this opens every
lock in this factory?
Let's hope you're right.
Dickon, what do we do?
He's the most complex machine
I've ever seen.
We have to fix him!
Looks like he was
never completed.
I don't think we can
bring him back.
No. There must be a way.
If this whole secret
garden was built by
Colin's mother just
to bring him to life
she must have left behind
a way to complete him.
If you're right, then Doctor
Craven will be after me as well.
Keep my uncle safe.
I will.
I promise.
I have to go now.
Dickon will look after you.
MARTHA: Miss Mary!
You must leave
now. Your uncle has returned.
(ELECTRICITY POWERING UP)
COLIN:
I am Colin. I am alive.
The doll was Lily
Craven's final piece.
It must be his
true power source.
MARY: He should be able to walk!
MARTHA: Excuse me.
(CHIRPING)
Good morning, Doctor Craven.
Let's have a cup of a tea
and a chat, shall we?
(THUNDER)
Father.
I'm Colin.
I thought I'd lost you.
I thought this place
held only death.
It came back to life
because of Mary and Dickon.
I'm going to live forever
and ever and ever.
Show me this garden
that your mother loved so well.
I want to see everything.
BEN: All rise for work
day number 219,676
at Craven Industries
Misselthwaite Factory.
By order of the
young Master Colin,
scheduled personnel,
please enjoy a day out.
DICKON: The cafeteria
will provide
hot porridge and treacle
promptly at noon,
alongside jammie
dodgers and tea.
BEN: Boy! How many times
must I repeat myself?
Stop fiddling with the machines!