No...
Ryo.
Ryo!
Somebody!
Anyone here?!
Is anyone here?!
- All right, listen up.
- Yes, sir.
There might be more people
under the rubble. We should...
Excuse me! I can't find my son!
Where are the rescued...
Ryo.
Mr. Kanda. You're okay.
Yuko, are you all right?
I'll get some blankets.
Have you seen my son?
Mr. Kanda.
What's going on?
Hello?
Somebody...
It's not safe in there!
Wait.
Hey!
Are you okay?
Thank goodness.
I woke up washed up on the beach.
No one is responding to me
and I can't feel any physical touch.
I didn't know what was going on
and then you called out...
I understand.
First...
Let's try to calm down first.
Take a deep breath.
It was a pretty big one.
For now, come to our place.
Oh, can you walk?
Like I said,
I came up with the idea
for this star sand.
Okay?
You've seen these
in souvenir shops, right?
I used to buy them for my family
on work trips.
Right?
That's all me.
There he goes again.
It's the truth, okay?
You see, I participated
in a student protest, right?
I went completely broke back then,
so I ran away to Iriomote Island.
And you stuffed the sand in bottles
and sold them, right? We heard.
Oh, do we have a new guest?
Oh...
From that earthquake?
Probably.
Well, hi there.
You must've been through a lot.
That...
It was huge.
Michael.
Um, what's this place?
Well...
It's hard to explain, but...
It's all right.
Don't worry.
We've got plenty of time, okay?
Kaori, give her a tour.
Sure. I'm Kaori.
This way.
I'm sorry.
What is all this?
I-I don't want to explain.
Well...
People who have regrets
in the living world are gathered here.
Well, it's not just here.
There are places like this
all over the country.
Regrets?
What do you mean?
Hey, Akira.
Don't beat around the bush.
Then you tell her, Shori.
So basically, you died.
But you can't go over to the other side
because you have some unfinished business.
Died?
I died...
Now, now. Come on.
Get some rest for today.
We have alcohol too.
I don't want any.
Come with me, okay?
You'll be fine.
There's probably a guy.
Probably.
Really? At her age?
Hang on.
This way.
The last occupant left.
So feel free to stay here.
I know it's a lot to handle all at once.
So get a good night's rest.
Are you all the same as me?
That's right.
We're your seniors.
We're quite the experts.
Goodnight.
Here's your baby. Congratulations.
Why won't you understand?!
I'm...
That's what you want!
Mind your own business!
There, there.
Ryo, come here.
Scary!
Happy birthday to...
Congratulations!
- Look.
- Move.
What are you doing?!
Mommy, look.
Stop!
Hurry up and go.
- I don't want to go!
- Why? I have to go to work!
I don't want to go to school!
Mommy.
Wake up.
- Mommy!
- Ryo!
- Hey.
- Morning.
Good morning.
Hey.
Hi there.
Good morning.
Kaori, I'd like some coffee too.
Sure thing.
Here.
What's that?
It's yoga.
A dead person doing yoga
and trying to stay healthy?
Shut it.
Yoga.
I'm the one who brought yoga to Japan.
Enough already.
It's the truth.
That's how I hurt my back. Right here.
Good morning.
Hey, miss. Good morning.
You look cute in daylight.
What's your name?
Minako Kawakami.
Minako.
Man, really. You're pretty.
Michael.
You can't say things like that
in this day and age.
What? Really? Why?
This old man here is Michael.
And the guy who brought you here is Akira.
That young man is Shori.
He used to be a yakuza.
That's Mr. Tanaka, a former banker
and I'm Kaori, a former hostess of a bar.
J-Join us.
Hey!
STOCK MARKET CRASH
1990 OCTOBER 2
This...
Well, it's an old habit of mine.
Can I borrow your car key?
Huh?
Oh, sure.
She's got a bad attitude.
PLEASE CONTACT US IF YOU HAVE INFORMATION
ON MISSING CHILDREN LISTED BELOW
Chinatsu!
Aiko!
Kazuki!
You too?
I got separated from my family.
I thought I might find them
if I shout their names out every day.
But...
if they can hear me,
it means they're dead.
I hope...
you find your family too.
The highway acted as a breakwater,
so urban areas were less affected.
We haven't found Kawakami yet.
Let's hope she's safe.
The rescue teams are doing their best
to find the missing people.
What we can do right now
is to work with the police
and report accurate news promptly.
Get to work.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Kanda, I'm right here.
- Oh, welcome back.
- Hi.
Uh, yeah.
Oh, thank you.
Great timing.
We're having hot pot tonight.
You wanna join us?
Sorry, I'm not in the mood for it.
That's exactly why you should come.
Okay?
Oh...
It is now autumn
At this empty beach
Even if
A single dream breaks
His one-thousandth time.
I won't forget you
Because I promised the sand
No matter how sad I am
I will not die
"Empty Beach."
I-It's such a good song. Right, Shori?
Sure, sure.
Minako, do you want to sing something?
No thanks.
Yeah? That's a shame.
Okay, here it is. The hot pot's ready!
Come on.
- Done.
- Come here.
Thank you.
So heavy!
Kaori's special hot pot!
Looks good!
- Have some meat.
- Come on. Let's eat.
Meat gives you energy.
- Let's dig in.
- Let's eat.
Yum!
Um...
Do you all have regrets
in the living world?
Well, yeah.
R-Regret is all we have.
Is that why you're all lazing around?
I wouldn't say we're lazing around.
Huh?
Well, I guess it does look like
we're just fooling around.
I don't mean to be rude,
but I can't waste my time like this.
Minako.
Could you stick around for just today?
Why?
Because
we might be able to help you.
Y-Yeah. That's what I was going to say.
Yeah, right.
It's time. Hurry up and eat!
Hurry.
Hi there.
We can't start without doing this, right?
Start what?
We always do this as a purification ritual
before making films.
He's a self-proclaimed film producer.
Come see when you have time.
They're all masterpieces.
Y-You can watch them all
in the cinema over there.
All right. Let's get going.
Okay, then. Let's go.
What's everyone doing?
Once a month,
on the night of a new moon,
we all get together and search.
What?
We search for the ones we're looking for.
This is so strange.
I didn't think I'd be with people
when I died.
Shori.
Trying to make sense of a contradiction
is a contradiction in itself.
That's true.
Oh, hey. Hey!
I found them.
Chinatsu.
Dear...
Aiko.
- Dad.
- Dad...
Kazuki.
I'm sorry.
Strange, isn't it?
We're dead, but we're here.
We definitely exist in this world.
We exist.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't protect you.
My back hurts.
Kaori, beer please.
Okay.
Here.
- Thank you.
- Does Minako want any?
I'll give it to her.
Thanks.
Here.
What did you think?
What?
Uh...
I was surprised...
and confused.
Who wouldn't be?
Minako,
I hope you find your boyfriend soon too.
Hey! That's enough.
Why?
It's my son.
I...
I have a son I raised alone named Ryo.
He's seven.
My only concern is
whether he's alive or not.
Will you let me stay here a little longer?
Thumbs up to that.
O-Of course you can.
We'll find him.
Thumbs up?
Thumbs up then.
Thumbs up.
Right, come here. Let's have a toast.
We understand.
Kaori.
- All right. Cheers.
- Cheers.
It's open.
Oh, come in.
W-What are these?
These are the notes I've been taking.
But you know,
I'll summarize them into one story.
I am an author.
Right.
Something wrong?
Um, thank you for asking me
to stick around the other day.
I feel a little better.
No worries.
I know what you're going through.
Are you looking for someone too?
Oh, no. I'm not.
I just want to take note of all this.
I want to keep a record that
there's a world like this after we die.
Is that your unfinished business?
I'm not sure.
Oh. You want the car, right?
You can use it whenever you want.
Thank you.
We'll definitely find him.
Don't worry.
You can rely on us more.
Minako.
Please let me interview you sometime.
Tell me about your life.
If you'd like.
Hi there.
Hey.
Nice.
Looking good.
Shut up.
I made a yakuza film a long time ago.
One of those half-assed films, right?
No, it's a very good one.
I'll show it to you sometime.
Sure, sure.
Okay, I'm off.
CHIEF CABINET SECRETARY
CONFERENCE IN CHAOS
NUCLEAR POWER PLANT "STABILIZING STEADILY"
DECEASED
They haven't found Minako yet, huh?
MISSING
FROM HOSHISUNA, MINAKO KAWAKAMI (35)
Boss, happy birthday.
Congratulations.
I appreciate it.
Drink up.
Thank you.
Dad, happy birthday.
Eat.
Thank you.
WHAT'S ON THE OTHER SIDE?
I'm back.
Hi.
Kaori, b-beer please.
Sure thing.
- I'll leave it here.
- Yeah.
What's wrong, Shori?
You look glum.
Huh? Do I?
Today was your dad's birthday, right?
How was he?
Well, he's gotten pretty old.
Well, yeah.
It's already been seven years
since you came here.
I wonder sometimes.
That it wouldn't have been this way
if I stayed by his side.
I made a yakuza film before.
But the yakuza t-today have it rough.
They're a symbol of society.
B-But they were separated from society
and they're not even given human rights.
I'll show it to you
when you come to the cinema next time.
Yeah, okay. I got it.
What's your unfinished business, Shori?
What's with the sudden interest?
I told my story to everyone.
I ended up here because I was killed
in a yakuza conflict seven years ago.
I left my wife behind.
Huh? You were married?
Well, not exactly a wife.
It wasn't official.
He's actually quite a softie.
What? Keep your mouth shut.
You've been looking for her
for seven years?
Well, I'm not really sure.
Maybe I don't want to see her.
It's not like I can hold her anymore.
WHAT HAPPENS
IF UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS LEFT UNRESOLVED?
Hello?
Is everyone else safe?
I see. Let's do our best.
Yeah.
Bye.
1970, OKINAWA
It is now autumn
At this empty...
Sasaki, Tamashiro was arrested.
I see.
Authorities are coming with an iron fist.
They're coming for you next.
Keep a low profile.
I know.
Tamashiro's arrest will be
the headline for tomorrow's flyer.
Yeah.
I'll get it done by the end of the day.
So, Maiko.
See you tomorrow.
Koga.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Don't worry.
The other day our comrade, Tamashiro,
was unlawfully arrested on the street.
We will never give in to
such oppression from the authorities!
That's right!
Now is the time for students...
We cannot let you
occupy the university any longer.
Remove the barricade
and come out immediately.
Sprechchor!
Give Okinawa back to us!
We're against the Vietnam War!
Remove the U.S. military base!
Charge!
Unite!
Koga!
What time is it?
It's still midnight. You should lie down.
Does it hurt?
You scared me!
Sorry. I kind of just walked in.
M-M-Minako.
W-What a surprise.
What was that film called?
Oh. In Search for Lost Time.
It's great, right?
Yeah. It ended halfway though.
Yeah, I know.
It's not complete because I died.
Really?
This film will leave a very huge impact
on young people today.
It's incredible.
The poster was going to be Maiko,
the heroine, standing alone on the beach.
And bam! The title right on top.
It was going to be a huge hit.
The poster was decided already?
O-O-Of course it was.
I was the decision-maker for everything.
The theme, story, and all of it.
But why did you want to
shoot a film about a student protest?
Oh, this.
This is a true story about me.
It's an autobiography?
Not exactly...
You see,
I was participating in a student protest.
Regardless of
whether it was right or w-wrong,
there was unity.
Films are the same.
A bunch of grown-ups working passionately
towards the same goal. It's amazing.
You really loved films, huh?
Yeah.
If it's an autobiography,
was Maiko your girlfriend?
Yeah, well. I-I guess s-she was.
What happened to you two?
Well, you know. A-A lot happened.
But I wish
she could've seen the completed film.
I think she might still be waiting.
Nah.
I wonder.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Hey, dinner's ready.
Come on, Kenta.
She said dinner's ready.
Hey, Kenta. Stop playing your game.
- Riko, this is for Mom.
- Okay.
Kenta! I said dinner.
Here.
You?
The usual amount.
- Kenta?
- I want a lot.
A lot... This good?
Yeah, thanks.
Kenta, you're gobbling up the food.
So? How are your club activities going?
Seconds.
- You have a match next week?
- Yeah.
Think you can win?
Piece of cake.
- They were mercy-ruled last time.
- Don't say that!
W-Why'd you...
I saw that game too.
Don't bring it up.
The baby kicked.
Really?
Wait, hold on...
Do it again.
- The baby kicked!
- Yeah.
- Kenta.
- I'm good.
Come.
It's vintage, but it's still usable.
Look, it's so shiny.
Hey, Minako.
Good morning.
What are you doing?
I was deeply moved
by your words yesterday!
What? Which words?
Why did you get him worked up?
I've got plans today.
Seriously, I'm not following.
Minako, you worked in TV, right?
More like a journalist.
Okay, then. Take this.
Listen,
I decided to complete that film.
Come again?
All right. Everyone listen.
TV shows come and go,
but films are unforgettable.
I can't have you doing this halfheartedly.
So what are we supposed to...
Right. Akira, you look slow.
So you can hold this.
What? This?
Kaori, you do the recording.
Wow, that's an important job.
- Tanaka, you're the assistant director.
- Yes.
Yes.
And Shori.
Y-You're good looking,
s-so you can play my son.
Here's the script.
What?
IN SEARCH FOR LOST TIME
Michael, you're the director?
I'm the lead and the director.
It's Yang Ik-june style.
What? What style?
- Huh?
- Okay, then.
Let's begin.
Take one.
Ready.
Start.
It's been...
50 years since then.
What's next?
- "I want to see her again."
- Huh? What?
What?
"I want to see her again."
Cut!
Ready, roll!
What was it?
Um...
Oh, your board is in the shot.
"I want to see her again."
It's not about the lines.
It's the emotion.
Okay. Once more.
I'm into it already.
It doesn't open smoothly.
"I want to see her again."
I know that.
Too bright!
How long do I have to wait?
Just get into...
Watch me and prepare for your role.
- Let's do this in one take.
- Yeah.
Oh...
- It's been 50 years since then.
- I know that.
W-W-What? W-Why are you turning it?
It's nothing.
We can start with "It's been..."
O-Oh, well. It's still the first day.
The team is not one yet.
Is that how it is?
Yes, it is.
Filmmaking is all about teamwork. Right?
Why are you asking me?
Anyway, I think we all need to
hold a review meeting.
Minako, I'll teach you about the camera.
I'm good.
- Why? Come on.
- Huh?
Is that a guest?
I'll go.
At such a young age...
Hello.
You can see me?
What's going on?
I'm new here too.
Let's go over there for now.
Your name?
Nana.
Hi there.
You like films?
What?
Nice to meet you.
I know. It's shocking, right?
I'm sorry, but...
I'm not sorry.
I'm so glad my shitty life ended.
We've got one very jaded kid in the house.
Huh? Who the hell are you?
Okay.
Young lady,
there's a place you can rest. Let's go.
That girl is you-know-what, right, Tanaka?
Probably.
Okay, I'm off.
Shori.
Huh?
Congratulations
starting your seventh year.
Shut up.
I'm sorry, Shori.
I've decided to dissolve the group.
KATO FAMILY
THANKS FOR LETTING ME
RIDE ON YOUR PRECIOUS MOTORBIKE!
I'm home.
Hi.
You're home early.
Yeah. I sent you a text.
I didn't realize. Sorry.
Curry for dinner?
Yeah, thanks.
Mizuki.
I got a day off next week.
Do you want to visit my parents?
I haven't had the chance to introduce you.
Yeah. Sounds good.
I think we should
talk about our future too.
You're right.
It's been a while.
You haven't changed at all.
He seems like a good guy.
Well, I'm better looking than him though.
I'm sorry.
Have a good life.
...memories of you
Even if you do not return
I won't...
- You're back late.
- Hey.
Kaori, I'll have a hard one.
Sure thing.
Because I promised the sky
No matter how lonely I am
I will not die
No matter how lonely I am...
Shori, did something happen?
...I will not die
I saw her.
What?
Seems like she's already over me.
She looked well.
I think she's getting married.
That's a relief, huh?
Yeah.
And you know what?
Her new man is such a great guy.
The complete opposite of me.
I'm so glad.
She'll be okay now.
I'm sure.
Hey, Shori!
Y-You haven't seen my film yet.
You're right.
I'll watch it.
Your boring yakuza film.
Yeah, t-that's what I'm talking about.
Then, let's go. Let's go now.
- Akira, get the car.
- Let's go.
Let's go!
- You're gonna be moved.
- Are you sure?
Hey, kid.
Make sure to live your life.
What?
You have anywhere to go?
You wanna join us?
Boss, what are you...
Oh, come on.
Doesn't hurt to have a bigger family.
What's your name?
Masashi...
Yamada.
So? It's good, right?
It's all right.
Come over once things are settled.
Let's go.
Shall we go?
Yeah.
I'm the one who made yoga popular.
Not again.
It was 30 years ago.
I was in advertising, right?
There was a fitness boom back then...
Shori's gone
so there's no one here to stop him.
- I was the one...
- Nana, good morning.
Morning.
Where's that yakuza guy?
He went to the other side.
Y-You're not making sense.
Do you have regrets or unfinished business
from when you were alive?
What?
I think that's the reason you're here.
You're freaking me out.
Is this some kind of cult?
A cult? How rude.
Oh, hey.
Do you want to shoot a film with us?
- Minako, shall we go?
- Ew.
Sure.
Nana, take a seat.
DECEASED
Every day,
I'm scared to look through this.
I wonder what'll happen to me
if I find Ryo's name here.
Yeah.
So you want to know about my life?
Yes.
I want to know more about you
before you move on to the other side.
Um...
I'm Minako Kawakami. 35 years old.
I was a journalist here, for Hokuto TV,
and a single mother to a seven-year-old.
Your husband?
We split up soon after Ryo was born.
I wanted to work but he didn't want me to.
Since then, it's just been Ryo and me.
What was this world like for you?
You mean the living world?
Yes.
I don't know.
I was so frantic with work and parenting.
Looking back,
I don't know why I was trying so hard.
If you could go back,
what would you like to do?
I want to...
go on a trip with Ryo.
Because I've never been able to
take him on one.
And...
I want to apologize to him.
There are lots of unknown facts
in the world we can't see,
such as atoms,
electrons and elementary particles.
For example, what we're experiencing is
three dimensional.
Four dimensional, if we add time.
Lisa Randall, a scientist...
It's gonna go viral.
This is genius.
Are you gonna post it?
- So true.
- Hey...
Yasuko.
Don't slit your wrist like Nana, okay?
It's so annoying.
Everything okay there?
- Yup.
- Sorry.
So let's review the word "dimension."
It is defined as an indicator
for measurement of space.
Okay. What is one dimension? It is a line.
Here's dessert.
Hey.
Oh, Nana.
I get that I died, but...
Can I kill a person?
There's someone I wanna kill.
Hey, Nana.
Don't say things like that.
We can't harm people in the living world
from this world.
How stupid.
I mean, you're all dead.
Hey.
It has no taste at all.
How long do I have to stay in this hell?!
Nana.
Why don't you come with us?
I want to show you something.
What?
Trust me and just tag along.
All right, then. Let's go!
Huh?
What's this?
Everyone who died and left behind
those who are important to them.
We all search together...
for the ones we are looking for.
The ones we're looking for...
I don't know what your regret is,
but we can help if you want.
Hey, over here!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
- Isn't this good?
- I got a message!
I...
There's someone I want to apologize to.
This is your baby's face.
There's the eyes and nose.
Here's the mouth.
I didn't want to die
until my daughter gave birth.
So, I fought my destiny and here I am.
This world is pretty lenient, isn't it?
I think so too.
I was able to be with them
for a long time.
I have no more regrets.
Watching my kids all this time
made me realize...
that they're very strong.
Maybe they would've been fine without me
from the start.
I think that sometimes.
That's not true.
DAY 32, NOTHING ON SHELTER'S NOTICEBOARD
HOKUTO TV, NO PROGRESS
Oh my, Michael.
Hey, why are you sleeping here?
Let's go to your room, okay?
Mr. Tanaka, give me a hand.
Okay.
Wake up.
Michael, you ready?
One, two, lift.
Okay, let's walk.
He's so drunk.
Is it going well?
Yes. I enjoy writing.
I can't see the end though.
It's your turn, Akira.
Tell me.
What? No.
I have nothing interesting to tell.
You always dodge the question
when it's about you.
Do I?
I want to know what your life was like.
Minako,
I'm sensing the spirit of a journalist.
You're right.
But...
I guess I don't mind telling you.
The reason why
I can't go to the other side.
Is this your...
Yes.
My dad looks stubborn, right?
I've always been sickly so for me,
his existence was the scariest thing
in the world.
Your lunch stinks.
What? She's picking them up.
What's she going to do with that?
Is she gonna eat that?
That's disgusting.
What a freak.
She got something on me. Ew.
- You okay?
- So gross.
Nana.
Y-Yasuko.
Yasuko, I'm sorry!
Nana...
Why...
Nana, why...
Yasuko, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, Yasuko.
I'm so sorry.
Why... Nana.
Nana.
I practically lived in my bed.
I was a ranch owner's son,
but I wasn't capable of physical labor.
I always thought
my dad didn't accept me
as a member of the family.
When they told me my remaining days,
I thought, "Why me?"
I took it out on my family so many times.
I've hurt them a lot.
I think...
this is the reason why I can't move on.
My dad, who's never even read a book,
has been writing a novel
for many years now.
A story about me.
If I were alive,
maybe he wouldn't be writing a novel.
Or maybe he would've anyway.
I'll never know.
But it made me happy.
It felt like I finally got to know my dad.
AKIRA CHEERED ON THE NEWBORN CALF...
Though...
I only wish I had known while I was alive.
Nana.
Your room's a mess.
My bad.
What are you writing?
I'm keeping a record of everything
that's happened since I got here.
BEFORE GOING TO "THE OTHER SIDE"
(WORKING TITLE) CHAPTER FOURTEEN
Something wrong?
You know,
I apologized.
But...
nothing changed.
Why?
I'm sure that one day,
your voice will be heard.
Don't worry.
That's not an answer.
You can borrow that.
Goodbye.
- Goodnight.
Minako!
Minako, he's alive!
Y-Y-Your son! He's alive!
He's alive.
HOSHISUNA HOME FOR CHILDREN
We'll wait out here.
Ryo has a fever again.
It's already been a week. Let's take him
to see a doctor again tomorrow.
Okay.
Mommy.
Ryo, we'll go to
the doctor tomorrow, okay?
I want to see my mommy.
I know.
I'm sure we'll find your mom.
Ryo.
I'm sorry I left you all on your own.
Mommy.
Are you there?
Yes.
I'm right here.
I wanted to apologize to you.
I went to pick you up from your school,
but I was washed away by the tsunami.
I'm sorry.
Mommy, we're going home together, right?
I wish I could.
Do I have to live here forever?
I'm so sorry.
I'll watch over you
so that you won't be alone, okay?
Okay.
Mommy.
Tell me a story until I fall asleep.
Sure.
Which story?
Something fun you did recently.
In the world I'm in right now,
everyone helps to find
each other's loved ones.
Like a parade.
That sounds amazing.
They helped me find you too.
I see.
Then, it's your turn to help everyone.
Yeah.
You're right.
Hey, Mr. Tanaka.
Yes?
I have one unfinished business.
Will you help me out?
If it's within my power.
Akira.
Don't give me that
"I'm so heartbroken" look.
What are you talking about?
I'm not.
Yeah, but Minako was a fox.
If I was younger, I would've...
Ew.
What?
What do you mean "Ew"?
Ew.
Minako.
I'm back.
Come here.
You want coffee?
Thanks, Kaori.
Michael.
I haven't thanked you properly.
Thank you.
Stop it. You're making me blush.
Your film.
Let's complete it.
Huh?
I'll stay until we do.
You want her to see it, right?
Come on, stop it!
You're gonna make me cry.
All right. I-I'll do it. Yeah.
This film is going to be great.
You too, Nana.
What? No way.
Nana, this is mandatory.
No way.
- Tanaka.
- Yes.
Get the camera.
As you wish!
All right.
Let's do this.
- It's rolling.
- Okay.
Take one.
Ready, start!
It's been 50 years.
This film is almost complete.
The protagonist, Koga,
believed in the revolution and
devoted himself to the student protest.
But in fear of getting caught,
he decides to go back to Tokyo
on the day of the protest...
without his girlfriend.
He ran away.
The pathetic fool.
Koga, wait!
I'm sorry.
There's no way I can start a revolution.
You don't have to.
Just stay with me.
We'll meet again. I promise.
And so, Koga quit the student protest
and ran away to Tokyo.
I know these will sell.
Maiko married Sasaki.
And Koga buried himself in work.
They both lived their lives
with a lid on the past they had shared.
50 years had passed.
Koga returned to
the city of Okinawa again.
Memories of that day come back to his mind
like it was yesterday.
M-M-Maiko...
He's really into it.
Are you Mitsuru Koga?
And by a strange coincidence...
Koga has an encounter
with Maiko's grandchild.
Huh? Me?
You know my grandma, right?
Huh?
Are you Maiko's...
Please come see her.
Grandma's been longing to see you.
Cut.
What are you, a prodigy?
You're incredible!
It's a thumbs up!
Wonderful!
Nana!
Stop it!
Please come see her.
- Michael, don't!
- He's mocking me.
I see.
You went on before me.
Koga!
Goodbye!
Koga,
live your life to the fullest.
Koga!
Maiko.
Maiko!
Koga!
Michael.
- No. Wait, Michael.
- Michael!
Michael!
What's wrong?
Maiko!
Michael!
Let's show it on the big screen.
Yes, let's.
What's wrong?
A-About that...
I want to give this film to someone.
But I feel really embarrassed
doing stuff like that.
Could you all go and do it for me?
What? Do it yourself.
I know, but...
Michael.
Let's go together.
I'll come with you.
T-This is kinda nice.
This whole camaraderie thing.
Okay.
I'll go.
For real? There's so many people.
Yeah. It's crazy.
Hey, you guys.
There's something I want to show you.
Come with me.
This way.
Look at this!
See this?
Is this you, Michael?
- You're a major producer.
- Don't flatter me.
You weren't lying.
Of course I wasn't.
I thought you were.
Yeah, we all did.
See.
Oh, wow.
"FILM SHOULD BE FREEDOM"
This is nerve-wracking.
I-I'm really bad at stuff like this.
You're gonna be fine.
We'll wait for you out here.
I changed my mind.
We came all the way out here.
But...
Koga. Is that you?
S-Sasaki?
What is it? After all this time.
I-I want to apologize to Maiko.
Please let me see her.
Come in.
Sasaki, when did you die?
Two years ago. Cancer.
I see.
What's that?
Oh, this.
It's my new film.
I-It's about me, M-Maiko, and you.
Films even after you died?
You film freak.
That's right.
This is the only thing I can do.
This way.
Maiko, you haven't changed at all.
She's always been rooting for you.
But she chose you.
You know...
I still think about
the time we spent back then.
We couldn't start a revolution.
But...
We were united. That, I know for sure.
Maiko.
M-Maiko.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Hi there.
Is everything okay?
It was perfect. Excellent.
You didn't give it to her?
Yeah, but if you think about it,
you can't watch films at home.
I'll do it when it's on DVD.
It won't be on DVD though.
Oh, c-come on. It's okay.
Now, shall we go home?
Hey, everyone.
Why don't we have a film screening?
We can invite everyone.
Great idea.
I was a-about to say that myself.
Really?
Yeah.
- Let's do that.
- Yes, let's.
All right. We're doing this!
Michael, we're ready.
Um...
Good e-evening everyone. I'm Michael.
I forced my friends to help me
and we managed to complete the film.
T-This f-film
has the power to revolutionize the era.
And I also think that
it c-connects the past and the present.
"Films even after you died?"
That's what my friend said.
But hey, whoever does it first wins.
I hope...
you enjoy the film.
So,
I have an idea for a new film.
Another one?
An autobiography.
I want to make a film
about the time I've spent here.
Michael, that's my idea.
T-Then, we can do it together.
This is going to be a masterpiece.
I can't let you.
No?
Minako.
You okay?
Oh, yes.
It just hasn't sunk in yet.
Same here.
To be honest,
I'm feeling a little uneasy too.
Hey, Mr. Tanaka.
Yes?
W-What is it like on the other side?
I can't tell you.
What?
Mr. Tanaka is kind of like our warden.
What? Why didn't you tell me?
That's so scary.
O-Oh, come on. Tell us already.
You'll find out soon anyway.
Tanaka, you're so hard-headed.
But you know what?
Making the film was fun.
Right?
Films are great.
A bunch of grown-ups w-working
passionately towards the same goal.
It's amazing.
- Yeah.
- Right?
Nana.
Make more films, okay?
You can use the notes in my room.
Work hard, Nana.
Why only me?
Akira.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Make sure to keep
a detailed record of this world.
You can count on me.
But you gotta stay on the offense.
Don't lose, all right?
Who's he competing with?
Let's have a toast.
A toast.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
We still have some food left. Eat up.
Let's eat.
Could I have some of that?
- Have fried chicken too.
- Okay, then one please.
Thank you.
Here's the fried...
- About this much?
- Yes, thank you.
A little bit more...
...SOUND OF WAVES, AND AN EMPTY BEACH
Knock, knock.
Is everyone asleep?
Yeah.
In the end,
Michael fell asleep while talking.
He really is full of energy.
Here.
Thanks.
Are you going to continue writing?
Yes.
I think I will
until my dad completes his novel.
I see.
Make sure to write about me.
Of course.
You're going to be the main character.
Don't. I just want a small part.
I wanted to be with you
a little longer.
Where's this coming from?
I kind of...
liked you.
What's with that confession?
Is it weird?
Yes, it's weird.
I wonder if things would've been different
if we met when we were alive.
I guess we'll never know.
Yeah.
Akira.
Thank you. It's been fun.
Me too.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Passing it to you now.
Watch out behind you.
- Thank you.
- What about this?
Right in the middle here.
All right. Yeah.
Wow, so many people.
Ryo.
- Long time no see.
- Yeah.
We still have some time.
You wanna go for tea?
Yeah, sure.
You've grown.
Thanks for coming.
First time in Tokyo?
Yes.
There are so many people.
Yeah, compared to that place.
Right.
Are you graduating next year?
Yes.
Do you know what you want to do?
Well, I'm not completely sure.
But I might want to do what my mom did.
Please tell me about my mom again.
Sure. Of course.
I'm looking forward to the film today.
Yeah, please do.
Nana!
It's been a while.
Oh, hi!
Long time no see.
Hello.
Thumbs up!
Tickets please.
- This way.
- Theater 2, please.
I'll see you later.
Enjoy.
I'm getting nervous.
Yeah.
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo