Lalbazar, Kolkata.
So, Abhiroop Babu?
Everyone gave me
their version of the story.
Now let me hear...
...your version.
Why are you laughing?
Just keep quiet.
Don't laugh at all.
Everything has happened because of you.
Keep quiet.
I am warning you. Keep quiet.
ONE WEEK AGO
Apu.
The button of the shirt has come off.
Wear some other shirt.
Okay.
But I am not getting my brown trouser.
It hasn't been brought
back from the washer man. Right?
Today, your lunch
isn't ready as well.
You have to eat at the canteen.
Okay.
And since you have to buy food
from the canteen today...
...go to the office walking from the
station. Don't take a taxi.
Okay.
Listen, what is okay about it?
Tell me.
What happened now?
How can everything
be fine for you, Abhi?
Don't you ever feel angry?
No. Look,
you have so much of work anyway.
And amidst that, if you have to look
into such trivial issues as well...
Which era do you belong to?
Your shirt, trouser, Tiffin...
Nothing is ready.
You are not angry.
I am asking you to walk to office.
And you don't show
any reaction to even that?
Abhi. Sometimes, I really feel that you
don't really care about what I say or do.
You are completely
indifferent towards me.
What is this, Apu?
You are turning this matter into another
angle now. Tell me. Is this right?
I don't care what is right or wrong.
You must make a decision today.
How?
Scold me!
What?
Apu.
If you don't get my trouser...
...I will go to office like this.
Buenos Aires.
- Argentina.
Rome? - Italy.
Copenhagen.
- Denmark.
My dear,
hope the food was enough.
Beijing.
But grandfather, there was
no fruit in fruitcake. - Correct.
My dear, a name may not
always show the true qualities.
Akashganga means Milky way.
Does it have milk in it, my dear?
Nor does sweet betel
have sweets in it. Tell me.
But grandpa, does money grow
on money plants (coriander)?
Keep quiet.
Fallen fellow! Lowly creature.
What is it?
Did you do homework today? - Move.
Chandu sir will take you to task today.
Forget it.
You couldn't leave it.
It is a big problem in the morning.
Every smoker has the same excuse.
I have decided now.
One in the morning,
one in the afternoon after lunch...
...and one before going off to sleep
at night. Three in a day. That is it.
What does Madhubala say?
Madhubala says that we must go in
for a sweet and peaceful mutual divorce.
If I challenge or ask for alimony...
...the matter will be stretched
over a long period of time.
I guess you should opt for a mutual
and amicable settlement.
You don't need alimony anyway.
- This isn't about the need, Abhi.
What he has done to me, it is
about squeezing him by his testicles.
I will rip it off him and make
him wear it as a pendant on his neck.
It is not just a case of alimony.
- Yes.
You are absolutely right.
You are correct.
You can hang them as
the pendant on his neck.
It will hang there for his entire life.
This is my husband's visiting card.
He is a lawyer. Honest.
Madhubala and all wouldn't
be able to do anything.
She has been bribed.
Hey, what do men think anyway?
What do they think?
They can do anything that
comes to their mind anytime.
And then,
fool us and show us their thumb...
...and get away from
the scene conveniently?
Oh my God.
Think about her husband once.
Why are you getting worried?
Don't get tensed. I will do it.
Asim seems to be at work.
He would have earned a lot
if he was into cricket betting.
How?
His way of earning is by
giving information about...
...the various stocks
kept in various warehouses.
Give these files to Dipankar.
There are seven in all.
Abhi. GM sir has called you.
GM sir has called him.
I have some bad news for you, Abhi.
There has been a notice from Delhi.
We are overstaffed
with B-grade officers.
We have to downsize.
That is why it has been
decided that from next week...
...you are going to be an A-grade
officer, Mr. Abhiroop Banerjee.
Next week,
you will get the letter in your hand.
Thank you, sir.
Yes. Keep this file.
Yes.
These are the files.
Very, very good. This will do.
Who is your designer?
I do it myself.
- I see.
Shall I ask for tea or coffee for you?
No, no. Let it be for today.
I have some more deliveries to make.
Okay, okay.
What about the check, Girish?
What are you saying?
The bill isn't made yet.
You can come next month.
Oh my God.
Abhi, that is wonderful news.
And we are eating
in this rotten canteen?
I want a treat. Today.
Tomorrow.
Why tomorrow?
What is so important
that you must do today?
Aparna should get
the first treat, right?
Are you going to be distributing
the sweets today?
Or after you get the letter?
Congratulations.
How did you come to know?
Thank you.
Even I was in the queue, right?
I can smell something burning.
Where are you going now? Home?
Don't you think it is going to
be a surprise for Aparna?
Yes. A good surprise.
Hey, darling.
- Look here, Miss hot.
Hey, do you want to come with me?
Did you see his face?
Yes.
His move failed.
- It is obvious.
"I am mesmerized with the beauty."
"There are flowers blooming all around."
"No one is..."
- Mr. Pakrasi.
Tell me, Abhi.
I wanted to say that you
still haven't paid the rent.
Hey, this is from Flury's.
Show me.
No, no. This isn't anything.
- Show me.
No, no. This is...
- What is this?
Show it to me. Wow, this is great.
- You have not paid the rent.
That is why I wanted to talk...
- Chicken patties. Wow.
And you were hiding
and taking it away? Right?
Now this is...
- Wow. Great. Just great.
Bengalis will die eating.
I got it but...
- You have satisfied me today.
Yes. But your rent for 6 months is left.
Hey, it will be done.
It will be done for sure.
I will get a payment within
a day or two. It will be done.
Now... Listen.
- "You want to cheat me."
"Do you think I am a fool?"
"Hey! My lover.
Don't cheat me."
What is this?
- Food.
All of a sudden?
The office canteen owner gave me...
...a gift for being
the most valuable customer.
Abhi. I don't like jokes at all.
Promotion.
What?
Sumit. Wait. - GM sir called
me on his own and gave me the news.
And then, he said...
- Mother. Patties.
Yes. - He said that
I will get the letter next week.
And listen.
- Yes?
Have you done the homework?
There is a little bit left.
- Then why are you reading Superman comics?
Please don't say anything to him today.
We have got such good news today.
Sumit, what are you doing?
I am a Superman.
Father.
- Yes?
Why does Superman
only stay in America?
If the traffic would
have been lesser in Kolkata...
...he could have stayed
in Kolkata as well.
Why only Kolkata? He could have stayed
in our 10/5 Ballygunge as well.
Make your father wear his underwear
over his pant. You will see that he...
...has turned into Superman.
I have given the ultimatum for the rent.
I will get it within a day or two.
Father.
- Yes?
Could uncle Anjan be Superman?
Anjan could do everything.
Yes!
Superman.
Yes.
- Now get down.
"This is a new morning."
"It is getting ready again."
"In another unknown hope."
"The traffic on the
road is always on the move."
"There is no time to stop."
"On a new date."
"It will call out in a new language."
"This is the beginning
of another new day."
"In the eyes of another new day."
"New colors can be seen."
"This is a new morning."
"It is getting ready again."
"In another unknown hope."
"There is no time to stop."
"On a new date."
"It will call out in a new language."
"This is the beginning
of another new day."
"In the eyes of another new day."
"New colors can be seen."
Yes. I will do this afternoon.
Where is the labor
payment file for April?
Sir. I had computed it and
sent it to Dipankar for tabulation.
He didn't get it.
Raju had taken it, sir.
Listen. You have signed for seven
files in the 'Out' register.
Dipankar has got only 6.
The labor payment file
for April is not there at all.
It cannot just vanish.
No.
- Can it?
So either look for the
file or make another file.
The audit will start tomorrow.
It is an important file.
And I guess you know...
...what will happen if the Lifting
companies don't receive their payments.
Yes?
The stuff will be lying
around and will rot.
How much of time will
it take to make a new file?
It will take a long time, sir.
It will involve taking print out of all
the documents of the various companies.
If I have to tally it
with the corresponding data...
If you don't get it, make it.
I will tell Dipankar.
He will come earlier tomorrow
and make the tabulation.
Okay?
Why are you standing here? Go.
Yes.
That was great.
- Superb! Bravo.
- That was a superb shot, crazy one.
Mind-blowing.
- Superb! Great.
Raju.
I had given you seven files
to give to Dipankar. - Maybe.
Not maybe. I did give them to you.
Hey, I transfer hundreds of files
from one table to another in a day.
How would I remember, Abhi?
That is right. But...
You are too much.
Great. Superb.
What is happening here?
We will lose if this goes on.
He is winning the match single handedly.
Too much.
Dipankar.
That was a great shot.
- I had sent 7 files to you.
One of them was the
labor payment file of April.
Yes. I have spoken to the
GM in the morning regarding this.
Yes.
But I have only got 6 files.
Can you please look around your desk?
Since you are asking me to do it,
I will search.
Come on, give it to me.
This is a very important file, Dipankar.
Okay. Wait for an hour.
I will look into this.
Dipankar. Meaning...
Do you consider playing carom
more important than the file?
Why are you bothering me?
Go on. I told you that I will search.
I did give seven files to you, Dipankar.
You are making a mistake, Abhi.
Wow. That is great.
- I am making a mistake?
I am making a mistake?
Tell me. Where is the file?
Great. Great. You are superb.
What is the score?
- 3 and 16.
3 and 16? Okay, come on.
Come on. Reset. Reset.
I will defeat you in the next game, sir.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Set it. Set it. Set it.
Now this table is going to be...
- The first turn will be mine.
Hey, show it to me. - Hey, don't worry.
We will win this time for sure.
Let us practice a bit.
- Hey, pass the striker to me. Come on.
Yes?
- Hello, Aparna.
I will be a little late today.
- Why?
Actually some urgent work came up.
Abhi. We have to go
to father's place today.
You had told me that you will go.
Such functions keep
on happening in your house.
Let it pass.
Abhi. Is everything fine?
Yes. Everything is fine.
I am hanging up.
Come on. Let us leave now.
- Yes. I have to reach home early today.
Are you going by train?
- Yes. Let us go.
I will call you.
- Yes.
How much longer is it going to take?
It will take time.
Should I wait?
No. Let it be. Leave.
Okay. Bye.
- Yes.
Hey, come on. Look at me.
- Hey, what is it in the bag?
Come on. Show it to us.
- Why are you ignoring us, darling?
You are so beautiful.
- Why don't you look at us?
She is superb.
- You bet she is.
"It is the same color
and yet it is different."
"It is the same way in
which the heart has been bound."
"And yet, I am running ahead..."
Hi. Hi.
- Happy anniversary, father.
Abhi didn't come?
He is stuck in important
work at the office.
"This is a dream.
It is changing again."
"No one knows the direction
in which life is moving."
"There and hopes and faith."
"Of expressing everything."
"Nothing really exists."
"Everything gets covered in the fog."
"At the end of another day."
"It is the beginning of another night."
"It begins in various places."
"How will it happen?"
"Where should I go?"
"The state of affairs is bad."
I see. Abhi. Come in.
No, I mean...
- "In this world."
The rent...
I see. The rent?
Hey, you will get it. You will get it.
Do you think I will steal your
ground floor in my pocket and run away?
No. It isn't so. But it is...
- Please tell your wife not to worry at all.
No tension. You will get it.
Actually you had told me
that you are going to get a payment.
It hasn't come...
- And today...
You will get it as soon as I get it.
Look, Mr. Pakrasi.
Yes.
- I am sure you don't like it that...
...I come to your place
for asking for money everyday.
Yes...
- Even I don't like it.
So if you could pay the rent...
Hello, father.
Abhi.
- Yes?
Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday.
Thank you. Come to me, dear.
Thank you.
Leave me.
- Why?
I have work.
- What happened to you? Hey.
Wow.
- Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Happy birthday.
- Wow.
Wow!
Thank you.
Mogambo is happy.
My Mogambo is happy with everything.
But now, if we don't
get the rent on time...
...we wouldn't be able to go for a tour
of Rajasthan for this veneration holiday.
There are only three months
left for that.
And if we cannot go, Mrs. Mogambo and
Master Mogambo wouldn't be happy at all.
No, no. Thankfully you reminded me.
Sumit. Get ready.
I am going downstairs.
Got it?
I am going and talking to Pakrasi.
I am going.
What do you mean you are going?
You got a shirt and had Payesh(sweet).
You must tell me
what I am going to get for my efforts.
Now...
The kitchen is closed tonight.
We will go out for dinner.
Yes.
- Mrs. Mogambo is happy.
I am leaving. Sumit, get ready.
- Yes, father.
What are you doing, Sumit?
Mother. You got to look cool!
Mr. Pakrasi.
Yes.
What is the matter, Abhi?
Didn't you go home last night?
No, no, I did.
So?
What brings you back again now?
I mean if you could pay the rent...
Hey, stop it. Rent!
Rent! Rent!
Don't you have any other work?
You are a strange man!
No...
- Be it night or be it day...
Now...
- You always come here asking for rent.
Do you think I am a thief?
Look... - I will not give the rent.
What will you do?
Get lost.
Go and call anyone you wish to call.
Come with me.
- Where?
Hey, I am telling you. Come with me.
Leave it.
- Come on. I am with you.
Stop it. Look, don't get into this mess.
Come on. Come with me.
- What is the need? Leave it.
No, no, I will talk to him today.
What did you tell him?
Look, daughter-in-law.
Why are you getting into this?
The ones who don't pay rent for
days on end are called thieves.
My husband is a very nice man.
- You...
That is why he trusts
lowly people like you.
Keep quiet. - No. I need to say this.
- What did you say?
No, no. - I called you a thief.
Cannot you hear me?
Oh no. Please keep quiet.
- What do you mean? - I need to tell him all this.
What is it that you don't understand?
I said what I meant.
If you don't understand,
I will say it again.
Listen to me. Please keep quiet...
- You are a thief.
Hey! Mind your language.
No. - Don't assume I will spare you
just because you are a woman!
Please calm down. Please. No, if you would
have paid our rent for 6 months...
...you wouldn't have had
to listen to all this today.
What is the need to say this?
- Hey, she is so strange.
Abhi. Let us go home.
Come on.
Father. What happened, father?
Did uncle say anything to you, father?
Abhi. GM sir has called you.
What have you done?
None of the figures tally
with the corresponding voucher.
You would have made extra
payment for 500 laborers.
There would have been
an extra payment of two lakhs...
...if Dipankar wouldn't have noticed.
This is what you have done?
What is the answer that
I shall give to my auditors?
My officer was on drugs
while working at night.
Sir. Sorry.
Actually Abhi is not
good with computers.
Maybe that is the reason
he has made these mistakes.
In that case,
this work should have been hand written.
You don't deserve a computer.
Sir. Shall I make the file?
It will be made quickly.
Do you have anything to say, Abhi?
Do I get any answer from you?
Well. Then I will
find the answers myself.
This wouldn't have had any value
if I didn't give this to you today.
Happy birthday.
It is very late at night.
Shall we go now?
Let us go.
You are not ready yet, mother?
- I will get ready.
Let your father come back.
I will get ready.
What happened, Sumit?
The ticket cost of Boss is 200.
- I like the songs.
Hey, Boss is great.
- I am a huge fan of him.
But the film is great...
- Hey, she is here. She is here.
She is here...
- Wow.
Hey, she is wearing a yellow sari.
Brother is so lucky!
She is so beautiful.
- Yellow fairy.
Hey.
Show it to us.
- Madam. It is such a nice sari.
Look at her body.
- Hey, she is so beautiful. Superb.
Hey... - Hey,
she is so attractive. Superb.
Show us the bag too, madam...
- Abhi!
Oh my God.
Brother isn't doing anything. - Abhi.
Hey, no, no.
He doesn't have the guts to do anything.
Let me see, dear.
She is so good looking.
- Abhi, do something.
Abhi!
Hey, friend.
How are you, my friend?
Anjan!
Father first. And then, mother.
Passed away in a span of two years.
That is it. Nothing was left.
Then I sold off the property of Kasba.
I completed all the work here.
And then, straight out.
I was out of India for ten years.
No connection.
One day, all of a sudden, I started
wondering what is our city up to.
Let me go and see.
That is why I am back.
And look, who would have thought
I would meet you like this?
Even I hadn't hoped that
I will meet you like this.
What are you doing these days?
Importer in the US of A.
These imported clothes
slow down the entire process.
6 buttons. 3 hooks.
And then, another button
in the southern hemisphere.
The zip comes after that.
And we are moving towards the jet age...
...where time is money.
That is why the best option
after graduation is to go to America...
...and sell Saris,
petticoats and loin cloth.
A cultural change in the US of A.
An attire of convenience.
Saris, petticoats and loin cloth?
Friend.
I can see that you still
have the bright spark. Yes?
And what about you?
I am one of the ordinary
officers of FGCI.
Do you have a problem?
No.
You are married.
I have a son.
Sumit. He is eight years old.
That is great.
So where are we going now?
Home. Aparna, my wife and
Sumit have heard a lot about you.
What did you tell them?
I have told them that you
were my bodyguard in school.
Do you remember...
...the way we thrashed the Sardar
child by throwing him on the ground?
Yes.
He entangled his leg into mine and made
me fall while we were at the flat race.
That means I command a certain
respect in your house, right?
A lot more than me.
Abhi.
Drop the plan of going
to your house today.
I am going to your
house for the first time...
...and I will
meet your wife and kid.
It doesn't seem right
if I go empty handed.
So?
I am hungry.
What do you want to eat?
Think about it and tell me.
You haven't lost the spark yet, friend.
Coffee and chicken snack?
- Bull's eye.
Come on.
For how long are you here?
I am here, friend.
I am going to be here for a few days.
Yes, sir?
- Two cups of coffee and chicken snacks.
And throw in some salad as well.
Wow! Some attitude.
So tell me. What is the problem?
What problem?
Something has happened for sure.
I can still read your face.
There are a lot of problems. Forget it.
Tell me.
Hey! Mind your language.
Don't think I will spare you just
because you are a woman.
You would have made extra
payment for 500 laborers.
Hey, fool. Get lost.
- Hello, yellow fairy.
You didn't give the salad, chief?
Why didn't you get the salad?
We don't serve salad with this.
Do you have LIC?
Yes.
- For how much?
Around five lakhs.
And along with PF and gratuity,
another ten to fifteen?
Yes. Maybe I do.
And what is the price of your house?
Around 10 crores.
Yes.
So friend, if something happens to you,
your family is taken care of.
What are you scared of?
For yourself or for others?
It is your birthday today, right?
Do you remember I
had told you long back...
...that you will be born
again on your 35th birthday?
Do you still believe in
palmistry and all? - Of course.
Check it once.
What is this?
Always remember.
Fear is just a state of mind.
Come on.
Hey!
Hey! Who is it?
Hey! Go off to sleep. Go off to sleep.
I think it must be a cat or a dog.
- Okay, boss.
I have got it.
- Let us go.
Anjan. Anjan.
I am very scared.
Then why did you come?
At that time,
I thought I will be able to do it.
But now...
The file wouldn't come
flying to you, friend.
Come on.
Which one is Dipankar's table?
Forget it, Anjan.
You don't have to do anything.
Come on. Let us go back.
- Which one?
This one...
What are you doing, Anjan?
Anjan, forget it. Don't do anything.
Look, everything is going to work out
on its own. Don't do anything. Leave it,
Anjan. No need to do anything.
Everything will be fine on its own.
Don't do that, Anjan. Anjan, don't.
- Take a look.
Check all of these.
Come on, check.
It isn't there. It is not among these.
In that case...
- What is it?
The whole office is
playing a game with you.
He is not alone in this.
Do something to make everyone aware...
...that even if a sheet of paper is moved
away from its rightful position...
...how difficult it can be.
What should I do?
Create mayhem!
Don't do that, Anjan.
- What are you scared of?
Anjan. Please stop it...
- Destroy everything.
What are you doing?
What are you so scared of?
What fear do you have?
Are you scared of society?
Of police?
- No, Anjan.
Or are you scared of losing the job?
- No. Don't do that.
One cannot live with so much
of fear in mind, Abhi.
If you have to live with your head held
high, You must give a befitting reply.
You must be a rebel.
Nothing happens on its own, friend.
Go ahead.
Do it.
Come on. Break it.
Hey, what is this? That is my table.
No, no, Anjan. No, no. Leave this.
Who is it? Who is it?
- Who is it? Who is it?
Come on. Come on, come on, come on.
Let us run.
Who is it inside?
- Come on, let us run. Come on.
Run, run, come this side.
Hey, stop. Stop.
Who is it? Who is it?
Come this side. Upstairs.
- He has gone upstairs. Come on. Upstairs.
Hey, who is it? Get hold of him...
- Come on, get hold of him.
Hey, stop. Stop. I am warning you.
- Stop. Stop.
Hey, this is closed.
Come on. Let us go that side. That side!
Come on...
- Hey, they have gone that side.
Come on, come on.
- Get them. Get them.
Hey, stop. Hey, get them. Get them...
- There they are. Come on, get them.
Hey, stop. Where are you running off to?
- Make it fast.
Hey, stop. Hey, get them. Get them...
I didn't get that file.
We will go there tomorrow
again and find out.
Hey. I am sure there would be
a store room for old files.
Go and look for it there.
- Yes. Okay.
And now?
- Now?
Go home. Even I will leave.
But where are you staying?
Grand Hotel.
Very good. But where can I find you?
Tell me the room number.
- 105.
Okay.
- I have taken a local number too.
Really?
- Yes.
Oh no. Yes, tell me.
9831060805.
60805.
Okay.
Okay, friend.
- Yes?
Tell me something.
- What?
You didn't even touch one table.
Whose table is that?
Yes?
- Nandini's.
I see. I see.
Ladies, right?
I have a lot of missed calls from Aparna.
- Got it. Got it.
Taxi.
Hey. Hey!
Ballygunge.
- Sit.
I am leaving.
- Yes.
Hello?
- Abhi. Where are you?
I called you so many times.
I just saw the missed calls. GM sir had called
for a meeting today at his place. Urgent.
The phone was on silent.
Abhi. Is everything fine?
Everything is fine.
Where are you right now?
I am on my way. I am coming back home.
The world has changed.
It is one in the morning, Abhi.
I told you. The phone was on silent.
I couldn't hear it.
The phone was on silent
and you couldn't hear it!
So what if you couldn't hear it?
Didn't you feel like calling
even once and let me know?
I didn't get a chance. - What
do you mean you didn't get a chance?
Abhi. Everything...
- Everything is fine.
Want to say something?
We will not go anywhere
for the veneration holidays, Abhi.
In fact, Sumit and
I were talking about this.
We are never here for the veneration.
Ekdalia. Mohammed Ali Park.
We only hear others speak
about these veneration.
That is why we have decided
that we will stay here this year.
We will see everything on our own.
And even I have some pending
payments after the veneration.
That is why there is no problem
even if we don't get the rent now, Abhi.
Really?
Everything will be fine, Apu.
Everything will be fine.
How are you?
- Fine.
Did you see?
- What?
See how quiet he is?
- Yes, I do.
Hey, what are you doing?
- Hey, leave me.
That is it.
That is it. That is it. That is it.
That is enough. Let go of him.
Leave him. Get up. Get up.
Hold your bag. Get up.
Great. What is your name?
- Rupam.
Look, Rupam. It is not a
big deal to stand ahead in queue.
Both of you will get seats.
But the point is that Sumit
comes before you everyday.
So he has the right to
stand ahead in the queue.
But yet, if you feel being a senior,
you should stand ahead...
...you can request Sumit nicely
and he will leave the place for you.
But if you want to push around
and exercise your rights, then...
Then it will be a case
of Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall.
Humpty Dumpty had a great fall.
Sorry.
- Never mind.
Come on. Shake hands. Friends?
Yes.
- Yes.
Okay. Come on.
See you in the evening, father.
- Bye, mother.
Come on, come on. Come on. Get up.
- Bye, bye.
I will not spare the fool!
I will bury him alive.
You have just managed to create
a ruckus. But we aren't scared, fool.
Fool. Lowly creature!
Hey, let that son of a
scoundrel come in front of me.
Let him come and stand in front of me.
I will teach a lesson to the swine.
I will take each one to task...
Hey, keep quiet. Calm down.
Listen to me.
- That scoundrel wouldn't be spared!
Mr. Abhiroop Banerjee?
Can you tell us anything
about this vandalism?
CPI, CPM.
Congress. INTUC. TMC. BJP.
I can't understand
whatever you are trying to say.
I wanted to say that this
can be politically motivated.
Politically motivated?
But how? - Normally office
vandalism is politically motivated.
And it can be personal as well.
Maybe someone took revenge
for not getting the tender.
It could be done by kids as well.
- Kids?
I mean small kids.
Small kids?
- Yes.
They are the ones who love playing
like this. Spraying ink all over.
That is the reason
I am saying this.
Mr. Banerjee.
Your style of joking is very,
very interesting.
But there was an incident
in the office yesterday...
...and that had your involvement.
And because of that, it can be implied
that you had a motive to do all this.
Sir, in that case,
a lot of things can imply a lot.
But they don't necessarily have it.
Like?
Like a fruit cake doesn't have fruit.
Sweet betel doesn't have sweet in it.
There is no milk in the milky way.
And in money plant(Coriander)...
That was a good one.
Come on. Finish it. Let us go home.
We will give them a surprise.
No. Tomorrow.
I have to meet someone today.
Who is it?
Madhurima.
Who is that?
You forgot?
Our Madhu.
Where did you find her?
At New York. JFK airport.
What does she do now?
She is in Kolkata.
She has a restaurant business.
So that means you haven't
come to see the city alone.
I had been hurt very badly that day.
I thought that the memory
would live with me forever.
And now?
Now there is nothing.
So I can go ahead with her, right?
Absolutely.
Oh no. I am leaving.
- What is this?
You didn't even touch your drink.
I thought I will have it.
But then, I thought I shouldn't
face a problem when I meet her.
Waiter.
Let it be.
LIC worth quite a few lakhs.
Gratuity. PF.
And a house worth 10 crores.
I will pay the bill.
You can go ahead.
Wow! I can see that my
Royal Bengal tiger has woken up.
You are the real Royal Bengal Tiger.
See you.
Hope you are coming
to my place tomorrow.
I will call you.
Now go and get your rent.
You will be able to do it, right?
I will be able to do it.
I told him that this particular
horse would win.
But he didn't listen to me.
- He is such a fool.
Come on. Let us have fun. You have won.
- Come on. Drink to your heart's content.
Hey, listen. I have been into
racing for the last fifteen years.
Yes.
- He is right. He is good at this.
What is it, Abhi? Want to have a drink?
You need to be civil here.
You have to stop doing all this here.
The rest of you. Get out. Come on.
Come on. Get out of here quickly.
Give me the rent.
Take this.
This is the rent.
How?
Hey, he called me on his own.
And he asked for forgiveness.
He was supposed to get a payment, right?
I think he has got it.
That is why he gave me the money.
Do you know what I think?
He was tensed.
Look, to err is human.
There is a saying you use for that.
In English. Burying or something...
- Bury the hatchet.
Abhi. Are you fine?
Does it seem to you
that I am not fine?
No.
You didn't go to
father's house that day.
Can we go there tomorrow?
No, Aparna.
Okay. Okay.
We haven't gone anywhere
for a long time.
It is Saturday day after. You
have a half day and Sumit has a holiday.
Can we meet you after
office and go somewhere?
We can go.
- Sumit will see us.
I will ask Sumit not to come here.
What is it?
Abhi. Have you consumed alcohol?
No. Some office colleagues got
hold of me to treat them for promotion.
I just tasted it. I didn't drink.
Freshen up.
I will serve dinner.
Nandini.
- Tell me.
I called you many times yesterday.
But you didn't answer.
I couldn't hear the phone ringing.
Or else, I would have
gone to your house today.
Thank God.
You didn't have to make an effort.
I will run an errand
today before I reach office.
You can go to office on your own.
Want to say something?
We are going to travel
back together, right?
Since I didn't come yesterday,
there is a lot of pending work.
Let me finish it.
Come on. Let us leave.
- Come on.
Aren't you leaving?
I told you. I have pending work.
I have to complete it.
I will wait.
From now on,
I will not return by train, Abhi.
That is why there is
no point of waiting for me.
Why?
Anjan.
What is it?
- Yes.
Why didn't you come to the hotel?
No. You told me that Madhu
is in the hotel. So that is why I...
So what? You know her.
- Yes.
Anyway, what is the problem?
- I have fallen really low in the eyes of Nandini.
Very low.
Friend.
A blacksmith melts
the iron in fire and beats it...
...as per his wish to
give it a desired shape.
But the fire needs help
to keep itself burning.
The bellow.
Our mind's desire is the fire.
And in order to keep it burning, you have
to keep pumping air into the bellow, friend.
You are my support, Anjan.
But you are the blacksmith.
You are the one to hit with the hammer.
You have to solve your
personal problems on your own.
And you?
I am there with you.
Taxi.
Come on.
Move.
Let go of me! Let go.
You have to agree with our demands.
- You have to agree. You have to agree.
Let our revolution be hailed...
Hail. Hail.
Stop.
- Hail. Hail.
Stop now. Stop.
Hey, where are you running off to?
Come here, you fool.
Abhi!
Let go of me...
- Abhi. What are you doing, Abhi?
Let go of him.
- Leave me, Nandini.
Abhi. Stop it. Let us go. Come on.
- I will thrash him more.
Get into the cab. - Is it because of
them you were scared to travel by train?
Leave him... - For his sake?
I will teach him a lesson.
Come here, fool.
- Please leave him, Abhi.
Come here, Abhi. Leave him. - I will
not spare him. I will not spare him.
Let us go.
Let us go. Come on.
What was the need to do all this?
Fighting on the street?
I couldn't even imagine
you would do this.
What has happened to you?
What were you thinking?
What were you trying to prove?
What are you trying to prove, Abhi?
Five into five.
- Twenty five.
Five into six.
- Thirty.
Five into...
Hello.
Is this Mr.
Abhiroop Banerjee's residence?
Yes.
Madam. I am calling from the
Park Street police station. Who is this?
I am his wife.
What happened? Tell me.
An unidentified
bag was found in Chowringee.
From the ID card inside,
we got the name and address.
Even a cell phone has been found in it.
Yes, yes, it is his phone.
Where is Abhiroop?
I don't know about that, madam.
Please ask him to come to the police
station tomorrow and collect his bag.
Yes. I will tell him. But...
What is the matter?
You seem a little different.
Have you been thrashed or something?
Blow of the bellow.
I am very scared, father.
- No, no, there is nothing to be scared.
We called up at so many places.
He is so forgetful.
I am sure he has lost the bag.
He can lose the bag. But where did
the man go? He wouldn't get lost, right?
It is only 10:15 in the night, Apu.
Abhi is changing, father.
Why do you say that?
Look, he won't come to me.
I will come to meet him tomorrow or day after.
- Yes.
What is this?
What happened to you?
Nothing, Apu.
A car crashed hard into the taxi.
What are you saying?
I hope you are fine.
I am fine. Nothing to worry about.
Father. Check once.
What is the need?
This needs the specialty of general
physician or an orthopedic doctor.
It doesn't need a psychiatrist.
And both of them checked me
in the hospital.
There was a phone call from
the police station, Abhi.
Your bag was found lying unattended.
Yes...
Yes. I guess it was at the time
when the car hit us.
It must have fallen out at that time.
I didn't realize.
Where were you for so long?
At the hospital.
It took so long?
I had a colleague with me.
She was hurt a lot more.
So I had to drop her home.
That is why it took so long.
Nandini? I had called her
because I was so tensed.
What did she say?
- She didn't take my call.
Oh...
I see.
Which hospital?
PG.
PG?
You went all the way
from Chowringee to PG?
There are so many nursing homes around.
I went there since it is
an authorized hospital of the office.
Strange.
I had called up at PG. But no, they didn't
mention any accident case on your name.
If you would have asked for Nandini Sanyal,
maybe you would have been informed.
Tell me, why do I have a feeling...
...that you are trying to interrogate me
again like before?
No, no, no, no.
I am not interrogating you at all.
Sorry. Sorry, Abhiroop.
Apu. I am leaving today.
Yes, father.
- Abhiroop. Take care.
Why did you call him?
I was worried, Abhi.
And what is the problem
if I call my father?
Didn't you see the way
he was interrogating me?
Father wasn't interrogating, Abhi.
Even he was worried.
Have you forgotten?
You had to leave your house
in one set of clothes.
You might forget it but I cannot.
This incident happened
so many years back, Abhi.
Why are you raising old issues again?
Even father has accepted you.
No, he hasn't.
Nothing has changed, Aparna.
He interrogated me today in the same way
as he used to do earlier.
Nothing has changed at all.
Sorry, sorry.
Nothing has changed.
Abhi. Open your mouth.
Open your mouth. Open your mouth. Yes.
What is the sweet for?
Hey, Dipankar has got a promotion.
Ranjit. Hey, Ranjit. Listen to me.
We have to increase the prize money.
There are so many teams now.
What is the matter, Dipankar?
Why are you sitting on my chair?
It is the order of the GM sir, Abhi.
I have got a promotion.
Sir. Sir,
why is Dipankar sitting on my chair?
You will get an answer for this from
the vigilance either today or tomorrow.
Meaning?
Meaning!
I mean that you have cheated us of money
on the pretext of labor payment.
12 lakhs in 6 months.
You are a lowly crook!
Sir. These are lies. Lies.
There is proof supporting your
lie in your computer.
All labor heads are fudged.
Sir, no, no.
'Hey. I am sure there would be
a store room for old files.'
'Go and look for it there.'
Abhi. What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Abhi. Abhi, calm down. Calm down.
Move away. Move.
Taxi. Taxi. Stop! Stop.
Grand hotel.
Yes, Rupam. Yes. How was it?
Sumit. Hang up.
- What are you doing?
One minute, mother.
What are you doing?
No. Hang up now. Right now.
What sort of deep friendship is this?
It is a holiday and you have not taken
a bath or eaten anything.
And you are stuck on
the phone for so long.
Sumit. Father will be waiting
for us without eating.
Okay. I am hanging up.
I will talk to you later.
Who is this friend of yours? What
do you talk to him about all the time?
Rupam. Mother, he is my new friend.
Who is Rupam?
Yes, sir.
Anjan Sen. Room number 105.
Sir, just a minute.
And I thrashed him very hard.
Rupam held me from behind.
Even I held Rupam
and made him fall down.
And I thrashed him very hard.
You have started fighting with people?
Father told me to do so.
But now, Rupam and I are friends.
Father told you to get into a fight?
Yes. Exactly.
Wait. I will be back.
Since he is not here,
call him on his phone.
9831060805.
Please.
- This facility is only for the guests here, sir.
This is a five star hotel.
It isn't a PCO.
THE OBEROI GRAND.
Hello. How are you? I am fine.
Yes.
Grandfather has called.
I am on my way back from PG, Apu.
There was no case registered on
the name of Nandini Sanyal yesterday.
And he hasn't collected his bag
from the police station as well.
Father. I think Anjan has come back.
My God.
I am going to his office.
Please reach there.
Take care.
- Yes.
What is it, Dipankar?
Why are you sitting here?
Now...
Sorry. Actually I have got
a promotion, sister-in-law.
And Abhi?
What is this? You don't even have
a semblance of injury on your body.
Meaning?
Didn't Abhi and you meet
with a taxi accident?
Abhi was with you last night, right?
Answer me. Tell me whether he was with you or not.
He...
He was with me.
What shall I do now, father?
I am brave.
I am a progressive and strong person.
I am like a storm and I am a cyclone.
I destroy everything that comes my way.
I am ferocious.
I am like an ailment.
I am like the fearless earth.
I finish all the evils
that come in my way.
I am full of rage and
impatient all the time.
I am the rebel king Bhrigu.
I have the courage
to step on God's chest.
I am the eternal warrior...
...who will always live
with his head held high.
Get up, friend.
Father. Anjan is back!
My God!
Where will I look for
him in such a big city?
Going by the graph, you should probably
look for him where Dipankar is.
Why aren't you taking
the matter seriously?
Officer.
You better put your act together.
Or else,
there can be a very bad incident.
You better act now.
Who is it?
Abhi.
Have you just watched the movie Batman?
Where is the file, Dipu?
My God.
You have watched a movie
and have consumed alcohol as well?
Where is the file, Dipu dear?
Give me way.
There is point of speaking rubbish.
Hey, tell me. Where is the file?
Why are you getting scared?
Tell me. Tell me.
Scared. Of you?
Tell me. Where is the file?
I have made it vanish.
What will you do?
Anjan.
Because of this man,
I have been able to turn from...
...a coward to a proper man. Right?
You should give him a medal.
You are too drunk.
- Yes.
Go home and go off to sleep.
Thrash the fool. Thrash him.
No, no. The file is in the wardrobe
storage of my house.
I will give it back to you.
- Keep quiet, fool.
But please forgive me.
So who is this friend, Anjan Sen,
in reality?
Oh no. How many times should I tell you?
He doesn't exist.
It is his imagination.
Anjan. The lorry is waiting.
Let us go!
Just as he made your file vanish...
...make this fool vanish from the world.
Have you ever heard of
a mental condition called Schizophrenia?
Abhiroop suffers from it.
He was my patient at one point of time.
I know him.
This can have different
effect on various people.
But in this case, whenever Abhiroop
is disturbed or depressed...
...he needs a support system.
And in case of Abhiroop,
Anjan becomes his support system.
He is a completely fictional character.
But for Abhiroop, he is a living being.
A walking,
talking, laughing human being.
And it started when his parents died
because of a motor accident.
Leave me.
Abhi, leave me.
Abhi. Abhi.
Oh my God. Abhi, please leave me. Abhi.
No, no. Don't do this.
I am asking for forgiveness.
I am leaving, friend.
We shall meet again.
A small kid used to
come on time every day.
And yet, he couldn't
stand ahead in the queue.
Why?
Just because the other
boy is more powerful.
What was the need?
What was the need
to steal the office file?
Yes?
What was the need? Tell me.
And bothering an
innocent girl like that?
Take revenge.
Do away with goodness.
There is no place
for decency in this society.
If you want to live
with your head held high...
...you have to live life on your terms.
I don't need anyone.
I will live life on my own terms.
With my head held high.
Hey, check the situation. The one who
cannot give respect to my wife and child...
...will be finished off.
I will finish him off.
- Abhi!
Move away. Get away from me.
Don't touch me. Go away. Not at all.
- Please go and inform the headquarters.
Hey.
I don't need people who cannot
give respect to me. Get lost.
Aren't you scared?
- What should I be scared of?
They are the thieves.
They should be scared.
Go. Go away from me. I will
finish off everything. Everything.
He dared to cheat me?
I taught him a lesson.
Get away from me. Move away.
Come on.
Why are you laughing?
Keep quiet.
Abhi.
- Yes?
Don't laugh at all. Keep quiet.
You are still laughing?
I am telling you. Keep quiet.
Where can I find you?
Tell me the room number.
105.
Yes. Tell me.
- 98310.
60805.
So I command a lot of respect
in your house, right?
A lot more than me.
Hey, you forgot? Hey, our Madhu!
What does she do these days?
She is in Kolkata.
She has a restaurant business.
Are you coming home tomorrow?
What is it?
Why didn't you come to the hotel?
And you?
The son of a swine.
Let him come in front of me.
Wow.
I can see that my Royal Bengal tiger
has come alive.
You are the real Royal Bengal Tiger.