For viewers over 12 years of age.
RUSSIAN SOCIETY
HISTORICAL AND MILITARY
REAL-DAKOTA INTERFIEST
It was May, 1942.
In the west, on gray nights
you could hear the sounds of artillery,
Both sides buried in the ground by 2 meters
holding your positions firmly
they finally stopped in trench warfare.
In the east, the Germans bombed day and night
the canal and the Kirov main railway line.
In the afternoon, they waged persistent fights
blocked Leningrad.
There was a resort here.
Several farms were saved at the 181st junction
on a long line of earth.
The Germans did it from time to time
over the turnout and command
just in case it kept there
two anti-aircraft stands.
Kumo!
Do you plant potatoes?
I will drink your Wasia, live!
I still have to work for these apples!
In my garden, when he comes back ...
SO SILENT HERE AT DUSK ...
Based on the novel
Boris Vasiliev
Due to silence and laziness, soldiers quartered
they had a sauna here.
There was enough left in twelve houses
young virgins and widows,
who can make a moonshine
almost from the humming noise.
Three days, the soldiers slept asleep, they watched,
and on the fourth someone's name day began,
and over the junction
the smell of local moonshine did not dissipate ...
Fiedot Yevgraficz!
- Fedot Yevgraficz!
Don't make noise! ​​What happened?
Again...
Stop it! Enough!
Narrator
SIERGIEJ GARMASZ
So what, WaЬkow?
You'll be reprimanded.
And back to the front, away from that nonsense.
Send non-drinkers ...
Hey, non-drinkers ...
Two teams, nearly 20 people, non-drinkers.
Even if you search the entire front - you also doubt ...
Send those who do not drink, and that ...
As for the women ...
Maybe you want eunuchs?
I do not know. Superiors know better.
- We will finish the enemy and right at you!
Yes, I know your soon ...
When I get there, please write ...
Okay, WaЬkow, get the non-drinkers.
And as for women too ... It will ...
But this time, watch out, Sergeant,
and you can't cope with them ...
Pluto, to the carts!
Sergeant, we'll meet after the war!
Higher nose, Yevgraficz!
Tomorrow I will bring new ones.
Maybe a week.
What about you?
Your army ... has arrived.
Finally.
The second day, a turnout without defense.
Have they come with the commander?
I don't like it.
And praise God ...
Because I'm already worried.
To enjoy too early ...
Collector!
Come on! Attention!
Comrade Sergeant. First team
third platoon of the fifth company,
an independent air defense battalion
came under your command to protect the facility.
The team commissioner, Sergeant Keryanov, reports.
So they found ... non-drinkers.
Anti-aircraft guns, by the way,
they lived after cha│ups ...
We're not an anti-aircraft gun.
We're anti-aircraft guns.
Or maybe more correctly recruits?
Who was fighting besides you?
You insult us, Comrade Sergeant,
we are under fire.
Junior Sergeant Osjanin,
how many are you targeting?
Too little ... for now.
What is your name
Private Bryczkin.
Jelizaveta.
Are you from the village?
Yes. This is.
I see ...
Take an example of how to use the tools.
Where are you from?
We are from Siberia.
From over the Yenisei.
Yeah...
A country not close ...
Why are you here?
Can't you see I'm deploying staff?
- Because ... borscht is ready.
What about borscht?
It will cool down.
By the way, Comrade Sergeant -
take care of the room ...
What room?
No bushes can be seen nearby ...
Higher Gray ...
We're out of luck, girls.
One boy and his lap is full.
Sure they lived after the chaos
and he with the hostess on the stove.
It's not true!
Girls, we have a crush on our Briczkina!
Dushka fell in love with a soldier ...
Poor Lisa!
LYSE BRICZKIN
The whole life of Lisa Briczkina
She lived in anticipation of tomorrow.
Where!
Here - I told you!
She waited every morning
impatiently happy.
The more that the life situation
she postponed the meeting
with this Christmas happiness for tomorrow.
They didn't kill her, they didn't destroy her,
but they only translated.
Even when together with the family
they were called the enemies of the Soviet power,
they took a house, a farm,
and with thousands of such boys,
they sent the ku│akєw to Siberia,
even then it didn't kill her faith
to the bright happiness of tomorrow.
Eastern Siberia, February 1941
So was her childhood.
What do you want?
what, boring?
Boring.
I left your father's address.
You will come in the summer, send you to a technical college.
You will die here.
And stupidity ... no need to do,
even out of boredom.
You can go.
Will you take a lift to the city?
Get in the back, girl ... Get in!
Next time try to be earlier.
His eyes are full of eyesight.
Is waiting for you...
Well.
He will wake up in the morning
you are not here and he gets nervous ...
Cє┐ ...
Watch out there!
Hфnde hoch!
What if it was Germany?
Where does Germany come from, Comrade Sergeant?
- Belts ...
What?
Photo belts!
Three days in arrest for violation
front zone discipline.
Yes...
One must knock, comrade Sergeant -
it's not your home or your barracks.
what is this?
You do not recognize?
You expose.
There is an order.
What order?
Suitable.
Female soldiers were allowed to dry out
underwear on all fronts.
The commander-in-chief personally ordered.
Have you not heard?
Damn it...
This spring, Fedot Yevgrafich
are 32 years old.
Until then, you considered your life successful.
Despite his incomplete four classes
he graduated from a punch school
and reached the rank of sergeant.
FIEDOT WASKOW
To marry a nurse from the garrison hospital,
who bore him a baby ...
And that's when the Finnish war began,
WaЬkow went to the front.
Sortawa│a, December 1939.
And after hurting,
when I was in the hospital,
His wife cheated on him with a punch vet
and went south.
Fiedot divorced her, and the boy
picked up through a court
and sent to my mother in the countryside.
And after a year his son died.
Since then, WaЬkow has smiled
only three times.
To the general who gave him the award,
to the surgeon who took out the bullet
and to his landlady, Maria Nikiforowna,
for default.
Come on!
Cannon for battle!
Azimuth 270.
- Distance 3000.
- It's 3000.
- Height 2500.
- It's 2500.
guess.
Ready.
Short! Fire!
Azimuth 290.
Distance 2500.
guess.
Ready.
guess! Load faster!
- Nadia!
drinking?
You what ...
- Azimuth 320. Altitude 2900.
- It's 2900.
Distance 3400.
Shoot!
Cheeky girls!
Look, the pilot pops out ...
Leave it alone, Rita. You won't hit him
don't waste any ammo.
Loaded.
- Stop it!
Who?
What didobi│aЬ?
I will give you to the tribunal!
RITA OSJANINA
comrade major ...
I know...
A shot down plane, whose job?
- Commander of the second unit,
junior sergeant of Osjanin
Zuch, Osjanina.
It's a pity you didn't catch the Live Pilot.
I would ask him what he is doing in your area.
Maybe off course ...
Okay, take the supplement.
The woman at the front, you understand
it is an object of constant attention ...
There are times when you can't stand it ...
what do you mean?
One staff commander,
Married, by the way,
found a friend.
A member of the Military Council found out about this.
Show me that friend
and you asked me to arrange it
good collective.
do you have a good collective here?
I understand.
Will you let me go, Comrade Major?
Go away.
Commander of Osjanin's unit.
Private Gurwicz ..
Private Czerwiertak.
Private Komilkov.
FIREWORKS
MOSCOW
May-41
Oh, my are here ...
- Congratulations, Dad!
Stalin handed over in person?
Yes - and my hand shook it.
And pass it on. Meet each other, Alexei -
my daughter Evgenia.
Do not trust the angelic appearance -
there is a devil inside.
пeniu - this is Lieutenant Lieutenant Guin.
We fought together in the Finnish war.
пenia ... He is married.
A new city, a whole new life ...
Good morning.
Hello.
Equivalent!
Attention!
Comrades Soldiers - For Your Courage
during the battle ...
I was ordered to advertise in the garrison
bathing day.
Extraordinary.
пenia, you are like a Russian!
Your skin is transparent.
Poor woman - yes a figure
wrapped in uniform ...
She is beautiful.
Beautiful and rarely happy.
Are you talking about yourself?
Sleeping, you can walk without a bra.
Oh no...
Beautiful underwear is my weakness.
Only a sergeant
I can't resist.
(But it will stop!)
Nobody can resist such a beauty.
(Oh, it will stop!)
Beauty, Ga│ka - is the work of human hands.
Make you a beauty today!
We wrinkle the sweatshirt where it needs to be
and you won't be able to take your eyes off!
If you want, take care of you.
I was kidding about the sergeant, kidding ...
Take it if you want.
Sleep, take care of me.
Press the sergeant today -
let it warm up!
and me!
- Come on!
Shame...
Yes Rita? Let me gossip ... this is some activity ...
And fall in love as you like,
I won't say a word.
But to annoy someone for no reason -
I don't understand this.
Do not understand?
Why don't you tell me where you run at night?
Sleep, why don't you sing something?
Girls, Penia knows so many songs ...
My mom, sister, brother ...
They all killed with a machine gun.
Was there a warning?
Shooting ...
The commander's family caught up -
and a machine gun ...
And I managed to hide
in the house next door.
I've seen everything ...
penia ...
And the colonel?
How could you?
Cє┐ I could!
I can ...
Red Sio
staff of the 11 rifle division.
September 1941.
Staц.
Comrade Colonel,
delivered detained.
Who is this?
Who knows, Maybe a spy, Or maybe ...
penia!
Now you're gonna raise me
or later, after a tip?
Comrade Sergeant!
What do you want?
what happened
- Germany is in the forest!
How do you know?
I saw it for myself.
Two, with vending machines.
In camouflage uniforms ...
Makaricz was killed.
Ah yes...
Declare combat readiness.
Kerjanov to me! Run!
Pine!
His maц ... пre or Ьpi ...
Pine, I'm listening.
- Says the 17th. Give me a third!
- Come on now! It's urgent!
Don't yell! Urgent ...
is that you, WaЬkow?
- Yes, comrade the third!
what's up
- Germany is in the woods near position!
We discovered them today, two in number.
Who will discover?
Junior Sergeant Osjanin.
I sounded the alarm, comrade third.
I thought to comb the forest.
How did they look? Your Germany ...
Masked, he says, with vending machines.
Probably the saboteurs!
Take five people from the squad
and shoot my feet the trace will not cool down!
Yes, comrade third!
So on this path you met them?
Here. They walked past me
towards the road.
and backpacks, you say, they had?
Yes, on the back.
I think TNT was good.
And since they are carrying loads, they can
the highway is not their goal.
On the railroad.
On the Kirovskaya railway road, I mean ...
An enemy has been located nearby,
in the number of two.
Our task to catch up with the enemy,
and taken captive.
In extreme cases, kill.
Junior Sergeant Osjanin.
Step forward.
Choose four soldiers
from his branch.
Komilkov's soldier.
I am.
a soldier four-drill.
That's enough.
We will be Lapats to Germany, not fish.
Take those that can shoot.
I can shoot.
Father taught me.
Briczkin's soldier.
One more thing ... Maybe someone knows German?
I.
What is this "me"? What does "I" mean?
You have to register.
soldier Gurwicz.
Maybe someone else knows?
- How will it be "hands up"?
- Hфnde hoch!
Exactly ...
Let it be Gurwicz.
Cє┐, at least we won't get wet.
All take off your shoes.
I ordered nothing.
At least it's good not to undress ...
Gadu│y ...
Yes...
With such onucami, after three kilometers
you rub your legs to blood.
Yes, clean your weapons
onuce humanly sewn ...
Who needs to be taught!
Get in order and get ready.
Get ammunition and packed lunch
for two days.
40 minutes for everything.
Perform.
Are you from the city?
You can see ...
Okay, I must write, obligatory!
SONIA GURWICZ
Minsk, October 1940
Good morning.
Sonia!
... Today at 4 am,
without a declaration of war,
german army
attacked our borders
in many places...
Sonia, let's go soon.
I was afraid you would not come ...
For cars!
It's B│ok.
I marked there in the book ...
Goodbye, Sonia ...
It is mandatory to write.
Sonia did not receive his letter.
He died at the end of October from
all your companions,
in the composition of one of Moscow
the mass-launch division
in the circle of WiaЯm╣.
So yes ... Listen to me.
A replacement for the duration of the operation
I appointed a younger Sergeant Osjaninъ.
If an enemy is detected,
or something unclear ...
Who can imitate an animal or a bird?
I am seriously asking!
In a forest, information cannot be given with a voice.
Germany has ears too.
I can.
Like a donkey.
Osw a lot ...
Okay, let's get quacks.
Like ducks.
This is how the drake calls the female.
- You speak well!
The signals will be as follows:
twice: ATTENTION - I see the enemy.
Three times - everyone to me. Sure?
For me.
WaЬkow realized that
That if the target of the Germans
there is a diversion on the Kirov railway line -
one of the most important transport arteries,
which was delivered from the Allies to the front ...
This stopping them isn't just that
task of local importance.
A turn to Lake Wope, which was discovered by WaЬkow
still during the Finnish war
The Germans could not know
there were only swamps on the maps.
So the Germans had a turn
only one way.
To the lake via Siniuchin╣ │╣kъ.
And it was impossible for them to miss those little marks.
Well, the Germans are marching.
Very good, even.
About 40 km.
Come on ...
Your father and mother live somewhere,
are you an orphan
I am an orphan.
You could say an orphan ...
You're not sure yourself?
And Who Is Sure Now, Comrade Sergeant?
You're right.
My parents are in Minsk, I studied in Moscow,
I was preparing for the session.
and suddenly...
Do you have a photo?
What are you guys?
Parents are hesitating?
Naturally.
Naturally?
If it were natural, I wouldn't be asking.
Sonia did not know
and she couldn't know
That her mother, Wiera Josifowna Gurwicz,
at that time she was wearing
on the chest the ╣thъ starъ
and the number soulless number of the camp
Little Trostiniec.
Neither her father nor her sister
She was no longer alive.
Maybe they got lost?
Private Gurwicz,
acidify three times.
Why?
To check combat readiness.
Did you forget how I taught?
No, I have not forgotten.
what happened
If anything happened ...
The Archangels would already be you
in that world they greeted.
You run like calves.
With a raised tail ...
What did you see along the way?
Gray order: younger sergeant Osjanin ...
Probably nothing ... She was at the turn
z│aman╣ ga│╣Я.
Bravo. Truth.
Closing?
I didn't notice anything.
Everything's fine.
Dew is knocked off the bushes.
On the left he is holding
but on the right it fell off the road.
They are eyes!
Bravo the Red Army officer Briczkina.
And there were still two tracks on the way,
German shoe
what their paratroopers wear.
Judging by the tracks,
I want to circle around the marshes.
And let's go.
Because we'll take these swamps to pass.
Now you can smoke
from 15 minutes.
Who needs it can improve.
Quietly! And don't diverge!
Yes. The route is dangerous.
The order of movement will be as follows:
I am first, followed by Gurwicz,
Briczkin, Komilków, Czetwiertak.
Junior sergeant Osjanin closes up.
Are there any questions?
Deep there?
Sometimes it happens ...
To you ...
Waist, I mean ...
Watch out for rifles.
Mud gas comes out.
We moved it ...
People like that
incredible things tell ...
they are fairy tales, of course
Are the leeches here?
There is nothing here.
Dead place ...
And above him we ...
Comrade Sergeant,
my shoe will fall off my leg!
Damn it...
Found?
No.
We must iЬц.
How without shoes?
How do you find him now?
Come on! Go ahead, follow me.
Don't stay.
Stay on the path, don't move!
- Help her!
Stop it! There is no going back!
Easy easy!
Not much left to the island.
We will rest there.
Drive.
Further it will be easier.
We'll get to the dry birch and take it easy.
How will I be without the shoe?
we made up something.
But already beyond the swamp.
Will you hold out?
It's cold, girls.
I'm all wet.
Do you think I'm dry?
I have a drink once and for all ...
Well, comrades soldiers ...
We take paths and follow me,
in the same order.
Leave them here.
A little more, comrade Red Army,
make an effort.
A little further, we will rest at the waterfall.
Well, comrade Red Army,
everything okay?
Everything is all right, Comrade Sergeant.
Are you not frozen?
There is no one to warm us to anyway.
And how? It's good?
Even a lot. Thank youъ
Comrade Sergeant.
Come on, comrade soldiers.
We still have an hour and a half to get there.
How quiet it is!
As in Ьnie.
From the left
Sinjuchina │╣ka begins.
On the other hand, another lake
It goes hand in hand with this.
His name is Leguntowo.
There used to be a monk here.
His name was Legun.
What elusive are you looking for here ...
It's full of ...
Germany has only one way between
lakes, through │╣ki.
We'll wait for them here.
Before we can come, we need to find the positions.
Main and spare - as prescribed by the regulations.
We will choose and we will wait.
Obey a combat order.
A row of up to two
armed with Fryc's teeth
moves in the Lake Wope region in order
reaching the Kirov railway line
and the Bia│omorsko-Baltic canal,
name of comrade Stalin.
Our branch, in the amount of 6 people,
ordered to defend │╣kъ Sinjuchin,
where we are to take the enemy captive.
Neighbor on the left - Lake Wope,
neighbor on the right - Lake Leguntowo.
Questions?
Please go to position.
Maybe we are sitting for nothing?
I doubt ...
That's what I mean - if those Frycw
not confused with tree stumps.
You can sleep, comrade sergeant.
Wake you up at dawn.
Come on with this sleeping, Osjanina.
We will have eternal sleep
if Frycєw we sleep.
Well, maybe they're sleeping now?
Fedot Yevgraficz?
Мpi╣ ...
Cє┐, Yes.
These are people too.
You said yourselves that │╣ka Sinjuchina
this is the only possible transition to the railroad.
There is no other ...
Wait Osjanin ...
Hold on.
We walked from fifty kilometers ...
But in an unknown place
every bush is terrible.
Are you thinking right?
Yes, Comrade Sergeant.
And if so, it might be safe
resting somewhere right now.
And I'll fall until the sun.
Shall we smoke, Comrade Rita?
Don't smoke.
Yes ... It's like ...
The fact that these are also like people ...
I didn't understand that a bit.
Okay you said - I need to rest.
You, too, rest.
Go look at the items.
How's it going, Briczkina
Didn't you notice anything?
quiet for now.
Watch everything.
Do the bushes move,
do the birds fear anything?
You are a man From the woods, you understand everything.
I understand.
What, Jelizaweta, did you work in the camp?
No. Mostly I was helping my father.
He is a forester, we lived in the forest.
At least you quiver well.
Lisa, Lisa, Lisawieta,
why don't you like me
Why don't you sing to me -
not suitable for you? "
There is a chant in our pages.
And here they sang ...
Later we will sing, Jelizawiec.
We'll follow our orders, then we'll sing.
Do you promise?
I did say.
Be careful, comrade sergeant.
You promised me.
Born in difficult years
We don't remember our way.
We - children of Russia's terrible years
We cannot forget anything.
Fingers for the ashes of summer!
Is there hope in you?
From the days of war, from the days of freedom ... "
Who are you reading to?
Anyone. Myself.
Why out loud?
They are poems.
You spoil your eyes.
It is clear, Comrade Sergeant.
I at all ...
Don't sit on stones.
They will cool down quickly and will be pulled on
you are warm. You won't notice.
Put on a stick.
All right, Comrade Sergeant. Thank you.
And don't read aloud.
At night, the air is thick, humid ...
Quiet here at dusk
five kilometers away.
Watch.
Watch, ┐o│nierz Gurwicz.
Dyed?
Natural.
Cluttered.
Nothing, Nothing, fix it.
Comrade Sergeant, are you married?
I am married, soldier of Komilków.
Where is your wife?
You know where ... At home.
Do you have children?
Kids...
You were a boy ...
How was it?
He died.
Just before the war.
Died?
Yes.
There was no one to watch.
She feels like ... she has abandoned us.
Why did you curl up like this, comrade soldier?
It is cold.
Yes, you got wet.
Show my forehead.
You have temperature, comrade soldier.
You feel?
It's because of the swamp ...
And the shoe is lost.
So you take it to drink.
what is this?
Mixture.
Hold on.
- Potion ... Spirit!
Spirit, Yes. and what?
No, I won't be five.
Carry out the order.
And immediately water ...
What are you saying, my mom
is a medical worker.
Mom is not here.
War is ...
And Germany is. Mom will be with those
who survived the war.
Are you clear?
Drink!
Don't inhale. You have.
Something like escaped my head ...
That `s nothing. You'll catch up tomorrow.
Rest, comrade soldier.
And you? Yes, without a coat?
Don't be afraid, I'm healthy.
Light up and get warm ...
It's okay ... Get well.
Mom is gone.
War is ...
And Germany is. Mother will be with those
who survived the war.
GALIA CZETWIERTAK
What about moj╣ Gal╣?
Gala!
- Rita!
What?
Quiet, quiet ...
Hear that?
The birds screamed.
Magpies. The magpies are awake, Rita.
Someone disturbed them.
Looks like we have guests.
GoЯ, Osjanina, housing the soldiers.
Quick but easy.
lest they get scared.
And he translates to me!
Good morning, Comrade Sergeant
Hi.
How's Czetwiertak?
Мpi.
We decided not to wake her up.
Correct decision.
I will be in range of your voice.
But don't show yourself.
He did not show himself.
Come on...
Come on ...
Here they are.
Both. Two.
Three.
Four...
Five ...
Six.
Seven eight...
Nine, ten ...
Eleven, twelve ...
fourteen, fifteen.
Sixteen.
Sixteen!
Comrade Sergeant,
There were two of them.
It was ...
I mean, these two were just scouting.
Gurwicz, listen.
Send me Briczkin, just quietly.
Crawl, comrade translator!
Life depends on it, do you understand?
Comrade Sergeant,
Comrade Sergeant ...
What about you?
Smile, Briczkina.
It is even better that it is theirs
sixteen, not two.
We would look for two in the forest,
oh yes they are here!
Way back Do you remember well?
Yes, Comrade Sergeant.
Listen, the Germans have left the pine forest.
You'll go there, and then along the lake.
where we have cut the bars.
Cheek girl. From there you will go
to the stream. Won't you get lost?
No, comrade Sergeant.
No. So fast, Yelisawto.
The swamp is the most important.
The road is narrow.
Step left, right, there will be a problem.
Landmark - birch.
Then two pines,
that are on the island.
Rest a bit there,
don't go right away.
Yes: weapons, backpack, bags - everything
leave here. You'll come faster.
Report the situation to Kerijanov.
We'll take some Germans,
but we can do it too long, you know ...
So ... Now I have iЬц?
Yes...
Don't forget to tense in front of the swamps.
So run ...
PъdЯ, Jelizawieta.
Ple is, girls.
Пle ...
There are sixteen of them,
and sixteen machines are power.
You will not stop such a force in front of you,
We can't forgive either ...
And I'll be here in an hour or two
I think so ...
How are you feeling
I'm fine. I slept well.
I sent Briczkina to the quarters.
We can count on support before the night.
Not before.
If we start fighting them,
we won't make it through the night.
We will not stop at any positions.
So what? Are we supposed to watch you go by?
We can't let them pass
straight on through │╣kъ.
You have to beat them off the course.
Let it come in a circle.
Directing around the Leguntowo lake.
But how?
Of course they didn't come here
to fight.
In this case, please be careful
to slip silently ...
So they must see us.
And that we didn't notice them ....
Then maybe I'll go somewhere else
and try elsewhere.
Another place is around Lake Leguntowo -
one day's march.
But who should I show them? Mustache?
Or yourself?
Stop, scout out.
And find out there are only five of us.
If for an hour, a half
we won't come up with anything else ...
Comrade Sergeant, what if?
came across lumberjacks?
What woodcutters? There is a war
the forests are empty, you just saw ...
now women are cutting forests.
Women...
It is true...
Forest workers work in brigades.
Look for them there in that bush.
You can't kill everyone
one shot.
And if you miss one
everything will tell who needs ...
Cє┐ girls
the eagle is mine!
Comrade Sergeant,
Comrade Sergeant!
Here come!
Help me.
Further...
On your seats, girls.
Komilkowa, for me!
Shout louder.
Maybe they escaped?
Maybe they escaped ...
Or maybe not.
They are not green either ...
They don't send just anyone for such a job.
Wait ...
I see ...
Recon.
Count us on your fingers.
Take care of them ...
This is probably a stupid idea.
But you girls ... maybe even ...
... you will be able to escape.
Stєj!
Raja, Wiera, go and have a bath.
If you don't want to ...
It is not!
Girls, get bathed!
Call Ivan!
Hey, Vaniusz, where are you?
Goъ!
Let's go!
- Wait a minute!
- And wait for me!
Who will work?
Goъ, goъ!
Where are you
Hear that?
Who will be working, I ask?
Come on over here.
Turn off. Ah you ...
They called from the area
the car is coming soon.
Enough, get out.
Get out, he said.
Enough, I order you to leave.
Get out! That's enough.
Give me a hand!
Go out, go out, play with fire ...
Come on, come on, go on, go!
Go ...
OK...
Now girls ...
Now we have no place to go.
If Briczkina, of course
support will not bring ...
Will bring.
In that case, let's drink a little ...
To her fast legs.
And your bright heads.
Look...
This is the culture of the Germans ...
They wanted coffee.
Why do you think so?
I can smell rum ...
So they stopped for breakfast.
But are all sixteen?
We have to count them, Margarita.
Who hasn't gone ...
12 people, two on guard.
So they're all here.
These two went on scouting.
They stood for a long time.
Dry the linen.
It's about time - we can change
our items, Margarita.
I have a little look around at the rocks.
And you and the girls are going
to the spare position.
Just quiet.
I understand.
Wait!
I spread the tobacco there to dry, take it away.
And my clothes, of course.
I will take, Fedota Yevgraficz.
Did you bring the pouch?
I forgot ...
Fiedota Yevgraficz, dear ...
I don't ... Okay ...
Well there ...
The smaller of machork╣ ...
At least you didn't forget your backpack?
Bring it! I know where it is.
- Yep, Soldier Gurwicz! Comrade translator!
Private Gurwicz shouted.
Komilkow for me.
Remain here to wait!
Germany...
Not good...
Not good.
That's why she screamed.
Hit inaccurately, must have been tall.
He missed the heart the first time.
Her breast interrupted.
Pole┐ here, Sonieczko ...
Get some rest.
They're here somewhere.
Here they are.
Stay here and when I pass by
occupy them with something.
Stone, ga│ъzi╣ -
as long as they don't see you.
I'll take care of them. Understand?
I understand.
Zuch, Komilkowa.
I am thankful to you.
Now ... Two already ... less left.
Leave me alone ...
You have to get used to it, drink ...
To lose your soul.
Here and the grown men suffer seriously.
And understand one thing ...
These aren't people.
Not men, not even animals ...
They are fascists!
And draw the appropriate conclusions.
You will find our Sam?
Find.
Go. Go to Sonia.
Don't wait long there,
later we will cry ...
Only no hysteria.
She was an exemplary student ...
Perfect in everything.
Both at school and at the university ...
Most importantly, there are no children
that would be sad ...
Neither my own nor someone else's ...
Now they won't be ...
A chain of generations ...
They cut it.
We will mark on the map.
And after the war, we will erect a monument!
what is this?
Boots.
I will not.
Why are you doing this?
because we have a barefoot soldier.
- Don't!
These are not good things, girls ...
In war, there is only one rule -
you have to think only of the living.
- Assume, order!
You can't ...
My mother is a medical worker ...
Stop lying. You don't have a mother.
And never did.
I read your papers.
You're an orphan - Don't be confused.
Why are you doing this?
Why?
Don't be malicious.
Otherwise, we will become bitter.
We will be as mean as the Germans!
They hurt?
That `s nothing. Scratch.
Thank you, younger sergeant.
For what?
In the second you gave me
to change the magazine.
From that moment to the grave cover
we will ride five together.
Comrade Sergeant, are you a communist?
Yes, what?
Please become president
our Komsomo meeting.
What meeting? For what?
Cowardice.
Begging...
That's good.
It's great...
Begging...
So let's not delay.
We will judge companion.
We'll make a protocol ... Yes?
And then Germany, our protocol
approved their resolution.
Therefore, as a sergeant
and as a communist ...
I cancel all meetings at this time.
Is it clear?
As for cowardice -
it wasn't him.
Cowardice only in the second fight
going out, girls.
And this is a mistake, a lack of experience ...
Right, Soldier Czetwiertak?
That's right ...
So I order you to wipe your nose and tears.
But using ours
stop, girls ...
Germany will not wait.
I can escape to the forest, look for them there ...
And that means we have to get on their tail ...
To recognize the situation.
War is not only about who will shoot whom,
but who will outsmart whom.
Wait here.
Shot in the back by his own.
They finished off the wounded.
You see, they have such a right.
Let's count ...
We took care of two there, Gala.
Two here. Should stay 12.
And it's not scary for us anymore
it's a trifle.
Comrade Sergeant!
- Fedot Yevgraficz!
- Comrade Sergeant!
What are you girls ...
Easy easy...
sucks your sister sisters ...
Five heroines like brothers.
Tell Fiedot ...
And Gala?
Our comrades have fallen ...
Death of the brave ...
Quadruple in a shootout.
Lisa Briczkina drowned in the swamp.
So together with Sonia,
We've already lost three ...
This is what it looks like.
For this price, we delayed the whole day
enemy from the lake. Day!
There is nothing here ...
Have you lost something?
The igniter has no ...
You were unnecessarily removed ...
Without a fuse, a grenade is a piece of iron.
So we were left without artillery, girls ...
it's Nothing, Comrade Sergeant.
We'll manage!
Hear me, comrades soldiers,
my order.
Wrєg, armed to the teeth,
is heading in our direction.
There are no neighbors on the right,
on the left also.
Therefore I command all soldiers ...
And hold the front personally!
Hold on to the last drop of blood!
Because there is Russia behind our backs ...
And this is simply our homeland!
There will be no help.
We have to come here bh ...
Probably the last ...
Here come! To the positions!
The sun ...
Give me the bandages!
Bandages to make the blood of the village ...
There is no.
Cholera...
GoЯ ...
Rita, it's nothing like that.
The shard passed right through.
Hey you guys!
Run away ...
chasing them to the forest ...
Reptiles ...
Hello...
Reptiles!
penia ... immediately ... she died?
There are no backpacks, no rifles ...
They took with them or hid ...
But they didn't beat us, you understand ?!
I'm still alive
I need to be knocked down yet!
Hurts?
Nothing hurts me.
Here it hurts ...
There's a wound here, Rita.
Yes, my dear...
I consecrated you.
I sacrificed all five.
for what? For ten Fryce?
Why so?
Everything is clear - There is a war.
It is known - war, of course ...
And then, how will there be peace?
It will be clear why you have come to perish?
Why didn't I let Frycom take over?
Why did I make a decision too?
What to say, Rita?
When they ask why our boys
did they not protect their mothers from the bullets?
Why are you married to Death,
and themselves alive and healthy? ...
We wanted to protect the Kirov bus
Bie│omorskie canal!
And there's security there too,
more people than five girls ...
- ... and a sergeant with a gun.
There's no need to...
Motherland Mother ...
It was for her ...
And we protected her.
First of all her.
And then the channels ...
My last request.
Will you fill it?
Take, two bullets left.
Be calmer.
And I'll go and look around.
I'll be back by evening.
And at night we will get to our own people.
Do you remember when I met Germans ...
I run to my mother, to the city ...
I have a son there.
One and a half years old, Alik ...
Albert, her name is.
My mom is very ill...
Don't worry, Rita.
I understood everything.
Kiss me ...
You are ...
Come on ...
On the groundъ! Everyone on the groundъ!
What? Have you defeated us? Yes?!
Five girls ...
There were five girls, there were only five!
And you didn't pass!
You didn't get anywhere,
and you will die here!
You will all die!
Personally, kill everyone!
Even if the command doesn't forgive,
and then judge me ...
Let me judge!
WeЯ ...
Comrade Sergeant ...
Comrade Sergeant!
Fedot Yevgrafich ...
They brought a supplement.
PIOTR FIODOROW
ANASTASIJA MIKULCHINA
JEWGIENIA MAGAACHOWA
KRISTINA ASMUS
AGNIA KUZNIECOWA
SOFIA LIEBIEDIEWA
BIOGKÓW JEKATERINE
ANATOLY BIEGYJ
DARIA MOROZ
WIKTOR PROSKURIN
ALIEKSIEJ I. BARABASZ
MAXIMUM WAY
OLGA GOMONOSOWA