Based on a true story
First edition
blood sand and gold
1990 August
Iraq's Saddam Hussein
Leading an army of 12
million invaded Quetta
Controlled the
nation within a short time
Iraq who ignored
the public's objection
refuse to retreat
With United
States as the leader
multinational
joint army of 50 million
Near Quetta's borders rapidly
After new year of 1991 January
with the retreating
deadline getting nearer
Under such
critical condition
Japan accepted the invitation to
join the arm forces from U.S.
Pressured under the
no. 19 statutory law
Get out
Dear Lily Alice
boycott you
Classy
But how do you
want me to help you
If you didn't
sleep with that woman
Alright looks like we
took some advertisement papers
With her pants
begged her not to
get involve in this
Alright alright
Take good care of Beck
And bring me some good stuffs
I'll take care of everything
Thank you for calling me
After that
If we go
according to my instincts
from 80 billion
dollars to 100 billions dollars
If its one of us
then say 90 billion
90 billion dollars
easy for you to say
No I didn't say that
the Washington suggested it
40 billion dollar was added
last year have you forgotten
Total there's 130 billion
what do you want
me to tell the people
Good tea
If you're really networking
Networking'? You can't
say this is networking
What do you mean
Japan will not send their army
The opponent knows
about this weakness
So you can't bargain anymore
For democracy
and help them fight
is the youngsters' mission
Its because of statutory law
no. 19 that we...
The other party
should know very well
But they insist that
backup is possible
Of course they're
not interested in our
country's backup army theory
But it's the
multinational's decision
Bring merciful is
not working anymore
I'm afraid
there's no options anymore
Its because of this we
should do this
with determination
This is what the
other party wants
Normally facing
this kind of situation
you'll enter into a dilemma
Logic doesn't work
It'll only make
the matters worst
Put it simply just use
money and get out of it
You take people as fools
Fujiwara-kun are
you satisfied with this
Japan already lost in this war
Of course there's no country
can go against U.S. now
The problem of
this war is the people
are not prepared for this war
Do you know what
you're talking about
Regretfully
January 17 joint
military starred to
invade Iraq
This is "War of Desert"
After a week
Japan decided to
pump 15 billion dollars in
Bore 5 more billion
its affecting our budget
But nobody shows any gratitude
Second edition Sergeant Kuhio
What are you looking at
Trees
Everyone come and have a look
Here stand properly
Look over here
This is Kuri-take
mushroom and its poisonous
you might die if you eat it
Mushrooms are
definitely nice to eat
But this really looks like
a real mushroom
lot of people mistaken it
You don't like children right
This is Kuri-take and it's
a type of poisonous mushroom
Its really poisonous
When we invaded Panama
The remaining army died
after eating these
Panama?
Panama is over there
They called me in the morning
and they're more than willing
to make us the wedding dress
Really
Because it's a Japanese bride
so I asked them to
use Kimono as the theme
They manage to get the
special materials
Where they used it for
Princess Diana's wedding dress
Mr. Kemo
Mr. Kemo?
Italy called someone Kemo
to find high quality silk
Have you checked
Because you said
you asked for help
from the dresser who
made Princess Diana's dress
Harder
Fighting jet's uniform
when the pilot is flying
Will automatically
tighten up at the calf's
If you don't make up your mind
you'll lose your pride
So the pilot's calf
will be more
stiff than normal people
Thank you
Its your turn
Forget about me
Quick from the arm that's
why you need to sleep facing up
You don't wear bra when
you're wearing a bath robe right
Change another hand
I don't hate children
I think so too
I feel unbelievable myself too
why do I have to say such thing
So I came here to
apologize really sorry
Will you still be here
I'll send these
documents over first
Please wait for a while
Come in
Sorry to disturb
I'm leaving now
Wait stop
Just a kiss
Kiss?
Can't do it here
I don't mean that
didn't you say we
must keep a distance
Don't you remember
Yesterday didn't you forgive
me over the phone
Phone?
I know you're drunk
but you really don't remember
Yes just like that
its over between us
But we love each other so much
That's what I hate the most
When do you want
to pass up the report
about the child
observing the mushroom
One day he'll hand up
Please register
check in please
You might be right
about me disliking children
That time it could be
I'm thinking about something
lot of things happened lately
But do you really know
I can see it too
5 minutes ago
where and what were you doing
I lied I don't
have such capability
I just finished
my mission yesterday
was at 1 million
and 6000 feet in the sky
After doing such job
you'll still have some
form of instincts with you
You're a pilot
I forgot to introduce myself
my name is
Johansen Elizabeth Kuhio
Marines from the U.S.
Pilot for the land army
Is she American
My father's ancestors were
born in Hawaii
So looks like a Japanese
Japanese is fluent
Yes French German
Japanese were taken
up after I join the army
I'm always around
here because of my duties
Staying in the
hotel opposite the forest
Very expensive right
Oh sorry you're
still working right
Who was that
U.S. pilot
The person
mentioned in the phone
is the one that
said something weird
When all of you went for patrol
Phone?
Not only Mr. Takahashi
you called me too
I caught a flu because of this
sorry
I gain extra one kilogram
I don't care about that
I know its urgent
but I'll go back very soon
Did Mr. Tabe Goro came
He called to say
he's going to be late
Oh when he comes
tell him that this
month's payment will be late
The receipt is written
a little bit
more time is alright
Then there is
Then depending on you
Do you have a cheaper room
Are there any
cheaper rooms'?
Before learning English
you have to be polite to people
Have you read this before
Yes
Once is not enough
you must know it
from back to front
As my wife
you have to attend
all kinds of functions
Must know the
current issues very well
So I'm learning English
I like English
In high school
I got second place
in English language
But because I have
to help out at home
Wrapped it inside
The rest will be
sent over after a week
After this mission finished
I'll report to Commander Johan
about me getting married
Remember you
said after you join us
The army will supply us
with 5 million yen
Oh that's salary receipt
So little money
after a long day work
I'm doubting I should buy
Exactly the same as the
one I saw in Nice last year
But the price is different
Please be careful
Thank you
Excuse me how much is that
Including the
tax is 390 thousands
I bought it
Please wait
Thank you for your suggestion
please do visit
Are you paying with credit card
I don't want
How dangerous
Why
Here where is that
You're asking for
directions its there
Turn right over there
walk for hundred meters
and you can see a flower shop
I don't understand
What do you mean
didn't I say its there
I don't understand
That see over there
Its not there its here
Over there right
Reached
No its not there
Why don't you know
how to open the car door
Enough don't touch anymore
Sorry I want to
give it to you as a gift
that's why I came
and find you immediately
Although its still a
bit early but if you do
Your Japanese is really fluent
No although my
father is Hawaiian
But he's always
mistaken as Japanese
So he decided to learn Japanese
But to be able to speak so well
Mr. Kuhio is really capable
Ms. Michiko is really capable
Oh how should I put it
Ms. Michiko
doesn't like this job right
Yes I hate it
I don't like to
socialize from the start
and it bothers me to stay here
But to be seen
as a career woman
Kuhio is scarier
Looked through me
just after a while
Everyone said that too right
Ms. Michiko
Said that you
really love this job
Because you're
good in socializing
very confident and strong
I'm impressed
I'm very strong too
we can be good partners
Cheers
Thank you
Oh thank you for the hard work
How many
40.
Then I want 20 more
Hello I'm Nagano
from Takaba Lunchbox
Its me
sorry
today really cannot
can you sit motorcycle
I know
Its important to do lunchboxes
as important as world peace
I like the ocean
that I see beside you
Mr. Yoneda
how is Ryo oh
the fever cool down
Ah that's good
You can go back earlier today
Oh then I'm hanging up
This is really
small is it a real prawn
Who are you
Oh Mr. Tatsuno long time no see
What prawn is this
Where's the boss
Looks like he gone out
Then I'll be waiting
Should be very
late when he comes back
maybe they'll
come back tomorrow
Where did you go
Do you know what is this
When you're in danger
Lock on your target
and reflect the sun
Then you can
tell your own location
to the helicopter
It can transfer up to 160 km
its our life saver to us
O
Do you want to teach the kids
about the mirror
and light in the class
This is science also right
I know I'll consider it
Why did you go
You haven't' finish your meal
You're back
Today the mission
finish earlier let's go back
Wait
Welcome
Total is 4634 dollars
One is for everyone
the other one is for
the kid with the fever
The rest give it
to your colleagues
Have you heard about it
Sorry you're so
busy all the while
I have special
mission all the time also
So next time I'll spend more
time with you and your family
I understand
Oh right ocean
Ocean'?
Didn't you say
What you
Came back so late
its already midnight
you went to this shop
Its not for you
Who did you go with your lover'?
Don't you say yes
keep saying world
peace or whatsoever
That person is alright
The gift is waiting
Has got nothing to do with you
What is this 250
and 400 thousands
I told you it has
nothing to do with you
What do you mean we're siblings
How many times you made me cry
and still you dare say it
Helped you to
clear your property debt
do you know how much I spent
This time you visit me
for similar reasons right
I tell you this
I will not give
you a single cent
Its not property debt its goods
Although its bad but
I'll give you back soon
I'll work and return it to you
Its useless for
you to say anything
Why did he fetch sister
that man doesn't have a car
What do you know
As a spy don't even
want to drive on a rest day
Is it a SPY
Not I'm not
plus its not rest day
He's doing some special job
I'm helping him
Special job is?
If I can tell you its
not troublesome anymore
Its secret secret mission
Mission what
does that person do
That person is the
first person in this place
I can see that
With Ms. Maria
the salary is
different too right
Ms. Michiko there's Mr. Tajima
Everyone is thinking whether
she's the mistress or not
Here please
Thank you I'll go over
to your place immediately
Very sweet very nice
That one as a return gift
although its not that sweet
Can you come over and talk now
Its not that convenient now
Its good news to Ms. Michiko
What are you
talking about don't do this
Ms. Michiko will
put the blame on me
That day asked
you to accompany me
let me treat you to a dinner
Treat me now
Diet
Stan again tomorrow
Did you break
up with Mr. Tatsuno
Oh I feel its too troublesome
Oh what about that American
Sergeant?
Is a good man right
It's a weirdo
suddenly he'll do sit up
Maybe because
he's from the natives
I'm looking at
"taxidermy" will
definitely be very excited
(In order to conserve the
birds' most original species
permanent animal specimens)
Then Rikaori you date with him
Looks like you
have a lot of fun
with the natives
Only happiness
No need to find anymore
(Stop the night
flying training immediately)
hello you can hear me
Now I'm in Israel's sky
In the pilot room
Now we're locking
Saddam's resident as a target
When you go back to Japan
there's a very important war
So you can to prepare the four
wheel drive when you go back
Four wheel drive?
Wait
Don't hang up
You're dating
with my sister right
Your Japanese is
very fluent right
Heard that you're an American'?
Hey
Are you listening
My English is not bad right
Last time Suga learn English
with me when we
were in the marines
Of course she taught
me a lot of other things
other than English
We can communicate in Japanese
no problem
You're not American right
No no I..
If you lie I'll kill you
No I will not kill you
Its "Don't kill me" right
Welcome
After you've
ordered please call me
If you have appointment
when you go into
the shop you'll first
Confirm whether the
other party has come or not
I changed to this table
take my ice coffee here
Take the sunglasses off
Sorry to let you wait
Royalty? Royal blood'?
My sister is not an idiot
But parents died
when we were young
Have to work
really hard to earn money
to keep me the
useless brother alive
So I haven't' been in
any relationships before
Just like this
Sister's money is my money
So you have to return
Of course its return to me
My sister still
believe in you until now
Pitiful
I say
This kid's
chocolate is not done yet
If you feel its inappropriate
we can go to the
police station now
All in all return 1
million first deadline tomorrow
The day after tomorrow
Eat quick
Tomorrow one
million same time same place
Don't you dare
Alright alright
don't care so much just eat
the people in
the shop will keep
The day after tomorrow
I'll really kill you
Ha-ha idiot
You..
What are you doing..
You...
Crazy...
Let go
(Hit..)
What are you doing all of you
why did you pull me let go
Calm down calm down
If you're
unhappy about something
just look at the sky
Let's go
Look at the sky you know
What are you doing just now
The day after tomorrow
hello can you hear me
now in the sky of Israel..
Its me
Just call and confirm
who's on the other side
Plus
Are you trying to ask
one million from my
sis and give it back to me
You call because of this right
Didn't I say
sister's money is my money
You get it from the other woman
You can get it from
the other woman right
I know it's a
bit difficult for you
Just like this can you put
it to the day after tomorrow
Who called just now
Oh my ex-girlfriend
Too naive
Welcome
The voice is really nice
Have you heard of
Queen Elizabeth before
Yes of course
My mom is Queen Elizabeth
sister's husband
Which means its
her sister-in-law
Really impressive
There's a social
circle that is only available
to the royal blood
Although that social circle's
existence is unknown
Yes..a circle
with a lot of people
Then everyone does investments
such circle
The participants are all VIP
so they're able to obtain
Information that are
not available to outsiders
All in all they
will not let the
royal members make any losses
Ms. Michiko
You should participate too
Partner with me
Partner with you'?
But first you have to hand in
deposit of
fifty thousands pounds
Convert into yen
is around ten million
But the money will double up
really fast and
return it back to you
Oh but I don't
have so much money
If I'm the one
who introduce you in
you have to pay
thirty thousands only
No twenty five thousands
shouldn't be a problem
Oh really sorry
Sounds like I really
want to earn money like that
Its not like that
What I said just now is to
COVE!' Up my nervousness
I'll feel
embarrass to say it directly
Actually what I want to say is
please partner up with me
Come to think
of it I don't even
care whether I
can make money or not
Just like what Michiko knows
antics are costly
That's why I starred doing that
Plus depending on
the insider information
The money you earned is always
more than what you expected
Then can you please help me
fill the money up
Actually I want to
be independent myself
But the money I need to spend
seems to be more than expected
An outsider's opinion
will normally decide
the success or failure
Even if it's a vase
The money spent to decorate
is cannot be taken lightly
Ha-ha excuse me
I'm being rude
I don't feel
anything rude about it
I really like to work
Just like what Mr. Kuhio says
Understood me as your partner
will support you Ms. Michiko
You can't be my partner
Because I'm already married
But still I'm very happy
I'm really happy too
Hahaha I lied to you
I'm not married
Welcome
Guest this guest...
Stop
Go towards the right
Yes over there
Wind
Rika is off today
I came to find you
Rika is a good girl
Someone who can
communicate very well
Ms. Rika I don't know
why I'm more afraid
Afraid?
Why are you afraid
I finally understand
after I think for a while
Ms. Haru
I like you
Consider it as
love at first sight
Actually I thought
there's no such thing
as love as first sight
All the while I feel
those who fell in love
at first sight are fools
Come to think of it
maybe I've become one too
But I feel really happy
That mistress is happy too
I want to date
you seriously can
sorry
You have a boy friend'?
Its not like that
Why don't you accept me
I'm just a nobody sorry
Wait
Ms. Haru did something happen
Nothing
We're chatting about some
private matters
Private matters
its working hours now
You as a U.S army
is that free
Aren't you in war right now
You think that
with that uniform
all the
Japanese will respect you
Mr. Takahashi
I told you this place
is a place to
keep living things
Who do you think you are
Plus have you really care about
the children before
Let's go
Do you have kids
Kids
Now not
but in the
future I'll have many
Protecting the kids is
our responsibility right
So that's the
reason we have war right
If war was a good or bad thing
Definitely that's a bad thing
But doesn't matter
whether it's a good or bad thing
whatever needs to
happen has to happen
That's the reason why we exist
In order to
protect your own country
You didn't even put
a tiny bit of effort
What do you
understand as a Japanese
It happened last year
my brothers died
He's the partner in charged
good friend of many years
That day
we were flying as usual
Fighting to
death with our enemies
But
that time we wanted to
escape from enemy's attack
When we were getting
ready to attack the enemy
Suddenly the oxygen was cutoff
The generator stopped too
everything went out of control
I want to save
him but that time
the plane was
starting to crack up
His neck bone
was hit by the
mirror that crashed
The body was gone
Don't you have any friend
Really sorry Mr. Kuhio
Japanese!!
Japanese!!!
Don't point fingers at people
What about that pilot
Not really clear
Take the umbrella
Oh nothing
Oh so this is it
Ms. Nagano Nin No.7
Thank you for waiting thank you
Why are you here
I asked the
administration to help me check
Your phone is alright
Look at this
The designing draft is here
Asked what kind of
materials do you like
Of course those two type
were chosen by Mr. Kabaku
Its not bad
Asked us to reply
as soon as possible
I personally feel its not bad
Chosen that
Although its really not bad
Then this one
This is correct right
But you have to pay
the deposit when you reply
Can you gather 10 million now
Looks like you're
poorer than I thought
Because we open up a new shop
But still its around 10 million
Oh that one is
Then you can only cancel it
Then you have to give up
Its not that
I know I'll go and get it now
Good evening I'm Michiko
Mr. Kuhio please
don't come to Ginza anymore
Why
Because I don't want
to see you in the shop
If you want to meet privately
I found a really nice a partner
Those troublesome procedures
I'll go and get it done
They asked me to
sign the contract fast
because the
house is high in demand
You need another sum of
money to bail yourself out right
Looks like it
How come I feel that I'm conned
When I was asked
I feel that the woman in
Ginza will answer like that
There isn't lies or so
just doing what you hope for
What is money to you right
Go to the washroom
We're from the police station
Want to ask about your customer
Tajima Ryuuji
What happen to Mr. Tajima
Didn't you watch the news
Got arrested in the
work place this morning
Really
1 billion and 300 million
1 billion?
Come to think of it
his money is not clean
Is it accomplice
Accomplice?
Don't get me involve
That we'll investigate
All of you are detectives right
Let all the fools go
Fools'? Who
The error in the spellings
didn't the other
victims make a report
That's Kuhio
Kuhio?
The Kuhio who con
people in marriage
Now its Sergeant
Are you laughing
Its nonsense really nonsense
Coke
Ok
You did it on
purpose didn't you
When did you arrive
What's this
Convert into 1 O
million its around
Why is it so troublesome
Please put it to good use
How much is one U.S. dollar now
I don't want to
get near you anymore
and cause trouble
Don't misunderstand its not that
I want both of you to break up
Plus the money
you took from sister
is not so little right
I didn't cheat her
You have to treasure it
her hard earned money
You can con it
from the wine server
Prepare the money for me
I'll contact you
as soon as possible
My name is Senoka haru
Ms. Haru
From the kids
I took back your mirror
I'll take and
give it back to you
Your base right
But now
we're doing some
emergency training
Its not good if he comes in
Better for me to go back
Oh really sorry
and I apologize for last time
Nothing
Then I'll be more
than happy to follow
Hello'?
Find me
We can't accept this
You know all of us are
working really hard
But you said you
can't pay us any salary
what's going on
Really sorry everyone
You're alone today
Its not like that
What do you mean
its not like that
Kissed and touched before right
Aren't you angry
There's nothing
to be angry about
Your lover and your
friends did such thing
But we're not lovers anymore
it has nothing to do with me
So sly
Sly? Why
You should know
I like Mr. Shinagawa
You like him'?
Don't you know
I really didn't know
Then get angry now
Alright don't be so loud
you'll disturb other people
Shut up
You decide to
really just leave like that
Haru
although it's a bit
weird to say such thing now
But still I feel that
American is suspicious
You better be careful
I told you it has
nothing to do with you
Am I really sly
Excuse me
to say something
that doesn't make sense
No Ms. Haru is not sly
The hunters
Nothing
Have you been to Hawaii
Then let's go next time
for the blue sky and ocean
Friends are not bad too
and I want to
introduce you to my parents
Your parents are in Hawaii?
They bought a
house after they retire
and they have barbeque everyday
Looks fun
Although both of us
can be really happy too
Haru
we're working for world peace
Of course I am proud of this
But still I get
misunderstood at times
Just like last time in
order to fulfill my dreams
sacrifices are necessary
When we attacked and
thought about the kids
who lost their parents
We get emotional
Last time the
friend I mentioned
he has a young child
Enemy or friends
it doesn't matter
Just that nobody
can take away the right
of the children to
have their parents with them
So I discussed with my friend
Must prepare a trust fund
for the children's future
Not only those
American children
but also the kids from Iraq
Kids from all over the world
Wants to get
Japanese's help too
Haru let's do this together
Actually I told Ms. Rika
but regretfully
She couldn't understand
Because I have a
really low salary
Thank you the most
important thing is the heart
Indeed Haru
understands me the most
Really happy to be able to help
What time do you
finish work tomorrow
I resigned today
Why its quite a good job
Its really
suitable for Ms. Haru
what a waste
Its better to continue right
Oh you're back
The mission came
suddenly in midnight
couldn't contact you
You're worried
about my job thank you
Nothing compare with lunchbox
world peace is more important
I slipped when I
was passed the forest
There're still mission
today you can go back first
Nothing
Its very late too
I'll prepare the
meals and wait for you
Oh depending on you then
Good afternoon
Just go in
Leave me alone I'm
waiting for somebody
Go and work
Didn't you say you
don't want to work anymore
Hey since yesterday
I didn't eat anything
Will it taste
better if we eat together
Going to the beach
Beach'?
What can you catch here
Butterfish
This fish has different colours
under different environment
The color is light
when its in shallow place
and it'll be darker
if its in deeper place
The fish you
catch here is black
Very deep right
Yes
I thought about dying
before because I'm too foolish
But if I really die then
I'll really be foolish
that why I didn't die
What's wrong what happened
This
This is 2800 yen right
The story about your
friend who passed away
you got it from the movie right
Why do you say that
Lately the jet fighters
are able to emit air
Its impossible for
that kind of thing to happen
Do you know
Ms. Haru you misunderstood
the story is true
My good friend McLuhan is true
McLuhan'?
Yes McLuhan
Didn't you say
its Johnny last time
You heard wrongly I think
I said McLuhan
Don't be stupid I
remember it clearly
Because when I
was in kindergarten
I name my dog Johnny
Why did you find
me I don't have money
Why is it me
- Ms. Haru let go
- Why
It'll break It'll break
Enough answer me
Why me
Their accomplice?
I have to be clear first
I'm your savior
Who are you
How much did he cheat from you
Everyone is really stupid
Hey don't move
My sister said 2 hours
whether to go to police
station or go home up to you
Just like what
I keep telling you
under the
restriction of law no.19
Have to bear the responsibility
as a joint country
Who wouldn't pay
can you call this joint country
with this kind of relationship
Its totally like
a sub-U.S company
Its because of people like you
that we got looked down
First you have to declare our
position to Japan clearly
U.S. and the world
How can we be so thick face
Japan is really lonely
Lonely more like
we're being ignored
Didn't realise at all
really sorry I
wouldn't be staying here anymore
Thank you
Yes its only
but not bad for a place to die
Let's die together
it'll come true when we die
What do you mean
its true initially
Its true so want
to prove to everyone
I don't understand
Johansen. Elizabeth.
Kushio is not related
Nothing to do with
the American pilot too
I like the you in front of me
just like this
I know
Die
Can you allow me to be
stubborn for once before I die
Let's eat the lunch
box in our shop together
Now?
Ok
I'm eating now
Please
Delicious
Really
Delicious hamburger
Yes this is the most
popular order in the shop
Its uniquely set
up with egg yolk sauce
So it seems
I'm cold
Haru
Get out of the way
The last dinner
Yes the last dinner
I was born in Hokkaido
my house is big
There're a lot of roses
The neighbours called
my house "Rose Garden"
Dad operates a few supermarkets
but he let other
people manage them
My parents are always
at home and play with me
You parents
thought you that too
All the while you're
sitting like that right
Yes indeed I was
told most of the time
Wait
What're you doing
So I said don't hit anymore
You don't care about it
After you enter the old house
the strongest
junior baseball team
Because I run fast that's
why I took the guarding position
But our pitcher is really good
So basically the ball
didn't come to my side
Because I'm really free that's
why I keep looking at the sky
That's why I like planes
After that...
After that I
underwent strict training
And became American's pilot
Until now
I fight for world peace
Really delicious
Then die
Who will die first
I won't shoot
That's right
You will not die like this
Its nothing my shooting is good
Close your eyes
Close your eyes!
But this is not
a real gun right
This is a real gun
I learn before
Learn a lot of things
Then what should I do
Nothing you'll die soon enough
Just now in the hamburger
I put some
poisonous mushroom inside
Although its just 200 grams
Found you
Wait
Let me go
I want to ask why
did he treat me this way
Its late
Since I'm dying soon
We ate poisonous mushroom
Did he really eat is
I ate it both of us ate it
You're too sly spit it out
Spit it out! Spit it out
That man ate with guilt
O
I cheated him and
asked him to eat it
Isn't that poisonous mushroom
Its really bitter
its impossible
that he'll eat it
You guys eat
normal mushroom right
Must be because
He really likes you
That's why he cheated me
So I don't understand
That's all
Are you an American
Its Japanese sorry
Are you Tom
What
You're Tom Watts
I'm Johansen. Elizabeth.
Kuhio
How many women did you
cheated using that name
I didn't cheat
They too are longing for it
I did what they want
Stop talking
using that kind of tone
Stand up
I want to give
you something special
(Kuhio)
Fellows
The first proposal
That's it
let's start on our next step
Understood
If you move forward
it's the enemy's base
Its difficult for battle
But the victory
will definitely be ours
I truly believe
fearless battle
Understood
The last plane
stopped at Virginia
Went over there with a F14
20 to 23 miles
away from enemy's base
One shot by one shot we shoot
In total we shoot 8 shots
Then when we go for
emergency gathering...
Please be quiet