The Assassination of Ryoma
Directed by Kazuo Kuroki
November 13, 1867
Come up and see me sometime.
Ryoma on the move.
Yesterday some guard came from the
Magistrate's office and left this.
Are you dissatisfied?
Whaddya think?
Well, it does kind of look like you.
Ryoma, wanted for the murder of two
Shogunate Officials
in Teradaya last year
They really make me look evil in this thing.
Wanted for murder: Ryoma Sakamoto
We'll I'll be on my way...
If there's anything else you
need, please ask Tokichi anytime.
Hey Shinsuke,
Why did you take on this kind of work?
I'm just a simple businessman,
although I may not look like it.
The Shogunate is going to collapse.
Well, there are many people
that would say the opposite.
That's just like you,
Mr. Shinsuke Kendo.
There are other ways to make a
profit regardless of the Shogunate.
Whatever...
We can talk about it again sometime.
I appreciate it.
Ryoma, The Peeping Tom
Nakaichi Shinsuke,
in accordance to the
laws of the Auxilary Guard
you are hereby ordered
to commit seppuku.
Control yourself, Shinsuke!
Ryoma Sakamoto...
just arrived.
Really?
That is good news.
Are you going to kill him?
Don't be foolish.
He's practically my best friend.
Why do you pretend nothing happened?
You know that he
and I were together once
Tai,
Ryoma is a beast!
That's actually one of his better qualities
Why, Shintaro?
Why aren't you more like a beast?
Cut it out!
Tai,
Knock it off!
Later later.
I'll pay you afterwards
What's up with you?
Sorry, but this is all I have.
It's only 100 yen. Forgive me.
You know times are tough right now.
Even rice costs twice as much,
but my salary stays the same.
Even farmers have it better than I do.
I'm sorry, cut me some slack.
You're worse than the
prostitutes in Shinagawa.
Here.
C'mon,
Hold it firmly.
It's got a kick to it. Hold it right.
Arms straight and stiff.
What the hell is wrong with you?!
Aim it straight in
front of your target.
Arms straight.
Now, pull this thing back.
Push down hard.
What the hell are you doing?
Like this.
Give it here.
Seems like a katana
(sword) is still better.
Whatever...
Strange...
Hold this.
Move your feet!
Why don't you help me look?
Don't just sit there!
Get your feet outta my face!
Shortsighted Ryoma
From Edo to Kyoto, then Kyoto to
Nagasaki, always on the move.
A lightweight gun is the best
weapon for someone in my situation.
Imagine being on the run for
three days with a heavy sword,
your back, arms,
and joints start to ache.
I said the same thing to Shinta,
but he's so stubborn.
He can't let go of his katana.
It's too late for him
to change his ways.
Right?
For example, if Shinta
and I went to Edo,
I would cost him two days of
traveling because of his sword.
While the cherry blossums scatter,
people might change alliances,
or your girl could fall
for some other guy.
Forget about it!
What the fucks up
with this stupid thing?
It's just like the color of blood.
It really is, isn't it?
I've heard that Ryoma Sakamoto
has gone into hiding.
Wow, you get your information fast.
The Bakufun spies are closing in.
So he's got to be somewhere.
That may be true,
but that is comforting enough.
Sakamoto may be a great man, but
he makes stupid mistakes.
We can't let him fall into the
hands of the Bakufun.
Agreed.
Hanjiro Nakamura.
Lately, he has become even more quiet.
Maybe it's because of all the killing.
What's the situation?
Nakamura,
the new kid is quite petulant.
That petulance is
good enough for the job.
Hey!
What a ridiculously long katana.
This stuff isn't used
in Japan nowadays.
Mr. Oyaji, reconsider.
If I bought this from you,
I would never be able to resell it.
I can't take it.
Oyaji, please take it.
Sorry. Why don't you try
a different pawnshop
Oyaji, just take it.
Stop laughing at me!
I told you not to follow me!
Captain, you are lost. Would you be
able to kill Ryoma like that?
What?
Failure will cost lives.
Ryoma Sakamoto is just that scary.
Wasn't that why we moved his
hideout to the warehouse?
Avoiding the watchful eyes of the
Shogunate was just a front,
we need to keep Sakamoto far away from
the provisional palace, in essence...
so that one of us could
kill him at any time.
That's why I told you
I was going alone!
Ryoma is a very cautious man.
He will only invite me to go inside.
It will only be when
I feel like the son of a barber
and he feels like the son
of a pawnshop owner again.
But..
You've said enough!
Mr. Nakaoka
I just felt like having
a meal with Ryoma.
Toukichi, make it as you always do.
Stop squirming around!
Where are you from?
You just won't stop moving.
If you keep moving around
I can't get anything done.
So what do you do?
A boat. I work on a
boat, just like you.
You're silly. Why would someone
working on a boat be targeted?
I wonder why.
Anyway, who cares?
What now?
Well, if you did
actually work on a boat...
then it's the same as my family.
My Dad's a fisherman too.
Oh yea? Whereabouts?
Shimotsui in Seto Bay.
Sure, sure. I know that place.
I've been there many times by boat.
It had a big port that could fit
two or three steamboats
They also had women as gentle
as the sea of Seto.
Pervert, you're really a weirdo.
You too. What kind of man would
want a shrew like you?
If I said the word, "Shinsengumi,"
would you run away?
Well, the captain is usually best at
rowing, so let's start rowing!
To Maiden, my sister,
Today I am taking a
chance to write to you,
I have spent my days and nights...
remembering what you said to me...
forgetting one's national
polity over lust
is an insult that
should never happen...
But these days I have been overcome...
overcome by a strange passion...
and it's growing strength
fills me with fear...
I know nobody will understand...
Ryoma is confused...
Ryoma is tired...
Ryoma...
shits five times a day.
So, there was this stupid cat...
that climbed up a tree
and couldn't get down.
I called to it and all it would do
is cling to the branch and cry.
I had no choice but to climb up
but the cat kept climbing further up.
I shouted at it to stop...
I put some mochi on a
stick to lure it down,
I tried everything but nothing worked.
If we didn't do something
the cat would starve
So I thought and said,
Fine! Just cut the damn tree down!
but everyone just started laughing.
I said, "What's so funny!"
They said it was stupid to try to
cut down a tree that was
ten feet wide for a skinny cat
and the moment I heard that,
I started laughing too
It was stupid, wasn't it?
The priorities of value
are competely wrong,
don't you agree?
I've been told that
I'm a little off in the head
At that time, they did have a point,
but after awhile I thought to myself,
That's not the point,
that it's not about the cat's life,
but more so that it should be
acceptable to at least come up with
the idea of cutting down
the tree to save the cat.
Every possibility
should be considered!
In other words,
it's how you see things.
Viewpoint!
What I'm trying to say is that when
you look at something differently,
you have the chance to see
a completely different image,
Sometimes a riddle becomes
all too obvious.
Other times you begin to question
something you've always believed
and visa versa!
It's a scary thought. Scary!
so scary it makes you want to run away
and before you know it...
before you know it...
Who is it?
Uta?
Sister.
It's been two years! Come in!
Who's that?
Nobody.
Violence from Left-Wing samurai
is a daily occurrence
Why aren't you eating?
It's good.
I can't eat the fowl from a man
who tried to kill you.
What are you on about?
Shinta is Shinta. Food is food.
Sensei, this is no laughing matter.
I get it!
This wasn't the first
time I've been targeted.
It's more like the third or fouth by now.
There were two times when I
seriously tried to kill Shinta myself,
but as usual, he is a tardy man,
and he arrived when I wasn't around.
I bet you, at least carry your
revolver when you go out.
Well, I wouldn't really call it going out...
Have you lost your mind?
I don't need you testing me!
I apologize. It's just that I'm worried.
Well, don't be!
People who worry too much will split their balls just stepping out of the bath.
Their life will never be fully satifying.
Eat!
Ryoma's favorite shoes were purchased
from the British Mr.Grover two years ago
Ryoma, the long-distance runner,
always accompanied by assassins
November 14, 1867
Imperial Court increases breeding
of pigs due to financial hardships
Is this chrysanthemum too big?
No, that looks just right.
It's very impressive of you, Mr.Iwakura,
to bring out the flag used 500 years
ago during the North-South dynasty.
The chrysanthemum symbol is the
best way to get the simple minded,
the weirdos, and those
who make excuses,
to obey and follow orders.
Instead of just one,
why don't we go all out,
and send one or two hundred of them
to the entire anti-government army.
The Satsuma and
Choshu region prepare to
reform a month after the restoration
of the government to the emperor.
Bills are falling from
the sky in Omiya!
Money is falling from the sky!
Where is the Captain?
I need to see the Captain!
Be quiet! I said he's not here!
Then Noda will be fine,
let us meet him!
Noda isn't here either!
Then Noda will be fine,
let us meet him!
Noda isn't here either!
Nishino, what are
you and Noda planning?
Where are you hiding the Captain?
If you are going to continue this
insubordination, you will be punished!
What are you waiting for?
If you're going to force me to commit
seppuku, then let me do it now.
Your humor is not appreciated. If you
die now, it will only cause problems.
What?
You are still considered
to be our Captain.
And will still need you to command
the Tosa Army to fight in the Satsuma-Choshu (Sa-Cho) reformation.
Your only weakness is that you
can't kill Mr. Sakamoto.
He was not there! How many times
do I have to say it!
I know it's uncomfortable,
but please be patient for a while.
We don't want Satsuma to look into your
relationship with Sakamoto any further.
And then what?
you guys will kill Ryoma?
It is our only option as the Tosa
anti-government movement.
You're over exaggerating.
Captain, when it comes to Sakamoto you
fully lose your sense of judgement.
Look, regardless of how it appears,
the Satsuma are not dependant on Tosa.
Even worse, following Sakamoto's
push for non-violent reform,
there is a movement to eliminate Tosa.
Nonsense. Why would they
need to do such a thing?
Simple. Tosa doesn't exist in
the future that Sa-Cho envisions.
That is why no matter how
much shame we endure,
we must maintain
obedience towards them.
By any means possible, we must
continue to hold on to that future.
You stupid fool!
What you see
is just the shifting of power.
That is all that matters to me.
If the Bakufu collapses,
what will the next era be like?
A bright and shiney new Japan?
I don't believe in such things.
Captain, if you continue to be
so depressed, it will be bad for you.
Here, why don't you have some
of that wine that you like?
Tae, if you would.
Uta?
I also have an overbearing sister
back home, named Maiden.
She still sends me
these childish letters.
Sisters have a strange presence,
they are oddly comforting,
and yet that makes them irrisistable.
I'm sure if I went back home I would
end up sucking on her breast every day.
Why do you carry this thing around?
Stop being so impersonal.
Did anything good come from
leaving your home town?
I'm sure with a sword like that nothing
good could have happened to you.
You are the quiet type.
You remind me of someone.
Who was it?
Right, it was Izou.
You remind me of a friend named Izou.
The way you carry yourself,
your gaze,
just like him.
He was called, Izou the Murderer
He was really good at killing people,
or more likely, he really enjoyed it.
Anyway, instead of dying in a fight
he was poisoned while he was in jail.
You're young but you look like
you're good at killing people too.
I don't know who asked him to come,
but that was pitiful.
What are you doing?
Is it good?
What's wrong?
Uta, don't do it!
Toukuchi!
Shinsuke, give my
apologies to your wife.
Sensei, where are you going
dressed like that?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm going to see Shinta.
To see Nakaoka?
It's great, hiding from my assassins by
blending in with the crowd. Ingenious.
But Nakaoka is one of the assassins.
Toukuchi, my shoes.
You're wearing leather shoes with that?
You imbecile, stop
talking and get them.
The Government of Kyoto
has banned disguises
Uta finds an opportunity to kill Ryoma
Throw up some more, you'll feel better.
Calm down, it's just me.
Be quiet.
Where is Shinta?
Here or Myouzen Temple?
What's up with you?
I'm not here to kill Shinta.
Why are you looking at me like that?
C'mon, where's Shinta?
Shintaro is going to get killed.
What?
He's being held by soldiers in the back
and they will make him commit seppuku
at any moment. Please help him!
You're in love with him?
Hurry, take off your kimono.
I'm saying take off your kimono!
You savage!
You idiot, it's not like that!
Shinta, it's me!
Look at me!
See? It's me!
Moron, I'm not here to kill you.
What the hell are you doing?
Relax!
I don't understand how this happened.
first you are after me,
and now your guys are after you,
This is a very strange situation.
I've met that kid before.
Who is he?
Dunno.
You don't know?
The only thing I know is that he tries
to kill me whenever he has the chance.
It's him.
I met him at Satsuma's palace.
The Satsuma's are
trying to kill me too?
Let's kill him.
Wait, wait. We're unarmed.
Where's your revolver?
I have it with me
but I forgot to load it
You're pathetic. You
haven't changed a bit.
You're the one who's pathetic, you're
trying to kill me too. Don't worry.
But, I can't let it slide.
Leave him be, he's not so bad.
I know, but I think I can kill him now.
What's up with him?
Stop it, you two! I'm going to shoot!
We need to be careful!
Hit 'im again!
C'mon, samurai, fight back!
What a pretty girl you are.
We need to be careful. Let's wait
until dark to return to the warehouse.
Yeah, it will be better
to wait until night.
I'm getting sleepy.
Yeah, I'm really sleepy.
What are you doing?
Stop it, old hag.
You fucking moron.
Coward!
A completely hopeless case!
Why avoid an armed reformation?
So not to shed blood?
For the value of human life?
Since when have you become a pacifist?
Besides, I've been meaning to kill you
ever since you started preaching
about that deceitful restoration.
Getting Tokugawa to resign his
position as Shogun,
sounds like one of your typical tricks
but it's been a month,
and how has the country changed?
We want to get rid of the old system,
we must pull them out from the roots.
Start having the Shogun and his family
commit seppuku, or else kill them.
That's reformation. And that is the
only way to create a true reformation.
Don't you understand that?
Of course I do.
- What?
I understand it, that's why I'm here, listening to your story.
I don't disagree with anything
you've just said.
So, what are you going to do?
Specifically.
That's not a problem.
I'm commanding the Tosa anti-government faction
and committing to reformationary
military of the Sa-Cho.
I see, and say you'll destroy the Bakufu?
Don't make it sound like
it's as easy as squashing a bug!
No, I am confident you can destroy
them. No matter what, you'll win.
But the problem is what happens next.
Who comes into power then?
You sound just like Noda.
Really? Just like Noda?
He has no vision for change.
All he's interested in
is who takes control.
Shinta, this is a concern of mine as well,
you destroy the Bakufu and create a
new system. Then who comes next?
what kind of government will he create?
That is what I think about!
I'm more of a realist than you!
and I have painted some
ideas of the future
I have addressed these ideas
to Saigo and Katsura, too.
But then, one day...
I did a handstand...
and while doing a handstand,
I looked at the world's movement.
It was a very odd scene
from that viewpoint,
there were all these
power-hungry phantoms!
Wait, Shinta.
I'm not just insulting
my allies for fun,
I'm saying that by doing a handstand,
we can figure out a way to
escape the strong pull of power.
Without hiding or running away,
we need to figure out how
to become independent.
Or maybe...
Maybe we need to completely
change our own lives.
Enough!
Enough of this psychotic rant!
You're near-sighted, but you always
speak with such a long stare.
First we need to completely
destroy the old order.
After that the new world will
finally start to reveal itself.
So first, I will become the
destroyer. A thorough destroyer.
That is my only mission!
Listen, Shinta!
Shut up! I don't have to
listen to this anymore!
Die!
All pigs need to die!
Han! Please run away with me!
Let me go!
Don't be stupid!
I'm still young!
Running away with an
embezzler like you
wouldn't bring me any joy in life!
Leave by yourself!
You are the only thing
I have going for me!
I'd do anything to support you,
I'd become a monk, or even
an apprentice at a pawnshop!
You've fallen pretty far from
your position in the Shinsengumi
I said it before, I have no intention
of rotting away with some old bore!
Now, you lazy monk. Get out!
Damn you!
That hurts!
Stop it.
Run away with me
Run away?
I love sleeping with you
I want to rent a house and do this everyday
I want to do this
from morning to night.
You're being inconsiderate!
Stop fidgeting and get out!
I'm fine being inconsiderate.
Feel free to do as you like.
You! Skinny! Cowardly! Potato!
Come down here!
Cut it out!
November 15, 1867
See, he's there alright.
And today it's a newcomer.
Just to be safe, I sent my wife
and kid back to the countryside.
Thorough as always.
But it appears I may have
made a miscalculation
That doesn't sound like you,
as a merchant you must always
be adjusting your calculations.
You have a point.
Wait.
Hold on with the Ryoma Sakamoto case.
What do you mean?
No idea. I don't know anything.
These are orders from above.
It was the same thing with
yesterday's Choshu case.
Why are the orders changing like the
eyes of a cat. Screw the orders!
Orders.
I'm sick of being
cooped up in this place!
It feels like my body is
starting to smell like mold.
Damn it!
If somebody wants to kill me, do it!
Shinta!
How about you?
Are you going to kill me or not?
Stop eating and get serious!
Stop wailing.
You're getting dust in my food.
What's with your
high 'n mighty attitude?
The best way to eat is sitting comfortably.
No matter how much you act like a
samurai, you're the son of a barbar.
And you are the
son of a pawnshop owner.
That's right, I am.
And why is it that the son of a pawnshop owner,
having been told by a lady to elope,
has to be kept up here?
She's saying she wants to make
love to me the whole day,
Isn't that a wonderful thing?
So why the hell can't I do that!
If you want to elope, be my guest.
Alright, I will.
I'll leave this
stinking warehouse today!
Is that what you meant
by changing your life?
I don't know!
I no longer know what is Ryoma and
what is the reformation
if my old identity as the son
of a pawnshop owner disappears!
think about why we started this,
it was because of our hate for
the real arrogant samurai.
and now we're trying our best to act
like samurai just to have a meal!
You bastard!
Who's the reformation for?!
What we're doing is reformation
for the samurai!
It's truly a joke that the sons of barbars
and pawnshop owners are
fighting for a samurai's reformation!
Stop wailing!
Stop being so arrogant, Shintaro!
Why don't you escape with the girl?
Is it because of the assassins outside?
No, it's because of yourself.
It's because of you...
You are the one that is completely
immersed in the reformation movement.
Shut up!
You don't even understand
anything about women!
Are you talking about Tae?
Tae is in love with you.
Wrong! The one that Tae
is really into is you!
Don't make a fool of me!
Shut up, you womanizer!
A package arrived from Nagasaki!
Alright! It came!
From Nagasaki?
I ordered 5,000 rifles from Hartmann.
it'll be too late to stock up on
guns after the battle begins.
I was actually thinking of
giving you a few, too
You really are a hopeless case.
Maybe.... Maybe I am.
Was there a small
parcel that came with it?
What's wrong?
Fuck.
My 5,000 rifles turned into this.
What do you mean?
He couldn't find the rifles.
So instead, he's giving me this.
Well, there's no point in being glum.
Let's take a photo to change the mood.
Ryoma.
You have to wait ten minutes.
Unfortunately, that picture
no longer survives today
Tonight, I'm going to Nagasaki.
To Nagasaki?
I can get away in the middle of night
And then what will you do?
Even if I can only find 100 or 200,
I'm going to supply the rifles.
And then,
I'm going to reconstruct the navy.
Reconstruct?
I'm going to recruit a ton
of monks and fishermen.
They'll be useless.
You don't know that!
With good training you can learn using
a gun even when you're no samurai.
But even if you do that,
you're not going to make it for the
battle Sa-Cho are planning next month.
I know.
That's why I'm going to leave it up
to the Bakufu to destroy the Sa-Cho
Leave it up?
That's right,
and after that, my newly formed and
well-trained navy will come into play.
What do you mean?
We'll attack Sa-Cho.
Of course, it will be one
ambush after another.
I know we can't go against them head on.
Their forces add
up to be 3 or 4 thousand.
In that case, I can make my move
with 800 to 1,000 men.
Satsuma will definately target you.
By the way, Shinta,
What are you going to do?
I can't keep company
with your pipe dream
You will act along with Sa-Cho?
I understand,
both as enemy and as friend.
It's OK. Do as you want to.
But no matter how long you stay here,
you're only going
to start growing mold.
Escape with me tonight,
kill Noda,
and ensure the
Auxiliary troops to our side.
I don't need concern
from a man like you,
someone who has
lost all sense of reality.
I'll eventually just take the
Auxiliary troops with you in it.
You bastard!
Don't be mad!
Let's have a drink.
After tonight, we'll
be apart for awhile.
Damn it, I think I caught a cold.
Hey, you drunk.
Stop waving that murder knife around.
What the hell
are you doing, woman!
It looks like there
are swarms out there.
This place is no good for my cold.
Let's go to the
2nd floor of the main wing.
Don't be stupid.
the spies and assassins are all
focused on this place
We can't escape.
If we go to the main wing
it will be easier to escape later.
What'll you do with the woman?
She looks like she's fast asleep.
A strangely warm woman.
It looks like we can escape.
Wait.
Later in the night will be safer.
Where is he?
Gone.
He disappeared right from under me.
Let's run away.
Why should run away with you?
If we don't kill him,
you and I are both going to be killed.
Me too?
Yes
You too.
Well then, Uta...
Kill that man.
No way. I can't do it.
What's wrong? Are you scared?
You never told me, but...
Killing is your job, right?
Why can't you kill that man?
Is he an exception?
Stop!
I can't do it.
What?
Okamoto, from the Palace?
Yes, with Minekichi from
a bookstore he goes to,
visiting the soldiers on the front lines.
Fishy.
Just the two of 'em?
Let them in.
Don't drop your guard.
In those final moments,
what did you talk about?
Leaving already?
See Mr. Ryoma healthy and
safe is more than enough.
I'm OK, but I caught a cold.
I got the shivers. Why don't we
eat some foul stew?
Foul stew?
Don't be picky.
Toukuchi!
Sensei, I can get you some foul,
if that's what you want.
Alright, you go get it.
Please be careful.
You'll get stiff shoulders
doubting others all the time.
But...
You were completely
defenseless toward me.
I can't even count how
many times I could have killed you.
What's with you?
Are you still thinking about killing me?
I am an enemy and an ally.
No, that's no good.
When you start saying those things,
I get the urge to kill you too.
You are too scary
to have as an enemy.
Let's not let go of our swords.
What's with the damn chanting?!
The man you're looking for
is in the main wing.
Where are you going?
I'm going to take
that girl to Nagasaki.
Are you kidding?
You're giving up
your pipe dream for a girl?
That girl is also the daughter
of a fisherman.
So what?
I'll make her cook for my new navy.
What?
Don't get agitated.
I don't know!
but I think my pipe dream
would expand
if I incorporated women like her.
I dunno.
You bastard!
You are a complete moron!
in that case, take me...
What did you just say?
Idiot!
I'm saying that you should take me.
Are you...
Are you saying you'll be
a part of my pipe dream?
Who is it?
Mr. Minekichi?
Relax!
Subs by Robert Nishimura