Wha!
Hey! What up, roomies?
- Ooh, new high tops?
You know it.
Love, it looks like you
got here by unicorn.
- I did!
Jojo, you can't be late.
You're the team
captain, and FYI,
Nina just volunteered
to lead warm-up for you.
So nice of her!
See, I told you! Nina loves me!
Hey, it's Jojo!
Hey, so kind of you to join us.
- Hey, kid.
- Sorry I'm late.
Were you dancing with
the mailman again?
- What? Me, and mailman?
- No, I don't...
Maybe.
- Are you all warmed up?
- I'm always warmed up.
- All right, they're all yours.
- Five, six, seven, eight!
All right, that's was great.
Are you all warmed up?
- Yeah!
- Okay, there's something
I would like to talk
with you girls about.
Ooh! Are we picking out
new competition costumes?
Because I feel like this year,
we've gotta go head-to-toe
flippy sequins.
You know, the ones where
you flip them one way
and they're a happy face
and then you flip them back
and they're something else?
No, this isn't about costumes.
Then, are we learning our
new competition routine?
- Oh!
- No, this is not about
- a new routine.
- Hold on a second!
Are we finally getting
that new vending machine.
Please tell me there's
Sour Patch Kids.
This isn't about
a vending machine.
This is about my future
here at the studio.
After 30 years of teaching
dance, it's time for me
to turn the studio
over to new management.
Val, no, you can't leave.
You're not just our
coach, you're our mentor.
- A second mother.
- You taught us
about expressing ourself
through movement.
- And living in the moment.
- And freestyle Fridays.
Look, girls, I don't
want to view this
as something to be sad about.
I want you to look at this
as an exciting change.
I put a lot of thought into
who should take over the studio
and I found someone.
Someone who is just as
passionate about dance
and developing young,
creative spirits.
I know you'll be in good hands.
Girls, I'd like you to meet
your new dance
instructor, Poppy.
- Do you hear that?
- Yeah.
It's like she has
her own theme song.
- Not now, Mom.
- I'm changing lives.
It's Coach Poppy, and
thanks for the intro,
- but I got it from here.
- But I thought we discussed
- that I was gonna...
- Yeah, yeah,
I'm totally going to foster
their young, creative spirits
and move their delicate
minds and all that jazz.
- But the gradual transition...
- Transition you out,
though, first, Where
I was going to stay
for a while and make
sure the girls are okay.
Build, build as a team.
I just have one more
thing I want to say...
- Thanks so much!
- We don't validate anymore.
Sorry. Bye, bye. Whew! There.
That's better.
Now where was I? Yes?
- Bonding and team building.
- Right.
Speaking of which, would you
like to be my special helper.
- Okay.
Here. Take this and
build me a latte.
Four shots, five Splendas,
no foam, it's annoying.
This is a dollar.
Then feel free to get
yourself an ice water.
Okay, go on. Go. Go, go.
Aw, cheer up ladies.
This is going to be fun.
So, so fun, as long
as follow my rules.
Number one, if you're
not five minutes early,
then you are late and if you
are late, you are locked out.
Can you hear my heart beating?
- It's cool, we got it.
- We got it.
- Here's the deal.
- I am here to build the A Team,
but right now, you guys
are just the Okay Team.
So starting today, every
class will now include
boot camp-style
conditioning.
Aw, we're all disappointed.
Aw, I'm sorry. I
don't make the rules.
Oh, wait, hold on.
Yes I do!
Back up and form three lines.
Let's go! Burpees till it burns.
Lunge for days.
Push-ups till you throw up.
- Breathe. I am strong.
- I can do hard things.
And finally, every
dancer must wear
the same uniform in gray.
Not gray.
Did I just say that out loud?
- And you are?
- I'm Jojo.
I've been taking dance here
since I was, like, mm, five.
Aw, cute! And does Jojo,
who's been taking dance here
since she was, like, five,
have a problem with gray?
No! I mean...
- Well, yeah.
- Yeah.
- It's just so gray.
- Oh, yeah.
Could we possibly
like juj it up.
- Juj.
- Yeah!
We could add some color,
maybe even some sparkles.
- Sparkle?
- Yeah!
- You know what?
- That is a great idea.
You know, let me think
about that for a second.
Nope! Moving on!
Oh, before I forget.
No high tops, no ponytails,
and absolutely positively
no bows.
- Did you just say no...
- Bows.
Knees up! Let's go!
That is not... what is
this? Get those knees up!
Knees, knees,
knees! I said knees!
- Hey!
- Hey, guys!
- You okay, Jojo?
- Me? Oh, sure. I'm great.
Yeah.
This is a tough
transition for all of us,
but we know it's been
extra hard on you.
What? No, I'm good. I'm good!
Plain gray, it's
actually my favorite.
Uh, you know,
it's like we're twirling,
leaping, cinder blocks!
Enough about me!
Someone's about
to have a birthday
and we have some major
planning we've got to do.
Oh, you guys don't have
to go to a ton of trouble.
Are you kidding me?
It's your sweet sixteen,
of course we do!
We've got to do it up big!
Yeah, like a Velcro wall
or a mechanical bull.
Ooh! Yeah!
Well, I did see this
one guy on Instagram
who can make a life-size
cotton candy sculpture of you.
- Done!
- Absolutely.
Jojo, please don't break
the dress code again.
My quads are still burning
from all the extra squats
we had to do last practice,
when you forgot to
take out your bow.
Oh, I'm so sorry
about that, Nina.
It won't happen
again, I promise.
Hey, guys, ready to go in?
Jojo, your bow.
Val gave me this bow.
Told me she hoped that
I would always dance
to the beat of my own drum.
I don't know if I
can do it, guys.
Looking the same as everyone
just doesn't feel right.
I know this is hard, Jojo,
but you know the rules.
If she catches you with a bow
again, you're off the team.
Hear me out.
What if...
What if she doesn't see it?
The doors will be closing
in five, four, three...
- We're here, we're here!
- Ready to boogie!
Two!
Delightful. Gather around.
Now, as you may know, our
first opportunity to compete
will be at the upcoming Main
Street Dance Competition.
Small potatoes, but we
are going for two reasons:
One, to scope out
the competition.
And two, to practice
crushing them.
That way, we'll be ready
for the real competition.
The real competition?
The First Position Competition,
the only competition
that matters.
Ooh, I look good.
Look at me.
Anyway, I digress.
First things first,
to the mirror! Voila!
Let's go, let's go,
let's go, let's go!
Now, when you look in the
mirror, what do you see?
Cement? Storm clouds.
Statue of me.
- Gigi.
- Jojo.
Okay. When I ask a question,
I don't actually want an answer.
You don't?
No, I want you to wait an
appropriate amount of time,
till you feel just the
right amount of awkward,
and then I will
answer it for you.
Do you understand?
- But I was just...
- No!
Again, that is a question
I don't actually
want an answer for.
- Okay, but I was just being...
- Moving on!
Ciao!
All right, who here can tell
me why we practice so hard?
Oh, that's actually a question
I do want an answer to.
To express what's inside of us?
Nope.
So we can bond as a team?
Not even close.
To squash the dreams
of our competitors.
Ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding!
Yes! I smell a winner!
Go ahead, Tina!
- It's Nina.
- Back up! Listen!
Now, it's time for me to
make you all into winners.
All right? Back up! Spread out!
Two lines! Let's go!
No!
Come on! Come on, ladies!
- That is not low.
- You call that low?
Low, low, low,
low!
Stop! Everybody freeze.
Freeze, freeze, freeze. What
is going on around here?
And by here, I mean here.
What?
Jojo, your personality is
poking me in my eyeball.
You're sticking out
and pulling focus.
You know what you are?
You're a pop-a-color.
- Yeah!
- No, that is not a compliment.
Stop popping! There's
no popping. Pop it off!
Miss Thing, you
have to blend in.
You... you want me to... ha.
- Yeah, get it out.
- You can do it.
- Both: Blend.
- In.
- Um, Coach Poppy?
- You are?
- Afraid. Oh, I mean, hi.
- I'm Ruby D and she's Ruby M,
but most people just
call us the Rubies.
Apparently, it was
a very popular name
the year we were born.
There's also two
Olivias, four Sophias,
and a growing number of Avas...
I'm sorry, are
you still talking?
I stopped listening.
The glare from your
glasses is distracting.
- Okay.
I think what Ruby
is trying to say
is that Jojo is a great dancer,
maybe the strongest we have.
If you find yourself
drawn to watching Jojo,
- doesn't that just mean...
- No! No, no, no, no, no!
I don't want to see
individual faces.
I don't want to
see none of this,
or this...
Or this.
None of it.
I just want one glorious,
homogenized blob of
perfect technique
and if the Rubies can't
get with the program,
then, well, maybe the Rubies
can start a Jojo fan club
with all the free time
you have on your hands
when you're off my team.
- I'll do it.
- What?
I'll try harder to blend in.
- Terrific. Moving on.
- I love this place.
And she's still talking.
It's my second home,
and you guys, you guys
are all like my sisters.
Most weeks, I spend more time
here than I do at my own house
and when I'm here, I feel
like I'm at my favorite place
and I'm with my favorite people.
So I'll do it. I
can blend, watch!
See, look at me.
I'm a dancing robot.
I feel nothing.
Totally dead inside.
That good, eh?
- What is that?
- What? What is what?
That glittering
monstrosity on your head.
- Oh, this!
- This is a new product
to fluff my bun, actually.
- It's called a bun fluffer.
- That's not a bun fluffer.
That's a bow.
A big, happy, glittering bow,
and I do not like glitter, Jojo.
Who doesn't like glitter?
Look, Poppy, if
you want to be part
of Mr. Melody's Glitter Girls,
then I'm going to
need you to sparkle.
Give me sparkle!
Sparkle! Sparkle!
Ugh, stop.
Halt! Poppy, cease and desist!
I need some expression!
Give me this and this, and this!
Show her how it's done, girls.
- See, see, see!
- Look at your little sister!
If Rosie can sparkle,
why can't you?
Yes, Rosie, yes!
Give me Madonna!
Paula Abdul!
And Miss Jackson, 'cause
you're in control!
And I'm never going to stop.
Uh, uh, uh, excuse me, madam,
but there is no crying in
Mr. Melody's Glitter Girls.
But I saw you crying
in the parking lot.
Out!
You are hereby banished
from the Glitter Girls.
And FYI, Poppy, you will never
success if you can't sparkle.
What do you think is
happening right now?
Maybe she's having a flashback.
I am, I'm almost done.
Okay, I'm done. Where was I?
Ooh, I know!
And I do not like glitter, Jojo!
Right. And I do not
like glitter, Jojo!
And you are like human glitter,
and I just don't think you're
the right fit for this team.
- What? No, no, no!
- I will do anything.
- Anything?
- Anything!
Okay, well, if you want
to stay on this team,
then I suggest that you
find your sparkle switch
and turn it off.
Okay.
- Moving on.
- Form two lines, eyes on me.
Okay. We've got my bags.
Desi! Hey!
Jojo! Hi!
Aw, how are you?
- I'm good.
- Girl, should I call 9-1-1?
Because someone's
stolen your sparkle.
I didn't even recognize
you without your bow.
- Yeah. Me neither.
- New coach, new rules.
You, though...
you look fabulous!
I know, right?
The only good part about moving
away from my mom's new job
is that I could start
fresh at a new school,
new dance studio and
just be who I really am,
and this, is who I really am.
Aw, I love it!
You seem so happy, and
that makes me really happy.
So your new studio,
are they good.
- Oh, it'll do.
- But I miss you guys.
It's just not the same.
Trust me, literally
nothing is the same.
- These are some warm-up suits.
- What does P-PAC stand for?
Poppy's Performing Arts Center.
Jojo, be like Beyonce
and get in formation.
- Oh, these are so heavy.
- See you, Desi.
- Bye.
And there's so many.
Excuse me, guys.
Don't mind me! Sorry.
And now, formerly known
as Dance Mentions.
From Poppy's
Performing Art Center,
please welcome the P-PAC!
Wow, so precise and in sync!
So graceful, and yet,
I'm intimidating by them.
Almost scared.
That's exactly what
I was going for.
What in human combination?
Jojo, knock it off!
Then that lift at the beginning,
that was like the best
time we ever did it! I...
Hey, Desi! Congrats!
Oh my gosh, your
team was amazing.
- Stop, you're too kind.
- Tell me more.
- And you guys are fantastic.
I loved your solo.
Yeah. Nice solo, Jojo.
Apparently a fourth place
trophy is too embarrassing
to even bring home.
- Don't even sweat it.
- This competition is just
a warm-up to the first
position competition.
I'll see you there, right?
- Of course you will...
- Jojo!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations?
- How about you're welcome,
'cause you basically
gave 'em first place!
I mean, look at her.
What am I supposed to do...
Take this little thing.
Everybody else was
giving fierce blue steel
while you were out there
looking like human jazz hands
with a glitter manicure
and you know I do not
like glitter, Jojo!
I'm sorry, guys.
Listen, I tried to turn off my
sparkle switch, I really did.
Then it was like
the beat kicked in
and I just felt it in my bones.
It was like, my brain knew that
I wasn't supposed to sparkle,
but nothing told
my feet or my face.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know what, this
isn't working out.
We're breaking up with you.
- What? We are?
- No, we're not. We're not.
- Then I am!
- It's not you, Jojo, it's me.
- What?
- No, who we are kidding.
It's totally you.
P-PAC your bags.
Oh, and FYI, you will never
success if you don't learn
how to turn off your sparkle.
- I...
- No, no.
- Please just...
- Zip it!
Moving on!
Guys.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
You know, I've
gone to that studio
almost every day
that I can remember
and without it, I
don't know where to go.
Oh, sweetheart.
You know she tricked me.
Told me she wanted to
cultivate a competitive spirit
in our youth and
foster creativity.
- Yeah.
- Uh-uh.
Then she changed the locks
and didn't even invite
me to the competition.
That's why you weren't there!
Oh, and she also changed
the name of the studio.
- She didn't.
- She did.
To Poppy's Performing
Art Center.
P-PAC for short.
- P-PAC?
- P-PAC.
Oh, I'd like to P-PAC
her right in the face.
- Oh, wow.
I am so sorry, Jojo. I
feel like this is my fault.
It's not your fault, and I
don't want you to be sorry.
Coach Poppy is who
should be sorry.
Hey! We had a feeling this
is where you would be.
Are you okay, Jojo?
Okay, girls, come with me.
I want to show you something.
Even though it seems
everybody else is doing things
one way doesn't mean it's
the right way for you.
You don't need that studio
to do what you love.
If you really want to perform,
you'll find a way
to do it anywhere.
Wow! Look at this place!
What is all this stuff?
Odds and ends, just things
I've collected from decades
of putting on dance
recitals and shows.
- Are there mirrors in here?
- Oh, lots of 'em.
Do you guys see what I see?
Three, possibly four,
different kinds of spiders.
No. Potential.
Guys! I have an idea!
- Ooh, breakfast for dinner.
- Close!
Why don't we start our own team?
Uh, like a dodgeball team?
No, no, no, like a dance team.
Jojo and the Rubies.
We're already sound
like a rock band,
and there's still so much
time. We can make up a routine
and register for the First
Position Competition.
- I don't know, Jojo.
- It's a fun idea.
So fun, but the thing is,
Poppy says we're going to
win Nationals this year
and I've never won anything.
Not even "Solitaire."
Yeah. Part of me totally
wants to quit the team
and joins yours, but
the other part of me
knows my folks will kill me
because they already paid
for my competition costumes,
and since I'm both
a people pleaser
and a chronic rule
follower, I'm not quite sure
which particular part
to pick presently.
- It's all right, guys.
- It was just an idea.
- JoJo.
- No, really.
If you guys want to stay
in the P-PAC, I get it.
It's totally okay.
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
We're still going to hang
out on my birthday, right?
Are you kidding? We better be.
- Again.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
And one, two, three, four.
Lines, lines, seven,
eight, two, two.
What are you doing?
Five, six, you're looking janky.
Stop. Oh, y'all look a hot mess.
Y'all got my choreo
looking basic.
Take five and go get
better. Just... would you?
Hey, remember this?
Hey. What is that?
- What? What was what?
- Who? What? Where?
Knock-knock. Who's there?
What's that move? Do it again.
What move? This move?
- Oh, I like it.
- We're putting it in.
Let's go!
You're all right, Bobo?
I know, we haven't been
to a park in a while,
but suddenly I have a lot
of free times on my hands,
so you better get ready
because it looks like
we're gonna be doing
this a lot more often.
Hold on. You stay here.
I'll be right back.
Looks like I'm gonna
need more hot chocolate.
You wanna win?
Well, winning costs, and right
here is where you start paying.
Uh, yeah, so I knew
you would agree, girl.
Yeah, so I'm going to just
talk to you later, okay?
Bye-bye. Beep.
That was a really great
practice today, coach,
- really great.
- Spit it out, Phoebe.
- Ruby.
- Right.
I was just wondering
if we can end practice
on time next Saturday, I'm
having a few friends over.
How nice. What's the occasion?
Oh, it's nothing, my birthday.
Oh, fun!
So we can end practice on time?
- Of course not.
- We will stop when we're done.
- Oh.
- Also, what should I bring?
- Excuse me?
- To the party.
Oh, it's not a party,
more of a get-together.
Oh, even better.
It will be a bonding
experience for all of us.
- All of us?
- Yup, the whole team.
See you at 6:00, and no glitter.
- Hey, what's this?
- A dance team?
But we're not dancers.
Technically, I saw you dance.
You're just not a technical
dancer technically yet.
- Huh?
- I'll show you.
Pepper, remember when
you were playing football
and you... you faked
right, you ran to the left.
You did a little twist-twist,
and then you spun,
and then you spiked the
ball after the touchdown?
- Yeah.
- Let me see that.
Okay.
Hey!
All right, all right.
Jess, let me hear a
little... something.
Seven, eight.
Hey!
See, now that was a dance.
Sunnie, let me see
your best soccer move.
Okay.
Hey! That was incredible.
- Jess.
- I've got it.
Hey!
I did that?
- You did that.
- Should we all try?
All: Yeah.
Five, six, seven, eight.
- Whoo!
- Hey!
I wanna show you guys
this little dance
that I've been working on.
This is called the JoJo Jam.
Here you go.
You go back, forward,
pump, pump, kick,
kick, a twist, twist, slide.
Hey!
You see, dance is all
about expressing yourself.
Everyone has a little
sparkle in them.
You've just got to let it out.
Jess, let's hear a
little funky beat.
Hey!
- Hey, let's go.
- Hey!
- Hey, wait.
- Why are we doing this again?
Yeah, what gives?
Why do you want us to be
part of your dance team?
Well, my coach kicked
me off the team.
She said that I needed
to find my sparkle switch
and turn it off.
And I tried. I really did.
But what can I say? I'm sparkly.
So now I'm all on my own.
No you're not I'm in.
My first season, I
missed a penalty kick
that could have won my
team the championship game.
When I cried on the field,
my coach called me "Weepy"
for the rest of the year.
In third grade, Max Cohen said
I couldn't play football
with him at lunch
because he said I
played like a girl.
So I practiced every day
since to prove him right.
I'm in too.
My step-mom told me cheerleading
isn't a real sport,
so she wouldn't let me
try out for the team,
so now I make up
cheers around the house
encouraging her
to cook something
that actually tastes
good. I'm in too.
You know, it sounds
like we've all been told
that we don't fit in before.
On my last team, we
all had to be the same.
What if on this team
we celebrated
everyone being unique?
- Yeah.
Guys! Oh, yeah!
Who are all those people?
Looks like she found
some new friends.
Are you still going to tell
her we're using her moves?
Are you still gonna tell her
that she's uninvited
to your birthday?
You guys, we can
totally do this.
Do what, exactly?
Register for the First
Position Competition.
If you finish top three,
you qualify for nationals.
This year they're
in Springfield,
which is just a
couple hours away.
Do you really think
we have a shot?
Judging by what I just
saw, I know we do.
- Oh, my gosh!
If I tell JoJo I gave away
her moves, she could ask me
to tell Coach Poppy that
she can't have them.
I'm sure that
would go over well.
And if you tell JoJo
that Coach Poppy
is coming to your birthday,
she'll be nice and come anyway.
But Coach Poppy said no glitter,
and we both know
what that means.
So what do we do?
Hey, good practice, everybody.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good day, good day, good day.
That was awesome. We did it.
- Yeah. Hey, girls.
- Hi.
My Rubies!
Man, it's good to see you
guys. Come on, come on.
You gotta come in.
Check this out.
- Wow, it looks great in here.
- Thanks.
It's so weird not seeing
you every day. We miss you.
I know. I miss you guys too,
but hey, at least we're gonna
see each other at the
First Position Competition.
- Awesome.
- You're gonna come watch?
Close. I'm actually
competing with my new team.
- Cool.
- So cool.
Wow, so that's your new team.
I thought those were
just some new friends.
Well, I mean, they're that too.
- Bonus.
- Yay for new friends.
You guys, you're
going to love 'em.
Oh, actually, hold
on one second.
Sunnie, she forgot her
ball, which is so Sunnie.
I'll be right back.
"Which is so Sunnie."
Oh, my gosh. I just
made fun of her.
Why did I do that? I
don't make fun of people.
I'm a nice person,
or maybe I'm not.
Maybe I'm a terrible person
that doesn't want
JoJo to replace us.
- All right. Take a breath.
- It's perfectly normal for us
to feel jealous about
her making new friends.
- She looks so happy.
- I don't want to tell her
she can't come to my birthday
and bum her out again.
I can't believe JoJo
has got a new team.
And she's competing against us.
Do we tell Coach Poppy?
I don't want to
bum her out either.
There she is.
Ladies and gentlemen, the
girl who kicked so high
in fifth grade she gave
herself a concussion.
The only Jo who's so extra
she needed an extra Jo.
JoJo the Baroness
of Bows is back.
Desi, you are too much,
which by the way happens
to be the perfect amount.
Someone looks like
herself again.
What do you mean, my bow?
No, no, it's more
like your smile.
This old thing?
I'm glad to see
you're back to being
the rainbow glitter sparkle
dream queen that you are.
I mean, you're not wrong.
So where are the Rubies
and the rest of the team?
I've got my own team now.
Remember, ladies, second
place is just first losers.
First loser.  Loser.
Don't worry about her, guys.
What are you doing here?
I'm competing with my new team.
Didn't you guys tell her?
It must have
slipped their minds.
Hey, Nina, long time no see.
You guys look great, by the way.
- It's good to see you, JoJo.
- You look...
Like, I don't know what
team you belong to.
You guys don't even match.
That's because we're all unique.
Cute. So, JoJo, are you sad
that you're not with
the A-Team anymore?
No 'cause now she's
on the J Team.
That's right.
- I think your mom is calling.
- No, that's not my mama.
Mama, mama.
Oh, you don't know
my mother's ringtone.
- Yeah, I do.
- Tell her I say, "Hi."
- Ooh!
Mama, what?
Whoo-hoo! Go, J Team, go!
That's our move.
That human sequin
stole my choreography.
Hey!
And now give it
up for The P-PAC!
- All right, ladies.
- Let's go, let's go, let's go.
I want those lines. Hustle.
JoJo, I have to
tell you something.
Reba, will you please?
- It's Ruby.
- Join the crew. Thank you.
Did I just see
what I think I saw?
Yeah, they just
did the JoJo Jam.
Are they pulling out jump ropes?
Is that even legal?
Our third place winner,
who will be continuing on
to nationals, is Troop TNT.
- We're going to nationals.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Guys, don't stress, all right?
We danced our hearts out.
We don't need some
gimmick like jump ropes.
Second place, also headed
to the national level of
the First Position
Competition, goes to.
The J Team!
Thank you so much!
And the regional winner of the
All-American First Position.
Dance Competition
goes to The P-PAC!
- Whoo, yes! That's mine!
- Give it to me! Oh, I won.
- Congratulations.
Don't think I didn't notice
you trying to steal my moves.
Nice try, but it didn't work.
- Your moves?
- I'm so good.
- This is perfect.
- Right.
Good luck at nationals.
Only losers need luck, honey.
Moving on!
- JoJo, I can explain.
- I'm so sorry.
- Winners never apologize.
- Moving on!
Girl, when I say,
"Moving on," move it on.
Come on now, child, we
move on when we win.
- Guys, we did it!
JoJo, this was all my fault.
I know.
And I take full responsibility.
You should.
And I'm pretty sure your
neighbor is calling 911 on us.
Can we come in please?
Did you get the fruit
shaped like flowers I sent?
I did. Thank you.
And the flowers
shaped like fruit?
Mm-hmm.
Are you just going to ghost us?
- I've been busy.
- It's nothing personal.
I don't know if you saw any
of the TikToks I tagged you in
or the embroidered
pillow I had sent over.
You really can find
anything on the Internet.
Like the pillow says,
"I didn't offer
your moves to Poppy.
"She saw me doing them and
then put it in the routine
because she loved it,"
partly because it's
great choreography
and partly because I'm
such a skilled dancer.
I mean, do you know how
it felt to see my moves
in the hands of the coach
that kicked me off the team?
We are terrible,
terrible people.
I know I should have told her
that she couldn't have them,
but she scares me, and
for a split second,
it felt like she
almost liked me.
I get it.
I threw away my first bow to
try and get her to like me.
Guys, we can't let Coach Poppy
or anyone come between us, okay?
- Okay.
- It's a deal.
I miss you guys.
I'm so excited to party at
your birthday on Saturday.
Actually, I wanted to
talk to you about that.
What?
What is it? We're still
hanging out, right?
Our practice schedule
is so crazy right now,
I just think we should
postpone until after nationals.
What? No way. No.
All of us are under
so much pressure.
It's just not the right
time for my birthday.
- Not the right time?
- Are you kidding?
It's your sweet 16. We've
got to do something.
It's not a big deal.
Seriously, we'll party
after the competition.
Okay, I'm going
to get a picture.
- Yes.
- That was awesome.
The lights, the
crowd, the energy.
Yeah.
You think that was awesome,
just wait until nationals.
Who knew second place
could feel this good?
Hey, we made top three.
We get to move on.
That's all that matters.
I'll tell you what matters.
That Poppy person needs
to be put in her place.
- Yeah, I second that.
- She is not cool.
Agreed. Part of me wants
to win at nationals
just to see her face.
I think we can do it.
Look, you all did well,
but if you really want a
chance to win at nationals...
And squash Poppy's dreams.
That too.
Then we'll do whatever it takes.
Okay. Well, here's the thing,
it's not enough to do your best.
You really need to push
yourselves further.
You can't just dance
with your body.
You've got to dance
with your soul.
- Wait, did we learn that move?
- It's not a move.
It's a feeling.
Do you ever have that
feeling in your gut
when you wanted something so bad
and everyone told you
you can't have it?
I think she means like
when you're in overtime
in the finals
and you see the other team
starting to celebrate,
so you decide to school them
with a penalty kick that lands
with the sweet sound of you
ruining that pizza party
they thought they were
about to just have.
Oh, why didn't
you just say that?
- Are you guys ready for this?
- Yeah.
'Cause we're about to
go to the next level.
J Team on three.
One, two, three.
All: J Team!
Hey, thanks for coming
on such short notice.
I'm a big fan of your work.
Whoa, it's like
looking in a mirror.
This thing is oddly realistic.
You're very talented.
Hold up, I've gotta go get
the birthday girl to see this.
Sounds like someone's home.
Surprise! Happy sweet 16.
You're having a party.
More of a get-together.
Without me.
- I thought everybody was here.
- Is that the pizza guy? Oh.
Yeah.
It's just the pizza guy.
JoJo, wait.
Happy birthday.
How you doing?
- Okay.
- Really?
It seems like you've got
the weight of the world
on your shoulders.
Kind of feels like
somebody put my heart
in a blender and hit puree.
Ouch.
I think I lost my best friends.
One of them stole my moves, and
the other, she had
a party without me.
I'm so sorry.
I thought I knew them so well.
I know that Ruby D.
Isn't capable of
staying up past 10,
and I know that she has an
irrational fear of frogs.
- Frogs?
- Right. And Ruby M.,
I know that she has a secret
crush on her neighbor,
and I also could tell you
exactly how she orders pizza,
pepperoni, pineapple, no cheese.
- No cheese?
- Exactly.
So how is it that I know
so much about these girls,
but I never could have predicted
they would do this to me?
Oh, come here. Oh.
How they betrayed
me feels awful,
and it makes me not want to
be friends with them anymore,
but then I think about not
having them in my life, and...
And that feels worse.
You know, sometimes
friends outgrow each other,
and that's okay,
but try to understand
what was in their hearts
and at least
consider forgiveness
before you walk away.
People make mistakes.
It was all just so much easier
when we were at the old
studio and you were our coach.
Now with my own team, I...
I'm just afraid I'm going
to let everyone down.
- No way.
- You are a born leader, JoJo.
- Am I?
- Yes.
I just keep thinking
about nationals,
and I keep feeling
all this pressure.
Pressure to come up
with something different
to set us apart
from everyone else.
You know, Coach Poppy,
she busted out jump ropes,
and that really seemed
to wow the judges.
Yeah, well, she's
a doozy, all right.
I just feel like
we need something,
something different to show
them how special we really are.
I want you to close your eyes.
Go on.
Now I want you to envision
what your ultimate dream
performance would be.
My ultimate dream performance.
Singing.
It's always been my dream.
In my ultimate
dream performance,
it would be dancing and singing.
In front of a huge audience?
- How did you know?
I was a kid just like you.
Too bad it's only a
dance competition.
Is it?
I mean, just because everybody
is doing things one way
doesn't mean it's the
right way for you.
But what if they disqualify me
for doing things differently?
Well, at least you gave
them your dream performance.
Guys, I got a big
idea for nationals,
but no risk, no reward.
Are y'all with me? All: Yeah.
Heck yeah! J Team on three!
One, two, three! All: J Team!
Five, six, seven, eight.
Awesome day, everybody.
J Team, whoo!
You guys are looking great.
Thank you.
- JoJo!
- Whoa! Y'all scared me.
Sorry. We didn't want
to go in because...
- What are you guys doing here?
- Need some more moves?
Or are you here to uninvite
me to something else?
Sorry, I thought that was going
to feel better than it did.
I feel awful about what
I did on my birthday.
I know.
I got your texts
and snaps, DMs, PMs
218 to be exact.
Coach Poppy invited
herself to my party,
and I was too scared
to uninvite her
so instead I uninvited you.
It's all right, Ruby.
It is?
Yeah. Friends outgrow
each other all the time.
No, JoJo, please.
We were supposed to
be friends forever,
apart or together.
We are.
We were.
- Practicing your JoJo Jam?
- Oh, come on.
I've been practicing
all week.
- You're right.
- We messed up bad,
and I'll understand
if you never want to be
friends with us again.
Good, great, terrific.
Where did you get that?
We took it out of the
trash and saved it.
The three of us are a
team. We always have been,
and we need to be on
the same team again.
We want you to come back.
Am I missing something here?
It's Coach Poppy
who calls the shots.
She wants you back
on the team, too.
She said she made
a huge mistake.
Coach Poppy wants
me back on the team?
We all do. The whole team.
Even Nina said the team's not
the same without your sparkle.
We'll do anything
if you'll just come back
and dance with us again.
Come on. Let's get out of here.
- Wait.
- Maybe it's not what we think.
My team does need a lot of work.
Let's go.
But I made a commitment to them.
And Coach Poppy was right.
I do not belong in the P-PAC.
I'm me, and I like
bows and sparkles
and being exactly who I am.
And letting my team know
that they should be exactly
who they want to be.
Do you think there's a way
we can still be friends?
Maybe, but I'm
still sad, and hurt.
But we can try.
We'll take it.
And we promise we'll never
betray your trust again.
- Oh. Well, did...
- Did you get her back?
Um. No.
She said she doesn't want to
come back and be on the team.
-  Good.
Good?
- Well, yeah. Oh, come on.
- You didn't actually think
she was going to leave
her team, did you?
Oh, cute! You did.
Well, then why did you
ask us to go get her back?
Because I wanted to poke
a few holes in that pesky
self-confidence
of hers. You know.
Make her wonder whether
she made the right choice,
and hopefully drive a wedge
between her and her team
as a bonus.
We can't risk her winning.
You sent us to sabotage
our friend's team?
You used us.
Well, duh!
I told you we were going
to win the nationals.
And we will.
Hey, guys. What's the deal?
Nationals are just
a few days away.
What do you care?
Don't you have another team
to go practice with now?
What are you talking about?
Your old team, who
doesn't need so much work.
We know you're
going back to them.
We saw you with them at
Val's house this morning.
- Who? The Ruby's?
- Yeah.
The girls who stole your moves.
And didn't invite
you to their party.
Look. I know they messed up,
but they're my friends, too.
- People make mistakes.
- Yeah, we know.
Just like the mistake we made
wasting our time on the J-Team.
- No, no, no.
- Just hear me out, please.
- Go ahead.
- Go running off to your friends.
Don't worry about us.
- Yeah.
- We'll make it easy for you.
We quit the J-Team.
Jess. Pepper. Sunnie.
Guys, just hear me out. Wait.
- No thanks.
- I'm not in the mood.
Any of the J-Team
answer your calls?
Not yet, but I'll keep trying.
- How did I get here?
- I have no team to perform with,
but even worse, I let
all of my friends down.
- JoJo.
- I never meant to hurt anyone.
I know that.
All I ever wanted
to do is perform.
But, now I feel like the
universe is telling me not to.
Do I just listen
and give it all up?
Do you remember that day
I gave you your first bow.
You were so upset you couldn't
nail your triple pirouette
you wanted to quit.
But once you had
that bow in your hair
and the music started,
there was no stopping you.
I think I practiced
all day and night
until I wore a hole
in my kitchen floor.
I remember. Nothing's changed.
If you really want to perform,
nothing will stop you.
From all of the noise.
Might fall.
Ha. Well, well, well.
Look what we have here.
It's JoJo, everybody.
What does she have on?
Hey, guys.
You know, I was
really bummed to hear
that you didn't want to
come back and join us.
Where's the rest of the J-Team.
Oh. It's just me that'll
be competing today.
The rest of my team quit.
- Oh.
- I'm really sorry to hear that.
Thanks.
It's okay, though, because
I'm still going to perform.
I love performing.
My favorite thing, ever.
Nothing can stop me.
- Cute. Good luck with that.
- Moving on!
And now, the P-PAC!
- We're about to start.
- Where are the Rubies?
I don't know. I've looked
for them everywhere.
What are you doing here?
You should be on the stage.
- Go back out there, Sheena.
- It's Nina!
- Sheena be working my nerves.
- I swear I ain't gonna let her.
- Ha ha!
- The Ruby's parts
- are coming up.
- I know. Hold this.
Turn around.
I've got to put this
on me for one second.
You know what? You're going
to have to cover for them.
- But I don't know their parts.
- Yeah, yeah.
The show must go on, Trina.
- Nina!
- Who cares.
My part isn't over!
- Yeah, Honey!
- That is my girl...
Get me down! Get me down!
Ahh! What's your name?
What's your name? Help me!
Help me! Oh!
Ooh! Ooh!
That was unexpected.
I always knew she had a
little sparkle on the inside.
Well, you're next, kid.
Val. I don't know if I
can do it. Not alone.
Yes, you can.
But it's a team
competition, and we're...
Listen. None of that matters.
Winning isn't the goal anymore.
And now, please
welcome The J-Team.
- You remember that ultimate
performance you imagined?
Your only goal now is to
go out there and do it.
Just live your dream.
Just live my dream.
We love you J-Team!
What made you guys
change your mind?
The Rubies told us everything.
We should have listened to
you when you tried to explain.
We just assumed you'd want
to go back to your old team,
because you'd have a
better chance at winning.
Are you kidding me?
Whatever the result of this
competition, I already won.
- Pardon me. Make way.
- Coming through.
Hi. I need to
speak to a manager.
How very dare of you to put
the rest of us to shame.
Why do we even bother.
- Aw, stop it Desi.
- Your team was amazing.
What I want to know is
how you did that one move.
The one where you're
like "bam, oomf, cappa."
- That's the JoJo Jam.
- Of course it is.
I demand you teach
it to me ASAP.
- Anything for you, my friend.
- I knew her first, girls.
- Here you go, Jess.
- Woah!
- Yeah!
And Pepper, this bow is for you,
'cause it's spicy,
just like you are.
- Oh, yeah.
Each one of these
bows is unique.
Just like all of you.
It represents how
we're all different,
but we're all on the same team.
- Congrats, J-Team.
- Yeah, you guys were awesome.
Did Poppy kick you off the team?
She tried to, but we quit first.
Mm-hmm.
Well, technically
she kicked us off
while we were quitting, but
that's besides the point.
- It was mutual.
JoJo. We wanted ask...
And it's cool if
you want to say no,
we'll totally understand.
Can we be on the J-Team?
Well, since we are on our way
to the First
Position Competition.
World Championships.
I think we could use a
few extra J-Team ladies.
- All right, you guys.
- We've got a lot of work to do.
So we should get
started right away.
Are you guys warmed up.
All: Yes.
Good, 'cause it's time to party!
- J-Team! J-Team! J-Team!