THE HOLY MOUNTAIN premiered
on December 17th, 1926.
The reconstruction was based
on two nitrate copies:
A tinted version from the
Bundesarchiv-Filmarchiv, Berlin,
and another one in black & white from
the Fondazione Cineteca Italiana, Milan.
The intertitles were -
when available -
taken from the copy of the Bundesarchiv-
Filmarchiv or corrected electronically.
Missing titles were added with the
aid of the censor's certificate...
...from December 16th, 1926 that the
Deutsche Filminstitut...  DIF provided.
The restoration took place in 2001
in collaboration with...
...the Bundesarchiv-Filmarchiv, Berlin,
the Fondazione Cineteca Italiana, Milan...
and the Friedrich Wilhelm
Murnau Foundation, Wiesbaden.
Lab: L'Immagine Ritrovata, Bologna
Friedrich Wilhelm Murnau Foundation
Those well-known sportsmen...
...who participated in the making of
THE HOLY MOUNTAIN...
...ask the audience not to mistake their
performances for trick photography.
All shots taken outdoors were actually
made in the mountains,
in the most beautiful parts of the Alps,
over the course of one and a half years.
The big ski race
is performed by German,
Norwegian and Austrian
master skiers.
The screenplay to this motion picture
was inspired by actual events...
...that occurred during a twenty year
period in the life of the great mountains.
THE HOLY MOUNTAIN
A Drama Poem with scenes from nature
by Dr. Arnold Fanck
Dedicated to his late friend,
mountaineer Dr. Hans Rhode
with reverence
Direction and screenplay:
Dr. Arnold Fanck
Production design:
Leopold Blonder
Sculptures:
Karl Boehm
Nature photography:
Dr. Arnold Fanck
and his Freiburg School:
Camera Operators:
Hans Schneeberger / Sepp Allgeier
Assistant Camera:
Albert Benitz and Kurt Neubert
Studio photography:
Helmar Lersky, Hans Schneeberger
Original score:
Edmund Meisel
CAST:
The Sportsmen:
The Dancer Diotima - Leni Riefenstahl
The Friend - Louis Trenker
Vigo - Ernst Petersen
The Mountain Guide - Hannes Schneider
Colli - Friedrich Schneider
The Actress:
The Mother - Frieda Richard
Produced by the cultural department of the
Universum-Film joint-stock company, Berlin
PRELUDE
There, where the rock falls steeply and
defiantly into the surf... is her home...
The sea is her love, wild...
boundless...
But her life... is dance...
vibrant expressions of a stormy soul.
Diotima's Dance to the Sea.
Diotima: Dancer Leni Riefenstahl
And so Diotima dances... dances
to satiate her longing for him...
whom she has seen in her dreams...
atop the highest mountain peak.
END OF PRELUDE
TWO FRIENDS FROM THE MOUNTAINS
"The Friend"
Engineer Trenker
Vigo
Ernst Petersen, student of medicine
At the entrance to the Grand Hotel
DIOTIMA DANCES THIS EVENING
IN THE GRAND HOTEL
And Diotima dances in the country
of her desire.
DANCE TO THE SEA -
DREAMBLOSSOM - DEVOTION
DREAMBLOSSOM
She seems... almost holy!
Were any people from
the mountains here?
Did you see my dance?...
What did you enjoy most?
The friend rushes upward,
high into the mountains, to savor
his overwhelming experience.
DIOTIMA'S ASCENT
A jubilant spring climbs
higher up the mountain.
And a joyous Diotima
immerses herself in it.
Just then, "the Friend" begins
his lonely descent...
...from the icy brow
of the tallest peak.
In an alpine meadow.
The mountainside reveals nature's
ferocious power.
The imposing pinnacle of the
highest mountain rises before her.
The meeting.
Did you come from up there?
It must be beautiful there.
Beautiful... arduous... dangerous
What does one search for, up there?
One's self.
And nothing else?
And what are you searching for,
up here... in nature?
Beauty!
And nothing else?
AT HIS HOME
Today I climb in search of the most
beautiful mountain that exists.
And tomorrow?
Tomorrow we will celebrate our engagement
together... very high up there.
You seek Gods... but it's people
you must find.
I suppose you came all this way just
to see me, not the ski race.
Look for me at the jumping contest!
He wants to go up there again...
without me.
Take me with you one time - into
your world... really high up...
At least up to the cottage.
"The Sea and the Stone
can Never Be Wed."
Winter, still draped
across his mountain.
Look... those enormous rocks
have been worn away...
...by the gigantic force of water,
in nature's eternal cycle.
And all the debris left by these mighty
waters... they are our mountains.
Why is nature so beautiful to us?
Because we invest
our very souls in it.
You, too, are like nature.
And that's why I love you so much.
The bustle of winter sports.
The mountain guide
Hannes Schneider
Have you finished marking
the race route?
How's the competition looking?
You'll probably be beaten.
By whom?
Colli... the shepherd.
Never.
Colli
Friedrich Schneider
Say, if your Friend
doesn't participate,
there'll be no competition
in the long-distance run.
Take me with you!
What's wrong with you, darling?
FEAR!
I will be back in time
for your dance tonight.
Goodbye... until tonight!
The jumping event has begun.
Diotima goes to watch the ski jump.
Colli prepares for the his final jump.
In wonderful style,
Vigo determines the winner.
The young victor.
But far away from the sporting bustle,
the Friend...
...seeking the most beautiful mountain
- for tomorrow...
I'm not sure I can ride
such a steep hill.
Now where would my beautiful,
gentle Madonna like to go?
Wild and fantastic,
like a gothic cathedral,
rises from its mighty foundation...
- the most beautiful mountain.
THE LONG-DISTANCE RUN
Come back the winner,
and I'll grant you a wish.
The route is marked.
High atop his silent world.
Colli fights for the lead.
Colli leads.
75 miles per hour on skis!
Relentlessly pursuing Colli.
Vigo closes the gap!
Overtakes!
Vigo in the lead.
Colli far behind.
Vigo still leads.
The others continue
the wild chase.
The two favorites find themselves
far behind.
Don't give up, we're nearly the last!
Racing through the forest,
they no longer notice the fairy tale
beauty of the snow-covered firs.
Pushing for the lead.
Colli goes wrong
All wrong!
The end of the fight.
Just before the finish.
I'll get you yet!
Vigo...  Vigo!
He begins his descent
into the valley.
May I have my wish now?
And what does the victor desire?
THE DREADFUL NORTH FACE
ABYSS!
When he comes home today,
I have a surprise for him.
A new dance...
A hymn of Joy
I really think... she loves me.
Well, finally you appear!
Come with me, I need you.
We must scale
the Santo-north face.
Now?  In winter?
Are you mad?
You're my best friend.  Come with me.
We'll be mad together.
I'll come get you.
I must go away...
with a friend of mine.
- A magnificent man,
whom you should meet sometime.
The ski racers go to the cottage,
to celebrate the day's events.
What has come over you?
Sorry, Vigo.  It's not you.
But please do not ask.
To the north face of the mountain.
Before the dreadful Santo-north face.
Are you afraid to come with me?
Look, we should turn back.
The Foehn wind is coming down.
Let it come... the stronger the better!
And let storm and avalanche roar
their wild songs with it.
The very walls come alive
with the flow of the avalanches.
It comes boiling up from the valleys
in a terrible tempest.
TURMOIL!
Something must have
happened to him!
Snap out of it!
Do you hear me?
You really are mad!
Take me back down again!
Is there something you desire...
down there... among the rabble?
A dancer...
- Diotima
It was you!
VIGO!
And Diotima must dance...
her hymn of joy.
I can't fasten you to anything!
It's all ice!
Vigo...  I'd never do anything
to harm you!
I've gone with Vigo to conquer
the Santo-north face
I can dance no more!
You cannot just walk out in
the middle of a performance.
Our ski-master and his friend Vigo...
- have not returned
from the Santo-north face.
Are there mountaineers among you...?
Men who would climb up,
through this night, up to Sella cottage,
to alert the skiers?
Who among you will climb?
For my sake?
Was one man not enough for you?
Vigo...?  He is but a child!
They're all... children.
I am climbing up to the cottage.
I will find the way.
But no single man has the strength
to lift a body from an overhang.
Sacrificing the comrade -
perhaps one's self with him -
the greatest dilemma of the mountains.
THE DEED
We drink to the welfare
of our absent ski-master.
Nature unleashed!
Cut me free...
I can't bear it anymore.
At least save yourself!
Why... why?
How to we reach Mount Santo?
First down to the forest... then
over the bridge and up again.
Have you found the bridge?
Losing faith
Why?
HIS WORLD
And with the last of his strength,
he holds his friend, long since frozen.
Dawn breaks upon
his tormented soul.
A peaceful calm settles upon the frozen
world, and upon the soul of Diotima,
who at last learns the fate
of her beloved.
Fallen!
He has fallen!
He held onto his fallen friend the whole
night, and thus sacrificed himself.
Among us, the greatest attribute...
is loyalty.
Peace lies upon the eternal sea...
silently it spreads,
rolling out in broad waves, to soothe
the world's suffering and strife.
Above it all looms a Holy Mountain...
a symbol of the greatest values
than humanity can embrace...
fidelity... truth... loyalty...  FAITH
END
Music: Aljoscha Zimmermann
Ensemble
Sabrina Zimmermann - Violin
Antonio Clavilijo - Cello
Dieter Paell - Percussion
Markus Steiner - Percussion
Aljoscha Zimmerman - Piano
Sound engineer - Thomas Schmaelz
Recorded in April 2002
Violetmedia Soundstudio, Munich
Film transfer and digital postproduction
Wagner & TaunusFilm