I want you to know!
I left!
But... but I'm not dead!
There's a village
called Le Forge
and if you follow the road,
you come to the sea!
In the sea, there is a boat.
I live in it.
You can even stay here
if you come!
It'd be nice if you came!
You can write to me
care of the Café du Forge.
They're friends of mine.
Ludo.
OK, this time you've got pâté,
sardines, bread and milk!
How's that?
And I put in some candles.
- I want a stamp too.
- A stamp?
Nicole!
Got a girlfriend now?
Then I'll buy you a shirt
next time.
All right.
Got a bottle of Monbazillac
and some biscuits?
Don't hide, Ludo.
Don't be a smart aleck.
Say hello to me.
I told you to air out this place!
You're nothing but a pig!
You mustn't save fish heads.
They smell bad.
OK, so you don't want
to talk today either.
I'll read you something.
They put their ears
against the door and listened.
Not a sound.
The wolf had gone away.
The danger was gone.
Nothing to fear.
So they ran to their flutes and
fiddles that they had never left
and began to sing
and dance again.
Who's afraid of the big bad wolf,
the big bad wolf!
Who's afraid of the big bad wolf.
Tra-la-la-la-la!
The wolf,
who was waiting at a distance,
heard their music and singing.
It was all he could do
to keep from laughing.
He had fooled them!
So he got an old sheep skin,
a big basket and a...
What are you doing here?
I've told you over and over,
not to come up here!
I have to teach him something.
You won't let him go to school.
We can't let him rot up here.
You know he's a half-wit!
You're disgusting,
you little idiot!
- Come on!
- I'm sorry!
Hello, Ludo.
Well, say hello.
Hello.
Today you're eating with us
and two guests.
Did you wash this morning?
I've brought you some clothes.
Hurry up and get dressed.
How dumb can you get?
Come here!
It buttons up the front.
Let's drink to it.
Pour us some champagne!
Micho,
do you want to talk now or later?
I'm not very young,
but I'm well off, as they say.
I'm very,
very happy to marry Nicole
and I agree to take Ludovic too.
I'll be sort of his,
his father.
You're not his father.
You're my father!
Be still, Tatav!
My boy.
That's all I have to say.
I was sure my daughter and you
would make a good match!
Don't just stand there.
Go wash it off!
Ludo, eat your food
before it gets cold!
You don't talk much.
You will in time.
Why doesn't he talk more?
He has always been that way.
You'll call me Papa, won't you?
You're not his papa!
Of course I am!
He gets a father,
you get a mother!
You don't lose anything!
Why doesn't he go to school?
He soon will, just wait.
We'll enrol you, won't we son,?
Look... you've even got
a ring for your napkin,
with your name on it, LU DO VIC.
And I'll show you
how to fold it, OK?
You're reading upside-down.
I've got lots of comic books!
My father bought 'em for me.
Who is your father?
Micho.
He is not! Liar!
Mother said it was Micho.
That's a lie, you dumbbell!
Your mother's not your mother.
She's your sister.
And I'm not your brother.
My father is not your father,
Have you ever seen your father?
And you!
- Me?
My father's
the richest man in France!
Why do you groan at night?
I don't groan.
Your mother says you're strange.
I don't like her.
You are strange,
but you're a nice kid.
Here!
Don't grind your teeth tonight.
Come on, hurry up!
But tomorrow, for once,
you'll go to school with Tatav!
And you!
Me? Don't expect me,
to take you to school every day!
Now you behave and be polite.
I don't want to!
Go on in!
This is Ludovic Bossard,
our new pupil.
Go sit in the back, son.
And so,
Julius Caesar exclaimed
to Vercingetorix
I said go sit in the back.
Are you deaf or what?
And you!
And so Julius Caesar
exclaimed to Vercingetorix:
"Of all the peoples in Gaul,
the Belgians are the bravest!"
Repeat that, Bossard!
Well, Bossard?
Can't you repeat that?
And you!
Come with me!
Get up there!
On your knees!
Now will you obey?
I'm sorry.
First put my pillow up,
Now go sit on the stool.
How's the weather?
Sunny.
I'm sure it must be windy.
How's school going?
Answer me.
You just won't talk.
Did you put this here?
That's nice of you.
But these aren't flowers.
My favourite flower is the rose.
Have you ever seen roses?
You never want to talk at all?
Why do you groan at night?
I don't groan.
Yes you do. Sounds weird
in the middle of the night.
Mama said you weren't all there.
It's too windy here,
it's exhausting.
That's why I keep catching colds.
Mama used to put cups on me.
Take away this tray,
I'm through.
And go get the glass cups
in the kitchen!
Now do you understand?
You light it.
Then you press hard,
but not too hard.
Try one on yourself first.
I'll feel safer.
Slide your finger under the cups.
That's right.
Turn around and shut your eyes
till I say to open them.
All right.
If you can't do it right,
just quit.
What are you doing?
I'm freezing.
Take them off quick.
How old are you now?
Five.
You're more than five years old,
you idiot.
You're eight years old.
Eight years.
That was eight years ago.
It was so hot that summer.
We took ten dips a day,
but that didn't help.
We kept eating ice cream
at the café on the canal.
Look at me.
Get out of my sight.
Ever been with a girl?
Been where?
You really are a moron.
I've been with one.
We even felt each other's weenie,
or rather I felt hers.
And it cost me.
Weenie!
Cost me five bubble gums
for her weenie! Two for her tits.
Is that the one you want?
It's for your father?
No, it's for Mother's Day.
isn't it too big for your mother?
- And you!
- What did you say?
It's that one she wants,
she told me so.
It costs 4,000 francs.
3,700 francs.
- Is that enough?
- No, not quite enough.
All right, take it.
If your mother
wants to exchange it, she can.
- Have you seen my mother?
- Your mother?
She's a phony. She only
talks to me when Papa's around.
Ludo.
Ludo come here.
Where did you get that?
At the Bazar de Paris.
Why did you give it to me?
You always say
our knives don't cut.
It's not a knife to eat with.
What good is it anyway?
It's a present.
But the money...
Where did you find it?
It's a present.
Must've cost a lot.
At least it'll cut good.
You're capable of
stealing the money.
Who did you steal it from?
From Micho?
Tatav?
Who then?
If you won't answer,
then you are really a thief.
A dirty little thief.
From my purse?
Is that where you got it?
You stole from
your own mother's purse?
A liar and a thief!
You'll be punished,
you dirty little thief!
Dirty little thief!
Before going to his study,
Prince Jean enjoys family life
like all other fathers.
The little princes
are delighted to be with him.
Little Princess
Marie-Astrid is proud
to show how she spins her top.
My gold bracelet is gone.
You had it last night.
Where did you put it?
If I knew, I wouldn't ask.
I've looked all over.
It didn't just disappear!
Have you seen it?
Well, can you beat that!
I found it all by myself.
But where?
We looked everywhere.
I'm the one who found it!
But tell me where.
Where we put our shoes.
I found it in a shoe!
Take that dirty thing away!
It is full of germs!
What ever gave you the idea
to look there?
You deserve a reward.
What would you like?
Come and say good night
in my room this evening.
Well, that's easy enough to do!
But you'll be sorry
if your room is a mess!
Now go and play.
I'm not an idiot!
I'm Ludo!
Will you two stop that!
Shut up!
Can't hear yourself think
in this dump!
If you keep that up,
you'll turn him into a priest!
A dirty bigot like you!
And I don't want that!
Why did I marry an old man?
What do you want to be later?
Me?
A plane driver!
You mean a pilot.
You could be a sailor.
Sailors are cute!
They wear bell-bottoms
and blue collars.
They see the world.
Where are they?
In the navy.
You'd wear a nice cap.
But with your silly ears...!
Queen for a day!
How'd you get here?
We're on vacation.
Tatav'll be home
from school tomorrow.
Why are you so quiet!
when you walk around?
You're becoming a dirty sneak!
Did you take a bath
in my bathroom?
No I didn't.
I could smell your odour.
I had to air it out!
It was my father
who took a bath there.
Micho, you mean.
Who is my father?
Stop talking nonsense!
I'm not! I saw my father!
He came after me in a car.
Don't be a smart aleck!
That's enough, get out.
He steals, spies on me,
rummages through my things.
He's a maniac.
I can't stay here alone with him!
He's not like us,
but he doesn't do any harm.
I get nightmares!
His green eyes stare at me,
as big as balloons!
That's not his fault!
- Is it my fault?
- Calm down.
You know,
I can't sleep when I want you.
I won't let you!
Not as long as that idiot's here!
For the baby you want,
forget it!
I won't have a baby
if he stays here!
You promised
to put him in a home!
OK, I'll write to my cousin.
You keep saying that,
but you don't write her.
Come and help me, please!
Have a drink!
You don't drink enough
for your age.
Women! Nothing but bitches!
Berthou...
She told me she doesn't sleep
with fat guys.
Than...
She said I'm ugly and
have blackheads on my nose.
I'm ugly too.
And people say I'm not all there!
And you're a Jew too!
A Jew...
I don't care. Anyway, I'm fat.
Not as fat as you used to be.
Don't waste your breath, pal.
You know...
I don't want you to...
go to the nuthouse.
Your mother's
going to send you there.
That's not even true.
Come on, we're going for a drive.
Come on!
That's Cordouan over there
and Saint-André.
When there's no fog,
you can see the lighthouse.
And that over there?
What's that?
A military base, obviously.
With a French flag on it!
It was an American base before.
I'm cold.
Come on,
let's get something to drink.
Do you know that cafe
on the canal?
A glass of Monbazillac
and a glass of Martini.
My name is Ludo.
I know how to read labels.
I can even write sort of.
I can remember good
with my memory too.
Six sardines in anchovy oil,
4 tablespoons every 24 hours
to fortify the body,
- and Jesus is the Son...
- Yes, all right.
Do you like this place?
Yes, it's nice.
We drank grenadine
and soda in those days.
My parents knew the woman here.
She hasn't changed.
She liked me.
She called me her "Sunshine".
She didn't recognise me today.
On festival days, my parents
let me come here with Marie-Jo.
Who was Marie-Jo?
A friend of mine.
She was jealous of
my nice dresses and my long hair.
So she said I had ugly hands,
but I don't.
Jealous!
Yes, she imitated me.
If I carried a purse to mass,
she carried one too.
But actually,
we weren't at all alike.
We went to the beach together.
We used to meet here.
I met him at that table.
He made us laugh with his accent.
Who?
The American.
- Hello, Will!
- Hello.
Tonight, love-amour,
we're celebrating!
...that I danced in your arms!...
Don't touch me, you bastard!
It's from my cousin
at the Saint-Paul Home.
She agrees to take Ludo in.
Is it a home for crazies?
No, just feeble-minded people.
My cousin runs the place now.
He'll be well treated there.
Health card, birth certificate,
papers, papers!
We'll have to tell her!
Your ID card ought to do!
I'm not his mother,
it was an accident!
Then who is his mother?
Me? Tatav?
Tell him everything
while you're at it!
- All night! All night long!
- Shut up!
Tell him what they did to me,
everything I had to do!
Shut up!
When am I leaving?
You scared me!
What are you talking about?
In the first place,
how do you know you're leaving?
At night, I hear you talking.
The truth is,
I like you.
I don't want you to go there,
understand?
It's your mother.
She says you're not all there!
What's that place I'm going to?
It's...
It's a sort of home!
A home for children.
But I'm not a child!
No, you're a grown-up boy now.
- But the others, they're...
- Jealous!
And can I come back?
If you don't, I'll come and get you!
I'll come to see you!
So will Tatav!
I could've learned
to work with you!
If your mother sees you,
she'll get mad, so run along.
Sit in this chair.
Tomorrow you're going
to the Saint-Paul Home.
It's a home for children...
who are difficult.
You'll be well treated. Micho's
cousin will look after you.
You never spread
enough butter on.
At home, I had fresh croissants
every morning.
With Mother's
home-made blackberry jam.
Are you listening?
I'm talking to you!
Yes.
Yes, Mama!
When you are polite, you say
"Yes, Mama."
Say Mama .
Never!
You've never said
"Mama" to your mother!
Go on, say it!
Go ahead, you idiot!
Say it!
Just for once!
You don't want to.
You don't want to say "Mama"
to your mother!
You're right, you shouldn't,
because I'm not your mother,
understand?
It was an accident!
Every time I see you,
I see those three guys!
I hear them
under that yellow lamp!
Every time I see you,
I see those three bastards!
I'm not your mother, understand?
I'm not your mother!
They're your mother,
all three of them!
It's those bastards!
Those three bastards!
Bastards!
This is the boys' wing.
The girls have the other wing.
This is your room.
It overlooks the garden.
My name is Ludovic Bossard,
I'm 5 foot 6.
Me, I'm OK.
- It's my ...my mother who...
- Yes, I see.
My name is Mademoiselle Rakoff.
Understand?
Yes, Mamzelle Roff.
RA KOFF, if you don't mind.
- Mademoiselle Rakoff.
- All right.
Good!
You make your bed every morning.
You can use the grounds, but
you're not allowed to go beyond.
You're not allowed to hide,
or to go into the girls' wing
or to lie down during the day.
Those are
the only regulations here.
Do you have any questions?
Where is the sea?
We're not near the sea,
you know that.
The sea is very far.
You can see we're
in the middle of a forest.
That's not even true.
Don't be impolite!
Unpack your suitcase
and join us
in the chapel for a concert.
- At what time?
- Time?
Where do you think you are?
Time doesn't exist at Saint-Paul.
I blow my whistle
for each activity in the day.
Understood?
I'll see you later.
Now you all know Ludovic,
our new friend.
Will he please come up here now.
The sheep stands for your soul.
If you are good and pure,
it will be close to the Lord.
If not,
it'll be far behind the others,
far away from Jesus.
Bless us, oh Lord.
Bless this food
and this gracious table.
Provide bread
for those who are hungry.
So be it. Amen.
I made it.
It's for my mother.
When I go home,
I'll make one for you.
I'll get the shells out
on the breakwater.
Come here!
It's a good thing
your parents didn't come today.
It makes you think about it.
Maybe they had a flat.
My mother once had a flat
and I fixed it.
Yes, maybe so.
Come and talk to me
whenever you're unhappy.
And remember,
we're your family now.
Your real family.
That's not even true!
Why didn't you come?
I have...
a...
necklace...
with...
mussel shells.
But...
if you don't come,
I can't give it to you.
And...
when can I go back home?
Lise!
You're not allowed to be late!
- Be on time from now on!
- I don't care!
That's enough!
Odilon, stop it now.
Calm down.
That's enough, calm down.
Ludovic's going to apologise to
you in front of everyone.
He stole my picture!
Let him go, Doudou!
What picture?
Of my mother.
- She didn't come to see you!
- It's mine.
- Thief!
- That's enough!
That'll do now. You'll be
forbidden to talk for six days.
Until you agree,
I'll keep this picture.
But it's my mother!
My mother!
It's my mother!
At this rate,
you'll soon cover the ceiling.
This home is a family,
Ludo, a family!
Yes it is.
When I say "Ludo is our child",
this means...
you are our little boy.
That's a lie!
I'm my mother's son
and that's all!
Your mother!
A fine mother indeed!
She should've taught you
to be polite!
I'm not to blame
if she doesn't come.
I hear she's pregnant!
Just an act, I bet!
So stop bugging us with your mother!
Shut up!
You!
You're just like me!
No-one comes to see you either!
You haven't got any
husband or any children!
No-one loves you!
And your hair is all grey!
You're an old lady!
Here's a letter
from your stepfather.
And my picture?
What picture?
My mother's picture,
the one you took.
You don't think
I'm going to give it back.
It's not your mother.
- She gave it to me.
- Liar.
How old is she?
And her hair?
She has long red hair.
She's not an "old lady",
you mean.
I'll give her the picture,
when she comes to see you.
Lise!
Poor little Ludo.
He's unhappy
because he hasn't got his mama
to hug him and kiss him.
She has not been nice to you.
Poor little sweetheart.
I feel sorry for you.
I'm almost your mother here,
aren't I?
I can give you
all the love you need.
Do you think I was down here
by accident?
I know you come here with a girl.
Tell me which one!
It's not even true.
You do dirty things with a girl!
With a mother like yours,
I'm not surprised.
What kind of a son
can you expect from a slut.
Anyway, I'm sending you away.
I can go home?
Home?
You don't have a home, idiot.
You're going
to the insane asylum.
- Understood?
- I won't go.
You won't go?
We'll see about that.
I won't go.
My mother's coming at Christmas,
for sure.
She's calling for me
at Christmas.
I don't want to go
to the madhouse!
Little Jesus,
when you descend from Heaven...
Hasn't your girlfriend
answered yet?
By the way,
some cops came by this morning.
We don't see cops often here
and we don't like 'em.
They were looking for a nut
who escaped from the crazy house.
No-one like that around here,
we said.
I've been hunting for you
for half an hour.
Hello Ludo.
I hurt myself climbing up
and I got my dress dirty.
How can anyone live here?
You've come to get me?
Yes, how did you know?
This is your room?
Why didn't you come at Christmas?
At Christmas?
What a silly question.
I had other things to do.
Well, now here I am.
I've come to talk to you.
It's time we made up.
That's right.
If you want, I can be a sailor
and we can go away.
Wait a minute...
You've ruined my life.
Because of you,
I had to marry an old man,
but now we're getting a divorce.
Even after you left,
you spoiled my life.
I was always scared
you'd do something awful.
To think you've
never called me "Mama"
and yet you wanted me to come
and see you? No way.
But you...
you've never loved me.
Don't start
talking nonsense again!
I've never been able
to stand the sight of you,
but that has changed too.
I'm getting married again.
Mademoiselle Rakoff likes you.
She's willing to take you back.
You can't keep living here
like a tramp.
Why not?
Listen to me.
Calm down.
From now on, we'll be friends,
alright?
Call me "Mama", Ludo.
Call me "Mama".