[both laughing]
- [Red gasps]
- [screeches]
- [Red yells]
- [distant buzzing]
- [both shriek]
- [letters clinking]
[ominous music]
[rain pattering]
[hurried footsteps]
[whimpers]
[shrieks]
[splashes]
[screams]
- [pipe rumbling]
- [splashes]
[squeals]
[thuds]
[shrieks]
[snickers]
[gasps]
[ominous music]
[screams]
Huh?
[foreboding music]
[shrieks]
[manager] May I take your order, ma'am?
[Granny] What would you recommend
that I'd really like?
[manager] Uh, this.
[Granny] And this one, right here.
- Mm-hm.
- And a salad, I think.
[manager] Of course.
Oh! Ah.
[Chuck grunts]
- [manager] Hello. Welcome.
- Huh?
Have you a reservation, sir?
[chuckles]
Uh! Um, Gra... Grace, under...
- [Grace grunts, sighs]
- [Chuck groans]
Right on time.
[chuckles]
- [manager] Uh-huh.
- He's not here yet?
I have a reservation under Grace.
[manager] Uh...
Um, hmm.
Uh-huh? Hmm?
- [Chuck groans]
- Mm?
Uh, really nice to meet you.
Ah, and it's nice to meet you.
[chuckles]
[rain pattering]
[Grace] Declared missing
from a shipwrecked ocean liner,
only to return alive
after five-and-a-half years
on a desert island.
[chuckles]
Ever since I first read your story,
I've been dying to turn it into a book.
Thanks for being here.
You're way more handsome
in real life than in your pictures.
[spits, coughs]
- [Grace] You haven't had lunch yet, right?
- Uh...
Um, not yet.
That's good. I ordered ahead for us.
[Chuck] Oh. Uh, thank you.
Let's just cover the basics
while we're waiting for our lunch to come.
Is it all right if I record?
[Chuck] Yeah, it's okay.
- [recorder clicks]
- Right.
How have you been since your return?
Busy, I guess.
Adjusting to city life again
has been a little rough.
Has it, now?
Oh! Are there strange habits
that you can't break
from your life in the wild,
like capturing and eating pets,
or running around town
with only a spear and a loincloth?
[gasps]
Uh, no.
Not like that at all.
It's just it hasn't been easy
being around this many people.
[gasps, sighs]
Yes, of course.
Well, I really appreciate
you doing this interview.
I had heard you were turning down
everybody that asked for one.
Well, I've been rather torn about that.
I've been worried that no one
would believe what I've been through,
not all of it.
But there are some
remarkable little creatures
that the world should hear about.
"Remarkable creatures"?
But weren't you stranded
on the island all alone?
[sighs deeply]
I was alone, and yet I wasn't.
I discovered some special friends.
What kind of special friends?
Sounds pretty mysterious.
- [Chuck] After the ship went down...
- Hm?
I floated in a ducky tube
until I spotted an island.
A desert island so small,
it took five steps to walk
from one end of it to the other.
[sighs deeply]
[Chuck] And after six long months
alone on the island,
something happened.
[sighs]
[rock scraping]
[sobbing]
[laughs]
[groaning]
[yells]
[Chuck groaning]
Hmm?
[gasps]
[Chuck panting]
[Chuck grunts]
[Chuck whistling]
[gasps]
[light music]
[upbeat music]
[Chuck sighs]
[Chuck grunting]
[sighs]
- [waves crash]
- Uh! Uh.
Huh?
Huh? Mm? Ah.
[Chuck humming]
- [wood clanks]
- [Chuck screams, grunts]
- [snaps]
- Ah!
[grunting]
[Chuck screams]
[water splashes]
[panting]
[grunts]
- [thuds]
- Oh!
[laughs]
[cheerful humming]
- [thumps]
- [gasps]
[groaning]
Ah!
[smooches]
[laughs]
Huh?
[gasps]
Oh!
Huh?
[gasps]
[grunting]
[paper rustles]
Dude, it's rescue time!
[laughs]
- [panting]
- [motor engine clanking]
[grunting]
- [rope snaps]
- [gasps]
- [rope cracks]
- [groans]
- [grunting]
- [clangs]
- [stomach rumbles]
- So hungry.
[groans]
[light music]
[squelches]
[Chuck cheers]
[squishes]
[grunting]
[light music]
Ha-ha!
[chuckles]
[munching]
[muffled chuckle]
[gulps]
[slurps, munches]
[gasps, retches]
Wow, is that fish? Ew!
[sighs]
Huh? Ahh.
[both gasp]
[squeaking]
[excited humming]
[chuckles]
Hmm? Hmm?
[grunting]
- [rock thuds]
- Phew.
- Ah!
- [both gasp]
[gasps]
[slurping]
[smooches]
[slurps]
[groans]
[screams]
Uh? Huh?
Huh?
[gulps, sucks]
Woo-hoo!
[Chuck grunts]
[yawns]
[sighs]
[snoring]
[both laughing]
- [Chuck snoring]
- [wrapper rustling]
Ah. Huh?
[grunts, gasps]
Uh, hmm?
Uh, huh?
[clatters]
Hm?
- [farts]
- [slaps]
[shushes]
Huh?
Uh...
[snickers]
[gasps, screams]
[both scream]
[gulps]
Ooh!
[squeaking]
[both laugh]
Uh, huh?
Huh?
[grunts]
Stop right there!
- [Chuck yells]
- [both scream]
[gasps, groans]
[Chuck yells]
- [both screaming]
- [thudding]
[grunts]
- [both scream]
- [thumps]
[whooshes]
[grunts]
- [yells]
- [thuds]
- [grunting]
- [both scream]
[Chuck panting]
[screams, gasps]
[thumps]
- [screams]
- [both laugh]
[moans, grunts]
- [thuds]
- [laughs]
[grunting]
[all screaming]
[thwacks]
[both shriek]
[grunts]
[screams]
[yells]
[munching]
- [yells]
- [thuds]
- [crackles]
- [engine starts]
[whirs]
[gasps]
[both scream]
No!
- [thuds]
- [whooshes]
Stop!
[pants]
No, no, no!
Stop!
[engine revving]
[playful music]
[loud ringing]
- [explosion]
- [Chuck gasps]
[groans]
Huh?
Uh...
[sighs]
[warbles]
Huh?
[whooshes]
[thuds]
Huh? Ahh.
- [farts]
- [slaps]
- Uh...
- [shushes]
- [grunts]
- [both scream]
Uh... ah.
[laughs]
The bugs couldn't be real, though.
- [Chuck] Pretty hard to believe.
- Huh?
I get that.
Truth is, I didn't believe it
at first, either.
Being stranded on an island
with weird little bugs like them.
[shudders]
- [keyboard clacking]
- Uh...
Oh, could you describe again
how the bugs looked?
Plus, did you name them?
Names, huh?
Yes, of course.
The red one who's always
ticked off is Red.
And the stretched-out
long one's name is Yellow.
- [Grace] Yellow.
- And together, I called them...
- I called them Larva.
- [Grace] Larva.
Uh, yes!
There were two bugs, and he called them...
- [Chuck] Oh, hang on there.
- Huh?
There weren't just two.
There was a third.
[Grace] A third bug?
[Chuck] Yeah.
A primitive one living in the jungle.
Like a cave bug or bug Tarzan.
[gulps]
- [sighs]
- [stomach rumbles]
Uh...
[munches]
[retches, spits]
[snorts]
[chuckles]
- [snarls]
- [gasps]
[thumps]
- [roars]
- [both scream]
[leaves rustle]
[both screaming]
[both panting]
[exhales heavily]
[snorts]
Ooh!
[munching]
[gulps]
Wow!
- [stomach rumbles]
- [sighs]
Huh?
[mumbles]
[snorts]
Ah!
[grunting]
[muttering]
[foreboding music]
[gulps]
[gasps]
Ah!
[laughs]
[munching]
[gulps, sighs]
- [stomach rumbles]
- [gasps]
- [farts]
- [groans]
[panting]
- [farting]
- [screams]
[Chuck whistling]
Huh?
[sniffs]
[gasps, groans]
[sniffs, gasps]
- [farting]
- [groaning]
[sighs]
- [stomach rumbles]
- [groans]
- [screaming]
- [farting]
[gasps]
[Red groaning]
[mumbling]
[screams, gasps]
- [Red farting]
- [bug mumbling]
[laughing]
[gasps, screams]
- Ooh!
- [thumps]
[gurgling]
[bird mumbles]
[gasps]
[slurps]
- [screams]
- [thumps]
[squawks]
- [farting]
- [groans]
[steel clanging]
[clattering]
[slurps]
[suspenseful music]
[liquid sloshing]
[sloshing continues]
- [Red grunts]
- [bug] A-ha!
[Red squeals]
[thwacks]
[groans]
[gasping, screaming]
[mumbles]
[Red groaning]
[munching]
Oh!
[gulps]
Huh?
- [mumbles]
- [nervous giggle]
- [chirping]
- [gasps]
[ominous music]
[snarls]
[screams]
[squawks]
[squeals]
[screams]
[grunting]
Hmm?
[screams]
- [gasps]
- [bird snarls]
[squawks]
[rasps]
[thuds]
[tense music]
[bird squawks]
[panting]
[bird snarling]
[Yellow screaming]
[bird screeches]
[both screaming]
[gasps]
- [gasps]
- [screams, sighs]
- [thumping]
- [groaning]
[saliva plops]
[both screaming]
[thuds]
[yells]
[grunts, snarls]
[gasps]
[squawks]
- [stomach rumbles]
- [groans]
[both grunting]
[grunts]
- [Yellow gasps]
- [bird snarling]
[Red shouts]
[grunting]
Uh?
[caws]
[calm breathing]
[bird caws]
[tranquil music]
- [stomach rumbles]
- [screams]
- [farting]
- Huh?
[sniffs]
[squawks]
[thuds]
- [both screaming]
- [thuds]
[whooshes]
[cracks]
[splashes]
[gasps]
[grunts]
- [farting]
- [thumps]
[snarls]
[screams]
[farting, groaning]
[grunting]
[Yellow screams]
[gasps]
Ah!
[chiming]
- [bug moans]
- Huh?
- [blowing air]
- [thumping]
[coughs]
Ah!
[thuds]
[mumbles]
[chimes]
[gasps]
[grumbles]
- [moaning, laughing]
- [farting]
[snorting]
[squishes]
[munching, laughing]
[gulps]
[squeaks]
[slurps]
[stomach rumbles]
[burps]
Ooh!
[farts]
[groans]
Uh.
Ah!
Oh!
[laughs]
[grunts]
[snarls]
[giggles]
- [mumbles]
- Oh!
[lively music]
[munching]
[Red yells]
[grunts, yells]
- [gasps]
- [branch snaps]
- [thuds]
- [screams]
[babbling]
- [roaring from distance]
- Huh?
[sighs]
[gasps]
[grunting]
Uh...
[screams]
[thuds]
- [gasps]
- [vine snaps]
[thuds]
[groans]
Huh?
[light music]
[gasps]
Huh?
[sighs]
[giggles]
[mumbling, laughing]
Uh...
- [thwacks]
- [screams]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[slaps]
[sobs]
[snarls]
[mumbles]
Huh? Uh...
Mm.
[grunts]
[laughs]
Whoo-hoo!
- Uh...
- Huh?
[leaves rustle]
- [giggles]
- [mutters]
[munches, gulps]
[sniffs]
[chomping]
[Red] Uh...
[gasps]
- [grunts]
- [slaps]
- [snarls]
- [squeals]
[mumbles]
- [squishes]
- [laughs]
[festive music]
[Yellow giggling]
[humming]
[gasps, laughs]
[grunts]
A-ha!
[chuckles]
[gasps]
[smooching]
[both gasp]
[yells]
[somber music]
[Red sobbing]
[thuds]
[grunting]
[yells]
[groans]
Huh?
[mumbling]
[whimpers]
- [slaps]
- [groans]
- Uh...
- [both mutter]
[muttering]
Huh?
[rain pattering]
Uh.
[gasps]
[sighs]
[sobs]
[scraping]
- Ah...
- [Red babbling]
[babbling continues]
- [branch snaps]
- [Red groans]
[Red babbling]
[slurps]
[roars]
- [Red babbling]
- [thwacks]
[Red squeals]
- [vine rustles]
- [thuds]
[sighs]
- [screams]
- Huh?
[heartbeat]
[gasps]
[laughing]
[grunting]
- [smooches]
- [gasps]
[yells]
[sobs]
[panting]
[whimpers]
- [approaching footsteps]
- Huh?
[sobbing]
[yells]
[gasps]
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
- [thuds]
- [smooches]
[gasps]
[both laugh]
[calm music]
[Chuck] After that,
they were always together.
- [Grace] They were always...
- Red had the biggest crush on her.
[both chuckle]
Turns out bugs are just like
little slimy people.
Hmm, uh...
[laughs]
Uh...
Um...
[chuckles]
I see that you don't believe me either.
Hey, I really don't not believe you.
Unexplainable stuff happens
all the time in this world.
[Grace] Just the fact
that you were stranded
and came back is an incredible story.
Yeah, well, guess that's true.
Um, then it was you and these three bugs
stuck on the island together
the whole time?
Well, no.
It wasn't just me and the bugs.
[calm music]
[grunts]
Hm?
[gasps]
- [squishes]
- [squeals]
[both screaming]
[screaming]
- [mumbles]
- [yells]
[both screaming]
[thumps]
- Uh?
- Ooh!
- [crate rumbles]
- [both scream]
[foreboding music]
[both scream]
- [thumping]
- [both screaming]
[crashes]
[both] Huh?
[whimpers]
[both] Uh...
[Chuck sobbing]
I miss you, Clara.
[continues sobbing]
[whimpering]
[seal panting]
[chomps]
[both gasp, laugh]
- [snoring]
- [plops]
[gasps]
- [panting]
- [chuckles]
- [barks]
- [Yellow chuckles]
[howls]
[both] Woo!
- Woo-hoo!
- Hee-hee!
[splashes]
[thumping]
[grunting]
- [clapping]
- [all laughing]
[whines]
- [waves crash]
- [both] Huh?
[all sigh]
[humming]
[all gasp]
[sighs]
[seal humming]
[sobbing]
[Chuck] Clara.
[sobs]
Clara!
- [seal barks]
- Huh?
[pants]
Clara?
[grunting]
[gasps]
[eerie music]
Clara?
[wind howls]
[barks]
- Clara?
- [barks]
You are not Clara!
[pants]
- [Chuck] Huh?
- [twinkles]
"Clara"?
[gasps]
Ugh.
[whimpers]
- Huh?
- [Clara pants]
[barking]
[humming]
Uh... Hmm.
[chuckles]
[snoring]
[both mumbling]
[barks]
[both gasp]
[panting]
Huh? Uh...
[Chuck] Clara?
- Clara!
- [all gasp]
- [water splashes]
- [both gasp]
- Mm-hm. Mm-hm. Yes.
- [both muttering]
[both yell]
Clara, now flip.
- [thumping]
- Good. Good, girl.
- Now, dance.
- [slapping]
[chuckles]
That's right.
All right. Come on, Clara.
[both grunting]
Clara?
[all gasp]
[both scream]
[Chuck] Clara?
[all gasp]
[thuds]
[grunts]
- Clara.
- [barks]
[in slow motion]
Clara.
[both grunt]
That's good, Clara.
[farting]
- [barks]
- Huh?
[both laugh]
[all laughing]
[groans]
Come, Clara!
- [both] Huh?
- Right. That's it.
- [grunts]
- [farting]
Uh? Huh?
Clara!
- [Yellow farts]
- Clara!
- [Chuck] Clara!
- [Yellow farts]
- Clara!
[whimpers]
[all grunting]
- [Chuck] Let go of that flipper!
- [barks]
[Chuck] Uh?
[both gasp]
Uh, huh?
- [Clara whines]
- Clara, where are you going?
[whimpers]
- [both gasp]
- Clara.
- [Chuck gasping]
- [water splashes]
- [Yellow farts]
- Clara!
- [splashes]
- [Chuck sighs]
[grunts]
This is completely your fault!
[yells, grunts]
[groans]
- [thumping]
- [grunting]
[gasps, groans]
[grunting]
[humming]
[both grunting]
- Huh? You're humming?
- [Red mumbles]
[all humming]
[humming continues]
[vocalizes]
[all humming]
[screeching]
[cawing in harmony]
[all humming]
[gasping]
[cawing in harmony]
[gasps]
[Chuck sighs]
- [both sigh]
- [Clara humming]
[both gasp]
Huh?
[Clara humming]
- [both laugh]
- Clara!
- Stop it, you stinking bugs!
- [yelling]
Uh? Huh?
[whimpers]
[Chuck] Clara.
Mm-hm.
[muffled chuckle]
[barks]
Ah, Clara!
Oh!
[Chuck] Clara!
[chuckles]
- [imitating Clara humming]
- [Grace] Uh... Oh!
[giggles]
Are you serious? A singing seal?
Yes. Whenever I heard Clara's song,
I felt happy and warm.
[laughs]
This is some tale.
Bugs that act like little people
and a singing seal?
What comes next?
Does an alien visit the island in a UFO?
- [laughs]
- [Chuck] Speaking of...
[gasps]
What?
There was one there.
[thunder rumbles]
[Chuck] An actual alien.
[suspenseful music]
[whirring]
[munching]
[whooshes]
[burbles]
[clangs]
[clanking]
[whirring]
[crunches]
[warbling]
[metal clanking]
[calm music]
- [Chuck grunting]
- [sand rustling]
Choice. All right!
[snickers]
Ah.
Hmm.
- [thumping]
- [Chuck grunting]
[groaning]
Uh?
A little one.
Maybe I could just...
- [thwacking]
- [groaning]
[grunting]
[Chuck yells]
[screams, grunts]
[splashes]
[groaning]
[yawns]
Mm-hm.
[gasps]
- [slaps]
- [snickers]
[babbling]
[warbling]
[digital whirring]
- [beeping]
- [both gasp]
[camera shutter clicks]
- [chimes]
- [whirring]
[both gasp]
Huh?
[laughs]
- [thumps]
- [laughs]
- [burbles, clicking]
- [both laugh]
[thwacks]
[both squeal]
[panting]
[metal clanking]
[thuds]
- [robotic murmur]
- [both gasp]
[metal clanking]
[robotic muttering]
[both screaming]
[whirring]
- [pops]
- Huh?
Huh?
[bubbling]
[laughing]
[yells]
[both squeal]
[rattling]
[both laughing]
- [thuds]
- Huh?
[robotic muttering]
[both scream]
[thuds]
[Chuck grunting]
- [hard thump]
- [groans]
Are you kidding?
[both scream]
[sand rustling]
[foreboding music]
- [both screaming]
- [Chuck whimpering]
Uh? Huh?
[both panting]
- [Red squealing]
- [metal clanks]
[plants snapping]
[whirring]
[whooshing]
Ooh! Scary.
[plants whooshing]
Huh?
Uh?
- [plants snapping]
- [cutter whirring]
[robotic muttering]
[both sigh]
[thumping]
- [snapping]
- [panicked gasp]
[gasping]
[Yellow farts]
[robotic muttering]
[both gasp]
[Yellow farts]
- [thuds]
- [whimpers]
[clangs]
[thwacks]
- Hmm?
- [thuds]
Huh?
Ooh! I was a massive band geek.
[plays music]
- [both squeal]
- Huh?
Uh...
- [leaves rustle]
- Wha...
[thumps]
[Chuck groans]
[screams]
[whirs, beeps]
[whooshes]
[thuds]
[both gasp, grunt]
- [whirring]
- [both scream]
[grunting]
[squealing]
- [approaching footsteps]
- [robotic mutter]
[screaming]
- [low whirring, beeping]
- What are you, now?
- [clicking]
- Uh, huh?
- [slaps]
- Ha! Scary.
[both laughing]
Huh?
- [rattles]
- Huh?
[Chuck] Hey, are you a...
Crabsformer?
[whirring]
- Uh...
- Oh!
[whirring]
[Chuck giggles]
- [clicks, whirs]
- [Chuck] Oh!
[whirring]
- [snapping]
- [humming]
[thumping]
[sighs]
- [metal clanging]
- Huh? Come here.
[playing upbeat tune]
[thumping]
[thuds]
Oh! It's done!
Woo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
- [water splashes]
- [cheers]
[grunting]
[burbles]
[robotic mumbling]
[digital static]
[suspenseful music]
[clanking]
[zaps]
[laughs]
[Chuck] Oh, yeah!
- Rescue, rescue, rescue.
- [whooshes]
Ow! Ah, that's hot!
- Hot, hot, hot!
- [flame crackles]
Hot!
[groans]
[Chuck screams]
[whooshes]
[explosion]
[somber music]
[screams]
[groans, gasps]
My boat!
[flame crackling]
[clanks]
[robotic mumble]
[sobs]
[chuckles]
We didn't hit it off at first.
But I guess I owe him,
because he helped me build the boat
that got me home.
Uh, yeah.
- The Crabsformer.
- [keyboard clacking]
[manager] Your lunch is served.
- [exhales]
- [chuckles]
- [clanks]
- Huh?
[manager] Mangia!
- [Grace] Huh! Oh!
- [Chuck gasps]
- Uh...
- [Chuck] Oh, this is...
[stutters]
It's crab.
Uh, I didn't think...
- [Grace] Uh...
- [snickers]
[thumps]
[munching]
Hmm? Don't you want some?
- [Chuck munching]
- Mm...
- [Chuck] Mmm!
- Ah, why not?
[rain pattering]
[slurps]
It's really yummy.
I'm crazy for crab.
- [chuckles]
- [clacking]
Great! I'm very happy to hear that.
Hey, wait!
What kinds of things did you eat
on the island to survive?
It was hard.
I was hungry all the time.
- Huh?
- Let me tell you something about fish.
They don't care if you caught them
fair and square!
Uh, right.
[manager] And here's your coffee.
- Uh, thanks for that.
- Uh...
Although, Larva helped expand
my dinner menu.
[calm music]
[Booby mumbling]
[grunts, gasps]
- [stomach rumbles]
- [gasps]
[munching]
- [mumbles]
- Ah.
[humming]
- Huh?
- [laughing]
- [mumbles]
- [both gasp]
[sniffing]
[gasps]
[lively music]
- [mumbles]
- [gasps]
[gasps]
[shrieks]
Huh?
[plops]
[Booby sighs]
[sniffs, groans]
[sniffs, barks]
[flaps, sniffs]
[sniffs]
Huh? Huh?
[all sighing, gasping]
[panting]
What's that smell?
[mumbles]
[all munching]
[all gasp]
[Chuck] The savory aroma of seaweed
enfolded my entire body.
It was like waltzing with the waves.
And that ribbon of sweetness on top,
is making all my senses
do somersaults in sheer delight!
[bird cawing]
- [munches]
- Oh!
- [smooches]
- [giggles]
[screams]
- [squelching]
- [mumbles]
[munches]
[snickers]
[Booby spits]
[thuds]
Oh, my! That's great!
[retches, spits]
[all chuckling]
[sobs, grunts]
[thumping]
[squelches]
[screams]
- [thumping]
- [grunting]
[flame crackles]
Huh?
[screams]
[Red grunting]
[yells]
[rock clatters]
[grunting]
[inhales, grunts]
- [whooshing]
- [Red grunting]
[thuds]
[munching]
- [spits]
- [squishes]
[sighs]
Uh...
[giggles]
[gasps]
[mutters]
[muttering]
[sobs]
[bird panting]
[munches]
- [gulps]
- [screams]
[spits]
[chomps, retches]
- [spits]
- Oh!
[water splashes]
[gloomy music]
- [all gasping]
- [laughing]
[sobs]
[thunder rumbles]
[sobbing]
- [yells]
- [thunder rumbles]
- [cracks]
- [gasps]
- [screams]
- [water splashes]
[coughing]
[baby mudskipper coos]
[munches]
[smooches]
[gulps, giggles]
Huh?
[pants]
- [chomps]
- Hmm?
- [thwacks]
- [mutters]
- [Red groans]
[thuds]
[giggles, mumbles]
[all munch, gasp]
- [giggles]
- [Red grunts]
[action music]
[yells]
Hmm?
- [mumbles]
- [grunting]
Whoo!
[grunts]
[farts]
[laughs]
[screaming]
[chuckles]
[thudding]
- Huh? It's...
- [all gasp]
[Chuck] It's the island on a plate!
We're about to eat our entire island!
[all gasp]
[munches, gulps]
[Chuck] Oh, yes!
So refreshed!
[sniffs]
Wow!
[Chuck] I am one with this fish.
Yes! Smack me with your life force!
But there's deeper flavor.
True treasure!
Felt only in a humpback whale's
bellybutton.
Yes! The fabled rainbow clam!
The entire island plate.
Dare I say, the entire earth
is in my mouth,
massaging my taste buds!
- [all cheer]
- [laughing]
[grunts]
[whooshing]
[explosion]
- [all gasping]
- Oh! Huh?
[chiming]
Porridge?
- [Chuck] For real?
- [laughs]
[all gasp, mutter]
[all slurp, munch]
[slurps]
Mmm. Mm?
Ooh, what's this?
[gasps]
[all sigh]
[laughs]
- [grunts]
- [Yellow gasps]
[all munching]
[Chuck] This tastes familiar already.
[Chuck] This yearning...
I can't stop.
- This...
- [clangs]
...tastes just like my mom's porridge.
- Ah. Oh!
- [thuds]
[Chuck's mom] It's all right, my dear boy.
[wailing]
Mom!
[all wailing]
Huh?
Mom, can I please have one more bowl?
[sobs]
Mm-hm.
[all sobbing]
Hmm?
[slurps, munches]
[all screaming]
[munching, spits]
[all retching]
[thwacks]
- [all grunting]
- [Red squeals]
[Chuck] Is that your...
[screams]
[retches]
What, the bug's throw-up?
[groans]
Sounds gross, but it was so good.
- [Wendy laughing]
- Uh... Huh?
Mister, your story's
the funniest thing ever!
Tell us some more!
- [manager] Oh, Wendy.
- Huh?
You know you're not supposed
to bother the customers.
[chuckles]
Sorry, I apologize.
- [manager] My daughter is very curious.
- Hmm?
Uh, no, I'm fine with her hearing.
- You?
- Huh?
Mm, uh, all right, yeah!
She's very welcome.
Yay!
[giggles]
- [laughs]
- [manager] Okay, but be quiet.
Right, I'll be quiet, Dad.
[rain pattering]
[Grace] Well, shall we get back to it?
- [giggles]
- [Chuck slurps]
Can you tell us about Larva
in greater detail?
Uh-huh.
Hmm. Well, uh...
One minute, they're
at each other's throats,
then, turn around, and they're
risking their lives for each other.
[birds cawing]
- [water splashes]
- [Chuck grunting]
Fishy, you're mine!
How long has it been since I've had fish?
Whoa! Ooh, no!
[groaning]
- [thwacks]
- Oh!
[groaning]
- Huh? Huh?
- [Larva laughing]
[both laughing]
- [slaps]
- [thuds]
[both laughing]
[grunts]
I've had enough of you brats!
Go away!
[both blows raspberry]
[grunting]
Take that!
[Chuck] You guys ruin everything!
- Oh!
- [thumps]
[laughing]
[splashes]
- [screams]
- [squeals]
[thudding]
[screams]
[yells]
- [grunting]
- [Red squeals]
[gasps]
[mumbles, gasps]
[muffled scream]
- [squealing]
- [gasps]
- [loud thump]
- [thuds]
[both yelling]
What is this?
Hmm? What the...
[Chuck] Get off my sacred food!
- [thuds]
- [groans]
Oh, you beauty!
[smooches, laughs]
[gasps]
[Chuck humming]
You're gonna taste amazing!
Now, make a little fire.
- [squeaks]
- [humming]
[groaning]
- [Chuck] Yes! Burn, baby!
- [hisses]
Burn! Burn! Yes!
- [thuds]
- No! So close!
And yet so far!
But hey!
- What's this?
- [match rasps]
[snickers]
- Lucky me!
- [flame crackles]
Here we go! Here we go!
[grunting, yelling]
[pants]
- [sizzles]
- Huh?
[screams]
[muffled screaming]
[gasps, screams]
Mm. Lovely aroma.
- [Yellow grunting]
- Hmm? What?
Why you...
[puffs]
[match rasps]
[snickers, gasps]
[groans]
Go away!
- [match rasps]
- [Yellow puffs]
[gasps]
Stop it, all right?
I mean it!
Just let me grill my yummy fishy.
Huh?
[yells]
- [sizzles]
- Ah!
- That's how you want it?
- [match snaps]
[gasps]
- [sizzles]
- Hot!
[grunts]
[screams]
Now, it's your turn!
Burn!
[sizzles]
[screams]
[grunts]
[yelps]
- [bones crack]
- [whimpering]
[groans]
- All right, fish, where were we?
- [thuds]
- [puffs]
- [screams]
- Seriously?
- [whistles]
- [yelps]
Dinner is finally served.
- [splashes]
- [Chuck groaning]
[whale hums]
[whimpers, screams]
Why are you doing this? Why? Why?
Well, we'll see who wins.
[gasps]
[Chuck] Only one match left.
[gasps, grunts]
[Chuck] Stubborn little booger.
All right.
Draw.
[tense music]
- Ooh, look! What's that?
- Huh?
[laughs]
[gasps, screams]
- [farts]
- [snickers]
- [thwacks]
- Huh?
[grunting]
[laughs]
[farts]
[screams]
Oh, that's so disgusting!
Huh? Where's my match?
[gasps]
Oh, please don't let it go out!
Curse that farting bug!
[gasps]
[Chuck] Come on!
[yells]
[farting]
Hold on, flame, here I come!
Gas boom!
[flame roars]
[flame crackles]
- [panting]
- [sighs]
It worked!
It's burning! I win! I win!
[laughs]
[gasps]
[laughing]
Beautiful fire!
[laughs]
[squeals]
[screams]
[grunting]
- [grunts]
- [thumps]
- [gasps for air]
- [muffled yelling]
[laughs, screams]
[thwacks]
- [thumping]
- [groaning]
[heart beating]
[ominous music]
[popping]
Happy fish party!
- [thwacks]
- [groaning]
- [splashes]
- [Chuck] No.
Come back! Come back!
[sobs]
[burbles]
[narrator] The life of a pollack fish.
After the narrow escape,
the pollack's relief is short-lived
for there are countless dangers
that lurk in the ocean.
However, in the fierce struggle
for survival with its natural enemies,
the pollack has become
stronger and smarter.
Our pollack turns out to be a female.
With spawning season upon her,
many males begin their overtures.
The flashy movements of one male
are eye-catching.
The female pollack is interested.
- So begins their pollack romance.
- [smooching]
[screams]
[narrator] First comes love.
And then, of course, comes...
a hundred thousand to a million
little fishy miracles.
And when the time comes,
they will leave their parents' embrace
to start a new journey in the vast world.
Like their parents, they must survive
many hardships and seek out a partner,
so that they may fill the world
with little miracles of their very own.
The life of a pollack fish.
Fin. The end.
- Wow! Awesome!
- [chef] For real?
Those bugs are like a phoenix
or something.
Yes, they are. Those little boogers
could survive any danger ever! Uh...
- [chuckles]
- [gasps]
[groans]
- Uh...
- Chuck.
Lots of people seem interested
in this story of yours.
It's the first time that's happened.
- [Wendy] Mister!
- Huh?
Please! Please keep telling us your story!
This is the best story I've heard
in my 84 years on Earth.
So true!
I'm dying to try some of that
tasty bug cuisine.
Mmm-mmm.
Your lunch is on me,
if you agree to tell us some more.
- Uh...
- [Grace] Chuck?
- Chuck!
- [gasps]
Are you all right with them hearing
the rest of the interview?
Uh... Mm-hm. You bet.
I'm really touched you all wanna hear
what I went through.
- [Grace] Uh...
- Yay!
Uh, um... Great! Good!
Hmm.
If I'm honest here,
this is hard to swallow.
It sounds like a fantasy movie.
And you haven't heard the half of it.
I haven't even gotten to the crazy stuff.
[ominous music]
- [Chuck humming]
- [thumping]
Huh? Why is it so cloudy today?
Ah, who cares?
I've still got the best boat.
[laughs]
And today, wait for it!
We add the umbrella sail!
- [laughs]
- [bottle plops]
[humming]
- [wood thuds]
- [gasps]
Uh, wha... Why is this...
- Huh?
- [squeaking]
- [gasps]
- [snickers]
[thumps]
Did I ever tell you until college,
I was on the soccer team!
Ha! Rotten bugs!
- [wind whooshing]
- Ha, breeze feels nice.
- [umbrella pops]
- [gasps]
Oh, no! Ah!
- [water splashes]
- [gasps]
[Chuck sobs]
[yells]
[laughing]
[thwacks]
It's all because of you, bugs!
- [thunder rumbles]
- [Chuck] It's all because of you, bugs!
[both panting]
Ah, this ends right now, you hear?
No, you don't!
- [thuds]
- [groans, gasps]
You're done living up to your name.
[screams]
[squeals]
[screams, groans]
[thunder rumbles]
- [crackling]
- [groaning]
- [thudding]
[splashes]
- [birds cawing]
- [waves crashing]
[Chuck] Uh... Oh, my head.
What happened again?
Oh, right, lightning.
Those annoying bugs.
[groans]
Little monsters.
I can't wait to turn them
into puddles of goo on the beach.
[gasps]
[gasping]
[screams]
What the...
Who's that? This is not happening!
This can't be!
[whimpers]
Huh?
[gasps]
[slurps, munches]
[screams]
- [Chuck] A bug! A bug is me!
- [farts]
[both scream]
What have you done to me,
you horrible nightmare?
- [thwacking]
- [both grunting]
- [bird screeches]
- [both] Hmm?
[wings flapping]
- Food!
- [Yellow mumbles]
Oh! Finally!
[pants]
Uh? So big!
- [caws]
- [screams]
- [thuds]
[laughs]
[Chuck panting]
[cawing]
- [thumping]
- [gasping]
[groans]
Stay back!
Nice chicken.
[Chuck whimpering]
[screams]
[mumbles]
- [smooches]
- [gasps]
- [nervous chuckle]
- [groans]
- [yells]
- [thwacking]
- [thumps]
- [groans]
- [Chuck] Huh? You now?
- [metal clanks]
[Chuck] Come on!
Sorry, I pushed you so darn hard.
- [robotic muttering]
- [Chuck] Please don't hurt me!
- [Chuck yells]
- [robotic muttering]
[groaning]
Ooh!
[laughs]
[thumps]
[cheers, gasps]
[gasps, yelps]
Huh?
- [cheers]
- [stomach rumbles]
Oh!
[grunting]
[farts]
[farting]
[birds chirping]
[groans]
- [screams]
- [mumbles]
Ah! Somebody help!
- [thuds]
- [gasps]
I'm trapped in a madhouse!
[munching]
Mm! Yum!
[sobbing]
I'm a gross and revolting ugly bug.
Chicken tried to eat me whole.
That even worse...
[munching]
[Red laughs]
[gasps]
[chomps, giggles]
I just thought of them
as dumb little awful bugs.
- [ship horn blares]
- Huh? What? Sounds like... Oh, my!
[pants, gasps]
[ship horn blares]
[gasps]
Ah! I'm here! Please help!
Huh? What the...
Oh, bug, right.
- [thunder rumbles]
- Huh?
[Chuck] Just like the last storm.
Huh?
[Chuck] Really?
All right!
[Chuck] Look. Yum, yum, yum!
You know you want it!
[Yellow mumbling]
- [Chuck groans]
- [slurping]
No, not yet!
[gasps]
Huh? All right!
[Chuck] Here it comes!
- [bird screeches]
- [Chuck screams]
Not now! Let go of me!
[Chuck grunts]
Please! That boat was my ticket back home!
[sobbing]
- Huh?
- [farting]
[all screaming]
- [bird caws]
- [groans]
[gasps]
- [farts]
- [yelps]
[crackling]
[screams]
[gasps, panting]
[mumbling]
[sighs]
Of course, it was only a dream.
- [loud blaring]
- Huh? Is that a ship?
Yo, over here!
There's someone here!
- [Yellow farting]
- Uh...
[both laughing]
Why, you little rotten bugs!
Think that's funny, do you?
[both whimpering]
[groans]
[sighs]
Hmm.
[Chuck] I'm sorry for acting so mean.
[yells, grunts]
Ow! That hurts!
Why, you rotten little bugs!
[groans]
After that stuff, I was able
to understand them better.
- [Grace] Oh.
- [slurps]
[insect buzzing]
Huh?
- [loud thump]
- [all gasps]
Uh! It was a force of habit.
- I'm sorry!
- All right. There, there.
[chef sobbing]
[clears throat]
So you're telling us you shared a bond
with your bug buddies?
Yeah.
But not just my bug buddies.
With Clara, Booby, Crabsformer.
Mudskippers as well.
We were trying
to survive together, after all.
[all] Hmm.
Oh! I'm sorry, little fly!
- [rain pattering]
- [thunder rumbles]
Ah, the thunder's so loud!
- [chef] Oh!
- Wendy, it's all right.
Daddy's here, darling.
Is it gonna storm?
Looks like we're in
for some temperamental weather.
Weather.
The weather on the island
was absolutely cuckoo.
Either burning hot or freezing cold.
[Chuck] Freak tornadoes
would rip up out of nowhere.
[wind howling]
[thuds]
[Chuck] Why have icebergs
completely surrounded the island?
[Chuck screams]
[air hisses]
- Huh?
- [Clara whines]
[all gasp]
[wind whooshes]
- [robotic mutter]
- [crab burbles]
[squawks]
- [squeals]
- Huh?
[Chuck] Save me!
- [flame crackles]
- I'm not gonna be an icicle.
We have to burn everything we can.
[thudding]
[cracks]
[rips]
[yells]
No! The fire's going out!
There's nothing else to burn.
[Chuck] What do we do?
[gasps]
[pops]
[mumbles]
[grunts]
[muttering]
[munches]
[squeals]
[burps]
[gasps, screams]
[all gasping]
- [air hissing]
- [gasping]
[Chuck] Lighter. My lighter!
- There you are.
- [lighter clicks]
[all gasp]
[ominous music]
[rattling]
[farting]
[clinking]
[roars]
[whooshing]
[clanking]
[flame roars]
[sizzles]
Ha-ha!
Huh?
[both whimper]
[laughing]
We're saved, Clara!
We're saved!
- We thawed up! Yahoo!
- [barks]
[laughs]
[groans]
What is that stink?
[groaning, farting]
[mutters]
[smacks lips]
[gasps]
[thunder rumbles]
[both laughing]
[thuds]
[mumbles]
[both gasp]
[both scream]
- [thwacks]
- [all shout]
[thumps]
[both mumbling]
[thunder rumbles]
[screeching]
[both scream]
[thudding]
[all gasp, scream]
[groans]
Hungry.
[bugs panting]
You little devils!
- [thumps]
- What the...
Uh? Wha... A fish?
Ooh! I love you!
[smooches]
- [thumps]
- Huh?
[clanks]
What's happening?
- [barking]
- Cla... Clara?
[grunts]
Clara, why are you flying?
[groaning]
[wind howling]
What the...
Typhoon!
[screams]
[all screaming]
[groans, gasps]
[bird squawks]
[thumps]
[all groaning]
Save me, please!
- [thudding]
- [Chuck whimpering]
[squawks]
[thuds]
[panting]
[shrieks]
Ah, cave door's blocked!
[grunts]
Huh?
[mumbles]
- Ooh!
- [all mumble]
[Clara barking]
[Chuck gasping]
[screams]
Oh, quick! Quick!
[grunts]
Come on!
[Chuck] Please.
- [thwacks]
- Ooh!
[thwacking]
[groaning]
- [thwack]
- [Chuck] Ah!
Ugh, my butt!
- [all gasp]
- The rock is coming loose.
[grunting]
[wind whooshing]
Can't keep holding on!
[gasps]
[all grunting]
You guys...
[gasps]
Huh?
[all gasp]
Uh, has it passed?
[all cheering]
Whew!
Uh. Huh?
[whimpering]
I guess it hasn't passed!
[groans]
[screams]
[squawks]
Clara!
[all screaming]
[grunting]
[clatters]
[grunts]
Huh?
[whooshes]
[screaming]
- [grunts, screams]
- [thuds]
[gasps]
- [clinking]
- [grunting]
[snickers]
Huh?
- [rumbles]
- [all screaming]
Ah! No!
- [squeaks]
- [all screaming]
[thudding]
[shrieking]
[all screaming]
[groans]
[all gasp]
[calm music]
- Hmm?
- Uh...
Awesome.
[all screaming]
- [whale hums]
- Uh, a whale?
Uh...
[gasps, grunting]
[yelps]
- [crackles]
- Watch out!
- [zapping]
- [screams]
[groaning]
[Chuck] Is that the...
eye of the storm?
Are you kidding?
The storm's eye is an actual eye?
- [Booby mutters]
- Well, let's give it a poke.
This is pretty messed up right here.
[screams]
[wood clatters]
We've got to put that big eye out!
Come on, you guys!
[grunting]
Ready? Fly!
[whooshing]
[squawks]
[whooshes]
[caws]
[barks]
[all grunting]
[blubbers]
[yells]
[gasps]
[grunting]
[farting]
[gasps]
[thwacks]
[thuds]
[thwacking]
[Yellow shouting]
- [grunts]
- [roaring]
Storms have real eyes?
- It's just so... freaky.
- [manager] Mm-hm.
[Chuck] If I hadn't seen it
with my own eyes,
I wouldn't believe it myself.
[Grace sighs]
But I promise it's true.
- But that's bizarre.
- True that.
Awesome sauce!
[Granny] Any of them
wear glasses, you think?
[manager] Darnedest thing I ever heard.
Um, so, then, tell us
how you got off the island.
- Yeah!
- [gasps]
- Yeah.
- Tell us how you escaped!
Yes, do that!
- [Grace grunts]
- Did a boat come along?
- Did you swim across the ocean?
- Huh?
Get home.
That's what I was thinking
the whole time I was there.
[Chuck] But I failed to escape
so many times.
- I don't even know how many rafts I made.
- Hmm.
- [Chuck] But, one day...
- Uh?
...something happened
that meant we had to leave the island.
[Wendy gasping]
[Chuck]  Ba dup, ba dup, ba ba rap
Ba-ba ba ba
Ba rap ba...
[grunts]
Ba ba da ba...
- [grunts, sighs]
- [bubbles]
[water sloshes]
- [stomach rumbling]
- [water burbles]
Ah, this is so nice.
- [rumbling]
- Huh?
[screaming]
[spits]
What the...
[Chuck] A volcano?
- [explosion]
- [Chuck screams]
[squawks]
[harmonizing]
- [yelps]
- [fireballs thudding]
[rumbling]
[grunts]
Everyone, get on the raft!
[groans, gasps]
[screams]
- [explosion]
- [gasps]
We need to leave now.
- [Chuck] Everybody here?
- [robotic mutter]
[Chuck] Uh, what about the others?
[mumbles]
[gasps]
What are they doing?
[grunting]
[muttering]
- [thuds]
- [screams]
[panting]
[gasps]
[Booby grunting]
[muttering]
- [coughs]
- [mumbles]
[rumbling]
[thumping]
- [shrieks]
- [Red grunts]
[groaning]
[both gasp]
[whooshes]
[both scream]
[loud thud]
[both gasp]
[both mutter]
[dramatic music]
[whimpers]
[grunts]
[clatters]
[both yelp]
[whimpers]
[fire crackles]
[squeals]
- [gasps]
- [whooshes]
[both screaming]
[panting]
[Chuck] You know, until 11th grade...
[grunts]
...I was on the baseball team!
[Chuck sighs]
We've got to escape.
- Huh?
- [bugs muttering]
- [explosion]
- [gasping]
[screams]
[yells]
[groans]
[whooshing]
- [Chuck grunts]
- [cracks]
[both whine]
- [rumbles]
- [Chuck] Huh?
[yells]
[Chuck] Uh... Oh, no!
How can we ever get across that?
[gasps]
Lava everywhere!
[grunting, gasps]
[all screaming]
[grunts]
Right. Come on.
[Chuck] It's live or die time.
[grunting]
I... I can do this.
[breathes heavily]
Hyah!
- [thuds]
- Oh! Ah, ah, ah!
[screams]
[all shrieking]
Ooh!
[grunts]
Until the 12th grade...
[thuds]
...I was on the...
[grunts]
...the Pole Dancing team! Whoo!
[cheering]
- [lava sizzles]
- [screams]
It's over now.
I guess this is how I'm going to die.
- Huh?
- [bugs sobbing]
[whimpering]
Uh...
[all gasping]
[grunts]
[light music]
- [thudding]
- [bugs groaning]
[all gasp]
You guys take care.
Hm. Enjoy my last performance.
[humming]
[all gasp]
Ahh!
[all whining]
[sobs, gasps]
[sobs]
I'm gonna die for acting nice.
I'm such a dumb, dumb, stupid...
- [thuds]
- What's that?
Co... coconut? Uh!
[all grunting]
Thank you, friends!
All right!
Hot!
Ah!
[whooshes]
[screaming, panting]
Made it!
[yells]
[all shriek]
[robotic mutter]
[Chuck screaming]
- [whirring]
- [screams, gasps]
- [thuds]
- [groans]
[all cheering]
- [Yellow mutters]
- [gasps]
[screams]
[farts]
[grunting]
- [cheering]
- [farting]
[gasps]
[all whining]
[munching]
- [stomach rumbles]
- [farts]
[mutters]
[upbeat music]
[thumps]
[groaning]
- [robotic mutter]
- [snickers]
- [grunts]
- [groans]
[munches]
[rumbling]
[groaning]
[all muttering]
[screams]
- [farts]
- [whooshes]
[all screaming]
[all yelling]
Ooh!
[laughing]
[mutters, grunts]
[Booby grunting]
[squeals]
[screams]
[whistles]
[whooshes]
[Red squealing]
[mutters]
[warbling]
[wails]
[birds cawing]
[groaning]
[sighs]
[sobs]
[squeals]
[whooshes]
[shouts]
[mutters]
[warbling]
[wails]
[whimpering]
[liquid sloshes]
[sighs]
This is the end of it all.
To ending this after all the suffering.
- [sobbing]
- [liquid sloshing]
I thought if I just got off the island,
then I'd be fine.
God, are you gonna end me this way?
[rain pattering]
- [thunder rumbles]
- Huh?
[gasps]
[rain pattering]
Rain! Oh, thank you!
[wind whooshes]
[Chuck groans]
Are you kidding?
Whoa!
Come on, paddle!
[all panting]
[screaming]
[yelps]
[splashes]
[burbles]
- [mutters]
- [screams]
[grunts]
[farts]
[Yellow grunting]
[action music]
[grunts]
[rasps]
[robotic mumble]
- [water splashes]
- [thuds]
[coughs]
Oh, thank you, dear friends.
[groans]
Everyone, just hang on!
We'll be all right!
[birds cawing]
[gasps, screams]
- [thumping]
- [Clara barks]
[groaning]
- [zaps]
- Ahh!
Save me!
[gasps]
We're safe! Look!
- [thwacks]
- What the...
- [whooshing]
- [all gasp]
[rapid whooshing]
- [slapping]
- It stings!
Where did all the flying fish come from?
- [zaps]
- Huh?
- [thuds]
- [both munch]
Thank you for this meal!
[munches]
So good!
[gulping]
Come on! It's party time!
[Chuck] Uh, that was good.
[all burping]
- [all laughing]
- [sighs]
You know, thank goodness
you guys are here.
- [chuckles]
- [pants]
- [laughs]
- [robotic mutter]
[groans]
[giggles]
[gasps]
- [laughs]
- [splashes]
[upbeat music]
[squeals]
[whirring]
- [screams]
- [thwacks]
[grunting, groaning]
[yells]
[gasps]
[sobbing]
[both giggle]
[upbeat music]
[snickers]
[grunts]
[chuckles]
[snoring]
[upbeat music]
[thumps]
[yawns]
[whimpers]
[seals barking]
[splashes]
[barks, sniffs]
- [burbles]
- [robotic mutter]
[all grunting]
- [clicking]
- [snaps]
[rustles]
[moans]
[drum beating]
- [thumps]
- [warbling]
[fireworks crackle]
- [rumbles]
- [water splashes]
[all cheering]
[upbeat music]
[thumping]
[groaning]
Oh! Owie!
Huh? Could it be?
Could it really be real?
[gasps]
[plane engine revs]
Am I back?
I'm really back!
- [tires screech]
- Huh?
[door squeaks]
Uh?
Then I said farewell to everyone
and I was alone.
Uh, but still, you at least were able
to return home safely.
[sighs]
Yeah.
But I lost the family I found there.
[Wendy whimpers]
I wonder if they're all all right.
Mister, don't worry at all.
I'm sure your little bug friends
are safe and happy somewhere.
- [giggles]
- Mm-hm.
- Just like you are.
- [manager chuckles]
- [chef] They've gotta be.
- [all chuckle]
[manager] You said yourself
they never die.
- [Wendy] They're strong.
- [Granny] We're right, you know.
Yes, you are.
They're remarkably strong.
And they keep on smiling, no matter what.
Yay, bugs!
[giggles]
Go on.
Please tell us other adventures
you had with Larva.
Ooh! Larva! Larva! Larva!
[Wendy] Best story ever!
Yeah, all right.
I'll tell you about the time
me and Larva went shark fishing.
- [Wendy] Yay!
- [gasps, chuckles]
We got stuck right in a big
humpback whale's blowhole.
- [Chuck] Oh, the smell.
- [all laughing]
[laughs]
- [rain pattering]
- [all laughing]
[calm music]
[Grace and Chuck chuckling]
Oh, it cleared up.
[door closes]
Oh?
[Wendy and manager laughing]
[manager] It's been great.
Come back anytime.
- [Chuck] Thank you!
- [Wendy] Bye, silly man.
- [Chuck] Oh, bye, Wendy!
- [manager] Silly.
Well, that was certainly something else.
I guess it was.
- I don't remember having a nicer talk.
- Uh...
Thanks very much for talking to me today.
Sure, not a problem.
I thank you.
I realized today it's not as important
everyone believe me as I thought it was.
As long as I still remember my friends,
I'll remember it's all true.
[Chuck] Whether people believe
it all really happened,
well, that's up to them.
I finally truly feel like
I've completely left the island behind.
[chuckles]
Mm, uh...
Well, we're happy to have you back, Chuck.
Thanks very much, Grace.
I won't forget your help. Ever.
[sighs]
[calm music]
[Grace] To be honest,
when I first heard his story,
I thought he was a big, lying liar pants.
Even now, I'm still not sure
I believe all of it.
But I've written this book
with the earnest hope
that everyone will hear
of his amazing experiences,
and the special friends
he made on the island.
And I hope people enjoy my writing too.
[sighs]
[Grace] Could it all be hooey in bunk?
Everyone who heard Chuck's
brave, intense story,
- myself included...
- [Wendy giggles]
[Grace] ...felt almost transported
to the island themselves.
It was clearly real to Chuck.
- And frankly...
- Huh?
- [groans]
- ...that's good enough for this writer.
[Grace] I hope it's real
to all who read this book as well.
[dramatic music]
- [gasps]
- [phone buzzes]
- [Chuck] Oh, Clara.
- [coin clinks]
[Chuck] Oh, no, no. I just left.
- Yes.
- [coin clinks]
- Hang on.
- [muttering from distance]
Huh?
[light music]
Uh, yeah! I'm still here.
Sure. I'll be right there.
I love you too.
[light music]
[coin clinking]
[both gasp]
["Look at Me Larva" by Lily playing]
What are you doing there
Looking so sad?
What is it?
Ddu, dduru, ddu, bba, bba
Stop hiding in your room
And worrying alone
There's no need for that
Ddu, dduru, ddu, bba, bba
With my special someone
With my one and only love
Oh, I will sing and dance
In the starlight
Look at me, Larva, Larva, va, Larva
Oh, look, Larva, Larva
Larva, la va, Larva
I will chant a magic spell for you
I love you
Look at me, oh, look at me
Look at me, I will make you happy
I love you
Luck will come to you
Unexpectedly
-  I love it
-  Hey
I like it so much
-  You love it
-  Hey
When you are around
-  We love it
-  Hey
Just like the sun
You shine so brightly
Love, love, love, love
My love, love, love, love
You're my love, love, love, love
Look at me, baby
Whenever the thought of you
Crosses my mind during the day
It makes me smile
Ddu, dduru, ddu, bba, bba
It's electrifying
Just to be holding your hand
Ddu, dduru, ddu, bba, bba
With my special someone
My one and only love
Oh, I will sing and dance
In the starlight
Look at me, Larva, Larva, va, Larva
Oh, look, Larva, Larva
Larva, la va, Larva
I will chant a magic spell for you
I love you
Look at me, oh, look at me
Look at me, I will make you happy
I love you
Luck will come to you
Unexpectedly
-  I love it
-  Hey
I like it so much
-  You love it
-  Hey
When you are around
-  We love it
-  Hey
Just like the sun
You shine so brightly
Love, love, love, love
My love, love, love, love
You're my love, love, love, love
Look at me, baby
Look at me, Larva
Ho, ho, ho, ho
I love you
-  I'll make you happy
-  I love you
Luck will come to you
Unexpectedly
-  I love it
-  Hey
I like it so much
-  You love it
-  Hey
When you are around
-  We love it
-  Hey
Just like the sun
You shine so brightly
Love, love, love, love
My love, love, love, love
You're my love, love, love, love
Look at me, baby
Subtitle translation by Uei-sung Kim