Off to Russia!
Mrs. West worries about
her husband's trip.
Cowboy Jeddy, Mr. West's
faithful servant.
Mr. West's
morning mail.
To Mr. West...
president of the Y.M.C.A.
Dear Sir, we have learned
of your bold intention
to investigate the land
of the Bolsheviks.
Enclosed are New York
magazines depicting
the types of people in today's
barbaric Russia.
We advise you to take
a guard and weapons.
yours truly T.P. Gallagher
A RUSSIAN BOLSHEVIK
TYPE!
"Dear, take Jeddie with you. He'll
protect you from these beasts."
A month later, West arrives
in the capital of the Bolsheviks.
Mr. West's suitcases!
A less distinguished traveller
Garter trouble.
"Courage, boss! I'll protect you
in this barbaric country!"
Comfort is a
relative concept.
On duty.
Once a fop,
now just a small time crook.
Zhban, the Count.
The rest of the Gang:
the "Dandy" and the "Countess"
And One-Eye.
"There's a smell of dollars
in the air.
A surprise from America!"
Jeddie's poor brain
gets all mixed up.
"We'll swindle this Mr. West!
We'll get those dollar!"
"The Bolsheviks got
the suitcases AND Mr. West!"
Ellie, an American.
No outsiders allowed here!
"Ellie!"
"Jed!"
Mr. West has taken refuge
in the office of an American firm.
Without his loyal bodyguard,
he's feeling low.
The Gang goes to work.
Zhban sets a trap.
"Tell me how did you
find my briefcase?"
" I'll tell you the whole story.
They'll love it in America!"
Prison
"I rescued the briefcase, just as
it was about to be stolen!"
"I took off my hat to the most
cultured government in the world!"
The trap is about
to spring.
"You better stay in my apartment.
You're being followed here."
"But I have a lot of luggage."
"Take the bare essentials.
We'll come back later for the rest."
Ellie tries to get the police...
to release her fellow countryman.
"I first met Jed in America.
He saved me from a
criminal attack!"
"You see, Jeddie's boss
made him think...
all Russians are
as wild as savages."
Jeddie is released.
Meanwhile, Mr. West is
getting a tour of Moscow.
"Just look what these barbarians
have done to the University."
"That's where the Imperial
Bolshoi Theatre used to be."
"My Palace..."
"I had to exchange it
for a hovel. Well, anyway,
you'll be closer to the cruel
realities of life today."
Tea, Soviet style.
Jeddie sets out with Ellie...
to look for his missing boss.
"Very accurate.
Just like in real life."
The countess puts her heart
in her work.
Gang Number Two!
"Get together ten scary-looking guys.
We'll put on a show of...
Bolshevik brutality for that
idiot American.
We'll pay in dollars."
Back in the office,
they discuss Mr. West's
disappearance.
"The Bolsheviks!
Run for your life!"
"Darling, I'll show them
how an AMERICAN acts!"
The Death Sentence!
Everything started
to spin around.
Awaiting Death
Zhban's shadow tricks
Don't despair, salvation is near.
Give bearer 1000 dollars.
We'll pull you up through the chimney.
Send out another $1000.
"Our friends are on their toes!"
Mr. West's long absence has upset
the people at the office.
"You've got to find Mr. West today.
I recommend that you go
to the police."
"We're safe!"
"I'll teach you
to kiss my wife!"
"Calm down! Calm down!"
"Pay him something,
for heaven's sake!"
"Have a look at a
REAL Bolshevik."
Reading about cowboys...
continues to fascinate
Russian children.
"He loves me,
he loves me not..."
Mr. West finally sees Moscow.
The University
Science for the
working class
The Bolshoi Theatre
"Now you're going to see
THOUSANDS of real Bolsheviks."
"Here they are!"
"And they are all GENUINE!"
Dear Madge, greetings from
Soviet Russia.
Burn those New York
magazines,
and hang a portrait
of Lenin on the wall
Long live the Bolsheviks!
Your John.
On the way to the
radio station.
The Moscow radio station