Princess.
That Feng San dared rape and
kill Princess Nan Chiang.
Princess Nan Chiang is my cousin.
Yet she got raped and killed.
How can I face my ancestors?
Take care of yourself, your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Feng Sau Ching is
head of Royal Guard.
He is to patrol the city,
but he let his colleague Feng San
do all these crimes.
So I beg your Majesty
to have him punished.
I didn't let Feng San do that.
Only that Feng San is really cunning
and he's skilled at martial art.
If you lie to me.
I'll kill all your family.
I'll have you head cut off openly.
Spare me your Majesty.
Hold it.
I take as granted that you've
follow me a long time.
I allow you to do something
to cover your negligence.
I give you 20 days
to capture Feng San.
Thanks your Majesty,
I'll capture Feng San within 20 days.
Thanks for sparing me, I'm retreating.
Uncle-instructor.
How are you?
That betrayer Feng San injured me.
Why did he injure you?
Two nights ago,
Feng San crept back,
and tried to steal
the Black Jade Buddha.
I found it and we fought.
He injured me.
and he stole the Black Jade Buddha.
Why did he steal
the Black Jade Buddha?
According to Buddhism books.
One day Evil went to see Buddha,
and ask Buddha:
I want to follow you.
Can I be Buddha as
I did so many crimes?
Buddha performed miracle
and turned the Wheel.
Evil sat on it, holding
the Black Jade Buddha, and said prayer.
He saw his whole life 100 times.
Seeing one's life
100 times at instance.
Feng San has nowhere to go.
Maybe he believes this myths.
He wants to make us of
Black Jade Buddha to escape.
He can't as the Wheel is not here.
I know that people from
Tibet have just arrived.
Wheel is one of their presents.
At midnight in 7 days,
it's the miracle day.
No, I must stop him.
Feng San, you can't run away,
let me arrest you.
Stupid, dog, you come late!
Feng San.
Stupid, dog, are you blind?
Is you brain blocked?
Don't you recognize me?
Our first rule forbids
to commit adultery,
but you raped and killed 13 girls.
Why did you do all these?
Stupid Dog, we started
practicing since 5.
We had to practice at dawn,
and could only sleep at midnight.
It was not human life.
Twenty-five years, we led
such a life for 25 years.
We finally practiced
superb martial art.
So it's harvest time for us.
We should enjoy ourselves.
I feel excited to rape and kill.
You are lunatic!
I must cut off my relation
with you today.
We have no more relation!
Your Majesty.
Though I can't capture Feng San.
But I will kill him.
It is also fulfilling my duty.
I must die too.
Take care of yourself,
your Majesty.
Help.
Someone has an accident.
Quick.
Be quick.
Where is it...
Bring some medicine.
Be careful.
Drag him out
Becarefu...
Easy...
Do me have medicine.
Still okay...
It's a great discovery.
It show that there was
homosexual in ancient time.
Right.
Then means there was
AIDS in ancient time too.
Shit, don't bullshit.
Of course.
In 1887 in Sweden,
someone rescued a frog which
had been frozen for a century.
In 1985 at Berkerly University,
a lotus shot up and it had been
frozen for 2000 years.
By theory.
If we electrocute these two ancient
bodies and they will survive.
Don't bullshit.
Now they are conserved in -10c
If we must rescue them.
Then we must thaw them.
But they will rot if we fail.
We can't take this risk.
We should send them to USA.
They have better instruments.
What do you think?
Right.
Yes, but we must go altogether.
It's a good chance to go
abroad with national fund.
Right.
I must go.
Me too.
You Li Pang. You want to flee
after slaughtering so many people?
Chai King is your student
so you want to flee.
Don't bullshit.
Our country has not future now.
We must leave altogether.
Don't let the 27 Army hear this,
they will suppress us by tanks.
Don't worry.
I've expressed
my support of the Central.
We're skilled at telling lies.
No one will suspect me.
We'll say
we sent the body to USA,
but we will kill Wue Kaixi.
And say we love our father land.
That bastard Li Pang
will surely allow us to go.
You mean that...
if we make a point to go to HK.
We can go to Volvo Club
and see something.
It's then ideal.
Good.
My I right?
Absolutely.
He's right in any way.
Hey, here comes the car.
Fat Bull, are you mad?
With such a small car,
how can we take them away?
Yeah, the boss is going to
X'mas party today.
We can take whatever we want.
How can I know,
I'll get a bigger car.
Or we will do a second time.
Shit, start work.
Which is more expensive,
frozen prawn of frozen abalone?
Tat, take whatever you find.
What is it?
It's protected items.
It's mysterious.
Let's see what it is.
No, we'll get shot if we steat it.
Tat, we didn't say to take it away.
Can I just open it and see?
Get something and open it.
It's a big freezer.
I've never seen this before.
What is it?
You idiot!
This is Terracotta.
No, Terracotta is not frozen.
How can it be frozen like this?
May I ask? What exactly is this?
It's body, oh god!
It seems your boss's son
is coming back.
Don't fool me.
He's at the party!
He's so cunning to come back to
check us.
Luckily we are clever,
or we'll be scolded.
You surprised me.
You bastard.
What happened?
Yes.
There are two possibilities.
First, the bodies
may have been stolen.
Another is.
The bodies changed into...
No that the bodies
have disappeared.
We will be executed,
what shall we do?
Yeah, Tat, use your brain.
I have a way.
It's so horrible here...
Am I in the hell?
How come there're so many monsters?
Why did I lose
all my martial art?
Very cold.
Who is it?
Who?
Boss, are you a new comer?
Queue up if you want.
Queue up.
The social workers have come.
Merry Christmas and Happy New Year.
Pretend you are hungry.
I am hungry...
I haven't eat for a few day already.
Happy New Year.
I'm hungry.
Good Health.
Thanks.
Have good grades.
Thanks a lot, Social Workers.
Merry Christmas...
This Christmas present is for you.
Thanks.
This is yours.
Excuse me, where am I now?
Kowloon City.
Kowloon City?
Where is Kowloon City?
In Kowloon.
Where is Kowloon?
In Hong Kong.
Where is Hong Kong?
In Asia.
Asia? I don't understand at all.
Then do you know Peking?
Peking, Of course I know.
How long does it
take to walk to Peking?
On foot? Maybe a year.
Is it that when I fainted.
I was smuggled to foreign land?
I think this guy is mad.
You must be careful with you words.
May I know what you are?
I am leader of Royal Guard.
I am an armed guard.
What are you then?
He's head of East Block, a eunuch.
How are you?
He is eunuch?
You are not castrated.
What are you then?
I am the King.
How dare you say you're the King.
I must take you out
and cut off your head.
Wait a minute.
Leader, I am innocent.
This is my paper,
please take it to the King.
What are you doing?
Miss, I know you are straight.
You paid debt for other people.
But what about your debt?
You must pay us the interest first.
Otherwise how can I face my boss?
Don't say any more.
You are insulting my talent.
Anyway, I don't have a dollar now.
You may wipe me off.
Or you must wait after New Year.
Don't say I am too much.
One of my customers
want some excitement.
He wants a girl pretend
to be raped in a car.
Are you crazy?
I am a model,
you think I am a whore?
You are model?
But he will give you $5,000.
No way.
I won't take it as
this is a sexual maniac.
Shit, dare you do it.
Show him some present.
Are you from a circus?
No, no way for that.
Why not? What is this?
Ask him to take off the mask.
Boss, take off the mask.
Lady, come on!
Do you like it?
Shit.
Tie up.
Be quick.
You sexual maniac.
You masked rapist.
What are you doing?
You speak foreign language, shit!
Help.
Are you frightened, miss?
Who are you?
They didn't say about you?
Boss...what is it?
What do you want?
Want?
Boss, he's horrible.
Kill him.
Miss, you are safe now.
Where did you come from?
Why are you so busy?
Miss, I have saved your virgin.
Why did you say
such rude remarks?
My colleagues owe someone money.
I am guarantor and
I'm responsible for the debt.
So I must work with that
sexual maniac. Do you understand?
You did it for others?
Miss, you are great.
You are a heroine.
I admire you.
I don't care, you made it a mess.
Tomorrow, you must
talk to their boss, OK?
No problem, I will do it as you say.
I must leave now.
Where's your pager?
Pager?
How can I find you tomorrow?
I have no shelter
as I'm newcomer here.
Your I.D. card?
I.D. card?
You are illegal immigrant?
Bitch, don't be so happy.
I will use acid.
Acid again? Bastard.
Follow me home.
In an hour's time.
You'll be OK, see you.
Come in.
Put you dirty clothes outside.
Or the house will be stink.
Mad.
It's terrific.
What are you doing?
What light is this?
It's light bulb,
where are you from?
I'm from Mi Chi
from Sen Xi Province.
Never heard of.
Where are you from?
Yau Ma Ti.
Yau Ma Ti?
Miss, we've only oil lamp at home.
Ours is by electricity.
Electricity, is it
something like lighting?
Right, a very big dynamite.
It collects all the lighting,
and when we switch on,
then the electricity
will come by the wire,
and light up the bulb, understand?
Understand completely.
You really do?
Men and women
shouldn't get together.
Is your house searched?
I am too busy to tidy it.
I can't imagine a girl's house
can be such a mess.
This is the first time I see one.
How can you such thing to me?
Hello, you've got
the wrong number, bitch!
You are bastard!
What is this?
Don't fool me any more.
You haven't seen a telephone?
Take it and study.
Hello, miss,
your Japanese has come.
Do you need money?
Come if you do.
You've got the wrong number, bitch!
You are bastard.
You learn fast, kid.
You are flattering me.
Miss, what is this?
It's electric kettle, to boil water.
Electric kettle?
What is that small house
we just got in?
It's a lift.
Lift, light, wire.
Electric kettle, telephone...
electric chair.
What are you laughing?
Electric chair for you.
Miss, may I ask...
Hello, dear, how are you?
Miss, how are you?
Dear, come to my place.
Why must I?
I am lonely,
I want you to embrace me.
Shit, men and women
shouldn't get together.
I am a straight gentleman.
I won't be seduced by you.
Get away from me, evil girl.
Where can you run?
No, I'm just joking.
No, be gentle.
Sexual maniac, stop!
Or I will kill you.
Where is he?
Where are the two?
Someone is there,
this is a moving picture.
A moving picture?
It looks so realistic?
lmmortals in pictures?
What do you mean?
You psychic.
They're acting.
You should have it at your home.
It's like the Chinese opera.
Then it is taken down
by machine.
Then transmit it through
wire to television.
It shows up for us, it's television.
Do you understand?
I do, completely.
You haven't bathed,
you are stink.
Take a bath, go.
Miss, behave yourself.
Behave? Shit.
Take a bath,
wash your ass, toes.
Wash your armpits,
go and wash yourself.
Miss, please leave for the moment.
Do you know how to use the tap?
I know, after checking.
Electric well, I am thirsty.
Water is not good, I'll try again.
It's salty.
I'll wash my face first.
Miss, men and women
shouldn't get together.
Miss, why are you so afraid?
A cockroach.
Is it this one?
Throw it away quick.
It's not bad.
It's more delicious
than the insects at home.
Miss, electric kettle?
He has superhuman powers.
I must sleep now.
Just go on watching.
But don't touch anything.
They're acting the opera
of our Ming dynasty.
He's playing His Majesty?
Mob forced into the palace?
Maybe it's only acting.
Ming Dynasty was over?
Our Ming Dynasty was over?
It must be acting.
It was 1644, more than
300 years from now.
Li Chang forced into Peking,
Sung Ching killed himself.
So I really got in the Wheel.
And was transit to 300 years later.
No.
My country was ruined...
Your Majesty...it's my fault.
I couldn't protect your Majesty.
How can I do?
I should die.
He got so concentrated
in watching TV.
He's a mad guy.
I'll talk with their boss later.
If I fail, I'll make a sound.
You must go in and 'B' him.
B' him? What does that mean?
This is to 'B' him, idiot!
Do you understand?
Beat him with my fists.
Look at yourself.
How can you negotiate like this?
You must be like me, this way.
How is it?
Be proud, OK?
I understood.
Be smarter.
Light the cigarette for me.
Stupid.
Our boss asks you in.
Put it inside.
What your men
did to me last night.
OK, I can bear it.
But my man can't.
You know people
from China kill easily.
He's good at martial art too.
Master Hung, your had
a lesson last night, right?
I seldom take him out.
But I take him with me today.
I will apologize to you,
and let's forget about yesterday.
Electric toilet bowl.
Ching...
Run.
Fighting.
Good...
Be careful.
I skip, I jump, I tumble.
What is it so powerful?
Are you crazy, it's a gun.
A gun?
I am best at
grasping little weapons.
I'll grasp it.
This is really powerful.
We can't beat him, let's run.
Go...
Jump from here
and it's near, jump...
It's so high, I won't jump...
Jump fast...
No...
Jump.
I won't jump.
Run.
Merry Christmas.
You shit.
So this is your man?
I can't bear.
Sit down.
So stupid.
Miss, what would you like?
Give me a coffee.
And this mister?
Just give him some water.
Sure.
See, watch careful.
This is I.D. card.
Police will kill you without it.
You can't find a job either,
understand?
Miss, you know so many people.
I hope you will get one for me.
And please find me a job too.
This is not a problem.
You must tell me
why you are so stupid.
You are so ignorant.
Where do you come from?
I'm afraid if I say,
you'll touch and caress me again.
I won't...say.
I'm Royal Guard of Ming Dynasty.
I am leader of the Guard.
I got in the Wheel when
I chased my bad colleague.
The Wheel turned
and it's 300 years later.
And I am in Kowloon in HK in Asia.
Forget it then.
What can you do?
Though I am an army.
I'm familiar with music,
chess, books and paintings.
I tried hard to learn them.
I'm interested in opening
locks wood work,
cement work, fishing,
hunting and folk dances.
I've taken care of myself since young.
So I know a little about washing,
ploughing.
planting, weaving and embroidering.
Moreover, when I was at the army.
I was in charge of food
for 500 soldiers.
It was easy job for me.
It's nothing special.
Men should always do this.
Don't say I'm bad to you.
I'll do you a favour.
You will be my body guard,
a Friday boy and serve me.
I'll give you $300 a month.
You should be happy
as I am good to you.
No, I am a straight man.
How can I serve a woman?
You are a man?
Have you heard: When in Rome,
do as the Romans.
Women are superior here.
Men should
serve women to prove them.
See...look closely.
Dare you woo other girls?
Does it hurt?
You asked for that.
Time has changed.
Even the money we are using,
bears a woman on it.
Go away if you must.
No I.D. card, the police
will kill you. I don't care a bit.
Why does this happen to me?
My country was ruined, I can only,
bear all these and find a chance.
Hope I can strengthen
my country one day.
Miss, I promise you.
OK, just learn now.
Put two lumps
in the coffee and stir it.
It's done.
What are you doing?
How can you stir it with your finger?
You...
I spend $300 to hire you.
How can you give that out?
Miss, have some tea.
What, I ask you
to serve my colleagues.
Why do you just serve me?
Take it over...
Ass!
I spend $300 to hire you.
I'm sorry.
Miss, have some tea.
What is it?
Lemon and mask.
What? You want me to beat you?
Country ruined...bear it.
Bear everything, country ruined...
Feng Sau Ching.
Ching, what are you doing?
Faster, I must go to toilet.
I'm washing the clothes.
Why so long?
What are you doing?
You wash the clothes like this?
You make me mad.
Help, my house is finished.
It's on fire, Ching, run quick.
Ching, help.
Ching, what are you doing.
I'm cooking something for you.
Shit, why don't you use
microwave oven but burn the log?
My God!
Where are there so many flowers?
I plant them, look.
They are lovely, what are they?
African violet.
Are you a man?
I don't know what he's drawing
for the whole day.
You are peasant?
Pay me back.
We're robbed...
How much is there?
Take the gold watch,
jewels are hard to sell.
Why don't you know anything?
Take it.
Thanks.
I'll take a bath.
Paging 996.
Miss is paging him.
I'll take a bath first.
Coming.
Open the door...
Some is coming, listen...
Open the door.
Why are you so afraid?
I know now, it's my husband.
Husband?
Open the door.
Ching.
You sexual maniac.
What is it?
Hey...you...l...
Ching, let him off.
Go away.
Don't beat...OK, I'm alright.
I've taught him something,
he won't do that to me again.
Are you really OK?
I am OK.
You must be careful.
OK, go down first, bye.
I'm bored,
my husband loves me madly.
When a man madly loves a woman.
It's troublesome, what should I do?
What about this?
Give me $5,000 and I'll send him away.
I've only $3,000, it's not enough.
Maybe it's enough, I'll try.
I'll go first, bye.
What is the work of models?
We must sell the clothes to customers.
We must always meet customers.
It's good to have good customers.
But there's bad customers.
They want to rape us
when doing business.
I'm scared, thanks your help.
It's good to scare them, right?
It's hard to make money
in Hong Kong.
It's good you know.
You bastard,
what do you want to do?
If you damage the TV.
No one will buy a new one,
I warn you.
What so funny to see?
Bastard.
If you let me drink this.
I'll let you lick my toes.
Bastard!
Honey...
He wants to rape me.
Shit.
Bastard, dare you bully my wife?
Bastard.
Husband.
I'll kill you if you don't
take off your hands.
If you don't take you,
you'll be a beggar now.
But you are so forgetful.
I helped you many times.
You make big money,
but you didn't give me a dollar.
Shut up, what I say is order.
Kneel down and
apologize to my wife.
Aren't you afraid of my gun?
Shit.
Your bullets are here.
These ladies are doing too much.
They take me as a slave.
I promised to serve her only,
I didn't say to serve her friends.
By the way, your man is not bad.
The lease he can
bear your bad temper.
His martial art is so skilled.
He's good at anything.
You must be happy with him.
Shit, you are crazy, what happy?
He's not my man, he's my servant.
As your servant?
What about letting me have him?
I'll give you $5,000,
what do you think?
I'll give you $10,000.
I'll give you $15,000.
I won't sell him. I won't sell him
however much you offer.
Forget it.
It's your turn.
Right, I want to ask you.
Does he know
he cheated with you?
How can he know?
Don't think he's smart,
he is indeed an idiot!
He can't run away from me.
Does he know what we are?
How will he know as
I am so elegant.
It's hard for you.
Do I look like whore?
You don't look like.
But everyone will know
from your voice.
You are whore?
Whore?
Don't shout, we are all whores.
Whore means prostitute.
So, I've been
helping her to cheat.
Oh God! I am a Royal Guard.
But I commit crimes with a whore.
I'm starving, be quick.
No, I won't serve
these whores again.
All I am doing is for the I.D. card?
Country ruined.
It's sad and bad for me.
Why so smart
when the country was ruined?
Is it possible I fell in love
with her, no...
I want today's paper.
All limbs are broken.
The murderer does like Feng San.
He's not yet died?
He is here? It must be him.
This man is called Feng San.
He is an evil wolf.
He rapes and kill and robs.
Beware of this man.
Please come.
Come on...Polly is a model.
She needs money badly
so she works for this time.
Polly.
Hi!
Hello, sorry!
Hello, is it Ching?
Ching, I've looking
for you a whole day.
Where have you been?
I'll be taking business later.
I'm afraid he will bully me.
Get ready to rescue me.
This woman wants me
to help her cheat again.
I am a Royal Guard,
I won't help her again.
996, right.
Say Miss is paging him,
ask him to find me quick, yes.
I must get the money first.
Of course.
Thanks.
Let's have one.
I don't take drug.
I'll take one.
Why don't you take a bath first?
No, you bathe first, I'll watch you.
OK, but you must
pay me extra money.
No problem.
Is this enough, take it.
How can I know if it is forget?
I don't know either.
I took it from a man
who cheated me.
I've killed him already.
I'm joking, forget the money
for the time being.
You have good muscle.
I'm excited, you have a good body.
Do I?
I must take a bath.
I am shy.
Why doesn't Ching come?
Your muscle is terrific!
I must think it over.
I don't know what I am doing.
Knowing Feng San is alive
but I don't do my duty.
Just for an ignorant woman,
and I forget all my duty.
Feng Sau Ching,
you are seduced by a fox.
No, I must carry out my duty.
You bastard, you are sexual maniac.
My guard will kill you
when he arrives.
You are sexual maniac.
Do you feel comfortable?
No...no.
Your hands are delicate.
No, I am a model, I won't do this!
It hurts, let me go, it kills me.
Miss, is it your?
Why don't you say?
I am not your Miss,
why do you want Miss?
This voice is familiar.
Why is it so familiar?
Ching, where are you?
I am in a telephone booth.
Don't talk so loudly.
I must say I have
no confidence with you.
I won't let you
make use of me again, bye.
Ching, Listen,
someone is trying to kill me.
He broke my arm, it hurts.
Someone broke your arm?
Yeah.
Who? Who broke your arm?
He looks like Lam.
Lam? Who is Lam?
Ching.
Hello...Lam? Who is Lam?
Excuse me, who is Lam?
Lam? This is Lam?
Don't you know Lam?
He must be illegal immigrant.
Mad.
Feng San, Lam is Feng San.
Feng San...
Miss.
Stupid dog.
Feng San.
Come to
Happy Valley Cemetery at once.
Don't act rashly.
Where?
The second gate.
Hey, where are you?
Dare you jump in?
Feng San, say, where are you?
Go to hell at once.
Stupid dog,
how are you these 3 centuries?
Feng San.
Ching.
Miss.
Don't come...
or I'll break her head.
You threaten me
with a common woman.
Don't you fear
others laugh at you?
What? At this world?
Make it clear,
you old-fashioned man.
Sung Ching is dead for a long time.
Ming Dynasty was ruined centuries ago.
Why are you still after me?
Why did you put
my pictures in the street?
This is my duty.
I was ordered to capture
and take you back.
I won't change
however the time changes.
I feel sick whenever I see you.
I must teach you something.
I'll kill your woman in front of you.
Stop, or I'll bite her throat.
I beg you,
I am not my woman.
I am her common friend.
Common friend?
Yeah.
Then you can enjoy
and watch my performance.
Wait, this is only a dispute
between you and me.
There's nothing to do with her,
let her go.
I am begging you.
OK, I am begging you.
I fear you, OK.
Why will you say this and beg me?
Just give me a reason.
I may release her.
I am impatient.
I will count one, two, three.
I love her, I fell in love with her.
How can you say these dirty words?
But, a man like you.
How will you with
such a dirty woman?
OK, prove it to me.
OK, what do you want me do to?
Drink this.
martial Art Ruining Lotion.
Think it over, drink it and
you will lose your martial art.
Don't ask me why
Because I don't want you
to shadow me.
Ching, don't drink it.
He eats words.
Ching.
Hero always loves beauty.
Don't try to be a hero.
But you are not a hero, you are ass.
You ruin your martial art
for a woman?
You forget the duty
from his Majesty!
I look down on you.
Don't let me see your again.
Otherwise I will kill you, go.
Colleague.
Don't call me colleague.
I know you will eat words.
Why you drank it then?
I have no chance if I didn't drink it.
Now I have a bit chance
after drinking it.
Because of this bit chance,
so I did all this.
Feng San, we've been colleague
for so many years.
You should understand me.
I'd rather die than being insulted.
Besides my parents,
his Majesty and instructor.
I never kneel to anybody.
But now I kneel to you
and beg you to release her.
Look at you.
You spoil my interest
in playing your woman.
Don't let me see you two again.
Or I will kill your both.
Ching, are you OK, Ching?
Miss, tie up the arm.
Be good from now on.
I must go now.
Ching, don't go, Ching.
Ching, what are you trying to do?
Ching, where are you going?
Ching, come back.
My horse, someone
robbed my horse, stop?
Ching, you must
go to hospital at once.
Ching...
You stupid dog, why did you seal,
your pulse with the gold pins?
If you must fight with me now.
With 4 hours.
You will be bleeding and die.
Tell me, why did you do that?
I can only seal
my pulse with gold pins,
to preserve my
martial art for one hour.
I must die with you.
Come on...
Shit.
Come on, professor, keep up...run.
Stupid dog...come on...
Stupid dog, come on...
Come on, keep up...
Feng San, didn't you say
you understand me?
You should know in order to
carry out his Majesty's,
in order to
rescue my beloved woman.
I will sacrifice myself.
Right, you are great, stupid dog.
It's bad, there is a car up there?
Don't move, just let him die.
Feng San, I must die with you.
You'd better die before me.
Stupid dog, come and
take me back to the King.
Shit.
Stupid dog...
Where are you?
Stupid dog, come and catch me.
Quick...
Follow me.
That way...
Faster, follow me everybody.
Ching, don't scare me, Ching.
Give him first aids.
Be quick.
The poison is in effect,
I'm dying.
Miss, farewell.
Ching, your must survive.
Miss, I am asking you
the eighth time.
Give me something new.
Who is he?
You'll get the same answer from me.
Same answer from me!
He's my man,
a Royal Guard form Ming Dynasty.
Shit, you fool me?
I'll sue you.
I tell you, if you can prove him
to be from Ming Dynasty.
I will lick your toes.
Doctor, how his Feng Sau Ching?
He was poisoned severly.
Fortunately the sea water
and we saved him.
I always say
Hong Kong's doctors are capable.
But there is something strange.
I've tested his cell.
It shows that he is over 300 years old.
He is from Ming Dynasty then?
Is the machine out of order?
How is it? Are you licking my toes?
Why did you beat her?
Miss, do you want to sue him?
I'll be witness.
I only want to see Feng Sau Ching.
He is unconscious. You can only
see him tomorrow noon.
And you must get permission
from the police.
Basically no.
But we police are nice people.
So I'll grant you this time.
Sir.
Sir, how is it?
Your man doesn't
want to see you, go away.
You fool me?
What if I do?
It hurts, take your hands off me.
OK, be quick.
Ching.
Ching, didn't you tell the police
you wouldn't see me?
Don't pretend sleeping, I know.
I don't want to see you, go away.
Are you crazy?
You become idiot after drinking
the potion? I am your miss.
You cheat me and make use of me.
You seem a model
but in fact you're a whore.
You are prostitute,
women like you,
will be beheaded in Ming Dynasty.
Beheaded you!
OK, I'll be responsible for what I did.
I confess, it's all my fault.
I am apologizing to you now.
Don't be like this,
I'll say you are my man now.
I'll be very good to you.
But I won't say you are my woman.
But you say you love me...
If I don't love you,
I wouldn't die for you.
But love is love, dying is dying.
I won't get on
with a woman like you.
I have my principles.
Don't you so smart, you!
I am nearly begging you.
What do you want?
I'll improve myself.
But men will never change.
Men will remain the same.
I am still a Royal Guard for 300 years.
Feng San is still a woman killer.
I cant help...
Ioving a bad woman.
But I can stop myself from seeing her.
Go away, I'm tired, I need rest.
OK, forget it.
You are so hard heartened, go.
Go away.
Aunt.
It's you.
I surprised you.
Does he know I made it?
No, I do as you tell me.
I said he looks like my late son.
So I make soup for him everyday.
Please take this.
I can't.
Take it.
Thanks.
I'll come tomorrow,
I'm leaving now, bye.
You dropped it everywhere.
I'll help you pick it up.
You step on my things.
Forget it, aunt.
Are you blind?
I am sorry.
What do you want?
I'll improve myself.
Miss, I want to give you back
the thermos flask.
Don't know if it's broken.
It's OK.
Take it.
Why are you giving so much money?
It's OK, I want you to do me favour.
What is it?
Thanks, I'll soon be back.
Don't make a sound,
Feng San is trying to catch you.
Why are you covering
your head? It's unlucky.
Shit! I saw nothing.
The exhibition of Buddha.
The Wheel is displayed the first time,
will be on show in HK in 3 months.
Now what you see,
is the Wheel
with a history of 500 years.
Master San, here are six cartons,
it's $488000, please pay now.
Why? You want to start
a war with these weapons?
If you want to do
a big robbery count us in.
Shit.
I will forever be looked down here.
It's not my land
I can't beat people in HK.
Shit, what's the use of martial art?
I must get these weapons
back to Ming Dynasty
and wipe out the palace.
I must kill the king
and I'll be King then.
Your history will be altered.
Master San, I don't understand
what you are saying.
Me either.
It's better that you don't understand.
We've stole some national
precious again. What good is there?
Yes, an ancient sword, I'll show you.
There's no rust after centuries.
It's Lun Chuen Sword.
Someone offered $180000 for it.
Shit, it's Feng Sau Ching's
Lun Chuen Sword.
No wonder my sword
was broken by him.
This sword worth ten million,
I'll take it.
OK, I'll sell it to you
if you give me one million.
You don't deserve to own it.
You don't know about it at all.
I'll show you.
It's a good sword,
it doesn't take up a dip of blood.
Ming Dynasty will be mine...
It's incredible.
The Wheel will be in HK.
Is this fate?
In 2 months and 17 days at midnight.
It's the miracle day.
The Wheel will perform great power.
Feng San will show up then.
It's time I carried out my duty.
Can you beat him?
No.
No? Why must you then?
Can't you stop being so stubborn?
No, I've promised his Majesty.
I must take Feng San back.
I'll be dishonest if I don't try.
I'll die will him if I can't beat him.
If I beat him.
I'll take him to the Wheel
and back to see his Majesty.
Then you're leaving...
and not coming back?
I don't belong here anyway.
What about me?
You'd better leave now.
Are you crazy?
You say you love me.
Love is love.
I must practice
within these two months.
I must refine a sword
to fight with Feng San.
I can't concentrate if you are here.
It hurt anyway, as Chuen says.
If love can't be forever,
it's good to have it once.
I don't care, I'll never leave here.
OK, if you insist.
But you must prove
you can improve yourself.
How to?
It depends on you.
We'll see.
Eat it, until I die.
Beware of the thunders.
You're lucky to have me feeding you.
It's tasty.
Your Majesty, I've refined a sword.
I must beat Feng San.
Hope Your Majesty bless me to win.
Ching, I'll give you
this bullet-proof coat.
This is your sword.
The Miss Sword...
Is that me? What happens?
I forget something, wait for me.
Ching...
What are you doing?
The exhibition is closed?
Where do you want to go?
Feng San, go to the rood for a duet
if you want to
get the Black Jade Buddha.
Stupid dog!
Feng San, you have done
so many evil deeds,
follow me to Ming Dynasty,
I'll beg his Majesty to spare you.
I must blow you up.
Ching...
Bitch, pay the money quickly.
No? Then why are you a Miss?
I am no more a Miss,
I word in a shop now.
How can I have money?
I have only $200 with you,
you may take it.
Take it all.
Dare your act!
This is water.
Ching...
You are alive? You didn't die?
Miss is sexually assaulting me!