Agreed then;
for whoever comes or calls,
tomorrow I'm gonna
leave for Paris.
Send a bunch of roses to
Madam Jordaine on my behalf.
The Duke of Fadda and
the Prince of Sebasto.
Allow me, dear Fabio
to introduce
the great officer Ferrani,
the Prince of Sebasto.
What do you decide, sir?
Countess of Parma.
- Reine-Claude.
- Countess of Parma, Reine-Claude.
Countess of Parma, Reine-Claude.
Countess of Parma, Reine-Claude!
The Duke of Fadda,
the Prince of Sebasto.
- That one in the box nearby.
- He is the Duke of Fadda.
- The other one is
the Prince of Sebasto.
- Who are the women?
That one on the left!
What Milan! Let the lady know
that I  leave for Paris at 17:05.
Allow me to say
that according to the telegram
it seems that widow Marta Rossi...
has bought all the shares
- All the shares? For my company?
But I've got three of them!
Except those three,
she bought the other 997.
So what? Just because she's
the owner? But I'm the brain!
Nonsense!
I'm leaving for Paris!
Very well. I'll send you
a telegram from Paris,
let the agency know that.
All done sir.
Today at Mirafiori
the climax of the season.
It'll be very smart.
What do you decide, sir?
- Ardour, Prestige
- Ardour and Prestige?
Ardour and Prestige.
Ardour, Prestige
Do you like these names?
- Did you give them yourself? - Yes.
- They're appropriate, but...
- Better the old fashion names.
- Yes, Countess of Parma...
No! Countess of Parma!
The names of these suits
are better!
- Ardour! Prestige!
- That's it! - Ok!
- Let's go!
- Sir, may I have a word with you?
- Right now, in here?
- But sir, you're about to leave!
All right then,
100 lire all together.
Don't be like that sir,
100 yesterday and 100 today.
100 lire all for
the evening and tailcoats.
It doesn't matter,
don't be a petty bourgeois!
150 deal!
- The Prince?
- He brought me a Russian Prince...
- He's Russian, but he's a Prince.
- 50 lire more for the Russian.
- All right, Duke?
- Sure.
Let's see...
Well, let's go.
Ok then,
today the introductions.
The Prince with Adriana
at Lambergo tea meeting.
The Duke with
Marcella at Mirafiori.
Remember,
I don't want people thinking...
'She's a model
at Maison Printemps.'
You may say:
'My wife, do you like her?
She dresses
at Maison Printemps'
Are you joking?
Either you're joking or...
Am I supposed to say:
'My wife, do you like her?'
Say then:
'My sister, do you like her?'
- He's kidding, he's kidding!
- Then say: 'This is my friend.'
- Make sure they understand.
- They won't let anyone understand.
That's right.
We are not "friends" of anybody.
Make your mind up,
let's go now.
- Cigarette, babe?
- No, thanks.
You don't want me calling you babe?
Shall I call you Marcella?
- Or Countess of Parma?
- How long before arriving to Mirafiori?
You look nervous, have you
argued with your boyfriend?
- What boyfriend?
- Don't you have a boyfriend?
What a cutie!
I won't spoil you!
Does the dress make you dizzy?
You can try to fool someone
else with these things.
- For me you're just a model
- And who do you think you are?
You're a model just like me
Got a title? I see how you use it!
How dare you talking to me
like that, little braggart.
You'll pay
for your words dearly.
Put it on the chief's bill
You'll strike a bargain!
I won't drop at your level.
For god's sake,
don't bother, stay higher!
Don't try following me,
I don't know you.
And if you see the boss,
tell him...  actually,
I will speak with the boss,
understand?
Go away!
- What sort of people!
May I go to smoke? - Yes, go on.
- Will you let me know
when you finish? - What?
- What are  you trying to do?
- Nothing. I'm trying to reverse.
- Do you think is that the way
to do it? - Do me a favour!
Don't be like that.
Haven't I got the right to try
the car as I wish?
- Ah, is that so?
Give me
your driving license.
Here it is,
but it'll cost you dearly.
- Don't worry about it. Your name?
- Gino Vanni, born in Udine...
- One moment. Are you Vanni?
- Can't you read?
Thing is with that hat on
I couldn't recognize you.
I do beg your pardon.
- It doesn't matter.
- A striker like you!
How could I not recognize you?
I remember that action
two Sundays ago towards the end.
I suffered about that missed goal,
I wasn't able to eat my dinner.
Even my wife was saying
'Why don't you eat?'
- What can you do? It's the feeling!
- Never mind. We'll do better next time
Come to the stadium and ask about me,
I'll let you in next time.
- Thanks, will do. Eleven and ten.
- What?
Try to understand.
I've got to do my duty!
An eleven and
ten fine you said?
Not sure but
I may have some small change.
- Here ten lire, did you say eleven?
- Eleven and ten.
- Here one lira...
- Don't worry.
No, I must have money.
Wait.
Here one coin...
- It doesn't matter really!
- No, wait.
- I have a stamp.
- Thanks and sorry about that.
After all they're good people, he
probably didn't want to make me pay.
But then he issued
the ticket already.
I never pay fines thanks to
my popularity.
You're not a fan, aren't you?
Pity!
How can one not
get excited for a sport.
so dynamic and healthy
like football?
I'm sorry, maybe you're waiting
for someone. I'll go away.
Will I see you at the races?
Yes? No? I hope so!
Well? I say miss,
what are you doing here?
During the day you don't train,
at night you go dancing, theaters...
- Who knows what you do at night!
- I dream. - Dreams!
- I dream of you
in small pants scoring a goal!
If I had a few kilos
less I'd show you!
- When I was a winger...
- They could tackle you no bother!
- In the game against Florence...
- Marco, stop bothering me!
- Actually, give me 500 lire. - What?
- I'll give them back tomorrow.
- Tomorrow!
- Yes, my aunt is coming.
It's 6 years you've been
talking about this aunt;
we all know she doesn't exist.
Doesn't she? Look at the envelope!
Sender, Marta Rossi. She's loaded!
She's rich and she loves me, don't
be stingy and lend me the money.
I can give you 100 lire only.
- They're not enough!
- Do you want them?
Don't show it
to everybody like that!
I've paid you 75 lire to take
the Miss to the races
and not to leave
her in the car park!
Do you call her "Miss"?
Dear sir the Duke of Fadda...
The Duke of Fadda
grabbed 75 lire to take her.
75 lire. Do you want me
to give them back?
- Yes
- Well, let's not overact.
Ok, I'll do it for you.
Where's the girl?
There she is.
- Dear Countess!
- Dear Duke!
I wouldn't have gave up
the pleasure of meeting you.
You're so kind Countess!
- Do you play?
- No. - I do. May I?
Sure!
Countess, I beg your
pardon for the nonsense.
I said earlier;
I was confused.
You see, I didn't know...
One moment, Grivola is favorite,
I'm going to the totalizator.
Grivola can't win
for goodness sake!
Are they giving Leda at 20?
What an effort!
They could give her even at 100.
She's old, lame and
with a whooping cough.
She couldn't win
even if she races alone.
- Hundred on Leda winning.
- Leda, 2000 against 100.
Hundred on Leda
for me as well.
- Did you take it for 20?
- 2000 lire for sure.
- If you want I'll give
it for 1000. - I... 500
- 1000!
- 500.
All right, spit it out!
That's where you
hide the money!
They belong to the ironer...
belonged!
- Hello, Jack.
- Did you play Grivola?
- Grivola?
No, I played Leda!
Leda failed to start!
That's when
you bet on a bastard!
One plays for fun,
after all.
Damn!
They said it was the favorite.
Yeah, right.
Favorite to come last sure!
It's Leda!
Leda! Leda!
C'mon babe! A bit more!
Yes! Leda!
Darling, dear!
Leda has won!
- So, I won 2000 lire then!
- Yes.
- But, you won them as well!
- Of course I won as well.
- God, so many people at the counter.
- If you wish, I'll go for you.
- Actually...
- Don't you trust me?
Yes, but...
- Well, you've got to collect as well.
- That's right. I've got to!
Thanks.
- Miss, what are you doing here?
- I'm waiting for... the Duke.
- Here he comes!
- Dear Miss, you always disappear!
It's 16:30! I've got to go
to the railway station.
I'm taking the car,
you'll get a taxi. Let's go!
- Leda, 2000 against 100.
- 1000, 1500, 2000, 2100.
- What are we looking for?
- 2000 lire - What?
I thought
he was a gentleman.
But dear, nobody is that
in front of 2000 lire.
- He'd be far away by now.
- Let's see. There is his car!
Was that him? Oh dear,
how could you trust
a stranger with 2000 lire?
- Did you know him? - No.
- Can you trace him? - No.
- What does this idiot
want with his horning?
The usual one
who wants his way.
Speed up, c'mon!
- I'm sorry, what about that lady?
- Who?
- Before there was a lady in here.
- Before, but not now.
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
I've got to pass
an important message.
- No message, I don't...
- No, a letter.
All right then.
Sir, your compartment
in the centre is ready.
- Are the suitcases all right?
- Yes, but there's a problem.
The widow Rossi called,
she's coming tomorrow.
- You told her...
- That you booked the train for Paris.
- What did she say?
- She gave me this message.
"If you leave for Paris,
you can stay there!"
Tell the lady that I am in Paris
and that she stops teasing me or...
- I could just give my notice!
- But... - Enough.
- All on board! - Actually,
I've got an idea. Porter!
- Good morning Sir!
- Good morning.
Now you'll see!
Today we'll have fun.
What time does
the widow Rossi arrive?
During the day,
she didn't mention the time.
Whatever time she comes,
remember to say...
that the director
is not around,
he's gone for a stroll,
just like that!
C'mon then!
What's this?
The new Jordaine's models!
- Those parcels arrived this morning.
- Yes, but...
I want to breath Paris's air,
let them put on straight away.
- But...
- No excuses!
I keep on managing this company and
choose my own designs in Paris.
Sir, the models from Milan
sent by Mrs. Rossi...
What a bore, what a trouble!
Milan!
Look at that! Paris!
I'm looking,
but you won't let me speak sir!
- These are the models from Milan.
- Has Mrs. Rossi sent them?
- Yes.
- Aren't they Jordaine's models!
So they are the models from Milan!
I thought there was something fishy.
Would that be
a casual lounge-suit?
- 2000 lire of cloth waisted.
- It costs 2300 lire.
Miss, have you heard?
The rug you're wearing...
..costs 2300 lire so, careful
when you take it off. Don't ruin it.
Make sure not
to show them to customers,
and if I see them again
I'll fire you.
- What's wrong with him?
- The new boss is coming.
- Does it look so bad?
- No - It's lovely.
'You look divine
in that dress, countess.'
I let myself being fooled.
Beside he was a bore and persisting!
I don't want to think about it.
- Not even about the 2000 lire?
- No, I want that!
Who is it?
- C'mon, don't worry!
- It's too much, go away!
Is Miss Marcella here?
An urgent message
for you, Countess!
Go away!
- I knew he wasn't the type...
- Who is it?
No!
'Countess, you disappeared
like a sweet dream'. - My god!
'The pain of not seeing you
and a debt of 2000 lire.'
- You were right then.
- I knew it!
'Please do call me
tomorrow at the stadium.'
Vanni!
Vanni! Phone!
Thanks!
- Hello?
- This is Count Buzzicanti
No! Two installments, two!
What? Waiting more?
Yesterday I waited almost two
hours in front the stadium.
I'm waiting since three months,
what do you think I should do?
Do as you like, you are free
to use the means you want.
Stop it now,
you understand?
Hello!
I beg your pardon, are you
looking for Mr Vanni? Sure!
Call Mr Vanni down the pitch!
Receptionist, put the call through
to Mr Vanni's private cabin.
- One moment, he's coming soon.
- He's coming soon.
Oh boy, they threw in turmoil
half stadium,
they treat them very well!
Hallo, is that Mr Vanni?
Wait, the countess would
like a word with you.
You shouldn't
have called me 'Countess'.
Done! Be indifferent
about the 2000 lire.
Hallo? Yes, it's me.
I'm so sorry but yesterday
when we left each other...
I and the Duke received
an invitation we couldn't refuse.
The 2000 lire? No rush for
such a thing at all.
Send them to me.
Oh no, I can't give the name!
You are right.
I don't know then.
- An appointment?
- You play hard to get.
I don't know, I don't go out
often and I've got a few commitments.
- Good.
- At my home? It's not possible!
No, on the street
it would be risky.
In a coffee shop
is not nice.
Give him the appointment now,
poor thing.
Almost every morning,
at midday, I pass by...
- Without commitment though.
- Two minutes only.
Just the time to sort my debt out
and give you my best regards.
Marco!
- Marco, my dear, in an hour!
- What?
An appointment,
at midday under the arcades.
Well, it wasn't
actually an appointment,
she's a lady, you know.
She said that almost every morning
she walks down the arcades.
- What do you do?
- At midday I'll be there.
'Oh, Countess, what a coincidence!'
Come on.
And what about aunty?
I forgot about her,
she had to come right today!
Call the countess and say blah blah
and move the appointment.
I can't! I don't know where
she lives, where do I call her?
- Do me a favour... - No money.
- I don't need money!
- You go and pick aunty up.
- You're crazy!
- How do I recognize her?
- It won't be difficult
She's old with glasses, shrewish
and strut. You can't miss her.
- Mr Vanni will you give me
an autograph? - Sure.
- Stop playing the diva. - Poor boy,
he just want an autograph - Good!
Me too!
So young and so wretched!
Pretending to be a star!
You're jealous, when you played
no-one was asking you an autograph.
- Mr. Vanni?
- One more autograph!
- Hurry up.
- A signature here.
- Done - One moment,
this is the judicial attachment.
I'm a bailiff, I'm gonna
take your car away...
... on a legal request from
Mr Buzzicanti.
- Unless you want to pay the 1.850 lire!
- I don't have time now.
- We can talk about it tomorrow.
- I've got to do the seizing today.
- All right, come back tonight.
- The car won't move from here.
- Either pay or...
- I'll pay!
- All right.
- See you tonight.
If you want to use the car,
you've got to pay now.
- And I'm doing you a favour because...
- I understand! How much is it?
- 1.850 lire and 75 cents.
- Here.
I think he won't give you
the 2.000 lire straight away.
- He was on a hurry over the phone.
- He'll take you for a ride - Oh, no!
- You used the Countess' money.
- What could I do?
- Shame!
- What?
I would have liked
this story ending happily.
- What's the problem?
- Where do I find a smart dress?
It's true.
I've got an idea!
The boss doesn't want
the models from Milan.
- Take this!
- Magnific!
Actually, I hope she won't come.
She said "almost every day".
- Maybe today she won't pass by.
- What if she will?
If she will... amen!
Oh Countess, finally!
I thought I couldn't
come this morning.
- But at the last moment...
- That's how luck strikes.
You're right.
Like yesterday with Leda.
It's true! Then...
- You're exaggerating
being in a hurry.
Hurry?
I'm not in a hurry!
So, shall we have
an aperitif at Conti?
No,
I just got the time for...
Do you really want to handle money
under the arcades... people watching!
- I've got my car.
- Oh no, I've got little time.
That's right. I'll take you
and give you the money on the way.
But if you don't want, we can meet
tomorrow in a more secluded place.
- Where's the car?
- There - One minute only
Two coffees and the bill.
Some nice music, a casual meeting,
two cars too close...
An unexpected win,
but substantial
- I hate this 2000 lire business.
- Why? - They bother me.
I would give anything to stop
this business between us.
It's easy,
as long as you...
As long as
I don't talk about it.
Right! Let's not talk about it
anymore as if it never existed.
Let's talk about us.
About us?
Don't you think it's too much?
I'd suggest
to sort it out, like you say.
Let's sort
the financial issue.
But who can guarantee
I will see you again?
I'm not saying you came for
the 2000 lire which are nothing...
- Well, not just "nothing"...
- Yes, but they are the reason...
- Countess, I won't give you
the 2000 lire - Why?
Because I want
to keep this link between us.
Next meeting we'll
talk about the 2000 lire.
Enough now.
- All right then,
but let's go now - As you wish.
- May I see you again?
- Of course!
- Oh my god! - What happened?
- Look at this!
- I'm sorry. Luckily it's nothing.
- Don't you see what a rip?
- A couple of stitches...
- Yes, two stitches! What shall I do?
What now? A new dress...
you can't understand.
Even with two stitches one can
see it's broken. Let's go!
- Where?
- Downtown, hurry up!
- You haven't told me
when we'll meet again.
I don't know now,
I can't say.
- And that money? - Well,
let's sort this business now.
- Now? But I want to wait.
- And I want it now.
- This sort of blackmail
is bothering me - Blackmail?
I start thinking
you came for the money only.
Of course, what do you expect?
If it's so,
you'll have your 2000 lire.
- Will I?
- Yes.
I didn't bring it because I thought
the meeting'd have gone differently.
- I'll send my servant today.
- Give it to my housemaid.
- Where?
- At 18:15 in Duca D'Aosta Square.
- Well, where shall I take you?
- To the Grand Hotel, please.
Wait to take the suitcases, they
may be mixed with someone's else.
- How much?
- 13.50 with the luggage.
13.50 for a couple of steps?
Couple of steps?
We crossed the city!
Look at the meter after all!
- I'll give you 5 lire.
- The price is right.
- How do you know it's right?
- Calm down, Mrs.
- I won't be cheated.
- Cheat? What a fool!
- Did you say 'fool'?
- No! The lady is a bit upset.
Get a doctor
and ask for a cure!
Rude and lout!
Taking advantage of a woman!
- Slap him for me please!
- Me? - I give you 5 lire!
- I'll sort it out, Mrs.
- Would you slap me?
I don't even think about it,
here 20 lire and enjoy Ishtar!
Gino, she just came!
- I saw her, move now.
- Have she seen you? - Sure.
- When?
- Two hours ago, at the arcades.
What? I'm talking about aunt!
She came now and
she's worse than the plague!
I had to tell her you had the fever.
If she sees us here, she'll kill us!
Let's go!
- Where's the hatbox?
- It's gone!
- It can't be possible.
- It is, with all such a bedlam!
- May I help you Madam?
- I'm waiting for someone but maybe...
- If you'd give me the name I'll check.
- It doesn't matter. Mrs Rossi.
- She has arrived just now.
- Who?
Mrs Marta Rossi, haven't you
asked about her?
Have you asked about me?
You can go.
- Have you asked about me?
- No, I mean, yes.
- What does that mean?
- It's a misunderstanding.
What misunderstanding? You asked for
Mrs Rossi, that's me you see.
I thought that you
hadn't come and then...
You asked about me because you
thought I hadn't arrived.
Let me go, please.
Goodbye.
- Don't try to leave or
I'll stop you - What?
Who are you?
Let's see, you are...
You are a customer
from Primavera stores.
No, I'm an employee there.
- Employee how, what, where?
- At the Maison Printemps.
- What?
- Model at the Maison Printemps.
Printemps! 'Primavera Stores'
sounds better!
So you are a model
at the Primavera Stores.
He gave you
this dress to come here...
and inquire about me, didn't you?
- You are wrong, Mrs!
- This is a rip.
- Let me explain.
Come to my room.
- But Madam!
- Undress over there.
- Madam, I've got...
- Undress!
Can someone sew in here?
- Sew? - Mending a rip
with thread and needle!
- I'll send the cloakwork attendant.
- Well do that then!
I'll show your manager. This time
I'm gonna have some fun
Put this dressing gown on.
Come in!
- I'm the cloackroom attendant.
- Look at this dress.
- Pretty! - I didn't ask
your opinion! Look at the rip.
- Oh dear, what happened?
- Mind your own business!
Fix it, and hurry up.
Sit there.
It's my fault.
I took the dress furtively.
- You've got some cheek!
- What are you saying?
I'm saying you wore
that dress under
the manager's order
and I want to know why!
If he'd know that
I took that dress,
going out with that dress,
I'd be ruined.
- You insist! - He said that
the dress is horrible.
Horrible ?
- He said the dress is horrible.
- Yes, that's what he said.
- So, this dress is horrible.
- Not for me. I like it a lot.
I've never seen such
a lovely dress before!
- Just the idea of those cuffs...
- The idea of those cuffs then?
- It's original.
- And the fabric?
Oh the fabric, the fabric is
extraordinary! Soft, light...
- I've got to say you wear it well.
- You're too kind.
You wear it finely
You picked a good choice.
Don't worry about your manager;
if he says anything...
actually,
I'll call him now.
I won't move from here.
I want to be the first to meet
such an arrogant hick coming here...
Hello?
This is the Maison Printemps.
The Grand Hotel?
- Widow Rossi.
- Ah, widow Rossi!
Hello?
Go away, please,
do me a favour, go away.
Close the door
and don't let anyone in.
Hello?
Yes Madam, it's me.
I'm eager to meet you.
What? Paris?
No, Paris can wait
I didn't want
to miss the pleasure...
You'll give me the pleasure
and honour tonight.
What?
Is it ok if I come tonight?
I'll come tomorrow then.
Enough, you talk too much!
Goodbye.
Done. I have treated him bad,
haven't I?
Maybe, but that little voice
was so tantalizing...
After 20 years,
it's always the same!
The same voice!
Come here,
who told you to go away?
20 years passed by and who knows
what happened to her!
Marta Piacentini,
widow Rossi...
- It must be her!
- Who Sir?
A woman from the times gone,
when I was young, rich...
..and I was traveling for fun.
He was a penniless, a
poor traveling salesman.
She fell head
over heels for me.
He insisted,
threatened to kill himself!
Jealous and so much in love!
She wanted me all for herself.
I trusted him a bit
and in the end
I became fond of him,
like I was of a cat.
Poor woman!
Maybe I'd have married her...
if in my life Henriette
wouldn't have appeared!
From a French noble family,
rich, smart, refined...
...living in famous hotels,
stylish!
And do you know who
that French woman was?
The cashier from
a day hotel in Marsiglia.
Men? You can
never trust men, my child!
- Very well!
- Who was it? - Nobody.
I just tested the bell,
you're pitiful.
Stop it! I'll get dressed put
the shoes on and go away now.
- Where to?
- To find the 2.000 lire, yeah?
- I've got to find it by 6 o'clock.
- Where? - Wherever.
If you find them,
you'll do everyone a favour.
Wait.
It's half past three Madam,
in 5 minutes.
I've got to be at the Stores.
You're right,
I like you a lot!
Hello? Yes, put him through!
My nephew: I wouldn't
recommend him to you! A rascal!
You can go, I'll give you the dress
as  present because you're nice...
..and I make you
Store supervisor.
You're dear, good and kind and
for this... let's not anticipate.
- Come here tonight at 8 bang on time.
- All right Madam, thank you!
Hello? Who is it?
I'm the big one
who slapped the driver.
I need to tell you that your
nephew is in bad condition.
He's delirious
and moans, poor thing!
I gave him
two injections already.
Yes, Fitina injections.
I see, apply
a hot poultice, two actually!
I've done that!
He was so hot that I had to
place an ice bag on his head.
Very well. Let's check
the temperature first,
and then let's make
a couple more. Thermometer!
#incomprehensible words#
Like I thought,
he's not running a temperature.
That's very worrying.
If he had the fever,
we could say:
'Poor thing,
he's got a fever' but...
I understand,
if I give you the 2000 lire...
and he wastes them with
his crooked life-style,
and then asks for more.
No! You've got to change life-style,
stop such a damned sport!
- What? - Shut up!
- Are we in the army?
You've got to have a family.
I could introduce
you a good girl for instance...
- Who knows how to make meatballs.
- My dear!
Meatballs are important
in marriage relationship.
Yeah, right!
If you think that I'll
sell you my soul for 2000 lire,
you're wrong!
It's 3 hours I'm suffocating under
the sheets to gain what? Same lecture!
You're a rogue!
Where are you going?
To a woman who doesn't
know how to make meatballs.
- A woman? So even this morning then...
- Yes, I was with a woman.
Who knows what kind of woman!
A wonderful,
elegant and beautiful woman!
- Excellent - Who wants 2000 lire.
- It's her's!
God! Do you let
a woman supporting you?
No, I owe her 2000 lire.
Yesterday at the horse races...
too long to explain,
but it's a serious thing.
If you care about
the family honour,
give the 2000 lire
to Marco. Goodbye.
Madam...
Did he give them to you?
Listen, I won't step
in your house ever again!
I...
What are you gonna
do now poor sonny?
What do you
expect me to do?
'A nice dream has finished but,
better to confess you everything'
'I'll try to give you the sum back
within two, three days. Gino Vanni.'
I told her that I would have
sent my servant...
- Servant? Am I supposed to be
your servant? - So what?
I'm good, generous but...
I get it, I'll go myself.
We've arrived,
I'm going away.
But the servant
doesn't know you.
I'll wait for you
at that coffeehouse.
- What are you afraid of?
- Nothing.
I don't want the servant may
think that I came to check.
He came himself!
- Shall I go then?
- Yes, I'll wait here for you.
- What if he courts me?
- Not a problem.
Are you Mr Vanni's servant?
- Don't be smart! Give it
to the lady - Lady? Ah!
Are you always so rude
when you meet a girl?
I don't have time to waste.
Good day,
are you surprised that I came?
- Forgive me Countess...
- Are you not taking me for a walk?
- Did you get the envelope?
- Sure.
Now all is clear
and we can talk.
- So, don't you want to take me
for a walk? - At your service.
- Can we talk to the driver?
- Sure.
- The walking is not pleasing you.
- Not really. Those damned 2000 lire...
We gave too much
importance to that money.
You sealed them in the envelope, me
in the handbag. Let's change subject.
- So you believe...
- Let's change subject!
- Look at my dress.
- Pretty.
It doesn't cost more than 200 lire,
What does that make you think?
Distrust of my car? By the way,
Have you managed to fix it?
Yes, it was nothing.
- The cloackroom attendant fixed it.
- The cloackroom attendant? - Yes
Have you looked at it carefully?
Don't I look a model?
- A model?
- A little tailor, a hatter.
What are you saying? You can't think
of mingling with some sort of girls.
The dress is not important,
it depends who wears it...
The model, the tailor..
it's a matter of style.
at the end of the day.
- I could never be with such women.
- Why have you stopped?
- Where are we going?
- I don't want to go too far.
- Are you in a hurry to go back?
- Yes - I'll go back then.
What are you doing?
A few kilometers
and we'll be there.
- I'm afraid we won't meet again.
- So what? - In that envelope...
You're still talking
about that nasty issue!
- You're right, but in that
envelope, Countess... - Well!
I forbid you to talk about it
and to call me Countess.
You don't want
to tell me your name.
I'll tell you if you wish.
- Marcella - Nice. I always
loved such a name.
Do you know many
women with that name?
No, you are the first.
I mean, no other
woman's name is so nice.
- Let's go - This way?
- No, that way.
- Shame!
- Why such a big sigh?
I told you. I've got the feeling
that we won't see each others again.
I swear I was really
fond of you, Countess.
- My words would sound
ridiculous after - After? When?
- Don't open it now Countess!
- Oh no! Remember what
you said this morning?
'I won't give you
the 2.000 lire, so...'
- So what?
- Take them back
- But Countess...
- I beg you.
Countess, I...
Just promise to me not trying
to find out who I am.
You have my word.
Countess, it's 8 o'clock,
satisfied of the driver?
- Yes, tomorrow then - For our
own appointment or our servants'?
- Our servants'.
- At quarter past six.
That lady who went upstairs...
- She goes to number 148.
- 148, thanks!
Miss, come.
10, 20...
- 37 and 80 of these roses.
- 37 and 80?
Yes, it's that simple. send them
to the the Grand Hotel, room 148...
..from Gino Vanni,
tomorrow at dawn.
Son, you couldn't say
sorry in a better way!
The roses moved me,
you deserve a kiss!
You've found a way to take
that money from me, you rascal!
- How much did you say?
- 2000 lire - I thought 3000.
I always exaggerate, here.
Stop it!
Enough talking, another kiss
and I'll go away.
I'll wait for you at the Grand Hotel
tonight, there'll be a big party.
At 8 o'clock!
She could've put 1000 lire
for me too!
- What happened? - The florist
must have made a mistake.
I'll give her
the 2000 lire at once!
- So, tonight at the appointment...
- Don't forget lunch with aunt.
- You go there.
- Me? No!
All right then so, I'll
get the taxi fare back.
- But you go to bed at 9!
- Yes.
But at quarter
past six my dear...
Tonight you won't go out so you will
celebrate your new manager post.
You got in touch with Mrs Rossi
trying to bypass me.
- I explained it was a coincidence.
- A coincidence? Should I believe you?
Describe Mrs Ross,
what does she look like?
I'm not worried of that hick.
She'd feel lost...
..among the customers I created. Today
I invited the Marchioness of Lambergo.
A ros dress.
I know Mrs Rossi since 20 years,
born Piacentini.
She'll find out
when she sees me.
She'll wrap her hands around my neck
and I'll make her jump like that!
..like a grasshopper!
Marta, dear, why...
Stay there! I don't know you and
I don't tolerate such liberty.
Let's get to the point, what
do you want to do?
I'll go by your arrangements.
Too easy! I arrange
and you criticize, no!
You'll arrange
and I'll criticize.
If you'll let me do it, I have
a few ideas for the launch.
- Let's hear one - In three months...
- Three months are too many.
In a week there's
an exhibition at Sestriere.
What are you plans today?
Tonight there's the opening
season party at the Grand Hotel.
Dinner at eight, dancing and 10.
I'll personally take care...
- I'm sorry!
- One moment, please.
A table for three, good.
- How can I help? - I'd like to know
the room number of a Countess.
- She's young, beautiful, smart.
- May I have the name...
- If I knew the name...
- Cloackroom attendant to 115!
- Attendant?
- To 115
- Attendant, to 115.
- I'm going.
Yesterday you mended a black
dress with ermine cuffs?
- Yes. - Do you know the lady
who gave it to you?
- Sure.
- Here.
- Give her this - All right.
- In person.
'This money burns in my hands'
What a fool!
'When we'll meet tonight, the field
will be clear of financial issues'.
What clear field is he on about?
Romantic and loudmouth like his dad!
But I like him.
- Good evening young man.
- My nephew sent you to tell me...
The club suddenly called him...
I understand, he's not coming.
For the second time he prefers
a cow's company to his aunt.
No, for goodness sake!
Madam, you're not right entirely.
You always tackle him.
You tell him: 'No this, that's fine!'
And he does the opposite.
- Have you dined already?
- No, actually I...
I won't keep you then,
goodbye.
- Marcella, where is she?
- She left her handbag in the car.
- What? The handbag in the car?
- Here she comes!
You risked5t 3 months salary by
forgetting your handbag in the car.
- I didn't forget the handbag.
- So why were you left behind?
The Countess can't come,
she'll call you.
- She said don't try to see her tonight.
- Wait! Did she not say something else?
- No.
- Is that all? Where is she now?
- I don't know.
- You don't know? I understood!
But, I won't say
anything... no!
Well, you maybe follow me.
So, who would you represent
tonight? A princess?
- You tell me.
- Oh well, if you ask me...
These people
in here have to believe.
But you, do you really
like such a farce?
That wretched says that a good
product is obvious by itself.
Such assumption
works for wine and cheese.
We need a subtle advertising,
pervasive. Look at this.
'Would you like
your woman to adore you?'
'Buy the Maison Printemps
toiletries'
- What do you reckon? - Tell me,
do you dispense these tickets?
- I've got a great idea! Here.
- Sir?
Give them to the girls.
While they dance, secretly...
the girls will slip the tickets
into their partners' pockets.
The day after
everybody will read...
'Buy the Maison Printemps
toiletries!'
- Fantastic! - For that you've got to
introduce the girls to all men...
so they'll dance nonstop.
Agreed?
It depends.
On what?
Well, each introduction
is a responsibility.
- The price?
- It's not up to me to say.
I trust your sense of understanding.
A Duke introducing, the tickets risk...
- Shall we do twenty lire?
- Twenty lire!
- Twenty-five?
- Let's say thirty.
All right thirty then.
- But where are you looking for me?
- Ah, it's you.
- What should I do to you?
- Sorry, aunty - No.
Don't be a bluster,
you need the money.
I swear dear aunty
that money right now
is the last thing in my mind!
- Yes!
These are the 2.000 lire
that you sent me back.
What? The 2000 lire again?
It's absurd!
Stop it,
otherwise I beat you.
I'll give you another 2.000 to spend
and don't send them back to me.
Give them
and we'll see this time.
Have fun
with your great love!
Great love?
For goodness sake!
It's not worth
wasting some feelings.
It was just a fling,
I won't think about it.
- I feared you were in love.
- Me in love?
Don't make me laugh!
I'm not that naive.
It's ok to fall in love,
but with a good girl.
- Who can cook meatballs.
- Yes, meatballs too!
Better the meatballs girl
then that tramp...
of my butt who distributes small
tickets with the phone number on them.
Just a moment, aunty,
I'll be right back.
Don't be too surprised,
but I can't stand.
this business
about the tickets at all!
It's an order from your manager;
I don't have anything to do with it!
- Sure! - And then?
- Don't insist because...
- May I have a word?
- I'm sorry that you...
- You didn't expect it, didn't you?
- Don't speak like that to my cousin!
- Is she your cousin? I'm delighted!
- Do you want me to send him away?
- I want to give your money back.
- I am the duke of Fadda.
Pleased to meet you, Gino Vanni.
I want to give back to the lady...
2000 lire that she asked me
to collect on her behalf.
I wish to sort my debt out.
- Good idea. Do it then.
- One moment!
I don't remember
of giving him such a task.
- But dear, we played all day
at the races! - It was another one.
And even if it was true, he shouldn't
give me the money in here.
- So much quibbling...
- That's enough, I don't know anything.
If I'll remember about that sum
I'll know how to ask it back.
No! It's me who says enough.
And that's why your duo
amused me for too long now!
Here the 2000 lire,
do what you wish.
Countess, Duke!
Keep this money! You'll give it
back to me when I'll say so!
Merely after I tell
you are rude and I won't let
anyone treat me like that.
- Did you understand?
- Yes, I understood.
I understood
many other things too!
I am rude because I didn't
bow to the Countess...
or because last night I waited
one hour and fifteen minutes...
for the Countess to arrive?
- I would have explained.
Or maybe because I interrupted
your flirting,
your distributing
of scented tickets?
- The tickets... - Would you have
explained that too - Sure.
I was so naive to believe you
worth of a feeling.
It's really funny! Tell it to
the people of your world.
- Add me to your affairs.
- If you don't stop it...
I've got to be careful, you could
send me an entire a whole band.
And now that you've lost that
little goodness I thought you had...
Do know that
the other day I did notice...
in the envelope there was no money
but simply written paper!
- So, why did you get in the car?
- You always understand everything...
but maybe you'll
never understand that!
Marcella!
- All is over then.
- It looks like.
- But the 2000 lire
are still there. - What?
Now that we are
all together dear manager,
I can tell you are a beast!
- Madam...
- Beast!
Your idea of taking the models
to the Grand Hotel.
and join them to the party...
was totally silly!
- I've got to disagree!
It doesn't matter if you disagree,
that idea was silly nevertheless.
After all, do you think that kind of
advertising effective? Let's hear it!
- What do you reckon?
- I... - Don't be afraid.
They pinched me a lot!
I don't know if they did that
'cause they thought I was
or I wasn't a lady. Thing is
that I'm covered with bruises now.
The bruises have nothing to do with it.
They are the Miss personal business.
- Did they pinch you as well?
- Not me; but they made such advances!
- And you? Do you think that was
effective? - I don't know anything.
All I know is that I'm tired of
pretending to be a lady when I'm not.
I'm simply a girl who needs to work.
I'll tell you one more thing...
I'm not going to Sestriere
for the fashion show.
I won't go, I won't go
and I won't go!
- What happened?
- Nothing, Madam.
- I can't live like this anymore.
- Have you argued with him?
- That fool doesn't understand
anything! - Like all men.
I missed an appointment last night
because I needed to go
to the Grand Hotel and he...
It's useless saying anything,
it's all is over by now,
but it doesn't matter,
I don't care.
I see! Don't worry,
there are many cute guys.
Enough now. I don't want to suffer
again like I did for him...
for that arrogant loudmouth!
- Tomorrow is sunday, you'll
come with me to have good time.
Thanks, but I don't
want to go anywhere.
Oh you can simply
keep me company.
- Imagine, it's just a football match!
- The match against Switzerland?
- Oh, do you know anything about it?
- No, it's to keep you company.
Very well then.
We agree in football too!
C'mon! Go on!
- C'mon, Gino!
- Do you know Gino Vanni?
- He's my nephew unfortunately.
- Your nephew?
Nothing to be proud of!
I've got a nephew who
throws kicks, nice profession!
Few minutes before
the end of the first half:
Italy 0 Switzerland 0.
Italy started attacking.
Vanni is in a great form but reluctant
to kick towards the goal...
passes the ball
to the right wing.
Why do you pass? Kick!
Vanni missed
another chance to score.
Rascal, dirty rat!
Thinking about women, aren't you?
Like father like son.
His father was a bowls champion!
The first half ended
with the following score...
Italy 1 Switzerland 0.
Vanni scored 5 seconds before
the end of the first half.
Good! A bit shrewd,
but always a pretty boy.
I was afraid he fell
in love... with a Countess.
- She would have ruined him.
- Why?
It doesn't matter,
better like that!
What do you mean?
He said he wasn't in love,
he just had fun!
Now I want him to settled down
with a good girl.
I found her already, she doesn't
have a dowry, but that
doesn't matter. I'll take a million
from him and give it to her!
Madam, I regret what I said.
Please tell the manage
I want to go to Sestriere.
Really?
- Yes, it's better.
Good day! I've found you finally,
I've been looking for you for 5 days.
Would you be so kind as to tell me
where the Countess' apartments are?
- Young man, you're talking nonsense.
- It's about the 2000 lire.
The 2000 lire?
Please make yourself at home!
- Excuse me if I welcome you
like this - So, your cousin?
I'm gonna meet her
at Sestriere today.
- Is she in Sestriere?
- Yes.
Yes, and if you hand
the money over to me...
Happy now?
Did you like those models?
Italian models, my ideas and he
believes he did it all yourself!
- But...
- But keep quiet!
- What's this stuff?
- This is the ultimate moment.
The wedding dress
that ends the show.
Now you'll see a show
of 12 very new models.
A girl, through her debutant stage
to becoming a married lady.
It starts with a schoolgirl model
and it ends with an ultimate moment...
the wedding dress.
- C'mon! Who had such an idea?
Madam, I beg you.
We'll end up on the church magazine
'The family angel'.
- Give me the dress - A wedding
dress ending the fashion show!
It's my idea! You have always been
averse to the wedding dress...
and that's why
I've added it in the show!
True men prefer smart women,
low-necked...
but they need to understand that
they've got to marry them in the end!
- Only then fashion will have
a meaning! - That's enough!
A wedding dress ending the show!
I resign!
Miss Marcella, come here!
What's the matter
of being so cheerful?
It's thanks to you, Madam.
To hell with gloominess!
- What does that mean?
- I stopped being a fool.
I want to enjoy my youth
and whatever happens, happens!
I'm gonna slap you.
I'm sorry,
but I've got to change dress!
All right,
we'll talk about it later.
Are you a soccer
or a sportscar champion?
Soccer!
I'm feeling cold,
if we'd get a cup of tea...
Thanks but I don't have time.
Where's your cousin?
Wait on a minute.
We came all the way here...
Give me the money
and I'll take it to her.
I need
to give it personally.
- So, will you wait for me here?
- With pleasure!
- How come are you here?
- I wanted to go for a trip.
- With your beautiful lady.
- No, it's over.
- By the way, you mentioned
of a girl... - Well, she's here.
- Here?
- she's smart, elegant...
- Enough, I accept!
- Without seeing her?
As long as you like her.
Is she a cripple? No!
Hunchback? No!
So, I'll marry her then.
I'll get engaged
this very night.
Tell her that she has my agreement,
or rather that I am in love.
- May I?
- You again!
Yes, me again,
but for few seconds only!
Just the time to give you
these printed sheets!
They aren't written,
but printed!
- Have you come here on purpose?
- No, I'm passing by.
- Good luck, Countess.
- Thanks, same to you.
- Are you leaving now?
- No, I'm staying just
for a formality. I'm
gonna get engaged tonight.
Really? Congratulations,
when will you marry?
- I don't know yet but soon, within
the current month! - What a hurry!
Are you afraid
to change your mind?
No, I'm determined
and very much in love.
How touching!
Is your fiance beautiful?
I don't know... I mean, I know it!
She's beautiful and, above all, nice.
Nice, affectionate and loyal.
Do you know what 'loyal' means?
- It's not one of those women who are...
- I wish you a lot of happiness.
But make sure not
letting such a nice girl...
waiting too long because of me!
- You're wrong!
- My fiance... - I've got to go
to the tailor and measure a dress.
Actually, if you come back
in 10 minutes, I also
want to give you
an advice and some news.
Very well,
see you later Countess!
(host) Engagement!
First kiss.
Waiting.
What a surprise, isn't it?
It suits me, don't you think?
It feels a bit funny
in here but it's nothing.
You look so surprised because
you don't know my name.
Everybody talked
about it these days!
But you could've seen
it on the papers.
I obtained my marriage dissolution
and tomorrow I'll get married here.
It's a strange idea,
but we're a group of friends.
and here it'll
be more cheerful.
Weddings are always depressing.
Of course!
You know that by experience!
- That dress has an imperfection.
- What?
- Yes, orange flowers.
- Orange flowers?
I heard they
are a symbol of purity...
When a man insults
a woman, he's a lout...
Go away, you insulted me enough!
It's all over now!
I wouldn't start
it again for anything!
Go then once
and for all. I'm busy!
Yes! For a woman like you
marriage is just a dress!
Better a poor common girl,
a tailor, a hatter...
those who live
because they work! Understand?
They've got heart,
they know what love is...
and embody more nobility than
all the countesses on earth.
That's how I wanted my woman,
uncomplicated,
without frills and jewels.
- But with a big heart!
- Can't you see what I am?
- What are you?
- A mannequin!
In italian it's "fashion model".
That's what you say!
You? And do you work
in my aunty's firm?
Yes, at Primavera Stores!
So I know where to find you then!
Via Roma, 148. Telephone: 62347!
What an idea! Great! Great!
- I withdraw my resignation
- You withdraw your ideas! - Sure.