El Pez Que Fuma
I'm in prison, serving my sentence
Sentence imposed by society
I'm afflicted and ashamed
But I'm to serve it all alone
My guitar, that little orphan, plays no more
And though late, I now know it is real
That the one who plays so close to fire
If does not live cautiously, he will burn
I only ask my friends in the outside
To guard against liquor and its evil
That the only one, last and foremost
Is for ever the word Freedom
I'm in prison, serving my sentence
Sentence imposed by society
I'm afflicted and ashamed
But I'm to serve it all alone
My guitar, that little orphan, plays no more
And though late, I now know it is real
That the one who plays so close to fire
If does not live cautiously, he will burn
I only ask my friends in the outside
To guard against liquor and its evil
That the only one, last and foremost
Is for ever the word Freedom
Freedom
There they are! They arrived!
The mattresses arrived!
Come this way.
Watch out. Come.
Come.
A little down. You too.
Take that one to the 14th.
This one here in the 35th.
Check first whether it fits.
It fits well.
All right.
Let's change this one for the new one at once.
That's great. But, be careful!
It's all wholesale!
We be got new mattresses!
The mattresses!
My love!
Couldn't you bring those mattresses some
later?
I stayed awake till dawn.
I'm talking to you, Dumas.
Heron!
She's washing it, Heron!
Get that dog out of here!
Baby, that dog again!
Get it out of here!
Then the bedroom stinks!
Bring that dog here!
Shit, that dog is mine! Mine!
I'm gonna kill it!
I told you, I'm gonna kill it!
Heron! Heron!
She thinks she's too brave.
You, come this way.
You have a new mattress.
Take this.
Heron! Heron!
You have a new mattress, Heron.
A new mattress!
Watch out, watch out!
Look at this, Heron. Look at this. Look.
See how it swings. It matches your
movements.
Don't!
Don't take it away.
Leave that one.
Leave it somewhere around. Ill find a place
for it.
Do as she says.
Goodbye, Heron. I hope you enjoy it.
What are you thinking?
You know... life.
Well, my baby, come!
Let's start using the anatomical!
No, not in this room.
I think we'll have some spare ones.
Well, we can use those as replacement.
Let's move it around!
Nineteen and thirty-five cents.
Fifty-six and fifty cents.
One hundred and twenty-five.
Jesus's age and seventy-five cents.
33 and seventy-five cents.
- 1,548.
- From whom?
The stockbreeder and Dr. Brice.
They were really plastered, Heron!
One thousand five hundred forty-eight and
zero cents.
The two ducklings.
22.
Add it all up.
Tell me, what did it come to?
11,518.
Pay the eleven cases of whisk and with the
rest,
buy mortgage debentures. At 8.5 percent.
Don't you want any deposit?
No. Better buy the debentures.
You're so gorgeous, baby.
Do you want something?
You know what I want.
I'll take with me what you want.
But I'll bring it back to you.
Watch out. Don't you lose it somewhere.
Dimas, who is the macho here?
You are the boss, Heron.
You are a little less, aren't you?
- Almost, almost.
- No, just a little.
Almost, almost.
Tell me, Dumas.
You're just a little less boss. Tell me, baby.
Common, tell it to me.
Ole, toro!
Goodbye, my pretty little girl!
You're a hot delicious thing!
Don't you lose it! Take care of my ding-a-ling!
Don't you wear it out, my little girl!
- Who is it?
- Peace loving people.
Are you the Heron?
It depends.
Tobias sent me.
And what's the matter with Tobias?
He's fine. He sends his greetings.
When did you see him?
I was in jail. I spent three days there.
I was released last night.
Then Mr. Tobias told me to talk to you.
Look.
It's a photo of him stoned the day before
yesterday,
because he made a bet that his aura would be
seen.
He explained that you have an aura,
that can be yellow or blue,
and can be seen with Lobsang Rampa's third
eye.
Go, bathe yourself, pig!
Fuck, stop beating him!
It's enough!
What the fuck did he do to you?
Don't you meddle! Mind your own shit!
I'm gonna call the police!
Keep on beating him and you'll see!
They fuck and bring children like the rabbits!
And then they almost devour their own breed.
Fucking misery.
What does that jerk want? Money I have not!
- No, he doesn't. Me.
- What?
- I want to be in your business.
- As a whore?
Anything.
What do you mean by anything?
Anything you tell me to do.
And then I get into trouble for hiring a minor?
Don't you be stupid!
Do you want to see my documents?
Quintero Garcia, Jairo Javier.
Born on the 10th of the 10th, 1958.
Single and fag.
The tenth of the tenth, 1958.
Which month is the tenth?
It's October.
Dictatorship was already over.
There are many who are the same age as
democracy.
Right now there's no job for you, Jairo.
I was left a wreck.
Mr. Dumas. Mr. Dumas, spare me a second.
I would like to talk to you.
I was talking to Ms. Heron and...
Mr. Dumas! Please, Mr. Dumas!
Go away, please.
Who the hell told you to go to the racetrack?
It was Batman Sosa It was Batman Sosa
How the hell can I explain?
He gave me the money to bet and told me I
would win!
That fucking Batman Sosa
I told you to buy the mortgage debentures and
pay the whisk!
I didn't mention Batman Sosa!
But I also have my life, don't I? Am I your dog or something?
And if he puts me on a business, what Am I to
say?:
No, no way. My girl will lose her rag. Fuck you!
I'm not your girl!
Me your girl?
Because you lay with me?
Am I your girl for that shit?
Oh, baby, you don't know me.
This way you came in, this way you went out.
You can stay with your Batman Sosa
I reckon he's even a fag!
Don't talk to me so. Respect me
or I'll beat the shit out of you!
Will you?
What is it for? To pay for the car?
Very impressive.
I had the car insured last month.
In a week it'll be all brand new.
That's yet to be seen.
What do you know about insurance, dickhead?
You are always that way. Everything is easy to
you.
They could have killed me!
It was Tobias! I'm sure it was him!
What Tobias? Tobias is in jail.
After all, they should kill you for being an
asshole!
You shut up!
I'm more worth than a car, aren't I?
More than a Caprice? Let me tell you, you
aren't.
Right, then. Keep your money and your shit
and fuck off!
Get out of my way, fucking useless lame!
Coward!
Why don't you pick on a man?
If oil hadn't damaged my legs,
you would have been in serious trouble,
Dumas!
THE FISH THAT SMOKES
- What is it, jerk?
- Nothing.
What are you looking at?
- Is it your car? Your motorcycle?
- They aren't.
- So What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
I don't like people looking at.
Never mind. I saw nothing.
I can see in your face you're a rat.
Who are you informing?
I won't tell, buddy. Forget it. Stay cool.
Are we even, buddy?
Good evening.
Oh, Lord.
It seems you recognize me.
Why is it so you recognize me?
Darling, you seem to have lost something
the moment you saw me.
Could it be that we play in the same band?
All right. Silent, please.
And now, tonight's guessing game:
It begins with P
and ends in,
and we all like it.
Pussy! Pussy!
Wrong. It's pastry.
Ladies and truckers.
From Hamburg, big city of science,
we have tonight a Venezuelan lady
who has proudly represented our coat of arms:
The Satanic!
One more?
Two more.
Hey.
Who's that sitting with Maria?
They've been already an hour there.
Is he ordering gin or what?
No. Just mineral water and ice.
Is he? Tell her to come here.
Would you do me a big favor?
It's such a favor that in forty years from now
I will still be thankful from the bottom of my
heart.
Please, baby, don't you piss me off.
How come are you wasting the night drinking
cold water
with that good-for-nothing?
What do you have him there for?
It can't be so, Bunny.
Listen. I mean.
I don't want to get pissed, you see.
You know how I am when I get pissed.
What are you laughing at, jerk?
You can go laugh at your mother!
Me? How come?
Common, I'm laughing at nothing.
Try to get yourself something worthwhile,
something better.
Look. Maybe even my friend here wants.
I have no dough.
Want some?
What's the day today?
I said what's the day today.
Thursday.
Where is the Heron?
In the house.
I have a bruise here, you see?
It was Dumas who did it.
And your dog he also maltreated.
Listen, Daniel: What became of Linda?
Linda?
But I have no news of fer.
She's gone.
She hasn't written.
And God only knows...
I came for my severance.
He crashed my car.
He smashed it to bits.
Sheer shreds.
And then he comes and tells me:
No problem. We've got insurance.
Always the insurance.
I'm leaving, Heron.
There's a solution for everything, my daughter.
You get your car crashed,
the insurance pays for it.
You die,
then comes the insurance and pays for it.
Don't you go, Bunny.
Take a bath.
Go and take a bath.
Water it.
Watch as your shrubs get watered.
I met Pedro Vargas...
in Acapulco in 1953,
He was there, taking a bath in a pool.
That is, Daniel Santos
and the Sonora Macerate.
All of them.
All of them taking a bath at the pool.
In 1953, in Acapulco.
And all of them...
had their insurance.
Fire insurance.
Comprehensive insurance.
Accident insurance.
Don't you go away from me, Bunny.
You're leaving, aren't you?
Look! A pig!
Catch it! Catch it!
Catch it!
He caught it!
Now we re gonna kill it!
I'd better get off! Stop!
I'm going to buy me a horse.
Yes.
I'm going to buy me a thoroughbred.
A thoroughbred.
Why can't I have a horse
if I want to have a horse?
Listen, blond guy! Blond guy!
Fuck.
You destroyed my car, Tobias.
You destroyed my car.
But I have a horse.
Long live the Mariachi!
Heron!
Stone-made has to be the bed
Stone-made its headboard too
The woman who loves me
She's got to love me true
My sweet heart, why do you love him?
Heron!
Blond guy.
Watch out.
Give way, Blond guy.
No, wait a second.
Heron!
Dumas, I want my severance pay.
No way. You're not leaving this place, Bunny.
No, you lady, you stay here.
You, Ms. Bunny, you don't leave this place.
You can't stand me, can you?
Until today.
At noon, I'm taking a bus.
I will get a job.
No way. Staying up all night.
I can't even watch the soap opera.
I used to watch it before.
What's the use, after all?
They're the ones who get the profit.
And it's big money.
And we always screwed up.
And Dumas telling me off.
Again?
You'll have to pay double, you know?
Here. Here.
Here, tiny one. Come here, baby.
Take this, baby. Come, my tiny little one.
Black, come here! Here, my son!
Tell them to bring an orange juice.
But not sour.
I want some little sweet oranges
with little ice cubes.
Who did you leave with last night?
With the Monkey.
You're cheating on me.
I know you're cheating on me.
I know you are into something.
You always find the way to make me forgive
you.
But stupid I am not.
Did you hear, my baby girl?
Keep your hands off that dough!
What's up, buddy?
So what about last night?
Man, I'm broke. I'm really broke.
I saw when you arrived last night.
All angry and stuff.
I know it was not the right moment.
But I came to see whether you could get me a
job.
Doing what?
Anything, man. Whatever you tell me.
The thing is to earn something.
Listen, brother. I'll be frank.
I was released from jail yesterday.
I spent 3 days there for some investigation.
I mean...
A Portuguese's fish shop was robbed.
A friend of mine was arrested
and then they wanted to involve me.
Then I went to talk to the lawyer
and it was settled. I was released.
So while in jail, I met a man
who had a grudge against you. This man here.
What do you know about Tobias?
Why did he send you? Who the fuck crashed
my car?
- You know it!
- What car?
It was you! He sent you! What does he want?
What did he say? You're gonna tell me right
away!
But, my man. Brother...
You'll see, shit!
What does Tobias want?
Man, let me explain! I came here
because Tobias told me the Heron would get
me a job.
But you know, he's always stoned and angry
at you,
saying that you told on him and that he'll fuck
you up.
But I have nothing to do with it! I thought, since
I know you now
and we went on a binge last night, I could
explain.
I'm not scheming anything. If I were,
I wouldn't have told you. Actually, I wasn't
going to.
And I'm sure I would've got the job, anyway.
All right. Al right.
I'll be a jerk and will believe you.
Go away! Go away!
So, man, are you gonna let me go?
Then it is not worth being decent in this world.
In Japan, there's no official policy concerning
UFOs.
And they take this opportunity to invite you in
October
to the 4th Convention... of Astronomical
Sciences.
Do they pay for the expenses?
They don't mention anything here about
expenses.
Do keep on writing and thanks again.
I knew it.
Japanese are very serious people.
Don't they mention anything about the
Bermuda triangle?
Not a word.
We are in the tragic quarter.
October...
November...
December.
Why have so many ships vanished in the
Bermuda triangle?
For there is the headquarters of the flying
saucers.
I once saw a flying saucer.
I was driving down the highway with an aunt of
mine
and we saw one and it was very clear.
Was the radiation violet or orange?
I reckon... orange.
It's the classic Venusian saucer.
Violet: Mars.
Orange: Venus.
And when it is white...
The big mystery.
Then suddenly,
some sort of a hole opened
and the saucer sat on a small hill,
and two tiny men, this size, came out, and
greeted us.
You may laugh.
They are contacting us and you just laugh.
Aliens do exist
and they will be masters of the whole world.
Give me.
And also of the whores!
Hello, Jacinto..
Here.
I believe they suit you well.
If anything, we fix it.
Cool.
- Don't you have shampoo?
- I bring it right away.
Hey, Jacobin.
You don't waste time, do you, baby?
Wait!
Sorry. I was in the shower.
Never mind. There's nothing in there I haven't
seen before.
Go back in the shower or you'll catch a cold.
- What is it Tobias wants?
- Well... he...
You re wasting water and you don't pay for it.
What did Tobias tell you?
- How's he doing?
- Well, you know...
We didn't talk much.
But he always remembers you.
And what does he remember?
Well, he always goes:
And the Heron this, and the Heron that...
What did he send you here for?
Because I'm not buying that story you told
Dumas.
Well, I told you already: I'm looking for a job.
In this business?
Well.
I just need to begin.
Why, Jairo.
What a big thing...
What a big thing life is.
Here is the shampoo.
Well, baby, that way is impossible.
Look.
One searches, full of hope
The road that his dreams
Promised to his longings
In other words, they promised that to us.
That's life. Which is the road to your longings?
That's life.
But from the guts, baby. From the vaginal
Shit! Go on!
So you want me to give it tutti?
Start!
One searches, full of hope
The road that his dreams
Promised to his longings
One knows that the struggle is cruel and long
But one fights and bleeds
For the faith that makes him stumble
That makes him stubborn! That makes him
stubborn!
How come is it going to make him stumble?
See, one fights and bleeds.
But one insists and insists, so then one is
stubborn!
Come on!
That makes him stubborn
One goes crawling on the thorns
And in his urge to give his passion
Oh, Lord! It's not passion, it's love, love!
One goes crawling on the thorns
And in his urge to give his love
one suffers and self-destroys understanding
that one was left without a heart
Price for punishment that one pays
For a kiss that never comes
Or for a love that was unfaithful
Already empty from loving
And crying
So much betrayal
If I had the heart
The heart I gave away
If I could, like yesterday
To love without a premonition
It's possible that your eyes
That cried out to me their love
I'd close them with my kisses
Without thinking that like these
They were other wicked eyes
That ruined my existence
If I had the heart
The same one I lost
If I'd forget the one that yesterday
Tore it apart,
And I could love you
I would embrace in your illusion
To cry out your love
But God brought you in my destiny
Without thinking that it's too late
And I won't know how to love you
Let me cry like one
Who suffers in life the torture
Of mourning his own death
Pure as you are, you could've saved
My hope with your love
One is so lonely in his pain
One is so blind in his grieve
But a cruel cold
Crueler than hate
Dead spot of the souls
Horrendous tomb of my love
Cursed forever and stole
All hope
If I had the heart
The same one I lost
If I'd forget the one that yesterday
Tore it apart
And I could love you
I would embrace in your illusion
To cry out
Your love
Garden will live forever!
Give a tip to the guy.
It was Tobias, man.
It was him. No doubt about it.
But he's in jail. How come it's him?
Say it, Batman.
Last Sunday he got a visit in jail.
Tell him who, Batman.
The Camacho with two kids, just to make
believe.
It was Lead Hand who told me.
He told me to tell it to you and Dumas.
And then? Keep on telling me he's not.
That shit is very clear. Crystal clear.
They crashed me. Who?
Rivera, the Black. Who is he going out with?
The Camacho. It is very clear to me.
But I have an idea.
My name is Deborah.
They call me the Calcutta girl.
But I don't come from there.
I'm from San Cristobal.
But I like being called so. That I'm from
Calcutta.
Because it sounds like...
from a far away place.
Look.
Get up.
You may look like a fool, but have already
fucked two,
and they re two good mares.
Where are we heading?
All right? Take it to him.
Tobias.
Tell him I send it.
- And if they...
- There'll be No problem.
They'll allow you to pass it. Go. Go.
Go.
How's everything, Mr. Tobias?
You're all blue, blond guy.
I see you all blue.
Your karma is very intense.
Blond guy, that's right.
Now I remember.
I sent you to the Heron's.
You saw her. Did she give you some job?
Yes, thank you. Everything's fine.
What's that?
You brought it for me?
Thank you, blond guy.
This is the Heron!
Was she the one who sent it?
No. It was Dumas who sent it.
Judas!
What did he tell you?
Nothing. He went crazy.
What did he say about me?
That you should watch your back.
Jerk.
Listen, kid.
You know something?
In life, you have something like...
like a clock, you know.
I mean... If it's six o'clock,
you have to be at the right spot at six.
Right there, at six.
Because if you are there a bit before, or a bit
after,
poor kid...
Poor kid!
Look.
Bet it on the Reliance.
Keep your eyes open.
Make your bets!
I bet 100 on Reliance!
One hundred more! Paid.
I bet on it too! One hundred more!
Police. Your identification.
He's armed.
These ain't... these ain't policemen!
They ain't real policemen!
Well, Black man.
Black man, you're fucked up.
Who sent you? Was it Tobias?
Tobias sent you and you, jerk, went and obey
him.
Oh, dear.
Listen.
How much did he give you?
I'm gonna give you more.
In the name of God almighty!
The Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost!
In the Name of Saint Peter, Saint Paul,
of all the Heavenly Court!
Granted permission of the saint of today,
I offer the smokes of this cigar
to the God almighty and eternal.
May He grant luck to the Heron.
May He open to you, oh, Sister, all roads
clean.
So be it.
You know what? We re gonna set up a
branch.
But that's gonna be a five stars branch.
Oh, yeah. We're even gonna have computers.
Goddammit! Whores and computers.
Oh, yeah, with devices like the ones in the
track.
Everything's gonna be timed.
Listen, Heron. Heron.
Stick on me, stick on me like glue,
so that everything keeps on being fine with
you.
You know what, Heron?
I'm a man who knows how to thank.
As you hear. Who was I
when you put me in front of the business?
When you got involved with me, who was I?
Heron, I was nothing.
Nothing. I was nothing.
Nothing.
You with that shit...
Look at this!
What a big surprise!
You look like a kitten.
He did have fun.
I knew it, my little kid.
I knew it.
Today you became a grown up! The hell you
did!
No, I'm never wrong. I see some face
and say: There you go, that's it. That I know.
I always hit the bull's eye. I'm never misled.
And that's it. From tomorrow on, you with me.
Not anymore that shit of delivering toilet paper
and cleaning the toilets. No, no, no.
From tomorrow on, you are on my side,
- you go with me. Dammit.
- Count it.
- What?
- Count the money.
You re wrong.
I don't count money from a real man.
I don't get tips from anybody.
What's that beauty?
Is it new? Or is it the same
and you had it fixed?
There was no problem with the insurance.
Listen.
Knock on room 15.
A man who doesn't speak Spanish will
answer.
You'll tell him: Janis Joplin is dead
Repeat.
- That's right.
- What does it mean?
It doesn't matter what it means.
You tell him that. All right?
Janis Joplin is dead.
We sell this thing in three days.
In two.
Shall we try the product?
Jairo.
Do you like?
Monkey!
Let's go!
Give the car keys to the blond guy.
Blond guy.
Take the Heron to the business.
Heron!
A... as in America...
B, as in Beatrice.
C, as in Carmen.
D... as in Dalia.
Dima's women.
I don't understand why
a man has to have so many women.
As for me...
The only woman that...
that I've really had...
I mean, the only one,
it has been my mother, God rest her soul.
She used to prepare...
a delicious roast beef.
Well, of course...
that isn't the only reason.
I get sad when I remember the roast beef.
But...
She was so... so soft...
and all so white.
And those teeth of hers, those teeth of hers.
I think that...
when you lose your mom, you lose all.
Oh, my darling!
A mother's love
is the greatest thing of all!
Remember mom
when I was a little girl,
on Basalt Street, in Maracaibo.
She used to take me to the market
and she would go and buy me candies.
Louder.
I said my mom was very good.
With her long braids...
They were long...
So long they would reach the floor
and would go like sweeping it all along the
market.
You would be tempted...
You would be tempted to paint my mom.
Did she die too?
She was buried in Cabins.
I haven't been able to visit her.
Why?
In that area the Americans found oil.
And then one day,
one day that...
that I saw oil, I thought,
I thought that oil was her.
Shit. How sad, isn't it?
The money, the business.
The whores!
Why don't we go to Cabins
and take some flowers to her tomb?
After all, oil is ours.
She is also ours.
And I'm your son and I'm your mother.
Were two little orphans.
Do not go with that man.
How's everything?
Under control.
What do you plan to do with that money?
Nothing.
I feel like buying me a horse, Heron.
I have a chance at the track.
Three months or so...
Or we go away, Heron. To Disneyland,
or to Miami, to Europe.
So what do you think?
It can be.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
-Come, my Heron. Come.
- Come.
- No, not now.
What's the matter, Heron?
! already purchased the little house
That I for so long promised to you
And full of daisies... Come here, come.
Come.
What do you want me for?
You're always that way.
No problem. If you're cool, no problem.
What's the matter with you, Heron?
Nothing. I'm fine.
Heron, Heron, come here.
- What's going on?
- It's OK. Keep your money.
But, wait a second, Heron. What did they tell
you?
What did they tell you?
I've done nothing! What...?
It was the Pick lock. I'm sure it was him.
He's not collecting the tickets anymore!
Who the hell told you, you make the decisions
here?
You're getting too bold, baby.
You seem to forget who's the boss.
I'm the one who gives the orders here!
You may be temporary, but I'm not.
That's the difference.
Count your money and then do as you wish!
Get yourself one of your broads!
Or you think I don't know it?
Oh, baby. I just act dumb.
Until I fucking feel like acting dumb!
What did they tell you? Heron! Heron! Heron!
Fix me a drink, Catfish.
What's going on, Heron?
Come with me.
Leave this place.
I don't wanna find you here tomorrow.
Whatever happened, that was it.
We were raptures... and so it happened.
But don't you believe it meant something.
I'm not believing anything.
Go watch, as I ordered you! What are you
doing out here?
Take care of that shit!
When I was a child, you used to take me in
your arms.
Do you remember that mom would then yell at
you?:
Be careful with your little sister.
Do not let her fall.
Why are you still here?
Where else would I go?
What happens, Heron?
Did you argue with Dumas?
I don't know.
What happens to my man, happens to me.
What happens to Tobias, happens to me.
What happens to Dumas... I don't know.
I have been not with men,
but yards of men.
Miles of men.
A highway of men.
And it's always the same, the same, the same.
Who's the candidate now?
I don't know.
If you want, we can have a campaign,
like for some type of election,
to see who gets more votes.
I only know that in this chair
will always sit the same man.
My blessing.
Ain't you gonna wash me?
Go.
No.
I'm staying.
What's the matter with you, huh?
What's the matter with you?
You're not leaving me!
I don't know what you gave me, what you did
to me,
I don't know if you put a spell or some kind of
voodoo,
but you're not leaving me.
It's true that I have my mistresses.
But no one's like you.
Because I'm not temporary here.
I'm gonna show you I'm not temporary.
I'm gonna show you you're the queen!
I'm gonna show you you're the only one!
I'm gonna show it to you.
What's up, man?
You were really boozed-up last night!
I saw you when you got here.
What's happening to you, buddy?
Things.
Last night, when you left, I saw the Heron.
She was strange.
What's wrong, buddy?
Women, dude, women are a serious thing.
With them you've got to be tough.
If you get besotted, then they get on top of
you.
I understand they have their quirks,
and the moon affects them, but that's like
driving:
If you hold the wheel tightly, nobody fucking
fishtails.
Buddy, you're great.
You're really... You're really a tough type.
Well, you're something like a university of life.
Listen, kid.
Are you teasing me?
No, buddy, no way. All things straight.
I give the credits to the one who deserves
them.
Eleven and seventy-five.
Nineteen and fifty.
What?
It's not readable.
It's not readable. You're blind!
A hundred and ninety-eight!
It looks like a six.
How come a six? It's an 8! The 8's gonna
haunt you!
I don't know what you're doing here.
You don't see anymore. Tonight you won't be
at the counter!
Last week a forged bill. Now, an 8.
I've been managing the business for 20 years.
Precisely! It's over!
Today was your last day at the counter!
Devote yourself to your saucers!
You're becoming a nuisance!
Who will you replace him with?
You know with whom.
So don't come asking baloney,
you know very well who's gonna be.
Stop that silly melody! And you go back to
your shit!
Go and wax! That's too much body hair
Do yourself up cause your value is falling!
You used to be worth 60, now you're worth 40!
And you're already 40 and all that hair in the
legs!
Here, Heron.
Kid, the other day when you brought the Heron
from the beach... what did she tell you?
About what?
About me. Did she tell you something about
me?
Well...
You know, buddy... Nothing...
What did she tell you? Nothing?
Well, she told me you were cool.
That Dumas does this, Dumas does that...
She asked if you had another woman,
if I had seen her...
She made you look like a TV star.
That you were good and quite a hunk, so
much
I almost regretted being a man cause you
wouldn't woo me.
What a drag, isn't it, Jairo?
It's just you're the master, buddy.
The good Lord made you stereophonic and full
equipped.
It is not counted.
Heron, let's go eat at the beach.
It needs to be deposited. Banks close
tomorrow.
Jairo, take this to the bank. You know the
procedure.
She lends you her car. No problem. Right?
Right.
The day will come...
when I will give you all this.
And I will tell you: Silva Maria, here you are,
buy yourself candies.
Or cigarettes. Here you are, buy yourself
cigarettes.
You're my female. You get me going.
I'll be right back.
Let go of me! Let go of me!
You'd better move your contacts
cause I'll have you fired from the police!
I know Tobias is behind all this!
I know it is Tobias! Heron!
Wait! Heron!
Drug trafficking.
Illegal gambling.
Impersonation of authority.
We finally got hold of you, Dumas.
All right, Kojak.
You can put there what you like for all I care,
but you'll have to prove that crap!
How is the little mother going?
My lady still doesn't know
who the father of the little son of a bitch is?
Give birth soon,
because there's a lot of work out there
and we re not going to support you.
Izaguirre, what is it now?
Until when am I gonna stay locked in here?
Such an easy case like mine,
that any dumb lawyer would've taken me out,
and you're all puzzled. So, what then?
Where are we going to celebrate?
You'll pay dearly for this, Dumas.
Miami?
I'm going to Miami with my love!
I thought you were different
I thought you were sincere
And! Gave you my fife
Without any condition
But it all was a dream
Of my enamored soul
Just like any other
You played with my love
Just like a tart
You played with my life
Whisk.
A bottle of brandy.
And if the heart cries
I ask Aim to be stiff
For a love like yours
I find them in the street
What's up, buddy?
How are things, blond guy?
Not him!
Her eyes shut
And yet the world keeps on going
Her mouth that was mine
Kisses me no more
Extinguished are the echoes
Of her sonorous laugh
And it's cruel, this silence
Which makes me feel so bad
Mine was the compassionate
Sweetness of her hands
Which gave to my sorrow
Caresses of kindness
And now that I evoke her
Overwhelmed in my despair
The braided streaming tears
Refuse to flow
And I don't have the consolation
Of being able to cry
All because your wings
So cruelly burned out life
All because that sinister
Grimace of fate
I wanted to embrace her
But Death defeated me
Oh, how [ hurt, and so deep within is my strife!
I know that now unfamiliar faces will come
With their charity of relief for my torment
All is but a lie
A lie is their lament
Today my heart
Is all alone
Like dogs of prey
The treacherous spirits
Watching over my loved one
Galloped after her
And hidden in the luster
Of her good glance
The crouching Death
Was marking her tempo
In vain I encouraged
Feverishly a hope
That pierce into my raw flesh
With its claws of pain
And meanwhile out in the street
In frenzied uproar
The carnival of the world
Was laughing and enjoying
Making fun of fate
Which robbed me of her love
All because your wings
So cruelly burned out life
All because that sinister
Grimace of fate
I wanted to embrace her
But Death defeated me
Oh, how I hurt and so deep within is my strife!
I know that now unfamiliar faces will come
With their charity of relief for my torment
All is but a lie
A lie is their lament
Today my heart
Is all alone
May the soul of the Heron rest in peace.
May the Lord release her from the pain and
give her rest.
- Rest in peace.
- Amen.
Our Father, Who art in Heaven, hallowed be
Thy Name.
Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive
us our debts,
as we forgive our debtors, and lead us not into
temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen.
May the Lord give her eternal rest.
May perpetual light shine for her.
- Rest in peace.
- Amen.
May the Lord give her eternal rest.
May perpetual light shine for her.
- Rest in peace.
- Amen.
May the Lord give her eternal rest.
May perpetual light shine for her.
- Rest in peace.
- Amen.
May the Lord give her eternal rest.
May perpetual light shine for her.
- Rest in peace.
- Amen.
May the Lord give her eternal rest.
May perpetual light shine for her.
- Rest in peace.
- Amen.
I'm in prison, serving my sentence
Sentence imposed by society
I'm afflicted and ashamed
But I'm to serve it all alone
My guitar, that little orphan, plays no more
And though late, I now know it's real
That the one who plays so close to fire
If does not live cautiously, he will burn
I only ask my friends in the outside
To guard against liquor and its evil
For the only one, last and foremost
Is forever the word Freedom
I'm in prison, serving my sentence
Sentence imposed by society
I'm afflicted and ashamed
But I'm to serve it all alone
My guitar, that little orphan, plays no more
And though late, I now know it's real
That the one who plays so close to fire
If does not live cautiously, he will burn
I only ask my friends in the outside
To guard against liquor and its evil
For the only one, last and foremost
Is forever the word Freedom
Freedom