Soft music
- ... ...
-It's just that at the moment...
I do not have the means
to feed him and…
you understand,
I don't want to abandon him.
I am offered a job
as a housekeeper in Switzerland.
-His first name ?
-I will be back.
have to believe me.
-Of course. His first name ?
-Ludwig.
--That's not going to make things easier for him.
Sign here.
- ...
Clicking heels
- Honey, I will miss you so much.
I'll come back and we'll meet again.
I don't abandon you.
-Would you like to read me a page?
-You are old enough to read alone,
NOW.
And you know what ?
I will have returned from Switzerland
before you finish your book.
-When you are far away,
you will think about me ?
-I promise you.
My baby…
-Madam ? Please.
Sobs
- ...
-I love you very much.
She walks away.
- ...
-Maman.
Mom, I'm done!
- ...
-THANKS. You come at just the right time, Ludwig.
Your mother sent you this.
Melancholic music
- ...
-She sent me another book?
-Not this time.
Our establishment will close.
You will be placed in the countryside.
Valencourt Abbey.
-In the countryside ?
Mom, how will she find me?
-You don't need mom anymore
at your age.
There, you will make yourself
lots of new friends.
- ...
-I could at least
take my books?
- ...
-Here you are, my little one.
-Here we go, come on.
Bells are ringing.
- ...
-Give it to me !
You don't scare me.
-It's sure, you're a big one.
Finished,
the cuddly toy.
He too will go through the window.
Say goodbye to him.
Look at the baby, he's going to cry.
What are you going to do ?
Call your friends?
In Valencourt, there are no friends.
Cry of rage
-Get out, dwarves!
-Luigi !
Growls
- ...
-Do you think you are strong?
No room for 2 chefs.
-Then you better leave.
-Crush it!
Ruckus in the distance
Light music
-Help me !
- ...
Grate squeaking
The door slams.
-Our new resident
is puny.
-That will take half a mouth to feed.
You won't have to deprive yourself.
Dare to say
that you haven't thought about it.
-No, I swear.
-Are you swearing? Whoa….
-Finally…
Welcome to Valencourt,
Ludwig.
I am Father Turpin.
This is your teacher, Mr. Leutellier.
-Delighted.
I see that the gentleman is a reader.
What wonders do you bring back?
Jules Verne.
Jules Verne. Encore Jules Verne.
Have you read them all?
-Yes sir.
-Which ones are your favorites?
-Those that my mother sends me.
Growls
Fracas
- ...
-Cleared !
-It's not all about the books.
Here, the practice of sport
is essential.
-As we can hear,
Abbe Turpin teaches the art of wrestling.
Cris
- ...
- Bastard!
-It seems that our residents have
looking forward to meeting their new friend.
So I'm going to ask you...
To ring the assembly,
my dear Mr. Leutellier.
-With pleasure, the abbot.
I release my arms to ring the bell.
Cris
- ...
The bell rings.
-Lets' go.
-It's not over, Octave.
-No, you're right.
It's not over.
Laughter
It's nice to empty
our chamber pots.
- ...
Come on.
-Ludwig is your new comrade.
I count on you
to give him a warm welcome.
-Welcome, dear friend.
Laughter
-How nice,
lieber Octave.
But despite his first name,
Ludwig is French.
is a tradition here,
to share his room
in alphabetical order.
Your dorm mates
will be Lucas, Luigi and Lucien.
-Where are they ?
-Lucas, Luigi and Lucien.
- Has anyone seen them?
Funny music
Laughter
- ...
Silence.
God... what else have you done?
-On a…
Stumbled while emptying our pots.
-Always the same.
Take it all away and go
shower.
Mocking laughter
- ...
-Charlemagne
is son of Pepin the Short.
He became king of the Franks in 768,
then emperor from the year 800.
He marks his reign
for the sake of unification.
Please, basically.
Mr. Lucas, try to imagine.
When you observe the boundaries
of Charlemagne's empire
and those, more recent,
of today's Europe,
what a reflection
Does this inspire you?
Roh.…
Is there anyone…
Who would make us an offer?
Is there anyone who could fly
Help.…
Of our poor
Lucas ?
-Oh!
-If Charlemagne had stayed at home
without “conquering” that,
there would be fewer schools.
Laughter
-Conquer.
School is your sworn enemy,
M. Lucas ?
-The worst thing is not school.
These are the ones who go there.
Some, especially.
-You're starting to interest me.
What is an enemy?
-A Boche!
Laughter
-You probably wanted
talk about a German?
Octave,
to whom I did not give the floor.
Tension music
Observe the contours carefully
of Charlemagne's empire.
I am speaking to you, Octave.
There is no longer really
from France, from Germany.
So can you consider
than
whom you consider to be your enemy,
M. Octave,
because of a ridiculous border,
drawn by people like you,
could become your friend?
If people like Charlemagne
or myself
suddenly decided
to make it disappear?
-Sir,
why are borders moving?
-Why are borders moving?
Mainly because of the wars,
my poor Lucas.
-However, it's always the same.
-What ? Here, here and here?
-It's Switzerland.
A neutral country.
-Very just.
Bells are ringing.
Ah, we'll talk about Switzerland
and the rest
the next time.
You close your notebooks
in the calm
on your desks.
Serious music
- ...
-Look at me, the Boche.
I'm watching you.
- ...
-It's just ink.
The choir sings the Alleluia.
- ...
-To celebrate the Almighty,
who sacrificed on this Easter day,
His only son,
and in remission of all our sins,
here are some oranges.
I will ask you to come….
One after the other…
Cheers
- ...
Calmly!
In calm and respect.
- ...
Remember James chapter 3,
verse 18. "The fruit of righteousness
is sown in peace.”
No, stop.
-Donne.
-With dignity!
Bunch of assholes!
It is a gift in honor of God.
It is necessary
one for each.
-He can multiply them, then.
-Be less sassy.
-Why not have taken
speech in class?
-I'm not like them.
♪ have a mother.
She is far away, but she thinks of me.
We are too different.
We'll never be friends.
-It was very necessary
to read Jules Verne…
Did you pretend?
Didn't he write: "Friendship
cannot exist between two beings
"perfectly identical"?
-Five weeks in a Balloon.
-What a memory.
What should be remembered?
Than the difference
is infinitely more rewarding
than the resemblance.
-Do you have parents, sir?
-Oui.
- So why are you here?
-Uh well…
My mom and dad held my hand
when I was learning to walk.
But there are all kinds of ways
to walk.
So if I can extend my hand to you...
To help you move forward…
I know why I am here.
-You piss me off!
(-Do you want this hand
catch you an orange,
(or would you dare to go alone?)
-I can't stand you anymore!
Tomorrow,
be at 7 a.m. on the rugby field.
It is valid for all.
Soft music
- ...
-Good night guys.
-GOOD NIGHT.
Ludwig cries softly.
- ...
-Standing ! Look at the treasure.
- Did you find a treasure?
-Quoi ?
- I stole them from Octave.
-I want one !
-Me first.
-It's me who decides.
-Wait.
We are four.
There are only three oranges.
How do we do ?
I'm the biggest.
-Like always.
-I stole them.
-You're fat.
-Non.
-I decide.
-Oh ! You are not going to fight.
Do you know fractions?
Modern mathematics.
An orange is made
of four quarters.
3 x 4 = 12.
We are four.
So 12 divided by 4 equals 3.
Everyone the same share.
-I did not understand anything.
-It would be easier
if I ate everything.
-And then the abbot is wrong.
It's not Easter Day.
It's Christmas.
-We even got gifts.
-The most beautiful.
What the good Lord didn't give us.
Brothers.
-Graduated tutoring. Lucas.
-Lucien.
-Luigi.
Happy music
- ...
-And Ludwig.
-They must return
borrowed books.
Some are unaware that they have pages,
they use it as a stepladder
to… steal jams from you
in your cellar.
And an essay.
They have to write.
Two pages minimum
with the use of the subjunctive.
I wrote everything down for you.
It's heard ?
-Yes. Jam and subjunctive.
-Voilà.
Tell 'em I'm gone
on holiday.
With family.
-I think you should
tell them the truth.
They… They listen to you.
[They trust you.
-My dear little ones…
What do you want me to tell them?
That I am mobilized?
That I'm going to the front?
Why worry them more?
They are children.
This is not the case
only a few weeks.
-May God hear you.
-I'm sure He hears me.
I am not sure
that interests him.
-Don't overheat me.
You know I'm sanguine.
- We should send you to the front.
A lightning operation. Divine Lightning.
-Leave before you receive my lightning.
And take this. You will need it.
It's not going to bite you.
It's a Bible.
-How do you say ?
-A Bible.
Come on.…
Melancholic music
- ...
-Hurry! Come on.
Did you hear things?
-Lots of things.
-What is happening ?
-He is carrying a suitcase
almost as tall as the abbot.
He got a lightning bolt on his forehead.
-Impossible.
-Yes, a flash. The big gray cloud.
So he goes on vacation.
-On holiday ?
-Vacation.
-In that case, so are we.
Let's go, come on!
-Wait for me, guys!
Hey, no one ever listens to me!
He sighs.
They forget me all the time.
Screams and laughter
Groovy music
- ...
...
-Youhou!
-Last to arrive
is a big slug!
- ...
-It's freedom !
- No more school!
-Come on ! We are almost there.
-Why the Lulus
ever experience this?
We're going to make them pay.
-"You are the salt of the earth.""
- He annoys me!
-Come on, get the ball out!
Cris
Yes that's it !
- ...
- Ouh, it fucks the roustons.
-Here we are !
- ...
-Wake up !
-It's not good,
the good Lord will punish you.
- Here, here is the good Lord!
-
! You have to be careful, though.
- ...
-ONE, TWO, ONE, TWO, ONE, TWO.
- And hey there!
-Hop !
- ...
-Come on, let's finish the cabin.
We start with the roof.
Luigi, Lucas, go get...
-Where are you the boss?
-Well said. It's me.
-It's not
what I meant, Lucas.
-He who hoists the flag,
it is he who decides.
-That's true !
-Pushes you !
-I never had it!
They argue.
I want to hoist it.
-Everyboy inside ! There's the witch!
Move over, big guy!
-I'm not fat.
-Let me, I want to see.
-Always on the prowl, the Louison.
With his potions,
she would poison the abbot.
-The abbot?
-He says it's the demon.
A maker of angels.
-Why does he not like her?
if she makes angels?
-
1 is wearing a dress
without knowing women.
-Where are they going ?
- They can't understand.
Magical music
- ...
She is so beautiful.
Cris
- ...
-Sir ? What is worth to us
honor?
-The region is being evacuated.
The Teutons try
to take us from behind.
-More…
Explosion
- ...
- Leave everything.
This is an order with immediate effect.
Gather the kids, we'll escort you.
Explosions in the distance
- Maybe it's a witch...
But it has the best fruit.
- Get the hell out of me!
Get out or I'll rip your guts out.
Your lice will cry.
- Do you have lice?
She really is a witch!
-Wait for me !
-Quickly ! Come on !
Detonations in the distance
Disturbing music
- ...
-Four children are missing.
Lucas ! Ludwig !
Have you seen four children?
-My father.
The Lulus are in the lead.
-Certain ? I will see.
-Wait,
you sprained my ankle.
-Good, come… Let’s return to the Lord.
-Slower, you're hurting me.
"He tore, but he will heal.
"He knocked,
but he will bandage our wounds.”
Hosea. Chapter 6. Verse 1.
Come on.
-Slow down, father.
You hurt me.
Laughter
-Attends !
-Attention !
Laughter
-I'll get you!
-Stopped !
If the abbot sees us,
we're going to have some oats… To the dormitory!
-No way
to go to bed on an empty stomach.
-Do you ever think?
Imagine the punishment
if we get caught.
-We'll get caught
only if the gentleman complains.
- Sir try
to think for the group.
-Me too.
I think the band has fangs.
Let's vote. Who is hungry ?
I know where the abbot hides his reservations.
In the sacristy.
There is a trunk full of sausages,
crispy loaves of bread,
Strawberry jam…
-Strawberries ?
- Not to mention the Mass wine.
This evening, it's chef Luigi who's entertaining.
-Have you ever tasted sacramental wine?
-And not just once.
If you prefer to go to bed...
-Okay, but we'll be quick.
-It's not okay to drink it.
-You believe that the sky
will fall on us?
Explosions
- ...-
-It's because of the Mass wine.
I told you.
No one ever listens to me.
Sinister music
- ...
They are all dead.
We're all alone.
-We are not alone, Lucas.
We are together.
Melancholic music
- ...
The abbey is collapsing.
We'll go to the village when it's daylight.
- ...
-Evacuation order?
The orphanage…
He was evacuated. And the village too.
It's marked there.
-So they're not dead.
-Why evacuated?
Shattering and breaking of glass
Disturbing music
- ...
-They left everything behind.
Metallic crash
-Jerk,
you really shocked us!
-The cannibals won't get me.
-It does not exist.
-Yes, the proof!
-Ludwig ?
-In theory, yes.
In New Zealand. Show me.
- Return to the hut.
We should never have come.
-Why eat people?
The boss makes the best welsh.
-Maybe they only like meat.
Very fat and very big.
-I'm strong!
-Yes, you're fat!
-Guys !
We are at war.
-On se dispute.
-Not you, the world.
Orders in German
-The cannibals!
I told you !
Nobody listens to me.
- Lucas! We head to the cabin.
Tension music
Come quickly !
-Ludwig !
- ...
Order in german
...
-Why did they stop?
[Did they smell our scent?
- Equip... Fire!
Little frightened cry
Words in German
- ...
-They kill each other
they have no one left to eat.
- No, he's a deserter.
Order in german
Tension music
- ...
creaking
Ludwig… Ludwig…
- ...
Words in German
Cri
Shots
It worked !
-Yes, you moron!
-Quickly !
Cries in german
(-Hurry!)
Words in German
- ...
(-Ludwig.)
(Come on. Come on.)
Holy bloody shit!
-You speak French ?
-Yes.
-I know how to get out.
Sorry for the bump.
Cries in german
- ...
Order in german
Disturbing music
- ...
-Everybody out!
- By what right do we set fires?
to reserves?
♪ I have animals to feed!
He speaks in German.
You don't impress me
with your gibberish, your gun.
We are in France. We don't shout
on the ladies.
To invade, you need good manners.
- ...
Your mother didn't teach you
good manners ?
I know orphans
better educated.
Orphans, yes!
Are you looking for a deserter?
I'm not surprised
that he got the hell out.
Eh ? That he's gotten the hell out!
- She waves us away.
- Do I look like a deserter?
Do you see a deserter?
Get the hell out of me!
Before I get mad.
He speaks in German.
Come on !
I don't want to see you anymore!
-Fast.
-Fast!
Soft music
- ...
-Guys, guys…
Are you sure she's Belgian?
She could have said anything.
That's how it is, girls.
-How would we know?
It's not marked on it.
- Just ask him.
-I'm going closer to him.
She's cracked.
-She says she lives in Brussels.
Her parents sent her
sheltered with his uncle in France.
The convoy was bombed.
She ran away.
-Bombed?
That's it, anything.
-What's in his suitcase?
- Chick stuff.
Doll, dinette, thimble.
She's cracked.
-Then why are you following me?
-Who are you ?
-It's not for the ladies
to introduce themselves first.
-To the ladies ?
You'd have to be one.
-You want me to prove it to you?
-It's good.
We believe you.
Sigh
-My papers.
-Ah.
Here is Lucian. Luigi.
Lucas and I are Ludwig.
Together, we are the Lulus.
-I'm Luce.
It makes me a Lulu.
-Non.
In theory, no.
-Because… ?
-Because you are… well…
You see…
-Voilà.
- Well yes, we are a band of…
-No, no.
You have parents. We are orphans.
-Voilà.
-Where do you see my parents?
-Nowhere.
Until further notice, I will be a Lulu.
What way ?
-To be.
-Merci.
You come ?
- Yes, we are coming.
Luigi breathes.
-Is that your headquarters?
The Germans
just have to behave.
- You stay here. We need to talk
between men. I have a plan.
-The war,
It's not a girl's thing.
You understood ?
What's the matter ?
Oh, wait for me!
-What's your plan?
-My plan ?
-No one listens to me.
-No more having a girl around.
-Excellent plan.
-Quite simply.
- We talk in the cabin.
-Yes, excellent.
-No need for a girl.
-It's true.
-She will never follow us.
She doesn't have the skills.
-It's certain.
-A girl means problems.
-Always whining.
-His dresses will get us noticed.
She has no place here.
She'll never have it.
Chantone light.
- ...
Lucien, Luigi and Ludwig
continue to debate.
Imagine if the Germans are coming.
She's going to scream.
-It's risky.
We have to get rid of it.
-I have an idea.
Let's put a spider
in her hair.
-Serious ?
- Girls are afraid of spiders.
-Do you smell that smell?
Happy music
- ...
-Oh !
-Watch out !
- ...
-I choked!
-War is not a girl’s thing.
All right.
It's also not
a boy thing. It is…
An adult thing.
- So we don't care.
-Here, we are relaxed.
-Not long. You have to get organized.
Let's find where to go.
Or sleep. What to eat.
-I have an incredible idea.
Do you know how to do the splits?
- But… it's serious.
The Germans are everywhere in the village.
Maybe even in France.
-So we wait
that the army repels the invader?
-Do you have a better solution?
-Become German?
-And the wheel?
I adore. Look.
Light music
- ...
-Lucas, stay here.
Okay, what was I saying?
I said that the army...
Luce, you can stop
to do anything?
♪ was talking.
-Do you think the water is cold?
-Luce, let’s try
to find solutions.
-Too bad, I would have given a kiss
to the first able to jump.
-It's dangerous, isn't it?
-Jump or kiss me?
-In theory, both.
Kiss you
can transmit diseases.
Jump after eating
can cause hydrolution.
If you agree
let us think...
♪ have the solution.
-What is your solution?
-Go to Switzerland.
There's no war there. And there is…
- What is it?
What else is there in Switzerland?
- There's... chocolate.
And a naked girl.
Cry of joy
Can't swim, girls?
-We have to save her.
-Help !
Help ! Help !
Cris
-Oh, wait for me!
-Luce !
-I got you!
Happy music
- ...
-Like that !
Thunder
-It will rain.
- Who cares, we're wet.
- ...
-What are you waiting for, the residues
miscarriage? An invitation ?
Drink. It's soup
not arsenic.
-Thank you Madam.
-You give me some madam, now?
Like the villagers
who need my drinks
and spit on me in public.
Phew. I do not care,
they can say whatever they want.
Go out !
It should suit you.
It has to be useful,
there are no more kids here.
Go change there.
-Did you have children?
-Only one.
About his size.
He is at war. I'm waiting for him.
-That's why
that you didn't leave.
-Here, the dress in which
my husband took me dancing.
Go to the bedroom too.
And you, come on!
Put it all on me.
We're not at the Ritz.
And pas de cabine.
Your bistouquettes don't interest me.
Thunder
Lucas groaned.
What do you want ?
-Your husband too,
Was he a wizard?
-Of course.
A real.
We lived in a house
in gingerbread.
-And where is he?
-My husband ?
You just finished it.
See, this broom?
It was his.
-A balai volant?
-No, a broom that sweeps.
It is your turn. Go to work.
I'm not going
accommodation and food to the eye.
-Do you want us to stay?
-A night ! Afterwards, leave!
Out of my sight, the abandoned packages.
-How long does it last,
a war ?
-It lasts too long.
Soon there will be more than that,
orphans.
-What do you call
a childless parent?
-We don't call him.
We let him cry
in his corner.
-And your son?
What is his name ?
Someone is coming down the stairs.
Soft music
-Anselm.
-You told him stories,
to your Hansel? You know,
bedtime stories?
-Of course.
Loads of stories.
Terrible stories.
With murders and demons.
-Go ahead, please.
-In a village, there lived a woman.
Very bad.
And very cruel. A day…
Thunder
she sees 5 disgusting pigs
who prick his raspberries.
So she gives them soup.
Poisoned soup.
when they sleep,
she cuts them into slices
like sausage.
It is what I am going to do.
Hum…
I will feast.
That's it, end of story.
-It's the most beautiful story
that anyone has ever told me.
Soft music
-We didn't have to
tell you a lot, my little one.
- ...
Thunder
Cracking of wood
-Hop.
I think we have enough wood
for winter.
-My father says that the wood is hot
four times. When we pick it up,
when we cut it,
when you put it away, and...
And a little when you burn it.
-Stopped. Stop smiling.
If you want a chance, stop.
At that age, girls like
bad boys.
-What are you talking about ?
-How silly you look when you look at her.
-Silly?
-It's later that girls love
the good ones. Look mysterious.
- Dark?
-Yes. Try to see?
-Mysterious. Like that ?
-Yeah, it's not bad.
Keep this. Keep it.
-Mysterious.
Louison coughs.
Soft music
- ...
-What's wrong with him?
-We are back.
-Look at the children,
the beautiful apples.
-Lucas, can't you come help us?
-I'm not here !
-Looks like I found myself
my red armbands.
-It's what ?
-The Boches,
as soon as they find a kid,
they put a red armband on him
and at work.
-Witches do the same thing.
-And mothers too?
How about making a pie?
-OUI !
-Go peel them, I'm coming.
-Come.
Who prepares the dough?
-TOI.
-This wood is hard to split.
It's a bit like the heart.
The harder you hit it, the harder it gets.
While sometimes...
Just take it
from the good side.
-Louison. Someone there.
-Those damn Boches…
They won't leave the village
without their deserter.
They look like French officers, right?
Let's take no risk.
Go hide, my children.
Soft music
- ...
Disturbing music
-Louison Roussel?
I regret to announce
the death of your son,
died for the fatherland.
Please accept condolences…
dark music
- ...
Melancholic music
-You're in luck
to be orphans.
You have nothing more to lose.
I have to find Anselme.
My little Anselm…
He is waiting for me.
- ...
-How are we going to do without a mother?
-Like we've always done.
We don't care about adults.
They know that hitting each other
and abandon their kids.
- They know how to make pies.
- And hugs.
-And smiles.
-Guys, we have to go to Switzerland.
There they have wooden cabins.
Cabins, they call it.
Guys !
Wait !
-Oh oh ! Someone there
in our cabin. I was sure of it.
No one ever listens to me.
-You who always want to go ahead,
You're welcome.
-On. I'm the strongest one.
Disturbing music
- ...
Are you guys following me?
Hein ?
- ...
Someone is whistling in the cabin.
Do not move.
Words in German
It's a Boche!
It's a Boche, guys!
What do I do ?
-
will denounce us.
-Kill him.
-I can't shoot.
Do not move.
-Luigi !
-We are friends.
-What does it mean ?
-Friends.
-I don't know!
- Luigi, tire!
-I can not !
-Come on !
-I did what ?
♪ did what? I killed him ?
-"Friends" means "ami".
We are “Americans”.
No “guerre”.
““Amis”. We are “Amis”.
Amis.
Essen…
Soft music
- ...
(-What if it's human meat?)
-Well seasoned,
I wouldn't feel the difference.
-He's the deserter.
-He! comes from the desert?
-Non.
He fled the army.
If he gets caught, he's dead.
-Like us.
- You read a lot of books.
Do you know German?
-A sentence or two. In theory…
-Stopped.
Go to practice. Come on.
You go-y.
-I…
I think my pig is whistling.
The German laughs.
- ...
-I think my pig is whistling.
That's good.
Laughter
-What did you say ?
-I don't know.
I read it.
It means: "I believe
“let my pig hiss.”
Laughter
-My name is Hans!
-Ludwig.
-Ah, Ludwig !
He sings the Hymn to Joy.
- ...
-He would have done better
to stay at home.
-Hans.…. I.…. my wife
Woman. Germany.
- Oh, yes!
He has a wife in Germany.
He deserted to find her.
-She is fat, his wife.
- By dint of eating sausages.
-No. No. Not "big".
Pregnant.
- She eats children too?
-But no, she's pregnant.
-What are we going to do with him?
- He won't stay long.
He is going to find his wife
before the baby is born.
Ah, that's so romantic.
Quoi ?
Luigi mutters.
-It smells good.
Rabbit stew, it smells good.
-You still talk in your sleep.
-It smells of rabbit stew.
It smells of rabbit stew!
-Good morning.
Regulation
-Lucas, I can play the owl!
-We're going to get along well with Hans.
- Didn't you notice?
He wears a German uniform.
-It suits him so well.
- "It suits him so well."
“He’s so romantic…”
Maybe he tries
to poison us.
Ludwig imitates the owl.
-Bon appetit.
-Merci.
Ludwig imitates the owl.
- ...
-Hans ?
Fire.
-Fire. "Fire".
-Feuer.
-And that ?
-A rabbit.
Hase.
-Hase.
Cook.
-Cook.
- Cook.
Hans…
cooking a rabbit.
-No.
Hans cooks a rabbit.
Uh…
Rabbit cook Hans.
Laughter
No?
-Luigi, Lapland,
eat it all!
-We are making fun,
but it's an attractive accent.
-Oh yes ?
It's seductive to understand nothing
what they say?
-I understand what you are saying
and it's not attractive.
-Luce, it’s him
who separated you from your parents.
He didn't hesitate
to declare war on us.
-You are arrogant and stubborn.
-Remains ?
You are stupid and stupid.
-Gnangnan ?
Incredible vocabulary.
Even my grandmother says it more.
- Does she speak German?
You must love him as much as Hans!
-I don't like Germans!
-Who do you like? Answer!
-I like…
-Who do you Love ? Go ahead !
- Everyone except you.
I hate you.
-Don't be smart.
-Hey, friends.
Look, Hans taught me
to pick mushrooms.
-Mushroom. Owls,
little bunnies. Wake up,
It's not a story.
It's the war !
- They don't like rabbits?
-Love.
Here.
Love.
-You want some ?
-Schön.
Melancholic music
- ...
Luce…
To be a woman.
- ...
Und woman be…
romantic.
Cries of rage
-I hate it !
-Romantic.
Romantic.
It's romantic
to moan all day?
To slap me?
To contradict me?
-Woman to love.… “Gedicht”.
Clouds move across the sky,
The wind blows over the fields,
Wanders across the fields
My mother's lost child.
-Poetry.
-Poem.
Cries of rage
- ...
-Luce…
Screams of frustration
-The Germans ! The Germans
are gone. No one left in the village.
Come !
They left everything behind.
-Even the beds?
♪ I'm tired of sleeping on the floor.
-Not even an outlet.
- We can drink it.
-A village just for us.
We each choose our house.
- I'm having coffee.
- Me, I take the school.
-Moi…
Luce, which one do you take?
-The town hall.
- So I'll take this one.
-And you, Lucas? Which one do you choose?
-I choose the same as Hans.
-Hans ?
Which house are you taking?
-Ich muss…
Retrouver ma femme. Do you understand?
I will soon become…
Papa.
-You are already our dad.
-Don't leave today,
please.
-Of course I'll stay.
Soft music
- ...
-"Mr. Lucien is invited to the birthday
of Miss Luce tonight.”
Poem…
Girls like "Gedicht".
Poem.
“Gedicht.” Girls like "Gedicht".
Girls like "Gedicht".
He hits.
Someone is approaching.
- ...
On this birthday, dear Luce,
who offers you one more spring,
you shine like Venus,
and you are soft like a cactus.
-A cactus?
-You do not like ?
-I adore.
-HAPPY BIRTHDAY, LUCE!
-Merci !
How about some music?
-Didn't you bring a present?
-I wrote him a poem.
-That's not a gift.
“Jazzy music
*---
Don't put it too loud,
it will attract the Germans.
-The Germans ? Let them come!
♪ I'm no longer afraid of them now.
*---
Who wants to dance with me?
Mr. Mayor,
would you grant me this dance?
*---
-Allow me.
- It's a pleasure to dance with you.
-The pleasure is shared.
*---
Someone knocked.
-I believe…
my pig whistles.
A…
Strudel.
-Thanks Hans!
-Best wishes for your birthday.
I… Comment dit-on ?
Uh…
Pastry chef ln Berlin.
-It exists,
German pastry chefs?
Aren't they all soldiers?
Laughter
When I grow up, I will be German.
-Good idea.
Hans speaks in German.
-Certainly :
“Make a wish and breathe.”
Make a wish.
Go ahead, make a wish.
-A wish ?
Soft music
- ...
(Make it last.)
A Lulu's birthday,
it is that of all Lulus.
-Come on. One two three !
Laughter
- Sorry, Hans. You have it everywhere!
-It's all ok.
-Hold !
-We need to talk.
What if we expanded the family?
-Right away.
- Put yourself there.
-Gorgeous.
-Luce.
One.
Hans ?
-Yes.
Laughter
Happy music
-OLÉ!
- ...
-It should work.
Three crank strokes.
Come on !
The engine starts.
- ...
What ? My father is a mechanic.
Melancholic music
- ...
-Come with me.
-In Germany ?
-You are already in Germany.
Here, occupied zone. Soldiers…
Come back to the village, soon.
So, come.
I… lead you… in die Schweiz.
-In Swiss ?
-Are you taking us to Switzerland?
- Come on.
Commit. Get in.
-Lets' go.
-We are saved.
- I go up first.
-Thank you, Hans.
We'll even eat chocolate.
-Come on, Luigi.
-Are you coming, Luce?
-Luce ?
Luce ?
-Are you going in front?
-I stay here.
She sniffles.
A day,
my parents will come pick me up.
Go away, goodbyes are useless.
And it makes your eyes red.
- We can't leave without you.
- That's how war is.
One day we have a family and...
the next day, there is no one.
Run.
Humming
- ...
-THE GERMANS ! COME !
-Hans, stop!
Cries in german
Shots
Cris
Tension music
- ...
-Faster !
They come back !
- ...
Cri
-Covered !
-They annoy me !
- ...
-Come here !
-Come on!
-Non !
- ...
Cri
Oh !
Hans !
- ...
-It's what ?
Lucas? Where is Lucas?
Machine gun blasts
Explosions
Muffled cries
- ...
-Lucas !
Cris
Stifled chaos
-Vite, Lucas!
-Lucas, one!
The whistle of a bomb
Lucas screams.
-Luce, you stay.
-Hans !
Cris
-Come on.
Cri
Howls
Machine gun blasts
- ...
Explosion
-He is hurt ! He is hurt !
The whistle of a bomb
-Quickly !
Cris
-[Where are the others?
-They are fine.
Cris
- ...
Moans
- Luigi, come!
-Wait... No. Uh!
-I'll get help.
-His! His! His!
- I will carry you. Come on, come on.
Explosion
You have to walk.
-French?
-And. And.
Freund.
-Okay okay…
-I believe…
my pig whistles.
He groaned.
It means…
Anything.
- It's nonsense to stay here.
-No! Luce…
He speaks in German.
He groaned.
-No, I won't be able to do it.
♪ won't make it.
-But.
Luce… Retire.
Come on!
Melancholic music
- ...
He screams.
Moans
Rough breathing
-How are you ?
On and off.
- ...
-It's… It's stopped.
-We have to find the others.
-Louis. Louis.
He imitates the owl.
- ...
...
-They are there.
- ...
-Freund?
- M. Leutelier?
- It's us, sir.
We are your friends.
-I have more friends.
The Boches massacred them.
-But if. The Lulus.
Do you recognize us?
-Remember.
-No, don't shoot!
Don't shoot.
-The orphans of Valencourt.
-Please sir.
-Lucien. Come.
Luigi, one. One, one.
dark music
- ...
One…
-Sir. Sir.
Sir ! You said
that borders did not exist.
That we are all brothers.
Detonation
-No, Hans!
-Non !
Cris
-Fortunately
that I was there, lieutenant.
Sobs
- It was our dad!
-It's good.
♪ did my duty.
Sobs
- ...
-Hans…
tragic music
- ...
- Does anyone want to say something?
-I think my pig is whistling.
-I found that…
To keep Hans warm.
- ...
Explosions
-You miss her,
orphanage soup?
-Luigi, a soup?
- Yes, Father, of course.
I want soup.
She was hot, remember?
♪ wouldn't have believed
I miss this rotten soup.
- Are you going to say it every day?
-I'm hungry.
-Me too.
- Stop bickering.
Eat an apple instead of bitching.
In Swiss,
we will have everything we want.
-In Swiss ?
Do you still believe in Switzerland?
It's been weeks
that we turn in circles.
We are hungry, we have nothing to eat.
It's not an apple that's going to feed me.
-Say something.
-I have nothing to say.
-I'm fed up with walking.
♪ am tired of growing up
and not my shoes.
♪ I'm sick of you!
-Good riddance. Stay here.
You think I'm not tired of it?
To steal food,
to walk, to hide
and put up with your whims?
We are all the same,
except I'm not laughing.
- Yes, you are laughing.
-Where is Switzerland?
-Over there.
Calm music
- ...
-Wait for me !
No one ever listens to me.
- ...
-No sudden movements.
It's a Kalongo.
-Oh!
- African Warrior
to barbaric customs.
- We walked to Africa?
- We, friends.
We, cold.
Ooh…. cold.
Hunger. Hunger.
French. French.
- Do we speak normally?
I too am French.
Hum ?
-Why did you stop?
bloody black pudding?
It falls on me everywhere.
Little laugh
-They have never seen...
- As black as your white ass.
When I found it,
his blood flowed red.
-It's Gaston. He's a bit... boorish.
I'm Moussa.
-It's not a name.
-No, it's a title.
Title of the emperor of the savannah.
Lightning Warrior,
slayer of elephants.
- Did you slay elephants?
-Yes. You came across some
in the forest ?
No, they're all afraid of me.
He trumpets then sneers.
It's big, but it's all scary.
Soft music
- ...
-We coax them from the belly.
I will teach you to cook
lard beans.
Not a woman resists it.
You will thank me later.
-The village chief offered me
to the French army.
He didn't want me to marry
her daughter. It took a brave
to wage war.
I was thinking of a fight
with the tribe next door. I said yes.
They put me in a truck.
Then another. Then in a boat.
Days and days of travel.
Afterwards, the rain, the cold…
France.
-Have you never heard of it?
-You heard about
from Kolda?
-I know.
-In Senegal.
-Non.
-He's funny.
- Here, child. Give me that.
It must be your size.
-Hooves ?
♪ I don't have the money to pay them.
-I think it's a gift.
-A gift ? I don't give gifts.
It's my job.
-Do you know Switzerland?
-No, but I know how to get there.
A foundry uses
its own railway line.
They have trains that go to Switzerland.
Well, it's… over there.
About a day's walk. In the city.
-Which town ?
-Guise.
- There you go, Guise.
-Yes. The town is full of Boches.
Damn criminals, those.
-Not all.
Hans, he was nice.
-Where is your nice curly hair?
He left you?
-No, he is dead!
-Oh one less.
-You are fat,
old and nasty!
-If the soup is not good enough,
Get away with your gang!
There's no shortage of orphans.
-Gaston !
-Quoi ?
- They are children. -Good…
Well... since you didn't have parents,
no education...
I accept your apology.
- You're not that fat.
You are old in your head.
-Yeah…
- Say sorry, it will be fine.
-Eh ? I did not completely understand.
- Are you deaf?
-Oh, a little respect!
-When you say a kind word.
-Bah…
-Bah !
Cry of frustration
-It is very good.
Well sent.
Don't give in.
Soft music
- ...
they won't arrive
to go to town alone.
-You did well.
They are five.
- They are children.
I will guide them.
I didn't escape from my camp
of prisoners to freeze to death here.
And I took too much advantage of your inhospitality.
-So much the better.
I prefer to live alone.
-In my village, we say
that when someone saves your life,
you have to save his life in return.
-I'm the one who saved your life.
Not them.
-In my opinion,
Toubabs are all the same.
Little snowmen.
-Who am I going to yell at?
-I'm going to miss you too.
- ...
-Luce. Lucian. There are gifts.
Quickly, Luce! Lucien, wake up.
Look.
-Quoi ?
“There are treats.
-Ludwig !
-Wow!
Look at !
- You and I are a soldier.
Look at.
♪ got a deer.
-Wow! are they our size?
-Did you see ? There are our names.
-I love foxes.
They are so beautiful.
-You had a bear.
“There are treats.
-I have a spinning top.
-It's so pretty.
- What did you get?
-Why did he do that ?
-This is to say thank you.
And Wolof, on it jëre-jëf.
-BE-GIVE.
-Je-jef.
A man speaks in German.
- ...
Chut…
-Go out ! Get out.
I live alone. I told you.
What would I bother with?
d'un moricaud?
Hein ?
Where do you want me to put it?
In my pockets? My jacket ?
What ? What I ?
-I don't understand.
Translator, quick!
- Quoi? Translator?
No need for a translator
to understand
what an asshole you are!
Easy to understand :
leave me alone.
He speaks in German.
-Quoi ?
-He! wants to search the trailer.
-Again ? Your stupid sergeant
annoys me every week.
Guard the prisoners
instead of scratching your ass.
Translate.
-What does the man say?
-Translate. You're going to laugh.
You go-y. Vas-y, on va se marrer.
No, come on!
Get the hell out, the red armband.
We were 700 clog makers in these woods
before your bloody war.
There's more than just me. Are you proud?
-Ah ! Stop !
He speaks in German.
- Oh, but slowly…
Hey, oh, calm down!
Right away, the threats.
No, it's fine!
You think you're scaring me
with your guns? At six ?
(-Someone there.)
Intriguing music
- ...
- It is Octave.
-You know him ?
-Oui.
- ...
-Leave.
Leave.
Lucas.
- ...
Alarm!
They ran that way!
They went that way.
-Over there.
He speaks in German.
- ...
- No, you're not going that way.
You go no further.
-Silence !
Tension music
- ...
Detonations
-Come on ! Come on !
Melancholic music
- ...
- It's all our fault. All !
All !
Gaston. Everyone we love,
misfortune befalls them!
We can't be loved.
We're just bad luck.
Even our mothers couldn't.
-If. A mother loves her children.
-And you know what?
- I know, that's all.
-one more thing
what you read in your books.
-One.
I'll take you to town, okay?
We're going to mingle with the workers.
And presto, direction the train
for Switzerland.
Train whistle
-I have never seen so many houses.
-Do you believe that Paris,
is it that big?
-I saw there
the tallest tower in the world.
Hell. It even went beyond the clouds.
-What is it used for?
- To measure the pride of the French.
He's laughing.
Come on, it’s this way.
Soft music
- ...
Welcome to Guise.
Stay there, I'll look
the doctor, okay?
- ...
Dr Berrault.
-Oh, Moussa !
-Happy to see you.
-And I therefore.
- ...
-We walked a long way to come.
-You come from far away.
-Let me introduce you to Dr. Berrault.
-Hello miss. Sir.
-Bonjour.
-Ÿ has female doctors?
- We are in 1914.
You're 100 years late.
Hello, doctor.
- No doctor. It's Constance.
Show me this wound.
-No, that's nothing.
It's Leprechaun. He lost an eye.
-Oh I see.
But I have a whole jar of it.
-Madame…
Do you treat Germans?
-Everyone.
-Enemies.
-Yes. Pain has no boundaries.
Bon…
We will put you up on the top floor.
We have room
since the men were on the front.
And I'm going to reserve five rooms for you.
With a sequel for Moussa.
- Thank you, doctor.
- Will we each have a room?
-It is a problem ?
-No, it's the opposite.
That's wonderful.
We're not used to it.
-Madam, we thank you, but…
We're not going to stay.
We have to leave for Switzerland.
-Swiss or not,
you have to smell clean.
- We are clean.
It rained this morning.
-If there is no bath,
no theater and no swimming pool.
-A theater, a swimming pool
and what else?
-School, park, nursery, vegetable garden,
games room, library.
Shops, archery…
And our own station
with a train to Switzerland.
He leaves tomorrow morning.
-Tomorrow morning !
-Welcome to the familistery.
Unique social utopia.
-A social utopia?
-It's a world that doesn't exist.
-That's what I said.
-The factory and the station too,
is it the "famiphistery"?
Laughter
-Absolutely. The familiarity.
-The People's Palace.
Built
like the Palace of Versailles.
-So there is a king? And you…
You are the boss.
- You have had fleas before.
Fleas drink the…
- You don't know.
-Yes. And the bosses are…
-Petit ?
-It's the same.
So the fleas, the bosses,
dirty children… oh!
Oops ! Out.
What do you decide?
- On see low.
Laughter
-You have to scrub well.
Upbeat music
- ...
-I do not understand anymore.
You shouldn't smile.
Must write poems.
Gotta cook lard beans.
What do you do to seduce a girl?
-I hunt the lion.
I bring back his mane.
-The mane ?
-And you have nothing more European?
- Well, you...
Yes, in Paris, I saw something.
The women,
they love to dance java.
It's radical. Dance the java,
you catch the girl.
-On ?
-Hum.
Yes. You take her by the waist.
You hold her against you. Hmm?
And you turn.
You look her in the eye
and you turn.
You turn.
-After that ?
-When you feel that it is very ripe,
that she is under your spell,
you… well, you tell him something.
(-I love you.)
-Non.
But you can ask him
if she loves you.
-If she loves me?
- It's you, man.
-That's a bit pretentious.
If you want to give flowers,
it is your problem.
He speaks in Wolof.
Your head is not okay.
We must wait for the right moment.
She's sending you the signal.
Too early is too late.
(Calm.)
-Wow, it’s beautiful.
-Amazing.
-This way. They are waiting for you.
Do you like the dress?
We took it back to your measurements.
-She is magnificent.
She was your daughter?
-I couldn't have children.
Go join your friends.
The show is about to begin.
-The show ?
-It was scheduled for tomorrow,
but I asked the troop
kindly
provide you with representation.
Soft music
- ...
-It's a java.
-I had noticed.
-Do you like it?
-Would you like to stop?
Would you like to stop?
-Pardon…
i can make you
lard beans.
-Ÿ has something simpler.
-Like what ?
- ...
-Like that.
The music intensifies.
- ...
They sing.
Enchanting music
- ...
-Bravo !
-I loved !
-Gorgeous.
Cheers
-So, did you like it?
-Fantastic.
-Amazing.
They all speak at the same time.
- ...
-I take that as a yes.
We're going to celebrate with chocolate.
-Oui ?
-Madame Constance.
-I would like
ask you something.
I have not yet
talked to others, but...
I already know their answer.
It's hard to ask,
seeing as there are many of us and orphans.
-I'm listening to you.
-I don't think we'll ever find
better place.
So if you would like us,
we would like to stay.
-Please.
- Huh, guys?
- It will be with happiness.
-I will help you.
-I was missing someone
to amputate
The wounded.
Laughter
-What's happening to you?
We... said we were going to Switzerland.
We are almost there.
- We are fine.
We don't know what awaits us there.
Why leave?
-It's true.
-Theater.
-Because in Switzerland, there is my mother.
Moving music
- ...
- But you don't have a mom.
- Yes, I have one.
- ...
-Everyone has a mom.
How is this a problem?
- She couldn't feed me anymore.
SO…
She accepted a job in Switzerland…
-And what ?
Are you going to find her and forget about us?
Hold.
-A real Lulu would never have lied.
-Lucien.
Lucien !
- ...
-They will forgive you.
-I've lost twice
my family because of you.
I hate you !
(I hate you…)
- ...
-Yes, he hid the truth from us.
But there is more serious at the moment.
-The war is over,
you will find your parents.
We will have nothing!
-My parents don't care about me.
I'm just a kid to them.
A package they abandoned.
Why do you believe
that I followed you?
-T'as eu tort !
You were never a Lulu.
You'll never be one.
-Because it's you
Who decides who is a Lulu?
That's it ? You're the boss ?
If you're the boss...
I'm very happy
not to be a Lulu.
-Children, less noise.
-Me too.
You only bewitched us
from the beginning !
The Lulus are the three of us.
-You, leave us.
To act crazy,
it's time to grow up.
-I'm not crazy.
-Are you okay, Mr. Am I the strongest?
If you were the strongest,
we wouldn't be there.
-You, if you were really a leader,
Where would we be?
Chut!
-You are losers ! I never had
brothers and that’s so much the better!
Chut!
Disturbing music
- ...
Orders in German
-Colonel.
What is this morning visit worth to us?
- - ...
Why?
He speaks in German.
- ...
-There are no black prisoners…
-Madame.
He speaks in German.
-Moussa… What’s going on?
-We are no longer safe.
-We don't know it, but we're dead.
-Chut. Chat.
owl hoot
- ...
Ludwig ?
He says to go that way. Over there. Come on !
Thrilling music
- - ...
-What are we going to do ?
-Colonel !
How dare you ?
I know people
keep slandering us,
but how can you doubt me?
I tend to your wounded.
You can not do this.
You have always trusted me.
There is no one here.
The colonel laughs.
He speaks in German.
-Get up !
He screams.
- ...
-I hear the train!
He speaks in German.
-No. You will not pass.
The whistle you train
- You, prisoner.
-Non !
Comrades, save the children!
- ...
-Too late !
-That one ! Quickly !
-Go for it ! Come on !
- Faster, Lucas. Faster !
-Halt!
-Come on, Ludwig!
- ...
Detonations
Run!
Cris d'encouragement
-We are almost there ! Come on !
-Come on, Musa!
Mount, mount!
-Moussa !
-Non !
-Moussa! Moussa!
-Send me some chocolates.
Melancholic music
gasping breath
Slamming of the door
- ...
- So, you have a mom.
-That means I have one too.
Because we are brothers.
-And me too ?
-Oui.
In the end, we all have a mother.
-Dis, Ludwig…
What effect does it have
when a mom reads you a book?
Soft music
- ...
-Two years vacation
couple Jules Verne.
"During the night of March 9, 1860,
"the clouds merging with the sea
"limited to a few fathoms
range of sight."
"On this stormy sea
whose blades were surging
"projecting livid gleams,
a light building
"leaked almost dry canvas.
"It was a hundred-ton yacht.
Un schooner,
"name of schooners
in England and America.
"Ce schooner
was called the Sloughi, and...
"Vainly would one have sought to read
this name on his rear panel,
"just an accident,
sea ​​surge or collision..."
Soft music
- ...
Hiss of steam
-That's it, we're in Switzerland!
-We arrived.
Whistle
Not clocked
- ...
Well, we're going to have to learn German.
Happy music
- ...
...
Soft music
- ...
...