THE FIVE OF US
[chiIdren singing]
- Sophie!
- Isa and CIaudie are dry babies!
- Cheese!
One more for Iuck!
Cheese again...
Super!
Bye, Mom.
- We thought we'd stay for supper.
- Very funny!
- Have fun, girIs! Be good!
- Have a great weekend!
- Go!
[''Lady MarmaIade'' pIaying]
- We need more beer!
- Look, she's at it again!
- C'mon, guys aIways hit on you.
- Her, maybe.
Me, they Iook right through.
- It's aII about attitude.
Manon's so shy guys freeze up.
Whereas they think
Isa Iooks down on them.
- They're a head shorter than me.
- If they have one!
[giggIing]
- Hey! My naiI poIish!
Ah...!
- Why the rush to faII in Iove?
- I agree.
We have our whoIe Iife.
Loving you forever
day after day
- And Iove at first sight?
- A fairy taIe.
If it does exist, it doesn't Iast.
- How wouId you know?
- And you?
- WeII, it must be reaI.
They make so many movies about it.
- I'm Iiving proof of it.
You faII in Iove bIindIy,
not at first sight!
- I don't mean me.
I'm the fruit of Iove at first sight.
- That's proof it exists
but doesn't Iast.
- It couId've Iasted.
But Mom had doubIe vision!
- Fasten your chastity beIts, girIs!
Tonight is going to be wiId!
- Get off, Isa!
I'm a bundIe of nerves!
What if he doesn't come?
- Who'd pass you up?
- Don't joke!
I've never sIept
with a pro hockey pIayer!
- A good pIayer, you mean.
- OK, besides Boivin and SuIIivan.
But they did Iousy stickwork.
[howIing with Iaughter]
- Do you have to be in Iove
to make Iove?
- If I'm not in Iove, I can't.
- Me neither.
- You've never done it, Sophie!
Do you want
to sleep with me tonight
Do you want to sleep with me
Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
[repeating chorus]
I am Lady Marmelade
[''Lady MarmeIade'' pIaying]
You won't faII!
- CarefuI!
- Hey, no, no, no!
- It's about momentum.
I can throw a 200-Ib guy.
Is she aIright?
- She just threw up.
- Shh, it's not for sure.
- You knew?
- A toast before they come?
- To our Iast party before coIIege!
- And your move to New York!
- Who's buying beer?
- I can't get in a car,
I'm barfing up Iunch.
- We'II toss, except CIaudie.
- TaiIs!
- Heads!
We're going to town.
It's a smaII party,
but you can come.
- Thanks.
- Manon, right?
- Manon?
Let's get mapIe syrup for breakfast.
Huh?
MapIe syrup for our pancakes?
- No!
Sure, good idea.
- Coming?
[motorcycIe approaching]
- Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
You made it!
- To think Martin Gagné
cruised me once!
- That doesn't mean anything.
Every guy cruises you.
Don't teII me you--
- Nah, I'm not the Ieast interested.
A hockey pIayer, Anne!
[crickets chirping]
- Just Iike a stage.
With the crickets...
[imitating crickets]
They sound Iike cymbaIs!
- WiII you taIk to us
when you're a big star?
- I'II teII the whoIe worId about you!
My best friends...
And this is a song
especiaIIy for hers...
- ''For them''!
- Ah!
That's it - for them.
Yes, madame!
- The four of us can work for you.
Anne can do costumes,
Isa'II be bodyguard--
- CIaudie wiII handIe my PR!
- Oh! And I'II be your shrink!
- You'd be perfect!
- Sophie...
you have fame, you have weaIth...
but I sense
an emptiness inside you.
Do you ever get Iaid?
- He's backing up!
- I'm going to a party.
- So are we!
- Hi!
- Want to sit in front?
- Can I smoke?
- No.
- Where are they?
They've been gone hours.
- Let's take your bike and Iook.
- Hmm?
[guffawing]
- OK, I'II go with Isa.
- Are we far enough?
- I don't want anyone spying.
I see someone.
- So?
- It's Manon! Hurry!
Manon? Manon!
Manon!
Manon...
What happened?
Who did this?
- Fuck!
- Manon...
[crying]
Isn't Sophie with you?
Where is she?
Where's Sophie?!
HeIp her, I'II Iook for Sophie.
- Wait!
- Sophie!!!
- Great, it's mating time.
Hi.
My name's MicheI.
I wrote this song
so everyone knows
I'd like to tempt you
with my prose
I hope to make you discover
You want me as your lover
But your heart
rejects my tenderness
Your body
refuses my every caress
You don't care about my love
You're scared of my love
- Hey!!!
Come heIp!
- Isa?
- HeIp me!
- Isa?!
Manon!
Ah! Manon!
- Manon, can you hear me?
Yes. Sorry.
What were you saying?
- That team productivity
is proportionaI to the degree
of bonding of its members.
- And?
To that cause Stéphane
is organizing a section outing.
Rafting!
- I can't go.
- I didn't say when.
- I can't swim.
- We'II have Iife jackets.
Besides, our handsome Stéphane
used to be a Iifeguard.
And?
You know the guys in orange shorts
at CIub Med?
- No, I don't.
Did you find
the transport sector reports?
- Yes. Yes.
- Manon?
About the rafting, I reaIIy want
to deveIop our team spirit.
- It's a nice idea,
but I can't.
- How about a fiIm?
- It'd be hard
to find one everyone Iikes.
- Then how about
just you and me?
I'm staying in MontreaI aII week.
- We'II see.
- BaII's in your court.
Good night.
- BaII's in your court!
- You're such a snoop!
- He's been watching you.
I can't beIieve
you won't give him a chance. ReaIIy!
- Every girI on the fIoor's after him.
- This is about you.
Don't teII me he Ieaves you coId.
- I didn't say that.
I'm just not in a rush.
- AII singIe 32-year-oId women
are in a rush!
- Let's take the stairs.
- We can squeeze in.
[TV pIaying]
- Manon.
[phone ringing]
GiIbert Morin,
his stocks took a beating.
- I'II come back.
- No, give me one sec.
He's onIy down a quarter miI.
Yes.
Hi, GiIbert. Yeah, I heard.
Can I caII back?
I'm with a major investor.
Great. CaII you back.
Sorry.
- There's a new Woody AIIen.
- Yes. I Iove Woody AIIen!
And SyIvester StaIIone.
Let's eat first.
Not to brag,
but I make the best pesto in town.
It's divine!
- Let's eat out.
- Perfect.
[phone ringing]
TaIk about traveIing.
It's his passion.
He just came back
from Rajasthan.
- How do you know?
- Ah.
- Wear something bIack.
A sexy IittIe dress
with Iots of cIeavage.
[Manon giggIing]
- You're the big mystery
on our fIoor.
Who is the beautifuI Manon?
Does she have a roommate?
Friends?
StrangeIy, nobody knows.
- Nobody ever asked.
- Ah.
Why stock anaIyst?
- Because it's easy.
And you?
- Because it's risky and weII-paid.
- Hmm.
- Married? Divorced?
- SingIe.
- Mm. Good, me too!
- And your reputation?
- It's a myth.
- A myth?
- By definition,
a myth is a taIe in which
the protagonist's acts and deeds
are ampIified or modified
by the coIIective imagination.
- To the meeting
of myth and mystery!
[ceII phone ringing]
- Excuse me.
Yes?
Yes, honey.
I Iove you too.
Good night.
Kisses and papa-bear hugs!
- How oId?
- Four.
Joint custody.
JuIiette.
- Did you take her to Rajasthan?
- No.
- How was it?
- It was magicaI.
- TeII me.
- And our movie?
I... I crossed the desert
on a cameI.
One night,
we reached
the crest of a dune at sunset...
[muted]
- As a girI I was afraid
the air wouId become poisoned.
I imagined the city
covered by a huge gIass dome.
- Hmm.
No more rain,
no more bIizzards.
- Just a soft
warm breeze.
- Hmm.
That comes from...?
- Big heaters
at the corners of the pIanet!
- I'm tempted to say I want you.
- Maybe it's not a myth--
- Don't worry,
I'm a very cautious myth.
Never the first time.
UnIess you invited me up
for a nightcap.
Drunk, I'm an easy myth.
- If I did,
there'd be no more mystery.
- Ah.
FREE FOR LUNCH,
MYTH AND MYSTERY?
Say what you wiII,
hotdogs rock.
- I was afraid
you were the saIad type.
It feeIs Iike
you're x-raying my souI.
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
I've nothing to hide.
- Can I heIp?
- I'm Iooking for something sexy.
- I have just the thing.
- My other job's ending.
I have to work.
- I don't need anyone now.
Inside? Outside? Both?
- Just outside.
Outside, guys!
- OK.
[screaming]
- As per your request
for information on Richard Thibodeau,
in March 2003
the National Parole Board
met the offender
and reached the following decision:
day parole granted
in a halfway house.
[screaming]
[knocking]
- Manon?
It's Stéphane.
You weren't at work, so...
- I'm taking a few days off.
- Brigitte toId me.
Are you sick?
- No. I just needed some downtime.
How are you?
- Fine.
I'm off to Toronto for three days.
I wanted to see you before.
Am I disturbing?
- No.
Can I get you a drink? Beer?
Coffee?
- A coffee, pIease.
I'm aII out.
- A beer then.
- Have a seat.
- Some water?
As per your request
for information...
Thanks.
Your pIace is IoveIy.
- It's a bit of a mess.
How do you cope
with commuting to Toronto?
- You get used to it.
I prefer New York, but it's fine.
- How's your daughter?
- Good.
ReaI good.
I just took her to her swim cIass.
She's a reaI IittIe fish.
This isn't a good time.
- No, no.
- I shouId have caIIed first.
- No. It's fine, honestIy.
I'm gIad you dropped by.
I'm just a IittIe...
- When do you come back?
- Soon, in a few days.
- Is there anything I can do?
- No.
I'm reaIIy gIad you came.
I'II caII when you get back.
- Whenever you Iike.
- You're sweet.
- I'm not sweet,
I'm faIIing in Iove.
- Mr Dubois?
- Manon?
What a IoveIy surprise!
CIaire's inside.
Come in!
- Did you know he was reIeased?
- Mm-hmm.
I've been foIIowing his case.
When he appIied for paroIe,
I even attended the hearing.
He asked our forgiveness.
Forgiving doesn't mean forgetting.
I couIdn't go on hating him,
it's too hard.
PauI's different.
WeII...
For years, I...
I waIIowed in my anger.
It didn't bring Sophie back.
It brought me misery.
Anyway, whether we forgive him
doesn't reaIIy infIuence
the Board's decision.
He'd changed in prison.
He was so young.
- That's no excuse.
- You can read the reports.
- And shake his hand too!
CongratuIate him on the fine Iife
he has ahead of him!
- He doesn't understand.
- I don't either.
- If you want it...
it's yours.
As pretty as ever.
- Manon?
- I've had years
to think things over.
I've been in therapy.
I pIan to continue
when I'm outside.
I'm deepIy sorry...
for what I did.
I ask forgiveness
from everyone I hurt,
Iike Sophie Dubois' parents.
It wasn't about their daughter.
She was there, that's aII.
I'm sorry.
Very sorry.
SIeep.
Time for a deep sIeep.
Now...
the owIs have gone to sIeep.
The sheep don't make a peep.
- Bahhh! Bahh!
- Ah! Shhh!
Jeanne, go beddy-bye.
[phone ringing]
HeIIo?
Manon...?
Manon CIoutier?
- Come in.
- It's IoveIy.
- Thanks.
It's in a mess.
- Funny...
I'm often in the area but we...
- I made coffee.
So you have a daughter?
- She's 8.
They grow up so fast!
- She's adorabIe.
Ever see the others?
- Not as often
these past few years.
OccasionaIIy.
Isa has her store
in New York.
Sportswear
in Soho.
- It tickIes!
- CIaudie's a chef,
her recipes are top secret.
She's great.
Like to see them?
- I asked Sophie's parents...
if we couId go back to the cottage.
[traffic noises]
- Why not?
It was good, wasn't it?
- It was great.
Sorry, uh...
- Stuart.
- Sorry, Stuart.
Have to work.
- I don't understand.
- There's nothing to understand.
It was great.
- You were a modeI?
- Back in MontreaI.
Long time ago.
[door cIosing]
[phone ringing]
HeIIo?
Anne, how are you?
Shit!
- She wants to see us?
Where?
- No, I've never gone fishing.
Fish are stinky.
But I eat them.
I Iike fish sticks.
I'II ask Mom and caII you back.
Bye.
Sarah asked me camping.
Two nights with her parents at...
I don't remember, but it's not far.
PIease...
- You're too young to go aIone.
- I won't be aIone.
I'II ask Dad.
- No. Dad decides when
you're at his pIace. Here, I decide.
- Damn!
- Jeanne!
- Have a good trip?
- Yes, thanks.
AIways strange to come back.
- 15 years.
I'd prefer if we stayed in town.
The weather's nice.
We can sIeep outside Iike before.
- CIaudie's a case, isn't she?
- She screws anything that moves.
- She has a warm heart.
- She's a hottie, aIright!
- Shhh!
- I can't wait
for our party next month!
The Iast before I go.
- New York! You're so Iucky!
- You're stiII coming?
- My parents said
I can stay two weeks.
Then I'II record my demo here.
Are you nervous about going?
- Not if you're there.
- I'II aIways be there, Isa.
Even when you're the worId's
number-one modeI!
Even when
I'm the number-one pop star!
Me too, Sophie.
Me too.
[Sophie humming]
- When you come back,
I'll have gone for a few days
to a place close and far away,
where I left part of me
1 5 years ago.
Manon.
[Iaughing]
- Don't just stand there.
- I can't sing.
- Friends are aIIowed to sing off-key.
There's no reason to part
From those close to your heart
It's a sad role deep down
Playing the circus clown
Ooh-ooh-ooh
You make children laugh
But never for long
The laughter fades away
When the kids
are too old to play
- How's MicheI?
- He's great. We spIit up.
- I'm sorry.
- It's much better this way.
For me, and especiaIIy Jeanne.
Now we can taIk
without screaming.
He Iives three bIocks away.
- How's your Iove Iife?
- WeII, you know...
comes and goes.
Men are Iike cherries.
One's never enough.
And you?
- No comment.
- I've met someone.
If I don't screw up,
he might be my first Iover.
- Hup! Hup! Hup! Hup!
GUILTY OF RAPE AND MURDER,
SENTENCED TO LIFE
HORRIBLE END
FOR A YOUNG WOMAN HITCHHIKER
[Ioud rock pIaying]
- It's here.
The road to the Iake's right here.
We passed it, stop!
- Hey, stop.
- Stop!
- Ahhh!
- Don't move, Manon.
[whimpering]
[screaming]
What did I teII you?
[man groaning]
[screaming]
MANON IDENTIFIES SOPHIE'S MURDERER
- We have to appeaI,
get a Iawyer!
- He's been on day paroIe
for 5 months.
- He's out? It's unbeIievabIe!
- He's at a haIfway house,
under supervision.
- You couId run into him
grocery shopping!
- I'II change my name
to my mom's.
- If you meet face to face,
what'II that change?
- He won't recognize her.
- He saw her aII through the triaI.
15 years in jaiI thinking of her!
- He's changed.
- Sure!
- Maybe.
- No! That kind of person
doesn't change!
- They wouIdn't Iet him out
if he's dangerous!
They get therapy in jaiI.
- Therapy?
Don't you read the papers?
Most of them are repeat offenders!
- She can move.
- What?!
- Listen! No!
She has to know aII about him,
where he Iives...
- I aIready asked that!
AII they can say is,
he Iives in the MontreaI area.
That's the Iaw.
- Isa!
Why are you going there?
It won't bring her back!
Come on.
- MicheI, caII me!
This is my fourth message!
You're with our daughter!
It's my right to know where you are,
do you hear?
- They may be at a movie.
SmeIIs good!
- It's the butter.
- The port!
- Everything's fattening.
- Right, butter's fattening.
SaIt's bad for bIood pressure,
cream's awfuI for choIesteroI.
Put'em aII together?
Ambrosia!
CarefuI, the sauce dish is tippy.
And the cook's tipsy!
[Iaughter]
- CIaudie, you're amazing!
- It's just my job.
- AII I Iike about cooking is eating.
- I'd Iike to cook for friends,
but for me aIone...
- I get my joIIies from cooking.
- What about your Iovers?
- They're desert!
- There's nothing I Ioathe more
than cooking.
Every night I thank the Lord
for frozen dinners.
- You feed your daughter
frozen food?
- No, I microwave it first.
- Mm!
- Mm. Did Sophie ever teII you
she once cooked a fish whoIe,
without cIeaning it?
- Yuck!
[Iaughter]
- She bIindIy foIIowed
a recipe that didn't mention it!
[aII]: Ahhh...!
- She was baking potatoes.
The potatoes
were wrapped in foiI...
the butter was too,
so she stuck it in the oven!
I so wish she were here.
I think about her every day.
But it aIways Ieads to him.
I dream of kiIIing him.
I dream about it every night.
I don't make him suffer.
It doesn't make me feeI better.
I enter the prison.
I go to his ceII. Bang!
A buIIet in the head. Thanks, bye.
- It wouIdn't change the past.
- He doesn't deserve to Iive!
- Isa.
- Right!
I can't say I want to kiII him,
but he,
he waIks around free.
He's free!
He got a second chance!
What about Sophie?
Did she get a second chance?
- Isa, pIease.
- Can any of you
say you've forgotten?
That you trust strangers?
That you don't want
to kiII sometimes?!
- A toast!
To CIaudie!
To the one
it shouId've happened to!
Admit you wished
it had been me instead.
- What?
- You've aIways judged me!
- CIaudie, pIease!
- If it had been me
nobody wouId've been shocked.
You'd have said:
''She asked for it.''
I screwed anything that moved!
Bad Iuck!
I'm stiII here, and I'm stiII screwing!
Never the Ieast hitch.
No incurabIe iIIness,
no unwanted pregnancy. Just fun!
I've never been pregnant.
Even when I tried to.
- You're taIking nonsense.
- Maybe.
But I never said,
''With my judo, I'd have saved Sophie!''
I didn't want to come.
I didn't want to.
- AII because of a psycho.
- He's no crazier
than those who Iet him out.
- Anne!
It's MicheI!
- She's my daughter.
Of course I'm worried!
You won't get her ever again
if you don't return my caIIs!
Put Jeanne on.
Hi, my sweetheart.
I just wanted to say night-night.
And that I Iove you.
Ah... Yes, I know you know.
Tomorrow, my Iove.
Yes, bye.
Coffee, anyone?
- It's okay, I'II do it.
I don't beIieve it!
- Sophie!
Sophie!!
Sophie!
[crying]
[screaming]
- We shouId go.
- CIaudie's right.
- No, it's Isa who's right.
You'd have saved her.
- I'd have been as heIpIess as you.
- It's not a matter of strength.
- I'm not taIking about strength.
- If you move...
I'II kiII her.
I just want you to watch.
Afterwards I'II drive you back
and we'II party.
[Sophie screaming]
- No!
[screaming]
- What did I teII you?
- Why didn't you teII us?
We'd have understood.
- You were scared to death.
We'd have done the same.
- He was a psycho, Manon.
He wanted to kiII you both,
no matter what you did.
- I'II never know.
- I thought onIy moms
got up at dawn.
- Pancakes are a tradition here.
- FortunateIy,
some memories are sweet.
- ShaII I stir?
- Go!
- Ahh!
- Mm-mm-mm!
[aII]: Mm-mm!
- When Thibodeau
appIies for fuII paroIe,
I can make a victim statement.
- Aren't you afraid to be near him?
- Mr Thibodeau,
I have a right
to be at your hearing.
But I don't want
to refresh your memory of me.
Still, I want you to hear my voice.
You didn't hear it
the night you raped me
and stabbed me 1 7 times.
And killed Sophie
before my eyes.
She was 1 7.
Today I'm 32.
She didn't have my luck.
She didn't survive.
She didn't survive you.
You'll probably be granted
full parole soon.
You can rent an apartment,
find a job,
be around
1 7-year-old girls again.
I can't help
being scared for them,
despite your exemplary behaviour
during the 1 5 years
you spent behind bars.
That's why I ask you to listen.
Simply to listen to me,
for once,
for the first time.
One day our paths may cross.
I'll probably shake,
I may throw up.
But I'll keep right on going.
- Yes?
- It's Manon.
- Hey!
- FeeI Iike a hotdog?
- I'm on my way.
- I have the right to work,
to be in love.
I have the right to live, to be free.
Though I'll never be totally free,
like you.
- Given the psychiatric evaIuation
of Mr Thibodeau
and his modeI behaviour
and profound regret,
we have granted his request
for fuII paroIe.
We beIieve, Mr Thibodeau,
you no Ionger represent
an unacceptabIe risk to society.
That said,
we're counting on you.
Good Iuck.
- Thank you.
- You can't do that!
A rapist, a murderer!
You can't Iet him go!
- Bahh!
- My friend Sophie
had a big house in the country.
We used to sIeep
counting the stars.
- I'II teII you how many I count.
- You're stiII beautifuI.
And I stiII want you.
SubtitIes: Robert Gray,
Kinograph
DVD SubtitIing: CNST, MontreaI