♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ Every day how the sun keep shining
Not a cloud up in the sky ♫
♫ Every where the girl be hiding ♫
♫ All you know is, you gotta try ♫
♫ Wish this is could last for ever ♫
♫ It's gotta be a dream ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ Now if you think your ready for something ♫
♫ And your tired of the same old thing ♫
♫ Move along cause you might get lucky ♫
♫ By the feeling looking great ♫
♫ Wish this is could last for ever ♫
♫ It's gotta be a dream ♫
♫ Oh, I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ Paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best  ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ And something is gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
Ha, ha but that's just the way....
Would you hold the wheel for me please?
Thanks
Honk, Honk, Honk
Whoa
Oh
Alright there is another one
Ready, Fire
What a bummer
No points for you.
Are there any left?
Damn it, Ginger
Ride!
Thanks
Sir, Just jump in, sit on it.
It don't matter
Sir, where your going to?
Just let me of, where ever you going
Paradise beach
My girlfriend's Sarah, invited us out to spend a couple of weeks...
at her uncle's beach place
Sound's nice
Sound's great
are you kidding!
Man! Where going to party
You know, School's out
and is open season now
What's your name?
Scott, Scott Daniels
I'm Ducky, Ginger
Alright, guys and girls it's gonna be one super memorial day, weekend
With temperatures in the high 80's
More than a million people will be hitting the south land beaches
And halve of them boys!
Stay tuned baby, here are more of the sound's, you love the most
Target  ahead
Quick hand my that book
Hold on to me so I don't fall.
That's the last of them
School's out!
♫ School it out! ♫
♫ Nothing is gone hold us down ♫
♫ Malibu is calling ♫
♫ It's got the best looking girls around.♫
♫ All day and all night we get no trouble ♫
♫ Everything is fine, love is
here, that's summer time ♫
Alright, gentleman
Suck up you gut sailor!
What's your name Sailor?
Randy, Captain Blice sir
well straiten up
your on duty here
and I run a tight ship
Aye aye, Captain Blice
Grab the Captain's balls
What are you fool's doing?
I demand a military bearing in my men
Dower!
Captain Jack, and his filthy crew
Left Mexico with yet another load of the demon weed
They will be within our waters tonight
Every man must stand prepared
Take out the boats and lower the cannons.
Yes Sir.
Dismissed.
excuse me, excuse my
Captain Blice, Sir?
♫ I love a men in a uniform ♫
So your just bumming around the country sleeping in the woods he?
I prefer it calling traveling light
Where your crashing tonight?
Where ever I stop for the night.
How about staying with us?
Leaving spend the night,
Right Ginger
Well, we can ask Sarah
I'm sure she say it's okay
I don't want to border Gin!
Don't sweat it!
Sarah is cool
♫ Everything is fine ♫
♫ love is here that's summer time ♫
♫ Love is here, that's summer time ♫
Sarah! Whoa
This is it!
Sarah, Whoa
Oh!
Whoa, whoa
Come on, look at the house
Wow, whoa
What does your uncle do?
Real estate rounding or something?
Huh! Look at the view.
Yeah, Nice.
Hey, a bar
Whoa, great stereo
Pool table, Isn't it something
How many bed rooms
5 or 6
Hey, Ginger this bathroom is big enough for, where are you?
And are we there
And where do we get out?
Hi.
Who are you?
Scott, Scott Daniels
Oh!
The girls gave me a lift.
Oh, I have brought in your groceries for you
Oh, thanks.
You left them in the car
Oh!
Uh, where should I put the ketchup
Oh, Sarah. Scott here was tripping
around the country and....
we thought maybe he crash here for tonight
Yeah, I guess so
Hey, you guys come on!
Whoa, ginger hurry!
We need to see the hot tub and sauna, Come on.
Where is the hot tub?
Whoa!
Check it out! Whoa, this is neat!
Go, pool.
Yeah, yeah.
This is great.
Wow, what a place
Well look at those waves
I don't know about you guys,
I don't waste any more time
I got to dive in
Me too, I got to find a man
But what I'm, what follow you......
Whoops
Whoa,
- Whoa
- whoa
Let's head over!
whoa
Aah
Whoa
Alright!
That's it!
I think you getting sun burn.
Are you!
Whoa, Whoaaaa
Darling, use the stairs
Thanks for helping me to put the groceries away
Sure
When ever there is work to be done Ginger and Ducky
they always seem to disappear
Huh!
Hey about taking a walk on the beach?
sure
good
Hey, come back here!
Your quite different from your friends
Ginger and Ducky
Aren't they beautiful
Yeah, they are okay looking
There knock outs.
there the most popular girls in the school
I can understand that alright.
I never would have thought that,
they come all the way with me thou
Why not?
Nah, They just could go where they wanna to
The river the mountains
Where the boys are!
I don't know how they could do any better
than being here with you.
You really think that?
Absolutely
What a place!
What are we waiting for?
Let's have a party!!
Come on!
we gotta go and get ready
We don't have any arty goodies
Whoa oh!
my disperse
We sure could use a boy or two
huh, we can get the booze over the phone
But the boys?
We can get them the same way
Hey what's going on?
Ginger is gonna order some boys
How?
In the yellow pages
Hello, Pizza van?
Well, hello
howdy
Uh, Pizza!
That will be $7.83
What's on it?
Every thing, just like you ordered
Pepperoni, union, green pepper
sausage, anchovies
salami...
Is that a salami in your pocket?
or your just glad to see me?
It's a salami.
Will do.
Hey, look what I got?
Pizza boy!
Well alright.
Scotti baby,
How your doing?
Ginger, I'm not sure this is such a good idea?
What do you mean?
We deserve a party
We need a party!
I just don't know about this
School out now, it's time to have some fun you know?
Ginger I'm just afraid.
As usual
Oh, Sarah where not gonna have a orgy
It's just a little party
Okay, don't get carried away!
Hello, Glemms TV?
Do you have a repairman, you can send out?
Is he cute?
♫ Sometimes you win, sometimes you lose ♫
♫ Still gotta play the game ♫
♫ Nothing find you late at night ♫
♫ for the time to remember his name ♫
♫ Try not to break my heart ♫
♫ You got to look you got to touch ♫
♫ Here and something more ♫
We don't want any
Oh, yes we do
Alright, hi
I never seen them...
Uh, hi!
you around here before
Oh, I just moved here
♫ I need a real man, someone to hold.....♫
Really where from?
Oh, well originally down south
and recently I come from Minneapolis,
You know the twin city?
Figured!
♫ Oh, Tonight ♫
♫ I need a real man, someone to hold me tonight ♫
♫ I got a dreamer, he will be the answer tonight ♫
♫ Oh, Tonight ♫
Ginger, Ginger
where almost out of booze
Well get some more
Where did all these girls come from?
I don't know?
one of these studs must have called the pound
Yeah, you take over, and I cal for some liquid
Only a plumbers daughter!
but you give my tool a wrench.
Didn't you feel them?
I tough it was him!
Ginger, there's a guy and a girl in the bath room together
Yeah?
And there doing it!
How do you know?
I saw them
Maybe there washing each others back
Ginger, I'm not stupid.
No, but you are up tight
you get over it.
Willy's one's shop?
Do you deliverer?
Oh, great
Um, what does your delivery boy look like?
Yeah, how old is he?
Perfect!
Oh, so we just know how he looks
like when he comes.
Right, that will be 5 cases of pink triple
And 5 cases of beer.
No you better make that 6 cases
And some pretzels
I'm hungry
Got that?
Right, 10121 paradise beach
As soon as possible
Carl Purdue? Uh yes this is she
Uh, yes right away.
Who's Julie?
She's my uncle Carl fiancee,
why?
Yes,
Miss, Carmedy, this here is Willy one stop, out of  paradise beach,
Well, someone out of Carl's Purdue's place just put out an order in, and I Uh.
Oh, that's his niece
She staying out there for the summer
So, uh
why your bordering me?
I tried to get hold of Mr Purdue, but he wasn't in his office.
He is at a construction site.
Look what's your problem, Mr Uh?
Willy?
I just though that, well it's quite a bit a size order!
But if you say it's okay, sorry to border you.
Yes Julie, How are you?
yeah
Okay, okay listen this is the last one.
I won't delay any longer
For sure!
We got married in September,
the 15th, 8 in the morning.
Okay now?
Oh, that must be Sarah and her friends
I would worry about it.
There kids, it's summer!
there allowed to let of some steam
Julie, I'll take care of it.
Please don't press it, as soon as I get back
Okay
I love you
Bye, bye
How much trouble they can get in to?
When I was there age
Um, a lot of trouble
Hey!
How are you?
I'm doing alright.
Alright
Who are you voting for?
Both of you, alright
Oh, oh
Whoa
- Ah - uh
- uh - ah whoa
Alright
♫ Knock, knock on a good little tune ♫
♫ get switched by the man in the room ♫
♫ Get switched for a melody tune..... ♫
Whoa, o whoa
♫ Turn out the lights, you got 99 lives to play ♫
♫ All the girls, have to touch there touts
powerful wings....♫
Aah.. whoa
Whoaaaaaaaaa
Oh!
Hi!!
whoa, Whoaaaaaaaaaaaaa
♫ She melts me down and drinks me all night ♫
♫ Make love tonight ♫
Please slow.
That's good
Okay
I think it's coming.
I can't it's...
Well get a better shipment
I haven a little trouble
I'm almost there, okay?
It's good
♫ Well, turn off the light, where gonna make love tonight ♫
Oh, yeah
Shit
Bird fight
How do you like these pecks?
paddy, you like babe press-ion
Marlek, It's pointing the wrong way!
Huh, what's so interesting at the Purdue place?
Oh, Ooh
Oh, my lord!
Oh, uh
Something happening over there
and I don't think Carl Purdue knows any thing about it.
I'm calling the police
Oh, my good lord
Why aren't at the party?
I'm seem party's that match
Besides I'm been that rude
So, what's next
What's next
Yeah, what your gonna do,
just bum around the country?
Well, guess to find something that has meaning to me.
and go after it.
That can take the rest of your life.
Yeah, I guess it can.
I didn't know
one thing I got, is patience
You can't wait for ever
Maybe not.
But till I figure out what I want
I don't have any way to go after it.
How about you?
Got it all laid out I bet?
Why not?
Next fall, I start you see pre-law
Than a couple years of law school
Maybe, join up with a good firm, for a couple of years
Specialize and.....
Who, who is that 8 till 10 years
What if you get a fore in find, that you don't like to be a layer?
I don't plan to not like being a layer.
Your program and your.self sound just like a computer
Well, what's wrong with that?
Nothing, if you happen to be a computer.
Your a real life human being
So?
So follow your impulses ones a wile
Be human
Like Ginger and Ducky?
No!, Not like Ginger and Ducky
Like you I suppose?
Well?
You could do worse
♫ No where Trucking, and a wonderful life ♫
♫ I'm on a atomic rester, you ready to self, to say I hope ♫
♫ You guilty without me Hellacious ♫
♫ You thing all the troubles from the nights in the past ♫
♫ Happen the live ones last ♫
♫ Focus on you, with the rights and eyes, I hope you find....♫
Hi, there!
Oh, Hi.
We a .....
What's your name sweetie?
Jay, Jay Hammond
Now, Mam we have a neighbor, who has complained...
Your kinda youth to be a cop?
Wile I'm just a reservist, it's a summer job
My dad is the chief.
I go to Southern Cal. the rest of the year.
Now about the...
Oh, come in
join the party.
You know, me and Ducky
are going to Southern Cal. this fall.
Oh, yeah, Uh no
See I'm on duty.
Now about the complained.
Oh, relay. I wanna show you who Ducky is.
That's a Ducky.
That's a Ducky, the brunette.
♫ Dance wouldn't hurt ♫
♫ He takes your hand
and it's hot, hot, hot ♫
♫ And the drink seems to help him best un-cold ♫
♫ And he's stirring it once more ♫
But about the complained
What are you studying in school,
You gonna be a cop like your daddy?
No, this is just temporary
Study to be a veterinarian
Specializing in, Uh..
In what?
Animal husbandry.
♫ In their seeing view ♫
♫ When your lovers, and they
going somewhere, what they do ♫
♫ Neeeeeed ♫
♫ Nothing but you ♫
♫ Like they want you ♫
♫ When your lovers, remember when they look at you ♫
♫ When your lovers, it's the end and they see in you ♫
♫ Oh, when your lover ♫
♫ Then remember look at you ♫
♫ I wanna light you ♫
♫ Sometimes you win, sometimes you lose ♫
♫ Still gonna play the game ♫
♫ Nothing find you late at night ♫
♫ For the time to remember his name ♫
♫ Try not to break my heart ♫
♫ You got to look, you got to touch ♫
♫ And you give me something more ♫
♫ Is it love like a urban canyon  ♫
♫ Like bad as before ♫
♫ Try not to break my heart ♫
♫ I need a real men, someone to hold me tonight ♫
♫ Oh, tonight ♫
♫ I got a dreamer, he will be the answer to night ♫
Whoa!!
Oh, my god!
Whoa!!!
Come on Sarah, the water is great.
Come on, you been skinny dipping before
Whoa
How come your aren't down with the rest of them
Who, I can't swim
You can't ether
I can swim
Oh! man
You think I'm a prude to, don't you?
Oh, no I don't
your just fine
Maybe if you, you know
Go a little more now and than
Try to enjoy life
But your gonna be just okay
Honest
If I had your face and figure
Honey I never be wearing clothes
Thanks Doreen.
Huh, Paradise Beach, huh
Probably some kids toasting marshmallows
Cap, Look at here
Damn it, we picked up a boat heading this way from port
It's looks like a cutter, sir
Why, how far?
Oh, It's fast, Sir
How fast?
Real fast
About 15 minutes, top
Damn, okay Blice, but not this time
I quite, Dump
Jettison the cargo.
All of it
Trow it over the side quick trip to sea
Can we just keep a kilo?
Not even a lid, quick
Sir, oh god.
Dump it all
♫ We la ladi, ladi
we ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ We la ladi, ladi,
♫ I met a girl from south Carolina ♫
♫ She ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ What that means she moved to China ♫
♫ Ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ I know a guy his name is chuck ♫
♫ He ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ All night he likes to .......♫
♫ Ladi, ladi, low ♫
♫ I knew a girl from Chulavista ♫
♫ we ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ we did so much I got a blister ♫
♫ Ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ I got a guy, his name was Ron ♫
♫ He ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ He like me to do with my high heels on ♫
♫ I know a girl her name is Ducky ♫
♫ She ladi, ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ She make sure all the guys are lucky ♫
♫ Ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ Give ma a call, I don't mean collar ♫
♫ He ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ because I'm the cop with the big pistola ♫
Oh, ladi, ladi, love.
♫ I'm the pizza delivery boy ♫
He, ladi, ladi, love
♫ Eat my salami,
it gives my joy ♫
Oh, ladi, ladi, love
Going mud diving!
Sarah!
Uncle Carl
What I'm gonna do with you?
♫ I knew a girl from San Francisco ♫
♫ He ladi, ladi, love ♫
♫ She was glad when I used pistol ♫
♫ Oh, ladi, ladi, love ♫
I'm not angry, surprised yes
I just didn't think your the kind of girl who
take advantage of the situation like this
I'm sorry uncle Carl
It's just not like you
I know but
Did your friends,
Cinnamon and Goosy
Ginger and Ducky
Yes them, all this is
they doing isn't it?
Not, entirely
Well, it doesn't matter
we gotta put a stop to it.
Honey?
I have neighbors here, a position in the community
I just can't allow this
I tell everyone too leave
No
I'm no scrooge
Let them have fun tonight.
But Tomorrow
Everyone,
Including your two friends
Ginger and Ducky
What ever, Tomorrow they go
and you and I have a talk
Yes, uncle Carl
Right
Come on
Let's see, if I have a bed for tonight
God, I need a shower,
maybe a Sauna
Come on
What a drag!
There goes all whole summer,
It's not fair
Yeah, He sure didn't look like an old Fuddy daddy.
The fact is, he's kind a cute
Really?
I'll bet if he got to know us
He wouldn't be so mean
Ducky, That's it.
We gonna know uncle Carl, real friendly like you know!
I think we can change his mind!
Wait a minute, wait a minute
let me get my bearings
Sir!!
You know what is in that direction
Idiot!
Sir we didn't actually catch!
Ah Ha!
Captain Jack!
We meet again
Now your playing it tough, hey!
May I admire your spirit,
Captain Jack
I can say this for you!
You got balls, like me.
I don't play with mine all the time.
Oh, Smart guy, huh?
Well. Not smart enough, not for old Blice
We got you cold and you gonna pay
Huh, I wouldn't be surprised if they
lock you away for life, for this one.
But Captain
Yeah, there a lot of smart guys like you, out there.
But it takes only 1 good clean living American,
like my
To put an end to you and your filthy trade.
- Captain
- Yeah you....
buttered your bread
and now you gonna sleep in it.
- Captain
- Quite Gouwer
I wanna give this Sea scum a little piece of my ..
- Little mind?
- Yeah
There is a lot of weaker men you can con.
but not me.
To honest to clean too..
Slow, slow
There ship is clean, he must have dumped it over board
What!!!
We didn't get here in time.
You mean He....
Elegant bastard ain't he?
I.. get them out of here
Get them out of here!
Mind if I come in?
I just wanted me a little
Piece an quite
Well me too
I'm Sarah's friend Ginger
Glad to meet you, I'm Sarah's Uncle, Carl Purdue
Glad I meet you
Well, if you rather be alone
I got something to do
No that's alright
Sure it"s hot in here,
Isn't it?
That's the whole idea.
You ever heard of a cold sauna?
No
I hope you blame Sarah too much
for the parting going on.
I mean it really grew.
I guess it's kinda out of hand now
She should now better,
than to let it happen
She should have
May I
There's nothing like.... cold water.
When you really hot
No, there's nothing like it.
Feel so good to sweat
How old are you?
Huh?
I said, How old are you?
Oh, well, I'm older than Sarah
I'm old enough to know better
Isn't that what they say?
That's what they say about me.
Oh, your not so old.
You know it's hot in here.
Oh, I'm really sweating now.
Too hot?
Oh, no, I love it.
Okay
You look upset.
Bad bay at the office?
The worst
Let me give you a back rub.
No, please no, thank you.
I'm only trying to help.
What I need is a drink.
Okay, I get you one.
No no, besides whir all out
I just got the thing then
No, thanks I'm trying to quite.
These aren't cigarettes, they don't kill you.
They let you life, baby!
You mean, you mean those are, Uh
Sure, marijuana
Well all be, No I don't mess with that.
I thought that you where cooler than that.
You did huh?
I did
Well, can't let down a lady.
can you?
Give it up
Sure listen up.
- Well alright
- It doesn't give you trouble within here
-Well alright
- nothing would go wrong.
Now take a deep breath.
Are we doing here
Hold it in.
hold it in.
Deeper, that's it
That's it
Why Ginger?
You done work him out?
Is he dead?
We better call the cops, Where's the phone book?
You are the cops!
No, He's not dead
He just fell asleep
He works a little to hard, I give him a little grass
So he's in dreamland
help me get him up.
He, that's right, let's get him tomorrow.
Uh, uh, Tomorrow is my turn
Hit the beach at once
You, have super that.
he you ever put a show on?
No, I got never got in to that.
You would like it if you tried it.
I could show you how.
Yeah, I'll bet you could.
And you can teach me how to play the guitar.
I could probably show you a few things.
I always wanted to learn.
Oh, Hey Sarah.
Scott is gonna teach me how to play the guitar
Yeah
Hey, you play anything else?
Myself sometimes.
You think I could play something?
Don't ever try the accordion.
♫ Since I've been looking ♫
♫ for love every where ♫
♫ Someone to hold me ♫
♫ Someone will care ♫
♫ Know that your out there ♫
♫ Waiting for me ♫
♫ Love won't you hurt, I'm waiting ♫
♫ I'm waiting in patiently ♫
♫ So take her ♫
♫ If ever you find her ♫
♫ Comes along for every lonesome day ♫
♫ Take her, if ever you find her ♫
♫ I found Wonderful ♫
♫ When I found you ♫
Ginger?
Ducky?
Ginger!
Uh?
Whoa
What a night
I know
Spend the night in the bath tub,
because all the beds where full.
Oh, gees
Oh, It's world war 3
God, wake up soldiers
Time to face the world
Seen Ducky?
Yeah, ooh
My mouth feels like the
army marched trough it.
We got to get these people out of here.
This is a zoo
Just the zoo
Don't worry Sarah, don't worry
Ducky, open the door.
Excuse me
Oh
Oh, I uh...
We gonna need a bulldozer to clean this up
Ah, the water is great
Terrific
I think I get uncle Carl
And I need to work on my tan
Hey, how about a little help around here
- Later
- Loosen up Sarah.
You will still be here
That's what I'm afraid of.
Your dripping on the carpet!
Morning Mr Purdue!
I'm ready
What the hell's
Oh
- Who are you
- Ducky
Not how, who?
Ducky, Don't you remember
Last night you promised to take me sailing.
I did, Last night?
All last night, I don't remember
Don't remember?
Oh, after I helped tug you in and all?
Maybe I did.
You, tugged me in?
Thing are kinda fuzzy!
So, let's go,
you promised
Okay, alright
How about, letting me get dressed?
-Okay
- Okay, come on
Outside
Alright
Oh, oh
And 1, and 2 and reach.
And 3, and 4, and come on Harlen
Oh, hooligans,
Did you see that?
Hell's angels
Oh
I don't know how people can get sea sick?
The ocean is so romantic
Up and down
up and down
Don't you think?
I never thought about it quite that way.
You not still mad at me and Ginger,
Are you?
No, It's just I got neighbors and you know well.
I guess so,
It's hot!
I don't think that's a good idea!
Oh, I won't burn I never do
What are you doing?
Sun is better by you!
Alright I move.
Don't border there's room for both of us.
Oh, I think I'll have to find some other room.
Whoa!
Help, uncle Carl!
I can't swim!
Oh, Mr Purdue
Oh!
Well I'll never
Probably not, you old toad
Uh, she
I saw everything from the house
Ducky you could have drowned
Carl saved me!
Oh, Mr Purdue
You saved my best friend's life.
I really don't know how to repay you.
I just did, what anybody else would have done.
No, don't put your self down like that uncle Carl
your a wonderful guy.
It's to bad we had to screw things up, partying and everything
We didn't know you where against them.
I'm not against parties.
I give them all the time.
Maybe you'll give us a going away party!
Ducky, the man wants us out.
No party
I wouldn't say that.
You mean we can have a party?
I meant about of moving out.
Oh, Uncle Carl!
Thank you, we love you.
Uncle Carl your such a dub.
Whoa
What do I say?
♫ Without the love ♫
♫ Nights without the love ♫
♫ Sweet surrender,
I can't buy ♫
♫ You said you tried, come and help me with those eyes ♫
♫ Wont you hurry, won't you hurry, Come to me ♫
♫ I want the Nut sack and you, I know what I'll gonna do ♫
♫ I want the nut sack  to find me, All in me ♫
huh, feels good
Look great!
You rat
Hey, I'm only human
Your having fun?
Yeah, a lot
Julie Carmindy, please
Oh, hello dear, this is Wilhelmina Brinker.
over at Paradise beach.
By the Purdue place.
Fine, how are you, dear?
Oh, just a friendly call.
Well, As a matter a fact there is
something I thought you should be aware of.
I saw Carl Purdue this morning with a girl.
Oh, well, he sure didn't act like it was his nice
Well, if you really interested.
- Wang
-Whoa
I'm so sorry.
It's alright, just get the Limo
The limo?
Yes, The limo, go get it.
Wang, stand still
Now get the limo!
Hai
Hey, look!
Ducky, we don't have time to mess around.
We gotta collect wood for the band fire
Maybe something valuable.
Yeah, orange peels, and dirty diapers.
Well lock me in a freezer and call me a Popsicle!
Oh, my god!
Whoa!!!
Look another!
Where did It all come from!
Whoa
We are gonna have a party tonight
Yes sir, that what our computer panel tells us.
Paradise beach
Yes sir, by our calculations taking in consideration time,
The probably Buoyancy of the bags
The position of the sea wolf last night and sea currents
we can safely, that somewhere
In the area, approximating the perimeter
All right already.
Paradise beach.
I want every man break out in battle gear
Jack's gonna try to retrieve his evil cargo tonight,
and we gonna stop him
We not gonna let killer weed fall in the hands of our American youth.
Is my boat ready?
- Ship sir.
- Ship whatever, prepare to cast off.
Yes, sir.
Idiot!
Trow it to me!
Here okay?
Here, I got it, I got it
Ah, come on, I got it.
Here I got it,
Come on trow it! Ah.
surf up!
Who cares?
Hi, guys.
I got the munchies for tonight and
uncle Carl is paying for it.
He and Scott are at Willy's picking up the booze.
What are you guys up to?
Look what we found?
Is it?
It isn't?
It is?
It is just a little weed.
Well maybe not such a little.
How about 6 trash bags full.
6 bags full?
Like that?
Don't be mad, be glad.
Yeah, It's for the party!
Where gonna get busted!
Oh, Come on Sarah wake up,
it's not the middle ages.
Just because you don't wanna have fun, doesn't mean you have to spoil it for everyone else.
Why is everyone always on my case?
I don't mean to be mean, Sarah!
But just look at your self?
You don't want to have any fun.
Your a 50 year old teenager
You where kinda hard on her!
Maybe?
Whoa wie
- Alright.
- what can you do?
- Alright
- what's his name?
- Oh
- Evening
Let's go, the last one in the house is a rotten egg
Come on here, blue eyes.
Oh, well go!
Hay!
Hay
Marijuana
Puff me!
Awesome weed!
Marijuana
Huh, Who the hell are you?
I'm Me!
50 year old teenager about to loosen up,
and enjoy life.
That's not you!
Ow, yes it is.
I'm gonna find out what I've been missing all the time.
Sarah, you haven't been missing anything.
Everyone around here seems to think I have been
What everybody else think doesn't matter.
Sarah, listen?
I have been listening
I don't know, I don't know.
Oh, come on uncle Carl, you liked it last night!
Yeah, you told me it was great.
Well I have to admit..
I haven't slept like that
Since I was a kid
Relay, uncle Carl you so tired.
Oh, my
Oh, my.
♫ sometime you win, sometime you loose ♫
♫ Still got to play the game ♫
♫ Love can find you late at night,
try to remember his name ♫
♫ Try not to break my heart ♫
♫ You got to look you got to touch ♫
♫ Give me something more ♫
♫ Is it love like a urban canyon, is it love like bad before ♫
♫ Try not to break my heart ♫
♫ I need a real men, someone to hold me tonight ♫
♫ Oh, tonight ♫
♫ I got the dreamer, he will be the answer tonight ♫
Back off, man!
Hey, leave him alone,
who do you think you are?
Oh,!!!
Mm
Oh,
Oooooh,
Mmmmm
♫ I need a real men, someone to hold me tonight ♫
♫ Oh, tonight ♫
♫ I got the dreamer, he will be the answer tonight ♫
Idiot!
Watch the car, you fool.
Hay, your a little late
but don't worry there's plenty.
Oregano?
Hay, thanks for given my one
Hey, mama?
I'm not your mother!
Hey, I'm not in to incest anyway
Don't matter, are you popping pills?
I sure am
I'm a popper, he's a popper,
he's a popper
Wouldn't you like to be a popper to?
Oh, ah
Amigo!
Por favor!
Pick it up!
Pick it up yourself, wack pack
oh,
Now you made me mad!
Uh,
Whoa, haha!
Knock it off!
Hey get here?
Get in here?
Alright, whoa.
It's okay my friend
Amigo
That was great!
What, the grass or us?
O I don't know?
Shall we try all over again, so I can make up my mind.
What, Carl already?
Carl Purdue, what do you think your doing?
Julie!
Uh, nothing dear, your late,
but if you wait a second
Look at you, I'm shocked!
For these 2 little girls,  these children!
Julie, if you just simmer down,
you will see what has happened here..
has little to do with our relationship!
Oh, I'll say. I've never participated in such debauchery.
You allowed?
Hassie?
-What's a Hassie?,
- who's loud?
- Julie
- shut up!!
You pervert, you child molester
Our engagement is of!!
Oh,
Oh!!
Where sorry uncle Carl.
Yeah, unc. Is there any thing to make it up?
Well, screw her.
Do you have a cigarette?
If I got a cigarette?
That's what I said.
I rolled them my self!
What are you, some kind of a cowboy?
Hi, Doreen?
Hi you guys, how your all doing?
Come here!
Amigo, amigo
Get up  did yeah?
Ah,
Taste funny!
Must be the salt water.
Some of the bags leaked
Ah, Are you really a police men?
Oh,
Harlen?
Harlen, what are you doing?
I'm looking at the boats dear.
Ow
That's good Harlen, you should develop new interests
Captain on the bridge
Captain!
My bearings Gouwer
In you pocket, sir!
No you Idiot!
My bearings.
Ow, do we, sir?
Don't get to friendly Gouwer!
Not on duty,
see me after hours.
Ah, there they are the scoundrels.
Liberteens fronting there booty.
Maybe it's just a party, Sir?
For a weenie roast
Weenie roast?
Trying to contradict me?
I'll show you a weenie roast!
Tell the armorer bring out the cannons,
lower the assault boats.
We don't ave any assault boats, sir!
Damn it man, don't you have any American ingenuity.
- Mate 2
- Yes sir!
Gouwer, where is the unit photographer?
We don't have one, sir.
What, the first American assault, at our
own beaches and we don't have a photographer!
That's mutiny.
I have a instamatic, sir?
Fine, fine, It will do!
Bounty over the side!
Air Attack!!
Arrest them!
No, prisoners.
Wait a minute, what's that boys?
Shall we search them, sir?
Take a squid up to that house, and search it!
Yes, sir!
Let's go down to the beach.
Everyone out!
- Over here
- keep moving
- Come on
- I don't know
I'm going, I'm going!
- Yeah, let's go there.
Oh, yeah, yeah
Come on, keep moving
The girls going.
Ha ha you don't need a car.
Oh, yeah
Come on
Come on keep moving,
I'm going, I'm going, okay?
Can't a person, ever have any privacy around here?
Let's go, Down to the beach.
You know?
Who was that?
Popeye
Whoa!!
Bath room, bath room!
We found the marijuana, Sir!
Burn it!!
I like them to see it destroyed,
like it destroys their minds.
You kids, know what your doing to your self's?
Whoa!
Your body is a temple
Oh, I know.
And you should watch what you put in to it.
Oh, I do.
This killer weed, This killer weed
destroyed more lives
Then typhoid, syphilis, leprosy.
It rots your brain
Your in the bloom of youth.
And your letting this poison.....
People who indulge in such perverted practices
they grow up to be whores, pimps, killers
actors, politicians!
And coast guard Captain,
Captain, what's going on here?
What burning?
Rum!!
- What
- And where pirates
And pillagers.
You put your arm around her,
You do the hoosie koe
You put your arm around her
and you do the....
Well, Julie Carmendy?
What do you think your doing?
Walk along.
I surely will
Ladies!
What was that all about back there?
What do you mean, what was that all about?
I felt like it!
Why?
I know what I want now.
I wanna be just like you.
You could do worse.
And we hit, he where a dreamer.
You, where a marine?
No silly, I was a wave.
And I always, wanted to be a marine.
Like daddy.
Looks like the liberation of Paris.
♫ You tried to do what to tell ♫
Doreen what happened?
Oh, I've been invited
♫ I'm the one that doesn't knew the school ♫
Ah, paradise beach, okay. Once we
get there and gather round the stuff.
What that shipment and this I can retire.
Captain, It's a trap, Sir.
What, hot spit it out.
In the cove, Blice ship, the coast guard!
They're waiting for us sir!
- Damn
- What are we gonna do, sir
Dump the grass,
head back.
Engines full
We gonna pick up another load, sir?
That's it I'm out, your out.
Where going back, in to politics.
Is safer more profit.
Set a course for San Clemency
We go take a vacation.
It's about time my assistant earned his keep
How do you pretty ladies like to share a man?
Would we!
Yeah, what!
Fire is dying.
Ducky, that's fire works!
I thought it was empty
Oh, no
Guys, come on get out of here.
In coming artillery, Here they come.
Take cover man.
Come on regroup, come on
- I surrender,
- huh?
Fighter!
Go, man the ship.
The ship, man the ship
Fight!
I want a raise!
Just like I always thought it will be.
There will never be a party like this one.
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ Every day how the sun keep shining
Not a cloud up in the sky ♫
♫ Every where the girl be hiding ♫
♫ All you know is, you gotta try ♫
♫ Wish this is could last for ever ♫
♫ It's gotta be a dream ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ Now if you think your ready for something ♫
♫ And your tired of the same old thing ♫
♫ Move along cause you might get lucky ♫
♫ By the feeling looking great ♫
♫ Wish this is could last for ever, It's gotta be a dream ♫
♫ Oh, I wanna go to paradise ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ Paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ Where the girls all look so nice ♫
♫ They can come from the east or west ♫
♫ But know where they look the best ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away
Because paradise is where I stay ♫
♫ I wanna go to paradise  ♫
♫ For the look just once or twice ♫
♫ But it's gonna take me away ♫