It is useless to follow them.
They can no longer be harmful.
- Egyptians can ride on a saddle.
- Right.
And it's convenient
when you must run away.
Randus! Look down there!
Egypt has been conquered.
Caesar has won.
- And you along with him, master.
- Let's go!
Let's go, or we'll miss
the evening meal.
It is not a lovely sight, but better
under the cross that on it.
I nailed many
during the war against Spartacus.
- I am still nauseous over it.
- Come on. The camp is far away.
Kill me, Roman.
Kill me.
Relieving their suffering is against
the edict of the consuls.
Why did you do it? It could
cost you your rank and freedom.
From the Rhine to the Nile,
everything is now Roman.
- Nostalgic over your land?
- The winners have no land, master.
I didn't liberate you
to hear you call me "master".
You are free, Beroz,
and you are our best explorer.
Show it. Explore in the kitchen
and find something to eat.
If there is food,
I will surely find it.
Cleopatra is using Rome
to take revenge.
So many of her friends
will end up in chains!
Many.
Randus, Caesar wants to see you
in his tent.
- Alright.
- What does Caesar want?
Only he knows.
We could leave Egypt
in the spring, Caesar.
Two legions are enough.
One will cover the delta of the Nile.
And our adversaries?
My enemies are in Rome.
If affection doesn't move them,
then fear must do so.
- They speak of me as a tyrant.
- Your voice will silence everyone.
Rome does not love Caesar.
Only those who fear a man
too great for their stature.
Randus.
Come closer.
- You earned your day.
- I carried out your orders.
You couldn't have done better.
He took command of the cavalry
and blocked the enemy on the plain
with a cohort. Excellent job.
- You're a centurion. You deserved it.
- Thank you, Caesar.
Are you still determined
on not commanding a cohort?
Being a solder of Caesar
is sufficient for me.
A commander's breastplate
weighs too much in the desert.
You're getting old. 20 years ago you'd
have carried a much greater weight.
The only thing I have in common
with Caesar is our age.
Besides, my best compensation
is participating in your victories.
But you surely don't want
to refuse silver pieces.
Here.
Drink to my health, fellow soldier.
And don't sing hostile songs to
Caesar with the legion's drunkards.
Come, Randus.
Once the Egypt campaign is over,
the struggle among factions
could arise again in Rome
and degenerate in a civil war.
- You know that?
- Yes, general.
- I want a risky service from you.
- Caesar says "Go", and I go.
Pompey's faction
cannot be harmful anymore,
but Crassus undisputedly dominates
in the provinces of the Orient.
His word still has importance
in the senate.
And the more I know about
his intentions, the better, Randus.
I think one head is worth more
than two in Rome.
One word about this at Crassus'
court, and you lose your head.
You must be my eye and my ear.
Leave at dawn with a couple of men.
Go to Crassus as my ambassador,
in friendship,
and try to find out
what is happening in Zeugma.
It will be done.
The Nile is congested
with the traffic of the troupes.
It's better to board in Alexandria.
It will be a long, difficult journey.
It will be hard for you to survive
if Crassus allies with Pharnaces,
king of the Parti, and he attacks me.
I want to know as much as possible,
what Crassus' intentions are.
You risk your life in this enterprise
and I, the loss of a friend.
- My life is yours, Caesar.
- If it is mine, preserve it.
Which Barbarian god
does this amulet belong to?
I don't know.
I've worn it since my birth.
I know Thrace very well
to be mistaken. It comes from there.
I saw an identical one
when I faced Spartacus on the field.
- Your memory is magnificent.
- One doesn't forget certain things.
He wanted to kill me with a blow on
the neck. His neck had a similar one.
- It didn't bring him good luck.
- He ended up on a cross.
And yet he was a good soldier.
You weren't born yet, centurion.
You don't know.
Spartacus knew few and simple
rules of war.
He had understood our strategy,
and he could've defeated Rome.
But the mass didn't follow him.
Farewell, Randus. Good luck.
And remember. Caesar's gratitude
is as firm as his memory.
Verulus, do you know
why the Sphynx smiles?
- Nobody knows, Caesar.
- Because nobody wants to understand.
The Sphynx smiles on men, Verulus.
Grains of sand
raised by the hand of destiny.
This way you'll learn, slave!
I'll rip away your skin with this whip!
- What is going on? Stop!
- She tried to escape.
Enough!
Randus!
Vetius! I wasn't expecting
to see you in Egypt.
I was. The echo of your gestures
has reached Rome.
- You've advanced in rank. Good.
- What is going on, Vetius?
The centurion avoided that
a slave be badly whipped.
She is Clodia, my sister,
travelling with me towards Zeugma.
- Hello, Clodia.
- Randus is, of course, enjoying
the favors of Caesar.
- Stop. What is your name?
- Saida.
Here. Pay the merchant and keep
the change. I'll buy this girl.
- You've nothing more to fear.
- And you won't have to
unsheathe your sword to defend her.
- Come on. Let's get on board.
- You, follow us.
- Lumone, who are they?
Vetius is a patrician who exploits
the fortunes of his sister
at the court of Crassus.
He is the best javelin thrower
that I know.
Once, in Gaul,
he broke the head of an Eburone
from a shore of the Seine to another.
It will be an interesting trip.
Magnificent hit! Civil life
didn't make your muscles rusty.
On the contrary, it allows me
to practice every day.
- You want to try?
- No.
A centurion cannot risk
his reputation.
And yours, in the eyes of Caesar,
must be very great,
both as a soldier
as well as a diplomat,
since he is sending you
on a mission to Crassus.
- Maybe.
- He will ruin my ship.
Patience. Crassus will buy you
a new one.
Give me something to drink.
In Zeugma you'll find slaves
that are prettier than this one.
But maybe you, as your general,
only want Egyptian women.
They say that Caesar is attracted
to Queen Cleopatra's fascination.
No woman can compete
with a patrician Roman woman,
not even Cleopatra.
- Will you stay in Zeugma long?
No. I will pay homage to the consul
and give him news of the general.
Crassus will be happy to receive them.
When Caesar took command
of the legions,
he would've wanted to be with him
as during the good times.
If the gold of Crassus
and the iron of Caesar
were united, they would
be two invincible forces.
But with gold we buy
the iron of the swords
and Caesar is too shrewd
to forget that.
Everything has a price,
even your javelins.
- What do you mean?
- What I said.
- I didn't want to offend you.
- Forget it. Vetius understood.
It's best to be on the side of
the strongest. It's more useful.
The wisdom of Minerva
from the lips of Venus.
How long will the journey last?
If we don't run into fog, we'll
be at the port tomorrow at dawn.
That is, if the mainmast
doesn't break.
Darn! They went inside the wood
by a span.
It will take the strength
of Hercules to pull them out.
Gods of the Olympus, help me
pull out these spears
without ruining the mast
- Let's not disturb the gods.
Beroz, your sword.
Magnificent, Randus!
Let's throw them in the sea.
- What is happening?
- The old man is dead.
He rebelled when we took him away.
- He's still alive!
- Not for long. It's a mortal wound.
- I detest the sight of blood.
- Go! Go!
Hurry. Toss them in the sea
and clean the deck immediately.
Hurry, go on! Down!
Your tunic is soiled with blood.
How horrible!
Depth, 3 arms.
Rocky bottom.
Nothing in sight!
Depth, 4 arms.
- Do you see anything on that side?
- Nothing.
Keep your eyes well open.
Depth, 6 arms.
How foggy! I've been navigating for
20 years and never saw such fog.
Styx, where the dead are ferried,
can't be worse.
Don't you feel
like you're in your country, Beroz?
The fog of my forests is different.
I don't like this one.
I don't either.
Zeugma's coast is full of rocks.
We could end up in water
without realizing it.
Be careful. I must return to Rome
but not riding on a shark.
It's better than that nag of yours.
Depth, 6 arms.
The current is increasing.
I saw you at the camp
on the plain of the pyramids.
I am beginning to think
you don't have a voice.
I only heard you speak once.
At the port, remember?
When you said your name.
How does the noble Clodia treat you?
As a Roman woman treats a slave.
- As a slave.
- Not all Roman women are like her.
There are better ones
and worse ones.
You could've had a worse one.
Believe me.
Nothing matters anymore.
My home was destroyed
by your soldiers.
My father, my mother...
Their throats were slit like lambs.
They were only guilty of defending
the land where they were born.
You would never ask an object,
a lifeless thing,
if it is happy or not. So why
do you ask me how I am treated?
I am a soldier, not a torturer.
Anyway, I cannot change
the state of things.
There are masters and servants,
just as pretty and ugly women,
wise and stupid men.
The master finds this to be right,
not the slave.
Depth, less than 3 arms.
Visibility, almost none, Captain.
There, Captain!
We're about to collide!
Help!
Help me.
Look! The ship is moving away!
Saida...
Thanks to the gods, we are safe.
- You risked your life to save me.
- I had to. Can you walk?
- Yes.
- Let's leave, or it will be too hot.
Come on.
- What has happened to the others?
- When the fog cleared,
maybe they found safety.
How will we cross
the desert without food or water?
If we are fortunate,
we will encounter a caravan.
Come.
Look up there!
Come on! Keep moving!
Walk!
They are Lycian warriors, the most
ruthless predators of the desert.
Even Lycia is subject to Crassus.
Don't be afraid.
Go get them!
- Enchain him!
- Let me go!
Let me go, filthy savages!
Have them free me or you'll pay with
your head. I'm a Roman centurion.
- I am going on a mission to Crassus.
- Be quiet, you beast!
As big as you are, you could
be worth 8 gold pieces
and live a few years
dragging your chains.
But be careful.
One word from Murdock.
and you'll be ripped apart like
a carcass in the desert sand.
And this, in the name of Crassus.
Tie him! Put him with the others!
- Go on!
- Idiot. You want us all killed?
Get moving!
Whip them if they don't move!
Walk!
Go on!
Go on! Move!
Have them drink,
and then keep walking!
Water! Water!
Me!
Let go!
Save your breath
and learn the first rule.
If the whip of the Lycians scars
your skin, Gular can take it away.
Gular, we must not fight
among ourselves.
He has our same destiny.
- Stop! Split up!
- Scums!
Go!
To your places, animals,
or I'll kill you!
What is that?
Where you'll will end up,
this will be useless to you.
But it will give me at least
6 mugs of cider
that I'll drink one after the other
to the health of Caesar's ambassador.
Move!
They've rested enough!
- Have them get going! Go on!
- Go on! Keep walking!
Forgive me, foreigner.
Please forgive this madman, Gular.
I had lost my head.
Gular was a great gladiator. He hates
everyone, sees enemies everywhere.
From now on, I will obey you,
because I know who you are.
That amulet revealed it to me.
I saw it on a newborn boy.
His mother was Varinia
and was the wife of Spartacus.
The baby almost suffocated
under the weight of that slab.
I am a Roman, not a slave.
- Yet that is so.
- Shut up, wretches!
Come on, Baxus.
A bit longer, and we'll be free.
Why do you want to go to Zeugma?
Beyond the rocks, in the Lubar ruins,
the City of the Sun roads open,
and others are waiting for you.
I will lead you
to your father's tomb.
What are you saying?
You must be mad.
Don't pretend. I know your name.
I've been waiting 20 years to
shout it on the day of the struggle.
You will carry out what your father
began, as was promised, Randus.
Ssshh! Someone is coming.
- Where is the girl?
- She is here.
- Let her go!
- Let me go!
- My little dove!
Let me go!
Don't move.
If the gods assist us,
no one will whip your skin again.
I told you I was a Roman centurion,
and I will show you!
Come, friends!
The man who came from the sea
liberated us! He is our leader!
This is your amulet.
Food and water for everyone
and get ready to march!
Beyond Lubar, is the City of the Sun,
where there's freedom!
Don't reason as a madman. If you know
the road to Zeugma, indicate it.
Finally! I see that you managed
to fight even in the desert.
Neptune spared your life, and spared
my boredom in weeping over you.
- I thought you were dead.
- Nobody will see Gular in chains now.
Your people are waiting for you.
Listen to the voice of your blood.
You were fortunate not to find
sharks and moray eels.
When they find meat,
they only leave the skeleton.
So you had to use your sword
to conquer your freedom again.
The name of Caesar, noble Crassus,
wasn't enough for your warriors.
My Lycians don't differentiate,
but they are faithful auxiliaries.
I am sorry for what happened.
But the name of Caesar
opens every door
in Zeugma and wherever
my power reaches.
Saving yourself so fortunately
from the waves
to then suffer the whip and chains
like a slave
must have been
a very exciting experience.
Not as much as that
of Zarok's men.
You see? One Roman was enough
to wipe away
your best warriors.
You looked like
the god of war, Randus.
It's a matter of killing
or being killed.
You are right.
Killing to avoid being killed
is the elementary law
of war and of politics.
But who held the weapons
and was involved
in that unfortunate incident
must not live.
That group of slaves
must be put to death.
Zarok will personally deal with it.
They won't see tomorrow's dawn.
But not Saida. She is my slave.
I paid for her,
and do not want to give her up,
since, thanks to Randus,
she was saved.
I will spare her, but not the others.
They participated in a rebellion.
They witnessed an act
that offended my prestige
and my authority.
- You do this because they helped me?
- Yes, they helped the rebel,
not the Roman.
- Please, enough
of this melancholy reasoning,
and let's take care of the guest.
Crassus' renowned magnificence
must shine in his palace.
Clodia is right. We will make
your stay in Zeugma pleasant.
We'll also talk about the new
situation Caesar created in Egypt.
We are neighboring, as were
our villas on the Tiber.
Lumone, I entrust the guest to you.
You know the palace's customs.
- Let's go, Clodia.
- Come, Randus.
What are you waiting for, Zarok?
Carry out Crassus' order.
You know the legend of King Midas?
Crassus overtakes him.
He can't transform into gold
all that he touches
but knows how to squeeze it
wherever it is, without any qualms.
He sells as slaves
the inhabitants of whole villages.
Not even Caesar imagines how
powerful and dangerous Crassus is.
I saw a lot of gold
brought within these walls.
- What else did you see?
- Fortifications along the river,
blacksmiths making ballistae.
Who does he want to attack?
He tripled the number of guards and
all the princes are subject to him.
He sends armies and gold to Pharnaces,
fills coffers with precious stones.
- What does he give Rome's treasury?
- Nothing.
Crassus is the law and force here,
and has secret ambitions.
We'll try to find out more
by asking the servants.
No, they won't talk. They know
that betrayal would cost their lives.
You must be very careful.
One false move, and you are lost.
It doesn't take much here to end up
on the cross, water up to your neck.
When the tide comes,
they'll all drown as mice.
Their cries will sound out
in the entire palace. It's horrible.
Either Crassus is a heavy sleeper,
or he likes that concert.
When I was in the desert,
I heard about a strange place.
- The City of the Sun.
- Fantasies.
All the slaves talk about a city
where those who escaped the chains
find shelter,
but I am sure that it doesn't exist.
We must verify that. If it exists,
its inhabitants could help us.
To serve Caesar
any means could be useful.
It must be here. Among these
ruins there is the City of the Sun.
What is the use of all this, master?
To find out the truth.
Here. What is written, comes true.
The sword of Spartacus
is in the hands of his son.
I, Gular the gladiator,
was at Spartacus' side
in battle for 9 moons.
You all know me, and know
that I have never deceived you.
Whoever has seen death close up,
as I did, doesn't lie.
I am the only one, among over 6,000
who saved myself from the cross.
The great Spartacus,
who rests under the black stone,
placed this sign
around Randus' neck.
He was born from Varinia
before the last clash.
You are the man we were waiting for,
the leader of the slaves,
our hope, our revenge.
- Are you sure of what you're saying?
- I have no doubts.
You can do anything.
You have our lives in your hands.
You can sell us to Crassus, he who
crucified your father, or lead us.
The choice is yours.
Listen to your blood and decide.
You can deny the truth
and destroy our last hope,
but just say one word, freedom,
and to the sound of that word,
even the dead will rise.
Leave me alone.
Murderer.
You are a murderer, Crassus.
One day you will pay
for all your crimes.
We too, one day will be revenged!
Listen to how they shout.
They're like skinned pigs.
- Scums!
- Murderers!
Scums!
To arms! Hurry, run!
- Help!
- Out!
- Damn them!
- Help!
- Help us!
Murderers! Now it is your turn!
Hurry. Untie me and I'll help you.
I know who you are.
You are the son of Spartacus!
Tie them to the poles!
Now it's your turn, coward!
It's how you'll all end up!
Hurry! Beyond the river!
Find safety in the City of the Sun!
There's no time to lose! Go!
- Hurry, let's go!
- Help!
Help!
What is happening here? Guards!
- Clodia, what are you doing here?
- Give the alarm!
Round up the guards!
They are obliging me
to leave my rooms.
- Vetius, what is happening?
- I'll go see.
The shouts came from
the slave area.
- Where are the palace guards?
- What is going on?
They activated the dam, liberated the
prisoners and killed the guards.
Another two of my men
died on the poles.
Look. They left this mark
on the door!
Work, slave!
- Here he is!
- That's enough! Let's retreat!
- Go! Let's retreat!
- This way!
Spartacus has struck again.
Soon we will be free.
The province is in an uproar.
The people are resisting.
They don't want to pay taxes.
There were some dead, and
Crassus decided to be more severe.
Nothing serious, I hope.
It would be annoying if we should
talk about war again.
There is no war in the Olympus.
No one can threaten your peace.
Everyone come to the ground!
Hurry!
We exterminated them! Victory!
For over a month that cursed man
has been stirring up the population.
Crassus is worried about it.
Caesar could take advantage
to come here with his legions.
- You don't want that, either.
- What does that mean?
Caesar's coming would damage you.
You are Crassus' right hand man.
- You'll inherit the province.
- Is it a sin to be ambitious?
Who isn't, after all?
In serving Crassus,
I serve the Republic.
And if they should give me a tribune
toga, I'd know how to behave.
But you...
For however glorious he may be,
Caesar is a mortal being.
You could begin
thinking about yourself.
Yes.
If you want, my sister can
intercede for you. She likes you.
Crassus isn't eternal either. One day
we could divide our assignments.
I, the government,
and you, commander of the army.
It's the same old story
of iron and gold.
But it is not a bad idea.
I'll think about it.
- Of course I will think about it.
- Good.
This must be the area.
Let's form a second column.
- You want to take command?
- No. I will stay here with you.
I'm not familiar with the desert,
and the Lycians and I don't get along.
Right, Zarok?
You'll come with me. Your experience
will serve to capture the rebel.
Take half the men
and search the rocky area.
- We will meet at the oasis of Abal.
- I'm going.
Move forward! To the right!
Here. This is the place
where that cursed man appears.
- Are you sure?
- Yes. The information was exact.
Up there! Look!
It's him! Damn him!
We must capture him, dead or alive!
- I'll block him from behind.
- Alright.
Forward! Gallop!
Very good, Beroz!
Move forward!
There he is down there.
- He can't escape us. Come!
- Gallop!
Forward! He's ours!
They are trapped.
Damn it!
We've fallen into a trap!
Push!
To the ground!
Find shelter under the rocks!
Go on! Get off your horses!
Find shelter! Spread out!
To the ground!
Form a circle with the horses!
- Randus! We defeated them!
- Now disappear.
- They must find no one.
- Behind the rocks! Let's spread out!
Behind the rocks!
Hurry, master.
Vetius is waiting for you.
Come join us soon,
son of Spartacus. We are waiting!
Go! Spread out!
By all the gods, what happened?
That bastard tricked us again.
An avalanche of rocks fell
and crushed men and horses.
A massacre.
The mysterious gladiator was all
around. Impossible to capture him.
Impossible doesn't exist.
Just a few slaves don't frighten me.
I have tamed much more.
The rebellion in the Laurius mines,
the revolt in Spain, the rebels of
Spartacus, all under the cross!
Erased from the face of the Earth!
Are you sure, Crassus?
Are you sure the man you defeated
20 years ago isn't here again?
- You know who I mean. Spartacus.
- You are delirious!
Spartacus died on the cross!
- His body was never found.
- The crows ate him.
I saw some soldiers fall.
On their bodies they had
a mark like this one.
They say it's the mark of Spartacus.
Absurd! It's absurd!
This rebellion must be tamed, at the
cost of a province full of crosses.
And peace will return to Asia.
You have Crassus' word!
- You will help me, Randus.
- There is no glory
in fighting slaves,
but it is not up to me to judge.
I will serve you
for the glory of Rome.
For the glory of Rome,
many things are done.
Also destroying the Triumvirate,
as Caesar did.
Or destroying the Republic,
as he is trying to do!
If you serve me with loyalty,
you'll have no complaints.
They say I am a Croesus.
I am the richest man in Rome.
I can be generous
with who is faithful to me,
and ruthless with who is my enemy.
Have the prisoner enter.
The moray eels are hungry. They can
satisfy their hunger in abundance.
He's from Oboz. In his home
he had spear tips and Roman arms.
It seems he is in contact
with the rebels.
Your destiny has been marked.
You can save yourself only by
telling me where your companions
and your leader is.
Speak! Who is your leader?
Where is he hiding?
Answer! Speak, you scum!
Speak!
The son of Spartacus is everywhere.
His mark will lead us to victory
and you, to death!
- Murderer!
- Toss him to the moray eels!
- He dared defy me!
- Murderer!
March to the village of Oboz with
the best men. Raze it to the ground.
Massacre all the inhabitants!
Don't leave one person alive!
Maybe he is right in using
these methods, but they disgust me.
Of course. He's in trouble.
The rebels are digging his grave.
I wouldn't want to be in his place.
Not even with his gold.
Randus, do you really believe
the general will intervene?
Can you imagine it?
Caesar at Crassus' heels.
Stop!
Oboz is down there.
We'll surprise them in their sleep.
No one must remain alive.
Remember that! Go!
It is Baxus's signal.
They are coming. Advise the others.
Yes.
It's Gular. This is it.
Wait for them to reach the center
of the village and then charge.
- Did you blend the mixture well?
- To perfection.
I worked 10 years
in the Egyptian sulphur mines.
Sulphur and Greek tar. The Lycians
will feel the heat on their backs.
- I promise.
- On the ruin of our homes.
You'll rebuild them one day,
even more lovely.
Here they are! They're coming!
Go! Charge! Set fire
and kill, in the name of Crassus!
Kill!
Set fire to the roofs!
- On this side.
- We must catch them by surprise.
The homes are deserted.
They've all run away!
Damn them! Someone warned them.
They have spies at the palace!
Destroy everything!
Not one wall must be left standing.
Have no pity! Go!
When the village is destroyed,
we'll hunt them in the mountains.
Follow me!
Hurry! Let's leave the village.
We'll surround them.
Charge!
It's the two of us now!
Scum!
Being killed by the sword of Spartacus
will be an honor to you.
- And now?
- Leave your homes,
forget the past, reach the oases,
live in the caves,
on the mountains of Lubar,
in the ancient mines,
find refuge in the City of the Sun.
This is what Spartacus tells you
through his son's mouth.
Get ready for the day of payback.
Guards!
He managed to enter in here,
in my room,
in the most sacred place
of the palace.
This is a lair of traitors.
Their leader is here,
and could be anyone.
You, Vetius, or you.
- Or Randus.
- Right, Randus.
Where is he?
Why didn't he rush over too?
The German is guarding his door.
Maybe he's sleeping.
It's impossible.
He must have heard.
It all began with his arrival.
Rebellion, attacks, ambushes.
And that cursed "S" appeared
around since he came.
Then let's wake him,
if it's true that he is sleeping.
Break the door down!
By all the gods,
what is this commotion?
What's happening?
The rebels are in the city?
No. They are among us.
The law of war now goes into effect.
Really?
- Is it that serious?
- You will deprive us of your sword?
You are a consul of Rome,
so order, and you'll be obeyed.
Get out, leave me alone.
I will be very frank, Randus.
Caesar has finished performing
the role of friend with me.
He eliminated all his enemies
and it still isn't enough
for his cursed ambition.
But with Crassus,
the performance is different!
Ten years ago I lent Caesar
25 million sesterces
and I sent him to reap laurel plants
in Spain.
He was chased by creditors
like a hare with scanty fur.
But now I will spend my sesterces
to hurl Pharnaces and his army
on him.
- What do you think?
- Politics is not food for me.
Then you won't die of indigestion.
Tomorrow everyone will see that
Crassus still has so much energy
that he can wipe out his enemies.
It is up to you.
Either with me or against me.
I consider you too intelligent
to do something foolish.
If the hand that smears the walls
of the palace is led by Caesar,
we will soon know.
Crassus promised
an unforgettable performance.
He wants to win over the favor
of his guest, Manas,
King Pharnaces' brother,
and he will. Look. They're coming.
My noble Manas,
your presence honors us.
I hope you will be pleased
with our hospitality.
Hello, Randus. Crassus' celebration
will be a success with your presence.
You denied us your company
these last few days.
I hunted down the rebels.
Remember? I am a soldier.
But I could need your sword
and your presence too.
Nobody can hurt you.
A goddess isn't struck, but adored.
Listen, please. Today Crassus
will kill other innocent people.
You, who are so different
from the others, can save them.
I know they will be killed
in a horrible way.
- Save them, I beg you.
- I don't decide their destiny.
They are rebels. Their leader
is the son of Spartacus, they say.
He must save them.
While I must stop him.
I will show you how I punish
my enemies without shedding blood,
and how I honor my guests.
- Thank you.
I bet 20 denarii that not even you
know what that tent is for.
It must be one of Crassus'
strange inventions.
A very entertaining evening
is being prepared.
I doubt that an idea from Crassus
can be entertaining.
Watch and see.
My noble prince, what you will see
is strictly fruit of my imagination.
If it is equal to the gold
you promised us for our alliance,
it will be extraordinary.
My brother is camped out in
the desert with such a numerous army
that it can exterminate your enemies
or have every broken promise
paid for with death.
- Crassus keeps his word.
- So much the better!
From the desert they say that Caesar
is marching towards Zeugma
and you are threatened
by the rebels
led by the son of Spartacus,
the Thracian that dared defy Rome.
It is the illusion
of a group of desperate men. Wait.
Uncover it.
They will die slowly. Life will
slip away from their bodies.
As soon as the urn will be filled
with vapors, justice will be done.
That way! Hurry!
Up there!
- Vetius!
- Guards! Get him!
Go! Get out! Run away!
Guards!
You'll pay for my death.
My brother's revenge
will drown you all in blood.
Vetius, round up the guards
and barricade the entrance.
The time for revenge
has come, Crassus.
The son of Spartacus will do
justice for his father's murder.
The lever! Hurry, Lumone!
Nobody can deceive Crassus!
Your end has come, slave!
Bravo, Lumone.
Vetius, get him out and kill him.
I want his head at my feet!
Raise the gates!
Finish him off! I want his head!
Pull him up.
Let's see his face.
Randus!
Stop!
This man must tell me
many things before dying.
- Throw him in a cell!
- You won't spare him, I hope.
No. I want to have him curse
the day he was born
before he begs for his death.
Take him away!
News of the capture
of that traitor has spread.
The population is in ferment.
Armed groups are occupying
some villages on the hills.
The garrison isn't sufficient
and the soldiers are afraid.
You should give a demonstration
of force by killing that dog now!
His death will show the rebels
that Crassus is stronger!
Kill him!
What are you waiting for?
Kill him right away, or the slaves
will invade your palace too!
You are an imbecile, Vetius.
If you weren't, you wouldn't
have been my right arm
and my hitman.
You would have long ago
poisoned me with a cup of wine.
Rebel slaves, revolts.
Those aren't the dangers.
Sooner or later Rome crushes.
As I crushed Spartacus 20 years ago.
Spartacus ended up on the cross.
Why not do the same with his son?
- Or is this old age?
- Don't say that.
Thank the gods that I allow you
to sleep in my bed,
instead of a brothel of Suburra.
The hour is close. Caesar advances
towards us in obliged stops.
He only has two legions,
but they are enough for him.
He knows that only Crassus is impeding
him, and wants to wipe him away.
And his system is not wrong.
It has never made mistakes.
Here there is Pharnaces,
greedy for gold and glory,
with an army that is superior
to Caesar's,
and 100 times stronger than ours.
A multitude of Barbarians
led by a madman who,
in his sick mind, thinks
he can defeat the eagles of Rome.
Madness. Caesar would destroy him
in one clash.
But this will not take place.
I will lead that army
enslaved to my gold.
Pharnaces will receive the glory
of having stopped Caesar.
And finally
Crassus will have power over Rome.
For Pharnaces' alliance,
gold is not enough.
We must deliver to him
the man who killed his brother.
He needs blood
to cancel other blood.
His executioners
will take care of the traitor.
I must reach Pharnaces
as soon as possible,
give him the gold and the man,
suggest the tactic
in defeating the legions, and wait.
Then we'll return to Zeugma,
to Alexandria.
To Rome!
Prepare an armed escort.
Have the gold loaded,
and lock up the prisoner in a cage.
We'll leave the city after sunset
and in three days we'll return
with the army that defeated Caesar.
Wait.
That decurion, Lumone...
I've the impression that
he has lived enough.
Randus! Listen to me!
I have little time.
Crassus must not get me.
I couldn't believe my eyes
when I saw that is was you.
I couldn't believe it.
Forgive me, Randus,
but now I know what I should do.
- What?
- Caesar is 50 leagues from here.
I must warn him that Pharnaces' army
is threatening him.
Tell Caesar that I tried to serve him,
by serving also those
who suffer in slavery.
Until slaves exist,
there will be rebels
ready to give their life
for freedom.
If Rome is for crosses,
I am against Rome.
- Tell that to Caesar.
- Caesar is a just man.
- He will be merciful.
- Go, Lumone!
Farewell, Randus.
May the gods help me.
- Where is the Roman? Stop!
- Farewell, Randus!
Where are you going?
To Caesar.
The camp is ready, Crassus.
Go on, hurry.
I want double guards to watch over
my gold and my sleep.
I am tired. I need to rest.
I must be wide awake
tomorrow morning with Pharnaces.
It will be done, Crassus.
You are still alive, but not for long.
Finally you lowered
your false friend mask.
You ended up in a cage
like an animal.
You could have had riches
and power.
Instead, you chose the cross, Randus!
It will be your tribune toga!
We shall go too..
Go. I don't want anything
to happen to you.
Save yourself. You must escape.
I brought your sword.
Hurry, cut here.
Give it to me.
Go on, friends. Shoot!
It's our turn! Charge!
Go on! Hurry! Surround the tent!
You, over there!
Your hour has come!
Baxus! No!
- Mine or yours, master?
- He's mine!
And now let's take care of Crassus.
What do you want to do?
The Egyptians also taught me this.
Gold melts like butter,
but it's harder to digest.
Randus! Save me! Don't kill me!
Don't have me killed.
I am a Roman consul.
It's useless.
You condemned your own self.
The slaves and the oppressed
judged you.
And I, as a Roman soldier,
see an enemy of Rome in you.
You won't buy an army
to fight Caesar.
In exchange for my life,
I promise you freedom!
And gold! You'll have so much gold
you won't be able to count it.
Ask! It's gold!
Gold! It's not enough
to pay for their injuries
and a life of suffering and misery.
- They are yours.
- Randus! Don't have them kill me!
I don't want to die!
Saida, I beg you. Save me!
I have always treated you well.
Please, save me.
She is a woman. Let her live.
You are free, but remember
that you owe your life to a slave.
Lead her to the dunes
and let her go.
Clodia! Clodia, don't leave me!
I don't want to die!
Take me away.
- Grab him!
- Hold him!
You say you're the richest man
in Rome. You'll be even more so.
You accumulated gold by
spilling blood. Now you'll drink it.
Here. Some water and dates.
Give me a knife.
It will be more useful.
What awaits you now, Randus?
Who knows. Maybe a new life,
maybe death.
In revenging my father, I hoped
to help the cause of justice.
- And that isn't so?
- I don't know.
I am a Roman citizen
but now everything is different.
These people elected me as
their leader. I can't abandon them.
We defeated Crassus, but
the fight for freedom will be long.
I am not afraid, and wherever
you'll be, that will be my home.
I am ready to follow you, Randus.
Always.
My freedom, my life...
is you, my love.
Randus! The Roman cavalry
is advancing from behind the hill!
Let's attack them. They'll chop us up,
but at least we'll die as men.
Deliver yourself to Caesar, Randus.
Caesar will judge.
Gular, I am going to Caesar.
Don't move.
I had ordered you to observe
Crassus' movements.
- But not like this.
- I did my duty.
The plot was unveiled. The man
who killed my father is dead.
- Now it's my turn.
- No man, free or a slave,
knows the hour of his death.
If you are who the people shout
about, the son of Spartacus,
you'll understand why Rome
cannot allow you to live.
- I don't ask for anything.
- Nor can you have anything.
The problem with our lives
is not just freedom,
but in the force of things.
I entrusted the region's
government to Verulus.
He is a just man.
If the order will not be disobeyed,
many chains will be broken.
But Nature doesn't admit discounts.
You must die.
You are an example, no longer a man.
Rome must have one, too.
You will die on the cross
like your father,
and the others will see how it's
not possible to rebel against Rome.
You have been a good soldier
and a faithful friend.
Caesar says farewell.
What will happen to the others?
They will live.
Look!
The entire Zeugma population is here
as the voice of the rebel's death.
One cross is not sufficient,
Caesar!
If you kill the son of Spartacus,
you must kill us all!
Don't take away the man
who freed us, or crucify us too.
Even now, just as we did
20 years ago,
we say to you, "I am Spartacus!"
Caesar, listen to their voice!
Rome is the world, and you are Rome!
There isn't enough wood
for so many crosses.
We are in the desert.
Isn't that so, Verulus?
Yes, general, and never assigned
governor of a people who are dead.
Let him be liberated!
- Farewell, Randus, and good luck.
- Farewell, friend.
Now we have really won,
and forever. Come, Randus!
Here is your father's sword.
Farewell, Verulus.
Many times, a word of clemency
can be more useful to Rome
than the use of the sword.
- Farewell, Caesar.
- Let's go!
Forward!
There will always be a hand
ready to grasp it
in defense of freedom
and of human dignity.
And every man who rebels
against repression
will always be able to say,
"I am the son of Spartacus".