Oh!! Ah!! Oh!
Get in the game Louis.
Louis!?
What is it?
I just had a great story idea.
You can't even sleep
without working can you?
You ready?
Yeah, just
finishing up my homework.
Ok, wrap it up.
Come on, lets go.
How does this tie look?
I think you should lose it.
I always where this tie.
Yeah, but it's not
going to go with that suit.
You're trying to
hard to look like Kyle.
Ha. I can feel it
ladies, this is the one.
You always say that.
Well, after today it'll be fact!
Alright, don't forget
Makayla has her play tonight
and you promised to help
her with her short film script.
Ok, ok, got it.
Do your best at the meeting,
it will be nice to have you back
on the weekends.
Come here, love you. Good luck.
Ready?
Okay.Yeah.
Love you daddy!
Love you too.
Louis!
Get in the game.
Yeah...yeah, sorry.
Take that tie off!
What? Why?
Because I'm wearing a
tie, you don't need too.
This is my favorite tie.
It might
intimidate him...take it off!
Yours won't?
I'm required to wear a tie.
You should look more disheveled.
I've always worn
this tie in a meet -
Harold will be with
you in just moment.
Thank you...
not in this one.
Harold!
Jeff.
Kyle...
Ah.
Harold this is my client Louis.
-Louis.
-Ah, pleasure to meet you Harold.
You boys want anything to drink?
We're good, thank you.
Ice green tea, no sweetener.
Harold, I just
want to say thank you
for having us here today.
Louis and I are both very excited
that you are interested in his script--
I'm not.
Let me handle this.
Harold, you seem to have caught
us a little bit off guard here,
if um, if you are not
interested in the script then...
We're looking for
out of the box stories,
but within the box of
the mainstream audiences
right that's disaster
pictures, espionage thrillers,
superhero pictures,
astronaut pictures.
Your script doesn't
fit those categories.
So...
So, do you have
any scripts that do?
Your writing's got heart.
I'm sure you've got a
script up your sleeve
that's more mainstream.
Yes!Well not at the moment -
Let me handle this.
Uh, yes Harold, I do.
Actually, I have
an astronaut film.
Great. Send it over Kyle.
I'll have my interns
read it this weekend.
Oh, well Harold,
it's not quite finished yet...
We'll have it to you Monday.
Louis just has to put
the final touches on it.
Great. I'll see you then.
Ah, thank you.
I said no sweetener.
What the hell was that!?
That..that was me saving
us, that's what that was!
Louis, you don't
have a space script!
Then why did you say we
would have one by Monday!?
Because I want to make a deal.
Ok. And it's either his
way or no way. Alright!?
Harold has zero patience. None!
So it's either you play ball or
he kicks you out of the game!
See this is why you
need to let me handle
these situations - you don't
get these exec types...
I get them well enough Kyle!
Ok, alright, you know what?
You're right, you're older more
experienced, have gone to what?
Twelve failed meetings?
Sure, you got this buddy.
Good luck with the
script, see ya at the movies!
Kyle? Kyle! Wait, Kyle!
I got anxious ok? I'm sorry.
It's just...it's just earlier, I
had this idea about an astronaut
who crash lands onto earth -
Louis ok right!
I'll get you a deal.
If you can get this script
to me, written, by Monday.
And Harold goes for it,
some reason goes for it.
I'll keep you as my client.
But if he doesn't, you
can't get your shit together,
I'm going to drop you.
Kyle! Who are we kidding?
I'm your only client.
I have five now, thank you.
I can cut my
losses where I need it.
And I think an unsold,
stubborn writer who bounces from
agent to agent, counts as that.
Hope you don't have
any plans this weekend.
-Hey dad.
-Hey.
Guess what?
I'm almost done with my script.
Ugh, I wish I
could say the same.
Mom home?
No, not yet.
Ok, well when she
gets here tell her
I'll be in the office
working all weekend.
Dad?
What?
Did you seriously forget?
Forget what?
You know what, I don't have
time for these little games,
Daddy's got work to do.
Hey, how was school?
Good.
Good. Dad home?
Yes ma'am, he forgot again.
Did he really?
Mmhmm.
Ok, I'll talk to him.
How's your short
film script coming?
It's good. I'm almost finished.
I was hoping dad
and I could read it, but
I don't think
he's going to have the time.
Louis?
Hey.
You can't work
again this weekend.
Honey, I have to. The
RLO exec likes my writing,
but, they want something
a little more mainstream.
That's great honey but,
Makayla has a play tonight
and a soccer game tomorrow,
and she's trying to get
her short film script -
Oh...is that what I forgot?
Yes!
Alyssa...I can't, ok.
I have to have this
script done by Monday
or else I'll lose my
chance and Kyle.
You can barely stand Kyle.
But he's the
only option I've got.
Well, can you take a break and
try to make it out to both events?
I don't know, I mean,
I could always catch
another soccer game?
You haven't been
to one this season.
That's not fair, come on.
You know I have
been working alright,
I am on the crux of this.
Everything I've been dreaming about,
everything I've been
working on lies in this script.
Well can you ask for
a couple more days?
Makayla needs
you this weekend.
Ok. Umm...
Ill take a break, alright,
I'll come out to the play,
but that's the best I can do.
What about her short film?
I can't help her with
that, she needs you Louis.
I'll make something happen, ok.
I love you, alright?
-Wait, you know Monday is--
-Two days from now, yeah.
No, its-- -Alyssa, please?
I have to get this done.
Oh, oh, oh!
Control,
control?
Control, this is 5099,
pilot of solo mission Origin.
Upon entrance on Earth's
atmosphere my ship suffered
fractures causing a malfunction
and a crash landing into an
undetermined body of water.
I by some miracle
survived and have
a enough supplement
to sustain me for a week.
All other supplies
were lost with the ship.
If anyone is hearing
this, please send rescue.
I have decided that I will
continue on with my mission.
I will forge into
the intercontinent
to study
the topography,
the ecosystem, and
the atmospheric conditions to
see if this planet really
is worthy of re...re-
inhabiting.
Turning on my homing beacon
now...hoping it still works.
Ah,
please hurry.
5099 over and out.
Ehhh...a little wordy.
Well, we'll see about that!
Louis...
Louis!
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry. Time got
away from me, I forgot.
Forget has been a
popular word with you lately.
Alyssa...
this might be my last chance.
You're a good writer.
But nothing is selling! Nothing!
Half the time you
didn't have an agent.
Half the time I did...and
what do I have to show for it?
I can feel
this one, you know,
this one is different,
this one is unique.
You say that about all of them,
you just said that last weekend
about the one you just pitched.
Alright no, you're right.
I'll just throw in the towel,
I'll just be a stay at home dad,
you be the career woman.
That sounds great.
You know that's
not what I'm saying.
What are you
saying then Alyssa!?
Oh, I'm sorry I
must have forgot.
What I'm saying is that Makayla
needs you to be present in her life.
I am in her life!
Can you remember the last time
you were at any event she
was involved in?
Neither can we.
I'm not asking you to
give up your career,
I'm asking you to every once in
a while, put us in front of it.
Makayla especially,
she's growing up,
she's talking to boys,
she wants to be a filmmaker.
Alyssa...
if you can just give
me this weekend,
I promise you, I will do better,
I will be the filmmaker she
deserves to look up to.
Sure whatever you say Louis.
You're definitely
a man of your word.
Where do you
think you are going?
You'll thank me later.
Makayla!
Why'd you marry him again?
Yeah! Yeah, send me, no?
No one else wants to go.
Please! Send me
captain! Yeah, I know
there's nothing there, but
still! Let me go, because,
I'm a genius and you guys are --
Idiots, and I'm the
genius, I'm the genius!
Control, this is 5099
pilot of solo mission Origin,
I don't know if you
received the memo
but I am stranded here on Earth,
please send rescue, over.
Control, this is 5099
pilot of solo mission Origin,
I'm getting a
little chaffed here...
some ointment would be
greatly appreciated, over.
Roger that 5099, we
received your transmission
and will be sending spa
treatment right away over?
You will!?
I'm saved! I'm
saved! Oh! Aw! Oh.
I am gonna make it,
I gotta make it.
You hear that control.
I'm going to make it to
that ridge, by nightfall,
and then, I'm
probably going to die.
Um, Excuse me sir,
Uhh we're closing up now.
Oh, man, I'm sorry.
Come on, don't stop.
Don't stop.
What happens next, what happens
next., what happens next.
Oh oh oh ahhh!
Hello?
Hey champ how's it going?
Oh, it's going, I'm
on page twenty six.
Woah! Now
we're cooking with gas!
Grff, yeah, I um,
I don't know man,
I just don't know what
happens next, I'm kinda stuck.
Woah, woah, woah. Louis, Louis
you don't have time
to be stuck, clock is ticking.
Did you call just
to harass me, Kyle?
Hey man, I just wanted to
see how you were doing.
Glad to hear
you're staying focused.
Talk to you soon.LOUIS:
Wait, before you go...
what time?
Hello?
Anybody home?
Uhh, Thank God.
There was not enough time.
...they weren't even trying
Hey!
I know that's when...
How was the game!? Did you win?
Makayla?
Hey. Did they win or lose?
Alyssa?
Ok, I see what's
happening, the silent treatment?
Ok, you want to play
the silent treatment, I can too.
Bottoms up.
Control, this is 5099,
pilot of solo mission Origin.
After several days of walking
through an undetermined
continent of earth I have found
the atmosphere rather dense,
oxygen levels high,
sustainable organic growth.
I am halting my expedition
due to lack of food supplies.
I will set up a
primitive base camp here at the
coordinates in which I hope
you are receiving this message.
I see a clearing in
which a ship can properly land.
Be wary of steep entry,
the atmosphere is much denser
than expected, the shields will not hold.
Ahh, I guess that's it.
Thank you control.
Oh, one other thing.
Oompf....
Ahhhhh...hmmm.
Ahhh... Huh. Ahh.
Hey..ok, hey look,
I'm unarmed alright.
Can you, can you
understand me?
Ok. Alright. I'm... I'm just
going to sit down right here.
Oh!
Wow!
Dinner looks great.
Mmmm...what did you get on it?
B minus
It's ok, I know it was hard.
Yeah...
Mmmm...May I join you?
Aren't we being a little cruel?
You don't have to join me, I
just can't talk to him right now
Come on, finish your dinner.
So...
are there more, people,
like you, around here?
Do you have names?
My name is 5099.
I come from up there.
Yeah, alright
at least I'm getting
some vital signs.
Uhh, I come
from a place called Mars.
There are millions and millions
of people like you and I there.
Well, We all come from here, but
thousands of years ago Earth
was overpopulated and diseased,
and world wide wars
broke out.
And the earth was destroyed.
But my, your ancestors
found a new home for us.
The fact that you are
here is an absolute miracle.
Great.
You make the greatest
discovery of the century
and they are simpletons that
understand absolutely nothing.
Control, this is 5099
pilot of solo mission Origin,
I have found life on Earth!
Repeat, I have found two human
specimens both female on earth.
No signs as of yet
of any male counterparts
or other inhabitants.
Please hurry.
I will continue to study
them in the meantime.
5099 over and out.
Rise and shine.
Hey, how are--
wait no no no!
I thought we
were friends now, hmm?
Now that's how you go fishing.
Haha...oh, yeah,
too soon, I felt that.
Thanks Mom.
Dad did this.
Haha, good one.
No, really, I didn't do this.
Really?
So...
do either of you have a name?
Didn't think so.
Just checking...again.
Thought you two would open
up a little bit more by now.
Well... I think you two deserve
the honor of having names...
What do you think?
I'll take that as a
yes. Okay, you...
your name will be,
I don't know. How about Ava?
Yeah, Ava that's an old
fashion earth name right?
Ok, Ava it is.
And you little one,
since you are so small.
Haha, how about
we call you Minnie?
Minnie, Minnie, Minnie, Minnie.
Oh my God,
you both can
understand me can't you?
Come in.
Hey.
Talking now huh?
Making breakfast now huh?
Yeah, I cooked the
eggs a little too long?
Yeah. It's alright though.
How's it going?
Not too bad,
I've got about 40 pages,
I need to have
about 30 by 9am tomorrow.
Ouch.
Yeah.
Well I'll leave you to it.
Hey Makayla,
I'm sorry about all this.
Once I'm finished
with this I promise you
I will focus more
on you and mom, ok.
Hey! I got an idea, how
about I read you my script
like I used to, remember?
Nah, hey, how
about you help me with
my short film on Tuesday?
Short film?
You're making a
short film on Tuesday?
Dad! I told you two weeks ago.
I know. Look, I promise you
I'll help you out and I
will read the
script beforehand ok.
Whatever dad.
Oh, I'll whatever you!
Control, this 5099
pilot of solo mission origin,
after spending
several weeks studying
and interacting
closely with Ava and Minnie,
I have found that
they are naturally intelligent,
although our lack of ability
to communicate is immense,
they seem to understand me,
and I am beginning
to understand them.
I will push to continue
to find out where their male
counterparts are and
if they know or know of
any humans in the region.
5099 over and out.
Ok,
here's me,
here's you,
here's Minni.
Where are these people.
Oh, Ok, lovely, very nice,
Ava thank you, so much,
listen to me though, Ava...
where are these people? Hmm?
Three?
A third? Where are they?
Can you take me to them?
Owww!
Is that your husband?
Ava, I'm sorry.
Are there any others?
Besides these three?
Makayla, let's go!?"
Hold on!
Hey where you guys-
Hello?
Hey playa! How's it going?
It's going.
Yeah, you finished yet?
Uh, 47.
Yes!
Yeah, not too bad.
it could be worse.
No! Not you!
47 that's it?
Harold called this
morning, just checking in.
Yeah?
Yeah, so,
are you going to finish?
I don't know
man, I'm pretty beat
and I haven't spent any time
with my family this weekend.
Family!?
Louis, your career is at stake
and you are
worried about your family?
Ugh, you
wouldn't understand?
Oh no, no, no, I
completely understand.
So you're going
to commit to a project
that might as well
just be your career
and then flake out
because you love your family?
Wow, way to
provide to for them Louis.
You listen
here you little prick,
everyday I am
working my ass off
following these wild
goose chase lead you have me on,
what makes this any different!?
Because you took
the lead on this one pal!
Kyle!? Kyle!?
Serves up bad boy! Ah!
Control?
I don't think they
are coming for me Ava.
It's my fault,
it was my idea.
While other
missions were going off
to other possible
inhabitable planets
I chose the one we destroyed.
No one else
thought it was fertile,
I was the only fool who did
and they sent
me on my merry way.
But clearly, even
in the worst of times it was
fertile, or else
you wouldn't be here.
What am I
complaining about.
Louis?
Hey.
What are you doing?
Watching the fire.
Inspiration?
Yeah, I guess.
I'm almost finished.
Good.
Do you know what it's called?
Mmmhmm.
The Man From Outer Space.
Do you know how it ends?
I think so.
I just don't know what the main
character is going to decide.
You will,
goodnight.
Goodnight.
I lov-
Ahhhhh!
Ava! Wait!
It's alright...
Captain? 307?
Who are these people?
You were on a solo mission?
I can't believe you are here!?
5099, get ahold of yourself.
Ava, no no no no.
Ava, Ava, no it's ok.
These, these are
the indigenous people
I was telling you
about in my transmissions.
What transmissions?
We've received nothing
since your last distress call.
Your com gauntlet was
damaged in the crash.
I guess, but
how did you find me?
Beacon, placed under your skin.
Standard procedure
for situations like this.
You lit up as soon as
we hit the atmosphere.
Well thank God you're here.
You have to believe me
they are not going to hurt you,
ok these are my colleagues.
They're here to help us.
You don't know how good
it feels to see you both.
How long have
you been with them?
What?
How long have you
been with the indigenous?
Ava and Minnie,
about fifteen weeks now.
You've named them?
Well they don't
have any language,
I had to refer to
them by something.
I don't know what
you were thinking.
From now on they will be
called Female 1 and Female 2.
They are not your family.
They are a scientific discovery
and need to be studied properly,
not fraternized with.
I...I was studying them,
but I didn't have the supplies
to study them from afar.
Go back to the ship,
get yourself cleaned up.
We have food supplements
and medical supplies onboard.
We'll watch
female one and female two.
After you are ready, you
will escort us and the females
back to whatever
habitat they have occupied.
This is the greatest
scientific find of the century.
I thought for
sure he was lying.
So, what's your plan?
Go back to the habitat.
Assess. Decide
who to take with us.
How do I look?
Tired.
The suit.
Good. No tie?
Did you finish?
No.
Well what do you
think's going to happen?
I don't know. I'm hoping
they are going to like it
and give me few a
days to work on it.
Shouldn't you be
getting ready for work?
No.
Taking a sick day?
Why aren't you getting ready?
I tried to tell you
Friday, it's Labor Day.
Why didn't you tell me?
I tried to tell you but
you wouldn't listen.
I know I was distracted,
but you could have tried
a little harder!
Don't you dare shout at me!
Yasss.
That's good.
Speak.
It's labor day.
Yeah, so.
So we're not having a meeting
with Harold today are we?
Of course not, Harold is
on his way back from Bermuda.
Louis?
I have slept, maybe...
maybe six hours since Friday,
all because you said
that I had to have a feature
film script done by today.
Oh, ok, I'm pretty
sure Harold said that
and you agreed to it.
I would think that as my agent
maybe you would
help me to understand
that he actually meant Tuesday!
Listen, you were the one that
took control on this remember.
If you would have just
let me handle this, it would
have been different.
Get me the script by today,
I'll get it to Harold,
we'll go from there.
This is your career
Louis, don't get sidetracked.
Oh, harder baby, harder,
yah that's it...money.
I don't have time for this!
Jerk.
You're gonna let me say that?
Now from what I have noticed,
they are a nomadic
people, although they stay
contained in one area for
several days at a time,
they are very intelligent,
although they don't have any language of
their own, they seem to understand fine.
Have you tried
any other languages?
A few, yes, but they
don't seem to understand any.
They mostly communicate
through eye movement, hand
gestures, occasional grunts.
No males?
Males are dead.
Have you studied the
ecology of this place?
How did you know
the males were deceased?
It's obvious,
if there was a
male specimen here
they would have killed
you instead of taking you in.
What's their diet?
Uh, nuts, fruit, primarily,
occasional animal meat.
Ah, 307?
It will be nightfall
soon will it not?
Yes, why?
We have to leave before then.
Oh?
5099, control sent us
on a rescue mission.
They gave us supplies but not
enough for a few days here,
the trip back is-
Twelve weeks, I know.
We only have room for
one other passenger.
Ok, Well we could leave a
communications device here
so they can hear my voice.
We could set
up the com right here,
we could setup a
wind turbine right... here.
Female two.
I'm sorry what was that?
We're not taking you.
I'm sorry?
We're taking female two.
Minnie?
No, no. You can't do that.
What about her mother?
You will stay
here with the mother.
We'll set up a com
station, return in a few months.
Leave.
Leave the supplies for
the third passenger with me,
I can distribute them
appropriately that way I can
stay here and study them in
their natural habitat.
This is the greatest
discovery in decades,
Earth is inhabitable.
We have to take one back to
study it, can't you see that?
I understand that, but you
cannot break this family apart.
You mean their family?
Yes, their family.
This is not our choice,
this decison comes
straight from control.
5099, this
is your career at stake.
You will be known as
the man, the explorer,
who re-discovered
earth, our homeland.
Nobody believed you,
do you want to let that opportunity
slip through your fingers?
Ok,
ok, lets do it.
Can I talk to them first?
Ava,
darling you and Minnie mean
so much to mankind and I know
you can't understand
this yet, but your existence
is what will allow the
prosperity of our race.
We have to study,
ok, and we won't be able to do
that here
for another several months, so,
in order to make their,
our work faster,
we have to take her.
They need to take Minnie.
Wait, no!
Huh.
Don't touch them.
This not how you do this!
Stand down 5099.
I will not stand down!
This is not your call, Major!
I suggest that if you
want to be remembered
as the man
who rediscovered Earth
you step aside and let us
do what we came here for.
Came here for?
You said this was
a rescue mission.
You sly devils,
you got all my
transmissions didn't you?
Your job is to stand down!
Liars!
I finished it, I finished it!
I finished it!
It doesn't
have to be this way.
Then do something about it.
I sent the script to Kyle,
meeting is tomorrow, 1pm.
Makayla's shoot starts at 4PM.
I know, I know, I'll be there.
She's counting on you.
Ava! Ava! Stop.
Ava, Stop, Ava listen.
I'm sorry it was my job ok!
I shouldn't have done it,
but I had to.
Ava, Ava I'll leave okay,
but I can't promise you that they
are going to bring her back to you!
Where's that
stick you hit me with?
How was your weekend?
Was Good, was very good.
Quite relaxing actually.
How was Bermuda?
Your script Louis.
Very original.
Thank you.
So my interns tell me.
Unfortunately, it's not
quite what I had in mind.
This is a family film,
that's not something we do here.
Would you consider
developing it with us further?
Get it to where you
would like it to be.
I'm confident this can be
more than just a family picture.
I have the afternoon free.
Convince me.
You look concerned Louis.
I'm telling you we
should have gone west.
The ship is half
mile east of the camp.
We would have been there in
30 minutes if that were the case.
Calm down.
Here, take her
I'll figure this out.
Have you
lost your nerve sergeant?
Don't talk to me like
that, put the girl down.
Get out the beacon.
We should have
taken 5099 with us,
he would
have brought us back.
I'm not the one that hit him.
5099?
It's nothing.
Get on with it.
Neutralize.
Oh...
Think they got
that transmission?
What'd you say champ,
you ready to make this happen?
Louis, you gone
deaf, or you just excited?
He's just excited.
You have to do this.
This is your career on the line.
Louis,
say something?
Ok,
yeah, yeah let's do it.
You're such a fool.
You'll be court marshaled.
Your career is over.
What does it matter
if I don't have a
family to share it with?
Ok, alright they shouldn't
be following us anymore.
Louis,
Louis?
Harold asked you a question.
I'm so sorry, A.D.D I guess.
Page seventy three...
other than guilt perhaps,
what is 5099's
motivation to chase
after his colleagues and
the child, that seems abrupt.
Well, I think it's
because he's realized
how important
Minnie is to her mother,
and to he himself.
Ok, alright,
in that case he doesn't get
to stay with them in the end.
Stay still Jill!
I am!
Mom, what do you think?
Um, shouldn't she be
in the center of the frame?
No, rule of thirds.
Oh, well your dad
should be here any minute,
he can give you more tips.
Ok...
How long is
this going to take?
It's art Jill,
just let it breathe.
Well I've only got two hours.
I know.
So 5099, leaves them at the end?
Rescues them, but then the guilt
that he has causes him go his own way
because he cares for them.
Exactly.
The best love
stories are the ones
where the people in love
don't get to stay together.
No, they need him.
Do they?
Seems to me they're
getting along just fine
until he
crashes into their life.
And cut.
We're going to go
for another take,
but this time,
whistle while you read.
Where is dad?
I need him for my next shot.
Ava and Minnie need
a husband and a father.
But, in order to
protect them he has to leave.
Otherwise it wraps
up a little too neatly.
Life is never like
that, life is never simple.
A final conflict at
the end will really hit home.
Woah,
They won't be able
to track you anymore,
but they can track me.
So I need you to stay here.
Ok?
Don't follow me.
No, no, no!
Yeah, I like that.
Harold, that's beautiful.
So, story aside,
apart, lets talk
a little about a
preliminary ballpark for
a price range on an option.
He can't afford
to hurt them again.
What?
You're absolutely right,
5099 has to what's
best for the family.
He has to leave or
else they're in danger.
Now you're talking.
Yeah, but I'm not 5099...
I have to go to my family.
Excuse me.
Louis?
Louis,
Louis, woah woah woah,
what are you doing?
Hey, I, listen I
think we have him right
where we want him so,
how about you take over for now,
you're in charge.
What are you talking about?
My daughter is
doing her first short film
today and she
kind of needs me to be there.
Listen, You and I both know he
wouldn't be spending all this
time if he wasn't
interested in the script. Huh?
Bring it home for us partner.
I'll have a new draft in a couple
of days, Harold see you soon.
Kyle.
Sir.
That is one ballsy
client you have there,
I like him.
Thank you.
Trevor!
Iced green tea.
No sweetener.
Yes sir.
Would you like a drink?
He did it.
That son of a gun did it.
-Hey hey!
-Where are you?
Yeah, I'm on my way, I'm just
stuck in a little traffic, I'll be there.
It's 4:30 Louis, she's got an
hour and a half to finish this.
I'll make it happen, alright.
I'll see you soon, I promise.
Well hurry up!
He's not coming is he.
Just do the best
you can without him.
Jill!
Hey I'm here! Alyssa!
Makayla, what can I help with?
I read your script
babe, it's amazing.
Go to your room.
No no no,
please stay. I'm here ok,
look, I know I
messed up, Alyssa?
I can't wait to
see your movie babe.
Hmmm. Going to my room now.
Hey dad...
Hey...
Read me your script?
Yeah, absolutely!
You know what...
I got a better idea.
How about you show me your film,
I'll read you my script later.
Deal.
Ok, lets go.
Huh, oh my gosh,
this is good, this is good.
You think it's this
easy to stroll in like this!?
Hey...
I was just about to
read her my script
if you wanted to join us?
Don't act like
you're out of the woods yet!
At least I've landed.
He pants and
looks around the beach,
bits of wreckage
from his craft scatter
the sand. Some
large, some small.
Slowly calming, he looks
ahead and sees in front of him,
a tall mountain of
sand. He studies it,
then drops to his knees,
face whitening with desperation.
He blinks and seems to be
clearly contemplating his situation.
He lifts his arm and starts hitting
a cracked touch pad on his wrist.
It finally comes
to life, sort of.
He speaks into it.
Control...
do you read me Control?
Please send rescue.