Herbie!
Come on, Herbie,
we better go.
Herbie! Coming, Mom!
Come on, we're late.
Ah! One hat
at a time, Herbie.
Okay, Mom.
My name is Butch.
Butch Cassidy, ma'am.
Yes, sir, Mr. Cassidy.
All right,
Dad's here!
Oh, good,
you're home early.
Oh!
Hey, big guy.
What are you two up to?
I'm taking Mr. Cassidy
to the clinic.
Why don't you
take me, Dad?
Then we can plan
our trip to Wyoming.
Please! Hey, that's a great idea.
Herbie, I can't.
I just came home
to pick up some papers
and I've got to shoot
right back down
to the office.
You never take me, Dad.
Hey, we'll play some
ball after dinner.
Promise, huh.
Come on, Herbie,
get your bike.
Okay, Mom.
Herbie!
You brat!
I see you!
Women.
Hiya,
giddy up there, hiya.
Whoo-hoo!
Hiya, pardner, Telford!
Hiya, pardner!
How you doin'?
Herbie,
get back in here.
Herbie?
Herbie, careful.
Herbie! HERBIE: Yahoo!
Hey, you make every
shot count now, huh?
Every shot count. HERBIE: Yahoo!
Hiya,
giddy up there. Hiya.
Whoo-hoo!
You make every shot
count now, huh?
See you back
at the ranch! Whoopee!
Would this
go by the window?
Needs a lot of work.
I don't know,
that's the charm of it.
You don't want
to fancy it up too much.
How much
for this icebox?
$600.
You're kidding.
I wouldn't kid
about a thing
like that.
Yeah, but it hasn't
been restored. I mean...
Restored?
Restored to what?
Well, look at it.
Half the hardware
is missing.
Oh, hardware.
No buts about it,
that's $600.
Look, there's a crack. Honey.
Right here,
right through the door.
You probably want to put
booze in this thing.
Don't you?
Huh? Is that right?
Yeah. I thought so.
See, Mrs. Deerfield
kept milk in here
for her six kids.
She didn't believe
in drinking.
How am I, in good conscience,
going to sell you this icebox
knowing full well
you're going to fill it
with whiskey?
It ain't right.
She's dead, isn't she?
Not in my mind,
she isn't.
Honey?
Come on, honey,
let's get out of here.
He's strange. He's a bit weird.
How's business,
Telford?
It's good, Lyles,
real good.
Heard you sold something.
No, just a layaway.
Huh!
We're ready, Herbie.
Hi, Herbie.
I'll be with you
in a sec.
Butch.
- Er, Herbie...
- I mean Butch.
You can't
wear that gun.
Er, Butch,
the hat, too.
All right.
Now hold still, Herbie.
All right, don't
wiggle your toes.
Cassidy!
Herbie, put your head back.
Herbie, put
your head back.
Herbie, you've got
to hold still.
Mrs. McGrath,
if it looks like we've
got it under control,
perhaps we can
reduce the frequency
of his visits here.
We'll just have
to play it by ear.
Hi, honey.Hi.
Honey, if you feel
all right,
why don't you
get your bike out of
the back of the car
and start your
paper route?
I want to talk to
the doctor for a minute.
Okay, Mom.
I... I know what
you're going through,
and I...
Well, I just don't have
all the answers.
Some days he has
the energy
of two 11-year-olds
and other days
he can't even
get out of bed.
I know. I know.
Well, thank you,
Dr. Garson.
You're welcome.
Darcy, check this out.
You're gonna get
hurt if you keep
showing off, Herbie.
I wasn't showing off, Darcy.
There was rattlesnakes
everywhere.
Huh?
Yeah, they were
all the way up
to my handle bars.
One was even crawling up
my pant leg.
Ah!
Yeah. I had to squash him
before he bit me.
Oh, Herbie, you
and your day dreams.
Come on, Darcy,
let's go for a ride.
You know what, Darcy?What?
You're the
prettiest girl
on the block.
Herbie, I'm the only
girl on the block.
Whoopee!
Pony express.
Watson, grab the phone.
Mr. Bell.
Mr. Bell, is that you?
Sure is.
Watson, we're making history.
Pretty soon
we'll have all these
stupid sons of bitches
putting quarters
in these boxes.
Dad!
Watch your language,
he's just a child.
Hell, I learned
to talk that way
from the kid.
Didn't I, Butch?
Butch, isn't that right?
Well... Yeah!
It's the damn truth, ma'am.
My father
has a lot of wonderful
qualities, Herbie,
but language
is not one of them.
Only ignorant
people swear.
Wait a minute.
But...
It's me...
It's my fault, ma'am.
Well, if you're going
to be a bad influence
on my father
maybe you better play
someplace else.
I'm almost finished
with the bookkeeping, Dad.
Hmm.
I'm afraid Jeff is going
to have to check them
over again.
All that just because
the stupid sons...
Where's my paper?
I'll be right back.
Well... Here we are.
Let's see.
Ah, the Russians
are at it again,
look at that.
Wish to the devil
George C. Scott
was running things.
Uh-oh. Enemy.
Enemy! Lock the door.
Hmm.
Come on, Telford, open up.
Nancy!
Come on, Telford.
Honestly, Father.
You're really juvenile.
Hey, Telly,
did I tell you my dad's
taking me to Wyoming?
Wyoming?
Hey, Wyoming.
That's a wonderful state.
Listen, you remind me
to tell you the time
I hunted grizzlies
up in the Big Horns there.
You hunted grizzlies
in Wyoming?
Ho, ho, ho.
I hunted them,
I fought them,
I skinned them alive.
Yes, sir, Butch,
believe me.
Oh, come on,
Telford, don't tell
the boy wild stories.
You've never been
out of Cleveland
in your life.
Jeff,
that was uncalled for.
I don't think
he should be telling
the boy wild stories.
Tell me about Wyoming
tomorrow, okay, Telly.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Well, I gotta go.
Hey, hey.
Where are you going?
I think Billy Graham
is on.
Billy Graham?
Now, see what you did.
Billy Graham.
The kid's gonna go
and be a priest.
Herbie and I
were playing football
this afternoon
out in the front yard,
and he collapsed
at my feet.
He's so weak.
Robert, did you hear
what I said?
He can't even play
a five-minute game
of football.
Don't worry about him,
he's going to be okay.
Lighten up.
You just won't
accept the facts,
will you?
The facts.
You want to know the facts?
Okay.
Fact, they did
catch it early.
Fact, the treatments
are working.
Fact, he has stabilized.
My God, Kathy.
The first cloud
on the horizon, you make
a hurricane out of it.
Look, he's going
to be fine.
Sure.
Every human being
on the face of the Earth
has been subject
to disease and death.
Some of us are subjected
to even severe suffering.
Maybe even...
Hey, slugger.
How was your day?
Play ball
with the guys?
Knock a couple over
the left field fence?
I was at the clinic, Dad.
Well, play some catch
after dinner, huh?
I already played with Mom.
Herbie, Robert!
So Colter was
a mountain man.
And his bones
was rattling.
Were rattling.
Were rattling
inside of him,
he was so hungry.
So, Colter ate
a buffalo chip.
He was that hungry.
Got him through though.
Well, what's
a buffalo chip?
Now, honey,
I wouldn't bother.
You're kidding.
She doesn't know
what a buffalo chip is?
Well, that's why
I'm asking.
Mom, you really don't know
what a buffalo chip is?
Sorry, I don't think
you want to know
over dinner.
Herbert T. McGrath,
you tell me now,
I do want to know.
It's a gigantic cow dump.
A huge cow dump.
Oh!
They get baked hard
in the summer.
Well, mountain men like Colter
get so hungry...
It's just like a dark pancake
lying on the prairie.
Enough, Herbie.
You just pick one up,
plop it on in your mouth.
All right, Herbie.
Of course, it's not
as good as your chicken,
honest, Mom, really.
Thanks a lot,
I was worried there
for a minute.
That Colter...
He was some guy,
huh, Dad?
Yeah, he was some guy.
Hmm.
He was terrific.
I think we ought to
have him over for dinner.
Well, you wanted to know.
Didn't she, Dad?
Excuse me.
Yeah.You're excused.
Incredible stroke
of luck.
Now that we've picked up
the antique shop,
I have half a block.
Antique shop?
Antique shop.
Herbie hangs out
down there.
Well, the old man
wasn't paying his bills.
We close the deal
next week.
Next week? Robert.
You've been promising
Herbie that Wyoming trip
for months.
Can't you put
your business off?
I can't put it off.
This thing can't be
put on the back burner.
But his trip,
it's so important
to him.
It's all
he talks about.
This is a very
complicated case,
believe me.
So, Wyoming's
off, huh?
Right.
You lied.
You promised me
and you lied!
Way to go, hotshot. Thanks a lot.
I want to go
to Wyoming.
Look Herbie,
we'll go next spring.
I don't want to
go next spring,
I want to go now.
I can't do that.
You lied.
You always do that.
You make promises
and then you lie.
Herbie, look, I have
other responsibilities.
You promised!
Stop it, Herbie!
How dare you? Herbie, I'm sorry.
It's my job, Kathy.
You still miss your dog,
don't you?
Yeah.
Yeah, me, too.
Herbie, I...
I'm sorry about
what happened earlier.
I'm sorry
about Wyoming.
Hey, we'll get
another dog
and we'll all take
the trip to Wyoming
next spring. Okay?
Look, I know you're
disappointed. It's...
It's just...
I want to do
the best job I can
to provide for you and Mom.
I'm the one
that's dying, Dad.
Herbie. Come on, let's go.
The game starts
in five minutes.
Grab your bike,
we need you
at shortstop.
Okay, okay,
I'm coming.
Oh, Herbie.
Herbie! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it.
It's okay.
Okay.
Telly.
Telly?
Gotcha.
You scared me, Telly.
Well, you better
be scared
because I'm going to
cut out your gizzard
and I'm going
to feed it to the dogs.
Telly, people don't
have gizzards.
Well, I'll cut out
your liver.
Oh, duel
to the death, huh?
Ah!
Wait! Oh!
Hey, hey, hey.
We didn't
want to, Dad.
My shop?
You can't take my shop.
It's my life.
We, uh, couldn't
make the payments
any longer.
Well, wait a minute.
Who's taking
my shop?
Sloan and
uh, McGrath.
Butch?
Butch, wait a minute.
Don't leave.
It's not
your fault, Butch!
I need you, Butch.
Herbie, I got tickets
for the baseball game,
Saturday.
Herbie?
What are you doing?
I can't stand you!
Where is he?
What's the matter?
All right, Herbie,
I don't know what
the hell your problem is.
What's going on?
Why did you
do that, huh?
Answer me.
Somebody tell me,
what is it?
What is it?
You tell her, Herbie.
No, wait,
I'll tell her.
He stormed into my study
and he started throwing
my books everywhere.
You talk to him.
I don't seem able
to get through.
He stole Telly's shop.
Robert, calm down.
You're over reacting. Over reacting?
He destroyed
my study.
You stole Telly's shop.
You're a thief.
Don't you ever
talk like that to me.
Robert, stop it!
What are you
talking about?
Are you talking about
the antique store?
Yeah.
He stole it from Telly.
Robbed him!
Okay. All right.
I get it, I get it, Herbie.
Herbie, I'm sorry
for your friend.
But he didn't live up
to his responsibilities.
He owed people money.
People should
always live up to their
responsibilities, huh, Dad?
Yeah. Right.
Like Wyoming, huh, Dad?
Telly!
Herbie.
Telly! Enough.
What is wrong, Herbie?
Telly!
Now stop that now.
You're gonna
break the glass.
Let me go!
Telly! Telly!
I said
stop that now.
Herbie, what's wrong?
Telly!
Hey!
Telly.
Let me go!
You touch that kid again,
you'll be singing soprano
at the opera!
Dad!
I'm not
helping him move!
Oh! Where you going, Telly?
Well, Butch, they're...
They're sending me
away to die.
Going to
the old age home.
Land of the
stumbling dead.
Jeff, would you come in
and help me please?
I guess this is it, Butch.
End of the trail.
Final sunset.
Dad!
They're waiting for you.
We're...
We're ready to go.
Dad? I'm not deaf!
Just wanna make some
old friends comfortable,
before I leave.
Dad.
I wanna die.
Oh, Dad!
Think I will.
Why don't you leave?
Just, both of you, go.
Close the door
and lock it after you.
I'll be dead
in three days.
A skeleton in seven.
Dad, what is
the matter with you?
What the hell
are you doing?
Why did you do that?
You know you're gonna
need those this afternoon.
How do you
work this thing?
Listen, I know
how you're feeling and I feel
very, very badly for you.
But I am sick and tired
of your treating me
like a fool.
I mean, you...
You think I'm stupid,
don't you?
I sure do!
Yeah, well, I paid for these
and you're gonna wear 'em.
Jeffery!Hey!
Honest to God, Nance,
I try. I really do.
I'm patient,
I'm even-tempered,
but sometimes your father...
Sometimes he...
You really piss me off!
Jeffrey Bauman,
I am surprised at you!
Oh, I am, too!
Well, it's the truth.
Admit it, Telford,
you've always, always
had it out for me!
He thinks I'm stupid.
Well, let me tell you
something, pops!
I am summa cum laude
from Brandeis.
Summa! Summa! Summa!
That is not a stupid man!
Summa!
I think we better
take me to the home.
Summa! Summa!
Summa, Telford!
Jeffery! Why don't you shut up?
Everybody will think
there's a Japanese wrestler
loose in here.
Old fart!
Wyoming.
You can't take us all.
It's over
for you,
Cassidy.
Seems
like a nice place.
Let's move on to
something else.
It's very clean, Dad.
And, you know, the library
and the reception area,
I didn't notice that
this afternoon.
Oh, whoopee!
Well, we'll talk
about it this weekend.
You do remember
that you're coming
this weekend?
Yeah.
What's the matter
with him?
It's a very
nice place.
Never mind.
Hello.Hello.
So, how was dinner, Dad?
I hear the food's
pretty good.
It'll pass.
Oh, come on, Telford,
she's just trying
to be nice.
We wanna help you.
Help?
That's what everybody's
trying to do, help.
Here, look at this.
"Today is Friday.
Weather is sunny.
"Next holiday
is Halloween."
Okay. Oh!
Look at that.
What do we have here?
"Next meal
is breakfast."
Well, some people need
to know these things.
Yeah, like you,
for instance.
I'll be suffocated
with help here.
"The next person you see
tomorrow morning
will be yourself."
"Your next bowel movement
will be precisely
in two hours."
Dad!
Oh, it's
a duck farm here!
Duck farm!
Who needs your help?
Got plenty of help.
I can take care
of myself.
Duck farm!
Trying to help!
That's what it is,
a duck farm!
I want my money.
You mean close out
your account?
Yup.
May I ask why?
No, ma'am.
Just cough it up, $100.
Yes, sir.
20, 40, 50, 60,
70, 80, 90, 100.
Keep that
for your record.
This is where
we're going, Telly.
Hole in the Wall.
And we'll just be gone
for a couple of weeks.
Then we can come
right back, okay?
Ah, it ain't gonna
work, Butch.
Why not?
I mean, we can rob a bank.
And...
And shoot grizzly bear.
Please, Telly?
Well, I promised Nancy
and bozo brain I'd come over
for the weekend.
Please, Telly?
Besides, Wyoming
is not
what it used to be.
McDonald's
all over the place.
There aren't
any grizzly bears
left there anymore.
Jeff says you've never
been out of Cleveland
in your life.
Who the hell
are you gonna believe?
Me or him?
I told you I fought
grizzlies in Wyoming.
I'm sorry my dad
took your shop.
Well, not your fault.
I'm going anyhow.
With or without you.
Butch...
Well, all right.
Maybe.
I'll tell you what.
In the alley,
tomorrow night,
behind my shop.
If I'm there,
I'm going.
If I'm not,
I'm not.
Okay.
Oh, my God!
You scared me, Telly!
Its Hole in the Wall
or bust!
All right!
We're going!
Sure you got
enough gas?
Oh! Oh!
Compliments
of my son-in-law.
Climb aboard! All right!
Climb aboard! Let's go!
Here we go!
Yoo-hoo!
Telly, look out!
Ooh!
Wow!
Doggone drunk!
This thing sounds bad.
It hasn't been out
of the garage
in two years.
Telly, you just
ran a red light.
Huh?
Well, maybe
if it'd stop raining,
I could see a thing.
You just ran
another red light!
Well, it takes a while
to get the hang of things.
Telly, I don't
wanna get thrown in jail
in Cleveland.
Well, maybe
we better get off
the main drag, huh?
Oh, my God!
Dear God, no!
What's the matter?
Herbie's gone! What?
He's gone!
I'll call the police.
♪ Whoopee ti yi yo,
'git along little dogies
♪ You know that Wyoming
will be your new home ♪
I said I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to run out of gas.
I think somebody
drained my tank.
Honestly, Jeffery,
I told Dad that
we'd be here by 8:00.
I don't see
what the big deal is,
we just saw him
yesterday.
It's a rough time
in his life.
He hates me.
If that's what
makes him happy.
I will.
I know.
I tried to call you,
but no answer.
What happened?
Well, I don't know
how to say this, but...
Dad. Is it Dad?
Oh, no!
He's not, um...
Oh, no, it's not that,
he's all right.
He ran away last night.
Oh, no!
He what?
Hey, you feelin'
all right, Butch?
Look a little pale.
Homesick, eh?
Gee no!
My home's on the range.
Evenin'. Evenin'.
Might as well
fill her up.
Don't move, mister!
Don't move a muscle.
Get the keys
to the register, Sundance.
Will you put
that thing down?
Go on and do
what you have to do,
piddle.
Where's the bathroom, sir?
Inside the store, son.
Get back there
and don't move!
I'll blow your head off!
I got a boy
about the same age.
Kids get the darndest
notions nowadays.
Yeah.
Dadgum it.
Lousy transmission.
Sounds like my mother's
old washing machine.
Well, it...
No sense
in taking chances.
We better go back,
check it out.
Plenty of place
to turn here.
Butch, go inside
and get that guy
out here, will ya?
Mister?
Is anybody here?
Ow!
One peep out of you
and you're dead!
Now get that old man
in here, quick!
Telly! Telly!
Hurry, Telly,
I need ya!
Please don't
hurt him, mister.
Shut up, dummy!
Butch? Butch...
Hold it right there,
old man!
I want all of it.
Every last penny.
I don't have
anything, mister.
Don't tell me that!
Come on,
get up against there.
All right, take what you want,
but don't hurt my boy please.
Just don't hurt my boy!Please, mister.
Mister, please!Is that it?
Boy, I oughta...
Please!
Tough guy, huh?
Well, maybe I can use you.
What are you talking about?
Leave that boy alone!
Shut up!
I need a partner.
Robbing gas stations
and banks.
Yeah, I think he'll
work out just fine.
Look at him,
he even looks
like a bank robber.
No, I don't!
Is he smart?
No, please, Telly.
I flunked math.
Well...
Yeah, yeah, he is smart.
I have to admit that.
I am not!
I don't even know
my times tables, mister!
Flunked math!
Hell, you couldn't
even count the money!
Try to follow me and
I'll blow your heads off.
Butch, quick.
Get in the car.
Tell your nephew
he did a great job!
It was worth the 20.
Glad to help out.
All right.
Well, we didn't come out
of that too bad.
Eh, he was
in such a hurry,
he only got 20.
We can make that up easy
when we hit the bank
in the next town.
What do you mean?
A hold up!
Oh, sure. Well, as soon as
we make camp for the night
we'll plan out
the whole thing.
Uh-uh, no way! Uh-uh.
Oh, I thought
you wanted
to rob banks?
Telly,
some things should
just be make believe.
Oh.
Are you sure
you know where
you're going, Telly?
You wanna go to Wyoming,
don't you?
This looks like
a good place
to spend the night.
I think we'll pull off
right here.
There we are.
Looks like we got
some slow traffic up ahead.
Look, Telly, he's hurt.
He's hurt.
Hmm?
Telly, let me out.
Let me out, he's hurt.
Come here, boy.
Can we keep him,
Telly?
Can we?
Look, he doesn't
have a collar.
Wait a minute.
Let me see here.
And he is hungry, too.
Can we, please?
Now, wait a minute. Can we?
Oh.
Butch...
What's wrong, Telly?
You leave this dog be.
Just leave
this dog be.
No.
No, Telly. No!
He needs me.
He's hungry.
Did you hear me?
Leave that dog be!
Let me go!
You're just
a mean old man!
All you care about
is old chairs
and tables and junk!
Butch. Butch!
Come back here, boy!
Come back!
It's not your fault!
Come on.
It's not your fault.
I'm not
gonna hurt you.
Butch! Butch,
you come back here!
Butch!
Where are you going?
You leave that dog be.
Here, boy.
I love you, Butch.
You always do that.
You make promises
and then you lie!
I have
other responsibilities.
You promised!
I guess this is it, partner.
End of the trail.
The final sunset.
Herbie, I don't
ever wanna hear you say
you're dying again,
you understand?
Herbie. Herbie!
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Honey, it's okay.
Smokey!
Telly!
Telly, you let him die!
You let him die! Telly!
How could you?
How...
That's Old Grizz, son.
Eighteen years old
he was.
Friend of mine.
Yesterday afternoon
he came up and put his nose
right in the palm of my hand.
And I knew.
Knew what?
He was
telling me goodbye.
Guess he wanted
to take a last stroll
through the woods.
Wouldn't be right to
keep him from his last wish,
would it?
No.
Do you believe
dogs go to heaven?
I don't know.
I think they do.
Telly!
Well, I better
get going on this.
Sorry about it.
All right.
Come on, Butch.
Goodbye, Grizz.
Sorry, Telly.
Butch.
I love you, Telly.
Telly, when you looked
in Old Grizz's eyes, I mean,
well, how could you tell?
Well, Butch, I guess
when you reach my age
you just know
when another old dog
is near his time.
What do you see
in my eyes?
Your eyes?
I see a lot of mischief,
is what I see.
No, really, Telly,
look at me.
I see a good life, Butch.
Full of adventure.
Wow!
Look at these mountains,
they look like
ice cream cones.
Yeah.
You know what
we ought to do?
We ought to
buy a couple
of these mountains.
Take 'em back
to Cleveland.
You're right.
Folks back home would
appreciate seeing them
outside the kitchen windows.
We must be
getting close to Wyoming,
huh, Telly?
Yeah.
There it is!
All right!
Yoo-hoo!
Did not! Did too.
Old Butch
was all the time
shooting people.
Butch never shot people!
Just Indians.
All Butch did
was shoot Indians.
Well, I guess Indians
are people too, huh, Tel?
I guess they are.
Telly! Telly!
Indians! Indians!
Indians? There are
no Indians out there.
Yeah, there is, Telly.
There's Indians out there.
Oh, come on, Butch!
There's Indians, Telly,
really.
You gotta use
your imagination, Telly.
Telly?
Hey, Butch,
you in there?
Get out of here,
you dirty old man!
Oh, my golly!
I'm not Butch!
Well, I...
Telly, where have you been?
I've been looking
all over for you.
Hey, I thought
you were in there.
Come on. Well...
Hey, Telly,
let's go inside.
Why, you can't
go in there!
Did you read that sign?
They'll throw you
out of there. Come on.
Say, fellas,
what's the problem?
Well, boy
wants to go inside,
I'm afraid
he's a little too young.
Don't you worry about that.
My name is Lester.
I'm Herbie.
I mean Butch.
Yeah, and you can
call me Telly.
Well, you look kind of
familiar, Butch.
I've been around.
Hey, you fellas
play cards?
Er, cards? Er...
Well, yeah.
Well, come on in,
I'll take care of it.
Well, that's
mighty nice of you.
Come on, fellas,
this way.
This is gonna cost you
five bucks.
$5?
All right.
Well, I'll see ya.
I'm out.
Too rich for ya, huh?
$5.
All right!
I'll see that.
Hey, what do you
think you're doing?
I have an ace high flush
you're gonna have to beat.
Ace high flu...
I'm out!
Beats me.
Well, I guess it's mine.
What?
Butch?
Butch, what's the matter?
You all right?
I'm sick, Telly.
Excuse me just a minute,
I think the boy
needs a little air.
Back door there,
take him out.
Here, right here. Come on.
All right.
Guess that cigar
made him a little sick.
Come on, let's go.
Well, it's my deal,
is it?
Mmm-hmm.
Butch.
Butch, that is the meanest,
low down, rottenest idea
I've ever run across.
I know.
What kind of a guy
do you think I am?
Well...
Come on!
Well, I'm sorry, gentlemen,
but I think
I've done you again.
Well, beats me!
Oh, that beats me, too.
You know, fellas,
this is sure gonna make
things easier for the boy.
Oh.
He... He's in
really bad shape.
Yeah, I know.
You know what?
My God! Oh, my!
Butch.
Butch! Butch!
Butch, Butch!
Why didn't you tell me?
My best friend
in the whole world
and you sucked me in
on a trick like that.
Why didn't you tell me
you're dying?
I didn't think
you'd take me to Wyoming.
My God, you're dying.
I let you run me
all over that countryside
chasing some crazy dream
of cowboys and Indians.
Well, I need
that dream, Telly.
Well, maybe
I need it, too,
but not this way!
I've been playing nursemaid
to a sick little kid.
You used me, boy!
Did not.
Maybe I'm like
Old Grizz.
Maybe I needed to just take
one last walk in the woods
before I die.
You're going back.
But first you're going
to go to a hospital.
No, I'm not.You're going to a hospital!
No, way! Come on, boy!
Butch! Butch, you
come back here!
Butch!
Butch, we can
talk about this!
Come on, now.
Butch!
Butch, for heaven's sake!
Hey, Butch!
Come on! Come on.
Butch! Butch,
come back here!
Are you
all right, son?
No, sir.
Are you a preacher?
Yes.
Can I help you, son?
Yes, sir.
I have cancer.
I'm scared.
My friend back there,
he's mad at me.
Please help me.
Would you like to
pray about it?
Lord, this boy
has come freely
to ask for
a touch of your hand.
Calm his spirit.
Give him strength
to believe that is your will
for him to grow
in health and in strength.
And give him
faith to believe
for your great plan
of salvation.
Amen.
Feel better, now?
Thank you.
I'm ready.
I'll go now, Telly.
Why didn't you tell me?
My best friend
in the whole world
and you sucked me in
on a trick like that.
Why didn't you tell me
you were dying?
- It's okay, Herbie.
- It's okay.
Dr. Jackson, outside call.
Dr. Jackson,
outside call.
Hi, Sundance.
How are you, partner?
How you feeling?
Great. Next stop,
Hole in the Wall.
Yeah, I was afraid
you'd say that.
But when the preacher prayed,
it made me feel good.
It ain't gonna work.
You remember
Old Grizz, Telly?
It ain't gonna work.
You looked him
straight in the eye,
and you knew
that was the end of the line,
huh, Sundance?
Will you cut out
that Sundance stuff?
This isn't
storyland, Butch,
this is for real.
You're gonna go back
to Cleveland
and that's that.
Besides,
we're almost busted.
Busted?
Busted, broke.
Remember that $100
I gave you, Telly?
I still got it.
Gave me?
Well, that
you wouldn't take.
I still got it.
It ain't gonna work.
You all right, fella?
That ain't
gonna work, Butch.
Look, Butch,
even if we wanted
to keep on going
we'd probably
never get past
these bandage pushers.
Don't you think
they've already
seen the paper?
Here, look at this.
Front page.
We gotta make our move
while we still can.
Oh, no.
Butch, I... I...
I don't think...
I don't think we can, Butch.
I still don't think...
Well, maybe.
Okay,
you get your clothes.
I still don't think
it's going to work.
Well, all's fair
and square.
Right,
my vision of loveliness?
Well, sweet talked
another one.
Best deal I ever made.
Gun, pony
and the trailer.
Another sucker.
Well, like my
pappy used to say,
love 'em and leave 'em.
Your daddy
doesn't know
what he's talking about.
He does too,
he's a lawyer.
What's the matter, Butch?
He's here.
Who's here?
It doesn't matter.
I'm ready for him.
Butch.
What did it feel like?
What do you mean?
That preacher
praying for you.
Like warm honey.
Hard to beat warm honey.
Yeah.
Come on up there.
Oh, let me
give you a hand
with that, partner.
How are you
doing today, Telly?
Uh, right.
Get down.
Who are those guys?
I don't know.
What is it?
That's it,
Hole in the Wall.
Robert,
what do you see?
I see the car.
They're up there,
all right.
It's Herbie.
Thank God.
Let's get going. No, wait.
I'll go by myself.
Well, sir, that's up to you.
I can drive you up there.
No, it's best
if I go up alone.
It'll be all right.
Do you want me
to go with you?
No, please.
It's my responsibility.
Just give me some time.
Butch, that's the law.
Who's that other guy?
We got to
get out of here, Sundance,
they'll take me back.
All right.
Let's make a run for it.
Come on.
Grab that rifle, Butch.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Come on, come on!
Come on, now.
That fella
is still coming.
Come on, boy,
come on.
Come on,
Come on.
He's coming.
Who is that guy?
I don't know.
Come on,
let's keep going.
Hey, wait a minute.
What?
What's the matter?
I know that guy.
You do?
Well, who is it?
It's my dad.
Oh, no!
We better
get out of here.
Oh, no!
Hey, Herbie!
Herbie!
Please don't let him
take me back, Sundance.
Please, not yet.
All right, Butch.
We better split up.
I'll cover for you.
Well, old partner,
I guess this is it.
You know, I'd been
a rocking chair dreamer
all my life.
I would've died one,
if you hadn't
come along, Butch.
Maybe we should've
gone to Bolivia.
Bolivia?
I flunked Spanish.
Come on, get on.
All right.
Okay. Okay!
You go do it.
Give 'em hell, Butch.
Give 'em hell!
Go on!
Never say die, Butch,
never say die!
The rocks, boy,
you watch the rocks!
Herbie!
Another step
and you're history.
Stop!
I want to give up,
Mr. Stampley.
Don't make me do this!
I just want to
see my son.
You leave us alone!
Please, Telford!
Stop!
I want to see my son.Hey!
I just want to
see my son.
He doesn't need you now.
No.
But I need him.
Well, I need him, too.
You want to
take it all from us,
don't you?
Yeah, first my shop,
then... Then our dream.
Well, you can't
do that.
What are you holding?
Keep your hands up.
What have you
got there?
Your shop, Telford,
it's yours.
Yeah.
Well, I'll be...
Hey, look at that.
Butch.
Butch!
What do you
know about that?
Hole in the Wall.
I can hear it.
I'm not too old!
I'm not too old,
I can hear it!
I'm coming, Butch,
I'm coming!
Butch!
I'm here, Butch.
You're too slow.
You're dead.
You're a dead man, Butch.
You're too slow, Butch.
You're dead.
You can't take us all.
It's over for you, Cassidy.
Draw!
Butch!
Cassidy!
Good job, Butch!
Herbie...
Hi, Herbie.
Butch, it's Butch.
Yeah. Butch.
How's Mom?
She's fine.
She's waiting for you
down the hill.
She missed you.
I missed her, too.
Herbie...
Herbie, I'm...
I'm sorry I never
took you to the clinic.
Guess I wanted you
to be strong
for both of us, huh?
See, when you left home,
that scared me.
I thought maybe
I wouldn't
see you anymore. I...
I felt like
I'd failed you
as a father.
I was afraid
I was going to lose you, son.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Dad!
Eh, come on along, girl.
Come on.
Atta girl, atta girl.
You did good, girl.
You did real good.
Sundance!
We got to get
out of here, Sundance,
they're after us.
What is it, Herbie?
What's the matter?
Come on, Dad, hurry,
they're after us.
Come on, Dad,
they'll get us.
What are you
talking about?
Hurry up,
Sundance, hurry.
I'm going as fast
as I can.
Wow, here they come.
Herbie,
I don't see anything.
Look at 'em.
Here they come.
I am looking at 'em,
but I just don't...
They're getting closer.
Yeah.
Yeah, I see 'em, Butch.
I see 'em.
Let's get out of here,
Sundance.
Do you really
see 'em, Dad?
Yeah,
there's five of 'em.
Gee, Dad,
I don't see five.
I only see four.
No, no, no,
the guys in the back
are riding double.
Riding double?
Do you think
we're gonna make it,
Sundance?
Well, barely.
Just barely.
They're really
coming.
I think I see Robert.
They're not
slowing down.
They're not gonna stop.
Mom!
Mom, I love you.
That's too fast
for this road!
Herbie, Robert!
Yoo-hoo!