Nice to meet you, Emma.
Wake up, everyone!
Good morning, everyone! Wake up. It's morning.
It's morning!
-Wake up now.
Wake up. Get dressed.
Hey, Emma. Please tie my hair!
Let me borrow that!
Today's the last day I get to tie your hair for you, huh?
When I grow up, I want to become a "Mother" like Mama.
I see.
"The monster is over here! It will get you in its hand."
We won't be taken in with your scheme today.
Alright! It's done! Here you go.
Sorry, Emma!
Phil!
The Grace Field House Orphanage.
We are all not tied by blood.
Morning!
But...
Good morning!
We all live in this house full of so much vigor.
Morning, Emma! You are in high-spirits!
Even when we haven't had breakfast yet.
"Morning," you say. How old are you? 5?
I'm 15, just like you guys!
No way!
What? You're smaller in height compared to mine!
Stop it, huge-faced woman!
Come on now.
Shut up, pipsqueak!
Emma! Good morning!
Help me over here.
Good morning, Mama.
Living together with a kind Mama, along with a lot of siblings.
Thank you.
Thank you for this meal.
Everyone is a precious family member.
Hans, it's all over your mouth.
Look over here.
Come on. Here.
I didn't do well at all.
I think I had half of the items right.
Half?! How was it?
Time to announce the results.
Norman.
Ray.
Emma.
The 3 of you did amazing!
You three got perfect scores again!
Amazing!
We all do our very best in our studies.
Time to play!
Hooray!
We exert our best efforts in playing all-out with everybody.
Who wants to play a game of tag?!
Yes!
Alright! Norman will be it!
Alright!
Everyone, go and run!
Run, run, run!
1, 2, 3.
Run away!
The House rules indicates that we must never go outside.
We have to abide by that rule.
Phil.
It's dangerous to go beyond that gate.
You mustn't get near it.
Yes.
I got you.
I got caught!
You too, Phi?
You got caught first.
What now? You've captured everyone already?
You too though!
If there were kids who could ever escape
from the genius Norman, it'd only be those two.
That hurt!
Norman!
Are you okay?
Emma, I got you.
That was sly of you!
It's all in the game plan.
What do you mean by that?
You need to read your enemy's moves.
You are so unfair!
Emma!
We don't stay in this House forever.
Bye-bye, everyone!
Until we reach the age of 16 years old, we get arranged
to be adopted by our foster parents, and go on traveling to the outside world.
Let's see each other out there.
Be well, Conny.
Get along well with your new family, okay?
Thank you, Emma!
I believe that an unknown yet beautiful future awaits all of us.
Bye-bye.
Bye-bye!
Be well!
However, this place...
...was a world plastered with lies.
Subtitles by FURRITSUBS
1 more year left for us to stay here.
If ever you went ahead first, write us a letter, okay?
Of course!
So I say, but I have no one to write to by then.
I'm sure everyone will forget about this place soon.
I'm sure the outside world must be so much fun.
But, you know what?
I will write to you. I promise.
That's...
...Conny's!
She forgot to bring it!
If you chase after her now, you might still make it in time.
When I last took a glance, the lights by the gate are still on.
Let's go hand this over to her!
If we went out this late at night, we'll get scolded.
Moreover, we can't go past the barrier.
But... this is Conny's treasured toy.
Alright.
Let's just both get scolded later.
Conny?
Did you hear a sound just now?
She looks good!
Nothing beats human meat.
This is way out of reach for the likes of us.
All of the human meat produced on this farm is high-quality,
it's all luxury merchandise for the rich.
A 6-year old again?
We've been shipping out a lot of average stuff lately.
It's about time soon that we arrange the shipment for those
students that got perfect scores for whom you are so proud of.
Understood.
Wait a moment.
I smell something.
Emma!
Are you alright?
It's not true, right?
That wasn't Mama who we saw a while back.
That wasn't Conny who we saw.
That was... Conny.
Let's run away, Emma. Let's escape from this place.
We may not know what awaits us out there.
But, I'm sure we can escape from here.
I can't do it.
We can. As long as it's you and me.
I can't leave everyone else behind!
If they stay here, they'll get killed!
I don't want any one of our family left to die anymore!
It might be impossible.
No, it's not.
It'll be alright.
Let's escape from this place together with everyone!
Process the preparations.
Let's go.
Were you able to give it to Conny?
We couldn't make it in time.
We're all kept alive for the purpose of being devoured.
Good morning!
The Grace Field House is not an orphanage, but a farm.
Here you are.
Thanks.
Good morning, Emma.
Morning...
Emma!
Good morning!
Come on.
Mama...
Thank you.
Mama is...
Our Mama...
She is the demon's subordinate. She's looking out for us.
The reason she made us think that she was protecting us
from what's out there, is to trap us in here.
This too.
We're livestock.
Which explains why we've never gotten any
letters from those who have gone on their travels.
Let's go even if we don't know what lies ahead of this.
A wall.
It's so high.
But you or I could climb up it if we had a rope.
The problem now is how we can get everybody here.
We need to come up with a strategy so we can escape with everyone.
Unless we arrange that, we must never tell the others about what we saw last night.
Not even with Ray?
Do you think he'll believe us? That we're livestock? That Mama's just a caretaker?
Is Mama really our enemy here?
She lied to us.
What happened?
What should I do?
When we were out in the forest playing with Naila, we got separated from each other.
Is that so?
It'll be okay. Everyone, wait right here. Alright?
Mama...
Mama!
Naila!
I'm so glad you're okay!
I'm so glad!
Naila!
Are you alright?
Okay, everyone. Let's all go back to the house.
Yes!
She found her way too fast!
It's like Mama knew exactly where Naila was.
What Mama was looking at earlier wasn't a watch.
There might be a transmitter embedded somewhere in our bodies.
Probably over here.
In this area?
Everyone has it too.
The ear would be the easiest place to put in a transmitter for livestock.
Mama showed that pocket-watch on purpose.
It's a message telling us that we can't escape as we have a tracker on us.
It lets her know if someone goes beyond the gate.
It's Mama's way of declaring war against us!
Norman, do you have a moment?
What's up?
I can't reach this part here...
When I grow up, I want to become a "Mother" like Mama.
You look pale, Emma.
You don't have a fever, though.
It's nothing, Mama.
Is that so?
You know what? Conny said she wanted to become a "Mother" like you.
Yes. I know.
I'm looking forward to it.
I'm sure Conny will grow to become a
splendid adult, and an amazing mother.
Hey, Emma...
Did you go to the barrier with someone last night?
Dinner is ready, Mama.
I see.
Mama...
I didn't go beyond the gate. That's a given.
Really? That's fine, then.
Mama has been lying to us ever since we were born.
It's done!
We can now use this as a rope.
Next, how do we gather everyone over here?
As I thought, isn't it okay that we tell Ray about this?
You guys!
What are you sneakily talking about over there?
Ray?!
Sorry. I trailed after you guys.
Ever since you guys went to the barrier that night,
you've been acting weird since then.
What are you hiding?
Demons?!
Mama is an enemy?
I understand if you can't believe us, but---
I do.
You're a different matter, Emma. But Norman wouldn't
lie about something like this.
What's with that?!
Come on.
So, when do we escape?
It'll be impossible to bring everyone with us,
but with us three---
No.
I want to end it with Conny.
I don't want to see anyone else in that state.
She said we must bring the younger ones too,
and escape with everyone.
Are you an idiot?
Just escaping this place isn't enough, Emma.
If there are demons in the outside the world, that's even way worse.
There are no place out there where humans can live in.
If you take everybody with you, we'll all get annihilated.
But...!
Leave them behind.
That's the best choice.
No!
If there's none, then let's create it!
A place in the outside world where humans can thrive!
Let's change the world!
Let's change it! With our own hands!
Norman! You too?!
Please! Cooperate with us!
Let's escape from this place with everybody! Alright, let's go!
Well, before that, we need to know who our enemy is.
So, how do we do it?
Are you an idiot?
What the demons are after, is our brain.
The more developed our brains are, the tastier it is.
That's why they're letting us study, to develop our brains better.
Once you're past 6, you're plucked out in ascending order of our scores.
We're all shipped out unconditionally once we hit 16.
Remember what that demon said?
Those 3 students with perfect scores.
They're talking about you, me and Ray.
If we're doing this, we need to win.
For that purpose, we need to do something about these transmitters first.
Touching it is risky too because we might break them.
That's why, we must only destroy it until the time we escape.
But, how do we destroy it?
With this size and shape, something comes to mind.
Can you leave this matter to me?
You're fine with it?
Yeah.
If you say so...
Take a look!
Look at what I found!
Here we go.
You see this owl here? It has different text in each books.
You're right, Phil! You did great in finding these!
Well, yeah.
Seems like all these books are from Mr. Minerva.
If we're looking for Minerva's books, this room is full of it.
Oh? This is...
Doesn't this look like Morse Code?
Morse Code?
D-O-U-B-T.
Doubt.
Doubt?
And this one is "RUN."
Run.
Farm. Truth.
Danger.
And this one is...
Promise.
I get the feeling that all these will turn out
to be important guides for us.
What's our basis?
My instinct.
What?!
If this really was a message addressed to us...
Then, in the outside world, we have an ally named "Minerva."
Seriously?!
Everyone! Gather around!
I will introduce her to you.
This is Sister Krone. She has come to assist me.
I will live with all of you starting today.
Pleased to meet you all!
Let's all get along well.
Mama just initiated her first move.
She now has a wider look in this House.
Taking all of that into consideration,
the next shipment will be in a month and half.
Before that happens, we need to come up with a plan to bring everyone with us.
So we say, but they all completely trust Mama.
Will they be able to handle the truth?
Moreover, how do we even take everybody with us?
There are those who aren't physically ready for this.
They'll only hold us back!
I do have an idea for that.
I've heard a lot about you. Under your leadership, this plant
has shipped more top-quality produce than any other.
I am honored to have the chance to work under a person I admire and respect the most.
These are documents on my dear children.
Memorize all of them right here, right now.
Yes.
Game of tag?
Training disguised as a game?
I'll teach them how to use their bodies better.
About how to better use their brains, I leave that to the two of you.
Mama won't know if we execute it through playing.
However, why have I been summoned here?
They figured out the secret.
They saw what was in the truck, too.
T-Then, we should find and ship them out, as per the rules!
It's fine.
There is no need for that.
Just as long as they don't escape until their shipment date.
You won't inform the higher-ups about this?
I won't.
I'll properly take appropriate countermeasures against the kids myself.
You don't need to think of anything else.
Just take a close look after them, that's all.
You understand, right? Sister Krone.
I will do so, Mama Isabella.
Emma!
Take care.
I'm heading off.
Alright, so Norman's team will be it!
Alright!
Alright, everyone! Run!
1, 2, 3.
Run!
Let's sharpen our skills!
Keep stomping your feet!
A bit more!
More, more!
Okay, let's go!
Once you're done setting tracks, go this way.
Leave those branches here.
Thoma, get those prints done.
Let's go!
Ready, go!
1, 2, 3! Alright! Go! Great job!
Okay! You can do it!
Alright, you got it.
Come here. Over here.
Alright, you got it!
There you go!
Foot prints!
-Alright, everyone! This way!
No.
Those are fake prints.
Don't get deceived!
As expected from you!
The right way is this way. Come on, let's go!
Let's go!
Listen, when it comes to playing tag, it's a game that needs strategic plan.
We need to think about how the enemy moves.
That looks like a lot of fun.
Game of tag.
Let me in, too.
What? What do you mean?
I want to get along with everybody.
Sister, can you even run?
Of course! I'll capture all of you in one go!
Got you now!
This is a nice opportunity to know more about our enemy.
The match runs for 20 minutes.
I'll be it.
All of you, run away well. Alright?
Alright!
1, 2, 3, 4!
Expose the targets. I will take over Isabelle as the "Mama" of this house.
Run!
I got you!
Come here!
Got you!
Okay, got you.
We need to escape!
Okay, stop!
I got you!
Wait!
Next up, the 3 kids with full scores.
Emma! Surrender now and come out.
If ever you saw the harvest that night,
then I'm on your side.
Found you!
You got caught too, Emma?
2 more to go!
How many minutes left?
8 minutes and 40 seconds!
Good luck!
No way.
Too slow!
Where is he?
Why?
I can't capture him.
20 minutes match results: it's our victory. Sister.
These guys aren't just perfect-scores children.
You don't need to know who the targets are.
I have already taken control of this situation.
You don't have to do anything.
Yes, as you said, I am looking over them.
So...?
How did the game of tag with the children go?
What do you think of my children?
From what you have seen.
They're absolutely excellent, special children.
I see.
You understand it, don't you?
You're clever.
I expect you to stop making the wrong choices.
You may now withdraw.
Aside from that game of tag, Mama nor Sister
hasn't made any moves after that.
I'm sure they're thinking that they don't care even
if we know the secret as long as we can't escape from here.
Aside from the adults, someone else is keeping an eye on us.
There's a rat among the kids.
What?!
The kids do better at getting close to us more than the adults can.
Wait! Who would do that---!
We're all good children! No one would betray among us---
While we have no idea as to what we can do for now,
they must have already been feeding her information.
No way.
Of course, there's a possibility that they're the older ones.
Amazing!
So? What do we do?
Still, I need to tell the others about the house's secret.
Even when there's a chance that a spy is among them?
First, let's start with Don and Gilda.
What sick joke is this?
Mama is a breeder?
You mean, that "Mama" who has been so kind to us?!
Don...
Stop saying all that nonsense!
What do you mean by demons eating us?
What kind of a made-up story is that?!
Calm down!
That we're food!
Aren't we supposed to be family? Siblings?
It's all fake.
Stop kidding with me!
Stop it! It may be hard to believe, but we're telling the truth!
Believe in us! We want you to escape with us!
Did you see it?
Conny's... last state.
I believe in you.
Emma... you who loves Mama so much!
There's no way you'd make up a lie like this!
After all...
...aren't we family?
Gilda.
I'm glad they came to believe us.
When should we tell the other kids?
Before that... we're doing all this so we can expose who Mama's spy is.
I set up a trap for those two.
A trap?
I each told them where the dummy ropes were kept hidden.
I told Don there's a rope under my bed.
I told Gilda that the rope's in the ceiling of the second-floor bathroom.
Whichever rope disappears from either spots,
then we'll know who's the spy.
Good morning, Emma.
Norman.
You couldn't sleep?
Was just thinking if there's anything I can do on my own.
I see.
Once we do figure out who the spy is, will you leave that person behind?
Of course, not.
We will take them with us.
Even when they lied to us?
Even if they're the spy, they were still raised together with us.
Even if they lie and betray us, I still want to believe in them til the end.
That's right.
Norman.
What happened with the rope you set-up?
It disappeared. The one below my bed.
So, the Spy is Don?
No...
The spy was you... Ray.
Sorry. I lied to you, too.
I told Don a different location.
What do you mean?
I set-up a trap for 3 people.
Don, Gilda, and Ray.
And I thought it was going well.
That's right.
I am Mama's spy.
No way.
You being the spy would benefit the enemy the most.
There's no one else who can influence our plans better aside from you.
I guarantee regulation on the kids for Mama.
I am the device that makes sure everything goes as planned.
You can see me as the lapdog of the shepherd.
Why are you acting as Mama's lapdog?
I volunteered myself.
You know what? I found out the House's secret.
I want to make a deal with you, Mama.
Deal?
I asked her for two things.
I told her I will work for her, so she won't ship me out immediately.
And the other one...
If I showed satisfactory results, I will receive rewards.
Rewards?
With all kinds of junk.
If the House doesn't have it, I can have it delivered from the outside world.
But, Ray. You haven't told Mama yet about where the real rope is hidden, right?
That's right!
You're the one who set this whole escape in motion.
If you really are a loyal lapdog, then you wouldn't do this.
Is that true, Ray?
Yeah.
Everything that I did was for the sake of this very moment!
I did all of this in preparation for this escape plan!
Ray...
I've been preparing everything ever since I learned the truth of House's secret...
...so that no one will ever figure it out.
I deceived Conny who knew nothing, stole her little bunny,
and let the two of you go to the gate!
All of this was so that you both may never get killed!
Then, is that why you said you had an idea
about how to destroy the transmitters?
I've seen the actual things. I made experiments.
I affirm it.
The transmitters can be neutralized for sure.
You mean, you did that experiment from someone's ear?
To achieve that, don't tell me you had to sacrifice someone?
It must've been hard for you.
To have stayed quiet and not say anything after knowing the truth.
But, you must never use that plan again.
You're no longer alone in this.
Let's go to the outside world, together with everybody!
Ray is our best trump card!
He can deceive Mama. He's the best double spy!
What?
Double spy.
Don't you think that sounds cool, Ray?
Are you stupid?
Come on!
You can't always keep calling me an idiot!
My bad.
Okay. Well then, let's go make that rope.
Come on, let's do it.
Alright.
With this, we can destroy the transmitter from the other aside.
Once my package arrives tomorrow from outside, then it's completed.
Emma is taking this too lightly.
If we're seriously escaping, then you, me and Emma...
Together with Don and Gilda, just the 5 of us.
Emma won't be satisfied with this.
Then, just deceive her.
Pretend to take everyone with you,
but it should only be the 5 of us who escapes for real.
We can't do that.
Why? You do know, right?
That it'd be impossible to take everyone along with us!
That's what I thought from the start.
That night. The first time I saw Emma cry.
I thought, she might be crying because she fears dying.
Because, that's what I thought so too.
But, I was wrong!
Emma... she was crying because she was scared that our family might die.
In that situation, she was even thinking of protecting everyone.
I thought, she's really amazing.
And then, it came to me.
I wanted her to smile.
What I want now is to have Emma smile.
Because, I like her.
I mean, of course--- as family!
Stop making that face.
I want to become like her too.
Become someone like Emma.
Who will never give up in believing others.
No matter how implausible things gets, if it's Emma, I'm sure she can do it.
I never expected you to be a useless dog that
can't even keep watch while I'm away.
I already learned from it and even sold my friends to you.
I'm even reporting to you about what Sister Krone has been up to.
Besides, there was no need to have made them
see Conny in that state, right?
So, what did you come to report to me?
Norman is trying to kill you.
So?
They're gathering detergent and herbicide.
Poisoning?
Yeah.
So, there's a need to swap those chemicals with fake ones.
Do you know the location?
You'll do it with me?
Let's take care of it.
That concludes my report.
Oh, right.
I'll tell you in advance.
I received communication from the brass.
There will be no shipment next month.
Then, when's the next shipment?
January.
Your birthday.
It's finally me for the next ship out?
As you asked, we've brought detergent and herbicide.
Thank you. This will be helpful for when we're scouting.
You mean, you're climbing up the wall?
I and Emma will scale the wall and see what's outside.
What about the transmitters?
To make sure they're not checking,
Ray will stall her for us.
I'll handle Mama. Don and Gilda, you handle Sister.
What?! How do we do that?
How will you stall me?
So you guys really were Mama's targets.
Want to work with me?
I want to escape too...
...from my current situation.
There is a chip planted under this.
If you even take one step outside a farm, this chip will
discharge electricity and stop my heart.
I can only live inside these walls.
That's why I want the best possible
life for myself within the walls of a farm.
Live in the best farm.
Be surrounded with the best children ever.
Become the best "Mama" there ever is.
Do you know where I plan to do that?
In this very farm!
I need to get rid of Isabella...
...and become the "Mama" of this place!
If you kids escape, she'll be held responsible and will be disposed of.
Us running away will benefit you.
That's why, let's all work together in this.
The enemy is: Mama Isabella.
You were also born in a House too, Sister?
Yes, but not here in Plant 3.
What else? I'll tell you every information that only I know about!
If you still doubt me, you can come to my room tonight.
Come over.
She wants concrete proof so she won't ship us out yet.
Until she gets concrete proof of the uprising,
she's just pretending to socialize with us.
Then we shouldn't trust her, and not allow her to gather proof.
On top of that, let's just go and get the information we need from her.
Welcome, come in.
Well then, what do you want to know?
Do you know about the outside world?
Unfortunately, I've never seen the outside world myself too.
However, there are humans outside.
Since when have the demons been here?
Why has the world turned this way?
A long time ago, a long-withstanding war persisted.
There were humans who got preyed on by demons,
and humans who revolted.
When the demons and humans got tired of the endless battles,
they both made a promise .
Promise?
That they will divide the world where each side can live in peace.
They made a promise where the demons won't mess with
the humans, and the humans will stop killing demons.
The humans left a portion of their population in the demon world,
and the other humans disappeared and lived on the other part of the world.
Those who got left behind were slowly preyed on by demons.
They got subjugated and became food meat for the demons.
That's why this farm exists.
You are all raised for the purpose of being devoured.
What about the farm security?
Not that big of a deal.
There aren't that many guards deployed.
I don't even think they do regular rounds.
Even if we escape, they can check the transmitters.
You knew.
This one.
Mama showed it to us.
Do you know where it's located?
Where is it?
In your ear.
That's right. Thank you so much.
Let's go.
What? That's all?
No way.
You already know, huh?
How to destroy the transmitters.
Words aren't the only source of information, you know?
Their attitude, sight, blinking.
You learned that the transmitters were in the ear,
but you didn't try to touch and check.
Why is that?
Because, you already know.
You already know how to destroy the transmitters!
How do you destroy it?
Did you use some kind of tool?
Could it be...
You made it?
You made it yourself!
So you made it.
It's okay. She haven't gathered proof yet.
Let's go.
You made it.
Come by and play with me next time!
Until I get proof, you all won't be shipped out.
I look forward for that woman to mess up so badly!
I will become this house's "Mama"!
It has arrived. The promised reward.
Thank you.
I'll still be alive in the next 2 months, so I'll use this to commemorate that.
That's right.
By the way, Sister has started getting close to us again.
I see.
She never understood the warning I gave her.
Well, tomorrow then.
Well then.
It's about time.
Hey. Look my way. Come on.
Smile!
What's that? What's that?
Lemme see! Lemme see!
Amazing! Let's take a photo with everyone!
Then, I'll take it.
No, I'll take it.
Me!
Go ahead!
Let's take a photo with everyone!
Come on! Let's take some photos!
Mama! Sister too!
Alright, taking it now. Everybody, smile!
Here I go!
Ready, go!
That camera is the last component.
We can now destroy the transmitter.
Alright, later this afternoon will be the inspection.
Once the inspection is done, it's about time we escape.
Ray, Emma, Norman! Here I go!
Ready, go!
Let me see.
Alright! Everyone! Let's do some laundry!
Yes!
Don't wanna.
Don't wanna do chores.
Time for a raid!
That will destroy the transmitters?
Yeah.
Where do we hide it?
Sorry, Phil! We need to borrow your piggy bag for a bit.
Got it!
She's already searched her so this spot will be fine.
Alright!
Emma, this is bad!
My piggy bag!
Oh, you guys...
Is the proof in here?
Oh?
There's something in here.
I can hear it making a sound!
I wonder what's inside?
Should I open it and see?
Sister Krone...
This is from headquarters.
Open it and read.
I have been appointed as "Mama" of the 4th plant?
It's unfortunate that we have to part ways.
Pack your luggage at this very instance and go back to headquarters.
Grandmother is waiting for you at the gate.
Right now?
Farewell.
As if I will allow things to go the way you want it to.
Grandmother...
There's something I need to report.
There are kids from Plant 3 who knows the secret.
The 3 top students are taking the others with them
and are planning to escape!
But...
She is keeping them under control, right?
If she has them under control...
...then there is no problem.
But as per rules---
I did the same thing too. I had her under control.
Also, no one is as capable as Mama Isabella with her best techniques.
She is special.
Her and her Plant.
You can never replace her.
It's my loss.
You must absolutely escape, you damn kids.
Thank you for this meal.
Well then, I'm going now.
I leave the lookout to you guys.
If ever Ray can't stall Mama, let me know asap.
Got it!
Let's start with swapping the materials.
Yes.
Sister Krone.
I've eliminated her.
I no longer needed her here, so I disposed of her.
Same to you too.
From now on, I'll keep them on a leash myself.
What are you---
Hey, wait! Hey!
Hey! I said wait! Hey!
Wait! Hey!
What?
What's the meaning of this?
Ray didn't give us a signal but Mama is here!
Did something happen?
Don?
I'll go check inside the house!
Dammit!
That hurt!
Sorry.
More over, Ray...!
Let's go! We need to stop Mama!
What's wrong, Mama?
14 years. We've lived together for 14 years.
But this is the first time I'm talking to you without pretense.
Nice to meet you, Emma.
Norman.
Right now, we are talking to each other as breeders and livestock.
But, please don't take this the wrong way.
I love all of you.
That is why... I came here because I want you to give up.
Give up?
What about?
Resisting.
You've lived in a loving, comfortable home.
You die feeling content and satisfied.
What about that makes you unhappy?
Escaping is futile.
Your time has been decided until the very end.
You, all 5 of you... I wanted you all to live a happy life.
Go, Norman!
Emma!
You're alright!
It doesn't hurt. It doesn't hurt.
You just broke your leg.
You are top-notch children I raised with affection.
I need to protect all of you.
With this, you won't be able to move for the meanwhile.
Tomorrow will go as planned.
Tomorrow?
Behave and celebrate that day with us, Emma.
I've received word from the brass.
Congratulations, Norman.
Your shipment date has been decided.
I need to talk to you.
Norman, you need to escape tomorrow on your own.
Sorry, I can't.
We decline that.
Come on, just listen.
To be more precise, pretend to run away tomorrow.
Hide until Emma heals her leg.
And then, escape with us when we do.
If I run away, you or Emma might get shipped off.
I absolutely don't want any of the two of you to take my place.
Thank you.
It'll be okay.
I've already sorted out my feelings.
Sorted?
They can take my life all they want.
But, I'm not giving them anything else.
I will win this. I'll make sure your escape plan is a success.
That's more than enough for me.
Norman...
This is fine.
No, it's not.
No way this is fine!
I've prepared everything for the last 9 years so I can save the two of you!
Even if you run away, Emma won't get shipped off until she heals her leg.
Only I will get shipped out! So, run away!
Here!
Then, you two can just break your own leg too.
A good idea, right?
Let's all get a fracture!
Emma, what are you---
We have to be in the best possible shape or we won't get shipped out!
Now that's an idea! Time to break something.
No, wait. There's no guarantee that they'll delay the shipment if you're hurt.
Then, let's catch a terrible cold.
They won't eat you if you're sick!
You guys are so strange.
We're not!
That's way better than having you get killed!
Didn't you say it yourself? That we will escape together with everyone!
If you aren't with us, then I don't want it!
It'll all be okay.
We will escape from this place with everyone.
Let's all live together.
Norman.
Hey...
Since when did you know the House's secret, Ray?
I still have memories from when I was an infant.
What?!
People naturally lose their memories of when they were still babies.
It's called Childhood Amnesia.
Only those memories from the age of two to four years get forgotten.
However, I was different.
I still have memories in me of days before I got into this House.
Then, you remember your mom's face?
I don't.
If it's memories before coming to the House,
then do you remember anything from outside?
Yeah. From when I got into the headquarters.
Headquarters?
Ever since I got out from my mother's womb, it was the first place I saw.
I saw demons and adults, and a lot of other babies aside from me.
After that, I was brought to this House.
That's why, you can't run away from the gate.
It's connected to Headquarters.
Use this on the transmitter so you can head to the other side.
Place this on your left ear and turn the switch.
Thank you.
Don and Gilda are creating a new rope.
For the meanwhile, you need to erase your presence tomorrow.
Until Emma's leg heal, then we escape.
Understood.
We will never let you die, Norman.
We will all live and escape from this place for sure!
Yeah!
What is this?
Everyone! I have good news!
What's it about?
We've found a foster home for Norman!
This might be sudden but he's heading off tonight.
Tonight?
Is this goodbye?
That's right.
That makes me sad, but...
Congrats, Norman.
Congrats!
Anna... Sherry...
Thank you, everyone!
Write us a letter!
Well then.
See you.
Let's go.
Emma.
Don't force yourself, okay?
We'll bring more next time if it's not enough.
Thank you.
Be careful, Norman.
We'll all escape together.
I'm going.
It'll be okay. It'll all work out.
Alright! Gather around, everyone.
Will something interesting happen?
Are you okay?
Oh?
Norman isn't in here.
Norman!
Hey!
Everyone's here! Hurry and come!
Over here! Over here!
Why did he come back?
You rascal! What are you doing?!
I made sure to make a way.
What?!
I climbed on top of the wall.
It's a cliff ahead the wall.
It's not a height that we can just jump over.
So, this is the outcome of what I found when I was walking up there.
We are probably in the 3rd Plant.
This here is the headquarters.
It was only this portion here that had a bridge.
If you're escaping, you need to go through this bridge.
Norman, Mama called for you.
Tell her I'm on my way.
Got it.
I'm returning this to you. I didn't use this at all.
Use this for when you escape with everyone.
You! You were really planning to return here from the start!
I'm sorry, Ray.
If I run away, escaping will be even harder.
I can't afford to make a mistake.
So that not any one of you will die.
I've done everything that only I can do...
I will guarantee that your escape will be a success!
Thank you for everything you've done for me at this point.
I lived a good life all thanks to the two of you.
It was so much fun.
I had so much fun!
I was so happy!
Dammit!
Norman! You can still escape now! Let's escape together!
My feelings won't change.
You know that, don't you?
I'm off.
Well, then. Be well, everyone.
Take care of your health, Norman!
Thank you!
Eat you meals properly, okay?
I don't want to be separated from you.
Norman! I'll distract Mama. Please, run away.
You idiot! This isn't what you're supposed to do right now!
Shut up! No! I won't let you go!
Emma...
Understand what I'm feeling.
No! Those are the only feelings I won't accept!
The truth is... you want to live, right?
I've had more than enough, Emma.
I can live on while smiling even with just those feelings you have in you.
It's time, Norman.
I know you are sad but please calm down.
You weren't able to do anything. Making a fuss is futile.
Alright!
I leave Emma and Ray to you.
I will write you a letter, as promised.
You'll read it for me, right? Emma?
It will be okay. Never give up, okay?
Emma...
That was admirable. You did the right thing.
Now, I can finally ship Emma and Ray on term.
"They lived a happy life in the House."
That's right.
They will lead blessed lives.
Hey... were you happy, Mama?
I am, because I met all of you.
Well then, wait here.
Did I startle you?
Could you be... Mr. Minerva?
You... actually know that name?
Minerva... he disappeared.
Then, you are?
I am the overseer who protects this world.
You mean, the world where both humans and demons decided to make a promise?
Yes. You really know a lot, huh?
You mean, you're the overseer for the demons.
I plan on doing this for the sake of the humans.
The demons can only live on by eating human brains.
That's why it's gravely important to develop smart brains.
Thank you.
Thanks to all of you, the humans from the other world can live in peace without any problems.
I owe you my gratitude for being captured.
Is there no one in the human world who could be our ally?
There is.
Aside from us, there are also humans who are trying to help human livestock.
Is that so?
But...
They disappeared.
It's also my job to search for them and annihilate them.
It's all lip-service. They're wolves in sheep's clothing.
I can save this world by sacrificing someone else.
Did I make you feel despair?
No.
I'm sure there's people in the human world who wants to save us.
They will come in numbers. Even if you annihilate them, they will still come up one by one.
Am I right?
There's still hope even with just that.
Really?
Yes.
What an interesting kid you are.
We hold hope that we can change the world.
I'm absolutely sure we can change it.
Alright!
Let's play tag!
I'm giving this to you.
If you have to run away from here, then go.
It's impossible for me now.
You poor thing.
In the end, Norman died. Ray's in a pathetic situation.
You can't do anything on your own.
Your escape plan won't ever happen now.
The best way to avoid being tormented by despair...
...is to resign yourself to fate.
You're only hurting because you're trying to resist it. Accept it.
You know what, Emma?
I'm thinking of recommending you as a Mom prospect.
You can't change the world.
If that's the case, then just do your best to survive in this world.
Become a "Mama" and give up everything.
I can't.
Emma?
Checkmate.
Ray.
It's your birthday tomorrow, right?
Yeah.
I'm getting shipped out tomorrow, so...
Today is the last night.
I see.
It's goodbye then?
It is.
Hey, you.
Have you really given up for real?
The truth is you haven't, Emma.
I haven't given up.
You too, right?
Yeah.
In the end, we both had the same mindset.
Let's escape, Ray. This is what I came here to tell you.
Yeah. These past 2 months, we weren't able to talk properly.
Mama is stubborn.
Even if we didn't do anything during those times, she was still watching us.
That's why I used that to my advantage.
By keeping her eyes on me, I left the preparations to Don and Gilda.
Alright, go!
Okay, let's go! Go!
Over here.
Training with everyone. Gathering of tools and food
and cold-weather gear we need.
Everything is done!
Let's escape from this place tomorrow afternoon.
No.
We can't shake off Mama's surveillance,
so escaping by noon is impossible.
I believe this is the best thing I can do.
I'm going to set this house on fire tonight!
You'll spark a flame?
Move away.
While Mama's distracted from putting it out, take that chance to escape.
Headquarters will see it as an evacuation and not an escape.
That way, we can avoid extra security at the bridge.
We'll take that chance to escape.
But, what if Mama stops trying to extinguish the flames,
and starts going after us to protect her products?
We can't get a chance to escape from that.
I know that.
That's why I will stop Mama's advances.
Ray!
Isn't this the best?!
A perfect scorer set to be shipped out starts flaming up!
There's no way Mama can leave me alone!
This is something I've decided since long ago.
I've never even liked studying or reading at all.
But I endured, I persevered, and got my scores up!
I increased my value and made it all the way to the highest tier!
But, I'll take that away from them tonight.
Right before their long awaited harvest.
Don't think you can eat me or feed me to anyone!
Livestock? Produce? To hell with that!
I'm human! Screw you all!
Ray!
Make sure you survive, Emma.
Bye-bye.
Ray!
Ray! Ray!
Emma!
Mama! Ray! Help him!
Ray got caught in it!
Ray?!
Ray!
What has he done?!
Mama!
Take everyone outside! Please!
Yes!
Ray!
Step back, Emma!
It's not working! I can't extinguish it.
Emma! You need to hurry up and get away from here!
Emma?
Those children.. what were they wearing?
There they are!
It's Emma! Emma!
Emma!
Thanks for waiting, everyone!
Alright! Let's escape!
Yeah!
Here Emma!
-Thank you.
Let's go!
Alright! Now!
Let's go, Ray.
Norman figured it out.
You---!
This is Norman's message.
"I won't let you die right here! I'll show you something good. Just shut up and comply."
What?
I'm sorry, but I don't plan on letting you die.
Emma?
I, Norman, and the kids won't ever let you die.
Emma! We brought it!
Thank you.
Well then, get changed.
Ray's substitute. Done.
That leaves the transmitter. Sit down and hand out your ear.
Alright. Let's get this started, Norman.
To my dear friend, Emma.
This letter contains the plan for here on in.
Everything will probably happen before Ray's birthday.
I've been caught by what Ray said that day...
All of this was so that you both may never get killed!
Which means, he's not counting himself.
On top of that, he's been storing gas cans.
Ray plans to light up a fire and die in it.
Let's go!
Make use of Ray's plans, outwit Mama, and take everyone with you to escape.
Everything is going all according to Norman's plan.
These guys, do they know the whole truth?
Yeah, I told them everything.
Checkmate.
Everyone, there's something we need you to listen to.
It's something every important.
What's it about?
What for?
So that's what it was.
Everything is Norman's strategy.
Is this everyone?
How about the little ones?
We left the kids aged 4 and below.
But, it's not that we've given up on them.
I talked to Phil.
I'll wait right here.
That's why, you can leave me here.
I promise you. 2 years before you get scheduled on your shipment, I will definitely come back to you.
They completely got me in.
But, you are all still alive.
Emma and Ray!
I won't let any one of you escape!
Mama!
Phil...
Where's Emma and the others? I'm scared, Mama!
We're scared!
-You'll be fine!
You'll be fine! It'll be okay!
Mama will be back right away, so all of you wait here, okay?
Mama, don't go!
Don't go! Don't go!
You can do it!
Go, go!
This is 73584 from Plant #3. There's been an escape! Sound the alarm!
Intercept them when they reach the bridge!
The alarm.
It went off earlier than planned.
It doesn't matter if you kill the unexceptional ones.
But don't ever hurt the topnotchers.
What do we do? The bridge is still too far from here.
That's fine. We were never planning on going across the bridge.
Mama and the headquarters will think the same thing that you're escaping through the bridge.
It's not risk-free, but there's spots that will do.
Let's go!
Alright!
Let's go.
It might be dangerous, but I found a spot that will do.
This is it!
This is where we cross to the other side.
Don!
Got it!
We're crossing from here?
There we go!
Alright!
Yay!
Don!
Yeah!
Alright! I'm going ahead!
We're counting on you!
Yeah!
Made it!
Alright!
Nice one, Don!
Let's go! Let's go!
We're up next!
Ready, go! Launch!
Alright!
Alright, everyone prepare. One by one!
Give me your hand.
Hold on tightly.
Thank you.
Ray!
I'm going ahead!
Shouldn't you normally be scared?
Let's go!
Ready, go!
Just how much have they trained for this?
Ray!
Wouldn't this be the thing where Norman said he'll show you something good?
Alright!
Here you are!
Norman...
Is it really okay... that I'm still alive?
It's okay!
It's okay not to have given up!
Live on.
Okay.
Ready, go!
You can do it!
You got it, Sherry!
You did well!
Never give up in believing others.
No matter how implausible things gets, if it's Emma, I'm sure she can do it.
The transmitters... aren't showing up.
Could they have...
Alright!
Next is you, Gemima.
What should I do, Emma? My hands...
I'm sorry.
I just keep thinking about what will happen if I fall.
Gemima... you know what?
It's alright!
Let's cross together.
Tie the rope that you used to pull everyone up around me and Gemima.
Got it.
Done!
Alright, here we go. Gemima.
You can do it!
Ready, go!
Alright! Next is you, Emma!
Mama.
Wait right there, Emma!
I never imagined I'd be standing up here again.
I also stood at this spot when I was the same age as you.
I knew a boy named Leslie.
He was killed when he turned 16 years old on his birthday.
My beloved Leslie.
After I learned the truth, I outwitted Mama and came here.
And then, I knew.
A deep cliff. A dark forest.
There was no place outside where I could live in.
I was in so much despair that I gave up everything and aimed to become a "Mother."
As the job entails, I had to look out after the children, and with the song that Leslie made...
I sang that song as a lullaby and had the child in my womb hear it.
A song that only I and Leslie knew.
What happened... to that child?
He died right after he was born.
I still vividly remember the day I got you in my arms.
I thought, I wanted to become the best Mama there is.
Living alongside with the children in this farm,
and provide all of you with so much love more than ever.
If I could let all of you live for even one more year,
I wanted to create a happy time for all of you.
There is no place outside where you can ever thrive in.
You can't change the world.
If we can't, then we can just create one!
A place where we can all live in!
Emma!
We don't know what what kind of a world there is out there.
I may not be able to go living on my own...
But, I am not alone.
I, together with everyone, will go to the outside world.
If you jump then I'll cut the rope.
Go ahead.
If that's what you want to do, I don't mind.
I will still go, no matter what.
Emma, you don't get it!
I do.
I was raised this way by you, Mama.
Reading into the opponent's next moves.
You're the one who taught me that, Mama.
Checkmate.
You raised everyone with trust in the family,
you raised us all until we're back in good health.
You did all of that, Mama.
For the purpose of getting high scores for the shipment.
Is that really all to it?
The truth is that, you're more than proud that your kids have crossed all the way over there.
You're wrong.
You want to change the world too, right? Mama?
No.
The truth is that... you really want to see us all grown up, don't you?
No!
Farewell.
Mama.
Let's go.
Be well.
If the world will permit it, I sincerely hope you all find a light...
...in the end of the tunnel.
Ray?
Where did you hear that song?
I heard it from inside your womb, Mama.
I have memories of when I was born.
You know this song too, Mama.
I don't.
Listen... I already figured out the house's secret.
Mama!
It's Mama!
Everyone, it's Mama!
Everyone!
Mama!
I am so sorry, everyone.
73584.
Report to us.
Are you okay?
Look at this.
It's Norman!
Norman... he's smiling, right?
Everyone, take a look at this!
This is the pen that Norman left for us.
This owl... isn't this Minerva's?
It flew!
No way! It flew!
Let's go!
Alright!
Alright, let's get going!
Let's go!
Be careful.
I take full responsibility for everything that happened.
We're finally outside!
The morning sun.
Emma, what can you see over there?
Subtitles bu FURRITSUBS
Visit:
LJ account- furritsubs.livejournal.com
Twitter- @furritsubs // FB: Furritsu Kuromatsu
If you love the work that I do, support me through:
ko-fi.com/furritsubs
[T/N: This is the most perfect live adaptation I've seen in a long time!
I hope they create a part 2 for this film! One that doesn't follow S2, of course *wink*]