Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Next
stop, Rainey Avenue,
doors open on the left.
Oh my gosh, mommy!
- Mommy!
- Oh my god!
This is
the eastbound E train.
Next stop, Washington Avenue.
Ah.
There you are.
Maya told you, didn't she?
Now how would you know that?
She tells you everything.
I think you read my mind.
What did I
say about doing that?
Very clever, it's impolite!
Stop it, Vista!
I'm not joking!
You know you're never
allowed in my head.
All right, come
on, hand it over.
Come on.
That's not fair!
Hand it over.
Reading a person's mind,
unless it's for a mission is?
A privilege that
warrants approval.
That's right.
So
where are you going?
I'd like to have an address.
Why?
Well, 'cause I
know Ansel will want
to write to you.
New York City.
Squirreling back to Manhattan.
I have a little gift for you.
It's just your watch.
Oh no, it's a compass.
Matter of fact, it's the
compass my mother gave me.
She told me it would take
me wherever I wanted to go,
bring me home when I was done.
Thanks, I guess.
You hate me.
I beg your pardon?
I read your mind.
Don't think that.
I mean, I don't hate you.
I was a little
frustrated, that's all.
Mind if I ride with
you for a while?
Fine.
Stay together,
everybody stay together, come on.
My favorite!
The
Hyperions Family Museum
will be closing in 10 minutes.
Thank you for visiting.
The United
States Space Program
calls upon the high
security to assist
in the tests of Earth.
This is a housing
project right here.
This is, people would live here.
This is a five story building.
The museum
will be closing very soon.
Please follow the
green exit signs
through the gift shop.
Thank you for visiting the
Hyperion Family Museum.
Who's that?
Professor
Mandulbaum here.
The Hyperions and I hope
you had a grand time.
Please visit again soon.
- Okay.
- Right.
Yeah.
Oh, ma'am we're closing.
Sir, Ma'am?
Ma'am?
Everybody against the wall!
Ansel, your gun!
Oh, shit!
Get against the wall.
Now!
Make a little group,
that's it, together.
Okay.
Ansel?
Ansel!
What's this?
They're locked in.
Locked in?
You work here?
Me?
You, yes, come here.
I need the key to
this display lock.
There isn't a
key to that case.
What do you mean
there isn't a key?
What is this, what
am I looking at?
Fingerprint identification.
It's the only way
to open the case.
Which one of you can open it?
I need to make a phone call.
Distro Chex soap
and American Millimeter
Films present
Professor Mandulbaum's
Hyperions!
Where each week we're
invited into the mysterious
headquarters of the world's
only superhero family.
And now your host,
Professor Ruckus Mandulbaum.
Good day, Hyperion
club members.
And welcome to Hyperion Hall.
How are you doing
today, Mercury?
Suit up for adventure!
You can say that
again, old friend.
You know, it's been
nearly 20 years
since the remarkable story
of the Hyperions began.
And nearly 20 years
since I invented this.
The Titan Badge.
I know it doesn't look
like much, does it?
But believe you me,
this little device
packs quite a punch.
Let me show you what I mean.
Everyone you know
from your best friend
to your math teacher is filled
with this magical material.
It's called DNA.
DNA is given to
you by your parents
and acts like a
blueprint for the body.
Everything from eye color
to the shape of your nose
is contained in this
little strand of DNA.
So what does this
little fellow do?
Well, when I make a badge,
I make it for one person.
It plugs into that person's DNA
and changes one piece
of their blueprint.
For example, I can tell the
body to have x-ray vision
or to be able to shrink
to the size of an ant.
So you see, this Titan Badge
can grant an individual
a superhuman power.
Imagine that, a
real life superhero.
So the question became
who do I choose to
give this power to?
I traveled the globe in
search of the brightest,
most selfless young
people on earth,
finally finding three
suitable candidates.
Maya was given the
ability to teleport
from place to place with
nothing more than a thought.
Vista was granted the ability
to read and influence minds.
And Ansel, the youngest
of the children
gained super strength,
becoming the strongest human
ever to live.
I brought the children into
my home where we trained,
awaiting the day when their
powers would be needed.
And boy, were they needed.
Adventure!
Exploration!
Heroic rescues!
For 20 years, the
valiant exploits
of Professor
Mandelbaum's Hyperions
have shaped out world.
Calling all Hyperions.
And
for nearly 20 years
we'd been invited each
week to witness retellings
of their unbelievable stories
through the Hyperions
television program.
Follow team leader Maya,
the teleporting Titan!
Vista, the mind-reading
rapscallion!
And Ansel, the
strongest boy alive
as they show the world the
meaning of the world family.
Over the years, the
Hyperions have faced
innumerable threats
both at home and abroad.
Our contributions to world
peace are beyond debate.
Members come and go.
Every few years we bid
farewell to the old class
and welcome three new
team members to carry on
the tradition of service.
In fact, just last month,
we announced the end
of our second class,
and the search for our third
generation of team members
has already begun.
So far, we have chosen only one.
Meet Apollo, our
brand new Hyperion.
But the search continues
for the other two.
Could you be the next Hyperion?
Next question,
how's the family?
The family is,
gosh, what is it?
Marvelous.
Marvelous, right.
Look, I can't remember
all these lines.
I mean why are we even
doing this interview
with what was her name again?
Meredith Lane.
She's very influential
with the 15 over demographic.
Sign here.
Once again, how's the family?
Family's fine,
thank you for asking.
They're marvelous.
Marvelous.
Hyperion call.
Sir, Mercury's ringing.
- Let me get that.
- They're going to have to call back later.
We're almost at the studio.
Sign here.
What's your name?
Delano.
I need you to call this number.
Call it over and over again.
If no one picks up,
hang up and call again.
Do that until you get an answer.
When you do, yell out for me.
Understand?
Are you the real Vista?
Say you understand.
I understand.
What are you doing?
What did I just say?
Hah, yeah, no, oh!
So close.
Come on, a little higher.
Oh, good throw, good
throw, like a rocket.
What the hell
is going on here?
Trying to knock down
the security cameras.
Police can tap
right into those,
see right into here.
Who are you?
Olly Pinkletter, I'm the
junior security guard here.
Yeah, Ollie here,
he has some experience
with robbing places
and so you know,
just tell her, go ahead.
I robbed the place across
the street two years ago.
Yeah, he's giving
some advice, that's all.
Cameras, knock 'em down,
how to deal with
hostage negotiators.
Oh and, you forgot to frisk me.
Pardon me.
But I think you two need
to tell the rest of us here
what's going on.
Is this real?
Yes ma'am, this is real.
Miss.
- That's what I hate.
- Mr. Ansel.
My name is,
Do you mind signing this?
Well I want that too.
I usually take
the bullets out.
Anna, Anna, A.
Would you mind taking
a picture with me?
Maybe try this on.
- I mean not now.
- I was here first.
- I'll show you the exhibits and I know everything.
- How close to the actual plane?
- What did he say?
- Ah!
I have a gun.
Okay?
This is real.
Now, just,
take a seat over there
and we'll be out
of here in no time.
Okay, uh,
look, what did he say?
On the phone?
He didn't answer.
He didn't answer?
What are we gonna do?
How are we gonna
get out of here?
What's our next move?
I need a minute to think.
Vis.
Hey, Ollie.
Is there a way to get out of here,
like a loading area or something?
- Oh yeah, actually, if you head down-
- Hey, hey, hey, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
We are not going anywhere
without those badges.
All right, we talked about this.
Okay.
You said this would
take five minutes.
You said we'd be
out of here by now
and nothing can go wrong!
Yeah, well you
said that the badges
were only protected by
a single pane of glass
which is what I
based the plan on.
Okay, well yeah, I did say
that, yes, that is true.
Hyperion Family Museum.
It's the police.
They want to talk to
whoever's in charge.
Hey, Vista.
Vista!
What am I gonna do
with these people?
Hey.
Just give us a minute.
Yeah, you guys
could just, I guess,
Oh boy.
On scene and we
are now in position.
Remember when we
enter, take a moment
to assess the situation.
Assess, plan and act.
Right, okay.
Ready?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm ready.
Remember to breathe.
Shit.
Hello, Maya.
Agh!
Junior Mints.
No, I think we
did really well.
Honestly.
Oh, thank you.
I feel like I did pretty good.
Don't, don't scratch that.
But the hole's itchy.
Gunshots to the
chest can sting.
I'd recommend next
time using your power.
Turn my skin into metal?
I think it would have made
a difference, don't you?
Yeah, if you think so.
Are you there, Maya?
Are you there?
Go for Maya.
It's a bad connection,
can you speak up?
Excuse me, I beg your pardon.
Thank you so much.
Hello?
Yes, I need you back right away.
The news is saying there's
a hostage situation
at the museum!
Somebody's attempting
to pinch my shit!
Wait, are you alone?
Did I say shit?
On my way.
Maya.
Speaking French.
Merci.
Looks like you're
gonna be staying
with Dr. Charles
for the week, okay?
Do you want the remote?
Who's Dr. Charles?
Where am I?
Paris.
Every time I stay here,
I beg Dr. Charles to get cable.
Oh, MASH.
Who's Dr. Charles?
Oh, he's our
private physician.
Look, do me a favor.
It's very important you
don't tell the Professor
about your injury.
Don't tell him about Dr.
Charles either, okay?
Yeah, of course.
Why?
There are some details the
public shouldn't know about.
And since the Professor's
the face of the team,
we wouldn't wanna put
him in a situation
where he'd have to lie
to the public, would we?
Hey Maya,
what's your ETA?
Leaving now.
Sergeant, I don't
want you to worry a bit.
I've written every
single word you've said
in my notebook.
I won't let you down again, sir.
Over and out.
All units,
we have a code 805,
repeat, code 805.
All right people,
look alive, goddamit!
Sergeant Burns just confirmed
that we've got a
Hyperion en route.
Not a good time to look stupid.
Oh God.
Hey, Fitzpatrick, come here.
I locked my keys in the car.
Take care of that one.
Are you
Captain Woodcock?
Looks like
a hostage situation.
Any idea how
many are inside, demands?
No words
from anybody inside.
What about
security cameras?
Cameras inside
are just for show.
Non functional.
You've attempted
contact by phone?
They keep hanging up.
Have you tried
knocking on the door?
The
Hyperion Arm Device
attaches onto the forearm.
The Titan Badge is
then locked into place
allowing the precision
needle to act as a highway
for the DNA altering
material to,
We've run into
a small problem.
Nothing big, but we might need
more time than we discussed.
What constitutes
a small problem?
Nothing, really.
Everything's fine.
When will I have them?
I'll call you.
Maya.
Vista.
What are you doing here?
These men think there's a
robbery going on in there.
There is.
Well, do you have the thieves?
How many are there?
Have you spoken
to the Professor?
Not yet.
Well, let me in, I'll help.
I can't.
I'm the one robbing the place.
You're kidding.
No.
And I need the
Professor right away.
Have you lost your mind?
Don't bother trying
to teleport in here.
I have the cork.
You don't.
What is the cork?
Well, this little device
acts as my security system
in preventing any abuse
in power that may come
from granting the
Hyperions super powers.
With one push of a button,
I am able to generate
a power-free radius
where none of the Titan
badges can function.
Let me give you an example.
Take this dashing super
powered Hyperion Team member.
Mmm?
Yes, you.
Would you mind showing
us what happens
when you attempt to use
your power in the cork zone?
You stole the cork?
How did you get it?
It doesn't matter.
The inside of this museum
is off limits to you.
Vista, you're
making a big mistake.
We need the Professor now,
we don't have much time.
Who's we?
I, I need the Professor.
Did you seriously
drag Ansel into this?
Bring him here.
What the hell
are you thinking?
Holding up the museum,
taking hostages?
And then you have the
nerve to make demands of me
and your father.
You don't get to do
that, young lady.
Drop the weird
babysitter routine, Maya.
I'm not trying to be
your goddamn babysitter.
I'm trying to talk to
you one adult to another.
What are you doing here?
I just need the
Professor to come.
That's all this is?
Some bizarre way
of reconnecting?
This has nothing
to do with you.
Of course it does!
You abandoned us 10 years ago
like a spoiled brat.
And then out of nowhere
you hold up the museum.
And dragging Ansel into it?
I'm trapped, Maya.
Let me get you and
Ansel out of here.
I can't.
I'll take you home.
I can't, I can't go anywhere.
This is gonna break
your father's heart.
Don't call him that.
Don't call him what?
He's not my father!
Vista, be gentle.
You've both made mistakes.
I was a kid.
I was allowed to make mistakes.
How many apology letters
do I have to write?
I sent hundreds.
And all the while he just
dragged my name through the mud
for like 10 years,
as if cutting me off
in every way wasn't enough?
I wake up every other night
with lingering pains
from years of injuries.
Broken bones, gunshot
wounds, stab wounds,
I was stabbed!
He wasn't always
aware of everything.
Oh, please.
Vista.
Don't be so eager to
destroy the man's legacy.
He cares about you.
He cares about the team,
not the people on it.
And I'm no longer an employee.
You're wrong. Ruckus has never
just thought of us as employees.
Not you, at least.
What's that supposed to mean?
Come on, Maya.
You were always the favorite.
Ruckus cares about
all of us equally.
Vista!
Don't forget which one
of us used to read minds.
Leave your men
outside of the building.
Nobody enters.
Yes, ma'am.
Maya.
Just give me a moment.
Look, I know I'm not
supposed to be seen in public-
I'm kind of in the
middle of something, Ares.
I completely understand.
I don't wanna be a bother.
Wait, what country is this?
Is this Idaho?
What's on your mind, Ares?
Maya, I wanna be
back on the team.
I could train like you did.
I'm a Hyperion
through and through.
- Ares.
- Look, I know the Professor and I
have had our fair
share of headbutting.
I wasn't perfect.
Hell, sometimes I
was even a burden.
But look at these!
I've photocopied
some news articles
I believe highlights some
of the great work I've done.
Like this one, when I assisted
in the Atlantic
Pipeline rupture.
Or this one when I assisted
in the USS Sherman expedition.
And I didn't even
complain when I was asked
to supervise
negotiations in Korea.
Even though the dear
leader was super handsy.
Ares, please be understanding.
You've done a wonderful job.
I could do more, Maya.
The Professor's firm
on this, it's time to go.
You're gonna have all the
money you'll ever need.
Don't make waves again.
Let it go.
You go home now, Ares.
What
happened, who was it?
Maya.
Hey, what's your name again?
Delano.
Can you give
me a hand up here?
What did Maya say?
She's
bringing the Professor.
- Delano.
- Yes?
I need you to help
me block this door, okay?
So maybe some boxes.
Do you have anything bigger?
Yeah.
- What else have you got?
- I was thinking about
what we talked about
earlier, remember?
If things were
to get out of hand,
instead of just handing
over the badges,
why don't we just use 'em?
It hasn't come to that yet.
Yeah but I still kind of think
we should at least be ready
to use the powers.
Ansel.
I need to know that
you're doing this
for the same reason I am.
Oh, of course,
this is about Ruby,
getting your daughter back.
- Right.
- Yeah.
So we stick to the plan.
We do what they ask,
give them the badges
and they'll let her go.
Okay, but how do we
know that they will?
If we were to use the badges,
it just would make
more sense if,
Ansel.
You know that the badges
don't make you happy.
You're so much
more than some guy
who can lift a
car over his head.
Besides, how many
people need cars
lifted over their heads anyway?
Our guest this evening
requires no introduction.
He is known and beloved
throughout the world
as the father and
leader of the world's
most famous family
of superheroes.
He is of course, Professor
Ruckus Mandulbaum.
Welcome to the show, Professor.
Thank you for
having me, Meredith.
I suppose we should
also welcome Mercury.
Yes.
Say hello, Mercury.
Adventure awaits!
Brilliant.
And how's the family?
The team is just,
don't tell me, it's right
on the tip of my tongue.
Marvelous?
Why yes, yes, thank
you, marvelous, marvelous.
Now you're in the middle of a
transition, are you not?
With the second
team being replaced?
Yes, we are retiring
the second generation
and currently in the process
of finding a new team.
We do have a new member.
- Apollo.
- Yes.
That's me.
And
how is he coming?
I don't know what you're saying.
You adopted children
from the original team.
Vista and Ansel.
Yes, that's correct.
But not Maya,
she was an adult already.
No, we hired Maya.
And why was that?
Well, Meredith.
Because the team
would be required
to travel from the
highest mountain
to the deepest ocean,
we realized that some
adult supervision
might be necessary
on certain missions.
And when I met Maya,
she was a very
responsible young woman
and I knew she would fit in
very well with the children.
Now when you were replacing
the original children,
you mentioned the concept
of using robots instead.
Yes.
I was noodling on robots.
But you know, in the end,
to be a Hyperion one must
have heart and compassion.
And of course,
robots can't replace
the soul required
to be on this team.
Well, Professor,
there were many groups
who read into that
original desire
to use robots as a
sign that perhaps
there were more problems
under the surface of the team
than were being revealed to us.
Is that accurate?
Problems?
I can't think of any.
Hello.
Sorry to interrupt.
Professor, we have
a bit of a problem.
What?
A problem.
Oh gosh.
I do beg your pardon, but,
Problems?
Not really, just late
for an appointment.
So sorry.
Thank you.
Hyperion Hall,
known throughout the world
as the headquarters of the
world famous superhero team.
Behind the walls of
this elegant structure,
world leaders have
sought the assistance
of the Hyperions.
It is also, however, the home
where Professor Mandulbaum
has raised his children.
And like millions of
fathers around the world,
Professor Mandulbaum
has had his fair share
of challenges bringing
up his children
Ansel and Vista.
Who can forget the
public rebellions
of his often disobedient Vista?
After several very public
attempts at running away,
young Vista in her most
rebellious act of all
publicly condemned the Professor
on the eve of her
ill-conceived wedding
to Wes Harrison, the
Andy Warhol superstar
and former television
child actor.
In spite of the Professor's
unconditional support and love,
Vista abandoned the family
leaving millions of
concerned citizens
wondering if the team they
had come to love and rely on
was on the brink of collapse.
But Professor Mandulbaum
saw an opportunity,
an opportunity to refresh the
team that had grown stale.
And so after releasing Ansel,
the Professor introduced the
world to three new youths,
leaving Maya to
train the newcomers.
Every few years, the Hyperions
will retire the old class
and welcome the new,
thus ensuring continued
safety for the human race
for generations to come.
In the famous words
of the Professor,
"May we forget the
mistakes of our past
and look with anticipation
to the future.
Leave behind the old
and embrace the new."
Grab a pen.
You're about to
make a statement.
It's Vista and Ansel.
They've taken hostages.
Vista and Ansel?
I spoke to her, Ruckus.
Face to face.
I bet she talked him into it.
Do the police know it's them?
I don't think they
know about Ansel
but they did see her.
In uniform.
In uniform?
Oh, that's just great.
That's just great, that's
just be-loody marvelous.
Ruckus, Vista needs you.
Oh, I bet she does.
I bet she does!
The problem is, Maya,
and you can correct me if I'm
wrong, even though I'm not.
I seem to remember
her telling me
she never wants to see me again.
- Ever.
- She wouldn't tell me what was going on.
Can't you see what
she's trying to do?
She's trying to destroy me!
She's in trouble.
Yes, that's a great way
to ask for help, isn't it?
Taking hostages.
Wait.
These are how she's
been asking for help.
I thought I told you
to get rid of those.
You're making such
a mess in here.
Akiko just cleaned!
Every month she writes
you another letter.
The least you could
do is read one.
I don't need to read them.
I know what's in them.
They're probably just
asking for more money.
Why can't you
just let that go?
She was upset.
Of course she's upset.
Ripped from an orphanage,
dragged to a beautiful mansion
where there's, what's this?
Caviar, open trays of caviar
all over the house,
I mean who has that?
Hmm?
I mean that's a
little off, but still.
Forced to have
super powers, fame.
Maybe she doesn't care
about the powers and fame.
Who doesn't care
about power and fame?
I mean what is she,
some kind of an alien?
I mean what more can I give?
All I do is give, give, give.
And who's on my side
at the end of the day?
I am.
Nobody.
- I wanna see the cork.
- Hmm?
The cork.
You have it, right?
Yes.
I'll never show it to you.
You don't lie to me, Ruckus.
Maya!
Oh, sod it.
What did I say?
Maya!
Maya?
God, I do wish you'd
stop rushing off,
you know how I hate
chasing you like this.
Why are you packing?
Are you going somewhere?
How long have you been
lying about the cork?
Do you know how dangerous
that could have been?
What if it fell into
the wrong hands?
Well, it didn't.
Bugger.
Vista said
something today.
It really got me
thinking, Ruckus.
Do share the wisdom.
Can't wait to hear this one.
I'm sure it's a real doozy.
She said you loved the team,
not the people on it.
You don't really
believe that, do you?
I'm not sure what I
believe anymore, Ruckus.
All I know is that I'm tired.
I'm tired of saying
goodbye to people I love.
I'm tired of the fight and
I'm tired of the burden.
Ah.
There you are.
I'm tired of taking sides.
I'm tired of you disappearing.
Look!
I really didn't mean
to rattle your cage.
Would you at least have
the decency to stay-
Ruckus, look at me.
This isn't just about
the cork, Ruckus.
It's about us, all of us.
I wish you would just say
what it is you want to say.
I understand Vista hurt you.
I know you're scared.
I know you loved those two kids
and I know why you dismissed
Ansel when she left.
But Ruckus, I'm not sure
they know how you feel.
Every penny I spent
should have told them.
The PR team said I
had to start fresh
with whole new Hyperions.
What choice did I have?
Like it or not,
you formed a family.
You have two children
and you have me.
We've never understood
where we stand, Ruckus.
What are we to you?
What am I?
Professor?
Yes?
What is it?
I've just received word
that we're about to hear
a prepared statement
from one of the culprits
in the museum hostage situation.
Again, ladies and gentlemen,
this is going to be live.
And five, four, three.
My name is Vista Mandulbaum.
My brother Ansel and I
have taken four hostages.
We've come for one thing,
our Titan Badges.
The badges are currently
locked in a case
that only Professor
Mandulbaum can unlock.
Nobody will leave this building
until we have those badges.
Well.
That appears to be all we're going to be
hearing from the scene, so in summation,
from what we've just heard live,
Professor, what do you think?
Yeah.
At least we know where we stand.
Dice, you
get to roll first.
All right.
So everyone gets
a pack of cards.
That's for you.
Thanks.
And you get to choose
whoever you wanna be, yeah.
Was spotted
over the eastern seaboard.
Well, it's
difficult to see
through the
tremendous smoke here
on the streets, but
I believe, I see yes!
Ladies and gentlemen, I
could see Ansel Mandulbaum.
He's carrying, he's
emerging from the haze
and he's carrying,
oh I can't believe
what I'm seeing.
He's carrying the
missile above his head!
Ansel Mandulbaum
has saved us all!
He stopped the missile!
Ansel has saved countless lives
and I have never seen
such a display of heroism
and self-sacrifice
in all my life.
Ansel Mandulbaum, the
Hyperion super team
has caught a rogue
soviet missile.
The crowd is cheering.
What a moment to
witness in person.
Citizens are in tears
and they are reaching out
to thank the young hero.
Hey, Mr. Ansel?
You wanna get in on this?
I'm hot, I'm tired,
this is like flying coach.
- Oh, new player.
- Here you go,
here are your blue cards.
Hey, all right.
You get to roll first.
But first you have
to choose a guy
from the characters
left in this box.
Did someone take Ansel?
I did, I'm Ansel.
I hope you don't have
a problem with that.
I was kinda hoping
I could be Ansel.
Hey, look, let's
see who's in here?
Okay, look there!
Here's Ares, you could be him.
He's pretty neat, he's blue.
Yeah, yeah.
- That's fine, yeah, yeah.
- Great, that's okay?
Okay good, okay good, let's go.
- All right, so.
- Were you there?
Can we all focus here?
Ant, can we all
focus for a minute?
Ansel is supposed
to roll the dice.
I don't feel like playing.
Okay, that
was very dramatic.
Okay well he
seemed kinda upset.
You were bullying him.
Don't put it on me.
I think he has some
emotional issues.
What'd I do wrong?
No, no.
You haven't done anything wrong.
Well, that's
not entirely true.
We did warn you about
seeing Vista, Ansel.
I missed her.
She just wanted to talk.
But didn't we tell you
not to talk to her, Ansel?
She wants to ruin the team.
Dad, I'm sorry I saw Vista.
But I wanna stay.
My boy, you've
done a grand job.
Maybe it's for the best.
Now you can be free to
think of all the things
that you would like to do,
like what would you like
to be when you grow up?
This, I like this.
Well,
the team just feels,
we all feel that
perhaps it's time
for someone else to take
on the responsibility.
Do I have to move out?
Of course not.
Well I'm sure we can secure
you a wonderful place nearby.
So you can visit as
often as you'd like.
My point is,
if you need someone to talk,
I'd be more than
happy to volunteer.
Yeah I'll keep that in mind.
Everybody stay here.
Stop right there!
Is he
SWAT or something?
He's not a cop.
Are you?
What
happened to you?
He kicked me in my chest.
Broke the pen in my shirt.
My brand new pen.
But who is he?
Don't give me that.
He's yours, isn't he?
How did he get in here?
When will
I have the badges?
You're in the building.
I wanna talk to Ruby.
First you
deliver the badges.
No, you put her on now.
Mommy?
Hi, honey.
Are you okay?
Where are you?
Mommy's just picking
something up for you.
I'll be right there.
I'm coming to get you.
Okay.
Are they being nice to you?
Are you watching TV?
I'm losing my patience.
You have 30 minutes to
get me those badges.
You're here.
Ah, good evening
everyone.
Let's greet the fans.
- Mhmm.
- And then straight up to Vista.
Right, will do.
Ah, hello, hello, how are you,
nice to meet you, hello.
Are they treating you well here?
Very well, thank you.
- Professor, Alvin Delano.
- Hello, hello.
I'm the curator.
Ah, yes, yes.
All your creations here.
Quite the stain
you've got there.
Yes, exploding pen.
Hi
Professor, I'm Sarah.
I own the paper.
I have this book
that I used to know.
Oh yes yes of course.
What are you gonna say?
Just that we need
his thumbprint.
Mr. Professor,
would you please
- sign this for me?
- Yes?
Ah, oh, what's this?
It's you,
a mask of you.
Really?
Ha, doesn't really look
like me.
Eh, it's pretty close.
You gonna tell him about Ruby?
Ready?
Yes, I suppose so.
I must say, the hostages seem
pretty upbeat, don't you?
Unnaturally so.
What's this?
Ah, there you are.
Congratulations, Vista.
It's a real fine mess
you've gotten yourself
and Ansel into.
I gotta keep an eye on
those people out there.
Wait, wait, don't
you mean hostages?
I think that's what you
call people you hold
against their will.
You do realize that armed
robbery is a felony, don't you?
You have any idea of the strings
I'm gonna have to pull?
To get you out of this mess, hm?
I'll watch them.
No, you stay right here, Maya.
Why does she have to be here?
I don't know, why does
Ansel have to be here?
Because he's my
partner in this.
Oh, please.
It's true.
That doesn't
sound like my boy.
Not my Ansel.
Is it true?
What?
That you're half to
blame for this mess?
Maya, would you do me a favor
and escort Ansel outside
for a moment please?
Fine.
Shouldn't I at least
stay to help explain?
It's okay.
I'll meet you outside.
- 15 years and
- Of course the first thing
- that comes out of your mouth is about you.
- Nothing has changed.
- You're still just a spoiled
- You think the whole world
- revolves around you!
- Little child!
- Money, money...
- You have everything anyone could want to have.
You won't be satisfied
until you've burned...
Fixate on the one time someone didn't
fall on your stupid precious little line.
You're still a spoiled
little child!
It's good to see you, Ansel.
Really?
Yeah, of course.
I've missed you.
Things aren't the
same without you.
I've missed you too.
Are you still in Detroit?
No, I moved a few years ago.
Now I'm living with
Vista, actually.
Oh, really?
Haven't you been
receiving our checks?
I have.
You're sharing
them with Vista.
She needs me.
Her and Ruby both.
Who's Ruby?
You're spoiled
and you're selfish!
You have any idea
what you've done?!
You and your stupid persona.
I beg your pardon?
You don't even know when you're on television
anymore. You can't tell the difference.
Have I ever met the real
Ruckus Mandulbaum anyway?
I know who I am.
I don't have to
prove it to anyone.
Least of all, you.
But you want your
little badge, don't you?
You always get what you want.
That's her.
That's Ruby Red.
Why didn't Vista tell
us she had a daughter?
How old is she?
She's five.
Want them so badly?
You think these
little bits of plastic
will bring you happiness?
Fine, they're all yours,
whatever you want.
That's all I've
been asking for.
Give, give, give,
that's all I ever do.
And we have an audience.
Let the grand show begin.
It's all yours.
Well?
Aren't you gonna put it on?
It's a decoy.
It's a decoy?
Well of course it's a decoy.
You don't actually think
I'd allow the real badges
to be out in the open in a
traveling exhibit, do you?
Dad, please.
It's Dad now, is it?
Ladies and gentlemen, I do
apologize for the delay.
This'll all be over momentarily.
In the meantime,
please help yourselves
to some Hyperion juice boxes
from the gift store.
You don't understand.
I understand when
I'm being manipulated.
Ruckus, stop!
Maya, they're
making me do this.
Enough
of this nonsense.
Ansel, you can come with us.
Dad, you need to listen.
Ruckus, hear them out.
I've heard all I need to hear.
You can't leave us!
They have my daughter!
Did you say daughter?
Ruckus.
Hmm.
What an adorable little girl.
Tell me, is she a friend's
kid or a union actress?
Because if she has talent,
I may be able to use her
in an upcoming episode.
Do you honestly think
I would lie about this?
I've seen you do worse.
Don't do this.
Put it in the case.
I hope it makes you happy.
I knew you'd end up abusing
the power I gave you.
Baby, what are you doing?
Let's go.
Don't even listen to him.
It's ours.
Now you haven't
given me anything.
- Sir?
- Hmm?
What's
the situation?
Well there's nothing
more I can do in there.
So I suggest you go in and
resolve it your way, Captain.
No, hold that.
Ruckus, wait.
Captain, it's a bit
more complicated
than we expected in there.
Can you please be
patient and hold off?
Have the negotiator call
and tell Vista we'll be back
within the hour.
Right away, ma'am.
Nobody enter that
building until we return.
- Captain!
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, Miss Maya?
We just received
this message for you.
Professor?
Hmm?
Professor, I'm needed
at the White House.
Can you just go
home and stay there,
we'll talk when I'm back.
I'm not gonna be long.
Fine.
Just teleport me
back to the office
and then you can read the
President his bedtime story.
You're not going
anywhere with me.
You acted like a
stubborn ass back there.
Well how am I
supposed to get home?
I had the car brought
here, I'll find you a driver.
Well what happened
to my driver?
Ah, for God's sake.
To heck with it all,
I'll drive myself.
Ruckus!
Captain!
The Professor's never
driven a car before.
Can you find someone to
drive him home, please?
On it.
Thank you.
That man will do.
Time's up.
Excuse me.
Would you mind picking a station
and sticking to it please?
Thank you.
Oh, what a day, what a day.
What are you looking at, hmm?
Like you're so brave.
Wanna know what kind
of a day I've had?
I'll tell you.
I'm a grandfather.
Vista has a daughter.
Suit up for adventure!
Hmm?
Oh, you wanna see?
There.
Yes.
All the badges.
They want all the badges to
release my granddaughter.
Your life's work.
Yes, yes it is.
How can you give them away?
You can't destroy them.
What choice do I have?
What else can be done?
No, this won't do.
This won't do at all.
- Sir?
- Hmm?
Miss Maya insisted that
you stayed at Hyperion Hall
until her return.
Tell me.
How long have you worked for me?
Oh, 10 years, Professor.
And in those 10 years
have you ever known me
not to do whatever I wanted?
No, sir.
Although I do appreciate
your concern, Lucy.
I'm Lucy, sir.
Hmm?
I'm Lucy
and she's Marian.
Right, yes.
Yes, I knew that.
Ah, okay, right.
Evening, Professor.
Hmm, Ares.
Well, well, well, I
should have guessed.
We were beginning to wonder
if you were ever coming back.
I could be mistaken but I think
this may be your first
time in a room with a gun.
Yes, you might be
right about that.
So.
Kidnapping eh?
I learned from the best.
Oh it's amazing what
other people's kids
can get done for you.
Isn't it?
Yes, well I'm not
entirely sure what it is
you've gotten done here.
Oh, I've gotten
the world famous
Professor Mandulbaum to
hand deliver my Titan Badge.
Oh, I have it, yes.
I think I'll take it now.
No, no,
no, I don't think so.
He doesn't get it, does he?
He doesn't understand
what it's like.
You triggered something
in us, Professor.
There's no going back.
I can't live like them.
Look, Ares.
I want my badge.
There's nothing more to say.
Why don't you take
the guns off of them?
Because if you think
about it logically,
they're really in
the same boat as you.
I still need them.
You think I'm stupid?
I can't just steal my own badge.
Then what?
Live the rest of
my life in hiding
knowing the whole
world is after me?
It's no secret how you feel
about Vista, Professor.
She's the most hated person
in the world 'cause of you.
If you hadn't seen
it for yourself
you would have never believed
she wasn't the one to blame.
And Ansel, this guy
wants his powers back
more than anyone.
His life's pathetic.
A gift
of an old fool.
Look, Ares.
The badge.
It's beyond repair.
Let me see it.
I'm not sure you
want to, but all right.
That's all of it.
Why would you do that?
Make me another one.
No.
I'm afraid that's quite
out of the question.
You'll make me another one!
Or I'll kill everyone
in this room!
You're not going
to kill anyone, Ares.
When did you get it?
Wait.
Okay.
I think I get it.
Ooh.
Shots fired, shots fired!
Squad A, come with me.
Squad B, maintain the perimeter,
keep those people back!
Goddammit, Garrett, come on.
Give me my gun, give me my gun!
I don't wanna miss the show.
All right.
Ugh.
Stop, Vista.
Wait, just wait.
I would never hurt her.
You know that.
I had no choice,
I needed it back.
Vista, it's him you're angry at.
It's the Professor!
He did this.
Ruby, darling.
Go in that stall
and lock the door.
That's it.
Now, block your ears
and sing our song.
I'll be right there.
Ansel!
Hey!
Oh, it's good to see you.
Wait.
Where's the Professor?
Professor?
- Professor?
Professor!
Maya!
Ansel!
Medic, I need your help.
Get someone
over here, right away.
No, no, no, no, no!
No, Dad, Dad.
I need you
to look over here.
Stay with me.
But paramedics
were reportedly seen
rushing Professor
Ruckus Mandulbaum,
the world famous leader
of the Hyperions,
believed to George Washington
University Hospital
where he remained overnight.
He is now back at
home in Hyperion Hall,
recovering where thousands
of fans and supporters
have gathered to share
their messages of love.
Sorry, Ansel.
I have so,
so many blueprints.
It's okay.
No, its not okay.
Hey, Ruby Red.
Let's give your mom some time
to talk to granddad, okay?
All right, come on.
Bye.
Hey.
I don't know what to say.
I love you too, Dad.
Just like
your parents at home,
I sometimes need to help
my children fall asleep.
When counting sheep
doesn't cut the mustard
for my girl Vista, I
sing her this song.
Now arriving
at 7th Street Station.
This is the last
station on the red line.
Please mind your step
upon exiting the train.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull