An earthquake devastated Tokyo and its vicinity on September 1, 1923.
It disrupted the lives of 1.9 million and killed 105 thousand.
In ensuing chaos and paranoia, vigilante groups,
police and soldiers massacred Koreans and the socialists.
On September 16, Amakasu, a military police lieutenant,
brutally murdered Sakae Osugi, his wife and their 6-year-old nephew.
Osugi was a leading anarchist.
To the voice I hear from the north
I yell.
Tell me where a wonderful country is.
For guilty and weak people to live.
Where is it?
Ready?
And...fight!
Break up!
Immediately!
Sir, it was an accident...
You heard me. Break up right now!
The Great Kanto Earthquake
was felt 50 km away from Tokyo.
Don't panic!
Quit fooling around and...
do your chores!
Very good.
Kiku!
Yes.
Here I go!
- Lower!
- OK.
"Tamaiwa Women's Sumo"
Don't rest!
Go in harder!
Once again!
Roll
or you'll die!
Yes!
You left your life behind for this!
Go home and plow!
- I'll stay!
- Come on!
Next!
Out of my way!
Kiku (Chrysanthemum)
Women's sumo originated
in the mid-18th century.
It's mostly forgotten that
women's sumo was popular in
rural areas up until the 1960s.
In the 1920s there were
over 20 women's sumo stables.
Some were small while
the big ones had 30 wrestlers.
Most stables came from Yamagata
and toured all over Japan.
Let me through!
Osaka, September 20
We're not just socialists!
We're anarchists!
We oppose and deconstruct everything.
Anarchism
It deems the establishment harmful and
upholds free association.
"Tetsu Nakahama, The Empty Party Leader"
Who would be able to spare
20,000 yen?
We're not here to borrow money.
Your chairman is a duke.
I'm here to collect what his family
owes us from way back.
You might have forgotten that debt.
Sin the duke's ancestor started the
Onin War 600 years ago
his family has ripped us off
billions of yen.
Repay us.
I represent all proletariats.
Come on, pay us back now!
Are you mocking our cause?
Great.
You are hilarious.
I love the bluffs you try to pull off.
For making me laugh.
I can't afford 20,000 yen so
I'll give you an IOU.
Mr. Morimoto, are you trying to
trick us?
Don't be silly.
I'm a man of my word.
Alright.
I'll honor a man's promise.
Guillotine.
Championing a free society?
Sure they will!
They were known as "robbers"
because they robbed capitalists
to finance their activism.
The Guillotine Society
Excuse me!
Most of the money they robbed
went on drinks and women.
- Hurry up and cum!
- Don't rush me.
Tetsu!
Damn it!
Don't just barge in!
I was almost there.
You ruined it!
Dai, I thought you...
quit womanizing.
Mr. Osugi was killed!
What?
What's up?
What is it?
"Osugi was killed in prison
by Military Police Lieutenant Amakasu."
It's their scheme.
The authorities use the recent disaster
to control people.
That way they can mobilize citizens
for their own use!
While the fearful citizen
are paralyzed.
He's right!
It's time for a riot!
An assassination! Anything!
Get out of my way!
What are the merits of a world
run by terrorists?
It's not about merits!
It's about retribution.
We rob rich people every day.
Does that make it a revolution?
Enough!
Let's eat.
It's too hot for a hot pot!
Tofu was on sale.
Naka, no more poisonous
mushrooms, please.
Shut up, coward!
8 days ago,
Osaka Textiles LLC
Hurry up!
- Oh no!
- What?
It's not him!
Kiichi Naka shot a wrong man.
At an Osaka Textiles union meeting
Naka was beaten up and fired.
He meant to shoot and rob one of
the executives, Ichiji Iio.
But he mistakenly shot an executive
named Otokichi Shoji.
Ogawa?
Ogawa is back!
Tokyo is hell!
Yoshio Ogawa, ex-monk
Have some water.
Come and eat, monk.
I've made up my mind.
I'll sacrifice myself
for people and the world!
Thank you.
As Shusui Kotoku said.
"Where water flows there's a conduit.
Ask for no reward, just act!"
Yes, we'll kill bad politicians
who bully citizens!
Yes!
You keep saying the same thing!
You do nothing! You're our enemies!
Yunoshin, stop!
Let's act.
How?
Avenge the bug-eyed man.
We'll kill Amakasu?
He's detained.
He has a brother in Matsuzaka.
Matsuzaka?
It's not far.
What? You want to kill a boy?
Yes, he's a substitute.
What do you say, Yunoshin?
He's innocent...!
He's from the Amakasu family.
If you insist, go.
I'll kill someone more important.
You big shot.
We have no choice.
Who'll go?
Come on!
It's hell in here!
You're right.
It is hell.
Who wants more?
You know, the weak
won't survive this time.
Goro Amakasu!
The assassination failed
Let go of me!
Yunoshin Tanaka was arrested
Are you okay?
Mmm. This is my plan.
We need to do this to
keep Guillotine Society alive.
I won't run anymore.
They're here.
Give us your money for the revolution!
The Kosaka Murder Case
October 16
Furuta!
Hurry up, Furuta!
Daijiro Furuta, wanted for murder
Tetsu Nakahama has a bladder infection
from syphilis
You guys!
The 4 of you only stole this much!
He was supposed to have 10,000 yen!
- He did.
- Where?
Where is it?
The man who Furuta chased, had it.
Sorry.
You killed a man and got no money!
What's done is done.
Sorry I couldn't join you.
Where's Kurachi?
I bet he ran as usual.
- Again!
- He's all talk!
Tetsu!
It stinks!
- Don't wash your testicles here!
- Lay off, it hurts!
The police!
Run!
Stop!
Stop right there!
Go now!
Are you OK?
But Tetsu...
I know what I'll do!
What?
Something even Shusui Kotoku
couldn't do!
- Kill the Emperor?
- No.
That wouldn't be worth risking
my life for.
The Regent Prince.
Killing him will
unnerve the Emperor.
Come on, our enemy is in Tokyo!
The Chrysanthemum and The Guillotine
Kiku.
What's that smell?
Oh, no...!
Add water and no one will know.
Tokachi River!
You could have taken care of it!
A recession followed the earthquake.
Refugees left Tokyo to survive.
Navy Funabashi Radio Station
(10 km east of Tokyo)
Opportunists sold pig feed
and even compost to the refugees.
They were known as "Food scrappers".
Go away!
l know you can't pay!
Come and get it.
Only 2 sen a bowl.
It has fish, it's nutritious.
The authorities are busy
with the disaster now...
Let some male spectators
wrestle your girls!
Or get the girls to show their tits.
Right.
I agreed to sponsor you in these
hard times.
We should work together to make money.
Sir, we'll do our best to
make it worth your while.
Leave it to me.
Well, I guess you know best.
Don Sakata has a point, Boss.
- Shut up.
- Right.
It's tasteless.
Sorry.
You burned it?
You obviously added water.
Go cook some more!
You ate it up like a pig.
Who said that?
Give her a break.
She learned a lesson.
She's right. Get along, girls.
Says he.
In hard times like this
we have to suck it up.
What's that smirk?
You have an attitude!
You fucking with me!
- You hit me!
- Stop it!
Lay off!
Stop them!
Do something.
Yeah.
By the way, we're not showing our tits.
Sumo is our thing, Boss.
I know!
Sanji, hey!
Sanji!
Damn it...
Break it up!
Stop it!
Yona lsland from Ryukyu
I'll make a new pot, Plum Country.
Teach me, please.
How to be strong like you.
Please teach me,
I promise I'll do my best.
Attention everyone, from the east
to the west.
We're Tamaiwa Troupe, Imperial Japan's
women's sumo!
We're evergreen pine trees as
seasons change.
We appreciate your support
over the generations...
We will remain unchanged!
They wrestle and their tits
wobble around!
Don't their tits get
in the way?
You look like a spook!
Were you a sideshow freak?
His Majesty Emperor issued the
Proclamation to Lift National Morale.
His Majesty disapproves of excess and
harmful ideologies!
The socialists corrupt urban
culture and demand freedom.
It caused heavenly imbalance
and the earthquake!
Farmers make the best soldiers.
Imperial Japan will
surpass the West.
We must educate Asia's barbarians!
The Chinese, Koreans and the Taiwanese.
We'll make them
His Majesty Emperor's subjects!
We don't have enough enlisted soldiers
to win an inevitable war.
So us veterans will be called
to the battlefield!
You!
What's going on?
What's this?
No more vigilantes!
Veterans must raise funds
and help with disaster relief.
You know about the order!
What about the riots that
the Koreans and socialists caused?
Who's giving these orders?
The higher-ups.
We have foreign pressure.
Our national integrity is at stake.
Break up!
- You have no right!
- Control yourself.
You sold out!
What are you saying?
You're a disgrace to the Emperor.
What?
Wait a minute!
Wait!
They're dressed.
Not when they wrestle, I hope.
I hope they'll be naked.
Hey!
They won't be naked, fools!
Absolutely not.
I, Officer Maruman, won't allow such
a perverse show!
Go on.
Move on!
You missed your breakfast, right?
But...
Before someone sees you.
Is your period regular?
No, but...
Abort it.
You don't need the trouble.
What's that for...?
Did my husband send you?
What?
Kiku, the Boss is looking for you!
It's all muddy
but you can eat it.
Kiku!
Wait!
Hey, who is that man?
Osugi, the man with the stare!
I'm in front of your skeleton
calling out to you.
We demand that a fixed minimum wage is set.
Labor Union Meeting
Anarchism!
Long live, anarchism!
He remains silent.
He watches me and smirks
disapprovingly.
We're taking over this meeting!
Sakae Osugi's famous meeting takeover.
Workers! You're not slaves
to capitalists.
Follow us and find a new way to work!
The wide white of his eyes
is wet with
passionate black tears
sparkling like waves in the sun.
And he stares at me.
You should
t-t-take advantage of this!
Practice a new way of living.
That's not all.
You should also think for yourself!
"Look at his face,
he won't live long," I thought.
"So you say," he told me.
"You won't live long either."
"That's fine with me."
"I want to die before I'm 30."
"You know what that means?" he asks.
"It means
I've already outlived you."
Listen to me! We're not their slaves!
Act directly!
Direct action by laborers
is the most effective activism!
Watch me!
This is the power we have!
Observe the power that we have!
Take him away.
Watch me!
This is the power we have!
With that daring smirk, he stares
with eyes of deep white.
Tetsu! I couldn't catch
anything for breakfast.
That's how it is sometimes.
Kyu?
Genjiro Muraki
Kyutaro Wada
Kyu.
You sloth!
Sorry to wake you, Gen.
To avenge Osugi, we'll target
the martial law commander Fukuda.
Tanaka, the Minister of Army
and Shoriki, the National Police
Agency's director.
This just wasn't on my mind.
You're too impulsive.
Come on, Old man.
Good morning, Furuta.
Hello.
Did you two sleep well?
Yes.
Wada.
Yes?
Osugi shouldn't have taken part in
the rice riot in Osaka.
He was targeted because he was
in the papers.
"That's what riots are for!"
"The Bolshevists did nothing
b-b-but watch Osugi in action!"
"Then we ignited it!"
"T-t-t-the nation found us
too menacing to handle!"
Right?
The Bolshevists were arrested.
The time for activism is over.
- That's negative...
- Listen!
The Guillotine Association
plan to kill the Regent Prince.
Are you serious?
Seeing Tokyo's devastation,
I thought...
Nature can be destructive
but it didn't destroy civilization.
Only people can upturn it.
Kyu and Gen. I know you want
to avenge Osugi's murder.
Help us achieve our objective.
- Do you realize what's at stake?
- At stake?
- Terrorists kill!
- I know!
I'm not finished.
You never decide, it's boring.
The women's sumo troupe is in town...
Let's go.
- You can t!
- Why not?
Because...it's sumo
and they'll be naked.
That's why we'll go, genius!
You ask me to quit sumo
But how could I?
Sumo is like the most
dashing man in the world
Look at this!
Dai, come on!
Imperial Japan's Women's sumo!
How's that?
Go, Plum Country!
Amazing!
Strip off!
Attention please!
Imperial Japan Certified!
Women's sumo!
Let's hear it for our wrestlers,
ladies and gentlemen!
Out of the East corner is
Mogami River!
Out of the West corner is
Little Cherry!
They'll strip off...
They're both tiny...
What! They're not getting naked?
Go, Cherry!
Destroy all enemies!
Go!
That's good!
Cherry, hold on!
Amazing!
Cherry won!
Tokachi River!
Go, Tokachi!
Tokachi!
Look at me!
Look at me.
You're the best, Tokachi.
So good!
Beat her!
Go, Brocade Waka!
Go, Mount Hideri!
My girl won!
Waka, Japan's best!
You did well, Mount Hideri!
Brocade Waka won!
Fun spoilers...
Out of the East corner,
Tiger Katsu!
Kyu and Gen, you might have
been tailed.
Maybe so...
but we lost them.
Yona the spook!
Did you go to Ryukyu?
Yes, it was a propaganda tour to
recruit activists. It was fun.
You planned to kill Hara
so Kyu went to Ryukyu and Osugi
to an entomology lab in Gifu.
To avoid being named as suspects.
Nakaoka killed
the Prime Minister, not us.
Tiger Katsu!
Wonderful!
Go back to Ryukyu!
The Emperor's Tokyo is in ruins
and you shamelessly watch
women's sumo!
Shame on you!
We came to offer solace
to the refugees.
We have the legitimate patronage of
Mr. Kantaro Sakata.
Sir.
With his encouragement
we decided to hold a 10-day
tournament here.
You beard him, Chairman.
He's a veteran. Stay low.
Sanji.
Out of the East corner, Kiku!
Out of the West corner,
Camellia Tama!
Beat her!
Go, Kiku!
Give us an upset!
Tama won!
Out of the East corner,
Plum Country!
Out of the West corner,
Haguro Cherry!
Listen up!
One sign of anything immoral,
I'll shut down this promotion!
Mark my words.
Understood?
- Plum Country won!
- Number one!
I had a great time.
Too bad no one was naked.
Somewhere, friends we've never met
are fighting.
It's good to know.
That's slick.
We've decided on a target.
General Fukuda, the
martial law commander.
- We'll join you.
- Now you're talking!
Then...
What?
Ready money.
Are you robbing us, Tetsu?
Certainly not!
You're the man!
...With little money.
That's all I have.
We'll wait for our chance.
You know your way back.
Take care of yourself, Gen.
I'm not that frail.
Listen, Furuta.
Whatever you do,
don't waste your life.
Long live anarchy!
Hurrah!
Wanna help us?
Hey, wait!
She's so stuck-up!
Sorry about lunch...
Was the Boss upset?
No. It tasted good.
One day you'll have a gingko-leaf knot.
Like a champion? I hope so.
What did you two talk about?
Watch out for Cherry.
That's right.
She has a thing for women.
Huh?
Watch out.
What's this?
Tokachi. Oh, Tokachi...
If you want, you can move
into my place.
Come on, why not?
Look.
OK?
Tokachi.
Who are you?
Help!
Siberian Intervention veterans got
a medal of honor and pensions.
Within a year
many of them had committed crimes
and the honor was revoked.
Where have you been?
How about working for a change?
Hatsu.
See if Mom's OK.
Hello!
The sumo wrestlers.
- But sirs...
- Are they here?
- Tetsu!
- Don't worry.
Sorry, wrong room!
Sorry.
Wrestlers!
The wrestlers are here but...
- Thanks.
- Wait!
Hi, there!
Who are you?
- They let themselves in...
- I'm Suzuki, a novelist.
I'm working on a novel
at my second house.
He's my assistant.
The sumo wrestlers impressed me
so much today.
They are a symbol of today's women!
I want to write about them.
I'd love to interview them.
I see.
In particular Tokachi River
and Kiku.
So we'll join you tonight
if you don't mind.
We don't even allow
fans to meet our girls.
How about them?
They're sponsors.
Oh, come on! I'll sit here.
No you won't, sir.
I'm not moving.
I'm gone!
Forget about them, Chairman.
Have a drink.
Pardon me.
My fellas worked with you veterans
as vigilantes, remember?
But my boys are all idiots so
they harassed anyone
they thought was Korean.
I guess some were Koreans but
many were just country folk.
They killed them anyway
and were jailed.
None of you got jailed?
Tetsu.
You hear that?
Imperial Army soldiers
aren't so foolish!
Hey, come on!
Wait!
Why are you so upset?
Drink up and forget it!
It was a miserable show today.
It was just a bunch of guys
out to seduce you.
Really.
Your pussy is your attraction,
not sumo.
Say that again!
Sure!
Stop acting like a hooker.
Stop it!
Let go!
Everyone knows
that you turn tricks
wherever we go.
You don't know what it's like!
Katsu!
Lay off, you two!
You thief!
It's mine!
What's wrong with me
making use of my body?
Sumo is the same thing!
You think you're special?
This money...
Come on, everybody pick it up!
Pick it up!
We share profits.
That's enough!
Katsu!
You're my niece but this is too much.
We all have our troubles!
Don't take your frustration
out on others!
It's mine!
No one can have it except me!
Stop acting like a dad.
Katsu?
What happened?
Get off me!
Tokachi must be Korean...
The Korean miners in my
neighborhood spoke like her.
You heard her, Cherry?
I don't care
if she's Korean or not.
You don't?
Tetsu.
Huh?
We need bombs.
With explosives, we can't fail.
Guns are no good. We need bombs.
I guess so...
Are you thinking about
those sumo women?
We were tailed.
Ouch!
That's not the welcome I hoped for!
Tokachi?
- Are you OK?
- Tokachi!
Did it hurt?
I'm fine.
So this is the second house
of a novelist!
You said you wanted to interview me.
I was bored with my
slow-witted assistant.
The moon's beautiful.
We could drink outside.
Great idea! Very stylish.
It's cold.
- Stay here.
- What?
All men like Tokachi.
It's invigorating...
What is?
I'm from a fishing village
so the ocean affects me...
It's by Genkai Sea.
Heard of it?
I crossed it from Korea.
Sorry.
I came to Japan on my own.
The Japanese back home treated us bad.
I thought that I'd be better
off here.
I was wrong.
I was a hooker in the
red-light district in Asakusa.
I feel dirty.
You aren't dirty.
The earthquake hit
and I managed to survive
but then I was mobbed.
They made me sing the national anthem
and say difficult words
like 15 yen and 50 sen.
They thought Koreans would revolt.
They gathered us up on the other side
of Ara river.
At around 10 at night
vigilantes, fire brigade members and
schoolkids body searched us.
After the body search
they made us line up.
They tied us up so we couldn't move.
They said to wait.
"Move an inch and you're dead."
Around midnight...
I heard gunshots from the other side
of the river.
I heard a boy scream, "Mom!"
And then...
At daybreak...
The vigilantes started to...
chop off the Koreans' heads.
I was so scared...
I wasn't ready to die.
I broke free and ran.
When I got to the foot of the bridge
I noticed
I was treading on bodies.
The Koreans' bodies were
strewn all over.
Damn it!
Why...?
I didn't do it but I apologize!
I'm sincerely sorry!
Goddamn it!
Damn you!
Damn... One more bout.
You won!
When I first saw women wrestle
I couldn't believe it!
How could women be so strong?
I thought maybe I could
be strong, too.
Why did you want that?
Farmers aren't happy when
their babies are girls.
Some girls were sent
to work at a textile mill.
They might die from tuberculosis at
the mill
or leave the mill to be saloon girls.
My sister died, leaving behind a
husband and a baby.
I had to replace her.
I thought it wouldn't be so bad
but I was wrong.
So you ran away.
Things change when you're strong.
The poor can get rich.
And the weak
could become healthy.
The dead might have lived
if they were strong.
We could live instead of being
resigned to misery.
That's what it means for women
to be as strong as men.
The weak can't change anything.
I want to win.
Against who?
Let me see...
Those who've looked down on me.
That's silly.
Tussle me one more time.
What was that?
Show me that technique!
It wasn't intentional...
It's uchimuso!
It's cold!
You won't become Champion!
- Women can only be Ozeki.
- Not the Champion?
We leave that to men.
Tell Ichiko Kamichika.
She'll yell "Liberate women!"
You'll catch a cold!
Go, beat him!
Me?
Look at Mount Fuji
We're women's sumo.
Covered with white snow
Come see women's sumo.
Melting in the morning light
Like a man's passion
melts the heart of a maiden
The women's sumo is here.
Say it louder!
Women's sumo for the proletariats!
Come see women's sumo!
More cheerfully!
We fight with the working class!
Please come.
We have a full house every day.
Don't miss us!
"Come to Tamaiwa Women's Sumo!"
We fight with the working class!
Come see us!
Come on! Pick up these fliers!
Hold on!
- Thanks.
- Keep it up.
Come to women's sumo.
Women's sumo fights with proletariats!
Women's sumo for the working class!
Come and see women's sumo!
Come eat my fish!
I caught them!
Beneath Paris, City of Lights
Blood-red flowers
bloom in a dark corner
In the murk of crime and punishment
Evil flowers bloom
The dark and cold sewer is their home
Where the Apaches grew up
is always wet
So deep underground that no light
would reach
Where the rogue Apaches were born
and lived
I have a dream.
I have a dream!
I'll build a new country in Manchuria.
Everyone's equal.
Everyone has a job.
No one's rich or poor.
An equal paradise!
Is it possible?
Yes.
I'll go!
Tetsu Nakahama and Tokachi River
You can love anyone you want.
Be selfish.
Be crazy!
Dance!
Dance, Katsu!
Go, Katsu!
Never been in the sea?
It's my first time.
Which one's Little Cherry?
Haru Oishi from Honjo, Tokyo.
Is that you?
Take her away.
What's going on?
Her husband reported her as missing.
I need to ask you questions, too.
Sanji.
Take care of the afternoon show.
OK.
Cherry!
Has it been a year that she's
been with us?
You owe your husband an apology.
Are you listening?
I will not apologize to anyone.
- I should've burned down the house!
- What?
You traitor!
Let her get up!
Get up, traitor!
I'm happy to be one!
Since I have no hope,
I'll do what I please!
Come on! Shut up!
Cherry!
Don't let them beat you!
Get up!
Cherry! Don't let them beat you!
Cherry, stay strong!
The men with the sumo women
are socialists!
There was a Korean wrestler.
The riot never happened!
Listen, Maruman!
Don't be pushy, veteran!
The killing of the Koreans...
You just followed the orders, OK?
Remember that!
I have an issue with the sumo women...
What's that?
None of your business.
I'm busy!
Give me water.
Give me more.
I remember him.
You made me jump.
What is it?
Remember the man with the police chief
at the inn?
The bald man?
He's Matsutaro Shoriki.
From the Police Agency?
He started the rumor about
the Koreans' and socialists' riots.
I heard the Army Cavalry killed many
Koreans at the internment camp.
I guess Shoriki was reassigned
as part of a cover up.
Tetsu, leave that.
Watch this. Let's go!
- Where to?
- Come on!
Wait!
Come on, Dai.
Dai.
Shoriki is insignificant!
- I'll kill him by myself.
- Gen said to get Fukuda!
You don't really care.
You're aimless.
Guillotine? It's a game for you!
Because I'm a poet!
Were you really going to learn how
to fly and go to Manchuria?
Regular folks won't understand me!
Hey, wait a minute.
Come on, listen to me.
Yunoshin would be free if you
hadn't made him do it!
He volunteered. You were there.
He operates as a free agent.
You're all talk and that won't change.
I killed a man.
I'll go to hell by myself.
Bastard!
You cocky virgin.
I fed you all these years!
Go screw a girl.
For once, give your testicles
some relief.
Kiku will be happy
to break you in.
Your brain's addled with syphilis!
Hey, you're letting him get away.
Damn...
I'll deal with you later.
How will you do it?
I won't need you.
Hey!
Stay away.
Conductor!
Tomorrow may never come.
It has to be now.
There's no other way!
OK. I'll cover for you.
Go for it!
Come on! Hurry up!
What's going on?
What do you want with me?
Stop!
You go around!
Get them!
Hold it there!
Let go!
Wait!
- The show's starting.
- I can't wait.
Please.
Let me go!
You were with the socialist.
I'll interrogate you.
You're not the police!
They approve.
The police left her alone though!
Don't interfere!
Let's stay out of it.
Sanji!
The Boss left you in charge!
It's showtime.
The audience is waiting.
I want to get you girls back next year.
Despite these hard times,
I invited you here.
You're so kind to us, Mr. Sakata.
He'll soon release you.
You've done nothing.
OK, then.
Tokachi.
Come back soon.
Let's work!
Okay?
Guys!
Speak!
What horrible schemes do you
Koreans have?
I know you Koreans are arsonists!
You wish we all burned to death
so you start fires and poison
our wells.
You did!
No...
Then prove it.
Say "Long live the Emperor."
Japan belongs to the Emperor, the
Living God and even you're his child.
Say it!
Long live His Majesty!
Do it.
Let me go!
Why didn't you let me kill him?
Tetsu! Dai! You have to come with me!
What's wrong?
Some military men took Tokachi away.
- What?
- She was tied up and beaten...
Calm down. Show us where they are.
That way.
Come on!
I'm useless...
A man like me will never achieve
anything in his life...
Idiot!
The revolution is second
to saving a woman!
Speak!
You should go back.
Won't you call the police?
No police.
It's up to us.
- But...
- Listen!
Become strong and
change the world, Kiku.
Go now.
The veterans are torturing a woman!
To the old battery!
Stop, you bastards!
Are you okay?
They're socialists! Arrest them!
Come on!
You bastard.
You fought in Russia?
You wasted 4 years in Siberia.
You fought the Russian revolutionary
army for nothing.
We wanted to teach barbarians,
like those Westerners.
God sent us on a mission.
You were shameless bandits.
You were busy giving VD to
the Siberian women!
Hold him down.
You think you're smart.
You have no idea
what it's like to march through
a blizzard, starving.
The hunger stops you
questioning orders.
But even that
is better than the life of
a starving peasant!
You socialists
understand nothing!
The first time I met Dai...
It was at the Peasants Association
in rural Saitama.
We tried to get the farmers involved
but for the duration of our stay
no farmers came.
But even now, I strongly
believe that
it isn't the guy next to you...
who's the enemy.
We should fight together!
Hold him up.
I'll behead him.
No, don't!
Don't do it!
Aigo!
Why did you...?
I can still hear it...
Those Koreans crying "Aigo!"
They begged to be shot.
There was a couple together and we
killed the man...
The woman screamed out, "Aigo!"
Get off me!
The Cavalry camped nearby
and left the villagers to deal
with the Koreans.
In some villages, 3 Koreans were
burned to death.
We killed 4 with swords and
buried the bodies.
- Shut up!
- Let me speak!
The vigilantes made us do it!
They were too scared to do it
themselves.
They just watched.
Remember what the socialists
said about us!
They said that we'd drawn
the short straw.
For a meaningless war!
They're wrong...
They're wrong!
Take this.
Swing this sword and
chop off the socialist's head!
They don't do anything productive.
They just bark.
Come on, do it!
His Majesty...
May he live long!
Long live, His Majesty!
Out of the West corner,
Tiny Dragon!
Out of the East...
Kiku!
I'm here!
There's Kiku!
It's time.
Ready...fight!
East wins!
She won by uchimuso!
It's uchimuso!
The technique?
- Kiku!
- Way to go!
Great!
Kiku won!
That was amazing!
That was good.
Where's Tokachi?
And where are the others?
We can't find them.
You almost became murderers!
Hey! Over here!
I won!
I finally won!
Long live Kiku!
Long live Japan's working class!
Long live revolutionaries!
Why?
Why did you leave me out?
Ouch...
It hurts.
The vigilantes were charged
for the Koreans' massacre
but pardoned a year later
when the Regent Prince married.
The Government nullified
their crimes.
Ready, fight!
Tumen River, Korea
What?
OK, show her the money.
You understand bombs? You sure
the guerrillas will sell us some?
That's the 1,000 yen they asked for.
Oh no, she conned us!
What?
She said the Heroic Corps were allies!
For Koreans...
all Japanese are bad.
I don't believe that!
We can only get explosives
here in Korea.
How? We're broke now.
I'll get some money.
I'll talk to some people in Japan.
Osaka Entrepreneurs Association
Remember your promise.
Mr. Morimoto, I insist that you pay
what you owe us.
I can get you 3,000 yen tomorrow but
this is all I have now.
You're the man. I'll pick
up the rest tomorrow.
You've come all this way,
I should offer you some tea.
Hey!
How about some noodles?
Great!
Or maybe sushi?
Sushi! That sounds good, too.
Don't resist!
It hurts! Take it easy, will you?
I'm not just any old robber!
I'm Tetsu of the Guillotine Association!
Stop talking, you criminal!
Speak later.
Keiji Kurauchi
Behave!
Tetsu Nakahama, arrested
Long live revolutionaries, damn it!
The US Congress passed the Immigration
Act of 1924 on July 1.
With this the world began excluding
the Japanese.
Thrust!
Focus! Again!
Ready!
Thrust!
This is when Japan began its
military expansionism.
A year after the earthquake
there was a record-breaking drought.
The concerned farmers asked
the women's sumo to visit.
They hoped it would anger the Gods
and bring on the rain.
Welcome!
Mr. Tanaka.
You must be tired.
I'm your sponsor.
I'm Iwaki, the Boss.
Come inside when you're done.
Shut up and eat!
They certainly eat with gusto.
Their bodies need it.
I'm in awe of them!
More!
Give me more!
Hold on.
Wait.
I said more!
- Wait!
- What's wrong?
Everyone, we're very sorry.
What? I'm far from being full!
That's all for today.
I'll make sure you have
plenty tomorrow.
I'm sorry.
The sponsor is penny-pinching.
I'm hungry...
There's a wise saying about that.
What's that mean?
Any food on a empty stomach
tastes good.
Right, if there's food...
At least we get to wrestle.
Isn't the sponsor a landlord?
Not like us peasants.
I don't know. Ask the Boss.
He's a bit of a buffoon, isn't he?
You say strange things,
like your predecessor.
You mean, the first Cherry?
That's right.
Cherry the First was a strange woman.
This should be enough.
Tokachi River...
I wonder what happened to her.
She was a bit of a wanderer.
Right. She disappeared when we
were last here.
Did Kiku join us a year ago?
No wonder I feel old.
You'll soon have wrinkles
and white hair.
You don't!
I don't know. Like my mother
used to say
when you're at school
your life has stages.
In real life,
you work your ass off
and there are no stages.
10 years pass. And before you
even realize 20 years pass!
Time sure flies.
That saying is painful to hear
at my age.
Everyone ages and that includes
you lot!
Sanji...
Boss.
The police!
Hello.
This is not sleazy, its not even
entertainment really...
The drought has impacted rice
production
so it's like a rain dance.
You were promoted? Congratulations!
After the Captain resigned.
Most promoters left town because
of the recession.
No one has time for sumo.
If you do anything immoral
to promote your show
we'll shut you down.
I hate police bastards.
Tiger Katsu and Sanji
If any socialist outlaws turn up,
let us know
immediately.
Ready.
Not yet.
Go, Plum!
Kiku, beat her!
Ready.
And fight!
Go, Kiku!
Plum Country wins!
You're much stronger now.
I'm not.
You are.
Not enough to change.
Where is Tokachi?
We parted at Shimonoseki.
We asked her to come with us
to Korea.
But she declined.
That was it.
She must be waiting in Manchuria.
Huh?
Tokachi loved Tetsu's stories.
About his new country in Manchuria.
Where everyone's equal and has
a job and food.
No one's rich or poor.
Tokachi often said she wanted to
live there.
Tetsu said it'd be possible
in 100 years.
Tokachi would wait in Manchuria
for thousands of years for that.
Thousands of years...
But Tetsu can't go anywhere
for years.
Why?
He's in prison!
Dai.
The day's almost over.
I'm going.
I may never see you again...
Take care.
How arrogant! Is that all you've got?
After all those months and that's it?
Forget stupid Manchuria!
Of course Tokachi isn't waiting.
I bet she's screwing men for money.
- You don't mean...
- I do!
I know now.
We can't change anything.
The weak remain weak.
I'll be back.
I won't wait thousands of years
for you!
The son of a bitch told me
I was useless.
So I dared him to be straight with me.
You know what he told me?
No.
He said,
"Do you think we were equal?"
What kind of bullshit is that?
Tetsu never makes any sense!
Around here?
OK.
Put it down.
No good.
What are you looking at?
Don't look at me like that.
You're always so aloof.
- You act superior...
- I don't!
You think I'm a coward
because I ran.
No, I don't.
I came back!
I'm all you have.
You and your stuck-up face!
You look down on me.
You always have.
When there were more of us,
not just us two
did you ever talk to me?
Did you come over and talk to me?
I talked to you but you just
nodded and gave a phony smile.
Did you care about any of
us back then?
Tell you what.
I don't give a shit what you
think of me.
You'll never understand what a
great person l am.
Don't act like we're friends!
I knew it.
The tougher the shell
the greater the explosion.
Damn it.
I don't know...
Cigarette tins don't hold up...
I'll make one.
I don't know what to do
since Tetsu left me alone!
Did you say "alone"?
Hey.
You said you don't know
what to do alone?
Did you say "alone"?
You ignore me!
I don't ignore anyone!
I never ignore anyone.
I often think
of that son of a bitch, Tetsu.
What if he was executed?
What if he's dead?
I think about that.
Sometimes all night long.
Then what happens?
How would I feel?
I'm so sad.
To lose that son of a bitch.
I'd feel so sad
if the son of a bitch
was executed.
What about me then?
I killed a man.
I deserve to be executed!
Don't be silly.
I'd hate it, Dai.
I'd hate it if you died.
Get the police to stake him out.
Kiku, you have to talk.
Sanji is right. We have to
protect our troupe.
I don't know...
Why?
The authorities are stronger now.
Do what they ask.
No way.
Times have changed and
so should we, Boss.
We go against the tide!
Wrestling is popular in American
circuses now.
Sumo is so old fashioned...
You punk!
That hurt!
Sure it hurts!
Break up!
Let him go!
- Come on!
- I'll get you!
Stop!
Ugh, damn it!
That's enough, you two!
Katsu here is like a daughter to me.
If you want to be with her, say it!
I want her!
This has nothing to do with you!
- Stay out of it!
- Sanji.
You can leave if you want to.
Hello! Excuse me.
Yes?
I heard you've been taking
care of my wife.
Kiku!
Are you sure?
Come back any time!
Take care, Kiku!
Thank God for his rage.
What?
Katsu!
Our sumo troupe is history!
I have an idea for a new sumo group.
We won't focus on the win but
on the wrestlers.
We'll give the spectators
stories of the wrestlers.
And you'll be the star!
I don't know what you're saying...
I'll tell the police about
the socialists. The troupe is over.
What did you say?
I can't hear you!
Don't! Stop that!
What happened to the baby?
It died in my stomach.
Kiku, where are you going?
She didn't care about the kid when she
went, she's so selfish...
Do women have to live for children?
Get over here!
I bet you learned to drink by now.
I tell you, her sumo is impressive.
I hope you see my point.
Right, Kiku?
Weren't you ashamed to expose
yourself in public?
Women's sumo is for horny men.
Even if you were right, so what?
- Where are you going?
- To piss.
You got a little tougher?
Help!
That hurt, Tomoyo.
Dear, Dai, I'm still active
though I'm in prison.
I'll publish a poem collection
from here
and call it, "My Nation and Freedom,
Special prison issue."
"Black Bread" written by Tetsu Nakahama
I'm sure you know what
Black Bread means.
Number 136, lights out!
By the way, about Tokachi River.
If you ever learned her whereabouts
let me know.
Those who trace my footsteps.
Those who follow me!
Go beyond international borders!
The time will come!
It will all happen in autumn!
Then what would happen?
How silly!
Whatever it will be!
What did you...?
What did you do to her?
It's none of your business.
It is my business.
Speak up!
I do what I want to my wife.
You're horrible... You animal!
I want to be strong!
I want to wrestle!
Is it an inevitable fact?
Is it a fact?
Is it servile behavior?
Is it a fact? Or reality?
Social justice! Idealism! Freedom!
We should all be eaten by the devil!
Know that desperation does
not equal extinction!
In the face of desperation
there is but hope, nothing but hope!
Give Kiku back.
That's enough. Go away!
Let her go back to sumo.
You're book smart but what use is it?
You can't have her.
I love you!
The revolution is second
to saving a woman!
It's "Thank you, Master" or
"Damn you, you won't get
away with this!"
One or the other.
Nothing else is worthwhile.
Who cares how humans came to be?
It's too much!
Come on.
I don't know...
what got into me.
What?
I'm...
going back.
Katsu!
Wait!
Let me go.
It's obvious I'm not going to
be happy with you.
Katsu, wait just a minute.
I've never liked weak men like you!
Katsu!
You have a mean crotch!
You can't get to her.
Tomoyo is my woman.
No one owns Kiku, except herself.
It's a bomb.
Die with me.
After all
we just wanted to live like humans.
Can't humans survive without
fighting?
Maybe we can't survive without
fighting because we are humans!
Tiger Katsu, you're the star though...
It's just...
something got into me.
You say such a thing...
You shouldn't have.
It's not my fault.
You're to blame, not me.
I've done nothing wrong.
Damn you!
Where do you think you're going?
I can't hear you!
My hearing's gone.
Where are you going?
I'll take him to the doctor.
But they'll find out who you are!
What?
They'll find you!
You're strong, Kiku.
Be the best Ozeki in Japan.
So you have nothing to fear!
Kiku is fearless.
I don't know what you're
talking about!
A truly strong person
never has to take lives.
Kiku, you're different
to me. You'll be stronger.
No! No!
Don't be a baby.
You have to take care of yourself.
Who knows when we'll meet.
Maybe never.
But I'll think of you
when I'm dying.
No!
That's not what I want!
The Chrysanthemum and Guillotine
Let go of Kiku.
Then I'll take you to the doctor
so you can live.
Or I'll leave you here to die.
Go! Go back to the sumo troupe.
Tell them he changed his mind.
Go before we are seen.
Sir.
Hey, stop!
Stop!
Katsu!
She collapsed!
Tiger Katsu!
What happened to you?
Katsu, why?
Boss!
Whatever happened to her?
She's too stiff to fit in.
Put her down.
What the hell are you doing?
Stop it!
Don't!
Let go! I have to because
she doesn't fit in.
Remember how she used to be so stiff?
She could hardly open her legs.
I'll do the other leg.
I knew you'd come back.
All wrestlers want to die in the ring.
But it never happens.
We die on the side of the road.
It's always miserable.
Put her in.
Don't we all wish to die on the road?
Dump it at a temple.
Before the sumo god punishes us.
It's raining again.
The Sun God has been upset lately.
We're shutting you down.
Sanji testified. We're doing a search.
Go away! This is no place for
the likes of you!
Our ring is sacred!
Stay out!
Go away!
You ask me to quit sumo
But how could I?
Sumo is like the most
dashing man in the world
You get thrown doing sumo
You get dumped by a man for sumo
Kiku!
Your parents disowned you
You have no home to go to
Even if you lost your voice
or got skinny
You'd endure it,
it's all for the glory of sumo
Arrest them all!
Arrest them!
Don't resist!
You bitch!
Keiji Kurachi, Lumpenproletariat
Arrested in 1924.
Released from prison in 1935.
Continued to be an anarchist / activist post WWII.
Died in 1960.
Kozo Kawai, Philosopher
Arrested and sentenced to life in 1923.
Died in prison in 1943.
Yunoshin Tanaka, Poet / postal worker
Arrested in 1923.
Junk peddler / poet post WWII.
Died in 1966.
Jiro Konishi, Ex-banker
Sentenced to life in 1923.
Released on parole in 1940.
Owned a small diner post WWII.
Year of death unknown.
Gentaro Uchida, Shop clerk
Sentenced to life in 1923.
Released from prison in 1938.
Year of death unknown.
Eikichi Shigeno, Shop clerk
Sentenced to life in 1923
but released in 1938 and owned a bookshop.
Year of death unknown.
Kiichi Naka, Textile mill laborer
Arrested in 1923.
Released and owned a bookshop in 1934.
Rearrested in 1935 but not convicted.
Died in 1975.
Yoshio Ogawa, Ex-monk
Sentenced to life in 1923.
Died from an illness in Kofu Penitentiary in 1936.
Kyutaro Wada
Arrested with Furuta and Muraki for the failed
General Fukuda assassination attempt in 1924.
He committed suicide in prison in 1928.
Genjiro Muraki
Arrested in 1924 for serial bombings
in a failed attempt to assassinate General Fukuda.
Died of pneumonia in jail in 1925.
Daijiro Furuta
Arrested together with Muraki in 1924 for serial bombings.
Sentenced to death in 1925, and unappealed.
Executed a month later.
He was 25.
Tetsu Nakahama
Sentenced to death together with Daijiro Furuta in 1925.
Published "Black Bread" his only poem collection, in prison.
Executed in 1926 at Osaka Penitentiary at the age 29.
There's a record of a women's sumo stable touring in Hawaii,
Colonial Gyeongseong, Busan, Saipan, Palau and Manchuria in the 1930s.
Women's sumo came to an end in around 1955.
Directed by Takahisa Zeze
English subtitles by
Dean Shimauchi