Stéphane and I have known each other for years.
We were neighbours.
One day, a guy pissed on the low wall
that separated our two houses.
His parents accused me.
And mine accused Stéphane.
That's how we met.
In between two yelling sets of parents.
THE MOULIN ROUGE
Yeah, go!
- I'm getting ready to fire!
- Yeah! go ahead, go on!
- Hey, are you okay?
Wait, wait!
- No, the old woman.
The old woman, go on!
What are you doing there?
You clowns, are you mad?
Why are you throwing rocks at people?
They had a very small apartment.
My parents couldn't understand how eight
people could live in there, jammed together.
They thought the apartment
would collapse one day.
And that they'd deserve it.
They couldn't stand all the noise,
the—effervescence.
There were always unbelievable
scenes in Stéphane’s house.
One day, his little sister nearly jumped
out the window because of her boyfriend.
It woke up the whole neighborhood.
I enjoyed going to Stéphane's.
It changed me a bit.
At home—
No one had any passion.
My father spent his time reading his newspapers.
And my mother listened to the radio.
Sometimes I tried to stimulate them a bit.
To talk to them, to make them react.
To be a little cheeky.
Well, I quickly stopped that
because I got slapped.
I know Stéphane's uncle said that
my mother had a broom up her arse.
I think he had a point.
Stéphane and I have always gone to the same school.
I remember one day, Stéphane wasn't
paying attention in the French lesson.
The teacher pointed at the door,
and told him to take it and leave,
He really took the door—And he left.
It took them two weeks to find it.
We'd hidden it at my house.
The neighbourhood held no secrets for us.
We knew all the gossip.
So sometimes we made use of it.
When the tobacconist wouldn't sell us cigarettes,
we threatened him we'd tell everyone
about his affair with the florist.
But that didn't work all the time.
Go on, run, run!
Stéphane was a big fan of cabarets.
Especially the Moulin Rouge.
He felt it was special.
Apart from the dancing girls,
I didn't really see the point.
But all that luxury, that glitter—
It intoxicated him.
One evening,
Stéphane found out he'd have to move
with his family to eastern France.
His father had found a job and of course
he was going to have to help him.
When he told me the news—
we didn't talk much.
But I knew it was coming soon.
I had to act fast.
My parents would have killed me
if they knew what I did that day.
I would have been disinherited, that's for sure.
At the same time, even I wasn't proud of it.
But it had to be done.
It was for a good cause.
I had managed to pay off one of the guys
who worked in the Moulin Rouge’s kitchen
To let us in through the back door.
I kept it secret right up to the end.
To the big night.
I always wondered what Stéphane
was thinking that day.
I don't know if I was happy to be here,
or happy for him.
Anyway, his expression was weird—
It was so funny.
Inside, it was another world.
We could already hear the music rumbling,
the ground shaking, people applauding.
Step aside, please.
Step aside.
We found ourselves in the wings, backstage.
We passed dancers getting ready
amid all the excitement.
Come on! Hurry up! Two minutes ! Two minutes!
No one paid any attention to us.
We were completely part of
the scenery, part of the crowd.
Then the show.
People laughing, drinking, singing.
All the glitter, all the joy.
Stéphane’s eyes were sparkling.
To be honest, it was really amazing.
He left the following day.
Some time later, I found out he ran away
from his military service.
His superiors were furious.
Apparently, the refectory door was missing.
English subtitles by
jeremys and Marseille
TNT 2023