Valerie, open up!
Have you finished?
Shut it!
Miss, you can remove the fuse
for the doorbell.
Try them all, you'll find it.
Yeah?
I'm a friend of Benoit.
Isn't he in?
He's catching up on his sleep.
- Antoine?
- Hi.
I've just got back
from the States.
Look, Valerie's...
Can I crash here for a night or two?
Take the room at the end.
Valerie, I'm writing to tell you
I've moved into Benoit's place.
He's never here but I'm sharing
with a certain Frederic,
who has an amazing capacity
for doing nothing.
Since you left me...
Since we separated
I've not written much.
My play is a bit stalled...
I'm writing lots.
My play is almost finished.
I thought we could have dinner...
TRAINEES
Valerie,
I'm writing to tell you I've been
living at Benoit's for 4 months.
He's in America
and I share with Frederic,
a nice young chap
who's good at cooking pasta.
I think I left a few floppy disks
with you.
Could I pop round for them
one evening?
I was wondering if...
Valerie, You haven't heard
from me for a year now.
I'm at Benoit's place.
He's gone to America
and become a dickhead.
I'm sharing with Fred, a nice lad.
I'm not sure what it is he does,
but he's good at cooking pasta
and listening to my play,
now finished...
...now almost finished.
I was near your place
the other day
and I thought you'd be happy...
...pleased...
...that it might amuse you...
Valerie...
Valerie,
You'll be surprised by this letter
after three years without news.
I'm living
at dickhead Benoit's place.
He said he saw you in New York.
I'm glad to know you're travelling.
I'm sharing with Fred,
an endearing young man.
I started on my play again.
It's finished now.
It's almost finished.
It's amazing the noise you make!
Can't you piss down the side?
I like pissing in the middle.
It gives me a feeling of power.
Self-affirmation!
Mercier complains about hearing
you affirm yourself in the night.
I can't help it.
If I don't do it in the middle
it's not like having a real piss.
No sense of relief.
Nothing else to eat?
No vegetables?
Stuff that grows in the earth?
Like lettuce or a tomato?
A tomato. Remember what that is?
These aren't bad
with water and sugar.
How long does familiarity last
with someone
you don't see any more?
Why do you ask me that?
I don't know whether to put
"Valerie"
or "My little Valerie".
"My dear Valerie"?
How long's it been?
Four and a half years.
Put "Valerie"...
or "Dear Madam".
- How much is the pencil?
- 17 francs 50.
17 francs 50?
It's not even been sharpened!
- How much is the pencil?
- 17 francs 50.
I'll take it.
Antoine, it's Fred. I'm in FNAC.
I've got a problem.
Could you get down here quick
with the emergency funds.
All of it, because...
Yes, OK...
It's loose change
from buying bread, newspapers,
milk, cigarettes and...
Go on...
Go on, they're really interested!
Hardly any left!
I'm sure they ripped us off.
Shut it!
What? What's wrong?
Stealing photographic paper?
The photographer whose ads
I stick up buys it off me.
Aren't you sick of this bollocks?
What's got into you?
I was ashamed in that office.
Ashamed!
Are you lecturing me?
No, I'm not lecturing you.
I looked like a twat
with my jars of copper coins.
It's pathetic!
You're not so conscientious
when I nick your Babybel cheese!
Pathetic!
Hey, you've got five of a kind!
Again!
Very good. You now.
I'm not asking you to shout,
but to express...
love!
Love, the need for another.
It's like gulping down
fresh air...
Vital air!
Are you sticking them up
for someone
or are you the photographer?
It's me.
I'm the photographer.
I need some photos doing.
That's lucky.
Maybe... I don't know.
I'd have to see your photos.
I've got a portfolio.
I'll give you a ring.
I'll give you my personal number.
That's the studio.
The dance aspect of acting,
you see.
Concentrate on that
in your article.
The director as choreographer.
Choreographer?
If you came to training
you'd understand.
I'm off now.
Yes. Right away, Mrs Kowarsky.
- Here.
- Thank you.
When will you be able to pay me?
As always, in five weeks.
- 700 francs isn't...
- If you need money,
I know someone who's looking
for a crossword-setter.
Two floors down.
- Just mention my name.
- Thanks.
But I've got some good news.
We've finally got
the paper's new key-rings!
Take your pick.
Could you lend me 1,000 francs?
It's Henri's birthday.
He collects exotic fish.
Sorry.
I'd like to help you out but...
I couldn't afford a goldfish.
It's OK.
Give him some seaweed.
- He collects fish?
- Yes. Does that surprise you?
- On the contrary.
- What do you mean?
A certain family likeness.
You always slag off
the men I'm with.
- He should eat them.
- Stop it!
Fish is brain food.
- You're jealous.
- No, I'm just being stupid.
Those drinks we had...
I never slagged off Valerie.
- Why? Did you want to?
- No. On the contrary.
After all, she took you from me.
If you hadn't met her
we'd still be together.
I'd still be starving, poor,
badly dressed, depressed,
and still wouldn't know
what an orgasm was!
Very funny!
It's weird,
drinking in the afternoon.
Why? It's nice, isn't it?
Like being on holiday.
How many times
have you read that paper?
How can you spend so much time
looking at the photo of an engine?
But look at it!
6 cylinders.
That many?
You wouldn't understand.
No.
Is 6 better than 4, then?
Yeah. More of them!
Such a...
Such a fascinating conversation!
There's a girl over there
at least twice as tall as me.
This is Sandra.
Hello.
We're going out for dinner.
When did you get here?
This afternoon, from the States.
We were having a nap.
- Any messages?
- Just your mail, over there.
It's filthy in here.
You haven't nicked a white shirt?
We never go in your room.
Are you sure?
With mother-of-pearl buttons.
Stuff your mother-of-pearl buttons!
See you, then.
- What got into you?
- He pissed me off.
"Back from the States, any mail?
"Have you seen my shirt?"
Wanker!
He's always just getting back
from the States.
Has she got a full load, his bird?
Is she French, American?
No idea. She never spoke.
He must have given her instructions.
She wasn't that great.
Wasn't her left eye a bit funny?
Her arse is really flat.
No tits to talk of.
You can tell that
from the shoulders.
Especially with big girls.
Plenty of nasty surprises,
once you got her kit off.
The bastard!
Yeah?
It's me.
I forgot to tell you.
My gran wants to sell the flat.
You'll have to move out.
We'll talk when I get back.
Benoit Benoit!
Don't arse about!
Look...
It's not that big an emergency.
And we can find another one.
How will we pay for it?
You have to show pay slips.
Have you got any?
Most of the time
I'm paid cash in hand.
No social security, even!
She can't just kick us out.
There are laws against it.
We can go
to the industrial tribunal.
Industrial tribunal!
The industrial tribunal
is for when you've got a job.
Yeah?
It's Nicolas.
I've come for a shower.
I don't know. We could sue her.
We're not even paying rent.
His gran's been lending us the flat
for free for the last five years.
How could we sue her?
How can you be so stupid?
Do you go to evening classes?
I'm trying to find a solution.
I'm thinking.
Just count your cylinders.
You're better at that!
Where are you going?
You're pissing me off!
Sod off, then!
Am I in the way?
Not unless you use
all the hot water.
I brought you
some in-flight meals.
You remind me more and more
of my parents.
You haven't consummated
your relationship, have you?
One, two, three.
Hello, it's Frederic's mum.
Hello.
- Did I wake you up?
- No, I was working.
Fred!
Your mum.
- Yes?
- Are you coming to see us?
I don't feel like it.
I'll make you
a lovely rabbit in mustard.
And I've made you some pickles.
All right!
Come for lunch on Sunday.
We've lots to talk about.
I won't ask you for the money.
What this about money?
I'm going to bed.
We're supposed to share our money.
I paid the bills
the last three times.
- I supply our food.
- You nick it!
- So?
- So...
We only eat what you can fit
in your pockets.
Cheese, hamburgers,
tins of sardines,
fish fingers...
All stuff in square boxes!
I want to eat real food.
Do you understand?
A lettuce, for example.
Nick a lettuce next time.
Understand?
I'm warning you.
You'd better find some money.
Can I buy you a drink?
Hello.
They're lovely.
How long have you been doing this?
A year and a half.
Shall we do it right now?
Have you got your camera?
Is my make-up all right?
And the light?
Yeah... Well, I don't know...
Shall we?
Right here.
Right... Sit down there.
Look at all these damn buttons!
It went off all by itself!
Sometimes it does that,
it just goes off by itself.
- Is it much further?
- No. Just there, on the right.
What are your shirt buttons made of?
Sorry it's dark.
But the light damages my eyes.
Have a biscuit.
Thank you, madam.
So?
You've come about the flat?
Yes. Benoit must have told you.
- Benoit
- Your grandson, Benoit.
You want to buy the flat?
No, not at all.
You see, we're students...
We'd just like a bit more time,
so we can sort ourselves out...
I say...
Could you try and find my glasses?
They're big, wrap-around ones,
to protect my eyes.
Of course, madam.
Did you hurt yourself?
No, not at all.
So you're students?
Yes.
What are you studying?
I'm a 7th-year medical student
and Fred's doing advanced maths.
Pure, applied...
I'm still hesitating
about which way to go.
Pure, applied...
- I've found your glasses.
- Are you sure?
I think Mrs Picard stole them.
She realised I suspected her
and brought them back
in the night.
She gives me injections
while I'm asleep.
She used to be a nurse.
No, I don't think
there's anything to worry about.
What do you know?
You don't live here!
It's true, you don't.
You're right.
Do you want me to check the lock?
Yes, have a look.
Anyway... about the flat?
What flat?
The flat.
You'll have to go.
I want to settle my affairs
while I'm still compos mentis.
I bought it
off Mr Roland Hulot of the bar,
in 1937. On 9th May.
Now it's worth a lot more.
Billions!
No, you'll have to go.
I want to sell. I have to sell!
I have to sell... Yes.
If I may...
The market's not good at the moment.
I'd advise you to wait.
It'll go up again.
I'm saying this for your sake.
It'll go up.
- Are you the one doing medicine?
- No. Antoine.
Me.
I wonder...
Could you look at my tongue?
Fred!
- What is it?
- I'm very worried.
What if we have to leave the flat?
- We'll talk about it tomorrow.
- No, now! If you don't mind.
I've come to a decision.
All this has got to end.
I'm going to get a proper job.
Getting started was OK at first,
but I've been getting started
for ten years.
I want a calm life.
Money. A telly.
Some creature comforts.
We don't have to leave right away.
She has to find a buyer first.
And the price will go up.
We're fine.
We're fine, I tell you.
Don't worry.
I don't know what it is.
I don't usually worry at this hour.
Is that the right time?
Shit, it's back again!
- What?
- My heart thing.
It starts beating weirdly.
Listen.
Do you hear it?
- Two beats instead of one.
- I don't know...
Put your head there.
Well?
It's nothing.
It's just your nerves.
I know it's my nerves.
That doesn't mean it's nothing.
This isn't a healthy life
we lead, Fred.
We eat junk.
We don't live properly.
We drink too much.
We need to get a grip.
Sylvie told me about her sex life,
and I realised that we're sexless.
A sex life is important, isn't it?
Yes.
What did Sylvie tell you?
- Can we talk about something else?
- Why?
It's good to talk about sex.
With sex, half of the pleasure
is doing it,
the other half is talking about it.
Maybe we should get
some of the other half.
Why don't you get back with her?
- She scares me.
- Why?
She's too much of an expert.
Like shagging a winner
of the Nobel Sex Prize!
Don't worry about that.
Just slip her your big schlong!
That'll sort her out.
All I want is to live with Valerie
in a nice, three-room flat,
and get 45,000 francs
in royalties a month.
You're being silly now.
Have I told you
about our first night together?
Have mercy!
And the time we made love
with her 14-year-old cousin?
I've never told you?
No, I'd definitely remember that.
It was during the winter break.
We were at her aunt's.
We were shagging all the time
back then.
The problem was that her cousin,
who was very beautiful,
always wanted to know
what we were up to.
One evening, we left her
watching some crap on telly...
some kids thing...
And she came up to our room.
We were on the bed, naked,
and we heard her coming upstairs.
The exciting thing was,
we knew she'd try to come in.
It made it all...
I don't know how to explain.
- You know...
- Yes, yes. Carry on.
The door opened.
She saw us
and, rather than screaming
or being embarrassed... nothing.
Nothing.
- She started taking her jumper off.
- You're having me on!
Slowly,
as if it was perfectly normal.
Valerie took her hand,
pulled her onto the bed
and started stroking her hair.
I was shaking!
You can imagine.
And then her little cousin
bent over me...
You're having me on?
Yeah.
You bastard!
Piss off, you bastard!
You little pervert.
You were enjoying that, eh?
Did you have a bit of a stiffy?
What do you think?
I'm a man!
Piss off now!
I want to go to sleep.
- Do you want to be alone?
- Sod off!
Well... the former tenants
seem to have left a few things,
but you can still get
a good idea of the layout.
You have a hallway,
with two windows onto the courtyard.
A huge lounge
leading on to one bedroom,
which you can also reach
from the corridor...
Back into the hallway,
and the second bedroom,
which is much bigger
and gets lots of light.
I'm showing people round.
Didn't anyone tell you?
Sorry, I...
I don't usually sleep here.
We had a few too many to drink
last night.
I'll be right with you.
Sorry.
Cockroaches everywhere!
You put me
in an embarrassing situation.
You shouldn't be here.
If you'd cleaned, at least!
How hard is it to use a sponge?
Like that!
The bottles...
We'll put them over here.
Give the tea-towels
a bit of a shake.
If you wash up regularly
you don't get nasty smells.
And the windows are disgusting.
If you don't have
any cleaning products
use an old newspaper.
It works very well.
There!
It takes no time.
Clean windows
make all the difference.
I have a brother who lives like you,
so I understand.
Your mind's on other things.
People are strange.
If they walk
into a dirty flat,
they think it's always been dirty
and always will be.
Excuse me.
Thanks.
People are strange like that.
Where do you put
your dirty clothes?
We wear them.
- Have you got a big bed?
- What?
A big bed or a little bed?
A big one.
But what size?
140cm by 190cm or 160cm by 190cm?
I've no idea. Why?
I wondered if you could put me up
for a few days.
Of course.
We're getting kicked out.
Come when you like.
- Have you got a sofa, too?
- Yes.
- When can we come?
- Who's "we"?
Frederic and me.
What's so funny?
You're like hitch-hikers.
The car stops
then all your pals appear.
You know
I don't get on with Frederic.
OK, I'm sorry...
I shouldn't have asked.
Look, she hasn't even seen us.
She's depressed since dad died.
Hello, mum.
Darling! Hello.
- Hello, Antoine.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine. And you?
- You don't look well.
- I am. Why do you say that?
Just a hunch.
I see so many depressives
that I know the signs.
Ask for an appointment.
Antoine, it's very nice here.
Antoine!
There.
Perfect. Stop!
Stop! Shit!
Marc, please.
Just a couple of seconds.
Could you explain
about the exposure time again?
You're a pain, Fred.
This is the last time.
You never understand anything.
It's not as if it's complicated!
And my portfolio?
When am I going to get it back?
- No problem.
- And my 500 francs?
They're gloomy.
That's what makes them stylish.
Maybe, but you can hardly see me.
- I look ugly.
- No, you don't.
Employers will be surprised
when they see you,
rather than being disappointed,
which is what usually happens.
That's obviously you.
No, I'm sorry.
I don't want them.
I'm not blowing 500 francs
on photos I can't even use.
Hang on.
- What are you doing?
- A second opinion.
- Excuse me!
- Stop it!
- Please...
- Stop it! Don't!
Don't worry.
Could you give me your opinion
about these photos?
Tell the truth, don't hold back.
You'll see.
They're not bad...
This one lacks contrast.
Some of them are overexposed...
This is too grainy.
They're too direct for portraits,
and with sensitive film
you should have...
- I'll have another coffee.
- Coming right up.
Wanker!
Hang on.
- You can have them.
- Thanks.
They could always come in handy.
Look, couldn't we have another try?
I'll do them the way you want.
I won't be so...
radical!
- OK. I have to go now.
- How about Wednesday?
- Perfect.
OK.
Get a good eyeful, did you?
"The beginning of all our woes",
5 letters... "Birth".
"After a long, hard life",
5 letters.
"Death".
"It keeps you out of heaven,
but releases you from hell",
seven letters.
"Suicide".
And it goes on... "Solitude",
"impossibility", "resignation..."
And there are far worse.
I thought it was quite original.
What can I say?
"Out of the door", 5 letters.
"Fired"?
How often did you do this last year?
Just watch.
I'm going to amaze you!
- Tap them both...
- Go on.
Let me wipe away the snow.
Hey, my ski-pass!
Are you ready?
Shall I give you a push?
No, don't push me!
Ready!
Five, four, three, two, one!
Are you all right?
I dug the edges in...
You know what I'd like right now?
To be in a car crash.
Not a big one. Just a broken leg
and a couple of cracked ribs.
Lying in a hospital bed
and waiting for my body to heal,
for my bones to knit back together,
like so many little miracles
happening inside my body.
The bones knit back together!
The ribs move back into position!
My eye goes down.
My lip scars over.
I watch myself heal,
I feel myself getting better.
Then there's physiotherapy.
You know what you're fighting for,
why it's such hard work.
Why?
So you can walk again.
It's simple!
Then, one day, you walk again,
and it's sublime.
You even dance,
and better than before.
One leg's shorter than the other.
You meet a girl who likes dancing.
You dance with her
and you shag her, for fuck sake!
So easy. Life is easy.
It's marvellous.
- Is it big?
- Fairly.
The rent was fixed in 1948!
- What floor?
- The fifth.
And no lift.
Don't complain.
At 1,800 F a month...
Don't forget to buy fags
on your way home!
- Are they nice?
- They're friends of my sister's.
Hi, Nico. How are you?
Come on in.
Hello.
- So, Claire...
- Sorry about the mess.
Want something to drink?
Beer, wine?
I'll put Jeanne to bed.
Want to see her room?
Yes, I'd like to.
- And the theatre?
- Sold out.
Can't get seats for your parents
for two weeks.
As long as they get
to see your play.
- Do you think they'll like it?
- I'm sure they will.
But it's a bit low-brow.
Write something else.
You're a good writer.
Knowing how to write doesn't mean
you've got anything to say!
If I wrote anything else
I'd be an impostor.
I'm not an author, I'm a craftsman.
Subject, verb, object, joke!
I made leek and potato soup
for tonight.
I love you.
Well, then...
It's perfect.
The paint is in good condition.
No redecorating to be done.
I think we'll take it.
We'd like the hand-over fee
in cash, if that's possible.
- The what?
- The hand-over fee.
We'd prefer the 25,000 francs
in cash.
I didn't know.
Didn't you tell Nicolas?
I thought you'd told him.
No.
25,000 francs?
We can't do it for less.
I thought it was a flat for paupers.
Paupers who've saved up
a lot of money!
Well...
OK, we'll take it.
On three, OK?
One, two, three!
- What are you doing?
- We need to be sure.
Is it on three, or after three?
Just let me do it.
- Please don't make a noise!
- I'm doing my best!
- But it's bound to make a noise!
- You're right.
Take your time.
It was your idea,
we can't stop now.
Why not?
No one's forcing us.
Come back!
Come back or I'll scream!
- Where's Karate Magazine?
- That way. Watch for an alarm.
- It'd have gone off already.
- A direct line to the cops?
This isn't the Bank of France!
We'll never get there at this rate.
- Warn me when you stop!
- I heard something.
Let's go.
Have you got gloves?
- I brought mittens.
- Mittens?
They're all I could find!
Quietly.
Fuck!
If Agnes could see me now.
It's crazy.
I can't stop thinking about her.
I think I'm in love.
- She's...
- What?
She's so pure.
There's a sort of aura about her.
She's so gentle, so kind...
- Who?
- Agnes! The photo girl.
- Stop it!
- What?
Concentrate on what you're doing!
When she looks at you,
it's so gentle...
You know she could never do
anything nasty or perverse.
Stop it or I'm leaving,
I'm warning you!
I can't help it
if she's on my mind.
I'm besotted.
You should understand that.
You and your one great love
of ten years ago,
your stupid fantasies,
your posh flat,
and your kids
that you take to the square
to play football.
Listen to me for once!
- Not so loud.
- Oh, piss off!
We're committing a burglary
right now.
A burglary!
You have to dress it up!
- Stop arsing about!
- All right.
If we get caught,
I'm the one they'll go hard on.
- Because I'm older.
- Here it is.
Too big. It won't fit.
Let's go, then.
No, hang on.
Quietly!
- Stop moving.
- What?
I said, stop moving!
Give me that.
There, try it.
Go on, get it in.
What's wrong?
It scared me to death.
Do something!
Like what?
Shove a Bic up its arse?
Here, pussy...
What's your name?
- Give me the crowbar.
- No! No violence.
I just want to scare it off.
Leave it to me.
All right?
You did it, Antoine!
You got it open!
Good God, we're in!
Only 50-franc notes.
This isn't Le Figaro, you know.
Great! 500s!
Don't stop now,
you've hit a seam!
Hang on.
Look.
- Antoine, that's enough.
- Hang on.
We've got to go.
It's getting light.
We'll get caught.
I'm going, Antoine.
- Stop!
- Look!
OK...
Stop arsing about now.
We'll get caught.
It's getting light.
Come on, let's go.
What's the matter with you?
Come on!
I'm warning you!
I'm going now.
What are you doing?
Put these in your bag.
- What are they?
- Stamps.
You twat!
It's little things like that
that get you caught.
Well, you never write, do you?
Fred, wake up.
Let me sleep.
- I feel awful, Fred.
- Take a pill.
Let me sleep.
I was just having a nice dream.
You shouldn't go waking people up
like that.
- We did a bad thing.
- Yeah, right. Go to sleep.
We'll give the money back.
I'll take it before
they get to the office.
- Are you sick or what?
- Yes, I've been sick!
I feel disgusted with myself.
You'll get over it.
Go back to sleep.
Know how many small businesses
have gone bankrupt this year?
That's one of them.
Shut up.
I don't want to hear it.
They employ seven people.
Seven!
Not to mention the freelancers.
People like me
and Mrs Kowarsky.
Who?
The cleaning lady.
She's got two kids.
She's paid cash in hand.
That's what that money's used for.
Calm down.
We'll discuss it tomorrow.
It'll be Monday then.
It was your idea
to go and burgle the place!
So stop it!
Go to bed.
Go on, off to bed.
Off to bed.
Look straight ahead.
Don't move, Agnes.
Fred... Excuse me.
Can I have a word?
I'll be right back.
- Where did you get that camera?
- I bought it.
We were supposed to wait a while
before spending the money!
It's an investment, nothing at all.
What do you want?
The editor wants me
to go and see him.
I got the feeling
he suspects something.
- I don't want to go.
- Don't be stupid!
Not going
would be like a confession.
Act as if everything's normal.
I told you
we should have taken it back!
Don't start that again.
And stop whispering.
You speak like that
all the time now.
Can you come with me, please?
- I can't.
- Why?
- Because I can't.
- Yes but why?
- I've got something to do.
- What?
Agnes... I have to tell her
I love her. Now.
It's now or never, understand?
I've got to go.
Sorry but I've got to go now.
Fred, will you be in later?
I can't find my keys.
When will the photos be ready?
I don't know. Monday.
- Agnes?
- Yes. What is it?
I just wanted...
It's not easy to say but...
You move me.
That doesn't sound very nice.
How can I put it?
You get to me.
When I'm with you,
I feel sad and happy
at the same time.
And a bit ashamed, too.
Like I'm not worthy,
and you're someone
beyond my reach.
Even, sometimes,
when I'm next to you, I think...
I think I ought to go
and have a bath.
There.
Oh, yes, also...
As soon as you've gone, I miss you.
Even when you're with me but
looking somewhere else, I miss you.
Don't look at me like that.
It wasn't an insult.
It was a declaration.
I've nothing to be ashamed of.
Yes but I've already got someone.
His name's Patrick.
He's a stage manager.
Right...
That's good.
No, I mean...
He must get to see lots of plays.
He doesn't really get time.
Too busy.
Yeah, of course.
It doesn't change
how I feel about you.
And at least I've told you now.
I can't cheat on him.
No, I know you're not like that.
Or he could watch.
- Sorry?
- He could watch.
Watch what?
Us. We screw and he watches.
We enjoy that now and then.
What a mess!
I've got to go, I'm late.
Call us if you're into it.
Or call me, rather.
Excuse me.
I called you
because we've got a problem.
We were burgled
and all the cash was taken.
Shit!
We can't pay you
this month, and we'll be giving you
less work for a while.
- That's OK.
- Really?
I mean, I could do you
a few articles
for nothing.
All hands to the wheel!
- You can count on me.
- Don't bother.
And your article
about Van Damme...
Pierre would prefer an interview.
So I'm going to ask Caroline
to do it.
Good idea.
- If that's all...
- No problem.
The cleaning lady found them.
Right next to the safe.
It's almost funny.
I don't understand.
We've always been fair with you.
I helped you out.
Why spoil it all?
- I needed money.
- Everyone needs money.
We didn't call the police.
Relieved?
We'll settle this ourselves.
Right...
Found your keys, then.
Get the money and the camera.
They don't want it back.
It's OK, I'll manage.
All right?
It's only superficial.
I don't think you've got
any serious injuries.
They're pros.
They know what they're doing.
I've thought of something.
I think it could have been
the perfect job.
- Please, be quiet.
- Just let me tell you...
It won't take long.
The thing is...
It was perfect
because it was dirty money.
It didn't even exist, it was used
to pay people cash in hand.
What they were doing was illegal,
so they couldn't do anything to us.
Do you understand?
You should have just denied it.
84 francs 90, please.
We'll just take the cream
for the eyes.
I'll give you some bandages
and disinfectant
that are past their sell-by dates.
We've always got some left over.
Got your keys?
This doesn't work.
What's happened?
We've been kicked out.
The bastards
went to town on you, eh?
Come in.
You should go to the police.
They're not allowed to beat you up.
Go on.
Hello Taxi! Go ahead, please.
Yes, what address?
20B, Hippolyte-Maindron.
Yes, hold the line.
Your code!
Hold the line.
Yes, what address, please?
I'm sticking it out.
Two more months, then I'll ask
for management training.
- Do you like it?
- That's beside the point.
- But you liked writing.
- No. I liked waiting
for something to happen.
Writing's morbid.
You watch the time go by,
thick and sluggish...
I'm healthier now.
I see people, eat regular meals.
Look.
Nearly all my dandruff has gone!
You look tired.
At least I get you out
from time to time.
You're right.
A bit of greenery does you good.
It was mum who chose
this horrific thing.
I've planted thyme,
rosemary and tarragon.
I've got pay slips now.
I'll be able to get a flat.
But I'm not sleeping well.
The flat vibrates.
It's right next to a metro line,
I think.
I've got something here...
What's wrong? Stop it!
Stop it. Are you all right?
Come here.
Lots of people work.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
All I said was
I like what you write.
You've never read anything else!
You're ignorant!
You're not interested in anything.
What's going on around you?
What's going on in Africa
or the Middle East?
Just because he's been reading
Le Monde for the last three days!
What was that?
What did you say?
Nothing.
- What did you say?
- I didn't say anything.
Don't lie, I heard you!
What did you say?
Agnes? It's Fred.
I didn't wake you, did I?
Anyway... Remember what you said
last time I saw you?
With your boyfriend.
Let's give it a go.
Wednesday's fine.
OK. Goodnight.
I recently moved in with a friend,
and that's when
the symptoms started.
He lives next to the metro,
and the vibrations
shake the whole flat.
How can I explain it?
- Can I borrow that pen?
- Be my guest.
Here's my ear.
The little bones of the inner ear
are here... Right?
Exactly.
And these little bones
keep my body upright and balanced?
I think that the vibrations
of the metro,
which I'm very sensitive to,
are disturbing the workings
of my inner ear,
hence the dizziness and nausea.
That's it.
Have you ever had
these sorts of symptoms before?
Before living there?
No, never.
Why, is it serious?
No, it's just fatigue.
I'll prescribe something
for the nausea and a tonic.
Apart from that?
- What?
- There's nothing else?
No family or work problems?
No more than anyone else.
I'll give you a colleague's name,
in case.
Could you write it there...
Hi.
- I'm Fred.
- Patrick. Come in.
Isn't Agnes here?
No.
She went out to buy some fags.
She won't be long.
So you work in the theatre?
It must be interesting.
I mean, you must get
to see all sorts of stuff.
It depends.
And you're a photographer?
Just getting started.
The thing I like about it
is that it's immediate,
it's there!
- I like it.
- Should have brought your camera.
- I didn't think.
- Stupid.
Sorry.
Look what I found on the stairs.
- All right?
- Fine.
Going to pour me a drink?
Can I roll one for myself?
No, take this one,
I'll roll another.
Thanks.
Agnes, take your top off.
Not yet.
Go on!
I don't bloody want to!
Come on.
Don't talk, it's distracting.
- Just one word.
- Last time,
it spoiled it for me.
- Always the same!
You can talk to me before,
but not during.
You only think about yourself.
And now you're going to sulk.
I'm not sulking.
- You are, you're sulking.
- I'm not.
I'm annoyed, not sulking.
You're sulking.
No!
Look at you.
Am I sulking?
I'm pissed off!
Can I have a glass of wine?
Come on, it'll be better
in the bedroom.
Where are you going?
In the bedroom.
Forget I'm here.
Sir? If you'll come this way...
He had a nervous breakdown,
that's all.
It's like being tired,
but incredibly tired.
He's depressed. Understand?
Happens to 20% of the French.
Like piles.
He'll need looking after
for a while.
He's in the nut-house.
20% don't end up in the nut-house!
You're a pain.
The nut-house!
I spent a week there.
- Really?
- Yes.
Why?
Cocaine, poppers, ecstasy...
Not all at the same time, mind.
They kept me in for nine days,
then a week with my parents.
- I preferred the hospital.
- Why, what's it like?
Like a hospital.
You walk in the park,
take medicine,
people come and see you
and bring chocolates and flowers.
And the shagging that goes on!
Really?
Yes. I met
this young schizophrenic there.
He fucked me so nicely...
You have to go and see him,
talk to him...
Be with him.
Even if it scares you.
Is everything all right?
It's not too hard?
The head nurse
said you're a lot better.
What day is it?
Tuesday.
Tuesday the what?
What's the date?
I don't know.
Do you want me to bring you
something next time I come?
Some condoms?
No.
- Or...
- Yes?
Shit!
I can't remember anything any more.
Shit! I forget everything
at the moment.
I want you to bring my lamp.
I went for a piss the other night
and banged my head.
It's for his own good!
You had a job as a mechanic.
Why didn't you go back there?
I'm not interested,
do you understand?
Is loafing about all day
so much more interesting?
- I take photos.
- That's a new one!
You'll end up like Antoine:
no job, no money!
He's doing really well.
The telly bought
the rights to his play.
We're rolling in money!
Give me the keys!
As I promised not to mention
your debt, here's a letter.
What's this?
A list of things
you could do instead.
I don't believe this!
"Paint the spare room,
wash the car, clean out the shed"?
I'll tell you something.
You know what granddad
once said to me?
He said, "It's sad
but your father's an arsehole."
Frederic!
Here are the keys.
Thanks.
Tell him you're sorry.
Brown it in butter
with a few onions.
Whole onions, mind.
Watch out, a car!
Warn me earlier.
What's the point
when it's already there?
- Keep an eye out.
- I've never done it before.
All the same...
Let's go.
The sauce is very important.
A bottle of good Bordeaux
and a spoonful of white flour.
Hurry up, will you!
- You're so tense!
- Of course I am!
- Fancy a blow job?
- Leave it out!
All right?
Surprise!
I've fixed it.
I had a hard time
getting all the parts.
Second surprise.
To my folks' country home!
We can go as often as we like.
Nicolas and me cleaned it up.
It took us four days
but it's spotless now.
You'll be able to rest there.
We can go tonight if you like.
Great, eh?
Come on, up you get.
- What are you doing?
- Taking the bus.
But I'm taking you.
I'm not going to Nicolas' place,
I'm going to my mum's.
Hang on.
Wait, Antoine!
We can go later on if you like.
I'll drop you off at your mother's.
What the hell's wrong with you?
I'm sorry. No, wait...
I'll drop you at your mother's,
no problem.
I don't want to see you any more.
It's over between us. Finished.
Why do you say that?
What did I do?
You bastard!
I cleaned the whole fucking house!
Are you taking the piss or what?
You know what? You can fuck off
and die, you wanker!
Mental case!
Look at me, you bastard!
Look at me, you fucker!
You fucking wanker!
He's not in.
I know but he's not in.
Goodbye, Frederic.
- Are you all right?
- I'm all right.
Antoine. When did you get out?
A month ago.
I'm staying with my mum.
You said I could come
and stay with you when I got out.
I'm moving out.
I'm moving in with Henri.
He'll be here in a minute.
- Never mind, then.
- No, come in.
Come on.
I can't even make any coffee.
It makes me hallucinate, anyway.
We have to talk.
I haven't seen you for weeks.
- Aren't you going to let him in?
- He'll go away again.
Sylvie?
Are you there?
It's mostly in the morning,
sometimes at night, that it hurts.
Right here, you see?
All I can tell you is,
it'll pass.
All by itself.
You sleep better, you see things,
you breathe...
You're less afraid.
And one day
you realise it's gone.
How long does it take?
Fifteen years, at least!
Move your elbow.
I've got your toe
on my left testicle.
You should be so lucky!
I'm getting a hard-on.
We haven't really got room!
It's like a scene
from one of your plays.
Agnes!
Do you have a Minitel?
What a pain!
It's in the corridor.
Valerie. My name's Frederic,
I'm a friend of Antoine's.
He's told me a bit about you.
In fact, he's done nothing
but talk about you.
He's told me how you met,
about your first nights together,
about how you broke up,
about your life together,
he's played me
your favourite music.
He often says
you're the "love of his life".
He loves that expression.
He thinks it's tragic.
I don't suppose any of this
makes any sense to you.
I've been telling him that
for years.
But today I'm doing
what he's often dreamt of doing:
I'm writing to you.
I wouldn't have done this
but for a serious development.
Antoine got ill.
I don't know how or why.
He spent three weeks
in a psychiatric hospital.
He's not gone mad,
it was his nerves.
He was depressed.
Like 20% of the French.
He just needed looking after
for a little while.
He got out two months ago
but he won't see me any more.
I don't know why.
I wish I could write like him.
I want to ask an odd favour of you,
and I hope this letter
convinces you.
It pains me,
not being able to help him.
I get the feeling
he thinks it's all my fault.
I don't think that's fair
and I can't get it off my mind.
I'm asking you to help him
and to help me.
I need it.
I thought it better to write
so you wouldn't feel
under pressure.
I'll wait in the cafe opposite
until five.
I'll be drinking a beer,
or a coffee if there's no draught.
I'm tall, quite handsome,
and there'll be a blue helmet
opposite me.
You're not that handsome.
Hi. All right?
Well, there you go...
I'll leave you.
Do we know each other?
Who are you?
"Do we know each other?
Who are you?"
I think I'd better stop
taking the tablets.
I lived with Valerie.
She got married
and left me the flat.
Your friend slipped this
under my door.
So, anyway...
With one thing and another...
She got married?
Who to?
A big bloke. Nice.
She used to talk about you
like a sailor lost at sea.
So when your pal showed up
I couldn't resist it.
My name's Lorette.
This is OK, eh?
I'm sorry.
Why?
I don't know.
It's embarrassing.
It's full of spelling mistakes.
Don't be shy.
We're almost like old friends.
I don't know anything about you.
You pal's sitting over there,
looking all tragic.
- Are you going?
- Yes, to work.
What do you do?
Social worker.
No, I'm joking.
I work in a bank.
I won't go into details,
you're depressed as it is!
I was so looking forward
to meeting you I haven't eaten.
We could meet again if you like.
It's up to you.
Tomorrow?
I'd like that but I'm not
great company at the moment.
I'm obsessed with death.
Ennui.
I've no appetite,
can't get a hard-on,
I live with my mum
and I watch telly.
I haven't talked for ages.
I'll need a three-hour nap
to get over this.
- My stomach's rumbling.
- Are you hungry?
Do you want my sandwich?
Go on, it's no sacrifice.
I usually give it to the pigeons.
There they are, look.
Waiting for it.
Thanks, Antoine. See you tomorrow.
You will be here?
Yes. Or on the bench opposite.
- All right?
- Yes.
Still staying with Nicolas?
Not for much longer. I'm looking
at a studio flat in Vanves.
That's good.
Were you pleased to see Valerie?
Yes, I was pleased.
She's really pretty.
She's not as small
as you made her out to be.
Going to see her again?
I don't know. Maybe.
Well, I'll be off.
Hang on...
Were you really pleased?
Yes.
I didn't know, you see,
I wasn't sure.
I'd better go, I'm tired.
Thanks.
I'll tell you something.
I'd always hoped you'd do that.
Pass it! Behind the tree!
Go on!
Hey, sonny!