The Last Bath
Oh girl Rita? What are you
doing up here? Go downstairs!
Sorry, sister.
Glad I see you! I already left you
the flowers there. Everything is there.
- Is everything on the altar?
- Yes yes, I left it as you asked.
So girls... Go! To have lunch.
The van is not supposed to be
waiting for you, like yesterday.
Andor!
Girl, you've been here for half an hour.
Come on. Hurry up.
Wherever I do it.
go down there
and in front of the altar you already
have everything to make the arrangement.
And it is: one, three, five. And those
little leaves all around the vase.
- One, three, five...
And make it quick so we
can go to lunch, It's okay?
It's okay.
Sister Josephine, you have a call.
It must be Lourdes. Tell
him I'll call him back, okay?
It's not Lourdes, it's from outside.
- It's okay.
- See you then.
See you soon.
Look, unfortunately I
don't bring you good news.
Yea?
Your dad was sick for some time, and...
Look, Josefina,
your daddy passed away today.
- It was his nephew,
Alexandre, who found him in bed.
Father Manuel has already
taken care of everything.
The funeral will be tomorrow.
Yes.
Alexandre is here with me.
He can't be alone in that house, can he?
Poor little thing...
He turned fifteen last week...
He's still very cute.
It is my sister?
Angela? No one has yet talk to her.
friends and companions
flee from my disgrace.
My relatives are far away.
Those who seek to take
my life they set up traps.
My God, acknowledge my guilt.
Do not abandon me, Lord my salvation.
God our Father,
you rightly condemned sinful
man and you promised her life
by penance and the final resurrection;
we humbly beg you to
deign to bless this grave
while your servant's body
descends to the earth,
receive his soul in
Heaven, by Christ our Lord.
Amen.
Almighty God wanted to
call our brother to himself
whose body we delivered to the earth
to return to the place from
which it was taken...
Receive your soul and take it
to the presence of the Lord.
Oh son then?
So go.
Don't look like that, boy.
Go...
You will see that
everything will be fine.
Look that still tonight you'll sleep
in your bed, in your little room.
And look what your aunt will
take very good account of you.
My mother hasn't arrived yet...
Have you been able
to talk to Angela yet?
Do not.
He's got that idea she comes from.
The last time she came here,
look, it was at the festivities
of Our Lady of the Agony,
four years ago.
She appeared there with a man,
it's not even known if he was a
boyfriend, if he was a husband.
But since she fell out with her father,
she never set foot here again.
Can I?
Do you have a little bit of chamomile tea
there with some cookies to eat something.
You've been rolling
up all dinner. Come on.
You have to eat.
You have to help the aunt. Come on.
Adelaide spoke to your teacher and you
don't have to go to school tomorrow.
Eat a little more, Alexandre.
Alexandre, eat a little more...
I am not hungry.
You shouldn't walk around barefoot.
The slippers broke when I fell.
Excuse.
Turn, turn, turn, turn.
Get up here.
- Do you want the blanket?
- No.
It's here folded at the bottom of the
bed, in case you get cold at night.
See you tomorrow.
- Good afternoon.
I'm from social security, and
I come to talk about Alexandre.
Allow me to offer you my condolences.
I have some documents here, Dona Josefina,
and I would like you to read
them very carefully.
Our great concern, Dona Josefina,
it really is Alexandre's well-being.
If he doesn't have anyone
to take care of him,
he will have to go
to a reception center.
But I would like you to
reconsider this possibility.
I can't imagine myself
to come back here.
But it doesn't have to be here.
- It might be...
- Yes Yes. I understand, but...
I don't know if Father
Manuel explained it to you,
Yes.
Okay, I have the congregation...
- Yeah, he told me.
- and it would be very complicated,
because I'm a few months away
from taking perpetual vows
and suddenly this is a...
- I understand.
- it's a twist a little too big.
But of course I understand
that he doesn't...
- It's just that Alexandre can't stay alone.
- He can't stay.
He can not.
Unfortunately
or luckily it's my daily
life in the congregation.
Because we also have an institution
of girls who come by court order.
And so I know these processes.
But right now...
I think I need to fit.
Because Dona Josefina
would assume parental power.
- Perental.
- Exactly.
I thought you were in your room.
Sometimes it's important
to let off steam.
If you want to talk...
Today when I came home,
I... I passed Alice.
She was here, wasn't she?
She was.
Alice was here because she
she's worried about you.
I'm going to the orphanage, right?
We'll talk about it later. Now,
when you get home in this state the first
thing all you have to do is go to the bath.
Come on.
Go there.
how long have you don't
you shower, Alexandre?
I do not know.
- huh?
- I do not know.
Don't you know?
So why don't you shower?
- Because of the hand.
- Because of the hand?
And you are going to walk pig
while you have your hand like that.
It doesn't matter.
Yes, ma'am. Then?
Put a plastic bag in your
hand, that's no problem.
Oh! Get out there!
But aunt, I'm cold.
You're cold, nothing. You have
to stay a little longer like this.
Which is to make sure it all dies.
She lifts her head up, because it
still gets in your eyes, come on.
Ready. let yourself be
like this a little more.
It doesn't hurt anyone.
You're going out on this one.
Treat Adelaide well that she
has been a great friend of yours.
I come tonight.
See you later.
We don't live alone in the world.
sometimes before we think in our person
we have to think about others.
It cost you something to go to
Adelaide's house, have warned her?
Do not.
No?
Do you have something to tell me?
Sorry, aunt.
Let's go to sleep?
See you tomorrow.
Alexander.
Then?
What's up?
I can't sleep, auntie.
What time is it?
It's half past three.
Go to your bed, go.
It's just that I had a
nightmare about the grandfather.
Go have a glass of water.
And then you go back to bed.
But...
I wet the bed, auntie.
So go...
Let's go to sleep.
See you tomorrow.
Aunt.
When are we going to Porto?
When you behave yourself.
I really wanted to go back there.
I only went there once with the
grandfather. We went to see the dragon game.
The mother was with us too
only she didn't get to enter.
Did she do like her aunt?
She went to live in Porto...
You are boring today.
But I'm sure she
doesn't like me anymore.
Of course she likes it.
And will the aunt abandon me too?
Will she also return to Porto?
But who was here to take care
of everything? Was it you?
Yes. I can take care of the house, then!
It would also be cool to live alone.
Is there? Don't you need me?
Do not.
No?
So you want to come here
and wash your clothes?
Oh aunt...
does the aunt know my father?
Do not.
Grandfather and mother
never said anything to you?
I was never told anything either.
Was he from here?
If I told you I don't know who it is,
how do you want me to know
whether he was from here or not?
Where are you looking at?
- Shut up!
- You're looking at Sandra's tits.
I'll soon show you
some scenes on the net.
Look, do you want to go to my
house and play console soon?
Ya, it could be...
But then lend me your cell
phone for me to talk to my aunt?
Bruno, Alexandre!
Shall we stop whispering?
My God, why are you so good?
If you trusted me with my nephew...
if this is what you want from me...
give me a signal.
Help me know what to do.
Didn't you wash your hair?
No, I'll have to wash it
with that crap in eight days.
It's okay. But in the meantime
you can wash with normal shampoo.
Look there, is that a bath?
What is this here?
- I don't know, it shouldn't have left.
- Everything dirty.
Bath!
There...
What is it?
Nothing.
There.
Sorry, you're gonna have
to tell me what that is.
It hurts me here.
It's a little red and it hurts.
Show there.
Come on.
No, let it be.
What you have everyone
has. It's all in this world.
You got it all on fire.
try washing there and pull it back.
I am unable.
- Can not do it?
- No... It hurts me.
So we have to go to the doctor
to see what you have there.
You may need a circumcision
or that it's just inflamed.
I do not know. Turn around there.
Ready.
Now...
Be careful it will come out hot.
Give here.
Comes here.
Ready. I'll enjoy it and make dinner.
And hurry up, okay?
I thank you Lord.
because being angry with me
Your anger was appeased
and you consoled me.
God is my savior. I have
confidence and I fear nothing.
The Lord is my strength and my praise.
You can come now.
Good Morning.
Beware that I'm going
to open the window.
Then?
Did you get to sleep?
Didn't you have pain?
No. It doesn't hurt anymore.
Orange juice...
The aunt has to go to Porto
tomorrow. If you want to come with me?
- I can go?
- You can.
So I do.
Aunt, can we go to Dragon Stadium?
That's the hardest thing.
I do not know.
I don't know if we have time.
Give here.
I know you were very brave.
When I opened my lip it was
ten. Ten people grabbed me.
Show. Well, I noticed
that you have a scar here.
This time it was only three.
When you were born you had
the infirmary all around you.
Because?
Because a child hasn't been born for a
long time and you were like a kind of...
Ah, yes it was. The grandfather
even told me this story.
Look, this is the Church
of Santo Ildefonso.
It's on the Battlefield.
And this is the street I told you about.
Look at the tram.
Let's walk?
- No, we don't have time.
- Oh, okay.
The city of Porto was not
like that for some time.
- Yeah, I guess.
- With so many people.
Aunt, aunt, aunt! Buy me these sneakers?
- Come on. Go...
- Aunt! Please!
We've already taken such a long tour.
- O aunt, look here!
- I have to go now. Come on.
40% off, aunt!
You don't need sneakers. You've
stopped in stores three times.
Yes, I need to go there! Please aunt.
God bless you. See you soon.
I miss you so much, sister.
I need your help so much.
I know.
the death of your father it
must have shaken you a lot.
And now there is this child.
But be strong and pray a lot so
that God illuminates your life.
I would be unable to leave my nephew.
There are many ways to love God.
Devotion to others, charity
are other ways of us relate to God.
You are my family.
Josefina, we love you a lot.
But you have to go on with your
life spiritual wherever you are.
You can always count on us.
Thanks sister.
Four.
Five.
See you tomorrow.
Aunt.
can you pet me just until I fall asleep?
Give it a way, go.
You only put it on
again tomorrow morning.
Then there are no more drops.
You don't feel those little
bites anymore, may I help?
No, aunt. But now don't talk...
You're so spoiled.
Oh aunt, don't dry my hair
too much. To be sexier.
- To stay longer what?
- Sexy.
That's what Claudia said.
Who is Claudia?
A friend of mine.
Sit there and I'll cut you
a little bit of that hair.
She puts her head back.
Look at me.
- Do you want me to cut your bangs?
- No. Let it be.
- My name is Nuno Mota. I am the
notary of Vila de S. Sebastião.
Yesterday your sister was here.
Yes.
She is the head of the couple and
that's why we can proceed
with the distribution of his
deceased father's assets.
I'm so sorry... Has Angela been
to the village of S. Sebastiao?
Angela Antunes, right?
Angela Antunes, yes.
- I wanted to know what day Ms.
Josefina could come to my office.
Just a question. Don't you
have her contact information?
- I can't make it easy
for you, Ms. Josefina.
- But we set a date and you
clarifies everything with your sister.
A hypothesis: if the mother
comes back, what happens?
Well...
- If the mother comes back, it's obvious
that the mother always has priority.
But if...
how am I supposed to
explain this? And so...
having a history of a mother who has
already dropped out different times,
how does this work?
Only if something very serious happened
- is that it could be prevented the
union between a mother and a child.
Is everything all right, Dona Josefina?
Oh aunt.
Aunt!
Aunt, can you buy me this sweater?
- So ugly.
- Is nothing.
Do you like it?
I like.
Come on, come here.
What size is it.
Yes, it's just one.
It's an M.
Can you try it?
Yes.
- How much is it?
- Ten.
- How much?
- Three?
- Ten. Ten euros.
- Ten?!
- Yeah.
- Do you like that?
- I like!
It's okay.
So Josephine?
Angela.
Do you want to come in?
I go first.
How is Alexandre?
It's okay.
where is he?
he walks with football games
there at the championship and...
today comes a little later.
Are there oranges?
No. This year I haven't
picked oranges yet.
I miss the oranges in our backyard.
Everything is so neat.
I'm sorry he's not here.
I went through moments very complicated.
I was hospitalized and...
meanwhile i got married
with a wonderful man
which has helped me a lot.
And I think I'm ready to restart
and I would love to
have my son by my side.
I will leave my card here.
Tell Alexandre to call me.
Why didn't you wake me up, aunt?
Good Morning.
Sorry, I fell asleep.
So what about Professor
Filipe didn't call?
He called, but I don't know why the
phone was silent and did not hear.
Aunt, we have a day full of
important games. I really have to go.
No, it's not important. you never stay here
having lunch with me so you'll stay today.
Auntie, but I really have to go.
How are you going? Say it...
- I'll go by taxi.
- Are you taking a taxi? With which money?
With mine from my savings.
alexander i don't want
you to walk by taxi alone.
Aunt, I'm not a baby anymore.
And if you're that worried,
buy me a cell phone.
Play, play!
Look here, look here!
Look here.
Go!
Come on, Alexandre. Let's go!
Shoot!
You're going to fail, big guy!
- Good!
- You're a sham.
Alexander.
Come on, Frederick! Good feint.
Go Go!
Cut!
Come on Alexander is yours. Kick!
Goal!
Well played!
Congratulations. Congratulations.
look... you're going to high school
in S. Joao in September, or not?
Yes I will. You're
going too, aren't you?
- Go, go.
- It's gonna be really cool.
- Hi.
Has the mother arrived yet?
No Fred, I think it's
Rafa who come pick us up.
Okay I'll see.
- Then fine?
- Hi.
- You know yesterday was really cool
after the game. - It was, wasn't it?
- Did you get home all right?
- I arrived, you too?
- You played really well.
- Thanks.
My brother is not so much anymore.
Oh, don't say that.
Claudia!
He is my brother.
- Goodbye.
What are you doing here?
I came to see you play.
But weren't we supposed to meet at home?
So we came back together.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
Wasn't this grandfather's cell phone?
It was. And now it's yours.
There you have my number.
And I put money on your cell phone
in case you need to talk to me.
Thank you aunt.
Aunt,
there will be several parties
now farewell to the second cycle.
But I just wanted to
go to one. I can go?
And you only want to go to one, why?
For the aunt to let me go.
And this is when?
For the week.
If you're good, it can be.
If you don't behave, you won't.
And you Gabriel, what are you drawing?
It's a duck and a rabbit.
Philip!
Hey there!
Oh, Bruno!
Can I talk to Alexandre?
Alexander can you get
up please and come here?
Son...
Excuse.
This is Edgar, my husband.
Alexander, my son.
Hi.
I went to the house there.
You weren't. I left my number,
I was waiting for you to call me.
Did you go?
Did not know...
The aunt didn't tell me anything.
Do you want more
bread? That I won't eat.
It's okay.
Is very.
Enough, enough.
My son is fantastic, isn't he?
He is.
What do you think of the three
of us going to live together?
Me, you and Edgar.
So what about Aunt Josefina?
- My dear...
- She's been taking care of me.
The aunt came to help
you and I appreciate it.
But that's life.
What do you say?
Alexandre, don't be late!
You are listening?
Your mother also takes pictures
of you to body parts or hair?
Like this?
What does she have my hair?
I am, good night.
Josefina?
Hello Angela.
Pass me to Alexandre, please.
Alexandre went to a party the
end of the course and it is not.
Come on. Go call him.
Angela I'm telling you
that Alexandre is not here.
He never is?
- You're gonna make me go
there to talk to Alexandre?
Come on. Go call him.
Do what you want.
I don't know what else to tell you.
I'm sick of calling and he
doesn't answer his cell phone.
Are you the one with it?
Do not.
It's okay.
So, good bye.
Goodnight.
- Come on.
- Help here.
The state of this guy...
Rafael, look at his coat.
Screw this!
Calm.
The key?
Open the door there.
Are you okay or not?
Are you okay to enter?
I am.
Calm.
You are fine?
Come here.
Can you support yourself there?
Help me take your pants off... Go.
Look, just to let you know I'm leaving.
Alexander then?
- Are you leaving like this?
- Yea.
Because?
Since you lied to me
and cheated. It is not?
- I lied? On what?
- Yea!
That my mother was here at home
and she didn't tell me anything.
she left you her number and
she hid it from me, didn't she.
- We can talk?
- I don't want conversations with you.
Wait, wait, wait. We can talk?
Sometimes, since you lie to me so much, he
could have lied to me about my father too.
- I did not lie. I didn't lie to you!
- Let go of me. Drop me!
- I didn't lie to you, Alexandre.
- Let go of me, let go of me!
- I didn't lie to you, I didn't lie to you.
Mom, are we going to have dinner?
Baby, do you bring
the suitcase over here?
Let's have dinner?
Love, give money to Alexandre
for him to go eat something.
He arrives?
But weren't we all going together?
go to the restaurant
down here and eat anything
that we are already jaded.
Come here, Alexandre, come.
Listen...
your mother has been with
migraine in the last few days.
That's why we'd better stay, is it?
Okay. But do you want something?
No, nothing is needed.
But go is fast, before it closes.
Oh, and if there's no money, say down
there that we go there tomorrow and pay.
What are you talking about?
I want to leave please.
I can no longer...
What?
I can no longer do it.
Can't what?
Angela, talk to me.
Let's go.
Let's go where?
Please let's go.
Where are we going, Angela?
I don't want to go back to that house.
- I don't want to, please.
- Calm down, Angela.
Angela, Angela.
Calm down, will you?
Calm down, calm down.
- Good night.
I want a strong drink.
Please.
What is your name?
Josephine.
Josefina...
It's a good name, Josefina.
My mother chose it.
And where are you from?
I'm from here.
Of Untim.
From the Douro.
Untim from the Douro.
Well,
finish it there and I'll take you home.
Not because my nephew is picking me up.
No...
Aunt, no. Aunt, come here I'll help.
Aunt, come here. Aunt, come here.
Come here. Pass the arm.
Come here.
Can you climb?
Lean there...
Aunt, do you want me
to go get you something?
Do not stay here.
Stay here.
Sit here next to me.
There is so much that I I
would like to explain to you.
- Aunt, don't talk now. Let it be.
- I do not know how...
Aunt...