Ah, my dear Ann, so
glad to see you again
after all these minutes.
20 of them at least.
50 minutes, Johnny.
= 50 minutes!
50 years away from you, Ann.
You're not flattering me, Johnny.
Now what have you been doing?
Waiting for the specimen of Dr. Lee's.
I could check with Dr.
Lee's office nurse, you know.
But I'll let it go at that.
Aw gee, thanks, Ann.
Dr. Lee would like to have the report
as quickly as possible.
=t don't think we can run another test
this afternoon, Johnny.
Oh, that's okay with me.
But if the boss wouldn't spend
so much time experimenting
with those rabbits,
he'd get done with...
That's Mr. stendahl"s business, Johnny.
And if you wouldn't spend so
much time running errands.
Deliver this to Dr. Jackson.
Okay, Ann.
Coagulation test for Dr. Lee.
= sh.
= another blood donor?
Yes, the transfusion's
just been completed.
How is the experiment
progressing this time?
Mr. stendahl will know in just a minute.
Well, Ann, there is a chance
this time the electric needle
accomplishing its purpose.
Oh, I hope so, Mr. stendahl.
But I can hardly believe
that rabbit's been dead for 12 hours.
I know, and yet the electric current,
plus transfusions has revived the heart
so that it is functioning.
There's the proof.
Now everything depends upon what happens
when the heart is no longer
stimulated by electricity.
If the heart stops beating
when the current is switched off,
can you resume the process?
= no.
There's only one chance and this is it.
All right, Don.
Well, start putting the equipment away.
= Ann!
Mr. stendahl!
Look!
= it was dead.
Now it lives!
We've made a successful beginning at last.
That's wonderful, Mr. stendahl.
Did you say something about
a coagulation test, Ann?
Yes, Mr. stendahl, but I can run it.
And I'll watch the rabbit, sir.
Thank you, Don.
Thank you, Ann.
Maybe I would like to
relax a little while.
What do you want?
I've come for the body.
What body?
Here.
= oh.
The ape woman, huh?
City medical college wants her now
instead of in the morning.
City college.
Fine time of the night
to come for this one.
But you're welcome to her.
Glad to get rid of that animal.
Wait a minute, I gotta
check with the police first.
- Police?
- Yes, the law.
What gets me is, why move
that stiff at this hour?
We're scheduled to be taken
to the city medical
college in the morning.
Mm-hmm.
But this is the time we
generally move 'em, ain't it?
Yeah, in, not out.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, anybody here?
Are you kidding?
I wonder where Fred is.
= can't be far.
Looks like he's just been eating.
Keep your eyes straight ahead!
Oh, yeah, what gives.
Shut up, get over in that closet!
Hey, let me out of here!
- Let me out!
Let me out of here!
Come on, let us out!
Open it up!
Open the door, come on, let us out!
Hey you! - Come on!
Let us out of here!
Let us out, come on, let us out!
Let us out of here, let us out!
Open it up!
Fred!
Hey, Fred!
Hey, let us out of here!
= let us out!
Let us out! - Open it up!
Open the
door, come on, let us out.
Well, what do you know.
How did you two guys get in there?
Where's Fred?
= that's what we'd like to know.
Some guy locked us in there.
Hey, you better go outside
and see if our wagon's still there.
I don't get it.
I went out to eat and Fred stayed here.
Maybe you was lucky.
= get down!
So, you're afraid of her, huh?
You say, you didn't see
the man who held you up?
Okay, you think you could
recognize his voice?
Oh, I think maybe I could.
Huh, if I ever heard it
again, I'd remember it.
Get that, will ya?
Right.
Well, whoever the man was,
he came here for something.
There's only one thing you
can take out of a morgue.
It's for you, Harrigan.
= thanks.
Harrigan, homicide squad.
Huh?
Where?
Oh, yeah, I get it.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
That oughta help.
Your dead wagon crashed and burned
on the Ridge fort highway,
I always liked that old bus.
Me too.
Maybe this is the answer
to what this is all about.
Where are you keeping the ape woman?
Over here, you want to see her?
= yeah.
Fred used to say I'd wind
up in one of those things.
But you can't figure about
death, even when it's murder.
Fred, it's Fred!
What's he doing in there?
Obvious, isn't it?
Blood count, coagulation,
sputum and acetone level.
Four more.
I won't get around
to those tests til later.
I've gotta finish these slides
and deliver them to Dr.
Jackson immediately.
Dreaming again?
Mm-hmm.
Same old dream, 'bout when
you finished medical school.
It's only one more year.
Plus two years internship.
Sometimes those three years seem endless.
= t know.
It's really tough when
a guy can't even afford
to buy his best girl an engagement ring.
If she wanted one.
Darling, you know I do.
Well, why didn't you say so?
= did I have to?
= look.
Do you suppose you could
make my fraternity pin do
in place of a ring for a little while?
Darling, it's a beautiful pin.
Okay.
Consider yourself engaged.
Yes, sir.
Anything else?
Oh, yes.
Gee, you think of everything, don't ya?
Only the important things, darling.
Is this strictly in
the interest of science?
I'm sorry to break this up.
I'm Harrigan from headquarters.
Oh, another one of those tests
from the police department.
We haven't had one here in a long while.
No, just some information.
Are you stendahl?
No, I'm Don young,
one of his assistants.
And this is miss forrester, another.
Glad to meet you.
How do you do.
I'm working on a case
and I thought maybe you
lab people could tell me
what this is.
It's a surgical smock.
Oh, is that what you call it.
Yes,
surgical smock.
Say, would you mind trying this on?
I'd like to get an idea the size
of the man who was wearing this.
Certainly.
A little bit chewed up, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
= not a bad fit.
No, it could have been worn
by a man about your size.
You don't suspect me, do you?
Oh no, if I did I'd ask you a lot
of routine questions like,
where were you last night?
Well, I was here at the lab
til about eight and then...
Don and I were together all evening.
Yes, we're engaged.
Oh, I see.
Well, if I suspected you, miss forrester,
I'd ask you where you lived?
Well, that's easy,
1021 east grove street.
And you, Mr. young?
= 381 beacon street.
What's this all about?
Not a thing.
I just wanted to find out where
to send the wedding present.
Now, I'll take that
smock if you don't mind.
And thanks a lot for the information.
You two can pick up where
I so rudely interrupted.
Well, I wonder what that was all about?
= Don?
You didn't do it, did you?
Yes, I did.
And I'm gonna do it again.
Well, I better get those
slides over to Dr. Jackson.
I won't get back by closing time as it is.
Grab them for me, will ya?
Mm-hmm.
I couldn't be sure of the fit,
but the laundry marks checked.
Here he comes now, get a good look at him.
Tail him, George.
Right.
Yeah, hello, Ann.
Hello, Mr. stendahl.
= where's Don?
He's out delivering
slides to Dr. Jackson.
Oh, well then you'll
have to come with me.
I have an emergency for Dr. kellogg.
= Mr. stendahl?
Mm-hmm?
= t have some news.
News?
Don and I, we're engaged.
Well, congratulations, Ann.
Thank you.
I was wondering when
that was gonna happen.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Mr. stendahl, did you see this
in the paper about that ape woman?
Yes, strange isn't it?
What would anybody want with it?
And to commit murder for it.
Well, we better be going.
Mr. stendahl, I'd
like to make a telephone call.
I'll only be a minute.
I'll wait for you in the car.
Hello, mother?
This is Ann.
Listen carefully now.
If the police ask you where
Don and I were last night,
tell them you were with us
until after one o'clock.
No, I can't explain now.
But please, mother, be sure
and tell them just what I said.
Goodbye.
I'm sorry I detained you.
That's all right, Ann.
It's a long drive out there.
Started so late, be dark before we arrive.
Will we be gone that long?
Mm-hmm.
Is there a phone there?
Probably.
Don?
Well, I told him I'd wait.
He has enough to worry him as it is.
Don, worried?
What about?
Did you read about that clue
to the murderer who stole
the ape woman's corpse?
= clue?
Oh, the surgical smock you mean?
Yes, just before you returned
to the office a detective was there.
= detective?
Yes,
he had that smock with him
and he got Don to try it on.
Nothing unusual about that.
They probably checked a number
of places using surgical smocks.
I know, but he wanted to know
what we were doing last
night and where we lived.
I think he suspects Don.
Oh, don't be silly, Ann.
How could Don possibly be
implicated in a thing like that?
Quiet!
Get back!
He seems to know you.
My affection for dogs,
they understand that.
Hello, moloch.
Ann, this is moloch, the caretaker.
How do you do?
This way.
Oh, moloch?
How's the patient?
She's all right.
She's in the other room.
= good.
Is Dr. kellogg here.
Oh, no.
Unfortunately, he's tied up in a meeting.
Take off your coat, Ann.
Come in, Ann.
Come here, Ann.
Quite harmless.
Nothing to be afraid of.
You.
T can't believe it.
Moloch, you clumsy fool,
they found that surgical smock
and traced it straight to my laboratory.
Her body's been well preserved.
They say she had the
strength of a gorilla.
= it isn't human.
Precisely.
This is a manmade creation, an experiment.
That's why I had to have the body
to prove or disprove my
theory of restoring life.
After all, I'm not experimenting
with a human being.
This is an animal, we
should recognize it as such.
But you committed a murder to get it.
Oh, yes.
You see, moloch is a true scientist.
He understands the
unimportance of a mere life
when it might impede progress.
= t can't understand
how I could have been so wrong about you.
All the time Don and I worked for you,
we both looked up to you as a great man.
I sincerely hope to
vindicate that judgment.
I want to take an experiment here
that no one has ever dared to try before.
Why did you bring me out here?
I told you, to help me.
Certainly you don't think
I'm gonna have anything to do with that?
Yes.
Well, I'm not.
Now, please let me out of here.
Ann, I need you.
What do you mean?
I need your blood.
Oh, no, no!
Oh no!
Why?
Her heart's beginning
to feel the strain.
You gonna take much more?
About another pint, if
her heart will stand it.
Not worried about her, are you moloch?
If you take out too
much blood, she'll die.
Oh, moloch, I believe you feel sorry
for my pretty assistant.
Don't be a fool!
We're scientists, not sentimentalists.
No offense, moloch, but with that face,
you're not exactly a Casanova, you know.
This is more in your line, moloch.
If I can succeed in
bringing her back to life.
Stimulated by the electricity,
the heart's been beating
regularly for about two hours.
It's now or never, moloch.
All right, take off the oxygen tent.
She's alive!
= this is what I've dreamed of.
Now let the doctors laugh at my theories.
Here's the proof.
Yes, we must let her rest
and breathe and live.
Ann.
Ann, we did it, she's alive.
Please let me go.
You'll be all right, now, Ann.
There's nothing to worry about.
Here.
It'll help you get your strength back.
Ann will be all right, now.
Well, moloch, all this only
proves half the theory.
What's half a theory.
Well, so far we've brought
life back to this hybrid.
If she can be transformed into a woman,
then I'd have brought
back life to a human.
Then why don't you do it?
Isn't as simple as all that.
The method for that transformation
has taken years of research.
And I don't have the records.
If I could only get them.
Of course, I know they're
in Dr. Fletcher's office.
But she didn't come
home at all last night.
She didn't even phone her mother.
I'm sure she's all right, Don.
= where could she be?
She's never done anything
like this before.
Well, perhaps she stayed
overnight with some friends.
No, I checked with everybody we know.
Didn't she say anything to you last night?
Hope I'm not busting in
on some vital experiment.
No, come in.
Thanks.
He a friend of yours, Don?
Oh, this is Mr. Harrigan
from police headquarters.
Oh, how do you do?
You stendahl?
Yes,
I'm glad to meet you.
= mutual.
= miss forrester here?
No, she isn't.
We were just talking about her.
She didn't come home last night.
Her mother was...
Yes, I know, her mother
telephoned headquarters.
That's why I'm here.
Where were you last night?
I was out looking for her.
Her mother phoned me.
She was very worried about Ann.
Must have been out pretty late.
I was, why?
One of my men called on you.
Oh, about the smock business?
Oh, it's just routine checking.
Surely you don't suspect my assistant
of being involved in anything...
Stealing a body from the morgue?
You'd be amazed how
suspicious we police get.
By the way, young man,
speaking of the morgue.
Why would your fiancee ask
her mother to lie for her.
What do you mean, lie?
Well, Mrs. forrester says
that her daughter told her
to tell the police that
you were both with her
until late the night
of the morgue incident.
Ann said that?
Yeah, obviously
preparing an alibi.
Why should she want an alibi?
That's what I'm going to find out.
Does that boy sound like the
one you heard in the morgue?
I don't know, could have
been, but I'm not sure.
Are you talking about my voice?
= yeah.
How about it, Jim?
No, I couldn't swear to it either.
Okay, fellas, thanks
a lot for coming over.
Say, what's this all about?
Do I look like a killer?
= you don't have to look like one to kill.
You're wasting your time, Harrigan.
Don has been my assistant
for several years
and I assure you that his
character is unimpeachable.
Yeah, what about the
disappearance of his fiancee?
You any theory about that?
Well, yes.
Could possibly be amnesia.
Amnesia, I don't believe it.
Well, Don, Ann has been
working awfully hard lately.
I myself am to blame for that.
It was very thoughtless of me.
Well, you'd know more about that than I.
I hope he's wrong, kid.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Goodbye, Mr. Harrigan.
Oh, I'll be seeing you.
I've got to find Ann, sir.
Something must have happened to her.
I'm sure she's all right, Don.
But you said it might be amnesia.
Oh, well, that was just a wild guess
to appease our detective friend.
If you don't need me, sir, I'd...
I know, I know.
You want to go out and look for Ann, huh?
Go right ahead, Don.
= thanks.
Why do you always find
it necessary to kill
every time I send you for something?
Well, he come in and
switched on the lights.
Oh, I see.
You certainly turned that
office into a shambles.
I done it right, huh?
You, yes, moloch, you did very well.
All right, bring Ann in.
You want the ape woman, too?
Not yet, leave her upstairs for a while.
There must be something wrong.
She killed him!
I need some more of your blood, Ann.
Not much this time.
Just enough to get from it
the glandular secretions
that Dr. Walters used
in transforming the ape
woman into Paula dupree.
How is she?
Weak, that's all.
You don't have to worry about her, moloch.
Stendahl, look!
What is it?
Her hand!
The transformation is taking place.
Dr. Walters' data is correct.
I, myself, proved that I can restore life.
But now I can change that life
from one form into another.
Take off the oxygen tank.
So this is Dr. Walters' creation.
Paula dupree.
Paula?
Paula dupree?
Do you understand me?
Paula!
Her brain.
The only brain she ever had was subnormal.
In some ways subhuman.
Come, Paula.
You stay out here, moloch.
She must have absolute quiet.
The slightest shock
might prove very harmful.
Paula?
What's your name?
Are you hungry?
Paula?
Moloch!
What are you doing with that needle.
Look at the meter, she's dying.
And you thought you'd
bring her back to life,
you crazy fool.
You'd have killed her.
= then she's dead?
She's all right now?
You ain't gonna hurt her no more?
No, moloch, we must make sure
that nothing happens to her.
I have a new problem now.
Possibly I can solve it.
I shall try.
Ann will help me.
Paula's brain is gone.
Her reactions are those of an animal.
= ain't that what Paula is?
Practically.
Dr. Walters succeeded in
transferring the brain
of his nurse into Paul dupree.
You're gonna put in a new brain?
Yes,
don't worry about miss forrester.
We're going to take good care of her.
= just don't hurt her no more.
Certainly not, moloch.
We'll take very good care of her.
I just can't understand it.
Maybe Mr. stendahl is right.
Maybe it is amnesia.
Take it easy, kid.
We'll find her.
I can't believe that anything's
really happened to her.
That's right,
don't let your imagination
run away with you.
This stendahl, you think
a lot of him, don't you?
Yeah, he's been
wonderful to me and to Ann.
He's a great man.
You mentioned some experiments
that he'd been working on.
Just exactly what are they?
Well, he's developed a
theory of resuscitation
and it works.
= oh.
How?
By electrical impulse.
You mean,
restoring life to a dead body?
Yes, he's been at it for years.
It's quite a
trick if he can do it.
What does he experiment on?
Oh, Guinea pigs, rabbits, monkeys.
Just the other day he brought
a rabbit back to life.
No kidding!
1 see.
Well, I've got to be going.
I wish you'd
let me know the minute
you hear anything about Ann?
I certainly will.
See you later.
Oh, hello Harrigan.
How are you, stendahl?
Very well, thank you.
Any word about miss forrester?
Not yet.
But I think we'll find her before long.
I certainly hope so.
Been busy lately?
Yes, yes, they keep
us biochemists on the run.
I guess they do.
I'll be seeing you.
Well, drop in anytime.
Thank you, I will.
Well, I had hoped
we might have heard
something by this time.
Not even a lead to go on.
= too bad.
Oh, Don.
Did you start that test for Dr. Allen?
I'll get on it right away, sir.
Thank you.
Work is an excellent antidote for anxiety.
Yes, I guess you're right, sir.
Shut up, Jake!
Quiet!
Who are you?
What do you want?
Never mind that, where's stendahl?
= he isn't here.
Well, I gotta see him right away.
If you care to leave your name, I'll...
Never mind my
name, I gotta see stendahl.
Are you a friend of his?
Ain't none of your business.
Where is he?
= t don't know.
Why didn't you say so!
Where have you been?
I went in to get you.
That ape woman's gone.
= t know she is.
Didn't I tell you to watch her?
Yeah, but she got away.
Where did you go?
Your place in the city.
Oh, you fool!
Say, doc, I ain't sure,
but I think somebody tailed
me all the way out here.
What makes you think so?
I seen lights back of me all the way.
Good evening, Don.
Mr. stendahl!
I hardly expected to see you here.
= what is this?
What are you doing here?
Let go of me!
Moloch is my assistant, Don.
Yeah, well, tell him
to take his hands off me.
All right, moloch!
What I want to know is where'd
he get my fraternity pin?
I gave it to Ann.
Oh, I see.
Well, gentlemen, shall we go inside.
I'm performing a little experiment.
As long as you're here,
you might be interested in seeing it.
I call this my country laboratory.
= Ann!
What are you doing to her?
I told you,
I'm performing an experiment.
Ann has been most helpful.
If you hurt her, I'll...
Nobody ain't gonna hurt her.
You seem to be jumping to conclusions.
Why have you got her strapped...
Moloch, tie him to that chair!
We thought you were such a great man.
Such a wonderful man.
I regret that I must
destroy that illusion.
= t know.
What do a couple of lives mean
when it might impede scientific progress.
Is that it, stendahl?
I see that I've taught you well.
Moloch, see if you can find Paula.
Release the dog, it might help you.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Paula, that ape woman?
Yes, I brought her back to life, Don.
Now I'm going beyond that,
beyond what Dr. Walters
and Dr. Fletcher accomplished with her.
Her brain was destroyed.
I'm going to give her a new brain.
You mean Ann?
Yes,
you can't operate,
you're not a surgeon...
Don, you always said
that I was better than any surgeon alive.
But, but, you can't experiment!
You can't operate, not on Ann!
This is, this is...
= this is science!
Operations are impersonal, Don.
Ann, he must be insane.
I.
We're gonna get out of here, darling.
Believe that and hang on!
= Paula!
Maybe the dog will find her.
Perhaps, if she hasn't
gotten too far away.
Paula!
= listen!
There's the dog.
Yes, come on.
Get back, Jayden.
Paula.
= I'll hit her back...
No, moloch!
Any shock might undo
everything I've accomplished.
Paula, we're going back.
Do you understand?
Paula, we're going back to the house.
You're all right, Ann.
Oh, Don.
Can you walk?
I'll try.
Get away!
Take her into the house, moloch.
Did you find anything interesting?
= just the usual lab stuff.
How do you figure stendahl in this?
= just a hunch.
What about this fella, Don young?
= he's in the clear.
I've just been using him to...
Old orchard road.
That's out off the Ridge
fort highway, isn't it?
I think so, why?
Here's a light and power
bill paid by stendahl.
413 old orchard road.
That ambulance burned
up out in that district.
Yeah.
I think we're about ready.
What are you gonna do?
Perform a very interesting experiment.
He's gonna take out her
brain, don't you understand?
He'll kill her.
= no.
Our friend is a little hysterical.
He's gonna kill her!
You've gotta stop him.
You ain't gonna do that.
You told me.
Shut up,
moloch, and get out of here.
= no!
You ain't gonna hurt her.
Keep away from here, moloch.
Stay where you are, I tell you!
Fool.
= Ann!
= no.
Take it easy, kid.
Who got stendahl?
= she did.
Good, that'll
save the state a little money.
Kind of rough going
for a while, wasn't it?
= yeah.
Darling.
This is really getting
married in the rough.
No engagement ring.
No honeymoon.
= t don't mind.
Is he after us?
= not at 15 miles an hour.
Are you Don young?
Yes, sir.
What's this for?
Don't know, Harrigan's orders.