The Moon Child
I almost forgot to tell you.
Don't ask for Coke.
Why not?
"That gives you cancer,"
he says.
Is he normal?
Outwardly yes.
What did he do?
I do not know.
He's not tracking.
Disturbed, yes.
Hello.
I've already seen you.
Probably.
To drink something?
Water.
Sit down.
No, don't have to.
Thank you.
Damn.
You shouldn't have been drinking after me.
Now you are infected.
In a month you will have a tumor.
Jacob... it's a joke.
Asshole!
You never make friends that way.
You are hopeless.
I don't give a shit.
If you weren't sick, I would hit you.
Drop dead!
I want water.
I'll take it myself.
Fancy a video game?
You can be really stupid!
Why did you do that now?
I'll apologize.
Stomcup.
Come on now off.
What are you doing?
Come with me.
Come on baby.
Damn!
Tackle!
What's that weird thing?
Let me go!
How's the pain?
Present.
So we continue to take painkillers.
Maxilase 3000?
That one as well.
I can still smell the burning smell.
That will remain the case for a while.
You must rest well.
Sorry to disturb,
but it's Roman.
He called three times already. Is something wrong?
Not really, but...
Tell me to call back.
He's in your consulting room.
In my consulting room?
Yes.
What is going on?
Issues.
What is that?
Where did I leave my glasses?
Write about a fantasy character:
knight, damsel, dwarf, wizard.
Name, properties, motivation,
story, age, appearance.
Fifteen spelling errors.
'Age' is TIME.
Chloe.. is the webshop designer
my next appointment?
Ask her to wait ten minutes.
What interests you?
Not the dwarf, not the knight, not the wizard.
So the lady.
Yes, and then...
I had to go to school to keep from being
bored and now I'm getting stupid work.
Don't whine, we only have ten minutes.
It sucks.
I'd rather know if they don't find a cure.
What are those doctors doing?
Investigate, Roman.
While you think of the damsel.
Or made-up damsel, blonde, brunette?
Brunette.
What a surprise.
Psychological profile?
If you fell in love with her?
uh, cool.
Cool.
Like me, but a girl.
So cool.
Well done, great!
Bye.
Can you sit down?
Awesome.
Give her a round of applause.
The next candidate is a doctor.
A professor of medicine.
Good evening sir.
Come on.
Good evening.
What is your name?
David Assollant.
You are?
I'm a surgeon.
Shall I call you professor then?
No... David is fine.
David...
Tonight you are here for a purpose.
Yes, to fund a potholing trip.
For children with XP.
XP. Can you briefly explain that?
Very short.
It is a rare genetic disease
that causes poor recovery
of DNA under UV radiation.
Beautiful.
Applause to David!
Are you ready for the 50000 dominoes?
Yes. 47500 to be exact.
47500. Go ahead, David.
(A thunderous applause)
What is happening?
Afterwards we add up the points of the finalists.
Not the easiest part...
I'm looking for a man, quite tall, in his fifties.
Have you seen him?
No idea.
I didn't pay attention.
But see for yourself.
Thank you.
I've been looking for you for two hours.
I waited until the end.
Is the party over?
Everything fine?
Yes, it's fine.
Will you join the others?
You go.
I'll wait here.
Tell Angèle and Lucy I'm getting some rest.
Tonight I'll show you something amazing.
Awesome!
Go now, Roman.
What is happening?
Fixed short circuit.
So no heating.
But it's day.
I have to call.
It was never made on time.
Aren't you sleeping?
I'll call outside.
He's panicking.
He was acting weird last night too.
A public appearance is not for him.
He enjoys it!
Once when we were on guard duty,
we decided to play mime.
David disappeared, but when it
was his turn,
he suddenly appeared
in one of those restraint suits
with gold hypothermia foil as a
cape.
On his head he had a star-shaped
crown made of polystyrene.
They came from all floors.
Patients, nurses, everyone.
He was drunk,
but he was a prince.
What was he?
Halley's comet.
That morning he had been told that
his brother had passed away.
He hadn't told anyone.
Let's go.
Boys, take it.
Come on, wake up.
I have no gloves.
Anna has no gloves.
No gloves?
If you don't mind choking.
Please baby.
Thank you.
Here we go.
What did you want to say?
I have to tell you something.
It's personal.
I don't like that.
Who do you think you are?
One trip and he plays the gentleman.
I don't want to hear it.
You die like us, sick handsome.
You are a jerk.
What's with Anna?
I don't need to talk to her.
No.
But you have to be nice.
Since she's terminal, I do
n't need to talk to just yet.
We don't pity, Roman.
You know that.
Look at me when I talk to you.
Go apologize.
You don't care.
You've had tons of chicks.
I do not know what it is.
I will never make love.
No more time for that.
We do everything to give you time.
I've been married for seventeen years,
so I haven't had that many chicks.
Liar!
I know.
Jerk.
I didn't know your brother was dead.
That sucks.
In the second gene therapy we are developing,
we do not insert an exogenous gene into the XPC cell,
but ask the cell
to correct its mutation itself.
For this we use the homologous
recombination technique
repairing double-strand damage
after exposure to oxygen or
nitro radicals in the environment
or remote radiation.
There's the substitute.
Where?
Five rows down,
four to the left.
Doctor Carlotta Nicoli.
With the long hair?
Yes.
I sent you the results of Habib's
DNA repair.
My secretary got them.
I watch it. It's quite a bit...
I watch it.
Promised. Do not walk away.
David.
Everything fine?
Yes, I'm fine.
Bravo, this is good for you.
Thank you.
You're a bit of a hero.
If you say so.
You were so ranting about grants,
they had to ask you.
You're going to wake them up.
I'll try it already.
That's what we sound like!
XP - advanced stage
I'm tired.
I'm going to get some sleep.
I have an appointment in two hours.
I'll wake you up.
Letter from WHO is here.
They called.
Mathilde asked if you don't
want to work on guard duty on the evening of the wedding.
In case you forget.
Come on.
I didn't say anything about the transfer.
You do that?
Yes.
I'm actually hungry.
Paul's girlfriend is not happy with
our move.
Female friend?
Does he have a girlfriend?
Yes.
Already a month.
Why can't I see her?
You are indeed free between
midnight and five o'clock.
I want to see her.
Have you tasted?
It said "Di Bufala" on the suit.
Yes.
Awful.
Trial.
No, this early in the morning...
Awful.
They cheated me again.
I'm going to sleep for an hour.
are you waking me up?
The Adventures of Arthur Gordon Pym,
by Edgar Allan Poe.
Bah.
How so?
You don't even know him.
It's about storms, survivors,
shipwrecks.
Really something for you.
Someone named Poe? No, thank you.
At the time it was one of my favorite books.
It will feel cold for a while.
I knew it by heart.
Beginning and end.
Oh yeah?
And how will it end?
"Then we plunged into the embrace
of the waterfall,
where a chasm opened up for us.
But in our path stood a veiled
human form alone,
a lot bigger than any
other inhabitant of the earth.
And the color of his skin was
perfectly white as snow."
Sit up straight.
You can have it.
Look at the back.
Why?
You bit into it.
On your first visit,
when you were two years old.
You bit others too.
I have two small CBCs
in basal cell carcinoma.
We don't have to do anything right away,
but...
Come a little closer.
Wait, no.
Like this.
Anything else to register?
Yes.
If I
operate on you at the end of the week,
I'll do the rest right away.
There's no hurry.
I'm the doctor.
I decide if there is a rush.
And I might go on vacation.
Shows.
That is nothing.
It can wait.
I wipe it clean.
I'm making some photo galleries.
Head up.
Hair out of the way.
Guard.
You're in top shape, boy.
Very funny.
Really... it's going well.
Are you still taking your vitamin B12?
Yes.
And Aldara?
Do you use those?
I know it's no fun
but we have nothing better against carcinomas.
Why are you looking like that?
Just like that.
But your shoes are cool.
Are you okay?
David's going on vacation.
What?
He forgot to tell us.
Ah, well...
that's good news.
It must have been about three years ago.
It's okay.
Blockage of the ear canal causes
partial deafness in the right ear
without affecting daily
life.
Hoogachtend, blah-blah-blah...
David Assolant.
I receive wine as a gift after every ENT operation.
Miss Nicoli is here.
Should I let her in?
Chloe, take those flowers away?
The smell is too strong. Horrible.
Hello. Doctor Assolant.
Mrs. Nicoli? Miss. Nice to meet you.
We met in Paris.
Yes.
Didn't I keep you waiting too long?
No problem. I'll be right there.
Drink your coffee quietly.
We can talk here.
Fine.
You can immediately discover the department.
I saw one of your patients outside.
A moon boy.
Have you talked to him?
No.
He will be my first XP.
You must give me his antecedents.
As a student I saw you at a
colloquium in Montreal.
Do you remember?
You are running against an American doctor who...
Coffee please.
I won't hear you say things like that
again.
That is not entirely true.
You look a little disappointed.
No.
Not at all.
I'm going upstairs and we'll talk later.
Today it will be difficult.
I'm busy.
But we got acquainted.
Bye.
I don't want you to pay for my coffee.
I wanted someone stronger.
Someone who
can cope with acne, hives and cancer.
I think you are not suitable.
Jacob!
Hi.
How are you?
Like with a kid who swims alone at night
.
Guillaume scolded me.
Don't mind.
This is Aitor.
Hi.
This is Noémie, my neighbor and
William's new girlfriend.
I did not know that.
It's scary to swim in the dark.
How do you do that?
There are no waves.
It's not dangerous.
You are insane!
We freeze. Bye.
Are you asleep yet?
On the wedding cake.
Come on.
Do you do it or should I call.
No, you have to.
You have one new message.
Come by tomorrow.
I have to tell you something. David.
Hello.
How are you?
Good. And with you?
Hey Hello.
Well...
How are you?
What does the hood look like. Or is the seam.
Roman, in the lock in two minutes.
Inside.
Hello.
What is?
Why doesn't it?
Hello.
I'm Dr. Nicoli, I replace...
Yes, I wanted to talk to you about
Ms. Boar's spinocellular.
Will you join us?
I'll be right back.
You must introduce me.
I can't show up all at once.
But you did.
Doctors should support each other in the face of adversity.
I know that.
It's not mine.
It's Article 56.
You're leaving, that's not easy.
But I'm here.
Yes, you are there, that is clear.
I am not done.
How do we do it then?
I am not done. That's just the way it is.
Sorry.
I must earn your succession
, but I do not despair.
Damn.
Sorry.
My colleague...
No problem.
Are you moving?
And.
I'm leaving, Louise.
I'm going to or WHO in Geneva.
To work with the director
on rare diseases.
Care for XP patients, including,
or subsidy, and so on.
So it will be a little less fieldwork.
More ministerial work, so to speak.
Like this.
Congratulations.
Yes I am happy.
Real.
I didn't know you applied for that job.
A few years ago. Twelve years ago.
Then I didn't get the job...
and now yes.
Nothing will change for Roman.
Someone will take over from me,
you will not be left to your own devices.
Do you understand what this means to him?
You must tell him.
What a mess.
What is happening?
Isn't the suit out yet?
No.
Have you not been in your sas?
David has something to tell you.
I'm going to Belgium.
Anna is dying.
She has...
I'm coming.
I want to see her.
Damn disease.
Do I hear me, Anna?
It does not matter.
No, I'm kidding.
You do not have to be scared.
I'm sure they're exaggerating.
It is nothing.
Your friend in the hospital is nice.
She's not my girlfriend.
It's none of my business.
Did you have sex with an older girlfriend or a prostitute the first time ?
Are those the options?
In the books you give me, it's
always one of the two.
It was my cousin.
So a bit of both.
I'm not your schoolmate.
All right...
Sorry.
But that's not the point.
You dare not ask the real question.
What the kissing and undressing was like.
I do not care.
How so?
How was it then?
What?
Then.
Well, after that...
I lay naked against her,
against her skin.
And when you're ready...
you will wonder whether to laugh
or cry.
I will do like everyone else...
You will hide in her hair.
And after that, when you've made love, you'll
find it wasn't so hard,
that you didn't need to know anything
and that your bodies were doing pretty well.
And if you could do it over,
you would do it over.
But that's not really the point.
Actually, yes.
No.
The woman we love should not
complain. That's what it's about.
I'm not hungry anymore.
Then don't eat any more.
It is hot here.
Good evening.
Don't worry,
it's not a gun.
Were you scared?
- Not really.
Anyway.
Just kidding.
It's okay.
Would you like something to drink?
Good evening.
Hello Mama?
It's me.
With David's phone.
We ate in a restaurant.
Do you piss while calling your mom?
Yes.
You don't call while you piss.
She must have heard.
She's my mother.
That's why.
Go wash your hands.
And shake off the drop before you put it away.
Did no one teach you that?
With all fingers, not just those two.
I'm just telling you.
Thank you.
I wanted to go to rugby or evening training
, but the spots are full of UVs.
Did your father play?
Can't bomb me.
He was there that first time.
He carried me.
Bullshit.
There were three of you when
I gave my diagnosis.
I said it was once in a
million that something was incurable...
well, that the cure would yet be found.
I had to protect against cancer.
If you hadn't said that, he might
have stayed.
Maybe.
He has another child with his new wife.
It doesn't happen twice.
The child may be sick.
He should have stayed and
shared the misery with us.
It's great misery.
What would you have said if you had
known I was sick in Mama's tummy?
That they had to keep me?
Don't know.
What do you think?
If you prevent someone like me from
being born,
That means I shouldn't have existed.
Do you feel that way?
And.
They lost.
Yes, they lost.
It does not matter.
It's a game.
Losers are the most beautiful to see.
Good...
I'm afraid.
Yes, me too.
Slept good?
Yes.
You're lucky you can shave.
Do you want to do it?
I cut you, I can't.
No look.
I trust you.
I hold it like this.
Take this.
Your fingers like that, like a claw.
Like this.
Now you gently put it against it.
You tense the skin.
Like this.
Carefully. And when it's flat,
you gently go up.
So...
Go ahead.
Nice.
And rinse.
You start again.
Yes please.
So... Stop, stop.
That's good.
Now you are waiting for your own beard.
Roman, come on.
What is that?
Is that the Atomium?
Is he a guide?
I can not hear you.
Yes, he is my guide.
They want to come with us.
You do match the decor.
Bye.
Did you say yes?
No.
It could have been fun.
Well...
The psychologist doesn't want me to
become antisocial because of my suit.
Do you see her again?
Just kidding.
Take it off.
Cool, is it?
Yes.
Funny how small cars are.
Do not you think so?
Yes very nice.
They are really tiny.
Sometimes I get bored.
But it would be even worse without you.
Yes, but sooner or later...
What?
Nothing.
I won't be there anymore.
You are not dead yet.
No, that's not.
And the backpack.
Do you never lock your car?
No never.
That way they take what they want without destroying it.
Dad had his new child this afternoon.
Are you happy? Are you going there?
Certainly not. I don't want to see him.
And the child leaves me cold.
Roman... it doesn't leave you cold.
You know what? We go together.
No!
Why, no?
Come on.
I'll call your mother and my wife that we'll be late.
It's two hundred miles!
Two hours.
Damn!
Which one is it?
The girl under the lamp.
Okay, cover up.
Why?
They are UV lamps, against jaundice.
Come a little closer.
I'll take it off. Take off your glove
, then you can touch her.
I will hurt her.
No. Put your hand in.
She's hot.
Feel her feet. At the bottom of.
That's the best spot.
Go ahead.
She's ticklish.
I'm putting it back on.
Put on your glove.
Finished?
She's ugly, but funny.
A leather dress like an hourglass
Spicy, but not fast
And in it, like a sailor
a rocking girl.
She seems somewhat English
What a beauty
And Moody Blues sings the night
Like white bridal satin
In the harbor of the night
A rocking girl
On the quay
What a beauty . Terrible.
What a beauty
Thank you.
Bye, mom.
Good evening.
Monday we will remove that stain in my neck
. After the holidays, we said.
Eight o'clock.
You won't be treated any worse
now that he's gone.
Is he leaving?
Didn't he tell you that?
No.
He would tell you.
He is transferred.
Ten. On site, please.
You start, I finish. You trace.
Certainly not.
You only watch. That was the agreement.
Excuse me?
I do the deletion.
How so? We
prepared the operation together.
Should I just admire the head of the department?
He apologizes, but he did
n't plan it that way.
Fuck that old jerk.
His mother called.
She looks for him everywhere.
You are no longer my doctor.
Was that you that night on the beach?
Yes.
What were you doing?
Walking around.
I'm doing my pedicure internship. Beyond.
What are you doing tonight?
Nothing.
It's Jacob's birthday. I invite you.
- Okay.
It's a costume party. Pack of your choice.
See you tonight.
He didn't show up.
I heard.
What are you doing?
I'm leaving.
I don't have to pack a lot.
Find someone else.
For the record.
I want you.
It may be the job of my
life, but not what I dreamed of.
I dreamed of someone strong.
Someone who can deal with hives,
melanomas... and a substitute, damn it!
Not such a tone, Carlotta.
You are ten years younger than me.
This department runs smoothly,
you just have to keep up.
It took me twenty years to
build this.
So don't think...
that you can teach me a lesson.
Why should you love your job more
than I do?
Why would it be more valuable?
Is it more legitimate because you
know an incurable boy?
Doctor Assolant!
What a man!
Jesus.
Out.
No.
You go out.
What is?
Nothing.
I have some medical knowledge, you know.
Isn't there a Band-Aid here?
In right drawer.
No, the judge.
Halley's comet.
I don't know if I would have recognized you.
You are a minor, I decide about your health.
He doesn't touch me anymore.
It's about helping guys like you.
He cares about the money.
Hold on, Roman.
Your cocktail.
Thank you.
Can I do that too?
Trial.
Say no, mom.
Say you can when I'm older.
I'm sorry about the surgery.
Also apologize to him.
I don't owe him anything.
Quit it.
Look what I found in the image.
A mummified bird.
You have a crazy job.
Just my half-sister.
That's how she looks.
You are kidding me.
How do I come across?
Why are you getting rid of it?
Did you make a choice?
The steam menu.
Two.
Hello, come in.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Hi.
Who are you going to bite tonight?
We'll see.
We're not training tomorrow.
They switch places in the stadium.
Special lamps, without UV.
For you.
I did not know that.
I didn't ask anything.
Do you know my girlfriend?
Yes.
Back.
We can kiss.
White on white, that does not stain.
Dancing, Miss Japan?
Why not?
Come.
I hear you wear a mask during the day
. Why not last?
That is a secret.
So you go out at night.
Yes, with the bums and drunkards.
Will you take me with you one day?
On a night.
If you want to.
I feel like.
Sorry. I was in the hospital,
I had a...
An operation that went wrong.
I called.
I need him for a second.
Do you come?
What is?
What happened?
Listen.
I'd rather you openly piss off
than to feel such pity.
It's awful.
Five thousand euros for places.
We got a Belgian.
That is normal.
Oh yeah? I have no pity.
I'm afraid.
You are awful.
I don't know which of us...
Okay, I'll stop.
We go back to our old life.
You can't just force a job on someone.
Just go.
I'll be right away.
Sir?
Call an ambulance.
I thought I had seen Roman.
Did he come for you?
And.
He's been coming for three days.
To prepare for the operation later.
He's with the anesthesiologist now.
And did he cooperate well?
Yes.
But he did say you find him difficult.
He's a bit upset. Squirt
Spino into his neck.
Why wasn't I there when you spoke to him?
Because it's not necessary.
I wanted to show you his folder today.
You must rest.
Are you okay? Shall I join?
No.
What?
Nothing.
Come follow the operation.
I'm sure I'll need you somewhere.
We don't have to tell Roman anything.
He wants nothing more to do with you.
Did he say anything else?
He thought my office was ugly, badly decorated
and with a terrible smell.
I saw Mrs. Garnier was gone.
It was too early.
She had relapsed.
Bye Roman.
Are you going to lie on the table?
Are you OK?
I could have had a drink with you,
then I would have taken you home.
What's holding you back?
I do not have a car.
And I'm supposed to stay until tomorrow.
Then I'll take you home tomorrow.
Hi.
Are you hurt?
It's okay.
Don't I get a kiss?
I'd rather break up, Noémie.
I don't like it.
It's pointless.
I prefer that I decide.
It was nice wanting to go out with you,
but now it ends.
I'm not leaving because you
arouse pity.
I want to continue with you.
Now you don't say anymore.
Hello.
When I lost my brother ten years ago , I didn't want to heal anyone.
And then suddenly there was Roman.
I couldn't cure him, but he
needed care. I went for it again.
When Audiberti greeted people,
he shook hands and asked:
"And? Still five fingers?"
This morning I realized I
could no longer answer yes to it.
From now on I am a doctor without patients.
I would like to leave the hospital
alone one last time, without crutches.
Although I would have liked to have given you a lift.
Kiss, David.
I've been waiting for ten minutes.
You have to put a coin in it.
Nice of you to come.
How are you?
Yes fine.
I'm going to see if there's...
are you coming to me?
Yes, I'm looking around...
Do that, look around.
Stripes from last summer.
Very nice.
Bye, mom.
Hello.
I didn't know you'd
be so early.
How was the movie?
Was okay.
What are you doing here?
I was invited.
I'm going to get something, I'll be right back.
Did you bring the flowers?
She never waters them.
Did you eat?
- Yes... What was it?
Quiche and bacon cubes.
She can't cook. Never could.
It's hot. No, don't touch.
What is it?
Chocolate cake.
Take the salad cutlery.
That's not cake.
Of course it's a cake.
A chocolate cake.
See, that's...
Goodbye, Harold.
I think it's not baked enough.
No, it looks fine.
Damn!
Stand up!
Let me go!
Off the field! To the locker room!
And not a peep!
It hurts.
Laurent, you take over.
I'll sort it out.
There is nobody home.
Oh..-no?
Mom's not home.
Then where is she?
To a drink.
A party for my doctor.
My ex-doctor.
Then why did you come to play?
I didn't want to go there. That's my right.
I didn't want to go there.
It's none of my business, but...
It's none of your business!
I didn't think you were cowardly.
I'm not cowardly.
I don't know what he did.
What then?
Also a too hard tackle?
Did he treat you?
Good evening.
Hello.
Everthing okay?
Good evening.
One two three four five. OK, so.
Yes, it's fine.
Where is our hero?
How is Roman doing?
Good.
David, come on.
Good evening.
It hurts me to say goodbye.
I know your talent will go elsewhere.
When you were a young student,
you asked me for advice one day
when choosing your specialization.
I couldn't help you.
You objected to some of my choices.
Are you coming for my father?
And.
A precocity, and a reliability
for which I ask all your friends for a
grateful round of applause.
Good evening.
This isn't mine,
it's from the book of David.
It's called Michael.
Coward, you have courage.
But where?
Don't know.
He is like a stranger to you.
I don't know how
to activate it.
So look no further, it's here.
Fool that I am,
dozed off because of your slovenliness,
and indifference because you run away
to new horizons.
Then search.
It's stupid not to.
But don't go get him where he isn't,
or in yourself. He wouldn't last.
He destroys you
and does not survive. It's not a laugh.
Good evening.
I'm not that young, but I can
read a nice text.
Like I just said...
Give him a warm round of applause.
Thanks again.
Thank you.
I'm not much of a speaker.
Sorry.
It's always hard to leave...
from people you love...
Horrible.
From a job that…
that I have dreamed of since childhood.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
A year later.
Come on!
Come on Roman!
Come on guys.
Harold takes him
.
Have you had this before?
No.
Roman, are you okay?
It'll be fine.
And?
What?
Where is he?
Good.
Thank you.
Very good.
Turn around, young man.
We are waiting for the results of the MRI.
Roman, are you freaking out?
Roman?
Are you afraid?
Don't know.
And?
Yes, he's here with me.
Good.
What kind of webshop interior did you want to do?
I explain to him and call his mother.
No, I prefer to do it myself.
You stay with us.
Web shop interior?
Now.
Tomorrow we have to do a biopsy.
I'm not free.
How so?
I go to a movie with friends.
It's been agreed for a week.
Okay.
Then come tomorrow night.
Thank you.
What are you doing tomorrow?
Did Carlotta tell you that things aren't going well?
Is that why?
No.
I am visiting friends.
What a butt-licker.
And I wanted to see you.
So...
Last year I didn't want you to leave.
Have you wondered what I went through?
Yes, but I'm not a doctor.
I made love.
I'll go now.
Bye.
Hello.
It's broken.
He knows very well what he has.
He vomits constantly.
At what time tomorrow?
Seven o'clock.
We gave him some to sleep with.
I don't have my suit.
Where is it?
Mama took it to wash.
Does not matter. We don't
need it where we're going.
I'll bring him back in eight hours.
Will the head of department prance?
I do not care.
Come on.
Are you succeeding?
Yes.
Give me your hand.
Lean on me.
Are you OK?
Yes.
You just have to say it.
Beech is.
This is millions of years old.
It is beautiful.
That's why we came.
Because it's beautiful.
Can I say something?
I'm not asking you to leave me,
but I don't want you to stay.
If you're a worm, it means I
'll make it.
But I'm not staying.
Those high nylons
Like strings on a violin
In that piece of skin troubled
By bow from which my song
flows
What a beauty
And under or barely closed
veil
A jesus black tuft
Moist in his cradle
As a swimmer, no longer expected
How long will it take you?
An hour or thirteen. It depends.
I'll call.
Am I out of the operating room?
Then we do it in reverse.
You call me, okay?
Everything fine?
Did it go well?
I walk with you.
Bye.
Safe journey.
Hello David?
With me.
It is over.
Where are you?
At the lake?
Lucky.
Did it go smoothly?
They say I'll make it.
With this.
And the rest can wait.
Everything is OK.
To kiss. And call me occasionally.
I like that.