And we continue listening to good music,
and almost reaching the end of our program
we have Dr. Maximiliano
Espósito with us
who has just released his
new book "Tribal Education."
Explain to us briefly Maxi,
what the book is about?
Well, the book is an investigation
that took me many years.
I am a psychiatrist and I work
mostly with boys and teenagers
who have the particularity
that they grew up
or are growing up
in orphanages or reformatories.
Therefore they are not
raised in traditional families
and studying the subject, I found
that when they grow up in these groups
without the model
of a "normal" family.
Other codes are established,
there are other traditions,
and there are other rites
that shape their minds in another way,
as happens for example in tribes or clans.
The subject also comes from your own
life experience, right?
Yes,
I became an orphan when I was a kid,
and I lived all my childhood
and adolescence in foster care.
It was a house in the countryside
where many boys lived.
Well, Maxi, thank you so much for coming,
this is the end of the
program for today….
SEVEN ARRESTED FOR THE SEXUAL EXPLOITATION
OF WOMEN IN SUBURBAN WHOREHOUSES
VOICEMAIL
Hi, Maxi, I'm Héctor,
Héctor from Totorales.
Well, many years have passed….
I would have liked to talk to you.
I was calling you
all morning but it was useless.
I'm not calling you
with good news. Dad is dead, Maxi.
Dad died.
I don't know if you're interested
in coming,
I had to let you know, right?
I'm calling everyone.
We will have to start
with the inheritance.
There are the fields,
the house, it's sort of a mess.
I believe that dad left you something.
Well, I did my part in letting you know.
If you want, you can come.
We can have a look
at this last will issue
so you can say goodbye.
We are here, always. Bye.
Waitress! A wine, please.
IMPLANT AND ORTHODONTIC SPECIALISTS
MORATORIUM
LOAN GRANTED
INTEREST
DEBT PAYMENT
INTIMATION
72 HOURS PERIOD
DULY NOTIFIED
Hello?
Good morning, we are calling
from the Continental Bank
Are you Maximiliano Espósito?
Yes.
Mr. Espósito, the reason for this call
is for the fulfillment of your obligations
with the Continental Bank,
regarding the credit
that we granted you….
ESPOSITO SLAUGHTERHOUSE
Shit!
TOTORALES FUNERAL HOME
She was such a good person!
A saint has departed!
She died alone, poor thing!
María!
Oh, dear María!
Dear, María!
THE MORNING
DIRECTOR: JUAN MANUEL ESPOSITO
Hello.
Is someone there?
-Maxi….
-Héctor.
I can’t believe it, you came!
-How are you?
How was your trip?
It went well.
Maxi, how long has it been
since you last came?
I don’t know, like ten,
fifteen years.
How did you get my telephone number?
No, it has been twenty-five years
since you left.
Have you seen anyone else?
Have you just arrived?
Yes, I just arrived,
a little while ago.
First, I passed by the wake house,
I thought that maybe you were there.
Look, what happened to dad
took all of us by surprise.
Well, but he was very overweight.
Have you had the wake yet?
No, not yet.
We still have to do some paperwork.
But it's…. all on track.
We were waiting for you, Maxi.
The truth is that I came for a short time,
I can’t stay long.
But you just arrived
and you already want to go?
Not now, but I can’t stay long.
You were talking to me
about the inheritance,
with whom should I talk about this?
Well, you only came for that?
Sebastián is handling
the paperwork.
Why don’t we go to my office?
You can talk directly with him
he can explain everything
about the paperwork
and also about the
wake. What do you think?
You can estimate
there is around 4,000 head of cattle
and we have only twenty-five employees.
What was the name
of the manager?
-Bacigalupo.
But he died a long time ago.
Here, the one that took over was me.
The others got on with their lives.
I was the only one that
stayed on the farm with dad.
But the farm made the money
for everyone’s studies,
trips,
rent, and parties.
And the others know
about the inheritance?
The others know it very well.
Dad and I put in a lot
of time and effort in this….
and everything works well, too….
but dad's will is
that we all talk about it.
To stay calm and discuss everything.
For me, the important thing
is that you came,
you can say goodbye to dad,
and we can finally finish with
everything that was left half done.
What was left half done?
Oh, I can’t believe this.
Motherfucker,
and on top of that he plays dumb.
How many times do I have to say to you
that you can’t do that here?
Go away!
Go home!
Don’t even think about
coming here tomorrow!
Can you believe it?
You have to be on top of everything!
Okay, people are arriving.
What’s up?
Look who I brought.
Maxi!
It’s so nice to see you!
Juanma!
Hey, I saw you in the La Mañana newspaper,
you are the editor-in-chief!
You’re always so perceptive.
It’s your fault,
you always gave me everything you read.
You got me interested in it.
I started writing and fell into the vice…
the profession!
Juan, did you bring me
Benitez’s thing?
Did you bring it?
Yes, I left it in dad’s office.
Why don’t you leave it
on my desk, in my office?
Have you seen the house?
Yes, I’ve been looking downstairs.
Okay, come with me
and I’ll give you the tour upstairs.
Okay, let’s go.
Do you know? Recently,
I discovered a secret,
a Polish writer, living here in
Argentina, about one hundred years ago
who wrote wonderful articles, and
he wrote a novel called “Nightmare”.
Juancito, it wouldn’t hurt to sweep here
every once in a while, right?
It’s hard to get,
but I can send you a book.
Yes, please.
It’s great, it’s wonderful.
There hasn’t been any light
in here for a while.
Dad was living alone
these last few years and let himself go.
Here is dad, Maxi.
Poor dad.
Poor him.
Why did you leave?
Why did you leave, dad?
This way Maxi, come here.
Over here, over here.
I’m sorry,
we should have told you.
Maxi, calm down.
Maxi, Maxi, calm down,
calm down.
This struck very hard for all of us.
Calm down, try to breathe.
Breathe,
breathe.
It’s all going to be okay,
calm down.
I can’t understand
why you keep Aldo like this.
He must be buried.
What you are doing,
it’s not normal.
Do you realize that?
It’s not the time yet.
Some things need to resolve.
Dad is okay with that.
How is he okay?
Hector, what are you saying?
What needs to be resolved?
What does that have
to do with being able to….
bury him?
Juanma
are you okay
with what is happening?
Because it’s not okay.
Maxi look, this hurts all of us,
it’s complicated.
We must be organized.
We must do things
like dad wants.
He must be a part of this,
he has to see that we respect his will.
Maxi, look at me.
Be calm,
everything is going to be okay.
There’s no problem.
Don’t ask me to be calm.
It’s horrifying what you are doing.
I don’t know if you realize that.
I can’t let this continue.
Have you reported his death, at least?
I’m going to the police.
Wait a minute,
Wait a minute…. you’re blind.
Try to understand
our point of view.
You’re thinking this the wrong way.
Try to understand.
Hector, what do you want me to understand?
That you went crazy?
Please, let me go.
What do you want,
to go to the police?
Do you want to go to the police?
We will go with you.
Okay, we are already here.
The three of us.
At the door of the police station.
What?
I don't care about your dessert,
come here!
We will wait for you inside.
Here comes the sheriff.
You’re messing around again?
How are you, guys?
It’s been a long time
since you last visited me.
What are you
laughing about, dude?
We have been waiting
for you for half an hour.
You can come at anytime,
don’t worry….
I came as fast as I could,
I’m here now, right?
Hello. How are you,
Maximiliano Espósito?
Don’t you know me?
Oh, yes.
Oscar.
Hey, am I so different?
Look when you came back…
It’s been a long time.
Well….
We were talking….
I explained to him
the situation with dad.
But it seems there are doubts
about how to continue.
This is a delicate matter,
it’s going to take some time.
I can solve this as the sheriff
but the family comes first.
We have to do things as we do them.
You understand
what I’m saying, right?
No, actually, I don't understand.
Dad is fine where he is.
He is at his house.
He is not in danger,
nothing will happen to him there.
We will solve this among us
when the time is right.
And then we will deal with dad.
I’m sorry,
but I don’t think it’s okay
to leave him
just lying there.
It’s a serious situation, right?
The normal thing to do
is to take him to the morgue,
or a cold store….
We don’t have a morgue here.
We merely have something to write.
Look at the junk
I have as a computer.
What I mean is that maybe
there is something we can do,
that is what I mean.
Yes….
to wait.
I don’t think it will take much longer.
SECURITY POLICE
Maxi!
Hey, Maxi!
You’re tired, right?
Yes, a little bit.
Do you want me to take you to the house?
You can rest for a while,
or if you want, you can stay the night.
-To the house?
-Yes.
No, I don’t want to go there for now.
You can come home
for as long as you want!
There's a guest room as well.
Oh, if so you can stay in mine too,
there is no problem.
Thank you, now I need to be alone
if it’s okay with you.
Whatever you need.
I’m going to walk around town.
Okay.
Maxi, in times like these
I need to search for spiritual guidance.
Some comfort.
Are you still going to church?
No.
Well, think about it.
When you are ready,
I’ll wait for you at home.
Okay.
I live next door to the Monzú’s,
do you remember?
The Monzú, yes.
My house has black iron gates.
You can come at any time,
it’s okay if you come late.
I’ll be up. Any time.
Thank you.
I’m sorry,
I didn’t mean to scare you.
Javier….
I’m a little surprised,
nothing else.
Finally!
Come.
So, you followed the priesthood path.
Well…. yes, it’s logical.
This was always my house
since we were kids.
How kind of you to come!
Yes, Héctor called me a few days ago.
I arrived and have been catching up
with the situation.
I don’t know if you know….
Yes, poor dad.
It took us all by surprise.
Oh, so you do know?
That he is still in the house.
Do you know that?
Sometimes things don’t go
as you wish, Maximiliano.
Death is not an easy thing.
Yes,
but this situation isn’t normal.
I don’t know what Héctor is thinking
but it’s not okay.
There is a reason to have a wake
for the dead, to bury them.
You must know it better than anyone,
rituals are not a whim.
And that is why I’m telling you
that death is not an easy thing.
Let alone in a case like a dad’s….
because dad was not an ordinary father.
Aldo Ventura was a patriarch.
And for a patriarch’s
favorite son like Héctor,
the grief will be a pain that
will be with him until the last day.
And that is something
we will need to respect.
I understand what you mean,
but I don’t agree.
At this moment, our father
is sitting in a chair, rotting.
Do you think that that is okay?
God doesn’t close a door
without opening a window.
You must learn from the pain.
That you realize that you have a chance
to heal your soul’s wounds.
To heal the wounds in your heart
for leaving your father and his mission.
I didn’t leave anybody.
I have to apologize to you
because I committed
the sin of injustice.
You were also a favorite son.
You’re the other favorite son.
And, it's normal
that you couldn’t solve
the things in your past.
Dad….
was a man that worried
and did a lot so we could have a home,
so we can live abundantly.
That is why you see us like this,
close to each other, the ones that stayed.
And maybe, if you hadn’t left,
today, all of these situations
may have run a normal course.
I didn’t leave anybody.
Maximiliano,
dad worked harder for your
education than for any of us.
And when you had a chance,
you turned your back on the man
that gave you a home,
who raised you as his own.
You left him heartbroken.
You were always his favorite.
And one day you were gone
and left him a void
without even an explanation.
Anyway, he'd talked to us about you
and told us you were going to come back.
And you know what?
He was right because you are here.
What I think is that nobody
can decide on the future
of another person,
not even your father.
Dad was at your side
to guide you,
so don’t stumble,
don’t deviate.
I don’t know, maybe.
Maxi,
life, it’s not an easy thing,
but neither is death.
Maxi?
Maxi, is that you?
Anita….
Hi.
It’s so nice to see you!
Were you passing by?
No, no. I just came out of school.
I’m a teacher,
can’t you tell?
Yes, I noticed.
It’s so weird to see you here
after so long. When did you arrive?
Yesterday.
And why did you come back?
Because Aldo died, my dad.
A few days ago. Didn’t you know?
No, how would I know?
The Espósitos are closed.
I’m so sorry, how are you?
So-so.
The truth is that
this is something very faraway for me.
I came because
I need to do some paperwork.
You didn't visit before?
No.
I assumed you were in Buenos Aires,
but I never heard anything about you.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
What happened to you?
Will you ever tell me?
It’s been so long that I don’t know
if I wanted to explain.
I don’t know what to say.
Yes, it is true, it’s been forever
since we were children.
I can tell that
it wasn’t so bad for you.
I can’t complain….
Do you have some time?
I would love to know about you.
Now? Yes, I have some time.
-Have you eaten?
-No.
Do you want to go to my house?
I can make you something delicious.
Okay, yes!
Come on!
That way?
-This is crazy, right?
-Yes….
I’m all yours!
Please, stay. Don’t leave….
Maxi?
Do you know that if
you come here to live,
you could be the hospital director?
You have a trajectory no one
else has, you’re better than anyone.
Do you think so?
I have a lot of commitments
in Buenos Aires.
We are struggling with….
the college group….
Here,
you could be the secretary of health.
You were always so good with people.
You could even have your study group,
make agreements, whatever you want.
What can I say?
That sounds nice.
Come on, don’t be mean. Stay.
You can stay
at my house as long as you want.
And when you collect your inheritance,
you can spend it with me.
Are you going to miss all that? Come on.
Hey, how is everybody?
Maxi, it’s so nice to see you!
Dieguito! How are you?
How are you doing?
It’s so nice to see you!
Very nice! You look the same.
You look the same!
Oh, please, I have grey hair!
I missed you, I mean it.
I don’t know the rest,
but I missed you.
Thanks.
Dieguito,
why don’t you stop bugging
the associates with the raffles,
focus a little,
and put together a good team because
they are beating the crap out
of us every Saturday?
Diego is the President
of the Juventud Unida,
you must see how he maintains the club.
Oh, congratulations!
President….
It was a joke.
Dude, it was a joke.
What? Are you sensitive?
I think I’ve already told this one.
Once the old man tells me,
“You are going to kill a pig.”
He put me in the truck,
and took me to the pigpen
that was behind Fernandez’s post.
He gave me a knife,
got me into the pigpen,
and I started, of course, running
towards the pigs to kill one of them.
At some point I slipped,
I went to hell, I fell in the pigpen.
And the old man looks at me and says,
"If you don’t bring a dead pig
you can’t enter the house.”
Tough old man!
Do you remember when he took
us by force to Canullán’s brothel?
What a son of a bitch!
Yes, I remember that it was just before
I entered the police academy.
He forced me to get naked,
handcuffed me to the bed,
and called the Paraguayan girl,
do you remember the Paraguayan?
And he tells me,
“You must learn from now
because this is what you are going to do
everyday.”
And he didn’t leave until I was hard
and started fucking!
What a son of a bitch!
Want to play?
Thank you, I don’t play Chess anymore.
Come on, while the food goes down.
No, really,
I haven’t played in a long time,
I must be rusty.
Thank you, but no.
What are you saying,
that you forgot how the pieces move?
Don’t be a chicken!
It’s only for a short time.
Do you know how I learned to play this?
One afternoon in the slaughterhouse,
came a big group of Aberdeen Angus,
that are black, you know?
And the slaughterers,
the guys, are all dressed in white.
They sent them one by one, pim, pim, pim
and they killed them.
Then I said,
“At work,
I play Chessboard every day,
how can I not learn how to play?
So, I learnt.
But….
I always play with
the white pieces,
they are the ones
that work for me.
Check.
Good, Maxi, great!
It’s yours, Maxi, finish it!
Maxi!
Shit!
Calm down!
Maxi, calm down!
Hey…
I changed the sheets earlier today,
and there was nothing!
In the bathroom?
No, there’s nothing!
I didn’t see anything!
Wait, wait, chill.
You’re not thinking straight.
Calm down.
We were together yesterday
and you didn’t take anything.
Think, when was the last time
you took them?
Yes, I know.
Slow down, Maxi.
Stop and think.
I’m here for whatever you need.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I left the medication
in the room upstairs.
Do you want to go with me?
You go and do
what you have to do.
But I’ll stay as long as you need, okay?
You’ll be fine, go.
At this point in my life,
guarding as if I were a patrol officer.
But for you, we do whatever is needed.
We miss you so much.
Who’s there?
It’s me, Maxi.
So, you came back.
I thought you left again.
Thank goodness.
Show your face!
Show!
What are you doing here?
I forgot something the other day
and came looking for it.
You? What are you doing here?
I explained this to you
at the police station.
Hurrying up the paperwork.
Are you going to take him?
Not yet.
We’ll see.
And when are we going to bury him?
We’re almost there, aren't we?
Sadistic, son of a bitch.
You ruined my life, you fucked all of us.
What more do you want?
You can’t be here anymore.
I’ll bury you, dad.
What are you doing?
What’s your name?
Tell this man what is your name.
Lucía….
She arrived yesterday from Misiones.
Brand new.
And how should I know
she is brand new?
That no one touched her?
Easy, Tito,
it’s all checked out.
Tell this man how old you are.
Eighteen….
Of course, when they’re fifteen,
they’re eighteen.
And when they’re twenty-five,
they are also eighteen!
Hello.
Yes….
Is everything ready?
Is it all arranged?
Okay. I’ll be there shortly.
Let's go.
Hey.
Hey!
Wake up.
Maxi.
Hey, Maxi.
Today is the day.
Not everybody is here,
but we’re enough.
Today we define inheritance.
Dad….
Dad must decide
who will continue all of this.
Do you remember now?
Do you remember now,
Maxi, what we used to do here?
Maxi, it’s this and then
we are almost done.
Today it will be defined.
We’re all grown up….
Someday it was going to be our turn,
right?
This is a family issue,
and we need to solve it among ourselves.
There are a lot of ways to do it,
but it has to be done between you and me.
And if you don’t want to,
I and the guys
will agree to make a clean break.
And we will feel sorry for dad.
Héctor, you’re crazy!
We’re all crazy.
So, let’s finish this.
Yes or no?
Dad, we’re almost ready.
My sons!
This moon is tying the fate that
walked far for so many years.
You will feel the whip
on the back to stop,
and choose the path to take.
My little orphans,
I went back in time,
to flay the ox
and the seedless bull!
To hold you in the comfort of my love….
Dad, it’s so nice that you are here.
No, dad, I’m Héctor.
Dad, I’m your favorite.
I fulfilled everything.
Maxi is the traitor!
Maxi left you.
I’m your Tito, dad!
I’m your beloved Tito.
As you wish, dad.
You decided.
Thanks for choosing me.
It’s so nice to be with you.
I love you so much.
The wild horse doesn't get tamed,
the savage one doesn't get settled
the ring is not taken
if the horse bucks.
After the first there is no prize,
there is only slaughter!
The blood is drunk
and it gives power.
The lineage is absorbed
and never gets lost.
My boys, my orphans.
Long live the Espósitos!
Okay, thank you very much, guys.
It’s beautiful.
It seems like another house.
Yes.
Okay, kids, we’re here!
Come on, come on, it’s this way.
Now we’re going to see the house
and going to say hi to Maximiliano,
he will take care of you.
He is my brother, so from
now on, I’ll be your uncle.
Hey, you’re here!
Welcome, what a joy!
You’re going to have a lot of fun here,
and there is room for everybody.
Tomás! Come here, Tomás, my love.
Don't separate yourself
from the rest because you may get lost.
The house is very big,
and we’re going to see all of it.