- Master, are you all right?
- Yes.
I'm all right. I'm
lucky to still be alive.
We must get our Master Chen
to go into hiding at once.
Master, you'd better try and run.
Master, take care of
your leg. We'll cover you.
- Right. Be careful.
- Let's go.
Father. Take care.
Hey!
Yen Ting Hua, running dog of the Ching,
You should be ashamed
of your evil deeds.
- You bastard!
- Shut up!
I respect you, Chien Huan Li,
Because you are a brave man.
If only you will tell
me where Chen is hiding,
I will spare your life and reward you.
Stop it.
I'm one of the Sien Yi clan,
founded by our great hero Hiu Fei.
I'm no betrayer.
I wouldn't have anything
to do with you, you bastard.
You have created some evil
ways to terrorize our people,
And even if it costs me my life,
I will challenge you.
I advise you to think it over.
I want your life!
Huh! So, we'll see about that.
Now tell me where Chen is.
Haah!
We've just moved here,
And already you're causing trouble.
What have I been teaching you?
Study, and act with thought.
- What else?
- Train hard, to help others.
- Have you trained today?
- Not yet.
Grandpa, shall I start now?
Go ahead.
Finished.
It was much too quick.
I couldn't see it clearly.
I'm getting old, and my sight is going.
Once more, and slowly this time.
Oh.
Well, what is this?
Footwork
It looks all right, but not very steady.
Come on.
Proper stance. Oh!
You said a proper stance,
not an improper one.
Go on.
- Cross stance.
- What else?
Unicorn. Left, then right.
- Firm enough?
- Very firm.
- Then move.
- Oh. I can't.
Why not?
Because it's too firm.
Oh, really?
Hmm. Can you make another firm stance?
Oh, yes.
The twisted stance. Look at this.
Not that.
Another new one?
The upside-down.
Aah! Not that one!
Get up there!
Now stay there.
Stay steady, and mind my bowl.
This bowl I collect my income in.
Take care.
If anything happens
to it, you've had it.
Grandfather, where are you going?
I'm going to the toilet.
No! I can't bear it!
Come back quickly!
- This one is pretty.
- Ah.
This one is for you.
And this one is for you.
Unicorn!
No, I'm sorry. It's not for sale.
Here, son.
Place your bets!
Bet with your eyes. A
lot quicker than by hand.
Come on, place your bets.
I'll try.
Quickly. Quickly!
Place your bets! Hey,
hey, hey! Hands off!
There are only a few
winners. Hands off, hands off.
No bet.
Ahh! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Over to me. There we are.
Put it all on.
You don't really want to
play anymore, now, do you?
But it's so easy.
- Ah, so easy.
- I'll go when i've won this.
Ah. Don't move. Look!
No! You missed it!
Such bad luck. Beaten again.
I must win this time.
- Here, I'll do it.
- No, I'll do it.
Here, let
me change it. You won't regret it.
Just you wait and see, all right?
Ah, and now this one.
Open.
You win.
Winners again.
That's mine! That's yours.
For helping you to win, I'm
going to take this as my tip.
Good-Bye. Don't go. Let's go again.
No more now. You'll lose everything.
Mmm.
Eh? You're big. Why
didn't he see you?
Mmm. Slow up!
Wine and food? Celebrating
new year, are you?
- What do you want?
- You to stay away!
- Who are you to tell me?
- Who am I?
Huh.
You must have heard of the great bear.
And stony egg. And ironhead.
Watch out! That's me!
I don't give a damn who you are.
Go on, get him. Stay there!
You had better return all the money.
Right! Right!
- Why should I?
- Because of this.
Kill! Get him!
Huh?
Good.
He beat me.
Don't be worried, little
one. You must beat him back.
Don't you worry. I'll try.
Don't worry.
Hyaaah!
Stop!
An earthquake!
Ohh! Oh, my head!
There's a hole in the ground!
My head! Ohhh!
- What's your name?
- Stony egg.
But now... ohh!
You're a broken egg!
Now you're a scrambled
egg!
Now you're a rotten egg!
All right, Humpty-Dumpty?
And you're ironhead?
You hit there. Now hit there.
Go around!
Head up!
Turn away!
Run away.
Kill him!
You're a very big man
with a very small brain.
He's called the great bear,
but he looks smaller from here.
You wanna fight?
Help!
You nearly crushed me dead!
- You want the money back now?
- No, I don't!
- I'm going.
- Of course you can go now.
Don't try to follow me.
No, we won't follow.
W- What shall we do?
Get him up right now.
Let's go.
Mmm. Good wine.
It's from the same place?
Same shop as usual,
but it's much better.
Much more than usual.
- Yes, much more.
- Good boy.
- Where did you get the money?
- Huh?
I was very lucky. I found
some money out in the street.
That's why I bought it for you.
- You were lucky.
- Yes.
You go out and see if you
can find some more money.
The truth.
What's that?
One became two, two became
four, four became eight.
Oh. You've been gambling.
And they asked you to return it.
Yes! How did you know, grandpa?
And you showed them your kung fu.
No, I didn't. I merely struck
a pose, and they let me leave.
And what pose was that?
Well, it was very basic.
You twit!
I'll practice. You enjoy your wine.
- Wait.
- No need to train today?
- Yes, but I'll train with you.
- Huh?
Come on. Grandpa.
All's fair in love and
war. I'm your grandson.
Ah, still
up to your tricks again.
That is called short but dangerous.
Well, I'll take the short one, then.
Ohh! Aah! Aa-Aah!
Wait! We're not through.
You missed.
This is called long but powerful.
Whatever you say. Long and
short, I'll take them all.
Hey!
Practice makes perfect.
I'm sure you're right.
Rabbit. Broken thread.
Tree. Cloud.
Fisherman. Flying phoenix.
- Hey.
- I'm not through yet.
- The flute player.
- Hold it!
Tiger's tail.
Now let's practice.
Hey, where you going? Tiger's tail.
Tiger's tail.
First, second and third.
Iron gate. Iron wall.
Ha.
This is known as following the tide.
Now here I come. The sweeping broom!
Grandpa, take it easy!
I'm not like you.
Shooting star.
No!
Dizzy? Now I am.
No, no, no, no. On the head. Look up.
Casting the net. Snowflakes.
Rooting a tree. The mill.
Dragonfly. Forest birds.
- Come out.
- No. No.
- This bird's staying.
- You're not coming?
Oh. Maybe a little force will help.
No! No, no! No, no! No!
I- I'm coming.
Rolling guard!
One becomes two!
Two becomes four!
- Grandpa
- You idiot!
- My head's sore.
- Shut up!
Stick on the back.
Withdraw. Withdraw. Withdraw.
Let's see when you will behave yourself.
Sweeping strike.
Oh. Embrace the moon.
Advance to defend.
The swallow's jump.
- Why aren't you jumping?
- I'll jump later.
Later? I'll help you.
No, this is it!
- That's the end.
- What?
That's the end! But I'm starting.
Grandpa, stop or I'll die.
How will you learn if you stop?
How many times have I said, "don't
teach our kung fu to others"?
But you insist on doing it.
Our kung fu isn't illegal.
You mustn't teach other
people, or I'll thrash you.
Well, I'll try.
But you must.
Go and get yourself a proper job,
like everyone else.
You idiot.
Come on. Try it.
Mister, will
you buy-
Boy, why are you so happy?
Mister, will you buy
Mister, why the hell
are you so damn sad?
Is it you or me who's lost someone?
Now I'll serve you.
Here.
Mister,
This comes when we don't expect it.
You need someone...
to handle all the arrangements for you.
And now, remember that we
have all types of caskets...
poor type, normal type,
rich type, super-rich type.
And if someone comes in
dressed like me, then...
you show them this one here, huh?
And if someone comes in dressed in
filthy rags, then show them this one here.
This type is meant for the likes of you.
What? How can anyone be buried
in this thing? It's rotten.
Why not? All these coffins
have been used before.
At least more than three times.
- More than three?
- These are secondhand.
What's secondhand?
When we dig them up, that
is called secondhand goods.
- Who will buy them?
- Everyone.
My funeral parlor has a monopoly.
- We sell them.
- Is it ethical?
Ehh. No talk of ethics here.
Remember. Oh.
Also, you will have to
remember the various brands.
Now, this is teakwood,
rosewood, willow wood,
And that's cardboard.
When customers come,
knock and let them hear.
Boss, it sounds like plywood.
Hey, they're not to know that.
You're dumb. Come over here.
Now, my precious,
You're not for sale.
- Is it for you?
- Yes- Uh, no!
If the price is right, then
I'm willing to sell her.
Ah, I have polished her every day.
And, oh, don't forget to tell
the client her good points.
Which are?
Let me show you.
Now, living people would
find it comfortable...
because it is completely airtight.
- They'd suffocate.
- But not with a built-in fan.
Oh.
I wouldn't mind living in there.
Let me demonstrate. Inside.
Nice and comfortable.
So cool and peaceful.
Listen to this.
Come, listen. Listen to this.
It's like someone calling me.
Ohh! Ohh! Oh!
It's frightening.
Idiot! Would you like...
Would you like to try it?
It's too narrow.
But it's not.
It's big enough for three. Okay.
Aah! Ohh!
My god! What the hell's happening?
I was only demonstrating!
I didn't ask you to shut
me in! Let me out of here!
I'll kill you when I
get my hands on you!
You'll be in here,
and I'll be out there.
What are you trying to do to me,
you little bastard?
- Aaah!
- I can't get you out.
- Hey, did you find him?
- Nope.
He is nowhere.
- Hey, find him?
- No!
Damn his ass! Where
the hell has he got to?
I don't want trouble.
If you continue to follow me,
I'll break every bone in your body!
- Big brother.
- Damn it, who's your brother?
Uh, we three think that you
are the greatest. We really do.
You what?
I can't even take care
of myself, you fools.
You all want to end up being like that?
But, my brother, we
think you're the greatest.
The time is right.
You can make a lot of money.
Right! Why don't you make it, then?
I think you're all mad. Hey! Hey!
We can't make it without
you. I already have problems.
Don't you give me any more.
Hey, wait, we wouldn't dare
cause you trouble, my friend.
If I do any wrong, I'll
change my name to Rotten Egg.
Right, and you can break my
iron head any time that you like.
Hey, you've nothing to lose.
Come with us and meet our boss. Right.
Oh, then maybe I'll come along with you.
Well, now,
It's nice of you to come.
And what do you think of
Ti Cha's proposal, hmm?
Teacher? Who's the teacher?
No teacher.
Oh! My name is Ti Cha.
Said quickly together,
they sound the same.
It gives me an air of superiority.
- You must come from Japan.
- Why do you say that?
An imitation.
That's not funny!
Little gimmicks are important...
right. If you want to succeed.
Right. Right. Right.
My friend, why don't
you coach at our school?
Your monthly salary will be 100 tails.
On top of that, any fees
will be shared by us both.
Also, I'll pay when you fight.
- Isn't that fair?
- Yes! Yes!
One hundred?
One hundred.
I want it, but then
there's my grandfather.
He forbids me to fight anywhere.
You've no idea what he's like.
Hey!
All I know is, I have ideas.
Now, all I want is for you to fight.
- But my grandpa!
- You wait.
And that is all.
But will it work?
But of course it will.
Now, after lunch I'll take you
to see our beautiful school.
What is the everything clan?
Well, we teach every type of kung fu.
That's why we call the school that name.
What crap. You've nothing.
Hah, that's right.
When we started, two students,
and they're nonpaying.
Isn't that disgraceful?
So then, it's important to
choose the right name. Right?
Hah, right. My young friend, help me.
A name. Now, that's hard.
What do you teach?
We teach the S.S.S.
- No such thing.
- Huh? But of course!
First, let me explain
what they stand for.
One, you're smart if you join.
Two, it's the silver you must pay.
And lastly is our superb kung fu.
- What if I refuse to join?
- Well, then they stand for something else.
Firstly, you're stupid not to join.
Second, we're sorry we wasted time.
And lastly, you must leave soon.
Why not make me go?
Now, wait. Let me change first.
If you have guts, then
you'll wait. See to him.
Oh.
Uh, M-Master.
Master.
What's up?
Uh, business.
What business?
Uh, take a look. Come. Come.
He's the
bodyguard of a big brothel.
He-
Uh, I'm sorry.
He has students-
Some say 40 or 50.
If you beat him, they will come here.
One is 15 tails.
One-Fifty for ten. That
isn't bad money, huh?
Right.
Fifteen is 225.
- And 20?
- Three, clear.
- Thirty?
- Uh, that's...
Don't worry about that. Just fight.
But it isn't that simple. You look.
He is enormous and so damned fierce.
Just look at the size of what hits.
I won't fight. Get someone else.
Hey, we have a deal.
I use my head, you, your hands.
Well, how much will you pay
me for my hands, teacher?
Uh, all right, 50.
- Oh, it hurts!
- Uh, 60.
- Oh, my legs!
- Uh, 70.
- My stomach! My head!
- Uh, 80. 90!
- Oh, my shoes ache.
- The shoes ache? Uh, a hundred.
Eh? They've all stopped. Go first.
- You'll come?
- Oh, yes.
Hmm. Hmm.
Damn!
Is that fat fool coming out or not?
What is wrong, eh?
You haven't changed.
Heh. Very clever.
I am the master, after all.
I'm not cruel, so i've
decided not to fight you.
Bullshit!
I'll fight you if it's
the last thing I do.
You toady. You're
really asking for it now.
You insist?
Well, my lowest laborer
can give you a lesson now.
Okay? He'll enjoy it.
Here.
Now... Why are you here?
Master.
You idiot...
Now you teach him a lesson.
- That thing?
- Uh, right!
This one is good enough for you.
- Go on.
- Okay.
- Do you want to fight?
- Yes.
Don't get so mad. Have
a cup of tea first.
Heh! Ho!
What you looking for?
Be careful.
Woo-Woo-Woo-Woo-Woo
Aah!
Master, i've beaten him.
- Back to work.
- Hah!
Hmm.
Admit defeat.
You're beaten. "Yes."
You'll hand over the
protection money? "Yes."
And I'll take over your school? "Yes."
And you'll leave now? "Yes."
Did you hear that?
- Did you see that?
- Yes.
- Well, take him away.
Quickly!
- Hey there.
- Hmm?
Why are you standing there?
Are you the one who defeated Lu Ying?
Correct. I'm the one.
- You must be good.
- Hmm.
Yes, I am good.
In fact, I'm one of the best.
Oh. Then I want to
see how good you are.
Show me your finger technique.
Uh...
Eh? Nobody learns any of
my techniques without paying!
Right. Right.
Shiao Seng! Shiao Seng! Shiao Seng!
Shiao Seng!
Why don't you answer when I call you?
That's not my name.
It's what I call you.
Look. Another one.
Small one. He'll be easy.
Oh? Then how about a discount?
- Twenty percent.
- Good.
Let's start!
Name, please.
I am the willow sword.
What? "Shitso"?
Kicking!
I'm mad!
Waah!
More money against a sword!
- Uh, ten! What?
- Do it yourself!
- Well?
- Uh, 20?
- How much?
- Thirty!
More!
- Forty!
- Forty?
- Seventy! Seventy!
- Forty, maximum!
Aaah! Aaah!
- Double! Double!
- Double it?
It's a deal.
This time it's for real!
Did that hurt your balls?
Hyah!
Hah!
Try hitting it now.
Down! Up! Down! Up!
Down! Up! Down! Up! Down! Up!
Yeah! Music time!
It's stuck.
You're bleeding.
- Aaah!
- Wrong side.
That was bad!
I think you still have a lot to learn.
I'll show you what I know!
Aaah!
You stupid bastard!
This is not funny.
My advantage! Now see
about your britches!
Don't leave!
Now, don't use your sword.
Only when you have to.
Otherwise, you might lose your nose.
- Run!
- Aah! Yes!
- Come here.
- Yes, grandfather.
Grandfather.
Are you feeling better?
- Much better.
- You need more rest.
Hey, I'll get you some tea.
Where are you working now?
Still the same old place.
You must be good and obedient...
to the people you work for.
I'm very obedient.
- Is work hard?
- No, not at all.
Just fighting and...
Uh, grandfather, I'll
go and get your medicine.
Master.
What's wrong?
It's big business coming in.
- Big?
- Yes.
Take a look.
- Wow, he's huge.
- Yes, he is quite big.
Hey, I think I
know him. He's a...
Not as big as me. I'll tie
him up and throw him out.
You think that he's
as stupid as you are?
If you want to beat him, go ahead.
Uh, master, you can do it.
- You don't say.
- Yes, yes.
Look at yourself. You're wealthy.
- What?
- Gold there. More there. And there.
- Even your teeth are gold.
- They're not.
Well, almost.
You're wealthy now. You wear the best.
Your food's the best.
You're chubby all over.
We have to risk our lives to pay
for that? We'll soon be dead!
Well, if you don't fight him,
who's gonna pay all the expenses?
I don't know.
Eh, uh, 500 tails!
Five hundred?
- Y- Y-Y-Y-Yes!
- Promise?
Yes? All right!
Don't move!
Do you know him?
He's a sex maniac.
Really?
- Yes, you can go.
- Uh, thank you, thank you, uh...
Uh, where is he?
You go on out. Then I'll follow.
- You rascal!
- So says the master!
Oh!
Uh, not bad.
But it's nothing compared
to our little waiter.
Get the fellow out here!
Be patient.
You'll wear yourself
out before you start.
I've no time!
Let me tell you something.
Learn self control if you want to win.
Otherwise, you're as good as dead.
Goddamn you!
Eh, there he is.
Aah! You?
The master's
out, and I'll take his place.
Be careful of that
shark. He'll eat you up.
Aah! Yes.
Ooh!
Oh, you look so pretty.
My heart is throbbing.
I'm worried. You're so big and strong.
- Don't worry.
- But why?
Don't worry, don't worry.
Here, give me a kiss.
Oooh!
I'll hit you if you do that again.
Hit me again. Hit me all you want.
Oh, it's sore.
- Let me soothe it.
- No.
- What big hands!
- How big? Big enough to do this?
Aah! Do that, and I'll give you hell!
So, you know kung fu.
Just a little.
Right. Let's have some
fun!
What hairy legs! Oh!
Don't you think they're sexy? Whoo!
Wow! And such big feet.
To step on you with, stupid.
Huh?
Wait!
Wait.
Slowly, I'm going to
pull down the blind.
Hmm!
Well, what are you
doing, lying down there?
Are you angry?
Naturally!
Great. That's great.
Ooh! Mmm!
Let me do it.
L- Let me, let me.
He's a fella! Aah!
Huh? You're a fella? Oh. Waaah!
Hit this!
And this!
That's mine. Hand it over.
The money's mine!
Aaah! Take it back now!
H- He doesn't
want it!
Tell me, where is Chen
of the Sien Yi clan?
Oh... I...
Master, someone in the village
has put up the Sien Yi school sign.
What the hell is this?
Grandfather, don't feel sad...
if one day I should be killed.
This money is to provide for you.
Your loving grandson.
Three in a row! Yes!
- Every move is superb!
- Oh, look at that!
Better ones coming up.
Did you see that?
On the head! On the ass!
You see how obedient he is?
Yeow! One for the toe!
And one for the bottom!
Yaaah! He's gone for a crap!
A crap!
Well done! Now the
money will all be mine!
I can't wait to see it!
Nice.
Nuhh!
You lost on purpose! Are you
trying for another increase?
We made a deal. No more.
But this time I don't want anything!
Stop! You beat me!
You can take the money!
- Let me go!
- You can't go!
That beast said that I won!
I'm ruined!
Who are you calling a beast?
Well done!
Mister!
You're good. I'd like
to employ you here.
Get lost!
- He knows kung fu.
- Mind your own business.
What's wrong?
- How come you're so hairy?
- I'm not hairy.
It's up here.
Hey, who the hell was he?
Hey, what the hell was he
doing roaming around here?
That's true. That's right!
Found him! Say there!
You are?
- Where's my grandson?
- There aren't any grandsons here.
Who are you?
I am...
I am the leader of this place.
God damn him. That great name.
Hey, we've been very fortunate
since we changed the name.
Where's the master?
Yes, where is he?
He ran off long ago.
Hey, who are you?
I'm your master's master.
Master!
He's your man.
I've really had it this time.
My grandfather will kill me.
Boy, where does Chen Ping Fe live?
Silly boy.
Chen Ping Fe. Grandpa.
Chen Ping Fe, you can't run.
I won't run.
It's not that you
won't run.
You can't run.
Don't you feel lonely
living here alone?
You are always following.
How can I be lonely?
Chen Ping Fe, you'd
better start digging...
or you won't be buried.
Old man, you're too sick.
Get up.
Old man, you're finished.
I may as well kill you.
Aah!
The unicorn.
He won't escape.
Grandpa!
If you... Grandpa
wouldn't be dead.
If not for me, you would be dead.
Y- You bastard!
You should be ashamed.
It's all your fault.
Grandpa!
If you hadn't left a trail,
Yen wouldn't have found him.
Who's Yen? Why did he kill him?
Why did he kill grandpa?
He killed him because...
our clan fought the Ching.
You're with our clan?
That's right. Your
grandfather was looking for me.
You are... You
are the unicorn.
You're not fit to be his friend!
You just stood by while
he was being killed!
Tell me, how the hell could I help?
Even without kung fu, he'd win.
- Where are you going?
- To kill him.
You can't beat a cripple like
me. How can you beat him?
You go, and your grandfather's
body will rot here.
Grandpa!
As long as you're alive,
there'll be chances for revenge.
I'll kill him!
Aside from revenge, you must eat.
Try it.
Ah, don't eat rice.
Eat this!
Hey.
Eat.
Shing, take a rest.
Master, I'm not tired.
Master.
Oh, that really hurt.
Pull me along.
Come on.
Go on.
- What, no strength?
- I can't with you on top.
Well, I'm down now.
Then I can do it.
Oh!
- Did that hurt?
- Yes, of course.
That's because you didn't yelp.
Yelp? What?
Okay.
Yelp. Yelp.
- No more.
- Why not?
- It's time to go home and eat.
- Eat? Great.
- What's this?
- That one's for you.
Yelp. Yelp. Yelp.
Hey. Hey.
You're usually very happy. Why so sad?
It's far too much yelping.
Ah, get up.
You're out of breath. Breathe in.
All right.
Breathe out.
In!
Close your mouth. Swallow it.
Hold your breath.
Too late.
Yelp.
That was too early.
Master.
Keep working.
Master. Master!
Such a lot of commotion.
And you sleep through it like a pig.
Who's been here?
If someone had been here,
you'd be dead for sure.
Well, I will have
to sleep with one eye open.
Oh, like this?
In kung fu,
you must learn to use
your brains as well.
Otherwise,
you'll tire yourself.
Now, already you're losing your voice.
Show me.
I'll teach you to
adjust to circumstances.
Now, see if you can get past that door.
Go on.
Comfortable?
What's wrong now?
Don't let it slip.
Your waist.
Come here.
Up to your tricks again.
Move!
My hand. Now your legs.
Oh! Oh.
Just like a dead chicken.
You're getting stuck in the wrong door.
Forget it!
- There's another window.
- Thanks.
Useless bum.
Master, catch!
Well, not so bad, eh?
Not bad.
Now, catch!
Master. Master.
There.
I'm still one up on you.
Shing Lung, I'll go get some wine.
You wait here.
I'll go over there.
Hey, master, you gave me too much.
You...
What do you want?
Speak up.
Why the
hell did you attack me?
Dumb kid. And he's crazy.
Sir, let's go.
Goddamn!
Young man, what's your
grievance? You're crazy.
Your kung fu is not bad.
You dare fight me
without knowing anything.
You're dreaming.
You!
You must be tired of living.
I'll help.
How dare you bite me.
You stupid boy! Causing
trouble everywhere.
Sorry. He's always
causing trouble. Damn him!
Let's go home.
Lord, I beg your forgiveness.
If you're his grandpa,
you should teach him.
Yes, sir.
I'll take him home.
Sorry. Come on, you stupid boy.
The unicorn!
- He's disappeared.
- He can't get away.
Aah! You're so impulsive.
Fortunately I came in the nick of time.
How many times do I have to
tell you you must change?
I'm useless.
No good.
It's too late to be sorry.
You're lucky you didn't get
injured badly by them this time.
Lucky?
I am glad you were too angry
to remember our clan's kung fu.
He didn't know who you were.
Otherwise he would have killed you.
That's why he only
wounded you very slightly.
You were very lucky to
get away with your life.
Now,
Let me tell you something
about your kung fu.
It isn't too bad. It's
just that you're erratic.
That is why you feel so tired.
You can't attack well because
you're wasting your energy.
Then what do I do?
I think you know...
our clan's techniques by now.
Well, now I want to teach you...
a new technique.
This technique...
will be Jian.
Joy, sorrow,
down, up,
real, imaginary.
Play on your opponent's emotions...
and affect his judgment to win.
And remember that you are not alone.
Now I'm going
to teach you a new technique.
It's derived from the wire fist.
You must use your
brain and body together,
Thereby exerting your
power to the fullest.
Play on your opponent's basic emotions.
Joy will help you to remain here.
Anger allows you to attack viciously.
Sorrow will fool him till the very end.
Happiness will tease him and scare him.
Master.
Master!
Unicorn, let's see if you
can crawl any further now.
Stop! Damn, you beat an old man up!
Kid, you can speak.
I am not dumb, though you really are.
- Huh?
- Brother.
I will kill him.
You son of a bitch!
- You dare to call me that?
- You!
You damned idiot!
Can't you even stand up?
Chicken!
Use it.
Once more, please.
- Still bursting?
- Brother, feel better.
I'm better. Ready?
Missed me!
Missing something?
Kill him!
Kill the bastard!
Stay there, or I'll kill him!
No, don't worry.
Give that to me!
Killer!
If you must, you may as well kill him...
or he'll only be a useless cripple...
for the rest of his life!
You kill him!
Master, don't worry. I'll get them.
He will, but at what price?
Master!
I'm sorry...
You useless buffoon.
You damn fool, what do you want?
I'm avenging the death of Chen Ping Fe.
- Huh?
- You die!
Who is Chen to you?
Huh. Damn child.
I'm going to get rid of you.
Not easily!
You bastard.
Get up.
Get up!
Now you're going to die.
No matter. Steady.
Ah. Steady. I must...
get my... second wind.
Now, steady.
You are too late.
Huh?
Baby.
Huh!
Don't lean on me.
You were saying?
You're dead.
Grandpa.